<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Farming Practice in the Sand Hills Section of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1916-05-25">1916-05-25</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 156. Valentine Substation Bulletin No. 1. The University of Nebraska BULLETIN OP THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXVIII, Article IV FARMING PRACTICE IN THE SAND HILLS SECTION OF NEBRASKA. Report of Experimental Substation, Valentine, Nebraska. James Cowan, Superintendent. E. A. Burnett, Director. Distributed May 25, 1916. Concrete block barn at the Valentine Substation. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (thi itiim or ih( uaivusin.) HONORABLE PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, President, Falls City. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director; Animal Husbandry. C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. j. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomology. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy H. C. Fiixey, A. M., Farm Management. R. F. HOWARD, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. LOVELAND, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Snyper, M. S., Supt. of Experimental Substation, North Platte C. B. Lee, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry. Howard J. Gramlich, B. Sc., Associate in Animal Husbandry M. H. Swenk, A. M., Associate in Entomology. George K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. H. A. McComb, B. Sc., Horticulturist of Experimental Substation, North Platte. L. L. ZOOK, B. Sc., Assistant in Dry Land Agriculture, U. S. Department of Agriculture, North Platte. J. W. CALVIN, B. Sc., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. Erwin Hopt, B. Sc., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). J. A. Ratcliff, A. M., Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology E. G. WOODWARD, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper, B. Sc., Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, A. M., Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. 'Florence A. McCormick, Ph. D., Assistant in Agricultural Botany H. E. Vasey, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Jambs Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine FRITZ Knorr, B. Sc., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. 'Resigned. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS. PAGE Summary 5 Introduction 9 The demand for western experiment stations 9 Geography of the Sand Hills country 10 Primarily a cattle country 10 The Kinkaid Act of 1904 11 Valentine substation 11 Precipitation in the Sand Hills section 12 Description of Sand Hills soils 12 Dune sand or range land 12 Wet valley land 13 Little farming attempted in wet valleys 14 Improving wet valleys 14 Dry valley and bench land 15 Humus the great need of the Sand Hills soils 16 Other climatic conditions of the Sand Hills country 16 The Sand Hills farmer should be a stock farmer 16 The size of the farm unit 17 The substation soil is typical of that of the average Sand Hills homestead 18 Equipment at Valentine substation 18 Field experiment work 19 Improving Sand Hills pasture 19 Improving winter feed production 20 Alfalfa in the Sand Hills 22 Variety tests of clovers and alfalfas on light sandy soil 23 Depth for planting alfalfa seed on dry sandy land 26 Rate of seeding for alfalfa on dry soil 28 Inoculation in alfalfa culture 29 Alfalfa and sweet clover 29 How to keep a stand of alfalfa 31 Nurse crops in alfalfa growing 31 Prevention of soil blowing 32 The best time of year for seeding alfalfa 33 Rolling newly seeded alfalfa land 33 Row cultivation of alfalfa 34 Seeding alfalfa on sod 36 Cultivation of alfalfa 37 Preparation of ground for alfalfa 37 Other permanent forage crops 38 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Annual forage crops in the Sand Hills Sudan grass 39 4(1 Grain-producing sorghums Feterita 41 41 Corn in the Sand Hills Small-grain crops 42 4:5 Potato culture in the Sand Hills Variety tests Growing seed potatoes under a mulch Potato diseases and pests Stem rot The Colorado beetle 47 50 51 52 58 53 Rotation of crops in the Sand Hills Tree culture in the Sand Hills section 53 55 Preparing land for tree planting Planting so as to facilitate cultivation 55 56 Importance of clean cultivation in tree growing 57 Important points in tree culture in the Sand Hills Varieties of trees for the Sand Hills 57 58 Orchard and small fruits in the Sand Hills The kitchen garden in the Sand Hills Use of the feet in sowing garden vegetable seeds Lawns «0 61 82 63 Establishment of a dairy herd 65 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">SUMMARY. The Valentine Substation was established in 1910 for the purpose of aiding settlers and farmers in the Sand Hills district. There are nearly 20,000 square miles of Sand Hills country in Nebraska, situated in the northwestern section of the State. Of the total area, there is not at the present time more than 200,000 acres that is not settled, and there are no whole sections of 640 acres open to homestead entry. Generally speaking, the chief characteristics of the Sand Hills which affect farming are a light sandy soil, small precipitation, and extreme variations of temperature. The Sand Hills country is primarily a cattle raising country, but the Kinkaid Act giving 640 acres for a homestead instead of 160 acres as under the old homestead act has attracted settlers in large numbers, and many of these are farming in favorable localities with considerable success. The dry valley bottoms and the better portions of dune sand land are the principal farming lands of the Sand Hills country. Under cultivation, this land needs above everything else preserva - tion of humus or organic matter, to enable it to retain moisture and to prevent the blowing of the soil. No method of improving the range land in the Sand Hills country by the introduction of new grasses has been discovered, but the native herbage rapidly improves if it is not overgrazed and if fires are kept from running over it. The pasturage on the ranges is of good quality. The hay for winter feeding, while not equal in nutritive quality to the range grasses, can be readily and cheaply improved by growing red and alsike clover among it; also winter forage can be greatly improved on the drier farming lands by growing alfalfa. Work done at the Valentine Substation has proved that alfalfa can be grown in most sections of the Sand Hills country, and it is recommended that where possible it should be made to take the place of intertilled forage crops, because it would do away with the danger of soil blowing. It is also of more value than any other forage crop that can be grown. Experiments have shown that for this section of country alfalfa exceeds all clovers, includ - ing sweet clover, in its adaptability to the conditions found here, and that it is more valuable than any of them and costs less to seed. Sweet clover has been found more adapted to hardpan lands than to Sand Hills lands. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 6 Alsike and red clover, especially the former, are well adapted to wet valley meadow conditions, and when sown in with the native grasses are valuable for increasing the protein element in native hay. Slender wheat, brome, and western wheat grasses are the only grasses that succeeded in making stands under dry soil con - ditions on cultivated ground at the Substation. None of them made much hay, and it is questionable if it is profitable to attempt grass growing on any but wet valley bottoms under the prevail - ing conditions of climate. Sudan grass has yielded as high as 1,667 pounds of hay on light sandy soil when sown in rows 21 inches apart. Sown broadcast it yielded 1,649 pounds per acre. It is much relished by stock. None of the other varieties of grain sorghums tested at the Substation equaled the upright headed dwarf milo in yield. The yield amounted to 11.2 bushels per acre on light soil in 1913. this being the highest recorded yield of three years' investigation. Feterita is a good yielding grain sorghum and stands drouth well, but has not fully matured on the lighter upland soils. As a forage crop it is not relished by stock. Corn yielded 13.6 bushels under conditions similar to those in which milo gave a yield of 11.2 bushels. At the Substation the variety known as Minnesota No. 13 gave heaviest yields. Corn in the Sand Hills has shown a very decided local character. Imported corn rarely does well until acclimated. Of the so-called small grains, grown under conditions similar to grain sorghums and corn, the heaviest yields were obtained from winter rye, 11.80 bushels; emmer or spelts, 11.5C bushels; and winter wheat, 11.30. Along with the return given by the milo maize this shows a remar liable uniformity of yield in bushels per acre. All of these yields are strictly comparable with that of corn— 13.60 bushels. The Irish ICobbler potato has outyielded all other potatoes in tests covering three years. The best depth to plant in light sandy soil is from 4 to 5 inches. The best yields were obtained with rows spaced 42 inches apart and 24 inches in the row. The most profitable size of sets was medium quartered. Potatoes raised under ordinary conditions from seed that had been grown under a mulch yielded 13 bushels per acre more than when grown from seed that had been produced in the ordinary way. Potatoes grown on light, sandy soil under a mulch of 6 inches of hay yielded 50 per cent more than when grown in the ordinary way. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 7 Scab and stem rot are the only potato diseases of importance that have come under observation at the Substation. The formalin treatment has been applied with varying results. It is probably quite effective when the infection is confined to the seed alone, but the varying results obtained would seem to indi - cate that the disease is frequently communicated by the soil. In such a case, the only remedy would appear to be a rotation of crops. For the Colorado beetle or potato bug, arsenate of lead has been found as effective as Paris green, and there is less risk of injuring the foliage of plants when using it. Where a sufficient supply of manure is not available, or where owing to scarcity of moisture the ground is not capable of absorb - ing or assimilating sufficient manure, a rotation of crops is desirable in order to help to maintain the humus or organic matter in the soil. Alternating hoed crops with small grains helps. Many farmers practice a weed and corn rotation and claim success for this method. The best quick-growing varieties of trees are Norway poplar, cotton wood, and box elder, but the first two species are short - lived. Fast growing trees such as cottonwood, poplar, and box elder should not be mixed in with the slower growing varieties, but should be kept by themselves. Of the slower growing, deciduous trees, the American elm and the honey locust have done best; to these may be added the Russian olive, which is, however, moie of a lawn tree. Among trees of the coniferous order, bull pines have done best. Jack pines kill back and grow straggly and do not seem to have the vitality of the bull pine. Among other trees that have not done well are the ash, hardy catalpa, and red cedar. Cultivation is most important, since weeds are the main enemies of the trees which succeed here. The spacing should be such as to permit cultivation, preferably with a disk. Care should be exercised when cultivating, especially with a shovel cultivator, that the shovels do not tear and break the roots owing to overdeep cultivation. For tree culture in the Sand Hills country, clean cultivation and the preservation of an earth mulch is much more essential than watering. When watering has to be done, it should be done thoroly, and more in the shape of a soak than a sprinkle. The quantity of water which it takes to soak the roots of a tree thoroly is not frequently realized. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. Frequent light sprinkling is to be avoided, as it has a tendency to give the tree a shallow rooting habit. For the same reason, mulching with straw should also be avoided. Spirea Van Houttei has made the best lawn shrub under Sand Hills conditions. Next to it is the buffalo berry. Tartarian honey - suckle has done well also. Tamarisk and lilac, tho but recently planted here, seem to do well. Orchard trees, including apple, cherry, pear, and plum, do well in favorable situations, under conditions which include either irrigation or subirrigation, in the Sand Hills section. Where orchard trees are unsheltered from prevailing winds, or where they have to depend on precipitation alone for moisture, they do not as a rule prove a success. All varieties of small fruits grown in the Sand Hills are subject to practically the same limitations as orchard trees, and succeed or fail under practically the same conditions. Vegetables grow splendidly in the Sand Hills, especially in the valleys and in sheltered places where they can be irrigated or where there is subirrigation. Some varieties succeed on the drier uplands in light soil. Early planting is essential in this case. Great care should be exercised in planting garden seeds, especially in dry light soil, that the ground after sowing be well compacted. For this purpose it is best to use the feet, as the degree of compactness can be easily gauged by the feel of the ground beneath them. In laying down a lawn in the Sand Hills, it will frequently be found advisable to add sod to the surface soil. Well-rotted manure should also be liberally applied. Seed for lawns should be sown early, using a nurse crop of some tender grass which will kill out when frost comes. Top-dressing of lawns is of especial benefit in the Sand Hills, and old well-rotted manure should be used for the purpose. It is not necessary to keep a blue-grass lawn green during the hottest weather, as it has been found that it will revive quickly, even if allowed to get quite brown. In watering lawns the same principle as applies to trees is applicable. A lawn should be soaked, not sprinkled. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FARMING PRACTICE IN THE SAND HILLS SECTION OF NEBRASKA. BY JAMES COWAN. INTRODUCTION. This bulletin is to cover the experimentation undertaken at the Valentine Substation during the past four or five^ years, and it is hopedithat farmers thruout the Sand Hills section, and more particularly the large number of new settlers, will find it helpful in solving at least some of the problems'", which' confront them. Increased confidence is felt that it will be serviceable in this way, because of the fact that the experiments were not chosen in a haphazard or arbitrary way, but were selected as subjects for investigation solely on the evidence of the interest shown in them. During the year ending March 31, 1914, more than five hundred letters were received and answered at the Substation, a majority of which were seeking information on the subjects of farming practice discussed in this bulletin. Besides these, a large number were from persons residing in various parts of the United States, whose interest had been aroused by the recent land drawings. Generally speaking, the larger Sand Hills problems so far as they relate to farming are: (1) The conservation of moisture and of organic matter or humus in the soil; (2) the prevention of soil erosion by blowing, which causes loss thru the removal of the surface soil as also thru the abrasion and covering of grow - ing crops by the particles of sand and soil so shifted, or blown, as soil movement due to wind is locally termed; and (3) an increase in quantity and especially in quality of winter forage for stock. THE DEMAND FOR WESTERN EXPERIMENT STATIONS. Sometime previous to the year 1904 a demand had arisen in the western and mid-western sections of Nebraska for an Experi - mental Substation which might deal with the special agricultural or farming problems arising out of the climatic or other conditions peculiar to those parts of the country. It was in compliance with this demand that the North Platte Substation was established in that year. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. The demand for this western Experimental Substation was emphasized chiefly because of the difference between eastern and western conditions of climate, particularly as regards moisture. The amount of precipitation grows gradually smaller as an ad - vance is made in a westerly direction, until, as compared with that of the extreme eastern parts of the State, the precipitation on its western boundary is considerably less than half. As the only Experiment Station in Nebraska previous to the establish - ment of that at North Platte was at Lincoln, which is situated near the eastern boundary of the State, it was felt that experience obtained under the climatic conditions at the Station at Lincoln could not always be made the basis for recommendations appli - cable to farming in the western sections. But the work done at North Platte relative to soil tillage and other operations connected with crop production has been carried out for the most part on what is known thruout the west as "hard" or table-land, which, with local modifications, does not differ greatly from much of the farming land found in the eastern and southern parts of the State, and is therefore without particular reference to soil conditions prevailing on farming land in that portion of the State known as the Sand Hills section of Nebraska. GEOGRAPHY OF THE SAND HILLS COUNTRY The Sand Hills region of Nebraska stretches nearly three hundred miles, extending westward from about 98° west longitude. Its northern boundary is the Niobrara River, and its southern boundary the North Platte River. Its climatic conditions are similar to corresponding western parts of the State, but its soil, as stated, is essentially different from that of the "hard" land areas. The Sand Hills region covers an area of nearly 20,000 square miles, or about one-fourth of the area of the State of Nebraska. It contains many valleys of hard land, and many rich pasture districts, with smaller areas of meadow land inter - spersed. PRIMARILY A CATTLE COUNTRY. Until within rather recent years but little attention was given to the agricultural possibilities of this large section of the State, and it was devoted almost entirely to cattle raising, for which much of it is admirably adapted. But the steady westward movement of settlers and home - seekers at length called attention to it as a possible area for settle - ment, and homeseekers began to settle in the most desirable </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 11 places, especially along the lake margins and in the river valleys, where were situated the natural hay flats or meadows. In this way many of the desirable locations were taken up prior to the passage of the Kinkaid Act. THE KINKAID ACT OF 1904. The most outstanding feature of the Kinkaid Act was the amending of the old Homestead law so as to permit the home - steader to file on 640 acres, and under its operation the most desirable locations in the region were soon taken up. Amendments of this Act coming into force on June 6, 1912, accelerated the settlement of most of the land remaining open at that date, until at the present time less than 200,000 acres remain open for settlement over the Sand Hills section, and no entire home - steads of 640 adjacent acres are now included in the available area. VALENTINE SUBSTATION. Just as a demand had arisen previous to the year 1904 for a Subetation to deal with the hard land problems of western Ne - braska, so again in the years immediately preceding 1910 the need for a Substation to handle the Sand Hills problems and assist the farmers and settlers of that section in their efforts to raise crops and establish homes began to make itself felt. Pressure thus brought to bear resulted in the passage of an Act by the Legislature of 1910 granting an appropriation of $15,000 for the establishment of a Sand Hills Experimental Station under the direction of the Regents of the University of Nebraska. The land, amounting to about 1.984 acres of the old Fort Niobrara Military Reservation lying immediately east of the City ot Valen - tine, the county seat of Cherry County, and between that place and the Niobrara River, was leased to the University of Nebraska by the Secretary of War, with the understanding that it could be retained so long as it should be used for experimental purposes. Subsequently the land comprising the Fort Niobrara Reservation passed from the control of the Secretary of War into that of the Department of the Interior, and most of it was thrown open for settlement in the year 1914. That occupied by the Substation at Valentine was reserved and tendered to the University at the nominal price of $1.25 per acre, and has been purchased by the Board of Regents. Subsequent to the action of the Secretary of War, an additional 40 acres lying between the west line of the Substation and the city of Valentine was deeded to the University by the people of Valentine to be used as the site of the buildings and permanent </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 12 improvements. This land has been found of great value for experi - mental work, as it is representative of the lighter and drier Sand Hills farming soil. PRECIPITATION IN THE SAND HILLS SECTION. Following is a table showing the precipitation by months since the Substation at Valentine was established. As the average precipitation for 25 years at Valentine is 22.46 inches, and the average given in the table only 17.93 inches, it will be seen that the work done here has been handicapped with an average yearly shortage of 4.53 inches of moisture. Table 1. — Record of precipitation by months for five years, at Valentine, Nebraska, as reported by the United States Weather Bureau. Sap- I Oe- I No- I De- Year J»nu- Feb- , March April May June July Auf- tam- to- van- earn- An- ary ruary ust ber ber bar I bar null DESCRIPTION OF SAND HILLS SOILS. Exception is sometimes taken to the name of the Sand Hills section, but it is as descriptive of the general features of the country as any other could be. As will readily be understood from the name, sand of some description is the prominent if not the prevailing feature of the country. The various Sand Hills soils may be sufficiently classified for the present purpose under the names of dune sand or range land, wet valley land, and dry valley and bench lands. DUNE SAND OR RANGE LAND. Dune sand or range land comprises by far the greater portion of the total land area. This land, generally speaking, is more or less unfit for cultivation, altho it contains many level areas, which, with proper care, could be farmed profitably during years of average precipitation. As the land immediately surrounding the Substation is composed of this class of soil a number of the experiments given below refer to work done in connection with it. Dune sand land has been classified as level to rolling, very rolling to hilly, hilly to very hilly, and broken. The greatest ;»10. 1.61 I 0.27 Ml.... 0.40 0.71 ISM.... 0.49 0.34 I »&amp;.... 0.15 0.44 l»U 0.07 0.56 LtU. ... 0.67 1.36 If aim. 0.64 0.61 a, 0.48 1.26 1.19 0.47 bis I 0.12 2.34 2.43 2.94 3.53 2.27 1.16 6.12 I 2.14 1.37 0.99 i 0.68 3.06 0.99 : 2.07 I 3.13 1.03 3.94 1.69 3.94 1,13 2.06 j.41 2.06 4.96 3.60 ! 2.60 2.64 2.50 Mil 0.67 0.20 0.12 2.17 4.81 0.05 1.43 1.07 0.01 ; 1.16 0.19 0.45 : 2.65 1.79 0.08 l.«l 1.61 0.14 : 1.22 18.44 0.30 17.90 il.il 15.99 0.88 18.03 0.68 19.29 6.M 17.M </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 13 obstacle to farming in this class of land, apart from the nature of the soil, is the scarcity of moisture. To a certain extent as a consequence of these, there is a tendency of this soil to blow or drift after it has been cultivated for a few years. Fig. 1.— Blow-out in the Sand Hills It is this land that is used for summer pasture for the large herds of cattle that are found over the entire Sand Hills country. Used for this purpose the average capacity of this class of land would be about 32 head of cattle per section of land, or one head per 20 acres, while the average pasture season per year would be about seven months. The poorer portions of this class of land are almost pure sand from the surface downward, while in the better stretches the soil is a sandy loam, generally shading away to pure sand at a depth of from 30 inches to 3 feet. Generally speaking, this land is well covered with grasses which form a nutritive summer feed. The most conspicuous of these are little bluestem, Hall's beard grass, long-leaved reed grass, and western stipa. The Sand Hills pasture land is wonderfully rich in its variety of natural grasses. WET VALLEY LAND. In striking contrast to the range land just described is the much more limited tho fortunately quite extensive class of land known as wet valley land. It is on this land that the greater proportion of the winter feed for cattle — native hay — is produced. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. This class of land is known geologically as Gannet fine sand, and is classified as a soil formed from wind laid deposits. Altho its name suggests sand, the soil itself is much more suggestive of muck and has been formed on this deposit by the decay of rank growing vegetation induced by the wet situation, for these wet val - leys are the natural reservoirs of the surrounding country thru which they are distributed. Sometimes the reservoir takes the form of a shallow lake of dimensions which vary according to the seasonal or periodic rainfall. The surrounding hay meadows vary in size with the rise or fall of the lake. Others are all meadow at the drier seasons of the year, but often become shallow lakes during more moist seasons. In these valleys a few of the most valuable grasses are western wheat grass, slender wheat grass, big blue - stem grass, switch grass, wild timothy, and wild rye grasses. These valleys, while widely scattered over a vast area, are more numerous in the northern portion of the Sand Hills country. If a line be drawn straight south from Valentine for a distance of about forty miles, the main portion of the wet valley lands will be found to dot the country east and west of such a line. These valleys run for the most part in a general west-to-east direction. They are comparatively narrow, have abrupt hills rising on each side, but especially toward the north which makes them ideal winter feeding grounds for stock. Being sheltered from northern winds, and with hay close at hand, stock can be winter fed at a minimum expense. LITTLE FARMING ATTEMPTED IN WET VALLEYS Some farming has been done along the higher margins of such valleys. Corn has been raised, and alfalfa finds a congenial place when not too close to subsurface water. For the most part, however, these lands are covered with a rank growth of grass. IMPROVING WET VALLEYS Within recent years systematic and efficient drainage has been carried out in a number of these valleys, draining the lakes and marshy spots and adding large tracts to the hay-producing lands of the region. When drainage is effected, the reclamation of the land is generally still further enhanced by seeding in timothy, alsike, and red clover, by scattering the seed over the surface. This sowing of leguminous seed is especially to be commended as a cheap method of supplying the nitrogenous or protein element which it is said is lacking in the native hay of the Sand Hills country. No sufficient data are at hand in regard to the value of such valleys for agricultural purposes. Surrounded by cattle ranges, they will probably always have their greatest </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Farming Practice in the Sand Hilk. 15 value as winter-feed producing lands for wintering live stock. It is probable that with enough drainage to lower the water level sufficiently beneath the surface they might be made to grow immense crops of clover and especially of alfalfa, which would be of greater value than native hay. DRY VALLEY AND BENCH LAND. The dry valley country is the third of the soil areas into which the Sand Hills country has here been divided. It is probably the most interesting from an agricultural standpoint, as it is certain that a greater variety of agricultural activities can be developed upon it than upon the other areas. It may be said to partake more of the nature of the hard lands than the others de - scribed. As indicating this, it is not uncommon to meet with stretches of buffalo and grama grass in these dry valleys in addition to many of the grasses mentioned above as common to the other divisions. These dry valley soils may be generally described as formed from water deposits, superimposed upon sand to a less extent than in the case of the "wet" valleys — which have a muck soil intermingled with wind blown sand. Geologically it is de - scribed as Valentine loamy sand. In general, these dry valleys have water underlying them, but the natural drainage is such that the water is retained at a sufficient depth below the surface to allow cultivated crops to be raised. Generally these valleys may be described as subirrigated, but they are not all so, and frequently their condition as regards moisture and moisture storage capacity resembles the better class of level or cupped dune sand land and valley bench land with which they are here classed. They are situated for the most part in the southern section of the Sand Hills country, the center of their area being probably somewhere in McPherson County. Previous to the passage of the Kinkaid Act, Sand Hills home - steading was largely confined to the wet valley country, as the possession of hay land gave the key to the surrounding range land, which was at that time public domain. It was these earlier settlements that later became the nuclei of the large cattle ranches of the present day. When the rush of Kinkaid settlers began after 1904, it was found that a considerable amount of the wet valley lands, or hay meadows, was already deeded. The remainder was rapidly taken, and the later settlers frequently found them - selves compelled to homestead in the dry valleys or on the better class of dune sand and bench lands, where sufficient native hay could not be cut for their own use. It therefore became necessary to raise winter feed by tillage. This was generally done by attempting to raise corn fodder and cane. Along with these the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 16 homesteader grew vegetables, including potatoes, which grow well in the Sand Hills under favorable conditions. Frequently some small grains, such as oats, rye, and white spring emmer (spelts) for draft animals, and poultry, were grown. Thus, farm - ing was gradually instituted in the Sand Hills country proper. HUMUS THE GREAT NEED OF THE SAND HILLS SOILS. For the first few years good crops were raised, if there was sufficient rainfall, and so long as the vegetable matter contained in the grass sod turned under with the first breaking lasted there was little or no trouble. But organic matter is quickly depleted in a hot sandy soil. The fibrous vegetable matter which gave the soil cohesion becoming used in part, and the ability of the soil to store moisture being thus lessened, it became more fre - quently dry than previously. The combination of dryness and looseness thus brought about by tillage of the soil combined with the action of high winds soon started that blowing or drift - ing of the upper soil which is one of the chief difficulties with which the Sand Hills farmer has to contend, and which, if unchecked, will, in the course of a few years, convert a fertile field into an immense sand pit. OTHER CLIMATIC CONDITIONS OF THE SAND HILLS COUNTRY. The question of moisture in the Sand Hills country has already been referred to and a table covering the last five years of precipitation given. Neither in this respect nor in any other referring to climate does the Sand Hills district greatly differ from corresponding longitudes in other parts of the State, except that, owing to its greater altitude and the more active radiation from the sandy soil, the nights are cooler, and the safe period for maturing such crops as corn and grain sorghums is correspond - ingly snorter. THE SAND HILLS FARMER SHOULD BE A STOCK FARMER. The Sand Hills farmer should be a stock farmer, for reasons so obvious that it is not necessary to discuss them within the limits of this bulletin. At present, the Substation at Valentine is engaged in trying to throw light on whether he can profitably be a dairy stock farmer, but as this work is only in its initial stage it will not be discussed here. In the meantime the chief problem is how to raise the most valuable kind of stock feed without deteriorating the land, which after all is only a Sand </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 17 Hills phase of the problem of how to make the farm pay without decreasing the stored up productivity of the soil, the accomplish - ment of which has been quoted as the chief end of good farming. Fig. 2.— Native Sand Hills pasture. THE SIZE OF THE FARM UNIT. Mature has established a rough balance between the capacity of the Sand Hills range for summer feeding and the capacity of its winter-feed producing lands. Granted the homestead of 640 acres as the proper unit in Sand Hills farming, how much of this should be winter-feed producing land to enable the farmer to stay with his homestead? No attempt is made here to define how much land a farmer ought to have. The law has already fixed the number of acres which he can have under the Home - stead Act as stated above. Probably 150 acres is a fair average for producing winter feed. Some contrive to get along with less, but a little more would be better. Eighty acres of good hay-producing land would furnish him with all the winter feed for the cattle his pasture would carry; 100 acres would be ample for both them and his work animais. In good years he might have some hay to sell. An additional 60 acres would be ample for raising his cultivated crops, such as potatoes, corn, cane, rye, and spelts. This would permit the use of his manure and rotation to assist in keeping his soil from blowing. A good proportion between pasture and cultivated </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 18 land would be three-fourths pasture and one-fourth crop-produc - ing land. Undoubtedly authorities would differ widely about this proportioning, but it may be accepted as near the average. THE SUBSTATION SOIL IS TYPICAL OF THAT OF THE AVERAGE SAND HILLS HOMESTEAD. About one-fourth of the land at the Substation is capable of cultivation and about three-fourths is suitable only for pasture. That is, out of the 1,124 acres which comprise the entire farm, considerably less than 300 acres is fitted for hay or other crop production. The range or pasture land represents every one of the classifications as applied previously to this kind of land. There is no land of the wet valley description, but both the sub - irrigated dry valley land and the dune sand land, or Valentine sandy loam soil without subirrigation, are well represented. On these, many experiments have been conducted with such crops as alfalfa, corn, cane, grasses, grain sorghums, garden truck, and trees, while methods of controlling blowing soil, the conservation of humus or organic matter, and moisture have been studied. Attention has also been given to the effect of various methods of handling manure on such land. EQUIPMENT AT VALENTINE SUBSTATION. When first placed at the disposal of the University Board of Regents, the land now comprising the Valentine Substation was open prairie land none of which had ever been fenced or broken. The pasture land was cut up by numerous wagon trails over which freight had been hauled to Fort Xiobrara from the town of Valen - tine and vicinity. These trails and the unlimited grazing to which it had been subjected while lying as opsn range in the vicinity of a cattle-shipping point had rendered it bare in numerous spots where the sand had blown out and completely destroyed all vegetation. During the first year of occupation this land was fenced, and stock of all kinds was excluded. The larger blow-outs were covered over with stable litter and otherwise treated to prevent further drifting of the sandy soil. This treat - ment has resulted in a great improvement of this land, and it is a reasonable estimate that the amount of grazing available at the present time is 40 par csnt greater than it was before the land came under Substation management. In the spring of 1910 as soon as title had been acquired to the land donated for a site by the citizens of Valentine, plans for a number of cement block buildings were prepared. These consist of a modern, furnace heated, 8-room dwelling house with full basement; a horse barn 36 by 54 feet with hay storage above; </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 19 a dairy extension 35 by 62 feet; an implement shed 20 by 60 feet with storage above, and an engine room, boiler room, milk separating room, and workshop; a silo 16 by 32 feet; ice house, root cave, water tower, well, etc. As sand is one of the pre - vailing commodities of the country, it was determined to demon - strate its usefulness by making these buildings of cement blocks. Fig. 3. — Concrete block residence at the Substation. FIELD EXPERIMENT WORK. If we consider only the natural feed resources of the Sand Hills country, it will be generally conceded that as between the nutritive quality of summer pasture and natural hay fed in winter, the winter feed is the more needful of improvement. This is largely because winter conditions are much more exacting than those of summer, but it is also quite probable that the coarser hay grown for the most part in muck soils is less nourishing in its natural state than the finer mixed grasses found on the ridges and uplands. IMPROVING SAND HILLS PASTURE. So far as is known, nothing has been found so well adapted to the sandy pasture areas of the Sand Hills country as the native grasses. The amount of pasture produced on any given area where </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 156. these grasses grow is in direct proportion to the amount of seasonal moisture available. This is because sandy ridges and the lighter class of dune sand land do not conserve moisture. This being so, the hope of improving Sand Hills pasture lies more in better management of existing resources than in intro - ducing new varieties of grasses, which, even if found suitable, would be subject to the same limited supply of moisture as those now growing there. Better management in this case would con - sist of more moderate grazing and less trampling by stock, also the prevention of fires as far as possible, and the covering of bare places with light manure, coarse wild hay, cornstalks, or litter of any sort that would help to hold the loose soil from blowing, and provide a lodgment in which seeds could take root. A good deal has recently been written about the value of sweet clover for sowing in bare sandy spots and blow-outs, and many experiments with it for this purpose have been made at the Substation but without much result. Where sand has drifted on to a clayey subsoil or where sand has been blown off and left a hard pan subsoil exposed, it has been found that sweet clover will take root and flourish if it gets into contact with the subsoil; but where the sand is deep and dry, very little success has been attained even when assisted by a mulch of manure or litter. In such situations, weeds of various kinds often do well, and if the seeds of these are encouraged to grow they will fre - quently take root and help to bind the sand. Work along this line has brought better results than trying to grow sweet clover in such places. Objection might be raised to growing weeds, but the main thing to do with a blow-out is to stop it if possible. Little fault is to be found with the quality of summer pasture in the Sand Hills, as stock fatten rapidly on it whenever there is abundance for their requirement. IMPROVING WINTERIFEED PRODUCTION. Fortunately the question of improving winter feed by the introduction of tame or imported varieties of forage or hay - producing plants is very much more simple than that of the improvement of pastures. As pointed out, progressive stock owners are doing so by introducing such leguminous plants as red clover and alsike into their meadows by simply scattering the seed on the surface early in spring and letting the weather work it into the ground. Alsike has been found best suited to the lower lying situations, and red clover to the drier parts of the wet valley hay meadows. On dry valley bottoms, alsike is not suitable, but red clover seeded in the meadows does very well after it has once obtained </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 21 a stand. In such situations it has been found advisable to plant it (1) with a disk drill, having previously removed the press wheels, or (2) by disking the sod with a common disk and sowing broadcast. In the latter case a good deal of seed is lost, as all does not hit the disk cuts or trenches. Red clover seeded in native grass meadows at the Substation on what may be classed as dry valley bottom land has increased in quantity every year, producing an abundance of seed and reseeding itself. Sweet clover is also easily seeded in native hay meadows. While to a certain extent it must have reseeded itself in the meadows here, it does not thicken to the same extent as red clover. At the Substation this is considered fortunate, and it is hoped that it will soon disappear, as it is looked upon as a detriment to any meadow, having passed the proper stage for harvesting long before the haying season is on. Its woody stalks look like large last year's weeds among the grass and would detract from the selling value of the hay. Alfalfa has been seeded in the meadow here in the same way as described above in the case of the clovers, but made no stand. Red clover alone has increased the value and quantity of hay cut and justified the cost of seeding in a dry valley meadow. The quantity of seed required if a good stand is wanted at once is about the same as should be used when seeding on tilled land, as much of it is lost under the conditions of meadow seeding. Under favorable conditions, a full stand can be obtained when seeding clovers on sod by using either 8 pounds of alsike, 12 pounds of red clover, or 25 pounds of sweet clover per acre. It should be remembered that alsike is best for very wet land only, and that sweet clover is objectionable for the reasons given above, in either wet or dry valley meadows. Much lighter seed - ings than those aforementioned can be used, of course, if the owner of the land is content to wait until the clover gradually thickens as it seeds itself. All work of this kind should be done as early in the spring as possible, as the clover seed has then a better chance of connecting with the soil than when the ground is dry and hard. The young clover also does not have to compete with the growing grass so much as if it were sown later. At the Substation in the spring of 1915 an experiment of sowing patches of red clover on the meadow just before the snow had quite disappeared was tried. No preliminary preparation of the ground had been made for this purpose. The practice has not given good results. On reclaimed wet valley land, however, the soil conditions are more favorable for sowing on top of the ground. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. ALFALFA IN THE SAND HILLS. If red and alsike clovers find their best application in the wet valley meadows of the Sand Hills, where no cultivation accompanies their seeding, alfalfa is undoubtedly the chief legu - minous crop of the dry valley and bench lands as well as of the heaviest class of dune sand land. Realizing this, more work has been done with alfalfa than with any other single crop. At the time this Substation was established, a limited amount of alfalfa was being grown thruout the Sand Hills; and while, in the opinion of those best qualified from their acquaintance with it to judge, it was considered an entirely successful crop, a large number of people were more than doubtful as to the advisability of trying to grow it. But within the last few years this doubt has disappeared, and it would be hard now to find a settler who is not either already provided with a patch of alfalfa or planning to get one. Experiments have covered pretty fully the following points of investigation: 1. Character of Sand Hills soils on which alfalfa will succeed. 2. Tests of varieties for Sand Hills. 3. Comparative tests of varieties of alfalfa with some clovers, especially with sweet clover, as to drouth resistance on light soils. 4. Depth at which seed should be placed in light soils. 5. Amount of seed per acre and best method of sowing and covering. 6. Comparative tests of spring and fall seedings. 7. Experiments with inoculation. The results of the investigation indicate the following: Subirrigated dry valleys with permanent water not less than 6 feet from the surface make the best alfalfa ground. On such ground, generally speaking, there is little difficulty in getting stands of alfalfa. As far as is known, alfalfa on such land is reasonably permanent, being less so as the distance to water decreases. On such land at the altitude of the Substation (2,859 feet) three and sometimes four crops totaling, on an average of two years, a yield of over two tons per acre -have been cut each year. On bottom land, not subject to subirrigation, the yield is lighter, and the number of cuttings is less. On the better class of dune sand land two light cuttings a year and in some years one, have been sufficient to exhaust the moisture in the soil. As showing what land of this class will do under more abundant moisture conditions, at the Substation this year (1915) four cuttings of alfalfa have been obtained from one and a quarter acres, totaling in weight of cured hay 8,475 pounds, or at the rate of 6,780 pounds per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 23 VARIETY TESTS OF CLOVERS AND ALFALFAS ON LIGHT SANDY SOIL. The variety tests of clovers and alfalfas were begun on light sandy soil in 1910. The land was broken from sod about the end of June of that year. The work was not well done, as the surface sod had dried out and was difficult to break. The ground immediately after breaking was disked twice and harrowed. Seed was broadcasted with a hand seeder and covered by harrow - ing. The work of seeding was done July 2, following a heavy rain. The plots were half an acre in size. No cutting was done the first year. Few weeds grew, and the land was covered before frost with a light dressing of manure put on with the spreader at the rate of six loads per acre, to help in protecting the young plants from frost. Fig. 4.— Dry land alfalfa field. The depth of covering was about the same for all except that the unhulled sweet clover seed was planted deeper. The first table gives the time taken to germinate and the percentage of stand one month later. The rain during July, 1910, amounted to 2.14 inches, making the moisture condition favorable for obtain - ing stands of alfalfa or clover. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. Table 2. — Results of variety tests of clover and alfalfas on light sandy soil. Later, the sweet clover thickened to 60 per cent, subsequently to what appeared to be a full stand. On the other hand, all the other clovers thinned out more or less. Alfalfas held their own. No mowing was done the first year, but one mowing was done the following year, 1911. The dry weather succeeding the first mowing and lasting during the whole of June, July, and well into August, scorched the plants to such an extent that they did not recover until late in the fall. The fall of 1911 was damp, and subsequently these made strong growth and W»nt into winter in good, strong condition with the exception of the alsike and mammoth clovers. The following yields were secured from the first cutting, which was made June 22, just as the dry weather began to affect the growth: The weather for six weeks succeeding the harvesting of the foregoing was the driest on record for the time of year. This burned down the crop to such an extent that little recovery was made till October, in spite of a wet fall, and no more harvesting was done. The following spring, 1912, it was found that the mammoth and alsike clovers had almost disappeared and that the red clover was also much reduced in stand. The alfalfas and sweet clover stood the winter well and the former was twice Variety Date of sowing Date of germination Nature of stand August 2 jrimm alfalfa Common alfalfa Furkestan alfalfa Red clover \lsike clover Mammoth clover Sweet clover July 2 2 2 2 2 2 •&gt; July 10 10 12 8 8 10 27 Per cent Full stand 85 75 55 50 15 30 Variety Grimm alfalfa Common alfalfa Turkestan alfalfa Red clover Sweet clover. . . . Alsike clover. . . . Mammoth clover Pounds hay per acre June 26, 1911 1,580 1,550 1,240 800 1,560 too poor to cut showed only a few bunches and was not cut </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills 25 harvested, but the second crop of sweet clover was allowed to seed out as given below: Table 3. — Comparative yields of alfalfa and sweet clover, 1912. The reduced cutting in June from that of the previous year was undoubtedly due to the continued scarcity of moisture. A shortage of 11 inches from the average was registered in the period covered since these crops were sown. The average pre - cipitation in this district covering a 25-year period was 22.46 inches, while in 1910 it was 18.45, in 1911, 17.09, and in 1912 only 15.99 inches. The sweet clover made a satisfactory second growth but was not cut, in order to give it an opportunity to re-seed, which it did, but this failed to germinate. Possibly the drouth of the succeed - ing very dry season was the cause for the failure, altho it has sub - sequently been found that sweet clover fails quite frequently to re-seed itself on this class of land. The field was converted into a horse paddock in the fall of 1913, and in 1914 the alfalfa which was the last survivor of all the varieties tested had itself mostly disappeared. In the foregoing it will be observed that the variety known as Grimm alfalfa has apparently stood the test of extreme dry weather better than the others, yielding more than either the common or the Turkestan. This apparent superiority of Grimm alfalfa, however, has not shown in more extended tests, common alfalfa yielding just as well in general. In the case of the depth seedings as exhibited in Table 4, where careful records of yields were kept, it will be found that those from common alfalfa considerably exceed those of the Grimm variety. Grimm alfalfa has shown a rather finer quality of hay at the Substation, but whether this is an inherent quality or due in this case to some other cause has not been determined. The foregoing is only one out of about 40 parallel experiments in seeding alfalfa and sweet clover, which have led to the con - clusion that alfalfa will grow on sandy soil wherever sweet clover will. Variety First cut in lbs. June 22 ! Second cut in lbs. Aug. 26 Total per acr&lt; Mmm alfalfa Common alfalfa Turkestan alfalfa Sweet clover 1,340 1,180 960 1,325 "i 700 400 300 not cut 2,040 1,580 1,260 1,325 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. Bulletin 156. Furthermore, some of these experiments show that it will grow where sweet clover sometimes fails, and that for general purposes it is the best and most profitable leguminous crop that can be raised on cultivated land within the Sand Hills area. No inoculation was given the seedings described above. So far, then, as the experiment goes, it went to show: 1. That alfalfa will grow well on sandy soil without inocu - lation. 2. That alfalfa is fully as hardy under trying Sand Hills conditions as any of the clovers, including sweet clover, with the advantage over the latter that the alfalfa does not need to re-seed, while the other does and in this case failed. 3. That as the years in which the experiments described were conducted were years of small precipitation, averaging approximately 6 inches a year below normal, it is probable from the showing here made that a ton and upward of alfalfa could be cut per acre in an average year, and that on light sandy ground, such as is to be found almost anywhere in the Sand Hills country. 4. That while the table given here shows the heaviest yield in the case of Grimm alfalfa, this has not been the case in more extended tests in which common alfalfa has yielded as well and in some cases even better than the Grimm variety. DEPTH FOR PLANTING ALFALFA SEED ON DRY SANDY LAND The question as to what depth alfalfa seed should be planted on dry sandy land is one which is very frequently asked, and at the Substation some experiments to determine this important point were undertaken. In order to make sure that the seed was being placed at known depths, the Brott method of row seeding was adopted. This is a method of seeding alfalfa origin - ated, or in any case brought into prominence, by Mr. Lewis Brott, a farmer who resides near Sextorp, Cheyenne County, Nebraska, who has been successful in raising alfalfa seed on high, dry uplands, and who has published a pamphlet describing his methods. It is substantially as described below except that Mr. Brott advises much heavier seeding. The distance between his rows also is less than the 42 inches adopted for convenience at the Substation. The corn planter is fitted with wooden slippers, which can be adjusted on the stub runners at any depth required. Onion seed plates with a brush cut-off are then used in place of the ordinary corn drop plates. The seed was deposited at the rate of from 3 to 4 pounds per acre, at depths varying from one-half inch </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 27 to 6 inches. The corn planter was not altered to give narrower rows, so that the distance between these was 42 inches. The work was done on a very light sandy loam. The three varieties of alfalfa mentioned in the previous experiment were used in duplicated plots of one-tenth acre each. The weather succeeding sowing, which was done near the end of June, 1911, was exceed - ingly hot and dry, the precipitation for that month being only 0.99 inch, while the next month had only 0.68 inch. Under these conditions broadcasting alfalfa on this class o* land was a complete failure. Seeding by the corn planter method was a failure at a less depth than 1 inch, and also at depths below 4.5 inches. The table given below will show the further results. It is assumed that there are 4,200 feet of row in an acre when rows are 42 inches wide. This is close enough for this comparison. The combined rainfall of April and May previous to harvesting totaled slightly over 6 inches, while June was hot and dry with little over 1 inch. Cultivation between the rows was given with a five-shovel one-horse cultivator early in April when the plots were also cross harrowed with a drag. A second cultivation, but without harrowing, was given during the second week in May. The plots were mowed on June 17 and harrowed as soon as the crop was harvested. Subsoil moisture was scarce, and this com - bined with scorching weather after harvesting, gave the second growth a poor start which the copious rain of July did not fully recuperate. No second cutting was made, and in August the plots were turned into a hog pasture and grazed down. Below will be found the yield from the various depths of seeding. Table 4. —Comparative yield per acre of alfalfa planted at various depths. 1913. 1 inch !1J inches 2 inches 2J inches 3 inches 4 inches The foregoing would seem to indicate that, generally speaking, alfalfa seed is not sown deep enough on very light unretentive soils. It looks as if a depth of 2 inches is the best for seeding, and when it is remembered that the depths given above are in compressed earth this is all the more significant, as any depth in compressed earth may reasonably compare with a depth one- Variety irimm alfalfa "'ommon alfalfa furkestan alfalfa deep Lbs. 1,420 .! 1,590 950 ! deep Lbs. 1,580 1,480 1,160 deep Lbs. 1,620 2,040 1,220 deep deep ! deep Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. 1,160 1,390 800 1,860 1,680 1,120 1,300 800, Lost note </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. half inch greater in loose soil. It should be noted that this seeding was done after the soil was thoroly warmed, and also that the weather was exceptionally hot and dry while the seed was ger - minating. Earlier seeding with cooler and damper weather might show something different from the foregoing. Generally speak - ing, alfalfa seed should be less deeply covered in the spring than later on, as the soil at that season is cold after the winter period, and seed sown too deeply is liable to rot. There is little danger of covering alfalfa seed too deeply with the drag on sandy land. At the Substation it has been covered by disking on this class of land and has done well. RATE OF SEEDING FOR ALFALFA ON DRY SOIL. In the spring of 1913, experiments were conducted to find the best rate of seeding on light, dry, sandy soil. Here again the three varieties of alfalfa already mentioned were used in duplicate one-tenth acre plots. The seeding of each of these was done at the rate of 2, 4, 8, 12, 14, 18, and 24 pounds per acre. The land broken in 1911 was planted to fodder corn, backset the following spring, was sown to rye, and grazed off and disked. Some manure was spread over it in the spring. After disking and working over, it was used for the purpose here indicated. In 1913, the alfalfa seed was sown broadcast and covered with a drag harrow. As dry weather followed the sowing, it was rolled. A stand was obtained on all the plots. This was clipped with the mower in the fall, as it had become weedy. The following year, 1914, it was cut once for hay, with the following results. Table 5. — Yield of alfalfa at different rates of seeding. Pounds per acre seeded 2 4 8 12 14 18 24 These figures show the best seeding to be between 12 and 18 pounds. This has been found correct on this class of soil in other work at this Substation, and seeding is now done at about 15 pounds per acre on well-worked and packed soil. Much depends on the soil being in good tilth. Seed can be saved by sowing on a good seed bed, as less of it is lost in good, firm soil. The reader rnmm alfalfa ... ommon alfalfa . 'urkestan alfalfa 380 440 300 790 920 500 1,110 1,220 980 1,480 ; 1,540 i 1,250 I 1,460 | 1,600 ! 1,120 1,600 1,410 1,180 i 1,440 1,400 1,060 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Farming Practice in the Sand Hilh. 29 may compare the heaviest yields in the above table with the heaviest yields when sown in the row system as recommended by Mr. Brott. It will be found that the row system gives the heavier returns. It is not believed, however, that this would be the case in richer or moister soil. These experiments are not strictly comparable, because the latter was conducted one year later than that with the alfalfa in rows. Aside from this the rainfall in the latter year, that of 1914, during the months preceding harvesting was favorable to the yields from the plots sown broadcast, being slightly greater. But they go to show that the space left between the rows is not lost ground when growing alfalfa on dry soil, and this finding has been sustained by other experience obtained here. INOCULATION IN ALFALFA CULTURE. Experiments with inoculated alfalfa seeds and soils have been conducted here. The ground chosen was somewhat heavier and lower lying than the light sandy land on which all the previously described experiments were conducted, but was not subirrigated. Both Grimm and common alfalfa was used. Strips of one acre each were inoculated with soil from an old alfalfa field, and seed for two more acre strips was inoculated with cultures supplied by the Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. Along with these, two more similar sized strips that had neither the seed nor the soil inoculated were sown. No records of the yields from these strips were taken as no apparent difference could be observed, either in their appearance or in the yields from them. This result is in line with all the work done with alfalfa at this Substation on whatever class of land it is sown. Bacteria can be found on the roots within a short time after the plants are up, which would indicate that the nitrogen - producing organisms are present in the soil and that inoculation is unnecessary. ALFALFA AND SWEET CLOVER. While in recent years sowing sweet clover has been much rec - ommended for Sand Hills land, on account of its alleged ability to grow where alfalfa will not, experiments here have not shown that it has any such advantage over alfalfa. Out of a large number of experiments conducted here during the last three years there is not a single instance of sweet clover having succeeded where alfalfa failed. On the other hand, there are at least three instances of sweet clover having failed where alfalfa succeeded. This refers only to sandy soil. One case at least is known to the </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. writer in which sweet clover succeeded where attempts to grow alfalfa failed. The ground in this case was a shallow, sandy loam with aXstratum of hardpan underneath which prevented the water below it from rising. The sweet clover flourished in this situation, probably because its roots succeeded in getting thru the hardpan. Tests with sweet clover seed at this Substation have shown that only about 60 per cent of the sweet clover grows. Where alfalfa is sown at the rate of 15 pounds per acre, it is safe to sow sweet clover at the rate of 25 pounds. This and the higher price of the clover makes sweet clover seeding expensive. This spring (1915) alfalfa seed was bought for $6 per bushel, the price of sweet clover being $9 per bushel. Quite recently sweet clover sold for more than double the price of alfalfa seed. But taking it at the figures quoted above, and seeding in the proportion given, we have the cost of seed for seeding 1 acre with sweet clover $3.75; cost of seed for seeding 1 acre with alfalfa $1.50 or two and one-half times greater cost in the case of sweet clover. Generally, stock prefer alfalfa, at least before they acquire a taste for sweet clover. At the Substation, hogs spend more time grazing on the sweet clover than on the alfalfa patches. Other fanners have the same experience, while others again report that their stock will not eat sweet clover either as hay or as pasture. No one ever complains of stock refusing alfalfa if it is properly cured. Following will be found a series of six different tests of six different samples each of sweet clover seed and of Grimm alfalfa, common alfalfa, and Turkestan. These tests seem to indicate a very low germination for sweet clover. In actual work, however, sweet clover would show over 100 per cent higher than is indicated here, as a large proportion of the seed is " hard-shelled " and takes longer to germinate than the time given in these tests, which were read eight days after putting to test. How long it takes hard-shelled clover seed to germinate has never been determined here. TABLE 6. — Germination tests of alfalfa and sweet clover. Test No. Grimm alfalfa Common alfalfa Turkestan alfalfa Sweet clover 1 2 3 4 5 6 Per cent 94 87 93 75 94 93 Per cent 98 92 89 99 91 87 Per cent 86 78 82 69 90 82 Per cen 32 17 42 23 35 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 31 HOW TO KEEP A STAND OF ALFALFA. There have been more reports received at this Substation of failures to keep young stands of alfalfa than of failures to obtain them. On our sandy soils, loss in this way can usually be at - tributed to one of three causes. These are ( 1) sun scorching, (2) soil blowing, and (3) loss from drying out, which in the case of young stands frequently takes place some time during the fall, winter, or early spring, and is often but wrongly supposed to be caused by frost and the severity of winter weather. This is natural, as it is usually early in the spring that the trouble is discovered, which leads to the supposition that the damage has been caused by the cold of the preceding winter. To these may be added another trouble which has been very apparent in work with alfalfa this year (1915), viz, failure of the alfalfa when in its two leaf stage, or when it is from two to three weeks old, to survive, evidently after it has used up the plant food in the seed. Apparently this failure is not entirely due to drying out, as it occurred this spring while the surface of the soil was constantly damp, as well as in drier weather, and is probably caused by its failure to secure plant food from the soil. This occurred only on the lighter soils. NURSE CROPS IN ALFALFA GROWING. A nurse crop is the most frequently suggested remedy for the first and second of these troubjes. Experience here has shown that a nurse crop is a worse evil than the trouble it is intended to cure. While it may to some small extent prevent soil blowing, and will also help in providing shade for the young slower grow - ing alfalfa, it will cartainly compete with the latter for what - ever moisture there is in the ground. On dry, sandy land, soil moisture is the one great necessity of which there is seldom an abundance. In more humid climates, or where moisture can be controlled, as in irrigation, the sowing of a nurse crop with alfalfa or clover is a good practice, and frequently works for the benefit of the alfalfa crop, as well as being otherwise profitable. On sandy soil it is better to grow some sort of small grain, or even corn or cane, as a nurse crop the previous year. In the case of small grain it should be so cut as to leave a long stubble, and unless the soil is very loose it ought to be disked as soon after cutting as possible, taking care not to level too much of the stubble. Left in that condition all winter it will catch and hold snow, which will drift into the stubble and stay there. The disking, by loosening the ground, will help to admit the moisture freely. A second disking might be given as early in the spring as </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. the ground will permit. This will assist in retaining the moisture by forming a mulch. When the ground has become warm, the alfalfa can be seeded, preferably with a disk drill, having the press wheels removed. Enough stubble will be left standing after all the work has been done to help materially in breaking the wind, and thus prevent soil blowing. It will also give some shade to the young plants and will not take up the moisture accumulated in winter as a nurse crop would do. This plan has been tried here and is one of the most successful for the purpose. Where corn or cane has been grown and cultivated, it is frequently possible to sow alfalfa seed about the first week in August and cultivate it in when the corn is being put away. Last year a good stand was obtained on a farm near the Substation by sow - ing and covering with the last cultivation given to the corn. Cultivated corn land is not so liable to be dried up as land which has just grown a small-grain crop. Consequently it is less neces - sary to wait for the winter moisture before sowing as was recom - mended in the case of seeding after a small-grain crop. No experience along this line in sowing after cane has been had at this Substation. PREVENTION OF SOIL BLOWING. Light dressings of manure are frequently recommended for the purpose of preventing soil blowing in newly seeded alfalfa fields. This plan has been frequently tried at the Substation by spreading the manure before the alfalfa came up, and in other cases after it had appeared. It has never worked successfully. Unless the manure is laid on thick enough to prevent all soil movement, the soil drifts and forms wreaths or banks deep enough to bury the small alfalfa plants. The soil is thus left with its surface covered with little banks. Stubble, on the other hand, by breaking or sifting the wind, reduces its velocity at the surface of the ground but does not bank up the soil by stopping it alto - gether as does manure. This is not meant, however, to detract from the value of manure as a preventer of soil blowing. It is all right for that purpose when applied to crops that are less easily buried than young alfalfa or to such plants as may be lightly covered after they are once up and are of a stronger, more rapidly growing nature than alfalfa in its early stage of growth. Manure may also be applied to fallow land to prevent soil blow - ing. But the best way of all to use manure on such land is to get it into the soil as humus, where it will act against soil blowing both by making the soil more fibrous and by tending to keep it more moist as well, and where it will also be useful on account of its fertilizing properties. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 33 THE BEST TIME OF YEAR FOR SEEDING ALFALFA. In this section of country there are four months to choose from during which alfalfa may be seeded with reasonable hope of success, these being May, June, July, and August. Seeding earlier or later than these months might possibly succeed, but the chances of success would be reduced. Subdividing the above period, the best parts of it would be from the middle of May till the middle of June, and again from the first till the middle of August. The former period would come within the term of spring sowing, while the latter might be called fall sowing. Where alfalfa is sowed on newly broken sod, June is probably the best month for sowing. The work should be done as soon after break - ing as possible, and June is the best month for breaking. When the breaking and other preparation of the land is well done it is usually easy to get a stand of alfalfa on sod. But for soil that has been under cultivation for some time it has been found in recent years that fall sowing is better. If the precipitation record on page 12, is studied, the reason for this will be appar - ent. During the last five years more rain has fallen on an aver - age during the month of August than in any other month, and as is well known, the wind movement in August is much less on an average than it is in the earlier part of the summer. Moreover, while the heat of August may appear as oppressive as it is in June, the direct rays of the sun are very much weaker, and the daily period of sunshine considerably less. All these circumstances — less wind, less sunshine, and more moisture — are favorable to the growth of a stand of young alfalfa under Sand Hills conditions. Whether wetter springs and drier falls might shift the advantage to spring sowing, it is impossible to say positively. Again, at the Substation, showery weather used to be waited for before sowing alfalfa seed. Now, if the ground is fairly dry and there is not too much fear of soil blowing, the seed is put into the seed bed, and is there, ready to take advantage of the first rain that comes. Alfalfa seed does not spoil by lying in dry ground. It spoils by drying after having had sufficient moisture to start growth. ROLLING NEWLY SEEDED ALFALFA LAND. Rolling ground which has recently been seeded to alfalfa — either as a method of covering the seed after sowing, or as a means of firming the soil about the newly sown seed or young plants in dry weather (in order that by restoring the capillary action of the soil the moisture from beneath may rise and supply the deficiency at the surface caused by lack of rain) — has fre- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. quently been tested, sometimes with very good results. In using a roller for this purpose, it is better to cross the field, as by so doing the roller is brought in contact with more of the surface of the field than if it were used lengthwise of the lands. Rolling has been resorted to in order to help cover broadcasted alfalfa seed on rough or stubbly ground. We have a number of plots of both alfalfa and sweet clover at the Substation that were preserved by rolling at the right time, while the alfalfa sown on similarly planted plots that were not rolled never germi - nated. There is less risk attached to the practice of rolling fall seed - ings. At that time there is likely to be less wind to sweep the soil, the surface of which has been left smooth and pulverized by the roller. Rolling, of course, is also less risky when done on weedy or stubbly ground for the reason that the wind cannot sweep such so severely as it can clean land. Rolling can generally be done in the Sand Hills with bss chance of harm apart from that caused by wind — than on sails that are heavy or clayey, as there is less tendency to glaze or bake in the light sandy soils of this section. ROW CULTIVATION OF ALFALFA. Reference has already been made to the practice of seeding alfalfa in rows, when discussing the experiments made to de - termine the best depth at which to seed alfalfa. In these opera - tions the seeding was done with a corn planter, fitted with slippers on the stub runners as previously described, in order to insure accuracy of depth, and for the purpose of packing the soil along the seed rows. No other method of seeding alfalfa on light sandy soil tried at the Substation has been found so successful as this in getting seed to germinate promptly. This is due to the fact that it can be placed at exactly the depth judged to be best under the local conditions. At the same time, the soil on either side of the row has all the advantage of having been rolled without the disad - vantage of having the entire surface of the field pulverized and made more liable to damage from sweeping wind and from loss of moisture as the result of increased capillary action due to roll - ing. Also, the tracks of the slippers form shallow flat-bottomed furrows, and if the rows are run as they should be at right angles to the direction of the prevailing winds these afford some shelter for the plants in the first stages of their growth. While this method of seeding is, as has previously been stated, more certain of success than drilling, or broadcasting on light sandy soil, it is one better adapted to alfalfa being grown for </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 35 seed production than for hay. In the latter case, especially when the rows are cultivated, it is impossible to harvest the hay in dry weather without getting it badly dusted while raking it up. Cutting with a dropper attached to the mower has been tried but does not work well, as alfalfa will not slide like grass, and if heavy will not cure evenly in the dropper windrows. On the other hand, when grown for seed, there is less objection to dust, as it can be eliminated from both seed and straw in the process of threshing. The advantages claimed by advocates of rowed alfalfa — that it can be thoroly cultivated without damage to the crowns — has been met by the introduction of the drag-bar and other improved alfalfa cultivators, and the only advantage claimed here for the row method of seeding is its greater certainty. The ordinary width of the corn planter— 42 inches — is much too great, especially where it is not the intention to cultivate along the rows, but this can be overcome by setting the seed plates to drop the seed more thinly, and, after going over the field once, straddle the rows with the planter and go again, thus reducing the width of the rows to 21 inches. At the Substation certain good results have followed the use of disk openers on the corn planter when seeding in alfalfa. These have been experimented with in opening furrows from 2 inches to 6 inches in depth, at the bottom of which the seed was sown in the trenches made by the stub runners. Slipper attachments are unnecessary when sowing by this method, as the disks take the weight off the stub runners, thus preventing them from cutting too deeply. A ring, or a drag made of a chain or other material attached behind the stub runners so as to drag along the bottoms of the furrows, will be useful in helping to fill in the seed trenches and cover the seed. Up to a depth of 4 inches it is possible to open the furrows and sow the seed at the same time, but for greater depths of furrow it will be better to open the furrows first to the depth desired, and then remove the disks and sow the seed in the ordinary way with the corn planter. When sowing in furrows, no slipper attachments will be needed, as the compact soil at the bottom of the furrows will prevent the stub runners from cutting too deeply. It has been found that alfalfa sown in this way has proved more drouth resistant than when sown at the surface either by broadcasting, drilling, or the Brott method. While no comparative yields from the various methods have been tabulated here, still it has frequently been observed that alfalfa which has been sown as here described remains greener in the fall and recovers earlier in spring from the effects of winter. Probably the reason for this </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. is because of the protection afforded the alfalfa crowns by the filling in of the trenches with soil, thus giving them more im - munity from unfavorable weather conditions, such as scorching heat or cold. On the other hand, it has been found that alfalfa sown in this way takes longer to arrive at a full crop producing stage than when sown by other methods. The increased labor involved, and this weak initial growth, preventing as it does early culti - vation for the purpose of checking weeds, for fear of covering up the young plants, are serious objections to this method. Alfalfa has been sown here by using the common two-row lister with onion seed plates and brush cut-off attachments and planting the seed at the bottom of the lister furrows. This is much the same as using a corn planter with disk openers as afore - mentioned. Still another method is to use the disk or other drill, stopping a sufficient number of the seed spouts between those left open to give the desired width between the rows. It should be kept in mind that all of the foregoing discussion relates to the seeding of alfalfa on light sandy soil in a dry climate, also that sowing alfalfa seed in furrows as described is more safely practiced in early fall than in spring, as the ground at the latter season is more thoroly warmed, and, besides, there is much less likelihood of the wind blowing the soil into the furrows and covering up the young plants. It should also be remembered that the foregoing is applicable only to soil that has been previously in cultivation, and that with soil of the description under investigation, unless special means are taken to prevent the loss of humus, the difficulty of establish - ing a stand of alfalfa on such land generally increases in proportion to the number of cultivated crops that have been grown upon it. SEEDING ALFALFA ON SOD. Under advice given out as the result of experience obtained here, the practice of seeding alfalfa on freshly broken sod is in - creasing, and with gratifying success. ► i While failures to obtain stands of alfalfa on land that has previously been cultivated are numerous at this Substation on the lighter soils, there is no record of a failure to establish a stand on lands of corresponding quality when the work was done on newly broken sod. Of course it is not meant to convey the idea that any freshly broken sod land will grow alfalfa, because land for that purpose should be chosen as carefully as if it were in - tended for any other crop. One objection frequently made to the practice of seeding on </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 37 sod is that the grass is likely to come back and kill the alfalfa. This has not been noted here to any extent. Probably a good deal depends on the nature of the sod before turning it over, but the trouble more frequently arises from poor breaking. When breaking sod for any purpose, but particularly for alfalfa, the "cut and cover" system ought to be avoided and a complete severance effected between all of the sod and the sole or part immediately under it. When this is done, and the upturned surface properly worked down with disk and drag, there is little fear of interference from grass. Some of the advantages of seeding on freshly broken sod may be mentioned. Probably the greatest of these is that there is likely to be little or no soil blowing, owing to the fibrous nature of the sod soil. Another great advantage is that there will be little or no competition from weeds during the first season, and another that freshly broken sod is a great conserver of moisture, which is sure to be found even in the driest seasons just beneath the cut or slice. Still another advantage of seeding on fresh sod is that by so doing, it is possible at the same time to get a crop of sod corn, as the objection to a nurse crop previously cited does not obtain to any injurious extent, at least with corn. CULTIVATION OF ALFALFA. Experiments conducted in the cultivation of drilled and broad - casted alfalfa in comparison with alfalfa that had not been so treated showed little or no advantage from cultivation where the alfalfa was broadcasted. Rowed alfalfa, on the other hand, invariably showed improvement when cultivated. Probably one of the reasons for this finding is because clean cultivation of rowed alfalfa had the effect of destroying most of the weeds between the rows, and also of establishing a mulch on a surface which, from exposure to the sun, would otherwise have been baked. It thus has the effect of conserving moisture. The average Sand Hills soil is naturally loose, and cultivation makes dusting of the hay at harvest time unavoidable. PREPARATION OF GROUND FOR ALFALFA. As previously stated, it is good practice to seed down freshly turned sod. When land that has been cropped has to be plowed for alfalfa it is, however, much better that the plowing be done the preceding year, so as to give the soil time to pack and settle, provided that by so doing it will not interfere with the retention of moisture by turning under stubble and other roughage which might otherwise intercept drifting snow and also keep the soil </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 38 from blowing. Where danger of doing so is present, it might be better practice to defer plowing until early spring, and by extra work with the disk run almost straight, and with the drag harrow, work the soil to a compact seed bed. Generally speaking, Sand Hills soils are friable and not at all liable to clod, so that they exclude many air spaces by packing easily under such pressure as is given by the trampling of teams and the working over with the above-named or other implements. Alfalfa does well when seeded on land that has just raised a cultivated crop, such as corn or potatoes. Following such crops, no plowing is necessary, all that is required being that a proper seed bed be prepared by top working the soil. Good stands of alfalfa have been obtained here by broadcasting the seed before the last cultivation of corn and covering with the cultivator. This method is somewhat wasteful of seed but can be used suc - cessfully, provided the cultivator is not run deeply. A still better way of sowing would be to use a small disk drill, such as is used for sowing winter wheat in a standing corn crop, and seed - ing between the corn rows. Potato ground could not be seeded in this way, nor in the fall, on account of harvesting the crop. Seeding would have to be done before the alfalfa could be sown, and this, except in th» - case of a crop dug for early marketing, would generally be too late for alfalfa seeding. In this section alfalfa seeding should not be attempted later than the end of the second week in August. In the Sand Hills it is frequently advisable to sow alfalfa in small grain or in cane stubble, but this has been discussed on page 31. No other matter pertaining to Sand Hills farming rivals the subject of alfalfa in importance except perhaps the introduction of better and still better live stock. It is the writer's firm belief that there are few Sand Hills farms or homesteads, so poor but that a spot can be found within their 640 acres upon which alfalfa can be grown, if the work is gone about in an intelligent manner. Once a stand of alfalfa has been established, there is no other farm product possible to Sand Hills conditions that will so well repay the labor that has been bestowed upon it. OTHER PERMANENT FORAGE CROPS. Some work has been done with permanent forage crops other than clovers and alfalfas, but the results have not been important. Timothy will grow freely almost anywhere in the wet valley region, provided the land is not too wet. It also does well on subirrigated dry valleys. On the drier parts of these, brome grass does very well. The following experiment was carried out </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 39 on light sandy upland for the purpose of determining the most drouth-resisting grasses. In cooperation with the Bureau of Plant Industry, Washington, D. C, awnless brome (Bromus itwrmis), slender wheat, tall oat, western wheat, and orchard grasses were sown on one-tenth acre plots in 1912 but made so poor a showing owing to the drouth of that year that it was believed that the experiment had been a failure. The plots were mowed in the fall to kill any weeds that had grown, -and left till the following spring, when the grass on three of them grew, the slender wheat grass making by far the best showing. The weather the year following that in which they were sown was again very dry, but cuttings were made with the following results: Pounds hay Variety per acre Slender wheat 860 Brome grass 570 Western wheat grass 510 Both brome grass and slender wheat grass made a good fall growth, and the latter was quite promising in spite of the small return in hay as given above. Unfortunately, owing to a misunder - standing of instructions, these plots were plowed under early the following spring and lost. More seed was sown but it did not germinate, and the experiment has not been repeated. ANNUAL FORAGE CROPS IN SAND HILLS. It is quite unlikely that any great increase in quantity or that a better quality of hay could be got from seeding any known grass on the drier cultivated lands of the Sand Hills country. Methods have already been indicated whereby wet valley hay may be improved. If, therefore, forage crops other than sweet clover and alfalfa are to be grown in such situations, it would seem that dependence must be put on annual cultivated crops such as corn and cane, millet, rye, white spring emmer (spelts), and other small grains to be cut for hay. In the Sand Hills, the great objection to these as compared with such a crop as alfalfa is that the soil cultivation required to grow them soon destroys humus, with the result that the soil does not retain moisture as it should, and begins to blow. Alfalfa, being a perennial, once established lasts indefinitely, and can get along without culti - vation. When a stand is once secured, it prevents soil blowing. No experiments have been carried out in this connection with the plants named above at this Substation for forage purposes, as their use and capabilities are well understood by Sand Hills </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. farmers. Some experiments have been carried out with variou 1 : substitutes for the above forage plants. Thus far, however, Sudan grass alone has shown results which are worth mentioning. SUDAN CRASS. This recently introduced grass, as it is called, is a wild sorghum. In favorable years it produces abundant seed, which is not unlike flaxseed in appearanca. As a forage plant it can be either sown in rows or broadcast. Sown in rows for forage, 5 pourds is sufficient, but if for seed 3 pounds is enough. On poor, light sandy land at the Substation, when sown in rows, it yielded seed weigh - ing about 32 pounds per bushel and at the rate of 8 bushels per acre. For convenience, the same width between rows as for corn may be used. Sown broadcast at the rate of 24 pounds per acre, it was found to give a better yield of hay than when seeded heavier or lighter. Table 7 will give the yields from various methods of sowing, which was done near the end of May, 1913. Experience obtained at the Substation in the production of Sudan grass seed during the season of 1915 was less encouraging. Selected local grown seed made a very poor stand, and failed to ripen. The stand from seed supplied by the Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C, was better, but the seed from this also is immature. Undoubtedly the lateness of the spring had much to do with this result, but the experience has caused some doubt as to whether Sudan grass will maintain its native vitality under Sand Hills conditions. A similar experience was had this year with feterita. TABLE 7.— Yield of Sudan grass hay from rows and when sown broadcast. The hay from land sown broadcast was very foul, and probably 30 per cent of the weight ought to be deducted from the return of hay on that account. As a stock feed it is relished by all kinds of animals and is eaten with less waste than any cane that has been fed here. No exact record has been kept of the yield of Method of seeding late of seeding per acre i— Yield lows, 42 inches apart . . . Lows, 21 inches apart . . . troadcast [road cast iroadcast Pounds i 24 30 Pounds 1,224 1,667 2,374 2,498 2,298 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 41 seed when sown broadcast, but from observation made on light land here, it probably averaged not less than 8 bushels of ripe seed per acre in 1914. Its chief importance in the Sand Hills is its hay-producing ability, and it is reassuring to know that it will be likely to be found producing an abundance of seed for planting. GRAIN-PRODUCING SORGHUMS. Grain-producing sorghums were tested at the Substation during 1911, 1912, and 1913. Most of the seed was furnished by the Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. Several samples of dwarf milo seed obtained locally were grown along with these as checks. The seed of all varieties was selected from heads showing early ripening qualities each succeeding year. Many of the varieties were unfitted for our northern climate and altitude and did not ripen seed. Returns from the best yielding varieties are given in Table 8. Table 8. — Yields of grain sorghums Planting was done in rows the same as for corn, and with a corn planter. The rate of seeding was about 6 pounds per acre. Planting was done according to the seasons — first planting May 22, second May 27, and that of 1913 on June 1. Some of the kaoliangs are early, but they are low in yield. The marked in - crease in 1913 is due to the better season, when more rain fell than on either of the two preceding. FETERITA. On land similar to that on which the other grain sorghums above described were grown, feterita has shown remarkable drouth resistance, but has failed to mature seed properly, tho on richer soil it might do differently. As a forage crop it is poor, being strong stalked, with few leaves, and is woody and sapless. It may seem surprising that milo should ripen seed when feterita failed to do so. This may be accounted for by the fact that the milo used in the tests was home grown and was therefore Variety Yields in bushels per acre Dwarf upright milo Dwarf black hulled kaffir Brown kaoliang No. 261 . . . Brown kaoliang No. 328 . . . 1911 5.8 4.0 ;i.4 3.8 1912 5.0 3.8 3.6 4.0 1913 11.2 9.2 7.5 5.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. acclimated, while the other was not. The 1913 seedings of grain sorghums were all later in maturing than in the previous years, and this circumstance without doubt also adversely affected the ripening of feterita. Also, it may not be quite correct to state that the feterita did not ripen, because some heads did apparently mature, and were preserved, and seeded the following spring, but made a very poor showing, presumably because even these picked heads were not quite mature. In 1913, a cooperative experiment with seed supplied from the Substation, which was carried out on lower lying and much richer land in 1914, is reported as having yielded an estimated return of 30 bushels per acre. Some of the seed resulting from this test was secured and planted here but failed. The spring of 1915 was, however, very unfavorable to the culture of grain sorghums in the Sand Hills country. Fig. 5. — Dry land cornfield in spring CORN IN SAND HILLS. Because the cultivation of corn is one of the best understood crop-growing operations among Sand Hills farmers, comparatively little work has been done with it in an experimental way. However, in 1911 in cooperation with the Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture, which sup - plied some of the seed, varieties supposed to be suitable for Sand Hills conditions were planted. Three of these were of local pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 43 duction and were placed in competition with the imported varieties. The object of this experiment was, primarily, to ascertain whether a better yielding variety than the local ones could be found, and also to obtain corn yields for comparison with the grain sorghum yields, and those from small grains, all grown under almost identical conditions as regards soil and climate. The local grown varieties were — a small yellow dent, the com - mon main corn crop variety of the district; a white dent, some - what larger and later than the yellow, also commonly grown over the Sand Hills section; and a calico corn. The dents obtained locally were variously named, scarcely any two persons agreeing on a common name for the same sample. In Table 9 the first three returns are from the local grown seed. It is interesting to compare the above yields of corn with those of the grain sorghums already given, as well as with those of the small-grain yields given in Table 10 farther on. As all of the years in which these experiments were conducted had less than normal precipitation and more than the average heat, it is presumed that the conditions were more favorable to grain sorghums than either to corn or to small grains, and when the risk of the former failing to mature in cooler seasons is taken into account the comparison is still more favorable to corn as a crop for the Sand Hills. SMALL-GRAIN CROPS. During the years 1912 and 1913 some experiments with small grains were conducted in cooperation with the Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture, Washington, Table £ 9.- -YieU ds of corn. Variety Yields in bushels per acre ■ 1911 1912 ! 1913 Small yellow dent, local variety White dent, local variety Calico corn, local variety Minnesota No. 13, imported Australian white flint, imported . Ardmore yellow dent, imported Sels No. 13, imported 6.0 4.2 12.5 6.5 4.0 11.2 5.8 4.3 10.8 a few ears 4.8 13.6 matured a few ears 3.6 9.0 matured . . failed . a few ears 3.9 record miss- matured ing </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. D. C, from which most of the seed used was obtained, having been selected as varieties of small grains most likely to suit Sand Hills conditions. The first season, that of 1912, was one of severe drouth, the precipitation being more than 6 inches less than normal, while the evaporation owing to high winds and hot sun was exception - ally great. Fig. 6.— Oatfield on Substation farm. The soil on which the experiments were conducted was similar to that on which the grain sorghums already referred to were raised. It is a light sandy loam with a subsoil of sand, and is entirely without subirrigation. It was broken from sod in the summer of 1910 and planted to corn, which was cut for forage. The ground was backset the following spring and cane was drilled in, which was cut in the fall for hay. Winter wheat and rye were sown in parts of it in October, 1911, being put in with a press drill in the cane stubble, which had previously been disked. The weather was favorable, as nearly 5 inches of rain had fallen in that month. The remainder of the ground was left in stubble until the following spring, when it was sown to the spring varieties of small grain here discussed. Considerable snow fell in March, 1912, and was well retained on the land by the cane stubble. The grains were drilled in one-tenth acre plots on April 3, the weather in that month being favorable as regards moisture, tho there was one rather severe freeze. Considerable rain fell in May, but drying winds were frequent. All grains, however, made a splendid start. The June rainfall was scant, while other- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 45 wise the weather was hot, with frequent high winds. The weather in July was a continuation of the same, with still less rainfall than in the previous month. Under these conditions the small-grain experiments were nearly all complete failures, and the only ones which were tabu - lated were Kharkov wheat, a winter variety, and the winter rye, and spelts. In the following year, 1913, these experiments were repeated with the following results: Table 10.— Yields of small grains. 1913. An approximation between the yields of milo maize, winter wheat, winter rye, and emmer, as well as corn, may here be noticed, and by turning to Table 4 on page 27 a return of 2,040 pounds of alfalfa will be observed, but which was made in 1912. However, a record of alfalfa made the following year, 1913, from the same plots was kept. Two cuttings were made, amounting in all to 2,230 pounds, which may fairly be classified for com - parison with the other yields, having been harvested in the same year and on similar land. Rate of seeding Yield Species or variety SPRING WHEAT Kubanka Velvet Don Galgalos . WINTER WHEAT Kharkov . . Turkey Red Spring rye Winter rye Emraer, Lot 1 fmmOT T rtt 9 Pecks 3 3 3 Bushels 5.9 4.8 5.4 4 4 3 4 5 5 11.3 10.0 8.6 11.8 11.5 10.8 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. No data are at hand for comparing the value of these various products nor the cost of their production. While these returns are small, it is questionable whether with the exception of alfalfa they could be duplicated on the same land under the same weathe: conditions, as the soil on which they were made deteriorates rapidly under cultivation, owing to waste of humus which it has been found difficult to replace fully, because the soil cannot assimilate barnyard manure except in small annual quantities, owing to moisture scarcity. Under such conditions and consider - ing the various yields, it would seem that on this class of land, alfalfa would be the best crop to grow. On somewhat heavier soils manure and crop rotation will go a long way toward keeping intact the supply of humus. Compared with the above yields of small grains, the return from an 8-acre field of oats sown in 1912 on the Substation farm on a piece of subirrigated ground may be mentioned. The yield from this field was 344 bushels, or 43 bushels per acre, and it will be remembered that 1912 was the driest of all years since the Substation was established, when the yields of the grain sorghums, corn, and small grains were less than half of those given above, which are the returns of 1913, a year more favorable for all crops in this section. The difference is, of course, due to the available moisture in the case of the subirrigated land on which these oats were raised. The experience with small grains sown on light sandy soils which are not subirrigated would seem to point to the conclusion that they have little place in dry land Sand Hills farming, except perhaps for purposes of rotation, for which winter rye and emmer, grown to be cut for hay, would seem to be best adapted. 1 The yield of 2,374 pounds hay from Sudan grass sown broadcast is sub - ject to an estimated reduction of one-third, so that the return given here for Sudan grass, 1,667 pounds, is the yield from an acre sown in rows 21 inches wide. Table 11. — Comparison of crop yields per acre in 1913. ighest yield of alfalfa, pounds 2,230.00 ighest yield of Sudan grass, 1 pounds hay 1,667.00 ighest yield of potatoes, bushels 54.15 ighest yield of milo, bushels 11.20 ighest yield of winter rye, bushels 11.80 'ighest yield of emmer, bushels 11.50 ighest yield of winter wheat, bushels 11.30 ighest yield of corn, bushels 13.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 47 Indeed, many experienced Sand Hills farmers are of the opinion that small-grain crops grown for their grain alone are not profit - able, and when the small yields and the cost of the machinery needed for their production, such as seeding, harvesting, and threshing machinery, are considered, there is much to be said in support of their opinion. POTATO CULTURE IN THE SAND HILLS. Many inquiries are received at the Substation on the subject of potato growing, with special reference to the adaptability of the Sand Hills country for potatoes, and also as to the varieties best suited for local conditions. The Early Ohio is the most widely grown of all potatoes in the Sand Hills, being, indeed, almost exclusively grown in many parts of it, and for this partiality there are good reasons. One of these is its earliness, which enables it to mature a crop before the soil attains its maximum heat in the early part of fall, at which time the immature potatoes of less early varieties are liable to be damaged by heat and the drying of the soil. Another reason fo- the popularity of the Early Ohio is its heavy yielding qualities. On the other hand, its color, which is red or pink, detracts from its value in the larger markets. It is besides quite susceptible to scab and other diseases, like stem rot, which have increased within the Sand Hills country during the last few years. In order to obtain data on the subject, some experiments were begun in cooperation with the Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture, which supplied most of the seed used. A field broken from sod in 1910 was backset the following spring. The soil was of the lightest and driest description, being in fact just the better quality of dune sand land. After back - setting, a little manure was spread on top to prevent blowing. One experiment was for the purpose of finding out the best depth to plant potatoes in such land. Another had for its purpose the ascertaining of the best distance apart in the rows, and another the size of seed best adapted to such conditions. The 1911 experiments were a failure because of the want of rain in June and July, when the total precipitation for the two months reached only 1.07 inches. The work was continued during 1912 and 1913, when the seed being used was frozen in a cave which had hitherto been sufficient for winter preservation of roots. The results of the two years' work are given in Tables 13 and 16. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 48 Table 12. — Comparative yields in variety tests of potatoes. 1912-13. year 1912 Total I Width Length Depth of Yield yield Market - of row of row planting per per i able tubers Variety 1. The best depth was from 4 to 5 inches 2. The best distance apart in rows of 42 inches wide was 24 inches. 3. The best size was a medium potato quartered. Whole as well as half potatoes yielded a larger total crop and more marketable potatoes, but had more waste from unsalable, small, or deformed tubers, and the gain in yield scarcely made up for the extra outlay in seed. In a very dry year it is safer to try to raise potatoes from a smaller quantity of seed onlthe same principle that a thin crop of grain is less likely to burn up in dry weather. Table 13. — Comparison of yields of quartered Early Ohio potatoes planted at various depths. year 1912 Width be- Distance apart I Planting Total yield Marketable tween rows in row depth per acre tubers per aci depth per acre tubers per acre Inches Early Ohio 42 Early Rose 42 Irish Cobbler 42 Eureka 42 I Feet Inches 42 3 42 3 42 3 42 i 3 Lbs. Bu. 27.5 45.8 23.4 39.0 28.4 47.3 26.2 43.7 i BmMi 41.5 36.5 45.0 41.0 YEAR 1913 Early Ohio I 42 Early Rose 42 Irish Cobbler 42 Eureka 42 42 ! 4 42 4 42 4 42 4 26.4 ' 44.0 I 24.5 41.25 ! 32.5 54.15 ! 24.6 41.0 41.0 40.0 52.5 39.4 Inches 42 42 42 42 42 Inches 21 21 21 21 21 Inches Pounds , 2 1,680 i 3 2,860 f 4 3,120 5 3,080 6 2,770 YEAR 1913 Pounds 1,050 2,490 2,810 2,845 2,590 42 42 42 42 42 42 24 24 24 24 24 24 i 3 3,060 4 3,190 5 2,870 2,620 2,980 2,790 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Farming Practice in the Sand HUls. 49 Other than to show that the best depth for planting is about 4 inches, there is not much else to be gathered from Table 13 except that there is a greater proportion of unmarketable potatoes when planted at the lesser depths. Table 13 also shows that in the year 1912 the heavier yield was obtained from planting 5 inches deep, while the 1913 test shows a decided advantage from the 4-inch planting. Probably the difference in results is owing to the great humidity of the latter year. Some of the yields exceed those of Early Ohio in the variety test given in the table, but this is accounted for by the difference of the soils and other conditions. Table 14. — Comparison of yields of quartered Early Ohio potatoes from different spacings of potatoes along rows. YEAR 1912 Width be- ! Space apart Depth Total yield Marketable tween rows in row planted per acre tubers per aci planted per acre tubers per acre The experiments, as will be observed from Table 14, are identical for the two years, 1912 and 1913, except that the spac - ing of 12 inches, 15 inches, and 36 inches were eliminated in the latter year, and the depth of planting was increased from 3 inches to 4 inches. The smaller proportion of unmarketable potatoes observed in 1913 may be owing either to the greater depth at which the sets were planted, or to the slightly more favorable potato season of 1913, as compared with that of the previous year. In 1913, the superiority of a spacing of 24 inches in its relation to the yield of marketable potatoes is more pronounced than in the previous year, tho this result would scarcely be expected on account of the greater moisture of 1913 which would nehes 42 42 42 42 42 42 _42 Inches 12 15 18 21 24 30 36 Inches Pounds 3 1,900 3 1,810 3 2,370 3 2,640 3 2,890 3 2,800 3 2,470 Pounds 1,190 1,170 2,015 2,390 2,655 2,650 2,290 yeah 1913 42 42 42 42 18 21 24 30 4 2,596 4 2,575 4 2,995 4 2,480 i 2,315 2,345 2,855 2,330 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. be reasonably supposed to favor of closer planting. It is possible that the more complete shading of the ground by the closer planting in 1912 — a hot, dry season — had some effect upon the result. TABLE 15. — Comparison of yields of Early Ohio potatoes from of sets. various sizes In the above table it will be observed that the yields of market - able potatoes are larger in proportion in the latter year. Several causes may have contributed to this. There was more available moisture during the growing season for one thing. Another is doubtless the deeper planting practiced during the second year. In this connection it has been observed at the Substation that the depth of planting has very little effect on the depth which the crop occupies in the soil, when the tubers begin to set or form. But if the soil is hard beneath them, as it frequently is with shallow planting, they expand upward instead of more or less equally upward and downward, and this has the effect of eventually bringing them closer to the surface, where many of them become unmarketable thru sun scald. Otherwise, the table shows that quartered potatoes are the best sized sets to use for planting under ordinary conditions, when the usual difference in value between potatoes at planting time and harvest time is considered. VARIETY TESTS Variety tests were carried out with 12 varieties, mostly of early sorts. As was stated, the first tests were failures on account of dry weather in 1911. The tests were continued in 1912 and 1913 with the same seed. YEAR 1912 Size of sets ™**£ Spaced Depth in row planted Total yield Marketable per acre tubers per acre i Inches hole 42 Inches Inches 24 :i Pounds Pound* 3,770 3,290 Half Quarter . Eighth 42 42 42 24 3 24 3 24 I 3 3,540 2,890 2,190 .': 3,210 2,655 2,015 YEAR 1913 Whole . . . Half Quarter . 42 42 42 24 I 4 24 4 24 4 4.140 3,780 2.995 .1.775 3,440 2,866 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 51 The late varieties eliminated themselves by failing to mature in the first year, and no late varieties were planted in 1913. Only four of the early varieties are given below, and the figures are those of 1912 and 1913. The most successful competitor was the Irish Cobbler. This is a fine, mealy, white potato, with a deep rooting habit, which is probably the reason why it did so well under the conditions of this test. The subjoined yields are small, and this is accounted for by the nature of the soil (the same as described in the previous experiments), as well as by the mois - ture shortage accompanying the years in which the tests were made. Assuming that there are 4,200 feet of row m an acre when the rows are 42 inches apart, lengths of 42 feet were dug in each variety, 42 feet being the one-hundredth part of an acre. It would appear from the foregoing that the Irish Cobbler might be substituted for the Early Ohio with advantage. CROWINC SEED POTATOES UNDER A MULCH. In addition to the foregoing, some work was done in testing the value of growing seed potatoes under a mulch. Only one variety, the Early Ohio, was used in this test. The result given below is the average of three different tests made in 1913, all of which showed decidedly larger yields when potatoes were grown under a litter mulch. The comparison here given is for returns per peck of seed planted. The seed was cut as nearly alike as possible. The reason for the yield not being given as per acre is because, to save labor in mulching, the potatoes grown in this way were planted in rows only 2 feet apart, and at half the ordinary distance apart in the row. I'nmulched potatoes, average yield of 3 separate pecks seed, per peck 84.5 lbs. Mulched potatoes, average yield of 3 separate pecks From this it will be seen that the average yield when potatoes were mulched was nearly 50 per cent greater than in the case of unmulched. The returns are of marketable potatoes only. The proportion of unmarketable was larger in the case of the unmulched than in that of the mulched. How this would work out in a year more suitable for potato growing it is impossible to say. Probably the advantage of mulching might not be so apparent in seasons of more precipitation. The potatoes in these experiments were all dibbled in at a uniform depth of 4 inches. When the sprouts began to appear above ground the rows were clean cultivated in the case of those that were to be mulched, and the soil stirred with a garden fork to loosen it. The ground was then covered with straw to a depth of about 6 inches, and no seed, per peck 126.0 lbs. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 52 more work was done on them until harvest except to pull weeds. The unmulched potatoes in competition with them were culti - vated four times during the season. The following year, 1914, seed that had been raised under a mulch as described was placed in competition with seed that was grown under ordinary condi - tions. Again, three lots of each were selected, and the averages of three tests are given below. The potatoes in both cases were grown under ordinary field conditions, the object being to de - termine what value mulching transmitted to the potatoes for seed purposes. The average of three different tests is given below in terms of one acre. Table 16. — Comparison of yield from seed grown under a mulch with that from seed grown in the ordinary way. This shows a gain in the case of potatoes grown from mulched seed of nearly 13 bushels per acre. On account of the loss of seed this experiment was cut short at this point. POTATO DISEASES AND PESTS In the Sand Hills section, while potato blight cannot be said to be unknown, the only diseases that have come under observa - tion here which seriously affect the yields are scab and stem rot. The formalin treatment for scab, which consists in soaking the seed for 2 hours in a solution containing one-half pint of commer - cial formalin diluted in 15 gallons of water, has been tested here with varying results. Samples of seed infected with the disease have been treated, and every precaution taken to prevent reinfection, and yet the crop from such has been found infected. In other cases the formalin treatment of scabbed seed has been followed by the desired result. This would seem to point to a source of infection other than that of the seed. If no potato crop has previously been grown in the ground, the infection has probably been con - veyed by manure. In any case it is better to disinfect the seed, as, unless the ground has been previously infected, doing so will in all likelihood prevent scab in the ensuing crop. Width of row Length of row Yield per row Yield per acre market- able tubers nmulched . Inches 42 42 Inches 42 42 —tzr- 42 42 Pounds 29.25 37.50 _! Buskds 48.70 81.M lulched . </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 53 STEM ROT. Stem rot is becoming increasingly common in the Sand Hills section. It can be detected, by slicing across the stem end of the tuber so as to leave the tuber stem in the center of the slice removed. If the disease is present it will be detected by the presence of a dark colored concentric ring of irregular shape. On paring deeper this ring usually becomes more distinct, and the tuber will be obviously unfit for human food. In combating this disease the seed should be disinfected with the same formalin solution recommended for scab; also, all seed showing discoloration when cut should be rejected and the knife used in cutting dipped in a strong formalin solution before using on other seed. It is further recommended that land that has grown a crop of potatoes affected either by scab or by stem rot should not be used again for the same crop till after the lapse of several years. THE COLORADO BEETLE. The potato bug or Colorado beetle is the only insect pest that has done much to damage potato crops at the Substation. This pest seems first to invade the crop on that side of it nearest to grass or to where weeds and other vegetation are growing, and if attended to before it has had time to spread, it can fre - quently be checked without having to spray the whole field. For spraying purposes, Paris green and arsenate of lead have been found about equally effective. When using the Paris green, some quicklime should be mixed in with it as it helps it to adhere, and also shows up on the leaves of the plants, thus serving to detect whether they are reasonably protected by the spraying. A solution containing one pound of either Paris green or arsenate of lead to 100 gallons of water is about right. In very bright weather the plants will stand its being stronger. Arsenate of lead appears to be safer than the Paris green, as no vegetation injured by applications of that insecticide in reasonable strength has ever been observed here, while plants under shade have been quite seriously injured by applying the Paris green too strong. However, it is quite safe to use Paris green on potatoes if applied as prescribed above. ROTATION OF CROPS IN THE SAND HILLS. While at the Substation the land used in growing the main corn crop has not had any rotation of crops but has been kept under corn since being broken from sod five years ago, the yield and the fertility and texture of the soil have apparently been maintained and even improve This has been done by the </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. liberal application of barnyard manure put out on the ground during suitable winter weather or in early spring. This heavy dressing is possible on account of the greater moisture available, owing to the soil being subirrigated to some extent, thus assisting in speedier decomposition of the rougher parts of the manure. While this is true, it is probable that an occasional change to some small-grain crop would be good practice, were it not that the land adapted for a sure corn crop for the silo is limited. It is reasonably certain that on the average Sand Hills home - stead, by applying the manure produced on the land used for growing corn, and by occasionally rotating the corn with emmer or with rye, the soil on bench lands and dry valley bottoms could be kept without serious deterioration. But, where no manure is applied, or where the quantity supplied is insufficient, the defi - ciency cannot be made good by a rotation. This is particularly true if the rotation is one in which the main bulk of the crop is taken off the land, as would be the case in cutting small grain for hay. The soil would be gradually depleted of its fibrous organic matter. To overcome these conditions, a system of farming recom - mended and practiced by some Sand Hills farmers, but which may appear wasteful and extravagant to owners of high-priced land where the precipitation is much greater and the soil more retentive of moisture may be worth description here. This is the system of allowing the half of the land used for corn growing to grow to weeds every second year, and raising the corn crop of one year on the land that was under weeds during the year previous. The advocates of this method contend that it Ls conservative of the two principal desiderata of Sand Hills soil organic matter or humus, and moisture, and that the Government, recognizing the peculiar requirements of Sand Hills farming, framed the Kinkaid Act, granting 640 acres instead of 160 acres, in order to meet the exigencies of the case. They further contend that the practice is no more wasteful of land space than the well-approved system of summer tillage or fallowing for wheat, while it is much superior in that, instead of using up organic matter as does the practice referred to, it is a means of increasing it. The weeds, frequently of the sunflower variety, grow up thickly when the ground is given over to them, and in consequence they do not grow so large as to hamper future operations. In the spring following this weed crop, the corn is listed in, and the subsequent cultivation, which is best done with a sled cultivator, is relied on to work up the land, and roll the dead weeds into the lister furrows, where they are covered up with soil and quickly become decomposed, thus adding to the humus in the soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 55 Under this system the land is never allowed to lie bare of vegetation, but is protected from the high winds that prevail in spring when, otherwise, under ordinary farming conditions, it is most likely to be found unprotected. The advantage which such a system offers, owing to the possibility which it affords of keeping the ground protected by vegetation at every stage of crop pro - duction, can perhaps only be appreciated by those who, from actual experience, have become familiar with the problem of soil-blowing on the lighter class of cultivated soil in the Sand Hills saction, where it has quite frequently become the most important of all problems, upon the solution of which the home - steader's ability to support himself on his land depended. The weeds, being left on the ground all winter, help in the con - servation of moisture by arresting drifting snow and holding it on the land which is to bear the future corn crop. Furthermore, it is claimed for this system that the crop of the one alternate year will outyield those of two crops raised in successive years, and with little more than half the amount of labor, and this, whether it is attempted to raise corn every year on the same ground, or whether a small-grain rotation is used. In addition, they maintain that, by alternating in this way with a "crop" that is turned under in its entirety, the soil is built up, whereas by following the other methods it soon becomes poorer, especially if little or no manure is applied. The system is described here for the consideration of the newcomer farmer, with the assurance that some of the most progressive and pros - perous farmers in the Sand Hills not only recommend it but put it into practice. TREE CULTURE IN THE SAND HILLS SECTION. Only a few of the outstanding features and results of tree culture as carried out at the Substation will be given here. In all, about 2,000 trees have been planted at the Substation. This number is made up of cottonwoods, Norway poplars, box elders, honey locusts, black locusts, American elms, green ash, hardy catalpas, Russian olives, a few cedars, and about 500 bull or rock pines and jack pines. PREPARING LAND FOR TREE PLANTING. The planting was mostly done in the spring of 1911. As the land had only been broken from sod the previous year, then backset in the spring of 1911 just before planting, it is quite probable that the soil was not in first-class condition for tree planting. However, the desire to have a grove and windbreak </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. started as early as possible prevailed, and the work was begun as stated. The erection of a woven-wire fence on one side of the strip of land intended for the grove and the placing parallel to that at the distance of the width of the grove of a low bank of manure had an excellent effect in trapping snow during the winter of 1910-11, so that when planting time came in the spring the land was found much better stored with moisture than it would have been if left in its natural state. In view of subse - quent experience it is realized that several mistakes were made at the beginning of this work. In the first place, in order to make a showing it was decided to plant cottonwoods, Norway poplars, and box elders, all of them fast growers, but also more or less short lived. These were mixed in with slower growing but usually longer lived trees, such.as the pines, locusts, elms, ashes, etc., the idea being that as the Tatter began to occupy the ground the others would die or could be thinned. The trees were placed in rows 8 feet apart but only 4 feet apart along the rows, with the intention that when the less permanent trees were removed permanent trees 8 feet apart in every direction would be left. PLANTING SO AS TO FACILITATE CULTIVATION. It was soon discovered that the great enemy to tree growing was the amount of weeds that sprung up. Had the trees been 8 feet apart each way, it would have been a very much simpler matter to keep them clean without injuring their roots and stems. The cultivator could, in the case of the wider planting, have been run more freely across or at least angling to the rows as is done in cultivating checked corn. It was found that the roots of the cottonwoods and|Norway poplars grow close to the surface, and for this reason it was impossible to cultivate so deeply as was otherwise desirable for the deeper rooting pines and de - ciduous trees. Later the difficulty was overcome by using a small Acme harrow to destroy the weeds. The common disk is almost ideal for tree cultivation, as it can be used to better effect than any other implement for the purpose and with less effort on the part of the operator. Its roller - like action has no tearing up effect on the roots with which it may come into contact, such as have the shovels of the ordinary cultivator. Disk harrows can, of course, be got at any practical width, but where it is inconvenient to keep one small enough to cultivate between 8-foot wide rows, it would be well to plant the trees at distances apart that would admit of cultivation by the disk used for general farm work. It should also assist greatly in the cultivation and keeping of a grove or shelter belt free from </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 57 weeds if space were left at the end of the rows and on both sides of the grove, or belt, to permit turning the team, so that cultiva - tion could be done crossways, as well as along the rows. IMPORTANCE OF CLEAN CULTIVATION IN TREE CROWING. Clean cultivation is important, as upon its being well done depends frequently the life of the trees in seasons of moisture scarcity. Neglect of cultivation allows the moisture to be depleted by transpiration thru the weeds that are sure to grow, as well as by excessive evaporation from the uncultivated surface of the soil. Instead of the method adopted in this case, of mixing trees of distinctly different rates of growth, the better practice in tree growing would be to keep those quick-growing, short-lived, shal - low-rooted trees in a place by themselves. In the spring of 1914 it was found that many of the cottonwoods and Norway poplars which had grown with great rapidity during the previous three years had died during the preceding fall or winter. For this there were probably several causes. The average precipitation during the years in which they had been growing was 17.30 inches in - stead of a normal 22.46. Their phenomenal growth had also something to do with it, as trees of such expansion must have made heavy drains upon the moisture in the soil, which, at a later stage, had become so exhausted as to be incapable of keeping up the supply. A certain amount of root pruning, the result of cultivation with shovel cultivators, had also more or less to do with causing their death. IMPORTANT POINTS IN TREE CULTURE IN THE SAND HILLS. In tree culture in the Sand Hills country, the following points are to be considered: 1. Select good fresh stock. 2. Firm planting is absolutely necessary. Trees will not do well if this is neglected. 3. Trees should be set far enough apart and be symmetrically spaced so that clean cultivation can be given without necessity for much hand hoeing. 4. Keep slow-growing trees separate from quick-growing, and shallow-rooting varieties separate from trees of a deep - rooting habit. 5. Do not mulch with manure. While doing so may at times save trees from drying out, the trees which survive without mulching are much more likely to be permanent. Mulched trees have the shallow-rooting habit. 6. Clean culture is much more to be depended upon than </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. artificial watering to preserve trees. Experiments proving this conclusively have been carried out here. The right kinds of trees have never suffered from want of moisture at this Substation if properly cultivated and kept clean. 7. If watering has to be resorted to, do it thoroly. One soaking that goes as deep or deeper than the deepest root is worth many sprinklings. Indeed, trees are frequently killed by con - stantly sprinkling them, especially when no after-cultivation is given. 8. Deciduous trees are better for being pruned before they are planted, or it can be done soon after. This, however, should not be severe, but sufficient to counterbalance the amount of root pruning which they have sustained in transplanting. After - ward, great care should be taken to see that pruning is so done as to avoid forks which, if allowed to develop, are sure to result later in broken limbs and disfigured trees. In the Sand Hills almost all kinds of trees have the tendency to fork, but some, like the box elder and honey locust, are much more inclined to the habit than others. A low down branching habit makes it more difficult to cultivate trees. On the other hand, it has been found that small branches low down have the effect of protecting the tree trunk to some extent from the action of the sun. VARIETIES OF TREES FOR THE SAND HILLS It is not presumed that all the trees which do well in the Sand Hills are mentioned here. What is aimed at is to mention the most suitable varieties that have been experimented with in Substation work here. 1. The Norway poplar has made the quickest growth of all planted, but, as indicated above, many trees of this variety died from drouth after the third year. All trees mentioned here have been grown on light sandy loam, with no moisture except what is derived directly from overhead. 2. Cottonwoods come next in rapidity of growth, but like the Norway poplar they have proved short lived under the con - ditions mentioned. 3. The box elder makes quick growth, and so far as yet shown at this Substation is more drouth resistant than either the poplars or the cottonwoods. Few box elders thus far have suc - cumbed. Their greatest defects as shown here are their tendency to die back, and of all trees grown here they are the most difficult, perhaps, to keep in good shape. On more retentive soil the three species named are perhaps the best that could be planted for quick shelter. They are all comparatively free from injury by </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 59 borers, the worst of all insect pests with which trees here have to contend. 4. Of the slower-growing deciduous trees, the elm and the honey locust have undoubtedly done best, and the percentage of surviving trees is almost the same in the case of either. This amounts to about 60 per cent. The chief fault of the honey locust is its tendency to kill back, altho this has not resulted very frequently in spoiling the tree entirely as in the case of the catalpa. Some of the American elms planted here are among the most promising trees we have. 5. Green ash has not done well. Apparently it is a poor drouth resister and is subject to attacks from borers. Probably its inability to withstand drouth is the cause of borers attacking it. It has been observed that unthrifty trees are generally the first to be attacked. There are very few good specimens of ash at this Substation. 6. The Russian olive is'^scarcelyjsuited for forest and shelter belt purposes. At the same time,|it has given fair satisfaction here and does well if a good start can be given to it. For Sand Hills planting, good strong trees of this variety should be used. Small, weak trees are almost sure to fail. But with a good-sized healthy tree, well looked after during the first year, the chances of success are greater. It withstands drouth as well as any tree known here, and makes a good variety in lawn trees. 7. Of the jack and bull pines planted, not more than 25 per cent have survived. Some of the latter are fine specimens, and it is hoped that they can be kept alive. The jack pine is not so satisfactory. It kills back considerably, and is straggly and unsightly at best. The only other coniferous tree attempted to be grown here is the red cedar. It has been disappointing, show - ing weak growth, and each year trees that looked fairly well in fall are found beyond recovery when spring opens. In view of the fact that the red cedar is recognized as one of the most drouth resistant of trees, this failure was a surprise. It probably in this case was due more to exposure to high winds than to lack of moisture, as the few trees that survived occupied the most sheltered situations. From observations made here from time to time on these and other evergreens, such as pines, spruces, etc., it is believed that high, cold winds are more injurious than lack of moisture. In any case, the first symptoms of approach - ing failure have frequently been observed soon after exceptionally severe winter weather had been experienced. 8. The so-called hardy catalpa has not justified its name here. Out of 25 trees planted in 1911 only five are now alive, and these are not increasing in size, as they die back almost to the ground every winter. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. 9. Lawn trees and shrubs that have done well, in addition to the Russian olive already mentioned, are, first, and best of all, Spirea Van Houttei, which flourishes, giving a fine display of blossoms in early spring, and during the most of summer exhibit - ing a profusion of graceful, fernlike foliage. It requires but little care and is most worthy of a place in every lawn or garden. Next to it, perhaps, is the buffalo berry, which can be obtained wild in most places and stands transplanting very well. The Siberian pea tree has done well here, but is more susceptible to drouth than some of the others. The sumac also grows well, but its habit of growth is too suggestive of the persimmon to be pleasing to people familiar with that plant. Tartarian honey - suckle also does well but is an ungainly plant. Among the shrubs more recently tried out here, tamarisks and lilacs are the most promising. Nursery orders for small weak trees should be avoided when - ever possible, as trees of strong and somewhat mature growth do best in the Sand Hills. Trees that, to a certain extent, have begun to form their habit of growth in the nursery have given best satisfaction when planted out at the Substation. ORCHARD AND SMALL FRUITS IN THE SAND HILLS. The land surrounding the Substation, which has been already described as a light sandy loam on a subsoil of pure sand, is ill adapted for growing either orchard trees or small fruits, and in consequence very little work of this kind has been attempted. A few hardy apple, pear, cherry, and plum trees were set out in 1913, but, as was expected, the results have not been encouraging, the plum trees alone having made anything like a thrifty showing. In 1915 a few plums were found, but they dropped off shortly after setting, altho the moisture supply was abundant at the time, owing to the frequent seasonal rains. Strawberries are the only small fruit which have been experimented with at the Sub - station; but, altho it has been found possible — with the help of water from the pump and by keeping the plants mulched with litter and protected during winter — to raise a crop, the returns, at least in our opinion, are far from repaying the labor involved. Whether the lower, subirrigated parts of the farm would grow these and other small fruits or the hardier varieties of orchard fruits has not been ascertained here, but it is almost certain that some of the small fruits could be handled successfully. On the lower benches along the Niobrara and other rivers, when sheltered from the prevailing high winds, hardy varieties </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 61 of apple, pear, plum, and cherry do well, and are beginning to be commercially important, along with the fruit grown in the valley bottoms along the rivers where irrigation is practiced or where the ground is so subirrigated that the under surface water can be kept at a uniform level by drainage. Under such conditions it is possible to raise abundant crops of apples, pears, crab apples, cherries, and plums, as well as an abundance of small fruits, in average years. Among apples the Ben Davis, Gano, Wealthy, Mclntosh, Charlamoff, Duchess of Oldenburg, Wallbridge, Yellow Trans - parent, the Northwestern Greening, and the Whitney crab do well; as do also the Duchess and one or two other varieties of pears; and the Compass, Sapa, and Opata cherries, hybrids between the sand cherry and the plum, are adapted to Sand Hills conditions, even on dry bench lands being found to do well. Red and white currants flourish profusely in some of the sheltered valley bottoms under cultivation, as do the gooseberry, dew - berry, raspberry, blackberry, and strawberry. The most promi - nent wild fruits are the sand cherry, which grows on sandy uplands and along the river and hill canyons, the sour cherry, grape, and plum flourish, the last in great profusion. THE KITCHEN GARDEN IN THE SAND HILLS. Perhaps no other section of the Middle West surpasses that of the Sand Hills in the variety and quality of the vegetables grown in it. This is true, particularly of the sheltered bench lands wherever irrigation can be applied, as well as of the subirrigated valley bottoms. It is unnecessary to mention here all the varieties raised, as the list of them would be co-extensive with that of the Middle West seedsman's catalog; but asparagus, cabbages, celery, onions, tomatoes, and all varieties of the cucurbit family are grown with great success. On light, dry soil such as surrounds the Substation buildings already described in connection with alfalfa and other experi - ments, unless a supply of water from the windmill or tank is available there is some uncertainty in the attempt to grow vege - tables. From the nature of the crops grown, the soil humus in a gar - den composed of such light dry soil is quickly depleted, and it is highly necessary that the supply should be replenished by the careful application of well-rotted barnyard manure in such quantities as can be well assimilated by the ground. This should be put on before the land is plowed in the fall— as all garden land </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. should be, after raking off and destroying old vines and other garden rubbish. The fall plowing and removal of infested rub - bish helps greatly in keeping the garden free from the various garden pests. The plowing in of well-rotted manure in fall, besides adding to the direct fertility of the soil, helps to make it more retentive of winter moisture, and both combined have the effect either of retaining heat in the soil during winter or of absorbing it more freely in spring than land not so treated. This has the effect of making the garden earlier than it would be were the manuring and plowing left over till spring. With these precau - tions, and planting as early as the state of the ground will permit, the following vegetables have been grown successfully at the Sub - station every year without artificial watering, with the exception of the abnormally dry season of 1912 when most vegetables failed except such as could be watered. Beans, beets, early cabbage, corn, carrots, cucumber, watermelons, muskmelons, squashes, early peas, early potatoes, radishes, turnips, and toma - toes. All hardy varieties should be got into the ground as early as possible, and in the case of the less hardy it is better to take some chances by putting them in early, than to wait till later, as the surface soil in which the smaller seeds must develop is very apt to become dry as soon as the weather begins to warm up, making it difficult to get good seed germination. USE OF THE FEET IN SOWING GARDEN VEGETABLE SEEDS In sowing vegetable seeds in dry Sand Hills land gardening, probably more seed is wasted by putting it into too loose ground than from any other cause. Especially is this the case with people who have recently come into this country from more moist or heavier soiled regions where firming the ground around the seed is not so necessary. Small seeds, as most garden seeds are, should be placed at the bottom of a very shallow furrow and the soil pressed down firmly upon and around them. For this purpose nothing surpasses the foot, as it is self -registering, so to speak, and anyone with experience can tell to a nicety by the feel of the ground under it, just how much pressure is necessary for the desired result. Few people realize how important this one simple point in gardening practice is, especially in a dry climate and on porous soil, or understand the vast loss of seed, not to speak of time and effort in preparing ground and sowing, that is caused by its neglect. Even if the seed does grow, it will come up much faster on land that has been well firmed after seeding. Some experiments along this line have been conducted at the Sub - station. Corn and navy beans were planted with the ordinary </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 63 hand corn planter. Alternate rows of either were then gone over with the heel of the foot and well pressed down, and the soil firmed. In the case of the beans the percentage of seed that ger - minated in loose soil was 82, while in the pressed rows there was a stand of 98 per cent. The corn in uncompressed soil showed a germination of 87, while in the soil receiving the heel treatment after planting, the percentage was 96. The compressed corn showed up three days in advance of the uncompressed. The beans were all up before any record of germination was obtained, but the compressed rows showed a marked superiority over those in the rows that had not been firmed. No experiments were carried out with smaller seeds, but firming of the soil is still more important in their case than it is in that of such large seeds as corn and navy beans, for the reason that they are planted at less depths and therefore in looser and drier soil. LAWNS. Second only to that obtained from a grove of trees is the comfort and satisfaction derived from a well-kept lawn adjoin - ing the dwelling house, whether the situation be on the farm or in the town. Altho in the Sand Hills the farmhouse is usually placed as close as possible to the more fertile and productive land, yet, because of drainage and other considerations, the site usually chosen is on elevated or sloping land, which generally means that the surrounding soil is of a light, dry character, where it will take considerable care and frequent attention to establish and maintain a grass sod. The towns and villages in the Sand Hills are also frequently situated on land of a light or sandy nature, and as no residence in these is considered complete without its patch of blue grass, the subject of lawn making and maintenance is of sufficient importance to justify notice here. At the Substation a blue-grass lawn of more than one-third acre extent was laid down over four years ago, and has been kept in good condition since, without excessive expenditure of time and water. In order to reduce the work of keeping this lawn in thrifty condition, great care was taken in laying it down. The original soil being of poor quality, it was considered better to enrich it by adding sod or turf from another part of the prairie, and an abundance of old well-decomposed manure. The ground in front of the house, which was in sod where it had not been cut up by wagon wheels, was carefully cleared of all building debris, such as sand, shingles, ends of plank, bricks, and stones, all of which are quite frequently incorporated in the lawn </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. soil, especially in cities and towns, where they are often the cause of future trouble and disappointment. The sod was then thoroly disked till it resembled plowed land, when it was plowed with a stirring plow and disked again. About thirty loads of old manure were then applied and mixed in with the soil, after which an equal number of two-horse loads of sod cut from another part of the prairie was added and harrowed till it was well pulverized. It was again turned with the stirring plow and left in that state till spring, when it was well dragged and smoothed down with a leveler made of two 16-foot planks joined by cross planks 4 feet in length, which was dragged over it to plane the ground and give it a uniform surface, as is done when preparing land for irrigation. This smoothed surface was then dragged in order to furrow the soil to receive the seed, which, after being sown with a hand seeder, was covered with a large garden rake. Then the soil was firmed by putting a planker drawn by two horses over it, in the absence of a roller, which would have done still better work had it been available. The seeding was done as early as the state of the ground would permit. The weather turning dry and windy, the surface was protected by a dressing of rough prairie hay and litter, which held the soil in place, and also prevented excessive evaporation, and the whole was sprinkled from the hose as frequently as it was found necessary to do so. The seed, which was sown at the rate of 6 quarts per 450 square feet, or 3 bushels per acre, was a mixture of Kentucky blue grass, Italian rye grass, and white clover, in the proportion of 4 parts by weight of blue grass to 2 of Italian rye grass and 1 of white clover. The Italian grass and clover were for the purpose of raising a nurse crop. The Italian grass grew rankly, shading the ground, but was killed out at the beginning of winter by frost, as was expected. Its dead leaves were left in clumps protecting the blue grass, which had come up more slowly baneath them. This lawn has received two top dressings of 4 or 5 two-horse loads of well-rotted manure since it was laid down, this being done at the beginning of winter. Top dressing a lawn occasionally is very beneficial especially in the Sand Hills country. Besides enriching the soil, the dressing fills up the pits that are excavated around the grass clumps by the action of high wind on a sandy soil. Whenever it is considered advisable to water it, the lawn is well soaked instead of being sprinkled, as only sprinkling the surface favors a shallow-rooting habit. No attempt is made t • keep this lawn green during the hottest part of the season, as to do so would incur the use of a large quantity of water. It is allowed to get brown but not burnt, and it is found that as soon as water </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 65 is applied, or when rain comes, or when the weather turns cooler the grass quickly revives. No reseeding has been done since the lawn was established, and the grass is thicker now than at any previous time. The grass is cut with a two-horse mower, but never close down to the ground, as it has been found that out in the open, close cutting such as is done with the hand lawn mower is injurious to the grass. Under trees or where lawns are frequently and abund - antly sprinkled, close cutting may not show such | injurious effects. The grass is raked off soon after mowing, all except the last fall cutting, as the dried grass is apt to give the lawn a burnt up appearance unless removed. Fig. 7. — Concrete block dairy stable and silo at the Substation. ESTABLISHMENT OF A DAIRY HERD. It having from the beginning been the purpose of the Board of Regents of the University to establish a dairy herd at the Valen - tine Substation, a dairy barn of 30-cow capacity, also a silo of 100-ton capacity and other equipment for dairying purposes, were included in the permanent improvements. The cow barn was </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin 156. finished in 1913, and at the beginning of 1914 dairying operations were begun. The herd is composed of a number of pure-bred Holstein cows and a larger number of the common milch cows of the district, headed by a pure-bred Holstein bull. As the results obtained will probably later form the subject of a bulletin, it is unnecessary to refer further to them at this time. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Farming Practice in the Sand Hills. 67 (i-19-'16-12M.) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>