<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-third Biennial Report OF THE WARDEN OF THE STATE PENITENTIARY To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">t z *-- ■&gt; , , I- ■■-'■* </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Twenty-third Biennial Report OF THE WARDEN OF THE STATE PENITENTIARY LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">402 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION Warden W. T. Fenton N. T. Harmon Minnie Murphy W. A. Kirby Deputy Warden Matron Steward E. M. Johnson. G. E. Williams Jas. O'Connell Chaplain Physician Clerk EMPLOYEES OF THE INSTITUTION Captain of Guards D. G. Kavanaugh C. J. McCarthy J. Coen Chief Engineer Night Engineer T. Cokeley A. Werner P. Sullivan E. F. Slagle J. Auch Yard Master Farm Superintendent Assistant Farm Superintendent Day Turnkey Night Turnkey H. Arends H. Evans. Day Chapel Turnkey Night Chapel Turnkey T. J. Glennon J. McNeil Day Keeper West Cell House Night Keeper West Cell House A. L. Cavanaro C. Blake Day Keeper East Cell House Night Keeper East Cell House J. Jenkins C. O. Coen W. Shroeder L. J. Kennedy J. M. Matney Gate Keeper Keeper of Inmate's Dining Room Steward's Clerk Hospital Steward Guard M. F. McWilliams B. Pendarvis Guard Guard Guard Guard Guard Guard Guard J. C. Boyd B. Miller M. Werner T. J. Smith J. Lodge </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 403 J. Reardon R. Dwyer R. Ross Guard Guard .Guard Guard W. Hepfinger SCHOOL OFFICERS AND TEACHERS *Jas. O'Connell Superintendent §L. W. Skelton Principal Commercial Course JE. F. Slagle Teacher Teacher tL. J. Kennedy JF. L. Dinsmore Teacher tT. O'Rourke Teacher fW. Rifenberg Teacher tW. Bohus Teacher tT. J. Brown Teacher 'Chief clerk of the institution SClerk, Handoraft Furniture Company. |Guards. tlnmates. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 404 NEBRASKA STATE PENITENTIARY To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerden. Gentlemen : I have the honor, herewith, to submit to you my report as Warden of the Nebraska State Penitentiary, for the biennial period beginning December 1st, 1912, and ending November 30th, 1914, during which period Honorable S. M. Melick was Warden from December 1st, 1912, to January 17th, 1913. I wish to present to you, gentlemen, a complete report of my work since I took charge of the institution showing conditions as I found them and conditions of the institu - tion at the present time. On taking charge I found the buildings and the general surroundings in a dilapidated condition. The roofs of both cell houses were in very bad condition, letting the rain and melting snow run down through the iron cell houses which cost the State a large sum of money. The iron in the cell houses had become rusted and would in a short time be of little value. We found it necessary to replace the roofs on the west cell house and an asbestos roof was put on and on the east cell house a gravel and tar roof was put on. The administration building was found to have a leaky and bad roof and had to be repaired in many places. I found the cells in bad condition and it was necessary to paint all of them. I also found that the bath house was in a very un - sanitary condition. There were twenty or more old, rusty bath tubs, where disease could be transmitted from one in - mate to another. We at once installed shower baths and now have a clean and sanitary bath house. The old dining room and kitchen were unfit for use and, after completing our beautiful dining room, I can truthfully :ay that we have one of the finest prison dining rooms in the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 405 vest, equipped with new furniture and china dishes taking the place of the old tin plates and tin cups. We have a fine sanitary and well equipped kitchen, with fine range and steam cookers. Until we took charge, two years ago, the prison kitchen did not have a range or stove of any kind. The hospital facilities were very poor until the comple - tion of our new building but we now have a very modern and sanitary hospital for the care of the sick. Our sewerage system was badly in need of repair and drainage was poor. This we have improved in many ways. Much of the plumbing was rusted out and pipes were leak - ing all over the institution, most of which had to be torn out and replaced by new pipes. Our steam pipes were laid in the ground, but this has been improved by taking up the pipes and replacing them in conduit, thus saving much fuel. The bath house and laundry roofs were found in bad shape and it was found necessary to replace them with new roofs. The water supply was inadequate for the institution, and during the summer of 1913 we were compelled to haul water from College View, two miles distant, in tanks for washing and flushing purposes. For many years this shortage of water has existed and much money had been spent in former years trying to get a sufficient supply of water close to the institution. We decided that it was un - wise to try further for water close to the institution and after putting down a test well about a half mile north of the institution and gettin? an abundant supply of good, pure water, we decided to locate our wells and pumping station there. We now have an abundance of water for all pur - poses, which is forced through the mains from the wells to the reservoir south of the prison. The pump at the well is run by a dynamo, power being furnished from the plant at the institution. The outside of the prison was in total darkness at night. We had cement lamp posts made by the inmates and erected in front of the administration building and also in front of both cell houses. The grounds are now well lighted. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">406 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF The guard's dining room was also badly in need of re - pairs. A re-inforced concrete floor was put in over their dining hall and over this four rooms were built for the steward's living quarters. We have converted our old dining room into a good school-room. We have sixty school desks which we pur - chased second hand. The room is now well equipped to carry on our school work. Mr. O'Connell, who is an exper - ienced school man, looks after the school, assisted by sev - eral of the inmates as teachers. Our enrollment last win - ter was one hundred forty-five and the results were very satisfactory. When the school opened we had thirty-five of our boys who could neither read nor write. At the close of the term last summer all except one could both read and write. The grounds in front of the building were very low and the water, in time of heavy rains, did not carry off. We have improved this condition by hauling in about seven hundred loads of earth, which raised the grounds about two feet in front of the prison. Our old kitchen has ben cleaned and painted and equipped for a sanitary vegetable room, where vegetables are peeled and prepared for the different kitchens. We found over one thousand window lights broken in the different buildings. These have all been replaced. The cement walks in the prison yard were gone to pieces and have been replaced by new walks. We have been handicapped, heretofore, on account of not having any winter feed for our stock. This has been taken care of by the erection of a new cement silo, which holds about one hundred seventy-five tons of ensilage. We will now endeavor to build up a good dairy herd. All of our buildings have been thoroughly renovated and painted. Gentlemen, I think the above items cover the improvements for the past two years. REGARDING DOPE TRAFFIC IN THE INSTITUTION On taking charge we found that about seventy-five to one hundred men were addicted to the use of morphine and </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 407 other opiates. We were compelled to lock up these unfor - tunate men and place a guard over them in order to prevent them from harming themselves. After several weeks of treatment by our prison physician, Dr. Williams, assisted by Dr. Humphrey, we were able to cure these men of this awful habit and we now have them back to their normal condition and they fully appreciate the fact that they have given up the habit. We discovered that this traffic had been carried on by some unscrupulous and unworthy em - ployees of the State and some working under the contrac - tors. Some of these men had ordered morphine in bottles by the gross from Chicago and other cities and made large profits by the sale of it to the unfortunates who had fallen victims of their traffic. I at once discharged all of the em - ployees who were in any way connected with the traffic. I can now truthfully say that we have not one dope fiend in the institution and the men are now enjoying good health and the moral atmosphere of the institution is the very best. DISCIPLINE The discipline of the institution is neither unduly mild nor severe. Continued stresss is laid upon the importance of self-government on the part of the inmates. The of - ficers are urged to stimulate in them the desire to rule from within. PAROLES We are highly gratified to report that the parole sys - tem in operation is becoming more satisfactory from year to year. The per cent of reclamations has been much great - er the last two years than at any previous period, only fifteen per cent having violated the conditions of their pa - roles in the past year. Two years ago parole violations were as high as forty-two per cent. The reason for this, I think, wes largely due to the dope traffic which was carried on in this institution. When men went out using the drug in nearly every instance he was returned. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 408 EMPLOYMENT FOR INMATES The last session of our legislature abolished the con - tract system in our penal institutions. The broom contrac - tors who have employed from one hundred fifty to two hun - dred of our boys are slowly moving out and by the time the legislature has convened they will be working but few men, if any. This is a problem which every State is confronted with where the contract system has been abolished. As to which is the best and most profitable work for the State to engage in, is a very important question which must be passed upon and decided by the next legislature. When the legislature passed this law it also passed a law prohibiting the State from manufacturing any article which would come in competition with any industry now operating in Ne - braska. They also appropriated thirty-five thousand dollars for the establishment of a twine plant to be operated by the State. On investigation we find that it would be impossible to build and equip a twine plant for less than a hundred and fifty thousand dollars. In addition to this amount it would be necessary to have not less than one hundred twenty-five thousand dollars as a revolving fund to purchase raw mater - ial and carry on the business of manufacturing twine. We also find that the cost of coal at the price we must pay would cost a great amount of money and the profits in the twine business being very small we do not believe it the proper industry for the State to engage in. RECOMMENDATIONS I would respectfully recommend to the legislature that they so modify the law so as to allow the Honorable Board of Commissioners of State Institutions to establish the broom industry and the furniture business in this institution. The work carried on in a penal institution should be work which requires a great amount of hand work and that the value of the article should be represented mostly in the labor performed on such articles. We could furnish brooms and furniture for the different State institutions which, of course, is a very small item, so small that it makes it neces - sary that we be permitted to put those articles on the open </seg>
            <seg id="p010">1 i &lt; J 4 ! 1 1 CD P Z UJ li ! I _ 8 &amp;5 &gt; s </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 409 market. I am confident that the tax payers of this State do not desire to have these men left idle on our hands and the small amount of manufacturing that we do at the prison in the lines of brooms and /urniture cannot and will not, in the least, harm industries of free labor already established in our State. We feel confident that an appropriation of not more than thirty-five thousand dollars, with the machin - ery we already have, will equip our broom and furniture shops and carry on these two industries. We are confident that it will bring more revenue into the State than the twine business owing to the small amount we would have invested and give many more men employment than would the twine business. ROAD WORK Governor Morehead has for many years advocated working as many of our boys as possible on the roads of the State. In this matter I heartily agree with him and would recommend to the Honorable Legislature that they pass some legislation whereby the State can work a number of these men at building roads. FARMING We have in our prison farm only two hundred ninety - six acres. Under our honor system we work on this land, during the crop and vegetable season, from twenty-five to forty men. If we had another half section close to our in - stitution we could work many more men outside the walls on the farm. Therefore, I recommend that the legislature look into the advisability of purchasing more land for the penitentiary. REFORMATORY In view of the fact that there is some question regard - ing the advisability of establishing a Reformatory, in case the Reformatory is not established, I recommend that the penal laws be changed so that every man between the ages of eighteen and twenty-five years and, having a limited edu - cation and sentenced to the penitentiary, a part of his sen- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">410 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK tence shall be that during his incarceration he shall attend school at least two hours a day. And further I would rec - ommend, providing the Reformatory is not established, that the legislature appropriate a sufficient amount for the erec - tion of a school building at the penitentiary. It has become apparent to a large number of our jurors and legislators, and I firmly believe they are right on this question, that the protection of society and the reformation of the offender are the elements always to be considered. REGARDING ELIG1BLES FOR PAROLE In almost all of the progressive States of the Union they now have their parole laws so arranged that, after a life-man has served a certain number of years and shows a disposition to reform, the Board of Parole can parole him. They also have laws where long term men, such as twenty-five and thirty-year men, after they have served six, seven, or eight years, and show a disposi - tion to reform, the Board of Parole shall have the right to parole them. I would heartily recommend that our legis - lature pass some legislation along this line as it is a difficult matter to reform men when they have nothing to look for - ward to but a life behind the walls. We have men in this institution who have been sentenced for twenty-one and thirty years who are as susceptible to reformation as those who have only a sentence of one year. CANNING FACTORY 1 would recommend to the Honorable Board that a small canning plant be placed in one of the old rooms of the fac - tory building for the purpose of canning corn, beans, peas, tomatoes, and fruits of different kinds. I would recommend that a small plant be put in here with a capacity of canning for our own institution the first year and, if it proved sat - isfactory and economical. I would recommend that tHe ca - pacity be increased later and that we do canning for all the State institutions. The Government now has a plant for steam canning, which I understand is very satisfactory, and the plant could be installed with a small amount of capital. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 411 RtCREAfiON AND AMUSEMENTS Our recreation and amusement consist of yard priv - ileges every Sunday morning for two hours. The men are permitted to associate and converse together during the time they are in the yards. During the summer months the Beatrice Creamery Company kindly donated to us fifty gal - lons of butter milk each Saturday. This was put on ice on Saturday and placed in the yard for the men on Sunday forenoons. We have abolished the old rule of silence at the meals. During the baseball season we played ninety games of baseball, playing the amateur teams of Lincoln and the State Farm. We played those games in the evenings after the boys had finished their tasks. As our enclosure is not large enough to play on the inside, we were obliged to play outside the walls, the boys being taken out in groups of from seventy-five to one hundred twenty-five. We have a band and orchestra. The orchestra furnishes music in the new dining hall during the meal hour. We expect during the coming year to purchase a moving picture machine. This will be purchased from a fund made from the receipts at shows which the boys expect to put on at Thanksgiving Christmas and New Year. We also expect to put on a good show during the session of the legislature. 1 wish to state that the boys have fully appreciated the new privileges they have been granted and not one has taken advantage of them in any way. REGARDING REVENUE FROM SHOPS As the number of men for the past two years has been much less than in former years and the fact that we em - ployed as many as forty men putting in our new water sys - tem and about the same number employed on the new build - ing and other improvements and also an unusually large number have been engaged in raising the garden truck, the amount of money from the shops turned into the State is not so large as in some previous years. Another reason for th'e amount not being so large is that, for the past two months, we have had comparatively few men working in </seg>
            <seg id="p014">412 KIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF the broom factory, as the contractors are removing their machinery and slowly moving out. Our chair factory, here - tofore, has been working fifty-two men, but, owing to the European War making it impossible for them to get suffi - cient material for the reed and fiber chairs, the number of men has been cut down to thirty. The material used in making these chairs is purchased almost entirely in Ger - many. ESCAPES We have had no escapes from the institution since tak - ing charge. One man, who had been furloughed for a few days to Tecumseh, broke faith with us, but he was captured and brought back. We worked the boys on the outside with - out guards. Our honor system has worked very satisfac - torily and we expect to work a greater number outside dur - ing the coming season. FOOD FOR INMATES We are feeding our men well. Heretofore there was no variety of food. There was no stove or range to prepare it. We hear no complaint whatever about the food since we have changed the old menu of hash every morning. Fol - lowing is our average daily menu : Breakfast — Fried breakfast bacon, brown gravy, fried po - tatoes, wheat bread, coffee. Dinner — Roast pork, boiled navy beans, stewed turnips, cof - fee. Supper — Cottage fried potatoes, brown gravy, hot biscuits, syrup, tea. RELIGIOUS WORK It is with deep sorrow that I report to the Governor and Honorable Board the death of our venerable and grand old chaplain who passed away last January. For eight years he has looked after the spiritual welfare of our boys and the good work he has done for those who are now here and those who have gone out into the world shall live on as a monu - ment to his memory. I heartily commend the Honorable </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 413 Board for their wisdom in the selection of our new Chaplain, Rev. E. M. Johnson. He is doing a great work among the men and they all hold him in high esteem. Our volunteer, Catholic Chaplain, Reverend Father Moran has for many years looked after the spiritual welfare of the boys of that faith. He makes his visits every two weeks and is doing a good work. With these two gentlemen working in perfect harmony for the spiritual welfare of the unfortunate has placed the moral standard of this institution on a high plane. The good people of Lincoln and the surrounding suburbs who so kindly and unselfishly give their services every Sunday to their Sunday school classes deserve a great deal of credit for their work in the interest of humanity. The superintendent of the Sunday school, Mr. Cordner, has been a faithful worker for many years and deserves much credit for his work among the boys. I desire to thank all of those good people for their hearty co-operation for the betterment of the men in this institution. Dr. Leavitt and Chaplain Johnson and Dr. Bullock and Captain Gifford deserve a great deal of credit for their faithful work in securing employment for the paroled and discharged boys, many of whom they have placed in posi - tions where they are making good and are a credit to so - ciety. CONCLUSION In conclusion I wish to express to Deputy Warden Har - mon my sincere gratitude for his faithful and loyal service to the State and the support he has given me at all times in the elimination of the dope traffic and the reforms that we have brought about during the past two years and I desire to state to the Honorable Board that much credit is due to him for the good and faithful service he has performed. I also desire to express my sincere thanks to Captain of the Guards, Mr. Kavanaugh and all the other guards and em - ployees who have been faithful to every trust and assisted me in cleaning up the dope traffic. And to you, gentlemen, members of the Board of Commissioners of State Institu - tions and Governor Morehead. 1 wish to thank you for the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">414 KIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF kind consideration and official courtesy you have always shown me. The statistical report of the institution by the chief clerk, Mr. James O'Connell, the financial report up to the time the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions took charge, also the report of the chaplain, librarian and mat - ron, and the report from the farm you will find filed in this report. Respectfully submitted. Lhifolv, Xthittska, Norember 30, 191!,. CHAPLAIN'S REPORT Tii W. T. Fenton, Warden: It is with pleasure that 1 submit to you a report of the work in my department of your institution. From the death of Chaplain P. C. Johnson in January of this year until my appointment, June 1st. the Prison was without a regular Chaplain ; different persons were secured to con duct the regular Chapel services on Sunday. Since my appointment, the services have been conducted by me per sonally, or under my direct supervision. 1 have been ably assisted by Mr. J. E. Storm and his daughter Esther, wh&gt; had charge of the music until August, and by Mr. J. E. Enix and Mr. Thompson, who have directed the music since Mr. Storm's retirement. Other assistance has been given by Mr. J. G. Cordner, who has superintended the Sunday School, and a competent corps of teachers who have faithfully done their work in that department of the religious activity. Soon after I took up the work I arranged to meet all who wanted to receive special Biblical instruction and a class of 66 members was organized to meet on Saturday night for Bible study. Under the direction of this depart - ment, a Volunteer Prison League was organized- and ■ 107 of the prisoners joined this body by taking the following pledge: _•---". "I promise to pray morning and evening; to read the W. T. Fenton. Warden. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 415 'Day Book' every day; to abstain from all intoxicating drinks; from the use of profanity, and all other indecent language; to obey all the rules and discipline of the in - stitution ; to keep cheerful and enlist others in the 'Prison League'." The League meetings were held on Monday nights until the night school began and, since that time are held in connection with the Bible Study on Saturday nights. Thu members of the League make up the program for thes._&gt; meetings and conduct them under my direction. I spend every Sunday afternoon visiting the prisoner - in their cells and talking to them about their moral and spiritual welfare. At least twice a week I visit the men in the shops in order to give a word of cheer and encourage - ment while they are busy at their tasks. The moral condition of the prison body is on a high plane. The prisoners show a deep appreciation of the re - ligious work that is bein? done. They are very attentive at the Chapel services and at the Saturday night Bible study. The attendance at the Sunday School is voluntary and about half the inmates attend this part of the service. As one of the results, we ljave seen four conversions in the past six months. Besides the work that has been mentioned, Father Moran of the Catholic Church conducts special services for those who are associated with the Catholic faith. These services are held each two weeks on Saturday night and Sunday morning and have been well attended, with profit able results. My work as Chaplain has been very pleasant and i have been most cordially treated by the officers, guards, shop-overseers, and the occupants of the prison. I want to express to you, especially, my appreciation of your as - sistance and co-operation in the religious work in the in - stitution. Respectfully submitted E. M. Johnson, Chaplain Li.icohi, Nebraska, November Jo, mJ, </seg>
            <seg id="p018">416 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF REPORT OF LIBRARIAN To. W. T. Fenton, Warden: It is with pleasure that I submit to you a report of the library for the past biennium from December 1st, 1912, to November 30th, 1914. The Prison Library is under the State Library Com - mission and we receive frequent visits from Miss Florence Waugh who has general supervision of the libraries in the State institutions. There are thirty-two hundred carefully classified vol - umes on the shelves and a complete catalogue is given to each inmate with the privilege of selecting his reading. One of the prisoners acts as librarian under the supervis - ion of the Chaplain. The present assistant has been in this position for nine months and his records show that ten thousand two hundred forty-nine volumes have been read in that time, making an average of eleven hundred thirty-eight volumes per month, or four books for each man. The character of the reading may be seen by one month's itemized report for October, 1914: General Works 16 Philosophy 45 Religious 45 Sociology 24 Science 23 Useful Arts 25 Fine Arts 21 Literature 228 History 74 Travel 58 Biography 60 Fiction 791 Total 1427 It is the purpose to have works read which are of a high character and to keep out such reading matter as would not be uplifting. Respectfully submitted, E. M. Johnson, Librarian. Livolv, Nebmska. Nwmber 90, I91h </seg>
            <seg id="p019">—4 . jfll w9r f S Is ft c p &lt; S i I 1 u. C g a: </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 417 REPORT OF CLERK To. W. T. Fenton, Warden Herewith is submitted the report of the clerk's office for the biennium, 1913-14 : The report of the financial affairs of the institution differs very materially from the preceding biennial reports. The Board of Commissioners of State Institutions, which took charge early in the biennium, adopted a different sys - tem of monthly reports and required that a detailed state - ment of all financial transactions in each of the several in - stitutional funds be transmitted to that office each month, where they will be compiled, and it is the policy of the Board to make all future biennial reports of all the State insti - tutions both to the governor and the legislature from that office. The instructions of the Board for this biennium re - quire that each institution report the condition of each of the funds from the beginning of the biennium, December 1, 1912, to April 1, 1913. Accordingly, I have given a brief statement of the balances on hand December 1, 1912, the total expenditures for the period, and the balances April 1, 1913. With respect to the earnings of the institution the same prevails in the Institution Cash Fund. In the earn - ings from other sources the earnings are given for the biennium. A comparison of the earnings from the broom and fur - niture contracts during this and preceding years show a decrease. This is due to three causes. The number of in - mates has averaged about one-fourth less and during the latter part of the biennium the broom contract, because of the law abolishing contract labor, has been reducing the number of men employed. During the larger part of the biennium it was necessary to employ a large number of in - mates on the new construction work done. An average of thirty men were employed on the new dining room and hos - pital, enlarging and repairing the sewerage and plumbing systems, putting in the new water system and in general </seg>
            <seg id="p021">418 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF repairs on the entire plant. This labor saved the State sev - eral thousand dollars. You will notice a difference in the sources of earnings. Formerly it was the custom to report all income as earnings. I have eliminated all sources of income but those that show actual earnint-s. These are Special Labor, Chapel Stand, and Barber Shop. To these should be added the steward's report of earnings on the farm. The income from all other sources, such as dining room, sale of old horses, cows, hides, bones, and all other useless materials should be credited to the funds that produced them. This makes the earnings comparatively less. An inspection of the tables submitted by the Board for the report on the Movement of Population, Statistics, and Vital matters will show that there is much data called for that has not been recorded in this office. This is to be re - gretted, as these statistics are of the utmost importance in the study and care of the State's defectives. I would sug - cest the standardizing of these forms and the procuring of suitable books of record so that all future statistics may be full and reliable. Those given cannot be very satisfactory to the Board. Respectfully yours. Jas. O'Connell, Clerk Lincoln, Nebraska. November 30, 191k. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 419 Report on Penitentiary appropriations for the period beginning De - cember 1, 1912. and ending March 31, 1913. LAND PURCHASE Balance on hand December 1, 1912 $ 328.00 Expenditures for the period Balance on hand April 1. 1913 $ 328.00 BATH TUB AND KITCHEN UTENSILS Balance on hand December 1, 1912 $ 1058 99 Expenditures for the period Balance on hand April 1, 1913 OFFICE AND CONTINGENT Balance on hand December 1, 1912 Expenditures for the period Balance on hand April 1, 1913 GENERAL Balance on hand December 1, 1912 Expenditures for the period Balance on hand April 1, 1913 MAINTENANCE Balance on hand December 1, 1912 Expenditures for the period Balance on hand April 1. 1913 DEFICIENCY Deficiency Appropriation for the Biennium 1911-12 Expenditures to April 1, 1913 Balance on hand April 1, 1913 CASH FUND INSTITUTION Balance on hand December 1, 1912 Total receipts for the period Total received Total expenditures for the period Balance on hand April 1, 1913 On deposit in the state treasury In the vault EARNINGS FOR THE STATE GENERAL FUND Bioom contract Furniture contract 13126.02 $50444.24) REPAIRS iBiennium, 1913-14) $37318.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">420 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK EARNINGS KOR THE INSTITUTION CASH KUND (For the period, Dec. 1, 1912, to April 1, 1913) Special labor, all sources $967.52 Barber shop 36.90 Ohapel stand 74.71 * 1079. 13 SAVINGS TO THE STATE •Electricity supplied other state institutions 325,126 K. W. H. @ 5c $16256.30 Labor on new construction and general repairs 8623 days &lt;g $1.00 8623.00 $25879.30 $76402.61 Total earnings and savings •Electricity supplied at the lowest current price. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 421 HOME GROWN PRODUCE OF INSTITUTION DURING BIENNIUM ITEM QUANTITY VALUE Cabbage Spinnaeh Turnips Carrots Parsnips Onions 31400 Pounds $ 251.20 180 Bushels 108.00 1600 bushels _ 400.00 240 bushels 120.00 300 bushels. 150.00 678 bushels 542.40 Radishes Lettuce Rhubarb Peas 328 bushels 196.80 592 bushels 532.80 35 bushels 24.50 94 bushels 75.20 Beans 170 bushels 136.00 Potatoes Tomatoes Beets 1707 bushels 1024.20 248 bushels _ 124.00 137 bushels 95.90 Cucumbers Peppers .... 25 bushels 20.00 15 bushels _... 18.75 Sweet corn Piccalilli 2500 dozen 250.00 184 gallons _... 73.60 Beef 2020 pounds 202.00 Pork killed Pork shipped Poultry 23231 pounds 2090.79 15520 pounds 1211.89 800 pounds 144.00 Oats Veal 1111 bushels 511.06 435 pounds _ 36.97 Alfalfa Hay 82 tons 1312.00 14 tons _ 182.00 Milk 11680 gallons 1868.80 Straw Fodder Millet Wheat Rye 50 tons 150.00 130 tons 780.00 2 tons 26.00 1155 bushels _ 1155.00 730 bushels 657.00 Ensilage Corn .... 119 tons 1309.00 950 bushels 532.00 Eggs Bran 365 dozen _ 65.70 700 pounds _ 7.00 Shorts 3900 pounds _ 46.80 Total $16430.46 HOME GROWN PRODUCE ON HAND AT CLOSE OF BIENNIUM ITEM QUANTITY 800 bushels 45 tons 14 tons VALUE Turnips Alfalfa Hay $ 200.00 450.00 126.00 Straw Oats 5 tons 15.00 700 bushels 10771 bushels 322.00 Wheat 1077.66 Ensilage Rye 95 tons 1045.00 10 bushels 125 bushels 154 gallons 18 « bushels 9.00 Corn 70.00 Piccalilli 61.60 Wheat sowed 18.80 Total $ 3395.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">422 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK STOCK ON HAND AT CLOSE OF BIENNIUM Horses 9 Calves HI Mules 3 Pigs, fall 103 Colts 1 Pips, spring:, and sows 101 Cows 18 Pigs, boars 1 Heifers iyear and over) 11 Chickens 75 Bulls 1 Ganders 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 423 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION •Includes those who have been previously incarcerated in this or other penitentiary. For Year Ending ' Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30, 13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Present at begin- ning of period 374 7 381 352 5 357 328 4 332 Admitted: For first time 95 2 97 62 1 63 228 5 233 385 8 393 Readmitted* 14 14 8 8 24 24 46 46 Returned from pa- role or furlough 1H 16 8 8 18 ..... 18 42 42 Returned from es- cape made before commencement of period 1 1 1 1 1 1 3 3 8 Total received 126 2 128 79 1 80 271 5 276 476 8 484 Discharged : Expiration of sen- tence 29 2S» 18 18 17 17 64 64 Died 4 4 1 1 4 4 9 9 Pardon 6 6 6 6 Order of Court 1 1 1 1 2 2 4 4 Transfer to other institutions 7 7 2 2 10 1 11 19 1 20 Executions 1 1 - 1 1 Paroled or fulough- ed and not return- ed during period 87 1 88 71 2 73 189 1 190 347 4 351 Total released 135 1 136 93 2 95 222 2 224 450 5 455 2 95 222 2 224 450 Average population 358 7 365 341 5 346 342 8 350 ' 347 7 354 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">424 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK TABLE II. AGE OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 My 1,11 ending Total AGE Nov. 30, for to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Bienmum M F T M FT MFT MFT 16 and under 18 yrs 1 1 2 2 5 5 8 8 13 40 40 60 60 20 50 50 92 1 93 15 49 49 86 86 18 and under 21 yrs 7 7 13 21 and under 25 yrs 22 1 23 20 25 and under 30 yrs 22 22 15 :)0 and under 35 yrs 26 1 27 1 8 40 1 41 73 3 76 5 30 2 32 49 2 51 . 4 15 15 23 23 2 9 1 10 14 1 15 •J5 and under 40 yrs 14 14 5 40 and under 45 yrs 4 4 4 45 and under 50 yrs 3 3 2 50 and under 55 yrs 8 8 1 1 8 8 17 17 60 and under 70 yrs 1 1 4 15 5 16 1 1 1 1 70 and over Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 251 5 256 428 8 436 TABLE III. RACE OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total RACE to to Nov. 30, for June 30, It No&gt; ov.S mJk 30,1 13 IS 914 Bien iiennium nnium M F T M M F F T T M M F FT M T M F F T T White Nejrro Indian Chinese Japanese ... 97 97 10 2 12 l i 58 11 1 59 220 11 28 2 .. __ 1 _ 5 225 376 28 49 2 2 1 _ 1 1 6 381 2 51 2 1 1 T»-A— 1 - c oce t oo o i ■■•• </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 425 TABLE IV. EDUCATION OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1.13 ending Total EDUCATION Nov. 30, to lo for June 30, 13 Nov.30, 13 1914 Biennium M F T M FT MFT MFT None 4 4 3 3 11 11 18 18 10 31 1 32 52 1 53 Primary 11 11 10 Common school 63 2 65 46 High school 25 25 9 1 47 177 4 181 286 7 293 9 26 26 60 60 25 25 9 College or Univ 5 5 1 1 6 6 12 12 Unknown Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 251 5 256 428 8 436 TABLE V. CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 ending Total CIVIL STATUS Nov. 30, for to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT M FT MFT MPT Single 72 1 73 50 28 1 29 17 4 4 2 1 51 182 4 186 304 6 310 17 66 1 67 111 2 113 Married Widowed Divorced Separated Unknown 4 2 2 1 1 7 7 3 3 3 3 1 2 2 3 I 1 Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 251 5 256 428 8 436 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">426 KIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF OF OSE COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 NATIVITY Dec. 1, 12 t &gt; June 30, 13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M V T M F T M M F F T T M M F T F T Nebraska U. S. other than Nebraska: Arkansas Alabama Colorado Connecticut California Georgia fowa Illinois Indiana Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Michigan Massachusetts Minnesota Missouri Maryland Maine Mississippi Montana North Carolina New Jersey New York New Mexico Ohio Oklahoma Pennsylvania South Dakota South Carolina Texas 17 i 1 1 2 1 14 7 4 3 2 1 1 1 2 I 1 . 11 1 . . ___ 2 2 1 1 17 1 1 1 I 1 14 7 I 1 2 1 1 1 2 I i ii 1 i 2 2 13 1 14 1 1 " i ".'.'. ". l 1 i 2 2 1 1 4 4 4 4 2 2 5 5 2 2 "~i"..'Z 2 i ... " i 8 ...... 8 1 1 1 1 1 1 " t~"L 2 2 '.'". 2 48 2 1 I 1 2 1 . 17 22 7 3 I 2 1 3 . 1 13 1 ~ 2 . 1 t 1 6 1 12 2 13 '""£".'. 1 1 48 2 1 I 1 2 1 17 n 7 :} •5 2 1 ■i 1 14 1 2 1 2 6 1 12 2 II 5 78 I I 8 3 6 3 35 33 13 11 10 3 4 4 4 . 26 2 1 I 1 I 3 . 17 1 13 . 2 15 1 2 7 1 1 1 2 79 I i 8 ■•! 6 3 M :i4 13 12 10 I 4 4 4 ■ 2 1 3 1 2 3 17 1 II I Ii 1 2 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 427 TABLE VI NATIVITY OK THOSE COMMITTED— (Continued) For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year ending Dec. 1. 12 July 1,13 to Nov.30,13 Total NATIVITY Nov. 30, to for June 30, 13 1914 Biennium M F T M F T M FT M F T Vermont Virginia 1 1 1 ■&gt; H 2 7 1 6 8 8 West Virginia Wisconsin 1 1 1 2 3 3 ! ! 1 • 9 Washington D. C Total native born 1 1 1 86 2 88 1 M 1 1 1!I7 2 199 338 5 343 55 Austria 1 1 3 3 4 4 Canada 1 1 5 7 5 England 1 1 3 3 4 ..._. 4 15 8 19 Germany 4 4 4 Greece ■1 2 2 2 Ireland 3 3 :i 3 6 6 1 1 1 Italy 1 Jamaica 1 1 1 1 Japan 9. 2 2 2 3 3 4 4 Mexico 1 1 Norway 1 1 1 1 Poland 2 2 2 2 Palestine 1 1 1 1 13 2 13 Russia 2 Sweden 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 1 Spain 2 2 2 Scotland West Indies 1 1 3 1 1 35 2 37 50 2 52 Total foreign born 12 12 ■i 10 10 11 19 1 20 40 1 41 251 5 256 428 8 436 Unknown 11 Totals 108 2 110 IW 1 70 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">428 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF w «C Hf OOSC CO OC qCM CO t- ■ M - - ! — 1 1 1 1 I ~ — 3s «c osoooc tit-oo« coooqp'-icot- n *-4 CO — &lt; E — h tfil *• ■" ! "" : Hi 1 1 1 i 1 1 la S 5 ! fc " 1 ! T MM I 1 1 1 1 1 i|z -f«&lt; u. - | j- I ; | | | i j l j | i 1 j ~T~\ •• ■ } : : : : TH i T ■ V Uil irl I I' N ii! is 1|| j 8 |! IN Jlljl|||l|| I I il ill LI™!J*W I a,L ! Ig 2iilHill. s l&amp; I JlJSitLiltilHljiJi C 3 S- _ _ c « "X— — — 9 "* i-; 2 » T : </seg>
            <seg id="p032">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 429 — k -» ■w ie ■* ihjc o _ § H a 111 *■ i ! ! ! ! a r- u ts Jg — »-tr.'C'*f T ji ut -^&gt; ■-( CO O5 I i ~ i : : : : tD I „ x j_ I ™- - ! — fl -H C^ W Is -:*i H mm i ; m N ?!■ s ? . i- ri !*= -"** &amp;. ! ! i I ! ! ! i " i i i : i : : : T~ T I HI Mill I jllll I MM : jllll I ||. | ; I ill 1 ! 4 ! jj'l 1 1 Evil s-sl s| 5 &lt;J G -g </seg>
            <seg id="p033">430 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ) For Year Endinp Nov. 30, 1913 OCCUPATION For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending to to Nov. 30, June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Total for Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Auto machinist Barber Bell hop Butcher Ball player Bookkeeper Blacksmith Blacksrrith helper Butler Bartender Bakers helper Baker Boiler maker Cook Clerk Cleaner &amp; presser. Carpenter Cow boy Cement worker Chauffeur Car repairer Cabinet iraker Construction fore- man Dressmaker Engineer Electrician Farmer Fireman Florist Gunsmith Housework Horseman Horse trader Harness maker Hotel keeper Laborer Lumberjack Lineman Lithographer Laundryman Lather 1 1 4 4 2 2 8 8 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 4 4 1 1 1 1 3 3 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 - 1 2 2 1 1 6 6 8 6 17 17 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 3 8 - 4 4 1 1 2 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 3 3 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 4 4 1 1 26 26 14 14 49 49 5 5 5 5 1 1 1 1 ... 2 2 1 1 3 3 2 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 17 17 15 15 58 58 1 1 1 1 1 12 2 :::::::: 1 :::::: \ t * ;; 1 1 1 1 14 14 3 3 7 7 1 1 4 4 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 31 31 3 3 2 2 7 7 3 3 2 2 2 2 1 1 3 ■■'. 1 1 1 1 6 « 1 1 89 89 10 10 1 1 1 1 .... 6 6 3 ..,:.. s 1 1 1 1 1 1 90 90 2 2 3 3 1 . ... 1 2 2 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 1 251 5 266 428 8 43fi THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS tai TABLE VIII. PREVIOUS OCCUPATIONS OF THOSE COMMITTED— (Continued) For Year Endinir Nov. 30, 1913 OCCUPATION Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 to f&gt; June 30, V.i Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30. 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T Miner Machinist Machinist's helper Musician Moulder Marble Cutter Merchant Moving picture operator Motorman Nurse Porter Painter Plasterer Photographer Plumber Paper hanger Printer Policeman Railroader Ranchman Rubber Real estate Roofer Stonemason Sailor Salesman Solicitor Shoemaker Saw filer Stock buyer Steward Soldier Steeple jack Steam fitter Teamster Telegrapher Traveling saleslady Tailor Undertaker Waiter 1 1 1 1 2 2 "i.Z i ZZZZZZ. i i i i "»".".."." 3 "iZZ. 2 2 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 ...... 1 2 2 1 1 2 2 1 2 2 2 1 1 "iZZ. i ZZZZZZZ i i i i l l "4"."..... 4 "iZZ. i 1 1 '"iZZ. 2 "~iZZ. 2 "•'...... i'~iZ~. i 4 4 5 5 2 2 "TZZ. i 1 ] 1 1 1 1 7 7 6 6 T'Z" 7 "iZZ. i 1 1 1 1 2 2 "~iZZ i 1 1 1 1 4"Z" 4 «"""' 3 2 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 7 7 '.Z. i if "iZZ. i 8 8 5 5 8 8 2 2 12 Z.'.'. 12 9 9 2 2 1 1 8 8 2 2 2 2 1 I 1 4 .. 4 4 4 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 5 5 1 1 3 3 2 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 12 12 1 1 1 1 4 4 1 1 15 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">432 FIKST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE IX. RELIGIOUS AFFILIATIONS OR PREFERENCES OF THOSE COMMITTED TABLE X. NUMBER OF CONVICTIONS OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 RELIGIOUS PREFERENCE For Year Dm. 1. 11 July 1, 13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, II Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Protestant Catholic Hebrew Not reported 78 1 79 50 50 U8 1 149 276 2 278 23 23 13 1 14 68 68 104 1 105 2 2 2 2 7 18 6 6 33 4 37 46 5 51 Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 251 5 256 428 8 436 5 256 2* ,3i For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 CONVICTION Dec. 1, '12 to June 30, H July 1, '13 ending Total to Nov. 30, for Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium M F T MFT MFT MFT First Second Third Fourth Fifth Industrial school 93 2 95 12 12 2 2 1 Z-l 1 58 1 59 222 5 227 373 8 381 6 6 19 19 37 37 1 1 3 3 6 6 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 1 1 I I 5 5 9 9 Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 251 5 256 428 8 43H (in 25 !5fi IS </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 433 TABLE XI. COUNTIES FROM WHICH COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year D«c. 1,1* July 1,13 endinif Total COUNTY Nov. 80, to to for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Bienniam MFT MFT MFT MFT Adams 1 1 4 41 6 s Antelope Boone l l l i 1 1 X ■ s ■ Bit Butte Buffalo 3 14 2 2 9 » 14 1 15 5 5 1 1 6 6 2 2 t . . 2 Bovd Brown Butler Burt 1 i: i i i i i i 2 2 4 4 6 B Case Clav 1 1 R 8 » H 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 Custer during Cherry 1 4 4 _, 1 1 5 5 4 4 1 1 1 1 5 1 6 Cheyenne Dawes 3 3 2 13 5 16 2 6 6 8 2 s Onknta Dawson D"dire 3 3 1 1 4 4 1 1 1 i a 2 4 2 2 19 19 26 ■ 4 Deuel Dundv 1 1 1 1 2 2 S *; 2 X 32 32 16 16 68 2 70 : 116 t 118 D^i'grlas Fillirore Furnas Franklin GarfieW Grant 1 1 1 1 I ...... 2 1 1 1 1 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 1 1 1 1 2 2 2 2 2 I Garden Gajre 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 G^SDei Hall 1 :i 3 5 5 7 7 15 If, _. 1 1 1 1 Holt 1 1 1 Howard Hayes Hooker Harlan 1 i~Z i i I i :::::: 1 i : 1 2 ? S 2 2 6 5 3 c 2 2 2 Hamilton Jefferson £ 1 1 1 1 1 1 S 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">434 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF '— ( ontinuei ) For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 COUNTY Dec. 1. 12 to June 30, 13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M r T M F T M P T M F T Kearney Knox Keith ... Kimball Lancaster Lincoln Madison Merrick Morrill McPherson Nance Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe Pawnee Perkins Platte Pierce Phelps Richardson Red Willow Rock Sarpy Scotts Bluff Seward Saunders Saline Sioux Sheridan Thomas Thurston Webster Washington York 8 ... 3 1 1 _" .......... 2 1 2 1 _. 1 1 i ... .......... l ... l T".'.. 2 1 1 3 ... T 8 :i l i ; i . 2 1 2 i '. i . i . 3 i i i 2 1 1 3 „... 2 '".'. 1 HZ 2 S .'. 1 _„... i.. i i l 2 ... _ 4 1 .. 4 23 8 ... 6 ... 2 ... 1 ... 1 ... 2 1 1 5 1 ... ...... " t _ 2 3 3 5 5 2 1 ~i T _ 1 7 '.Z. 2 1 1 . 2 ... 1 4 ...... a \ ... l l 1 2 ... 1 2 1 T i 2 i 1 T.i X 5 2 i l i i 5 1 2 3 4 5 1 ...... 7 3 1 2 4 3 1 2 2 1 2 4 1 35 11 6 2 1 1 2 3 4 8 1 1 3 5 3 1 11 1 3 1 9 11 1 3 1 2 2 6 2 4 3 6 3 1 2 -1 1 ■ 11 a 2 1 1 2 ■i 8 1 1 3 r ■ 4 12 3 1 9 11 1 A 2 2 6 2 ■i 3 fi 3 Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 251 5 256 428 8 43i </seg>
            <seg id="p038">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 435 TABLE XII. CRIMES FOR WHICH COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year ending Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 to to Total CRIMES Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MPT M F T M F T M F T Assault to wound.. 1 1 2 Assault to injure. 1 1 6 — 8 Assault to rob 3 1 1 2 6 Assault to kill 3 -1 Assault to rape 1 ■ 6 Arson 1 :i 5 1 6 Attempted arson 1 1 40 n Burglary 17 II Breaking- and en- tering 18 -1 35 16 67 1 1 1 4 1 1 Bribery Bigamy ■2 1 Blackmail Canying concealed weapons 2 1 3 I Cattle stealing Crime against na - ture 2 1 2 1 Embezzlement Enticing to carnal intercourse 1 1 1 Forgery 16 11 :i6 ■ Felonious assault 1 1 1 1 1 Foeticide 40 1 41 Grand larceny 12 1 U a in Gambling 2 2 Hog stealing 2 2 4 15 22 Horse stealing 2 5 2 1 31 Highway robbery 6 23 1 Incest 1 1 Kidnapping 1 Larceny as bailee 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">436 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XII. CRIMES FOR WHICH COMMITTED— (Continued ) For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1. 12 July 1, 13 ending Total for Biennium (RIMES to to Nov. 30, June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 T M F T M F T M F M F T Larceny from the person 2 2 1 4 1 :i 1:3 1» Manslaughter Murder 4 1 Mortgaging proper - ty not his own 1 1 Obtaining money under false pre - tenses 2 ti s Obstructing rail - road track 1 1 Purchasing stolen property Rape X -I 12 Receiving stolen property 2 1 Removing mort - gaged property 1 1 1 Seduction 1 Shooting with in - tent to do great bodily injury 2 2 1 3 1 Shooting to wound Shooting to kill 1 1 1 1 1 1 fi Shooting cattle 1 1 1 2 Stabbing to wound Selling mortgaged 1 1 A 2 i 5 3 property 2 2 Statutory rape Wife desertion 3 1 69 1 70 251 5 256 428 8 436 Totals 108 2 110 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">THE BOARD OK COMMISSIONERS 437 TABLE XHI. TERMS OF SENTENCE OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year ending Dec. I, 12 July 1, 13 to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 Total for Biennium TERM Nov. 30, 1914 M F T M F T M F T M F T Fixed: Death 1 1 1 1 Life 1 1 9 9 10 10 25 years 1 1 1 1 2 2 22 years 1 1 1 1 20 years 1 1 1 1 1 1 3 3 19 years 1 1 1 1 18 years 1 1 1 1 15 years 1 1 1 1 2 i 13 years 1 1 1 1 2 2 12 years 1 1 1 1 10 years 2 2 2 2 8 years 1 1 1 1 7 years 1 1 1 1 2 2 6 years 2 2 2 ■&gt; 5 years 1 1 1 1 4V4 years 1 1 _ 1 1 1 3 years 2 years 1 year 1 1 5 5 3 3 y 9 2 2 2 2 2 S 3 1 1 I 0 10 10 Indeterminate : 2 to 3 months 3 to 6 months •/ 2 2 1 2 1 1 1 4 to 6 months.. 1 1 _ 1 1 6 to 10 months. 6 to 12 months 12 to 13 months 12 to 15 months 12 to 18 months 1 to 2 years. 1 to 3 years... 1 to 4 years... 1 to 5 years 1 to 7 years.. . 1 to 10 years. 1 to 15 years 1 to 20 years 2 to 7 years 2 to 15 years. 2 to 20 years.. 3 to 5 years... 3 to 6 years 3 to 8 years. 3 to 10 years. 3 to 12 years. 3 to 15 years 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 3 3 1 1 fi fi 7 1 1 3 3 4 4 3 3 1 I 7 7 11 11 :{ 3q I 15 1 16 21 1 22 1 1 - 1 1 6 17 4 4 26 26 3H 1 37 16 1 17 9 1 10 25 25 50 2 52 34 34 23 23 78 2 80 135 2 137 - 1 1 1 1 18 18 10 27 10 2 29 K 2 57 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 7 10 10 . 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 2 2 1 1 1 1 8 8 1 1 17 17 26 26 Totals 108 2 110 69 1 70 j 261 5 256 428 8 436 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">438 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XIV. DURATION OF IMPRISONMENT OF THOSE DIS - CHARGED, PAROLED OR ESCAPED DURING BIENN1UM years : 1 1 1 1 Totals 151 1 152 1 98 5 103 225 3 228 474 9 483 TABLE XV. CHARACTER OF PARENTAGE OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year Endinp Nov. 30, 1913 !?„.. V^., . . Cn^;»r. For Yeai Mm 9t .r Ending ft 1013 DURATION OF IMPRISONMENT Nov. 31 Dec. 1,12 ! to June 30, 13 o, i»ia 1 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Bienniuni M F T M F T M F T M F T M F T M F T Less than 6 months 1 and less than 12 months 12 and less than 18 months 18 months and less than 2 years 2 and less than 3 years I and less than 5 years 5 and less than 10 years _ 10 and less than 15 years 15 and less than 20 5 39 37 19 15 22 11 ■ 1 li HI n 19 15 ■ 11 ■i 2 II lx ti 18 I 7 . 1 1 2 •t I 9 43 110 20 39 6 17 18 30 5 10 7 9 1 9 ; 16 2 112 190 1 40 94 17 42 30 63 10 37 9 27 4 . 1 17 5 195 3 97 42 ... 63 ... 37 ... 27 ... 4 For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T M F T M F M F T M I F T M 1 F T Both parents dead. Father dead Mother dead Both parents living Unknown 18 23 14 39 14 1 1 18 24 . 14 40 14! 3 16 7 .. 27 .. 16 i 3 17 7 27 16 87 39 42 83 1 88 108 2 41 78 2 44 63 83 149 30 1 109 4 82 2 65 1 150 30 Totals.. 108 2 110 69 1 70 251 5 256 , 428 8 436 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 439 TABLE XVI. CAUSES OF DEATH OF PRISONERS For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, '13 ending Total CAUSE to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Abrupt termination of morphine 1 1 1 1 Chronic Nephritis | 1 1 1 1 Executed 1 1 _.._ 1 1 i i i l Obstruction of bowels 1 1 1 1 Suppuration of Perotinitis 1 1 1 2 &gt; 1 Syphillis _ 1 1 1 1 Tuberculosis 1 1 1 ..._. 1 2 2 1 1 . 1 2 2 Valvular heart trouble 1 1 _ _ 1 1 1 Totals 5 5 1 1 4 4 10 10 TABLE XVII. AGES AT DEATH For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total AGE to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT 21 years 1 1 - 1 1 24 years 1 1 j — — 1 1 1 1 28 years - 1 1 ! ' - \ 1 1 31 years 1 - — 1 1 1 34 years : 1 1 1 1 2 2 37 years _ 1 -..-. 1 1 1 38 years _ 1 1 1 1 ._ _ _ 1 1 1 1 41 years - - _ 1 1 1 1 44 years 1 1 1 1 Totals 5 5 1 1 4 4 1 10 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">440 URST BIENNIAL REPORT OK TABLE XVIII. STATISTICS OF PAROLED PRISONERS On paroie Nov. 30, 1912 _ ."..'.". 7. 62 Paroled during biennium 842 Returned from parole: For default _ 1» Without fault _ - - 2 Escaped from parole and not retaken 69 Pardoned while on parole 1 Died while on parole _ none Discharged from parole - _ _ 139 On parole Nov. 30 1914 - - 184 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">THK BOARD OK COMMISSIONERS 441 t- IO T N © 5 .-H &gt;O^ fiS »« i sfii CC IC SO — O5 -^t bee &gt; . "a &gt; 01 I SI" CC lit CO »-*"■*«• 3 2 5 tx J?9En '~"5 - -ON »hS?io | 9 5 z XX — ©IC « oi'-C ai c - o II1I I x ij'ftiilii r 3 z « H It-lOTNOSH »■» OS U3 «D « -* TOO — CN — &lt; — O © os JO CO d : IEft» I* 3 - 1 I h- &gt; \ ■■•::: : ■ : W &gt;-s 2 * ! t-osec -"N n** \£&gt; 2 2 - " § - *~ "«» - / rig IS S s l-Sfeg88 88 |JH S-gJf £££££ £&amp; a ) ao l -' /J 0(i)a)i)a&gt;i) d « liliilljll.^ UuIJm aa,aaa| j — «— '*- *^ V- („ ■_ t_ v- &lt;— "5 — OOOOOOOOOO^gg Illlillllilfl EEESSESfctE «« 3333333333 oo </seg>
            <seg id="p045">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 442 MATRON'S REPORT To W. T. Fenton, Warden: I herewith submit my report as matron of the Ne - braska State Penitentiary for the biennium beginning De - cember 1, 1912, to November 30, 1914. The female ward was under Mrs. S. M. Melick from December 1, 1912, to January 17, 1913, and under Mrs. W. T. Fenton from January 17, 1913, to September 11, 1913, since which time I have had charge. At the beginning of this biennium there were in the female department seven negroes and one Indian woman, while at the present time we have four white women and one negress. The women's quarters have been thoroughly renovated, having been painted and varnished throughout, and they now present a very neat and clean appearance. Besides taking care of their own clothing and rooms, the women do the laundry work for the warden's, deputy warden's and steward's families. They also occupy them - selves by reading books and magazines from the library and in making their own clothing. The discipline of the female ward has been very good during the biennium The women attend chapel services regularly every Sunday and seem to take great interest in the Sunday school lessons. Mrs. Storm had charge of the women's Sunday school class for some time, but owing to ill health resigned in favor of Mrs. Oldham. Both the ladies have taken great interest in the female inmates and have done everything by counsel and advice to raise the </seg>
            <seg id="p046">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 443 moral standard. We wish to thank both Mrs. Storm and Mrs. Oldham for the interest shown. During the past year one woman has been transferred to the Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk. The health of the inmates has been very good and no one has had any serious illness. Respectfully submitted Minnie Murphy, Matron. Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 19H. \ REPORT OF CATHOLIC CHAPLAIN To W. T. Fenton, Warden: I take pleasure, as the voluntary Catholic chaplain of the Nebraska State Prison, in making a report of my work for the past biennium. The attendance at our religious service is voluntary. I am glad to say that the boys of my faith have in the past two years been very attentive to their duties. The words of encouragement I have received from the boys in con - versation make me feel that good is being accomplished. The official chaplain, E. M. Johnson and the deceased chaplain Rev. P. C. Johnson, whose death I regretted very much, have always treated me with the utmost courtesy. I wish to thank Warden Fenton and his family for the hospitality extended to me. I also wish to thank the guards for their courtesy and I desire to thank the inmates for their attention and respectful manner during the services. Respectfully yours. Rev. Robert F. Moran. Denton, Nebraska, November JO, 191i. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">I-IKST BIENNIAL KEPOKT ()K 444 CHiEF ENGINEER'S REPORT To W. F. Fentttu, Warden: it is with plMttuc i report to you a.s chief engineer of the Nebraska State ■ eniiennary. i tie motive power at this institution consists of two high speed iMgiam. uvc return tubular boilers of one hun - uieci twaBty-nve bone power each, two forty horse power motois, two twenty horse power motors, and one forty ■OIM power motor, 'i he two lorty horse power and the two twenty horse power motors are of r airbanks &amp; Morse make, l he ntiy horse power motor is of the Westinghouse make. The generators are Allis-Chalmers, Bullock type, three hundred ampere each, two hundred forty volts, directly connected to Atlas high speed slide valve engine. In addition to furnishing po»\er for our own institu - tion, we also furnish about thirteen hundred kilowat hours to the State House, Governor's mansion, and Orthopedic Hospital each month. We are now and have been for three years working under an overload of from thirty to fifty per cent. The two engines being of a very inferior type, about forty per cent of their energy is wasted, thereby in - creasing the amount of fuel used about forty per cent. I would suggest that if the State would put in ade - quate machinery they would make a great saving in their plant consumption and also make the service much better than it is now. The wiring in the cell houses is all exposed and should be placed in conduits, thereby eliminating the danger of fire. In conclusion I would suggest that the electrical equip - ment in this plant be replaced with new and more up-to-date and more economical machinery. Respectfully C. J. McCarthy. Chief Engineer. Lineal)/, Xthttixka. Nocrmhur .JO, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">THE BOARD OK COMMISSIONER 445 PHYSICIAN'S REPORT Ti&gt; W. T. Fentou, Warden: I have the honor herewith of my service as Prison Physic to November ."50, 1914, inclusive to transmit to you a report ian from January 15, 1913, On taking charge, 1 diseove per cent of the entire prison p phine and other opiates habitual of these men was very much imp rob every man of the last asset &lt; age and altruism, it is needless 1 moral condition of these men \va ing incident to being cured of il out a parallel in the realm of 1 constant attention and some ta ered that approximately 20 topulation were using mor - illy. The physical condition 1 and as morphine will of respect, love, hope, cour - to add that the mental and its worst. The suffer - -&gt;rphine habit is with - in ills and it required ,ct to effect a cure. I am delighted to Bay that all these me n have been cured of their habit and desire for narcotic d igs. Mentally and morally they have been restored t'&gt; Iheir normal state and are capa- ble of resuming their nlaee in icietv ter from the new well and linage bv replacing and re - *tem. enameling all the cells, dpi in in &lt;x the inside walls of eted the sanitation so much An abundance of rood the establishment of better dr layinnr much of the old sewer si paintinT the naileries and kal: the whole institution has perfi needed. Steam prepared food is detrimental to proper diges - tion and assimilation. Your installation of a steel range and the proper preparation of the food will improve the general health of the men which is essential to good disci - pline and modern prison regulation. The new and well - ventilated dining room will add materially to the comfort and health of the institution. For the first time in the history of the prison it is now provided with a modern hospital and in the future we will be able to do modern surgery and apply modern meth - ods for the cure of many physical defects that are responsi ble for the commitment of much of the crime committed. A very large per cent of those committed to the insti- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">446 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF tution are suffering from bad teeth and pyorrhea which is responsible for many ills which cannot be treated success - fully without first removing the cause. I would recommend that some arrangement be made whereby the inmates could have necessary dental service. The prison population at the beginning of my services was 381 and 424 have been admitted since, making a total of 805 inmates under medical observation. Of this number 451 have not been excused from duty by reason of either sickness or accident. 354 have been excused to cell by reason of accident or minor ailment. 151 have been placed in hospital by reason of more serious accident or illness. Seven men have died, which is a mortality of less than one per cent. The average daily number of those excused by reason of accident or confinement in hospital does not exceed three per cent. Of the whole number there are 284 that 1 class as re - formable, 97 doubtful and 43 nonreformable. Fifteen inmates have been examined by a legal board of insanity and have been transferred to the hospital for the insane by order of the Governor and Board of Commis - sioners. Of this number 6 were positively insane when committed. To me the work as prison physician has been very at - tractive and I have not realized a sitrn of a burden in the performance of my duties. I would feel selfish and ungrate - ful did I not express to you my aopreciation of your co-op - eration, also that of Deputy Warden Harmon and Mr. Kavanaugh, Steward Kirby and Chaplain Johnson in im - proving the mental and physical condition of the inmates and the sanitation of the institution. Very Respectfully, G. E. Williams. Prison Physician. Lincoln, Nebraska, November SO, 1914. </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>