<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE State Inspector of Oils TO THE Governor of the State of Nebraska FOR THE YEAR January 1 to December 31, 1911 Also for the Year 1910</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE State Inspector of Oils TO THE Governor of the State of Nebraska FOR THE YEAR January 1 to December 31, 1911 Also for Year 1910 WM. HUSENETTER, State Inspector of Oils Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">To the Honorable Chester A. Aldrich, Governor of the State of Nebraska. Dear Sir In conformity with the provisions of section 4554 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for the year 1909, I have the honor to transmit herewith a detailed statement of the affairs of the Oil Inspector De - partment for the year 1911, beginning January 1st and ending Decem- ber 31st of said year. My predecessor, at the close of the year 1910, having failed to make the annual report for said year's business, and having received from various sources many inquiries for this report, including requests from many eastern institutions, I have considered it wise to include with my 1911 report to you also that of 1910 as gathered from the 1910 records of my predecessor. Yours very respectfully. Wm. Hbhencto, State Inspector of Oils. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">OFFICE FORCE w HiisEnrrra State Inspector of Oils W. 8. Jat Deputy, First Distrirt, Lincoln I.. A. Donahue Deputy, Second District, Omaha 8. I. Nibs Deputy, Third District, Nellgh Jab. S&lt; hoonoveb Deputy, Fourth District, Aurora D. G. Etiiebton Deputy, Fifth District, Bartley F. A. Wisreij Deputy, 8ixth District, Lexington itua Jones S Stenographer, Wymore 1 to take position with a state institn Mias Jones resigned June tion. Mrs. R. M. Stewart appointed stenographer June 1. Mrs. Stewart resigned September 1 to attend to private business. Mr. I' W. McDermond appointed stenographer September 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Year 1911 During the past two years the coming into use of gasoline engines for power purposes has in a measure revolutionized the power sup plying instruments very materially, and to a very great extent the gasoline machines are supplanting the steam engines for purposes of power, from the fact that power by gasoline machines can be furnished much cheaper than by steam engines. In this connection this de - partment has had to confront a very serious and difficult proposition. The manufacturers of these late inventions have succeeded in bringing forward a gas engine that can be operated with very low grade oil, which is very inexpensive, thereby making the power much cheaper to power users, and right here comes in the trouble which the oil department has been confronted with. The 1909 legislature, at the suggestion of Arthur Mullen, then state inspector of oils, treated and passed the present oil law, which requires all of the lower grade of petroleum oils to pass the tests of oils used for illuminating purposes, thereby prohibiting their use for any purpose whatever. Believing the prohibition of using these cheaper oils for power pur - poses very unfair to the power users, I took up the matter with our state legal department, hoping for a more liberal construction of this prohibitive statute, but have been unable to secure this relief, owing to the fact that this provision in the oil law appears very positive. Realizing this so great an injustice to power users, I have tolerated the use of these low grade oils without making any prosecutions, but even with this leniency the users of these low grade oils and seller-, of gas machines have been very nervous, realizing that they were used in violation of the oil laws. I have recommended to the men and sellers of gasoline engines that a friendly suit be brought in some equity court for a more liberal construction of this statute, and have promised my earnest co-operation and assistance in this court pro - cedure, which I think will be done in the near future. Ehe business of the oil department for the year 1911 has been par larly gratifying. The amount paid to the state treasurer in 1910 was $24,742.99, amount paid to state treasurer for 1911 was $36,741.41 — a gain of a little over 43 per cent, which the following tables will </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. rAKATiYE Statement or Inspections ami Receipts ok the Depakt MB.XT FOB THE YEAKS 1906 TO 1911, INCLUSIVE. Barrels Barrels Total Fees Approved Rejected Inspected IMC 222,712 None 222,712 $22,271.20 1M7 261,735 760 262,495 26,330.30 IMS 263,597 185 263,782 25,825 . 00 IMS 331,983 562 332,545 33,307.25 1910 411,991 762 412.753 41,344 .20 1911 501,261 411 501,251 50,842.60 Total 6 years 1.993,279 2,680 1,995,538 $199,310.66 •351 88.498 $8,898.40 I ■■! 1911 over 1910 89,270 Increase a little more than 21 per cent over 1910. COMPARATIVE STATEMENT OF THE AMOUNTS PAID TO THK STATE TREASURER FOR THE YEARS 1906 TO 1911. INCLUSIVE. $113,976.41 Increase over 1910, $10,391 5G; a little over 43 per cent Increase 1911 over 1909, $17,708.95; over 100 per cent. f »,Aio . j a 11,845. :!4 1J.599.15 17,425.60 24,742.99 35,134.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 7 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Bakbei-s Approved and Rejected and Amount w Fees fob the Yeam Beginning Ja.niahy 1, 1911, and E.ndinu Decembsb 31, 1911. Barrels Barrels Total Bbls. Fees Months Approved Rejected Inspected Collected January 33,517 ... 33,517 $3,354.60 February 31,419 ... 31,419 3,156.60 March 32,0«5 3 32,068 3J19.30 April 39 599 ... 39,599 3,97».«O May 40.929 ... 40,929 4,111.10 June 38,287 ... 38,287 3,84t.i» July 48,519 ... 48,519 4,80.36 August 47,616 . . . 47,516 4.76C.M September 51,705 ... 51,705 5,174.70 October 46,015 121 46,136 4,616.05 November 46.237 162 46,399 4,643.50 December 45.032 125 45.157 4,520.10 Totals 500,840 411 501,351 $50,242.60 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Statement o»- Mileage Used and Received fob the Yeas Ending December 31. 1911. Received Used Balance W. S. Jay Miles, 14,000 12,804 1.1M L. A. Donahoe " 12,000 11,108 892 8. I. Nle« " 24,000 23,908 Jas. Schoonover " 20,000 19,062 938 U. G. Etherton " 18,000 16,312 1,688 F. A. Wisner " 28,000 27,504 496 Wm. Husenetter " 15,000 14,994 « Total 131000 125 692 5408 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">I OFFICE OF THE STATE IN8PECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. IicvoicK or OrriiT Fubnitube and Equipment of the State Insfeltob ok Oils, December 31, 1911. Two roll-top desks. Sectional filing case, two sections. One sectional filing case and bookcase combined. One letter press. One check protector. One No. 6 Smith Premier typewriter, No. 938. One No. 2 Smith Premier typewriter, No. 124284 One typewriter table. One typewriter chair. One office chair. One Burroughs adding machine No. 27796. One electric fan. One Cram's atlas. One set Cobbey's Statutes, 1907 / One set Cobbey's Statutes, 1909. One set Cobbey's Statutes, 1911 One Compiled Statutes, '907 Two waste baskets. One cuspidor. Office books, records, supplies and desk furnishings. Two IXI- office knives. Postal scales. One dictionary. One wardrobe cabinet. One mirror. One brush. One comb. Two pair office shears. One riveting punch. Three new Foster cups complete. Six set of stencils. One Coal-Oil Manual. One clock. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 M rCE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OII.S, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Statkmf.nt Siiowim, Division m State Into Districts for Convkw iencf. In Handling Inspections for Year 1911. First District — W. S. Jay, Deputy, Lincoln. Auburn Beatrice Curt land Douglas Falls City Humboldt Pawnee City Lincoln Weeping Water Nebraska City Wymore Plattsmouth Teeumseh Second District — L. A. Donahob, Deputy, Omaha. Merman Lyons Mil lard Omaha • Council Bluffs • Dakota City South Omaha Sioux City Missouri Valley I. Niks, Omaha. Third District— S. Ains worth Albion Niobrara Norfolk Spalding Spencer Schuyler Bloomfield Columbus Emerson Fullerton Ho wells O'Neill Oakdale Wayne Orchard West Point Ponca • North Bend Plainview • Neligh Humphrey Hartington Randolph * Scribner Stuart Fourth District — Jas. SonooNOVBR, Aurora Fremont Geneva Ashland Crete Seward * Surprise Hebron Valparaiso David City Swanton Wahoo StromsburK York Fifth District — 0. a. Etheeton, Bartley. Edgar Sutton Blue Hill Grant Superior Bloom ington Beaver City Cambridge v Curtto Holdrege Stratton Hastings Wauneta Minden Upland McCook Red Cloud * New stations. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">M Sixth District — F. A. Wisnek, Lexington. Greeley Rushville Bridgeport Broken Bow Callaway Lexington Sumner Kearney Sargent Kimball St. Paul Loup City Sidney Central City Chadron Mason City ScotUbluff Gothenburg Grand Island Ravenna North Platte • Wood River Ogallala * Valentine Ord • Gordon </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS M OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement fob the Yeah Beginning Januaky, 1911, akb Ending December 31, 1911. RECEIPT Dr. From Inspection fees $50,823 .30 Copies of reports 95 . 00 Bond refund 14 . 50 Unused mileage 41.81 Sale of hydrometer 1 . 75 $50,976.36 Cash on hand January 1 1,200 . 00 $52,176.36 UlSIll KHEMENTS. Cr. $15,841.81 Paid to State Treasurer W. A. George 36,134.56 $50,976.36 Balance on hand January 1. 191* \£00 . 00 'o Salary Chief Inspector Expense of Chief Inspector Salaries Deputy Inspectors Expenses of Deputy Inspectors Mileage books $2,000. M 111. 10 7,200.00 2,159.31 2,731.10 Postage 44.00 Express Telegrams Telephones, rent and tolls Supplies, stationery, printing, miscellaneous Stenographer Hank exchange Office assistance Replace check 146.75 359.00 883.83 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 ANNUAL REPORT NEBRASKA. Fi.&gt;a.m ial Statement Fkom Jam aby 1 to 20, 1911. KECMPT8, Balance on hand January 1, 1911 $1,200.00 From Kansas City Oil Co., fees $16.90 H. Barghalm. fees 25 National Refining Co., fees 163 . 60 Mutual Oil Co., fees 245 . 80 Marshall Oil Co., few 48.60 Cbanute Refining Co., fees 28 . 30 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., fees 8.20 National Refining Co., fees 63.00 Omaha Oil Co., fees 162.60 Mate Oil Co., fees 62.00 National Fidelity * Casualty Co 14 . 50 xi :;.&gt;;: $2,013.65 IIIMIl'KKF.MKMK. To E. B. Oaddis $31. M Western Union Telegraph Co .40 Central National Bank .30 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 68.44 Woodruff Bank Note Co 7.50 M. J. Brouse, Deputy, salary and expense 72.57 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense J2 . 97 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 106.01 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 94.95 F. M. Colfer, Chief, salary and expense 113 . 35 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary M.M B*U.«o. hand January 20 1.371.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 rCE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OP OIL8, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement Covering Business Prom Jahuabt 20 to Jaw- uart 31, 1911. Dr. • receipts. Cash received from P. M. Coif er $1,371 . 88 r Independent Co-op. Oil Co., December fees... $31.70 C, B. ft Q. R. R. Co., December fees 15.90 Union Pacific Ry. Co., December fees 102.40 National Refining Co., December fees 19.20 Independent Co-op. Oil Co 3.10 Independent Co-op. Oil Co 8.60 Kansas City Oil Co., January fees 6.00 Wm. Stleren, January fees 1.25 Beatrice Oil Co., January fees 39.30 Standard Oil Co., January fees 2,425. 10 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., January fees.... 16.30 Mutual Oil Co., January fees 116.60 Marshall Oil Co., January fees 81 . 40 Manhattan Oil Co., January fees 37.40 National Refining Co., January fees 238.30 $4,513.43 DISBURSEMENTS. To E. R. Slier, postage $10 . 00 American Express, express 1 . 11 W. 8. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 49.9"&gt; Nina Ryan, extra stenographer, salary, 5 days 13.46 Helen Jones salary 31 . 28 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 49 . 80 C. Q. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 54 . 75 Jas. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 50 . 90 P. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 51.44 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 310.00 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., replace check 34.80 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 11 . 15 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent 4.00 8. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 59.01 Western Union Telegraph Co., messages 3.10 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 73.70 $819.54 Paid to State Treasurer W. A. George 1,493.89 Balance on hand January 31, 1911 1,200 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement fo« the Month of February. 1911 RECEIPTS. Dr. Balance on hand February 1 $1,200.00 From E. E. Case, February fees $5.10 F. A. Wunderlich, February fees 1.80 Heck * Wamsley, February fees 14.00 Kansas City Oil Co., February fees 44 . 65 St. Joe Oil Co., February fees 5.85 Omaha Oil Co., January fees 27.70 In ion Pacific R. R. Co., January fees 127.00 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., January fees 53.50 Farmers' Ind. Co-op., February fees 12.40 Norfolk Oil * Chemical Works, February fees 2.40 Beatrice Oil Co., February fees 32 .00 Marshall Oil Co.. February fees 13.20 Omaha Oil Co., February fees 43.20 Manhattan Oil Co., February fees 30.30 Mutual Oil Co., February fees 144.90 National Refining Co., February fees 147.70 C. R. I. * P. Ry. Co., February fees 12.20 8Ute Oil Co., February fees 45.70 Standard Oil Co., February fees 2,471.80 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co.. February fees 4.70 National Refining Co., February fees 15.90 Standard Oil Co., January and February "~ * -^ u».» </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS niSIUKSEMEMS. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $200.00 Woodruff Bank Note Co., printing 8.75 State Journal Co., printing 25 . IS Jas. Sohoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 140.00 U. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 133.16 Lincoln Drug Co., Jars ■. . 3 . 60 Helen Jones, Stenographer, salary 70.00 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 178.66 V. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 136.58 I. Niea, Deputy, salary and expense 148. 14 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 108.80 W. 8. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 128 . 15 American Express Co., express &gt;■ State Treasurer W. A. George 1.984 . 27 Balance on hand February 28 1,100.0© </seg>
            <seg id="p016">If, OFFICE OF THE STATE IN8PECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Finani-iai Statement foe tr Month of March, 1911. KECEIPT8. Balance on band March 1 $1.200 . 00 From Kansas City Oil Co., .March fees $78.55 Norfolk Oil * Chemical Works, March fees.. 7.70 City of Wakefleld, March fees 14.00 Wm. Stleren, March fees 1 .26 Farmers' Ind. Oil Co., March fees l«.10 Heck ft Wamsley, March fees 16.10 St. Joe Oil Co., March fees S.55 trican Lub. « Supply Co., March fees 4 . 80 lap Ind. Oil Co., March fees 13.00 8t Joe Oil Co., March fees 4.05 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co.. February fees 26.90 r. P. Ry. Co., February fees 81.80 Chas. Wanek. March fees 1.50 Beatrice Oil Co., March fees 16.10 State Oil Co., March fees 16.30 Marshall Oil Co., March fees 97.70 Mutual Oil Co., March fees 264.10 Chanute Refining Co., March fees 7.20 National Refining Co., March feei 201.60 Manhattan Oil Co.. March fees 30.50 Standard Oil Co.. March fees 2,232.20 Ind. Co-op. Oil Co., March fees 4.00 C, St. P., M. ft O. R. R. Co .80 National Refining Co., March fees 18.60 Standard Oil Co., copy of report 6.00 3.164.S0 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 1IISIU ■KHKMK.NTK. Cr. To Nebraska Telephone Co., rent $4.00 George Brothers, printing 4 . 00 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 120.00 Woodruff Bank Note Co., printing 10.00 Capital Drug Co., jars 4 . 50 Win. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 196.76 Helen Jones, Stenographer, salary 70 . 00 W. 8. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 126.96 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 110.10 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 129.11 Jag. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 164.45 U. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 138.56 K. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense. . 131.70 George Brothers, printing ;!9 . 2o W. A. George, State Treasurer 1,924 . 92 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">IX ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. FiXANt iai. Statkmknt kok nit Month or April, 1911. KECE1PTK. Balance on hand April 1 $1,200 .00 From Heck * Wamsley, April fees 16. 10 Farmers' Oil Co., April fees 5 . 40 terican Lub. * Supply Co., April fees 1.80 Joe Oil Co., April few 8.55 Chas. Wanek, April fees 1 .00 City Oas Co., Ravenna, April fees 1 .25 Farmers' Ind. Co., April fees 13.20 St. Joe Oil Co., April fees 5.40 rck * Wamsley. April fees 16. 10 ft N. W. Ry Co., March fees 12.90 Omaha Oil Co.. March fees 77.80 tP. Ry. Co., March fees 83.50 . Co-op. Oil Co., April fees 5. 10 State Oil Co., April fees 32.00 tional Refining; Co., April fees 285 . 30 ihattan Oil Co., April fees 32.60 Mutual Oil Co., April fees 177.00 Omaha Oil Co., April fees 60.60 Marshall Oil Co., April fees 152.20 Beatrk-e Oil Co., April fees 23.30 tB. ft Q. R. R. Co., unused mileage 32.28 adard Oil Co., April fees 2,963.20 Standard Oil Co., copy of record 5.00 National Refining Co., April fees 15.40 Kansas City Oil Co 77.90 4,104.88 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 DISBURSEMENTS. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $80.00 T. J. Thorpe Machine Co., stencils M.tJ Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls, March 4.65 C, B. t Q. R. R. Co., mileage MO. 00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 8.70 Harry Porter, clock and paper 3 . 10 W. 8. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 141. 86 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 134.94 8. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 138.02 .las. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 142. 0G I.. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 111.90 Win. H Usenet ter. Chief, salary and expense 181 .91 Helen Jones, Stenographer, salary 70.00 U. O. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 133.25 Lincoln Telephone Co., April rent and tolls 4.35 George Bros., printing 2 . 7f&gt; Payne's Printery, printing I.M W. A. George, State Treasurer 2,661 . 91 M.104.8S Cash on hand April 30 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">NFBRASKA. Financial Statkmknt k&gt;r the Month of Mat, 1911. RECEIPTS. Cash on hand May 1 $1,200.00 From Farmers" lnd. Co., May fees $28.80 Kansas City Oil Co., May fees 70.7.1 St. Joe Oil Co., May fees 16.65 C . B. * Q. R. R. Co., April fees 15.60 r. P. Ry. Co. April fees 70.60 Carson « Salberg. May fees 2 . r.f&gt; C. ft X. W. Ry. Co., returned mileage 9.5:! Beatrice Oil Co., May fees 31 .90 State Oil Co., May fee* 24.00 Marshall Oil Co.. May fees 102.10 M utual Oil Co., May feee 271 . 50 National Refining Co., May fees 327.10 Omaha Oil Co., May fees 56.30 Manhattan Oil Co., May fees 61 .70 Standard Oil Co., May fees 2,997.20 Standard Oil Co., copy of record 5.00 National Refining Co., May fees 19.00 Independent Oil Co., May fees 3.20 $5,312 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 DI8UU...JEMENTS. To Postal TeWgruph Co., message $0. 40 Nebraska Telephone Co., May rent and tolls 10.35 Payne's Printery , printing 1 . 75 C, B. &amp; Q. R. R. Co., mileage 120.00 C. £ N. W. Ry. Co.. mileage 80.00 A. B. Allen, Assistant, salary 40 . 00 Payne's Printery, printing 1.50 Payne's Printery, printing 7 . 00 Helen Jones, Stenographer, salary 70.00 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 126.^U U. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 131 .10 U, A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 108.10 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 184.66 Jas. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 142.15 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 128.98 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 134.69 Lincoln Telephone Co., May rent and toll 4.70 R. H. Stewart, Stenographer, salary 21 . 50 Nebraska Telephone Co., April rent and tolls * 25 George Bros., tags 8 . ?.O » Paid State Treasurer W. A. George 2,782 . 95 $4,111. «8 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">■12 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement for the Month of Jine, 1911. RECEIPTS. Dr. Cash on hand June 1 $1,200 . 00 From St. Joe Oil Co., June fees J1J.30 Superior Oil Co., June fees 6.45 J. L. Hopkins, June fees .25 F. E. Bingham, June fees .25 Heck ft Wamsley, June fees 15.90 State Oil Co., June fees 16.50 Kansas City Oil Co., June lees 70.70 Beatrice Oil Co., June fees 32.20 Marshall Oil Co.. June fees 65.20 Mutual Oil Co., June fees 177.10 National Refining Co., June fees 309.30 Omaha Oil Co., June fees 68.50 Manhattan Oil Co., June fees 79 . 30 Union Pacific Ry Co., June fees 88.80 C, R. I. * P. Ry. Co., June fees 13.00 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., June fees 2.60 Standard Oil Co., June fees 2,850.00 Standard Oil Co., copy of June report 5.00 National Refining Co., June fees 20.10 3.833.45 $5,033 a </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 DISBURSEMENTS. To C. * N. W. Ry Co., mileage. E. R. Sizer , postage 10 . 00 E. R. Sizer, poet cards and dues 10.00 Payne's Prlntery, printing 6.50 Payne's Printery, tags 10.60 State Journal Co., envelopes 11. 50 Lincoln Telephone Co., tolls and rent, June 6.05 C. E. Burns, typewriter supplies 1.25 R. H. Stewart, Stenographer, salary 70.00 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 146 . 50 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 106 . 60 F. A. Wlsner, Deputy, salary and expense 132.46 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 140.52 U. O. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 129.85 Jas. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 146.05 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 180.91 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 9 9" $1,357.59 W. A. George, State Treasurer 2,475.86 ,3.833.45 Cash on hand July 1 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement fob the Month or July, 1911. RECEIPTS. Cash on band July 1 $1,200 . 00 From Kansas City Oil Co., July fees $64.25 Superior Oil Co., July fees 11.40 Inter-State Oil Co., July fees 16.30 Jas. Taylor, July fees 13 . 30 Heck * Wamsley, July fees 28.30 Powell * Nelgson, July fees 1J.00 Beatrice Oil Co., July fees l«.10 Charles Wanek, July fees 1.00 State Oil Co., July fees 34.60 Marshall Oil Co., July fees 97.10 Omaha Oil Co., July fees 61.00 National Refining Co., July fees 244.60 Mutual Oil Co., July fees 225.40 Manhattan Oil Co., July fees 62 . 30 Standard Oil Co., July fees 3,808.90 Standard Oil Co., copy of July record 5.00 National Refining Co., July fees 18.20 Independent Co.-op. Oil Co., July fees .90 Etional Refining Co., copy of May report. . 5.00 tional Refining Co., copy of June report 5.00 B. * Q. R. R. Co., June fees 20.60 4,751.15 2* </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 DISBURSEMENTS. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co.. mileage 1260.00 Sanitary Towel ft Laundry Co., towels 1.60 Payne's Printery, stationery 4.00 Payne's Printery, tags 7.60 American Express, express .80 W. 8. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 133.60 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 130.14 Jits. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 141.60 V. O. Etherton. Deputy, salary and expense 137.97 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 184.16 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 136.lt I.. A. Donehoe, Deputy, salary and expense 113.90 R. H. Stewart, salary 70 . 00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls, July 7.M Paid State Treasurer W. A. George 3,423 . 36 Balance on hand August 1 1,200 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">M OFFICE OF THE STATE IN8PECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. FiKAxriAi. Statement ro« ini Mokth of Arui'RT, 1911 RECEIPTS, Dr. Casn on hand August 1 From Kansas City Oil Co., August fees $11.70 H. J. Stelnman, August fees .25 J. V. Carye. August fees .25 Herman Bredemier, August fees 1.25 Inter-State Oil Co., August fee* 4.65 Superior Oil Co., Shelby, August fees 5.30 Petroleum Produce Co., August fees 10 . 00 Superior Oil Co., Elkhorn, August fees 6.10 State Oil Co., August fees 42.90 National Refining Co., August fees 404.50 Independent Oil Co., August fees 1.80 Mutual Oil Co., August fees 241.50 Manhattan Oil Co., August fees 61 .60 Omaha Oil Co., August fees 50.30 National Refining Co., August fees 28.00 Marshall Oil Co., August fees 64.60 Standard Oil Co.. August fees 3,702.40 4 637 . 10 C, B. ft Q. R. R. Co., July fees M.M Union Paciflc Ry. Co., July fees M.M C, St. P., M. ft O. Ry. Co, June fees .76 C, St. P., M. * O. Ry. Co., May fees 1.75 Standard Oil Co., copy of August report 6.00 16.977.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DISBURSEMENTS. Cr. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 1240.00 Payne's Prlntery, stationery J.50 Western Trunkllne Co., circulars |;fj State Journal Co., printing 1.76 Payne's Printery, supplies 6 . 00 R. H. Stewart, Stenographer, salary 70.00 Win. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 176.66 W. 8. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 130.95 U. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 117 . 60 Jas. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 147.06 L. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 116.1% F. A. Wlsner, Deputy, salary and expense 125.48 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 130.68 Lincoln Telephone Co., July and August 8.66 Nebraska Telephone, August 8 . 60 Paid to State Treasurer W. A. George 3,481. IS $4,777.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">OFFICE OK THE 8TATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Financial Statement m&gt;k the Month of Septembkk, 1911 RECEIPTS. Cash on hand September 1 $1,200.00 From Superior Oil Co., September fees $27. IS tional Refining Co., September fees 348.20 ependent Coop. Oil Co., September fees 4.90 Eer-State Oil Co., September fees 12.90 n Planter Refining Co., September fees. . 6.15 ndard Oil Co., September fees 4,048.40 Marshall Oil Co., September fees 169.60 National Refining Co., September fees 25.00 Mutual Oil Co., September fees 222.50 State Oil Co., September fees 51 .80 Manhattan Oil Co., September fees 95.30 Omaha Oil Co., September fees 41 . 30 5,053.20 C, B. * Q. R. R. Co., August fees '... 15.80 Union Pacific Ry. Co., August fees M Standard Oil Co., ropy of September report 5.00 National Refining Co., copies of July, August and Sep- tember reports 16 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">STATE INSPECTOR OP OILS 29 To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $240.00 Payne's Printery , cards 3 . 50 i.inooin Traction Co., fixtures 7.00 i'ayne's Printery, letter paper 6.60 P. W. McDermand, Stenographer, salary 70.00 H. Ohoshi Co., carbon paper 4. IS Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 183.16 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent, September 4.00 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 119.30 L A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 116 . 66 Jas. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 160.79 U. O. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 126.50 P. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 120.56 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 125.21 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 7.00 Paid State Treasurer W. A. George 3,887 . 49 $6,178.80 Balance on hand October 1 1400.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement for the Month of October, 1911. MCCTEIPTS. Cash on hand October 1 $1,200 .00 From Superior Oil Co., October fees $27.85 Inter-State Oil Co., October fees 13 . 10 Norfolk Oil * Chemical Works, October fees 13.00 State Oil Co., October fee* 59.90 National Refining Co., October fees 430.60 Marshall Oil Co., October fees 32.10 Manhattan Oil Co., October fees 61 . 80 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., October fees.. 1.70 Standard Oil Co., October fees 3,564.80 Mutual Oil Co., October fees 286.90 Omaha Oil Co., October fees 28.40 4,520 . 15 Union Pacific Ry. Co., September fees M.M C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., September fees 26 . 10 C. St. P.. M. * O. Ry. Co., September fees .40 C B. * Q. R. R. Co., September fees 40.70 C. * N. W. Ry Co., August fees 13.30 Standard Oil Co., copy of October report 6.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS To C. A N. W. Ry. Co.. mileage $262.10 Payne's Printery , envelopes 2 . f&gt;0 W. 8. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 131.35 1.. A. Donahoe, Deputy, salary and expense 109.50 S. I. N'ies, Deputy, salary and expense 131.48 Jas. Srboonover, Deputy, salary and expense 138.70 U. O. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 125.00 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 128.23 Win. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 191.60 P. W. McDermand, Stenographer, salary 70.00 l.i nroln Telephone Co., rent 4 . 00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 11.40 Western I'nion Telegraph Co., messages .38 T. J. Thorpe, Machine Co., stencils and stamps 26 . 00 E. R. Sizer, Postmaster, postage 12.00 $1.344. 24 Paid to State Treasurer W. A. George 3,315.71 $4,659.95 On hand November 1 1.200 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 ANNUAL REPORT rCK OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OP OILS, LINCOLN, NKHRASKA. Fi\an« iai Stvtf.mknt kok tiif. Month of November, 1911. i:F.&lt; EIPT* Caak on hand November 1 $1,200.00 From Superior Oil Co., November fees $6. 15 Farmers' Oil Co., November fees .25 Superior Oil Co., November fees 7.80 Norfolk Oil k Chemical Works, November fees 14.20 Chanute Oil Co., November fees 5.00 St. Joe Oil Co.. November fees 2.40 James Taylor, November fees 7.20 tional Refining Co., November fees 368.20 ependent Co-op. Oil Co., November fees. . 4.40 Manhattan Oil Co., November fees 99.40 Standard Oil Co., November fees 3,762.70 Mutual Oil Co.. November fees 193.20 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., November fees 27.20 Oil Co., November fees 29.00 4.527.10 Standard Oil Co., copy of November report 6.00 National Refining Co., copies of November and October reports 10.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 33 mSBIJUHEMKNTli. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $160.00 Harry Porter, stationery 3 . 40 Nebraska Typewriter Co., repairs .75 Western Union Telegraph Co., messages l.M Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 6. 10 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent 4.00 P. W. McDermand, Stenographer, salary 70.00 Win. H Usenet ler, Chief, salary and expense 181.91 Jas. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 136.60 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 125.50 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 131 .95 V. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 128.15 V. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 124.25 Paid State Treasurer W. A. George 3,468 . 89 14,542.10 Balance on hand December 1 1,200 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">M rCE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement »x&gt;b the Month of December, 1911. RECEIPTS. Dr. Cash on hand, December 1 $1,200.00 Prom Jansen Milling Co., December fees $13.00 Powell ft Nelsson, December fee8 12.20 St. Joe Oil Co., December fees 13.20 Stmte Oil Co., December fees 42.40 National Refining Co., December fees 434.10 r [dependent Co-op. Oil Co., December fees. . 3.40 ugh Elliott, December fees 14 . 50 Marshall Oil Co., December fees 86.00 Manhattan Oil Co., December fees 142.00 Mutual Oil Co., December fees 241.50 C. R. I. ft P. Ry. Co., December fees 13.00 Standard Oil Co., December fees 3,283.90 Standard Oil Co, December shipments 145.40 4 444 60 Hans Hansen, Oakland, 1 hydrometer 1.75 I'nion Pacific Ry. Co., October and November fees... 179.40 Standard Oil Co., copy of December report 5 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS nisisnesKMENTH. To Kostka Glass &amp; Paint Co., hydrometer $0.65 A. B. Allen, office assistance 20.00 George Bros., printing 11.00 A. E. Merwin, carpet sweeper 4 . 00 I.. A. Donahoe, Deputy, November salary and expense. . 109.15 Postal Telegraph &amp; Cable Co., messages .70 American Express Co., express .38 W. H. Hosmer, circulars 3 . 85 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 5.40 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent 4 . 00 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 200.00 E. R. Sizer, postage IS . 00 George Bros., printing 4.10 Sanitary Towel Co., 6 Mo. to January 1 3. 00 W. S. Jay, Deputy, salary and expense 130.40 L. A. Donahoe. Deputy, salary and expense 108.85 S. I. Nies, Deputy, salary and expense 131 .70 Jas. Schoonover, Deputy, salary and expense 135.25 V. G. Etherton, Deputy, salary and expense 125.14 F. A. Wisner, Deputy, salary and expense 133.40 Wm. Husenetter, Chief, salary and expense 184.66 P. W. McDermand, Stenographer, salary 70.00 $1,396.73 W. A. George, State Treasurer 3,234 . 02 Balance on hand January 1, 1912 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">a (0 | — ,- o a i — * ft. O p 2 8/ - . .- X X •— -- w h ▼ K l: lO X T. ic t^ &lt;c i^ ia « c ■g M^r * — f X — S l- -l i- i &gt;o te • I s 0} | iliiii I fig o X « I •-9 w 3l »O C ill iC i oD I OS « rt •■* *-• g stecec c I iiilsijl 5 D O I 5SSS83 I £ 5 j a to cc ic i^ © f- x *»• es "■»• 2* (£ S 1 miji OD 5 5 5 ikui </seg>
            <seg id="p037">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS P.7 c sssasstss — r- u5 as t^ tc &lt;-• S84SS888a ■:• io n c n w 888 ! 1 5 r- ib ci ?* it oa » »o CO S5SS5s2RgS « o « ■ I n ... ■ n ■ od *i - t** 35 5« op : . TT 1 v4 S o t* SO ih ■ ■ ■♦ ■ (D '«M ■ " a a f 3 » C» — 3D ■ • - « ft t m tc :i • ■ i*« : : : li 1 3 - SSSSS2 : : : | SSfc2»* : : : Q SB ■ -X ■ n«4 ■ * 1" • -i-i •» eo ■ si • • us • A « ■ • ■ ] I 3 S be JS- S55SSS2 :S S o «o "^ «5 ■ ?22 : -g :|S? : ga • • » • » n • ■I : I JJ. 1 1 | "-3 O « &lt;-&lt; M CO |A M *f-&lt; 5;hiCO3X« -ID 5D diA • CD ■ © 00 ■ I J 2 &gt;» © t» — c* ~- rs i-t ■* 88| = | ;S5 : «- ■ I 1 I *i^ *^ r" «^ *0 * 7 • X WO • &lt;D ■ • O 10 ® 35 « • O ■ ■ . . »o fi * I h 0 | ao^flO^eo^ric* - x ■ • 8 Z I I X h&gt; O C4 » 9( O -^ ••^ c~ W O d C* • ■*#• iD -* &lt;N « tO -^H»ft2* «■* •■* • 00 &lt;N T n I kn T lf^ (^* |^ Q) 00 t* 5"" • • - • Ji J I o V iiiipii </seg>
            <seg id="p038">ANNUAL REPORT ■*» Ss3Si«.SzS£S£lf.SSa|SsSS8|8 • -«~- ' w |**| "g: "a ';s I If-a-B-aiaa-ci^-t-ai ; s 5 B I :::::::::::::::""::"" 5 •f :::::::: :| : :S :::::: | I ::::::::::: : : I I : I i IT ........... . . .... . s &lt; ■ ■ « • c • « • • • « ■ • ■• • ■ • ■— • » 2S • ■ w ■ ■ • . n • rm : = : j j ] j ;" j T '■ \ ! § go g •• -..•©« -^ • «■•••• • • • ct eo • . *i . • ■ • ie ■ • .... ss • • • • ■ • o o 1 ::::.::: :S :S : :3 :" I :::::.•:;•:: :*; : : : : • : : 2 ■ 8 k ! Ill ill! !!■"■!! I !!!!■!! | I p : : i" 5 : : : :S2 :::::::::: S I 2 : : : : :2 :gS ::::::::::: 2 c I i • •«« •■ »- I I : : : : : \^ : : : :8 :* : : ] 4 : : : Ililiiiili J </seg>
            <seg id="p039">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. tPAKATivE Statement of Inspection- and Receipts of the Depart - ment for thf. Years 1906 to 1910, Inclusive. Barrels Barrels Total Fees Approved Rejected Inspected Collected INC 222,712 None 222,712 $22,271. SO 1907 261.735 760 262.495 26.330 1908 263,597 185 263,782 25,825.00 1909 331,983 562 332.545 33,307.15 1910 411,991 762 412,763 41,344.20 Increase 1910 over 1909.. 80,008 200 80,208 8.036.95 Comparative Statement of the Amounts Paid to the State Tbeas - trer for the years 1904 to 1910, inclusive. Increase 1910 over 1909, $7,317.30; a little over 42 per cent. Increase 1910 over 1908, $11,143.84; a little over 81 per rent #0,1/0* . £O 10,023.31 1906 9,228.78 1907 13,845.34 1908 13,599.15 1909 17,425.60 1910 24,742.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. IiurnrTioN ami Fees Collected for the Year Bbc.innixo January 1. 1910, ( \n Kndino December 31, 1910. Barrels Barrels Total Bbls. Fees Months Approved Rejected Inspected Collected January 32,941 ... 32,941 $3,300.95 February 29,709 141 29,850 2,988.85 March 33.049 ... 33,049 3,308.95 April 34,855 4 34,859 3,501 .90 May 23,632 2 23,634 2,378.35 June 28,396 180 28,576 2,864.70 July 34,272 122 34,394 3,446.45 Auftust 36,767 ... 36,767 3,680.60 September 38,405 1 38,406 3,840.60 October 37,245 122 37,367 3,73».«6 Xovember 46,338 ... 46,338 4,642.40 December 36,382 190 36,572 3,657.20 Totals 411,991 762 412,753 $41,344.20 MILLAGE. Statement Showisi. Groan Mileage Purchased and Used Under the 1910 Administration for Year Ending December. 1910. Received Used Balance Mltas 123,000 120,910 2.090 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">STATE INSPECTOR OP OILS 41 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Financial Statement fob the Yeak Beginning January 1, 1910, awd Endi.no December 31, 1910. RECEIPTS. balance on hand January 1, 1910 $1,200.00 From Inspection fees for year $40,542 . 10 Sale of copies of monthly reports 60.00 Sale of copy of record .50 $41,80J.60 UIHIHKSEMENTS. Cr. To Salary of State Inspector Mullen $1,666.80 Salary of State Inspector Colfer 333 . 33 Salaries paid deputies 7,200.00 Salary paid stenographer 840.00 Expenses State Inspector Mullen 246.58 Expenses State Inspector Colfer 26.51 Kxpenses six deputies 2,195 . 66 Paid to State Treasurer 24,742 . 99 tileage londlng companies, premiums Supplies, printing, exchange 'elephones, rent and tolls 1 Cxpress •ostage zz </seg>
            <seg id="p042">ANNUAL REPORT 42 OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Fi.nanciai Statement fob the Month of Jasuaby, 1910. RECEIPTS Balance on hand January 1 $1,200 . 00 From Standard Oil Co., January fee* $2,477.00 National Refining Co., January fees 286.00 Beatrice Oil Co., January fees 23.20 Marshall Oil Co., January fees 88.60 Omaha Oil Co., January fees 84.70 Manhattan Oil Co., January fees 9.10 Superior Oil Co., January fees 14.20 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., January fees 20.90 C, B. * Q. R. R. Co., January fees 82.00 Union Pacific Ry. Co., January fees 105.20 Kansas City Oil Co., January fees 23.90 Chanute Refining Co., January fees 2.25 Uncle Sam Oil Co., January fees 5.10 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., January fees.. 22.70 Iowa Tank Line, January fees 54 . 60 Wm. Stieren, January fees 1 . 50 Standard Oil Co., copy of January report. . 5.00 M </seg>
            <seg id="p043">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 43 To C. B. t Q. R. R. Co., mileage books $140.00 C. * N. W. Ry Co, Mileage books 40.00 State Journal Co, supplies 6 . 60 George Bros., printing 6.70 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 4.35 Adams Express Co., express 1 . 71 I'nton Pacific Ry Co., mileage books 40.00 E. R. Slzer, Postmaster, postage 10.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 8.80 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 A. F. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 201.16 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 136 . 77 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 122.51 V. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 136.92 M. J. Brouse, Deputy, salary and expense 116 . 89 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 127.36 A. J. 0' Mai ley, Deputy, salary and expense 133.16 L. O. Brian, State Treasurer 2,004 . 02 Balance on hand February 1 1400.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Financial Statement for the Month of February, 1910. RECEIPTS. Italan' &lt;■ on hand February 1 $1,200.00 From Standard Oil Co., February fees $2,072.90 National Refining Co., February fees 253.50 Marshall Oil Co., February fees 186.40 State Oil Co., February fees 56 . 80 in- Oil Co., February fees 55.20 Sui&gt;erior Oil Co., February fees 8.00 Omaha Oil Co., February fees fiO.50 Manhattan Oil Co., February fees 16.40 1'nion Pacific Ry. Co., February fees 110.40 C. A N. W. Ry Co., February fees .'.3.70 C, R. I. A P. Ry. Co., February fees 12.20 C. B. A Q. R. R. Co., February fees 36.30 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., February fees.. 22.80 Iowa Tank Line, February fees 15.50 Win. Stieren, February fees 1.50 Neligh Milling Co., February fees 14.10 David From, February fees .25 J. Whitney, February fees .25 P. D. McKillips, February fees .25 A. Whitney, February fees .26 Jacob Demuth, February fees .50 Don Hiner. February fees .26 Kansas City Oil Co., February fees 24.80 I'ncle Sam Oil Co., February fees 6.10 Standard Oil Co., copy of February report 5.00 2,993.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 DISBURSEMENTS. To Missouri Pacific Ry. Co., mileage books $20.00 C, B. k Q. Ry., mileage books 80.00 C. * N. W. Ry. Co, mileage books 40.00 Union Pacific Ry Co., mileage books 40.00 C, R. I. £ P. Ry. Co., mileage books 20.00 American Express Co., express .27 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 5.00 Jacob North, directory 5 . 00 C. ft N. W. Ry. Co., mileage book 20.00 K. R. Sizer, Postmaster, postage 10.00 Adams Express Co., express .56 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 8.05 Woodruff-Collins, printing 6 . 75 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 A. P. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 185.77 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 114.15 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 114.87 P. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 126.45 M. J. Brouse, Deputy, salary and expense 124.24 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 12S.48 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 146.81 L. G. Brian, State Treasurer 1,726.47 Balance on hand March 1 1,200 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Fi&gt;am ial Statement kob Month ok March, 1910. RECEIPTS. Dr. Balance on hand March 1 $1,200 . 00 From Standard Oil Co., March fees $2,206.50 National Refining Co., March fees 278.90 Omaha Oil Co., March fee* 122 . 70 Marshall Oil Co., March fees 351.60 State Oil Co., March fees 13.10 C, B. * Q. R. R. Co., March fees 94.50 I'nion Pacific Ry. Co., March fees 98.50 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., March fees 20.90 Beatrice Oil Co., March fees 28 . 40 rependent Co.-op. Oil Co., March fees 8.90 A. Wunderlich, March fees 1 .75 Kansas City Oil Co., March fees 37.90 Chanute Refining Co., March fees 36. '0 I'nele Sam Oil Co.. March iees 5.00 George R. Carson, March fees 3 . 90 Standard Oil Co., copy of record 5 . 00 95 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 ni.SBfKSEMENTS. To American Express Co., express $2 . 07 C. B. * Q R. R. Co., mileage book 60.00 I'nion Pacific Ry. Co., mileage book 40.00 C. * N. W. Ry . Co., mileage book 40 . 00 E. R. Sizer, Postmaster, postage 20.00 C, B. * Q. R. R. Co., mileage book 20.00 Lincoln Telephone Co, rent and tolls 5.55 Woodruff-Collins, printing 192.75 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage book 20.00 George Bros., supplies 7.25 Nebraska Telephone- Co., rent and tolls 9.10 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage book 40.00 Adams Express Co., express 4 . 40 O. E. Rector, Druggist, supplies M Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 A. F. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 190.42 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 134.85 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 119.12 P. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 122.33 M. J. Bouse, Deputy, salary and expense 135.68 Francis Colter, Deputy, salary and expense IK. 03 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 130.87 $1,481.02 L. Q. Brian, State Treasurer 1,832 . 93 Balance on hand April 1 1,200 .00 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">4&gt; ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement kok the Month m Apkii., tMS. ■am Dr. Balance on hand April 1 $1,200.00 From Standard Oil Co., April fees $2,682 . 90 National Refining Co., April fees 243.00 Marshall Oil Co., April fees 114.20 Superior Oil Co., April fees 18. 95 State Oil Co., April fees 12.50 Omaha Oil Co., April fees 94.10 Inion Pacific Ry. Co., April fees 76.70 C. H. &amp; Q. Ry. Co., April fees 20.70 Kansas City Oil Co., April fees 79.45 Incle Sam Oil Co., April fees 13.20 Chanutf Refining Co., April fees 16.10 Beatrice Oil Co., April fees 34.00 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., April fees 26.50 tependent Co-op. Oil Co., April fees 7.90 tual Oil Co., April fees 48. 3« American Lub. k Supply Co., April fees 12.15 Wm. Stieren, April fees 1.25 Standard Oil Co., copy of April report 5.00 .i.;i"n J" </seg>
            <seg id="p049">STATE INSPECTOR OP OILS niSItl'USKMENTS. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage books 1280.00 E. R. Sizer, Postmaster, postage 20.00 American Express Co., express .33 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 5.45 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 12S.43 A. .1. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 131.82 T. .T. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 113.61 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 126.50 M. J. Bouse, Deputy, salary and expense 123.25 U B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 131.89 A. F. Mullen, Deputy, salary and expense 181.46 Nina Ryan. Stenographer, salary 70.00 Adams Express Co., express .M Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 10.50 L. G. Brian, State Treasurer 2.182.40 Balance on hand May 1 1,200 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">N ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. FlSAKCIAI. STATEMENT FOR THE MONTH OF MAT, 1910. rw eipts Dr. Balance on hand May 1 $1,200 .00 From Standard Oil Co., May fees $1,479.10 Mutual OH Co., May fees 135.70 Omaha Oil Co., May fees 126.90 National Refining Co., May fees 185.40 State Oil Co., May fees 30.50 Manhattan Oil Co., May fees 25.20 Marshall Oil Co., May fees 104 . 60 Beatrice Oil Co., May fees 19 .40 Superior Oil Co., May fees 5 . 00 C. B. * Q. R. R. Co., May fees 47.30 Inlon Pacific Ry. Co., May fees 69.80 Chanute Refining Co.,* May fees 16.00 Kansas City Oil Co., May fees 52.10 Iowa Oil Tank Line, May fees 41 .00 Win. Stleren, May fees 1 . 25- American Lub. * Supply Co., May fees 9.10 I'ncle Sam OH Co., May fees 4.80 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., May fees 13.00 Chas. Cass, May fees 6 . 00 Standard Oil Co., copy of report 5.00 Beatrice Oil Co., copy of records .50 2,377.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8 51 HINIiriulEMKNTS. To Woodruff-Collins, supplies $38.50 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage book 40.00 E. R. Sizer, Postmaster, postage 10 . 00 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage books 80.00 American Express Co., express 1.09 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 4.80 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage book 40.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 6.15 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 128.10 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 110.10 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 122.95 M. J. Bouse, Deputy, salary and expense 124.68 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 117.00 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 138.34 A. F. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 186.11 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 $1,218.71 L. Q. Brian, State Treasurer 1,159. 13 Balance on hand, June 1 1,100. 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">:,2 ANNUAL REPORT OKK1CE OK THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Kinam iai. Statement h&gt;k the Mo.ntii ok June, 1910. KBEUTS, Cr. Balauc r ou band June 1 $1,200.00 From SUndard Oil Co., June fees." $1,995.60 Mutual Oil Co., June feet 104.80 Beatrice Oil Co., June fees 19.40 Superior Oil Co., June fees 13.30 Marshall Oil Co., June fees 84.40 Manhattan Oil Co., June fees 26.60 State Oil Co., June fees 54.70 tional Kenning Co., June fees 229.30 aha Oil Co., June fees 122. 10 Union Pacific Ry. Co., June fees 77.30 tB. * Q. R. R. Co., June fees 28.80 nute Refining Co., June fees 16.00 Kansas City Oil Co., June fees 64.15 American Lub. ft Supply Co., June fees.... 4.50 I'nrle Sam Oil Co., 'June fees 7.00 Wm. Stieren, June fees 1.25 Independent Co-op. Ref. Co., June fees.... 15.50 Standard Oil Co., copy of June report 5 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">msni'RSKMFNTS. Cr. To Western Trunk Line Co., supplement t . . $3 . 82 Sanitary Towel Co., towel rent 3 .00 American Express Co., express .42 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 4.90 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 60.00 C. 4k N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 80.00 C, B. A Q. R. R. Co., mileage M.M Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 Woodruff Bank Note Co., supplies 12.50 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls CIO A. F. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 185.44 I.. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 139.58 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 113.19 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 126.30 M. J. Brouse, Deputy, salary and expense 121.25 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 123.60 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 144.40 I1.J13.49 U O. Brian, State Treasurer 1,656.2! Balance on hand July 1 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">•■4 ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. Financial Statmhwt for the Month of Jdi.t, 1910. Balance on hand July 1 $1 JM.M From Standard Oil Co.. July fees $2,693.40 National Refining Co., July fees 108.20 Manhattan Oil Co., July feat 27.10 Omaha Oil Co., July fees 105.60 Mutual Oil Co., July fees 117.10 Beatrice Oil Co., July fees 28.10 Marshall Oil Co., July fees 90.60 State Oil Co., July fees 14.80 C, B. A Q. R. R. Co., July fee* 32.30 C. A N. W. Ry. Co., July fees 13.40 t'nion Pacific Ry. Co., July fees 114.80 Kansas City Oil Co., July fees 48.75 L. C. Kendall, July fees 6.10 Kansas-Nebraska Oil Co., July fees 8.10 American Lub. ft Supply Co., July fees.... 8.40 Chanute Refining Co., July fees 12.20 Independent Co-op. Co., July fees 6.90 Iowa Oil Tank Line, JuJy fees 11.60 O,ltv . * D Standard Oil Co., copy of report 5 . On </seg>
            <seg id="p055">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 55 Cr. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $80.00 E R. Sixer, Postmaster, postage 10.00 R. W. McGinnis, mileage 80.00 Woodruff B. N. Co., supplies 4.85 State Journal Pub. Co., supplies H.M Adams Express Co., express .41 American Express Co., express 1.06 Woodruff B. N. Co., record book 11.60 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 40.00 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 4 . 40 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 10.35 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 127.44 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 109 . 50 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 134.16 M. J. Bouse, Deputy, salary and expense 131 . 95 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 130.65 O. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 154.34 A. F. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 189.71 $1,339.11 L. O. Brian, Treasurer 2,132 . 34 Balance on hand 1.200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">NEBRASKA. Financial Statement fob the Monttt of AuatrHT, 1910. IIIMEIPTS Balance on hand August l 11,200.00 Prom Standard Oil Co., August fees $2,818.00 National Refining Co., August fees 192.90 Inlon Pacific Ry. Co., August fees 69.20 Mutual Oil Co., August fees 191.40 Superior Oil Co., August fees 6.00 C B. * Q. R. R. Co., August fees 20.20 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., August fees 13.40 Omaha Oil Co., August fees 154.80 Manhattan Oil Co., August fees 4S.60 Marshall Oil Co., August fees 46.50 Beatrice Oil Co., August fees 28.20 Kansas City Oil Co., August fees 61.80 Chanute Refining Co., August fees 28.10 Independent Co-op. Oil Co., August fees.. 12.20 Farmers' Mutual Oil Co., August fees 12.30 MM.M Deduction, account duplicate payment on UTLi-10658, Norfolk, for Standard .13.00 $4 880 60 From Standard Oil Co., copy of August report 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 D1S.HI KSfcMENTK. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $180.00 C. B. * Q. R. R. Co.. mileage 20 00 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 Western Trunk Line Co., supplements 1 .23 Woodruff Bank Note Co., supplies 5.50 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 6.65 ■rtelle Nicholson, copying records 48.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 14.30 A F Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 178.61 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 131.70 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 108.75 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 140.26 M. J. Brouse, Deputy, salary and expense 132.40 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 117.90 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 138.49 L. Q. Brian, State Treasurer 2,390.91 mjm.m </seg>
            <seg id="p058">H ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OIL8, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement fob th« Month ok Seitkmhui, 1910. RECEIPTS Dr. Balance on band September 1 $1,200 . 00 From Standard Oil Co., September fees $2,773.10 National Refining Co., September fees 296.10 tependent Co-op. Oil Co., September fees 44.30 •shall Oil Co., September fees 172.00 Beatrice Oil Co., September fees 15.90 Superior Oil Co., September fees 14.60 Omaha Oil Co., September fees 78.50 Mutual Oil Co., September fees 94.70 Manhattan Oil Co., September fees 13.10 State Oil Co., September fees 32.20 C, B. * Q. R. R. Co., September fees 36.70 Union Pacific Ry. Co., September fees 114.60 Kansas City Oil Co., September fees 81.40 tmers' Mutual Oil Co., September fees.. 16.1* nute Refining Co., September fees 32.10 Iowa Tank Line Co., September fees 19.70 C, M., St. P. * O. Ry. Co., September fees. . 5.60 Standard Oil Co., copy of report 5 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">R9 ntSBlRSEMFNTS. To C. A N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $».•• E. R. Sixer, Postmaster, postage 10.00 Hastings Republican, supplies t.M Woodruff Bank Note Co., supplies 9 . 50 Lincoln Drug Co., supplies 2 . 2f&gt; C, B. 6 Q. R. R. Co., mileage 2n . 00 Adams Express Co., express 1-49 Woodruff Bank Note Co., supplies 1 .76 American Express Co., express 1 . 88 Chas. J. Tagllabue, supplies 13.50 Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls I.M Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls 11 . 10 Central National Bank, exchange .06 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 A. F. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense SO*. 41 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 131 .62 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 148.00 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 130.25 M. J. Brouse, Deputy, salary and expense 126.65 Francis Golfer, Deputy, salary and expense 164.03 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 176.48 $1,310.07 L. Q. Brian, State Treasurer 2,536. 6S Balance on hand October 1 1,800.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">ANNUAL REPORT NEBRASKA. Financial Statement for the Month of October, 1910. RE&lt; ETFTS. Balance on hand October 1 $1,200. 00 From Standard Oil Co., October fees $2,801.00 National Refining Co.. October fees 224.(0 Mutual Oil Co., October fee* 238 . 80 Marshall Oil Co., October fees 82.20 Superior Oil Co., October fees 12.80 Omaha Oil Co., October fees 82 .70 Manhattan Oil Co.. October fees.. 32.80 Independent Co-op. Co.. October fees 13.00 I'nion Pacific Ry. Co., October fees r,:!.:,0 c. H. * Q. R. R. Co., October fees .16.90 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., October fees 6.70 (".. St. P., M. ft O. Ry. Co., October fees. ... .80 Farmers' Mutual Oil Co., October fees 30.10 Kansas City Oil Co., October fees 30.35 Beatrice Oil Co., October fees 16.10 National Refining Co., S. C, October fees.. 15.80 Chanute Refining Co., October fees 23.20 Chas. Case, October fees 5 . 30 G. R. Carson, October fees 2.70 z,i?.9 . 2r. Standard Oil Co., copy of report 6.00 $4,944.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS 61 E. R. Sizer, Postmaster, postage 10.00 John M. Gilchrist, premium on bond 8S.40 A. F. Mullen, Chief, exchange on checks 1.50 A. F. Mullen, Chief, salary and expense 306.19 L. B. Arnot. Deputy, salary and expense 127.37 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 111.85 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense lit. 25 M. J. Bouse, Deputy, salary and expense 164.05 Francis Colfer, Deputy, salary and expense 120.(1 A. J. O' Mai ley. Deputy, salary and expense 138.19 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 7-u . Oo Nebraska Telephone Co., tolls and rent 15.35 Lincoln Telephone Co., tolls and rent 5.40 Woodruff Bank Note Co., supplies 6 . 50 United States Express Co., express 1 . 3u American Express Co., express .49 L. O. Brian, State Treasurer 2,380.70 "alance on hand November 1 1,200. 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">a ANNUAL REPORT OFFICE OF THE 8TATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA. Financial Statement kob the Month or November, 1910. RECEIPTS. Dr. Balance on hand November 1 $1,200 . 00 From Standard Oil Co., November fees $3,331.00 Marshall Oil Co., November fees 148. 10 ttlonal Refining Co., November fees 362.70 tual Oil Co., November fees 194 .60 State Oil Co., November fees 62.00 Omaha Oil Co.. November fees 92.90 Superior Oil Co., November fees 6.00 Beatrice Oil Co., November fees 48. 10 tB. * Q. Ry. Co., November fees 36.90 on Pacific Ry. Co., November fees 75.90 R.I.1P. Ry. Co., November fees 13.10 Manhattan Oil Co., November fees 62.80 Kansas City Oil Co., November fees 114.80 Chanute Refining Co., November fees.... 12.20 I'ncle Sam Oil Co., November fees 6.10 National Refining Co., 8. C, la., November fee^ 15. 90 t dependent Co-op. Co., November fees.... 7.00 m. Stieren, November fees 2 . 50 F -Continent Oil Co., November fees 16.00 mere' Independent Oil Co., November fees 20.10 A. Wunderlich, November fees 3.00 Nebraska-Kansas Oil Co., November fees 11.80 4 642 40 Standard Oil Co., copy of report 6.00 $6,847.40 Amount due from A. F. Mullen to Francis Colfer, fees for October still uncollected 100.00 Total debits $6,747.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 IHMH KSKMKNTN. Cr. To C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage $320.00 E. R. Sizer, Postmaster, postage 10.00 E. B. Gaddis, Deputy, salary and expense 131 .25 National Fidelity &amp; Casualty Co., bond premium 2:: 3» C. * N. W. Ry Co., mileage 40.00 Francis Colfer, Chief, salary and expense 195.66 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense US. 00 L. B. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 146 . 88 M. J. Bouse, Deputy, salary and expense 135.00 P. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense 168.40 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 157.48 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary W.W Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls s .:!=. Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls :!:! . 9 r i Woodruff Bank Note Co., supplies 18.00 American Express Co., express .75 Adams Express Co., express .6! $1,561.58 U G. Brian, State Treasurer 2,985.82 Balance on hand December 1 1,200 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">04 ANNUAL B-PORT OFFICE OK THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS, LINCOLN NEBRASKA. Kl&gt;A*CIAL STATEMENT tOK THE MONTH UK DECEMBEK, 1910. KBCEIPTH. Balance on hand, December 1 $1,200.00 Balance October fees received from A. F. Mullen 100. 0C From 'Standard Oil Co., December fees $2,780.50 •Marshall Oil Co., December fees 48.60 •Omaha Oil Co., December fees 69.70 •SUte Oil Co., December fees 92.00 Beatrice Oil Co., December fees 16.10 Manhattan Oil Co., December feea 33.50 •C, B. * Q. Ry. Co., December fee« 15.90 •National Refining Co., December feea 163.50 •I'nion Pacific Ry. Co., December fees 102.40 •C, St. P., M. * O. Ry. Co., December few. . 1.30 •Mutual Oil Co., December fees 245.80 Kansas City Oil Co., December feea 34.80 Jansen Milling Co., December fees 12.10 Mid-Continental Oil Co., December fees 13.00 Chanute Refining Co., December fees 11.90 Farmers' Ind. Oil Co., December fees 16.10 Standard Oil Co., copy of report I.M rncollected, including Omaha Oil Co., November bill, *9290 801.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 niSIIFRSEMKNTS. Cr. To K. R. Sizer, postage $10.00 C. * N. W. Ry. Co., mileage 100.00 Sanitary Towel Co., towels I.M Woodruff Bank Note Co., supplies 7.60 1'acittc Express Co., express .X\ C, B. A Q. Ry. Co., mileage 40.00 F. J. Pratt, Deputy, salary and expense US.M Nebraska Telephone Co., rent and tolls I.M Electric Supply Co., changing light 1 9n American Express Co., express .M Lincoln Telephone Co., rent and tolls 4 !&lt;•• Adams Express Co., express .79 E. B. Gaddis, Deputy, salary and expense 125.90 Y. M. Colfer, Chief, salary and expense 173.17 Nina Ryan, Stenographer, salary 70.00 U n. Arnot, Deputy, salary and expense 145.87 A. J. O'Malley, Deputy, salary and expense 132.95 M. J. Bouse, Deputy, salary and expense 131. 35 T. J. O'Connor, Deputy, salary and expense 112.25 Central National Bank, exchange .90 U O. Rrian, State Treasurer 1,756. 53 Balance on hand January 1, 1911 1,200.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">M ANNUAL REPORT I 88SSSt8«8tt89tt«ttSS988a SiSiS S — — ejr»i.tiot^*2ad*ic^- — citict^jisxh — » a? go « ? c** *5 '^ 5£ l ?5 m m *^ '^ *^ I i»- aa " » = gee Jg gjH ■ • ll ! &lt;S • • •" :SS : | II q t ft CC • CO f» O * QD • ■ * a§i 8 | c &lt; O « tt - « h XX h ft ifi h M • O - - - ■ ■ •— QC « BpS-irh- &gt;e e S jJ •«•••■•••■ O s™" : ::::::: Hi 1 qd " : i : : : : I TTHIl I MM ■ &gt;» w x «*■ x 3 »r: r- ■ ee 5* ■* 2* • eo — ■*• • ■ ■ «; x ■ ■ •^ ftC^WftC W ■ *- W — "^ — • ■• *l • ■ " : " : : : : : : MA -% « r: x •* « " *"« "go w ic"b x «: t* • - - Q • * * iLi — T I- ■» . s s — — sSPSSS?? :28 : : :g . : : •« » ce -r — • n ■ • • w\ i tt OS ■ H W I* r* rm ■ • • ml 1 O X "X^^"CT ■ 'O^* w CCuTQu •P'5 • ■ • • • • • m _q o* n • wj o •V«O ~- I l* X C* •- O(?* •cD^joeej'* ■ - • - • **%* i ::!•:;: 'm 2 n i ifcii|lijSf|ifliJ||w!l|itlli !ll|ll|t »i lifliif ijp]l|ii i </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>