<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  A HANDBOOK OF NEBRASKA GRASSES</title>
               <date value="1915">1915</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 148. The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXVII, Article V. A HANDBOOK OF NEBRASKA GRASSES With Illustrated Kkys for Thkih Ikentikication, Togethkr With a General Account em Tiikir Structure and Economic I mfobtance, Bt E. Mfad Wilcox, Geokge K. K. Link, and Venus W. Pool. Distributed April 1, 1915. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA, THE GOVERNING BOARD. ITMI tfaCMTt Of TH1 UNlVEMtTV.) HONORABLE PHILIP L. Hall, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, President. Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER. Omaha. E ORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. ORABLE EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey. ORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex officio. K. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director; Animal Husbandry. C. W. PCOSLET, B. Sc, Director of Extension Service. .1. S. DALES, M. I»n., Financial Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. E. Mbad Wilcox, Ph. D., Aijricultural Botany. F. W. l T i-8ON, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. U W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. •R. K. Buss, B. S. A., Annual Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsen. M. S. A.. Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bkinki:, B. St., Entomology. T. A. Kies.-kmiai h, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. H. C. Fillev, A. M., Farm Manag&lt; ment. W. J. MoitKll.1., M. For., Forestry. •R. A. Emerson, D. Sc. Horticulture. R. F. Howard, A. H., Horticulture. G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. S.nvder, M. S., Superintendent o1 Experimental Substation. North Platte. C B. Lee, A. XI., Associate in Animal Husbandry. Howard J. Gramlich. B. Sc, Associate in Animal Husbandry. M. H. SwENK, A. M., Associate in Entomology. ,i ikhe K. K. Link, A. &gt;!.. AmMmM in Agricultural Botany. ■A. McComb, B. Sc, Hortii ulturist of Experimental Substation, North Platte. K, Zook, B. Sc, Assistant in Dry Land Agriculture, V. 8. Department of Agriculture, North Platte. J. W. Calvin, B. 3c, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Bakker, A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). Ekwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Aaronomy (Crops). i. A. Ratcliff, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. L. B. Stukdevakt, A. M., M. I)., Assistant in Animal Pathology. E. G. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Hairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper. B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. Sc. Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. Florence A. McCormick, Ph. D., Assistant in Agricultural Uutany. H. E. Vasey, A. M., Assistant in Aym ultural Botany. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fkitz Knoku, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. H. L. Nye, Foreman Demonstration Form. Culbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS. Introduction 5 -. Structure of grasses g Directions for use of the keys t) Tribe key to the grasses 11 Notes on economic grasses 77 Bibliography of agrostology 95 . . </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">[\\ K. MKAI) WI1.COX. UBOBUI K. K. LINK. AMI VKXI S W. IML* INTRODICTION. IPlie true grasses belong to the one family I'oaceae, often ■il &lt;;ramineae. ami constitute a very well defined natural iff of plants. This family comprises upward of 3,000 species ributed among; alxmt .'{0(1 genera. From the economic point lew the family is of supreme importance thru the fact that ' belong the cereals, which supply a large part of the fo&lt;»l nan. and the forage grasses which are so important as feed our domesticated animals. I The genera and species are for the most part separated In flcial characters — a fact which renders their study and iilen •ation extremely difficult even for the expert. The experience lie authors has convinced them that much of this difficulty is be credited to the "keys"' found in our common manuals, ■oretically a key is intended to assist one in properly identi ig a plant, but actually many of the keys, upon close inspec- I, are found to contain so many vague and contradictory tements that they can lie depended upon only by the expert who. on account of his working knowledge, makes slight use of the keys. It occurred to the senior author some years ago that an illus 1 rated key might solve many of these difficulties. An accurite illustration conveys a more definite idea of any particular struc - ture and leaves less room for doubt than any number of words. In fact, the serious and annoying inaccuracies of most keys to the grasses became more and more apjMtrent as the work of pre - paring the illustrations progressed. The authors are fully con - vinced that illustrated keys of the type here employed will prove useful in many other groups of plants. The noiiienclature here employed is largely that of the seventh edition of Cray's Manual — tho our purpose has not been to insist upon any particular name but to provide MUM wherein the student can with some certainty attach to any given plant some one name which has been properly authorized. * Resigned November 1, 1911. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 The present key includes most of the species known to oecw in Nebraska, tho ■ few of minor importance and very restricted distribution have Iteen omitted. Then- arc provided also mmc data on the economic value of certain of the most important secies. iPhe illustrations for the grass keys have been drawn ex|»r this publication. They are derived in part from actual lentic specimens and in part redrawn in modified form from oub manuals and monographs. The authors have made free of the manuals, monographs, etc. included in the Kibli iphy and take this opportunity to commend these publication* he attention of all who wish to learn more of our commoa mes. It is hoped that the keys here presented will facilitate stndy of the grass flora of Nebraska by farmers and student* STRUCTURE OP GRASSES. tThe grasses are herbs i rarely shrubs or trees I with extensive ons root-systems. They may be perennials with rUaaOMl ;. 1, A) or sym podia i fig. 1. B). or annuals with sympodia. 1 extensive system of rhizomes enables these plants to form »od" and may render their eradication difficult. The primary t soon disappears, its function being taken over by inimemii* &gt;ndarv roots which arise from the nodes. pig. i. I They have cylindrical stems with hollow intei-nodc* and generally swollen closed nodes {fig. 2). In some species, such as maize and sorghum, the stems are filled with pith. The leaves are 2-ranked. narrow, parallel-veined | If 3 1 and consist of two parts, the sheath (flg. 3. O and 2. the blade. ( flg. I, A). The sheath with its margins im </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Pur. rarely grown together, envelopes the iiitei-u&lt;»de I or less of its length (fig. 4). At the junction of the nd the blade, on the inside, is an erect membranaeeons. or hairy appendage, called the ligule (fig. 3, BV Ehe flowers are grouped in spicate, racemose, or paniculate rescences which in turn are composed of partial inflores es. the spikelets (fig. fil. \ « \R, c « H si. Fig. 3 FiK. 4. {Figure "&gt; shows diagrums of a typical spike, raceme, ami icle. In an inflorescence, the branches are generally sub- Jed by bracts (in grasses such bracts are wanting). In a ;c i fig. 5, B) the flowers are sessile on an elongated main axis, rachis; in a raceme (5, A I the flowers are stalked and borne the rachis, in a panicle (5, 0) the rachis bears racemes later KThe flowers, generally perfect (rarely unisexual) (figs, (i ami are arranged in spikelets which consist of a shortened uxi*. rachilla (figs. 6, A. and 8, A), and 2 or more 2-ranked bracta p. 7. A. and Si. B* </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 finally the lowest liracts arc empty anil arc then railed t's i tig. !S. Fl. Sometimes the fhlM arc absent or then - lie ."!-4 glumes. In the axil of each succeeding bract, the 1a i tip. 8. E) is a flower (tg. S. B, ('). which is subtended usually enveloped by a bract, the pain i tip. s. D). The Fig. 7. leiiuna often ltears a stiff bristle, the awn. which is covered l&gt;\ liackwai-dlv turned hairs. A flower consists of .'{ staniens I sometimes 1. 4. or ti i i tiu 7. Hi. an u\ar\ i tij;. 7. l&gt; and S. I! i . composed of three carpel* which bear two featherv papillose stigmas I fljf. 7. C), and the lodicnles. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 I The fruit of ||1 SHU is called ■ caryopsis. having tin- pt'ri&lt;;ir]i I seed coat intimately united. The embryo lies in contact li t Ik- mimfttm I fig. 9, Ai by mtmm of its cotyledon. The t of the cotyledon next to the endosperm is tiie ■ratellnin ;. '.». C), MTrteg as an absorbent organ in jrci-miiin tion . The •eh. oil. anil protsia of the endosperm aixl embryo render the il &lt;il grasses of high ecoiioinic value. Fig. 8. DIRECTIONS FOR USE OF THE KEYS. A }joo&lt;l hand lens will lie found a necessity in the study of tbe glasses. The l&gt;ejrinner should carefully study the statements under "Structure of (irasses" I p. (I). With a s|iecinieu of the irrass liefore him he is then ready to begin the work of identifi - cation. As an illustration we may select the awnless hrome grass. HromiiK int'rmis. We lie{{in with the "Tribe Key to the Grasses" ip. 111. At the top of the jiajre are found three lines, each di'scritiinj; a &lt;°cr- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ain group of grasses. We must decide which of the three lines liest describes our grass. Since in our grass the spikcleis nre in a panicle, like the m treinc rijrht hand irawtag of figure 1(1. we refer next to the lines l»elow marked '•,"!. " We must in our grass has one or two or evidently has more than one right-hand drawing of figure marked ••?" ip. Hi. here decide whether the spikelet more flowers. Since this spikelet flower, as shown in the extreme 12. we turn next to the liiu-^ Here our decision is required as to the character and location of the awn on the lemma. By consulting the two figures we see plainly that this grass l&gt;elongs to the tribe Festuceae (p. 44 I. I Our plant being "erect" we turn to ''2" below. The rachilla ound to be "naked," t. e., without any silky hairs, so we refer '3." With the aid of a lens the "lemma" must be examined to prinine the number of its "nerves" or veins. Evidently it has nany," as shown in the right-hand drawings of figim- &lt;»."&gt;. and ce we turn to "10" (p. 49). I Our plant is described by the second line under "10" so that turn to "11" (p. 4!t). The lemma will be found to be "rounded the back," which takes us to "14" tp. 50). The lemma hetafl iked at the base," we go to "15" (p. 51). Here we find that the second line under "16" describes mm grfws and we turn to "II." Mow. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Kfhe exact location of the stvle with reference to the tip of ovary must next l&gt;e determined. This ln-infjs us to the genus nnis. I Co determine the exact species of Bi-omus we must refer to Uev to the species i&gt;f this genus (p. &lt;&gt;0 I and proceed 111 the re manner to find the name of the plant liefore us. THIBK KKY TO THK (iKASSKS HG. PAUI r pikelets sessile, allernatiug on opposite sides of the rachis Hokdeak III M t pikelets sessile or somewhat |&gt;edicellate. on one side of the rachis - 1" t pikelets sessile, forming a cowpaet head; or com |iiiiuiillv pedicellate, forniing :i I'aniole '■'• Hi 1- ■2. Uluiue keeled ChlobibsaI 11 41 (Jhime not killed 1'amckak 11 IB Figure 11 Chloridkae. Panicbae. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11' FIG. PAGE !. SpikHets with one perfect flower ' 4 12 Spikelets with two to ninny lowcn 7 12 14 Figure 12. 4. 7. I. Spikelets. at least sonic of them, imbedded in the rai-his Maydbak [Tripmcum dnrtijloidfn is the only s]&gt;e&lt;-ies nf this tribe included in this key] 13 '.14 4. Spikelets free, mine imbedded ."i U 11 Figure 13. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">A Handbook of Nebraska Uraxxes. 13 no. pack G Spikelets in pairs, one sessile and perfect, the other pedicellate and staminate, empty or reduced to the pedicle Andropouoneae 14 14 5. Rpikelets single 6 14 Figure 14 H. Andbopooonbae. 6. Glumes none Obyzeai 15 ~1'1 6. Glumes 2 Ac;rostidea« 15 24 6. Glumes 3 ' Panickak 15 15 6. Glumes 4 I'halarideae 15 'S-'. Figure 15. ■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 I Handbook of \ebr&lt;mka Grasses. 7. Awn, if present, straight and arising at or near the apex of the lemma Festuceae 16 -44 7. Awn always present, straight or twisted and arising midway between the base and the apex. . Avkneab 16 39 Figure 16. FE8TUCEAE AVENEAE ANDROPOGNKAK. 1. Spikelets arranged in a panicle 2 1. Snikelets arranged in silky racemes 8 15 •' 1. Spikelets arranged in silky racemes. 2. Pedicellate spikelet wanting. . Sorghastrutn nutans 17 !*2 2. Pedicellate spikelet present Andropogon halepenxis 17 T'.t </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 \ FIG. PAUK 3. Racemes single Indropogon mfiriM 18 7!&gt; 3. Racemes in pairs 4 4. Fourth glume with long twisted awn Andropogon furcatux IN 7'.i 4. Fourth glume with short straight awn Indropogon hallii 18 7!l PANICBAE. Spikelets not surrounded b.v bristles nor spines. . .3 1!» Spikelets surrounded bv iirominent bristles or - in Ifi spines B II 17 &gt; Figure 19. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 FIG. PACK 2. Rpikelets in a one-sided spike or raceme 3 20 2. Spikelets in a panicle Panicum 20 It 3. Racemes in terminal digitate whorls. Dit/itaria xanguinalis 21 84 3. Racemes scattered 4 21 17 Figure 21. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 KIO. PAGfc 4. Glumes awned Echinochloa crus-galli 22 85 4. Glumes not awned Ha»palum stramineum 22 90 Eckinochloa crus-galli Patpalum itraminenm. '). Spikelct surrounded by thickened spines Cenchrus tribuloides 23 83 r&gt;. Spikelel surrounded by bristles 6 23 18 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 PIG. PAGE 6. Bristles downwardly barbed Set aria verticillata ~M 92 f&gt;. Bristles upwardly barbed 7 24 Setaiia verticiUata i 7. Second j^miie shorter I linn the third Bttmrim ftenoa 25 '■&gt;- 7. Second glmne equaling the third Srtaria riridix 25 92 Figure 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I Handbook of Nebraska 0fWM. 19 ! PANICUM. PIG. PAGE Spikelets Spikelets pointed rounded sit the tip 2 26 • &gt; at the tip I L'ti l&gt;ii 2. First ghuue not over oM-fonrth the length of the spikelet 1'anicunt dichotOMifloruM 27 H 2. First glume about oiic-linlf the length of the spikelet 3 27 20 .'. Pint jrluino two-thirds to three-fourths the length uf the ■pikelet. . . .Paniemm virgatum 27 M Figure 27. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 I Handbook of Nebraska Grassex. '!. Spikelets L'.o mm. long or less: blades not crowded toward the base Panicum capillare 28 "■■' r pikelets 2.5-S.8 nun. long; blades crowded toward the base 4 28 •1. Spikelets 2. (&gt;-.'{.:{ nun. long; panicles erect. Panicum barbipnlvinatum 28 s '&gt; I. Spikelets 4.5-S.fl nun. long; panicles drooping Panicum miliaceitm 28 'M\ Figure 28. ' I . 'f-t » '. • / SM Kx'S ' *"£.* X**~' . '^S*V / £&lt;^ I'diiium capillare. Panicum barbipulvinatum. I'aniaim niliactum 5. Spikelets less than 2 nun. in length 6 5. Spikelets more than 2.5 mm. in length 7 21 6. Spikelets l.S-l.!t mm. long; blades with long spreading hairs on the upper surface; first glume triangular, one-third to one-half length of spikelet Panicum praecociux 2!t M fl. Spikelets 1.6-1.8 nun. long; blades with short apprensed hairs on the upper surface; first glume, not triangular, about one-third length of spikelet Panicum huachucae 29 S!i Panirum praeeociiu Paninw, kuarhiuw -Ji? </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 FIG. PAOE 7. First glume oue-half the length of the spikelet. . . . Panicum leibcryii 30 8H rret glume less than one-third the length of the spikelet 8 30 8. Spikelets densely hairy. .Panicum wilcoxianum 30 90 S. Spikolets sparsely hairy to smooth Panicum ficribncrianum :il&gt; !W FiRure 30. Panicum ncribnei ianum </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 1 Htimlhuok nf \cbnixkd (Irasxex. OKVZEAK. FIG. PACih rpper sjiikehMs pistillate, some loug-amwd; lower ■pikelets staniinate, awnlcss. . . ./.itauia aqnatica 31 'M •&gt; 1. Sjiikelets all alike and awuless 2 i\ Bpikeleta '2. •"&gt;-:&gt;. 0 nun. loiifi. . . .Imtim cirgmica 31 88 2. Spikeleis 4-5 nim. long Leeraim oryaoiica 31 B8 Figure 31 y.izania u./'ia/iV.i rfas. l.eeisiu trgmUm. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 HHALAItlDKAU. 1. Third iin.I tmttk glumes ;i\uied upon the back flQ. PAGE r." • • I nl li'i-ra ill hum odoratum nrd and fouitli ghnmi rodlmentarr, not awned 2 2. First iind second -jinnies with winjt'l'ike keels. 32 7!» o „. • Phalurits cnnuriensis 32 90 -. inrst ;md Rerond jinnies not winged Phalariz nrundinacea 32 90 Figure / h.ilin.s ranarienri* I'halarit arundinaetn . </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 I Handbook of \ebrasku On AGROSTEDEAG. FIG 1. Spikclets in ■ close spike 2 33 1. Sjiikelots in an open or contracted panicle 4 33 Figure 33. £ [ W^ X. 4. •) (ihiiiies awuless llopecitnu yeniculatus 34 79 2. Glumes awned 3 3. Glumes with a long slender awn Poly/toi/on mon8pelien8i8 34 91 3. Glumes with ■ short abrupt awn. . Phleum pratense 34 N Alopmtnu geni* ulatu* Polypugun mutujxlietuis. Phleum /iratrnse </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 no. page 4. Lemma awn-pointed or with terminal awn.. 5 35 I. Lemma awnless or with a dorsal awn 8 35 27 rehilla prolonged behind the palea Brachyelytrum erect um 36 81 5. Kachilla not prolonged behind the palea 6 36 26 Figure 36. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 •i • &gt;■ ,) &lt; fi. Lemma long and Barrow with three awns Arixtidtt H7 :to •!. Lemma narrow with one long twisted awn sti/xi :\~ H. l^mma short and narrow, awn-pointed or with a slender awn Wuhlenberyiu M 6. Lemma broad, the short awn falling soon after flowering 7 37 Figure 37. i Arhlula Stipa MuMenlieri/iu 7. Lemma smooth Oryzopxis micrantha 39 7. Lemma with long silky hairs. .. Krinroma cuspidata '£'.) M Figure 38. , I O-yJ « V \ / I V , j \ / /l (I / I- 1 I / &amp;&gt; KriO'&lt;ma cii*pidata. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 FIG. PAGE 8. Lemma with long basal hairs 9 39 8. Lemma without basal hairs 10 :'.!) 28 Figure 39. / ;;L 9. 10. 9. Lemma awued ; basal hairs abundant Galamagrostis 40 35 9. Lemma awn less; basal hairs not abundant Calamovilfa longifolia 40 )S-"{ Figure 40. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 H :&lt;7 FIG. PAGE 10. Flower not plainly pedicellate 11 41 10. Flower plainly pedicellate 12 41 29 10. Flower plainly pedicellate. 11. Lemma shorter than or equal to the glumes Agroati* 42 M Lemma longer than one or both of the glumes . . . . Sporobolua 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">A Handbook of Mebrimka &amp;ras*es. 29 FIG. PAUK 12. Panicle contracted at maturity; first glume shorter than the second. .Cinna arundiimcea 4."? M 12. Panicle open at maturity; first glume equal to the second China hit if nl in 4:; &lt;: Figure 43. r m *H, *-% Cinmi latifolio. I i huh uniiiilinactii </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 AltiSTlDA. K1G. l'AIJK 1. Awns twisted ;it the liiisc into a spiral column Vristida tubercnlota 44 SO I. Awns nut twisled at the liase •&gt; 2. Central awn coiled at the base I rixtidu baxintmru 44 80 -. Central awn unt coiled at the Itase .'{ t. First nne-tliird the length of the second 1 rixtidu Umgiteta 44 80 !. First {flume alxmt wjualiii}; the second 4 SI Figure 44. mmmlm </seg>
            <seg id="p031">I Handbook of S'ebnixhu (Irtixxrx. 31 &gt; i rifl. paqb 4. First glume 5-7 Mired irintida oliyantha 4.". m 4. Fii-st glume l-."{ nerved 5 Middle awn horizontal ; ii;uch lonjjer than the lateral «■ 4 ristida yrucilis 4.T M Middle awn not horizontal; as long as the lateral ilw " s I ristida pmrpmtva 45 so Figure 45. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 ST1PA. FIG. PACK 1 . (Hume* 1.5 em. long Of less BUpm ririduln 4« !I4 1. Glumes 2.0 cm. long or more 2 o 2. Lemma 8-12 mm. long; awn slender and curled Stipa comata 46 'J'S 2. Lemma 20-25 mm. long Stipa spartea 46 M </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 1 MUHM3NBE-.GIA. PIG. PAGE I . l'auicle open Mmhlemherpim (MMfWM 47 N!» Panicle contracted 2 47 Figure 47. .Vuhlenbergia pungent. _'. Lemma awn-poiuted :: 48 34 2. Lemma long awned 4 4g .-{4 V I. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 FIG. PAflE I limit's nravlv fqml in length to tin- lemma ]/ iihleiibrn/ia in liiines longer th.ii) the lemma and awneri. Muhlenbeifim nir.r'ciiini 4!i -sv \fulilrnbrrtiiii i iff Ml 4!t H 4. (iliiincs H|Wll to tlic Icinina 1/ iihlfiibrnfia si/lrntirti 41 v ' 4. (iluincs one -half as long as the leninia Muhlfiibcryia tiniiifinia 4!) §9 4. Chimes h ss than one fourth as loaf as tin' lemma WukienhergM tehrebtri 4!t §1 Figure 49. YuUenlitrgia .Vuhlenbert/ia Muhlenltenjia Vithlenlicr&lt;i&lt;a .Vuhleiilttriiin </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 &lt; AL.AMAUKOSTIS. WO. I'ACiK 1. Panicle open, luaiiclifs Hprmdini; ics sprt-iidinji CtihinHtfimxtix iiiiKitlrnxis 50 . . . . VmUimmgnmti 1. Panicle narrow or mntmrtfd •uniiaiii &lt;1 • i -. Leaves Hat ; basal hairs alioiit eqottliag the low ('tlUluiiujinxtix iiK.rjxnixii ."»ll fv5 Sill Ililil'S illHMIt i ('(ihinitHjroxt ■J. Leaves rolled lojietlur in drying; Imsal liairs half as lonij as llie (lower ('oltliiKif/roxlix nrf/lccta ."id H i^cilur in drying; is I lie (lower Cmtmmagrt Figure 50. i Figure 50. kCnlamni/rtutit iiiespiiii.it). </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 AGROST1S. t'IG. PAtJK 1. Palea conspicuous [grout i* alba 51 7^ 1. Palea very small or wanting 2 2. Panicle narrow Agrostis exarata 51 7s 2. Panicle diffusely spreading 3 3. Culms weak, usually spreading on the. ground Agroxtis pervnmiii" "&gt;1 ~K Culms and leaves erect Agroxtix hyemalix ."&gt;! 78 Figure 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">1 Handbook of Srbrtinku (imxxrx. 37 SPOROBOM S. pin. pagi FIO I. Panicle contracts 2 1 . Panicle open 5 B 2. Spikelets 3-5 nun. or more in length 3 W more in length '.I 2. Spikelets 3 nun. or less in length 4 i- less in length 4 Palea long awn-pointed Sporobolim aaper ■ !•:', &amp; Sporuboliw aaper ■ !•: rlea not long awn-pointed; panicles conspicuous Sporobolux vaginiflonix ."&gt;•_' M ninted: panicles conspicuous . . . . iSporobolux rayiniflonix ■ !•: 4. Sheaths inflated and including panicles ind including panicles $l)on&gt;bolux )i&gt;-()ltetiix U '■&gt;'■ Upontbolux ncfilcrtiix H '•••'• 4. Sheaths not inflated. .. .Uporobolux brerifoliux 52 '-I-'! ed . . . . Spon&gt;boli&lt;x brerifolinx 52 '■•■ Figure 52. Figure 52. / 1 f % P Sporobolwi Sporolmlu* Sfmrobolvt Spurohohu imrtiljiilus Sfx,rob&lt;ilvi Spordbohu ciiqinilimiis. neqttclux breeifoliui atper. raginiftimis. negltcius bretifoliu* j. First glume about equaling the second (i ~&gt;:\ M First ghnne one-half aa long as the second 7 5:{ :W &gt; Figure 53. 6. 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">1 lluiidUiml; &lt;&gt;( S'ekrnxkm Unman. 38 . I KM. PAOK C». lVnniiiiil with ;i lmiii rhiwniM 1 Sliuiiilinlils iix/k-i ilolilix 54 !••&gt; (i. Annual Sporoboltu oomfttuu "»4 '••:• First glume Mrs-pointed ttporohohu lntrn&gt;l&lt;i&gt;is 54 H 7. First jrluine not Rwa-pointed SpnrolHihtx in/iitiinilriis 54 !•:'. Figure 54. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 AVENi AK. . . , PIG. PAUt" I. Awn of second ghuM book-like Holcma lunuhix 16 S7 I. Awn of second flower not hook-like l&gt; B 40 I B 40 Figure 55. •&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 .1 Handbook &lt;&gt;( \fl&gt;rank&lt;i tirmmei. rra. page 2. Upper Hower of spikelei perfed ; tin- lower stmninate irrhrmmtkermm clatinx M sn 2. Flowers all perfrct, or tin* iip|M'r ones stain inate 3 '!. S|iikcltMs less than 12 nun. long I)&lt; xcliuuipxHi flcxuoxil 5H |4 :!. Spikelets nioiv than VI nun. long Iwm fatim M II Figure 56. AirhenoOientut rtti/itt* /'&gt;.«(7i&lt;(»i//.v/K ifrswMt Aetna futua. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 CHLiOKlDKAE. no. pack r pikelets, with staminate flowers, in conspicuous spikes; pistillate flowers partially included in broad sheaths Buchloe dactyloides 57 82 1. Spikelets with perfect flowers 2 2. Spikes digitate 3 57 i'2 2. Spikes racemose 4 57 4J Figure 67. U •/ I * inftl i It* 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Mpikelet I -flowered . . Spikelel 3-6-fl»weved Ci/nodun duel i/lmi 5,S S4 I'h'iisinc imliiii 58 85 Figure 58 Cj/uodoM ilac/i/luii Elewine itnliin. 4. Spikt'lcts not crowded Schciloiinurdiix pmnieul»tm» 59 !»•_' 1. Spikclcls crowflcd '.&gt; ."VI 4 5. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 Via pack Rachilla extending hevoml tin Rower and bearing . awns (i (id 4:'. r&gt;. l.'acliilla not extending beyond the Mower .s tiO 44 Figure tin. V ( 6. (i. Spikes numerous lioiili Ioiki inrtijtciulnhi til Sit &lt;!. Spikes one to fonr 7 7. Kiichilla with tuft of lonij hairs at the base HohIiIoiiii iilii/nstiirlii/a HI SI 7. Rachilla without tuft of lon&lt;i hairs at the base. . . . lioiitrlwia hiiKiitu C&gt;\ 81 Figure 61. "A &gt; \ **$ H '. '. I ' * &gt; \l 1 i/_ V .1 • &gt; Tu, NhA life r \ W\ I A W 1 / « I ffwhlllliii cttrtipendul'i ImMm oliiiimlark/ia. Jiiiitelomi hirmtti </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 S. Kaehilla mit extending beyond the upper spike - let Beckmannia erucaeformi* H2 8&lt;i S. Kaehilla extending beyond the upper spike - let ft '••. Spikes more than 5 cm. long, Bpmriimm michauxiauu U It 9. Spikes lesn than 5 fin. long tfpartina yrncilix &lt;»if !••_' Figure 62. tiMta prostrate: spikelets surrounded by stiff leaves in terminal rlusten ...M Huron «&lt;//((i//o»« lio loose or contracted rlants erect; spikelets in panicles 4." 2 63 Figure 63. Mmmroa nquamitu •1 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 rio. i-ai.k -. Kachilhi clothed with long silky hairs exceed - ing the florets Phragmitr* com miitiix f&gt;4 90 2. Rachilla naked, or with short hairs 3 64 Figure 64 PkraipmUtH eawumum&gt;n. .'{. Lemma l-3-nerved or nerveless 4 65 4fi '{. Lt-iiiiiia 5-manv-nerved 10 65 4!» </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 KIU. PACJK 4. LeaUM hard; seed beaked and protruding be - yond the glumes and lemma Diarrhena diandm t!« ■* I I. l.ciimia soft: wed not henked nor protruding. .5 fifi hiiirrhfna iliatuirn 5 o. Lateral nervex of the leinina hairv Triplaxi* inn/nirea «7 !»4 o. Lateral nerves of the lemma smooth 6 67 17 « </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 6. Lemma hairy at the base. . . . ft&gt;dfi&gt;lditi fhamtm H !&gt;1 ti. l.i'inina not hairy ,m i !■«• liaw 7 68 7 68 7. Second glume very unlike the lirm . . . .Siilunopholis 69 52 7. Second glume like the tirst 8 69 48 Figure 69. * S/Jiewpk'Ji.-. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 1 Handbook of Subraskn Via**?*. rn;. S. l'auicle dense ami spike-like. Koeierim crixtata 70 87 »8. Panicle open 9 pikelets 2-Howered ; aquatic. . .('atabroxu aqitatica 70 pikelets 3-many-flnwei'ed ; tarwti'ial Kim§i'9»ti$ 70 s Figure 70. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 KIU. PAGE 10. Spikelets with upper flowers sterile and folded about each other Melica nitinx 71 88 10. Spikelets with the upper flowers perfect, nar - row, or abortive 11 71 Mrlini niten 11 11. I^enmia compressed and keeled 12 I'l M 11. Lemma rounded on the back 14 72 M Figure n. 01- II U. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 12. Panicle contract e&lt; I Uistichliti xpicata 73 84 11'. Panicle open 13 13. Lemma awned or awn -pointed.. Dactylix tjluinrrata T.\ 84 1 :?. Lemma awnless Pun 78 ftl Figure 73. 14. Lemma with a basal tuft of hair*; aquatic Scolochkm frxtucacea 17 !i2 14. Lemma naked at the base 15 74 51 N'li/m'/f/i ■*( '&lt; ■ ' </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 15. Apex of lemma acute, entire, pointed, or awned. . Frxtucu 75 18 IS. Apex of lemma 2-toothed. awn below the apex; or awnless and liroadlv rounded or obtuse at the tip 1« 75 16. Style attached below the apex of the ovary. . It nun us tin If?. Style attached to the apex of the orary. . . .17 Figure 75 || I i Fettnca. Hi 17. Lemma otiscurely B mmnei. . . .Pmocimeitim miroidm 7t; !»1 17. Lemma prominently li-7-nerved 18 18. Second glume 1 mm. long. . . .Olyceria nervata lit -7 IS. Second glume '1. 0-3. r&gt; nun. Ions: Glyceria tjrundix Tti Figure 76 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 A Handbook of \ebraxka Grouses SPHENOPHOLIS. FIU. I'ACK 1. Panicle dense tfphenopholix nbtimulu 77 M Figure 77. SpheHopkottM tAtwuUu S/l/lfHl'llhllliK /KtHl'llS KRAGROSTIS. I. Lemma with (diKCiire lateral nerves. 2 78 H 1. Lemma with |ii-oiniiient to conspicuous nerves. . . .4 78 54 Figure 7K. CD /- ■-&gt;. i. I. Panicle Intqpr Sfthino^holix pallrn* 77 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">1 Handbook »/ \ihmttka Qrmmm 53 2. «pikelets 2-5-Howewl Eragrostis capillari* C ' 8C -. Spikelets more than 5-floweml :; 7&lt;» ka •■! 7!» 54 Kragrostti capillarit. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 { Spikelets t; 20-flowered ; panicle 15-30 cni. long.... Eragrostis pilnxu 80 M '. Sj.ikelt-is in W-iowrwd; panicle 3-6 cm. long. /■'rut/rout ix hifpnoidtx SO Mi Figure 80 Kragrustix pUasa. F.raijrimti.1 hypnoiiii 1. t&gt;pikelets less than 3 mm. wide 5 4. Spikelets 3 mm. or more wide 7 56 "&gt;. Sheaths overlapping Brmgnutit prctinacea 81 86 V Sheaths shorier than the inieruodes 6 81 55 Figure 81. 0 / . t;. Krwffroaiu f&gt;fcfiutt&gt; nt </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 &gt; n&lt;;. i-A(iK «. Panicle narrow. :iv, cm. lon« ; spikelets 10-40- tiowered EfgrottU hypnoides 82 86 6. Pauicle 6-24 cm. lonj;: s| f ikelets .5 lo-Hovered. . Ermgroatia pUom H2 sti Figure 82 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 A Handbook of Xebraska Gruxxt-s. ' i FIG. I'AI.F Sheathe shorter than the iuternodes, panicle 5-15 cm. long Erugrostis megastachyu 88 M Sheaths overlapping panicle 22-07 cm. long Erngrostix trichode* 83 II Figure 83. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">A Handbook "( \rhraxka SfMN. 57 I. Lemma without basal hairs Poh mi huh &gt;C&gt; 01 I. T^emnia with bsisal h;iirs 2 85 Figure 85. AVmi annua. 2 2. Culms greatly flattened; flowers usually hroader above than below the middle Poa cnm/H-emta 86 91 2. Culms rounded, not greatly flattened 3 86 58 Poa ronijrressa I </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 no. pauf. Intermediate nerves distinct foa yralfnxix 87 !il Intermediate nerves mil ilistinct . I'oa nrtiinralix 87 91 I. Leaves - niui. wide or lesM, iiivolute when dry 2 88 59 I. Ijeavet* 4 mm. wide or more, flat when dry 4 88 60 Figure 88. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 -'. Spikelets 5-13-tiowered fntrnm ovtofloru S!t 87 2. Spikelets 3 G- flowered 3 :{. Panicle close, contracted, expanding while in bloom Fettuca ovina 8!» 87 I'anicle open and spreading Ftxtura aHiiica §■ M Fettuoa altaica m M Figure 89. i w V \ % A i } r f 1 to v r ! A'/ ,l - i .i &lt; j t'rstiica ovina. flntmtm ittoaea </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 FIU. l'AUE 4. Spikelets 5-10-Hower«*&lt;l Festuca clatior 90 86 t. Spikelets 3-5-flow»&gt;red Fextuca obtnsa !H) 87 Figure 90. h'estwa elatinr. h'rxtuca oltltistt. B1IOMI S. 1. First glume 1-nerved 2 !tl «1 1. First glume S-Mnred 5 !M VH\ Figure 91. II </seg>
            <seg id="p061">I Hmtdbouk of \chniska flHMUm. 61 KKi. !'A«1K Awn longer than the leimiia; low annuals. '-. Awn shorter than the lenmin or wanting: tall perennials :\ »2 &lt;&gt;2 1 A Tl»r» liiiiiniH t-\\ •&gt; &gt;&gt; • 1. . . * -- — . !„ .. l_ </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 K IK •'!. Lemma with awn 1 nun. long, awn-pointed, or awn - less Bromus inerm is !&gt;3 81 .'?. Lemma with awn 6 mm. long or more 4 4. Culms stout; branches of the panicle more -or less spreading or drooping. .Bromus dliatux !)3 81 4. Culms slender; branches of the panicle erect. . Brnmu* erertux it:-! Hi Figure 93. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 i KIG. PAfll %. Lenimn a wued c, 94 Lemma awnlens or with short ;i\vii; Marty an long as broad Bramma hrhmefitrmia !M g] Figure 94. 0. Lf niiiju Lairy 7 1)5 g^ 6. Lemma smooth f) 95 g5 Figure 95. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 1 Handbook of Nebruxkii (JrtiMxrx. FIG. I'AUE 7. Lemma covered with short appressed hairs. Bromus hordeaceus 96 81 7. Lemma covered with long silky hairs 8 8. Second glume 3-nerved Bromus porteri 96 H 8. Second glume 5-7-nerved Bromux kalmii 86 tf'2 Figure 96. Bnmuu hardeactu* . Hromux /lorteri. Hromux kalmii. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">4 Hmidlinnk of Nebraska &lt;ha**r*. 65 Kit;. PAUK !». Awns Htraight 10 97 66 9. Awns strongly bent near the base. . Bromn* squarrosus 97 82 Figure 97 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 lit. Sheaths smooth Bnntiim tecnliuHa 98 82 in. Sheaths hairv It mm it* rmcemntma !&gt;8 82 r pikelets aolitan in the notches &lt;&gt;f the y.ijj/^ig rachis ' 2 !»!l (iT I. Spikelets 2-6 in each imteli of the zigzag rachis. . . .:! &lt;Mt «&gt; Figure 99 ■i </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 1. Spikelet with its edge to the rachis Lolium 100 70 2. Spikelet with its side to the rachis. .Agropyron 1 00 71 Figure 100. a 1 I M v .1 * I M I P • A J I V &lt; •&lt; i.'y h, t ■V- </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Kl'.. I'AUK 3. Spikelet 1-flowered. with two aborted spikelets. . . . Hordeum 101 7ti 3. Rpikelet 2-nianv flowered 4 101 Figure 101. / \ * 4. llordeuvi. 4. Glumbes minute or none Hyxtrix patula 102 87 4. Glumes usually equaling the lemma. 5 102 K!l 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">A Handbook of A'ebraska Onixxr*. 69 FIG. PAUL ."&gt;. RachJN articulated and fi;igile Sitanion hystrix 103 92 Figure 103. Sitanion h)/~(rijr. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 LOLJIM. 1. Lemma awn-pointed or awnless Lolimm pmrettme 1&lt;&gt;4 tf!t 1. Lemma long-awned 2 2. Glume shorter than the lemma Lolium multiflorum 104 8!» 2. Glume as long as or exceeding the lemma. . . . Lolium trmulentum 104 8!&lt; Figure 104. l.olivm perenne. l*litim mullifinrum. iMlium temtdentum </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 AGROFYBON. PI(i. PAGE 1 . With rhizome 2 105 1. Without rhizome 3 105 7l' Figure 105. :i. 2. Hpikelet 3-7-tiowered Ayropyrun repent 106 77 2. Spikelet 7-13-flowere&lt;l Agropyron xmithii 106 78 Figure 106. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 Kli;. l-AGK :{. l^eniina loug-awued \groyyron caninum 107 77 3. I .fin ma short-awned. or awn less 4 4. Spikes 8-20 cm. long; green or straw colored Agmpyron tenerum 1117 7S 4. Spikes t-M cm. long; purplish Afropgrom biflorum 107 77 KiRure 107. ■V»™™» tentmm l./ro/n/ron hi riorum. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 ELYMUS. FIG. PAUE 1. Lemma awulcss or awn-pointed. Ely in us condensatug 108 85 1. l.i-iimiit conspicuously nwned 2 108 Klf/mus condemn! us. 2. Spikelets divergent from the rachilla of the broad spike 3 109 74 •J. Spikelets appressed to the rachilla of the nar - row Rpike !.• IN 75 Figure 109. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 S. Spike slender Elmyua striatus 110 86 \. Spike stout 4 110 Figure 110. Eli/mtts ttrimtm. 4. Lemma smooth Ely m us riryinicux 111 H 4. Leiiuna rough or hairv 5 111 75 Figure 111. KhfWIUM rinimirlls. 5. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 PHI. PAliK tike loosely flowered; long pedicelled Elymiis cano ike densely flowered; included at the base Elymus canadenxix 112 80 Elynnix lobiiKlnx 112 H Klt/miui canadenxi Htymi/i roliiixtit*. ..Elymu* ylaucux ll',\ Elyiniix inncnuttii 113 s li. Spikelet 3-6-le«wcd «. Spikelet 1-S-flowei-ed A*/ i/THUJt •//•IHi'U </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 I Handbook of Nebraska Ura*se«. HORDEIM. Vlii. 1'AfiK 1. Spikes bushy; with spreading awns. Hordeum jubatum 114 87 1. Spikes narrow; with nearly erect awns. Hordeum pu*illum 114 87 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">77 NOTES ON ECONOMIC CRASSES. No grass can l&gt;e grown under cultivation on any large scale unless it is possible to secure its seeds in sufficient quantity and at a reasonable price. The failure of many otherwise very de - sirable species to seed freely under cultivation makes their line quite impossible. The use of grasses for specific purposes depends upon various other characters, only one of which is here mentioned. Rhizomes of many perennial grasses are continued by the formation of shoots from the lower nodes of the flowering shoots. The method by which these shoots are formed determines whether the grass will be a ''bunch'' grass or a sod or "turf grass. The buds mentioned develop within the sheath and if they continue their growth enclosed by the sheath they are called intra- vaginal. Such grasses are apt to form bunches or tussocks. On the other hand, if these buds early break thru the sheath, then extra - vaginal shoots result and these spread the grass over a consider - able area by means of the resulting stolons. This type of grass will form a more or less compact turf or sod. Moreover, buncli grasses would be of little value as sand binders in comparison with grasses of the latter type. The following notes have been compiled to serve as an in - troduction to further study and experimentation with our na - tive grasses. The Department of Agricultural Botany desires to receive specimens of our native grasses and information con - cerning their behavior. Such specimens will furnish us more accurate data regarding the distribution of our various grasses thruont the several counties. AGROPYBON. biflonuii. Purple Wheat Grass. (Fig. 107.) A slender perennial of western Nebraska. rAgropyron caninxim. Awned Wheat Grass. (Fig. 107.1 An erect grass sparingly naturalized in cultivated ground and meadows. The bearded nodding heads re - semble somewhat heads of wheat. I'nlike Couch Grass this species has no rootstocks. It may readily be propa gated by the seeds, which are easily gathered. rAgropyron repens. Couch Grass. (Fig. 106.) A stout perennial grass which forms a dense sod by means of its extensive system of rhizomes. It is a vain </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 "buuls itself tun" and the sod must again U' broken to restore tlie yield. It should prove to lie ■ valuable sand binding gran on railroad embankments and other places subjei-t to blow-out. It is ordinarily considered a nox ions weed, the eradication of which is verv difficult. • ■ '.'/"'/'.'/'"" xniithii. Western Wheat (irass. I Fig. LM.) In the western part of the State this is one of our most valuable grMMS. ll is an erect perennial resembling in man.v respects Couch &lt; irass. but on account of the bluish color of its foliage often receives the name "Hlnesteiu." a name, however, which should he reserved for species af . I lid n&gt;i&gt;(/i/t,ii. \firop!/r&lt;)ii li in i iiiii. Slender Wheat Una. I Fig. 1(17.1 •&gt;■ This is a perennial bunch grass of the western prairie*. The seed can ordinarily be secured on the market, and its cultivation may be expected to increase in the future. It produces a large amount of forage and ri]&gt;ens an abun dance of seed. ACiltOSTIS. \t/ro8tix tilbti. Redtop. I Fig. 51.) fc This is an upright hardy perennial whose rhizomes form a rather dense sod. The existence of many forms Ml this s|M'cies has led to much diversity of opinion as to the value of the grass under cultivation. The taller forms ■ •niav Ik' cut for hay. while the low -growing sorts are un - surpassed lawn grasses. It prefers a rather moist soil and should do best when sown with clovers or other grasses. It prefers a rather moist soil and should do best when sown with clovers or other grasses. In low ground it often drives out the native grasses. ifTWMt crarata. Northern Redtop. i Fig. 51. 1 This is a variable ■pecien found in the wet places in the . wesiern part of the State. Some of the forms are to be recommended for cultivation on account of their heavy foliage and vigorous growth. S. Agroxtix hyemalix. Hair (irass. (Fig. 51. i A well-known slender grass of the earlv summer found thruout the State. The panicle is often blown aliout like a lumbleweed. '■» Agrmti* pertmmmmn. Thin (irass. i Fig. 51. i This species is much like Af/itixtis In/rnitilix but flowers IDIll'll I'ltt'l' 111 t 111* Kf'lSlll) ( 'ilSS 4 "&lt;&gt;ll!l ! V </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 11. 11 11' I II 15 AI.OPKCIIUS. llopei-urua geniculmttt*. Water Foxtail, i Fij;. '.l'.\. :»4.i A low slender father | &gt;i-&lt; m-ii 11 1 Ix-ti t perennial &lt;;ris&gt; "f eastern Neliraska. In that region in low pastures and meadows it provides exrellent gvasiag. One of the forms of this jrrass is a jrood turf AMMIOIHMJO.V. Imdrupogtm fiinntux. Big Mluestem. (Fig. is. i This is a very tall perennial that formerly was very aliundant on the ]&gt;rairies thruoiit the State. In the west en counties it still forms a verv important pan of the native hay and when rut early is relished by stcM-k. I'll less the moisture supply is adequate it does not seed freely, and this is a serious defect of any y;rass when cultivated for hav. I mlni/iut/oii ItaltjHiixix. •lohnson (Irass. (Pig. 17.) This is an introduced jrrass loag iri-own in the South and to a limited extent in our southern counties. It de velops a very extensive system of roolslocks and in the South it is nearly impossible to eradicate it when mice established. This is a stout erect perennial which makes a luxuriant growth in the Sand Mills where it can 1m- recommended as a s;ind binding j^rass. It must lie cut early if to lie used for hay and. tho more woody, is perhaps as valuable as the Hijr Hluesteni. \m4ntfngom tcop*ri*t. Little I'.luestein. i Fijj. is. i This rather slender perennial is a common prairie j:rass thruoul the State. It is often associated with other species of I mil njidiimi and with them may constitute a large par! of the native prairie hay. The stems are gem - erally reddish in color. AXTHOXAXTHI'M. {iithii.riiiilliinii (iihinitiim. Sweet Vernal &lt;lrass i Fijr. 32.1 A |«&gt;rennial sweet scented jrrass with slender i r ct tnfted stems. The bitter taste of its leaves reader* il somewhat unpalatable for stock Iho a sinill amount adds a rather pleasant fragrance to hay. It* carlin&lt;&gt;s irivis it some value as a pasture -rass. \ it(lr&lt;&gt;ii&lt;i&lt;/&lt;ni luillii. Colorado Sand (ii-ass. i Fij;. l*.i </seg>
            <seg id="p080">A Handbook of Nebraska (Iraxsrs. 80 IiriHtida buxiniiiicii. Tufted Triple Awn. I Fig. 44.) An erect, tufted. much-branched pnrwrial common in the Sand Hill region. tAristida gracilis. Slender Heard (irass. (Fig. 45.1 A slender tufted annual of northern Nebraska. tArixtida longiseta. Hog Town (irass. (Fig. 44.) A slender densely tufted, wiry percmfal found in dry soils in western Nebraska. tAristida olitjiintha. Prairie Triple Awn. (Fig. 45.) Tn poor dry soil over most of The State. tAiixtirfa purpuren. Purple Beard Grass. (Fig. 45.) A common perennial prairie gross tliruout the State. tAiixiidti titbrrculoxii. I.ong-awncd Poverty Grass. I Fig. 44.) A rigid, we h-bra whrd perennial in dry sandy soi'. Kearney County. ARRHKNATHEIUM. \rrlicnathrniin datiiix. Tall Oat Grass. (Fig. 56.) This is a tall loosely-tufted ptnaaM which makes an early growth, thus rendering it of some value in pastures. It grows rapidly and is very drouth-resistant. Tt does not form a good sod and must therefore be sown with other aperies. AVENA. 23. A vena fatuu. Wild Oats. (Fig. 5t&gt;. This is an erect glabrous annual found in waste pla&lt;-es. It is generally regarded as a serious weed pest — particu - larly since its stiff twisted awns are rather troublesome fa stock. BEGKMANNIA. t. Reekmannia crueaeformis. Slough Grass. (Fig. 62.) A stout, tall, erect, coarse perennial growing in tuftt. along river banks and irrigation ditches. When young it is readily eaten by stock. It is particularly well adapted for low irrigated alkaline soils. Common in western Nebraska. BOVTEIiOUA. r. Koutelotw niitiixndnhi. Tall (iiaina (irass. (Fig. 81. i A tall densely tufled |&gt;erennial with tough perennial i'i io1 s Tlwi li'iY iff i"( *■ 1 1 1 i I \ &lt; '■) ' &lt; ■ 1 1 Iiy s t &lt; it "l\ wti iffi lio W(*vf*t* AKIHTIDA. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 &lt;»n the range prefer the Blue &lt; iraiua &lt;Jras«. Its manv liasal leaves render it a rather valuable pasture gram in try regions and it cures readily when cut for ha\. Thruout the State. ■ Houteloua hirsutti. Black &lt;iraina. (Fig. til. I This is one of the common tufted perennial grasses of MB wesTern Sand Ft ills. When abundant it forms excel - lent pasturage, it-s dense tufts and fine leaves being much relished by stuck. Thruout the State, but most abundant westward. ■ Bouteloua oli(/(jKtuclii)ii. Mine Grama. ( Fig. til. I This is the commonest and most valuable species of Grama Grass on the Great Plains. It is a slender, erect, tufted perennial with strong rootstocks and numerous basal leaves. \o other grass withstands the tramping of stock as does this, and it is thus unsurpassed for grazing purposes. The leaves are short and crowded at the base of the short stem producing dense cushion-like masses pressed close to the ground. It is often improperly called Buffalo grass. Tt is very drouth- resistant and very com - mon thruout the State. BRACHYELYTRUM. SB. lint'hyeJytium erection. Bearded Short Husk. (Fig. 36J A slender perennial with unhranched steins in open wooded regions. BROMUS. St. R ronnitt hrizavfoniii*. (Fig. 94. &gt; A slender, erect, tufted annual with nodding panicles of very large spikelets. introduced from Europe. SO. Hionius riliatus. Swamp Chess. (Fig. 93.) On good soils in wooded parts or shady pastures, it should make a vigorous early growth. Common thrnout the State. 31. Bromu* erect hi*. (Fig. 93.) ■ Introduced from Europe. Valley County Bromu x honlcuceiix. Soft Chess. (Fig. 96.) An erect or ascending annual or biennial found in fields and waste places. tt. Rrnmtts im'nui*. Awulestt Brouie Gram. (Fig. 93. » This is an erect vigorous, hardy perennial with strong creeping rootstocks enabling it to form a thick and firm t 1 I i. ! ,. II •! t t\'|i \ f I "^ l!T*JtTti* lilt l'l wi 11 1 'Ml \ *1 till W* 1 lipl V I "1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 tiv;ile&lt;l ill many parts of I lit- Stale for 1 1 ; I v . The slroii': jx'icii nia ! cIimimiI' i- of iliis urass ;nnl its irreat drmitl: resisting po\\( ■!■ ar • ipialitirs which reeoiinnend it for jren eral cull i\;ii inn pariieularly iii Hcmiarkl regions. This drnul Ii resistance was proved for tins graM M IMIK-Ii ;is ".'I \ears auo in I Military win re it is still called llunjraria" Iumiiic t;r,i&lt;s. It thriven well on loose sandv soil lint on better soil larger yields may be expected. When well ( siaMislml ii is not injnred by sprinjr and fall frosts. It should !&gt;&lt;■ icnicnil'i red that this pwa is often not eaail.i eradiraied. and it is. therefore, not serially adapted for use in a short rotation. In the western part of the Stale, it is highly prized for its nd-binding ubilltv and for t 1 • i — jmrpose it is very i fit n el ved. t ::i. HmuiH* knlmii. Wild &lt;"he Fi^. !»&lt;;.i This is a ratlin- ston! i-ennial found in eentral and 1 1 i Fig. '.&gt;»;. | ■ly related hi Brotnu* knlmii It is a perennial found mil in northwestern Nebraska. Hminitx riici iikixiix. Smooth r.luine (irass. I Fig. '.IS. i A r.itlier s'emler animal introduced from Europe. Ii pr(«dn«-es iia\ of rather p 1 quality. Lancaster fVnmtr. lironttix xiraliiittx. ( "liess. I Fiji. 98.1 This is a well known introduced annual weed of grain fields and waste plaees and now found praetieally thruont Nelnaska. It was intiodined in agrienltnral seed into the various parts of the Stale. The idea i-oinnioiily enlertaineil liy many farii'irs that wheat drgf wrateii into Phew utterly wiiln.iii fonndntion in fact. Hinnnix nqiitiniMMH. \F\ff !I7. i Introduced from Rnro|ie and now reported from lto\ Imite and Howard I'oiinlies. linniiiix liilnnnii. i Fig. '.\'1.\ \ low tufted annual which is fast hrroming a eominon weed in the eastern |iarts of the Stale. It was inti-oduei&lt;! from Knrone. m (HI.ok. 10 Illlrlilnr ihlrl flluiilts. I'.uli'.ilo &lt;;i;|ss. I Fi&lt;:. ST.) This. I lie genuine lllllfnlo &lt;irass. is clainiecl to ha\&lt; I'ornierU heel much more silmndaal mi the prairies thai at the present time, h forms numerous, creeping, l.ram-h tin i rtli western Xclintfika. lii'inniix /nirliri. Wild &lt;"liess Tliis s|«'cies is very clus </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 lag stolons, siniiliii- in those found in Iteruiudn gnua, which root ;ii the nodes, ench joint thus forarfaK ■ new tuft. Tims a close nun nf tine leaven is formed which nnv fc|■( l l• considerable areas. 1 1 is unsurpassed for wintt t ■tarage Bad is roaaiderfri »m&gt; of the beat graam for shceji ]i;isiurcs. Taroooni the suie. Imt most ibandani in the western counties. C.\I,.\M K.KOMIS. ■ Cmimmmgm»tit twaaaY nail. Yellowtop. i I'ij;. 50.) A stout native prairie jjrnss of the western h;ilf of th&lt; State. It often occopien rather large areas to the exclu sion of other graam and may then yieW consiilt nihle ha\ Ktine i|ii:ility. It gruwi lust in rather low moist meadow - d hits done well unili r cultivation. 4"J. t'uhnii'it/ioxt is iiir.rjitniyi. i Fi^. ."() A rather siout ere&lt;t itraM reported from KulTalo. Pnatet anil Thomas Counties. (."!. Ciif'iiinifirostis nci/lcchi. I'on.v Crass. (Fig. Hi.) A rather slender, erect native iterennial on prairiea more common in the western i»ari of the State. CAIiAMOVIU'A. 44. Ciiltiiici ritfa longifoKa. Lwtjr-lrnved Keed Crass. I Fig. 40. '. A sto\it lon«;-|eaved grnwi forming an extensive svstei'i se'niarid regions tl f little &lt;&gt;r no forage value. Common in the Sand Hill region. &lt; \t\ijkos.\. 45. r,it&lt;ihn&gt;xit iitiinilicii. Water Class. (Fig. 70.) A rather soft and weak nquatk irrass of central am' western Xehraska. »•;. Crm-hnu tribuioide*. Sand Bur. i Fi^. S3.) A coiiimon annual weed thruout the State. If rut befor the "wwi" are formed it makes good liny. t'INNA. IT. C'nii'ii hi nii'liiKlcKi. Wood Keed Crass. I Fiji. l"..i A tall unlive perennial common in woods and « K endows -particularly in the eastern part of the State nil latifolin. &lt; Fig. 4:'.. i A perennial somewhat smaller than the preceding of l-lii/.oincs. 1 1 is iiiisui|&gt;;i&gt;sc(l ;is ;i Siuul-liiiider for t'n- CFM'HRVH. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 CVNODON. 4ft. Cytiodon dint y Ion. Itermuda GrMB. (Fig. 58.) A creeping perennial that pm readily in poor. sand.v soils where other grasses will not thrive. It is very widely cultivated in the South and should prove useful as a sand binding grass in many places. It is extensively grown as a lawn grass in the South and is propagated thru the use of pieces of the sod. DACTYLIS .-It Itiutylix yloinnvta. Orchard lirass. ( Fig. 73. &gt; A valuable perennial introduced grass often found escaped from cultivation. It is a bunch grass and makes N rapid, early growth, producing an excellent quality of ha\ . Its common name is based upon the ability of the gras* to make a good growth in shady situations. To counteract its well-known tendency to form tussocks, often consider - ably raised above the ground, it should be sown with sonic other grass, preferably awn less bronie grass or meadow fescue. It cannot be recommended for the drier soils of western Nebraska. DESCHAMPS1A. 51 I)&lt; si inn, ,f, sin flcxuosu. Wood Hair OfM*. (Fig. 5&lt;i. i A slender, erect, native perennial of little value except in woodland pastures as it grows well in shaded ground. It yields an inferior coarse forage which, when young, is eaten by stock. It shows a tendency to form tussocks. IMAKRHKN A. In moist shaded places in eastern Nebraska. DIGITAUIA. 53 Digitaria sanguinalis. Crab (irass. (Fig. 21. ) This is a well-known introduced annual often found in cultivated fields and constituting, particularly in eastern Nebraska, one of our worst lawn weeds. l&gt;uring the latter part of the season it makes a very rapid growth and ma\ take absolute possession of a lawn. It is less common in the western counties. iusTirHi.iv .-,4 Dixtichlis spivaln. Salt &lt; irass. (Fig. T.i.) Thill ill on t*i*t*i • t w i t*v «*i** i hu w i 1 1 i &gt;m ATtonui v** u v wt *&gt;i i ■ i &gt; f i mi* ib nn eie&lt;i »ir\ !_i.isn « mm an exrensi\t system oi 52. IHarrhena diandru. ( Fig. H(i. i </seg>
            <seg id="p085">.4 Hnndbtiok of Nebraska U-rnsses. m rootstorka which often (am such a compact sod as to render it a nuisance in farming lands. It is a good sand hinder, hut otherwise has no agricultural value. Tt thrives in alkali soils even when the ground is heavily crusted with alkali. Thrtionl the State. KCHHfOCHlX&gt;A. IVoMmoMm rruH-galli. Barnyard Grass. (Fig. 22. i This is a rank-growing annual weed well-known in rich. cultivated grand, particularly about dwellings. Tt is so thoroly dispersed thruout the State as sometimes to appear to be indigenous. The species presents several quite dis - tinct forms, each having its own peculiar qualities. One of these has been cultivated in several places and is valuable for green feed and silage, lnit is too coarse and succulent to make good hny. A coarse tnfteil annual generally regarded as a weed, particularly in lawns and about dwellings. Introduced from Euro|&gt;e and not common. * ELYMUS. 57. Elymm canade-nsix. Wild Rye Qram I Fig. 112. » A stout, smooth perennial which probably has some agricultural value aliho it has not been very thoroly tested. Ft is very abundant on the prairie, low flats, and along the smaller streams thruout the State. When cut early it should form a good i|— lltj of hay. tho the frequent pres- ence of "ergot" might render its use for this purpose dangerous. 58. Eh/muH condenmtux. Giant Rye Grass. (Fig. 108.) A stout tufted perennial grass of central Nebraska com- mon in wet alkali soils and along streams, the banks of which are often protected from erosion by its rootstocks. This grass should also be of service as a sand-binding grass along railroads, etc. When young it makes good hay and when allowed to stead it provides considerable winter forage on the range. LF.himus (ihiticu*. i Fig. US.) In moist soil. Central Nebraska. KI.KtSlNK. ."&gt;»■&gt;. Bletuime mdtea. &lt;;&lt;&gt;(»»&lt;• &lt;ii;iss. i Fijj. r&gt;8. i till. Eli/mug mamunii. Miii'oiiii'k Lvme (linns, i Ki&lt;;. 113.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 r,i F.iiiitntx robtmtu*. (Fife. 112 A stout leat.v |ii'ri'iiui;il in rich moist soil in reatral ami western Xehnmkii. h'lnmux xtritittis. |)eniielt &lt;Srass. I Fig. 110. i A slender lulled |ierenni;il of llie central and northern eoimties. hJlytHMM riri/iiiirtiy. LyilU' • Irass. iFlgJ. 111.1 A slout i ii i-enniiil nf Hm' ":;slcrn ;md northern counties KKACatOHTIK. An erect tutted jirass of i'rv tields in eastern Nebraska. Hiiiuraylix hiijiiioiili ". Creeping Meadow (rrass. I Fi S-J. I This &lt;rrass lias [traatrate imieli ln-aiiehed stems. Ofcan in low wet |&gt;laees. |&gt;ar) ieiilarlv alon^ sirrams in eastern Neliraska. Hriif/rnxi ix megnatmvhtfn. Stink (iiv.ss. t Fiji. s:{. i A sliowv niueli -liranelu-d annual wliieli emits, wlien fresli. a stroDK unpleasant odor. A rnnimoa weed tlirnout 1 1 i • - State. r,7 Hrttfinixtis inctiiimi'i. ('ninh Uram. i Fijr- M.I A t-atlief in-ettv weed cmnilton in dry fields except in tlie extreme westetn pai-t i)f tlie State. r,s Knif/ruxtix j/iloxn. Slender Mfttdow Crass. (FigK, 80. 82.) A slender dprnmbeut introduced irrass occasional in waste places. Lancaster and Sheridan Counlies. h'.iunnixiix trirhnilix. Rlow-oul drass. i Kijr. s:s. i This is a prctu j;rass of wtndv soils and in Mow outs v\ central and western Nclirask \ !t has &lt;ri\ en fooA results under cultivation and promises well as a hav gniM th ■ the folinee is rather wirv. KICKM-OMA. To h'ri'icDinii riix/iifhilu. Indian Millet. I Fig. 38. ) A rather •lender native iterennial lmn&lt;-h frnm which thrives in drv saudv soil, even in tvpical sa-;e-liiMish land, and is much esteemed for trrtir.ine. M'estern Nebraska. FKSTK A. 71 I'isl.icii rlliiiiu. Roagh Fescue &lt;!l"lss. I Fi};. Sit. I /•'&lt; yt IK" rfatior. Meadow Fescue. I Fig. 96.) 72 (.4. l-.'nit/nixlix ciii&gt;illnrix. [V\g. 7-&gt;. I This jmtciii! i;i I ifritfw is ;i nfltive &lt; &gt;f Kur&lt;&gt;iM\ but luis Ioiilt </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 ■ Im-ch cultivated in rarioni part* of the I'nited States and is now iliiiinl\ Mturalised. Its tlrnutli -resistance recnm iiii-imIs it fur use in Nchraskn where it can be employed as ■ pasture gram Sowing with orchard grass lias proved successful. It docs lust 011 nic.isi soils rather rich in llllllMIS. I'ls'mii ohtusu. i Fig. !mi. i A rather siout. erect, gtabrom pcicnnial in oped woods n nd thick* is of tlic nnU in count ii s. I. h'&lt; xl in-n ott( l fiiini. Slender rescue. I Fig. Sit. I An erect animal, in HUdj soil lliriioiit llie Slate An erect, tufted perennial found on prairies tliruout the State and a|i|tar&lt; nt Iv indigraoni 1 in many places. 76. Qljfrerim grmmdia. Rrrd Meadow GruM. (Fig. 76.) An erect, tall aquatic grMa i»f the Sand Hill region of central and northern Nelu-aska. 77. Glf/ceri* ncirnhi. Fowl Meadow liniM. I Fig. 7t&gt;. i An &lt;'recl aipiatic gTNMP \videl\ disl lilmted. All introduced perennial. It is not liked In stock, bnt inav lie of some value on soils where better irrasKes will not gTOV. &lt;ienerall.v considered a weed. IKIIillKI M 7'.t. Iloi &lt;l&lt; nut jiibul urn. S&lt;|uiireltail (iiass. I Fifj;. 114.1 A striking and rather picttj annnal weed found thruont the State. 80. Htnilrinii itiixiHiiin. (Fig. 114.) A slender erect perennial in dry or alkaline soils thruont the State. HVSTKIX. 81. H.ifsiii.i !&gt;&lt;&gt;lnhi. Battle P.rnsh. i 1'i.u. 1A2.) A slender tufted perennial of fertile moist soils of rant ern Nebraska. kiiki.i i:i \. 82. Kuril tin ciislnhi. I'rairie June Onw, (Fig. 7*.) An erect, perennial hunch ;;i;iss of the prairits anl o|ien meadows. For early forage it has some value and 75. Fixtiioi nriiui. Sheep's Pewnw. I Fig. 89.1 &lt;.I.V&lt; KKIA. HOM'tTS. 78. Ihihns tinnitus. Velvet &lt;irass. i l-'i;j. Tut.) </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 nuder irrigation it makes good hay tho the yield is low Common thruout the State. LEERSIA. Leersia oryzoidet. Kice Cut Crass. (Fig. 31.) A rather stont grass in wet soils thrnout the State. s:&lt; Leemia rirginua. Virginia Cut Crass, i Fig. 31.) A slender decumbent grass roawa in wet soils thru the eastern counties, but not found in tho extreme western part of the State. LOL1VM. IjOlium multifloruiii. Italian Rye Crass, i Fig. 104.) A biennial or perennial introduced plant and one of our well-known hay grasses for rich and rather moist lands, particularly in the eastern counties. It is a rapid grower and forms a good turf. It starts earlier, grows more rapidly, and has lighter green foliage and taller, coarser stems than the Perennial Rye Grass. For temporary meadows it can be recommended but is of too short dura - tion for permanent pastures. The seed is generally rather free of impurities and can ordinarily be secured on the market. Lolinm perenne. Perennial Rye (irass. (Fig. 104.) This perennial has been cultivated in England for up ward of two centuries. Like the Italian Rye Grass it prefers moist and rich loam and clay soils. In this region it cannot be considered as at all the equal of timothy for hay or other purposes. Lolium temulentum. Bearded Darnel. (Fig. 104.) An erect generally rather stout annual in waste place* ST and cultivated grounds. MELJCA. SS Sfelica nitens. Melic &lt; irass. i Fig. 71.) An erect grass found ai a very few points in eastern Nebraska. Ml HLENBKRUIA. S» Miililenbergiu meximiia. Wood Crasn. (Fig. {•.) A much-branched, spreading or ascending grass found in shaded meadows and along streams in many part* of the State. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">I Iliindbiiok of Mebruuku tJnumm. 89 1/ nhlitibcrgia pungent. Klow-out (Trass. (Pig. 47.) A tufted rigid native perennial in dry soils of the Sand !)ll. Hills and prairies of western Nebraska. Muhlenbergia racenioaa. Wild Timothy. (Fig. 49.) This is an upright, sparingly -branched perennial with 91. rootstocks covered with thick scales. It is an excellent hay grass when grown under suitable conditions. Common in wet soil thruont the State. 1/ iihlrubfrgiii sctinlirri. Nimble Will, i Fig. 49.1 A prairie grass. Cherry. Holt. Lancaster, and Valley !&gt;2. Counties. M uhlrnbergia sylratiea. (Fig. 49.1 !«. A perennial in woods and on hanks of streams. Harlan ( 'ountv. 94. Muhlenbergia tenuiflora. i Fig. 4!t. i An erect perennial in rooky woods. Webster County. MINKOA 95. Munroa squarrosn. False Buffalo Grass. (Fig. 63.) A low much-branched annual not liked bv stock. Com- mon in the Sand Hill region and often found in blow-outs. OKYZOPSIS. 96. Oryzopsix wicnnitha. Mountain Kicc. i Fig. 38.) A slender erect perennial in woods and along streams in the extreme northern and western counties. PANICUM. 97. Pmmtctm bnrbipulvinatum. (Fig. 28. t An erect grass freely branching at the base. Common in the western counties. !ts Panictim capilhnf. Old Witch (Iiass. (Fig. 28.) This is nn annual with coarse branching stems and hairy leaf sheaths. In cultivated ground it often become* a troublesome weed. For fall feed on stubble it may have some value. Common thruont the State. 99. Panicum dichotomifloruw. (Fig. 27.1 A weedy annual grass of the eastern counties. I'nnuum huachveac. (Fig. 29.1 inn In prairies. Buffalo. Cherry. Hall, and Holt Counties. I'tiniriuii leibeifiii. (Fig. 30.) 1(11 A slender perennial in dry or moist soil. Dixon and Stnnton Comities. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 l&lt; I'liiiii'ini ii:iliiii&lt;mn. Rumjiesin Millet, i Fif _' x This is i hm aching annual which km long bm &lt;-u It i vaied in Asia ;unl Kuropc iinil to a limited extent in the Inited States. When nil in Rnvn it fin-nislies a large amount of excellent green feed fur slock. I'lniii-iim jnifi oiinx. (Fig. -'■*. ' &lt;&gt;n dry prairies. Ouster and Hall Counties. I'cniiinii xri iliniriitiiiuii. (Fig. •'&gt;". I An ereel brandling |&gt;erennii!l 'Iruout ihe Stale I'tniiciiiti rii'/nt inn. Switch Gram, t Fig. 37.) A stuiil. erect. unbranched perennial found on prairies ihrinnit the State. When cut hefore ripe it jirodueeH a vei v valuable hay. I'lniiriini irilin.iitniinii. Wilcox's Panic ( irass. I Fijr. oil. I Common in Ihe Sand Hill region of central Nebraska PAHPALI.M I'uxjmhiiii ntramincmn. Beard (Iv.iss. (Fig. 22.1 A perennial frt'iii:cnl in sandy soil tliruont the State I'lMi.tias I'liiilinix nriiiiiiiiHift a. Heed Canary (irass. (Fig. 32. i A slout pi rennial of wet soil widely distributed thrnout the State, particularly in the eastern counties I'lnilinis muni i&lt; axis. Canary ''Mass, i Fig. 32.) \n erect annual glUM often found alons; streets in towns Ikixlmtte. Kiarnev. and I-am-aster Counties. i-ni.ii m. I'hli'un jiKitrnxc. Timothy. I Fig. 34.) This is the best known and most largely cultivated hay grass in the northern States where it has become thnndy naturalized. On dry soils only lighi yields can be exueoted. It is often sown wilh other wrasse-; or one of the clovers. rm: xi.mi 1 1 s. I'liriii/niilrs I'liiniuniix. I Fig. &lt;J4. 1 ( hie of the tallest of our native grasses, in ponds and alonj; streams thriiout the Slate. The stems often run along the ground for as much as 40 feet, striking root at each node. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 112 II 114 115 m; 117 UK FOA. Hun iiiiiimi. Low Rpear &lt;!rass. i Pig. 85.) A low spreading, introduced annual weed which has 1 le its appearance in eastern Nebraska. /'off foiiijH fxxu. Canada l.lue (irass. f Pig. 88.) This is a slender perennial i»f liluish -jrreen foliage often confounded with the genuine Kentucky Mine (irass from which it may be distinguished li\ iis flattened, decumbent. wiry stems, shorter leaves and shorter, narrower and smaller panicles. It it adapted to somewhat more sterile K&lt;&gt;il than Kentucky lilue grass. Iml on the whole it is scarcely to l&gt;e recoinnieiidi'd for Nebraska. Thniout til? State but not common. 1'tni ni'iiiDKilix. Spear (irass. i Fi«j. ST. i A tufted, erect, perennial grass of weslern Nebraska. I'oa i&gt;iatr&gt;isix. Kentucky llliie (irass. (Fig. BT.) This is a well-known lierennial gTMM native of jiarts of North America and now much grown as a pasture srrass. it is in fact the champion pasture &lt;rrass of the limestone region of Tennessee and Kenincky. With us it is uni - versally employed as a lawn where it makes a firm sod. It is better adapted for use in pastures than as a hay crop. However, it is a shallow-rooted plant, not at all suited to drouthv conditions. POLYPOGO.V I*oltfpogon mon*pelienni». Heard &lt;ir;iss. i Fifj. 34.) An introduced pipit in fields and waste places. Kearney Count v. PUCCINEIJJA. Puccmellia miroulea. i Fi«r. 7fi. i A tufted perennial in alkali soil. Cheyenne. Dawes. and Sioux Counties. im:di hi i&gt;i \. HnlfitUHu pemwom. Ulow-out &lt; irass. (Pig. UN. i This is a sioul perennial native to the sandy soils nf the West. Its deeply penetrating and widely spreading rootstooks render it the saad-Mnding grass par excellence. It is in fact a typical blow-out jxrass well worthy of trial where drifting sand beroaws troublesome. A common • Tass thruout tlie Sand Mill re &lt;r ion. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Itt 8CHEDONNAKDUS. Xchedonnardus panifiilatiix. Wild Crab Grans. (Pig. 59.) A low weedy grass in dry phizes thruout the State. SOOLOCHLOA. ftvoUichlou festuvuiiiu. Sprangle Top. (Fig. 74. 1 A Btout, erect perennial in wet ground or shallow water. Grant County. SETAK1A. Setaria glauiu. Yellow Foxtail. (Fig. 25.) An erect annual and. like Srtnrin ririilis. often appeal - ing in quantities as a weed in alfalfa fields where it has been introduced in alfalfa seed. A coinnion weed thruou' the State, but most abundant eastward. Srtiirid rrrticitlatn. Bristly Foxtail, i Fig. 24. i An introduced annual weed often found near dwellings. Its bristles are Itnrlied downward, and this feature enables its heads to clina; to clothing and other objects. Tn the eastern part of the State but not common. Setaria riruiis. (ireen Foxtail, i Fig. 25.1 A common weed of fields and waste places where it flow - ers somewhat earlier than the yellow foxtail from which it may further In- distinguished by its greenish bristles. It is a common annual weed found thruont the State. SITANIOX. Sitanion hystrix. Wild Rye Grass. [Fig. 103.) A low tufted perennial sjiecies of western Nebraska. resembling somewhat squirreltail grass. Ory soil in west em part of the State. SORGHASTBUM. Rorghastrum nutans. (Fig. 17.) Common on prairies thruout the State and of consider able value for hay. Tt is a stout perennial forming a large proportion of our western prairie hay. Tts long root-leave* provide forage of good quality. During dry weather it does not seed freely. It does best on the richer prairie bottoms. SPARTlSiA. Spartina grartlis. l.iitle Cord Grass, i Fig. 02.) A pretty grass of western Nebraska in saline marshes lwt of little or no value for forage. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 Spartina vtichitiu'uiun. Slough Grass. (Fig. 62.) This grass makes a rather coarse hay and must In- cut when young. It is well adapted for sand binding on ac - count of its strong, scaly rootstock. In wet places thru out the State — but most common in the southeastern counties. SPHKNOI'HOI.IS. Kphniopholix uhtusata. Early Bunch Grass. (Fig. 77.) A tufted perennial — often growing in moist soil. It is readily eaten by stock and supplies a considerable amount of forage of good quality. Common on prairies thruout the State. Kphenopholix pallens. Eaton's Grass. (Fig. 77.) On wooded bluffs thruout the State. 8POROBOMS Sporobolux nxper. (Fig. 52.) Sandv soil thruout the State. Kportibolux axpcrifoliug. Prairie Grass. (Fig. 54.) A low perennial grass of dry prairies in the western half of the State. Sporobolus brcvifolius. (Fig. 52. ) An erect, slender, tufted grans in dry soil — thruout the State. Sporobolm confunua. Prairie Grass. (Fig. 54.) An annual found only in western Nebraska. 8porobohi8 cryptandrus. Prairie Grass. (Fig. 54.) A common perennial grass of dry sandy prairies — thruout the State. Sporobolus hcterolepis. Wire Grass. (Fig. 54.) Not common, tho found occasionally in eastern and northern Nebraska. fiporobolus ncglectus. Small Rush Grass. (Fig. 52.) In dry soil. Brown County. Rporobolm raginiflorus. Southern Poverty Grass. (Fig. 52.) An annual grass of roadsides and waste places in east - ern Nebraska. STEPA. Stipn c'linatii. Needle Grass. I Fig. 40.) A well known grass of the High Plains of western Ne braska. It is often very troublesome to sheep and other </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 titipa spurt ca. l'urcnpiue Grass. (Fig. 46.) This nmmMm the jirecediDg species, but is stouter and like it is a great pest to sheep. It is most abundant in the eastern Nebraska prairies. Mipa riridiria. Feather Bunch Grass. (Fig. 46.) Occurs thruoiit the State — particularly in western coun- ties. TRIPLAS1S. Triplanis purpiirru. Sand Grass. (Fig. (57.) A low annual grass of the Sand Hill ravines of north western Nebraska. TR1PSACUM. Tripsacum ductyloidcx. (iaina Grass. (Fig. 13.) A stout, coarse, perennial of moist soil iu southeaMern Nebraska. When young it is much liked by stock. ZIZANIA. Zizania aquatica. Indian Rice. (Fig. 31.) An annual (raa groviag in ponds and along streams thruout the State. The nutritions grain is often eaten by </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 ' BIBLIOGRAPHY OF AGROSTOLOGY. rICATIONS OF THE UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRI CULTURE AND STATE EXPERIMENT STATIONS. ANON. 1895. Grasses as Sand and Soil Binders; Alphabetical List. Teak T*. B. Dept. Agr. 1894: 580. 1897. Miscellaneous Notes and Descriptions of New Specie* of Grasses. Bnl. T&gt;iv. Agrostology U. B. Dept. Apr. 4:36 - 39. 1899. Recent Additions to Systematic Agrostology. Pirc. Div. Agrostology T*. S. Dept. Agr. 15:1-10. 1902. Grasses anfo Forage Plants fov the Year 1901. Yearb. U. S. Dept. Agr. 1901:672-673. 1903. ITav. Pastures, and Forage Props. Yearb. T\ S. Dept. Agr. 1902 : 721-722. 1913. Grass Demonstrations in the South, fire. Bur. PI. Ind. T. S. Dept. Agr. 110 : 3-5. Bai i.. P. R. 1900. Grasses and Fodder Plants on the Potomac Flats Tire. Div. Agrostology T\ S. Dept. Agr. 28:1 18. 1902. Johnson Grass: Report of Investigations Made Dur - ing the Season of 1901. Bill. Bur. PI. Tnd. U. S. Dept. Ajrr. 11:1-24. Fig. 1. 1902. Winter Forage CrOM for the South. Farmers' Bui. F. S. Dept. Act. 147: 1 36. Figs. 1 24. 1903. Pearl Millet. Farmers" Bal. V. S Dept Atrr. 168:1 16. Figs. 1-3. 1914. The Grain Sorghums: ImniiffrHni Prop* That TTav Made Good. Yearb. V. S. Dept. \sr. 1913:221-238. P's 29-35. Figs. 1-12. Beal. W .T. 1886. Makinsr a Lawn — Mixed Lawn Grasses Analyzed. Bnl. Mich. Exp. Sta. 11:1 10. 1886. Rei&gt;l'"s to Questions About Grasses. Bill. Mich. Exp. Sta. 16:17. 1891. Pomparing the Yield of Old Meadows with Those Re cently Seeded. Bnl. Mir*. Exp. Sta. 77:1-6. Bbnn»tt, B. L. 1900. Permanent .Meadow ;m«l Pasture PfalBt* Kernmdn and Orchard Gi'ass. l»nl. Ark. Fxp. Sta. 61:1216. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 1898. A Report Upoa t lie QfMMa and Forage Plants of Central Texas. Bui. l»iv. Agrostology V. P. Dept. Agr 10:1-38. Figs. 1-14. 1898. Cattle Ranges of the Southwest ; History of the E\ hnustion of the Putlliy and Suggestions for Tts Restora tion. Farmers' Bui. U. B. Dept. Agr. 72:132. Figs. 1-9 1899. Progress of Experiments in Forage Crops and Range Improvement at Abilene. Tex. Circ. Div. Agrostology U. R. Dept. Agr. 23: 1 20. Fig. 1. 1902. Experiments in Range Improvement in Central Ti-xas. Bui. Bur. PI. Ind. T T . B. Dept. Agr. 13:172. Pis. 12. Figs. 1-6. Bi-ffi-m. B. C. 1893. Grasses and Fornge Plant*. Bui Wvo. Ex]. Stn. 16 : 223-248. Cabsidy, .1., and O'Brink, D. 1890. Sonic Colorado Oraimen nnd Tlieir Cheniieal Analysis. Bui. Colo. Exp. Sta. 12: 1-151. Illust. Ckik. O. F. 1908. Change of Vegetation on the South Texas Prairies. Cire. Bur. PI. Tnd. V. B. Dept. Apr. 14:1-7. Cotton. .T. S. 1905. RtMt M:ui:i&lt;:&lt;'ii&gt;('iii in the State of Washington. [&lt;ul Bur. PI. Ind. U. 8. Dept. Agr. 75: 1-28. Pis. 13. 1910. Improvement of Pastures in Eastern New York nn&lt;] the New England States. Tin-. Bur. PI. Ind. V S n.pt. Agr. 49:1-10. Pis. 12. 1894. Millet. Bui. Mlcfc. Exp. Bta. 117:164. Illust Davt. J. B. 1902. Stork Ranges of Northwestern California: Notes on the Orasses and Foraav Plants and Baaajr Conditions Bui. Bur. PI Iit.l. P. S T»&lt;pt. Agr. 12:1-81. Pis. 18. Figs. 1-4. DlLLMAN. A. C. 1913. Orasses for Canal Hanks in Western South Dakota. Cire. Bur. PI. Tnd. P. S. Dept. hgr. 115:23 31. Fies. 1 2. fl VKMAN. H. 1900. Kentn.ky Foraar Plants The brasses. Bui. Ky ?&gt;p. Sta. 87:' 55-1 22. II!' CltoZIKR. A. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 Garman, H. 1902. Kentucky Forage Plants— The Clovers and Their Allies. Notes on True Grasses in the Plots in 1900-1901. Analvses of Forage Plants from the Plots. Bill. Ky. Exp. Sta. 98:1-61. Tllnst. 1001. Range Improvement in Arizona (Cooperative Experi - ments with the Arizona Experiment Station). Bui. Bur. PI. Ind. T\ B. Dept. Agr. 4: 1-31. Pis. 1-6. Figs. 1-5. 1902. Forage Conditions on the Northern Border of th» Qicat Basin. Being a Report Upon Investigations Made During July and August. 1901. in the Region Between Winnenmeca. Nevada, and Ontario. Oregon. Bui. Bur. PI. Ind. V. 8. Dept. Agr. 15: 1 60. Pis. 1-6. 1903. Forage Conditions and Problems in Eastern Wash ington. Eastern Oregon. Northeastern California, and Northwestern Nevada. Ral. Bur. PI. Ind. U. S. Dept. Art. 38 : 1-52. Pis. 1-9. 1904. Range Investigations in Arizona. Bui. Bur. PI. Ind. T. ft Dept. Agr. 67: 1 62. Pis. 1-10. 1912. The Crrama Grasses; Boutelmm and Related Genera Contrib. U. R. Nat. Herb. 14 : 343-428. Pis. 67-83. Figs 19-63. Haf.lioan. C. P. 1913. Starting a Lawn. Circ. Mich. Exp. Sta. 20:139-142 Illust. Harris. F. S. 1913. Pastures and Pasture Grasses for T'tah. Circ. Ftah Exp. Sta. 15:35-41. Tllust. Hkxdkrson. L. F. 1903. Grasses and Forasre Plants in Idaho. Bui. Idaho Exp. Sta. 38 : 193 256. Hii.i.max, F. H. 1896. Field Notes on Some Nevada Grasses. Bill. Nevada Exp. Sta. 33:1-13. Hitchcock, A. S. 1901. Bermuda Grass. Circ. Div. Agrostology T T . S. Dept Agr. 31 : 1-6. Figs. 1-2. 1903. North American Si&gt;ecies of Leptochloa. Bui. Bur. PI. Ind. IT. S. Dept. Agr. 33 : 1-24. Pis. 1-6. 1904. Methods T T sed for Controlling and Reclaiming Sand Dunes. Bui. Bur. PI. Tnd. U. S. Dept. Agr. 57: 1 36. Pis. 19 &lt;iKIFFITHi». D. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 r 1905. Xortli American Species of Agrottit. Bui. Hur. PI fnd. U. S. Dept. Agr. 68:1-68. Pis. 1 37. 1910. The Xortli American S|mm ics of Putucnm. Contrih r. s. Nat Hctfc. 15: 1-396. Fi«rs. 1-307. Hitchcock, A S.. and Cloth in. &lt;;. T.. 189°. Xative Agricultural Oranea of Kaama. Bnl. Kam Rxp. Sta. 87:1-29. Bitchcock, A. S.. ami WnrrcA-n, J. M. 1901. Forage Plant* for Kansas. Bnl. Kmuk Exp. st i 102:170 220. Illust. II" M. T. 1897. Simic Ameriran Panicums in tin- Herbarium Herolin cnsi' ami in the Herbarium of Wl lldenow. P.nl. Div. kgMU tolofrv T. s. l&gt;fpt. Ajrr. 4:17-23. Fi&lt;_'s. 7-15. Jones, L. R. 1902. Vermoat Graaan and ('lovers. Bui. Vt. Exp Mk 94:1 37-1 S4. Fi?s. 1-32. Kkakn-rt. T. TT. 1895. Xntrs on firaaaej ami Fora^w 1'lants of tke Smiih eastei-n Rtatw. Bnl. l&gt;iv. AgroKtotog? I". S. Dopt. Airr 1:1-28. Fijrs. 1-7. 1898. A BerWoa of the North Aiueriraa Sjiecies of Ctilmmm (fmstix. Bui. !&gt;iv. Airrosioloey T". S. l»ept. A'jr. 11:142 ng. l. Kk\nfpy. P. 1!. 1899. Smooth Bionie (Irass. fire l»iv. AfTOotolopv I". S l&gt;ept. Art. 18: 1-9. Fi-xs. 1-2. 1899. Experiment* with Forage Plnntn in Ontario, ("in- Div. AKTOstoloK.v I". S. Dept. Agr. 20: 1 3. 1900. The Structure of the Carvopsis of Gramei with Refer enco to their Morphology ami '"lassification. Rerined RdH Bui. l&gt;iv. Acrostolotn • T". S. Dent. Agr. 19:1-44. !'ls. If. 1900. Cooperative Experiment* with ftraaaea ai&gt;d Foratx Plants. 15ul. Div. Agro*tolog&gt; !'. S. !&gt;e].t. \&gt;rv. 22186 Pis. 113. Fiir. 1. 1103. Summer Range* of Eaatem Verndu Rheen Bnl. Xev Exp. Bta. 55:1 r,6. Pis. 1 31 Kianhi.v. 1'. P.. and Doti.n. S. IS. 1001. A Preliminary Report m the Suiiiinei- KjtuajH ■ ■' Westei-n Xi'\ac!:i Pheep. I!m! \e\ P5xji Sl.i 51 ■ 1H" Hitchcock, A. S. Bitchcock, A. S.. ami ('mask. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p099">I Handbook &lt;&gt;) A rliriixkn &lt;lnixs(.s. 99 Keyser. A. 1913. Variation Studies in Brome Grass (A Preliminary Report). Bnl. Colo. Exp. Sta. 190:1-20. Pis. 1-19. KlI.LKBKEW, -I. I 1898. Gnum and Forage Plants. Hul. Tenn. Bxp. Sta. 11:1-141. Knapp. P. A. 1910. Suu.&lt;i&lt; stions for Setting Permanent Pastures with Brrmada Oraw as the Basis. Rnr. PI. Tnd. V. S. Dept. Agr. 4 pp. Knight, H. &lt;i.. Hkpner, F. K.. and N'ki.son, A. 1906. Wyoming Forage Plants and Their Chemical Com position. Studies No. 1. Bal. Wyo. Exp. Sta. 65: 1-52. 1906. Wyoming Porage 1'lants and Their Chemical Coin position. Studies No. 2. Bnl. Wyo. Exp. Sta. 70:1-76. Fi&lt;is. 1-31. I90R. Wyoming Porage Plants and Their Chemical Com position. Studies No. :S. Bnl. Wyo. Exp. Sta. 76:1-120. Fie*. 1 50. 1011. Wroming Forage Plants and Their Chemical Com - position. Studies No. 4. Bui. Wyo. Exp. Sta. 87:1-152. Figs. 1 44. Lvov. T. L. 1899. Rnngariaa Urome Grass. Bnl. Nebr. Exp. Sta 11:35-63. Ltoh, T. Lm and Hitchcock, A. S 190-1. Pasture. Afeadow. and Forage Crops. Bui. Xel&gt;r. Exp Sta. 84: 1-66. 1004. Pasture, Meadow, and Forage Crops in Nebraska. Bui. Bur. PI. Tnd. T\ S. Dept. Agr. 59: 1-61. Pis. 1-6. 1890. The Best Agricultural Grasses. Bnl. N. C Exp. Sta 73- 1-100. Tllust. McCarthy. G.. and Emery, F. E Mei.i-, P. H. 1886. Wild Grasses of Alabama. 85 pp. 25 pis 1889. Grasses of Alabama and Their Cultivation. Bnl. AIm Exp. Sta. 6 : 35 pp. 25 pis. M&lt;&lt;'.\i:tiiy. &lt;i. 1896. Forage C.rassps and Ha v Making. Bnl. N. (3. Exp Sta. 125:37-87. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 Merrill, E. D. 1901. Some Arizona Grasses. Otic Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 32 : 1-10. 1901. Ai-istida purpureu Nutt., and Its Allies. Oirc. Div. Agrostology V. S. Dept. Agr. 34:1-8. 1901. Some Species of Grasses Published by S. B. Buckley. Hire. Div. Agrostology U. S. Dept. Agr. 36: 1-2. 1901. Some Changes in Nomenclature. Circ. Div. Agroe tology V. S. Dept. Agr. 35 : 5-6. 1902. The North American Species of Spartina. Bui. Bur. PI. Tnd. U. S. Dept. Agr. 9 : 1-16. Miller, M. F., and Hitchinson. C. B. 1913. Grass Investigations in the Ozark Upland. Bui. Mo. Exp. Sta. 108 : 89-138. Illust. 1888. Report of an Investigation of the Grasses of the Arid Districts of New Mexico. Arizona, Nevada, and Utah. Bnl. Div. Botany T*. S. Dept. Agr. 6: 1-61. Pis. 1-30. Nelson, A. 1898. The Red Desert of Wyoming and Its Forage Re - sources. Bnl. Div. Agrostology t T . S. Dept. Agr. 13: ;-72. Pis. 1-5. Figs. 1-24. 1899. Some Native Forage Plants for Alkali Soils. Bnl. Wyo. Exp. Sta. 42 : 23-45. 1901. The Brome Grasses of Wyoming. Bui. Wyo. Exp. Sta. 46:1-21. Illust. Nelson, A., and Nelson, E. E. 1903. The Wheat Grasses of Wyoming. Bui. Wyo. Exp 1913. Some New Grasses for the South. Yearb. U. S. Dept Agr. 1912 : 495-504. Pis. 65-70. Oqhh, E. L. 1897. Leaf Structure of Jouvea and of Eragrostis obtuti - ftora. Bnl. Div. Agrostology T*. S. Dept. Agr. 8:12-20. Pis. 8-9. Pa m mel, L. H. 1897. Notes on the Grasses and Forage Plants of Iowa, Nebraska, and Colorado. Bnl. Div. Agrostology T*. S. Dept. Agr. 9: 1 47. Figs. 1-12. 1905. Quack and Wheat Grasses. Bui. la. Exp. Sta. 83: 397 Nbaly, G. C, and Tracy, S. M. ISta. 59:134. Pis. 1-5. ley. R. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 Pammil, L. H. 1905. Soil Binding Grasses. Bui. la. Exp. Sta. 83: 417421. Figs. 8-9. Pammel, L. H.. Ball, C. R., and Scribner, F. L. 1904. The Glasses of Iowa. Part II. Supplementary Rpt. Ta. Geological Survey 1903. XIII, 436 pp., 270 fig*. I'vmmki.. I.. H.. Weems, J. B.. and Scribner, F. L. 1901. Grasses of Iowa. Part T. Bui. la, Exp. Sta. 64:71 .544. Figs. 1-137. 1901. Pastures and Meadows of Towa. Bui. la. Exp. Sta. 66:385-592. Figs. 138-220. 1901. The Grasses of Towa. Bui. la. Geological Survey 1:525 pp., 220 flgs. (A Reprint of Buls. la. Exp. Sta. 54 and 56.) I'llTH. G V. 1905. Grass Lands of the South Alaska Coast. Bui. Bur PI. Ind. TJ. S. Dept. Agr. 82:1-38. Pis. 1-4. 190fi. North American S]&gt;ecies of Fextucn. Oontrib. F. 8. Nat. Herb. 10 : 1-48. Pis. 1-15. 1913. Sudan Grass, a New Drouth-resistant Hay Plant. Oiro. Bur. PI. Ind. F. S. Dept. Agr. 126: 1 20. Figs. 1-6. Pittuck, B. C. 1898. Grasses and Forage Plants. Bui. Tex. Exp. Sta. 46:1011-1030. Rydrerg, P. A. 1895. Flora of the Sand Hills of Nebraska. fontrib. V. S. Nat. Herb. 3: 133-203. Pis. 1-2. Rydberg. P. A., and Shear, C. L. 1897. A Report upon the Grasses and Forage Plants of the Rorkv Mountain Region. Bui. Div. Agrostology F. S. Dept! Agr. 6 : 1-48. Figs. 1-29. S\\ii-m».v. A. W. 1913. The Reseeding of Depleted Grazing Lands to fulti vated Forage Plants. Bui. T T . 8. Dept. Agr. 4:1-34. Pis 1-8. Figs. 1-4. 1913. Range Improvement by Deferred and Rotation Grar. ing. Bui. IT. S. Dept. Agr. 34: 1 16. Pis. 15. SCRIKNRR, F. L. 1889. Grasses ou Mountain Meadows and Deer Parks. Bui Tenn. Exp. 8ta. 2* : 59-67. 1894. Hungarian Brome Grass. Ciro. Div. Botany TJ. B, Dept. Agr. 1:1-4. Fig. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 1895. Grasses ;is Sam) ;ind Soil Minders, ieaifc. V. S Dept Agr. 1894:421 436. Figs. 100 110. 189fi. Qnuf of the Salt Marafcea. Ycaifc. r. s. Dept Apr 1895 : 325-332. Figs. 75-79. 1806. 1'seful iind Ornamental Grasses. Mill. Div. Agros tology T T . 8. Dept. Agr. 3: 1-110. Figs. 1-80. ET.ist of Crnsscs Collected by E. I'iilnier in the Vicinity Aciijmlco. Mexico. 1894-5. liul. Div. Agnatotot? \ . i, lit. Alt. 4:7-11. Figs. 1-4. K American Graam. Mul. T&gt;iv. Agrostolonv T". S. Dept r. 7:1-831. Figs. 1-302. \e\v or Little Known Oraaaea. Mill. l&gt;iv. Agrostologx V. S. Dopt. Agr. 8:5 11. Fig. 1. 1897. Chaetochlna Srribn.. noni. now Mul. Div. Agros - tology T. S. Dept Agr. 4: 38-39. 1897. The &lt;!(&gt;nns Tmopkorus. Mnl. I»i\. Attrostolouv II. B. Doi)t. Agr. 4:5-7. Pis. 1-2. RJ'axpaittiit scnhniiii Bcribn., s|). nov. Mnl. Div. Agro&gt; logy U. B. Dept Agr. 4:36. 1898. Division of Agrostology. Yciirli. V. S Kept. Ai;r 1897:160-175. PL 1. 1898. American ftraaara I. Revised Edit. Mnl. Div. A&lt;rros tology U. S. Dept. Agr. 7: 1-331. Figs. 1-302. 1898. Lawns and l.awn Making. Yearb. V. B. Dept. Apr. 1897-355-372. Pis. 8-14. 1898. Eoononiir Grasses. Mul. Div. Agrostologv I*. B. De|it Agr. 14:1-85. Figs. 1-91. 1898. Description of New or T.ittle-Known (brasses. Bill Div. Airrostology T7. 8. Dept. Agr. 11:42 58. Pis. 1-17 Figs. 1-12. 1899. Southern Forage Plants. Fanners' Bui. T T . S. Dept Agr. 102:148. Figs. 114. 1899. New Species of North American Grasses Circ. Div Agrostology T T . P. Dept. Agr. 16: 16. Figs. 1-2. 1899. Cooperative Range Grnn nnd Forage Plant Bzoeri Hunts at Hisrhmore. S. Dak. circ. Div. Agrostolojrv T". S Dept. Agr. 21:1-10. 1899. Grass and Forage Plant Investigations on the PacHh Coast. Cire. Div. Agrostolocry V, B. Dept. Agr 22:1-7. S.RIBNKH, P. K K Crass Harden*. Yearb. T. S. T&gt;c|.t. A»t. 1895:301 . Fijis. 68-69. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 1899. Sand ISi nd ing Crasses. Yearli. V. S. Dept. Agr. 1898:405 42(1. I' Is. 28 30. Figs. 110-120. 1899. American Crasses II. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. S. Dept. Agr. 17:1-340. Figs. 303-627. 1899. Mew Species of North American Crasses. ("ire. Div. Agrostology T". S. Dept. Agr. 9:1-7. 1900. Economic Onm, Revised Edit. Bui. l&gt;iv. Agros tology I'. S. Dept Agr. 14:1-85. Figs. 1-91. 1900. Ptognm i'\ Economic and Scientific Agrostology. Yearl.. P. S. Dept Agr. 1899 : 347 -366. Figs. 5-9. 1900. American GlMKi i. liul. Div. Agrostology (T. S. Dept. Agr. Edit, a 7:1-31!). Pigs. 1-302. 1900. New or Litlle-Known Mexican Classes. Ciic. Div. Agrostology V. S. Dept Agr. 19: 14. Fig. 1. 1900. .Miscellaneous Notes and Descriptions of New Specie*. Bui. l&gt;iv. Am-ostologv r. S. Dept. Agr. 24:39-50. Figs. 1-10. 1900. American (ii asses ill. Hul l»iv. Agi-ostologv U. 8. Pept. Agr. 20: 1 11)7. Figs. 1-137. 1901. Classes in Elliott's "Sketch of the Botany of Smith Carolina and Georgia." Circ. Div. Agrostology I". S. Dept. Agr. 29:1-12. Figs. 1-4. 1901. Range Gnu and Forage Plant Experiments at High more. S. Dak.; Report of Progress, circ Div. Agrostologx F. B. Dept Agr. 33:1 5. 1901. List of the I'uhlications of I he Division of Agros - tology. Circ. Div. Agrostology C. S. Dept. Agr. 36:1-8. 1901. American Grasses IL Revised Edit. BvJ. Dtr. Agrot tology U. S. Dept. Agr. 17: 1-8*9. Figs. :!(i::-(iL'7. 1901. New or Little-Known Grasses. Circ. Div. Agrostolog\ U. S. Dept. Agr. 30 : 1-8. 1901. Our Native 1'astnre Plants. Yearb. I". S. Dept. Agr 1900:581-598. Pis. 76-79. Figs. 7". &gt;;,. 1902. Records of Seed Distribution and Cooperative Ex]&gt;eri nients with Cirass(*s and Forage Plants. Bui. Rnr. PI. Ind I'. S. Dept. Agr. 10:1-23. Kcribneb, F. L., aud Hall. C. K. 1900. Studies on American Classes. Miscellaneous Notes and Descriptions of New Species I till . Div. Agrostology SCBIBNEE, F. L </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 Scribner, F. L., and Merrill, E. D. 1900. Studies on American Grasses. The North American Species of Chaetochloa. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 21:1-44. Figs. 1-24. 1900. Studies on American Grasses. Some Recent Col - lections of Mexican Grasses. Bui. Div. Agrostology 0. A Dept. Agr. 24 : 5-30. Figs. 1-7. 1900. Notes on Panicum nit id urn Lam., Panicum scoparium Lam., and Panicum pubescens Lam. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 24: 31-38. Figs. 8-13. Scribner, F. L., and Smith, J. G. 1897. Some Mexican Grasses Collected by E. W. Nelson in Mexico. 1894-95. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr 4:11-16. Figs. 5 6. 1897. Native and Introduced Species of the Genera Hot - ilium and Agropyro-n. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. S. Dept Agr. 4:23-36. 1897. Ichanthus lanceolatus Scribn. and Smith, sp. now Bui. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Div. Dept. Agr. 4:36-37. PI. 5. 1897. Elymus robust us Scribn. and Smith, sp. nov. Bui. Div. Agrostology V. S. Dept. Agr. 4:37. 1897. Elymus intermedius Scribn. and Smith. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 4:38. Sbwall, J. A. 1892. Grass and Forage Experiment Station at Garden City, Kans. Rpt. U. S. Sec. Agr. 1891 : 342 344. Shear, C. L. 1900. Studies on American Grasses. A Revision of the North American Species of Bromus Occurring North of Mexico. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 23 ■ 1-66. Figs. 1-40. 1900. Rescue Grass. Circ. Div. Agrostology T\ S. Dept. Agr. 26 : 1-4. Fig. 1. 1901. Field Work of the Division of Agrostology : A Review and Summary of the Work Done Since the Organization of the Division, July 1, 1875. Bui. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 25 : 1-67. Pis. 1 28. Shepard. J. H., Saundkrs, D. A., and Knox, W. H. 1901. Native and Introduced Forage Plants. Bnl. S. Hiik. Exp. Sta. 69: 1-54. Figs. 1-10. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 Smith, J. G. 1895. A Note on Experimental Grass Gardens. Cire Div. Agrostology l T . S. Dept. Agr. 1:1-4. 1896. Forage Conditions of the Prairie Region. Yeark T'. R. Dept. Agr. 1895 : 309-324. Figs. 70 74. 18!)7. Meadows and Pastures: Formation and Cultivation in the Middle Eastern States. Farmers' Bui. U. S. Dept Agr. 66:1-24. Figs. 1-9. 1898. Experiments in Range Improvement. Circ. Div. Agrostology V. S. Dept. Agr. 8 : 1-5. Fig. 1. 1899. Grazing Problem* in the Southwest, and How to Meet Them. Bui. Div. Agrostology D. S. Dept. Agr. 16:1 - 47. Figs. 1-9. 1899. Forage Plants for Cultivation on Alkali Soils. Yearb. P. S. Deft. Agr. 1898 : 535-550. Figs. 125-128. 1899. Meadows ;\nd Pastures: Formation and Cultivation in the Middle Eastern States. Edit. 2. Farmers' Bnl. C. S. DqK. Agr. 66:128. Figs. 1-9. 1899. Studies on American Grasses. A Synopsis of the Genus ftitaninn. Kill. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 18:1-21. Pis. 1-4. Smyth, E. A. 1897. Grasses. Bui. Va. Exp. Sta. 81:101-114. Spii.i.man, W. J. 1900. Forage Plants in Washington. Bui. Wash Exp. Sta. 41:1-60. Sprago, F. A. 1902. Forage Conditions of Central Montana. Bui. Mont Exp. Sta. 36:1-40. Figs. 123. Tracy. S. M. 1892. Cooperative P.raneh Stations in the South. Bpt. U. 8. See. Agr. 1891 : 344-351. 1894. Forage Plants for the South. Farmers' Bui. U. 8. Dept. Agr. 18: 1-30. Figs. 1-17. 1898. A Report upon the Forage Plants and Forage Re - sources of the (iulf States. Bnl. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 15: 1 -55. Figs. 1-20. 1900. Agrostological Notes, circ. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 27 : 1-10. 1901. Notes on Calamovilfa. Circ. Div. Agrostology D. 8. Dept. Agr. 35 : 2 3. 1901. Three New Species of Panicum. Circ. Div. Agros tologvF. S. Dept. Agr. 38:3-4. </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 Tracy, 8. M. 1901. A New Specie! of Poa. Oire. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 35:4-5. Troop, J. 1889. Grasses of Indiana. Bui. Ind. Exp. Sta. 29:1-42. II lust. Vasey, G 1883. Grasses of the United States; Being a Synopsis of the Tribes and Genera, with Descriptions of the Genera, and a List of the Species. Special Rpt. IT. S. Dept. Agr. 63 : 1 47. 1884. Agricultural Grasses of the United States. Special Rpt. U. S. Dept. Apr. 32. 1885. Grasses Needed for Agriculture in the United States, and the Necessity for Experiment Stations. Misc. Special Rpt. U. S. Dept. Agr. 9 : 168-173. 1886. Report of an Investigation of the Grasses of the Arid Districts of Kansas. Nebraska, and Colorado. Bui. Div. Bot. U. S. Dept. Agr. 1: 1 lit. Pis. 1-13. 1887. Grasses of the South: A Report on Certain GraaaeB and Forage I'lants for Cultivation in the South and South west. Bui. Div. Bot. U. S. Dept. Agr. 3: 1-63. Pis. 1 16. 1889. Agricultural Grasses and Forage Plants of the TJnited States, and such Foreign Kinds as Have Been Introduced, With an Appendix on the Chemical Composition of Grasses by Clifford Richardson and a Glossary of Terms Used in Describing Grasses. Revised Edit. Special Rpt. U. S. Dept Agr. 32: 1-148. Pis. 1-114. 1890. Grasses of the Southwest. P.ul. Div. Bot. U. S. Dept. Agr. 12 1 : 50 pis. 1891. Grasses of the Southwest. Bui. Div. Bot. U. S. Dept. Agr. 12= : 50 pis. 1892. Grasses of the Pacific Slope. Bui. Div. Bot. U. 8. Dept. Agr. 13 l : 50 pis. 1892. Monograph of the Grasses of the United States and British Columbia. Contrib. U. S. Nat. Herb. 3:1-89. 1893. Grasses of the Pacific Slope. Bui. Div. Bot. U. 8. Dept. Agr. 13- : pis. 51-100. 1893. Descriptions of New or Noteworthy Grasses from the United States. Contrib. U. S. Nat. Herb. 1:267-280. 1893. Descriptions of New Grasses front Mexico. Oontrib. H. S. Nat. Herb. 1:281-285. 1893. Notes on Some Pacific Coast Grasses. Contrib. 1*. S </seg>
            <seg id="p107">A Handbook of Nebraska Oragaen. 107 Vinall, H. N., and Ball, C. R. 1913. Feterita. a New Variety of Sorghum. Circ. Bur. PL Ind. F. P. Dept. Agr. 122:25-32. tTHOus, F. L.. Griffin. H. H.. and Payne, J. E. 1901. Bromii* hirrmi*. Bui. Colo. Exp. Sta. 61 : 1-10. Westgate. J. M. 1904. Reclamation of Omm Cod Sand Dunes. Bui. Bur. PI. Ind. U. S. Dept. Agr. 66: 1-38. PIb. 1-6. Williams, C. G. 1911. The Farm Grasses of Ohio. Bui. Ohio Exp. St;i 225:151-174. Tlhist. Williams, T. A. 1895. Forage Plants. Mill. S. Dak. Exp. Sta. 45: 1-19 1896. The Renewing of Worn-Out Native Prairie Pasture*. Circ. Div. Agrostology U. 8. Dept. Agr. 4:14. Figs. 1-4. 1897. The Renewing of Worn Out Native Prairie Pastures. Revised Edit. fire. Div. Agrostology U. S. Dept. Agr. 4:1-4. Figs. 1-4. 1897. Timothy in the Prairie Region. Yearn. I T . S. Dept. Agr. 1896: 147-154. Figs. 29-30. 1897. Grasses and Forage Plants of the Dakota*. Bui. Div. Agrostology T T . S. Dept. Agr. 6:147. Figs. 1-11. 1898. A Report upon the Grasses and Forage Plants and Forage Conditions of the Eastern Rocky Mountain Region. Bui. Div. Agrostology l T . S. Dept. Agr. 12: 1-78. Figs. 1-30. 1899. Sorghum as a Forage Crop. Farmers' Bui. TT. S Dept. Agr. 50 : 1-19. 1899. Millets. Yearb. U. S. Dept. Agr. 1898: 265-290. 1899. Millets. Farmers' Bui. T\ S. Dept. Agr. 101: 1-28. 1899. Poa fendleriana and Tts Allies. Circ. Div. Agrtw tology U. S. Dept. Agr. 10: 1-6. Fig. 1. 1900. Succulent Foratre for the Farm and Dairv. Yearh. U. S. Dept. Airr. 1899:613-626. 2 pis. Wir.LiAMS. T. A., and Siiepard, J. H. 1894. Native and Introduced Forage Plants. Bui. S. Dak Exp. Sta. 40: 1-208. Pis. 1 58. N. E., Dinsmobe, S. C, and Kennedy, P. B. 1906. Native Forage Plants and Their Chemical Oomposi tion. Bui. New Exp. Sta. 62: 1 41. Figs. 1-22. Wooton, E. O. 1896. Some New Mexico Forasje Plants. Bui. N. Mex. Exp Sta. 18:57-95. </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 Wooton, E. O., and Standley, I'. ('. 1912. The Grasses and Grass-like Plants of N. Mex. Bui. N. Mex. Exp. Bta. 81: 1176. lllust. REPORTS OF THE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTURE (1885-1900.) Hates. ,T. M. 1892. The Grasses of Northwestern Nebraska. Rpt. Nekr St. Bd. Agr. 1891:130134. Bessey, C. E, 1886. Grasses. Rpt. Xebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1886:84-91 1887. The Grasses and Forage Plants of Nebraska. Rpt Neln-. St. Bd. Agr. 1886: 204 237. Pis. 1 10. 1888. The Grasses and Forage Plants of Nebraska. Rpt Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1887: 140 152. Pis. 1-20. 1889. Annual Report of the Botanist Upon the Grasses and Forage Plants of Nebraska. Rpt. Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1888:131-142. 1890. The Grasses and Forage Plants of Nebraska. Rpt Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1889:144-173. 1 pi. 1891. A Dozen Grasses and Clovers for Nebraska. Rpt Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1890 : 100-108. 1892. A Preliminary List of the Grasses of Nebraska. Rpt. Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1891 : 124 130. 1892. Some Grasses of Boxbutte and Scotts Bluff Counties. Rpt. Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1891:134. 1892. Some Grasses of Southwestern Nebraska. Rpt. Nebr St. Bd. Agr. 1891 : 134 137. 1893. A Preliminary Description of the Native and Intro duced Grasses of Nebraska. Rpt. Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1892:209 279. Figs. 6-27. 1895. Grasses at the State Fair. Rpt. Nebr. St. Bd. Agr. 1894:107-110. 1896. Grasses at the State Fair. Rpt. Xebr. St. Bd. Ap\ 1895 : 223 224. 1897. Grasses at the State Fair. Rpt. Xebr. St. Bd. Agr 1896:79. 1897. Grasses and Other Forage Plants. Rpt. Nebr. St. Bd Agr. 1896 : 80-93. 1898. Grasses at the State Fair. Rpt. Nebr. St. Bd. Agr 1897:107-109. 1898. The Forage Problem in Eastern Xeln-aska. Rpt. Nebr St. Bd. Agr. 1897:111-115. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 Bessky. C. K 1898. The Forage Problem on the High Plains. Rpt. Nebr. St. lid. Agr. 1897:117-120. 1001. Some Agricultural Possibilities of Western Nebraska. Bpt. Mckr. St. M.I. Apr. 1900:75-116. Cl.KMEXTS. F. E. 1894. The GrMM of Northeastern Nebraska. Rpt. Nebr. St. P.d. Agr. 1893 : 66-69. I'ammel. I.. H. 1808. The Forage Problem in Nebraska. Rpt. Nebr. Sr. ltd. Agr. 1897:120 122. Reprint from Mul. Div. Agro* tology V. S. ])e|)t. Agr. 9: 10-11. Kyi.bebg. P. A. 1804. The Classes of Central Nebraska. Rpt. Nehr. St. Md Agr. 1893:60-73. 1893. The Classes of the Sand Hills of Northern Nebraska. Bpt. Nebr. St. ML Agr. 1892 280 291. 1808. Selected Popular Descriptions of Forage Plants Rpt. Nebr. St. ISd. Agr. 1897:132140. 1898. The Forage Question in the Prairie States. Rpt. Nebr. St. P.d. A»r. 1897: 122128. Reprint from Yearh. T\ S. Dept. Agr. 1895:300-324. WKr.r.FR. II. -I. 1800. A Catalogue of the Flora of Nebraska. Rpt. Nehr. Si Rd. Asrr. 1889: 177-302. Wim.iams. T. A. 1898. The Renewinj; of Worn -out Native Prairie Pasture*. Rpt. Nebr. Si. Md. Agr. 1897: 128-131 Woods. A. V. 1893. A Few Notes on the Crasses of the "Mad Lands." Bpt. Nebr. St. M. Agr. 1892: 201-203. Wouks. A. I'"., and Smnhkhh. 1). A 1S04. The Crasses of the Republican Valley. Rpt. Nebt St. Md. Agr. 1893:73 74. 15K.M-. W. .1. 1806. Classes of Nuftli America. Vol. I. Chapters on the Physiology. Coni|&gt;osition, Selection. Improving, and Culti Smith. .T. &lt;i. BOOKS. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 Beal, W. J. ration of Gmm; Management of Grass Lauds: also Chapters nn Clovers. I iijurions Insects, and Fungi. XIII 457 pp. Figs. 1175. 1896. QrMMI of North America. Vol. II. The Grasses Classified. Described, and Each Genus Illustrated. With Chapters on Their Geographical Distribution and a Bibli - ography. VIII. 70fi pp. Figs. 1-120. Henry Holt and Co.. New York. Button, N. L. 1901. Manual of the Flora of the Northern States and Canada. 1'p. 61158. Henry Holt and Co.. New York. Bkitton, N. L., aud Brown, A. 1913. An Illustrated Flora of the Northern United States Canada, and the British Possessions from Newfoundland to the Parallel of the Southern Boundary of Virginia, and tram the Atlantic Ocean Westward to the 102d Meridian. 2d Edit. 107-295. Figs. 254 719. 1909. New Manual of Botany of the Central Rocky M— tains (Vascular Plants*. 646 pp. American Book Co. Chicago. Punt, C. L. 1903. GfMM and Forage Plants. A Practical Treatise Comprising Their Natural History: Comparative Nutritive Value: Methods of Cultivating. Cutting, and Curing: and the Management of Grass Lands in the United States an«1 British Provinces. Revised Edit. VIII. 398 pp.. 171 «l's Lee and Shepard. Boston. Khancis. M. E. 1912. The Book of Grasses. XVI, 351 pp.. 81 pis.. 118 figs Douhleday. Page and Co.. Garden City. N. Y. r:KEL. E. (Trans, by Seribner. F. L.. aud Southworth. E. A. i 18!&gt;0. The True Grasses. VIII. 228 pp.. 11(1 figs. Henn Holt and Co.. New York Hitchcock. A. S. 1907. Grasses. Bailev's Cyclopedia of Agriculture. 2:36;") 377. PL 12. Figs.' 515-564. The Macmillan Compan\ Chicago. 1!»14. A textbook of grasses with special reference to tin economic species of the United States. XVII. 27fi pp., &amp;i figs. MacMillan Co.. New York City. ("oirLTER. .T. M.. and Nelson. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 KlI.T.Kl.UKVV. .1. |{ 1878. Tlif Grasses of Tennessee; Including Cereals anil Forage Pints. 511 pp. The American Co.. Nashville. Trim. I M:i;&lt; ivai.. J. 1002. Agricultural Botanv. Theoretical ;unl Hraeticiil. Edit. 2. Pp. 457-552. Figs. 149-191. Duckworth bud Co.. London. I'or.vp. H.. and Ci.kmkxts. F. E. 1900. The Phytogeography of Nebraska. 2d Edit. 442 |&gt;)i Botnnirnl Seminar. I'niversitv of Nebraska. Rdbinfox. It. L. and Febkald. M. L. 1!»0S. Gray's New Manual of Botany (Seventh Edition, illustrated, i A Handbook of the Flowering IMants and Ferns of the Central and Northeastern United States and Adjacent Canada. 926 pp.. 1036 figs. American Rook Co.. Chicago. Shaw. T. 1903. Grasses and How to Grow Them in North America XVII. 453 pp.. 20 figs. Webb Publishing Co., St. Paul. Si-it. i. man. W. J. 1!&gt;0."&gt;. Farm Classes of the United Slates: A Practical Treatise on the Grass ( 'rop. Seeding, and Management of Meadows and Pastures. Descriptions of the Best Varieties, the Seed and Its Impurities. Grasses for Special Condi tiims. etc. XV. 24S pp., 54 figs. Orange Judd Co., New York. tAsniR(ii:u. E.. Noi.i.. F.. Si iikmk. H.. and Karsten. G. 1908. A Textl&gt;ook of Botanv. 3d English Edit. X. 746 pp. 779 figs. The Macinillan Co.. New York. Vasky. G. 1885. A Descriptive Catalogue of the Grasses of the United States. Including Especially the Grass Collections a't the New Orleans Exposition Made by the T\ S. Department of Agriculture, and the State Exhibits of Grasses, with Notes on Such Species as are More or Less Employed in Asirioul ture. or Deserving of Trial for Cultivation. 110 pp. Gib son Bros.. Washington. Wuti.. H. M. 1908. Grasses: A Handbook for I'se in the Field and L-th oratory. VI TT. 190 pp.. 81 figs. University Press. Pain bridge. Wivq, J. E. 1911. Meadows and Pastures. 418 pp.. 1 pi.. 59 figs. Plunders Publishing Co.. Chicago. </seg>
            <seg id="p112">no. p.vi.k I; &lt;i nifty ri 111 bifluniiii HIT Ifropgrrm mm'mm 107 li/ropi/rnii rtpemt 1 M 77 '.'/'"/'.'/'"" xmithii KM! TO \yn&gt;i&gt;!/roii t&lt; iifiinn 107 TO Agrost ideae 21 {firnxtix alba 51 TO [firostin ixarata 51 7s ii/rnxtix hi/fmalix ."ii 7^ ii/roxtix ln/rniillix ."ii 7^ {t/rnxtix i«i( iminix 5] Tn llo/ici-nnix i/i iiiciihit ux :!:*&gt;. :!4 7!&gt; 1 nihofxiiiuii Utrcatiix If) 7!» l mdropogon furtmttu is 79 1 ml 111/11111011 halepeiixix 17 7i&gt; I udropogrtH htilrpeiixix 17 7i&gt; I ndropogon Imlii is 7!» I ndropogon halii is 7!» 1 mdropogon tcopmrimt is 7!&gt; 1 iidm/tot/oii xcujmriiix IS 7!" Androi»og(»ueae 14 Androitogoucae 14 I iithoxtiii/ltitin (idoriititin St 7'.i 1 lit hn.nl ntli II in ' ill 1 1 lilt Hilt ol! 7'.l :!•&gt; ;_ 1 rixtida bnsirumea 44 M iristida bnsirumea 44 M 1 rixtida (innilix 4."&gt; no 1 rixtida (/nidlix 4."&gt; no i rixtida Innt/ixita 44 v|1 I rixtida Inni/ixcta 44 v|1 I rixtida &lt;iti&lt;l&lt;mthtt 4"&gt; m&gt; \rixtida piirpurea 4."&gt; W 1 rixtida tiilirniiloxa 44 91 I rixtida tnbrrciiloxa 44 91 I rrlirniltlirnini ilntiilK 5«i 91 I nna fatua .*&gt;&lt;; &gt;u Aveiieae ■'-!• Awiicil Wheat (Jrnss ll»7 77 Awnless Iti'uiiic (irass M Si Barnjard &lt; Jrass ~- 95 .).» Beard Oraai B, 34 '■&gt;". u] Beard Grass. I'urjile 44 Bl Beard Gram, Blender 4.~&gt; N Bearded Darnel 104 B8 Mearded Short Husk :«i SI Hrrkiiiaiiiiia triicarforinix (!2 ""I* H12) </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 FNi. I'AiiE Bermuda (irass Piiiuda ( irass - )( s littgl'ilphv ;,- B""** 1 "I" 1 . 1 '.)., Bluesteni 1$ 7y Black &lt;Ti-juna yj gj Blade 3 H ■■•■"" a ag •! RIow-ubI ( irass 47 i , ; ,s. 83 S(;&gt; s ;t. 9] Itluc &lt; iraiua &lt;;i sl ISluc (iiass. Canada m; §] l.luc (iiass. Canada {$&lt;; ill Btae Graw, Kentucky gj &lt;H Itliicstcin. l.ijj is -&lt; t Uluestem, Liltle |g 7&lt;( Bottle Braafa jjg s7 1'xiitle IJnish ]()•» s - Hmitclona ctutipemdmlm (il j^t linuli luiid hiixiitu i;l S ] (il si Boutelomm otifottmckpt f\ si ttelomm otifoctmckpm C&gt;1 v 1 rkgelytrum erect urn :u; hi Brmckyelgtrtim erect mm ■!(; f&lt;l 3t HI |{I -"' •■' ......".".". 7. 8 Bract !"•' •;■ 7, 8 8 I'.i ist ly Foxtail 24 !il' Bristly Foxtail 24 ill' Hunch &lt; li-ass. Early 77 ;i;j Hunch &lt; irass. Early 77 ;i;j »■ 11 ;r.i Miiim-Ii &lt; irass. Feather 41; 1.14 Miiim-Ii &lt; irass. IVatlicr 4C, 1.14 P.i-onic (ii-ass, Awnlfss &lt;):• si P.i-onic (ii-ass, Awnlfss &lt;);• S | Ili-nnic (irass, Bnooth its 8- ISionif (irass, 8iik»i(|i !),s y-&gt; Bromtu hrisaeformit D4 g\ Bromtu brismeformit D4 g\ HriinniM cilia tux aj gj linniiilx (Hiatus &lt;j;; gj HniiiiiiM errrtux &lt;K&gt; yj Hrniiuix lionlcucrnx &gt;j{j &gt; 1 linnintx incnnix !);[ S | Hrniiiux htilmii jig s -. Bromtu kmlmii jig go Hiiimiix porteri &lt;Kj v L &gt; linniiilx Klciiiioxiix &lt;)g s &gt;( Urinimx xccalinilx !ls S" 1 HiDitutx xmiliinix &lt;)S S" 1 Bromtu xqiuinoxnx &lt;I7 s-' Bromtu xquanoxnx &lt;I7 s-' Bromtu tectorttm &lt;(2 S"' Bromtu ttctorum \y± ,s-&gt; Bmckloe imctptoidn r&gt;7 mj Bmckloe dactyloidea .",7 gf Buffalo Qraai 57 gj Miiti'alu (ii-ass 37 &gt;L &gt; I'utfiilo (Jrass, Palm (^i Of ' 'iihniintjrtixtix &lt;&lt;iiiad&lt; itxix 50 aj ' 'iihniintjrtixtix caiiadcnxix 5(1 aj ' 'ttlttnttif/roxtix iit&lt; jjitiitxti 5(1 ' alii iiHit/roxt ix iiicj-jMiixH 5(1 ' 'iiUimayrwslix ncylcctn 50 ' '&lt;ihiina&lt;/roMtix nri/hctii ~ ( li ' 'mlamovilfa lougifolim 40 ( 'iiloniorilfa loiii/ifulid 40 &lt; 'auadii Hlne (irass S(i &lt;ll ( 'anarv &lt; iiass 32 &lt;jo </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 ./■ fk;. VMm K opals 1* brnxii initial an 70 S3 U Ciitiibmxa iKjiinl ii-ii Ctmeknu tribuloides -'.'&gt; Chess N 8S Chess. Soft N SSI ( Mi.-ss. Wild !•»» 82 &lt; MotMsm 41 &lt; 'hlorideae 41 Cinnit arundinacea 415 83 r ni mi arundinaceu ±3 &amp;'• &lt; 'iiiiut latifolia 4:! 88 &lt; 'in mi latifolia 4:! 89 Colorado Sand Grass 18 "!• Colorado Sand Grass U "'•' Cotnli Grass 81 v( ' ("oinli Grass 81 9t ( 'old Grass, Little C-' '••- ( \,n\ &lt;;ras.s. Little ■ '••- Ooocfa Grass KMi Oamtk Grass KM&gt; 77 ( 'rah Grass -1 ( 'rah Grass -1 Grab (Jrass, Wild "&gt;!&gt; '••- Grab (Jrass, Wild -V.i ".^ Trifping Meadow Grass 80, 82 Creeping Meadow Grass 80, 82 vl Cm (Jrass. Rice 31 v Cm (Jrass. Rice 31 v Cut Grass, Virginia : &gt;1 M Cut Grass, Virginia :&gt;1 * v &lt; Uiundnn dtutylon H 8i &lt; 'i/iiiidon ductylon H 81 l&gt;m ti/lix glomcrata H s^ Ihn li/lin glomiiata 7:&gt; I )ainel, Bearde«l 104 Bfi I &gt;ainel, Bearded 104 DmmmM Grass 110 Bf Ihxiliiiiiipnia flexuosa M s t hunilu no diandra Wi IHyitariu xanguinalis 21 M IHxtirhlix x/iicata 7:! *U I»oj; Town Grass 44 H Karly lhineh Grass Ti '••:; ICanm's Grass 77 !&gt;:! Eihiitochbm cnixgaUi |Z 96 •&gt;.i 77 Kconomic grasses, notes on Eltuxine indica |8 Eltuxine indica ElymuH canad&lt;:nxi8 112 Ehjmitx condennatux 198 s -" Eli/m us glaucus 113 s " By HI macounii 113 IB Eh/nuts robiixtvx 112 N1 ElymtiK 8tiiutux 1 10 M Ely ma* vin/inivux Ill *&lt;■ Endosperm '•• 10 Eragro8t\8 vupillarix 7!) 81 .' ."/ • *•** .•••••••••• » • — </seg>
            <seg id="p115">* 115 HO. pac;k Eragnmtiti iiuf/axtiichya K? gg Eragrostia pectinacea SI m; Eragroati* piloaa MO, 82 86 Erugroatia trichodes H m; F.iincinna ruxpidata :{8 M European Millet 28 !mi False Kutfalu Grass ttf S!i Feather Hunch Grass 46 !»4 Fescue, Meadow !K) M Fescue, Rough 89 M Fescue, Sheep's S!» ST Fescue, Slender S!&gt; &gt;7 Featuca altaicu 80 M Featuca elatinr !M) M Featuca obtusa !K) 87 Featuca octoftora S'.l 87 Featuca ovinn M 87 Feetuceae 44 Flower 6, 7, 8 ' Fowl Meadow Grass 76 87 Foxtail, Bristly 24 K Foxtail, Green 25 M Foxtail, Water :«, 34 79 Foxtail, Yellow 25 92 • iaina Crass 13 &lt;)4 Giant Rye Grass 108 85 &lt; Hume 8 Qtpeeri* grandia 7« 87 (Hyceria nernita 7li 87 &lt; i&lt; m &gt;sc Grass || 85 Grama, Black 61 81 Grama, Blue 61 81 Grama Grass, Tall 61 80 &lt; ireen Foxtail 25 !»■_' Hair Grass 51 7£ Hair Grass, Wood 56 84 Holvua lanutua 55 87 Hordeae 6« Hordeum jubatum 114 87 Hordeum pusillum 114 87 MJ fiA^ »■ / *y* f i/1 / it Jif 1 I !• &gt; ~ </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 .&lt;• F1U. 1A..K Indian Millei 38 M I mliaii Hire 31 !&gt;4 Inflorescence o ' Italian Bjc (irass 1(14 vv Johnson (iiass 17 ■!' ■ I itn«* (iriiss. Prairie 70 &gt;7 Kentucky Itlue (Jrass 87 !&gt;1 Kciiiuckv Blue (Jrass 87 M KmUriu crittata 7(1 87 K&lt;nl&lt;ria ciixliiln 7(1 tfl Leaf It, 4 I! Lemma 8 Lemma 8 l.itrtiiii utyaoiiet SI vv Lrrmia uryziiidt* 'M vv Lrrrxia liit/inim :tl ~- s Let i sin liiii'ui'nu :tl v &gt; Ligale ■&gt; 7 Little HIiH'sicin IS ft Little Oofd GraM •»- '•'- Lodieale 7, s &gt;&gt; Lodicnle 7. s Lnli inn mult ifionini 104 v I. nil it m iiiiiII ifiminii 104 v Lnli iiiii ixrciun' 104 *- v I, 'ili ii in jicrciiin 1 104 *- v Lull ii m triniilciitiiiii 104 vv I. 'ilium Iriinilriitiiiii 104 vv l-niifj-aw lied l'overty (iiass 44 M Luiifj-aw tied Poverty (iiass 44 M I.Kiijjh'aved Heed (irass 40 Low SjM'ar (irass 8G !tl Lynii' ( irass Ill 8&lt;» l.v (irass. .MacouiTs 113 H M;n&lt; nin"s Iaiiic (it-ass 113 H .Ma.vilcae Ill Meadow Fe«cne '•** 91 Meadow (irass. Creeping so. 83 M Meadow ( irass. Fowl 7(! -~7 Meadow (it-ass. Ke«»d 7(i Meadow (irass. Slender Ml. 82 s "&gt; Melic (irass 71 ~* v Velica niterw 71 vv Millet, EniojK'an HI N Mountain Hue 3^ ■ 1/ ulilciibiijiiti intxifdiKi 4!t H 1/ iilihnbiriiin itumjeux 47 1/ tilth nlii i i/ia ruceinoMti 4!t H • Miililenbci i/ia Mchiebcri 4!l 89 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 FIG. PAUK renbergia tenuiflora 49 gcj oa xquarrosa (53 63 8!) Needle Grass 46 !);; Nimble Will 4,, ' s ,, Node ;;;:: ; ,; •&gt; Northern Redtop 51 y s Oat Grass, Tall M m M 8( , Old Witch Gram 28 Orchard Grass 73 gj Orvzeae Oryzopsit micmnlha 3g g«j &gt; Panic &lt; Jrasis, Wilcox's 30 90 ticeae 25 ' cl e • •■: '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 5 7 IS Panicum barbipuhinatum 28 8!» Panicum capillare 28 ■ Panicum dichotomi flora m 27 8!l Panicum hutichucac 2't ««i Etvum liiidchucac 2!( 89 icum leibergii m 8!) icum iniliacriim -»s on a 90 Panicum praecoaug 2!t 9&lt;l Panicum scribneriatium ;&gt;0 9^ Pan icum virgatitm 27 90 Ecum wilcoxianum :jd '$q &lt;alum stramineum 22 9(1 nnial Rye Grass 104 v arideae M 90 ■s; Phalaris arundinacca 32 &lt; M i Phalarig canarienxix •».» &lt; Ml t haian-s caminenxis ;(2 90 PhUum prutciiHi- ;&gt;4 mm M 90 Phragmites communis (^4 .„, Poa annua a-, ,', , 85 91 Poa compreasa gg yj Poa nemoralig 37 &lt; ( j Poa pratensis j Polypogon MMjMHMtii 34 9 j Pony Grass 5q q.j Pciirupine Crass 46 , u ' * *" S' ' </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 Indis FIG. I'Ai;E Poverty Grass, Southern 52 !»3 Prairie Grass ■ 54 93 Prairie June Grass 70 87 Prairie Triple Awn AH SO I'iKiint'lliu airoidet &lt;•• Purple Heard Grass 45 M Purple Wheat Grass H»7 Itaceme •"&gt; ' Uachilla &lt;i " Kachis ■ 1,'itlfichliu jkfHN N M lied top -"il v I Jed top. Northern H ~ s liced Canary Grass :!2 M •&gt;.» Kee&lt;l Grass. Long-leaved 40 Ueeil (irass. Long-leaved 40 &amp;5 Reed Grass. Wood 4:! ■ Ueed Grass. Wood H 83 Heed Meadow Grass Tfi 87 Uee&lt;l Meadow Grass Tfi 87 Ithizoine 1 '&gt; Itliizome 1 '&gt; tttee Cut Grass Si vs tttee &lt;'ut Qram :&gt;&gt; l Rough Fescue Grass S'.l M Rough Fescue (Jrass S'.l M llusli (Jrass. Small •"&gt;- l|:: RjC Grass. Giant HIS Rjc (Jrass. (Jiant H&gt;S H !t\e (Jrass. Italian 104 -- v live (Jrass. IVrennial K&gt;4 88 live ( Jrass. Wild MS, 112 &gt;:.. H Sail (irass ":! M Sail (irass ":'. M Sand Hur 2:! 83 •'•! ; Sand Grass (&gt;7 'M Sand (irass liT !»4 Sand ( ii ass, Colorado 1M II Sand (Jrass, Colorado l!S "!• s&lt;h&lt;ii(,uiitir&lt;lux pmmkmtmtu* •"»!) H Scolockloa U'xtiiencea 74 M Scolockloa jestucmoem S.utelluni !• 10 Srtariu ylaiica 25 M Srturia vertitilltilti 24 M Sitiiria riridix 25 II Sl.eath I li Sheep's Fescue S!l Situnion hi)ntri.v 101? !(2 Slender Beard Qraa 45 M Slender Fescue S!) sT Slender Meadow Grass SO, S2 M Slender AVlieat Grass 107 7S </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 Sniiill Kush Grass 52 'J3 Smooth Hromc Grass H v - Boft Chess % 81 Sorghastrum nutuns 17 'XI Southern Poverty Grass Bl 93 Spart ina gracilis B2 92 Upart ina michauxiana (iL' !•:! Spear Grass 87 !tl Spear Grass, Low 85 91 Sphevopholis obtumtn 77 93 Sphcnupholis pmlieua 77 !•:'. Spike B 7 Spikelet I 7 Sporobol ux taper Bfi 9.! Sporoboluti aspcrifoliu* ."U !••'• Sporobohis brerifolius H !•:'. Sporobolus confutus 54 M Sporobolu* cryiitandrus 54 93 Sporobolus heterolepis 54 93 S&gt;l)f&gt;robolu8 neglect us "&gt;ii !•:; ti/Hjiubolux vtHjiniflonix 52 93 Sprangle Top 74 !»!' Sf]iiirreltail Grass 114 87 Stamen 7, 8 I Stigma 7, 8 8 Stink Grass s."! titipa roiniltii 4&lt;i !t:i Stifm s/xirti-n 4C&gt; 94 Stipa viridmlm 4(J 94 Swamp Chess !K» 81 Sweet Vernal &lt; trass :»2 7!i Switch Grass i&gt;7 9&lt;» Symi&gt;odia 1 &lt;; Tall Grama &lt; Jrass fil 80 Tall &lt; &gt;at Grass 3fl g(i Thin GrasK 51 78 Timothy M 9() Timothy, Wild 4!» 8!» Triple Awn. I'rairie 45 80 7V/ jixinum duct j/loiilrx \'.\ 94 Tufttnl Triple Awn 44 80 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 Velvet Grass 55 87 Vernal Grass, Swwt ■ 79 Virginia Cut Grass 31 88 :',-2 79 Virginia Cut Grass Water Foxtail ::::. :!4 I* Water ( irass TO 83 Western Wheat Gram 107 78 Wheat Grass, Awned 107 77 Wheat Grass, Purple 107 77 Wheat Grass, Slender 107 78 Wheat Grass, Western 106 78 Wilcox's Panic Grass 30 90 Wild Chess !&gt;6 82 Wild Crab &lt; Jrass ■ 92 Wild Oats EBB 80 Wild liye Grass 183, 112 85, 92 Wild Tiniiiihy 4!t 89 Wire Grass 54 93 Witch Grass, Old ■ 89 Wood Grass 49 88 Wood Hair Grass 56 84 Wood Reed Grass 43 83 Yellow Foxtail 25 92 Yellowtop 50 83 Zizunia aquatica :'.l 94 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>