<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Summary of the Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes</title>
               <date value="1932-01">1932-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 267 January, 1932 A Summary of the Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes J. O. RANKIN and ELEANOR H. HINMAN Department of Rural Economics DOLLARS O gJO ' 100 • Tip IOQQ gjQ ISQO ITJQ gOOO total |ilHHHHHttHHElll£ili^ $&amp;ss'//// ]{']][■•■' ■ i DOLLARS O 250 200 750 1000 I2JO lAQQ ITAO 2000 Brooo BaoTMiNC . tHD^y CE " EBau.ot.cb . AVERAGE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING The "average value of family living" includes the value of all goods used foi- family living during a year in the 340 homes .studied. Both purchased and home-raised goods are included. The twelve months covered by the data ended June, 1924. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN \V. W. UURR. DIKECTOK </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Introduction ....; ;j Sources of data :i 3 Scope of this study • 4 Analysis of the Families Studied ' ; 4 Composition of families and households ........... , 4 Age of operator and 'homemaker .. 6 Nativity of operator and homemaker ..'..... 10 Education '....., : ■. 1 1 Size and value of farm and dwelling- . ; 16 Non-farm income . IS The Value of Family Living and Factors Affecting It lit The value of family living, by main items..... . 19 Tenure and the value of family living , ....'.. 21 Expenditure group and the value of family living 2:! Size of family and the value of family living.. 25 Age of operator and the value of family living '.... -~ Locality and the value of family living _'.-._ 30 Value of farm and the value of family living 32 Comparisons .-... ...: 34 Conclusions : 36 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A Summary of the Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes .1. 0. RANKIN AND ELEANOR H. HINMAN' The term "standard of living" is used in this study in its objective or economic sense, which has been denned by E. L. Kirkpatrick as including "the economic goods contributing to the maintenance of health, transportation, education, re - creation, and social relationships of the family as well as those satisfying the more material needs — food, housing, fuel, and clothing." - It is a commonplace observation that this economic standard of living varies less in farm homes than in the homes of different income groups in towns and cities. Nevertheless it shows marked variability even in farm homes. Certain averages appear to be characteristic of various local - ities, tenure groups, and sizes of farm families. A study of the economic goods used in a sampling of Nebraska farm homes for a year throws light on the wel - fare and social conditions in such homes, and upon the differ - ences .between the standards of the various types of farm homes. The distribution of the expenditures is an indica - tion of the relative value set by the families upon various kinds of satisfactions. Such a study is of use in interpreting the Nebraska farm community and in helping to form a basis for the understanding of its economic, social, and edu - cational needs. Source of data. — The data presented in this study were collected by field workers in 1924 from 342 unselected farm homes located in four typical farming areas, namely: one near Ft. Calhoun in Washington County, one near Waverly in Lancaster County, one near Fairfield in Clay County, and one near Dix in Kimball County. The data on goods used cover the year ending the day the enumerator called, which was sometime between June 1 and 30, 1924. This year was one of moderate prosperity on Nebraska farms, income in general being considerably lower than during 1918-20, but considerably higher than during the depressions of 1921 and 1 Hnscd upon a survey conducted in 1024 in co-operation with the Bureau of Agricultural Economics, 11. S. Department of Agriculture. Acknowledgments are due to members of the departments of Economics, Rural Economics, and Home Economics of the University of Nebraska for counsel and suggestion. Tabulation was tinder the direction of Mrs. Dorothy B. Dane and the junior author. Table 5 includes data from a survey made in 1920 and described by the senior author in Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 19G, Nebraska Farm Tenancy — Some Community Phases, p. 4. October, 1023. • Kirkpatrick. E. L. The Farmers' Standard of Living: A Socio-economic Study of 2,886 White Farm Families of Selected Localities in Eleven States. U. S. Dept of Agr. Bui. 146G, p. 2, 192G. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 1930. 3 The yields and values of the principal crops in 1023 were also moderate; the high grain yields in 1924 of course did not particularly affect family expenditures in the year studied.* The economic standard of living on Nebraska farms varies with the variations in income, although the variations in the standard of living may be less than those in money income because of the value of home-produced goods, and the use of savings and credit. Scope of this study. — The present study is a summary of the data obtained in the survey just described and confines itself for the most part to analyzing the money value of the goods used by the family and to various factors affecting the distribution of that value. For a detailed analysis of the quantity and quality of goods used for food, housing, house operation, clothing and advancement, the reader is referred to a series of earlier bulletins based on the same survey. 5 ANALYSIS OF THE FAMILIES STUDIED COMPOSITION OF FAMILIES AND HOUSEHOLDS Persons per household, by tenure and expenditure groups. — An analysis of the families studied is necessary to an understanding of the factors affecting their standard of living. Of 342 families from which reports were obtained, 337 indicated tooth a man as operator and a woman as home - maker. These families averaged 2.9 children living, of whom 2.3 resided at home. The members of the family living in the home averaged 4.3. This is the same as the figure given for rural Nebraska in the 1920 Census/' In addition, relatives, friends, or paying boarders were received in many homes for varying periods, and some hired help was boarded. The unit in measuring these transients was one person for one month. The 337 homes received guests to the extent of 2.2 person-months per home, and boarded hired help to the ex - tent of 1.6 person-months per home. The owners' families averaged more children living, but fewer at home, than the other families. This was because the owners were in general oMer men, and many of their chil - dren had grown up and left home. The part-owners, with 2.8 children living at home, had larger households than men 'Farm Production in the JJnited States, by States, 1924-1028 — Crops and Mark - ets. 6:370-373. •Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, pp. 94-97, 1930. • Rankin, J. O. Cost of FeedinR the Nebraska Farm Family. Ncbr. Aitr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 219. 1927. Rankin, J. O. The Use of Time in Nebraska Farm Homes. Nebr. Acr. Exp. Sta: Bui. 230, 1928. Rankin, J. O. The Cost of Clothing the Nebraska Farm Family. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 248, 1930. Rankin, J. O. Housing and House Operations Costs on Nebraska Farms. Nebr. Atcr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 264, 1931. •Fourteenth Census of the U. S., 2:1274. 1920. • </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Standard op Living in Nebraska Farm Homes Table 1. — Persons per household and family, and person - months of transients boarded, in 337 Nebraska farm homes | Persons Sons and daughters Other dependents Expenditure and Per l»or family per household tenure Kroup ■ Homes *&gt;°™&gt;f i Relatives, I 'Hired " om At home I Away boarders I help 1 ■i i i \ Person- I Person- Number Persona Persons Persons I months I months All families 337 4.3 2.3 0.6 2.2 1.6 Owners :.... 112 3.9 1.9 1.3 2.2 0.8 Part-owners .... 60 4.8 2.8 0.3 3.2 2.3 Tenants 157 4.3 2.3 0.3 1.9 2.0 Hired men 4 8 4.6 2.6 0.3 0.0 0.0 Under $1,200 ........ 83 3.2 1.2 0.7 0.9 0.2 Owners 31 2.8 0.8 1.5 0.8 0.1 Part-owners .... 7 3.7 1.7 0.0 3.4 0.0 Tenants 38 3.2 1.2 0.3 0.8 0.4 Hired men * 7 4.7 2.7 0.1 0.0 0.0 $l,200-$l,799 131 3.8 1.8 I 0.4 2.3 1.8 Owners 41 3.5 1.5 1.0 2.9 1.0 Part-owners .... 18 3.4 1.4 0.1 3.1 2.3 Tenants I 71 4.1 2.1 I 0.1 1.7 I 2.2 Hired men * I 1 j 4.0 2.0 1.0 0.0 I 0.0 $l,800-?2,399 88 5.1 3.1 0.5 3.0 1 2.6 Owners 26 5.1 3.1 0.5 2.2 1.4. Part-owners ...". 22 5.3 3.3 I 0.4 3.8 i 3.4 Tenants .......I 40 ! 4.9 2.9 I 0.5 3.1 i 3.0 $2,400 and more ..I 35 6.5 4.5 I 1.5 2.8 I 1.5 Owners j 14 5.4 3.4 2.9 3.4 ' 0.6 Part-owners .... 13 | 6.5 4.E 0.5 2.3 I 1.8 Tenants \ 3 | 8.4 6.4 | 0.5 2.6 I 2.3 ■Expenditure groups are classified according to the value of goods used in family living, including the value oif home-produced food and fuel and the rental value of the house. 1 Each; home in this table included a man as operator and a woman as home - maker. Excluded from the table was one farm occupied by a bachelor living alone and four where a woman was both homemaker and operator. * Unrelated in blood to employer. • * Ths eight families of married hired men are treated as a "tenure croup" for purposes of comparison, although this use of the term 1s perhaps not strictly accurate since these laborers held no property rights in the land they worked. The terms owner and tenant are used in the usual sense. Fart-owners are farmers who own a part of the land they operate and rent part of it from someone else. of any other tenure. Tenants had fewer children living than farmers of any other tenure, mainly because they were usually younger men. Owners' homes received guests as much as the average, but boarded fewer hired men. Part - owners boarded the most outsiders — 3.2 person-months of guests and 2.3 of help. Tenants received slightfy fewer guests and boarded a little more hired help than the average of all tenures. The families were also grouped according to the value of all goods used in family living, including estimates for goods furnished by the home farm. These are called "expenditure </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 I I ■!__,,' | ■■ | g~! ■*LLH0MES 0OWNEW EJpARTOmJERS T] ~ = 4_ @TENANTS Qh»£OMEN ££?£££*" . . _| Fig. 1.— Children per family and per household in 337 Nebraska farm homes. The shaded bars indicate the average number of children per household in the respective tenure and expenditure groups. The unshaded bars indicate children living away from home. groups." The average size of the household increased from 3.2 per home in the 83 homes expending less than $1,200 for family living to 6.5 in the 35 homes expending $2,400 and more. The number of children residing at home increased from 1.2 to 4.5 per home in the same groups, and the total number from 1.9 to 6.0. The entertainment of guests in - creased from less than one person-month in the group ex - pending under $1,200 to nearly three person-months in the groups expending from $1,800 to $2,399 and $2,400 and more. The amount of help boarded was greatest in the group ex - pending from $1,800 to $2,399, where it averaged 2.6 person - months. Homemakers. — In 92 per cent of the homes studied, the homemaker was the wife of the operator; in three per cent the mother; and in a few other cases a daughter, sister, or other relative. There was not much difference among the tenure groups in this respect. A slightly larger proportion of owners: had daughters as homemakers and a slightly larger proportion of part-owners had mothers. AGE OF OPERATOR AND HOMEMAKER Age of operator and homemaker. — The average age of the operators studied was 43 years in the 323 homes which reported this item ; and their homemakers were three years </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Standard op Living in Nebraska Farm Homes Table 2. — Average age and experience of operators and homemakers on 328 Nebraska farms Expenditure and Average age of Operator's years tenure group 1 .__ I On present As farm '..' ■ Operator Homemaker | farm operator Years Years Years Years All families 42.7 39.8 10.1 18.4 Owners 51.8 47.8 17.6 25.7 Part-owners 40.8 39.1 8.4 10.7 Tenants 37.4 35.1 5.7 14.0 Hired men 34.5 28.4 1.3 Under $1,200 42.6 42.0 9.9 18.6 Owners 56.6 55.0 20.8 32.2 Part-owners 33.7 40.4 2.7 12.0 Tenants 34.9 34.8 4.2 10.8 Hired men 31.4 25.7 1.3 $l,200-$l,799 40.8 36.3 - 8.5 15.6 Owners 50.8 44.5 14.9 22.1 Part-owners 38.2 35.9 7.6 13.7 Tenants 35.5 31.5 5.2 11.9 Hired men 56.0 47.0 1.5 $l,800-$2,399 43.5 41.0 10.8 20.2 Owners .;........ 46.2 43.3 15.9 23.5 Part-owners 43.7 40.1 10.3 18.8 Tenants 41.8 40.2 7.5 19.0 $2,400 and more 47.7 44.6 14.8 23.8 Owners 54.2 49.7 22.5. 26.9 Part-owners 43.3 41.1 I 9.0 19.3 Tenants 43.8 41.4 1 9.7 24.8 . ■ Expenditure eroups are classified according to the value of all living costs, in - cluding that of home-produced food and fuel and the rental value of the farmhouse. younger. Owners averaged 52 years, part-owners 41. ten - ants 37, and married hired men 3.5 years. Within each ex - penditure group, the owners were older, on the average, than the part-owners and tenants. Part-owners and tenants in the two upper expenditure groups ($1,800-2,399 and $2,400 and more) were older than those in the two lower expenditure groups (under $1,200 and $1,200-1,799). Homemakers aver - aged slightly younger than operators in every tenure and ex - penditure group except part-owners under $1,200, in which group two of the seven homemakers were mothers of the oper - ators. Operators' farm experience. — The farmers studied in this survey had been farm operators for an average of eighteen years, and had resided for ten years on their present farms. Owners had. had by far the longest farming expe - rience — twenty-six years, of which eighteen had been spent on their present farms. Part-owners, with seventeen years of </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 TABLE 3. — Age distribution of operators on 323 Nebraska farms 1 Tenure and Opera- . Percentage expenditure groups tors ; Under 25-34 35-44 I 45-54 | 55-64 Over 25yrs. yrs. yrs. ' yrs. j yrs. 64yrs. i No. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.et. P.ct. All operators , | 323 2.8 25.7 32.5 21.4 11.8 5.9 Tenure groups Owners 107 0.0 4.7 24.3 33.6 21.5 15.9 Part-owners I 57 1.8 24.6 42.1 21.1 10.5 0.0 Related to landlord*! 14 . 0.0 28.6 57.1 7.1 I 7.1 0.0 Unrelated ! 43 2.3 23.3 37.2 25.7 I 11.6 0.0 Tenants | 152 | 4.6 39.5 I 34.9 13.8 I 5.9 1 1.3 Related to landlord* 58 1 6.9 37.9 37.9 10.3 | 5.2 1.7 Unrelated 94 3.2 40.0 33.0 16.0 j 6.4 1.1 Hired men 7 14.3 57.1 I 28.6 ! 0.0 I 0.0 j 0.0 Expenditure groups I Under ?l,200 | 75 4.0 40.0 | 18.7 I 10.7 1 14.7 j 12.0 $l,200-$l,799 1 129 4.6 30.2 I 35.7 | 17.1 | 7.8 I 4.6 $l,800-$2,399 ' 86 i. 0.0 14.0 | 40.7 I 31.4 | 10.5 ' 3.5 $2,400 and more 33 | 0.0 6.1 | 30.3 1 36.4 I 24.2 3.0 1 All the operators in this table were men. * In blood or by marriage. experience, had spent half of it on their present farms. The eight married hired men averaged fifteen years of farming experience, but had spent only a little more than a year of it on the farms where they were employed. The farm expe - rience of owners in the highest and the lowest expenditure groups, measured by the number of years as operator, aver - aged longer than that of owners in the two middle expendi - ture groups. The average experience of part-owners and ten - ants, on the other hand, showed a direct correlation with ex - penditure for family living. Nebraska farm tenants had remained longer on the same farms than the average American farm tenant. A computa - tion based on census figures gives the average number of years on the present farm as about 3.5 for all farm tenants in the United States and 5.7 for all in Nebraska. 7 The Nebraska figure agrees with that for tenants in this study. Thirty-six per cent of all farm owners in the United States and the same percentage in Nebraska had lived on their present farms for fifteen years or more, but only 4.5 and 5.5 per cent, respectively, of tenants. Age distribution of operators. — Of the 323 farm oper - ators whose age was indicated, about one-fortieth were under * U. S. Census of Agr.. 1925. Summary Statistics, by States, pp. 82 and 85. In estimating the average, 20 years was assumed as the approximate midpoint of the "16 year and over" group. ■ . </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes 25 years old, one-fourth from 25 to 34 years, one-third from 35 to 44 years, one-fifth from 45 to 54 years, one-ninth from 55 to 64 years, and the remainder, about six per cent, were over 64 years old. Owners were concentrated in the older age groups and part-owners and tenants in the younger age groups. Part-owners and tenants related in kinship to their landlords were younger than those not so related. The group spending less than $1,200 for family living con - tained a much larger proportion of the farmers under 35 years and over 64 years of age than the survey as a whole. Forty-four per cent of the operators in this lowest expendi - ture group were under 35 years old and twelve per cent over 64 years old, compared with twenty-eight per cent and six per cent, respectively, of all operators studied. The group PER CENT O 10 20 30 40 JO 60 70 80 90 IOC operators Mffiai IIIIHHIHI IIIIIIIIIK 3%&amp;&amp; %&amp;$&amp; 9$8$iS&amp;&amp;C'//C / y^/ / /y/\\\\\\\\\\ lit;'/':--'' £ owners p8%$3«»»58 i iSS^/////////////////7A\\\\\\\\\ TTTTTTTTiT Illlf-:: 1 --;- y-: : :-\T: I tenants ■B111II «8838S8g£%^ |S R pillllll|llllllllllliiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiW$o^^ « MS2" ■illllll llllllliuil mm m&amp;s$$&amp;ssgt®i^^ . 1 i^^z^m&gt;x&gt;^^ iiHiiiiiiiliiiiiiir.v PCRCENT 0 10 20 30 40 JO 6O TO 80 90 100 ■ UNDER mp.ZS.ZA rn&gt;3J-44 prn4J-i4 nm-W-8* me* YRS 2JYRS. HyRS. K^YRS. E2yRS. lini^rRS^ E3*N0M0RE Fig. 2. — Age distribution of operators on 323 Nebraska farms. spending from $1,200 to $1,799 was strongly concentrated between the ages of 25 and 45 years, sixty-six per cent of the operators falling between these ages. "The groups spending from $1,800 to $2,399 and $2,400 and more were mainly be - tween the ages of 35 and 64* 82 per cent of the first-named group and 91 per cent of the last-named group being in - cluded between these ages. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 Age distribution of homemakers. — Of 336 homemakers' whose ages were indicated, about one in fifteen was under 25 years, three in ten were from 25 to 34 years, the same pro - portion from 35 to 44 years, one in four from 45 to 54 years, one in sixteen from 55 to 64 years, and one in twenty-five over 64 years. In general, the distribution of homemakers closely followed that of operators except that there was a slightly larger proportion of homemakers in the age groups below 35 years and a slightly larger proportion of operators in every age group above 35 years except the 45-to-55-year group. Table 4. — Age distribution of 336 Nebraska farm home- makers 1 Tenure and Home- Percentage expenditure groups makers ■ I Under| 25-34 | 35-44 | 45-54 I 55-64 ! Over : L 25yrs.l yrs. 1 yrs. | yrs. | yrs. |C4yrs. . „ , , No. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. j P. ct. [ P. ct. | P. ct. All homemakers | 336 7.4 29.5 28.9 23.2 ■ 6.8 ! 4.2 Tenure groups Owners '. | 109 0.9 I 11.9 | 22.9 40.4 1.14.7 i 9.2 Part-owners | 65 4.6 30.8 | 38.5 ! 20.0 I 4G 15 Related to landlord! 16 0.0 50.0 I 31.3 I 12.5 | 0 0 6 3 Unrelated ! 49 6.1 24.5 I 40.8 I 22.4 ! 6.1 0 0 Tenants [ 154 12.3 40.3 29.9 i 13.0 | 2.6 j 1.9 Related to landlord | 59 15.3 42.4 23.7 15.3 | 1.7 j 1.7 Unrelated I 95 10.5 38.9 33.7 11.6 I 3.2 | 2.1 Hired men | 8 25.0 50.0 12.5 12.5 ! 0.0 j 0.0 Expenditure groups [ Under $1,200 1 82 13.4 29.3 | 14.6 20.7 ; 9.8 ' 12 2 $l,200-$i\799 :... 126 10.3 36.5 I 30.2 16.7 ! 4.8 i 1.6 $l,800-$2,399 | 89 1.1 25.8 I 39.3 27.0 ! 5.6 j 1.1 $2,400 and more | 39 0.0 15.4 j 30.8 41.0 ; 10.3 i 2.6 1 All the homemakers included in this table were women. NATIVITY OF OPERATOR AND HOMEMAKER The 1,446 Nebraska farm families surveyed in 1920 and 1924 were predominantly of native birth. In four-fifths of these homes both operator and homemaker were native Americans. In six per cent of the homes only the home - maker was native, and in four per cent only the operator was native. In nearly eight per cent of the homes both homemaker and operator were foreign-born. No colored families were included in this study. The parentage of the native farmers was not learned. The 1920 census gives 19.8 per cent of Nebraska farm operators as foreign-born and 79.9 as native white. This is in </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Standard op Living in Nebraska Farm Homes Table 5.— Nativity of operators and homemakers in 1,H6 Nebraska farm homes surveyed in 1920 l and 19&amp;U i ' Percentage Tenure K roup Families Op. only H. M. only Both 1 Both foreign- foreign- foreign- * ■ native born born born Number P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. All families 1,446 81.9 6.2 4.1 7.8 Owner 493 77.7 6.9 5.5 9.9 Part-owner 229 77.7 6.6 6.1 9.6 Related to landlord 52 88.5 3.8 3.8 3.8 Unrelated 177 74.6 | 7.3 6.8 11.3 Tenant 669 86.2 5.7 2.5 I 5.5 Related to landlord 270 88.1 5.6 4.1 2.2 Unrelated 399 85.0 5.8 1.5 7.8 Manager 2 7 85.7 14.3 0.0 ' 0.0 Hired man 2 48 83.3 ' 4.2 2.1 10.4 1 The 1920 data, were obtained by a new tabulation of the survey described by the author in Nebraska Farm Tenancy — Some Community Phases, Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 196. 1923, p. 4. 2 None of the managers were kinsmen of their employers. Only two of the hired men were kinsmen of their employers. fair agreement with the results of this study, in which 14 per cent of the operators were foreign-born and 86 per cent native. The trend in percentage of foreign-born operators has been downward since 1910, when. 27.5 per cent of Nebras - ka farmers were foreign-born. 8 More owners and part-owners were of foreign birth than farmers of any other tenure. In these tenures one-tenth of the farm homes studied indicated that both operator and homemaker were foreign-born. One-eighth were of mixed composition, about evenly divided between homes in which only the homemaker was native and those in which only the operator was native. About three-fourths of all homes in these tenures were wholly native American; but about seven - eighths of tenants', managers', and hired men's homes were wholly native American. Naturally, the related part-owners and tenants were more commonly of American birth than those unrelated in kinship to their landlords. EDUCATION Operators' education, by tenure groups. — Completion of the eighth grade was the commonest education for the Nebraska farm operators studied. Nearly half reported eight grades of schooling and no more. Four-fifths of the opera - tors had completed the eighth grade or more, but only three - "Fourteenth Census of the U. S., 1920, Vol. G, Part I, p. 41. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 TABLE 6. — Education of operators, homemakers, and children of 18 years and older in 330 Nebraska farm homes classi - fied by tenure * Percentage completing specified Tenure group I Persons . grade in school - i ' i i i ~ -8 9 12 | 13 16 I ■- i ■ I I ■ All . I • No. | P. ct. ' P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. | P. ct. Operators 322 81.4 j 36.3 | 14.6 I 5.6 ! 2.5 Homemakers I 323 83.3 42.1 i 22.3 I 8.7 I 1.5 Children I 280 93.6 65.0 ' 42.5 I 21.8 j 5.4 Owners Operators ! 105 72.4 25.7 11.4 ' 4.8 i 1.9 Homemakers : 108 76.9 | 35.2 I 13.9 I 5.6 0 9 Children I 172 | 94.2 | 66.9 | 43.0 I 23.8 j 7.0 Related part-owners Operators I 13 i 92.3 | 61.5 I 15.4 i 0.0 0.0 Homemakers ...., I 14 92.9 | 50.0 | 28.5 | 14.3 7.1 Children I 12 I 100.0 I 58.3 I 58.3 | 25.0 0.0 Unrelated part-owners I • ) ■ Operators | 42 90.5 j 38.1 j 11.9 I . 7.1 | 4.8 Homemakers i 43 I 86.0 | 41.8 | 30.2 ! 16.3 ' 2.3 Children i 32 I 100.0 I 68.7 | 50.0 j 21.9 ! 9.4 Related tenants Operators I 61 85.2 j 45.9 I 19.7 ; 6.6 4.9 Homemaker3 ; I 59 88.1 ! 44.0 i 23.7 ! 10.2 I 3.4 Children ! 24 91.7 I 58.3 i 50.0 1 29.2 I 0.0 Unrelated tenants - Operators : | 94 83.0 ; 38.3 | 14.9 | 6.3 1.1 Homemakers I 92 87.0 ! 47.8 ; 26.1 ! 7.6 ! 0.0 Children I 38 I 84.2 i 57.9 ! 23.7 | 7.9 \ 0.0 Hired men I . . ' Men I 7 85.7 ! 28.6 i 28.6 | 0.0 ! 0.0 Homemakers 7 57.1 I 42.9 ! 28.6 | 0.0 j 0.0 Children 2 | 100.0 | 100.0 I 50.0 i 0.0 I 0.0 "Children under 18 years are omitted because a' large proportion of such children are still attending school. 3 The percentage completing the grade includes those who continued further. eighths had completed the ninth grade or more. One opera - tor in seven had graduated from high school (twelfth grade). One in twenty had completed a year of schoo'ing in addition to high school; some of these operators had. attended a college or university and some a business or professional school. One operator in forty had graduated from a college or uni - versity; these are indicated in Table" 6 as having completed sixteen years of schooling. ' Owner-operators, in general, had had less schooling than operators of any other tenure group studied except married hired men. Less than three-fourths of the owners had finished the eighth grade, as compared with nine-tenths of the part-owners and about five-sixths of the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">. Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes tenants and hired men. One-fourth of the owner-operators had completed one year or more of high school, as compared with three-eighths of the unrelated part-owners and unre - lated tenants, nearly half of the related tenants, and three - fifths of the related part-owners. The proportion of the owners who had graduated from high school and college, how - ever, was only a little below the average for all tenure groups. The superiority of the part-owners and tenants in amount of schooling is probably due to the fact that they were younger men and had therefore had better educational oppor - tunities than the owners. Homemakers' education, by tenures. — The farm home - makers, on the whole, were a little better educated than the operators. One-sixth of the homemakers had had less than an eighth-grade education; two-fifths had had eight grades and nothing more ; a fifth had entered high school but did not graduate ; more than a fifth had finished high school or gone beyond it. In the part-owner and tenant homes the women, like the men, were somewhat better educated than in the owners' homes. Education of children.— The children of these homes were much better educated than their parents. Only the 280 children eighteen years and over are considered here because the others might not have finished their school attendance. Eleven out of every twelve children had completed eight grades or more ; nearly two-thirds had had one year or more of high school; two-fifths had graduated from high school; one-fifth had attended college or professional schools; and one-twentieth had graduated from college. Owner, part-owner, and related tenant children all stood high m amount of education received. Forty-three per cent of the owners' children had completed twelve grades or more as had 58 per cent of related part-owners', 50 per cent of the unrelated part-owners', and 50 per cent of the related tenants' children, but only 24 per cent of the unrelated tenants' chil - dren. Only six per cent of the owners' children had received less than an eighth-grade education, no part-owners' children and eight per cent of the related tenants' children; but sixteen per cent of the unre'ated tenants' children had not completed the eighth grade. More than half the children of this last - named group, had dropped out of school at the end of the eighth, ninth, or tenth grades. This table does not nec - essarily mean that unrelated tenants' children are inferior m education to their own parents. Since the average age of tenants was only 37 years, 0 the proportion of tenant families ■ Table 2 of this study. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 with children over eighteen years was relatively small. An earlier report l0 shows that Nebraska owner and tenant chil - dren averaged about the same number of grades of schooling completed for children of each age from seven up to about fifteen years ; above that the tenant children began gradually to drop behind. TABLE 7. — Education of operators, homemakers, and children of 18 years and older in 330 Nebraska farm homes by expenditure group 1 Percentage completing specified Expenditure group Persons grade in school * p 1 8 9 12 13 16 ' ' __j ! ■ • ' I ! All . No. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. | P.ct. | P.ct. Operators I 322 81.4 36.3 14.6 i 5.6 | 2.5 Homemakers \ 323 83.3 42.1 22.3 i 8.7 \ 1.5 Children | 280 ] 93.6 | 65.0 | 42.5 j 21.8 5.4 Under $1,200 ! Operators I 71 j 84.5 32.4 I 9.9 I 1.4 ! 0.0 Homemakers ;.. 72 73.6 36.1 I 19.4 I 4.2 0.0 Children I 59 88.1 1 71.2 I 45.8 ! 20.4 1.7 $l,200-$l,799 I Operators 132 85.6 41.7 I 18.2 5.3 2.3 Homemakers 129 89.1 t 48.8 I 21.7 i 7.8 0.8 Children ! 65 95.4 | 52.3 36.9 i 10.8 4.6 . $l,800-$2,399 Operators i 84 76.2 j 3.1.0 ; 10.7 7.1 3.6 Homemakers ! 90 I 83.3 [ 36.7 I 22.2 12.2 3.3 Children I 72 I 90.3 I 69.4 I 33.3 13.9 5.6 Over $2,399 ! i Operators 35. | 71.4 I 37.1 I 20.0 I 11.4 5.7 Homemakers 32 81.3 I 43.7 I 31.2 12.5 3.1 Children I 84 | 98.8 j 66.7 [ 52.4 38.1 8.3 1 Children under 18 years arc omitted because a large proportion of such children are still attending school. 3 The percentaite completing the Rrade includes those who continued further. Operators' education, by expenditure groups. — The operators' years of schooling did not seem to show any very clear correlation with the value of the goods used in family living. The percentage having completed twelve grades or more increased from ten per cent in the lowest to twenty per cent in the highest expenditure group, but the percentage with less than eight grades increased from sixteen .to twenty - nine per cent in the same respective groups. ••Rankin, J. O. The Nebraska Farm Family. Nebr. Apr. Exp. Sta. Dul. 185, p. 23, 1923. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes Homemakers' education, by expenditure groups. — The homemaker's education was somewhat more closely related than the operator's to the family expenditure. The pro - portion of homemakers who had completed twelve grades or more increased from twenty per cent in the lowest to thirty - one per cent in the highest expenditure group, while the pro - portion with less than an eighth-grade education decreased from twenty-six to nineteen per cent in the same respective groups. [1 ,eh ■ I • ' I ' ' ' ' Jr s , 0 — if it — K j , I I "^g^^ -Ma^LJ- -fcgaL. a Fig. 3. — Percentage of operators and their children 18 years and older who had completed the specified grades in school. Children's education, by expenditure groups. — The chil - dren were generally better educated in the higher expendi - ture groups. Twelve per cent of the children in the lowest expenditure group had had less than eight grades of school - ing, but this decreased to one per cent of the children in the highest expenditure group. Only two per cent of the chil - dren in the lowest expenditure group had had college educa - tions or the equivalent, but this increased to eight per cent of those in the highest expenditure group. Many children in the two lower expenditure groups, however, had graduated from high school — 46 per cent of those in the "under-$l,200" group and 37 per cent of those in the ?l,200-to-$l,799 group. The probable explanation of this deviation from the trend is the fact that these groups, especially the lowest, contained so many elderly couples whose children had left home. A few </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 years earlier, when their children were completing their edu - cation, many of these elderly farmers would probably have been found in a higher expenditure group. Table 8. — Size and value of farm and farmhouse on 340 Nebraska farms ' E =^ r | -r I -r I ™r S v^&lt; . sss - —— larm acre farm ■ house ' house A ni£ milieS ooH i * 83 - 93 I * 28 ' 004 I 6 - 5 I $2,035 i $60-3 Ownerj 235 -° 120.14 28,237 | 6.8 2 259 71* Part-owner 600.9 57.18 34,344 [ 6.5 2 458 &gt; 654 Tenant 297.7 ! 84.25 25,080 | 6.4 1 755 i 525 Hired man | fill 97n I •&gt;?&lt;&gt; Under $1,200 245.1! 85.94 £^084 5.9 1 Owner 206.8 I 122.67 25,367 f 6.1 1 363 ! 491 Part-owner 412.9 I 56.81 23,457 | 5.9 1,543 I 393 Tenant 242.2.1 70.77 17,143 | 5.7 l^S I 308 .Hired man 1 ... fin 1 &lt;*99 i o-it $l£00-?l,799 1 304.7 | 85.11 SSfiSO | G3 ifll j Us Owner ! 286.3 I 86.37 I 24,730 ! 6.6 1,936 I 699 Part-owner ! 372.1 | 83.43 ! 31,047 I 5.7 1,622 ' 638 Tenant ;... 293.4 i 84.86 I 24,902 | 6.2 1609 561 Hired man I ! ... . ] 170 1 900 S^'i §l,800-$2,399 1 421.4 | 76.29 I 32V147 I 7io 2,631 K58 Owner | 185.2 I 164.12 I 30,390 I 7.4 3,010 I 820 Part-owner ......[ 804.0 ! 47.60 I 38,278 | 6.7 2,516 '&lt; 557 Tenant I 347.1 ! 85.40 | 29,642 | 7.0 2,454 I (510 $2,400 and more..| 407.6 | 98.51 | 40,148 | 7.6 3,389 ■ 890 Owner 226.1 | 183.56 I 41,500 ! 7.8 . 3,821 i 1 025 Part-owner 658.6 ! 57.79 | 38,589 | 7.4 4,008 ' 973 Tenant j 344.8 1 116.30 I 40,094 j 7.6 1,822 1 519 "The value of the farmhouse was estimated for 340 farms. A few less than this -number reported the acreage, the value of the farm real estate, and the rurniture. SIZE AND VALUE OF FARM AND DWELLING Size of farm. — The average size of the farms studied was 334 acres, as compared with 329 for all Nebraska farms. 11 Part-owners had by far the largest farms — 601 acres in the survey farms and 589 acres for all part-owner farms. In the survey, tenant farms averaged 298 acres and owner farms 235 acres. In the census, however, the owner farms were somewhat larger (273 acres) and the tenant farms some - what smaller (264 acres) . Value per acre. — The value of all farm real estate per acre was $84 for the farms covered by the survey and $60 for all Nebraska farms as reported in the 1925 Census of Agriculture. The principal reason for this difference is that the survey included no data from the grazing areas in the sand hills and the northwestern high plains. These areas 11 U. S. Census of Agr.. 192B. Summary Statistics, by States, p. 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes together constitute more than one-fifth of the land surface of the state and consist mainly of very cheap land. The value assigned to each survey farm was the estimate made by the farm operator with the assistance of the enumerator. The owner farms in the survey averaged $120 per acre; those in the census only $69. The part-owner farms in the survey averaged $57 per acre; in the census, $41. Part-ownership is commonest in the western part of the state where land is relatively cheap. Tenant farms in the survey averaged $84 per acre; in the census, $71. 12 . The value per acre showed very little relation to the expenditure group. Value per farm. — The farms in the survey were some - what more valuable per farm than the average for the state as reported by the 1925 census. Survey farms were valued at $28,004 and census farms at $19,760 for farm real estate. DOLLAR* I. I . I i OLLARS iopoo [Jail Browner fflUfflj&amp;R | W^HrrS "***' ° all UNDER «BOO *!»» - 1799 ♦iBOO - 2399 I *2*OO AND MORE FARMS TOTAL VALUE OF FAMLY UVTNG Fig. 4. — Value of farm real estate per farm, by tenure and expenditure groups. Part-owner farms in the survey were worth $34,344 and in the census, $24,020. Owner survey farms were valued at $28,237 each ; owner census farms, $18,840. Tenant sur - vey farms were worth $25,080 ; tenant census farms, $18,675. The value of real estate per farm showed a moderate correla - tion with the value of the goods used for family living. The real estate value increased from $21,064 in the lowest ex - penditure group to $40,148 in the highest expenditure group. Rooms per house. — The average size of the dwelling house was 6.5 rooms. Owners' houses were a little larger than part-owners', part-owners' than tenants', and tenants' « U. S. Census of Ari\, 1925.- Summary Statistics, by States, pp. 9 and 22. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 than hired men's; but the difference was only from 6.8 to 6.1 rooms. The size of house increased steadily from 5.9 rooms in the lowest to 7.6 in the highest expenditure group. The larger families in the higher expenditure groups made larger houses necessary, and the more valuable farms made them possible. Value of houses.— The average value of houses was $2,035. Part-owner and owner houses were above average in value, tenant houses a little below. The value per house rose from $1,367 in the lowest to $3,389 in the highest ex - penditure group. It increased a little more rapidly than the value of the farm. In the lowest group the estimated value of the house represented about 6.5 per cent of the total value of the farm ; in the highest, 8.4 per cent. Value of furniture. — The value of the furniture was estimated at $603 per home. Owners' furniture was worth about $109 more than this average, part-owners' furniture about $50 more, tenants' about $80 less and hired men's furni - ture considerably less than half the average for all tenures. The value of the furniture per home increased steadily from $406 in the lowest to $890 in the highest expenditure group. While the increase in general living costs trebled (from $974 to $3,022), the increase in total value of furniture only doubled. NON-FARM INCOME Three-fourths of the families surveyed were dependent upon the farm for their entire income. About a tenth re - ceived from $1 to $299 from outside sources during the year studied. A thirtieth received from $300 to $599, a for- Tarle 9. — Percentage of 340 Nebraska farm homes reporting income from other, than farm sources, classified by tenure groups* • . . i I • • I . i : . " Amount of non-farm All Part- I Hired income • I tenures. Owners ! owners 1 Tenants men j. ! [ - I . : ! P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. I P. ct. ■■ P. ct. No non-farm income 75.4 68.1 66.7 83 1 87 5 $l-$299 9.7 10.6 10.0 9.4 0 0 $300-$599 3.5 4.4 5.0 2.5 00 $600-$899 2.9 6.2 3.3 I 0.6 0.0 $900-$l,199 1.5 2.7 3.3 | 0.0 I 0.0 $l,200-$l,799 1.2 2.7 1.7 0.0 0.0 $1,800 and more 0.9 0.9 1.7 0.6 0.0 Amount not stated 5.0 4.4 8.3 3.8 12!.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes tieth from $600 to $899, and a few families larger amounts. One-twentieth of the families received some non-farm in - come but did not state how much. About one-third of the owners and part-owners received non-farm income, and about one-sixth of the tenants. Non-farm income was much less common in Nebraska than among the 1,205 farm families studied by Kirkpatrick in eleven other states. 1 ' Only twenty-four per cent of these non- Nebraska families were wholly dependent upon the farm for income, as compared with 75 per cent of the Nebraska families. Nearly half of the families in the Kirkpatrick study received income up to $300 from non-farm sources ; eleven per cent received from $300 to $599; seven per cent from $600 to $899 ; four per cent from $900 to $1,199 ; and six per cent more than $1,200. THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING AND FACTORS AFFECTING IT THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING, BY MAIN ITEMS Goods purchased or furnished by the farm. — Three hun - dred forty of the homes surveyed reported the value of the goods used in family living with sufficient completeness to be studied in this respect. The average value of all the goods used in these homes during the year was $1,681. Of this amount, $931 was for purchased goods and $750 for goods furnished by the home farm. Home-furnished goods included home-raised food and fuel and the rental value of the farmer's dwelling. Food. — Much the largest item in the value of the goods used by these farm homes was food, which was worth $726, or 43 per cent of the total. About two-thirds of the value of the food was supplied by the home farm. The value of this food was assumed to be what it would bring if sold in the neighborhood. The home-produced food included most of the meat eaten, especially pork and poultry, nearly all the dairy products, the greater part of the vegetables, and some of the fruit. A quantitative study of the food consumed in these farm homes showed an abundant and hearty diet with plenty of meat, potatoes, milk, eggs, and cereal pro - ducts, but a possible shortage of green vegetables during the winter. 14 Clothing. — The average cost of clothing in the 340 homes was $202, or twelve per cent of the total family expenditure. This ligure includes the value of the materials and paid labor used for home-made clothing, but does not include the 11 Kirkpatrick, E. L. The Farmers' Standard of Living. U. S. Dept. Agr., Bui. 1466, p. 58. 192G. "Rankin. J. O. Cost of Feeding the Nebraska Farm Family. Nebr. Aur Exd Sta. Bui. 219. pp. 9 and 12-32. 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 value of the sewing labor of the women of the household because this is very hard to estimate. In 328 homes which particularized clothing costs, the average cost of clothing per person was $49. Men's and boys' clothing costs averaged $47 per person, rising from $14 for boys one and two years old to $85 for single men from 22 to 25 years old, and sink - ing to $40 for men of 60 years and older. Each man or boy over eleven years ol'd bought during the year an average of about four shirts, four pairs of overalls, two and one - half pairs of shoes, one and one-half hats, and smaller quanti - ties of other garments. Women's and girls' clothing costs in these 328 homes averaged $52 per person, rising from $13 for girls one and two years old to $132 for single women from 22 to 25 years old, and sinking to $38 for women of 60 years and older. More than half the cost of the women's clothing was for outer garments, mainly dresses, coats, and hats; nearly one-fourth was for footwear, and the rest for under - garments and accessories. 15 Rental value of house. — The rental value of the farmers' dwellings was assumed to be ten per cent of the value of the house, which was estimated as replacement cost minus depreciation. This rental value amounted to $204, or 12 per cent of the total family expenditure. A detailed study of housing conditions on these farms showed relatively little house and room overcrowding but a considerable shortage of such modern household conveniences as running water, baths, furnaces, and electricity, and especially of modern sanitary sewage disposal* systems." 1 Nebraska farm homes in general showed a notable increase in modern household conveniences between 1920 and 1930. Ir . Furniture and furnishings. — Furniture and furnishings were bought during the year to a value of $43 per home, or three per cent of the total family expenditure. This in - cluded lamps, rugs, draperies, house-keeping equipment furniture, and musical instruments. Operation goods. — Operation goods at $239 were one of the principal items in the value of family living, and amounted to fourteen per cent of its total. The chief opera - tion items were an annual automobile cost of $124 per home and a fuel cost of $96. In addition, operation goods included household cleaning supplies, telephone, postage, express, &lt;5»«* n | ki^« J " °" f O8 ,n ",', Clot . hin * the Nebraska Farm Family. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 248, pp. 6, 10-13 and 16. Costs per person and per family in Iiulletin 248 were based upon the 328 homes which itemized clothing costs and excluded Homes lor which only a lump sum for all clothing was recorded. "Hankin. J. O. Housing and House Operation Costs on Nebraska Farms Nebr Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 2G4. 1931. • "Nebraska Agricultural Statistics, 1920-1930. Published annually by the Nebr State Dept. Agr. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes hired household help, laundry, ice, and insurance on furni - ture, but these items cost little. The automobile costs in - cluded interest at five per cent of the value of the car, de - preciation at twelve per cent, license fees, gasoiine, oil, tires, and repair costs. Nine-tenths of the families studied had automobiles, which were valued at $209 per farm or $199 per car, since several families had two or more cars. A little less than half the value of the fuel used for heat and light was supplied by wood and corn cobs raised on the home farm. Coal and kerosene. were the principal fuels purchased. Health. — The health costs averaged $73, or four per cent of the total family expenditure. They included dental work, oculists' fees and glasses, doctors' fees and medicines, hospital and nursing costs, fare to and from physician or hospital, and funeral expenses. Advancement. — The amount spent for advancement and recreation averaged $91, or five per cent of the total expendi - ture. The principal items under thi3 heading were $29 per home for organizations, chiefly the church; $27 for recrea - tion, including moving pictures, social affairs, vacations, and sports or hobbies ; $20 for school costs excepting school taxes ; and $10 for reading matter. 11 * Other goods.— Personal goods worth $48 were bought during the year. This included such costs as jewelry, candy, tobacco, gifts, and toilet articles. Payments on life and health insurance amounted to $50 per home. Unclassified costs amounted to $6 per home. TENURE AND THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING Value of living, by tenures. — -Part-owners had higher expenditures than any other tenure group. They spent $2,057 per family during the year studied, while owners spent $1,655, tenants $1,594, and hired men only $972 per family. The part-owners had the largest expenditures because they had the largest households and the most valuable farms, and because they were mostly at an age when both their earning power and their demands were relatively large. Part-owners spent more than any other tenure for food, clothing, rent, furnishings, operating costs, health, and insurance. Owners spent more than any other tenure for advancement. A few owners' sons and daughters who were in college and were being wholly or in part supported by their parents increased the advancement costs for the entire tenure. The personal costs of owners were also higher than in any other tenure. The health costs of owners were only $48 per family less 18 Rankin, J. O. The Use of Time in Farm. Homes. Nebr. Aur. Exp. Sta. Bui. 230. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 TABLE 10. — Average value of family living in 340 Nebraska farm homes, by tenure groups ■- All Part- Hired Item tenures_ Owners owners Tenants men Number of homes reporting 340 113 60 159 | 8 Value | . All goods used $1,681 $1,655 $2,057 $1,594 | $972 Food 726 680 871 716 I 471 Clothing 202 200 248 . 191 | 103 Rental value of house \....\ 204 226 246 176 127 Furniture &amp; furnishings - 43 40 53 42 I 38 Operation 3 239 238 . 271 \ 234 113 Health 73 48 117 74 58 Advancement 4 91 120 I 111 67 I. 22 Personal^ ] 4 g 55 | 52 42 | 33 Insurance 0 ..I 50 46 I 85 43 I 7 Unclassified I 5 2 3 9 1 0 Purchased goods [ 931 906 1,152 882 | 587 Furnished by farm 1 750 . 749 | 905 I 712 | 385 I I I Percentage distribution | P. ct. \ P. ct. | P. ct. P. ct. ! P. ct. All goods used :... 100.0 100.0 I 100.0 100.0 | 100.0 Food : | 43.2 41.1 | 42.4 45.0'. 48.5 Clothing . 12.0 12.L | 12.0 I 12.0 ! 10.6 Rental value of house C. 12.1 13.7 | 11.9 i 11.0 I 13.1 Furniture &amp; furnishings -I 2.6 2.4 | 2.6 ! 2.G 1 3.9 Operations ] 14.2 | 14.4 | 13.2 \ 14.6 11.7 Health I 4.3 | 2.9 5.7 i 4.7 ! 5.9 Advancement * .....I ■ 5.4 7.3 ! 5.4 I 4.2 , 2.2 AH other , I 6.2 6.1 I 6.8 I .5.9 ! 4.1 Purchased goods I 55.4 | 54.7 56.0 I 55.4 60.4 Furnished by farm ,| 44.6 1 45.3 44.0 ! 44.6 i 39.6 1 Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. 3 Purchased during year. 3 Includes fuel, household supplies, automobile and telephone costs, postage, ex - press, freight, hired household help, laundry, ice, and insurance on furniture and equipment. * Includes school, reading matter, church, organization dues* donations, and re - creation costs. j * Includes such costs as jewelry, candy, tobacco, gifts, and toilet articles. * Life and accident. than for any other tenure. Tenants averaged less than part - owners for every item of expenditure except unclassified costs, but spent more than owners for food, furnishings, and health. Percentage distribution of expenditures, by tenures. — The percentage of the value of family living devoted to food increased from owners to part-owners, tenants, and married hired men in the order named. Owners used 41 per cent of their total outgo for food and the married hired men 49 per cent. It is a general observation that those in easier economic circumstances assign a smaller share of their total expendi- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes p*R7 . —I^_ M _1_^__^^_1 [ I "° s °° ™° '■ W 5» doo g«o too — ■ roon Hootmng Srent 0D«j«noN 0hc*L-m HUKS}?*" 13*"- Fic 5.— Average value of family living in 340 Nebraska farm homes, by tenure groups. tures to food than those in harder circumstances, but the larger households of part-owners required a relatively large food consumption. The proportion of the value of family living devoted to advancement decreased from owners to part - owners, tenants, and hired men in the order named- and the proportion devoted to house rent decreased from owners to part-owners and tenants. Other percentages did not vary much between tenures. EXPENDITURE CROUP AND THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING Value of living, by expenditure groups.— The average value of family living trebled between the group of homes spending under $1,200 and that spending $2,400 and more, as shown in Table 11; but not all items increased at the same rate. Operation costs were only twice as high in the upper - most expenditure group as in the lowest, while clothing costs were four times as high, health costs and advancement costs more than six times as high, and furniture costs ten times as I a- A he e3 l treme o rang . e of familv livin S costs in the homes t7 U o£ d - WaS fr ° m $555 in a tenant home in Clay County to $7,355 in a part-owner home in Kimball County. The in - comes of these farm families were not learned, so it is im - possible to say how closely the variations in expenditure cor - responded with variations in income. Percentage distribution of expenditures.— The value of food and operation goods formed decreasing percentages of the total value of family living as the latter increased The cost of clothing, furniture, health, and advancement required increasing percentages. The percentage devoted to othlr </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 Table 11. — Average value of family living in 340 Nebraska farm homes, by expenditure groups Value, in group spending Distribution, in group spendii^ 7 " Item $2,400 ; ! spMon 2?itl «Ho»' I 1 ' 800 " ond Under «.200- $l.!)00. and $1,200 $1.799 $2.399 more $1.2P0 $1,799 $2,399 more Number of homes " p. cU p. cL j p t \ p ( reporting 83 132 89 36 .... I All goods used I $ 974|$1,499 $2,069 $3,022 100.0 100.0 100.0' 100 0 0 .** 450| .661 907 1,152 46.2 44.1 43.8 1 38&gt;T Clothing 93 178 263 388 9.6 11.8 12.7' 12.8 Rental value of | | • | house i | 133: 171| 263 339! 13.6 11.4 12 7 112 Furniture and ■ i , furnishings-' 11 35 56 116 1.1 2.3 2 7 3 8 Operations 163| 230 283 341 16.8 15.3 13.7; il3 Health 27 66 80 188 2.8 4.4 3.8i o'3 Advancement * 37 74 101 254 3.8 5.0 4 9 84 Personal 5 ........ 30 38 56 103 3.0 2.6 2*7 i 34 Insurance 0 30 44 58 104 3.1 2.9 •&gt; 8| 3*4 Unclassified .0 3 2 37 0.0 0.2 0 1! 12 Purchased goods.. 495 826 1,142 1,796 50.9 55.1 55 2! 59*4 Furnished goods.. 479 673 927 1,2261 49.1| 44.9| 44.8' 40^6 1 Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. * Purchased during year. 'Includes fuel, household supplies, automobile and telephone costs, postage, express freight, hired household help, laundry, ice, and insurance on furniture and equipment' Includes school, reading matter, church, organization dues, donations, and recreation ■Includes such costs as jewelry, candy, tobacco, gift*, and toilet articles * Life and accident. RCT.I .... I 1 fRCT" -^jjj- 1 .GOOOS njRNISHEDBY r ARM . - •40 : '. — ■ — 4q. 30 — ~^_ — : : v, " ■ RENT AND OPERATION so : 1 — _ : — — IT 2C ■ "advancement SI I . I lo j JNDERSI200 £ 1200-1799 SlflOO-2399 $2400 AND MORE Fig. 6. — Percentage distribution of the value of family living- in 340 Nebraska farm homes, by expenditure groups. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes living costs varied little or irregularly between the expendi - ture groups. The proportion of purchased goods increased from 51 per cent of all goods used by the homes spending under $1,200 to 59 per cent of the homes spending $2,400 and more. . SIZE OF FAMILY AND THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING Value of living, by number of children. — The number of children living at home exercises a very important effect up - on the family expenditures. In the Nebraska farm families studied, the total value of family living increased with each additional child residing at home. The increase was most rapid up to three and above five children. Expenses increased from $1,285 in homes with no children to $1,896 in homes with four children, decreased to $1,818 in homes with five children, and then jumped to $2,333 for six children and $3,007 for seven or more. As shown in Table 12, the cost of food and clothing had a definite correlation with the num - ber of children living at home, while the cost of operation goods, health, and advancement showed more or less correla - tion. The cost of food and clothing increased with each additional child, but that of advancement showed no definite increase until six-child homes were reached. [Doubtless these large families contained more adolescent sons and daughters whose recreation costs and school costs would naturally be higher than those of younger children. Rent, furniture, in - surance, and unclassified costs showed no definite correlation with the number of children in the household. XXJ-ARS 0 400 800 1200 1)500 2000 3400 ZPOO 3£0O C X I'-*-! II t f J"I r't III It^Nj^^^S^tJ^ r p f I III!**.* - ■ I" *l ■^^■■^^^^■■■■■■■■■^■■■^dxx iii.iilili.iury*wvw\r x j^j mi- ■ • •, i 30U.ARS O 4OO BOO 1200 1)500 ?P00 : 3400 2P0O VOO Fig; 7. — Average value of family living in 340 Nebraska farm homes, l&gt;y number of children residing at home. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Experiment Station. Bulletin 267 Table 12. — Average value of family living in 340 Nebraska farm homes, by number of children per household Children living at home Item \ 7 and 0 I 1 I 2 3 4 5 6 more i : j Number of homes reporting 65 76 71 56 35 17 61 14 Value I All goods used ?1,285|$1,466!$1,668 ?1,847 $1,896 $l,818!$2,333!$3,007 Food 505 1 621 710 819 845 877 1,037 1,384 Clothing ., 1261 159 204 217 240 231 487 436 Rental value of I house i I 1941 175 1 193 226 240 189 1 230 i 256 Furniture and I . )•■' furnishings 2 32 26 49 51 43 40 31 i 29 Operation 3 224 235 247 238 241 2461 2331 304 Health 49 62 77 109 911 55f 132 i 113 Advancement 4 73 84 88 791 931 72! 118! 276 Personal 5 43 44 45 57 1 47 f 431 56 70 Insurance 8 36 44 53 471 561 65 1 9 137 Unclassified 3 16 2 4l 0] 0| . 0 2 Purchased goods.. 714| 834 935| 1,007 1,016! -9961 1,310 1,633 Furnished by farm 571 1 632 733} 840 880! 8221 1,023 1,374 Percentage - I ■ I | distribution P. ct. I P. ct. I', ct. | P. ct. I P. ct. P. ct. ' P. ct. ' P. ct. All goods used......| 100.01 lOO.Of 100.0| 100.0| 100.0! 100.0* 100.0 1 100.0 Food .... 39.3 42.5| 42.6| 44.4 44.61 48.3 41.4 46.0 Clothing 9.8 10.8! 12.21 H-8 12.7! 12.6 20.9 14.5 Rental value of house 1 15.11 11.91 11.5| 12.21 12.7! 10.3 9.9 8.5 Furniture and I ■ furnishings- 2.5 1.8) 3.0| 2.71 2.3! 2.2! 1.3 1.0 Operation 3 17.5 16.01 14.81 12.91 12.71 13.5! 10.0 • 10.1 Health 3.7 4.2 4.6 ' 5.9 1 4.81 3.01 5.6' 3.7 Advancement 4 5.7 5.7 5.3 4.3 4.91 4.11 • 5.1 1 9.3 All other 6.4 7.1 6.0 5.8 5.3 1 6.01 2.8 6.9 Purchased goods.. 55.2 56.9 56.1 54.5 53.6 54.8] 56.2' 56.0 Furnished by farm 44.8 43.1 43.9 45.5 1 46.4 45.21 43.8 ' 44.0 1 Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. . ''Purchased during year. 3 Includes fuel, household supplies, automobile and telephone costs, postage, ex - press, freight, hired household help, laundry, ice, and insurance on furniture and equipment. • Includes school, reading matter, church, organization dues, donations, and re - creation costs. * Includes such costs as jewelry, candy, tobacco, gifts, and toilet articles. ' Life and accident. Percentage distribution of expenditures, by number of children. — Food and clothing demanded increasing per - centages of the total value., of family living as the number of children in the household increased. The food percent- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes ■SO — _ 50 40 J -^---**' ; 40 § 3 °"*^!*"Ij^&gt;g^_ — »| ALL.OTHE t i 's* "*" 10 -"clothing 1 ma ■ - - ~^^ c ACVANCEM INT 0 I 'I 2 | 3 | 4 | j | 6 |7ORM3RE CHILDREN LIVING AT HOME Fig. 8. — Percentage distribution of the value of family living in 340 Nebraska farm homes, by number of children residing at home. age, however, did not increase much with increase in number of children after the three-child homes, while the clothing percentage kept on increasing up to the six-child homes. Rent and operation goods formed decreasing percentages of the total value of family living as the number of children in - creased. The number of children appeared to make no differ - ence in the proportion of goods furnished by the home farm. ACE OF OPERATOR AND THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING Value of living, by age of operator. — The age of the farm operator is closely correlated with the size and age of his family, his saving and spending needs, and even with the type of satisfactions he desires. It therefore exerts an in - fluence upon his family expenditures, as regards both their total amount and their distribution. As shown in Table 13, the value of family living rose from only $1,242 in the Nebraska farm homes studied where the operator was under 25 years old, to a peak of $1,904 in homes where he was from 45 to 54 years old. Above this it declined to $1,273, or almost its starting point, in the homes of operators over 64 years. The value of family living was low among young farmers with small families and among elderly farmers whose children had grown up and left home. It was high in the homes of middle-aged farmers because of larger families and more adolescent children making large demands for expendi - ture. Probably the middle-aged farmers also had a higher earning capacity than their juniors and elders, and where adolescent children were present in the home, these doubtless increased the family income as well as its outgo. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 TABLE 13. — Average value of family living in 339 Nebraska farm homes, by age of operator ' Age of operator Item .. Under I 25-31 | 35-44 I 45-54 | 55-64 I 65 yrs. 2o yrs. | yrs. | yrs. I yrs. 1 yrs. -I &amp; more No. of families reporting. :| 10 i 90 | 107 72 I 40 20 Value | ■ | All goods used i $1,242 \ '$1,442 j $1,787 I $1,904 I $1,806- SI 273 Food | 444 ! 638 ! 783 I 832 ' 743 534 Clothing | 160 1 169 1 207! 258 ! 209 125 Rental value of | house a | 146 I 163 J 212 ! 220 ! 264 191 Furniture and •} j ■ - furnishings 3 .. 94 I 24' | 42 54 i 32 18 Operation ■• 250 | 222 , 248 | 254 I 245 193 Health 38 I . s)4 I 76 i 55 ! 69 58 Advancement ■'■ ..I 56 I 50 | 81 I 138 i 147 62 Personal" 31 39 | 45 I 50 I 61 75 Insurance 7 16 43 | 79 I 39 ' 35 17 Unclassified | 7. 0 ! 14 I 4 1 0 Purchased goods.... | 783 I 804 991 ' 1,040 97S 679 Furnished by farm I 459 ! 638 ; 796 | 864 8°8 55)4 Percentage distribution P. ct: : P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct All goods used | 100.0 ! 100.0 100.0 100.0 100 0 100 0 Food 35.7 | 44.2 I 43.8 43.7 41.1 IU!) Clothing 12.8 ! 11.7 ■ 11.6 13.6 110 ug Rental value of | housed | 11.8 i 11.3 ; 11.9 11.5 14.G 1.11 Furniture and | ■ 1 furnishings 3 I 7.5 I 1.7 -! 2.4 ' 2.8 IS 14 Operation * ! 20.1 1 15.4 \ 13.9 i 13.3 13.6 'lo'l Health I 3.1 I 6.5 4.2 I 2.9 . i 3.S 4 6 Advancement r &gt; ..■ 4.5 | 3.5 ' 4.5 ! 7.3 ; 8 2 4 9 All other I ' 4.5 I 5.7 ! 7.7 ! 4.9 ' 5.3 7' 2 Purchased goods....! 63.0 I . 55.8 | . 55.6 ! 54.6 I 54 2 53 3 Furnished by farml 37.0 1 44.2 &lt;■ 44.4 • 45.4 ' 45.8 46.7 1 Where the operator's age was not Kiven. he was assumed to be three years older than his wife. See Table 2. 3 Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. 1 Purchased during year. •Includes fuel, household supplies, automobile and telephone costs, postatre. ex - press, freieht, hired household help, laundry, ice, and insurance on furniture and equipment. • Includes school, reading matter, church, organization dues, donations and re - creation costs. •Includes such costs as jewelry, candy, tobacco, cifts. and toilet articles. ' Life and accident. The costs of food, clothing, and operation goods attained a peak in the homes of farmers aged from 45 to 54 years. The rental value of the house and the amount spent for advance - ment attained their peak in the group just o'der, where the </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes operator was from 55 to 64 years old. Furniture costs were highest in the homes of operators under 25 years old, be - cause most homes in this group had quite recently set up housekeeping; but they attained a secondary peak in the homes of operators from 45 to 54 years. Health costs showed a special form of variation. Lowest in the youngest age group, they jumped to $94 in the 25-to-34 year group, sank gradually to $55 in the 45-to-54 year group, and rose slightly after that. Undoubtedly maternity costs of the operator's wife were mainly responsible for the high health costs in homes where the operator was from 25 to 44 years old. Per - sonal costs were higher in each successive age group than in the group just younger. Insurance costs reached a peak in the homes of operators from 35 to 44 years old. OOU.ARS 0 ISO SOO ISO 1000 I2JQ IJOQ nso 20QO DOU-ABS 0 ISO SOO 7J0 1000 I2SO 1500 17.50 2000 Brooo HJojotwc BIremt HSBy*' Fig. 9. — Average value of family living in 339 Nebraska farm homes, by age of operator. Percentage distribution of expenditures, by age of opera - tor. — The most marked correlation of age with the percent - age distribution of expenditures was found in the proportion of goods purchased, which decreased from 63 per cent of the value of all goods used in the homes of operators under 25 years old to 53 per cent in the homes of operators over 64 years old. The older farmers got relatively more of their living from the home farm. Food required a slightly larger share of the total family expenditure in the homes of farmers from 25 to 54 years old than in the homes of those older and younger. Operation costs required a larger share in age groups under 35 and over 64 years; the differences between age groups in the percentage of the total expenditure devoted to other items were slight or irregular. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 LOCALITY AND THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING Local variations.— The four .localities studied showed characteristic variations in the value of family living and in the distribution of costs. These were due in part to varia - tions in the productivity and character of the farms and in part apparently to social conditions in the local commun - ity. The farms of the two easternmost areas, located in Washington and Lancaster Counties, resembled one another in most particulars, but the Clay and Kimball County farms were divergent. Washington County area.^The farms studied in Wash - ington County averaged 147 acres, or almost exactly the size of the average farm in the county as recorded by the 1925 census. The value per farm studied was estimated at $27,770 or a little more than the 1925 census figure of $23,057, based on all farms in the county. The average number of persons per farm on both survey and census farms was 4.5. 1 ' 1 The farms studied, therefore, appear to have been reasonably typical of the county so far as the indications go. The total value of family living on these farms was $1,910, or more than in any other three areas. Nearly half was furnished by the home farm. The value of food, advancement costs, and personal costs were higher in the Washington County area than in any of the others. Life insurance costs were lower in this area than in the others. Lancaster County area. — The farms studied in Lancas - ter County were considerably larger and more valuable than the average farm in the county as reported by the 1925 census. The survey farms averaged 221 acres, worth $37,106, the census farms 154 acres, worth $20,268. The survey households also were a little larger — 4.5 persons as compared with 4.2 persons. 20 It seems reasonable to suppose, there - fore, that the value of family living may have been some - what higher in the homes studied than in the average Lan - caster County farm home. It averaged $1,793, of which 45 per cent was furnished by the home farm. The rental value of the house, furniture costs, and operation costs were higher in this area than in the other three studied, indicating that the families in this locality took especial satisfaction in im - proving and maintaining their dwellings. Clay County area. — The Clay County farms studied averaged 199 acres, worth $24,783, or a little larger and more valuable than the average farm in the county, which consisted of 194 acres, worth $19,848, according to the 1925 "XI. S. Census of Art-.. 1925, Part I, pp. 1133, 1147. and 11S3 "Ibid., pp. 1129, 1142, and 1180. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes Table 14. — Average value of family living in 34.0 Nebraska . farm homes, by counties • I • All County in which homes are located Item j homes L Wash- Lan- I I 1 ington caster Clay I Kimball Number of homes 340 | ■ 79 99 84 78 Value All goods used | $1,681 i $1,910 $1,793 $1,283 $1,736 Food i 726 865 737 548 763 Clothing ...: ! 202 214 188 142 271 Rental value of house 1 1 204 242 264 125 172 Furniture and furnishings- | 43 -19 61 26 32 •Operation :l I 239 252 272 209 | 217 Health ! 73 66 75 51 101 AdvancenVent 4 ...| . 91 101 90 84 91 Personal"' t 48 67 52 I 29 | 43 Insurance" | 50 36 50 69 I 46 Unclassified j 5 18 4 0 0 Purchased goods 931 973 984 719 1,048 Furnished by farm 750 937 810 564 688 Percentage distribution P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. j P. ct. All goods used | 100.0 100.0 | 100.0 100.0 | 100.0 Food | 43.2 | 45.0 | 41.1 42.6 | 43.9 Clothing i 12.0 11.2 I 10.5 11.1 | 15.6 ■..' Rental value of house' I 12.1 12.7 14.7 9.8 9.9 Furniture and furnishings- I 2.6 2.6 3.4 2.1 1.8 Operation :! j 14.2 13.3 15.2 16.3 12.5 Health I 4.3 3.4 f 4.2 4.0 5.9 Advancement 4 ,. I 5.4 5.3 5.0 6.5 1 5.2 All other ! 6.2 6.3 5.9 7.6 | 5.2 Purchased goods...: j 55.5 50.9 54.8 56.0 | 60.4 Furnished by farm i 44.6 49.1 | 45.2 44.0 | 39.6 ' Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. 3 Purchased during year. ' Includes fuel, household supplies, automobile and telephone costs, postage, ex - press, freight, hired household help, laundry, ice, and insurance on furniture and equipment. ' ' * Includes school, reading matter, church, organiration dues, donations, and re - creation costs. • Includes such costs as jewelry, candy, tobacco, gifts, and toilet articles. ' Life and accident. census.-' The households studied averaged 4.3 persons or smaller than in any of the other three areas studied. It happened that these homes contained an unusually large pro - portion of elderly couples whose children had left home and whose, wants accordingly were few. The value of family "Ibid., pp. 1124, 1137, and 1177. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 living in this area was $1,283, or lower than in any other area studied. Less was spent in this area than in any other studied for each of the main items in family living except life insurance, for which the Clay County homes expended more than those of other areas. Kimball County area. — The farms studied in Kimball County averaged 746 acres, worth $16,106. They were slightly larger and less valuable than the average Kimball County farm, which consisted of 733 acres, worth $16,310, according to the 1925 census. The households on the farms studied were much larger than the average for the county, for they contained 4.8. persons as compared with only 4.0 per - sons on the census farms. 22 The value of family living was $1,736 per home in this area. Only 40 per cent of it was furnished by the home farm, or a smaller proportion than in any other area. These Kimball County farms are in a dry-farming region devoted mainly to extensive small-grain farming; the scanty rainfall severely limits the amount of home-produced vegetables, dairy products, and fuel. More was spent for clothing and health in this area than in any other studied. The relatively large health costs were due mainly to the. larger families in this area, but possibly there was also more ill health per person. A previous survey has indicated that the number of days of illness per family and per person increases from the southeastern part of the state to the northwestern part. There was more house overcrowd - ing in this Kimball County area than in the others and the working day averaged a full hour longer — conditions which may be supposed to put a strain upon the health of the family; 23 VALUE OF FARM AND THE VALUE OF FAMILY LIVING Value of living, by value of farm.^The value of the family living of owners and part-owners showed some cor - relation with the value of their farms, according to Table 15; but this correlation was less pronounced than that with the size of the family. The value of family living did not vary much in the three groups of homes occupying farms worth respectively under $10,000, from $10,000 to $19,999, and from $20,000 to $29,999. Above this point the family expenditures increased more rapidly and reached $2,545 per home on farms worth more than $50,000. The expenditures of tenants showed less correlation with the value of the farms they operated than in the case of owners and part-owners. "Ibid., pp. 1129, 1142, and 1180. PP. ?l!n k d n 2lf'i?28 The USB °' T ' me ' n Farm Home *- Nebr - A «- E *P- St«- Bui. 230. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes Table 15. — Average value of family' living in homes of 105 . Nebraska farm ovmers and 57 -part-owners, by estimated _value of farm ' Estimated value of farm Item * .-■■;' Under I $10,000- $20,000- $30,000- $40,000-| $50,000 __ ' $10,000 1 $19,999 $29,999 $39.999 $49,999 1 &amp; more I : i i i No. of families j reporting I 31 I. 29 51 18 17 16 Value 1 ; ' All goods used | $1,596 |. $1,476 $1,680 $1,968 $2,153 | $2,545 Food.... ! 700 619 715 I 821 I 875 996 Clothing j 214 162 205 218 f 300 307 Rental value of : house- j 203 | 183 204 320 | 262 \ 350 Furniture and !'■••■ I furnishings 3 39 I 15 65 I 79 I • 46 j 25 Operation * | 220 236 237 | 234 j 292 I 307 Health j 56 124 52 | 48 | 62 I 54 Advancement"' .J 71 65 105 | 116 | 190 j 259 Personal 0 1. 40 46 46 I 54 ! 65 I 85 Insurance 7 49 . 26 49 76 | 49 I 162 Unclassified 4 0 2 2 j 12 I 0 Purchased goods.... I 868 812 926 | 1,002 i 1,212 | 1,438 Furnished by farm 728 664 754 I 966 I 941 | 1,107 Percentage distribution I P.ct. I P. ct. \ P.cl. ': P.ct. I P. ct. \ P.ct. All goods used ! 100.0 ! 100.0 | 100.0 ! 100.0 | 100.0 I 100.0 Food 1 43.8 I 41.9 I 42.6 I 41.7 I 40.6 I 39.1 Clothing ! . 13.4 I 11.0 I 12.2 | 11.1 | 13.9 I 12.1 Rental value of I house- i 12.8 I 12.4 | 12.2 I 16.2 | 12.2 | 13.7 Furniture and furnishings » " ! ■ 2.4 I 1.0 I 3.8 i 4.1 j 2.1 j 1.0 Operation •» ! 13.8 ! 16.0 | 14.2 I 11.9 | 13.6 | 12.1 Health I 3.5 ! 8.4 3.1 I 2.4 2.9 I 2.1 Advancement 5 ..| 4.4 I 4.4 6.2 I 5.9 8.8 I 10.2 All other I 5.9 I 4.9 5.7 | 6.7 I 5.9 | 9.7 Purchased goods....! 54.4 | 55.0 55.1 ! 50.9 | 56.3 | 56.5 Furnished by farm] 45.6 | 45.0 44.9 | 49.1 | 43.7 I 43.5 1 The estimated value of the part-owner farms includes both owned and rented land. 'Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. 3 Purchased during year. 4 Includes fuel, household supplies, automobile and telephone costs, postage, ex - press, freight, hired . household help, laundry, ice, and insurance on furniture and equipment. 1 Includes school, reading matter, church, organization dues, donations, and re - creation costs. * Includes such costs as jewelry, candy, tobacco, gifts, and toilet articles. 1 Life and accident. Percentage distribution of expenditures, by value of farm. — The proportion of the total value of family living devoted to food, operation goods and health decreased in geii- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 0OU.APS O 4Q0 aOO BOO 1000 2PQQ 24QQ C" |M I— W8&amp;&amp;S//A\\\V: ■:■■ 1 HFOOO gJoPERATON 5 1 ■ ■ ■ . . ■ . ■■ , -I., __ 5 4(Y)00 - 1 j DOLLARS O 400 600 (200 l&lt;300 2P0O 2*00 Fig. 10. — Average value of family living in homes of 105 Nebraska farm owners and 57 part-owners. eral from the owned and part-owned farms of low value to those of high value. The proportion devoted to advancement increased with considerable regularity from the farms of low value to those of high value. The proportion of the family living furnished by the home farm was greatest on farms of medium value (from $30,000 to $39,999). COMPARISONS Nebraska farm family expenditures compared with those in eleven states. — The Nebraska farm homes studied used goods worth about $83 more per home than those used by the 2,886 families studied by E. L. Kirkpatrick in eleven states, as shown in Table 16. The Nebraska average was very slightly lower than that for the homes studied in four New England states and higher than that for the homes in four Southern states and three North Central states. The value of the home-produced goods was greater on the Ne - braska farms than in any of the three geographic districts just mentioned. The Nebraska homes averaged more for food and insurance, and less for. clothing and advancement than the homes in any of the three geographic districts. The difference in advancement costs lay almost wholly in the cost of formal education, which averaged $20 for the Nebraska farm homes and $38 for the 2,886 farm families. This does not necessarily imply that Nebraska farm children get less schooling than those elsewhere. The Nebraska public grade schools supply their pupils with free text-books and school supplies, while even the high schools supply text-books. This is not the case in some of the other states. The health and operation costs in the Nebraska homes were considerably </seg>
            <seg id="p035">• Standard of Living in Nebraska Farm Homes above the average for all 2,886 homes although not above the average for every district. Apparently the Nebraska families take more satisfaction in abundant food and less in clothing than the farm families studied by Kirkpatrick. Owners and tenants. — -Owner homes in Nebraska spent $77 more per home for family living than the owner homes studied by Kirkpatrick in eleven states. These figures in - clude both owner and part-owner homes for comparability with the Kirkpatrick study. The Nebraska tenant homes spent $247 more than the tenant homes studied by Kirk - patrick. They spent more than those tenants for every item of the family living except clothing. It seems clear that the Nebraska tenants are able to maintain a higher standard of Table 16. — Average value of family living in 340 Nebraska farm homes compared with 2,886 homes in eleven states 1 j tem Nebr. 2,886 farm homes in 11 states farm New Southern I No. Cent. homes All England States 1 States .:-.-. ; . 7 .. I I . ■ Number of families reporting . 340 2,886 317 1,130 1,439 All goods used $1,681 $1,598 $1,692 $1,551 $1,613 Food 726 659 707 691 623 Clothing 202 235 221 242 233 Rental value of house 2 204 200 204 156 233 Operation 3 239 213 255 194 219 Advancement 4 91 105 118 104 102 All other 219 186 187 164 203 Purchased goods 931 914 1,036 844 942 Furnished by farm 750 684 656 707 671 1 Kirkpatrick, E. L., The Farmers' Standard of Living. U. S. Dept. Agr. Bui. 1466. 1026, pp. 16-17. The New England homes were in New Hampshire, Vermont, Massachusetts, and Connecticut; the southern homes in' Kentucky, South Carolina, and Alabama: the North Central homes, in Missouri, Kansas, Iowa, and Ohio. 'Ten per cent of the estimated value of the house. * Includes fuel, household supplies, automobile and telephone costs, postage, ex - press, freight, hired household help, laundry, Ice, and insurance on furniture and equipment. ... * Includes school, reading matter, church, organization dues, donations, and re - creation costs. living, or at least of comfort, than the average American farm tenant. This is partly due to the relatively high value and earning power of the Nebraska tenant farms 24 and partly to the prevalence of a relatively high class of tenants. Kinsman tenancy is common in Nebraska, being one-third of "In Nebraska in 19ZE, the real estate value oif tenant farms was $18,675 per farm; of all farms, $19,760. In the entire United States at the same period, the real estate value of tenant farms was $6,840; of all farms, $7,764. U. S. Census of Agr., 1925, Summary Statistics, by States, pp. 4, 9, 16, and 22. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 267 all tenancy. All this indicates that there is no great economic or social gulf between farm tenant and owner in Nebraska, and these conditions are reflected in the family living costs. . CONCLUSIONS The average standard of living in the Nebraska farm homes studied appears to have been in nearly all if not all respects adequate for the maintenance of health but rather limited as to comforts and certainly far from luxurious. In a few homes the living standard dropped below the level of health; in a few it rose to the level of luxury. In the "average home the physical needs of the family seem to have been, on the whole, very well provided for, but its social needs somewhat scanted. The living standard was relatively high in the value of the food and operation goods consumed and relatively low in the value of clothing, education, and recreation, as com - pared with the standards of comparable American homes in the other surveys quoted. No doubt the scanting of these items was due in many cases to necessity and in other cases to a desire to save money for building up the farm business, yet these forces must have operated in the homes in other localities. " The size of the farm household appeared to have more effect upon the standard of living than any other factor studied. Owners and part-owners had somewhat higher living costs than tenants, but the difference was less in Nebraska than in some other localities. Owners and part-owners on the more valuable farms had somewhat higher living costs than those on the less valuable farms, but the correlation was only moderate. The four localities studied differed somewhat in the amount and distribution of their living costs. The opera - tor's schooling appeared to have little correlation with his standard of living, but the schooling of his children showed considerable correlation with the standard of living. The proportion of the value of living used for food and operation goods decreased with increasing total family expenditures ; the proportion spent for clothing, furniture, health, and advancement increased. [3M1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>