<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Turkey Production</title>
               <date value="1933-04">1933-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 280 April, 1933 Turkey Production F. E. MUSSEHL Department of Poultry Husbandry 's-6-l / -sJ BsssWtfl-irSsiysy Li.* _ ' . . V^ftrr // Fj / '? I* 1 r — f_m ~ -* r - #»».***- * flP ■*" .—■-« THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OTHER PUBLICATIONS This bulletin is a revision of Circular 34, on the same subject, and supersedes that circular. Much new material has been added. Other publications on related subjects are listed below. MusseM, F. E. 1932. Hatching Turkey Eggs. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bulletin No. 269. Hoff, Paul R., and Claybaugh, J. H. 1982. Shelter Sheds for Turkeys. Nebr. Ext. Circular No. 733. Redditt, J. R. 1932. Dressing, Grading, and Marketing Turkeys. Nebr. Ext. Cir - cular No. 1448. Van Es, L., and Martin, H. M. 1930. The More Important Poultry Diseases. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. . Bulletin 195 (Revised). Fig. I.— The distribution of turkey production m the United States. Each dot represents 50,000 birds or major fraction thereof-. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Turkey Production F. E. MUSSEHL Turkey production has increased during the past decade, the present supply being estimated at about 18,000,000 birds per year. This increase is due chiefly to better knowledge of the control of blackhead, as well as improved efficiency m other phases of the industry. Competition m turkey produc - tion is much more keen today than ten years ago, and pro - ducers will need to analyze the job carefully to determine which methods will result m the greatest profit for the par - ticular conditions that prevail. The experience of many successful producers justifies this program : 1. Keeping breeding stock confined to fenced areas. 2. The use of incubators for hatching. 3. Artificial brooding m clean houses with gravel, screen, or board flooring m the yards until the poults are eight weeks old. 4. Moving the poults to wire-enclosed roosting sheds on clean range after they are eight weeks old for the; rest of the growing period. 5. Full feeding a complete ration with special emphasis on green feed. 6. Use of every practical method of providing clean feed, clean water, and clean range. Many producers who are following this program are hatch - ing 25 poults for each hen m the breeding flock, and are rearing 85 per cent of the poults hatched, and this may be taken as the goal of achievement. SELECTION OF A BREED Six standard varieties of turkeys are now recognized, all of which are descended from the wild stocks which originally ranged over the eastern part of the United States from Maine to Florida. The standard shape and color description of these are given m the "Standard of Perfection" which is published by the American Poultry Association. Table 1. — Standard weights of the recognized breeds of turkeys | £ d / 2* codTu^r Cockerel I Hen (1 Pullet COC k iiof S# dULlem (lessthmn yr.or (leu than or over) °gnl?) '»■) over) 1 yr.) Pounds I Pounds I Pounds I Pounds Pounds Bronze 36 33 25 20 116 Bourbon Red 33 30 23 18 14 Narragansett 33 30 23 18 14 White Holland 33 30 23 18 14 Black 33 30 23 18 14 Slate 33 30 23 18 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 280 The choice of a breed is not as significant as is the selec - tion of vigorous individuals. During recent years a good demand has prevailed for birds weighing from ten to fifteen pounds dressed. If this demand continues the smaller breeds may grow in popularity. The development of a demand for half turkeys may on the other hand remove objections to the larger breeds. management of the breeding flock An analysis of the production job shows that the cost of poults represents about three-fourths as much as the feed cost, which is usually the largest item. The number of poults raised per breeder, therefore, materially influences turkey production costs. Quick maturity and desirable market type are also recognized as important factors in the management program. Selection of breeders. — Breeders should be selected early in the fall before the market stock is sold. Desirable quali - ties are early maturity, smooth feathering, blocky and well - balanced body type with a straight, well-fleshed keel bone. Smoothness of feather and proper balance of shanks and other parts of the body are the best indications of inherent vigor, which is the most valuable asset that any breeding bird can possess. Age of breeders. — Well-developed, early-hatched, young toms of the previous year's hatch are usually more satisfac - tory than older birds. Two- and three-year-old males lack energy, and are inclined to be somewhat slow and clumsy, with a resulting lower fertility. Exceptions to the use of young toms may, of course, be made when selecting for ex - hibition qualities, or when a bird of unusual breeding value has been discovered. The particular problem when large two - and three-year-old toms are used is to prevent injury to the backs of the hens. This hazard will be reduced if the spurs and toenails are trimmed back, and the ends are rounded with a file. Early-hatched, young hens also have some advantages as breeders, chiefly that they will start laying earlier and will generally lay more persistently. This at least has been the experience with birds of the Bronze variety which have been used most at the Experiment Station. One pen of two-year - old hens in one instance produced as many eggs as did pullets, but the hens had been very carefully selected from a much larger flock the previous year. Persistency in laying late in the summer, together with molting late in the fall, is as use - ful a guide in the selection of turkey hens for good laying ability as it is in selecting chicken hens. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Turkey Production Size of matings. — When breeding birds for standard quality one is almost required to make pen matings ofi one male to 14 or 15 hens. Such matings increase the housing, fencing, and labor overhead, and are justified only when better than average prices can be obtained for eggs, poults, or breed - ing stock. For market production under present conditions, it is almost imperative that flock matings be made. Our ex - perience during the past four years with a flock mating of 50 females and four males indicates that good fertility and hatchability can be obtained from flock matings if the males used have been raised together and are put with the females at the same time. If it is necessary to use birds from differ - ent flocks, they should be housed and yarded together for a week or ten days before being mated with the hens. Good fertility can be expected when one torn is provided for 12 to 15 hens. I Until more research work has been done on the problems of turkey breeding, producers will do well to practice j out - crossing as a regular policy. It is suggested that new blood be introduced from an unrelated flock each year unless seyeral matings are made so that rather distant relationships can be maintained. The purchase each spring of 50 to 100 [ eggs from a flock having the desired type and vigor will usually be the safest way to obtain new breeding stock. The p'oults hatched from the purchased eggs can be marked with a toe - punch so that they can be identified in the fall when the breeders are selected. Pullorum infection. — Up to the present this disease has not been a menace in Nebraska, but care should be taken to obtain hatching eggs only from flocks of good health and vigor. If in the future Pullorum infection should prove to be a problem, it will be advisable to use the same method of testing the turkey breeders that has proved practical for chicken breeding flocks. Housing the breeding flock. — Turkeys do not need ex - pensive houses. Some producers simply provide elevated roosts high enough off the ground so that dogs and [other prowling animals cannot reach them. This is the extreme of economy, and one may ask whether a little more protec - tion would not return good dividends in the way of earlier egg production as well as a higher annual production perj bird. At the University Experiment Station an inexpensive, single-wall house 20 x 20 feet in size with the south side almost entirely open has been used with success for four years. Fifty hens and four toms are accommodated in this </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 280 j^_*__\___________r____-_. sW R.-&gt; _—\ _— —————— tt—_. Hjm^k .... ' _e___\____\ _ *^'^__\_\_\_Wm^^^t\ZZ-—^- Bb___H H_a_B! Hb—Hu \TPt1 f"S' ;J :.~--i-. j &gt;'•'—— ~-_w_ri__r. _* ■ »aH)_SKfPVKi_l Fig. 2. — A house for the breeding flock. house, and with more roosts from 60 to 70 hens could be housed in this unit. The space beneath the roosts is wired with lawn fencing, so that the droppings pass through to the floor. This saves much labor because a reasonably sanitary environment is provided, even though the droppings are left to accumulate for several weeks. The same device is used under the roosts of the range sheds provided for growing turkeys. Butter tubs, candy pails, or similar containers serve very well for dry mash and oyster shells. Common 12-quart pails are satisfactory as water containers. An alfalfa rack will also be very useful unless alfalfa meal is used in the mash mixture. Nests may be placed outside the house to conserve space. Barrels or boxes about two feet square with some protection against rain or snow will serve. In connection with the house it is well to have a small graveled or cindered enclosed yard to which the breeders can be confined in wet weather. This precaution is suggested for the control of blackhead. Though the hazard from black - head losses is materially reduced with older birds, even mature stock is by no means immune, and it is well to keep the birds confined whenever water stands in low places. Yard requirements. — Most turkey breeding flocks still enjoy free range, but we may question whether the hatching eggs conserved by keeping the flock under control would not </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Turkey Production more than pay for the fencing required. Where plenty of land is available the allowance of one acre for a breeding flock of a hundred birds is suggested. If this yard is | culti - vated and planted to a forage crop, feed costs will be re - duced, soil sanitation maintained, and the fertility and hatchability of eggs improved. Rations for the breeders. — Fundamentally, turkey hens have the same nutritive requirements as chicken hens. Dur - ing the winter months preceding the breeding season the flock may be maintained on a grain and mash ration, using a mash with a I0w protein level. To stimulate earlier egg production, the protein level should be raised about January 1st and maintained throughout the breeding season. A simple mash mixture which has given excellent results may be made of: Pounds Yellow cornmeal 335 Shorts or ground wheat 200 Wheat bran 100 Pulverized oats or barley 100 Alfalfa meal (from green, leafy hay) 100 Meat meal , 150 Salt 10 Cod-liver oil or other suitable fish oil 5 1,000 If skimmilk or buttermilk is available the meat meal may be reduced to 50 pounds and the cornmeal raised to 440 pounds. If alfalfa hay is kept before the birds, the alfalfa meal may be eliminated. Alfalfa in some form should, how - ever, be included in the ration for breeders, at least pntil a liberal supply of green feed is available. Oyster siell or high calcium limestone grit should also be available at all times. Germinated oats or barley is also relished by breeding turkeys, and when time and facilities permit it is well to offer one feeding per day of either of these. Oats and barley may be germinated with little labor by immersing a partly filled sack in a barrel of water for six hours and then letting it drain, after which the grain should be stirred about) in the sack several times daily and sprinkled as needed to, main - tain the proper moisture for germination. In five days the sprouts should be from one-half to three-fourths of an inch long, and are then ready for feeding. Whole yellow corn, wheat, and barley may be used to sup - plement the mash and alfalfa already referred to as essential. Observations made at the University indicate that eight pounds of grain and seven pounds of mash were required per </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 280 bird per month in addition to the green feed which was avail - able in the yards during a good share of the breeding season. laying habits of the turkey hen Egg production is apparently influenced by the same fac - tors as affect the production of chicken hens. The lengthen - ing day and more favorable temperatures ordinarily start U ft n a £? ut March 20th in the latitude of Nebraska. With better than average housing, and with the feeding of a good laying mash beginning January 1st, egg production may be advanced several weeks. The use of lights from five ? i£ k in 2"* m ormng ""til daybreak has also been effective in stimulating early production. icJH^^.^.^i.k 8 * 01 " 11 * season ma y be taken to be July 1st. The distribution of expected production from March to i™ w rt U l dlCa^ d '2 T able ?' These data ™re obtained from two breeding flocks maintained each year at the Uni - versity. Table 2. — Turkey egg production Ye « leSkSH n° ate __ i E »" per hen S5T5 female, flmegg m,^ AprU , M&lt;|y J^~ j™? 1930 57 March 8 5\9 14?7 j 9« Tn 5ol — 1931 56 March 13 3 9 16 0 119 li 2n'f 1£§2? 60 March 1 15.2 gj | &amp;| igj gj 'TJiere were two flocks each year. ' •Ltehta used from five o'clock until daylight from February 1st to March 15th. iwES ° n r£z e e ? ect oJ L age of turke y e «« s on hatchability are J h , e obser vations of Scott 1 indicate that for best SS l 8ftS**y essa shoul &lt;? be hel * at temperatures of from to 60 . In one experiment the hatchability of turkev eggs declined very markedly after 14 days of holdinc while in another the hatchability of eggs held for 21 days remained 2S2.J5? ; «?"£ ma £ antl cipate that the condition of the breeders at the time the eggs are laid will have an influence on the retention of good hatching power when eggs are held. in practice it will not be good policy to hold turkey eggs kroger than 14 days but it is interesting to know that ef fl which have been held for 30 days have hatched. management of the market flock „«, I H tch £? the e «««.— Incubators are being more widely SSL?" JS™ reasons : first, a turkey hen's time is too valuable ?£_ L T? Sea u S0 ? to . w »Frant usmg her as a hatcher; second, the use of mcubators is the first step in a sanitation program Min N°o re 269 see Experiment Station Bui 1 Scott. H. M.. Poultru Science, Vol. XIII, No. 1, 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Turkey Production Brooding the poults. — Houses and equipment which have proved satisfactory for brooding chicks may be used for poults. On some farms the overhead of brooding equipment is reduced by using the same houses and stoves for brooding a unit of early chicks. This is feasible provided the jequip - ment is cleaned and disinfected before it is used for the poults. The question of how many poults to brood in one unit is, of course, important. Small units of from 100 to 150 poults are the most desirable, but to reduce equipment and) labor overhead larger units are used. For a 10 x 12 foot portable brooder house 150 poults may be considered the maximum. For a 10 x 20 foot unit in a permanent brooder house, such as is now being used by some growers, 250 poults may be suggested. One may estimate that approximately one square foot of floor space per poult should be provided. Even with this allowance, the house will need regular cleaning | every few days after the poults are four weeks old to maintain a sanitary environment. Coal-burning stoves, distillate stoves, and hot-water heat - ing plants are all being used successfully for brooding poults. When carefully installed, distillate stoves have proved, prac - tical, especially late in the season when a constant produc - tion of less heat is required. Battery brooders have also been used for starting poults. Regular chick batteries arej satis - r . / '■;• "■ — -' •• ■■•; t\ = /fl ~? nWitWIBMl jBHHWm r . /mF^- —-Hi PI pp"; [7 _ " I -Hfljli jWfth—^ i_\\ ■ ' V?a\_\Wri -V —rrr ; fl I \ li ■■■'■■■ tzfh III-*" ""Il't^Si i___V' ~^*~ "^ T *■ -fc .-'\N^|; r|T ■:]"■- '■-&gt;»HFiT'Tr:~-'~- "'ZA_____ ' ■ '-^ ! Fig. 3. — A double-unit brooder house which can be used to brood poults until they are eight weeks old. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 280 factory for the first two weeks, but after that time a little more freedom of movement than is provided by battery trays is desirable. Growing poults require a great deal of the rickets-prevent - ing factor, and for that reason provision should be made for exposure to direct sunshine as soon as possible. This is de - sirable even when the ration contains a liberal amount of vitamin D. A small pen attached to each brooding unit with the floor covered with three-fourths-inch-mesh hardware cloth will provide for direct sunshine exposure without the hazards of soil contamination. Graveled or sanded yards may also be used, but hardware-cloth floors will usually be more econom - ical in the long run. Rations and feeding practice. — In general poults and chicks have the same nutritive requirements. There is evi - dence, however, that poults have an even higher requirement for certain of the vitamin essentials than have growing chicks, although research work on turkey nutrition has been thus far only fragmentary. The growth rate of poults on good rations is even greater than that of chicks during the first eight weeks. I * --*B_I i __ i _8iim[sssssssssssssssssB aJJfliWs-l^ffiKJSV H| I FlG. 4. — Sour skimmilk can be fed in crock feeders, which are easily cleaned. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">/ Turkey Production Poults should be fed as soon as they are placed in the brooder house. A complete mash mixture offered in waste - proof, reel-protected feeders is the basis of good f eedingl prac - tice. If sour milk or buttermilk is available, these should by all means be used. Milk is especially useful during the first six weeks. Two formulas which have proved satisfactory are listed herewith with modifications recommended when skimmilk or buttermilk is available. These will average about 20 per cent protein when meat scraps of average protein level are! used. Mash mixtures with higher protein content will stimulate a more rapid growth, but this is probably inadvisable. Table 3. — Mash formulas for poults _ ______ _____ Ingredients No . 7 wUhjkim- Nq g with. kirn- buttermilk buttermilic Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds 1. Yellow cornmeal 310 410 310 410 2. Shorts or ground wheat 200 200 200 200 3. Bran 100 100 100 100 4. Pulverized oats or barley.... 100 100 100 100 5. Alfalfa meal (No. 1 quality) 100 100 100 100 6. Meat scraps or high-grade meat meal 100 50 50 25 7. Fish meal 0 0 50 25 8. Dried buttermilk 50 0 50 0 9. Pulverized limestone -or sifted oyster shell 20 20 20 20 10. Fine salt 10 10 10 10 11. Cod-liver or other suitable fish oil (not needed after the eighth week) 10 10 10 10_ 1,000 1,000 I 1,000 1,000 At least five feet of mash feeder space should be provided for each 100 poults. Two one-gallon founts or crocks per hundred poults are also desirable. Both the curd and whey of the sour milk are valuable, and should be used. Water should be provided also when skimmilk is fed. After the poults are eight weeks old they are usually well feathered, and the season is sufficiently advanced so that they can be moved to simple and inexpensive range shelterj sheds. Extension Circular No. 733 has plans for a range shelter shed with corral attached. The corral with a floor made of removable slatted frames, which permit the droppings to pass through to the ground, provides a sanitary place for the feed hoppers and water vessels. Confining the growing birds to </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 280 '7 7; • ' : ' '''■- '■■'■'. --.'■■ ' '' •;-'.-.'•' ■■ ■ - 7~- ■'' ■ /'•■■'.■■'.'. ■-.-. 7 ■ •' ■___••'^B^f?^^^^ • ] UmnQ * ■_■_■_■_*__■_■ QS_k^___^_i H_G_D Bti3^_ES-i&gt;i»V7V_hjV LVflfl_^^__H I V@f B^^^HBM^^F_P^_V9_^_-_U^_-^W &gt; _-_K_-_^_&amp;_-_k_l_^ S^^^K^i T_^H__l_^___WJ^__^_l_EjrH_ff__^_ t&amp; i ' «__E __■__! __B____Brt^ r j Lr*v''S?SS^«UflPPPfl __wi._\_____wk_\ w_\w__\\\\_^_\\_\__\ JSz^-jA r 'j «sa_H___S_^_S_SEBBa_3!9 !^CT__!_w!r ' -v- '^rUi^** M ~ M- *~ M *~ a, *"*&gt; "~ —«sJ»s~»— —_■*_»_ Jti___d_aJ_t fl_\__\m__*__V?_t\\*-_?r^ , *^J __^mJ FlG ' 5 *Tl,T^?^? 0U i tS / h0ul iJ lav ? __**** t0 a well-balanced dry mash. This simple feeder with a lath reel keeps the feed clean. the corral whenever water stands in ponds or puddles will prove an effective method of reducing blackhead losses and will be much less expensive than the use of medicines and Table 4.— Feed consumption, not including green feed— Lot GX—98 poults - Pprind Infertile „ . _ fenoa hen eggg Gram Dry mash Skimmilk May 13-19 *"§ "" ***_* Pom $l T PB "2? May 20-26 30 ll M T _ JS»S___ _:•■■ | I SriSSV- :::: __ K i otr.g=::: :::: ss_. %g Total I 59 I 417.8 3,294.2 I 2,762 ~£2&amp; ei « ht of 9 ? surviving turkeys on October 28 was 1,143.2 pounds. Average weight was 12.3 pounds at 24 weeks. *»*«»•« 1 Whole yellow corn. ' ~ </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Turkey Production Table 5. — Showing growth rate of turkeys — Lot GX, hatched May 13 j Average weight of one turkey calculated from the weights of: ! Average Age in weeks 55 females 43 males (both sexes) Ounces Ounces Ounces At hatch 1.7 1.8 1.7 1 3.1 3.4 3.3 2 5.1 5.8 5.4 3 7.9 9.3 8.6 4 11.0 13.0 12.0 5 15.1 16.0 I 15.5 6 19.2 24.0 I 21.6 7 25.6 32.0 28.8 8 30.4 38.4 34.4 10 48.0 59.2 53.6 12 64.0 81.6 72.8 14 86.4 110.4 98.4 16 96.0 137.6 116.8 20 124.8 192.0 158.4 24 153.6 248.0 200.8 Forage crops for growing turkeys. — Feed costs can be reduced and the quality of the turkeys improved by provid- ! ing a clean range with a good forage crop constantly j avail - able from the eighth week until maturity. Not all the con - tributions made by green feeds can be expressed in terms of vitamins, minerals, or other nutrient groups, but the value of green feed is well recognized. ill H __M :.."".: H^H;---:&lt; rPWvsiHI * 1 ' Z&gt;1_? _m\ n ifei I j t; : 7*77:'7 n 7.;. : ; 1 HPM __^X r^cJ, :^__f_W__W_W_t 5 . -.■ ■'. _ ___/ i Fig. 6. — An inexpensive roosting shed with corral — arranged to house 100 birds. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 280 Alfalfa must be given first place in the list of forage crops for turkeys. When not more than a hundred poults are ranged per acre some hay can be cut also. If the sheds are moved regularly, the field can be used for several years without loss of stand. Where grasshoppers have proved a problem, the ranging of turkeys on the alfalfa field has been an effective control measure. Among the annual crops Sudan grass rates high also. This may be seeded about ten days after the usual corn-planting date, the seeding rate being about 15 pounds per acre. Sudan has the virtue of being drouth-resistant and tolerant of hot weather. If the first growth becomes coarse and unpalatable, it may be cut for hay. The new shoots from the second crop will be tender and palatable. Native blue grass provides excellent forage for turkeys when not pastured too closely. The disadvantage is that it dries up during the hot months. Other crops which can be used are cowpeas, soybeans, fall rye, and oats. Sweet clover has not proved as satisfactory as alfalfa. Rations from the tenth to the twentieth week. — The best and probably the most profitable turkeys grown in Nebraska are those which have constant access to a good mash mix - ture. Formula No. 7, as listed in Table 3, contains no ex - pensive elements except the cod-liver oil and the dried butter - milk. If these are eliminated, the alfalfa meal reduced to 50 pounds per half ton, the meat meal raised to 150 pounds, and the yellow cornmeal raised to 370 pounds, a more econom - ical formula results. When skimmilk or buttermilk are avail - able, formula 7-M without the cod-liver oil may well be used throughout the growing season. The bungalow-type outdoor feeder, as described in Circular 733, has proved very satis - factory for feeding dry mash to growing turkeys. From the twentieth week to marketing time. — Whole yellow corn, wheat, and barley may be included in the ration for the last six or eight weeks. Availability and relative costs will determine the proportions of these grains to be used. A satisfactory grain mixture which has been used at the University has been made of : Yellow corn 500 pounds, Wheat 250 pounds, Barley 250 pounds. The proper protein level for the ration to be used for the last eight weeks must still be determined. Some preliminary work done at this Station indicates that 16 per cent is suffi - ciently high if the quality of the protein nutrients is good. It </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Turkey Production Fig. 7. — Half-grown turkeys on alfalfa range. For this purpose nothing surpasses alfalfa. is possible that a lower level is sufficient. The modified No. 7 formula, as recommended for the tenth to the twentieth week, will average about 19 per cent protein. When two parts of this mash are used with one part of grain, the pro - tein level of the entire ration will be about 16 per| cent. Observations made at this Station indicate that slightly over nine pounds of feed are required to produce a pound of gain with vigorous, young toms from the twenty-third to the twenty-ninth week. A milk-moistened mash fed once daily during thie last month of the feeding period will increase feed consumption, hasten feather maturity, and put the birds in best condition for dressing. Total amount of feed required. — It has been observed that about 60 pounds of feed per bird, exclusive of green feed, are required for the first seven months. With goodj man - agement turkeys should average 14 pounds at seven months. Feed costs vary from year to year and in different communi - ties, but a reasonably accurate estimate of feed costs can be made for any particular condition by taking 60 pounds per bird as a basis. MARKETING Since roast turkey is traditionally the central figure j about which Thanksgiving hospitality is organized, the demand for prime birds is usually most keen at that time. Unfinished j </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 280 stock should, of course, be held for Christmas and later markets. Fortunately many turkeys are now being consumed throughout the year. Whether to sell turkeys alive or to dress them will depend on the local marketing service, distance from the final con - suming market, and the availability of labor for doing the dressing. Turkeys are considered dressed for market when they have been killed and bled and after feathers have been removed. The qualities which make a dressed turkey most attractive are as follows : 1. Straight keelbone and absence of skeletal deformities. 2. Plump carcass, well fleshed in all sections. 3. No scabs or bruises. 4. Well bled, picked clean, all pinfeathers removed. More detailed information on dressing and marketing tur - keys is given in Extension Circular No. 1448, which may be obtained from the College of Agriculture. TURKEY PRODUCTION-COST ANALYSIS Turkey production, like most other kinds of production, will always involve some speculation. Prices and profits will be influenced by the purchasing power of consumer. A careful cost analysis, however, will enable the producer to determine with reasonable accuracy whether production should be con - tinued, curtailed, or expanded. The following outline is not intended as factual, but only to indicate a way in which the job can be analyzed. Start with 1,000 poults 1. Value of 1,000 poults at 30 cents each $300.00 2. Brooder house overhead (10 per cent on $400.00 investment, o cov^ r fr* 6 " 8 *. depreciation, taxes, and maintenance) 40.00 3. Fuel for brooding (10 gallons distillate daily for 40 days at 7 cents per gallon) 28.00 4. Litter (2 tons straw at $5.00) 10.00 5. Land rental and seeding expense (10 acres at $8.00 per acre) 80.00 6. Feed (60 pounds per bird at 85 cents per 100 pounds) for 850 birds 433.50 7. Roosting sheds and fencing (10 per cent on $400.00) 40.00 Total ..$931.50 If 85 per cent are raised, the cost per bird at seven months, not tn - cludxng labor and managerial service, is on this basis, $1.09. There are opportunities for useful and profitable employ - ment in turkey production, but no one should undertake this job without realizing that this business is at the present time keenly competitive. [8M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>