<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00020.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00020.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fifteenth Annual Report of the Secretary of the State Banking Board, Showing the Condition of the BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF NEBRASKA For the Fiscal Year Ending June 30, 1907.  Submitted to the Governor and the State Banking Board September 1, 1907.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
        
            <seg id="p001">of the State Banking Board, Showing the Condi- tion of the HUIIJHXG AND I.OAX ASSOCIATIONS OF NEBRASKA For the fiscal Year Ending June 30. 1907. Submitted to the Governor and the State Banking Board September I. 1907 By E ROYSE, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">F THh KTATK &lt;»F NEBRASKA HOARD K. K. KMMKTI DEPARTMENT &lt;&gt;K BANKING HON. K. M. SKARLK. IH. .. Auditor of 1'uhlio Ai-oiunt- and I'ii - H«)N. L. (I. BRIAN Slatt Attorney ' • H\V. T. THOMPSON VSK N. R. PER8INGER MAIDK HodK. . . </seg>
            <seg id="p004">R Excellency, George L. Sheldon, Governor of Nebraska, and tl onorabkea B« M. Bearle, Jr., I.. ('.. Brian, and W. T. Thompsoi e State Banking Board of the State of Nebraska: Gentlemen: In compliance with section 3a of chapter 8 of the Compiled Statutes of the State of Nebraska for 1903 requiring the Secretary of the State Banking Board to make to the Governor and State Banking Board annual reports. I have the honor to submit herewith the Fifteenth annual report of the department of banking for the period beginning July 1, 1906, and ending June 30. 1907. showing the condition of the building and loan associations of the state of Nebraska at the close of business June 30. 1907. com - piled from annual reports of the several building and loan associa - tions submitted to the State Banking Board, in accordance with the provisions of the building and loan act. approved April 4. 1899. Tabulated statements, detailed reports, and such information and comments touching this report as is deemed beneficial will be found on the following pages. Very respectfully E. ROYSE. Seeretar\ State Itankin'' Uuuri </seg>
            <seg id="p005">E Compiled from the Annual Reports of the Building and Loan ciations for the years from 1892. the first year reports were ved. to 1907 inclusive, showing the totals of all Building and associations in the state for the years above stated. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OF THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THE STATK OF NKBRASKA On the 31st day of December. 1MB. ASSETS First Mortgage Loans *2,235,104.77 secured by stock of association estate 175,160.37 50.141.73 tpense.s and taxes paid ih with treasurer .... 75,632.66 69.994. IS All other assets 296.523. 96 Total »2,9O2,557.67 LIABILITIES Premiums paid $1,924,7M.1J 393.103.18 Kerest received les collected ler liabilities 434.85*. 82 116.013 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p007">SUMMARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1892 RECEIPTS. Balance on hand December 31. 1891 Dues 61.250.27 515,492.54 176.503.52 Interest Fines 10,999.81 197,409.15 I.oans repaid . Other receipts Total $1,024.60*. 81 EXPENDITURES Loans $641,548.63 17.550.16 10.769.46 Salaries Other expense* Withdrawals . . 199.864.38 M. 478. 95 Other expenditures. Cash on hand 70.389 . 23 Total $1,024,600.81 RECAPITULATION Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares issued during year 14,380 Number of shares matured, withdrawn and cancelled Number of shares in force at this date </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OF T1IK Hl"ILDlN(i AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS (F I HI STATK &lt;&gt;K XKHRASKA «»n tlit- :iiith &lt;la\ of l)&lt;vimb.-r. I* ASSET Kirn mortgage loans $2,804,316 ■ secured by stock of association estate Expenses and taxes paid Other assets not enumerated above Total Capital slock paid up Premiums paid Interest received Fines collected Other liabilities </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 ■MARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 30, 1893. EX PEN I HTURES $741.''. 22.141.11 Salaries 16.304.96 Other expense! Withdrawals . ( a»h on hand Miscellaneous expenditun 117.973.84 Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTION'S FOR THE YEAR 189 Bof shares in force at last report of shares issued during current year of shares matured, withdrawn and cancelled of shares in force at this date RECAPITULATION Number of associations in force December 31, 1892 Number of associations discontinued during year . Number of new associations during year I Number of associations in force December 31, 1893 $1. 289.310. 2t&gt; KBU1 BilJ ia. Balance on hand December 31. 1892 Fines Loans repaid Other receipts * i TM 683.746.81 21H.170.25 8.3) 217,377.66 87.613.70 Total ... I $1.289.:?10.2« </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 FIFTKKNTH ANNUAL KEHOKT OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATE OF NKBRASKA &lt;»n the Slat dav uf December. 1H94. ASSETS First mortgage loans tns secured by stock of association 1 estate tpenses and taxes paid 3h with treasurer . . . Other assets Total LIABILITIES Capital .-took paid up $2,694,342.84 Premiums paid Interest received 601.163.24 Fines collected MJH.U All other liabilities 145.154.40 Total $3,888,001.31 SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OF THK </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 SUMMARY OP SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDINf DECEMBER 31, 1894 REC EIPTS Balance on hand December 31, 189: Dues * 69,115.94 775,7«.«4 Interest Fines . 225,228.84 8,812.80 Loans repaid Other receipts 243.632.1* 122,357.61 Total $1,444,910.99 * EXPENDITURES Loans $671,896.81 27,232.88 Salarie Other expen Withdrawals 22,495.44 421,833.51 Kher expenditures sh on hand . . . 72,033.87 229,418.87 Total $1,444,910.99 rAPITULATIOX OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1894. Number of shares in force at last report Number of shares issued during year . . 61,059 1-10 26.712H Number of shares matured, withdrawn and cancelled Number of sharf-w in force at this date 16.540 1-10 71.811 RECAPITULATION Number of associations in force December 31, 1893 Number of associations discontinued during year Number of new associations during year Number of associations in force December 31, 1894 I </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 FIFTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OK THK. SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OF THF BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF TH1- STATK OK XK UK A SKA ASSETS First mortgage loans $2,818,386.84 Loans secured by stock of associations 267.543.48 Real estate Kxiiense* and taxes paid 139,043.38 Cash with treasurer All other assets Total Capital stock paid up Premiums paid ...".. Interest received Fines collected . . . All other liabilities Total &lt; &gt;n the Slat day of Dwashn*. 1886 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">rARY OF SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT— RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1895. EXPENDITURES $678/ Loans Salaries Other expense Withdrawals Eher expenditure* sh on hand 62.878.02 203.764.76 $1.44.". _ Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMRER 31. 189 Number of shares in force at last report 70 . Number of shares issued during year Number of shares matured, withdrawn, and cancelled 21.676 Number of shares in force at this date 70.615 RECAPITULATION 1 Number of associations in force December 31. 1894 . Number of associations discontinued during the year Member of new associations during the year Number of associations in force December II, 1895 . «1 ■s rvn»^Hi Balance on hand December 31 Sr'.'.::-:::::::::-::::::; I. 1894 63,484.94 775.161.51 215,910.35 7,454.89 250.: 132.526.45 Loans repaid Other receipts Total LSN.H </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 FIKTEKNTH ANNCAI. KKPi.KT OT THK SUMMARY '* THE CONDITION OK THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK THK STATK i»F NEBRASKA ■ !Ul lla&gt; l»l l)iv&lt;-mb.-r. l&gt;!Mi. asskts. K mortgage loan i mortgage loans in process of foreclosure estate ure and fixture ; rom shareholders md taxes pail a*su; •■.-.. . $2,832,071.61 117,368.24 177,492.84 2,175.4 56.891.46 98,763.82 169.497.26 317,572.46 Total $3,771,833.53 UAHIUTIES. Ppaid lunis unearned s undivided including reserve fund .'. s apportioned to shares i n force shareholders on incomplete loans ■ liabilities $2,582,078.82 100.537.55 382,320.47 429.4ns T-l 10.572.08 266,915.85 Total • ■&gt; -«i o*»o n 1 77 .. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 DECEMBER 31, 1896. REC K 1IPTS 88,470.44 778,083.64 216.297 54 Balance on hand December 31,1895 Dues Interest Fines 7,021.04 Loans repaid Other receipt 256,288.97 117,340.73 Total $1. 463.502. 30 EXPEN- DITURES $650,364.86 Salaries 26,342.95 114.447.29 370,924.08 Other expense Withdrawals, dues Eithdrawals. earnings itured stock, dues . . . itured stock, earnings sh on hand 102,738.07 97.368.26 54,657.84 Total RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR EMBER 31, 1896. ENDING DEC report 64.625 Number of shares in force at last Number of shares matured during current year 1.491 Number of shares in force at this date 64.891% Number of loans made for the payment of homestead mortgages during current year 451 Number of shares issued during current year 18,608 Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled during cur- 16.636^ rent year Nuniber of loans made for building purposes during cur- rent yea Number of shareholders 12.145 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Number of shares of »t&lt;n-k issued since organization 114,116 Number of series of stock issued since organization Numl«er of shares of stock withdrawn and cancelled 76,374&gt;4 Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure 136 111,740.43 Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure Total appraised value of real estate and improvements 4.406,969.10 U seourit Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the associ ation* as collateral security Value of other real estate held by the association IARES STATEMENT Total number of series issued Total number of shares issued Total number of shares withdrawn Total number of shares loaned on . Total number of shares outstanding RECAPITULATION tr of associations in force December 31. 18H.". r of associations discontinued during year . r of new associations during year Number of associations in force December 31, 1896 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SUMMARY HUILDINC; AND IjOAX ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATE OF NKBRASKA ASSETS First mortgage loan* $2,672,466. f&gt;i First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure Real estate 60,948.60 209.682.96 Furniture anil fixture: uses and taxes paid fr6m shareholders . Other assets Total Dues paid Premiums unearned Profits undivided, including reserve fund Profits apportioned to shares in force Due shareholders on incomplete loans . " 296.690 T.S.t4 .74 OF THK CONDITION' OF THK On thn :tlst clav of Dosemher. MtT </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 ECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE YE AK ENDING ECEMBER 31, 189 REC E IPTS Halance on haml . &gt;eceniber SI, 189 17.16 1 786,18: H»4«.M Interest l.m Loans repaid 427,440.77 Other receipts 12:!. 704. 36 Total $1.631. 1. EXPENDITURES. Total $1,631 EX PEN DITIRES $607.2 1 .1(1.7 ■ 4IMI ■ Salaries Salari Other expenses Other expen With.lawals. .lues 4 '"." ) fl " S , Withdrawals, earnings ''.7.157.12 Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues . . Matured stock, earning Cash on hand 157.12 Matured stock, dues J"2.914.48 J"2.914.48 95.900.80 Matured stock, earnings 95.9W.80 Cash on hand .99.69 80.799.69 $1,631 Ti tal RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER SI, tt ri'LATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS F EMBER 31. 'OR THE YEAR RECAHT EN D1N(; DEC Number of shares in force at last rei&gt;ort tS Nuir.t hares in force at last report Number of shares matured during t..e current year Number of -hares in force at this date 61 Number of loans ma. It- for payment of homestead mort - gages during fiscal year during fiscal yea Number of shares issued during current year 21.14SH Nuinl hares issued during curre hares withdrawn and car 21.14SH Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled during current year i ... i _ i 4 celled during curr ■ent Number of loans made for buililing purposes during the current year &gt;f shareholders SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT imber of loans made for huililing purposes during the hold IPPLEMENTAL REPORT Number of shares of stock issued since organization ... IV. inlier (1 f shares of stock issued since organization ... 13.1 Number of reriea of rt&lt; ck issued since organization k issued since organization M4 Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure 99 Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure W iia Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure .H, 576. 91 Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure ( 16.51 Total appraised value of real estate and improvements heir! as security tMt 1 estate and improvement nit Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the M ... as (■( llateral security " 2.54S Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the 4!- 1 Value of other real estate held by me associations .14 '!&gt; ste held by tue associations '14 24 SHARKS STATEMENT. HARES T ATEMENT Total number of series issued ies issued 644 a Total number of shares issued I' 1 »res issued Toal number of shares withdrawn Toal number of shares withrlrawi Total number of shares loaned on S1.MM Total number of shares loaned on Total number of shares outstanding I7.1M1 mtstandi RECAPITULATION. * EC A PI 1 I.ATION Number of associations in fore December SI, 1V" ; Number of associations discontinued .luring year ' Number of n* i w a-suriations during year nns in force December SI. 18H I </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 SUMMARY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OK THK. STATK OK NKBKASKA ASSETS $2,821,703.11 tst mortgage loans in process of il estate 192.450.98 tniture and fixtures n 146,254.85 and taxes paid Due from shareholders . Other assets 48,358 47,464.38 114,047 iM » $3,42X' Total I.IABII ITIES Capital stock paid up $j.;u).;.s&gt;;.; Profits undivided, including reserve Premiums unearned 330.247.31 47,517. m 19.476. II Due shareholders on incomplete loan Advance payments Matured stock unpaid Hills payable 110,120. M 5.550.00 Oth.r liabilities Total OK THK CONDITION OK THE &lt;)n the :&lt;lst day of December. Hw. foreclosure fund </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31, 1898 RECEIPTS. Balance on hand ijeceniber 31, 189 Dues Interest Fines Loans repaid Other receipt Total EXPENDITURES Salarie Other expen Withdrawals, du Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues . . . Matured stock, earnings Cash on hanil 56,779.34 146,2 r Total $1,846.8 RECAPITULATION OF SHARE TRANSACTIONS FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 31. 1898 Number of shares in force at last report 66.232 Ntimber of shares matured during current year Number of shares issued during current year 26,338 &gt;* Number of shares withdrawn and cancelled during current 10.MSH year Number of shares m force at this date 79.973 r umber of loans for payment of homestead mortgages dur - ing current year Sf*r&gt; r umber of loans ma.le for building purposes during cur - rent year Mt Number of shareholders SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Number of mortgages in process of foreclosure Amount of mortgages in process of foreclosure * 61,461 84 Total appraised value of real estate and improvements 5,1 83,247. 1« held as security Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Associ ation- as collateral securitv Value of other real estate held by the association 163.548 66 RECAPITULATION Number of associations in force December 31, 1897 Number of associations discontinued during year. Number of associations in force December 31. 1898 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SUMMARY i &gt;K THE rnxiHTH &gt;T i &gt;K THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASStK IUILI)IN&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS i &gt;K TH K UK Tin STATK OF NKBKAKKA ' &gt;n the -J'ltli &lt;1;m of .lun^. I s ! ASSETS. ASSETS. mortgage loan ■ mortgage loans $2,iS58.910 72 mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 37,253 50 mortfafe loans ". iiiortKagc loans in process of foreclosure. . . Heal estate 'ure i nd Fixtures .mil taxes paid rom shareholders I ota Real estate 165,094 . 9 Fuinture i.nd Fixtures Expenses and taxes paid 41 586.6 Due Irom shareholders Other MMta I &lt;iia . 13,31 LIABILITIES. LIABILITIES. &lt; apital &gt;ti-i-l* paid up B undivided, including reserv urns unearned fund 270,1 45.396 ■shareholders on incomplete ire payment- lo; ;ms !1.7 24.831.18 Matured stock unpaid ayable liabilities 4.617.59 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE SIX MONTHS ENDING JUNE 30, 1899. RECEIPTS Balance on hand December 31. 1898 Dues Intere t Fines . Loans repaid Other receipt Total Other expen Withdrawals, due ■wals. earnings stock, dues . . stock, earning hand Number of associations in force at this dat Number of shares in force at this date . . . Number of shareholders </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OF THE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATK OK NEBRASKA On the 30th day of .Tune. 1U00. ASSETS First mortgage loans First mortgage loans in process of Stock loana foreclosure 28.41 fi. 36 130.420.56 Real estate Furniture and fixtures Cash 105. sm; Delinquent interest, premiums and Expenses and taxes paid fines 20,879.59 ranee pai.l T assets . 116,519.33 Total $3,697,356.06 LI AUIL iTIES. Capital stock running Full paid stock Reserve fund Undivided profits Due shareholders on incomplete loan Premiums unearned Advance dues 15,970 Advance Interest and premium Bills payable 5 54 S 3fi M,4«t.» All other liabilities Total $3,697,35(5. Ofi $3,135,360.93 $2,717,380.04 664.04g.92 46.340.69 159,841.57 41.0S0.61 35.fi </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 JUNE 30, 1900. REC EIPTS. Balance on hand July 1. 1899 Duej ( running stock) 139,746.66 1,062.966.27 160,396.40 Dues (full paid stock Interest ■Premiums Fines . . . Membership and transfer fee: Loans repaid Real estate sale Rents Other receipt Total Salari. Commissions Other expen itndrawals. dues Brawals. earnings ed stock, dues ■ ■ ■ ed stock, earnings aid stock, dues . . aid stock, earning: on hand Hills payable Total Ir of shares in force at this date r of shares issued since organization r of shares issued during fiscal year r of shares matured during fiscal year r of shares withdrawn during fiscal year &gt;r of shares of running stock in force at this date r of shares of full paid stock in force at this date r of shares loaned on Kr of shares on which dues are delinquent r of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 KUILDIN(i AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS (IK TIU STATK ()K NKKKAKKA ASSKTS First mortgage loans $3,H41.- mortgage loans in process of Stock loans 25 436 3m 123.611 n&lt;. ■ •state I1O,2( Furniture and fixtures 2 849 1 1 quern interest, iiremiums and uses and taxes paid Insurance paid sets Total ■ ck runniir paid stock e fund rmlivided profits ■ Bolders i n in&lt;oni|jlete lo: urns unearned 14 Advance dues Advance interest and premium Hill- payable ■ liability 91.242 Total SUMMARY OF THK CONDITION OK 'I'llh In tin- :i'i|h . la \ of .luiii'. l!«i| foreclosure tin ;tns </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL TEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1901 REC EIPTS Balance on hand July 1. 1900 * 106,871 CO Dues, (running stock) Dues, (full paid stock) Interest 1,309,039.13 230." 280,928.33 Premiums Fines . . 36,851.21 I Membership and transfer Loans repaid 4,500.14 680.98C.08 Real estate sales Rents 16,197.53 6.886.81 74,034.83 Other receipt Total $2,951,823.89 EXPENDITURES *l.:us ■ Loans Salaries MS.l Commissions ,099.61 26.394.25 Other expenses . Withdrawals, due: n21.532.29 Withdrawals, earnings Matured stoc.k dues . . Matured stock. earnings Kull paid stock, dues . Full paid stock earnings Cash on hand UHM 192.256.93 Other liabilities Total $2,951 • SHARES STATEMENT Number of shares in force at this date 119.985 Number of shares issued since organization 248.198 Number of shares issued during fiscal year 40.109 Number of shares matured during fiscal year ::.2S0 Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year HJtl Number of shares running stock in force at this date .... 114.C13 Number of shares full paid stock in force at this date .... Kr of shares loaned on :!3.O65 r of shares On which dues are delinquent KM Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues of dues </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 SUMMARY OK THK CONDITION OP THK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF THK STATK OK NKBRASKA On the .With day of June. 1(K)2. ASSETS. First mortgage loans $4.090,595 . 56 First mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 20,776.17 Stock loans 141,870.96 Real estate 111.208.82 Furniture and fixtures 3,42:! 17 Cash 177,668.51 Delinquent interest, premiums, and fines 30,691.45 Expenses and taxes paid 23,059.31 Other assets 158,999 . 82 Total $4,758,293 LIABILITIES Capital stock running $3,820,900 . 57 Full paid stock 544.300.50 . e fund 75.320 . 36 544.300. 50 .• fund Undivided profits 169,360.63 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 48,041 .75 Premiums unearned 33,783 .47 Advance dues 17,032 . 44 Advance interest and premiums 1,761 . 89 Other liabilities 47.792.20 Total $4,758,293.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1902. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, 1901 Dues (running stock) $ 189,333.95 1,542,148.03 269.56C.32 Dues (full paid stock) Interest 318,175.12 Premiums Fines . . . ■ "' Rembership and transfer fe« &gt;ans repaid 6,249.54 S96.294.92 17,073.78 Real estate sale Rents Other receipt ■.70.419.10 $ 3.660,771.34 Total EXPENDITURES. $ l.:..S7,S91.79 Loans Salari 39.385.18 Other expen 3S.1X7.U 1. (■54.478.33 Withdrawals, du Withdrawals, earnings . Matured stock, dues . . Matured stock, earnings Full oak", stock, dues . Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand 71,829.44 120,101.50 I1.7M hs 1 tl.. r )0«.2O 20,469.02 178.068.51 Other liabiliti .577, 148. 9« Total I 771 :!4 SHARES STATEMENT. Number of shares in force at this date Number of shares issued since organization 269.243 Number of shares issued during fiscal year 40.4*1 Number of shares matured during fiscal year Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year Number of shares of Winning stock in force at this date . . Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this date *.30H Number of shares loaned on 36,79* Number of shires on which dues are delinquent 4.21 8 ■r of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 1 ,093 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 OF THK CONDITION OK THK Ul*lLI)IX(i AN'I) LOAN ASSOCIATIONS l&gt;K Tilt STATK &lt;)F NKBRASKA ASSETS Fiibt mortgage loan First mortgage loans in proc. Stock loans foreelc* urt i.urp and stationery D&lt;llnquint interest premiums and .uid taxes |&gt;aid Total LIABILITIES slock running, (Dues and div Full |&gt;;ii&lt;: stock fund 102.470.31 15S.7U.44 39,271.81 L'ndiviil&lt; ,' profits Out- shaieholders on Incomplete 1&lt; n PremVinis unearned Advance ones 26.136.49 14,050.90 Advance interest and premiums &lt; in r liabilities 3.176.40 $5.343. : S1MMAKY On the .'tilth lla\ of June. l!N).'t I slate </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 10. 1903 REC E IPTS Balance on hand June 1. 1 Dues, (running stock) .. Dues, (full paid stock) . 17«.77» 1.773.. :'.4o,118.99 Premiums Membership and transfer Loans repaid Real estate sales Rents Other receipt Total EX PEN DITIRES Commissions Other expens Withdrawals. :lue Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues . . Matured stock, earnings Full paid stock, dues . . Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand 144.433.88 49.168.82 i20.:&gt;' 2i. r 219.801 .17 Other expenditure •Jfi9.i&lt; Tota $:!.9rt2 SUPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT Number of shares in force at this date Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares issued during fiscal year Numb e r of shares matured during fiscal year Mumber of shares withdrawn during fiscal year Nuirter of shares of running stock in force at this dat Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this dat umber of shares loaned on Number of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues rmber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the ag " etat "ouit ct same. Number 208 tmbtr of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and thp aggregate amount of same. No. 4* $24.1 Number of borrowing stockholders . . . Number of non-borrowing stockholders I MM Number of minors holding stock in the Associations Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dur in« fiscal year v Average rate |&gt;er cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 SUMMARY OK THK CilMtlTlOT UK THh BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS OF Till- STATi: OK NKBRAKKA ( ) &lt; tn !lie .idth ilu\ of .hint-. 1IKI4. ASSETS. Iniortg.iK ■ loans mortgag ■ loan: in process of foreclosur.. loons eslat ure and nf tHtin i .v Hunt iiii.-rest. prenluu and Hn&lt; s ses and taxes paid assets . . $5,493,718.87 27 908 74 227J09.02 5&gt; 2ipii.286.02 H4H.7I 24.766.48 116,122.47 Total . . $6,217,350.40 LIABILITIES Capita! Mock ltinnir.K. &lt;I&gt;ues and divide. ids) Full | :.id stock 11 ■ *rv ■ fund I'ndiviild profits Due a'.iareholdf rs on incomplete loan* Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance hierrtl ami pramhunf Other liabilities . $4,851,576.89 863,331.13 144,332.60 191,013. 03 8&amp;.4S5.89 29.933.15 1 0.627. in 1,457.70 39.592.66 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDlil R.KS FOR THE YEAR EN^DING 30, 1904. JUNE REC EIPTS. Balance on band July 1, 1903 Dues, (running stock) $ 217,252.30 2,030,636.83 Dues, (full paid stock) Interest 351,692.41 447,128.78 Premium - Finos . . . 45.605.14 Membership and transfer fe&lt; Loans repaid 10,575.87 Real estate sales Rents Other receipts Total EXPEN DITURES. Salaries Commissions: Other cxpem Withdrawals, iluf fithdrawals, earnings atured stock, dues atured stock, earnings- Full paid stock, dues . Full paid stock, earnings Cash on hand 236,076.70 27,851.63 199.352.90 226.996.93 Other oxpe.iditui $4,469,832.87 Total SVPPLEMENTAL STATEMENT Number of shares in force at this date 174,022 Number of shares issued since organizaticn 381. 'i 75 Number of shares issued during fiscal year 52.942 Number of shares, matured during fiscal y&gt;ar 2.fi32 Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year 29.621 Number of shares running stock in force at this date .... 164,351 Number of shares of full paid stock in force at this date 9,b71 Number of shares loaned on Vumber of shares on which dues are delinquent 2.998 Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues 458 r umber of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the ag - gregate amount of same. No. 224 $147,110.00 f umber of mortgages in process of foreclosure, and the aggregate amount of same. No. 39 . . .• t 36,821 .00 Number of borrowing sotckholtlers 10.193 un btr of non-borrowing stockholders 13,306 Number of minors holding stock in the associations: .... •W Fverage rate per cent of interest charged borrowers dur - ing fiscal year 8^4 ing fiscal year Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal S year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year. 106 months Number of loans made for building purposes during year 1.061 Number of leans made for the naym°nt 'f homestead mortgages during year 1.246 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 FIFTEENTH ANNUAL. KEl'oRT OK THE SUMMARY OK THE CONDITION OK THE or thk ooNomoN ok thk MUILDIM; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS NG AND LOAN ASSOC] OK THE OF THE STATK OK NEBRASKA STATE OK NKHRASKA On Mm :Mlth &lt;lav of June, 1W&gt;5. ASSETS Kirst moi Igag^ loans $6,303,316.65 Kirst mortgage loans in process of foreclosure 38,432.59 Stock lor.ns, 190,609. »4 Real estate 88,352.91 Furniture and stationery 18,263.21 2a»h 403.460.08 Delinquent interest, premiums and fines 31.425.66 Expenses and taxes paid 24,876 '(7 Other uaeta 170,560.37 Total $7,269,297.48 LIABILITIES Capital stock running. (Dues and dividends) $5,522,879.23 Full paid stock 1,134,813.14 Reserve fund 172.244.90 Undivided profits 199,776.17 Due shareholders on incomplete loans 148,991.79 Premiums unearned 28,244 . 06 Advance dues 15,595 . 79 Advance interest and premiums 2,823 . 31 Other liabilities 43,929 .09 Total $7,269,297.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL YEAR ENDING 10, 1905. JUNE REC E IPTS Balance on hand July 1. 1904 Dues, (running stock) 198,718 ,431.9 506.1 499,443.22 mes (full paid stock) Interest Premiui 58,519.02 Membership and trans Loans repaid Loans repaid 1.318,317.U Rtal estate sali- :ir&gt;.114.45 Other rcc; ipt i JuH : Total $S.28*.4i Total $5,2X9 ■ EXPENDITIRES. EX PEN 1 HTIRES Salari Salaries M.lM.lt Commissions .7. Commissions Other expen Other expenses 4::.' Withdrawal*!, uues 1.472.795.48 Withdrawals, uu 1.472.T Withdrawals, earnings . Matured stock, dues Matured stock, earning.' Full paid stock, dues . Full paid stock, earning: Cash on hand Withdrawals, earnings .'95,319.91 Matured stock, dues • Matured stock, earnings ... 19.."&gt; ■ 19.541 .51 Full paid stock, dues I"5,J 175.1'" Full paid stock, earnings 44.'' on hand ■ ■ 404." 44.6(14 Other expenditures 1 MJ Total fSJSI ; SIPPLEMEXTAL REPORT. Other expenditur IPF LEMENTAL REPORT at this date Number of shares in force at this date Number of shares in for Number of shares issued since organization Number of shares issued ince organization uring fiscal year during fiscal yea Number of shares issued during fiscal year Number of shares issued d Number of shares matured during fiscal year Number of shares matured ;al year Number of shares withdrawn during fiscal year ... Rr of shares withdra r of shares of runn *n during fiscal year Number of shares of running stock in force at this date ng stock in force at this date Number of shares of full paid stock in force ;it this date Number of shares of full &gt;aid stock in force ;it this date Nomber of shares loaned on Numlx-r of stares loaned on Number of share on which dues are delinquent Number of share on whi du Number of shuiet subject to cancellation fir non-paym&lt; nt of dues Number of :,h;u ' c; NumlKr of mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the ag - gregate amount of same. No. 199 $135.8' BCt to foreclosure, and the ag Nun ate amoun lime. N( Number &lt;&gt;:* mortgages in procees &lt;&gt;f for.H-losure. and the aggregate amount of same. No. 32 i of mortea aggregate am me Number of loans made for building pun&gt;oses during fiscal year Number made for ildin ■a N'nnilii r of loans made for the payment of homestead mortgages during fiscal year .... I meal of homestead ;i Number of borrowing stockholders ... Number of non-borrowing stocholders Number of minors holding stock in the associations rvcrage ra»» per cent of interest chars d borrowers dur in?; fiscal year Average rate i&gt;er cent of dividend* declarer, during fiscal Awragc* runnii ick matured during </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 SUMMARY OK THK itlNI&gt;ITl(lN UK THK IU'ILDINc; AND LOAN ASSOCIATIONS ASSKT mortgage loan mortgage loans in proea Slock loans Real t state trniture and -.tatinmrv sh : Delinquent interest premiums and anil taxes paid Othfi 1 otal LIABILITIES I Lai stook running. (Due s and Full |&gt;aid stock . . • ■ fund Tii'livided profits Due shareholders on Incomplete Premiums unearned Advance dues Bee interest and premiums liabilities Total STATK &lt; &gt;K XKHRASKA (&gt;t) the .With ila\ &lt;&lt;t .Tune. 1!" </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 K JUNE 3 10 REC E I PTS Balance on haml July l, K Dues, (running stock) 404,023.50 15.71 Dues, (full paid stock) Interest rremiums Fines . . . Membership and transfer fe Loans repaid Real estate sales Rents Other receipt Total EX PEN r HTIRES Salarie Commissions Other expense Withdrawals, due Withdrawals, earnings Matured stock, dues.. Matured stock, earning Full paid stock, dn s Full paiil stock, earning Cash &lt;|i hand Other ex|&gt;eiiil Tot SIPFLEMENTAI. REPORT Ir of shares in force at this date r of shares issued since organization r of shares issued .luring fiscal year r of shares matured during fiscal year . r of shares withdrawn during fiscal year r of shares of running stock in force at this .late r of shares of full paid stock in force at this date r of shares loaned on Numb -r of shares on which dues are delinquent Number of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of due reclosure. and the ag Number of mortgages subject to fc gregate amount of same. No. 176 $110.2X0 Kr of mortgages in process &lt; ;regate amount of same. No f foreclosure, and tht 66 $ 42,641.39 Number of loans made for building purposes during fiscal Kr of loans made for the i rtgages during fiscal year . . lavment of honi' Number of non-borrowing stockhol riers 1MQ N'umber of minors holding stock in the Associations ... "91 ■hars-M borrowers dur \vemge rale !&gt;er cent of interest c la? fiscal yea Average rate i&gt;er cent of dividend year declared during fiscal Average running time of stock matured during fiscal Number of bororwing stockholder: </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 FIFTEENTH ANNUAL RKTORT OK THE SUMMARY OK THK CONDITION OK THE .SIXTY-SIX iu'ildim; and loan associations OK THE STATE OF NEBRASKA (hi Mm :!&lt;&gt;th da&gt; of June. 1!«&gt;7. ASSETS * 10,100,523.43 inorttratfe loan Kii»t niortna^c loan* in praeemi of for f MIMil'l MO.HtiO.ftt lieal K-tsit Kurniturt* •&lt; 1.1I lixlur •&gt;:i&gt; 4S,7«l.flt quenl inUicsi. pivmiuiDM and ,nd taxes paid tint 14,324.40 I'ot 11.422.8H0 LI A HI I.I riKs KKltick iniiiiintr. iDueN and id stork . dividends) • 8,344,40U.4) ZVt . i- fun W1.483 Tl Cndividi'd pn&gt;H1 khmrfholddrx on incunipk iumK uncarni-&lt;l ;i V2.M- 15. i:i:i 1 -i and premium lialiilitii - 1 4ti2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOK THE FISCAL VEAR ENDING JUNE 30, t» RECEIPTS Balance on hand Julv i. I!mh :h:.:um.h -. (Ru 4,193,448.46 1,012,473.16 i&gt;a I ii.3til.41 Membership and transfer fee repa -al oth. M.0TI.79 !l EXPEND] I'l IES Loans * Salaries Salar &lt; 'ommissions Com &lt; &gt;thiT expense* oth ;i Withdrawals, dues rawals. earning* ii « w i Matured stock, dues h&lt; Matured stock, earnings Mat Full paid stdi-k. dues Full paid stock, chu 2441 til Full paid stock, earnings &lt; :i-\\ on hand alleolls SUPPLEMENTAL &lt; i«i PPL.EMENTAL RE11 r I'lan of association IVrmanent. 34; i i I'ai' value of each share of stock I'ai' value of each -hare of Htock 40 :&gt;; &lt;■ a Number of series issued since orjrani/.ath Number of series issued since oriranizati Number of share* issued since organ izati Number of shares issued since uriranization Number of shares in force at date of last N lit date of lii-t ivi iso.iauri Utt.734.«ia Number of shares issued during fiscal \e N i footing of two preceding items... E. ».. Number of xharex withdrawn before matu fiscal year ber of -luii'- »ith&lt;lia»n Ixfoif matuiitv.d Number of shares matured during fiscal \ Number of shares matured during ti-i-al w-ai 14.1 Number of shares cancelled during lisca not withdrawn Number of shares cancelled dui-inir li-ca }ns Kooting of three preceding items Number ol shares in Force at this date .. N Number of shares of running stock in foi N n force at f i Number of shares of full paid stock in f&lt;&gt; N art- of full ])aid stock in force at I iit Number of share* loaned on N Number of shares on which dues are deli Number of share* on which tlue* arc delinquent I Number of shares subject to cancellation dues Numlu'i- of shares subject to cancellation i lH'Ilt of Tote] amount of dues delinquent at this &lt; 'I'ota A mo A mo Nimi his 1 1 a it a Amount of dues owing by borrowing sha « ii iwinjf sharel Amount of interest, premiums and tines i 1 imp d th aid Number of mortgages subject to foreclosi Kate amount of same. No. 1&lt;MI in aifarr Inn Number of mortgagee in process of forec Nu ml ae it and the at;' amount of Name, No. '&lt;&gt;i J.132 "4 in n - </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loan have been made Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans upon unimproved Appraised value of unimproved rea estate upon which loan have been made 51 Amount of Insurance in force and iijned to the Associa ;i »14.:«U.i. tions as collateral security purposes during fiscal Number of loans made for building yea. Number of loans nik for payment f homestead morttraj: i during fiscal year Amount of advance payment of loan during fiscal year 381 Number of borrowing stockholder Numlx'i- of non-borrowing itockhold :'1'S Numlier of minors holding stock in the association Average rate percent, of interest charged borrower! durln ve*r i^.'c rate per emt. of premiums charged borrowers dur inp fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividend* declared on running stock durii cal year ...... Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fi 114. &lt;»i- cal year Av*rag« rate per cent, of dividends declared dariag fisca *l6.&lt;t»8.ia.{.mt «5.3ti&lt;i real estato ♦2ti.o2;&gt;.i«&gt; sk matured during ti- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 STATEMENT Of total number of association number of shares in force and assets, from 1192. tlir first vear that authentic reports were made, down to the present tim&lt; N( I No ■&gt;►■ Sbarb M IN KoHl'E YEAR A "I 4&amp;.012J 84 til.ittu.l :(.ti.'a m 71,2311 -»mh _:ti si 70,615 :i.H-" «) He 541 153.424 j.343.4 I,! I 174,022 ti.21T. 5» l!W,o:{(» 7,2B»,2! til 22O,A4N S.9H1 ■ 115,372 ll.ll'-J.- H ii7,.'&gt;!t:j :!..v&gt;; M 7»,m.1 :i.4-&gt; m 106,825 :i,ti!c "&gt;!t lie. 4,314, 7 44. Mi 5M 130,083 4.7.&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 showing gains and losam of the Building and Loan Assoc Nebraska, iluring the year ending June Mb, l!»07. ■nding June 30th. 1!HI7. asskts, 11KI7 asskts.'O6 GAIN Albion... * tW.H70.:t!l t 65,400.33 * 3,410.06 Alliance Alliance 4t;.4f&gt;li.Oil 4U.821.58 5,634.51 Auburn 157,236.25 190,223.04 Auburn 157,236.25 1 DO. 223. 04 I $:r_\" Aurora 43,590.14 33,8*44.12 9,726.02 ice Stat&lt;- : 283,073.54 234,693.55 48.37!t.!t!i Aurora 43,590.14 33.8tt4.12 9,726.02 rice State : 283,073.54 234,693.55 48.37!t.!t!i 7O.««5.O1 51,31 1U.47K.43 7o.tiH.Vol 51,3 19,478.43 lilair 42,574.02 .5. r ..4M«.79 7,077.23 Ulair 42,574.02 :i. r ).4!ttt.79 '. 7.077.23 Cambridge 10,649.70 new 10,649.70 Cambridge Ul.ii4it.7tl new .il City ii.iiir.M7 L'.lti-t.l.") 7,498.02 ;il City Center 3«, 200. 8(1 30,292.29 ■&gt;.&lt;*;». ."il ('ha'|)|M'U l,0H9.67 new ; 1,089.67 fna|.|»-ll 1,089.67 new Columbus Kquitabl. 78,423.13 29,703.34 48,719.79 Columbus KquitaM' 7*. 423. 13 29,703.34 48,719.70 Colutnbua 248,279.05 240,125.15 8,153.90 &lt; 'oliiinlm 248.279.ai 240,125.15 8,153.1 153.90 52.909.97 39,384.14 13.S25.83 52.909.97 :tii.:!K4.14 13,525.83 Kairburv.. 9,092.44 4,30H.OO 4,786,44 Kairburv !). U!i^.44 4..KNi.(NI 4,786,44 Kaiill.ld. . 13.ti.Vi. 32 15.525.39 lXtUi. :\1 15.525.39 nil Stale L'7ii. *:(.-.. Ill 186,387.86 !K).447.4.t nil Stale L'7ii. *:(.-.. L".! 186,387.88 00,447.43 PremoDt Kquitable i 81,017.75 05.83 12,801.92 C 4,030.10 ls.4iiii K 4,030.10 18,4H«.95 Grand Island 424.138.99 T7«,«37.73 47,501. 2« i Island 424.138.99 376,«37.73 47,801.26 nyton agton 14.02 31.W55.31 2K.(i44.(l2 11,655.31 103,001 95,817.47 7.1- I03.0IM 95,817.47 7,189.:« 189 Haveloi4 ck 96.915.64 72.843.32 24,972.32 96,915.64 s4; 4.II7L' Booper 17,935.58 17,421.15 514.43 Boo per 17.Kt5.5H 17,421.15 "&gt;14.4:( Humbokh St. U\1A\ 15.365.47 9,796.94 Hunilxild i"&gt;. lnj.41 15.365.47 !i.7!Hi. c .i4 I1.714.A9 8.254.05 3,460.64 11.714.88 8.254.05 :t.4tiii.ii4 Lincoln American. 84,770.77 83,608.04 21,16273 Lincoln American. 770.77 63.608.04 21.16273 21. Mi: Lincoln Fidelity.. 4,263.65 new 4,2ft3.ft5 In Neb. Central. 1,519,54* 1,315.818.46 303,730.34 Lincoln Kidelitv 4.'Jii:!.&lt;i.") new 4.i &gt; i;:i.ti.-) Lincoln Neb. Central 1.519.548.80 1.315.818.4H 203.730.34 Lincoln Hav. A lx&gt;an. 16.071.911 2.114.93 13,957.06 in Security 104,772.90 35,064.80 69,708.10 Linroln Sav. 4 Ixan. 16,071. Ml i 2.114.H3 13,957.06 in Security 104.772.90 35.064.80 99.708.10 Lincoln [Tnion 30,255.70 new . .. 30,255.70 • in I'nion IO.25S.7O new M&gt;n B. * L. I9.244.6W lH.Wi7.liti 576.70 «)ii B. &amp; L. l!i.L'44.iiii 18.667.98 576.7 70 -.in County.... 38,677.82 :t5.5K8.()3 1 it.litit^i -■in County.... 38,677.82 :t5.5K8.03i 3,1*19.79 llHI &gt;ok 113.132.60 294.34 23.838.26 113.132.60 89.2!H.:M L 1 -Ka I'itv i-kaCity KJ.5ttO.BH 53,741.58 9,848.11 KJ.59it.6il 53,741.58 H.M4SI.U n Ui.OJ 18.884.01 1 li P . (144. xo n NuckolUCu 7. 781.84 3,703.00 4,078.64 :i NuckolUCo 7.781.64 3,703.00 4,078.64 an Grove. 10.971.53 12.628.67 . 1.657.14 an Grove. 10.971.53 12.628.67 .. Norfolk Klkhorn. 21.OH8.86 22.434.20 ■ •Ik.. ll.").-_ &gt; ii7..'&gt;2 109,913.27 5.354.25 Lou p. 9.311.11 5,068.01 4.243.10 North 1'latt. l!Mi. H77.H4 175,310.13 20,767.81 Omaha Banken 71,650.58 57,733.93 13,916.65 &lt;»maha Conservative... 2,562,803.95 1,837,540.49 7i'i.i")4.4ii Kia L. * B 1,719,019.99 1,245,666.77 473,353.22 la Mutual 3.680.13 4.7'iH.rwi LI Omaha Mutual 3,680.13 4.7!&lt;s..')ii Omaha Nehr. L. &gt;V 15 14!i.l4:t.!Mi l:i7. H74.44 11,169.5! Omaha Occidental. 1.456.725.34 1.053.3U8.15 403,327.19 l'a»«H' &lt; it\ 10,415.51 10,136.73 278 tsinouth Livingstoi 93, 90S. 11 81.356.61 12,545.50 ■iiouth ■iiouth 54,251.17 47.Hiii.7.") 7,084.42 Schuyler 8,200.91 32.985,03 24,784.1 98T&gt;,0: ; «1 63.504.47 61,912.15 1,5*2 Sidney 17.767.16 I5.OK2.16 2,705.00 South Omaha L'o^.:!L'4.7!t 150,273.73 52,051.06 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 List showing Gains and Low-. ( 'omduded ASSETS. I!t&lt;t7 ASSKTS.'lKi GAIN I&gt; &gt;SS Stratton . Superior. Tecumseh Trenton . t «..'loO.OB 2ti7.!t&lt;; * :{.iinl'.1o i!l.4Hi.7&lt;i .«.:{4ti.:{»i : 3.O7O.W 12«.2ti !'44.iiti 4,722.78 3,221.1 l.'.HI Valentine Wahoo . . :J4,931.21 :M.(iT7.ii7 45.8« !t:t. l.tl.OO S.H92.1M 17,438.06 Wilber 4,.-,7"&gt;. ir&gt; ').»"&gt;»!. 40 Wood River York Mutual 13.232.51 27,7:w.4ti 5,4!*3.lir&gt; 4!t:t.(t.' ( 73.K28.SB m.OKl York — Workingraen's 1H9.60 n.-w :{. lrt't.tKi $11.422,8tt0.8« I8.961,78H.11 r2.552.801.&gt; I </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 ■ ixty-six associations reported their condition at the close •iint'ss June 80,1907, ;m increase in the number of Associa during the year of five, to wit: i&amp;mbridge Enterprise I^oan and Building Association. happel) ChappeU Ruilding and Loan Association, incoln Fidelity Savings and Loan Association, inx-oln Union I»an and Savings Association. ork Workingmen"s Saving &amp; Tjoun Association, liesc have aocummulatod since tlieir organization Assets amounting to $49,428.32. There were 315,872.15 shares in force on June 80, 1907, be infj an increase over last year of 56,075.15 shares. The number of shares issued during the fiscal year was 110,734.65, being an increase of 32,857.65. Be number of mortgages subject to foreclosure at close year was liM), which is 7t&gt; less than a year ago, and the r in process of foreclosure, was 56 against B6« year ago. Tlie number of borrowing stockholders have iacn and non-borrowing (i.4!*:.'. The average rate of interest charged borrowers during the was *\'J7 per cent, and the dividend rates *.7&gt; per cent. Bie holdings of Real Estate has decreased during the year 4.'.«i. The Reserve fund has increased duringtheyear, $34,040.02 The increase of the Assets during the year has been $2,461,102.75. KM reason of some Associations showing loss of Assets, is. re closing up their business and going into liquidation. The earnings paid out during the year has been $o04,2t)7.4y. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">)F THE STATE MANKIND HOARD 43 h An examination of the forgoing summaries of the reports le condition of building and loan associations as a whole, n a very gratifyng growth, and demonstrates that they are ieipating in the general prosperity of the state. The Department tinds but little reason to criticise the man ■Cement &lt;&gt;f the various associations, and believes on the whole they are being conducted in compliance with the law. In. nients seem to be made, as a rule, on a conservative basis, with a view to protect the associations should a recession of financial conditions come about. There can be no question but that in prosperous times such as we have had during the past few years, there is some danger of over estimating the value n' cnritiea offered. Optimism is contagious and values only a rel ative term. With the present advance in real estate the - ■ danger that values may be overestimated. However, the Department believes, as before stated, that in the main, cc.n ;ervatism is the rule in making loan Bhere are some practices obtaining among the associations, I believe subject to just criticism. For instance, it ice of some associations having agents soliciting loitns who t a membership fee in advance. This practice works no hit) and gives no ground for criticism where the loan is pted. However, where the loan is rejected for any re it is a hardship on the proposed borrower, and could hardl cfauwed a square deal. This Department receives numerous complaints against this practice, and believes associations I prohibit it, if for no other reason than that it le;i ion often in the minds of the applicants that the number &gt;e is the ruling incentive with the agent. If the loan is •d the membership fee should be returned to the pr&lt;v borrower. I desire to call your attention to another practice, while not in conflict with the law in any way. yet in some instances cur ried to the extent that under certain conditions it might prove unfair to the- investor, and that is the practice of issuing too large a proportionate amount of investment stock compared to the amount of stock issued to borrowing members. It can be readily seen that in prosperous times, such as we now enjoy, witli the large amount of idle money seeking investment, that " iations may issue such an amount of this kind of sto&lt; - to bring embarrassment should there come a period of financial depression. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Another nutter to which I wish to call the attention of your lonorable body and the management of the various associations of the state is the provisions for the advance payment of loans, which I think in some instances, under the by-law* of assoeia tions, is burdensome and inequitable to the borrower. While it s true as a common practice that a debt is not due until the late of maturity specified in the contract, yet the building and oan law specifically recites that equitable provisions shall be nade in the constitution and by-laws for the advance payment of loans, thus making a loan made by a building and loan associ tion differ essentially from loans of the same character made »y ordinary loan agencies. It is tlie intention of this Depart nent where it finds provisions in the constitution and by-laws vlnch make the advance payment of loans burdensome and in suitable to the borrower to require u change ton fair and &lt;iuitable basis of settlement. As there has been some controversy from time to time re - garding the right of building and loan associations to invest their surplus funds in certain securities, the Department has requested from Attorney General Thompson an opinion as to the intent of the law. which is fully set forth in the following communication: STATE OF NEBRASKA, I Offick of Attoknby Genkkak i Hon. E. Roysc. Secretary State Banking Hoard. Lincoln t Dear Sir: I have your letter submitting the follow!] opositions and requesting opinions thereon: 1. Is a building and loan association authorized under the law to loan the maximum sum of S."&gt;.(Mmi to each of several mem l&gt;ers and receive therefore, in addition to a lien on the shares of stock owned by such borrowers, by a company or corporation to loans r a real estate mortgage given secure one or more of such -. Can a building and loan ; funds in "convertible assets" *u&lt; certificates of deposit of banks. V spoliation lawfully invest its has general fund warrants, nited States Ixmds. etc.?" Compiled Statutes 19(1 thorizes building and loan associ itions to loan monev to their members, and also provides that no person shall hold in his own right more than $5,000 par value of stock in any such corpora tion. Section 1 4^;,'.* provides that no loan shall be made to a member of the association in excess of the par value of his stock, and that for such loan the association shall have alien Section Usal of Chapter 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 upon the stock, and that ample real estate Mcarity shall be given to secure said loan. There appears* to be no requirement in the statute that the real estate offered for security shall be the real estate of the borrower. I am therefore disused to hold that, such an association may loan to any one of its mem ben the maximum amount allowed by the l,iw governing loan and building associations and that the association may tak. security therefore a mortgage on unencumbered real es1 owned by anyone authorized to execute a mortgage thereon. bAs to your second question you are advised that the title of act tinder which building and loan associations are organ in this state is in part as follows: "To provide for the organization, government, regulation, exam ination, reporting, and reorganizing or winding up of the busi ness of associations now or hereafter incorporated under the laws of this state and which shall be organized within this - ■aiswg money to be loaned among its members From the title and the body of the law it is clear the intent nd purpose of the legislature was to restrict the busine^ uilding and loan associations to transactions between the lation and its stockholders or members in the raising of money o be loaned among its members. There appears to be no pro - lsion in the law authorizing loans except to members. An in - estment. is not a loan. The buying of general fund warrants nd United States bonds is not a loan in common parlance, nor within the meaning of the law governing building and loan iations. but is an investment. A deposit of funds with a bank nd the receipt by the depositor of a certificate of de|x)sit may be regarded as a loan, but in my opinion it is not one autboi to be made by building and lo.m associations. In section 14-ali&gt; le legislature has specifically enumerated what such associa - ons iire authorized to purchase and to expend their money for. aving thus specified the matters and things in which the ,. ation may invest its money, the rule of construction expressio alterias applies with peculiar fitness to this question, and restrains such associations from investing its funds in any other manner. Very respectfully, W. T. THOMPSON, </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 '' s '*'*'* i i'*'**&lt;(iH»stion;isto whom sha ivs of building and loan associations shall be listed for assessment under the new revenue act, I herewith append the decision of the Supreme Court in the rase entitled "Nebraska Central Building and Loan Association vs. Board of Equalisation of Lan - er County", which settles the point at issue and dearly in - terprets the new law. as follows: Nebraska Cent. Mid- * Loan Ass'n v. Hoard of Realization of Lancaster County. apreme Court of Nebraska. March 7. i«.»o7.) atutes Title ,,f Act Building and 1.,'kit. Associations luxation. Section I:;, c. 17. ,,. »|, Laws IH9N (I4&gt;al». Comp. St l which provules the manner in which, and by whom the *fa ot building an( i | Oall associations shall be listed (hr. ku ..m.i shall he listed for assessment. is not unconstitutional: and wa not repealed by the provisions K venue Law i:io:s. p . _|o;j ( . nine. Such associations should assessed in the manner indi rated by that section, and an essment of the amount of the Fttfitfes taken to the association, which the assessor assumes unpaid, cannot be upheld. (Syllabus by the Court.) Appeal from District Court. Lancaster County: Cornish. Act-m by the Nebraska Central Building 4 Loan Associa twn against the board of equalisation of Lancaster county Judgment for plaintiff, and defendant appeals. Affirmed. •I L. Cal.hvell. p. M Tyrrell, and C. K. Matson for appell ■nt. Meld. Rk-ketts .V Kkketts, for appellee. BARNKS, .1. The Nebraska Central Building &amp; Loan Assoc.afon. the appellee in {h \s case, is a corporation organized under t,,e provisions of ch a ,,ter 17. [.. m;s. ()f thv Session Liws «.I I&gt;!MHse,r,ons |4h-h 1 to^H-a 33, in&lt;lusive, of chapter 16 of tie Compiled Statutes of P.,,,.-,.. having its principal office and Place o| busmess in Uncarfer county . It appears that in the spring ol ISHO tlie c-ounty assessor of that &lt;&lt;»unty found from an examination of the records, that the association had real es - tote Dmrt«agf« of record therein, amounting according to the face value to SI7o.&gt;7. He also found from his assessment rolls that residents of that county had returned shares for assess - *»r w,!! 1S&lt; u"" &gt;l " l&lt;llnK; " ul Uma : '^H-iation to the amount of ■ZO.UW. Hetliereup.,11 assumed that such shares should be </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 ■*d to said mortgages. He further found that a i&gt;ortion of mortgages had been paid, leaving wliat ha assumed to be paid balance thereon of S&gt;K&gt;0,&lt;&gt;oo. He tliereuiKin assessed the association the sum of £2 therefor. Tin' association objected to the assessment so n. and tiled its petition with the county bond of equalization, prat - ing that it lie set aside. The board overruled the object; and continued the assessment. The association thereupon ap - pealed to the District Court where, after a hearing, judgment whs rendered in its favor: the assessment was held to l&gt;e null and void, and the county clerk was ordered to strike the «. from the assessment roll. From that judgment the board of equalization has appealed to this court. It appears that the district court held that the association should have been assessed according to the provisions of sect ion 13 of Chapter 17, p. 91. Of the Session I&gt;aws of 1 «!•!», and it is conceded that if that section is valid, then the judgment of the trial court must be affirmed. The appellant contends, how. that the section above mentioned is unconstitutional be&lt; the act is broader than its title. Section 11 of article ;t of the Constitution, provides, among other things, that: "No bill shall contain more than one subject, and the same shall beclearl; pressed in its title." This provision of the Constitution has usually been held to be mandatory; but it has also recei\. it liberal construction. Indeed, there has been a general B-;ition to so construe it y a construction whose rather than toembarrass legisla - strictness is unnecessary to the accomplishment of the beneticial purposes for which it has adopted. Cooley on Constitutional Limitations, No. 1-M&gt;. The title to the chapter in question contains a general statement that it is "An act to provide for the organization, government, regulation, examination, reporting, and reorganizing or wind - ing up of the business of " building and loan associations; and the section under consideration provides that: "Such ciations shall not be subject to taxation on their capital stock. nor on their loans advanced on mortgages, but shares in ■&lt; iations shall, for the purpose of taxation, be oonskk and held as credits, and members and holders of such shares shall list the same for taxation, and the same shall be taxed in such manner and subject to such deductions as may be provid - ed by law for the taxation of other credits. " By the ad - option of this section the legislature has provided the manner in which, and by whom the shares of such associations shall be </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 KlI-ir.KNTH ANSMW1. I(KI"ORT OK THK listed for taxation. It appears that the act of 1H!»:» was a reen - actment of a similar law pa— cd by the legislative assembly of 1891, with some unimportant amendments, and section 18 was a part of the act of 1H!H, and was known as "section H" of that act It is an important fact that prior to the origmnl act there were no building and loan associations in this state, and the gen - era) revenue law of 1879 contained no provision for the taxation ich associations. So section s of the old act was a proper subject for legislative action, and was germane to the general subject of the organisation and regulation of building and loan "•iations. It was held in People v. Mahaney, IS Mich. 495, that the title of "An act to establish a i&gt;olice government for the City of Detroit" was not objectionable for its generality, and that the matters properly connected with the establishment and efficiency of such a government, including taxation for its support, and courts for the examination and trial of offenders, might constitutionally be included in the bill under its general title It was there said: "The police government of a city cmi Id not be organised without a distinct act for each specific duty to be devolved upon it. and this could not be passed until a multitude of other statutes had taken the same duties from other officer* before performing them. And these nevi tes. fragmentary as they must necessarily be, would often fail of the intended object from the inherent difficulty in ei pressing the legislative will when restricted to su \i Dirrow bounds ." In People v. McCalluin. 1 Neb.. 182, the court ezprt • as follows: "It is not required that the title should con tain an abstract of the bill, nor set out the particulars of the amendment. Whether this requirement of the Constitution is _:ned as a rule for the government of the legislature, an ob - ince of which is enjoined by a sense of duty and the official oath of each member, and not subject to any supervisory power of the courts, it i» unnecessary to stop to inquire. The Consti - tution not having fixed the degree of particularity with which a title is to express the subject, it is enough that the Legislature^ with this provision before them, have selected their own title, and although we might not agree u(&gt;on it as the most suitable or comprehensive one. the act for that reason is not to be declared void." In State v. Hemis, 45 Neb. 7:S"&gt;. 04 N. W. 851, the consti - tutional provision here interposed was discussed, and it was there said: "The test is not whether the title chosen is the most appropriate, but whether it fairly indicates the scope and pur- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">SKCKETAFO I &gt;!■ THK STATE BANKIN'i li&lt; 49 it pose of the act. Authority to remove unfaithful ofti&lt; proper if not a necessary incident of municipal government, and the provision therefor is obviously within the title of the act netining, regulating, and prescribing the duties and pom of government of cities of the metropolitan class." To the ■ effect are Whitney v. City of kit Pleasant, 11 Iowa, 482, and State ex rel. Wier v. Count; Judge of Davis Co., 2 Iowa. 280. .U before stated, section 13 merely provide* how the funds of the ass(K-iation shall he regarded, and by whom its shares shall be listed and returned for the purpose* of taxation. While it If the manner of such taxation to be further provided for by oth - er laws upon that subject. So we are of opinion, in view of the fact that when this section wa first enacted the general revenue law contained no provision foi the taxation of building and loan rightfully made a part of the act creating and governing them It is further contended t tislation. and is void for that reason. It has often been held t a law which applies to a particular class of persons ur irticular class of persons or our porations, and operates generally and uniformly throughout th stat within the prohibition of section 15, of article the Constitute loan associatio he act in question applies to all building and i class, and operates generally and uniform y as to such associations. Such laws have uniformly been up held by the courts. State v. B ka, -JO Neb. 375, 30 N. W. 2fi7; State v. Graham, Id Neb. 71, 11 N. W. 170: Van Horn v. State. lid. however, that the I&gt;-gisla tu re may not. arbitrarily and w thout reason, create a clan the result would bean infring be affected bv legislation, w inent upon the constitution thihition This raises the qu&lt; tion: Are corporations, known as "building and loan ass tions," arbitrarily and without i ison. placed in a class by them- selves for the propose of taxatk n. by the act in question? To answer this question, it is prop r to point out some of the dis tinctive feature iations. It appears that they may commence business upon the approval of their artiel&lt; incorporation, constitution and bylaws, without any capital. This privilege is not accorded to any other class ufeorporati They are not required to have any tixed capital stock. Their stockholders may withdraw from the association after :m&gt; days, on lid days' notice. In fact, such associations have no capital stuck, in the proper sense of the word. There is no uniformity in the face value of the shares of such an association. Mem '&lt;-i;itions, that subject was ri&lt;;l it the section in question is cla </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 i • \Mi 11 1 " 1 1 l ) \ II iC ill 1 1 1 1 \ ill^TiJillli t *T^ T^ *SO l' licit" ( * VO I*\" ■hare may represent a different actual value. The face value of .shares issued h.v such an association will amount tomany times thf money paid to the association thereon. The foregoing illustration would seem to give such ass&lt;«-i a distinctive character, and not only warrant, hut require them to be placed in a class by themselves for the purpose of K their property for taxati tion cannot be sustained in question is void, beca Ml. So it seems clear that this It is also contended that the ise it amended the revenue law law contained no provisions lor itions. for the most excellent a ■r building and loan associ i that no such association enact-ed. So the legisl ization and government of xisted in this state at the iture. when it provided for the buildinK and loan associations. deemed it at eessary to | ty lor taxation the manner of lis Kstly it is contended 1 hat lit of the law relating t&lt; t ■ revenue law of lKK-i. repealed aiding and loan associati and that such at ions sin be assessed according of section ."•&gt; of said law (Laws 1 !M »::. p. )o; An examination of that lection will show that building pecitically mentioned therein, .tretch of imaginataon to hold Bin associations are not deed it requires ;i great reat that they are included even by implication within its provision*. &lt; &gt;n the other hand, the record in this case discloses that when the present revenue act was before the legislature for pa.ss nn ."&gt;&lt;; originally contained the words "Building and Loan"; and when the bill was under consideration in the committee of the whole, it was considered that the provisions of that section should not be applied to such associations. And in view of the fact that section I :! of chapter IT. p. 91, of tile Session Laws of &gt;, contained a specific meth&lt; d for assessing the shan such associotions. the words " Muilding and Loan'" were st lick - en from the act. and thus the legislature evinced its approval ne method of assessment provided for as aforesaid, and its determination not to include such associations within the terms of the act then under consideration. Indeed, the section in question has l&gt;een in force since ls'.U. a period of more than 15 years, and all departments of the state have ac&lt;|Ui - 1 in its provisions. Such contemporaneous construction .titled to great weight in the determination of this ques - tion. If this manner of assessment is unfair and lacks exact of IK7J». As before stated, that </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 uniformity, us claimed by appellant, that is a matter to be iddressed to the consideration of the r^e^islatu re. and cannot be corrected by the courts. Appellant further attempt - justify the assessment on the ground that the association failed to furnish the assessor a list of all its members, their places of residence, and the number and value of the si owned by each of them. The law does not seem to 9] fically require sucli information, and even if it did, a failure to do so would hardly justify an assessment like the one in question herein. Indeed, we cannot understand how it be upheld y kn-oun the judgment of the district :oinir reasor court is hereby affirmed Nebraska Cent. Bld«'. A l^oan A Board of Equali ( zittion of Lancaster County. (No. 14,7.%.) (Supreme Court of Nebraska. Mav 1". 190 Motion for rehearing. Overruled 'V opinion, see 111 N. \V. 147 SEIXUVICK. C. .1. In the brief upon the motion for re hearing, it is contended that the decision in this case will permit shareholders in building and loan associations to offset tren ml ral indebtedness against the net values of their shares. This is nut the intention of the opinion. The point decided is that building and loan associations are not to be assessed upon their mortgages, but that the assessment is to be made ujxm the shares and against the owners thereof. We are satisfied that the holding upon this point is correct. It is true that section 13 of the act of !*!•!» (Laws !*!)!». p. 91, c. 17) which is referred to in the opinion, provides that the shares in such issociations ''shall for the purpose of taxation be considi ami held as credits"; but the revenue law of 1903 classifies credits for the purpose of taxation, and provides that i its that represent moneys in bank, loans, or moneys invested .ire to be assessed without offset of indebtedness. If money paid u|K&gt;n stock in building and loan associations is to b« considered as money invested, it would fall within the &lt; of credits that are not subject to offset of general indebted ness. The net value of such shares of stock can be easily iscertained from the books of the association, and there is no -hi for concluding that shareholders would necessarily evade taxation uiH&gt;n the values of their shares </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 We think nur former decision is ri^ht. and the motion for rehearing is overruled. Ipplications of the Standard Trust company of Birininn- Alabama. and the International Improvement Company nver. Colorado, for permission to do business in Nebras der the Installment Investment Company law, made X the year, were rejected by the State Banking Board. ■'n the following panes will be found detailed statements ■ condition of the sixty six building and loan associa - of the state at the close of business June M, H'&lt;&gt;7. Very respectfully, K. ROYSE, </seg>
            <seg id="p053">the sixtv - ■ condition of </seg>
            <seg id="p054">ST. \T KM KM THK CONDITION \LBION BUILDING AM) LOAN ASSO&lt; IATION VLBION. NKBRASKA Wli tile IWtl Kill K( Win. Weil Vice-I K. A. Mi.t.-i K. S. Thompsoi i&gt;. M. Needhara i RKl-l I' \ An, V A H IV H I" A I I V X Tul [.I A HI I.I I (■ • A.I A rest and i \ T </seg>
            <seg id="p055">ENDING JCNE :t &gt;, WW! v ■ « </seg>
            <seg id="p056">KTATKMKXT OK THE CONDITION 1&gt;I ALLlANTKlU'lLDINi; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION ALI.IANl K. NKKRASKA It. M. Hampton A. I). Etodf I!. K. &lt; iilnian. . I! M. Hampton. B. V Giin Vic.-l'i s. :\tt( hlUKi T H I I' I' l&lt; h' \V I ass i : r s * i l'I"f LIABI1.ITIKS i*d |ir.»!n ! holders inearr T.it &lt; &gt;n tin :&gt;&lt;it!i dav (it June, 1 OFFICERS Advance interest and premiun </seg>
            <seg id="p057">M Pl.KMEXTAL KKI N N I II * A A TS AND EXPEND1TTRKK FOR THB FISCAL ■ KNDINti JINK *», l'.iiT Kt:i 'El J'TS </seg>
            <seg id="p058">SOUTHEASTERN NEBRASKA ItriUHNi; AM) LOAN </seg>
            <seg id="p059">t f t </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 • STATEMENT AURORA BUILDING A LOAN ASSOCIATION Al'KoRA. NEBRASKA On tin- .'tilth (lav of .June. 1! IV. Vice-1 s, Lounsbury Treas I. n. cim- A'ti. I 111! I.. I .) H Hur N .1 Itn J&lt;n John E Up A. A. He VV. E I -■ rs ne \. Tol I LJABILJT1K.S « I OKTHE CONDITION i. i; Himti Schttisnnver Kand fixture*, t interest, i r« mid taxes paid runninir. HHie* :ind dmdends ■ led priplif. ireholcler-. on incomplete loai </seg>
            <seg id="p061">ITS AND EXPENDITURES F&lt;&gt;K THE FISCAL VEAI KNDING JUNE 30, 1'hiT x ♦ »• SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Serial or Perm </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 r I STATEMKNT OF THE CONDITION Ot STATE SAVINGS* LOAN ASSOCIATION «&gt;n the 30th day of June. Iito7. OFFK :rs H. II. Norm John Terry Vice-Pi DIRECTORS H H Norcros A. E. Webe J. S. McCleery A SETS i .ure I ■ uit* and office bid ■ nt interest premiums and tine : luxes paid To« &lt; LIABILITIES I II 4.472 Ailvar.i .nd premiums Otbei Total fi K ATR ICE. NK BRA S K A ■ «»•&lt;' - (;raff Tr, Pemberton Utornev T. J- ChidesM A. H !■ • - in proeeaa ol tor in- Itock running. I Dues jnd dividem stuck rund d profits pholder* on incomplete 1. ■ a unearned. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 i * Ma Ma Fill Kill rx As X N 11, I A 1 unr t t A N ■ I don tkno borrow) ENDING JUNE 30. 1'jot. EXPENI 'ITl'K KS PPL.EMENTAL KK1'( Ixat upon whi tl) tl iation as eollater i.l n.ortpra, i nt premiums charged foorrowei n ,,f Premium in*c fiscal ye; k during: ftw </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 1 STATK.MI OF THE CONDITION OF Tllh HKATIIICK Hl'IIJ)IN(; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION BEATRICE. NEBRASKA On the :!&lt;&gt;th dav of June. Mm PFICKII Kail. M. l&gt; Schaeke) Vice-1 . Treasui Attorn Kimmerlj - Idon. Sheldon. IRKCT II I- A til lix«'^ paid U ABILITIES und di\ nit- rids d- r&gt; mi iucomi .ml prf « </seg>
            <seg id="p065">\ XTKN I I A t • 1KNTA1 • i n A S AND KXl'KNIMTrKKS F&lt; )I{ THK FISCAL "i ENDING JINK MK l»rj KBCEaPTa »*t*m pt*r $!&lt;"*' per n - </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 KIFTI 1MI. KKl'ORT OF THK ■r &gt; ' i STATKMKNT OK THK CONDITION 1 &gt;K THK BLAIR BUILDING A LOAN ASSOCIATION BLAIR. NEBRASKA On the 30th (lay of June. 1SM»T OKF1 KKS EKinin . Si Harrison ellv .Pi Vice l'resi(l&gt; Sei-reta C. A. Schmi t . ' i'H;uil(in AttOIT IlIKKCTnKS r. W. An ASSKTs * H &gt;r&lt; re nd Hit -'. premium* and tl il Tot &gt;&gt; LIABIF.ITIKS k running. I Dues and dividends ; •-fund Ml ~d pmrlt .ireholder-i on inoonii»lete loan: -ins unearned Advance interest and premium </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK KI8CAL YEAR ENDING JCNE 30, 19OT </seg>
            <seg id="p068">STATKMKNT OF THE CONDITION ENTERPRISE LOAN &amp; BUILDING ASSOCIATION &lt; a.\ibkiim;i JRASK OFKK'l Geo, Wiliian I). I.. Tall. na Vice-Pi s, KIRKl H. I W w W I ' Mi AS k x w Tu LJABILJT1ES it-il i.mf ■ reboldi ed « </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 A RECEIPrS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE FISCAL VEAI ENDING JINK 30, 1907 A </seg>
            <seg id="p070">STATKMKNT CENTRAL CITY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OKFU'KH Vice l'i it i Treas DIRECTORS K K 1!.. H !■' K S|.ra Mi- Kit ASSKTS xmrt LIABII.ri'iKS ck runmnir. illursandd K )FTHE CONDITION OI CKNTRAL CITY, NEBRASKA On the :t&lt; &gt;tli diiv of June, 1!" ( ;. II i .ia \ K K. Spra)f McKndra - ;II1(1 laxe- |i: ■1 i.n.til- ■ m incompli . unearned and prewln—.. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">i &gt; i &gt; MKX i s I A A 1 &gt; I N ( i -M N E UKCKII'TS a" </seg>
            <seg id="p072">t t &gt; FIFTEENTH ANSI' AI. RKI'UKT (IF I HK STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION OF CHAPPELL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CHAPPELL, NEBRASKA On the .'ttith (lay of .Iuni&gt;. 1!H OFFICER ■1'ilin H. Werta Preside -id man Vice Presider Neumann s&lt; H. I. Uabicck Treasurer DIKKC'TORS idman Chav H. Soeten H I. naliiiiiiili K M. Jobnaoc Jobn K We ,i&gt; C Neun W K Uuudet H. (i. VV A KTS I i in procesN "f - I id Hit ■ Tola i IABILITIES IXies and dividends :il '.ront&gt; *l areliolders ums uneiirn eresl and iiremiun ree Kl interest, premiums and and tmxen paid . . Ma.... </seg>
            <seg id="p073">;ktary of the state haskinc; iioakd RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES KOK THK FISCAL VI KNUINd JINK ;i i. 1!« -\ &gt; S \ A A| A •lc per &gt;.taare per A A </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Vl'K.MK.Vl Till: fOXDITIl &gt;S c IF TIM (LAY CENTER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION \ ( &gt;ii tin' :&gt;' &gt;t li d»\ of .1 I'lIM V \\ I MT L 1 LJABIUTIKS « (LAY IKNTKR, M ■Me [&gt;&lt;&gt;«'&lt; '. Wan </seg>
            <seg id="p075">i i s N \ f A RKO'.IPTS AND KXl'K.NDITIKKS Foil THE FISCAL YEAI KNDING JUNK Mi, IW»7. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF TMh CK&gt;LUMBUS LAND. LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION tfBUS, NKB3.VSXA ( In the :hlth ilu\ ( if I! •FFK'ER I , L Lund Si-otl Vice I'i ... . 8e Henr) Hockenberjfei G. Berber i't'a&gt; \ttoi ■ ■ni interesi. prem d taxes paid 'S paid </seg>
            <seg id="p077">I x t» KK' KIPTS AND KXI'K.NDITlltKS POR THE FISCAL. YKAR EMD - ING JUNK 30, 1907. KKCKIPT 1 M KXPKN1 T &lt; a HPLKHKNTAL RKI'ORT *l«. diiizat anizai of last report al yt-av during risoul \ ear .hit. at this dat [fir non-payment o4 d this date i)K atiH-kholders &lt;]u«- and unpaid W*ge* suhjt*. t ti» foreclosure, and am(re|cate u mount ol ■\KKifKatf amount i»f sa it, iit«- upon whit-h A latioii as t S • &gt;wii ■ A TT Ml* ... ■&gt;■ Appraised liiiK purpo»fl during fiscal year it w' homestead mortxapf** (iurir ioc ffttlon •il hnrrow«n during fi »l barrowen durin; ft f.M'n-- Mim brt out IK lisr;il J - m ninff Mock tiurlni f i&gt;i - k &lt;] it ring </seg>
            <seg id="p078">STATEMENT OV THK CONDITION OF EQUITABLE BUILDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS AS CIATION fOLUMBUS, NKBRASKA &lt;)n the ."Kith day of June, )'«&gt;' Tol LIABILITIKS -n«-k runnini.'. I [)u«-^ and dividends . ,i si.,,-k e fund Undivided prultbi treholderN on incomplete loans . niH lint* arlifil T,,l WSWiram Speice . . Becker H. S. Kllii.tt . .1. .1. Sullivan • - interest ;iMd prenn </seg>
            <seg id="p079">RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FoK THE FISCAL VKAI! KNDING JUNE SO, 1'niT. UWKIPTS EXPENDITURES I I'I'1.K.MKNTA1. REPORT ■ X I V ient at this &lt;lat** m i ■lHMIIit I IK IIMUfl Appraise*! pun w I \ intic N iaii i ;iwals lal.l st... iiiK lis.nl *i borrow stock iim &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p080">BTATEMKN1 IIKTHK CONDITMNilh CRETE LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION &lt; KKTK. XKHKASKA )n tlie Mtb ilay of June, l!&gt;&lt; OFKK K ■ Haijrlit. . Fleming Vice-Pi H. Anderson s, 15. Aniltrs FresM DIRECTOHS /. \Vat*Tiii:tr M H Kiflinnii U W. H»I&lt;t«m \ F Ka K J Kademaoher H Uocidc II Mi « I Jill ire uml tixtur *rfst iirerinums uttd tine i iixi-s |&gt;uid c T LIABILITIKS » ies iind dividends udsUK e fund ed protu .rehold«*r&gt; on uneouiplete loans mis uneiirneil •f du»-- \iivam'i- int«re**i and preniiun Tot </seg>
            <seg id="p081">FHE STATE BANKING ItKt KIl'TS AND KXPKNDITURES H)K THE KIHt'AL YKAR KND1NG JUNK 30, Unit SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT Plan irf Asm" iation. (Serial "r Permanent ■ iiur hi .a- h share of stork . - Issued since organization, (if serial) ... illliZU \ si lit . es iSfcued si ii' e in nan izatii »[.... tliare* In fore* at d report . . I ist \ shares Issued during ttecal vt-ar footing of iwn I'lii eding Items \'o of siiaif- witbtirawn before maturiti during fi-n-ai year No. of shares matured during fiscal year No. of shares eam-elled during fiscal year, but not wlttk N. i ,.t ni: itf tiiM-t- Die -eding Items No. ot' shares in force at this date (t this ilat. No. of shares i&gt;f running stock in force at this date ... shares i»f full paid stork in force at this date . shares loaned on I No. of share* on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment ati&lt; r or non-payment of ! ti Total amount of dues delinquent at this date i of dues owinp by borrowing stockholders . t of interest, premiums and fines due and unps irtgages subject to foreclosure ortgaffefl in process of foreclosure and r i,f loans on Improved real estate /aim- of improved m*m| estate upon whit h In t at St. \ ll'i.lHlt V 1 fi es due ami unpaid A N«i. mortKatri-s subject to for it ' &lt;.f loans on impnn «-il real t-stat li Appraised vaiujp of Improvements . t A I Amount of 1' an's uixhi uni : Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon whi been made Appraised value of unimproved rt-al eatatr upon whiih Amt. Insurance in forve and sukigned to ti SiriiiuV ranre in i»;-f anil iisiigneii to tl 1 No of loans made t..r i i.ildin^ purposes during fiscal No. of loans iiia.li- for MillillnK purpose* during ns.-al y So loans made for payjiient of hom&lt; - Amount of advance payments of loans during tis. al \ * ■' borrowing storkliolders non-borrowins stockholdei I miiM &gt;s holding stoi-k in the association -.- rate per tent of interest charged b^.rroweis du cent premiums charged borrow II Amount of advance payments of loans durina N non-borrowing Mockhold mini -s holilillK stock in I ■ A nt of interest charged borrowers liurinR tis notif I premiums chanced borrower! JurinK \ non Plan of premium Amount &lt;r« &lt;hter 1 to reserve fund durinpr tiscal year Amount of louses ctiarjfeii to reserve fund during fiscal ve; riurlns fla &amp; "* Amount of dividends fle&lt;-lare&lt;) on full paid stork during fls- ■;* ■ ratp per rent of diviuends declared durine fiscal \ • • runninK time at stock matured during tisVal year Average rat»- p«T &lt;fnt of div </seg>
            <seg id="p082">8TATKMENT OK THK CONDITION Ol PAIRBURY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION KAIKIUUY. NKBRASKA OKKICKH- Vut-l'i S.-civta At to Uett K I.. Smipk .1 \ A Me A. V IV I' K II'M P S Ka ass hrrs i x: t Tol LIABILITIES nd dividends S id lilltits u-rs mi int'oiiip : - unearned and pi Tot On tht- Until (lav of .limr. 1!miT B'ritchett ini|&gt;kin&gt; \ Vii&gt;. Bvan*.. . . irtigan I&gt;IRK&lt;'Tl&gt; leu t iint-ifst premiums ;mil hnt I i axes paid </seg>
            <seg id="p083">TARV 1&gt;K THK STATE BANKING BOAHD IlKt'KIPTS « 1 ■ 3 I'l'l.KMK.NTAI, REP&lt; mancnt &gt; k N. laatlon, (if ization . . . &amp; ilu E it thii da if share* uf fit 11 paid stork in force at tliis date N., N. U Ko. ..f si tliis chitt Aniimnt «if lines owinc l&gt;v borrowing stm-kl iitnl unpaid inii :i- mount nit AtiKiiint of loans on Improved rra \ i 'iraist-'l valtio of improved real estate hihhi wliii-h loan I At .v; ■ poll W A tl iation as eollati Amount of advance payments r mount mount mount mount • ■ fund durtnn fiscal on riTnninc stork «1urinp fis.-al ; on full pnM stock dm dendi dt*ctmr«d during k niMtured durfi m i&gt; \M) KM-KMHTIUKS Kol{ THK HALK KISi'AL YKAK KND1NG JINK M&gt;. 1!«I7 XI'KNIMTIKI- \'o. of loans made for building purposes during flsral vi-ar Mo. loans made for payment of &gt; ■iation borrowers riurtns Hs-nl vear iMimnviTs (hiring: I . t eta par we -u on ~\i&lt;o </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 BTATEMKNT OK THK CONDITION OP THh FAIRFIELD BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION KAIKKIKLI). NK UK ASK A on the 30th ilay of June, !'■" OFFICERS r~i and Toi rKmrii-h. . . . I.. B»yjv. Anawalt . . T. I'. Bhtvely Vice Presidet KecreUri Tresxarei • mplete loans Premium* unearned ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p085">11 EXPENDITURES i .1.540. X peniiane S S I s N No ipruved rt- ;il estuie ui&gt;on vMeta louns have tK*en made madf ■n s A ■ct \ \U KNDING JINK 30, 1!m&gt;7 RECEIPTS I'PI.KMKNTA L KKPORT _';l!.- rllllill Hi 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 ■ \ BTATKMKNT EQUITABLE BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION FRKMONT, NKBRASKA OFF I T-'ICEKS Charles H. Ma.\ Krai.k Hammond. Arthur Traeadoll &lt; harl.s |{. Wazi.- I.- l.onniis I'. &gt; Preside .Hecreta Attorn I)lKKCTlU««i Arthur Tn B. \'t-M/i*' Friink h'o Ibitii A [JuDkhu f.' Kre.l Umt ASSKTS ' 71 .n uaire lo^ns in proct-** of fon ri .iti tin tn intrr.-Nt pri'tinunis and Hm ; tuxes patfi .is^lS Tola { LI A HII TIES . stock runninif. I Ihies and dividends . rt stock &gt;e fund • *1 protit .ire holders on incomplete loans unearned n. ■f dues ind i&gt;remium.s d Interest «- OFTHK CONDITION OK &lt;&gt;n the 3&lt;&gt;tli &lt;la\ of June, 1!«'T Frank H;immon&lt;l t. r..&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p087">SECRKTAKV i &gt;K THE STATE IIANKINii HOARD RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES K&lt;»K THE KIS( ,\l. KNDING JINK .To. »9O7 RECEIPTS II - Interest I.M m and transfer fees KXI'KNDITIKKS «to.&lt;*» r,.:: ,;,^ none - ■■&gt;#■ rawals, dues ■ awals, earnings *" '•• i.i-k. dues i*i6.fl* - ■ M-k. citruiiLKs - I slink, dues i stock, earnings , .iiil stock, dues paid Sim k. earnings Iparesai ■■&lt; ■ li mere- ri- ■in to hanil w?l XI ,i IHS.M it tier payment-. ' sri'Vl.KMKNTAI. KKI'IIKT. i'l.KMENTAI, RKl'dllT nf Association. (Serial or Permanent) ;tlue of t'Hrli share of stock faM.M k \'o. of series issued since organisation, (if serial* t" ihares ismh-iI since organisation fcJM iharea in force at date of last re|x&gt;rt W anization, (if serial) hist r*'i&gt;ort §! ia of shares issued during fiscal year '-■:« K ,if two |.lei e.litm [tens 1017 So. of ■hares withdrawn before maturity (luring fiseal year 41 •i N.. of shares matured during liseal year •«&gt; , of shares cancelled durini ir, hut not withdrawn n..n. - ►otinu i&gt;t" three nrei editiK items o of shaies in fores at this date . .' 0 &lt;&gt;f shares of running stock in foree at this date ■hares of lull paid sto&lt; k in foree at this date 1 of shares loaned on . of shares on which dues are delinquent ii. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues •.hi ital amount of dues delinquent at this date tMLiM mount of dues owinK by tMirrawing stockholders &lt;m«i nt of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid .i. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggi. nt of same. t. yiuoun) f». mortpaKes in process of foreclosure and aKI?re|rate amount of same mount of loans on Improved real estate tr •nrais.d value of Improved real estate upon which loans have been I made -*!&lt;».«•..• ipraiscd value of Improvements ' noiint r»f loans unon unimproved real estate MM |.piais«l value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made - Ma* mt insurance in force and assiKiied to the association as collateral security *" o of loans made for hulldlng i 'ing fiscal year ■ I. loans made for payment of ! iiort»ca«res during year mount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year o. of borrowing stockholders o of non -lw&gt;r rowing stockholders ■ .. of minors holding stock in the association Ite per cent or interest charced borrowers during fiscal year ic per cent premiums charged borrowen during fiscal year if premium mount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year I N witlidruwi for t this date at this (Int. imjucnt if iharea sulij.it t&lt;i cancetlmUoo for non-payment of dues su I amount »f .hus &lt;l.lin«iuent at this date ♦«S.«| nt at this ilat&lt; Amount of .lues owlnc by tMirrawing stocklmlilers -i. x ■mil. 4. t3.ttt.09 urt- and BfSreS*te amount of same Amount of loans on Improved real estate frt.MX v ■statt state upon which loans hav A.H I aulcned to the association as collateral .v luring nscal year 0. loans made for payment Miring y ■ar if loan luring ftsra v payment :&gt; botrowera during fiscal year \ nr K mount nf losses chanted (■• reserve fund durinp fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on runninK st.vk .turiiiB fiscal y.ar V </seg>
            <seg id="p088">STATKMKNT OK THE CONDITION I* TMh NEBRASKA STATE lU'II.DINi; AND LOAN PhfllKI! Mathew* B. Haimm olson . . . I 'i ■ •(1 prcifit i t-holdtT' ui^ uni-arnfil ASSOCIATION KRKMONT. NKHKASKA &lt;&gt;n the 30th daj ol June. V.« </seg>
            <seg id="p089">KNDING .IINh KCEIPTS t XrKXKITI ' MENTAL IE KIM pern II X •■ N lloUllt Ni No \ A&gt; A </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 ■i : ' STATKMKNT OK THF. CONDITION- Ol UEKIN(&gt; 1U1LI)1N&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION CiKRING. NKBRASK.V On the Mill day of June. UN OFFI V.K Mcpisi Miller ...IVcsi.l.i Vice Preside i \V. Bonham i . \V. Kiinhuiii Secret* r .Treaxui A. H \V...«t ft A MO K lla&gt; .1 \\ Kic ASSKTS ... n pr m lur&lt;? and Hxt 2 ■reunumN anA rtne: s«*s and taxt I.I To r.IABII.ITIKS (l)ticv und diridend&lt;(&gt; n. larrholdcr- mi infumplrte k&gt;»Di ami lii Tola </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 KM KIPTH AND KXI'KNDITIKKS Kol{ THK FI8CAL VKA ENDING JUHE », Mr,. ncam KKCKIl'T." on bud .July 1, iww .T R tinning stock &gt; ~ mil paid stuck) »l il lines paid stork emiums ship ami transfi • paid M Real .-st •a I estate sales Total KXl'KNMTtKKS KXPENDITfRES t -inns tpenses WBIk, dues i wills, earnings iwals. earnings stock, (hit's stock, earnings M ill paiil stock, dues F ill paid Stock, famines mi t&gt;t rep irt TMal srrri.KMKNT.u. rkpobt. ITI.KMKXTA1. KKI'DUT lan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) \ u value of Men snare &lt;&gt;f stork I -.■vies Issued since organization, (if serial i . .... \.i. c.f series Issued since organization, (if serial) No. of shares issued since organtsatior o. of shares Issued since organisation in forre at date of last report res in force at .lal •■ of lust r.-j~&gt; » of shales issued during fiscal year ■ i two preceding ite us » uf *liare* withdrawn before maturity, durin* fiscal year o. of shares matured (luring fiscal yen of Miai&gt;-s cancelled during ttf al year, imt not withdrawn ,,r Hire* in-.-, e linn Items shares in force at this date wit) 0 of shares of running stock in force at this .late ..f shares of full paid stock in force at this date loaned on shares (if full paid stock in force at this date rI i\ -is loaned "ii i .if dues (.wins by borrowln* st.nkhol.lt mount of dues owing by borrowing stockholder! of merest, nreernif mil 1i&gt;*n rtw ;i»l uni&gt;:iid .-t^aKes subject to f.i riount of same. ,rtKa(Ce« in pnwess of foreclosure and imount of - wi .rti:a«.s in proceM of forecloeui am«i\int of sam- Bl of Inans on 'mproved real estal t ed \aliu* of Improved real --state upon which I. wins have h.-ei. mount of loans on 'mproved real .■state . i vnluc nf Improved real -state upon which Itwins have been , il value of Imprnvements it. ...I value of Improvement* . upon unimproved i.-al esta mount of loans upon unimproved real estate •.1 value of unimproved real est»&gt;e upon wh'er. e, n mnde nit Insuran '""I assigiied to the association as collateral i !■"•■• loans made for building puriM.ses durlnj flscal year na made for payment of homestead mortiraRPS duriiiK year .. ■ insuran perurit) loans made for building purposef during fiscal year auree Tit of homestead mortgairea durl mount of advance payment of loans during lisra] year Amount of advance payment of loans ilurlnic lis.a] ypar 1 ,i|tiiirrnvin'.'-"i' l &lt;'&gt;i'it"'« \ 'I members of the A - A '1 members «&gt;f the Ami v o of non-borrowing stockholders minors holding stm-k in the association , rate per cut of interest charted horTowera durin; Hs.al rate per cent premiums charged borrowers duriiiK nseal yeai non-borrowing stockholders .... minors hol.linn st.M-k in the associate X i_-.- rate per cent of interest ehartred borrower* during tis.a! ire rate i&gt;ei cent premiums .hareed horrowers during Hscal year Implies I A !»rKeil borrowers durin A m o Ptemr.1 \«etio« credited to reserve fund durinK fiscal &gt; notion ( ■ credit) Amount of losses chars rve fund during Raeal "ear n-m mount of losses charred to reserve fund during it mount if dividends declared on runnimr stock during fiscal year .. Kt of divider - - e rate per cent of .!r \ 1 * Hi A </seg>
            <seg id="p092">■ STATEMKNT TIIK CONDITION OF THh EQUITABLE BUILDING AND [jOAN ASSOCIATION GRAND ISLAND. NKBKAKKA On tlie .Sntli dav of .lime. Itt h V, &lt;;. Rvai \"ice I 'res i W. liiiniii^ii See i Treas II. WiM.lle\ . \ 1 1 c . I&gt;IHKCT( K Bll 11 No x rt 4 ! UA MI. ITII.S &gt;ues und k « I omit] </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 .1. • ■&gt; i I 1 i ■ &lt;: s M 2 KXI'KXDITIKKS « 1*1 A i I'i'I.K.MKNTAI. RKPORT li;iri.|il tst repm t withdn this date i this dat« hi for non-paymenl it this date ■torkholdrrs t of sain si n«l to the association ..... . ICh&lt; Ml is AND KXPENDIT1 RES K( &gt;lt THK FISCAL "i ENDING JUKE *&gt;. ls«i7 HKC'KU'TS. animation, animation uni] durinji </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 UK THK CONDITH &gt;N ill HAKTIN&lt;iTON lUILDIM; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION belev.. Vic- I H HIUKi T( \\ A. Li I. K i n pi til rest. &lt;t MAMUTIKS IXies and dividend*. cned :»nd preniiun 1 STATK.MKNT HARTINGTON. NKHKASK on the 30Ui &lt;l;i&gt; of .Turn-, \\» EtohinxoD - Nelson . . ASSETS ■ -t prottu eboldeni </seg>
            <seg id="p095">RECEIPTS K H • « l sa : t i he wl I UK&lt; KI1TS AND KXI'KNDITIKKS Fo|{ THK FISCAL YKAU KNI&gt;- NG JUNK :to. MOT XPK N I &gt; I'LKMKNTAL 1U </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 OF THK CONDITION UK THE HASTINGS BUILDING AND U&gt;AN ASSOCIATION HASTINCS NI'.BKASKA OFK1 Dmrj Siikmann \V. F. Buchanan .1 . t ). Robmr. . . . nniKiTXJKs A 1 - -:«' 1OUQ: [ •►rtfcraire loans in pr*K?ess of foreclos .re and liilun ilelin-iuciit inlerevi premiums ami tines , .1 T..I LiABir ! NMfl and dividends e fund I'ndiTidrd prortis Ihie shareholders on im-oniplete loans l*remiums unearned Adranoe dues lincluded in tirst item Advance interest and premium^ % l«3.l«x ToU STATK.M KNT «Hi the :«&gt;th &lt;la\ of .lunf. l'XT President V ice President Swtvtan I. &lt; &gt;. Rohrer. I. H. Klerainu ;inn tv K Huchunan Wm. M Lootmb H » Com </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 ENDING JUNE :»&gt;. I'hi; RBCBFT8. I »it»s. (running stock lid—, i full paid «t4 Interest kl Kli M. .•( ami \ «. ■lMI l- kxpendit I'KKS A t ti irn Direct) alan A I IV IS.0M • I w; Wit Full .1-1, id advance pi i iverdrafts clue hanks and orerdraft^ prev ■ II ear repaid SUPPLEMENTAL, KKl'' HIT \sso.iation. (Serial or Permanent) of «uli share of stock pern .me A stock No. "I series Issued since organization ri.-s issued since organization, (if serial) if serial ;ucs issued since oiKamzatiof No So mii's In furoe al .late of last report last report ii.s issued during fiscal year N. [ two preceding items .... res withdrawn i»etore maturity during itseal year f tine.- preceding Item* So. of shares ill Force at this date :i (*.»■• are* in force at this date . . shares of runnlns stork in force at this (late ?w&gt; ues .&gt;f running stock in force at this date No of shares of full paid stock in force at this dat&lt; arcs .if full paid stock in force at this date Eo. of stares l'«necl on o "I share? &gt;m which dues are delinquent tares loaned on are* on which dues are delinquent ■ilhjecl to cancellation for non-payment of dues ... J N. En .&gt;f shares silhjecl to cancellation for non-payment of tad .i,l ammml of dues delinciuent at this date O7.H .till amount of dues delinciuent at this dat ount of dues delinquent at this date if dues owing by borrowing stockholders &gt;wing stockholders . . . ft?. 50 Aniciunt of int. rest, premiums and fines due and unpaid &gt;f Interest premiums and fines due and unpaid rages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of sarr N. tl No. No. 1 *W)O No. mortsmcM in process of foreclosure and aniiislii amount of same Amount of loans on Improved real estate ..f foreclosure and aggregate amount of sar if loans on improved real estate value of improved real estate uiwin which loai. tMin which loans have bam not appraised -"- Appr I value of improvements . .. not appraise &gt;f U an's upon unimproved real estal Ml I value &lt;if unimproved real estate upon which loans ha real estate upon which loans liav M ■en made irance in lo;.o and assigned to the association as collate! .,, i Fire A rll&gt; p Tornario Tornad No of loans made d.r bulldinii purposes durins fiscal year No' loans mad.- for payment of homestead mortgages durinK year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiseal year ans made lor I i.llding purposes during fiscal year : made for payment of homestead mortgages during year N'o if advance payments of loans during fiscal year A arrowing stockholders N. No «&gt;f non-liorrowinp stockholders No. of minors hohlinp stock in the n-borrowing stockholders bout % linc-rs holding stock in the association .......... rat.- per cent of Interest charge.1 borrowers during fiscal yf t of interest chai. &gt;l y^nr Averaice rate per cent premiums charge r« durinK fiscal year A rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal yt Pla premium .iriner fisc*al year credited to reserve fund during fiscal year A, Amount of losses charged to reserve fund durinn fiscal year Amount of dividends de.lare'l on runninK stock ihirins; fiscal year of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year &lt;&gt;f dividends declared on -running stock (hiring fiscal year nf dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year An rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year AV ■s repa izati Fire </seg>
            <seg id="p098">STATKMKVI IIKTI1K CONDITION c HAVELOCK HriU)l\&lt;; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION </seg>
            <seg id="p099">)IN(I .IIM « \ A A r»l v </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 STATKMKNT OK THK CONDITION' ol HOMI'KK HUILDINi; AND LOAN ASSOCIATION John K. Seine. \V. Hfini li Sander* B. Monniilv Presidei Secretai Attorne UIKKi'T Ills' a m riiimiii (\i-.i~ ii.ii ASSKIS i M...H irfi-iiMin itereiti i»ifiiminis ami H T&lt;i $ UABIMTIKS lid diridend» « • - f mill ireliolderN on incompteta limns ■ IT llt-ll uid prf IKKH'KK. NKIIKASKA on tin- anui d«\ of .Ian.-. r.Ki. OKFICKK-* Vice IVesidei Tressur t«-» ..I &lt;lrl» </seg>
            <seg id="p101">KTARY OF THE STATE BANKINli BOARD 101 XPBNDITURES FOR THK FISCA1 ENDING JUNE 30. 1!HI7. YKAIt RECEIPTS : hand July 1, ISO6 I irunninK ytix-k) i.I*7.0» (full paid stmk) t I.IW. nims enhh emhip and transfer fees - renal*! te sales Total 1 1&gt;:{ ".". te salt-s none EXPENDITURES ufOTtnn ■MS expenses i rawals. dues ■ a wals. earnings i rawa ■ awals. earl MaliiTt-il stock, ill Matured stock, dues 'nek, earnings Full raid stock, dues Pull paid stock, earnings :■ iiund ... . oates of deiiosit .. Total Id stock itesot deiiosit .. 1MM Sri'PLEMKXTAl. K PPLKMENTAL REPORT or Permanent i uion. (Serial or Permanent) 1'ai \alue of cadi share of stock ■ issued since organisation, (if m : shares issued since organization ganisatlon. (if aert nniaatton I N-» &lt;&gt;f shares in force at dale of Ifttt report 1 1 es Issued during risi-al year &gt;_• of two preceding items 11 ting of two preceding items N"i&gt;. of shares withdrawn before maturit&gt; during res manned during fiscal year s withdrawn before maturit&gt; during fiscal jrcfti ti uring fiscal year No. of shares cancelled during ftocal year, hut in « of three preceding items 'fir. hut not witmliaw three preceding Items 4 : N.. i.f shares in force at tliis date .... ;' shares of running stock in force at this i • shares of full paid stock in force at this ■ shares loaned on ■ shaies mi which dues an- delinquent .. t this dat» : shares of running stick in force at this date M ■ shares of full p«ld atock In force at this date shares on which dues are delinquent on w No. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment No. of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of due Total amount of dues delinquent at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing stock hoJd&lt; of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid trtgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of sanit- Vmount of loans on Improved real rstai- fit ttfjM * led value of improvements i A mount of loans unon tminiprovHil real estate ...... .... MBM I value of unimproved real estate upon which loans hav Ami. insurance in force and assigned to the association as col Fire, llti p» «.(»»■ i ornudo. *v.HM). UU t9S.0M&gt;.Pt I r building purposes during fiscal ms made for payment of homestead mortgages during year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year lorrowing; sto&lt; non - borrowing stockholders 46 ». of minors holding stock in the associate Krate per pent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal vear rate per tent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year i»f premium int credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock dun •ar .. fl.OOO.U Amount &lt;»f dividends declared on full paid stock ,»r . . A verage rate per rent of dividends declared durii t : HM Amount runnitiK tinif .if st.» k niatnrwi .lnrinft fls. al ■ , ■ n.iDe </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 STATKMKNT OF THK CONDITION OK Til HUMBOLDT BUILDIN&lt; LDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION Hl'MHDLDT. XKMRASKA On the :iOtli i\a\ at June. l!ti OFFU'KKS J. F. Xalsh K. Bow \'i&gt;-.-r s K. R. Butterlii A. A. Tanner niKKcn k w« H K ll.i I' l( Huttertield A I \V II. - .1 F W.v J H I);n ASS hn in p re aiwl tixtur T. UAHH IKS I xif s und dividend)* ■ i il'aid u ■ il prufil aretn»lders on incompleb -ins unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premium: </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 Kl 8 AND EXPENDITURES Ft &gt;K THE KI8CAL VEAK KNDI.Nt; JINK 30, I'.kiT Bi i 11 M on I'1'I.K.MKNTAI. HEI*OR za w n. w it I :il II All I A !»•-' A I Ml 74 \ EXPEXDITl'RKS </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 t OF THE CONDITION OF THE LAUREL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LAUKKL. NEBRASKA &lt;&gt;n the .'50th day of June. 1907. OFFU KS l f l™ h : r iw* r\ T - Graham Vicelp res &lt;iuy Wilson ' ' ' ' ' .p"! ''„'!.!"!. Treasurer K. P. Voter DIRECTORS ■I H. Felber W. T. (Jraham (iuv Wilson C. C. Sitrlu-lt C K. Nevin C. F. Furley F. P. Voter ASSETS H"ir-i lu.irt/iiire loans "tifaife l.)ans in process of foreclosure I ll.dSOOO Keal •-- Furnilure. Hxtures and supplies lent interest, premiums and fines s iiml taxes paid Other assets. Interest paid Total UABIUTIKS Capital stock running | Dues and dividends Full paid slock Keserve fund Undivided profits. Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total STATEMENT </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 KKCK1PTS AND KXFENDITURKS KOK THE FISCAL RECEIPTS Halancs on hand July 1 19041 Dues. | running stock] irti'oii Jl««-, Dues. I full paid stock Interest nooe Premiums Fines Membership and transfer few Ij&lt;&gt;uns repaid. Real estate sales Kent. T. EXPENDITURES I UHuN Withdrawals, due Witbdrawa's. earnings Matured stock, dues Matured stuck, earning Full paid stock, due Full paid stock, earning: &lt; 'ash on hand UPPLEMENT AL REPORT Plan of association I serial or permanent Par vaiue of each share tries issued since organization |if sen \o. of shares in force at date of last report No. of shares issued during fiscal year •■ Fooling of iwo preceding items No of shares withdrawn before maturity, during fiscal year No i»f -.hares matured during fiscal year shares canceled during fiscal year, but not withdrawn &lt; Footing of three preceding items * No of shares in force at this dale No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No of shares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares loaned on No. of shares on which dues are delinquent 4 So of shares subject to cancellation for nonpayment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date |j» no Amount of dues owing by borrowing shareholders Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid 5mS ' mortgages subject to foreclosure, and the atc&gt;?re?aie amount of .a me. none Bortracea in process of foreclosure, and the atft, r reirate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate $il 08QQ Appraised value of improved real estate upon which loans have been made. Appraised value of improvements. , *\t,MtM Amount of loans upon unimproved real estate Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon whisb loans bave been made Amount of insurance in force and assigned to the Association as collateral security IIS.fl0O.0U No of loans made for building purposes durinK nV- No. of loans made for payment of homestead mortgages durio* Hscal year 0 Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year No. of borrow in ir stockholder* No. of nonborrowinjf stockh&lt;»lders " No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent, of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year ■ Average rate percent, of premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year .041 Plan of premium bid Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount of dividends declared on running stock during Hscal year . . y- j ■ | Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal year Average rate per cent, of dividends declared during fiscal year M Average running time of stock matured during fiscal year . none matured YKAR ENDING JUNK .«&gt;. 1WVJ. = fllWllli i ill . . . other i-ii*nw» i!* n .V No. of shares issued since organization </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 STATEMENT OF THE CONDITION OF THI NEBRASKA CENTRAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION On the 30th day timer K. Burin 111) (Jib-on . . . I "it Vice-Pr&lt; See t\V. Pol* to. N. liu P. Leon a 1 DIKKUTOKS The.» S" «V Ki H. K Hi ASSETS • prt-u To MAIlIMTIh ■ i It! M ui \&gt; H LINCOLN. NKI5UASKA Manager of Aa </seg>
            <seg id="p107">KNDING JUNE 30, I" RBCBPTK. M \\\\'."." .■."".■.■.■"".■ ."".".""; II.-, ■ . . . 4 w 4 SUPPLEMENTAL RBPI »BT erUU or JYrnian- i ,, er , of stock inizatioi .... t date of last report ntj lisral yi-ar 'fore maturity during riscal year uririK Ms. al y.-ar til nut wilhtlruwTl KlnnA itli; M II in it this chit.- stu.k in force at this .hit.- lati d st.uk in fore.' at this date n due and unpaid i foreclosui - ount of s:r No. i of foreiiosure an.l aggiegate ainmint of same !=. .1.1)78. t.m. 5.J13. 4.(111. I UK). :UJt). 5. MB. 5.73ft : - N ll.i ; * 1 U ro\f.l i | 13 ived real estate upon which loan* have bi t.Tto irovementa nimproved t' Appraised value of unimproveil real estate upon wl nproved rf-a! f-state upon whit-h loans have and BMbiff] .llateral it i ulidinc purpose* durlnfc fiscal year B fiscal nent of homestead mortKapes during year Tien t a of loans during fiscal vear . cholden ' trkbolden lock In the association inter I borrower* during fiscal year P frve fund during fiscal year 'd to reserve fund durlnp fiscal vear . ■lare.l on runninK stock during fisi-al rear "1 y j&gt;er cent I ., w , , ■lared on full paid stock during fiscal year . f ' • f dividends declared duriru- e running time of stock matured during 1 IM m&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 FIFTEENTH ANNfAL RKPORT OK THE STATKMKNT OF THE CONDITION OF AMERICAN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION UNI ( &gt;LN, NKBRASK A On the *Hh day of June. 1801 OFFICERS \V. A. Si'l lei'k President John T. DorgM Vice President John H. McTlav Secretary John H. Westcott Trea- A \V. Lane .Attorn*] DIKKI'TOKS JohD T. Dorian John H. Westcott John H. Mol AW. Lane ASSETS nuriing? loans in prucewi or (oreeia stock loans Ke»l .- Furniture and fixtures IH-liiiMUt-nt interest premiums and Hne -'•s und taxes paid 1 "".tier assets Total LIABILITIES I'odivided pruflu Due shareholders on inconiiiiete ioan* I'temiums unearned AdTanee dues AdTSDOC interest and premiums Miscellaneous . . Totu. ot%ii-dne loan .uiv ~tock runninif |Du*-s .ind dmdend-, </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 RECF.IPT8 \ND KXPKNIMTIRKS b'OK THE FISCAL VKAK ENDING JINK 30, 1!«&gt;:. BBCBPTS. RKCEIPTS alantf un hand July 1, i.hks I Tilling StiH-k ) full paid sto. kl ' " M remiums Prem Fines ines fuihersliip aid otber fees * nans repaid •■ ■ ins Total EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURES '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'■'■'■'.'. luninissioits ' "*" Ithdrawals, .lu&lt;-s Plnlln pru it idrawaU. earnings lature I Mock, duel Mat latuied stork. .■Mrnhms 'nil paid sto. k. due* n'l paid sto k. *-iii I) i !) — - H isn un tiutul urriilure and sup|Of~ ■■ Total HI HUPPLEMENTAL ItKl'i HIT iZ s N :lti 'Uat N \ ■ w &gt;w V Her -!.«•. 1* p .11 Ml :1 rlurinK 1' BOOe &gt; Amount of dividends declared on running; stork during fUeal year A </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 1 ■ STATKMKNT OKTHKCON'lUTInN OF SECURITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. NEBRASKA On the .MU day of .lime. 11HIT Imere-t and tines lies </seg>
            <seg id="p111">1KTARY OF THE STATE n\SKI 111 I!! i KIPTM \M&gt; EXPENDITURES FOR THK FTS( AI. VEAR ENDING JUNE :to. 1!«&gt;7. RKO IPTJ «l b: I uV; .t 4 EXPENDITURES. ns ii. .1 eji &gt;:» M M Full |&gt;aicl s and ~ui'l Ti&gt; MMH i&lt; I-IM.KMKNTAI. itKI'KUT VLBMEKTAL REPORT. As or Pi ii— mill » Bued since uiicanization. (If aeri anization. &lt; if serial &gt; -shim] siiirr orsanlsatl ranixation sh;ii.-s iii force ;it date of last rvpfw &gt;f last repoti - iturit \ dnrioir fiscal year fKl riiiR ing tlfccal \«ar. i. in not withdraw «lati in force nt this date this ilat toi k in force at this dat ir k in force at this dat&lt; V irrowiiiR fetorkhold^ri nt ■ iimoimt ol N'i noit . t t No. mortpapes* in priHi mnt or sain nit of saiin in 'mpro\ i ( ■al frttate him m which loans liavi t'UlS i Al \ &lt;•(! i ■ ■ npofv-wh'eb luan-* haTft been rn;id« - i ton aa collatera pnrT^s.-s during h»tMH*stfa»l mnrtfr,a&amp;rrft ihirine' ) • Arnt Insurance in fin ■ tn t N &lt;is made for payment of homestead nmrtpaern dtirii - r pa if loans* during i. I pa kh.iirt n.wine Kt&lt; il i tlit- assiniatiun v t. it Ii -t i-harf'l borrowwt durinj Pscal \«-ai \ s « liarK&lt;-'l borrower! Auiinjc (Ural v»-nt nd during fund during: fisral r« ♦ m rnnniiiE: stork diirine Pucal year .. ilr t l« A, </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 t &gt; x I STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION OF LINCOLN SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. NEBRASKA &lt;&gt;n the 30th daj of June, 1!«»7 • Kl- EKS K. \V. Brown IV. H. H. Wilson Vice Pi I F Siiiiv.-ly Si I 'arks n A ISiiiwd Attc K. &lt; . Luiiaii Manager of Asm DIKKCTORS H H Wilson K. &lt;\ Hurd Frank I'.irk ASSh IS . m m proeesit «if fore r re andrtxtur iierekt. |.rt-iiiiuu)&gt; uod tin' it luxes paid LIAKIMT1K nuininit. I Ihle^ and dividends i' fund ■ il i&gt;rot1t&gt; art-hoKler-s »»n incomplete ..&lt;n\ unearne&lt;1 ■•■ intf iesj ;ind premiums Tot- </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 M) EXPKNDITVRKS FOR THE FISCAL 1 ENDING JINK 30, 1!hi7. .n Avera** rat* per rpnt of di .lurinir fiscal </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 FIFTEKNTH ANNCAI. RBPOKT OT THE : 3TATKMENT (IKTHK CONDIT1 UNION LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. NKBHASKA «&gt;n the :f"tli da.v of .Tuiv. 1!H &lt;&gt;!■ k'ek Vil . St. mart JohllAOD . . I'n Vic- I A. W. Mill 1. •'. Dunn Swieta Trernxui John M. Stewart Atti DIKKCIOH M I- .loLu^ A W M I. J. Dui H J VV A SKTS &lt; T. rt irr and tixtu ienl init-rrst. preoiiuiiis and line Til UAIULITIKS iddividfiuN ed pr.im ilei-N nn incompl •-.i rued -■^t und premi I </seg>
            <seg id="p115">* -• m SECHE'1AR\ ' iK THK STATS BANKING BOABD 1| tECKIPTS AND KM LNDIK'HKS K&lt; &gt;U THE PliM'AL VKAIi KND1NG .11. NK 30, I'.ttiT. RBCBPT8. RECEIPT hand July 1, u hand July 1, - &lt; running stock) (full j..i i.l stock* '..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'.'.. 14 l&lt; una ', ... .'. ......'.'.'..'.'..'.'.'.'.'..'.'...'.'.'.'... ,'.'..'..'. i' and transfer ff»-s repaid Total EXPENDITURES. KXi'KNIHTIItKS to. unions expenst i awnls, ilu* ■- tawiils, earningi ■ i stock, «tut-s ed stork, earnlnsi aid stink, duca ■id Mock, fiuninus '"""&lt; ' . L r """ .i B SII'I'I.KMKNTAI. RKPORT. il or Permanent) „_., of .a. ii ihare of stocft '.'./&amp; lued Binre orKanisatlon, (if serial ) •lni e uiyanization . . . iie» i" I • al date ..r laat lepoi t - issiicd during I &lt;&lt;f two ]•!&gt;■ edlns n. Aitiuimuii bpfure iiiutnritv during Ibwal ph malnri'd during tisral \'. I .11 t IK. I « I I nree nre inllng ii&lt;-;ns - in force at this date - &lt;&lt;f limning stork in force al tl s of full paid stock In f.M which dues are delinquent ..' i.dlaiion for non-payment of d I &lt; .&gt;f limning stork in force ;i t this .hit. es of full paid st.uk in for lit this dat&lt; amount of duea delimiuent at this di • t. t of duos owine hy horrnwin. t of interest. ]&gt;r«-nn . N I ""-':": ■ nount of A t of Joans on Improi ■■ proM-d real estate upon whiriiioana have value of Impm " ' u Al i ,.f ! •=. i value of unimproved real .state upon wnk-ti loans' hav - 11 1 ' ♦ ■ n ni &lt;i&lt;i** &gt; M nsurance In force and as.-iKne&lt;l to the ' association aa the auBfX-iation as t ecurity _ *— , loans made for build vear made for payment of" ne "rear us macl(&gt; for payment of Ing year "imit ' of advance pavmenta "i . year I'ormwine storkln-1 t of advance i avments of ■ t , ar horn^wine stockhol li N non-borrowina; stockholders .... Mint? stock In I . .■.'.'.■.'.■ • &gt;nt of interest chareeii borrowers •lurinK • t'er cent premiums charpe,! l&gt;orrowers_durlnK I - Hi. Ai t t ere-lited to reserve fund durine fiscal vear fiscal 1 "I LT1T rhar ' !Ve flln&lt;1 &lt;'"rin(t fiscal yeiir n ninnine stock dnrina; fi&gt; »tock diirini ZZ iff* rat^ jh" i durini; flu nont* 'lurinff fis </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 OKTHK CONDITION (}(■ FIDKLITY SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION LINCOLN. XKHKASKA ()n the *Hh day of June, ImiT OFKU'KKS I'n Vice l'i( s« .1 . Ha iiu i \tt. [HKKlT \. K«ir W. K. Sh»n .1 II li II I K .1 Hi A (i t A I! T» ASS* ■iniini.s iiml r Tn j I.IAHU.ITIKS Oiif -^ and dividends i •■ fund • it pr.)Hl-. i il ■ re^t arid |»r Tot STATEMENT U'. A. Kontytl VV. K. Sharp. . \V. .1. Hill H U. Treat </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 EKHTS AND EXPENDITURES TOR THE FISCAL YEAR I ing junk so, mn. RECKII'TS I. ■ &lt;• EXPENDITURES t I'LKMKXTAI. KEl'llllT ftK iatioi Amount of dividentis Aeolared &lt;»n running st«H-k ilurinfr fiscal year A </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION OP THr MADISON COUNTY BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION MADISON. NEBRASKA On the 38th day of .lime. 1'MIT OFPK e and fixtures Delinquent interest, premiums and One: K«IK»nses and taxes paid assets LIABILITIES Capital stock running (Dues and dividends! Full paid stock I ■ Reserve fund Undivided prortls.. 1.4.17 41 Due shareholders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Total . t mm </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 FRKCE1PTS AND EXPENDITURES hiiK THE FISCAL YKAR ENDING JUNE 38, liHH. A I YKAR ENDING JUNE 38, 1!HV KKCBPT8. RKOKIITN alancson hand.lul. - l.ltWXI I ! !!J2 I isani Balan Dues Dues Intert Premi Pines Memli ues. [running stockl ■' '•' • rui iues. I full paid stock! i .".""' full paid s itere-s 3«2 'remiums ' 'ines lembership and transfer fees repaid. leal est.ite sale- - K.-r :enn Total. BXPK 1 &gt;1 PUKES I 'ommissions (ther euwnsc - i wata dur-. twals earning- . ' &lt;?" !0 X toured stock dn ■» ll lalured stooU. earning paid stock, due- ■d ;;:r '*ull paid REoek. eaniinifs Jl on '' 1 art 'ash on hand - ut ,iiui 'axes and repairs real estate SUPPUUUCM TAI. IvKl'.Htr I't'LKMh NTAI. I. ■Ian of aisociatio , Iseriai or i&gt;eniianen I lie of ea.'h share of stoek .. *-' ' " ,i of series issued itaoe orn &gt;nna tioo I if -■• d vnrr ormuiixatloll O. of shares in force at date *&gt;f last repoli .1. of shares i&gt;sueil dunnir hsi-a' year oofnif of l wii pre '•'.* .&gt;. of share- wiUHlr»wn before maturity, during rtseal year 0 of shan-s matured dunni.' li-ea year o. of shares canceled durinv tisoal &gt;ear. but not withdrawn. PI N S Mo. nf share-- in force at date "f last ret&gt;o N K.Mll No of sh:m-s inquired t\n No withdraw I T r» ■%Hitin*f of thr -e preeen ntr item - u of shnres in force :it this dare N. "*o of shares, .f runnin; st.wk in fir,-e at this date o of shares of full lud ulKk u funs* at t:ils date . 1^,".'' 0 of shares oaned im "*; * o of h fh dues are delinquent 0 of -l.ar - snliieel to i-anee lation for i.onpayiiient of dues ot:il a uoiint of du-sdel n'lUe'it al this date mount of dues owtnc by borr.iwin« sh»reho Aei i oint of interest premiums and tine- due and uup.tv. •.i of mort/attes subject to fore.-losiin- and the atnrreifale anio.- Fa of nortncmiii process of roreehMare. and the vgrecalc Mnuuatol -a i &lt;■ Eof shares ,.f runnin -' st.wk in fir.-e ut thin &lt;U of shares of full iwd slock n for.-e at t:ns dj t:ils tl.i No V . &gt; i » f s So of - i«h rtue-s are delimit! No of -luir Milijrrl to CMll-e Uitinn fur i:onpaviiienl of due hisd Tot Amount of dues owinir by borr.iwing -harelio Her. A i O-int of interest premiums and tine-- due ;in&lt;l unpaid and t be ujfjfrei^i .n No of mort/attes subject Up fin • So. of nortffav** in proeewof toreekmwt. iinrtthe ftVfrevmtc u Amoun' of lonns on in:&gt;roved r»ai estate l&gt;pra s d va. ne of improved rea esialeu|&gt;&lt;"n whieh loan- lia .ppra s^d Talwe of inniro' e ienl- Amoun Aitprsi s &lt;1 va.ue of improved rm e»&lt; iii*- ui*&gt;n Appra sed rmluc of hni»ro" e ieni" \ mount of loan*. «i»«&gt;n uni.n|»rovt*d reml eaAa t \mount of loan- upon un.i,|&gt;ro\red real estate Amount Appraised value of unimproved real est»te upon whish loans have heen i iiile r...ne Appraisi Amount \mount oin-urani-e in for.'e and assigned to the A—o.-ialion a- e &gt;' ater.il security and m* N5 r No of loans made for Inn dmir purposes during ti-oal i ear No of 1- uns in So of loans ui.ide for purchase of ti.)ine-tead ilunnn Ilseal \ ear No lit] Amount of advanc ■ p.ivmenl of loans c'.uruit.' Hseal vear AnnMin So. of borrowing stockholders N'o of nonl«irn&gt;wintr stockholders No Iders No of minorsjioldinif stock in Hioo No of loldir asstK'iatiou Averaire rate i&gt;er cent of interest charged borrowers d innc iTemife rate i&gt;er cent. t&gt;f premiums charged t&gt;orr»»wers duriutf nacml year. Plan of premium . tl ' lt ». 1 . Amount credited to rese-ve fund durinit fiscal year ijia v Amount of 1 &gt;sses charged to reserve fund dilrini: fiscal year wSii Amount of dividends declared on runnini; stock dunnir fiscal year Tl «:«'".-&gt; Amouit of dividends declared on full paid stock durine fiscal year iTmo Krate per cent, of dividends declared durin running time of sti&gt;.'k matured during fiscal &gt;e^r </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 STATKMENT OF THE CONDITION I &gt;!• .nd premiun i&lt; MADISON Hl'ILDINt; AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION . running. &gt; ■-. :*T- Oil MlfOtllpiftf .m- unearned AdVltlX't* dlMI </seg>
            <seg id="p121">ii ENDING JINK *», 1!"&gt;T. ' M. ES Mai Kull PPLEMENTAL REPOR s xa N Mo this rlatf&gt; « II M \ S V [1 ttorrowpTS during \ P •nl vr strvk ilnrine flsral year .. * -' k, Amount of divWm </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 STATEMENT OFTHK CONDITION OF McCOOK. NEBRASKA OFF KK ■lohn K. Kelle\ . W. B. Mills... f. A. lVnnell.. Vs. ThortrrinsoD President I Vice President Secivtui\ Trea&gt;uivi UIKfX'TIJt John E. Kelley W. H Mills r. Lehn C. J.UBrifc K Hanson ■•&gt;" H ]». Waitc T H Campbell P. M Kimnit- 1 A Wileox ASSETS 10.1S50C I.MUO ire and Hitun • m dues and interest - and tales paid oiber a-s.-ts lher»sscl Total i 113.13*60 t lilt 411 7! Undivided profits areholden on incomplete loans 1'reiiiiuins unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums Totml THE MctDOK COOPERATIVE BUILDING AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATK &gt;N On the Mtfa dav of June. V.xr, •rlitaife loan- nnntit- loans in pnx-ess of for. ■ LIABILITIES .»ck runninK. I Dues and dmdendsl tind'. I t:t&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 H K( Kl Kl'S A N I ) K\ I KM'l 11 1\ r.S r*'I\ lrir* r im .-\ i j i ENDING JUNE 30, WOT. RECEIPTS. IPTS RECE billal alance on hand July 1, lint! ues, (running stock) I.u 1 ues. (full paid stock) Interest iterest I i'r rennums i" ' \ Ki Membership and transf* embership and transfer fees oans repaid eal estate sales Real estate Rents ents T»x Kedenu Hills payable fcx Redemptions. 11s payable Total I 3 Total KXPENDITVRES. EXPENDITURE: *s ommissions ;:; W t'ithdrawals. duel withdrawals, earnings i stock, dues I stiM-k, earnings itieaie IWI 1 r ills payable i*."JWi i*t all ash on hand Total * BUPPLKMKNTAL REPORT. SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT 'Ian of Association. (Serial ■* Permanent) ■ir value of each share of stork Permanent \ Jo. of situs Issued since organization, (if serial) - Istfued since organisation b iti force at date of last report - issued during tiscal year ,.r two prtt-edlnK Items :■•■■■,■ hist report al year . . . . 1 &gt;"c nf shares withdrawn tor ot mat it&gt; ilurniK lUcal year V t No. c.f ihare* matured .lurinR fiscal year fa c.f aharea matured during fiscal year ;,, nf shares cancelled during fiscal year, but not withdrawn So of shares ranc-elled durlni ar, but not withdrawn ciiitins.' nf three preceding items Jo. of shai es in force at tliis date ■ of rniuiiiiK stork in force at this date . of shares in force at this date ■ if sh.ii os of riinnine stork in force at this date t this date No! of shares of full paiil stuck in force at this dat fo. of shares ot full pai.l stock in force at this date ■ loaned on Co of shares on which dues are delinquent &gt;f nharefl &lt;&gt;n which dues art- delinquent B &gt;f shares subject to rancellation for non-payment of dues i '.mount &lt;&gt;f &lt;inps dflinouent at this date 165 imjuent Co. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues imitunt of dues delinquent at this date N. Tnt:il amount of Hues delinquent at tins &lt;late Amount of dues owing: by borrowing stockholders tcukhoMf A,, .mount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid an«l tint's due and unpaid \'o mortgage* subject to foreclosure, and . imount of same, I l mount of same. I $1 ft No v'o! mortpmre* In process of foreclosure and aggregate amount of foreclosure anil aRBregate amount of - k mount of loans on improved real estate flOl ITS, 8 t:&gt; t appraised value of Improved real ■" whlen nans have NUHu - Appraised value of improvements ,r nts A,., , moopl "f lonnK nwin imimnroved re Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made estate upon which loans have to the association as collateral Appraised value of unimproved real tl ninile Amt. insurnnee in force and assigned \mt. Insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral security ■ loans made for building purposes during fiscal year for payment of homestead mortgages during year .. durine fiscal year 1 tend nioftunees durinK year during fiscal vear II Xmount of advance payment nf loans during fiscal year if borrowing stockholders lt of loan t\V \'o. of non-borrowing stockholders N'.i of miners holding stock in the association Averace rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durinK fiscal vear iati K Averapre rate pe Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan of premium ■ • ■ • ■ • «,.'-' Averae ted to reserve fund durine 1 fiscal year 4MB.97 An Amount of losses charged tn reserve fund durinp fiscal vear Amount of dividends declared on running stock dun: Amount A rate per cent of dividends declared durinjc flsral year I Average runnlne time of stock m 1I5^ mos Al Tot </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 OKTHK lllNDi riON 1KASKACITY lUILDINti AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION 'li tile :il&gt;tli ( \y\ |i 'KKS \ I OKI' » \V llu K H U \ Ha \V H ASS* I « I.IAI1ILITIK&gt; ! 1 STATKMKVI NKUKASKA ( (TV. NKHKAKKA Ka-.tr M. S.-1/..T. . . VV. 11. Pita K. M </seg>
            <seg id="p125">KNImNIf .11 N r, 30. 1."* Dues, Iiues, Premi Fines M&lt; Ke K. EXl'ENIlll I I .,! SUPPLKMEN lization. liizatnui t N I niiiK fiscal year No k in force at this date for non-payment of iit tl clnt owir A, t the assm-iati .Hat. rill So . M Amount of advance payment of loans during fts. stock &gt;3 t of interest charEeil t«&gt;rrowers during fiscal year at 1 Amour i reiliteil to reserve fund durinp fiscal year * nd during fiscal vear Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year * 3.MI.M &lt; .f dividends declared during fiscal year k matured during fis- '** bmm v RECKIPTi- a i, itKi'oirr (if seria t this date delinquent tmkholtler 1 aKKre«ate amount of sair No. ml Agi -.nut of sar ill e.«t;it.- upon iati&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p126">OK THK (llNliIlli IX I &gt;K I III NELSON LOAN AM) Hl'IUMNi; ASSOCIATION Kp-KlCKK-i OIKKCT W .1 \\ H Ht-nr&gt; Km .Ir A \V MciU X lirfiii ■ ! l;i\is |i;ii(i I.I.\HIIJTIK&gt; t STATKMKNT NKLSON. NKBKASKA On the :t&gt; &gt;t 1 1 da.\ of .limv. 1&lt;N II. I lioudrk* \ Bud.. V. stiiiu- A. .1 Stomr . HloWll . ■ aiders neitrni </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 KND1NG JUNK 3tt. llxiT. RBCBPT8. * !(&lt; x XPKNDITu'Rl A I'l.KllKNTAL KK1 1 N N t t a t luring I I [I (i» &lt;liTi«1en«l fund iiurinp fiscal y v fiscal X </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 NUCKOLLS CX)UNTY BTILDIN*; AND U&gt;AN ASSOCIATION NEBRASKA iFFICKRS Vice-I'i Sfcretai IIIRKCTciR Jr. ■ ]&gt; Hrown H . K. Ciwdrich W W. Ha I V it.jttenHelii J. T. Dy&gt;art \V. A V'i Thomas liraham M \V Carte A t is i us in pr ireclosure ire mid tlxtu • ■nt intert-si, premiums ami Mne i r a\*-«. paid Tota LIAHII.IT1KS &gt; numirit' I Dues and dividends .- fund I profit* on incomplete loans ii.s unearned Advance dues Uuifr interest and premium: Total ' STATKMKN1 OK TIIK CONDITION OF TIIH NKLSON, On the :»ith (hiy of June. l« Bon. Jr. . . i. Peebler t. Iml.r. . 'ox. Jr... K. 1). iirown Att&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p129">SB RETAKY OF THK STATE BANKING HOARD 129 RECEIPTS Ualume on liand Ju I'lics, (running itocl Iiucs. (.fun paid al t 1'rt Mei XPENDITX'RES « w Wit Mat M Plan «•!' Ass«f lation. (Serial or Permanent izat niza I al jtear inaturilx &lt;J nl n force at this date N N ■nt \ twins st.t. ■ipaid mount amount of »a Appraised value of improvements Ami. Insurance in force and assigned to t : &gt;n as Ami ;ir A m N mlnon lioldins stork in the a- -;•■ rate per cent of interest eliarKetl borrowers during fiscal year A P Amount credited to reserve fund durti tj«j «« Amount of lopseR charped to reserve fund durinp fiscal year none Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fis«;tl vear . . iMO.74 Amount of dividends declared on full i \r . . non Averap Il'TS AND KXPEND1TURES WOH IHK FISCAL VEAU ENDING JUNK :n&gt;. IWI ri.KMKNTAL KKI'UHT at this date state upon which loans hav st--;ui </seg>
            <seg id="p130">* OKTHK CONDITH &gt;N 'I NEWMAN GROVE IMPROVEMENT SOCIETY ( 'n tin- :ii it 1 1 du\ of June. I" 1 OKFICBKS T. Kiiiliiiai Viwl'i D1KBCTO l^-ll,i-h\ &lt;■ \ K»l d K. H lie KhImti V. Pears' \l ASSKTS i pn isurr rt-st, (li- nes Paul f t?flifer b»l*iic« I.1AHII.ITIKS ideiKK Due imp: STATEMKNT NKWMAX GKOVE. NKHRASKA IU-theliv Randall Gerhart Randall , •&lt;• ;in&lt;\ Mxtu </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 &lt; .n t • RKCKIPTS 47" Fil Mi 4 w M Z..1 iz;l N t inpaiti A. I \ cnr.l to the asso&lt;iation as rollatpral flB.al 3 A A IITS ami KXI'KNDITIKKS K&lt;&gt;|; |H h: KIS( \ VRAR KND1NG JUNE 30, i!(t)7. XPENDITURI PPLEMENTAL HKI'OKT stntp upon wl </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 t STATKMKNT NoKI'nLK BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION NoKFOLK. NKHKASKA OFKI KK Vic- 1' nitv 1 .^euulk .I.»hn Welsh !&gt;. I M Jtiry Alex B.-U A 4 • rtiriitfe loans in procesit of fop at! '• und Hxtures Tuta LIABII.ITIKS . -lock runninir. (Dues and dividends' .- tund H« Adv... lx&gt;ana OFTHE Cl INDITll IN &gt;t On the :t«itli (lav of June, 1H0" II. A. I'ascwalk. l&gt;r Alix Bear. . i'. B. Durlaad. . K. W. Y.ul/. Ma|M&gt; A Ha/.™ Anton Huebulz Peter Stafford &lt;; B &gt; KTN ■t interest. i&gt;remiums ami and luxes p;iul "L-v i »ri &gt;ti t ftecoont xr s.iU! mi advance payiiient'* </seg>
            <seg id="p133">. ' No. ..f shares in force at this iiatc No. "f shares of running stock in force at II \imrai-eil value nf unimproved re:il estn'.' ni.nn tlHTe !&gt;«•► n m Vnit insurance in :or -o ;nul assigned to tli on as collatf ns made for I. nil. line purposes during nscal v - made f&lt;ir pavment of homestead mortgaicea durii f advance payment of lojtns durine fiscal year . ... t v sto^k in tl ■ il borrowers iJnriner floral j borrowers during A A - A </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 KLKHOKN BIILI)L\&lt;; AM) SAVINGS ASSOCIATN N UKFMKK* I'l A I &gt;• , Vice I 1 Si Attori A. IVKiier I K. ixliorne W A Wil I- K DSTCOI« 11 ASSETS «r I »cc sure in .1 • ■.- iMid UAKII.ITIKs 1 t-a itrotlis . irehuldeis mi inv unearned Advai STATEMENT OK THK CONDITION OF THK X )ItK )!,K. NKBR\SKA * 'u the iiin.li da\ (if .lunc. liM Wit/.iymai IMKKCTOKS RiH'k runnintr. t I tue&gt; ami diTldend« st.H-k </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 RES K.)K THK KIS.AL VKAK ENDING JUNE MK l!*&gt;7. RECEIPTS. INK 30, l'.nn RECEIPT i hand July Dues, (running stock) '■ on hand July 1 ISM hues, (running stock) I &gt;ues, ( full paid stock ) paid stc n teresi rship and transfer fees Loans repaid 1 .ite sales ■atedeiMisit ■■ aaJe Total »teilei KXPENIUTl'HBri. KXPENIHTl'HE ssions iwals, dues niings I stock, dues Htoek. earnings I.M &lt;i stuck, dues h'ull paid slock, earnings hand &gt;tt»e r dividends on paid stock. .rid insurance paid Tutal id- BUPPUBMSNTAL REPORT. PPLEMKNTAL REPORT or Permanent) Plan of Assorialiuii, (Serial or Permanent; li share of stock ■ued Bines organization, (if serial) 1-1 liz; No. &lt;•( shares Issued since organization shares in force at dale of last report ... &lt;»f last al year \n &gt;»f shares issued during fiscal year - of two preceding Items es withdrawn before maturity during iWcu. &gt;ear shares matured during fiscal year -Mares canceled durum fiscal yeai bu. Dot withdrawn three pre eding items sliares in force at this date Bhares of running stock in force at this .I." - shares of full paid stock in force at this date share* loaned on .... share? on which dues are delinquent ' shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of d tmount of dues delinquent at this date t of dues owing by borrowing stockholder* nt of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid ibject to fort-closure, and aggregate amount share* in (ore* at this riat N.i i if shares of running stock in force at tli .s of full paid stock in force at this d.ite share? (in which dues are delimiuent bjttel to cancellation for non-payment of il ■ mount of dues delinquent at this d Amount of dues owing; by borrowing; stock ' of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid i to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of samt No Amount of loans on improved real estate L-alue of improved real estate upon which loans 1 f II A A value of improvements sed value of unimproved real estate upon which 1 W been made Amt insurance in force and assigned to the association as - ny ' loans made for tiillding purpose? during fiscal ins made for payment of homestead mortgages durit t of advance payments of loans during fiscal Amt- insurance in foive and assigned to the association as ' non-borrowing stockholdf minors holding stock In the a- A rate per cent of Interest charged Inirrowers during fli rate per cent premiums charged borrower! during fiscal ye t premiums charg Plan of pre fund during fiscal year A t of losses oharped to reserve fund durinp fiscal year r of dividends declared on runninp stock during fiscal vear Amount of dividends declared on full paid stock during fis- re rate per cent of dividends declared during ftsrfti v runninR time of pto^k matured during fiscal yf </seg>
            <seg id="p136">STATKMKNT OPTHKCO.VIIITION il NORTH Lori' IU'1LI)IX&lt;; AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION NoKTII !&gt;Oir. NKIiKASKA i. -lit \-'.. A Hulrhii \ I \V II, ASSKTS I . I.1AHI1.1TIKS Dues ami divide S.H I R . i .-r- on incuuipl re&gt;l ami prern I 9.3 T«i FIFTEENTH ANNUAL I 1HK &lt; in the .Ultli (lav of .him-. 1 OKKICKK A. T. • K. .1. Babcuck K .1. Rihmn-k i ' • Vice l*re«i Seen Atta inert* </seg>
            <seg id="p137">H KTA h 1 V N H V A UFA KU'TN AM) K.Xl'KN DITl" KKS FOK THK KISi Al. YEAH KNDING .MNK 3«, 1'NiT. iremlums charged borrowers during fiscal y «erve fund during fiscal year 'flared on running stock during fiscal year r]fi rp*i on f -.f divi »f =to. </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 OFTHK CONDITION Ml- MUTl'AL BlIUMNt; AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION OKKICKK I la 1 1 i irai mi DIKKCTOKS • V Hue J. K. CUkbauirb Uco. W. I'inn Arthur Me N JuwnM Kunnie Frank T ltednii&gt;nd Thumus C. Pmtlenon STATKMKNT NORTH PLATTK. NKBRASKA ( &gt;n til.- .Mtli da Km;!- i . I 'attmton or \*on G« Vice l'i Se li'l (i I rank K. I'.iillaicl </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 IN&lt;; JUNK :;n. i RECEIPTS. n hand July 1. ma (running stock i ■„•; . &lt; full paid stock) .'i Interest 1 I- Premiums s Membership and transfer fees Loans repaid '' uxe*. aim kj 0 R'-nts Total R EXPENDITURES. EXPENDITURES I.,,; * * uissfons Other expenses Withdrawals, dues i Wit idrawals, earnings i V Matin i ■ a ■ k. earnings M Kiill paid stock, dues H h'uil paid stock, earnings &lt; lank on i.iiini M ■ Total BUFPUCNXNTAX REPORT. TLKMENTAL REPORT I r Association, (Serial or pHI ■■—■■— Hi ) Mrial until Mutch \ + &gt;b. then permanent i'ai value &gt;'i each share of stork isou (»&gt; No. ol »erl&lt; ince organisation, &lt; U Jo. "f shares issued since organisation z.rl \ii. i i taies in lurce at date of last report - io. of shares Isaued durlni ar «.oi ing of t wo pi .■ eding i i ■ lu «&lt;i *&lt; iii ;H It'll udm Ml .: No No. of shares nas uied during (is&lt;a1 year S*o. of shares in force at this date \o. u ! running sfock in forre at this date at this date No. of shares of full j aid stock in force at this date A lied on No. &lt;if shares of full laid stock in force at this tiat No N... of shares on which dues me delinquent jt-nt \'o. ..f shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues payment of du Potal amount of dues deUmiuent at this date Ymount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders A. \ 1 1, ou ni «&gt;f Interest, premiuma and 1 \ No. Til- i'i' 1 ' t to fo I of same. N &gt;unt of sai? t mount »&gt;f loans on improved real esi #lH-&lt; A Appra -'-(1 vu'iit* of iuii»r -^'-'i uanit huve iw*-n mude. ** A,.| » Appraised value of improvements $2:* M-on unimproved real e«1 iti Appraised value of improvements (33 \pi&gt;raised value of unimproved real estate upon which Ioan9 have i&gt;&gt;-t-ii made state upon which loans hav Amt. insnniii'i' in force and assigned to tl collateral irity . - • to the n illatf \it. of loans made for hutldtne |»urposep during fiscal year , us made for payment of homestend mort^atres during year .. t of advance payments of loans during fiscal year ;■ inoith . . WLj • mis made for payment of homestead niorteatres 'during year during fiscal year No. of borrowing stockholders No. of non- borrowing stockholders ln:t N No. of minors holdinp stock in the association te per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year t premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year the association ; '-r pent of interest rhargred borrowers during fiscal year is rharged borrowers during fiscal year none 1 borrowers during fiscal vear P 4 I borrowers d ;■ Plan of premium \ mount credited to reserve fund during- fiscal year a Amount of &gt;'&gt;-- ■^■ii;i''"'il to r.'Sf&gt;-v.» fir ■■ il vear \r*&gt;rm«t of dn-H*»nd&lt;» declared on ninnlnp stock during fiscal year .. »i . A.. nlnp stork during fiscal year i red on full paid Pto.-k during fiscal of dividends declared during fb • "f stock matured durinu </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 STATKMKVi llKTHK COSDITI IN * MUTUAL LOAN AND lU'IUHM; ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NKKRASKA i it ;i\ of .1 I'. Soutl K. Rcrm S&lt; IIIKKI'T M. Sa « i.i ahii. [Tit III, I. .V M An« </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 Sh RKCE1PTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THE HSr.\L VKAK KNDING JUNK :fi. l'tnT. N.&gt; of stuu*efl vitbdimwn before niaiunt\. during I N.&gt; of «httreii matured dnrips fineal \t'ar Nti of nh»res caneeled duriDff tNt'al \ear hut not withdru K^itintf of three precedini? itern^ No No No No No No •!. none taare, unrt t made. £** tot loans made for huildin^ purpose* during : of Iomu niiide fur pa\ mem &lt;&gt;f homestead m &gt;unt of advance payment of loans Gurint.' tis' uf borrow inir stockholders . i&gt;f nnnborr.iwinjr itoekbolderN i&gt;f minors holding stock in the association ra^re rate per cent, of Interest ehanred bon i.i ■ Avennre r;iie i»er cent, of premiums chiir»fed be ur Plan of premium . Amount credited to reserve fund durin An Ail An All |M Amouiil ■ [Tired to re — ear Amount of dividends deelured on rmini ■ S£ Amount of dirideods declared on full p during r A rsrace rate per cent of dividend-, de Average runniotf tinje of stock tnatured during </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 STATEMENT )K THK CONIHTII (N cl NEBRASKA LOAN AND Hl'lLDINJ; ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NKBRASKA On the .Unh da\ i if .1 \. Frj IV. Vice I'ii Sfi KB. Wilcox hristii </seg>
            <seg id="p143">ECKETAKY OK THK STATE HASKINC He i.\ 143 S AND KXPKNDITURKH F( »|{ THK FIHTAl NDINO .IIM KCKII I M XI .\ A Ml S « A I &lt; n </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 STATKMKXT HKTHK CONDITION Viet- I'n S,, \t DIRH T. HIS K E Brysii M Nat John H l&lt; K. A l'iiruiHee H. J Penfi.ld \V S. Wr ! \1 lln W. Sou K A KTS f fur r? I I ,nt il taxe* p;iiil T t A HI I ! riKS mninir I Duex and divider lls I I f Kuli paiil stock . fund I'ndmded proMt- ireholder- on iacoiupletp CreniiuiiiH unearned i: T» OMAHA LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION OMAHA. NKBRASKA • Hi the .Sntli da) of June. l!l ciKKH'KKS «.. \V. Loom K. K. Brjsoo.... • i . M. Nmttinifei I,H»U S. H.Tll. . K. II. Oaii ire loans - Furniture and Nxture ■ Jiiiiini: if at est«tc Advance tin***- ee interest arid premiums irnin^.s ar.d fxpen-.es </seg>
            <seg id="p145">I-.NDI N(i JINK 30, 1!«C RECEIPTS. A K L« Frem Kines I -nan: « EXPENDITURE I, Wit I I X Hl.l* R Total PPLEMENTAL REPOKT No. oi Mftl since organization, (if seria : shares issued since organizati it ilate of last repx h No. of shares in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this datf f shares of full paid stock in forte at this :; N. t tount of interest, -remiuni^ and Hiihs due and unp»td mortgages Bubject to forecloeure, and in 'iint of same. fl No No! mortgagi imount of sa Amount of loans on improved real esta v At \r Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have been made ■ ■ ■ which loans hav Amt. insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral No .of loans ma' ,1 luri N loan Ar No. of horrow * the associatir eratre rate per cent of interest charged borrowers durine ftwal vp omeo rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during li^ 1 borrowers durine fiscal vear « v *nva 1 to reserve fund during fiscal vear Amount Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year KT or nivinenns neciareu on luinim* &gt;n» i\ nuiiut. t nf dividends declared on full poid stock dnrinc Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fis • verage running time of stock matured during rises </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 KIKTKK.VTH ANNUAL ISK1MKT &gt;K rut &lt;■ ■ STATEMKNT Till n 'Mill I. IN UK Tllf [DENTAL BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION OMAHA, NEBRASKA I in the .intli (hiv of Jin Pn Vice rn \t LJABILIT1KS I .Til 4i-; 74 </seg>
            <seg id="p147">I KNIMNG JUNK 30, I'.mT. I FT t * t t A i ,1 </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 KlIITION «&gt;K Til SSEttVATIVK SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSCX IATION OMAHA. NKBKASKA ( &gt;ii tin- :!&lt; it li &lt;la\ of .hint-. 1 tKulin - (ieorirf 2nd Vicc-I liIKKiTci y. A Heuun A w 11 •mm n K n n. Uyrun K HiiNt ■ .1 i 1 It-iiri^im -I A Suririi ► A I" I M. Wilht A V S I I W r.i UAHIIJTIKS l&gt;i uleniK STATKMKN'I K Oilnii loho K. Kla.k ..lid Vk-.-l'r lai\ anil Tn - lUMl it-ti iiniftiM it ehn]d*Tv on incompteb </seg>
            <seg id="p149">SKCKrvTARY Or THE S FA FK KANKINii H ).\KI) 149 RECEIPTS AND KXPKMDITUHKS H\ &gt;U THK KISCAL YKAK KNDING JUNE 30, 1907. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, iWtt. . $ 5t.ftlH.4l Dues, (running st paid stock) JMitTlLtt MS ft T* Warrants and certificates of depo-.it IO£7H.«3 aid 7M.KK li Real estate sales g.x»* :*&amp; Rvnt i -i.-j ■» illje buildm* ifccet T EXPENDITURES. fe£"f *i .**•» t» Interest on warrants and certincate* of deim-.ii 7^^ $j Ktier expenses inciuuinic rent M7. Mlhtll t'lt.s and certificate* of deposit. . 1 . Office t&gt;uildintc :t • Total 4;.SJti_- UPPLEMENTAL REPORT. I 'Ian (if A— gelation. (Serial or Permanent) peraaaoem I iuc of each share of stock series issued sinre organization, ■ tic of each share of sto (if ' ieriii) ' '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. * m.nr (ii'iiiiiu".".'.".".'.I".*.*.".".".Ii;i mm Nc rganixation N i gamzaUon . isati Nil «&gt;f shares in force ;it date of last rei N" f last -rt No of shares issued during fiscal year . of t wo pre ■•* linn iterna ' sliares withdrawn before maturity No of shares issued during fiscal year III £M withdrawn before rnaturit Juring fiscal year m . i .luririK fiscal year norrconl shares matured during fiscal year u . - i.ires wit llraw 1 in 1 n ■ 'let donna rt-*oal year items II 3SS No. of shares in force at this date 09 wi f shai4s of running stork in force at this* date MXiV No. of shares of full paid stock in force at this date * nn N*&lt;»- of shares on which dues are delinquent Wo. of shares suhjpet to cancellation for non-payment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date \ mount of dues owing: hv borrowing stockholders no record Amount of interest owiov f n rU irowinff sh;ir-h.&gt;'iler- « mi 10 N'.» morteafte* sub.i&gt;rt to forei-losure. and ar-creirate amount of .same.fi *7 nTtfcRfcem in prorera of fore«*lo5iirp and as-pregate amount of same. ft f-i nproved renl estat- .*?i:tH 17 1 ■*• A,., ■stnlr upon which loans have been »).«.m75.i« \ if Improvements 1 real tnte upon which loans have p: \ f. SSfCTlpd t the axsoriatlon as mllateral iirr»of iiirin*' flsral year Vo t of home! ;t ad mortgages durinr rear and purohwic &gt;*f homesfeads mount of advance pavmenr of loan Xmonnt of advance pavment of loans during fiscal vear m&gt;nr N*o. of borrowing sto^kholrie^s S 161 Average rate per cent" of interest charged borrowers during fiscal vear 7 MO per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year none Plan of premium . noar V mount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year clited to reserve fund during fiscal year $ lt.44*t is [ospps charged to reserve fund during flsnnl vear $tt.*tt Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . 97O4flfcift 1 ct..-u- .ftirl'-" ftwrwl vear . Mfem«&gt; t of dividends declarpd during fiscal year etp running time of stock maturwi during flscM y^nr oottr- anrt the impmv-non nn rr&lt;-nrt No. of non-borrowing storkhoMers fl.&lt;n* N'o. of minors hoMine stork in the association &gt;*» </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 U T (IF" Til SI Crunk James AiBMOV rticaire loans in process of forcciosup i im ie fMMn and fixtures •tit interest premium- and tine -■&gt; and taxes paid Total I.1AB1UT1KS ■ -lock running. (Dues and dividend . d stock *■ fund ■ .1 profits ireholders on incomplete loans l*reniiums unearned AdTanoe dues ee interest and premiums Total « BANKERS SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOt lATIOX I'. Crook. Lincoln. Smith.. Korty.. I). &lt; rant- S\kes J. I). FoM*r • rtiratfe loiiiis </seg>
            <seg id="p151">151 RECEIPTS AM) EXPENDITURES FOK THE FISCAL YEAK NDIMi JUNE 30, 1907. RECEIPTS. Balance on hand July 1, igno | 1. JUk.lt Dues, (running stock) 1 Dues, (lull paid stock) Dues, (lull pai Intei est i in .ic IT, ■.•&gt;:.! -.. 1 R. (7.7&lt;&gt;.« EXPENDITURE « " .-i - rl Mat M Kull paid -st.i H «.n&gt; m PI'LKMEN TAL REPORT ssociation, (Serial or Permanent) I y II sto N, (if serial) Nil uf shares issued since or^anixat ■ sluit m in fi»rce at tlut*- ui u-i report No iur &amp;] ■ar No. f&gt;f s'taref withdrawn h^r.ire m»'iir''v during fiscal year r fiscal nr It WJlllll! Irt-i at** if running stock in force at this date No of shares of full paid stook in force at this date ff So Total amount of dues delinquent at this date 1 1. ML' 00 nut uf dues owing ''V borrowing stockholders Sl.'ttoot lit of&gt;interest. premitima and fines due and unpaid fiflijM line* due and unpaid $i nit w to foreclosure, and iiKKrejiate amount of same '. and aggregate amount of same. state tl- state (|. itatc u|i«n wliicli loans have been pon wliirh loans have liecn ■ tn.otn.at «l7.i»li..»i Appraised value of improvements Appraised value of improvements Amount i&gt;i loans unon unimproved real pstatf ■■•■••••■ U\.m.m ♦ ii... .. Amount i&gt;i 1&lt;mms linen unimproved real pstatf Amount .&gt;i loans unon iini'nproven real estate . MM Appraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans Appraised value of unimproved real estate i • Arnt. insurance in force and assigned to the association as collateral loom) si* N'.i of loans made for huildins purposes during fiscal year 5 f homestead mortKaee» during year *\ Amount of advance pa\'ments of loans during fiscal year No. of non-horrnwin^ stockholders No uf minors holding stock in the association No of minors holding stock in the association 4 e rate per cent at interest rharged borrowers during fiscal year I .■nt » Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year lount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year *_ lount of losses chareed to reserve fund during fiscal vear on running stork durlnjf fiscal year mount of dividends d*»rlar*»d on running stork durinj? fiscal year . fM37.4&amp; f dividpndp dprlnr#»d on full pnld Pto^k during ftncfll year flft) 00 vprasp ratp per cent of dividends declared durincr flscal year • * Averace ninninp (imp nf *tock matured diirlnir n&gt;&lt;-al vpht HM mos latn.n \o. uf share, sub • ilar, on lor iK&lt;m&gt;u) ■ &lt; ent ul Uut *Pntnl n mount nt »1 ups Hplinniipnt at this ilatf </seg>
            <seg id="p152">152 VIV KKMTH \ \ NT M. KKIMRT I &gt;K THH STATKMKNT PAWNEE i ITY SAVINGS AND BUILDIMJ ASSiK 1ATIOX Ua«ital &gt;u&gt;ck runnini |l&gt;ues aDd dividrndsl Kull paid sti&gt;ck Keiterve fund I-Hie Mliart*hulder&gt; on in«*oiDplet« loans I'rt-nnuni* uncurind I &gt;!•' THK COXDITI IN IF V ■ WNKE CITY, NKKRASKA til (lie Silth daj of .Inn-. 1!&gt;I&gt;7 </seg>
            <seg id="p153">i \ ' K BANKING HOARD 153 Kl.rKIrTS AND EXPENDITURES KOH THK FISCAL YKAK ENDING JUNE Ah 1!«&gt;7. RECEIPTS. HE r IPTS • ■ 'Hi hand July Uues, (running stuck) I'rutit and Insuriim'f Balance on liand July 1, iMt { ttl Dues, (running stuck) jus,;, Profit and Insurance ■i fillip and transfer fee* ! .... Int. r^.-it ■MFhip and tran Loans repaid Total &lt; anl Total * EXPE.NI&gt;ITl"P.ES KXPK.NI&gt;ITl"P.KS * ... expense! iwals. dues nings Matured stork, dues Mature! stuck, earnings ..nhand M. Total took, earnln Total SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT 3UPPI.KME NTAL REPORT Plan of Association, or Permanent 1 I Association. :Seiinl or Permanent) wnnuic permir l*ar value of each share of sto. k $_.,. Par value of each sha if ser organisation, (if serial i I shares issued since organizat &lt;ueii since organization i f last report I it date of last report ued during; fiscal yeai ued Muring fiscal yea Footing of two preceding items . I -hares withdrawn her. ire maturity during Usual year inolud.n* stiK-k retired shares matured during fiscal year Footing of two preceding iten -tiares withdrawn befitre tn^tiiritv. d ye*r. inclini,n&gt;f st«K*k retired ig fiscal year r. I, nt not withdraw n tn&gt;i * -■ of thrcp rre"P(Jing itet - sharps in force at this dat ■ sharps in force at this date . | shares of running stock in fore* at this dat ■ shares of running stock in force at this date - i&lt; which dues nr# tlplirniuent . sharps i»n which dues are ti^lirniuent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-pavment of tfv ' shares subject to cancellation for non-pavment of dues Total amount of dues delinquent at this date |ut.: t nt &lt;)iips owinc hv hnrrowinc stocl&lt;hn?')prR Total amount of dues delinquent at this date ■ Amount of interest, premiums and tines due and unpaid Amount of interest, premiums and tint 1 '* due and unpaid No. mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of ■ ■tKaees in process of foreclosure and a^srrpsrate amount of sa-ne t ii N'o a «i ••«. N tref in pro.ess of fore-loswre and a^yresate amount of same Amount of loans on "mproved real estate Amount of loans on "mproved real estate fa V7h.i In., .f I" ■ n-artp ■ isprt value of improvements fii.T.v. i »'l value of un'Tinroved r e»i est»i&lt;&gt; mxin wh'ch 'oans hare been ■ f loa id t a value of improvements ■ •■'1 value of unimproved real e&lt;t»i&lt;&gt; mxin h«Te he.-n niside. Amt Insurance in for e ;md assigned to the association as collateral security ; 'oans manp for nuilnlne rnrrtosp* rtnrlnj fiscal ■ ■ i ■rtfldp for payment of T-orttra«res during v- Amt Insurnnre In 1 il t the as t itv N V if t 1 \mount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year ■ trrowinu •iro&lt;* 1 -h"'n'e''s i nvment of loa ,1 in vear No of non-borrowing stockholders . • Ming Ptock in tl*e association rate w cent pre-niums charged borrowers during fls-al vear nor. n t • rntP re*- rent premiums rhargpfi borrower* during fla^Hi vear n.» I ' nre-"|u'ri \ mount credited to rese»re fund during fiscal vear Amount of dividends declared on running sto^k during florfl smv to 1 Averaee rate per cent of dividends declared durlnp flara] \ Average running tlnne nf matured during </seg>
            <seg id="p154">154 OK I'HK CONDITION OF I'LATTSMOl'TH LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION' OKI- KISS White litb. . . President Vice I'ii- ■ Palterxm Barwiek. Windliam 1)1 KKC 'ORS w ■ •' "'"'«■ W. Smith T M r»llllliw J K Mar li n Windhani Wn, Bi I) Ha« lu 'bus. K&gt;db«TK H ilulisir.mi A ETS '•rlirutrr laati (7 mi in pr »ri • i rr un&gt;1 lixtur Tot I .' ( ( LIAH1I ITIKS ruunini; I lhir^ and diridends I 5*74. • fund. Undivided prort is, on incumpleic loan! mi* unearned Advance due; Advari' Mid premiiimv Total STATKMKNT PLATTSMOITTH. NKBRASKA On the .ttith &lt;la\ of . I unc. I HO" .Seen Tren - Attorn. ■ni interest premiums and tine vuin-ril </seg>
            <seg id="p155">SKCKETARY OF THE STATK BANKING BOARD 155 RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES FOR THK FISCAL VKAK ENDING JUNE 30, 1!&gt;i&gt;7 RECEIPTS. RECEIPTS Glance on hand July 1 MKJ i es. (running stock) M ■t Interest Ui paid Taxes repaid Total ■ 1 ■ 4¥ EXPENDITURES. EXPEND!! JRES ♦ HI-l.M) U »WI I SUPPLEMENTAL ELBPOH PLKS1E.N VL, RJSPoUT I'luii of Association, (Serial or Pertnanen ■rial or Permanent) ol stuck I -ciit-s issued since organization, (if serial) e ui'Kunizutiuii. (U serial) . .Z&lt;t klltt I It'l-Ol t . . No i No &lt;&gt;f shares issued during fiscal year lg fiscal year R ll^cu. &gt;t-ai . N No. "f shares matured during fiscal year jring fiscal year t n&gt;c... j &lt; ar nut n*»t w itlHiruw n &gt;K It.' at this dat t this date stock in force at this date . stock in force at this date at this date n fore K in fi e at this date ■d in No of shares on which dues are delinquent iues are delinquent cancellation for non-paymen ancellation for non-payment of due t * 'limiuent at this date t at this date !&gt;y borrowing stockholders owing stockholders id fines due and unpaid v iuma and fines due and unr foreclosure, and aggregate a and aggregate amount of same. jved real estate il estate upon which ] • nts proved real estate upon wl iproved real estate upon which loans have ind assigned to the associat igned the association as collateral llriing purposes during fiscal ling purpo! durlnR fiscal year ent or homestead mortgaees t of home: tead mortgaees duriner year ents of loans during fiscal v ents of loan during fiscal vea lolders kholders 1 f minors holdinp stock in the association -&gt;ck In the association Avernee rate per cent of Interest charged borrowers during fiscal year nterest charged borrowers di A&gt; t premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year imlums charged borrowers di t Plan of premlu -ve fund durine fiscal year ha Ar Amount of losses cY anced to reserve fund during fiscal vear ,1 declared on running stock during fiscal year A declared on full paid stock dnrinc fiscal year . none nt of dividends declared durinar fiscal year le of stock matured during" fiscal year none Amount of ri Averace rate per - lnff tin ,\&gt; </seg>
            
            <seg id="p156">156 STATKMKNT OF THK CONDITION OK THK LIVINGSTON LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION t'LATTSMOl'TH. NKIiKASKA On the 3&lt;tth dav of .Turn-, liXPT OFKN ■:rs 0. H. Smith IVesilh-Ilt Marshall., nry R. iierinjr Hecretar) Treasure i- O. Fricke riunuas Wallin IUKK. &gt;i; T C X Marsha! Win. A Whiw VVuk Hollj H M S.K-ii hsen Wm Hasi Kredt;. F^cenberjcer Henr&gt; K (iermg AS ETS Urn mortn»ife io»n* ♦ -i .rtya^t* loans m proeeM i»f (oreeiosu ■slock U»an« rf Heal eslaie furniture anil riilure lent interest, premiums, tines and due: -•■s ami taxes paid ■ Me cuotrsct Insurance and taxes paid and advanced Pot ». *t«H*k running. (Dues) »id stock e fund • iled proflts on incomplete loans Premiums unearned Advance dues Advance interest and premiums IfcTidends declared Total Viet- l'it-,ui»-iit Attornev J. Henr&gt; H. r.,.&lt;l </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 I 1 K Nti JUNK :i&gt;. 1907 RECEIPTS and July 1. i*« I 457 7V Dues, (running stock) *i Dues, (full paid stock) Interest 7.«e 1» Membership and transfer fees Ml. as II. lii. S» I ST.. JB Ren ts none I III h-iimi ii&gt;i«j- .a EXPENDITURES * J1IMW M.i I stock 1 ££ 1 iixe&gt; pii.d 1 v.uioed Pl'LKMBNTAL REl'ORT Permanent) it stock lawi ■• ' nuzaiion, (if serial) IT utilization 7.137 n No. ft ..ai • il iliite ul lust report I.«S N*o. of sliaies issued during liscal year lin inn lisi al year, but not withdrawn mine No of Muire* withdrawn betore maturity, durm* nsciu year . ;jg lisi al year 15 tliis date inn k in force at this date ... ... : share* of full paid stock in force at this date . nun* No. of h area !■&gt; &amp;aU res on which dues are delinquent * bject to cancellation for non-payment of dues inquent at this date &amp;• o of dues owing by borrowing stockholders #•.!« ui '■st. premiums and fines due and unpaid tiju N.i mortgages subject to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. none in process (if foreclosure and aggregate amount of same none ount of loans on improved real estate £•■ AppraNed value of inmroved real estnte upon which loans have been made... &lt;iH7.a*&gt;.c« F upraised value of improvements I T(1; ,l nttne f unimproved real estate upon which loans have nnrft Xiil insumme in force and assimed to the association as collateral security HJI.W8.oe it urlt nx' mnde for huildins purposes during fiscal year 5 de for payment of homestead mortgages during year . . &lt;• payments of loans during fiscal year stockholders lrt 5 * iwing stockholrtf No. of non-borrowing stockholders 543 Via. of minors holding stock in the association ■ t of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year 10 t premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year i«M rlan of premium mount credited to reserve fund during fiscal vear Amount of losses charred to reserye fund during fiscal v&lt;-»r BOM nt of dividends declared on running stock during fTswjli year .. tK.Pii in »~ \mnimt of dividends declared on full paid stock during fiscal vear node 'nt of dividends declared durin«r PscM vear 10 \ Average running tlrre of stock matured during fiscal year l*&gt; mam. </seg>
            <seg id="p158">158 June, l'.n M. L WVav.r •I . A . I '■ Vice-] DIRKCTOI M I. W .1 I- A I if e • I.I Allll.ITIH - running I Hue*, and dividend r il |.r. .lit • ilt-rs mi incomplete loan &lt;• •■ intercut and |&gt;re.n K NTATKM ENT STHUYLER liUILDING AM) LOAN ASSOCIATION ScHUYLKR. NEBRASKA .1 A I Vnct .1. .1. I - : tillure~ KpremiumH miai un&lt;l ti»i&lt;~ pi .1 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p159">KND1NG Jl'NK *», IM RECKII'T K i t PPLE1IENTAL RKPORt f z iir withdrawn is date payment of dues it.- amount of same. ' &gt; iation an unilateral • &lt; 1 tmrrnwerp dtirfne fis&lt; i V RK( KIPTS AND KXI'KNIHriKKS K&lt; &gt;K THK FISCAL YKAK EXPEXDITI irnount «»f sat te upon wM»h loans have luring year fund &lt;1iirinp fif&gt;-al ve.ir </seg>
            <seg id="p160">160 STATEMENT OK THE CONDITION OK THK EQUITABLE lUJIIJJlNC AND I/)AN ASSOCIATION SKWAKI), NEBKASKA On the 30th day of .lune. 1907 .lolin Zimmertr ■ K. DickTnuii Graff D. H Krunklin M. C. Miller ■mrljaiii hiaiii •rttraife loans in process of tore - imni ire and tiitur • ni inierrsi pretniunui and tine; rs and taxes paid offlce supplies oertiiM-ut.f- :e UQltaid Total IJodivided profits l»ue sliareliolderson incomplete loans l*remi jais unearned Adiaocedue.s Advance interest and premium ■ Lanffworth; Tfaomai ~u&gt;ok running H*!**!. and dividendsl Kull paid stuck Kt-s«-rve fund </seg>
            <seg id="p161">ETAKY OK THK STATE HAXKIN 161 ltKCKlF'TS AND KXHKN'IMTrRKS KOK THK H VKAH ENDING JUNE MK IW,. liKCKIl'TN </seg>
            <seg id="p162">162 STATKMKNT V THK CONDITION l)l KIDNKY LOAN AND MI'lLDINli AKSCX'IATIO KIDNKY. NKHRASKA On the :tuth diiv of .lunc 1 (■VK 'h iM-mai JcHit .. I 'I Vice I A OIUHi'T V M. H I A I pn x x 1,1 a 111 1. n i . </seg>
            <seg id="p163">163 Ri RKCK1PT I I I 1 l 1 K V \ t s &lt;• is \NI) EXPKNDITURKS Koli THE KISi Al. VEAIt KNDINU JUNK M&gt;. 1!&gt;"7. 1 EXPENDITURES ■ I'LKMKNT \L KKI'ORT </seg>
            <seg id="p164">164 KIKTKRiKTB ANNUAL ItKl'OKT STATEMENT OF THK CONDITION OF THK SOUTH OMAHA LOAN AND lU'ILDINJ; ASSOCIATION SOl'TH OMAHA. NEBRASKA On the .{0th day of June. 1!*&gt;7 ireholders on incomplete loan: - ins unearned ■e dues ** interest and premiums Total •I. H. Loeohner. .. Kitzjreralil.. Miller A. H. M unlock.. . </seg>
            <seg id="p165">K. 165 r '&lt; VKAK KNDING JUNE :«', I".M»7 KECKII'TS Balance on hand July 1, KM I I0.6IK M nn.a-sxi Dues, (full paid st i ..&lt; ... IStlT.05 i m m Men Loa »-,.:l)l :i • KXl'KN HTUKKS M i • ■ I ;jj mi £K w \V Mat E IT.idivided I CPrL.RH KN TAI. KKI-OKT Ksrini*n«*n I I- u. of series issued since organization, (if serial) n aM( iSi No. No. *&gt;f shui m issued duritit; fiscal year J.ttSS So. of shares withdrawn before maturity during fiscal year No, wimJiau n in for. ill this dat No &lt; if shares of full paid stink in force at this dat No .s on which dues are deliminent payment «if due S, I I ili. r. es ilelilHllient at this date Amount of dues owing by borrowing sli»-k X Nn. mortcaffM sulij*'' t to foreclorare, and uKKiuKaie amount of same Nil. inortRaK t tn lore, losur !tl No. morttfajc** '" prorfBa of fine hisurr and ai^Kie^ate a nount of sam ii- at Ariniutit at luans on Improved real estate tat Appraised value of improvements Umnmt nt l"ans unon unimproved real estat A iprovet] real estate upon which loans hav been made flBM.OO Amt. Insurance in force and as-'iRned to the association as collateral rity #H«.3SiOi No of loans made for imildinK nurposes during fiscal year M) N'o. loans made for payment of homestead mortpa^es durinR year Amount of advance payments of loans during fiscal year *»*JI55 for luiildine nurposes during fiscal year 30 V payments of loans I t.orrnwinc stockholders t non-borrowing stocktiolders .... 1 minors holdiner stock in the a s iation v per cent of interest chare »d ■d borrowers durin* f*scwl vear 7H-IO Pverage rate per cent |iremiums chari Ml of Premium Ijorrowers during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year Amount credited to reserve fund during fiscal year £*«&lt;» Amount of losses charged to reserve fund during fts'-al venr nunr Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year .. t Amount of dividends declared on full rwld stock during fiscal year i »■»«• Amount of dividends declared on .full paid stock during nscal &gt; Average rate per cent of dividends declared during flscnl year « Average running time of stock matured during fiscal yenr II vision </seg>
            <seg id="p166">166 PRUDENTI K. S. Kubutktm. I I'. Darnell... S. II. HhII * '. ( '. Vennum I- S Huh. iind Hzlurr ' - .ilnl I Hies t U runr h'ull paiid sti&gt;ok • ■ fund * &lt;1ed pmtits irehulderN on incomplete nis unearned Advance due*. Advance interest and pmoioma Tut </seg>
            <seg id="p167">167 RECEIPTS AND KXl'KN. )I IVKXS Knit TH KlSiAI, VKAK ENDING JINK at, l'.K RECEIPTS Balance on hand Dues, (running si July 1, iw uck) I »5.«l I wa:a I lues, (full paid Interest stock) 7U.U. Premiums due Fines due and paid Mfinuei ship und Real estate sales Total Tota I EXPENDITURES. EXPEND1 T URES Loans # VHW m Loar Salaries Delinquent 171 :a He I Oitiei t-xpt i sm. I* Withdrawals, dues aod eanniitrs . ■,(,.- Kull paid stock, dues duo* s Kull paid sttxk. earnings ouoc Uash on bu-ad Total 4 &amp;3au.«s M.f Total SUPPLEMENTAL. REPORT. FPLEMEN I A.L, REPORT Plan of Association. (Serial or Permanent) 1'erma P I i 'iv value of each siiaie of stock fMN.MI i No. of series issued since organization, (if serial) uoe No. of series issued since organization, i if serial N". ot hi.a, i-s is&gt; \&lt; _;.iiiiZ;LHiiii N No oi &gt; uim-s in 1'iKf ;it tiate of last report N t I t No of shares issued during fiscal year lo •d during fiscal yea N. Footing i&gt;i* two i t '■ ■#■ ! lit" item No. of shares withdrawn before maturuy durlns l II N.i uf shares withdrawn before maturity liuiint II No. of sliares matuied duiing liscat year n.-i,*- No is nr No. of shares L-nm-eied duriuifnseal year buL uoi wiituirawn nnoc No ill. ■il dun iir ii' withdrawn hooi.iiri "f three ure. ediug it*-. us D No. of shares in force at this date i r« No. of sliaies in force at this date No. of s.iai'-.s of running stock in force at thli date force at No- of siai'-s of runiiiiiK stock in force at this date 17H No &lt;»f sliares of full paid stock in force at this date none No &lt;&gt;f shares of full paid stock in force at this date No of shares tomnad on . no No. of sliares on which dues are delinquent IS No. of shares nn which dues are delinquent IS No. of shares subject to cancellation tor non-payment of dues none .« No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Dune Total amount of dues delinquent at this date tntuO nit of dues owing by borrowing stockholders #7V 00 nt of interest, premiums and fines due and unpaid |Mi •? i-ntira^es subject to foreclosure, and atrnreuate amount of same. linquent at this date #7UU0 int of lines owing by borrowing stockholders ffti UO Vniount of interest, premiums and fines due and unraid i-ntira^es subject to foreclosure, and atrnreuate amount of same, re and Mggrtgmtm amount of same f foreclosure and aKKresate amount of same Amount of loans on improved real estate #4 lUUtiu Amount of loans on improved real estate . #4 itti «» Appraised value of Improved reaJ i !i 1 &gt;aus have been App Appraised value of improvements ♦&gt; Appraised value of improvements Amount of loans ui&gt;on nninii)rr&gt;\ ed roal estate Amount of li»ans ui&gt;on nniraprcn ed real estate fl.uwM» \ppraised value of unimproved real estate upon which loans have Amount of li»ans ui&gt;on unlraprvn ed real estate ♦l.uuM» if unimproved real tate upon which loans have force and assigned the association as collateral Amt. insura *l IMM» tv liMine purpf durin**- fiscal year 3 No r»- ■ad moTtsraces durinp year No. loans made for pavment of horn* ;t Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year No. of norrowinp stockholders No. of non-borrowing stockholder No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per cent of interest charged borrowers during fiscal year Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year Plan nf premium Amount credited to reserve fund durine fiscal year Amount of losses charred to reserve fund during fiscal venr Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year ■ of dividends &lt;!■ Average rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year Average running time of stock matured during fiscal yenr . . </seg>
            <seg id="p168">168 CITIZENS ByiLDING, LOAN AND SAVINGS ASSOCIATION SUPERIOR, NKHRASKA On the 30th dsj of Jun». I1MI7 W .1 I J K S - ith:irrt r. H. Stubi i&lt; irtgiufe lontr momraire loans Id proeexa »f for i ■ s Furniture and tixtures »rit interest. premium&gt; and ttne Rxpenaesand taxes r;i '1 Total » 'ai'itii. 'Iim'K running I Dues and dividends I Full paid slock t-e fund I'ndivided profits irehnlders on incomplete loans Premiums unearned AdTanee dues Advance interest and premiums Total STATKMKNT |&gt;K THK CONDITI \V. I*. lx&gt;ntr K. H. Ktuhhs Myera K H. Stuhli* </seg>
            <seg id="p169">169 KKCE IPTS IXIUl* Fl M il EXl'KNl ITI'KE &gt; I » Kit i. haw: Ma K m PPLEMENTAL REPORT flan of As I'ermat ■nt far of each share of stock No f"K* 1 nt ilate of last report ■ri (111 a] year a\ yea matured "luring fiscal y No. of ar ram No of sliares in force at this date No. of shares of running stock in force at this date No "f shares of full paid sto.k in force at this dat No. of shares on which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-pavment of dues . n» Tota date V mount of dues owing hv borrowing, stockhold •ct to forecl Amount of loans on 'nnprovpd ;t Appr Appm1sp&lt;1 TP hern n ;ide » ... A I" ■ Amt i aspipned tl assoriation as rollateral t T l E loans for pavmpnt of »'onn ount of artvanrf payment nf loa So of t No of No of i : itorkhoifiprw the a iation t of interest ».l nwers dnrine fiscal vear A Ave per rent premiums cha ■■1 borrowers during fiscal year n Plan of premium fiscal vear stock durirtar fiscal year . ti 4.»7 94 Amount credited to reserve fund rtnr Amount of dlyidends declared on runn rl on full paid stork riurinp fiscal year EIPTS AND K.XPKNIHITKKS K( &gt;K THE F1S( AL VKAI ENDING JINK :}(&gt;. l!Xi 14 t&lt;«&gt; I&lt;1 aniiation, (if serial) anization flues delinquent at t\ No. mortprapes subject tn fr&gt;r&lt; No. mnrtiraePF in proress nf fi and RRjrrepate amount of same. MM p find a^yreirate amount of same ate «J «.i (Xi ep during ftsral vear :trnd ninrtww during: &gt;'«• i durinp fiscal year Krate i**t rent of dividends derlarwi dnrinsr flsral year . . runninjf time 'tf Ftfwk mntur**d fliirinK 1 flnrnl ypnr ... 6 &gt;r*» </seg>
            <seg id="p170">UK THE CONLMTION OK THt TEXTMKEH Hl'ILDlNi; AM) LOAN TKi I'MSIH. NKBKASK UK KICK US * . nifrt profits RretaoMermoD mroiniilete loann l*rennums unearned \dT»ncr dues *ilv»nre interest and premiums &lt; STATKMKXT on ttu- .'SOU i du\ c( June, 1 In '7 Brundmit \ &lt; ). Shaw I. B. DoutfU* &lt;'kl&gt;iiai stock running. |I»ue&gt;and dividfmU . &lt;i stock Ke-frve fund </seg>
            <seg id="p171">171 KKCKIPIS AND K.Xl'KNDHTKKS FOR THK FISCAL YKAK KND INC I RECEIPT Balance on liand July 1, IMM Dues, (running stuck) Dues, (full paid sto&lt; Inters ■- Premi 11 er imere* Fi Membership and transfer few »r i:« U Rt T&gt; a EXPEND TURH U ii w w nr Mature ■,1 stoefc il lie M t I 1.1 St task on hand T SI ITLK1IEN T XL. REPORT Am Perm II if stock No. of series is.sued since organization, (if serial) No organixation No. t No. d du fiscal ye r No of shares withdrawn before maturity, duriotf tls**al year ir. luit not withdrawn h this date at No. of shares of full paid stock in f&gt; at this date No. &lt;&gt;f shares nn which dues are delinquent No. of shares subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues . Total amount of dues delinquent at this date lus.y Amount of dues owing by borrowing stockholders *. &lt; 1 fines due and unpaid ... ire. and agereeate umount of same. I ! «:. ire and a^Krepate amount of sam •am Appraised value of improved real eMute upon which loans have been made. . . I Appraised value of improvements fu tate upon which loans have fon*e an*1 nsM^-ne&lt;i to the association as collateral In? fiscal t rt rr^ort erases during year Amount of advance pavments of loans during fiscal vear N N et Ptock In the assoclatio \vprneft rate per cent of interest borrower? diirfne fiscal year arsed borrowers duriner fiscal vear Ir &gt; iwers during fiscal vear al vear •)'-" Amount of liis-iP-. chai-ypfi to reserve fiinfl «1wH»e ««-•&gt; 1 v»)%r Amount of dividends declared on nmnlne stock durlne fiscal year .. Amount of dividends denlpreH r»n full r&gt;^&lt;d ctn^k durine fiscnl year . verntre rate ner cent of dividends declared durfne" fiscal vear A \ era if e running tirre of stock matured during fiscal year . . none mmlured </seg>
            <seg id="p172">172 OF THK CONDITION I &gt;!•' TliKNToN LOAN AND BUILDING ASSOCIATION TRENTON. NEBRASKA OKI-ll K A DIHWTOKS 4. K KeynoUK Sinclair Hill Chu^. W DeWuld O li Hj I- A A Krs • r i pn» in ■ lit interest, premiums and tine-* and luxe-* [»aul t-&gt; I.I A HI ,i TIKS ai&gt;it:i: itloek running iDucs and dividend t&gt; n. ' li ITillttS irehtildcrs nn incomplete inn unearned Premiums m 1 run^ft* r and Meinbershii Toll STATKMKNT On tin- :t&lt;ltti &lt;ia\ of .lune. 1!K)7 &lt; &gt;. K. Reynold* Kir Hill... i: i oufui K. R«-yonoldx ■ I fixture Klines interest and premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p173">) • MKNT this dat t this da t *l i A r Tine v r&gt; A (i r fund d ninir st flf»^1nr*M H Am A« </seg>
            <seg id="p174">STATKMI IK i \ IN II VALK\T1NK BUILDING AM) L'JAN ASS(K'IAT] &gt; VALKN *. \ X &lt; ill S « </seg>
            <seg id="p175">) KXI'KWH IV.tHS W&gt;K : kni&gt;in«; .11 nk a», tun. RECKIPTS VEAK RECKIPTS ( ) . . . . II KXI'KMHTI'liKS « 1&gt; « - SUPPL.KMKNTAL REPORT la) or Permanent) - Sim e z [ date "&gt;■ during i during '■ M I ■ii during fi&gt;" n! yem ■reding items . . . It. C« at this il:n Ml forre ;ti I ■-•&lt;-k in fin |«tc MM t ilch iliics arc dettnqtMni i ■ fiiiums n - t tO f'i »f fort* hwu improved rr.-i! estate ..." ■.ppraiaed value of improved real e&gt;ulc u|m&gt;u »I»i.-1i Si^n^ liavi' In-fn made. - #M I mved r«*iii esUbte ttpuo w hi-'li toMW liav«- been nade. - l»" &gt; ■uvi-iii'-nls f&amp;&lt;£ JTrfHn nee and assign e&lt;1 to the association, as collateral &lt;■ «ii »r i-i.'i'.ihiir purposes during Am**] rinR ri-o-al -ear payment of homestead ir . . payment! of Umnm durti i fork hold* ■ &gt; 7» ; storkholderi 19 itr st**'k in i (ion t of interest rharfted borrowera durinc H it premiums rharired borrowers during fisral year rwin e fund during i A nrL r e.J t.i rcserxe fund diiriiK ; rle'lareii on running sto^-k during fiscal year . . IELC31 4t f ,lrn mm Avfratf rate per rprit of dividends derlarp^i durv II MM Average running titn* 1 *'f - i-d during </seg>
            <seg id="p176">KMKN IK CONDITION i pK Tl ASSKI I (llll.l I IK WAIIixt MITl Al. UiAN AM) I I 1! 1INC ASS(CIA r IM N WAI It hi. NKBKASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p177">Nl) K()|{ Till- KIHi'AI KNDINii .UN ii ii XPKNDI I" I " I £ f- * ' i i ♦ \ »-. A r * r n \ m </seg>
            <seg id="p178">STATKMKN SAL1NK CCCKTY bill LING AfM(lA'JJ(N WILBKK. NKliU ASK A )n I li»- .tutli da\ of June. 1 F. S 1KKCT S V H 1 ! I. .1 15- \&gt;~-h pr X XI $ .1 AlilMTIf I cmtvc fund nilmded pn iharelinid u Advance il ii pr A. H»Kpo&lt;liik) K. Mallatl . . .1. Suirk oninff. I Duet ami d tlv»n.-. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p179">NDINC Jl'XI ECE1PT 1 I I &lt; i KXI-KXlilTrilt 4 .\ II l.K.MKNTAI. HEl'OltT f it this da I t t of sa &gt;n v &gt; * A »r tt '.-M \ 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p180">STATKMKX'J ■KTHK OUXMTIOS 01) KIVER BUILDING AND LOAN ASSOCIATION </seg>
            <seg id="p181">NUINU .11 N K JU. I '.*i RECE1P' TS &lt; •SS B. (lu stock) i53 Prer, M ft fer •sta ■tent Tota IH.kW »: EXPENDITURES s Wit Mat Mai aw •a i i r k ng Total i- w.i ■ SI ri'LKHENTAL REPORT T nan lit stotk M issued since organization, (if serial Kanisal ■bam in force :it date of last re| No. &lt;n .shares issued during risial year of two preceding items shares withdrawn before mammy during fiscal year luring fiscal year -» witlidrau a this dat - of running stock in force at this date ■id st... k in force at this date limtuent subject to cancellation for non-payment of dues Lies delinquent at tins date | tl.oo wing stockholder . premiums and lines due and unpaid ...... ect to foreclosure, and ag^re^ate amount of saf. n Jue and unpaid No. 1 t ww tate I ( $:&lt;• Mi ts Appraiser value of unimproved real estate upon wtii&lt;-h loans ':av 1 t the associati .llalrril &lt;* iluring fiscal year i mortgaRes during year rone I f i:i ring fiscal year \ • f noii-l&gt;orrowing stot'khol the a: char* iation rl borrowers during fiscnl vf*ar borrowers during fiscal urns cha :p&lt; 1 fund during fiscal year lit** tn rpscrve fund during fiscal v. ared on running stock during nscal year $1911 4S nninp stock during fiscal year *I9H 4i Kl of dlvldmds dwlared on full pnfd ?tock dnrinir fiscal i«ir aeaa p rate pei cent of dividend." declared during fiscal vear Avernre running time "f =tock matured during fiscal </seg>
            <seg id="p182">182 KIFTKKNTH \SMAI. KKPoKT OF THK STATEMENT OK THK CONIJITMN i&gt;r YORK MUTUAL BUILDING AM) LOAN ASSOCIATE N ?re&gt;t. iirenimnis and linei all's paid - T r.lAHl ITIKS running. I Dues and dividend i in incmniilete loan inM unearned iij . , r duffs includf' Artranoe interest and premiums Total &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p183">ENDING JUNE 30, l!«i RECEIPTS K U Tot EXPENDI TUBES m IX w a •4 SUPPLEMENTAL REPORT ial or Permar r to |H&gt; jed since organization, (if serial) panizati N f last report al yea i. ares matured during fiscal year at at this date . e at this date a "luen ellation for non-payment of dues al amount of dues delinquent at this date it of lines owing hv borrowing stockholders \ in nint i&gt;f intfit'st premiums ;ind fines due and unpaid due and unpaid No. mortsapes subject to foreclosure, and atrprepate amount of same. t to foreclosure, and aggregate amount of same. So. mortgage* in process of foreclosure and aggresate amount of same &gt;rts:aKes in process of forei losnre and aggregate amount of same &gt;■ t of loans on mproved real estate 1w.3Uk.C0 \ mount of loans on mproved real estate *tv- Vppraised value &lt;*f improved real estate upon which loans have been ate upon which loans have he&lt; Appraised value of Improvements . . M of loans upon unimproved I • 1 "* 1 M -■d value of unimproved real est *• - upon have het-n made. n«' «&gt;■ Appraised valne of improvements - 1 ,f i real eati e Mn&gt; M x Ans have t&gt;et-n niitde. ICOLCO -'■d value of unimproved real estjt 1 - ui».n - have t&gt;et-n made. Amt Insurance in for -e :md assigned to the association as collateral Amt Insurance in rove :tnd assigned to the association as collateral security ft No of loans made for building purposes during fiscal year 10 ■ hulldlngr purposes during fiscal year lyment of homestead mortuaRes durti No. loans made for payment of homestead mortjfaKes during year . . tend mortKaRes durinR year Amount of advance payment of loans during fiscal year $31 Amount of advance payment of loans durins fiscal year $3I.MU.«i \ uTov intr --t tckhol'lrrs 75 No of non-borrowing stockholders non-borrowing stockholders No. of minors holding stock in the association No. of minors holding stock in the association Average rate per rent of interest chareed borrowers during fiscal year t of interest chareed borrowers during fiscal year &gt;, Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year » Average rate per cent premiums charged borrowers during fiscal year :» Plan of premium w Amount credited to reserve fund rturlne fiscal year I \niount of losses diareed to reserve fund durinR fiscal year : Amount of dividends declared on running stock during fiscal year . 11 paid stock during fiscal year t rate per cent of dividends declared during fiscal year :nning time i »f stock matured during fiscal year 9U wks </seg>
            <seg id="p184">STATKMKNT W fHK CONDITION II Cl .'(iMK.V'S SAVINGS AND LOAN ASSOCIATION Tot* * </seg>
            <seg id="p185">KKlKll'TS It, [Ml July II** T K. KXPKNIH ITItKS 5 m ' N s iir N i i\&gt;- nU AiiMnint ..r iiit(-rc^i premiums mul Hii^n due and unpaid unioiin' il en niiule. ■ &amp; I f II I x As* ,de f&lt;&gt;r payment &lt;&gt;f homestead rnortmnrefl durintf ti»»*nl year 5 is durinu' (l»«'ul yt loMcm iterest eha u 2 ver eer S •ditcd ml dur: il in rr .1 MendM ilt"*l;»rfil i&gt;n runiiiQtr wtock ilurinic iNr. idflni- d I KF.c KH'TS AND KXI'KN D1TIKKS Kn|{ THK K VfMR KNDINli .IINK :io. I1XIT. I'l'I.KMKNTAI. liKPOKT rowers (tunn* Bsei iirrower. ilurin* tl^- </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>