<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00031">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Why Some Hens Lay More Eggs than Others</title>
               <date value="1932-11">1932-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 44 November, 1932 Why Some Hens Lay More Eggs than Others H. E. ALDER Department of Poultry Husbandry svl ; '"AAA _\_\__\+\\ ' . * . ■ _f ' \'\L __x :^iP*^ --' "~~ —^-^-***— J^t&amp;*^____r*' '■ -*'' ' % ' -____jk&amp;0-^^^ ____-"-""■■.■ '""■■•■ ,w-y- '-"■'' fc 1 ■ ■ ( •&gt;***^*-*^ B^ ii^ M^'^^ t^^ Wl^s_a__t-a_a__-tta_ta_t^^^^ lm Single Comb White Leghorn hen No. B-6827, photo - graphed at the end of her fifth laying year. This hen had enough intensity and persistency to lay 961 eggs in five years. She weighed 3% pounds when she laid her first egg as a pullet, and when this photograph was taken she weighed 4% pounds. .**■■*- THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF agriculture experiment station LINCOLN W. W. Burs, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Why Some Hens Lay More Eggs than Others H. E. ALDER The 1929 report of the Storrs Egg Laying Contest, which has been conducted at Storrs, Connecticut, twenty-one years, shows that the best pen of ten hens entered laid 2,802 eggs, and the poorest pen laid 829 eggs. In the best pen the average egg production per hen was 280.2 eggs as compared with 82.9 eggs per bird in the poorest pen. Why did the one pen lay so many eggs, and the other so few? This prompts us to try to find out what factors are responsible for the number of eggs a hen lays in the course of 365 days. There are a number of well-recognized factors, and others that are more or less obscure. GENETICAL FACTORS Intensity and Rhythm. — "Cycle," or "intensity," is not only one of the very important factors but also one that may be measured accurately in the first few weeks of production. Figure 1 shows the cycle of Single Comb White Leghorn Hen No. L-997 that laid 240 eggs in 365 days, and 259 eggs before molting. Figure 2 shows the record made by Single Comb White Leghorn No. L-362, and Figure 3 shows the daily record of L-843 for 365 days. A I 1 1 |2|3|4|f |«|T|e|»|iolnli2li3li*Miig 17 je F 5 jjB3**j*g S5S.JS - X0TM - MiiiiZIIIIIiii — LLi. JL _ i. JI 2. — — i — — — — — -^i - oec » » « _._._. — _. — — j^i ~~f~ , *&gt;_iJJ.iJLii »;2I LL — — — — — — — — — — — *•* Tie - TT~» i a 7 ~ 7 7 7 ZiZZZiiZjii — £.2- ** yq. . % *ii_iiJi. «_«_i i «iI_III_IIIi &gt;ii __t— tpn i i J. JL ii JL *J.iJi±i_±Jii.i_i.i — -i — — — — -i2_ MM » I » » I 7 ~" 7 7 7 7 7 __\._L — — l- — — — i— — — — — — - *•*" "JwcT i * i »l_*AJ-_J._JL±l__-i — — -pi. — — — — — — — **- JULY 1 » nil _» i..i_.l-L2 i±_i.*._Ji.i_iiS. a* auc. »JLl_2i_l.L_22. — JL -ii ii.i._i_i. - i * * ** "stPT" 77~7i ±± — _._._. i_i._JL_ii._ -li — l i2- OCT »*» » »»1 \\\\ |»|&gt;l I 1*1 l»l I I'l I I ii \ TOTAL I -*Q Fig. 1.— Year's record of Hen No. L-997. hen that lays two days in succession, misses one day, and lays two more days in succession and continues in this man - ner, is said to have a "two — one" cycle. Such a bird would produce 20 eggs in 30 days. L-997, as shown in Figure 1, did not have a perfectly rhythmical cycle. For example, in November she laid eggs on the first, second, and third and missed the fourth day, and then laid on the fifth and sixth and missed the seventh and eighth. Rhythm is the regularity with which a bird repeats her cycles. Superior layers usually have regular rhythm. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Why Some Hens Lay More Eggs Than Others __l______±_&gt;tl__±MUl2~t*lZ\tnta\i' SoElbil23[Z4bt|26bT|»lMl3o|3l fr-QTAL SEPT - 3 A~ 1_H * _____ &lt;___. — l — __l_l_ll_l__\_l*__±_ m ±_l_l x x X X To- NO^ _X A_i_ 1—111—1 l — l — lH. — ll_Hl 1 Z A~* ~* **~ otc. _2.*_JLA_i._A.I_.*.2:.l_A.l.i.JL_*.li_JL-*__I-?i *" "~ JAN. XX **j._j.A A 7~77~"i'» * * X~T"x~ If n.. — 11 _.!.-_. 11±±±±L_. -!!_.-_. ±_._l_[_i I" "IT X2!--lll-lll-l-l-lll_llZil±H-ll_l±±a 1 ±_ APR. j X XX X _x ji Ji_ JL^. x___»_x _X_ JI _x_i_x X » X &gt;.! 2£!—l-Hl — ll___ll_llLl_.lH___ L l_ ' » iT'ij Ai__.i_» _.»i___*-l_».L__*_*_* __» A Jl_ J * ~ 3.a Juiy _ A x _x til i A _ A | _x _ ia *"g . I I I x| | | | | | | | | | || | | | | | | j | j | | 1 x| x| ~| I 3~ TOTAL &lt;Hf Fig. 2. — Year's record of Hen No. L-862. Persistency. — Pullet No. L-362 did not have any better rhythm or intensity, and eventually laid 32 fewer eggs, partly because her intensity was not quite so good, but more especially because she had less persistency. In the last two months she produced only 13 eggs, while L-997 laid 31. To make satisfactory records a laying pullet must have good intensity, no long pauses, and good persistency. A bird with good intensity for six or seven months may make a record of 130 to 140 eggs, but can never really be a profitable producer. Birds with a low intensity usually do not have good per - sistency. L-997 laid at a profitable rate, outside of a pause in December, for thirteen months, for she laid 19 eggs dur - ing November, her thirteenth month. In other words she produced 259 eggs during her pullet year. L-362 laid at a profitable rate for only about ten months. L-843 laid at about the same rate for eight months, and then slowly fell off. If these three birds had been trapnested during their first five weeks of production, sufficient information would have been obtained to have caused rejection of L-843 J.ili.J.Ali» 'O'l a !3|l4|li|ls|l7|ia|l»|20[Zlb;b3|a»bj|«|2T|2B|i»|30|3l|TOTAL oct. x x A_A_A ~ A_A_ » _____ H__-± *A_A 1 — 1 — 1 — 1 A »"*» *. x ~i?~ ___: i— ii i—i_± ii a_a_aa r ~u~ ____. — ! i AA_A 5 » A_ A_ A! A J i.y, . rts 1 — 1 * JL __ * JI XX 1 _ A - — 1 * A * __ "ch. x x A_ A_ A_A_A A *A_A_A * x ~T~ T~7i~ *___. ±1 1 AA_AA_AA_A_A_ * Ii ~TZ~ i«r a_A l± — l± — ±l — _. — ± — i______* *• xxx ~ir~ JUNE _.— ___ A_AA_A 1 7. _X XX X X _______ __!_- — ! 11-1_1 1 _x A_aZLI_A T '~ii *t£: A » 1 X XX T" X X X ~ SEPT I I I I X I 1*11 X "X 5 — TOTAL ly I Fig. 3.— Year's record of Hen No. L-843. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Circular 44 as a medium to poor layer and the selection of the other two as good layers. If one is equipped to raise more pullets than he desires to house, trapnests will soon pay for them - selves in locating the poor producers. Besides, the pullets that lay eggs undesirable for market purposes may be found and disposed of . Early Maturity. — Another quality that most good layers possess is early maturity. In a pen of 500 pullets the first half to come into production is always the better half. They will show better cycles, fewer pauses, and greater persistency. Why do some birds mature earlier, possess greater in - tensity, experience few pauses, and have great persistency, while others are slow to mature, show a low intensity, a number of pauses, and a low persistency? The domestic fowl is much more complexly organized than one might think. The diagram below (Fig. 4) indicates the special work done by each of the ten functional systems. Unless each of these systems is functioning properly and all of them are working harmoniously together, the bird whose existence depends upon them is abnormal and of little or no utility. Just as a domestic fowl is made of these systems, so is each system composed of smaller units. For example, the nervous system is composed of brain, FUNCTIONAL SYSTEMS OF THE DOMESTIC FOWL INTEGUMENTARY DIGESTIVE SKELETAL PROTECTION AGAINST HEAT. CHANCES FOOD TO A . SERVES AS A COLD. ANO MECHANICAL INJURY. SOLUBLE FORM. FRAMEWORK FOR ' \ 7 OTHER STRUCTURES. ' / EXCRETORY ELIMINATION OF WASTE MATERIAL. MUSCULAR S /%&amp;_ LOCOMOTION ANO _t_t_ 4 __\\\K MINOR ADJUSTMENTS 'S*'ia»\ OT VARIOUS KINDS . REPRODUCTION 1 Ef \ s^Z) PRESERVATION OF /jHf I s/_r+jr\ /0sfL^^^ , /AAAAAu circulatory / li'ir^^^^^ //Y DISTRIBUTES BOOT a(Zj&amp;Z&amp;_-l~ : W !^ n, __-l S-'^'V HEAT, NUTRIENTS. .---—-,.„_ ___T__V__W?\ _:\\ Zm* __T~-&lt;? ANOWASTE SECRETORY ' \__WA : - ~-&amp;-^l$r-=-^f MANUFACTURES \ \\%W iMffl____\ T~ ENZYMES ANO V tSss£ "^S^^LW ~~T respiratorc NERVOUS S^n.vrSS" 300 CONTROLS REACTIONS f7^__i WIM uxtu.n ANOaSuUS-5o«TS Fl ANO CARWES AWAY ALSO IN CONJUNC- li \\ CARBON DMMOC TION WITH THE -&lt;== — __ri____t\_\ ANOAWS MATERUUAY HORMONES COORDINATES • J rzS£_mL____9__\_^L IN CONTROLLING AND HARMONIZES / s=== = J-i_\__%-%9s-___ \ BOOT TEMPERATURES thc other systems^ '- — ' _!-==— not the fowl. Fig. 4. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Why Some Hens Lay More Eggs Than Others spinal cord, and nerves. Each of these structures is fur - ther made up of minute parts called cells. ii T^ e^ truc l ure a ? d Natur e off Cell..— The basic units of all of the systems shown on page 4 is the cell. The cell, like the systems, has a complex organization. Figure 5 represents AsffZrZ^ .^.'.v.vT^j^CELL VUAU- - &gt;&lt;^' l -'.:.-'77\7&gt;:;v.J;.-".v7^i^FXJX0 with living /i : -'•'- "" 7 ...»&lt; rTr^&gt;. PROTOPLASM, fOOO. /■'■'. j- :'&lt;■•-■.'- '■' ."■ \ WASTE ANO WATER. /. 77 :.■••' i .VT^Vtrr^^^v"' i •-; '• ':■'.■ . Va«0MOSOME - /&gt;•.'. 7-V7 y?v ■' -v.'-'-7;St-777&gt;&lt;&lt;ATHERE ARE from [_\t : i''.j-;&amp;r-/- ' •' ■ ■ .^_A&lt;^- : y&lt;:\ IT TO SSOF /7 -.■''■'"■:;'/■■ '.''• •'•.'•■•' •-''. ' -&gt;&lt;^. ; 77: - ' : \ THESE IN EACH /■•V !7.V-!-/ •'• : '• ]___________^' A" ':: .S-V J CELL OF THE i.'"::-:'-:?. . : ; :u .-' •'.." I .....■...["■' ' V..V' : '7V-- 1 oomestk I 7.7- 7.i : -.l -I_i^_K : tiiiili2 : l row - l •:■;•■: •-■&gt;; ;vA •,"-..'• •• .-.'■- ;-7.7^&gt;&gt;^7;v7"T r^NucLEus- V . •/ . •SV.' '• •'.:•'. ' ' . ■: /sSwi'iv'.y THE ENTIRE V .'r'-'.i '-..'A-V'-- •: '■'.■.' ■• : - -XtM7?Sil/ ROUND MASS. \. : '.'-i--'iiS^V;l. : : '/ : =&gt;^?t&gt;;.77; :^GENES-THERE \ - '^\&gt;M— r-5?V : 77. '-.""• ■ -V ARE A LARGE \7 • r ' ; 77-7:"'^7\7 vi \v' 77 \':iey number of these Xt : "7--. '■■'' . jV' W EACH CHROMOSOME. ''£-:V---'r.~:;'.--\'.-£pr EACH GENE MAKES A ; ; 77 ■■:__^^ DEFINITE CONTRIBUTION TO-' 71 WARDS THE BIROS EXISTENCE. Fig. 5. — Diagrammatic picture of the cell. a diagrammatical picture of a cell with the more important parts. The parts of the cell that we are most concerned with are the chromosomes and their genes or character deter - miners. Each cell of a chicken contains 35 or 36 chro - mosomes, with the exception of the eggs and sperms, which have either 17 or 18. Each chromosome contains a large number of genes. Whether a bird is black or white depends on the par - ticular kind of genes it carries in the cells of its body. One egg hatches into a Buff Cochin Bantam and another be - comes a Barred Plymouth Rock because each egg had a set of genes that determined the course of development. For exactly the same reason one bird lays 20 to 22 eggs per month for 10 to 12 months, while another will lay 12 to 15 per month for nine or ten months. Fundamentally, the thing responsible for early maturity, good intensity, lack of pauses, and great persistency is the presence of certain genes and the absence of others. Eye color, body shape, feather length and width, size of bird, shape of egg, rapid molt, etc., are all tied up with the genetic con - stitution of the fowl. By very careful selection for such factors as early matur - ity and late molt, we tend to fix the tendency and even - tually get a flock of birds that are fairly uniform in regard </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Circular 44 to these two factors. It is well to remember that one of the fundamental laws of nature is variation, and that therefore one must keep selecting the best and eliminat - ing the poorest. Only the factors selected for will become uniform. Let us consider egg shape, for example. If we set nothing but well-shaped eggs for hatching, in four or five years the shape becomes well fixed. The color of the shell may be unsatisfactory and hatchability poor because we have paid no attention to either factor, and have used the poor qualities as well as the good ones. So far we have listed three factors necessary for high egg production, namely : intensity, lack of pauses, and per - sistency. These are not the only considerations. There are others that should be mentioned. A bird must inherit enough vitality to carry her through the strain in - cident to laying intensely and persistently. This is a highly important matter, and depends just as much on those little genes as does eye color or plumage color. Some birds in - herit the vitality but do not have the urge to lay. Others inherit the urge to lay but do not have the vitality to carry them along. management factors Another large problem is management — from the time the egg is laid until the layer's record is complete. This in - cludes such factors as care of the egg before hatching, in - cubation, brooding, rations, methods of feeding, and hous - ing. Without proper management birds of the very best breeding become culls. Too often high-class stock is pur - chased with the feeling that the breeding is so good that the birds will lay regardless of management. Frequently the management will not be as good as if a cheaper grade of stock had been purchased, the reasoning being that the birds are not of extra good breeding, and will, therefore, require very good management in order to return a profit. Another factor that should be mentioned is disease. Pull - orum disease is responsible for poor egg records from some hens in a well-bred, properly managed flock. The ovaries become badly diseased and prevent eggs from forming in normal clusters or cycles, thus reducing the intensity of laying. Mortalities are materially increased in Pullorum - infected flocks. Other diseases, such as roup and bron - chitis, affect some birds more than others and materially reduce the number of eggs. The time of year the birds are hatched may to some ex - tent determine the number of eggs laid. June-hatched pullets, even if properly brooded and raised on clean range, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Why Some Hens Lay More Eggs Than Others are materially handicapped for making first-year records. If hatched June 15th, they are not six months old until December 15th. Cold, changeable weather may prevent production until the middle of January or the first of February. One cannot expect any considerable number to continue to lay later than the first of October the following fall. This makes an eight-months laying period. If 18 eggs are laid each month, the average could be only 144 eggs per bird. On the other hand, if the pullets were hatched February 1st, production, in the case of light breeds, should be good by August 1st. These birds can be kept in produc - tion for three or four months and will produce an average of 50 eggs per bird before undergoing a partial molt. The flock will be practically out of production from November 15th to January 15th, at .which time they should again be producing well. If they continue at a rate of 60 per cent from January 15th until October 1st, they will produce 153 eggs. This added to the 50 produced in the fall gives 203 eggs per bird during the pullet year as compared with 144 for pullets hatched June 15th. The pullets hatched February 1st must be fed four months longer at an extra cost of not over 50 cents and will produce 59 more eggs, * c ]V-, lf soId at 24 cents a dozen &gt; wi H return $1.18, or a net difference of 68 cents per pullet. Each early-hatched cockerel is worth from 10 to 20 cents more than each late - hatched one, thus- adding at least 10 cents to the 68 cents favorable to the early-hatched bird. If one were housing 1,000 pullets, this would make a net income of $780 00 for hatch 681 " m ° re f ° r the February hatch than for th e June summary of factors for good egg production 1 Genetical Factors. (a) Intensity— genes that cause eggs to come in cycles of three or more. (b) Good rhythm. (c) Persistency— genes that cause the urge to lay to continue twelve or more consecutive months. (d) Early maturity. (e) Vitality enough to continue at a high speed for a lone period of time. (f) Vigor enough to eat and assimilate large amounts of food. (g) No pauses such as the winter pause and those caused by brood - mess. 2 Management Factors. (a) Hatching and raising young stock. (b) Nature of feed. (c) Feeding practices. (d) Housing. (e) Disease control. MM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>