<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00027</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-fifth Biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction to the Governor of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1918-12-01">1918-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">TWENTY-FIFTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOR THE BIENNIUM BEGINNING JANUARY 7. 1917 AND ENDING JANUARY 8, 1919. W. H. CLEMMONS STATE SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE YORK BLANK BOOK CO. YORK, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Letter of Transmittal 6 Official Roster • Nebraska State Superintendents 7 Tribute to Dr. H. K. Wolfe 8 to 10 Applied Education 11 Lessons of Economy _ 12 to 13 High Schools 14 to 15 The Influenza _...15 to 16 Rural Education, Consolidation 16 to 23 Biennial Appropriations and Expenditures _ 24 Rural and Elementary Schools 25 to 27 School Improvements Emphasized 28 to 29 Educational Exhibit 29 to 31 Accredited Schools 31 to 35 Approved Schools 35 Normal Training In High Schools, Aid, Courses of Study 35 to 41 Shumway Act 42 to 44 Mallery Act _ 45 Vocational Education Under Smith-Hughes Act 46 to 51 State Aid to Weak Districts ..._ SI Certification of Teachers 62 to 56 Appropriated Funds 56 to 59 Agricultural Schools „ 60 to 61 State Normal Schools 61 to-62 Colleges and Universities .....62 to 63 Private Schools 63 Summary of Statistics From County Superintendents' Reports 63 to 67 County Superintendents 68 to 69 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">INDEX Accredited Schools 31, 33 Affiliated Schools _ 43 Agriculture 60 Applied Education 11 Appropriations ..._ 24, 46, 56, 57, 58, 59 Approved Schools 32, 35 Biennial Appropriations 14 Boys' and Girls' Club Work 30 Certificate Examination 55, 56 Certificates Granted By Institutions 53 Certificates Granted By State Superintendent 53, 54 Certificate* In Force 1917-18 .- 54, 55 Colleges and Universities 62 Consolidation _ 18 Consolidated Building Plans 20 to 23 Consolidated School Pictures 30 Consolidation Summary 18, 19 County Superintendents 68 to 70 Courses 40, 50 Director of Vocational Education _ 46 Education, a Business Proposition 18 Education, Hot-house, Force-pump 17 High Schools, Inspection of 14, 15, 34 Influenza _ 15 Lessons of Economy 12, 13 Letter of Transmittal _ 5 Mallery Act 4 Nebraska State Superintendents _ 7 Need for Thoroughness 17 Normal Training 36 Official Roster _ 6 Plans of Buildings 20 to 22 Private Schools 63 Receipts and Disbursements, Smith-Hughes 47 Rural Education _ 16 Rural High Schools 27 Rural Schools 25 Schools of Agriculture 60 School Improvements _ _ 28, 29 Shumway Act, Aid 42 Smith-Hughes Act, Aid _ 46 State Aid, Mallery Act 45 State Aid to Normal Training 37 State Aid to Weak Districts 51 State Educational Exhibit _ 29 State Normal Schools _ 61 Summary of Consolidation 18, 19 Summary of Statistics 63, 67 Thoroughness _ 17, 27 Tribute to Dr. H. K. Wolfe 8 to 9 Vocational Education 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL STATE OP NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION LINCOLN His Excellency. Keith Neville Governor of the State of Nebraska. Sir: — In compliance with the requirements of the law, I, hereby, have the honor to submit the Twenty-fifth Biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction. Most respectfully, W. H. CLEMMONS, State Superintendent of Public Instruction. December 1, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">STATE OF NEBRASKA Department of Public Instruction LINCOLN OFFICIAL ROSTER W. H. Clemraons „ State Superintendent •John A. Woodard Deputy State Superintendent Cora A. Thompson Assistant Superintendent Alice Florer _ Rural School Inspector ••A. H. Dixon .» Normal Training Inspector J. F. Duncan _ Normal Training Inspector J. D. French Head Certification Department ASSISTANTS Vada C. Vennum _ Secretary Ruth E. Wheeler „ Secretary of Normal Training Department, Bookkeeper and Statistician C. Blanche Stevens ,_ Stenographer Floa Cottrell _ Stenographer Maud Davis Stenographer Martha C. Woods _ .Clerk of Examinations Caroline C. Cooper Clerk of Examinations Mrs. C. D. Wheeler _ Assistant Clerk and Recorder of Examinations John A. Woodard resigned August 1, 1918 to accept the Principal- ship of the County High School at Miles City, Montana. A. H. Dixon resigned September 1, 1918 to accept the Superln- tendency of the City Schools, University Place, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA STATE SUPERINTENDENTS 8. D. Beale. 1869-1871 J. M. McKeniie _ 1871-18 7 7 S. R. Thompson 1877-1881 W. W. W. Jones _ 1881-1887 George E. Lane 1887-1891 A. K. Goudy 1891-1895 H. R. Corbett : 1895-1897 W. R. Jackson 1897-1901 W. K. Fowler 1901-1905 J. L. McBrien 1905-1909 B. C. Bishop 1909-1911 J. W. Crabtree ..19 11- (Resigned) J. E. Delxell „ 1911-1915 A. O. Thomas. 1916-1917 W. H. Clemmons 1917- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Tribute to DR. HARRY KIRK K WOLFE Born November 10, 1858; Died July 30, 1918. Age 59 years, 8 Mob., 20 days. It is fitting that the Report, to the Governor, of the Superintend - ent of Public Instruction should contain * tribute to the life, worth and memory of Dr. Wolfe who was for so many years a teacher in the University of Nebraska. His death occurred suddenly at Wheatland, Wyoming. He had gone there with his family to the home of one of his brothers for a short vacation. The story of the life of Dr. Wolfe Is not difficult to tell but the measure of his teaching and Influence cannot be taken. He was born into a good, intelligent Indiana home. His father and mother had been graduated from the University of Indiana and were devoted to the Intellectual, moral and spiritual ideals for which the institution stood then and stands now. He was educated in the home, on the farm, in the public schools, in the Uni - versity of Nebraska and in the University of Leipzig. He earned in these institutions the A. B., A. M., and Ph. D. degrees. His abilities and tastes led him into the classics while he was doing his under - graduate work. Later, under the inspiring example and teaching of that famous investigator. Dr. Wilhelm Wundt, he went into the field of psychology. To this subject and its kindred branches he devoted his study and teaching during the greater part of his public life. He was by no means narrow and technical in his teaching but both specific and comprehensive in his interpretation of the facts and meaning of the psychical powers and phenomena. Dr. Wolfe had many qualities of heart and character which caused him to be admired by his students, by his associates, by his friends, and by the people in general. Among these are consecration to duty, de - votion to ideals, genuine friendship, sincerity of purpose, faithfulness j to every trust, sympathy with human need and frailty, true measures • of the aim and office of instruction, appreciation of the responsibility which rests upon those who are examples for childhood and teachers] of youth, the patriotism of deeds, loyalty to his country's flag and j anxiety for the safe anchorage of the "Ship of State." These things j and his worthy life will live in the memory of the people of Lincoln,, of the university he honored both as a student and teacher, of Nebraska, in which he took a just pride and of the Nation in which he had ani unusual interest </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DR. HARRY KIRKE WOLFE </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">Applied education and needs have taught us, not only why and wherein our civilization has practically broken down and why recon - struction is necessary, but also, it has pointed out some definite and specific things which have to do with the social, industrial, religious, economic and educational life, and not alone of the schools but of the people as well. Without attempting to make a full list of the things the war has disclosed and, by the list, determine the kind of recon - struction work which ought to be done, we have the following: 1. While we have known all the time that the census takers of 1910 found 5,517,608 persons ten years of age and older who could not read and who could not write, we did not realize what that meant. It was only when we came to face the need of a well equipped army and a well drilled navy that we came to see that 5,517,608 is one out of seventeen of the whole population and what that signifies when we sit down to analyze causes; calculate chances and determine the kind of forces and agencies which must be employed if certain re - sults are to be secured. The percentage— one out of every seventeen — tells us the seriousness of the situation when we realize that our governmnt is by the people, for the people and of the people. 2. Our eyes had been closed to the physical defects of the young men of America. It was not until after the defects were dis - covered and published by the medical examiners of the general government that we gave the question any thought. Now we are asking what problems are to be solved before we have a nation whose men of military age are physically well and strong and ready for any task. The inspection taught us that many of the defects were not organic but of a nature and kind which can be prevented. Here again the war was the agency which revealed ourselves to ourselves. 3. We have thought because there is not a month in the year in which new wheat is not thrown on the market that it was not necessary to take any thought about the food supply. More frequently we have recalled the great fields in Minne - sota and Nebraska and the wide fields in the wheat belt of Oregon and Washington and have not taken Into the account — the millions of people to be fed. The demands and neces - sities of the war for a supply great enough to fill the bread baskets of many lands have shown us the need of increased production and the value of conservation of the supply. Now that our attention has been called to the great demand, what ought the schools to do that the present may be supported and the future be made certain? </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT LESSONS OF ECONOMY. 4. Since the war has taught us the economic value of school and child gardens and of the vast quantities of corn, potatoes and vegetables put on the market by children and youth, the place of the school in forming habits of thrift and Industry comes to us with new meaning. In the light of this great reservoir of power and field for production, what is the province of the teacher and school in the case? What new lessons are we to learn in home economics, in trade and in - dustry, in habits of economy, in agriculture and stock rais - ing and of the relation the school sustains to social progress and human welfare? 5. What is the best that science knows and what means ought to be employed to prevent the spread of disease? What shall be taught in the schools to encourage thrift and cleanliness? What is the relation of schools -and education to the safety of the home, to the wel - fare of the community, to the advancement of the state and the dignity of the nation? Because the school inspects to find the disease germs and to stimulate to a study of health conditions, a new field has been opened. By this means the school is performing a task so vast and so difficult and withal so necessary that only time can tell what intelligent interest and devotion can do. While something had been done before the war came, it is a part of a great forward movement which the war has shown to be so necessary. 6. One of the things which the new age and new conditions must bring to full fruition is to place woman in possession of the Bocial power and political authority which of right and equity belong to her. Every battle, every red cross movement and every liberty drive of the war show the insight, the un - derstanding, the executive ability, the loyalty and patriotism and the accomplishment of worthy deeds. Woman shows by work done that she ought to hold, as a permanent possession, a place of political honor and social advancement equal to that of her brother. What ought the status of woman to be in the municipal and political world, has been asked many times during the war. Now that the war Is over, It la one of the problems in human society and economics which the future must solve. What relation does woman's standing as a teacher and her place on boards of education sustain to the problem ? 7. The war has flisclosed, in a most striking manner, the truth of the statement: No people can be made permanently better unless they are made truly wiser first. Information, knowl- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 13  9 10 edge and inspiration are the forerunners of progress. Hence, in a country like ours, the need for keener insight, for more extensive observation and for a wider and widening sympathy are necessary if we are to have a more disinter - ested concern for the welfare of the community and state. If we are to make the progress we ought, there must be more concrete lemons in practical agriculture and geography and better equipment and more extensive libraries in all our schools. How can the public meet these urgent requirements? One of the outstanding facts which must not be forgotten 1* the place, worth and power of the individual. Equally Im - portant are the lessons the war teaches of the value, place and worth of the group — the efficiency of the team when its members have been inspired by a common desire and have been taught to work for a common end. When the members of a group are animated by the same spirit, im - pelled by a common conviction and inspired and guided by the same principles, the result is seen in the things accom - plished. Out or these facts naturally we ask: What advant - ages are the schools to take of the power of the individual and the meaning of the group which the war has pointed out? More than ever before, the present demands that we modify and enrich our courses of study, that we simplify our methods of instruction and that we define more accurately our aim and purpose in education. These things are called for that we may retain the language and literature, the history of philosophy of the past and at the same time we may put greater stress and more emphasis on ability to see, to hear, to think, to search, to describe and on the untold value of the intelligence and the skill which will enable a person to solve life's every day problems. What answer, dur - ing the next ten years, shall the schools and the other institu - tions of learning make to these demands? The war has made to stand out as never before in American history the supreme worth of strong conviction of duty, the value of unwavering loyalty and heartfelt patriotism, the unchanging necessity there is for right and righteousness, and the increasing need there is for all, both in private and public life, to conform to the standards of truth and to the principles of justice. What shall be the attitude and in - fluence of all our educational agencies in behalf of the high - est and holiest things in the moral life of all our people as it is manifested in our homes, in our business places, in our religious organizations, in our social relations and in our political institutions? </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT The High School Whatever may be said of infancy and childhood and of the kind of teaching and training a child ought to receive during these periods, they are no more important than the years which ought to be spent in the high school. The high school occupies a unique place among the agencies in American education. There are several things about the high school which make it of great interest. It has surpassed all the other institutions during the last few years of its growth. Colleges, normal schools, technical schools and universities have multiplied in recent years but the high school has surpassed them all in this regard. In 1889, there were in the United States only 2526 twelfth grade high schools, while in 1918 — the short period of twenty-nine years — there are about 14,000. This number ought to be greatly increased for there is no suf - ficient reason why any boy or girl in America should be deprived of the training and inspiration of a good high school. One reason for this is that a boy or girl who graduated from a good twelfth grade high school in May or June 1918 is no better prepared for the world of life and activity which lies between this year and 1968 than the father and mother were for the equal period between 1868 and 1918 when they had completed the eighth grade or its equivalent. The manner of life, the complexity of our institutions, the rapidity of our business movements, the large and various transactions, and the In - fluence of the telephone, the telegraph, the railway, the steamship and a hundred other instruments and agencies of progress demand the extra four years of training and education. Because of the day and condition in which we live, it is safe to say that every youth In America between the age of 14 and 18 ought for his own sake and usefulness and for the safety and stability of the Republic to be en - rolled in a modern twelfth grade high school and ought to be pres - ent and at work at least 36 weeks each year of the four. For the sake of the boy or girl, It is most important that the course of study and the methods of instruction shall be adapted to his capacity as a learner and to his prospective needs as a citizen and as a man or a woman. Moreover, these four years and courses of study should be free in a large measure from the technicalities of a trade and the outlines of his prospective calling in after life. By a good high school is not meant a continuation school such as is advocated by some. The continuation school, except for adults, is not adapted to our democracy because it is not American in spirit and purpose — not American in plan and de - sign. Speaking affirmatively, the continuation school is a part of a cast-making system and is, in essence, machine education. A democ - racy has no place for schools which do not prepare for citizenship and for the performance of public duties. The system from which the con - tinuation school comes, prepares children and youth to submit to </seg>
            <seg id="p015">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 15 autocracy and not to share In the .responsibilities of citizens. In some countries the system of elementary schools, purposely and deliberately, directly and consciously bars the masses of the people from higher education and from all hope of sharing in the joys, riches and satis - faction of a wider and constantly widening horizon. The continuation school adds to the same kind of training and thus fastens the door of opportunity against the peasant still more securely. The folk and continuation schools do not pretend to open the way for a peasant to reach a round on the ladder higher than the one on which his father stood. To know how to work with skilled hands is only one of the all-important things in the preparation of a boy or girl for the life of to-day and the demands of to-morrow. Every practical consideration says that the minimum time and course of study for all the children of all the people is a well-rounded twelfth grade high school that each boy and each girl may meet the demands of the present and the future. This open door of the high school to all will inspire ever increasing numbers of the high school graduates to enter the normal school, the special school, the college and the university. Thus will the boys and girls — the American citizens of to-day and to-morrow — be prepared for our diversified soil, for our religious and political life and for the fields of business and opportunity which are ever open to those who are trained in mind, skilled In hand and regulated in heart. THE INFLUENZA Perhaps the most destructive epidemic which, at any time, has visited the United States is what Is called the Spanish Influenza. Ne - braska has endured her share of the trouble. The toll of death from this destroyer, in all parts of the country, is far greater than from any other epidemic of which we have knowledge. The only thing which is to be compared to the Spanish Influenza in destructiveness is the scourge of diphtheria which appeared sixty or sixty-five years ago in New York, Pennsylvania, Ohio and elsewhere in the eastern part of our country. The diphtheria of that time, in its most malignant form, was confined for the most part to children, while the influenza takes from all classes and particularly persons who seem to be well and strong. This epidemic is mentioned in this Report because of its effect on the teachers and schools. In almost every community in the state, the schools have been closed from one to eight or ten weeks. This has been a serious drawback to the schools of all grades and classes, be - sides the deaths the epidemic has caused among the children and pat- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 REPORT OP STATE SUPERINTENDENT rons of the schools. It has disorganized the schools and crippled the work everywhere. To make up. during the remaining part of the year, the time which has been lost, each district and community must judge for itself the best thing to do. In some places, it may be best for the school day to open from fifteen to twenty minutes earlier than usual; in others, the afternoon session may be made a little longer and in others school may be held Saturday forenoon. It is probable that in all the schools the usual holidays and the spring vacation will be used to redeem a part of the time lost by the enforced vacations. Another phase of the influenza question is a serious one and ought to be taken up by the legislature so that in the future any like oc - currence will not fall so heavily on the teachers. The law in Nebraska is such that the Superintendent has held that when the school is closed by the local or state board of health, the teachers cannot be paid legally for the time lost. While the finding of the court is in harmony with the law, it works a great injustice on the teacher. In many cases it is a real hardship. This matter is called to the atten - tion of the members of both houses of the legislature that the present law may be repealed or amended. Instead of the law we have now, one can be enacted which will enable boards of education to deal with such matters in the spirit of justice and equity. Nearly all boards of educa - tion are disposed to be governed by the principles of right and fairness. If it were legal for them to do so, nearly all boards of education would pay the salary cheerfully. All realize the unequal advantage which can be taken of the teacher and, at the same time, the board of education act in harmony with the law. A new law on this subject would be just to the teacher, in harmony with the desires of nearly all boards of edu - cation, and fair to the people. RURAL-EDUCATION The greatest problem that faces the people of Nebraska to-day is the problem of Rural-Education. It is self-evident that the country boy and girl have not been and are not now properly provided for in their educational needs. The demand for better education knocks at the door of the country boy and girl and the question naturally arises: "What means shall be employed to satisfy this growing demand throughout the state?" The country-child should not be compelled at a tender age to leave home influences to better his condition educa - tionally. To keep these young people on the farm conditions must be changed. The boy and girl must be given an opportunity to satisfy their growing mental desires in their own communities. Back to the farm means education on the farm. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 17 HOT-HOUSE AXD FORCE-PUMP EDUCATION' The child is hurried through many text-books and the eighth grade; (then into college); then into possession of a diploma and then into life. Through this hurried process the child enters the business world with a dazed mind, unfitted and untrained for the work that is before him and a livelihood. This modern intellectual slaughter of the innocent should not go on. It is high time that we put up in our edu - cational system this sign: "Stop, Think — Change." We cannot hope for better conditions educationally as long as the child is thus treated. We are running long on credits and short in accurate thought-power. The child must be surrounded with an educational environment and teaching power strong enough to lead, to direct and to mold properly the growing mind and satisfy the unlimited possibilities of the child. The element of natural growth is pushed aside in our hurry and we must not permit this hut-house and force-pump education to exist but we must substitute in its place true educational and mental de - velopment. "A little learning has always been and Is a dangerous thing." True education means that the child has been taught to use properly its senses and to think. Our present system has shelved these es - sentials. The main object being to get through the eighth grade as quickly as possible, receive full credit, make time, and move on. It is thoroughness, not superficiality, that makes a thinker and counts in this world. Another year's work could be very easily put upon the subjects included in the eighth grade. We have forgotten in our hurry for quick understanding of subject-matter that the great lesson of in - competency is not a lesson of pride. We should not lose sight of the all-important fact, that we as teachers and directors, are responsible for the future manhood and womanhood of this country. We should not put out a product that is not able, because of our leadership, to solve easily and satisfactorily the every-day questions that must be solved by the child in order to make a progressive people. Education is not a question of time, it is a question of mental utility. We need not enrich the course of study through the eighth grade to find interesting work for the child, all that is needed is to give more practical arithmetic, a better understanding of grammar, a deeper in - sight into history, make better spellers, teach more penmanship and common sense capitalization, punctuation and abreviation. Our slo - gan should be not hurry, but thoroughness and the child's future wel - fare. THE AUTOMOBILE, RURAL-DELIVERY AND THE TELEPHONE Are doing their part In the solution of this question. These agencies make city life and country life almost the same, but they have not and will not solve the problem of rural education. The conditions in Nebraska have changed and we dare not expect these hopeful young </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT people In the country to take the same view of life and living as their elders. Rural education must be practical to farm-life and the possi - bilities of acquiring this education must be brought nearer home. The one-unit, two-unit and three-unit school buildings in the country will never satisfy the educational necessities of the country. We must form a larger unit, have a greater working capital and form a close-corpora - tion. EDUCATION A BUSINESS PROPOSITION Education in its final analysis is a business proposition. A com - mercial firm cannot do a big business on a small capital; neither can a school be maintained and give a child that which justly belongs to him without having a sufficient working capital to meet the needs and ideals of these young men and women. It takes money to conduct a good school just the same as it does to conduct a big business enterprise. CONSOLIDATION THE SOLUTION. In order to meet properly these conditions we must have a larger unit for educational purposes, — this means consolidation. By and through consolidation we get a large physical environment and an as - sessed valuation to maintain a good school. We also get a sufficient number of pupils to make the school interesting and to bring about the right Intellectual competition. Consolidation means country independ - ence not dependence. It also means back to the farm and not away from the farm. The course of study must be adapted to country life and country conditions and possess two essential elements, intellectual value and cultural value. There is nothing so binding to young people as the school. It brings about a close-corporation of human interests and un - like many things it does not grow weak with time but strengthens with age. SUMMARY. 1. There are sixty-two consolidations in the state. 2. Fifty-four have been organized in the last two years. 3. The assessed valuation of the consolidations in the state carry a working capital of $12,058,682.00. 4. There are fifty-seven carry-alls, most automobiles. 6. The state is transporting over a thousand students. 6. The largest consolidated unit is in Gage county; this district has eight automobile carry-alls, transporting 176 students. 7. Four of the consolidated schools are taking advantage of the Federal Smith-Hughes Act, and are complying with the Statf Acts, hence they are drawing aid from the Federal Govern &lt; ment as well as the State. 8. Consolidation insures punctuality. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 19 9. Consolidation solves the problem of over-crowded city high schools, by keeping the free high school tuition pupils in the country. 10. Consolidation has caused many young men and women in the country, who have dropped out of school, to resume school work at home. These young people will complete their high - school education in the country and no doubt take up work in some higher institution of learning later. 11. Consolidation has solved the problem of the community cen - ter, which is of untold value. 12. The consolidated schools next year will be doing twelfth grade work. 13. No complaints have come to the office concerning the trans - portation of pupils. Everything is satisfactory. The child leaves home comfortable and reaches the school building comfortable and on time. 14. The consolidated school building, planned by the State De - partment, is a complete unit within itself. It furnishes ample accommodations and provisions for all the grades from the primary through the twelfth. The building has an auditor - ium with a seating capacity of from 350 to 500. It has a nice library, school rooms for all the grades and recitation rooms for the high-school pupils. The industrial work is in the basement for the boys. There is a mechanical drawing room, a manual training room and an agriculture room. These rooms are separated by glass partitions. For the girls they have a sewing room, a Domestic Science room and a dining room. These rooms are separated by glass partitions. In the dining room there is a room for special labratory work and in the agriculture room there is a room for special lab - ratory work. The building is provided with separate rooms for physical and chemical labratories; also a room for special instruction in farm accounts, farm bookkeeping, shorthand 17 These figures and facts speak in favor of the consolidated school. and typewriting. 6. Facts concerning consolidated schools of Gage county: 1. Average salary of superintendents $160.28 2. Average salary of high school teachers 90.00 3. Average salary of grade teachers 71.00 6. Facts concerning city high schools of Gage county: 1. Average salary of city superintendents $148.00 2. Average salary of city high school teachers 84.50 3. Average salary of city grade teachers (6.66 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT </seg>
            <seg id="p021">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 21 All rooms are separated by glass partitions. -1 — - f i .1 ■-•ST--1 ,r: i . ; a 1 E Ear. | . l m »il!v.. K4I A- 4-./-.- asement of Rural School Building showing industrial work includii &gt;r boys, mechanical drawing, manual training and agricultural room &gt;r the girls dressmaking, domestic science and dining rooms, wi boratories connected with agricultural and domestic science room s; s </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT - c c t — 00 o 2 "So 0! - 1 g 53 s s a S 5 EJ I* — M ■ -w - \ 'ilZ ' m 111 \ — 5 1 I - ■ • u B B IS' o .' s o Is at 3° Is I! </seg>
            <seg id="p023">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">2 4 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT E it 222°~ O&lt;=O © © © © OO OOCO-O-OOOO g.g . © o © © o © o © © © © © © ©_ © © © © • o • o o o o 5 &amp; . ooooood© ©o*©*©' ©'©* ©'©'©'©* *©' '©*©'©© "ej. ©©©©©©to.* ©o©o ©5 ©o©5 •© "SS©© i &amp;£ °. » «°. «t •* •* i °. »•**'*. •* * o. us © s : © : © © © S ♦J 57 *«MMMMM« CO « N N c{ c&lt;T n" '. io '. ©' 00 n o»" If « :- : S 55 O i— i H E««i eoooouw • • . • • ~ ■ &lt;e n n ■ a&gt; .00 ■ © }: • ©©©©©00 00 1-Mt- ■!• .00 -O rSz" S "2 " 2 S 2 "° • • • ■ ■ • . &gt;«« o "osio •» ;;&amp;l o«»oet-» , .I.. I! &gt;hh e 'na 'w g™ « eq n M n rt rt *ooci i •• ! «V i «a* Sg] * ::::::: ! , ! :5 i— i . • ©©©©©©©© c:©©© ©• ©©©©.©;©©•© °rl °. 0 . 0 . 0 . 0 . 0 . 0 . 0 . °. °. °. °. °. • °. °. ® °. - °. ' °. °. " °. §;• ©©©©©'©'©© ©©©*©' © * ©'©'©'©' *©* *©'© ■© &lt;" ©©©e©te©&lt;N ©o©© ©• no©© •©•©©•« • © &lt;e w &lt;c ■* r- © m &lt;c ■* •♦ ■» « 1 «:ioo , © ; © © ; n ";©5 -*C0CCr?NNMr-( « N N N Cl • H t-* O P5 &gt;0C •©*©* •« ■ •* . — ■ - . 1: :i . 1. ti • • 1-1 ■ • &lt;M 2* " ■ *• . « E S 2 S ' 2 ° ' ' w«©rtt-©oo.o&gt; Si . °. °. ; °. °. ; ■ .... ■ . ' '»«oi-oosn -m 3 5 ?£' !°e ! ! III! '. '. ' ' &lt;n to © oi eo i-&lt; t-&lt; " n s£&gt;- 222 ■!:" ■ • »»o«nM» ,0 '5T ©^cD5c.co«o -# .... . n u) v a n ao « a g™2 ■»«» -Nh ." .".n^rtV ua . V J5«S • •• *l «• 1H . &lt;H u s "■ •• - iti 222 '?° • ' ©©©©©©©.© 't ©©©■©©•• ©©©©©©©.© &amp;s 2 2 2 ■ 2 ° • ■ : : : : : : ::«"©©©"©■©©■• ©' &lt;s 222 •°°° • • .. .. ©©©©©©©■» °. " "i. ■ t * . . . . . ! . ; ; ; ■«■ » » © © © ; « — J I "•• CO CO • N &gt;-t" • • .... . . •• io" « r-" IO rt ©"©"■©" ■r© * *" .... .. .. n id n • n i\ " ■ ■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■■ - =5 • ■*-» ... ..I, — 4 -5 : • i : : : : : J : : C : : lijtijijiiiilyiilliiH^iii! •S % &amp;£^fe g g g |iaS"' g ° § B -SS Ml! a*- ■3 a * « « 13 a « « S-3-3-3 a'S " * S S § o|S2S </seg>
            <seg id="p025">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 25 RURAL SCHOOLS Much needs to be done for the rural school before it ran be said that it approaches the ideal as an educational agency. The increase in the value of lands and greater returns for the productions of the farm, enables the rural community to provide far better things in the future. This ability and progress is seen already in the stock, farm homes, roads and means of travel. As these things are improved, many fathers and mothers in the state are asking and planning for better educational advantages for their children. In all parts of Nebraska, improve - ment Is desired by all citizens. The reconstruction movements, as fax as they have developed, include the educational needs and changes. This is significant because it indicates a growing appreciation of the school in its varied activities and relations. Consolidation and stand - ardization which are set out in another part of this report, are the solu - tions in part of many of the problems of rural education. THE ELEMENTARY SCHOOLS The elementary schools of the state are represented by two classes of schools. One class is made up of rural schools (see page ) and the other of the eight grades in the town, village and city schools. The elementary schools in Nebraska which are found in the towns, villages and cities have made great progress during recent years. The gain has been threefold: (1) In the qualifications of the teachers; (2) In the new and Improved school buildings and equipment; and (3) in the interest and cooperation of the patrons of the district and the citizens of the community. The very distinct public sentiment In favor of education, the desire of parents to see their children enjoy the advantages for which they help to pay, the marked influence of the normal schools and colleges in the state and the accumulated means in the hands of fathers and mothers stimulate many young men and women to attend institutions of higher education. This, in turn, has a most marked effect on all classes of people and especially on teachers. Nowhere is this more marked than in the scholastic attain - ments, the professional skill and the educational spirit of those who teach in the grades. While there may be some persons in the state who still think that anyone can teach a child In the first grade how to read; in the fifth, or sixth, how to pass the final tests in arithmetic and geography; and in the seventh and eighth how to know civics and history, the superintendents and boards of education are constantly making an effort to find for all the grades those who have gathered intellectual treasures and whose lives have been enriched by contact with the world outside the home. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT ) I Boards of education have come to appreciate the teacher and the skill necessary to guide the steps of those who are trying to find their place in the woild of letters and in the world about them. The elemen - tary schools of Nebraska owe much to the members of the boards of education and to their superintendents, and also, to the patrons. But, most of all, the people owe a debt to the faithful teachers who have worked for the children committed to their care and tuition. Progress is indicated likewise, by the improved school buildings and heating ap - paratus, by the added maps and charts, by the superior text-books of these modern days, and by the beginnings of libraries adapted to the pupils in the grades. Equally gratifying and even more valuable is the interest shown by the fathers and mothers and by many other persons who come within the circle of child life and under the influence of the subjects taught. As time advances, it means a greater cooperation of the home with the school and a greater reliance of the school on the home. This means a greater influence for good in the elementary school and. through it, on the community than anywhere else in the educational system. Changing conditions in the social order are having a marked in - fluence on the ranks of the teachers and nowhere is it more distinctly seen than among the teachers who are in the grades and specially those who have charge of pupils in the fifth, sixth, seventh and eighth grades. The changes in the social order involve the compensation of those in the teaching profession as well as on the farm, in the store, at the desk, in railway employ, in the trades and industries and wher - ever men and women are employed. During recent years there has been an increase in teachers' salaries but not anything in comparison with the added cost of room and boarding and other necessary expense. As a rule, the hardship falls more heavily on those in the grades than in the kindergarten and primary, or in the high school. When a good well qualified teacher in the sixth, seventh or eighth grade resigns to take a place in some business house or in some governmnt position, it is almost a tragedy in the mental, moral and spiritual lives of the boys and girls left in the room out from which she has gone. Not only is it the best that turns aside to some other kind of employment, but it is the better and the best in a majority of cases. Others of course will be found to take yieir places and in time they will be among the better and after a while be numbered among the best. But, in the meantime the average of teaching ability and practice has been lowered and the lives of the children will be distinctly different from that which they would have been had not teacher No. 1 felt compelled to look for a position which would yield larger returns now and promise greater results in the future. In many ways, teaching has its returns and its rewards independent of the salary and they are of a character which make teaching, for those who are adapted to it, very enjoyable. These, however rich and valuable, do not help to make ends meet in the pres- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 27 ent and do not provide for the necessities of the future. While this plea for an increase in salary is made for the teachers in the grades. It applies to every teacher of every class and kind who is not receiving a fair share of the prosperity of the community where the work Is done. RURAL HIGH SCHOOLS The rural high schools in the state are supported either by the County as a unit, or by the people of a limited territory. The purpose is the same. They have been authorized by law, and they are main - tained to furnish high school education to those who live outside of the towns, villages and cities. As rapidly as it can be done, these ought to be increased until there is not a boy or girl of high school age in Nebraska who may not have the instruction, guidance and inspiration of a well equipped high school. These schools, like every other educa - tional agency, ought to be adapted to the varied abilities and desires of the communities in which they are established. In all of them, there ought to be the foundation subjects; good courses in algebra, plane geometry, English language and literature, physical and commercial geography, history and civics, physics and chemistry, mechanical draw - ing and normal training, agriculture and home economics. In addi - tion to the foregoing, let instruction in such other subjects as each community needs and suggests, be provided. By such a plan, each pupil would be able to make an honest living in the neighborhood where his education was obtained or in some other to which he might go and be a valuable and respected citizen of the commonwealth, where ever his lot might be cast. The biennial period upon which we are about to enter ought to see many of these rural high schools added to the list of those already established. THOROUGHNESS IX THK COMMON BRANCHES The past two years the slogan of this department has been "Thor - oughness In the Common Branches." We hold that the work of the eight grades serves as a foundation for higher work. Then if the child does not go to high school or col - lege, he has a working knowledge of common subjects. Only about five per cent of our children enter high school. A majority of those who do enter high school receive their first eight years training in the rural schools. Because Nebraska is an agricultural state, this will con - tinue to be true. It behooves the teachers in rural, town and city schools, county and city superintendents to join the campaign for "Thor - oughness in the Common Branches." in all our schools. This department has devoted practically all the time in the past two years in co-operation with county superintendents trying to make the work of the rural school so attractive through Standardization, Consoli- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT dation and General Community Work that boys and girls really have a desire to complete the eighth grade. Our thought is that if we give them eight years of practical work and they do it efficiently and they are really interested in school and school work they will not be satis - fied until they have had more and higher training. Webster. Polk, Merrick, Pawnee, Scotts Bluff, Hamilton. Franklin, Harlan, Clay, Nance, Richardson. Adams. Banner, Boone, Boyd, Buf - falo, Butler. Cass. Chase, Cherry, Colfax, Cuming, Custer, Dodge, Dundy Gage, Holt. Howard, Jefferson, Kearney. Keith, Lincoln, Loup, Madison, Nemaha, Pheli*, Pierce, Saline. Seward, Thayer and Washington coun - ties have all joined the campaign for ' Thoroughness in the Common Branches." Other counties may be working along this line that have not reported to the State Department. SCHOOI.-1MPKOVKMKXTS KMI'HASIZKO In the next two years, we shall strive not only for this, but also, we shall give special attention to those who are too old for the eighth grade and who are dropping out of school for ti'is reason. Some of the principles that have been incorporated into our schedule for rural schools are: Consolidation. Standardization. Clear-cut teaching. Play Apparatus. Correct Seating, Heating, Lighting, Ventilating. Adequate Reference Library. Community Work. Our ideal of Community Work is set forth in the words of William McKinley: "An open schoolhouse, free to all is an evidence of the highest types of advanced civilization. It is the gateway to progress, prosperity and honor and the best security for the liberties and independence of the people. It is the strongest rock of the foundation, the most en - during rock of the temple of liberty, our surest stay in every storm, our present safety, our future hope, aye, the very citadel of our influence and power. It is better than garrisons and guns, than forts or fleets." "An educated people governed by true moral prin - ciples can never take a backward step nor be dispossessed of their true citizenship and liberties." </seg>
            <seg id="p029">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 29 SUGGESTIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS A school is up to the standard if it is housed in a sanitary and properly located building, if well heated and lighted, if well ventilated, if supplied with good texts, pictures and a growing library, and if in charge of a well qualified teacher. Such a school and equipment give the country boy and girl opportunities equal to their cousins in the city. The state aid ought to be great enough to enable the State Superintend - ent to assist districts which are striving to reach the highest efficiency. The County Superintendent can do much if in possession of the mean* and if inspired by the co-operation of the people. Nance County had a special day last year when all the schools had a program bearing on the subject of proper standards. By some such means, pupils, patrons and teachers find what the conditions are, find what they are doing and what is to be done to reach the desired results. By the co-operation of one with the other, the school leads the community and the community in - spires the school. Each is a force in promoting the welfare of the other and together they advance the intelligence and civilization of both. STATE EDUCATIONAL EXHIBIT The Nebraska State Fair is strictly an educational organization. Although 12,000 feet of space was covered with school exhibits in Ag - ricultural Hall, the past two years, a great deal of the material could not be displayed for lack of space. This year some special features were introduced as follows: Penmanship A special display of the best penmanship from all grades from some of the best schools in the state was made. It was collected and displayed as a standard of what good penmanship should be in the vari - ous grades and high school. This proved an attractive exhibit for county superintendents and teachers. Lincoln City Schools — Red Cross Work The Lincoln City Schools had a booth representing a standard for Red Cross Work. Supt. Newlon had charge of the Red Cross work for Lancaster County, and the booth really represented the work of the city and county which had been done under his supervision. This was attractive to many from other Red Cross Chapters who were anxious to get new ideas, and also to the general public. Pern State Normal School Peru State Normal School had moving pictures of Peru and sur - roundings and of the activities of the school. This booth was crowded from morning until night with people who were interested In the lec - tures by Prof. Deliell and Prof. Jean, and the beauties of "Old Peru" in pictures. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Kearney State Normal School Kearney State Normal School bad a rest booth which proved very attractive. Prof. Etta Brown or Prof. John Stryker entertained their guests with kodak pictures of Kearney and surroundings and the activ - ities of the school. Art Exhibit Probably the finest exhibit of Public School Art work that has ever been made anywhere was made by the Prang Art Company. It was col - lected from the schools doing the best art work from almost every state. It was a fine standard for Art work in our rural schools and teachers profited by it. Coiutolklated School Picture* Pictures of the consolidated school houses and of the districts were an attractive feature from Gage County. This is one of the counties that leads in the number of its consolidated schools. General Exhibit The general exhibit was of a high standard, and gave evidence that the boys and girls in the rural schools only need a chance to become skilled workmen, efficient men and women. In 1917 Thayer and Rich - ardson counties carried off first premium for County Exhibit, Kearney and University Place first for City Exhibit, and Bennet and Nehawka first for town exhibit. In 1917, Polk county won first premium for the county, Kearney won the first premium for the city, and Stromsburg won the first premium for the town. HOYS' AND i.llll s CIA'B WORK AT THE STATE FAIR Boys' and Girls' Club work over the state has been well represented at the State Pair for three years. In 1916 and 1917 different clubs sent garden and canned products which were placed on exhibit back of the demonstration booths in Agricultural Hall. The individual and club premiums which were given, stimulated a great deal of interest In the exhibit among both the boys and girls and the club leaders. In 1918 an exhibit was required of each of the teams competing and the emphasis was placed on the club rather than the individual exhibit. The differ - ent teams which competed during fair week, canned about 60 jars of fruits and vegetables at the fair and these were also exhibited. The canning demonstrations put on by Junior teams proved a very successful part of our State Fair exhibit because they are "live exhibits." The teams were not only demonstrating Cold-Pack canning but they were competing for the state championship and this contest spirit encouraged them to do the very best work possible. Continuous </seg>
            <seg id="p031">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 31 demonstrations were put on, in the exhibit booth each day of the fair and the teams succeeded splendidly in holding their crowds. Several counties and cities over the state held preliminary contests and selected the best team to send to the state contest. The following teams competed for state championship in 1918: Lincoln County, Clay County, Scottsbluff County. Fillmore County, Lincoln City, Omaha City, Omaha City (Colored), Kearney City and University Place. The University Place club won state championship honors and a free trip to the Interstate Fair at Sioux City, Iowa, where they won for Nebraska the Interstate Championship. The Sioux City contest was participated in by teams from the following ten states: Iowa, South Dakota, North Dakota, Kansas, Missouri, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Illinois, Wyom - ing and Nebraska. The members of Nebraska's team demonstrated so skillfully that Mr. O. H. Benson. National Boys' and Girls' Club Leader, invited them to demonstrate before the national club leaders' associa - tion at Washington, D. C, in February. The demonstrations which were carried on at the county fairs, as well as at the State Fair were a means of teaching thousands of people how to successfully can surplus fruits and vegetables. They also in - terested many people in the Boys' and Girls' Club work carried on by the Junior Extension Service of the State University, co-operating with the U. S. Dept. of Agriculture. Canning is only one of the activities car - ried on for the Boys and Girls of the State. All of the various clubs en - couraged production and conservation which helped our State and Na - tion in its crisis and also taught the club members valuable lessons in industry, thrift, co-operation and patriotism. We hope to carry out our club motto, "Make The Best Better," in 1919, and help more Boys and Girls in Nebraska live up to our conservation pledge which is: "I consecrate my head, heart, hands and health, through food pro - duction and food conservation to help re-establish a world-peace." ACCREDITED SCHOOLS The University of Nebraska maintains two lists of accredited schools, a four-year list and a junior list. The graduates of the four - year list are admitted to the University (and to nearly all of the col - leges and universities of the United States) without entrance exami - nations in subjects that are properly certified as completed within these schools. Unless a graduate of an accredited school, a candidate for admission must be prepared to take examination in those subject! in which he desires entrance credits. "Accredited" schools are such as, under annual inspection by the University inspector of accredited schools, are found to have a well - balanced program of studies, satisfactory laboratory equipment and library facilities, and a teaching force adequate in number and com - petent in scholarship and professional training to accomplish the work </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT they are undertaking. This list of accredited schools is published yearly in the University Calendar, the University Journal, and the High School Manual. Any public or private high school or academy desiring to be placed on the accredited list should make request to the In - spector of accredited schools. The High School Manual, giving detailed Information in regard to accredited schools, including general and departmental suggestions as to courses of study and methods of in - struction, and the list of accredited schools, is sent upon application to the registrar of the University of Nebraska. Certificates of graduation from schools which are members of the North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools and of Accrediting Associations of equal rank will entitle the holder to admission without examination. An "Approved" high school is a high school which has had its work, equipment and condition inspected by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction and the high school is given a rank which enables it to receive pupils from districts other than its own, and to collect therefor free high school tuition for instruction of such pupils. The free high school tuition, in such cases, is paid by the school district from which the pupils are sent. 1. The University of Nebraska accredits. 2. The State Superintendent approves. STANDARD OF ACCREDITED SCHOOLS Every business and all institutions of whatever kind require a unit of measure and a goal to be reached If they are to be successful in their undertakings. If a goal is to be reached we must go toward it and if we work intelligently we must measure our rate of pro - gress, as well as keep in the right direction. This explains the need for standards no matter in what we may be engaged. All experience tends to prove that this is as true of the teacher and the school as of anything else. Not only are these things true, but we are constantly erecting guide-boards and using various standards. This gives the reason for introducing "Standards of Accredited Schools," into the report. They are as follows: 1. Not less than thirty units required for graduation 2. The minimum academic and professional preparation of teach - ers equivalent to four years beyond a four-year high-school course. In determining this equivalence, two years of experience In grammar grades or secondary schools to be considered equivalent to one year of higher preparation. 3. Not to exceed six daily recitations for each teacher. 4. Laboratory and library facilities adequate to the needs of instruction in the subjects taught. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 33 5. The location and construction of the buildings, the lighting, heating and ventilation of the rooms, the nature of the laboratories, corridors, closets, water supply, school furniture, apparatus and math - ods of cleaning such as to insure hygienic conditions for both pupils and teachers. 6. Efficiency of instruction, acquired habits of thought and study, general Intellectual and moral tone of the school evidenced by in - spection. 7. At least three instructors giving entire time to secondary subjects. SOME ADVANTAGES OP ACCREDITMENT Admission without examination to the University of Nebraska and nearly every college in the United States. Guidance in framing and steadying the program of studies and such groups as may be advisable. Expert assistance in selecting apparatus, texts and reference books. Annual Inspection of school and, when desired, a confidential re - port to the school board. Public recognition of the excellence of the school by publication of the list each year in the University of Nebraska Calendar and In the University Journal. Eligibility for recognition by the State Department of Public In - struction as Normal Training high schools and as Agricultural high schools under the Shumway Act. ACCREDITED SCHOOLS 1917 1918 Group A, 126 Pour-Year Schools. This group consists of schools that are accredited to the North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, and such other schools as meet the above standards: Group B, 168 Four-Year Schools. Schools fully accredited but not meeting fully the standards men - tioned above as to the preparation of the teaching staff or laboratory and library facilities: Group O, 44 Four-Year Schools. The graduates of this group may receive 28 points on credentials from their schools, giving them conditional admission to college or university. Additional credits may be secured by examination. 27 Junior Accredited Schools. The graduates of these schools may receive conditional admission to the university upon the completion of sufficient additional work in an accredited school to secure the minimum of 28 points. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT HIGH SCHOOL INSPECTION There are two methods of high school inspection in the United States. One of these is by the university of the state and the other by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction. In both cases the work of Inspection is done by persons appointed by the authorities of the university or by the State Department of Education. The principle is the same. That is, the task of the inspector is to find whether or not the high schools are measuring up to certain ideal, or prescribed standard. Where the inspection is done by the university, as in Nebraska, the purpose is to know whether or not a given high school is meeting in extent and quality of work that which is required for entrance to the freshman class without examination. In rases of this kind, the university appoints the inspector, erects the standards, and determines, through its inspector, whether or not, the work in extent and spirit, in method and quality can be approved. In such cases, in a sense and to a certain definite extent the university determines the courses of study and the standards of advancement. If the rules of the univer - sity are cast in a fixed and definite mold and no room is left for in - dividual choice, the ability to enter the freshman class is the goal, and the only goal in the mind of the student. In such a case the judg - ment, power and direction of one institution determine what may and may not be taught in the high schools and what standards of measure may be employed. In Nebraska this hard and fast line — this inflexible order — and this one line of advancement are avoided by permitting a large number of equivalents, by allowing the individual high school to make certain election and by clothing the inspector with much dis - cretionary power and authority. In other states the inspection of the high schools is vested in the office of the State Superintendent. This is the case for all high schools and courses of study as well as for normal training and the issuing of certificates for teachers. Where this is the method the state is, not only, the unit, but also, the power which may authorize any high school to offer any course or courses of study which the needs of the community may indicate. Where this method is followed, the office of the State Superintendent, through the inspectors, evaluates the work done. The work done in a particular high school, according to this method, may or may not relate to any special course of study outside of the high school in which it is taken. It is readily seen that these two methods are different — not an - tagonistic. They reach different ends or goals when carried to comple - tion. The merits of the first are ( 1 ) oneness of aim, ( 2 ) a large meas - ure of uniformity among the high schools of a given state, and (3) practically one goal to reach after the high school course is completed — namely, the freshman class of the university. The merits of the sec- </seg>
            <seg id="p035">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 35 ond method are greater flexibility in the courses of study of the high schools, (2) larger opportunity for individual choice, and (3) greater variety and number of goals which may be reached through the agency of the high school. HIOH SCHOOL REPORT, 1918-1919 General Statement. Number of high schools 563 Number of teachers in high school 2077 Number of students in high school (estimated) 36000 Average salary of high school teachers $85.90 Normal Training Number of normal training high schools 219 Number of teachers in normal training high schools 1438 Number of normal training students 3977 Number of normal training students from country 1917-18 2115 Number of normal training students from town 1917-18 2078 Physical valuation of normal training high schools $4,354,379 Average number of mills levied in normal training high schools 35 Summary Number of city schools 93 Number of rural schools 7125 Number of consolidated schools 62 REQUIREMENTS FOR HIGH SCHOOL APPROVAL 1. Number of teachers required in high school department: (a) One teacher for two grades. (b) Two teachers for three grades. (c) Three teachers for four grades. 2. Recitation periods shall be: (a) Forty minutes. (b) Thirty minutes if classes are small. 3. Course of study: The course outlined in Nebraska High School Manual. 4. School year: Nine months. 5. Qualifications of teachers: (a) Graduate of a university, college or advanced course of an approved normal school, or holder of a Nebraska Professional Certificate. t. Laboratories must have sufficient equipment. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT NORMAL TRAINING IN THE HIGH SCHOOLS While normal training in the public high schools in Nebraska had its beginning less than fifteen years ago, it has accomplished much. Our state had the advantage of the experience of some of the older states. This is especially the case with New York (where it had been given a trial more than fifty years before the attempt was made in Nebraska.) The classes maintained in the academies and high schools were in charge of the Board of Regents of New York until 1889. The board by voluntary action desired to turn the management over to the State Superintendent of Public Instruction. The legislature provided by law for this change in control. The commendations of Dr. William T. Har - ris, Commissioner of Education for the United States, and Hon. Andrew S. Draper, Commissioner of Education for the State of New York, came to the attention of Hon. W. K. Fowler while he was State School Sup - erintendent. In his report to the Governor and legislature, he recom - mended that normal training in the high schools be authorized by law. This was done by the passage of House Roll by Jenison of Clay County during the session of 1905. The bill provided for normal training in the Junior and senior years of approved schools to be selected by the State School Superin - tendent which must be accredited to the University of Nebraska and must employ at least two teachers exclusive of the city superintendent whose entire time is given to instruction in high school branches. The bill carried an appropriation with which to carry out the act and limit - ed the amount paid to any one school to aid in the normal training to $700 for the biennium. The bill was commended in its plan and details by President J. W. Crabtree, who was President of the State Normal School at Peru at the time, by Prof. W. R. Hart, of the department of education in the Normal School and A. A. Reed, Inspector of High Schools for the University of Nebraska. By the terms of the law, the State School Superintendent designates the high schools and has control of the general policy of the courses of instruction. The law which authorized the training of those who desired to teach requires the State Superintendent to be governed by seven specific particulars: (1) The high school must be accredited; (2) Two teachers, exclusive of city superintendent must devote all their time to instruction in high school subjects; (3) The training which the law authorized must be given in the eleventh and twelfth grades; (4) The course in training shall be elective; (5) There must be a library covering the history of education, principles of education, methods, and special training in in - dustrial education and agriculture; </seg>
            <seg id="p037">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 37 (6) Those in training must take agriculture; the classes formed must have at least ten students and each must continue under instruction at least eighteen weeks; and (7) The State Aid shall be $700 for the biennlum. The law required that the review studies should be continued at least nine weeks and that the professional training should Include obser - vation, school management and studies In methods of instruction. The Hon. J. L. McBrien, who was State Superintendent at the time, took great interest In the bill and in Its provisions. In recommending that normal training be taken up In certain high schools in Nebraska, State Supt. W. K. Fowler, among other things, said: "The imiasion of the training class is to provide the rural schools, that are not in a position to engage normal graduates, with at least a year of special preparation — largely in professional work. The province of the normal school and the province of the training class are. therefore, clear and distinct. The two are sup - plementary agencies and are not to be regarded in any sense as rivals. I am of the opinion that many training class graduates, after teaching a few years, will be enabled to complete a course of study In a normal school, a step impracticable before they gain a foothold from the training class. The normal school proper can - not supply the demand for teachers In the country districts. More - over, the graduate from the advanced normal course is, as a rule. beyond their reach, owing to the financial condition of a large majority of the rural school districts. The training class is the only means of providing trained teachers for the country schools." About the same time Michigan (1903), Minnesota and Kansas put into practice the normal training on the plan of the State of New York. Andrew S. Draper, Commissioner of Education for the State of New York, in his annual report for 1906 says: "The most fruitful if not the most hopeful source of good teachers for the district schools is found in the training classes. It is confidently believed that the agency for providing teachers for the rural schools will be ever increasing in its efficiency." The progress made during the first years of trial is Indicated by a paragraph in the report of I. A. Downey, as inspector, for 1907. He •ays: "We have now passed a mile stone in the history of normal training in the high schools of Nebraska. During this time we have been blazing the way through the forests, guided only by the </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT accumulated moss or necessity and the ever shining star of hope. That we would make mistakes was expected. That we have made them is now certain, but we are gratified to know that to a certain degree we have reached the clearing of accomplishment and fruition. There are many problems yet to be solved but, with the continued hearty cooperation of the educational forces of the state, we confidently believe that we will soon be able to put high school normal training upon such a basis as to make it a permanent part of our educational system. It is patent to those who understand the purpose, appreciate the popularity and have watched the pro - gress of this movement that it has come to stay. It should no longer be regarded as a temporary makeshift but rather as a use - ful and necessary department of the educational system which is making such marked progress in this commonwealth." The experience under the law of 1905 enabled the legislature to embody the improvement found in the statute of 1907. The advant - ages of the law were tested by requiring that all persons who desired to teach on a first or second grade certificate after September 1, 1907 must have had a certain amount of professional training. The law of 1905 did not require any inspection and contained certain other defects. These defects were corrected by the law of 1907. Under the provisions of the act of 1907, sixty-eight high schools and six academies were recognized by the State Department of Public Instruction as equipped to do normal training. In the schools recognized for the school year 1907-8 there were enrolled 640 seniors and 573 juniors. 448 seniors completed the normal training course. June 1, 1908, 550 were grad - uated from 65 normal training high schools. During the school year 1909, 98 schools graduated 763 and in 1910, 109 schools graduated 894. This elective course in the high schools for those who intend to teach has given them the opportunity to become more or less acquainted with agriculture, manual training end domestic science. This in turn has opened the way for cooking, sewing, raising and testing corn, cul - tivation of potatoes and other garden products. These things have brought the home life into the school and the school life into the home and thus fathers and mothers have become interested in the life and education of the boys and girls of the community in ways and to an extent far more general than was the case forty or fifty years ago. O. A. Gregory of Crete, who became inspector of normal training in the high schools December 1, 1909, says in his report to the State Department of Public Instruction: "These valuable results from normal training have been secured to the public with a very moderate amount of state aid. The average expense to the state per pupil graduating from the </seg>
            <seg id="p039">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 39 normal training class is less than $50. This, compared with the ex - pense of graduating pupils from a regular state normal, Is signific - ant. New York pays $500 per pupil graduating from her state nor - mals. Better results can be secured in our state by requiring more thorough preparation of normal training pupils, but since the work is done for the good of the state an appropriation of not less than $500 per year should be made to help defray the extra expense involved." The number of graduates reported from the normal training courses in 1912 was 1002. The enrollment of students in these classes for the school year 1913-14 was 3850. So far as we have been able to find the graduates for 1911 and for 1913 are not given in any of the reports. The city superintendents and teachers in reply to questions sent from the State Department of Public Instruction agree that the gen - eral results on the high school of the introduction of normal training subjects and classes can be put thus: (1) Improvement in the discipline of the high school; (2) Higher ideals of life and duty prevail among the students; (3) Better attitude toward the school authorities and manage - ment; (4) Greater respect for the aims, wishes and efforts of the teachers; (5) Greater devotion to study; and (6) Deeper interest in the welfare of the school and the good name of the community. These six things are worth all the cost if nothing more veie ac - complished. The following classification shows the conditions in the state: Seven counties have NO normal training schools. Twenty-three counties have ONE normal training school. Twenty-five counties have TWO normal training schools. Fourteen counties have THREE normal training schools. Sixteen counties have FOUR normal training schools. Four counties have FIVE normal training schools. One county has SIX normal training schools. One county has SEVEN normal training schools. A total of 219 schools making application for normal training 1918-19. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Sl'GGESTED COURSE OF STUDY FOR NORMAL TRAINING HIGH SCHOOLS 1918-1910 NINTH GRADE First Semester Periods First Semester Periods Second Semester Periods Second Semester Periods Algebra 5 Algebra 5 Algebra 5 Algebra S English and Bookkeeping 5 English and Bookkeeping 5 English 5 English 5 General Science, Physical Geog - raphy or Agriculture 5 General Science, Physical Geog - raphy or Agriculture 5 General Science, Physical Geog - raphy or Agriculture 5 General Science, Physical Geog - raphy or Agriculture 5 •Latin 5 •Latin 5 Latin 6 Latin 6 'Manual Training or Domes - tic Science ..._ 5 •Manual Training or Domes - tic Science ..._ 5 Manual Training or Domestic Science ..._ 5 Manual Training or Domestic Science ..._ 5 Bookkeeping 6 Bookkeeping 6 English includes composition, rhetoric and literature. •These subjects may be given in the 10th grade. TENTH GRADE First Semester Periods First Semester Periods Second Semester Periods Second Semester Periods Plane Geometry 5 Plane Geometry 5 Plane Geometry 6 Plane Geometry 6 Ancient History 6 Ancient History 6 Ancient History 5 Ancient History 5 Botany 5 English S English S Botany 5 Latin ! 5 Latin 6 Latin 5 Latin 5 Manual Training, Home Econ - omics or Soils and Field Crops ....;. 5 Manual Training, Home Econ - omics or Soils and Field Crops ....;. 5 Manual Training, Home Econ - omics or Animal Husbandry and Dairying 5 Manual Training, Home Econ - omics or Animal Husbandry and Dairying 5 ELEVENTH GRADE Second Semester Periods First Semester Periods First Semester Periods Second Semester Periods Solid Geometry 5 Solid Geometry 5 Algebra _ 5 Algebra _ 5 English 5 English 5 English 6 English 5 Physics 6 Physics 6 Physics _ 5 Physics _ 5 Cicero S Cicero K Cicero K Cicero S Arithmetic — 18 weeks S Arithmetic — 18 weeks 5 Geography — 12 weeks 5 Geography — 12 weeks 5 Mental Arithmetic — 6 weeks.... 5 Mental Arithmetic — 6 weeks.... 5 Orthography — B weeks 5 Orthography — B weeks 5 Medieval History 5 Medieval History 5 Modern History 5 Modern History 5 Drill Subjects: Drawing and Penmanship 5 Drill Subjects: Drawing and Penmanship 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 41 Subjects in black faced type REQUIRED. Full credit will be giv - en for all subjects except drill subjects. HIGH SCHOOL NORMAL TRAINING ENROLLMENT The enrollment for 1917-18 was seniors 1987, juniors 2206, total 4193. Enrollment for 1918-19 was seniors 1862, juniors 2104, total 3966. The number of schools which received aid in 1917 was 142; in 1918,151. The number of schools which applied in 1918 was 219. The number of students enrolled 1917-18 whose homes are in the coun - try was 2115. The number whose homes are In town, village and city was 2078. This difference of 37 between the total who live in the country and those who live in town has a two-fold significance: (1) It shows the large number of boys and girls of high school age living in the country who are brought under the influence and in - struction of the high school by the drawing power of normal training, and (2) The fact that they come in from their communities to se - cure the advantages of the high school and especially the normal train - ing and then go back to the rural schools to teach with an interest, an equipment, an outlook and a vision which, for the greater part of them, could not have been secured In any other way. The work done by the superintendents and teachers in the high schools to make the normal training a success and to make every dol - lar appropriated by the state to do all that one hundred cents can do are worthy of the fullest appreciation by the people of the state. Equally important and worthy have been the inspection, study, di - rection and suggestions of those who have been commissioned by the State Department of Public Instruction to have direct charge of the normal training. n uxvauei First Semester Periods Second Semester Periods United State* History 5 United States History 5 English 5 Methods and Observation 5 Physiology 6 Virgil 5 Chemistry 5 Reading — 12 weeks l 6 Virgil _ 6 Primary Reading Methods — 6 Rural School .Management 5 weeks 5 Grammar — 12 weeks 5 Civics 5 Composition — 6 weeks 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT SHUMWAY ACT At no time in the history of Nebraska have the people been so in - tensely interested in agricultural education as they are at the present time. The need (or greater industrial efficiency in America, is apparent. That the people are becoming keenly alive to this question and to the need of readjustment of education to meet the industrial demands of the times is attested by the many inquiries coming to the office of state superintendent. The opportunity for agricultural education should be carried through the high school, with the elective courses, finding a place alongside the other subjects in the course. The teaching should be very concrete and practical and should bring the pupils into working toucn not alone with the production of crops and animals but with the business and social life of rural people, as related to the business and social life of the nation as a whole. Fundamentally, it is the province of agricultural education to help solve the rural problem. The rural problem is a question of securing better farm practice, better organization, better farm business, bet - ter school facilities, and the development of a better farm life. Nebraska is a great state and has wonderful agricultural possibil - ities. These possibilities are as yet but partially realized. While the legislature has made provisions for the teaching of agriculture, manual training and home economics, the state has been slow to take advant - age of these provisions. The passage of the Smith-Hughes Bill (See Page ), by Congress, has had the effect of causing the people to realize more fully the advantages that may be had under what is known as the Shumway Act. This act provides for the teaching of ag - riculture, manual training and home economics in "any high school accredited to the State University, consolidated rural high school, rural high school, or county high school having satisfactory rooms and equipment." It also provides that these schools "shall receive state aid not exceeding $1,260 per year." In the second part of the act, it provides that those schools ac - credited to the State University shall provide an approved course in normal training for preparing teachers for rural schools. In the third part of the act, it provides that consolidated rural high schools, rural high schools and county high schools may qualify under this act though they may not meet the requirements set for ac - creditment to the State University, and also provides that until such schools can fully meet the requirements of accreditment they may re - ceive not to exceed $625 per year. Agricultural education has just secured a foothold in this state and the time is ripe for a rapid extension of Industrial education in those schools that are equipped to take advantage of the provisions of this act. The indications are that there will be more applications for </seg>
            <seg id="p043">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 43 recognition under this act than the appropriation asked for will war - rant the approval. In order that we may have a better understanding of the law, it is quoted In full. Section 142a. AGRICULTURAL HIGH SCHOOLS. — Any high school accredited to the State University, consolidated rural high school, rural high school, or county high school having satisfactory rooms and equipment, and having shown itself fitted by location and otherwise to give training in agriculture, manual training, and home economics, may, upon application to the State Superintendent of Pub - lic Instruction of this state, be designated by him to maintain an ag - ricultural and industrial department to consist of courses in agricul - ture, manual training, and home economics. Section 142b. Each such school shall employ a trained instruct - or or instructors whose qualifications shall be fixed by said State Sup - erintendent of Public Instruction, in agriculture, manual training, and home economics. Each school shall have connected with it a tract of land, suitable for purposes of experiment and demonstration, contain - ing not less than five acres, which must be furnished by the school re - ceiving such aid, and be located within the school district or within two miles of the central buildings of the school district. Section 142c. Instruction in such agricultural and industrial de - partment shall be free to all residents of school age within the dis - trict. Non-resident pupils may attend such high schools in accord - ance with the law, rules and regulations governing free high school at - tendance. When necessary to accommodate a reasonable number of boys and girls, who wish to attend only in the winter months, special classes shall be formed for them. AFFILIATED SCHOOLS Any rural school district which shall give instruction in agricul - ture, manual training and home economics in accordance with rules and regulations of the State Superintendent of Public Instruction and shall under this act become associated with a high school accredited to the State University, consolidated rural high school, rural high school, county high school or any educational institution maintained by the state, which gives instruction in agriculture, manual training, and home economics equal to that required of the accredited high schools receiv - ing aid under this act in conformity with the rules and regulations made by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction, shall receive as state aid $50.00 per year. Such state aid to said associated rural school shall be granted only upon the recommendation of the superintendent of the central school with which said rural school is associated in addition to the recommendation of the county superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 44 Provided: First. That no high school accredited to the University of Nebraska receiving aid under this act shall be located in any city in which the state already maintains a permanent educational Institution which gives instruction in agriculture, manual training and home econ - omics. Second. That not more than one high school accredited to the University of Nebraska and two consolidated rural high schools, rural high school, or county high school, in any county shall be added to the list of schools receiving aid under this act in any biennium. Third. 'Not more than two-thirds of the appropriation which may be provided shall be used for high schools accredited to the University of Nebraska, the balance to be reserved for consolidated rural high schools, rural high schools, county high schools, and for associated dis - trict schools. Fourth. Not more than thirty schools shall receive aid during the year 1913-14 under this act. Section 142e. In approving high schools accredited to the Univer - sity of Nebraska for agriculture, manual training, and home economics as contemplated in this act, the State Superintendent of Public Instruc - tion shall be governed by the following general requirements: (a) The school shall provide an approved course in normal train - ing for preparing teachers for rural schools. (b) At least three teachers exclusive of the school superintend - ent shall give their entire time to instruction in high school branches. (c) No one shall be employed as an instructor in agricultural training in any such school unless such person shall show proper cer - tificate of graduation from some agricultural college approved by the Chancellor of the University of Nebraska, or shall be certified by the Dean of the State Agricultural College as having the necessary quali - fications, or who has had a standard four-year course in agricultural training in a state normal school or in an officially recognized normal school, college, or university in Nebraska. (d) At least one-third of the instruction in the industrial depart - ment of such school shall be devoted to work in agriculture, manual training, and natural sciences, or to home economics, manual train - ing, and natural sciences. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 45 MALLERY ACT The Mallery Act, known as Senate File 109, Statutes of Nebraska. 1915, provides for the rural schools as follows: First. All rural high school districts having suitable grounds and a two room school, teachers qualified to teach agriculture, manual training and home economics, provides for the encouragement of such work in rural schools by giving to two room schools the sum of $100 toward the equipment, and $150 annually thereafter. Second. Where they have three rooms, this law provides that they shall get $150 toward the equipment and annually thereafter $200. Third. The same law for rural high school districts having suit - able grounds and four or more school room buildings, provides for the giving of $250 toward the equipment and a further sum of $300 annually thereafter. Fourth. The Mallery Act is a companion bill to the Shumway Act. Both Acts are for the encouragement of teaching agriculture, manual training and home economics in the rural schools. These state acts are altogether different from the Smith-Hughes A«t, as the Shumway Act and the Mallery Act both provide tor the cultivation of at least five acres of ground by the student and the teacher in charge of the school and they also furnish some money for the physical equip - ment of the rural school. The Smith-Hughes Act has nothing to do with the furnishing of physical equipment of the school, neither does it require any land for agricultural purposes. It is simply an act which provides for the teachers' salary who can teach agriculture and home economics in the public schools. The Smith-Hughes Act pays one-half of the salary to the teacher of home economics and agricul - ture. The State of Nebraska pays one-half of the difference. In other words, the State cf Nebraska and the Federal Government, under the Smith-Hughes Act, will pay three-fourths of the salary of the teacher in agriculture and home economics. Under the Smith-Hughes Act, the requirements for giving this instruction in agriculture, is that the teacher must have a four year agricultural course and the same is true of the domestic science teacher. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT VOCATIONAL EDUCATION IN NEBRASKA UNDER THE SMITH HUGHES ACT. The Smith-Hughes Act of Congress, approved February 23, 1917, has for its purpose vocational education. Specifically, it seeks to en - courage four definite vocations: agriculture, home economics, trades and industries, and the training of teachers for the three lines of work. The act contemplates a partnership between the Federal Govern - ment and the State or the accomplishment of these four ends. To participate in the funds from the Federal Government, the legislature must pledge the faith of the state in two respects: (1) To set apart a sum equal to that provided by the Smith-Hughes bill; and (2) To provide for a Board for Vocational Education to have charge of the work and the funds. Nebraska House Roll No. 800 (1917) accepted the provision of the act. pledged the good faith of the state to appro - priate sums equal to the funds allotted to Nebraska, created a Board of Vocational Education and prescribed the duties of its members. The board consists of the governor, chairman, state treasurer, as cus - todian of the funds, and the State Superintendent of Public Instruc - tion, secretary. House Roll No. 800 defined the duties of the Board as follows: "It shall be the duty of said Board and it is authorized and empowered to co-operate, as provided and required by the aforesaid act of Congress, with the Federal Board for Vocational Education in (he administration of the provisions of said act, and to do all things necessary to entitle the state to receive the benefits thereof. Said Board is further empowerd to do all acts and things, and to make such rules and regulations as are necessary to properly carry out the pro - visions of the aforesaid act and the provisions of House Roll No. 800." The legislature appropriated $2500 to defray the expenses of the Board in carrying out the provisions of the Act and an additional sum of $18,500 to meet the share of the state in co-operation with the pro - visions of the Smith-Hughes enactment. The State Superintendent In connection with representatives of the Federal Board prepared the plans for the school year 1917-18. The plans, as formulated, were adopted by the State Board of Vocational Education December 4, 1917, and they were approved by the Federal Board December 18, 1917. The State Board appointed C. A. Fulmer as State Director of Vo - cational Education. Mr. Fulmer entered on his duties January 1, 1918. A secretary to the director was selected. The director and the secretary have carried on the work for promotion of Vocational Education, have done the business which the Smith-Hughes Act re - guires and have laid the foundations so carefully and considerately during the first year of the life of the State Board and the provisions of the act have been in force that great promise in the future is assured. The foundations have been laid and the plans for growth and develop - ment have been carefully worked out. This is the more significant </seg>
            <seg id="p047">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 47 when we remember that one-half of the biennlum had passed before the work could be undertaken. Only a few high schools in Nebraska had, up to this time, maintained courses in agriculture which ap - proached it from the vocational side. The State Board decided to ap - prove schools at Blair, Ainsworth, Scottsbluff, Hastings, and Gothen - burg to exemplify the different types of agriculture in Nebraska. The war called away so many of the qualified teachers that Scottsbluff and Hastings were the only high schools which met the requirements. A type course in home economics was approved in the Alvo consolidated school district. These three courses were the only ones approved and aided financially during the fiscal year of the Federal Board ending June 30, 1918. In addition, the training of teachers for this work was begun in the University of Nebraska and considerable progress was made. During the last part of the year ending June 30, 1918, a survey of the home economics instruction was made in thirty-nine schools of the state. Beginning with February, 1918, the State Director of Vocational Education was given the additional duty of Special War Training Agent in Nebraska. This called for short courses in mechanics for con - scripted men. The war work has been exceedingly heavy. In the war training classes, from January 1, 1918 to July 1, 1918, 455 con - scripted men were given war-training courses in radio-buzzer, auto - mechanics, drafting, mechanical drawing, etc. The men were certified and were inducted into special army service. Over 300 other con - scripted men have been trained since July 1, 1918. Receipts and disbursements of Federal Funds for the fiscal real ending June 30, 1918. a. For salaries of teachers, supervisors, and directors Receipts Disbursements Balance j, 929. 91 % 1,190.41 $ 7.739.60 of agricultural subjects ....$ 8 b. For salaries of teachers of trade, home economics and industrial subjects, including war-t raining The balance in each case reverts to the Federal Board. The late start In the year prevented the use of all the funds. classes — 5,000.00 355.00 4,645.0 For preparing teachers of vocational subjects 6,504.79 2,941.25 3,563.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Appropriation and disbursments of State Funds during the bien- nium, prior to July, 1st, 1918. Disburse- Appropria- ments tion a. For salaries of teachers, supervisors and directors of agricultural subjects $ 907.69 $ 18.500.00 b. For salaries of teachers of trade, home economics, and industrial subjects in - cluding war-training classes 95.62 c. For preparing teachers of vocational subjects 1,470.62 Total $ 2,473.93 % 2,473.93 Balance $ 16,026.07 Appropriation and disbursement of expense fund of state board. Appropriation f 2,500.00 Disbursements Office help, fixtures, supplies, traveling, etc 1.362.60 Balance July 1, 1918 _ % 1,137.40 The following figures show the Federal Fund available for Voca- tional Education during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1919. All of this fund will be expended under the provisions of the Act with the exception of a small sum in the trade and industries fund and a small sum in the teacher training fund. a. For salaries of teachers, supervisors, and directors of agricultural subjects % 13,394.86 b. For salaries of teachers of trade, home economics and industrial subjects including war-training classes 5,512.56 c. For preparing teachers of vocational subjects 9, 10(. 71 Total 28,014.13 Vocational Education will no doubt be strongly emphasized In the reconstruction now that the war has closed. Boys and girls of high school age should be taught to be self-supporting. Courses of study should be offered to meet the needs of those who may not be permitted to pursue a higher education. The course of study in vocational agriculture includes thorough training in animal husbandry, farm wood-work, farm iron-work, soils and crops, farm machinery, motors, tractors, etc., and farm manage- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 49 i 1 I ment. Farm wood-work means the construction of ladders, step - ladders, whiffletrees, chicken coops, pig pens, self-feeders, garages, etc. Farm iron-work includes welding, sharpening of cultivator shovels, plow points, and such other forms of iron work as a farmer needs to do on the farm. Along with the manual side thorough courses are given on farm accounting, farm arithmetic and community civics. Each boy is as - signed a home project of importance which he carries on under the di - rection of the instructor and in co-operation with the parent. The plan is to tie the boy to the farm and not to wean him away from it. All of the work is exceedingly practical. The boy is supposed to have time to carry work in English and some other subjects as science or mathematics. The courses in agriculture require from two to four years. The courses in home economics are similar, in extent, to those in agriculture. The aim is to prepare girls for home-making and home-keeping which, after all, is as great a work as anyone can do. The course of study includes all forms of sewing, dressmaking, food study, preparation of meals, serving of meals, personal and home hygiene, etc. Piior to July 1, 1918, there was not a trade school of high school rank in Nebraska. This is, of course, as all know, an agricultural state. There is, notwithstanding this, great need for trade schools in Omaha, Lincoln and possibly in towns the size of Beatrice, Hastings, Grand Island. Fremont. North Platte, Alliance and Norfolk. Per - haps an intelligent investigation would show that many places in Ne - braska not more than half the size of Norfolk or Alliance would be greatly benefited by a trade school adapted to the specific needs of the community. There is in every good sized town an urgent need for an evening school and perhaps for a part time school also. These schools, to be of the greatest value, ought to be for boys and girls over sixteen years of age who are compelled to leave schqol in order to make a liv - ing. It is not too much to ask that the general public provide for their education in those branches of study and to the extent that is best for the individual and for the community in which they live. The Director of Vocational Education — C. A. Fulmer — who is well acquainted with the conditions in the state, having studied the whole situation carefully and Intensively, says: "I am satisfied that with the return from the army of well-qualified instructors in agri - culture at least fifty schools would be eager to qualify for the Smith- Hughes approval if we had the necessary funds. I am also satisfied that from fifty to one hundred high schools would qualify for home economics approval if we had the funds to aid them. I am equally well satisfied a score of town* would make pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT visions for evening and part-time classes in trade subjects, if we had the funds to aid them. It seems to me that no better expenditure of public funds could be made than in an appropriation of sufficient size to aid every school that would meet the requirements of the State Board." Beginning with this new school year, 1918-19, the number of ap - proved schools was increased and the work that is being carried out now is given below in detail Agriculture SCHOOL Teacher Salary Time E. Donovan $1,800.00 12 Mos. Blair High School I) Bratton-Union Consolidated District Franklin High School Hastings High School E. Wagner 1,800.00 12 Mos. W. Burby 1,500.00 12 Mos. W. Boehr 1,600.00 12 Mos. A L J Kimball County High School Irvin White 1,800.00 12 Mos. Nehawka Consolidated District H. E. Huston 1,944.00 12 Mos. Union Center Consolidated District F H. Beedle 1,800.00 12 Mos. A. Dunbar 1,800.00 12 Mos. Scottsbluff High School \V Home Economics Alvo Consolidated District Ruth Bush $ 810.00 9 Mos. Hooker County High School Leilia B. Moore 1,000 9 Mos Trades and Industries Smith-Hughes Department, Omaha Commercial High School (Day School). Principal E. D. Gepson $2,273.64 12 Mos. Robert Gait 1,515.57 12 Mos. (a) Carpentry (b) Printing 1,515.57 12 Mos w S. Crichton 1,615.57 12 Mos (c) Mechanical Drawing (d) Auto-Mechanics E H. Orchard 1,957.92 12 Mos 12 Mos Teacher Training University of Nebraska (a) Agriculture, four years' course. (b) Home Economics, four years' course. (c) Trades and Industries, two to four years' course. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 51 I War-Training Classes Radio Buzzer, Evening Classes 1. University of Nebraska. 2. Chadron State Normal. 3. Kearney State Normal. 4. Peru State Normal. 5. Wayne State Normal. 6. Doane College, Crete. Omaha Y. M. C. A. General Evening Classes Omaha Y. M. C. A. (a) Auto-Mechanics (b) Electricity. (c) Mechanical Drawing. STATE AID TO WEAK DISTRICTS December 1918. SUMMARY, 1917-18 Attention should be called to the fact that many of these dis- tricts are located in the western part of the state and include within their boundaries untilled land, grazing land and land of little value ■o that it is impossible, even though they levy the full limit of the law, to secure sufficient funds, in addition to the amount given by the state, to have the school that they are entitled to. It is very essential that under the present conditions, provision be made for Increased salaries to teachers for these districts. In my letter to the Governor, found elsewhere in this Report, I made the recommendation that the amount to be paid weak districts be increased from $385 to $575. Even this latter amount will not permit the holding of seven months' school in some districts without ncurring a debt 1. Number of counties asking for aid It Number of districts asking for aid 81 I. Number of districts granted aid _ 5] Average number of sections to district 14 Total amount paid $ 5,214.41 I. Total amount of levy $26,228.14 Total amount of income $31,508.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">KEPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT CERTIFICATE OF TEACHERS In the issuing of teachers' certificates, it is the policy of the present administration to be governed by the plan of certification as given in the school law, rather than by making rulings upon which to base the certification. It has, however, been necessary to make a few rulings on account of the scarcity of teachers resulting from war conditions, as the following will show. EMERGENCY BULLETIN' NO. 1 Lincoln, March 2S, 1018 •'To County Superintendents: As the war progresses it is very certain that no profession will be called upon more heavily than the teaching profession. It is like - wise apparent and necessary that every available and judicious step must be taken to provide teachers. To meet these conditions it Is deemed advisable, for the coming year at least, to adhere to the fol - lowing schedule for certification, county superintendents using their best judgment to suit local conditions. First, all teachers holding second grade county certificate 0 where all grades are 80 per cent or above, this cerificate may be re - newed by the holder doing the reading circle work only (no examin - ation required). If they have one grade or more below 80 per cent, they can raise one grade in one subject, do reading circle work and have certificate renewed. Teachers holding first grade certificates with no grade below 80 per cent the same conditions apply. If they have one grade, or more below 80 per cent, they can raise one grade, in one subject, do reading circle work and have certificate renewed. All certificates renewed for maximum life of statutory requirements. If second grade certificate which by law is good from one to two years and the teacher has used it but one year, make it good for another year without further examination. The same principle will govern the first grade county or any certificate where the time is more than one year. City certificates based on previously held statutory certificates can be changed to like statutory certificates by doing reading circle work and raising one grade in any subject below 80 per cent. Remember city certificates are not good in towns of fewer than one thousand. County superintendents will please canvass their counties for teachers who have been out of school work for some time and who held at the time of leaving their profession a good second or first grade, life, or any certificate, report such findings to the State Super - intendent and arrangements will be made immediately for proper legalizing such certificates without embarrassment to holders. The </seg>
            <seg id="p053">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 53 State and Public schools need such service. Let no one become dis- couraged. Counsel with the State Department. It is work, exercise of good judgment and common sense and not worry that will carry us through. This is not the time to grumble or find fault. Faith in God, faith in yourself and faith in others will provide every public schoolroom with a teacher. Most respectfully, W. H. CLEMMONS, State Superintendent. W. H. CLEMMONS, State Superintendent. P. S. — This is not progressive P. S. — This is not progressive but satisfies a condition and will but satisfies a condition and will allay worry." CERTIFICATION' allay worry CERTIFICATION OF TEACHERS the State Normal Schools, the OF TEACHERS The Certification of Teachers by The Certification of Teachers by the State Normal Schools, the University of Nebraska and Such Other Schools as May Qualify Under the Laws of Nebraska. During the past two years, certificates have been issued by such institutions as follows: 1917 Elementary State Certificates 410 First Grade State Certificates 765 Ufe Certificates 280 1,455 1018 Elementary State Certificates ~ 390 First Grade State Certificates 685 Life Certificates 310 1,385 Total 2.840 CITY CERTIFICATES City certificates are required in cities of 1,000 or more population. City certificates may be issued to holders of first or second grade county certificates or elementary, first grade, life or professional state certificates to teach in the grades. The city high school certificate or superintendent's certificate can be issued only to those who hold a first grade, life or professional state certificate upon which to base such city certificate </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Professional city certificates are issued only to those holding life certificates upon which to base the city life certificate. City certificates have been issued during the biennium, 1917-18, as follows: Below professional class 1,770 Professional class 365 PROFESSIONAL, STATE CERTIFICATES Professional state certificates may be Issued to graduates of a four year course in a college or university and who hold a first grade county certificate and who have had three years' teaching experience. Professional state certificates may be issued to the holder of a life certificate in another state. Professional certificates issued during the biennium, 1917-19 390 EMERGENCY CERTIFICATES The emergency certificate is issued upon a written request, giving the number of the district, signed by the county superintendent, the city superintendent (if for a city teacher), and the members of the school board in the district where the teaching is to be done. This certificate is non-renewable. Emergency certificates issued in 1917 136 Emergency certificates issued in 1918 490 CERTIFICATES IN FORCE 1917 — AS REPORTED BY COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS City Certificates: Professional Life 543 City 958 State Certificates Professional Life 788 First Grade 486 Elementary 446 County Certificates: First Grade _ 2,265 Second Grade 4,791 Third Grade 452 Emergency Certificates: 236 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 55 CERTIFICATES IN FORCE 1918 — AS REPORTED BY COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS City Certificates: Professional Life 1,034 City _ _ 1,437 State Certificates Professional Life $77 First Grade 4«1 Elementary State 524 County Certificates: First Grade 2,222 Second Grade 4,151 Emergency Certificates: 490 EXAMINATION FOR CERTIFICATES During the year 1917, regular two-day examinations were held the third Friday and Saturday of January, of March, of Hay and of July. Special examinations were held in April, June and August. A one-day examination was held the third Friday of November. In 1918, regular one-day examinations were held the third Satur- day of January, of March and of April. Two-day examinations were held the last Friday and Saturday of May, of June and pf July. For the benefit of Normal Trainers, a special examination was held in April. SUMMARY For the year 1917 examination papers graded and reported to county superintendents were as follows: County Subjects - 71,122 Life Subjects - 1,454 Total 72,576 For the year 1918 examination paper* graded and reported to county superintendents were as folio we: County Subjects . - 58,402 Life Subjects _ 1,408 59.810 Total 132,386 Total for Biennium </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 REPORT OP STATE SUPERINTENDENT READING CIRCLE REQUIREMENTS Three books were required for the year ending July 1, 1917. Ellwood — "Sociology and Modern Social Problems." Bachman — "Principles of Elementary Education." (For Rural Teachers) Dewey — "The Schools of Tomorrow." (For City Teachers). Examination in Ellwood, May 19, 1917; July 27, 1917. Examination in Bachman, May 19, 1917; July 27, 1917. Examination in Dewey, May 19, 1917; July 27, 1917. Two books were required for the year ending July 1, 1918: Strayer and Norsworthy — "How to Teach." Jewett — "The Next Generation." Examination in Strayer and Norsworthy — March 16, 1918; June 1, 1918; July 27, 1918. Examination in Jewett — March 16, 1918; June 1, 1918; July 27, 1918. APPROPRIATED FUNDS 1917-1918 State Aid to Agriculture and Manual Training Amount appropriated $ 20,000.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 $ 17,900.00 Balance on hand 2,100.00 Total 20,000.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 2,100.00 Normal Training: Amount appropriated $118,000.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 f 64,601.79 Balance on hand 53,398.21 Total _... 118,000.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 53,398.21 State Aid to Weak Districts Amount appropriated f 50,000.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 $ 9,398.00 Balance on hand 40,602.00 Total 50,000.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 40,602.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 57 Incidentals, County Superintendents' Supplies, Postage, Etc, Amount appropriated | 10,000.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 $ 8,142.33 Balance on hand 1,857.67 ToUl 10,000.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 1,857.67 Cash Fund: Receipts from April 1, 1917 to Dec 1 1918 * 18,704.85 Salaries from April 1, 1917 t oDee 1 1918 _ $ 12,048.01 Salaries from April 1, 1917 to Dec 1 1918 4,197.50 Balance on hand 2,459.34 Total 18,704.85 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 2,459.34 Traveling Expenses: Amount appropriated { 3,000.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 % 2,199.73 Balance on hand 800.27 Total _... 3,000.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 800.27 Salary of Superintendent: Amount appropriated $ 4,000.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 $ 3,000.00 Balance on hand 1,000.00 Total „ 4,000.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 1,000.00 Salary of Deputy Superintendent Amount appropriated f 3,(00.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 % 2,560.00 Balance on hand _ 1,050.00 Total 3,600.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 1,060.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Salary of Assistant: Amount appropriated _ S 3.600.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 $ 2,830.00 Balance on hand 770.00 Total „ 3,600.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 770.00 Readers: Amount appropriated i 7,200.00 Amount expended to Dec. 1, 1918 $ 4,199.50 Balance on hand 3,000.50 Total _... 7,200.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1918 3,000.50 APPROPRIATED FUNDS 1916-1917 State Aid to Agriculture and Manual Training Balance on hand December 1, 1916 $ 11,169.40 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 $ 630.68 Reverting to state treasury 10,538.72 $ 11,169.40 11,169.40 Normal Training: Balance on hand January 4, 1917 $ 42,102.68 Amount expended to July 11, 1917 ....I 42,102.39 Reverting to state treasury .29 S 42,102.68 42,102.(8 42,102.68 State Aid to Weak District*: Balance on hand December 1 State Aid to Weak District*: Balance on hand December 1 Amount expended to April 1, 1916 S 11,717.00 1916 S 11,717.00 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 $ 6,538.00 1917 $ 6,538.00 Revetting to state treasury 4,179.00 $ 11,717.00 11,717.00 Printing School Laws Balance on hand December 1, 1916 .... $ 566.13 Reverting to state treasury 566.13 Incidentals, Co. Supte' Supplies, Postage, Etc.: Balance on hand December 1, 1916 f 266.58 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 ....$ 266.19 Reverting to state treasury .39 $ 266.58 266.58 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 59 Cash Fund: Balance on hand December 1, 1916 Receipts to April 1, 1917 * 1,993.76 2.240.00 Expended to April 1, 1917 Reverting to state treasury 4,231.86 1.90 4,233.76 Traveling Expenses: Balance on hand December 1, 1916 Expended to April 1, 1917 $ 89.54 86.36 3.18 Reverting to state treasury 89.54 Salary of State Superintendent: Balance on hand December 1, 19 16 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 * 1,000.00 1,000.00 Salary of Deputy Superintendent: Balance on hand December 1, 1916 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 .. $ 600.00 600.00 Salary of Assistant Superintendent: Balance on hand December 1, 1916 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 I 600.00 600.00 Salary of Secretary: Balance on hand December 1, 1916 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 Reverting to state treasury * 430.00 S 400.00 30.00 430.00 Salary of Stenographer: Balance on hand December 1, 1916 Amount expended to April 1, 1917 * 280.00 280.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT SCHOOLS OF AGRICULTURE AT STATE FARM AND CURTIS In addition to the College of Agriculture, which is maintained at the State Farm, and in connection with it, the University conducts two schools of agriculture. One of these is at the State Farm and the other is at Curtis. These two Schools of Agriculture are maintained for the advantage of students seeking secondary education. The College of Agriculture is of the same rank as the other colleges of the University and its courses of study lead directly to a recognized degree. Many young men and women are not so situated that they can pursue such extensive studies. To this class, the university offers the advantages of courses of study of secondary education under most favorable conditions. The Schools of Agriculture are secondary schools in which agriculture is given special emphasis. Students who do not have sufficient high school credits to enter college are accepted. Graduation is not allowed by a degree. The courses of study in subject matter and in extent are intended to qual - ify young men to be practical farmers and young women to be efficient home keepers. To men, the schools give full training in agricultural subjects and to women they offer training which fits them for the re - sponsibilities of homes. Not only is the practical side of education given special attention but, also, there is offered a cultural training equivalent to that given in a good high school. The school at Curtis, although of equal rank and usefulness, is somewhat different from the one at the state farm. The chief differ - ence may be expressed in four statements: : 1. It seeks to fit young people for successful life in the open fields of western Nebraska. 2. It attempts to develop strong young men and women for life in the same general environment as that in which their childhood days were spent. 3. It deals with the problems of the farm and home in the semi - arid parts of the state. 4. It deals with dairy and animal husbandry and with all farm and garden production according to the best methods employed in dry land farming. Both schools adapt themselves to the wants of those who enroll and to the environment in which each school is located. The courses of study are so arranged that students who have not had the advantages of a high school can enter upon them directly from the eighth grade. They are enabled by this agency in the same time as required in a good high school to take those subjects which will </seg>
            <seg id="p061">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 61 make them efficient men ond women, useful citizens in a large way and of worthy standing among their fellow men. The studies for men include animal husbandry, Judging of live stock, feeding stock, poultry raising, animal pathology and hygiene, dairy husbandry, milk production and farm organization and manage - ment. The studies for women include domestic dairying, cooking, sewing, dressmaking, clothing and textiles, rural school lunches and color de - signs as they relate to the everyday problems of life. That the courses of study may be of the greatest possible value that can be reached in secondary education, where it is desired, opportunity is afforded for a review of English grammar, written composition, description, narration, exposition and select readings; public speaking and argumentation, and for regular work in the principles of political economy. Also, the way is open for high school science and mathematics. It will be seen from the foregoing statement that Nebraska is seeking to provide for the education and training of all classes of peo - ple to the end that the state may be occupied and governed by an in - telligent, loyal, thrifty, industrious and whole-hearted citizenship. THE NORMAL SCHOOLS The people of Nebraska have a right to be proud of their normal schools. Each one, from the day it began to enroll students, has made commendable progress. The progress in recent years, and especially as it comes within the limits of this biennium, has three phases: (1) The material and intellectual equipment, (2) deflniteness in the aim and office of instruction, and ( 3 ) the influence of the instruction in the Formal schools upon the life, method and character of the instruction of the teachers in the schools of the state. The better equipment is indicated by new buildings, additional physical and chemical apparatus, growth of valuable libraries, and improvement in the lawns, walks and grounds. The state boaxd of education has been both prudent and generous in the expenditure of the money appropriated for their use. Deflniteness in the aim and jffice of instruction is seen in the intelligent plans, in the content and icope of the subject-matter of study and recitation, in the richness and ariety of illustration, in the effort to induce the employment of nethods of research and the clearness of conception and presentation. The influence of the instruction received in the normal school is mani - ested by the methods employed by the graduates when they go into heir own schools. This influence is seen in the lives and actions of the ieople among whom they live and work. The years of the war and more particularly the nineteen months tmerlca was actually engaged in the contest have seen many leave for </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT tbe army camp and for the battle fields of Belgium and France. Thus the number of students has not increased as many desired to see. However much this may be deplored, it is after all, the glory of the normal schools that the young men who in times of peace were pre - paring for a life so useful as that of the profession of teaching, when the call came the young men were ready to march under the stars and stripes and if need be, into the very jaws of death. The lots In numbers was more than compensated and richly rewarded by the song of victory and the march of triumph. COLLEGES AND UNIVERSITIES When the age, wealth and population are taken into the account, not many states are as well supplied with institutions of college and university grade as Nebraska. In common with the institutions of higher education in general, the young men of these colleges were among the first to hear the call to arms. In some of the colleges, three-fourths of the young men put aside their ambitions, delayed their prospects, laid down their text - books and reported for duty. The entrance into the war explains the unorganized conditions of many of the colleges at the close of the academic year 1917. The general belief that the war would continue for three years and the need for large numbers of intelligent men in - duced the government to ask the colleges to open their doors for the school year 1918-19 to another class of students. The young men had the preparation furnished by graduation from a twelfth grade high school or an equivalent in time, study and subject-matter. This admitted them to the college and to the freshman class. The object of the government was two-fold: (1) To bring together a body of young men about 18 years of age that they might be put under mili - tary training and thus made ready for camp life and later for army service in France, if they should be needed; and (2) to give them such opportunities for a liberal education and such inspiration that they would be fitted on their return to civil life to support themselves and to carry their part of the world's work and responsibility. This in - volved some changes in courses of study, teaching staff, modes of pro - cedure and organization of forces. These things explain in part tht condition of the colleges and especially in matters of order and dla cipllne. In general, the colleges and universities of Nebraska are gainln in equipment and growing in means of support. Year by year, the are making substantial gains in the things which make them literati </seg>
            <seg id="p063">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 63 ingly worthy and permanently useful. So far as the State Department of Instruction is informed, the twelve colleges and universities in Ne - braska are doing the things for which they were founded with intelligence, earnestness and devotion. They are centers of life and light and leading; sources of good and inspiration; fountains of bless - ing and excellence. They exalt virtue, measure worth, dignity labor and ennoble character. PRIVATE SCHOOLS There are in Nebraska eight business colleges, seventeen acad - emies, one teachers' seminary, one theological seminary, two private normal colleges, and two Junior colleges. These thirty-one schools besides the academies and preparatory departments connected with some of the colleges in the state are not required to make a report to the State Department of Education. For this reason, this report of the State Superintendent cannot speak clearly and definitely of their condition and progress. In general it may be said that they have been and are doing good work, that they are reaching the ends their founders intended, that they are serving in helpful ways the commun - ities where they are located and that they are realizing the expectations of their supporters. Prom statements received through private sources, the two normal colleges — Fremont College and St. Paul Normal School — have a good enrollment and the two junior colleges — the Luther College at Wahoo and Dana College at Blair — and Franklin Academy at Franklin have made substantial gains, both in the number of stu - dents and in means of support. SUMMARY OF STATISTICS From Reports of County Superintendents for year ending July, 1917. District Indebtedness: Outstanding bonds $ 9,487,573.72 Other indebtedness _ 1,216,517.70 Total $10,704,091.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT Value of District Property: Value of schoolhouses $12,782,587.27 Value of sites 3.829,195.04 Value of text-books _ 1,235,142.79 Value of maps, charts, etc 653,333.18 Value of all other district property 936,119.29 Total $19,436,377.57 Children Subject to Compulsory Education Law: Males 119,696 Females 117,218 Total 236,914 Children Subject to Compulsory Education Law Who Attended Required Time: Males 97,568 Females _ 98,745 Total 196,313 Aggregate Number of Days Attended by all Pupils: Males 9,315,622 Females 10,132.113 Total _ 19,447,735 Pubils transferred under Sec. 243, Art. 21 2,641 Number of blind children 65 Number of deaf and dumb children 301 iiength of Term: Months school held past year 56,930 Days school was open 1,191,860 Months voted for next year 57,672 School Tax: Mills levied last year _ 125,999 Money voted for past year $26,393,553.11 Total Mages Earned by all Teachers Males _ $ 960.237.39 Females 6,414,339.94 Total _ $ 7.374,577.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 65 Number of schoolhouse* : Frame 6.837 Brick 578 Stone or cement 105 Log 27 Sod 1SS Galvanized 1 Total , 7,«81 Number of schoolhouses built within the year 196 Number of districts having nine months or more of school _ 8,248 Number of districts having eight months or more, but less than nine months of school 2,807 Number of districts having four months or more, but less than eight months of school 1,184 Number of districts having no school or less than four months 196 Number of teachers actually needed 12,516 Number of schools other than public 861 Amount of district bonds issued in past year $ 735,763.95 Amount paid on district bonds in past year I 233,248.84 Amount derived from state aid to weak districts $ 9,398.00 Amount derived from state fund: January. 1918 apportionment ....$ 408,120.72 July, 1918 apportionment 550,256.74 $ 958.377.46 Amount derived from forest reserve $ 1,636.80 SUMMARY FROM ANNUAL REPORT OF COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS, ENDING JULY, 1918. Number of counties — 98 Number of school districts 7,216 Number of schoolhouses 7,681 Number of teachers employed: Males 1,150 Females 12,098 Total _ 13,248 Average Monthly Salary: Males $ 86.81 Females 56. U </seg>
            <seg id="p066">REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT 66 Enrollment: Males 149,491 Females _.... 150,520 Total 300,011 Census: Males • 198,329 Females _ — . 191,697 Total „ _ 390,026 Average Daily Attendance Males 104,825 Females 109,552 Total 214,377 FINANCIAL REPORT Summary From County Superintendents' Annual Reports, 1916-17. Money on hand _ $ 2,684,210.60 Money Received: 1. From County 9,375,755.65 2. Sale of Bonds _ _ 900,828.54 3. Fines and Licenses 184,283.36 4. Non-Resident Pupils _ 291,366.03 5. Other Sources „ 1,084,489.93 Total ..._ „ _ $14,6.20,934.11 Money Paid Out: 1. Male Teachers _...$ 1,069,719.01 6,771,120.59 1,489,599.76 516,202.46 542,551.60 487,174.96 175,237.17 1.884,016.02 26,626.18 2,558,686.36 ...$14,520,934.11 2. Female Teachers I 3. Buildings and Site* _ _ : 4. 5. Repairs _ Fuel 6. 7. 8. Books and Supplies Furniture Other Purposes ... 9. Library Books _ ■ 0. On Hand „ Total _ j$l </seg>
            <seg id="p067">OP PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 67 FINANCIAL REPORT Summary From County Superintendents' Annual Reports. July 1917-18 In hands of District Treasurer at close of last year $ 2,525,807.66 Received from county and township treasurers 10,632,235.51 Received from sale of District Bonds 1,082,961.12 Received from local fines and licenses 99,637.11 Received tuition from non-resident pupils 347,152.74 Received from all other sources 1,636,802.53 Total $16,224,696.67 Paid male teachers $ 960 746.54 Paid female teachers 6,490,255.09 Paid for buildings and sites 2,172,507.74 Paid for repair* _ 499,822.17 Paid for fuel 705,945.54 Paid for books and supplies 691,078.05 Paid for furniture 234,312.63 Paid for books under Library Law 27,900.72 Paid for all other purposes 2,672,147.00 Amount in hands of District Treasurers, July 1, 1918 .... 1,869,881.29 Total $ 16,224,596.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS _ _ Minimum County Seat County Superintendent Salary Adams Mary Dungan C. A. Mohrman Hastings Nellgh... $1,600 1.500 Antelope. Arthur Banner.... Mrs. D. G. Williams Minnie Larson Arthur D D D Harrisburg Brewster . .. Albion Blaine. Boone A. L. Shamblin Bertha M. Sheckler Opal Russell 1,400 1.100 Box Butte. Boyd Alliance. Butte Hazel Sloniger 1,300 Brown. Buffalo Burt Mrs. Lenna Morris. Katheryn Laughlin W. T. Pouchex Ainsworth. Kearney.... 1.100 2,000 Tekamah 1,400 Butler Cass ... Oma L. Cady Alpha Peterson Emma Schwerin Addie P. Spangler. Edith Adamson Anna McFadden L. J. Gilkeson David City. Plattsmouth Hartington.. Imperial 1,500 1,600 1.400 Cedar.. Chase.. Cherry D 1.400 1.200 Valentine Sidney Cheyenne Clay Clay Center Schuyler Collar... Cuming. Custer... Dakota. Dawes... Dawson Deuel... F. J. Vogltance Emma R. Miller. T. C. Grtmes.... W. E. Voh 1,800 West Point.. Broken Bow Dakota D 2.200 1.100 1,300 Edna Rincker W. C. Bloom Chadron... Lexington Chappell.. Ponca. 1.500 Mrs. Retta F. Brown W. F. Richardson... John M. Matzen D Dixon. Dodge 1,400 Fremont Omaha... 1,800 Douglas.. Dundy Fillmore Franklin. Frontier. Furnas.. . Thomas J. Keenan Una Richards 2,200 Benkelman Geneva 1,000 Lillian D. Green. Pearl O'Neal 1,400 1,300 Bloomington Stockville.. Beaver City.. Beatrice l,45fr Mabel Keith G. W. Fletcher T. J. Trauernicht... Esther Johnson Florence Alderman F. W. Montgomery. Theodore A. Frye... Margaret L. Tracy.. 1,400 Gage. 1,800 Garden. Gajfleld Gosper Grant Oshkosh. Burwell Elwood... Hyannis Greeley... 1,000 l.OOfr 1,000 D Greeley Hall 1.600 Elisabeth Cunningham Arthur S. Nelson Grand Island. Aurora 1.440 Hamilton. Harlan Frances E. White Alma. 1,300 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION 69 COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS (Continued) Minimum County Superintendent County Seat Hayes Edgiththa Grant Hayes Center D Hitchcock. Holt Vida Day-Martin. Minnie B. Miller. J. H. Garrett Trenton.... O'Neill Mullen St. Paul... Fairbury.. Tecumseh Minden 1,100 1,400 Hooker... Howard.. Jefferson Johnson. Kearney. Keith 1,400 (1.400 W. G. Baker Henry Abrams L. C. Kuster Oscar Warp 1,300 1,300 Katherine Feather Abbie T. Pelletier Rachel McElroy Allen S. Stinson Mrs. Minnie P. Knotts. Aileen Gantt Ogalalla 1,000 Keya Paha.. Kimball Springview Kimball D D Knox Center. Lincoln 1,800 Lancaster Lincoln... 2,200 North Platte-. Gandy 1.800 Logan Loup D Alice C. Hill. Edith Wirsig... O. A. Johnson. N. A. Housel Taylor... Tryon.... Madison D D McPherson Madison 1.800 Merriek ... Morrill Nance Nemaha Nuckolls Otoe Margaret McCutcheon E F. Kelley..... Central City Bridgeport... Fullerton 1.300 1,100 Chloe C. Baldridge Bess E. Anderson Carterette Ebersole Charles Speedie Elsie Hammond Mrs. Margaret Bailar Alice A. Swanson 1,300 Auburn Nelson.. 1,409 1,400 Nebraska City. Pawnee City Grant 1,600 1.300 Pawnee Perkins Phelps.. Pierce... Platte.. iPolk D Holdrege. Pierce. 1,300 Lettie Scott. 1,300 Fred S. Lecron Columbus Osceola ... 1,600 Amelia Rasmussen.. Julia C. Barnes 1,300 Red Willow 1,300 McCook Richardson ,Rock 1.600 D. H. Weber A. F. Dugger L. J. Bouchal Cordelia Gramllch. F. E. Alder Falls City Basset* D '.Saline [sarpy. Wilber. 1,400 Papillion Wahoo .... Gering.... 1,300 iSaunders.. Bcottsbluff Sewaxd 1,800 Ada M. Haldeman. J. C. Greenwood... 1.400 Seward 1,400 riheridan {Sherman Rushville... Loup City. Harrison... Stanton 1,300 Pearle E. Summers. L. H. Currier 1,300 1,000 Sioux .... Btanton Vinnie Newell.. Ilah B. Ohlson 1.300 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 REPORT OF STATE SUPERINTENDENT COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS (Concluded) County Seat Minimum County Superintendent Salary Thayer... Thomas... Thurston Valley A. T. Holtzen. ... Inez L. Oakes .... Ellen M. Brown Hebron... Thedford Pender.... 1.400 D 1,300 E. D. Clason N. T. Lund ... Pearl Sewell. Ord 1,300 Washington Wayne Blair. 1,700 Wayne 1,300 Webster Wheeler York Gertrude L. Coon Edith Bowler Red Cloud Bartlett 1.400 650 Telfer C. Lord 1,500 York </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>