<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00010">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00010</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>FIFTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR JUVENILE DELINQUENTS, GENEVA, NEBRASKA.  FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900.</title>
			            <date value="1900">1900</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-29</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Laura Weakly</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Validation</item>
				     </change>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-18</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
				     </change>

				     <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FIFTH BIENNIAL REPORT 

OF THE 

SUPERINTENDENT 

OF THE 

Girls' Industrial School 

JUVENILE DELINQUENTS, 

GENEVA, NEBRASKA. 

FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900. 

LINCOLN, NEB 

URSAL COMPANY, PRINTERS 

10 &gt;1 

4 </seg>

            <seg id="p002">
w 

N</seg> 

            <seg id="p003">
Hon. \\ 

;mi A. Povnter 

Governor 

Hon. Fred Jewell Private Secretary 

iOAHD OF ITBLIC LANDS AND BUILDING 

V. \Volf« 

President 

Secretary 

Ih.i 

W. F. Porter 

('. J. Smyth. 
•I. It. .Meservt 

ICEUS 

AND 

Ml'LOYEF 

K 

B. Webei 

. .Superintendent 
lerk and Steward 

( 

Matron 

Family Manager 
Familv Manager 

M 

i 

Mat 

)ii and Hou 

sekeepinj; Teacher 
.rookinji Teacher 
. Laundrv Teacher 

M 

w 

\ 

istaii 

\. M 

K. Mundy 
Ddiiovan 

M 

Sewing Teacher 

. Enginepr 

K 

Engineer 

\ 

Farmer 

r. j 

w 

Extra-man 

M 

.Martin 

Phvsician </seg>
            <seg id="p004">
M 

1&gt; 


r .'{&lt;). 11)00 

I of Pul 

trial Soli 

Hid 

nlv v 

,\ 

\ 

Geneva. Neb., Xovembt 
Governor, and the Boa 
Lincoln, Neb. 

To Hon. W. A. Povntei 

Lands and Buildings 

Dear Sirs: It beoom 

my duty, as ir is also my pleasu 

present the fifth biennial report of the &lt; 
for Juvenile Delinquents for your consi 
you for the consideration and courtesy tl 
cial relations. We have asked from tli 
believed to be absolutely necessary foi 
never been refused (except your failuri 
which we have urged in everv monthly 

Girls" Indu 
ideration; i 
hat has ma 
lie Hoard o 

greatly appreciated by each and evei 
right here let me say that any good y&lt; 
it is we and not I that did it. 

&gt;n 

Verv obed 

B. R. II. W i 

S </seg>


            <seg id="p005">REPORT. 

st biennial report we have united added experi- 

KlIK 

ence with renewed efforts to better the condition of the school. 
While we have at all times endeavored to escape notoriety in 

public press, believing the same, whether favorable or other¦. 
to be detrimental and destructive to the best results in a 

u 

lie institution, vet now as we look back over the past two 
us. and frankly acknowledging our mistakes, I feel that in 

•andor we have met with a fair degree of success. To those who 
nav succeed us we tender our best wishes, and any information 

Ivice we can give will be most heartily given, for the good 
ie school and the best interests of the girls who have come 
i- almost like members of our own family. Our work has 

done with a full and believing faith in an all-wise Proviwhich 
has been our guide. 

il training of the inmates has been the primary ob- 

e institution, and could not be better in the home circle. 
Sunday school and prayer meetings have been a dis- 

nctive feature. Chapel exercises every Sunday, conducted 
ternately by the ministers of the several churches and any 
rangelists who happened To be in Geneva over Sunday, have 

een productive of much good. The ministers have done this 
heerfully without compensation, and I am convinced that this 
hange of ministers is even better than the appointment of a 

regular chaplain; but I very much regret that the last legislature 
refused to make an appropriation of two or three dollars 
per Sunday for this purpose, as recommended in my last report, 
and I again repeat the recommendation. No man can ask this 
work to be done gratuitously for four years without feeling that 
it is an imi&gt;osition on the ministers and discreditable to the great 
state of Nebraska. If there is any people that need the hope </seg>


            <seg id="p006">54 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

and strength and refining influences of divine worship, it is 
these poor unfortunate girls. The need of this provision was recognized 
by the legislative committee to whom I presented this 
matter two years ago, but they said. ''We can't make this appropriation 
now." I sincerely trust that the next legislature will 
realize what the purpose of this institution is, and that they 
will rise superior to any considerations of expediency and do 
their whole duty in this matter. 

Sectarianism has been avoided in our religious exercises, and 
no particular doctrine or creed has been taught. No attempt 
is made to change previous formed religious convictions, if any 
exist, and so far as is possible the desires and views of earlier 
teachings, if they have had any, are encouraged. No question of 
race or nationality. Catholicism or Protestantism enter into the 
teaching, but that one God rules over all alike. When you 
know the former circumstances and surroundings of the great 
majority of the inmates of this institution, you soon realize that 
more than mere educational and industrial training is necessary 
to eradicate these influences and to make of these unfortunate 
ones useful and respectable citizens. And, as I have heretofore 
said, "This institution is designed as the protecting arm which 
the state throws around them, that in the years of maturity they 
may be a blessing instead of a curse to society." 

The question is not, in our opinion, how to manage them while 
in the school — anyone who has authority can do that in their 
way — but what can we make of them in the future? And in 
this nothing will have a more lasting impression and better answer 
to the question than example; and we believe that money 
cannot be better spent than in moulding the untrained outcast 
into useful Christian life. Now, while we show in the latter 
pages of this report that economy has been fully studied and 
taught, also the industrial part of the work has been conducted 
in a manner we are not ashamed of, yet, as the future citizenship 
of the nation is dependent upon the boys and girls of the 
country, our prime object and aim has been to make better, 
nobler, and truer girls, who will make better women, out of </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
girls' industrial school. 

55 

every one under our charge. And let me add right here that 
two-thirds of our girls have been "sinned against far more than 
they have sinned," and while their own sex often turn on them 
when they have taken the first step downwards, the man who 
led them to take that step continues in the best society. 

• 
We have had but little sickness, and none of a serious'character. 
For months at a time we have had no one in the hospital, 
and when one has gotten in, the skill of our physician has very 
soon taken them out. Since the Board adopted the rule to have 
no regular days, but only call the doctor when needed, the expense 
has been only about one-third as much as heretofore, as 
it was common for some of the girls to get sick just about the 
time of the regular visiting day. 

When we took possession of the institution, we invited the 
people to visit and insj»ect the work done, and, as a result, we 
have had thousands of vistors register their names on our books, 
many from the immediate vicinity who had never visited the 
school before, and profess to be much pleased. We tell them 
that the institution belongs to the state, and we are their survauts, 
and take pleasure in showing our work. 

Besides our regular work, study, and play, we observe the 
holidays in an appropriate manner; and we are not ashamed to 
place our entertainments in comparison with those of other 
schools whose pupils have been more fortunate. Some of our 
girls have sung for the churches and religious conventions, and 
were always well received. We often take some of them to the 
city churches, and on one occasion took all but the kitchen girls. 
They have also attended Decoration day services, the fairs, etc., 
all of which is a great encouragement to them, and they have 
always been treated with respect by the public, with the exception 
of a few individuals who should be kept some place long 
enough to learn some manners. 

As we put in from eleven to twelve months in school, in half 
day each, our girls get about as many hours' instruction in the 
year as if they attended the public school, besides the industrial 
work. Thev become so attached to the school that in manv cases </seg>


            <seg id="p008">56 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

when we have found splendid homes for them, they get very 
lonesome at first and beg to be let come back. Many of them 
make a practice of coming home on holidays, and seem to be as 
happy as if at grandma's home. Eleven of our girls have married, 
and most of them have done well for themselves, and have 
homes of their own ; three of whom live in this county. 

As an evidence of the feeling of the girls for the institution 
after they have left it, I give herewith extracts from a few letters 
of the hundreds of the same kind received from them, and which 
fairly reflect the sentiment of all, showing that the most kindly 
recollections of the institution and of their life there is cherished 

by the girls who have left it 

Nov. 18, 1900. 

Mr. B. R. B. Weber — Dear Friend: I was very sorry to hear 
that you were going to leave the school. I am sure the girls 
will never get another superintendent that will be as kind to 
them as you have been. It will seem like someone has died 
there when you go. For you have always had a kind word and a 
pleasant look for every girl, no matter how bad she had been. 1 
was telling my husband just the other day that us girls never 
appreciated your kindness half as much as we do after it is too 
late. Who knows that the next man won't be cross and unpleasant, 
but we hope he will not. However kind he may be, he 
can never fill your place. I will try to come up before you go, 
if possible. Give my love to Mrs. Weber and Tillie and kind 
regards to all. 

Your friend, 

Mrs. L. W— 

July 17, 1900. 

Dear Mr. Weber: 1 received your letter this afternoon and was 
glad, as I always am, to hear from you, and am so glad that 
A can be sent out on trial. It will encourage her so much, 
and I think she will appreciate your kindness too much to cause 
her to do anything that would cause you to regret it. I think 
any girl who leaves the school and does not do right, has only 
herself to blame. 1 am glad that I was sent to the school for 
several reasons. One reason is that I learned to appreciate a 
good home and mother, and I think any girl who could be 
among such good Christian people as yourself and the rest of </seg>


            <seg id="p009">57 

UIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

the officers as long as I was, and not really try to do right, mast 
be a hopeless case indeed. 

Mr. Weber, I cannot thank you enough for what you have 
done for rue. But really, I did not appreciate your kindness to 
me while I was in the school, and at times it seemed that I did 
not care, but I was always sorry the minute I had done something 
to cause you trouble. If you had been mad at me when 
I did wrong, and gave me a good scolding as I deserved, of 
course I would not have felt so bad about it. But you always 
made me feel ashamed of myself. You looked like you only 
felt sorry for me, and then I would make up my mind to be good. 
How I succeeded, you know. I had a great many failures, and 
have them yet, but am really trying to do right. Thanking you 
again for your past kindness, and with best wishes for Mrs. 
Weber and all the officers, I remain 

Your friend, G 

Dear Mr. Weber: As I have a little spare time this morning, 
1 thought I would write you a few lines. I have just come back 
from taking my Latin lesson. I got a compliment from my 
teacher; she said I was the smartest girl in the school. So my 
head is so big, I can hardly keep my hat on. Can't Tillie come 
and visit me? How are all the girls? Give them my love, and 
especially P . I met a lovely lady from your old home who 
knew you so well. * * * I am so anxious for school to begin 
agaiu I can hardly wait. It is always dull during vacation. I 
must stop now as it is dinner time, and you know what that 
means.. From vonr friend. M . 

Mr. Weber — Dear Sir: I will drop you a few lines to let you 
know of my safe arrival, and thank you for getting me such a 
nice home. Mr. 'NYeber, it is just lovely, and I am so pleased 
with Mrs. J . She re so kind and good to me. They have 
two of the sweetest little boys; I fell in love with the littlest 
fellow at first sight. I hope everybody is well at the school, and 
that every girl will soon get on her "honor" and get a nice home 
like mine. It pays to be good. Mrs. J is going to take me 
riding this P. M. Once more thanking you,, I am your 

Loving pupil, M 

July 10, 1900. 

Dear Mr. Weber: * * * I like mv home verv much. They </seg>


            <seg id="p010">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

58 

are very kind to me. They have two children. I went to Sunday 
school and was going to church, but it rained so they had no 
meeting. I went to a sociable and had all the ice cream I could 
eat. Well, Mr. Weber, it is getting late and I am sleepy and will 
close. From your friend, M . 

, May 1, 11)00. 

Mr. Weber. — Dear Friend: Your kind and most welcome letter 
received. Am always glad to hear from you. So sorry that 
Mrs Philbrook is sick. Hope she is much better. I have been 
making garden. Am getting to be quite a farmer's daughter. 
* * * I shall never forget your kindness to me in many ways, 
and can never thank you enough, and don't suppose I can ever 
repay you. But can do as you told us just a few Sundays before 
I left, and that was "to help someone else." I am getting along 
all right. Haven't heard from B for some time. I must 
close. I have written all I can think of. Love to all. 

Your friend. I — 

— , May .5. l'.MMi 

Dear Mr. and Mrs. Webber: Don't think me neglectful for not 
answering your good and kind letter sooner, as I have been sick. 
but hope to be well again soon. You know while I was at the 
school I was sick and I missed some pleasures, etc., but it did 
me no harm and I am glad I went. I wish you could see some 
of the girls here now that could be nice, but are vile and have 
no reputation. I don't recognize them now, and I might have 
been as bad. * • • Give all the girls my love. I have written 
Mrs. B but received no answer. Possibly she has forgotten 
me, but I haven't her. She is so kind. Give Tillie my love, also 
Mrs. W , yourself, and all. 

Yours, A 

Mr. Weber — Dear Friend: I will now try to answer your kind 
and most welcome letter. Hope you are well and happy. We are 
going to have good crops this year. We have 530 chickens and 
six little guineas. .They are very cute — you ought to see them. 
I went visiting yesterday. Had a fine time. Went to a neigh 
bor's and picked blackberries. I bought a celluloid box and 
picture frame. • • • I must close, with love and best wishes. 
Good-bye. Yours trulv, W . </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
girls' industrial school. 

59 

, Aug. 14, 1900. 

Dear Mr. Weber: I expect you think I hare forgotten you, but 
I have not. I am coming to see you in September. It seems so 
long since 1 have seen any of you. I cannot wait much longer. 
I would rather go most anywhere than back to the school to live, 
but there is no place I would rather go to visit. • • • With 
love to you and Mrs. Weber and the officers. F . 

A.ug. 12, 1900. 

1}. K. B. Weber. — Dear Sir: This is Sunday and I will drop 
you a few lines. I am getting along nicely. Mrs. H is so 
good and kind to me. She is very patient. I have just finished 
the dinner dishes. I like it here so much. I don't feel lonesome. 
I have a nice little bedroom, and when my work is done I go 
there to read and write. Mr. Weber, I thank you ever so much 
for all you have done for me, and some day I hope it will be in 
my power to repay you. May God bless you and Mrs. Weber. 
You are doing more good than you think in that school. Love 
to Tillie and all. 

Your friend, J 

Mr. Weber — Dear Friend: 1 received your letter last week, 
and was glad to hear from you and hope you will be glad to 
hear from me. I am so glad you aren't going to stay there much 
longer. I hope you are reformed, and will be good when you get 
out dike me), and I hope you won't have to be sent back. I wish 
Tillie could come and stay with me during the vacation. Can't 
you let her? And can't you come yourself? The school is very 
good here. I think you would like it here, only you might get 
tired of me. I suppose it will rain tomorrow and spoil my new 
hat. I had a letter from a friend of mine, and she says they are 
having a terrible time with physical geography, and would not 
pass. I think it is the easiest study I have. I like it here very 
much. How are all the officers and girls? Well, I will have to 
stop. From your friend, M . 

Dear Mr. Weber: I thought I would write and tell you I like 
my home very much. They are so good to me. The Sunday 
school is not far from here. They have two very sweet children. 
We have sheep, cows, horses, hogs, ducks, chickens, and lots of 
other things. Please excuse pencil, can't find a pen. Give my 
love to all the officers. Oh, I went to S. S. Sunday. We have a 
nice one. Must close now. M .</seg> 

            <seg id="p012">
60 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

, May 30, 1900. 

Dear Mr. Weber: Received your letter and was very glad to 
get it. Mr. Weber, I am following your advice as near as I know 
how, trying to be good all the time. And I would like very much 
if you could get me a place where I could get my board and 
clothes and finish my education. Mamma will let me go. I am 
working out. Nobody could be better or take more interest in 
the girls than you, and it is not a disagreeable place at the school 
if one is only good. * • • Did the girls all go to the grave 
yard on Decoration day? C . 

C— 

Dear Sir: I got your letter this afternoon, and was so glad 
you wrote. I have so much to tell you, I don't know at which 
end to begin. • • • I like Mr. and Mrs. 1' very much. 
They are very kind to me. • • • Please send letters to me in 
a plain envelope, because they don't ~want people to know where 
I came from. If it won't make any difference to you. I like 
school here very much. Give my love to Mrs. Weber and all 
the officers, and tell Tillie to write me soon. I would like to see 

you all. but not bad enough to go back. Hoping to see you this 
summer. I must close. 

Your friend. M 

Dear Friend Mr. Weber: I received your kind and lovely letter, 
and was glad to hear from you. I am getting along very 
nicely with Mrs. W . The work is not hard, but I am busy 
most of the time. Sunday is my day. I was at church this morning.. 
It was so nice. I saw papa last Sunday. He said to tell 
you when I wrote that he was thankful to you for getting me 
such a nice home. Tell the girls I send my best regards to all 
of them. Tell M to be good and get that place that is wait 
ing for her. When you write you must tell me all the girls that 
go away. I may visit you Christmas, but don't tell the girls. I 
am so sleepy that I can hardly hold my eyes open, so good bye 
for this time. From your girl, M . 

Mr. Weber. — Dear Sir and All: Was glad to receive your letter. 
We are all well and hope you are, and that the girls are 
good. I wish the girls could all get a good home like mine. I 
just have the nicest time. * * * I went to Sunday school last 
Sunday and am going every Sunday. I attend the M. E. church. 

, March 27. 1900. </seg>


            <seg id="p013">61 

girls' industrial school. 

Just think, we had nine for dinner and seven for supper. So 
there were lots of dishes for Mrs. M and poor me. Did anybody 
bake you a birthday cake? 

Your patient pupil, J 

I give here a few letters from those with whom we have found 
homes for the girls. Space forbids my giving more, but I have 
many such: 

B. R. B. Weber, Geneva, Neb. — Dear Sir: I have been intend- 

ing to write to you, but have neglected it. We are getting along 
nicely. M is a good girl. Please tell me what is necessary 
now, according to your rules, to keep her. I think I would rather 
have her as one of the family. She is too young to be kept out 
of school. I think M is conscientious and tries to do the right 
when she understands what I want. Everything considered, I 
would not be willing to exchange her for any girl I have ever 

had. I remain. 

Respectfully your 

Mrs. M 

March 13, 1900. 

Mr. B. R. B. Weber.— Dear Sir 
lines to let you know how we are 

and Friend: I drop you a few 
getting along. S seems at 

home now. She finds plenty to do to keep her busy and from 
being homesick for the school. She is well satisfied with her 
place and seems to enjoy herself very well, and we are well 
pleased with her. Trusting that you are getting along well at 
vour school. I remain, 

July 18, 1900. 

Mr. B. R. B. Weber, Geneva, Neb. — Dear Sir: I must say that 
I am well pleased with L . and would like to have her stay 
with me for years, if she continues to be a good girl. It is so 
much more satisfactory to me to keep the same girl than to be 
changing. * * * L is enclosing a letter to you. I don't 
know what she is writing. I think she has been somewhat lonesome 
but seems quite happy now. Of course, my home is quiet. 
I think the organ helps her considerable. Hoping to hear from 
you, I remain. 

Respectfully, 

Mrs. B 

, Aug. 27. 

Respectfully, C. E </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
62 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Mr. Weber — Dear Sir: We like M real well. She is a 
very nice girl, and we will try and do our part by her while 
under our care. We have church and Sunday school, which she 
attends regularly. Can go every Sunday. She seems satisfied. 

• • • 

Yours truly, Mr. and Mrs. P , 

July 17, 1900. 

Dear Sir: I suppose you are wondering why we don't write 
about the dear girl. She is well and seemingly happy, and we 
are perfectly satisfied with her. She is obedient, kind, and 
anxious to do that which is for her good. She takes a great 
interest in the Sunday school and league, and I am sure if she 
continues as well that we will never want to part with her. One 
thing we admire in M is, she is so quiet and modest, — a 
most beautiful thing in a woman. 

Yours truly, Mrs. J — 

Dear Mr. Weber: I am well_ pleased with M . and will let 
you hear from time to time how she gets along. I think her 

;ets alone. I think her 

very nice. Will be very glad to 
you come to . 

have you call on us whenevf 

Very respectfully. 

Mrs. W 

March 18, l!HMi. 

Mr. Weber: Mr. P and my: 
M , and feel trulv that the ri 

self are very much pleased with 
jht one has come to claim our 

love and protection. It has always been a characteristic of my 
nature to sympathize with the unfortunate and try to relieve 
their trouble whenever I have an opportunity. Hoping that all 
can be done will be for the dear girl's best interest. I will close. 

Yours with much respect, Mrs. P 

Our girls go to bed, get up, go to school, play, work, have their 
meals, both church and Sunday school, prayer meeting, and in 
fact everything, to the tap of the bell. And these regular habits 
make it so healthful that many who come here emaciated in 
three months have gained from ten to thirty pounds. Our girls 
are fed from the same piece of meat, the same flour or bread, the 
same vegetables, the same butter (which is bought from the 
farmers, except what we make), as the officers have. They have 
cake nearly as often as the officers, with a few exceptions when </seg>


            <seg id="p015">63 

girls' industrial school. 

there is company in the institution. Each girl has a nice spring 
bed, always kept clean, and plenty of cover to keep them comfortable. 
They are dressed alike as near as possible, and, as 
you will see elsewhere in this report, make all their clothes, wash 
and iron the same, and keep them in shape at all times. 

The persistent efforts of parents and others to have girls released 
who have not earned their ''honor*' works great injustice 
to those who have no such friends, and all such efforts should be 
discouraged, especially where there is no money consideration, a 
hired attorney, etc. The very poorest should have every chance 
for release that is accorded to those more able and better 
educated. In this connection I have decided to incorporate 
herein the rules of the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings in 
relation to this institution. 

RILES AND REGULATIONS OF THE GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL 

SCHOOL. 

The following rules and regulations for the future government 
the officers and employees and the discipline of the inmates 

of the Girls' Industrial School for Juvenile l&gt;elinquents art 
hereby adopted by the Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings: 

FFICEE 

The officers of the Girls' Industrial School shall consist of the 
superintendent and his corps of assistants, to- wit: book-keeper 
and steward, matron, and family managers. All others employed 
in the school shall be designated as employees. The 
assistants are required to aid the superintendent, in every possible 
way, to enforce the following rules and regulations, and any 
neglect to render such assistance will be sufficient cause for 
relief from duty. 

SUPERINTENDENT 

The superintendent shall have control and management of the </seg>


            <seg id="p016">64 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S RKPOHT. 

school, subject, however, to instructions from the Board. He 
shall present a monthly report to the Board showing: 

1st, The number of inmates in attendance. 

2d, The number of commitments during the month 
3d, The number of paroles granted. 

4th, General condition of the school 

5th, Any suggestions or recommendations that he may think 
proper. 

He shall cause to be kept an account of all daily expenditures, 
which shall be certified to the Board in duplicate vouchers at 
the end of each month. 

He shall decide upon the admission of each commitment and 
the dismissal of each inmate. 

He shall keep a record showing 
1st. The name of each inmate. 
2d, When received. 

3d, From what county 

4th, From whom received. 
5th, Cause of commitment 

6th, By what authority committed. 

7th, Previous social, moral, and educational condition. 

The superintendent shall have power to appoint all employees 
and to discharge any employee, when in his judgment the in 
terest and harmony of the school require it. 

He shall have power to temporarily relieve from duty any 
officer for incompetency, immorality, neglect of duty or violation 
of any rule, which action on his part shall be at once certified 
to the Board for their consideration. 

The superintendent shall have power to excuse any officer 
from duty on account of absence or sickness, not to exceed 
twenty-four days in a year, and to excuse any employee not to 
exceed two weeks for the same causes. 

BOOK-KEEPER AND STEWARD 

The book-keeper shall also be the steward of the school, and </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
girls' industrial s« h 

65 

in I lit- absence of the superintendent shall perform bis duties. 
By virtue of his position he shall be secretary of the school. As 
book-keeper he shall keep account of all financial transactions 
of the institutions, and shall see that vouchers are properly made 
out at the end of each month. As secretary he shall perform any 
clerical duties the superintendent may require. 

FAMILY MANAGEE 

Th»- principal teacher of each family shall be called the family 
manager. Her duties shall be: 

1st, &lt;leneral supervision of those under her charge 

2d. To see that each inmate conducts herself in a modest and 

becoming manner. 

:td. To maintain proper cleanliness of each inmate 

4th, To give such instruction in the schoolroom as the superintendent 
may require. 

5th. To report the sick to the matron, and see that the re 
quireiuents of the physician are carried out. 

lith. To keep a daily record of each inmate's conduct. 

7th, She shall be held responsible for the playroom, schoolroom, 
and playground, dormitory, and for the enforcement of 
the rules pertaining thereto. 

MATROX 

The matron shall have general supervision of the domestic 
arrangements of the institution. She shall see that the work in 
sewing room, dining room, kitchen, and laundry is done in a 
proper and cleanly manner, and shall report all cases of mismanagement 
or any infringement of any rule to the superintendent. 


The Mrk shall be under her special care, and she shall see that 
thev receive careful attention, nourishment, and diet, as the 

case ?uay requirt 

EMPLOYEES. 

The employees shall consist of the housekeeping teacher, sew </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
LAKD COMMISSIONER'S KEPOKT 

66 

ing teacher, cooking teacher, two engineers, farmer, and gardener, 
and one man for general work. 

HOl'SEKEEt'Eli 

The housekeeper shall be assistant matron. She shall have 
in her charge a regular detail of girls, and teach them to keep 
the building, beds, bedding, and inmates' clothing in neat and 
healthful condition. 

SEWING TEACHKK. 

The sewing teacher shall have charge of a regular detail of 
iris and instruct them in cutting, fitting, making, and repair 

ing all garments for the inmates. 

'OOK1NC TKAI'HKI 

The cooking teacher shall have charge of a detail of girls, and 
teach them to make bread, pies, cakes, and to do all kinds of 
cooking, washing dishes, and other kitchen work neatly. als&lt;i 
instruct in canning and putting up fruil and vegetables in their 

season 

l.AUXKRY 

KACHEI 

The laundry teacher shall have in charge a detail of girls, and 
shall instruct them in washing, and ironing the clothes of the 

institution. 

ENUINEEK 

The engineers shall run the engine and electric light plan! and 
keep in repair the plant and other property to the best of their 
ability. 

FARMER AND CiAKDBXBR. 

The farmer and gardener shall care for the stock and bain and 
farm and garden, cut the meat for the cooking teacher, open and 
lock doors morning and evening. 

The other man takes the place of the night watchman, and is 
not an extra help. He shall carry the mail, run errands to town, 
and do any other work he is called upon to do. </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
67 

INUUSTKIAl- SCHOOL. 

GIKL8 

Tin- details shall be changed every three months, giving each 
iil a chance to learn the entire industrial work of the institu- 

tion, besides the regular school hours. 

The A and B classes shall not visit or converse with each 
other by talking or writing, except on special days agreed upon 
by the superintendent and matron given as a holiday. 

ENERAL RULES 

1st. Gentlemanly and ladylike decorum must be observed at 
ill times and places, and a courteous disposition manifested towards 
each other. 

26. After the inmates retire, all unnecessary noise, both in 
he building and on the premises, must cease. 

:',d. From May 15 to October 15 all lights in the living rooms 
must be extinguished at 10:30 p. m., except where permission 

is granted to the contrary by the superintendent, and from 
October 15 to May 15 the time shall be 10 p. m. 

4th. Officers and employees must not be absent from their 

rooms iifter the hour specified in rule three (3), unless excused 
by the superintendent. 

5th. Each person to whom the inmates are detailed shall see 
i hat they maintain proper discipline, and that they do not use 
improper language, or do violence to each other, or injure their 
own or the clothing of others, or mark or deface any of the 
property of the institution. 

lith. Each person must manage his or her department without 
infringing on the rights or duties of others, and any such in- 

terference must be promptly reported; nor must any article be 
taken from any department without the consent of the party in 
charge lor on the order of the party in charge!, or on the order 

f the superintendent. 

7th. Persons to whom inmates are detailed must be responsible 
for them. If the work assigned them is finished before the 

expiration of the regular time of detail, the person must report 
to the superintendent for further duty. </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
68 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S RErORT. 

8th. When the time of the regular details expires, all inmates 
must be promptly reported to the family manager by the person 
having charge, unless permission is granted by the superintendent 
to keep them longer, and the family manager is duly 

notified by the person asking the favor. 

9th. All persons employed at the institution shall attend all 
religious services on Sabbath, or whenever religious services are 
held, unless excused by the superintendent. 

10th. The superintendent shall assign to each officer and em 
ployee the regular duties required of him or her. and such special 
duties as he may see fit. 

11th. No intoxicating liquors shall be brought to the institn 
tion, except for medical purposes, and no person shall be em 
ployed in the school who at any time or place makes use of in 
toxicating liquors as a beverage. 

12th. Xo person regularly employed in the institution shall 
be absent without the permission of the superintendent. 

13th. No cigarettes or any narcotics shall be furnished or al 
lowed an inmate. Smoking or using tobacco in the building* 
are strictly forbidden at all times in the presence of the inmates 

14th. If. through the carelessness, negligence, or violation oi 
the rules, an inmate escapes, the person in charge will be inquired 
to pay the reward or expenses connected with her return 

RILES FOR INMATES. 

1. When a girl is received and recorded, the superintendent 
shall assign her to one of the following classes: 

(Mass 1. — For burglary, prostitution, forgery, perjury, and 
larceny, each inmate shall receive 6,000 demerits. 

Class 2. — For incorrigibility. disorderly conduct, assault, and 
similar offenses, each inmate shall receive 5,000 demerits. 

( Class 3. — For vagrancy, medicancy. and the like, each inniat 
shall receive 4.000 demerits. 

2. If the commitment papers do not distinctly specify the 
nature of the offense, the superintendent shall assign her to the 
&lt; lass he may think just. </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
69 

owls' industrial school. 

3. For imiusf i-ious habits, good deportment, and careful attention 
to studies, each inmate shall receive ten merit marks each 
day, which shall cancel a like number of demerit marks. 

4. For a perfect record during the entire month, an inmate 
shall receive twenty-five extra merits, and if a perfect record is 
maintained during three successive months, an additional reward 
of one hundred merits will be given. 

."&gt;. For furnishing correct information of inmates planning to 
escape, such informer shall receive one hundred merits for each 
and everv case. 

t». For attempting to escape, all merits due will be cancelled, 
and such additional punishment shall be given as the superintendent 
mav order. 

7. For misdemeanors committed in the school, inmates shall 
receive punishment according to the offenses. 

S. Corporal punishment cannot be inflicted except on order of 
the superintendent. 

9. When all the demerits of an inmate are cancelled and she 
has been perfect during one entire month, called the "honor 
month." a leave of absence of four months may be granted,' 
which will entitle the holder to leave the school, provided a suitable 
home is found. If good conduct and industrious habits are 
maintained, this leave of absence will be renewed for one year, 
and annually thereafter until majority is attained. Nothing in 
the foregoing rules shall prevent the Board from giving the 
superintendent authority to grant tickets of leave at any time, 
whenever the best interests of the inmate are subserved thereby. 

10. Each inmate shall be furnished a stamp and material to 
write home once a month. An inmate may write an additional 
letter each month if parents furnish stamps and material. Letit'ts 
written to the inmates of an unkind or uncivil nature will be 
returned to the writer. , 

11. Parents may visit their children semi-annually. but must 
not expect to he entertained more than one night at a time. No </seg>


            <seg id="p022">LAM&gt; COMMISSIONER'S KEPOHT. 

70 

visiting will be allowed on the Sabbath or during holidays except 
by special arrangement with the superintendent. 

V2. All ULLCWMrj clothing will be furnished each inmate, 
but relatives may send presents of inexpensive articles for personal 
use. such as tooth brushes, combs, handkerchiefs, mittens, 
neckties, hair ribbons, or any kind of innocent amusements. 
Suitable reading matter will be furnished inmates, but it is 
recommended that copies of the home paper or some good maga 
z.ine be sent in case relatives wish to show their children special 

favor. 

Kl Any girl having been committed to the Girls' Industrial 
School at Geneva, must be cancelled at least one-half her demerits, 
or prove to the Board that she was sent here, or sent back 
on her demerits in the school, or account of prejudice or error, be 
fore a parole or pardon will be recommended, without the Board 
first having evidence that the girl is to be provided with a proper 
home until she reaches the age of twenty-one. 

14. As far as practicable, each inmate attends school foil 
hours a day. and works four hours a day. Ample time is give 
for recreation and reading. Regularity of meals and hours &lt; 

sleep are observed. 

15. Any girl is at any time allowed to be placed in a home on 
trial, when she is on her honor, and when the superintendent and 
matron are satisfied that the home is a proper, place for the girl 
to go. and are satisfied that the girl can be trusted on her honor, 
and in every case those taking such girls from the school on 
trial shall give a receipt to the superintendent for them, subject, 
however, to the rules of the institution while in their care, and 
can not turn them over to other parties without the conseni of 

the superintendent. 

16. In every case of parole or pardon, the superintendent will 

be permitted to report and advise with the Board 

17. When a girl's record shows that she is trying hard to d&lt; 

right and cancel her demerits, some other punishment beside 

cancelling merits is recommended, and in no case should all her 

merits be cancelled for trivial offenses </seg>


            <seg id="p023">71 

(WKLS 

INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

is. No girl should be permitted to go out into the world without 
some suitable pi iw in charge. 

1!». &lt;iirls may be allowed to cancel demerit* by doing. extra 
work, or raking punishment when at their own request,71 

(WKLS 

INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

is. No girl should be permitted to go out into the world without 
some suitable pi iw in charge. 

1!». &lt;iirls may be allowed to cancel demerit* by doing. extra 
work, or raking punishment when at their own request,^&gt;ut will 
not be permitted to dictate how or what work or punishment 
sliiill be. 

20. No jjirl shall couversewith men who are employed or who 
shall visit the institution or premises, without the permission 

of the superintendent or matron (but this does not mean that 
they shall not* recognize each other as they chance to meet* or 

|.ilSS 

These rules may be altered or amended at any time it is 
Ifciiii'il necessary. 

\dnpted the 7th day of October. IXiil. 

J. V. WoLKE, 

Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. 

\Y. F. Porteij. 

Secretary of State. 

•I. 

B. Mkskhve 

State Treasurer. 

( ' 

I. Smyth 

Attorney General. 

uiiiug superintendent of this institution. I have been 

Sin 

iski-d several questions by legislative committees and others, 
md ;i* the close of my term approaches I feel that I can answer 

and 

I lii-in without bias or prejudice, and I embody niv conclusions 
here for the benefit of such as may be interested. 
A question often asked. "Should the superintendent have au- 

thority to employ or discharge?" I might ask in return. Is the 
superintendent responsible? If he is. and he was an officer of 
a corporation whose purjK&gt;se was the making of money for its 
stockholders, there would be no divided opinion as to the an 
swer. But the management of a state institution such as this 
is only rlie work of protecting and saving the lives of the nn 
fortunate and the erring. Its lesser importance as compared gt;ut will 
not be permitted to dictate how or what work or punishment 
sliiill be. 

20. No jjirl shall couversewith men who are employed or who 
shall visit the institution or premises, without the permission 

of the superintendent or matron (but this does not mean that 
they shall not* recognize each other as they chance to meet* or 

|.ilSS 

These rules may be altered or amended at any time it is 
Ifciiii'il necessary. 

\dnpted the 7th day of October. IXiil. 

J. V. WoLKE, 

Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. 

\Y. F. Porteij. 

Secretary of State. 

•I. 

B. Mkskhve 

State Treasurer. 

( ' 

I. Smyth 

Attorney General. 

uiiiug superintendent of this institution. I have been 

Sin 

iski-d several questions by legislative committees and others, 
md ;i* the close of my term approaches I feel that I can answer 

and 

I lii-in without bias or prejudice, and I embody niv conclusions 
here for the benefit of such as may be interested. 
A question often asked. "Should the superintendent have au- 

thority to employ or discharge?" I might ask in return. Is the 
superintendent responsible? If he is. and he was an officer of 
a corporation whose purjK&gt;se was the making of money for its 
stockholders, there would be no divided opinion as to the an 
swer. But the management of a state institution such as this 
is only rlie work of protecting and saving the lives of the nn 
fortunate and the erring. Its lesser importance as compared </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
72 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

with money-making, in this utilitarian age, may in The minds 
of some justify a different answer. If you were going To build 
a house, would you want to be told who you should take to do 
the woi-^ regardless of qualifications, even though the employee 
was a political friend? Would you think of selecting a captain 
for a ship or a man to run an engine because you owe him a 
favor? What would be discipline in the army if the authority 
of the commander could be questioned by subordinates? A 
superintendent may abuse his powers, but should he be held responsible 
for his helpers when he has had no voice in their selection? 
In industrial life, one person not in harmony with the 
management and spirit of the institution can do mow harm 
than twenty faithful workers can do good. If the motive of an 
efficient employee is to confer real benefit on the inmates, lie 
will not be interested in who is his real superior, the superintendent 
or the board, and the question of authority will rarely 
arise. 

I can speak dispassionately on this subject, because the Hoard 
have allowed me to select all but two of my force, for which 1 
am deeply grateful; and from the further fact that in the four 
years of my management we have found it necessary ii&gt; make 
a change in hut one office and of but one employee. Hut the 

more I study the question, the 
every one in the force of an 
through whom are carried out 
by its head, and whenever they 
out his orders, that moment thf 
to each other. 

more fully I am convinced that 
institution becomes an agent 
the proper measures suggested 
from any cause decline ti&gt; carry 
•y should sever their relationship 

Superintendent Hancock, of 

stitutions should be run for the good of the public, rather than 
the good of any partisan organization. The duties of officers 
in state institutions require much ability and talent, and will 
improve as much as teachers in the public schools. A change of 
administration causes unrest among the inmates, and disorganizes 
future plans, and creates uneasiness and disorganization. 
Position should depend ujKin ability. Find a man peculiarly 

Topeka. Kan., says: "Publii- in </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
HIRES' IXOrSTRIAL BCBOOL. 

73 

Utted, surround bin with good help, and you need have but 
little fear of the results." 

Superintendent Brown, of Red Wing. Minn., says: "Where 
appointments are made and vacancies created in any institution 
for political reasons only, the usefulness of such an institution 
is at an end." 

And while I endorse the above, it cannot be said that it is 
because of any partisan spirit, as I had made every arrangement 
to vacate under the four-year ruling of our Governor. However, 
let me add one word; you cannot overestimate the influence of 
the personal acquaintance with each inmate, and it takes time 
to be even able to call them by name. An institution should 
never be largely officered by the members of the same family. 

I have been asked if our institution could not be successfully 
ran with less help. It is difficult to estimate just what the effect 
of a recent supreme court decision will be upon the number of 
persons who will in the future be incarcerated in this institution. 
1 am not a lawyer; but unless some provision is made 

in the laws of the state, it seems to me that it must diminish 
the number of inmates so that a curtailment of the force will 
not only be possible but necessary. But aside from this, I have 
always believed that the physician to the institution should be 
a woman. Some of the reasons for this conclusion will be evident 
to anyone who gives the matter a moment's thought, and 
there are other and powerful reasons, which from their nature, 
could with more propriety be explained to a legislative committee 
than incorporated in this report. 

But the salary of the physician has been inadequate to compensate 
a physician for his entire time. The matron has the 
genera 1 care of the sick, and if these two offices could be consolidated, 
the salary of both offices would be adequate to secure 
the services of a person competent in both capacities. This 
would insure the presence of a physician in the institution. 
This is simply a suggestion. I would have made the suggestion 
two years ago, but as the positions were then filled it might have 
seemed to have a i&gt;ersonal application. As vacancies will occur </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
74 

LAN!) COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

in these |;osil ions al the beguiling of the year, the suggestion 
can stand on its merits. 

Another &lt;iuestion that lias been asked me is. Do von think 
ilif superintendent should be a woman? I would have to sec 
the experiment tried before 1 could answer in the affirmative. 
I believe that similar institutions in some of the states have 
lady superintendents, hut I have no definite information as to 
the character of their workings. There are times in institutions 
of this character when physical character is necessary — 
when physical force is the only power recognized by angry human 
beings, rebellious against confinement and pining for lib 
erty. I have seen all the women in our instiiution defied, and 
we have as good women as live, yet 1 can not conceive how 
they could have succeeded unaided. I do not think that any of 
the women connected with the institution, after four years" experience, 
would favor a woman as superintendent, or think it 
best. I am a great champion of woman and of her right to position, 
and fully recognize her ability and the value of her ad 
vice to me in the last four years, but 1 have had to do things 
in the position that a woman could not well do. I have tramped 
all night through mud and water tracking girls who were endeavoring 
to escape, and who would have succeeded if this were 
not done. 

There is a subject to which I wish to call your attention. I 
have talked with other sui»erintendents. and all are agreed that 
something should be done. What is to be done with inmates 
who are nearly of age and know that they cannot be detained 
longer than their majority? They don't care for reports or their 
record. They will run away every chance they get. and always 
try to take others with them. In actions and ofttimes in vfords 
they will say. "You can't keep me here longer than my next 
birthday." etc. Their influence and example are a menace n&gt; 

the discipline of the school. The importance of some action by 
1 Ik- legislature that will deal with this difficulty successfulh 
cannot be urged too strongly. If a. place could be provided, 
well fenced in and with plenty of work, where they could !&gt;&lt;¦ </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
lilRI.S 

IMHSTRIAl. SCHOOL. 

75 

fd until their records were made clean by good behavior 
Of course, the statute would have to be changed so that 

committed to the institution would be discharged not by 
rion (if time, but by pood conduct and deserving behavior. 

It []&lt;\&lt; cmild be done. I do not think there would be many who 

have to be transferred, as the knowledge would worl 

jtive if not a curt 

ii 

Then there are a few girls committed to the institution who 

weak intellect, and wh 
Ives. even when of age 

will never be able to care for 
and who may yet be on their 

They aie able to work sufficient to earn their support 
had some one to look after them, but without this re- 

ug influence they are permitted to go out into the world 
i degrade society and disgrace themselves. I understand 
if state lias an extra building at Kearney that could proh¦ 
arranged and used for such purposes at a small expense. 

n institution might be called "Industrial Keformity" or 
of Correction." and its purpose to finish a perfect record. 

\ place for those who fail to work out "on their honor" before 
irriving ;ir their majority is necessary to the most perfect work 

cliools. Inmates of the schools would know then that 
j;(mm1 conduct could they ever hope to secure their free- 

hen, too. in such ;i reformatory, more of a prison disci 
uld be enforced than has been deemed best for tht 

1 fully realize that such an arrangement would not 
t great help to our industrial schools, but would lessen 

r of sentences to our state penitentiary. Some one 
lid. "The hope of the world lies in the children." and 

ion of clime is of more importance than its punishment. 
ill study of the needs and spirit of the institution soon 
ed the Board as well as myself, and it has been our set- 

to avoid the tilling up of the institution so far as pos 

ible with justice to the committed and protection to society 

as a girl 1ms worked out her "honor" and cancelled her 

\* 

demerits, and made a clear record, we have found a home tot 

she had none of her own. We have alwavs had a snfti </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
76 

land commissioner's rei-ort. 

cient BUtber of applications to choose from to enable us to 
select one where the environment warranted the hope of continued 
good conduct. The country home was given the preference, 
and results have justified this decision. A very large per 
cent of the girls so located are doing well and move in the best 
society. It is true that some go wrong, but. perhaps, no greater 
per cent than of other girls outside with no better surroundings. 

Some parents will beg the superintendent and the Board to 
release a girl when we feel that she is not ready to go. and when 
she is released, soon beg the harder to have her returned. This 
is very detrimental to the school. Acting on this policy of find 
ing homes for the girls and paroling them when worthy, coupled 
with the failure of the last legislature to provide by appropriation 
for the payment of the fees of sheriffs for bringing juvenile 
delinquents to the school, the number of inmates in the institution 
has materially decreased during the past four years. For 
months at a time, there would not be a single commitment, 
while some were going out all the time. After a girl lias been in 
a home on trial, and all are satisfied, the board have irenerallv 
granted a parol, and we then have but little fear of her future 
us she then becomes one of the family, and with fear of the past 
and hoi»e for the future she usually proves a worthy member 
of society. 

We have been censured for giving the girls too much freedom. 
for not using the "rod," and for, taking them to church in town 
as a family, when the weather would |&gt;ermit. etc. Rut it was not 
long before every minister in the city was asking them to conu. 
to his particular church. We were told that they would rake 
advantage of such treatment, and would run away. A few have 
tried to escape — none have succeeded, and we would l&gt;e pleased 
to have the records examined as to the number who have tried 
to escape and the expense thereby incurred, as compared with 
any other four years of the institution. Another fact to which 
I .would call your attention is that the state has not been to a 
single dollar's expense for property destroyed maliciously under 
this administration. </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
GIKLS" INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

77 

The legislature of four years ago cut down the appropriation 

asked for by my predecessor, and allowed the sum of |38,800 
for the liienniuni, f750 of which was a deficiency of the previous 
biennium. and still we were able to turn back into the treasury 

the sum of f:i,20H.!tl of that appropriation at the end of the two 
years. The legislature of two years ago again reduced the 

amount appropriated to $35,790, or $3,000 less than the amount 
appropriated for the previous biennium. At this writing, November 
3t». 1900. twenty of the twenty-four months of the biennium 
have passed, and there is to the credit of the institution 

in the hands of the state treasurer the sum of f 12,301.70, or more 

than one-third of the appropriation, with a period of only four 
months yet to run. If the remaining months of the biennium are 
conducted on the same basis of economy, there will be in the 

neighborhood of $8,000 to turn back into the treasury of the 

present appropriations. And yet the girls will tell you that 
they have never been better fed and clothed than during the 

past four years 

We do have to punish sometimes. It is pretty hard for a 

girl to have to go to the "washtub, who has alwavs done as she 

pleased. Besides putting them on "'silence," giving reports and 
marginals, etc., we may take off special work that cancels demerits, 
and if unmanageable, put them in solitary confinement. 

They often beg to be allowed to take the last mentioned punish- 

incel demerits, and clear their records. I have known 

Hi' 

oluntarily go in for a week in order, to keep a "perfect 

niupi I 

Iii conclusion, let me say that it is impossible to live with 

these children without becoming attached to them. They look 
to you as a father. — some know no other living relative. I de- 

Id 

i-onveT our thanks and appreciation for the kindness we 
een shown (often under most trying circumstances) to 

¦veiv -'ill who has been under our care, and to assure them 

were freely forgiven when they have fallen short of 

doing their full duty, and to express the hope that we were a-* 
freelv forgiven the mistakes we have made. For, while we feel </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
78 

LAMl COMMISSIONEU's REPORT. 

rrnimnhlj pleased with the results i» the past four years, we 
are not perfect, and had our experience covered four times four 
years. I doubt not we could still look back and see where we 
might improve. 

And now in leaving these girls, it is mv greatest desire that 
my successor shall be a man with a great bin Christian hear! 
full of sympathy for the unfortunate. And to such I will say 
that if there is anything in my power that I can do. in the way 
of advice or suggestion, that will assist in making the future 
of the school more successful, that I will be only too glad to do. 

To successfullv carrv into effect tin* affairs of the institurioi 

as intended, must cost some money, aud. while the work must 
be done, it should be done right, but at the least possible expense. 
It now becomes my duty to estimate the amount of appropriations 
required for the next biennial period. In most 
cases we have asked for the same amounts that were asked 
for two years ago. The amount asked for salaries and em- 

Deficiency employees" w r ages 115 00 

ployees" wages is the same as asked for in the last 

le 

four years. 

Salary of superintendent, for two years 

*:!.ooo 00 

Salary of matron, for two years 

l.iiOO l»0 

Salary of clerk and steward, for Two years 

1.000 &lt;MI 

Salary two family managers, two years 

:',.2OO 00 

Employees' wages. I wo years 

. . . !».()00 00 

Medic-ine and medical attendance, two years 

. . . 1.500 00 

Placing children in homes, two vears 

(.50 00 

Fuel and lights, two years 

. . . 0.000 (10 

Water supply, two years 

. . . 1.450 00 

School, library, office supplies, two years 

1.0O0 00 

Board and clothing, two years 

15,000 00 

Repairs and improvements, two years 

1.000 00 

Furniture, kitchen and dining room, two years. . . 

750 oo 

Music and amusement, two years 

250 00 

Telephone, telegraph, freight, etc.. two years 

250 00 

Live stock, carriages, harness, etc.. two years 

250 00 

Incidental expenses, two years 

200 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
79 

&lt;;ikls 

ixnrsTisi.u. arHOOi,. 

W hile this amount is much less than was asked last session 
for current expenses. I believe it will be sufficient. The reason 
there seems to be a deficiency in the employees" wages requires 
a brief explanation. The first two years we had an old engine 
that had to be repaired in some particular nearly every % day or 
night, and made necessary the constant attendance of both 
engineers. 1'nder the rules adopted, each of the engineers was 
entitled to a vacation in each year, but neither ever received 
a day off until during the past year. Our appropriation was 
barely sufficient to cover the time, allowing one engineer to lay 
off half time during the summer months. The matter was presented 
to Hon. J. Y. Wolfe, rommissioner. and Hon. \Y. F. 
Porter. Secretary of State, as chairman and secretary of the 
Board, and I was instructed to pay the engineers for the extra 
time so employed. The appropriation is sufficient to pay in 
full all wages to January 1. 1901, but as three mouths would 
then elapse before the new appropriation would become available. 
1 ask that this sum of fllo be allowed as a claim of deficiency, 
that the engineers may not have to wait three months 
for their wages for the first three months of the year. 

A matter that 1 must call to your attention is that our drainage 
is deposited in large wells. In the spring, when we have 
heavy rains, these wells overflow, and at times run over the 
land adjacent, to the great annoyance of the owners. We have 
dammed up a kind of a pond to hold these overflows till the 
wells take it up again, but I am convinced that some other provision 
will have to be made within the next two years: the 
repair and improvement fund should be raised with the understanding 
that it shall be used only for this particular purpose. 
The amount necessary is hard to estimate, as it is difficult to 
fell the best way to overcome the trouble — but say $500. 

As these recommendations are special. I would ask for them 
separately from the general appropriations, and if not granted 
it would be understood that the work was not to be done.</seg> 

            <seg id="p032">
80 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

APPROPRIATION'S ASKED FOR SPECIAL PURPOSES. 

For improvement of system of sewerage $500 (Mi 

For ministers who act as chaplain ($3 per day). $150 petannum 
300 0d 

You* will tind appended statistical tables that are worthy of 
your careful study, also the physician's report, and the extraordinary 
expenses. I feel that I cannot submit this report without 
again speaking a word of praise for the noble efforts of my 
faithful assistants in the work. And in conclusion to thank you. 
Governor and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, for the 
earnest and hearty co-operation you have given me in carrying 
on this great work for the poor unfortunates of our beloved 
state. Very obediently submitted. 

B. R. B. Weber, 

Superintendent 

Table No 

Girls received since July 15. 1891 41 » 
(Jirls paroled and discharged 304 

(Jills died 

Girls sent to Insane Hospital 

Girls sent to Beatrice Institution (Feeble-minded Institute). 1 

Table No 

Girls received from former superintendent (February. 1896) 

Girls received since, to November 30. 1900 

30 

Girls paroled and released since, to November 30. 1000 

4:. 

Girls died from November 30, 1898 to November 30. 1900 

1 

Girls sent to Beatrice Institute since February. 1890 1 

Girls sent to Insane Hospital since February. 1890 

1 

Girls in school November 30, 1900 

1 </seg>

            <seg id="p033">STATISTICAL TABLKS 


girls' industrial school. 

81 

Table X'o. 3. 

.Showing Number Received Each Year. 

1891 19 

1881 6 

1882 5 

1892 51 

1883 9 

1893 29 

1884 5 

1894 32 

1885 8 

1895 26 

isst; 9 

1896 40 

1887 19 

1897 19 

1888 27 

1898 20 

IN89 34 

1899 IT 

1890 27 

1900 13 

Total 417 

Table No. 4. 

Showing &lt; 'uiimiitiiifiits by Counties. 

Counties Present Bienniuui. Previously. Totals. 

Adams 0 14 14 

Buffalo 2 20 22 

Butler 0 

•&gt; 

.; 

Kurt 1 

• &gt; 

Bnonf 0 

Clav 0 4 4 

Chevenne 

0 4 4 

&lt; 'lister 

(I 

•&gt; 

• &gt; 

&lt; "ass 

1 6 7 

Col fax 

0 1 . 1 

Cherrv 

0 7 7 

( 'miring 0 

•&gt; 

• &gt; 

Cedar 0 

•&gt; 

9. 

D.iwes 

•&gt; 

L.T, 

1'S 

I »;i wson 1 6 7 

Dodge 1 8 9 

Douglas 3 27 30 

•&gt;7 

Fillmore 2 7 9 

9. 

t 

i. </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
82 

LAXD COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

» 

Counties Present Biennium. Previously. Total 

Frontier 0 

Franklin 2 2 4 

Furnas 0 

¦ ) 

Gage 2 18 20 

&lt; i reelev 0 1 1 

Hall 0 12 12 

Holt 0 

Harlan 0 

Howard 0 1 

Hamilton 0 

Johnson 1 t&gt; 

Jefferson 0 *i t&gt; 

Kearney 

ii 

Lancaster 

Loop 

ii 

Lincoln 0 4 4 

4 

Kuox 

Merrick 

MePherson 
Nance . . . . 

Xemaha 

XiN-kolls 

4 

Otoe 

Pierce 1 

Polk 

Pawnee (I 

Phelps 1 

Platte 0 

Richardson 

Red Willow 

Seward 

(I 

Sarpy &lt;• 

Saline 0 

Stanton 1 

Sheridan </seg>


            <seg id="p035">83 

girls" industrial" school 

Counties Present Biennium. Previously. Totals. 

Thaver 4 

•&gt; 

i 

Valley 0 

o o 

¦&gt; 

Washington 0 

•&gt; 

Wavne 0 1 1 

Webster 0 5 5 

York 0 1 1 

&lt;&gt; * 

Not recorded 0 

Table No. 5. 

Showing Ages When Committed 

Age. " Present Biennium. Previously. Totals. 

Five vears 0 1 1 

Six vears 0 1 1 

Seven years - 7 9 

Eight years „ &lt;• 

Nine vears 1 !•"&gt; !•&gt; 

Ten vears 1 9 1»&gt; 

Eleven vears 1 lit 20 

Twelve vears 2 2i 2'.) 

Thirteen vears :! 40 4:'» 

Fourteen years 

4 6!» "3 

11 96 107 

Fill een years 

Sixteen vears C 47 

.).. 

...:... 2 r&gt; ii 

Seventeen vears 

Not recorded • 0 24 24 

Table No. »&gt;. 

Showing Parentage of the Inmates 

Nationality. Present Biennium. Previously. Totala 

Irish 2 II 11 

Americans 21 14(1 137 

Negro - 27 30 

Scandinavians 0 4 4 

Bohemian 0 

s s </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
84 

LAMi &lt;n.\£ilISl810XER's REPORT. 

Nationality. Present Bienniuni. Previously. Totals 

German 0 30 .50 

Scotch 0 

• &gt; 

Pole 0 1 1 

Hebrew 0 1 1 

Knglish 2 10 12 

• &gt; 

French 0 4 4 

Russian 0 1 1 

Not recorded 0 132 132 

Unknown 0 

., 

Tablk Xo. 7. 

Showing Social &lt; 'ondition When Committed. 
Present Bienuiuin. Previously. Total 

Showing Social Condition When Committed. 

Present Bienuium. Previously. Totals 

Both parents living 21 102 123 

Jtoth parents living 21 102 123 

Live together 7 &lt;&gt;•'{ 70 

Live together 7 03 70 

Live separate 16 56 72 

TO 

i _ 

Father dead 12 4n 58 

Father dead 12 40 58 

Mother dead 14 50 04 

Mother dead 14 50 04 

Either parent intemperate 4 :&lt;5 .'It) 

Either parent intemperate 4 35 31) 

Nothing known 3 120 12i&gt; 

Nothing known 3 120 12i&gt; 

Tahi.k No S. 

Table So. 8. 

Showing Cause of Coiumitment. 
Present Biennium. Previousl.v. Total 

Knowing Cans*' of Commitment. 

Present Hienniuia. Previously. Totals 

Porgerr (I 2 2 

Forirerv 

ii 

Vagrancy 2 33 :?5 

Vagrancy 

Mendicancy 0 •!&lt;&gt; :'.&lt;&gt; 

Mendicancy 0 30 :'.O 

Incorrifribility in vice 20 168 188 

Incorrigibility in vice 20 168 188 

Assault 0 :? :? 

Assault 0 

Prostitution nailed vice by judge).. 7 70 7(1 

Prostitution nailed vice hv judge). . 7 70 70 

Larceny 1 21 

Disorderly conduct 0 49 49 

Obtaining goods false pretenses.... 0 1 1 

Not recorded 0 2 

¦&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
IRI.S 

INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL 

85 

Table Xo. 9. 

Showing Proceeds from Farm Last Bieiiniuin 

&lt; 'm-umbers. .1(1 bushels $50 00 

Potato**. 1.100 bu WM» 00 

lieans. 12 liu Xi 00 

Sugar corn. 200 bu 100 00 

Pop corn, 65 l&gt;u 40 00 

Beets, (id bu 15 00 

Turnips, ."&gt;."&gt; bn 15 00 

Tomatoes. 1(10 bu 50 00 

Watermelons, (&gt; wagon loads 50 00 

Squashes, 2 wagon loads 20 00 

Pi«' plant. (i(H» jxiunda 25 00 

Lettuce, radishes, onionn. parsnips, and green beans. . 60 00 

&lt; 'abbage. 5.0H0 heads 200 00 

Millet and cane. 30 tons 150 00 

Alfalfa. 10 tons 30 00 

Clover, 5 tons 20 00 

Pasture, two vears 80 00 

&lt; 'hi.kens. 400 75 00 

Feed of all kinds 200 00 

SIATKON'S RKl'ORT OF DETAIL WORK. 

Family A. 
1899. 

Family A. 

Family B. 
1899. 
First Quarter. 

Family B. 
1899. 

18!&gt;!t. 

First Quarter 

First Quarter 

First Quarter. 

Housework R 

Housework R 

Housework 2 

Housework 

•-&gt; 

Kitchen 6 

Kitchen 8 

Kitchen 8 

Kitchen 6 

Sewing room 4 

Sewing room 4 

Sewing room 12 

Sewing room 12 

Laundry 6 

Laundry 9 

Lanndrv 6 

Second Quarter. 

Second Quarter. 

Second Quarter. 

Housework 6 

Housework 6 

Housework 2 

Kitchen fi 

Kitchen fi 

Kitchen 8 

Sewinj; room 4 

Sewing room 4 

Sewing room 13 

Sewing room 13 

Lanndrr ft 

Lanndrv (I 

Laundrv 8 

Laundrv 8 </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
86 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

Famil.v A. 
1899. 

Familv A. 

Family B. 
1899. 

Family K. 

1809. 

1899 

Third Quarter. 

Third Quarter. 

Third Quarter. 

Third Quarter. 

Housework 

Housework 2 

o 

Honsework 7 

Housework 

i 

Kitchen * 6 

Kitchen 6 

Kitchen 10 

Kitchen io 

Sewing room 5 

Sewing room 5 

Sewing room g 

Sewing room 

S 

Laundry 6 

Laundry fi 

Laundry 7 

Laundry 

i 

Fourth Quarter. 

Fourth Quarter. 

Fourth Quarter. 

Fourth Quarter. 

Housework 6 

Housework 6 

Housework 2 

Housework 

•&gt; 

Kitchen 6 

Kitchen 6 

Kitchen 10 

Kitchen io 

dewing room 5 

dewing room 5 

Sewing room 14 

Sewing room 14 

Laundry 6 

Laundry 6 

Laundry # 
1900. 
First Quarter. 

Laundry 

8 

1900. 

1900. 

1900. 

First Quarter. 

First Quarter. 

First Quarter. 

Housework 5 Housework 2 

Kitchen 6 Kitchen 

in 

Sewing room 3 Sewing room 15 

Laundry 6 Laundry 

!l 

Second Quarter. Second Quarter 

Housework 5 Housewor 

Kitchen 6 Kitchen 

ID 

Sewing room 3 Sewing room 11 

Laundry 6 Laundry 

in 

Third Quarter. Third Quarter. 

Housework 6 Housework 

Kitchen 6 Kitchen 10 

Sewing room 3 .Sewing room 11 

Laundry 6 Laundry 

8 

Fourth Quarter. Fourth Quarter. 

Housework fj Housework .' 

3 

Kitchen 8 Kitchen 

* 

Sewing room 3 Sewing room 13 

Laundry 5 Laundry 

1 </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
87 

girls' industrial school. 

achbr's report showing number in classes in bach family. 

Family B. 

Family A 

Miss Laura Bock, Teacher. 

Miss M. Duffy, Teacher 

Xo. A 

No. B. 

4 

Reader 1 

•&gt; 

4 
4 

ond Reader 

Third Reader 1 

11 

Fourth Reader 

&gt;~ 

0 

Fifth Reader 5 

¦is 

Arithmetic 21 

19 

eography 

21 

History .¦ 4 

•-&gt; 

I 

Physiology 

21 

Language 5 

Grammar 4 

i 

28 

Spelling 22 

•_&gt;v 

.»•&gt; 

Writing 

1 OF LAUNDRY WORK, NOVEMBER 30, 1898. TO NOVEMBER 30, 

1900. 

Miss Mabel Donovan, Laundry Teacher. 

5,632 

nesses 

skim ' 3 - 24() 

T 

Drawers 7 &gt; 362 

6,964 

Vests 

4,500 

Night dresses 

Hose 6 ' 975 

4,412 

Cdiset covers 

Handkerchiefs 3 &gt; 200 

Aprons 3 ' 463 

Towels : W^ 

Jackets 8 

12.906 

Xnjkin 

Table cloths 812 

2.355 

Wash cloths </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

88 

Sheets 4,316 

Pillow cases 6,329 

Shirts 340 

Doilies 98 

Bed Spreads 

¦)•): 

Overalls 105 

AViiists 450 

Collars 320 

&lt; 'uff s 127 

Sideboard covers 119 

REI'ORT OF THE CLOTHING MA UK IN THE SEWING ROOM. NOVEMBER 

30, 1898, to November 30. 1900. 

Mrs. S. H. Raley. Sewing Teacher. 

Dresses 421 

Night dresses 189 

*K 

Skirts 300 

Drawers 439 

&lt; 'orset waists 41ft 

rs 

Capes 

Towels 100 

Bath cloths 201 

Aprons 207 

Pillow cases 190 

i 

Sheets 114 

Sun-bonnets 29 

Sun hats 18 

ARTICLES MANUFACTURED IN THE KITCHEN 

RTICLES MANUFACTURED IN THE K1TCHE 

Mrs. A. M. E. Mundy. Cooking Teacher 

Catsup 44 qts. 

Pickles — cucumber 125 gait 

Jelly 234 glasses 

Sweet pickles "... 40 pts. </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
89 

GIRLS IXDUBTBIAL SCHOOL. 

Saner kraut 200 gals. 

Grape jam 29 qts. 

Canned fruit 

Frnit presor ves 18 qts. 

Bread »,340 loaves. 

HOUSEKEEPING TBACHHB'B REPORT 

Mis. S. M. Weber. Teacher. 

Girls Taught. 

First th; - ee months 10 

Second three months 8 

Third three months 7 

Fourth three months 4 

Fifth three months 5 

Sixth three months 4 

Seventh three months 4 

PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. 

Geneva, Neb., November oO, llMHt. 

Hon. B. R. B. Weber. Superintendent Girls' Industrial School, 

Geneva, Neb. 

My Dear Sir: Since my biennial report as attending physician 

and surgeon to the Girl's Industrial School of the State of Ne- 

braska, there have been the usual cases of sickness, which inci- 

dent to change of seasons, and exposure to atmospheric changes, 

as well as other diseases which come to an institution of this 

kind, including epilepsy, tuberculosis, scrofula, and kindred dis- 

eases. These constitute the routine that require constant atten- 

tion and care, if we expect to be successful in treating diseases. 

Among those diseases first spoken of, all yielded kindly to treat- 

ment, except in two cases, one a case of perityphlitis, which con- 

tinued beyond the ordinary time we look for improvement, but 

finally yielded, and she was restored to her usual good health and </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
90 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S KKPOHT. 

was paroled. Tin- other case was an attack of aeute articular 
rheumatism involving the left shoulder joiut and extending later 
to the elbow joint, and finally involving the whole arm and hand. 
This was the most obstinate and relapsing case of rheumatism I 
ever met with, and will say that the case finally improved so 
much that she took daily exercise and appeared to In- nearly convalescent, 
and she was also paroled and sent to her parents. By 
accident at play there were in two cases one broken bone in the 
B family. Both of these cases did nicely and were soon well 
again. These two cases constitute almost all the surgery required. 
The only contagious disease that developed was a short 
epidemic of varicella, this being the mildest of all eruptive 
fevers, but highly contagious. Few escaped inoculation, yet the 
well being of the inmates seemed to be very little disturbed; 
and I will say in this connection the hygienic regime of the institution 
has been so rigidly enforced, exercises properly enjoined, 
this with plain wholesome diet and cleanliness left few 
avenues for the admittance of any disease or sickness emanating 
from infection. 

On the loth day of May. 1898, a Miss Mamie Milford colored) 
was admitted to the institution from Crawford. Nebraska, having 
been rescued from a life of vice by some ladies of a mis 
sionary society. Physical examination revealed the fact fhat she 
was in a deplorable condition, there were mucous rales and extreme 
dullness over a large area of both lungs. Advanced tuberculosis 
was diagnosed and a grave prognosis given in the case. 
She gradually lost strength, and died on the thirty-third day 
after being admitted to the institution. It is a notable fact that 
this case, with another in 1894 constitute the entire death roll 
since the existence of the institution. -The class of patients in 
an institution of this kind furnish ordinarily the kind of business 
the judicial-medical man seeks, and 1 trust it may not seem 
flattering to my vanity when I say that results, indeed, have been 
first class, perhaps, not altogether through whatever skill I 
may possess, but commensurate therewith should be considered 
the disposition of the matron to render faithful service to the 
sick, properly observing my directions in detail. </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
u 

nit 

h&lt; 

i 

x 

n 

IRI 

INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

In conclusion, 1 will say to the patrons of the school who live 

every quarter of the state and send their girls here, to learn 
uu'thinji of the industrial pursuits as well as to get wholeme 
instruction and moral training with literary accomplishents, 
and to be properly treated when sick and nursed back to 
&gt;alth and vigor again; that could you know and realize all that 
being done for your girls, you could not even then fully appreate 
the services of those who are untiring in their efforts to 
:alt and benefit those placed under their care and treatment. 

Very respectfully yours, 

T. C. Canine, M. D. 


/ </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>