<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Use of Lard in Cake Making</title>
               <date value="18??">October 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Bulletin 320 October, 1938 The Use of Lard in Cake Making Helen Boeder ¦ . Cake Baked by the Hot-Lard Method '..¦'.. The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture ;-¦•; Experiment Station Lincoln, Nebraska '¦'¦¦¦'. ":¦¦' W.W. Burr, Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Summary 3 Introduction 5 hxperimental Procedure 8 Development of the Lard Cake 9 Manipulation of the Lard Cake 10 Observations on Tolerance Toward Variations 12 Household Studies 18 Conclusions 19 1 </seg>
         <seg id="p003">\ '•¦.¦¦ ¦ :..'¦¦¦ ... ¦ '.'.¦¦¦" ¦ ' ¦ - ' '¦ ¦ ¦ ' . . /¦•,.. Snmmaty I ¦¦¦•-¦- Ii an attempt to iind a means of utilizing the large surplus of lard on the market, the Nebraska Experiment Station undertook investigations in 1^33 to devise ways of using lard in home cake-making. The ob - jectives were (1) to develop a formula and method for making desirable cakes with lard and general-purpose flour, and (2) to devise a method for .using lard kept without refrigeration as is necessarily the case in many rural homes. • • :. Itj was found that lard could not be substituted, weight for weight, for butter in a standardized formula, nor did the theoretical substitution of lard for butter on the basis of fat content prove satisfactory. Variations found necessary in deriving the lard formula from the butter control formula were a 30 per cent reduction in fat when lard was used, a 10 per cent (increase in sugar, a 15 per cent increase in liquid, and 22 per cent substitution of cornstarch for general-purpose flour. The conventional method of mixing was found to be'unsatisfactory for use with lard cakes. Other methods of mixing were found necessary, to attain a desirable texture for lard cakes. Three methods of mixing were developed and are referred to as the hot-lard method, the single-stage method, and the cornstarch method. . Tjhe hot-lard method received most emphasis in the investigation, since it seemed best suited to meet the requirements for the soft or melted lards kept without refrigeration and for the high temperatures of summer. It is a variation of the procedure generally used in making muffins, in which the sugar, salt, and eggs' are beaten together until thick and creamy. The dry and liquid ingredients are then added, and finally, the fat, heated to 65° C. (149° F.), is stirred in quickly. T|he single-stage method, by which all of the ingredients are mixed together.at one time, is also a good method for use with soft lards, especially where a mechanical mixer is available. However, this method failed to mask a rancid lard flavor where rancidity is a problem. The cornstarch method is a modification of the sponge-batter method deve oped at lowa State College, and is desirable for use with firmer lards. The lard, one-half the sugar, and the salt are creamed until light. The cornstarch is then added, and afterwards the. liquid, flour, and baking powder.. Finally the egg and remaining half of the sugar, beaten until thick and creamy, are folded in. A successful lard; cake can be made by any of these three methods of mixing. The "hot j lard" and "single stage" methods are particularly desirable for soft lard. The "hot lard" and "cornstarch" methods mask the flavor of slightlyl rancid lard. : .. </seg>
         <seg id="p004"/>
         <seg id="p005">! The Use of Lard in Cake Making I HELEN BAEDER Nebraska is in the corn-hog belt of the United States and in 1932 ranked second in the number of hogs produced. Since 1934, production has jdeclined as a result of severe drouth and poor corn crops. Yet hogs still;constitute one of the state's leading products. Lard comprises ap - proximately one-sixth of the total cash value of hog products. Therefore the sale of hogs and lard directly affects the income of Nebraska farmers. This study was initiated in 1933, at which time there was a large sur - plusj of lard. 1 This surplus, coupled with the low price, due in part to competition with lard substitutes, constituted an economic problem which ft ufas hoped might be solved in part by devising additional ways of using lard. Relatively large amounts of shortening are used in the prep - aration of pastry, cakes, cookies, and various quick breads. It is generally conceded that lard produces.pastry of superior quality.' Lard is also widely used in the preparation of the other products named with the possible exception of cakes, j The relatively large proportion'of shortening used in cakes offers an opportunity of increasing the use of lard. In order to determine whether there is a potential outlet for lard by popularizing its use in cake making, a survey was conducted in order to discover what shortenings Nebraska homemakers use and prefer when making cake. Questionnaires were distributed through the cooperation oftjie county home agents and the state extension specialists. Each house - wife was asked to list the shortening which she most frequently used when making cakesj together with her reason for choosing it. She also indicated what shortening she would select by preference. In addition she gave those used and; preferred in case her first choice was not available. A total of 1,567 replies were tabulated, representing a fair cross section of the population of the state. The results, showing a comparison between the shortening actually used in cake making and the shortenings house - wives would prefer to use, are given in Table 1. jt will be observed that slightly more than half of these women used butter although almost two-thirds preferred it. About one-fourth used cream although less than one-fifth would have chosen this shortening. Not; quite one-fifth used lard and only three out of every hundred women used it by preference. A fourth of the homemakers used lard as second choice and more than one-third as third choice. The preferences expressed by jhese women indicate that if butter and cream had been eliminated, most of the women would have preferred lard. Manufactured products (hydrogenated fats, j oleomargarine, and vegetable oils) were little used and| not much preference was expressed for them. . The reasons listejd most frequently for the use of a given shortening were availability (or, the fact that the shortening was produced at home) andj the flavor and texture of the resulting cake. Nutritive value, cream - -IJV cooperative project outlined arid conducted by the Animal Husbandry and Home Economics Departments at- the College of Agriculture. Acknowledgments are due to ihe advisory committee: Dr. RebelMh Gibboni, Matilda Fctcn, H. J. Gramlich, Dr. M. J. Bliih. and Wm. J. Locffel, Chairman' and to Edna Snyder of the Home Economics Research staff for her aid in preparing this manuscript. </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 320 ing qualities, and cost were considered of secondary importance. Cost , was a more important consideration influencing the second and third choices. Table 1 .—Comparison of the percentages of shortening used by Nebraska housewives in ca\e making—first, second, and third choices with those preferred. First choice Second choice Third choice Shortcnins Used | Preferred I Used | Preferred Used | Preferred BuT^r 5U 653 215 165 13.1 3.5 Cream 2i.2 18.4 35.0 35.7 23.0 10.9 Urd IV.I 3.0 25.2 13.9 36.1 27.5 Hytlrogcnatct) 'vegetable fats 1.9 -M 2.6 9.5 3A 10.0 Butter and lard 1.7 0J 2.1 1.0 1.5 1.7 Oleomargarine 1.2 0.2 3.1 M 1.9 1-9 Others 0.9 0.1 1.7 0.6 3.8 2.5 Hydroßcnsucd lard 0.5 .. 0.5 0.1 0.3 Ve^tahle nils 0.1 0.2 0.1 0-6 0-5 0-7 Flavor other than that of butter or cream in a shortening is unimportant with the housewife. When neither butter nor cream is available, the majority prefer a tasteless shortening. The reasons given for using the shortenings actually employed by the women who participated in the study are shown in Table 2. The comments are ranked in order of their importance to the user. In noting the unfavorable comments regarding lard, it will be ob - served that the flavor of the lard and the poor texture of the resulting cake were mentioned most frequently and that availability and economy were considered the chief reasons for its use. It is possible that objections to the flavor ot hid arise from the use of lard which is not fresh or has developed a slight rancidity. On the farm where lard is produced and in cities or towns where it can be purchased at a low price, the amount of lard used in cake could probably be greatly increased if it were possible to devise satisfactory ways of disguising (masking) the lard flavor and of improving the texture of the resulting cake. Accordingly this investigation was undertaken for the purpose of developing (1) a formula and method for making successful cakes with lard as shortening and (2) a satisfactory method of utilizing lard which has become slightly rancid because of poor storage conditions. For the purpose of developing a standard for judging cakes made with lard, a standard butter cake was developed with the following character - istics: (1) slightly rounded top, (2) even golden-brown crust, (3) light fine-grained crumb, (4) velvety texture, (5) desirable odor and flavor, and (6) satisfactory keeping qualities. This butter cake is the type of cake which the homemaker would use as her criterion in judging any shortened j cake. I </seg>
         <seg id="p007">The Use of Lard in Cake Making Table 2.— Favorable and unfavorable comments on fats most commonly ).¦ -' used in cake making. Shortening - Favorable Unfavorable Butter .-..¦¦ 1. Texture I. Strong when old | 2. Flavor 2. Too expensive 3. Produced at home : ¦ . j 4. Nutritive value ' 5. Creaming qualities Butter and lard (mixture) 1. Produced at home ,1 • ,V- \ ; ;; 2.Flavor '¦"- .'- V . / ¦' " ¦. ¦ ¦.-/¦" ' .'!:¦' -.¦.¦¦ •. .'¦.'. ¦'"'; 3. Texture , , ' 4. Nutritive value ¦'&#132;'¦ 5. Cheapest : 6. Creaming qualities I Cream 1. Produced at home 1. Never certain of butter - 2. Texture ¦; fat content -¦:".¦¦ 3. Flavor. 2. Poor texture ' ... ; 4. Nutritive value ' ¦'!¦;[ ..':'.: ". '¦.¦¦'¦'¦¦'¦...¦.¦"!.' 5. Cheapest "'' : ¦¦'¦.¦ :f '¦'."¦ ''¦ '..: 16. Creaming qualities ; ••! Hylrogcnatcd vegetable 1. Texture ' 1. Expensive fats ' 2. Creaming qualities 2. Flavor 3. Cheapest 3. Odor .:'.' .;._ :.':'. .'. ¦"_.' ."¦' 4. Flavor '-- ¦ ¦¦' ¦.-¦".;..:, j '¦ ;.' Lard ¦ -I. 1. Produced at home 1. Flavor ¦¦:•:¦ V ' / '.: ::-' ; 2. Texture ...._¦.'¦.' '". ¦ 3. Texture 3. Consistency ; . . 4. Creaming qualities 4. Poor creaming qualities Hjdrogcnafed lard i 1. Texture : :' 1. Not very well known : . .'•'¦¦• 2. Creaming qualities ... •] . ¦¦.¦:. - ¦-,: '.¦ •".'¦ 3. Cheapest , •¦ ' ¦¦} :. ' . ¦ • ¦ ; . 4. Flavor Ol mrnargarine 1. Cheapest : . 1. Flavor : 2. Texture .'¦ 2. Detrimental to the sale of . : : 3; Flavor V . cream, butter, lard . 4. Others not available 3. Creaming qualities 5. Creaming qualities 4. Texture . . : 5. Little, nutritive value : .' .-.¦ 6. Shortening qualities not :. "'¦.-'¦- ¦'"..¦- , ¦ ¦¦'..¦ ¦¦"¦¦-: rich enough Vegetable oils 1. Cheapest ).!F)avor ¦ '; '•-¦".. .:'[' ... ¦¦ -' ¦¦"¦.•"-. ' '..' s .. ¦ 2. jToo oily ¦ - i ¦ ... 3. Texture I .-..;• ¦ .' 4. 'Expensive &#132; I . 5. Creaming qualities '¦¦I-' [. ¦-. .. ¦¦;- ¦ - - -¦¦:¦¦ ": '}¦'}¦ ¦ ¦ ;j. "...:•:.'. .. ¦ ¦¦'¦¦¦ ¦ ¦' </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 320 EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE Considerable exploratory work was done to determine suitable ingred - ients, storage conditions, equipment, technique, and methods of rating the cakes. The ingredients used were, as far as possible, Nebraska products and were as follows: granulated beet sugar, a commercial brand of prime steam-rendered lard, unsalted sweet-cream butter, eggs blended by a mechanical m.xer and frozen, a powdered whole milk made by a standard spray method, a mixture of equal weights of three popular brands of general-purpose flour, a combination type of baking powder, chemically pure sodium chloride, distilled water. No flavoring was used. The preliminary survey of baking practices referred to above showed that general-purpose flour was most generally used for cake making. Since this study was planned primarily to meet the needs of the homemaker, general-purpose flour was used in place of the more expensive cake flour. The ingredients were stored under uniform conditions during the investi - gation. A tempering cabinet was used to keep the temperature of the ingredients at 25° C. (77° F.) prior to mixing them, since most authorities agree that this is the optimum temperature for successful baking results. 2 The equipment used included the commonly accepted utensils for cake making with the exception of the baking pans. Specially constructed deep-loaf tin pans were used in preference to shallow pans, since deep pans seemed to magnify differences in texture and to make differences resulting from variations in proportions of ingredients, manipulative pro - cedures, etc., more apparent. From the "pup" cakes baked in these pans, it was possible to predict the results which would be obtained from a house - hold-size recipe. Each pan measured 3% inches in depth, 2 1/15 inches by 3'/, inches at the bottom, and 2% inches by 4 inches at the top. Rating of the cakes.—Volume was measured two hours after removal of the cakes from the oven by the seed-displacement method. The method used was that of calibrating true volume from the seed-displacement volume which has been developed by the Department of Agricultural Chemistry at the University of Nebraska for testing flours. The volume given is calculated on the basis of 100 grams of finished cake and represents the average of two test cakes. Computations were made per 100 grams of finished cake to give a uniform standard for comparison. A descriptive chart was used to judge the external and internal qualities ot the finished cake. People who had had considerable experience in rating food products served as judges. The judges checked the terms applicable to the characteristics of the cake in question. These were summarized and are listed in the results along with the cake volume. As a result of preliminary tests which consisted in varying the amounts and kinds ot ingredients and methods of mixing, the following procedure was adopted for the control cake. I] ! ¦¦I </seg>
         <seg id="p009">.-¦¦ ¦ The Use of Lard in Cake Making 'I.-. i ¦ ¦ •""."':.. ¦ ¦ Formula Used jor Test Butter Calces • :.";,¦¦¦¦¦¦ Weight Ingredient ; Measure i ~" j' Ounces | Grams Butter 'A cup 4 112 Sugar, granulated 1 cup 7 200 Salt '.";•¦ Vi pp. . -I-''-: 3 Eggj whole 2 4. 96 Flour, general-purpose I'A cups (sifted) 7 200 Baking powder, combination 2 sp. ¦ . . ..'• .. ¦ 8 Milk (whole powdered) % tup (whole liquid) &#132; 21 Water • | ¦ : ' ' 6 142 :. One-fourth of this formula yielded one test-loaf cake. "¦ A modification of the conventional method of mixing was used. All ingredients were brought to room temperature (25° C. or 77° F.) before mixing. The butter, sugar, and salt were beaten for 30 minutes with a mechanical mixer at medium; speed. 3 The egg was then added to the creamed mixture and beaten for two minutes at medium speed. The dry ingredients which had been sifted together and the liquid were added together in thirds and beaten jone and one-half minutes at medium speed after each addition. The entire batter was then beaten 15 seconds. The baking pans were lined with strips of paraffined paper, cut to fit the bot - tom of the pan to facilitate the removal of the loaves. The baking pans were not greased since there was a tendency for the volume of the cake to be slightly greater without greasing. [The cakes were placed in the center of a preheated thermostatically con - trolled oven and baked for 40 minutes at 370° F. (188° C). Two hours after removal-from the oven! the cakes were weighed and the volume : measured. They were wrapped in paraffined paper and stored until the following morning, at which time they were judged. DEVELOPAfENT OF THE LARD CAKE The formula and method used for the butter cake were used as a basis for developing a lard cake. It was found that when an equal weight of lard was substituted for butter in the formula of the control cake, the results were p00r.,; The cake's were heavy, compact, and peaked in the center and were unevenly browned. The results were undoubtedly due to differences in composition and physical characteristics of lard and butter. A 30-per-cent reduction of lard in the formula was found to give best results after" numerous preliminary tests. The substitution of lard for butter on the basis' of fat content did not work out satisfactorily. Other variations found necessary from the butter-control formula were a 10 per cent .increase in sugar, a 15 per cent increase in liquid, and the substitution of ;22.4 per cent cornstarch for general-purpose flour. (The most satisfactory formula developed from the preliminary tests was as follows. ! ¦:..{.'.: :'..¦'¦".-. * Creaming time agrees with that worked out at lowa State College: "The Creaming Qualities of Lards and. other* Fats and New Ways of J Mixing Them in Plain Cakei," iby E. L. Martin (unpublished thesis) 1933. Abstract in Journal, of Home Economics 26:52-1, 1934. Ie is equivalent to 8 minutes of band creaming. .!.''.. ' j </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 320 Grams Lard . 38.0 Sugar 110.0 Salt 1.5 Kgg, whole 48.0 Flour, general-purpose 77.6 Cormtarch . . . 22.4 Baking powder, combinalion 4.0 Milk, whole powdered 11.6 Water 80.0 This formula, mixed by the modified conventional procedure, was used as the cake formula ivith lard throughout the rest of the study and will be referred to as the standard lard test formula. This amount made two test loaves which were considered as duplicate checks. MANIPULATION OP THE LARD CAKE The formula and mixing procedure given above showed that a satis - iactory cake could be made with lard as shortening, although not as satisfactory as the butter cake. The study was continued, therefore, to determine variations in methods of mixing which might improve the characteristics of the lard cakes. Many different methods were worked out by varying the method of combining the ingredients or by using other types of ingredients such as powdered sugar. Of those tried the following three were most satisfactory and were developed for household use: (1) the cornstarch method, which is a modification of the lowa State College' 1 method developed for use with general-purpose flour; (2) a single-stage method, in which all of the ingredients were mixed together at the same time; and (i) the hot-lard method, which is a variation of the muffin method in which the eggs and sugar were beaten together, the dry and liquid ingredients added, and the fat added hot at the last. "Cornstarch" method.—ln this method the lard, salt, and one-half the sugar were creamed by machine for 30 minutes. All of the cornstarch was added to the creamed mixture and folded in with 30 strokes. One - hall the liquid and dry ingredients were added to the batter and folded in with 45 strokes, and this procedure was repeated with the remaining liquid and dry ingredients. The egg and remaining half of the sugar were beaten until thick and creamy (200 revolutions of rotary egg beater) and added with 55 strokes. The cakes made by this method were superior to those made by the modified conventional method. They were more velvety in texture, had a well-blended flavor, and more nearly approached the characteristics of a butter cake. "Single-stage" method. —All of the ingredients were mixed together at one time. Both the machine and the hand procedure were found success - ful. Both produced satisfactory cakes with a fine grain and velvety texture. However, this method failed to mask the objectionable flavor where rancid lard was used. * Reported by B. Lowe to Second National Lard Conference, Chicago, 1933., and known ai sponge tuner method. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">The Use of Lard in Cake Making " ,'¦ i- ' ' -: I ' ¦ ' ,¦" • : ¦ v .-««» &#132;™ ~ ¦ ¦ ' ¦ ' . ' " 1 ' r^^^B H^' ¦¦' ¦ ¦ '¦¦ ¦' 1 ¦ f^^^B -^ : •¦¦:¦ ¦ ¦ ..' '?£¦ f* ¦""&gt;.¦• ¦ ""•'¦" ¦~-"-"""-aK~'-"~iS-;S.\2^ I=s».'ratS&lt;4 »J3 '¦ ¦ -i - ¦ ¦¦'. &gt; : ' - "Vi • &lt;j^ "-'-¦ '¦ v^;iK;-.' ' ' ¦' ¦ f''''"* '^' "'¦-'¦r^^^te' .¦¦.'.;.;''^;&gt;;^^i^'t!r;' l o ' o fl Ep^ '". ''''¦'•"'!--'-'i**"w;^ '¦-' ¦bVK! . :¦¦,¦¦¦ ¦KRHji 1 Q ¦ ' i ¦•'"¦¦• "' "' ¦' ¦• i!¦ ¦ ! ¦ : ' -':'••'::' ." .. --".¦¦' '¦¦'¦.. ¦-- '.. ..¦¦•].¦. -. -. ¦;' .¦¦.-• ' ' .'¦¦¦ ¦;¦.'¦ ; '¦¦'. ¦¦ ' :": -¦'.' '.¦¦¦¦l '¦ •¦¦ ¦• ¦ '¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 320 "Hot-lard" method.—The sugar, salt, and eggs were beaten together until thick and creamy. One-half the dry ingredients and one-half the liquid ingredients were added together and folded in with 60 strokes, and this was repeated. The fat was heated in an enameled custard cup over water to 65° C. (149° F.) and stirred in quickly with 55 strokes. By this method the lard is entirely melted and produces a sizzling effect when added to the batter. The method gave satisfactory cakes which were light, fine-grained, fairly velvety in texture, had a well-blended flavor, and an outside crust comparable to that of butter cakes. • • i •. ¦ * *^ ¦*' **" -^ * ¦ . . . Fig. 2.—"Pup" cakes baked by four methods: A butter cake, B cornstarch method (lard), C single-stage method (lard), D hot-lard method. OBSERVATIONS ON TOLERANCE TOWARD VARIATIONS IN FORMULA AND PROCEDURE Before transposing these methods and formulas into practical house - hold procedures, experiments were conducted to show their tolerance to - wards variations in proportion of ingredients, addition or substitutions of </seg>
         <seg id="p013">1. ¦¦¦¦¦¦'¦ ' : } :- ¦¦¦¦:¦-¦; }¦' ¦'¦ ; . The Use of Lard in Cake Making I ingredients, and other variations. Most emphasis was given to the hot-lard ; method in this phase of the investigation, since it appeared to offer a ' solution for the use of soft or melted lards kept without refrigeration, and i for the high, temperatures of summer. ; Variations in proportions of ingredients with hot-lard method.—ln - '; gradients which were varied as to proportion were the shortening, sugar, and the corhstarch. Experiments were made in which the proportions of shortening, sugar, and cornstarch were varied, using the hbt-lard method. Differences resulting from variations in amounts are more clearly obvioiu in the "pup" cakes, than they are in the household-size cake, and it is therefore possible from "pup" cakes to predict results from the household - sized recipe. V": V.';'•'".'¦'.-¦. ¦'.'¦' I Fifty grams of general-purpose flour were used in the formula. In the experiments where the amounts of cornstarch were increased or decreased, the amounts of flour were correspondingly decreased or increased to main - tain ja total weight of 50 grams of starch and flour in the formula/Results of varying the proportions of ingredients are shown in Table 3. ; Table 3.— The effect of varying the proportion of ingredients in the test :|--¦"'. formula with the hot-lard method! ¦¦¦¦..| ." ¦ ' ¦ ' ¦¦•-¦" Vol.per' -¦;.-.. '¦¦:¦]¦ ¦. ¦ ~ Ingredient Amis. VOOgms. Remarks (¦ - ' 1- ofcalce :¦¦-.¦¦ - | .' -' . ¦ | ..........;• Gins, cc.' ' ¦ •..'¦¦¦'.'¦¦ '';..¦ ¦' v I .¦¦ " . Lard V 19.0 260 Standard lard tot formula. 1 ¦.¦ i 23.5 235 Lard.flavor, some large holes. ¦¦¦¦".' 28.0 232 Texture slightly coarse-f-firrn. ¦ .- ¦ ¦:' v 229 Odor and flavor of lard. ... Sugsr . 55.0 260 Standard 1 ¦ ' ¦ 48.0 240 ¦ Brcady, compact texture. : 50.0 242 ¦:; Fine grain, slightly compact. 52.0 246 ; Springy, fine grain, slightly shiny crust. . 57.0 242 Springy, uniformly brown, fine grain, dull ¦-'¦¦¦ &#132; ¦ ¦ .¦ • ' ';¦¦ . .. crust.' . :;" ..-¦¦. - -60.0 246 Very springy, well browned, slightly coarse, ¦' ¦ ' ": ,'".¦';.' tooswect. .. ¦ :: . ;' . Corrstarch 2.0 2 260 Standard 1 ¦'".' 3.7 Coarse, firm. 5.6 237 Coarse grained, springy and velvety. 9.4 234 Springy, most velvety of the group. ¦;.:. ;:,. 13.1 223 : Slightly crumbly, j... , .• 15.0 Too crumbly, cornstarcli'flavor. Baking powder 112 260 Standard 1 .\ . ¦; . | i. 15 232 Top slightly rounded. Slightly velvety crumb. 1 pne test cake.* The complete formula for ihc standard cake is v follows: . . Lard, 19 grams (65° C.) ¦ . General-purpose f10ur,138.8 grams 55 grams . Cornstarch, 11.2 grams (3 T. per c.) Salt, 0.75 gram, : Baking foviia, 2 granu Pffii 24 grams Powdered wtole milk, 5.8 granu Water, 40.0 grams ' . . -.' : ; . ... . 3pne tablcipoonful of bakinsr powder weighs 3.7 tjrams. . ' </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 320 ¦ The test formula showed a tolerance of ± 5 per cent of sugar. Below or above this margin the cakes were of inferior quality. Desirable cakes were obtained when 15 to 22 per cent of cornstarch !( was substituted for general-purpose flour in the formula. More than 22 per cent resulted in a crumbly, dry texture with a noticeable flavor o£ cornstarch. Beiow 15 per cent the texture of the cakes tended to be similar to that of bread. The proportion of lard cannot be increased in this formula and with this method without affecting the volume or lowering the desirability of the finished cake. Variation of room temperature from 25° to 36° C. during the mixing period did not appear to affect the consistency of the batter or the final volume or character of the finished cake. With other methods of mixing, in which the lard was creamed, 25° C. seemed to be the best room tempera- ; ture. Substitution or addition of ingredients with hot-lard method. —Sub- stitutions made in the formula were-. (1) all general-purpose flour and all | cake flour, (2) various kinds of baking powders, (3) different liquids, j (4) rancid lard, and (5) the addition of other ingredients. I The results shown in Table 4 indicate that all cake flour, all general - purpose flour, or the combination of general-purpose flour and cornstarch '¦ can be successfully used in this formula. Cake flour consistently produced Table 4.— The effect of substitutions or additions in the test jormula with the hot-lard method. Vol. per Ingredient Variations 100 gms. Comments of cake cc. Flour General purpose flour 260 Standard lard tcsY formula. and cornstarch No cornstarch 260 Not as fine grained or soft as test cake but satisfactory. Cikc flour 260 Velvety texture. Baking Phosphate S. A. S. 252 Velvety crumb, powder Phosphate 226 Coarse. Tartrate 230 Coarse. liquid All water: -15.8 cms. 255 Different from test cake. Whole fresh milk 253 No different in texture or flavor trom test cake. Sour milk and soda 253 More tender cake. Chmolate H «ms. chocolate lid Symmetrical, fine grain, large holes added l at top, somewhat dry. Good flavor. 10 gms. cocoa added 2 188 Dry, compact. 10 gms. cocoa added 3 225 Similar to chocolate. I Jr( ] Rancid 249 Marked rancid flavor. 1 Heatcil with lard at 65° C. * Silled cocoa with flour. 1 Oxna cooked with water till thick ami added with dry anil liquid ingredients. </seg>
         <seg id="p015">y ' ¦ ! •". ¦ ¦¦-.-'" ¦.-..¦: I The Use of Lard in Cake Making j a mare velvety texture and general-purpose flour a less velvety texture i than the standard cake. : I The combination; type of baking power seemed most desirable for this method. By working quickly, it was possible to use tartrate and phosphate baking powders successfully; otherwise the hot lard released too much of the gas before the cake reached the oven. No apparent differences resulted from variations in liquids except that combinations of sour milk and soda made a more tender cake. The flavor of rancid lard was masked by the hot-lard method. Other variations considered were: (1) the effect of varying lard temper - atures, (2) the effect of variations in manipulations, (3) development of a Tab .c s.— The effect of other variations in the test formula with the hot - . ¦ lard method. ¦'.' ¦•¦ ! ' •'¦¦¦¦'.¦ Vol. per. Vari:ble Variations Temp. 100 gms. ' Comments | : fat of cake ¦ - •. ¦ .|.":"-- '¦'¦&gt;• ¦ : : . °c. ¦ cc. -. . " ' , --¦¦ Temperature Lard heated, thcrmom- ;'.''-, : tcr used. \ - ¦'. 45 : 227 Not satisfactory. Firm. ¦"..'¦¦ ¦..¦:¦¦ 100 247 Desirable but test method ',:¦ '.. '.-.¦¦ ..- '¦ ' " .'¦¦: ¦';"¦¦ &lt; ' better. ' ¦.' ... '¦&#132;•'¦ 125 250 . Desirable ..but test method '.¦'.¦ .-¦;¦' :.. ¦ "' •.. ¦ . '¦¦ ¦¦¦' .¦ ¦ : ¦ belter. .: •,...'¦ ':'.. ¦;""¦'.'[ ¦ 200 222 Lumpy. Not satisfactory. :¦ . Lard heated without use : - of thermometer. 75 243 Satisfactory. Manipulation Heat.lard and milk to . : ' &#132; f ¦ ;..¦- boiling. AddatendHs . ; '"' . - strokes. ' • 65 238 Less desirable than test cake. Heat lA lard and milk to ..'-.' boiling. Add at end 55 •. ' strokes. ¦. 65 226 Not satisfactory. Add hot lard after beat-¦ r ing eggs and sugar. 65 . Not satisfactory. • . Add 'A flour and liquid, ¦'"¦ .. ¦:-, . then hot lard, then re- ¦'. . ;-.-¦ . ¦ maining dry ingredients. 65 ... Same volume as control. Add all dry and liquid 1 ¦' ingredients together, 120 66 248 No improvement. More diffi- • strokes. . , cult to mix. Add '/i flour, 30 strokes. :'¦ . Add 30 strokes. : .. ...;¦' . Add Vi flour, 30 suokes. 65 245 No improvement. Less v: Add/i liquid,3ostrokes. ;.'' springy. Ttmi: &#132; Batter stood 5 minutes before baking. ... 239 Loses lightness on standing. : Butter stood: 15 minutes ¦;,,before baking. ; 65 231 Loses lightness on standing. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 320 household method of heating the lard without a thermometer, and (4) adapting the formula lo a test cake. &lt; Successful cakes resulted as shown in Table 5 when the temperature of the lard ranged between 60 ° and 100° C. None of the variations in the method of adding the hot lard or the dry and liquid ingredients resulted in as satisfactory a cake as with the standard hot-lard method. A practical method of heating the lard from room temperature is that of placing it over gently boiling water for two minutes. I£ the lard were heated from refrigerator temperatures, it would of course require a longer time to bring it to 65° C. This method requires speed from the start of mixing until the batter reaches the oven. There is a gradual loss of lightness if the batter stands. Variations in single-stage method.—With this method all of the in - gredients were mixed together. Three procedures were used: two by hand, one in which the ingredients were beaten with a large rotary egg beater 200 revolutions; and the other in which the ingredients were combined with 175 strokes of a wooden spoon; and the third by machine, in which ingredients were mixed for one minute at low speed, followed by one minute at high speed. In this case tests were made merely to determine the most satisfactory method of manipulation. Since the method seemed less difficult to transpose into a household method, no variations in proportion of ingredients or substitutions of ingredients were made. The results are shown in Table 6. Table 6. — Results from differing procedures using the single-stage method. , Vol. per _ Procedure , ™ Comments Hand method, rotary egg beater, 200 rcvo- 2-18 Satisfactory cake. Velvety. lutions. Approaches butter cake. Hand mcthoil, rancid lard, rotary egg 253 Fine, even grain. Good texture, beater, 200 revolutions. soft, springy. Rancid flavor. Hand method, wooden spoon, 175 strokes. 240 Rather coarse and crumbly. Mechanical mixer. 255 Very good. The single-stage method could well be adopted as a household method where a mechanical mixer is available. It is a simple, easy method of mixing, requiring little time for preparation. When a household size formula is used, the cake is difficult to mix by hand when using a rotary egg beater. This method produces a cake having a desirable texture and flavor when fresh lard is used, but does not mask the flavor of rancid lard. The cakes made by the cornstarch method approached the characteristics of the butter control cake. They were not as light as some made by other methods, but had a velvety texture and a well-blended flavor. The cakes made by the hot-lard method were very light, had a well-blended flavor, and were more "chewy" in texture. </seg>
         <seg id="p017">The Use of Lard in Cake Making General comment on variations.— The characteristics of the cakes re - sulting when the ingredients of the lard test formula were combined for the different methods are shown in Table 7. Taiile 7.— Results obtained by the use of different methods of mixing | ¦¦¦¦.;•• lard cakes. . | . " Vol. per ' ' ~~ .:¦ Method 100 gins. Lard flavor Comments ¦- ) ¦". . ¦ -cake ;, ¦ ¦ -¦ ' ¦ "• ¦'.- ¦¦¦•[«.; ; ¦¦-¦¦¦¦ .;.. &#132; ¦¦¦ ¦ Hot-lard 252 to 262 Masked Satisfactory. . Cornstarch 230 to 241 Masked Slightly compact, velvety. Single-stage 247 . Rancid flavor T •".. .... .. not masked Slight odor, unevenly browned. Modified , fl . Rounded top. Unevenly browned, conventional ' 235 to 259 ™™a ""or Fine, even grain. Springy. Undesir - mediod not maskc'i able odor and flavor. In the study of the various methods of mixing, certain observations were made:' ';•¦-. ,-; .;. &#132;'¦'. '• ••: ¦;¦¦... . ";••¦••'¦ ."¦¦¦¦¦ The conventional method of mixing, using lard, produced a batter of a thin, flowing consistency with a shiny and gray-yellow appearance. With a change in the methods of mixing but with identical weights of ingredients, the consistency of.the batter was changed. A comparison of the] type of batter with the finished cake indicated that viscosity (resistance to flow) was directly related to the quality of the finished cake. An in - crease in viscosity: of batter was invariably associated with cakes of superior quality. [ With the hot-lard method it was necessary to develop a technique for hand mixing. When the dry and liquid ingredients were added by hand, the results were preferable to those obtained by a machine, as it was pos - sible to fold in the 1 flour by hand more thoroughly and uniformly. It is more difficult, however, to standardize hand technique. It appears that with each method of mixing used with the lard formula, there is ah optimum amount of mixing and the time necessary is deter - mined by the type of mixer used. ; lit is possible to mask the flavor of slightly rancid lard or other "lardy" flavors. Both the hot lard and cornstarch methods produce this effect while the conventional and single-stage methods do not. It is possible td| make a satisfactory cake using general-purpose flour. This is more difficult with lard than with butter since slight over-mixing is more likely to result in a coarse, bready texture in the finished cake. The substitution oi three tablespoons of cornstarch for an equal measure of flour in each cup of flour used will remedy this difficulty. I Some : attempts were made to determine reasons for the superiority of butter as compared with lard in cakes made with the conventional method of mixing. It was noted that when lard was used and mixing was done by the conventional method, the emulsion tended to break, resulting </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricvltvral Experiment Station Bulletin 320 in a greasy, waxy crumb. When a commercial emulsifier was used with lard in the control formula and method, results indicated that the type or. emulsion formed might be a possible explanation of some of the differences in cake characterises. It is recognized that butter is high in volatile fatty acids, whereas lard has a very small proportion." When the volatile fatty acids in butter were added to the lard in the control formula and method, results indicated that their presence also was related to the quality of the cake. Insufficient experimentation makes definite conclusions im - possible. Further study seems desirable. HOUSEHOLD STUDIES The formula and methods developed in this study have been transposed into practical amounts and procedures for household use. The recipe is the same for each method; the directions for combining the ingredients differ. Experiment has shown that better results in cake making with any method or with any shortening are obtained by bringing all of the ingredients to room temperature before beginning to prepare the cake. Recipe for lard cake: Ingredient Measure Weight in ounces Lard '/) cup 2Vi Sugar 1 cup 7 Salt !¦• tsp . Eggs 2 -1 Flour, general purp. I ,; cups 6 (sifted) Cornstarch '/i cup 154 Baking Powder 2 tsp. Milk % cup 6'A F\avonnß 1 isp. Directions for hot-lard method.—This method is particularly adapted for use in hot weather or in homes where refrigerated storage for the lard is not available. It is essential to work rapidly after the hot lard has been added. This method is successful if the batter is baked as a shallow leaf ( 1 % inches deep) or as a layer cake or cup cakes. It is not as light when baked in a deep loaf. Chocolate, cocoa, and spice make delightful varia - tions in cakes baked by this method. The procedure given in detail is as follows: 1. Regulate the oven to a moderate temperature, 370° R, for layer or cup cake; 350° F. for loaf cake. 2. Prepare pans. i. Measure or weigh all ingredients. 4. Sift flour, cornstarch, and baking powder together thoroughly at least three times. 5. Place lard in a suitable container and heat over boiling water for two minutes (or longer if lard is refrigerated). Let stand over hot water until used. All of the fat should be melted when added to other ingredients. 1 Food Impcclion and Amilyiii. by A. E. Leach, pp. 481-2, 508-9. Wiley and Sons, New York, 1906. </seg>
         <seg id="p019">!V . ¦.-..¦ ;. :.¦.¦¦¦•.¦¦¦.¦¦• . . ..... ; ¦. ... ;¦¦,.-. - :l . The Use of Lard in Cake Making . 6. Beat whole eggs, sugar, and salt until thick and creamy, using a . rotary beater. ; . ?! Add half of the dry ingredients and half of the milk at the same Si time with 60 strokes. Repeat. . ij 8. Add the hot lard and stir in rapidly with 55 strokes. j ¦'' 9. Place in baking pan and bake immediately, Directions for single-stage method.— This method is well adapted for ; use with household-size mixers. It takes little time for preparation but does 1 not mask rancid flavor. The lard should be at room temperature (25°; C.) so that it can be combined easily with other ingredients. The first four steps would, be the same as for the hot-lard method. : 5. Beat the eggs until well blended. .. ! 6. Put all of the (ingredients, together into the mixing, bowl and stir together with 175 strokes. : ' 7. Place in baking pans and bake. Directions for cornstarch method. —This method is best adapted for use with firm lard, sjnee the lard is creamed with part of the sugar. The procedure after the first three steps is: ... .4: Sift the flour and baking powder together.. 5. Set aside half the sugar and the eggs. . .'¦¦': 6. Cream the lard, salt and remaining half of the sugar until light .' "and fluffy (abojit five to ten minutes). .¦'•'¦¦"' -71 Add the cornstarch to the creamed mixture and fold in with 30 ¦'¦"I I strokes.- .-. &#132;J :-¦ ,' : - .- ¦ '¦ " .:,'_¦. ¦= '' ¦ 8. Add half of the dry ingredients and half the milk at the same time : with 45 strokes. Repeat. , 9. Beat the egg and remaining half of'the sugar until thick and creamy .. ;¦••[ (like whipped cream). Fold this in with 55 strokes. 10. Place in baking pan and bake. V.; Spices, chocolate, fruits, and nuts may be used as additions with either method of mixing. ¦ CONCLUSIONS ; Lard can be used successfully as a shortening agent in cake making, provided a suitable formula and method of mixing are used. The "hot - lard," "single-stage" and "cornstarch" methods are recommended. . The hot-lard method is a successful method of mixing for lard cakes, with general-purpose flour and-cornstarch in the formula. It is especially suitable for the high temperatures occurring during the summer and when lard is. kept without refrigeration. , • : The "single-stage" method is simple and produces satisfactory, cakes even from soft lard but does not mask "off" flavors. The "cornstarch'] method masks "off' flavors but is not suited for use with soft lards. .'¦ ; ; ¦:¦.-"¦! The flavor of rancid lard is masked when using the hot-lard method or the cornstarch method.' . ¦'•..: : ¦. ¦ ¦ ,: ¦'¦¦'•¦¦ ¦:. ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦'¦'¦'¦¦¦' ¦"¦¦- " ¦ :¦ :.¦¦ ¦ : . i5M';.' </seg>
         <seg id="p020"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>