<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Feeding Lambs in the Fall</title>
               <date value="1918-07">1918-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Hull.).,, 107 July. 1918 Feeding Lambs in the Fall Tin- ii»k nt »ilnu&lt; in dill ffi'iliiiK, Tin- I'oriilli'lil v», Ilic t\ry tot. &lt;'li|'|iini/ him Im fur I'uriiliclil IWiIIiik, I. mill", ifl (In- I'lirnlii'lil ji 111 1 on hi ip- uviiho N, I &lt;iKAMI.li H \Am\&gt;» ffd in cornflold m«k« good gain* and mv« labor AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN. NEBRASKA. U. S. A. Tile ikIiIiiiuii nt nil iiM'itl nrul &gt;'&lt;itiiiiM-i-i| niit &lt;'«!«* to tli&lt;&lt; I'oriilli'lil n»i inn, </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA I II K GOVKKMNU IUpXHIi (THE BECENT8 OF THE UNIVERSITY) Honorable E. P. Brown, Pretident, Davey. Honorable J. E. Miller, Vice President, Lincoln. Honorable Frank L. Haller, Omaha. Honorable V ictor G. Lyford, Falls City Honorable Philip L. Hall, Lincoln. Honorable Harry D. Landis, Seward. 'Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. W. G. Hastings, A. B., Acting Chancellor. E. A. Burnett, D. Sc, Director. Chas. E. Gunnels, B. Sc., Director of Extension Service. J. S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. C. A. Lewis, B. Sc, Bulletin Editor. THE WOKKIN*. STAFF F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. 'L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Agronomy. T. A. KlESSELBACH, A. M., Agronomy. H. J. GRAML1CH, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Animal Pathology. J. H. FRANDSEN, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology. M. H. SWENK, A. M., Entomology. H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Farm Management. R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture. G. A. LOVELAND, A. M., Meteorology. E. MEAD WiLCOX, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology. F. E. MUSSEHL, B. SC, Poultry. W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte. James Cowan, M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine. JAMES A. HoLUEN, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. •L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte. 'J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry. *G. K. K. LINK, Ph. D., Associate in Plant Pathology und l'hy*ioloyy. W. B. N evens, M. S., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. R. R. SpaffoRD, A. M., Assistant in Farm Management. 'Granted leave of absence for military service. 'Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Depart - ment of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. 'Granted leave of absence. THE STATION &lt;&gt;KH&lt; KKS </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SIMMARY I. The limiting of the corn mi ion and the substitution of Milage in a corn and alfalfa ration fed during the fall months decreased the daily gain by .07 pound, decreased the cost of 100 pounds of gain by $1.95 and decreased the loss per lamb by 13 cents. (Lots 1 and 2. table 2.) II. The feeding of a heavy feed of silage together with alfalfa hay, supplemented near the close of the trial with a small amount of corn, produced u 50 per cent gain in comparison with that made by lambs on com and alfalfa, increased the cost of gain by 56 cents per hundred, and increased the loss per lamb by 30 cents. (Lots 1 and 3, table 2.) Til. Fattening lambs in the cornfield with alfalfa hay in con - junction, in comparison with feeding shelled corn and alfalfa hay, increased the daily gain by .018 pound, decreased the feed re - quirements for 1 pound of gain and decreased the cost of 100 pounds of gain $6.83. It furthermore lowered the loss per lamb from H&lt;1. 06 to 53 cents. Hence, from every standpoint it proved justifiable. (Lots 1 and 4, table 3.) IV. The clipping of lambs to be fed in the cornfield did not prove profitable, the lambs failing to show an increased gain, altho they made their gain on slightly less feed anil at a cost of $1.28 per hundred less. Due to the severe discrimination on the market the loss per head was increased P&gt;."&gt; cents. (Lots 4 and 5, table 4.) V. The adding of .2 pound of oil meal to the ration of lambs running in the cornfield witli alfalfa before them increased the daily gain .0(14 pound, decreased slightly the feed required to produce 1 pound of gain, decreased the cost of 100 pounds of gain 22 cents anil lowered the lotts per lamb from 53 cents to 8 cents, a difference of 45 cents. (Lots 4 and 6, table 5.) VI. The addition of .1(1 pound of cottonseed nut cake to a group of lambs in tin infield increased the daily gain .030 pound, in - creased somewhat the feed required to produce 1 pound of gain and increased the cunt of KM) pounds of gain by 47 cents. Ft like - wise increased the 1 ss per lamb 11 cents. (Lots 4 and 7, table 5.) VII. Lambs grazed on blue grass pasture and finished the last ten days with a light ration of corn and oil meal showed a very satisfactory gain and a relatively low cost of 100 pounds of gain. The loss in this case was $1.07 per head in contrast to $1.06 per head \** on lot 1 fed corn in the dry lot and 53 cents in lot 4 fed in the cornfield. (Lots 1 and 8. table 6.) </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 167 4 - I ? ~; 02 *. i r- 5 E C «" S i I I e ? .5 Elfi : »a3! t ft I s iu n.iSM . as s x d ~ ~ ••!•!. 1 • • I = : c- — S £S 9 1 'tit "&gt; I 1i« Sir " W QC 14 = Silli tU si ? sSk S j t- oi x* m ii ri -&lt; B fl i 1 an- i 1 2 fg| k z i|j I 1 « 5;« 5 ii a SI i i ■: J ; {[[ ?S 5 3 is: Ill :*,*! s 1 53 t- «e « crirt t- © % « ~Nt^ N U5 O -. ill Mil! | lil; I 5«1 ; i *-. = ttl lill | t -o sill I : * * I in ;;;! I I 5 lilt ulli h =*? </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Feeding Lambx in the Fall 5 A 58 DAY LAMB FEEDING EXPERIMENT October 5 to December 1, 1917 BY H. J. GRAMLICH 1XTROIHTTIOX The primary object of this experiment was to continue exper - imental work i n the fall feeding of lamlis in cornfield* and in blue grass pasture, the desire being to check results obtained in this way with gain* secured on lambs under dry lot condition!. The lambs to be run in the cornfield were to he handled with the following objects in view: First, the advisability of clipping; second, the advisability of adding oil meal where lambs have ; ss to alfalfa hay in the cornfield, and third, the advisability of adding cottonseed nut cake under similar conditions. The lambs fed on blue grass were to be finished during the last few weeks on corn ami oil meal, the desire being to ascertain the relative efficiency of grass in comparison with the cornfield for fall feeding. The limiting of the corn in the ration and the adding of silage was to be tested in the dry lot groups. DESC'RIPTIOX OF THE LAMBS The lambs used in this trial were a good grade of medium weight feeders. They were of the black-faced breeding, apparently car - rying considerable Oxford blood crossed on a Merino foundation. At the time purchased, their weight was ."&gt;:{ pounds, which was a comparatively light weight for the season of 1917. as the large majority of the lambs which lefi the market centers for feed lots during this season weighed above •&gt;(&gt; pounds. Their quality was good and as a group they proved to be a very satisfactory experi - mental lot. The price paid, $17.8") per hundred, naturally proved to be too high, especially so when the lambs had to be marketed at an average of $16.35. At the opening of the experiment the lambs had increased in weight to an average of 57 pounds. At this time the cost amounted to $17.91 per hundred. In September, 11117. u load if western lamlis was purchased on the Omaha market to fall feed, the plan beinn to tVcd part of them under cornfield eoiiilitioiiK. The lainlix were purcbatteil Ht a time when the prospects for hiiiiH feeding were not very bright owing to the ahnontiallv hifili price of feeders ami the hitrh price of corn. The purchase price whs +1 7.K."&gt;. a figure previously regarded as excessively lii^rh hiii) which Inter, as the results indicate, proved to he such. OBJECT </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 167 6 RATIONS FED Lot 1. Corn and alfalfa. Lot 2. Corn, alfalfa and silage. Lot •'*. Oom (light feed), alfalfa and silage (heavy feed Lot 4. Cornfield and alfalfa. Lot 5. Cornfield and alfalfa. (Clipped lambs.) Lot 6. Cornfield, oil meal and alfalfa. Lot 7. Cornfield, cottonseed nut cake anil alfalfa. Lot 8. Blue grass pasture, corn, oil meal and alfalfa FEEDS PRICES OK 41.68 per bu. $1.40 per bu. Old corn New corn Cottonseed nut eake Oil meal $60.00 per ton .$60.00 per ton Silage Alfalfa ..$6.00 per ton .$2.~&gt;.00 per ton The prices used for feeds in this trial run very high, much higher than those used in any previous trial. However, they are none too high for the period during which the lambs were on feed. At the opening of the trial old corn was actually selling at $2.10 a bushel. However, it went thru a period of depreciation and dur - ing most of the period could be purchasd at a figure approximately that used in this trial. $1.68. On a basis of $1.68 for old corn, it was deemed but fair to put the new corn at $1.40. This allows ample for shucking the corn and for the shrink which naturally would have occurred had the corn remained in the field until November and then been marketed. The silage fed to lots 2 and 3 was made from corn which possessed very few or no ears and consequently is valued at but $6 per ton. Had it been good silage a charge of at least $10 would have been necessary to cover cost. The price of $25 for alfalfa hay is also much higher than normal. It in turn represents but a fair valuation, and must be taken into account in considering cost of gains. METHODS OF FEEDING The lambs in the dry lots were fed twice a day. TIiom- in the cornfields had access to water at all times and likewise to alfalfa hay. The oil meal and cottonseed nut cake in lots 6 and 7 were fed once a day. The lambs were weighed before taking into the field and likewise at the conclusion of the experiment upon three consecutive days. There was no appreciable loss during the trial, altho several lambs died in the cornfield lots when the trial was about half over, due to the fact that the feeder had allowed the salt to run out, and after being without for several days some of the lambs took too mueh. The plan had been to keep crushed rock salt before all lots constantly. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Feeding Lambs in the Fall 7 THE ADVISABILITY OF SUBSTITUTING SILAGE FOB PABT OF In this trial it was deemed advisable to ascertain if ullage could l»e worked into the ration as a partial substitute for corn where lamb* wen- being fall fed. These three lots of lambs were handled as follows: Lot 1 was worked up to a full feed of corn and parried on such thruout the trial. Lot 2 was carried on a light feed of corn, allowed all the alfalfa hay they wished, and what would !&gt;&lt;• culled » medium feed of silage. Lot 3 received no corn until shortly before the close of the test, but instead re - ceived all of the silage they would eat. During most of the trial they consumed over 2 pounds a day. They likewise had all of the alfalfa they wished in conjunction. The daily corn ration in these three lots amounted to .97 pound in lot 1. .47 pound in lot 2 and .14 pound in lot 3. The alfalfa consumption amounted to 1.99 pounds in lot 1. 1.49 pounds in lots 2 and 1.43 pounds in lot 3, while the silage consumption in lots 2 and 3 amounted to 1.09 and 1.9 pounds respectively. The gain on these three lot« of lambs decreased as the amount of corn decreased, which is but a repetition of results secured in previous trials. The daily gain in lot 1 amounted to .325 pound, in lot 2 to .256 pound and in lot 3 to .164 pound. Table 2 — Lots 1, 2 and 8. Lot 1 35 Lot 2 35 35 dumber in lot RATION Corn Aifalfs Corn Aifalfs Corn Alfalfa SUac. Alfalfa Silas* Corn (Light) Alfalfa Silas* (Heavy) Alfalfa SUM* Average final weight Average initial weight Average gain Average daily gain Average daily ration, lbs. — Corn Silage Ajfalfa Feed required per pound gain — Corn Silage Alfalfa Cost of 100 pounds gain Initial cost &lt;?i $17.91 per 100 lbs. Interest at 7%, 58 days Marketing cost Feed cost per lamb Total cost per lamb Selling price per 100 pounds Receipts (3.77 pounds shrink) Loss per lamb Nutritive ratio of ration fed 77.13 58.47 18.84 .325 .970 1.99 2.98 6.12 $16.85 $10.47 .108 .278 3.164 $14.02 $16.40 $12.06 $ 1.96 1:5.3 70.78 55.94 14.84 .256 .472 1.09 1.486 1.84 4.25 5.804 $14.90 $10.18 .103 .29 2.15 $12.72 $16.10 $10.97 $ 1.83 1:5.1 IHwr) 65.31 55.8 9.51 .164 .148 1.895 1.406 .872 11.55 8.57 $17.41 $ 9.99 .112 .286 1.66 $12,149 $15.90 $ 9.78 $ 2.26 1:5.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 16 8 Under feed required per 1 pound gain, practically :i pounds of corn mid (i pounds of alfalfa arc required in li&gt;1 1. Tliis is rather more feed than is required normally in winter feeding, an average tending to show about 4 pounds of corn and •'! of alfalfa. In other words, these lambs consumed considerably more alfalfa than corn and in making 1 pound of gain they look practically :t pounds additional hay to offset the 1 pound less corn eon&gt;unicd. My com - parison with lot 2. fed a medium ration of corn and a medium feed of silage and hay. it is found that to make 1 pound of gain they took 1.84 pounds of corn. 4.2.~&gt; pounds of silage and ."».* pounds of alfalfa. It will be noted here that the hay required is practically the tame as in lot 1, and that 4.2."&gt; poun pounds of corn. 1 pound of gain, In lot 3, it is found under feed requi a very small amount of corn and a very large amount of silage mid hay. the figures being .H!) pound of corn, 11. •"&gt;."&gt; pounds of silage, and !"i.."&gt;7 pounds of alfalfa; in oilier wordn, 20 pounds of roughness and less than 1 pound of grain, in contrast I i 111 pounds of roughness and 'A pounds of grain in lot 1 The cost of KK) pounds of gain in these three lots is found to be the lowest in lot 2. where some silage was used to replace corn, the figure here being $14.90. In lot 1, on straight corn and alfalfa, it was almost $2 higher, being $16.85, and in lot •'! it amounted to $17.41. The lambs were valued at $1(&gt;.4&lt;&gt; in lot 1, $16.10 in lot 2, and $15.90 in lot 3. On this basis the loss per lamb amount* to $1.96, $1.8.'} and $2.26 respectively, again showing in favor of lot 2. Lot '.I proved to be the heaviest losers of any lot in the test. The nutritive ratios of the rations consumed by these three lots are relatively narrow, due to the heavy alfalfa consumption. They varv from 1 :5.1 in lot 2 to 1 :5.7 in lot -i From this trial it would seem that fall fed lambs under dry lot conditions are rather expensive gainers altho eating a relatively large percentage of roughness to grain, this being especially true in lot 1. where the corn consumed amounted to less than I pound, being .97 pound, and the alfalfa consumption 1.90 pounds, and in this lot the lambs could have had more corn had they desired it. The practice of fattening lambs in the cornfield (luring the fall months is one which has become very popular and which is being used very extensively at the present time. Most men who follow this practice feel that they secure a larger gain for the feed con - sumed by feeding in this way than dry lot feeding, and also feel that there is sufficient advantage from the saving in labor and distribution of manure to warrant following this practice. iiiiifc "tl'scts 1.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Feeding Lamb* in the Fall 9 CORNFIELD FEEDING VS. DRY LOT FEEDING I.dt 1 Lot 4 Number in lot 36 Cornfield RATIO Alfalfa Alfalfa Average final weight Average initial weight Average gain :i 75.64 i.68 1K.M 19.96 .844 )7(i .87 Alfalfa &gt;!» .518 Feed required per pound gain Corn ',.224 Alfalfa Cost of 100 pounds gain Marketing cost Feed cost per lamb. Total cost per lamb Selling price per 100 pounds Receipts (3.77 pounds shrink) Loss per lamb Nutritive ratio of ration fed Liits 1 mill 4 in this trial were foil in the dry lot and oornfield respectively with the objeet in mind of ascertaining which would prove the more economical. In both lots alfalfa was kept before the liimlis all the time. Lot 1 hail a full feed of shelled corn fed twice daily, whereas lot 4 had access to corn in the field at all times. The daily irain made by the lambs in these two lots was slightly greater in the lot in the cornfield, the difference being .010 pound. The feed consumed a day amounted to somewhat more corn but considerably less alfalfa, the figures being .97 pound of corn in lot 1 and 1.04 pounds in lot 4. and 1.09 pounds of alfalfa in lot 1 and .527 pound of alfalfa in lot 4. It must he remembered, of course, that the lambs in lot 4 doubtless consumed considerable of the corn plant, and likewise had access to under - growth in the form of grass and weeds in the cornfield of which no record was made. However, this would be waste normally and consequently is not charged against them. As regards feed required to produce 1 pound of gain, 2.98 pounds of corn were consumed in let 1, whereas 3.22 pounds were consumed in lot 4. The chief difference is in the alfalfa requirements. In lot 1 this amounted to slightly over 6 pounds, whereas in lot 4 it was but a fraction over iy&gt; pounds. Consider - ing that the corn fed to lot 4 was new corn, containing some surplus moisture, it is doubtful if they required any more actual dry matter in their corn to produce a pound of gain than did the lambs in lot 4. TABLK 3 — Lots 1 and 4. Average &lt;laily »jain AvcraKf daily rati&lt; Corn Initial cost It $17.91 per 100 lbs. Interest ft ''',, r&gt;8 days $14.02 $12.31 $16.40 $16.40 $12.06 $11.78 * 1.96 $ .53 1:5.3 1:7.2 6.12 Sifi.HS $10.47 .108 .27K :s.i64 1.532 $10.02 $ 9.97 .112 .29 2.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebmska Experiment Station Bulletin 167 10 Under total cost of 100 pounds of gain, there is a very marked difference, lot 1 costing $16.85, whereas lot 4 put on gains for $10.02. With such a vast difference in the cost of gain it would naturally be expected that the loss would be less on the cornfield lambs than on the lambs fed in the dry lot. The figures here amount to •+l.!'t&gt; loss in the dry lot against 53 cents loss in the cornfield, or a difference in favor of the cornfield lambs of $1.43. The corn which the lambs in the field had was of a reasonably good quality and would have yielded 40 bushels per acre. The field which the lambs had access to was measured carefully and checkrows were husked out before the lambs had access to the corn; likewise, rows were left at the outside of the field to shuck out in order to ascertain the amount of corn which the lambs secured. From this it was felt that we were able to get quite a close check on the corn consumed by the lambs in the field. In lot 1 the nutritive ratio of the ration is 1 :5.3, which is rather narrow, while in lot 4 it is 1 :7.2, based on corn and alfalfa con - sumed. Were the corn plant considered, the ratio would be still wider. Hence, it is seen that lambs in the cornfield thrive on a relatively wide ratio. DOES IT PAY TO CLIP LAMBS TO BE FED IN THE CORNFIELD DURING FALL! Average daily gain Average daily ration — Corn 1.04 .87 Alfalfa .527 .518 Pounds feed required per pound gain — Corn 3.224 2.71 Alfalfa 1.532 1.6 Cost of 100 pounds gain $10.02 $ 8.74 Initial coit ® $17.91 $ 9.97 $ 9.19 Interest© 7%, 58 days .112 .108 Marketing cost .228 .228 Feed cost per lamb 2.00 1.76 Total cost per lamb $12.31 $11.27 $16.40 $12.60 $11.78 $10.09' I .63 $ 1.18 1:7.2 1:7 Selling price per 100 pounds.. Receipts (8.77 pounds shrink) Loss per lamb Nutritive value of ration fed ■InrlndM II. • rrcrltrA for wool. ABLE o 8 i am J. ~Lot 4 35 ~Lot 4 Lot 5 Lot 5 35 Number in lot. Number in lot 35 35 RATION Cornfield Alfalfa CornfUld Alfalfa (Clipped Iambi) Average initial weight Average gain Average daily gain r,r&gt;.6h 19.96 .344 51.31 20.01 .345 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Feeding Lambs in the Fall 11 During the fall months early lambs often appear to suffer con - siderably from the heat. Their wool has made considerable growth and actN as &lt;|tiite a blanket on hot days. Many feeders who purchase early prefer to clip their lambs before turning them in the cornfield on the ground that these lambs will gain more rapidly and show more net profit. To check this, lot 5 was clipped and turned in the cornfield. They had access to alfalfa, as did those in lot 4. After clipping, the lambs in lot 5 weighed 51.31 pounds in contrast to .")5.68 pounds, the weight of the lot 4 lambs at the start. As regards the rate of gain in these two lots, there is virtually no difference. The margin is slightly in favor of the clipped lambs, the daily gain being M4 and M4"&gt; pound respectively. The corn consumed by the undipped lambs amounted to 1.04 pounds daily in contrast to but .87 pound in lot 5. The alfalfa consump - ticn is practically the same, being .527 pound and .518 pound respectively. Under feed per 1 pound of gain, there is slightly less corn in lot 5 and a shade less alfalfa. The clipping, it might be said, sHved .."&gt;] pound of corn and .03 pound of alfalfa in producing a pound of gain. Due to this saving in feed rec|iiirements, the clipped lambs put on their gain for considerably less cost per hundred pounds than did the undipped ones, the figures here being $10.02 and $8.74 respectively. The chief factor in determining the advisability of clipping during recent years has been the relative market price pitid for clipped fut lambs. Due to the abnormally high price of wool there has been quite a tendency to discriminate severely against dipped lambs. The lambs in lot 4 sold for ifiti.40. whereas those in lot 5, due to the fact that they had been dipped, brought only $12.50 per hundred. This discrimination appeared to be ultra-severe, altho it was the customary discrimination made at the time. The lambs had clipped only 2..") pounds of wiwl at the time the experi - ment started. When sold they possessed an inch of staple. Possibly it would have been an advantage to clip the lambs shortly before Helling, as by that time the fleece would hnve at - tained considerably more weight and the lambs would have been discriminated against but little more severely than they were. As it was, doe to this severe discrimination, the loss on the clipped lambs was $1.18 in contrast to but . r »:j cents on the undipped lambs. The results obtained in this trial bear out financial state - ments secured in several preceding trials. In most instances, how - ever, the clipped lambs had made considerably larger gain, which tPtided to offset part of the discrimination in price. From thin and previous trails it would seem inadvisable to recommend the dip - ping for fall feeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">S&lt;hru*ku Wap9fimr.nl Station Uulletin 187 12 IMIKH IT I'AY TO AIM) A I'KOTKIN &lt; ON( KNTHATK WHEN FATTKMMJ I. \ vlUS IN THK inilM IKI.IH XiIiiiImt In lot minis Avrruifo Itnul wnlg-ht Avciuuc initlul wviifht Av*ru|f« Kuin Avi'fHKv dully ifdln Avenue* ilully rutinri, ll)«. Corn CuttoriM-iNl nut CMkr Oil m«Ml Oil I..-..I Alfulfu liu) I 1 i-i'il ro«t |mt lumli Tntul 4'&lt;mt par luiiili Hcllinic pric* par 100 pound*.... llivi-ipu &lt;:i. 77 pound* ithrink) \m»* p*r i«mb Nutritive ratio at ration tm\ It i« often &lt;l&lt;*«irc(l in the 1M UinVmu of lainlm to u&lt;t Ihcin rr.nl,, for niiirkri nt no parly h ilnti- n» potwilili 1 , To Hccompliall thiit the fi'&lt;'diii(f of protein NUiiplemcntM (win been rcHortml to. In tliiv trial lot » wn» fed oil incul Mini lot 7 cottotiMccd nut «ake, with the pur - j"i»r 111 tniiiil of I'lH-i'kiiiK with lot 4 ami aKcertaininir whether it ix pnxxililr to increawi* the train and the net profit thereby. The addition of a protein Miipplernent hIwh.vh narrowN the nutritive ratio of a ration. A ration which ix too narrow often provn •*■ |ii.iixivi', In the trxt n-porti-il in the followinKt the nutritive ratio wan reduced from 1 :7 to 1 :(( by milling the xiipplement. Kirxt, ax regardit the daily Kaiti: Dock the addition of a pro - tein NUpplement Imvmm the dally u»'n&gt; ' IM 4, reeeivinit no itup - plement, gained ,U44 pound, wherean lot 6, reeeiviiiK oil meal, gained .408 and lot 7, receiving cottonaeed nut cake, gained .383 pound. Hence, the addition of the protein supplement did in - ereane the daily gain, and by quite a margin. Aa regardi the amount of feed conaumed daily, the corn did not vary to Npeak of TAHLJC 6—LotM !t, a and 7. Alfuir* h«y 1'iiuniU fi'Kil r«-«|ulr»il p»r pounil K«in — Com .,.,,,,, .,,,.,,,,.., • ('iiUfimurd nut c«k« &lt; H»t ut 100 pOUMlU Kultl Initiul «'&lt;&gt;»t H 917.01 ptr 100 Ibn. InUraitt U T/i , (&gt;* days Murktlriif cunt :ir. 4 l...t 7 u CurnlUM Alf.lf. I ..rntl.M C.,rn(UW f'Mtonaawl mil . iik. Alf«lf» ......tic liUHi .:s44 7».2« 2:i.(M&gt; ,408 H0.4r, 5K.2 tin 1.04 1.04 i.w .16 ,M7 .IN .641 ,M 11,224 2.0M 2.;« ,4:t i.r.;i2 •If,.- . i v.vi .112 :it* 2.00 I 12.31 I 16.40 Ill.Th II .63 1:7.2 48 l.X) II4.W $ !• ■». .112 JM 2 ..'ill* f 1 2,«2 1 1 6.40 I12.M I .08 1:0.1 l.:i« 117.41 $10.42 .117 .346 2..TM I18.SS $16.40 $12.57 $ 44 I :«.:&lt;. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Feediny Lamb* in tin h'nll 13 in tin' three lot*, it beiiiK l.oJ pound* in lot* 4 iuhI (i iiml |,&lt;K&gt; pound* in lot 7, The alfalfa consumption amounted to virtually ,6 pound in till three InatancM. The oil meul eonawnptkM] ippros* limited .2 pound in lot ti him) in lot 7 it wa* I he plnii to lime the COttoimced nut eake approximate the Niinie. However, the lamb* (liil not »eelll to relixh the eiike a* Well UN tllO*c ill lot 6 relmhed the nil meul hihI enn*&gt;ei|iientl,v they did not ci,u*um« i|iiite iih niiii'li, the MIlliMllit here hcing .10 pound. To product 1 pound of irnin it rei|iilr«*d in lot. 4, 'Ml'l pound* of corn and 1.68 pound* of alfalfa, In In) ti, which had iieiw In oil meul, '1. liM hound*) of corn and .4* pound* of oil meul, together with 1 ,:(.'( pound* of iilfulfii, redu I the amount &lt;&lt;f corn nMPmwary t &gt; [il'iidllce I pound of tfllill li&gt; ..'&gt;! pound mid the amount of iilfiiH'.i iiy ,2 pound. On thii lm»i» the oil meal retunied h valuation of +7* per ton. Ah a rcNiilt of the highly miti»fiietory khiiim »ecured in lot (t, their Ion* wan only m v+nt* per brad in i'ontran( to n Iihm of '•&gt;'■'&lt; cent* on the liiuilm I hut did not receive oil meul, Till! comI of loo puunda tf»in i* »ilifliily l«aa in the oil uienl lamba, baing ifO.HO in eoutrilMt to flu ill' where no Hllppleinelit WMN fed, Turning to the cottonacad nut eake Iambi in lot 7, it I* found thai the corn reijiiired to produce I pound ut uuiii amouuted to L' 'i'i pouuiU in cotitniHl to :i 'I'l pouuiU in lot 4, rcceMuif no Miip - pleineni, mid thut the iilfnlfii amounted to \,'M\ pound* in contra*! to I, ,').'! pound* in lot 4. In aildition, lot 7 iei|iiircd, to produce I pound Of irilill, ,4U (NJUnd of eottou*eed mil ellke, llel , the .4 t pound of mil rake replaced .'!'■'&gt; pound of eoru and .17 pound of alfalfa. The cottouM-ed nut cake wh* thu* worth +II.WI, A* thi* cottoiiNccd nut cuke Mold tit &gt;M&gt;o per ton, it* um in the experiment did not prove jUMtinahle at the price, even tho it did InorraM the daily iniiu cou*ideralily. The cimt of loo pound* vain in thi* lot proved to In* f lull in eoiitnixt to +1" &lt;»2 in lot 4. The 1mm on each in mil in lot 7 amounted to D4 cent*, which i* II cent* than the Iihm on the lalllh* ill lot 4, In Humming up the above, it would »eein *tafc to druw the eon - elu*inu that the addition of n protein Niippleineut, cither cotton - need nut cake or oil meal, did iiierenxe the rule of t;iiiii of lanilm running in the cornfield. At the price* uaed in thi* teat the nil meul leaaened the Ionm materially, while th ttonaatd cuke In - crt'aaed it *lichtly. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 167 In Home sections considerable blue lthvn pasture is nvailiihle for use in feeding iiniimils during the full months. Due to the cus - tomary fall rains this grans is often very potable and live stock seem to relish it. Some feeders contend thnt this grass will pro - ilin-c flesh economically and resort to it in fattening lambs. In this trial we have handled lot 8 on grass iti order to secure a check on lot 1 fed in the dry lot thruout the test, and also on lot t&gt; whieh whs miming in the cornfield and had oil meal and alfalfa hay. The lambs in lot K hail no additional feed other than the grans. until late in the trial, when the grass became very short and it was necessary to supply alfalfa hay. During the last 10 days of the trial a limited amount of corn and oil meal was fed to them with the" idea of putting on some finish. This amounted to ."!&gt; pound of corn and .19 pound of oil meal daily. The lambs in this lot made an average daily gain during the trial of .24.") pound in contrast to A2~) pound by the lambs in the dry lot on alfalfa and eom. and .4(18 pound on the lambs in the cornfield with oil meal and alfalfa supplemented. The average daily ration of course is hard to compute owing to the t'nct that the lambs in U \ s. CORNFIELD VS. BLUE Table 6— Lots 1, 6 and 8. Number in lot Lot 1 35 Lot 6 35 Lot H 35 Corn Alfalfa CornfMd oil meal Alfalfa Him- k'rn»» Corn- Oil in.'nl&gt; Alfalfa RATION Average Anal weight Average initial weight Average gain Average daily gain Average daily ration, lbs. — Corn Oil meal Alfalfa Pounds feed required per pound gain — Corn Oil meal Alfalfa Coat of 100 pound* gain Initial cost Hi $17.91 per 100 lbs.. Interat ® lie, 68 days Marketing cost Feed cost per lamb Total cost per lamb Selling price per 100 pound* Receipts (3.77 pound* shrink) Loss per lamb Nutritive ratio of ration fed 77.31 58.47 18.84 .325 .970 1.99 2.98 6.12 $16.85 $10.47 .108 .278 3.164 $14.02 $16.40 $12.06 $ 1.96 1:5.3 n.u 55.6 23.66 .408 1.04 .196 .541 2.68 .48 1.33 $ 9.80 $ 9.96 .112 .228 2.319 $12.62 $16.40 $12.54 $ .08 1:6.1 70.54 56.31 14.23 .24. r » .79' .19' .9246 .56 .134 3.77 $ 8.83 $10.09 .113 .228 1.256 $11.68 $15.90 $10.61 $ 1.07 1:6 XT ■For taut ton da: ■« of trial </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Feeding Lambs in the Fall 15 lot 8 had u'i-hs.s as the main part of their subsistence. Owing to the dry weather over the latter part of the trial, they wore forced to depend considerably upon alfalfa hay and they consumed alto - gether during the tent an average of .92 pound daily. The total number of pounds of corn consumed per lainli amounted to 7.9 in contrast to "&gt;6 pounds (an even bushel) consumed by the lambs in lot 1 and 62 pounds by the lambs in the cornfield. Hence, consid - erably more grain was required by those on graM. This is very evident when it is noted under feed required per 1 pound of gain, that it took 2.98 pounds of corn on the part of the lambs in the dry lot and but .56 pound of corn where the lambs were on blue grau to make each pound of gain, and 2.68 pounds where the lambs were in the cornfield. The grass was charged against the lambs at 1/ 2 cent per day. This makes a very fair return for pasture and at the same time a very cheap method of handling lamb*. With this charge added to the cost of the hay and grain consumed, the total cost of putting 100 pounds on the lambs on blue grass amounted to $8.32, whereas the total cost where the lambs had corn and alfalfa in the dry lot amounted to $6.8"), and where the lambs were in the cornfield to $9.80. The loss on the blue grass IhiiiIin was increased somewhat by the fact that they were discriminated against when sold, buyers con - tending that they had grown quite well but lacked finish. This it an accusation which has been brought against grass lambs in com - parison to corn-fed lambs in previous trials. The buyer's judg - ment was well grounded as was proved later by the dressing per - centages furnished by the packing house, and the watery condition of the carcasses on the hooks. The actual loss amounted to $1,117 per head on the grass lambs in contrast to $1.96 loss on the lambs fed in the dry lot and H cents on the lambs in the cornfield. Normally the grass fed lambs have shown the most profit and the cheapest gain of any lot in the experiment. Possibly the fact that the grass was not us good as usual during this particular trial tends to offset any chance which the lambs had of showing the most profit. 7-H-IH MM I </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station litilletin 16 16? 32;: 122 S Z CIS ggg c ', I- t • «9« wVoi — e&gt; do- 3«4d k'ocob i (- &lt;fi 1 1- «"•■■■ °i '" ~T*T ~. •*. ** « "T ": •i i- •» ** 2 2*2 — — Z** zi °*' °' ® 2 " " "Z ««*» a ~¥ ~S2S ~lis ~i ~s "sis "Irsi ~ssss? v. »j o — — mwm d «i si d © e&gt;d~i «i tc w ~ a "s = 5ss = s =^ ~5SS Tm ~«a ** £ *" ~ S££ S x tI t. r. d &lt;=&gt;&lt;=&gt; -i.-t.-d. COO p4*2»J WWW C C»"X «wi- •» n ;j&gt; -m« £g* s "ix- * - 76?, i- si- HBI V. d — — m — ■» o ?i ri d © dsH www ■£ tc 1 d ■ 44 does r&lt; sss ss ■ - K fi qg g %» •» « m w « «c » si x oc»« si si © ««ie « 2*^* *"' ■/ si si »«ei ww «• M MM(» r ,a~8"fti~pS~8~P~*S5~SSfS"SS = ? ft K « t » M *Wf: S t- «FS n?8 eve «* ~ t- K X X J sss ?l ' -- i * •»r as* « "5 22: £22 °° * &gt;J ° C ' X ' *' x '* ■'•^ B "^ " a •■ §M' M«l *~i~«3~5K~a«i Sj •» *• — 2t ■* £ ii "' '"' *" * *~ l "" x « » x .-'.-:' .-r C •* * ©w-: r*** t *:•?*. r r*^ «i-v •• 0 01 0b O O © ft t ~ 10 I ™ I • (^ I * i • f i * i " i fl - «•«•» i-:-» 3 ,- S.i:S "ow is- — x Hi BBS S:S2 ci M M o ?. e&gt;. at *t* t- I ■ &lt;■ o I Sii 'E « a i' M5 sSs's s tsa sst; im m * &lt;• • 22— ?l — — '* * te't-t-" i- 1- 1- ■-,-,- 1 I I s «» ea- •5 g~l §55 5?S 3 B 4iB8 SS^ 181 I «• 0i xt? o © «! ,-" ts c « 10 r^ i- m: rt i« •*. * "a = 8 = S25i r "S = y ::r ?'6- BBS gas" $gs ** « ~ 11 — i2 )f £ • **' &lt;* * •- t-i^t- t- 1- » 9 I 2 i s S • XN« To 2 • •» • *22 S-- " * &lt;•&lt;•&lt;• «»•- ■«'«'■« ft c, s~f~3fi iii~l % ?5f 5s 8 ***. 3 3 a 9 ■£-. ~ ~ w es kx« »ojj ui J aioii www ujuiui 3 S!r ■ •5 B :- O* • S =d2 225 " " : ■•• ••• '-•- 1 - I ■ % g |i &lt;• • •»• m«u u&gt; 4 u&gt;i«i&lt; uiww mImIdi 9 a"W"lf» ?»8 it u sasssa ks= •» S ►:►:» «&gt;•»&lt; w 3 irfSS "*«■» «.o p u- : =ar» •-,.•. =lif •». I « L ~ 1 ..5 iig 52J 528 ztt y II i Hh ! E- c i I 151 |,| I Uhi Ijfi Jill III i|i]J , 1 II III Iff If 13 Is! IJ'ii I- • _, _ — _ „ - I 11 SE. c / 3 IBS 3 3 3 3 3 3 7 = 7 8 Sf!t SI S =88 SSS </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>