<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA State Board of Health BULLETIN</title>
               <date value="1917">1917</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA State Board of Health BULLETIN Published quarterly at the office of the Secretary of the Board, Lin - coln, Nebraska. Entered as second class matter, January 15, 1917, at the Post-office, Lincoln, Nebraska, under the act of July 16th, 1894. VOLUME 4 JANUARY, 1917 NUMBER 1 This Bulletin will be sent free to any person within the State upon request. SECRETARIES: C. T. BURCHARD, M. D., President, Falls City. H. B. CUMMINS, M. D., Vice-President, Seward. L. STARK, M. D., Treasurer, Hartington. E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Secretary, Lincoln. BOARD OF HEALTH KEITH NEVILLE, Governor. WILLIS E. REED, Atty. General. W. H. CLEMMONS, Supt. Pub. Instr. J. D. CASE, M. D., State Health Inspector, Lincoln. Where darkness is. there disease germs are more plentiful and live long. Where darkness is. there deeds of darkness breed. Where dark - ness is there live palor, anaemia, languor, feebleness and blindness. Look how eagerly the house geraniums lean toward the light! How spindley and fragile they grow if kept in a North window! </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Fourth Annul Bulletin 3 Report of Delegate to Conference on Poliomyelitis To the State Board of Health — Governor John H. Morehead, Atty. Gen. W. E. Read, State Supt. Dr. O. A. Thomas. Gentlemen : Pursuant to your direction I attended the conference held in the Bureau of Public Health on Poliomyelitis (Infantile Pa - ralasi.s called by A. H. Glennan, acting surgeon general, Wash - ington, D. C, August 17th and 18th. Representatives of prac - tically all of the state were welcomed by Secretary McAdoo of the treasury department to this, the first conference of this kind ever called by the Public Health Service. In the absence of Surgeon General Blue, who was ill, Assistant Surgeon Gen - eral A. H. Glennan opened the conference. Secretary McAdoo said in part: "The public health service is trying to bring about a more intelligent combat with this mysterious enemy. I have great hopes that you gentlemen will have some regulations which will be so reasonable that they will impose a minimum of discomfort and the maximum of benefit." On roll call of state, each state reported conditions therein, as follows: Alabama. 64; Arkansas. 3; California. 4; Colorado. 4; Connecticut, 323; Dataware, 2; District of Columbia. 16: Florida. 20; Illinois. 206; Indiana, 37; Iowa, 25; Kentucky, 16: Louisiana. 51; Maine, 14; Maryland, 66; Massachusetts, 105; Michigan. 97; Minnesota, 318; Missouri, 11; Montana, 15; Ne - braska, 10; New Hampshire. 7; New Jersey, 1,714; New York, 7,753; North Carolina 20; Ohio, 166; Oregon, 36; Pennsylvania, 336; Rhode Island, 53; South Carolina, 55; South Dakota, 22; Tennessee. 36; Texas, 30; Vermont, 13; Virginia, 29; Washing - ton, 5 : West Virginia, 8 ; Wisconsin, 70 ; which showed the pres - ence of anterpolimyelitis present in every state in the union. Ne - braska had but 10 cases to report at that time, with but two deaths, all of which were sporatic cases. We were proud to report the fact that Nebraska had declared the disease com- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Suit Board ol Health munieable and quarantinable since 1908, being the first state to quarantine anterior poliomyetlitis. We reported an epidemic in 1909, the effects of which is yet keeping our orthopaedic hos - pital busy. Two hours were given to considering what should be done for crippled and deformed, which are the sequela of anter - ior poliomyelitis. Only three states reported that care of these unfortunate cripples by the state and none but Nebraska re - ported an institution wholly for this purpose at the present time. Again we are proud of Nebraska when we could report that for several years we have had an institution taking care of all crip - pled and deformed children. Some of the leading men of the Atlantic States, after com - plimenting the west, had to admit that the west was more pro - gressive in this matter than the east. While we are exceptionally progressive in the after care of our children afflicted with infan - tile paralysisi, yet we are painfully deficient on account of our small appropriation in putting into effect many of the sanitary rules proctecting our state against another epidemic. The conferenie developed the facts as they exist overthe Unit - ed States, which show that some states did not quarantine the disease at all, while others, as New York, were putting into effect a quarantine of eight weeks, while Nebraska 'quarantine is for a period of thirty days. The conference discussed at length the opening of the public schools and adopted rules as follows: "When schools are opened, beginnings should be made with high schools, proceeding to lower age groups no more rapidly than coplete medical exam - inations can be made." Certificates of private physicians will not alone be a sufficient basis for the issue of a permit to travel ; permits for interstate travel should be based on medical examina - tion. It is believed that the federal government can pefrom all duties of notification and certification required in interstate rela - tio8ii in case of unusual prevalence of infantile paralysis. The epidemic prevalent in certain states at this time indi- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">FMTtfl ABaMfcl Bill* tlS 5 cates a probabillity of epidemic prevalence next year in states not gravely affected now. Under the head of minimum requirements for the control of poliomyelitis (infantile paralysis) the conference adopted the following rules and regulations: 1. Reports — Every physician, attendant, parent, house - holder or other person having knowledge of a known or sus - pected case of acute anterior poliomyelitis ( infantile paralysis) must immediately report the same to the local health authori - ties. 2. Placarding — Whenever a case of acute anterior poliomy - elitis is reported to the local health authorities, they shall affix in a conspicuous place at each outside entrance of the building, house or flat, as the case may be, a warning card. Defacement of such placards or their removal by any other than the local health authorities or the duly authorized representative of the State Board of Health is strictly prohibited. 3. Quarantine of Patient — All cases of acute poliomyelitis must be quarantined for at least six weeks. Quarantine most not be raised, however, until the premises have bee nthoroughly disinfected dj- or under the supervision of the health officer. All persons continuing to reside on the infected premises shall be confined to the infected premises until quarantine has been raised, except as hereinafter provided. No one but the necessary attendant, the physician, the health officer and representatives of the State Board of Health may be permitted to enter or leave the infected premises. Upon leaving they must take all precautions to prevent the spread of the disease. The nursing attendant may leave the premises only by permission granted by the local health officer. 4. Quarantine of exposures — Members of the family over sixteen years of age may be removed from the premises, upon permission of the local health officer, after thorough disinfect - tion of person and clothing. Such children may be removed </seg>
            <seg id="p006">V briska Stale ioard ol lemltfc only to premises upon which none but adults reside and must be confined to the premises (in the house) for two weeks from date of removal, during which period they must be kept under close observation by the local health authorities, and no child shall be permitted to visit or otherwise come in contact with them during this period. They must not return to the infected premises or come in contact in any way with the patient or at - tendant, until quarantine has been terminated. All children who continue to reside on the infected premises must be held under close observation for at least two weeks following the termination of the last case on the premises. 5. Exclusion From theSchools, Etc. — All children who con- tinue to reside on the infected premises must be excluded from the schools and other public gatherings for at least two weeks following date of releasing of quarantine. All children who have been exposed to the disease and who have been removed from the infected premises, in accordance with the provisions of rule 4, must be excluded from the schools and from all other public gatherings for at least two weeks from date of last exposure. The patient must be excluded from the schools and all public, gatherings for at least two weeks after the quarantine is raised. School teachers aid other persons employed in or about a school building, who have been exposed to the disease must be excluded from the school building and grounds for a period of two weeks following the date of last exposure and until persons and clothing have been thoroughly disinfected. Whenever the schools are closed on account of an outbreak of acute poliomyelitis, children under the age of 16 years shall be excluded from Sunday schools, churches, picture shows and all other public gatherings and shall be confined to their own premises. 6. Precautions — No person, except the necessary attend - ant, the physician and the health officer may be permitted to </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Fourth Annul Bolktin 7 come in contact with the patient. Such persons must not handle or prepare food for others and their intercourse with other mem - bers of their household must be as restricted as possible. The infected premises, especially the sick room shall be thoroughly screened against flies and any such insects as may enter the sick-room shall be exterminated therein. All toilets used by the patient or attendants and those in which discharges from the patient are deposited must thoroughly screened against flies and freely treated with an approved disinfectant. 7. Removals — No person affected with acute interior polio - myelitis shall be removed from the premises upon which he is found unless consent to such removal be first obtained from the local health authorities or the State Board of Health, and then only after strict compliance with the provisions of these rules. Under no circumstances shall permission be granted for the removal of any patient or article from the infected premises to any premises upon which milk or other food stuffs are produced, sold or handled. No person affected with acute anterior poliomyelitis shall be removed from any city, village, township or county in which he is found unless consent to such removal be first obtained from the State Board of Health. 8 Sale of Milk and Other Foodstuffs From Infected Prem - ises Prohibited — Whenever a case of acute anterior poliomyelitis shall occur on any premises where milk or other foodstuffs are either produced, handled or sold, the sale, exchange or distribu - tion on such premises in any manner whatsoever, or the removal from the infected premises of milk, cream, any milk products or other foodstuffs until the case have been terminated by re - moval, recovery or death, and the premises and contents and all utensils have been thoroughly disinfected under the supervision of the local health authorities, is prohibited. Provided, that in the event of acute anterior poliomyelitis occurring on a dairy farm the live stock, the properly sterilized milk utensils and delivery outfit, may be removed to some non-infected premises and the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nckratka Suit tart •! leitth milking done and milk cared for and sold from such other prem - ises by persons other than those of the household of the person thus affected, upon obtaining permission to do so from the local health authorities or the State Board of Health. Whenever a case of acute anterior poliomyelitis shall occur on premises connected with any store, such store shall be quar - antined until the case has been terminated by removal, recovery ordeath, and the premises are thoroughly disinfected, provided, however, that if the premises are so constructed that the part in which the case exists can be and is effectively sealed, under the supervision of the local health authorities, from the store, and provided further that the employees and all other persons con - nected with the store do not enter the part of the premises where the case exists and do not come in contact with the patient, his attendant, or any article whatsoever from the quarantined prem - ises, the store attached to the quarantined premises need not be closed. t). Delivering of Milk, Groceries and Other Necessities — Milk, foodstuffs and other necessities may be delivered at the quarantined premises, but there must be no contact between the patient or attendant and the delivery agent. The householder must provide a sterilized container (a freshly scalded bottle or pail to receive the milk, and the delivery agent must not handle this bottle or pail in making the delivery. No milk bottle, basket or any other article whatsoever may be taken out of or away from the infected premises during the period of quarantine. Be - fore milk bottles are removed from the premises after quarantine is raised they must be sterilized under the direction of the local health authorities. Mail which has been handled by the patient or attendant must not be taken from the premises. 10. Disinfection — All articles taken from the sick-room must be disinfected upon removal. Exposure in the open air of carpets, rugs, curtains, bedding, and similar articles from the infected premises for the purpose of airing, shaking, beating or sunning is strictly prohibited, unless, in the oinion of the local health au- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Foortfc AmuI Mktb 9 thorities, such may be done without danger of the spread of the diseases. Books, toys and other similar articles used to amuse the patients are best disposed of by burning. Under no circumstances should borrowed toys or books be returned. Library and school books must not be returned ; they must be burned. Bed and body linen which has been in contact with the patient and handkerchiefs or cloths which have been used to receive discharges from the patient must be immersed in an approved disinfectant before removal from the sick-room, and after removal should be boiled. All discharges from the patient must be thoroughly disin - fected before removal from the sick-room. No article of clothing, or other article, may be removed from the infected premises to a laundry or other place for washing unless previously disinfected by immersion in an approved dis - infectant, and the approval of the local health authorities has been obtained. House animals, such as cats, dogs or any other household pets and all other animals or fowls must be strictly excluded from the infected building, house or flat, as the case may be, during the entire period of quarantine. Any such animals which have been in contact with the patient must be subjected to a thorough disinfecting bath before removal from the infected building, house or flat, and must not be permitted to re-enter the same. Such animals must be confied in an outbuilding. Doga and cats running at large should be destroyed. Before quarantine is raised the infected premises and all articles of furniture and clothing therein must be thoroughly disinfected by or under the supervision of the local health au - thorities in a manner approved by the State Board of Health. 11. Deaths. Burials and Transportation of the Dead — When the body of anyone dead from acute anterior poliomyelitis is to be transported by railroad or other common carrier, the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">■* 10 Nebraska Slate Bo«rd ol Health official rules of the State Board of Health governing the trans - portatio nof dead must be observed. Dr. William Colby Rucker, assistant surgeon of the public health, who had a large part in arranging the meeting and who presided over most of its sessions, said : "This conference should do much toward allaying public hysteria. It should make the general public more at ease and more in harmony with the work which their local health officers are doing to prevent and control infantile paralysis." E. ARTHUR CARR, Secy, and Delegate to above Conference. THE UNITED STATES PUBLIC HEALTH SERVICE ASKS DO YOU Believe in national preparedness and then Fail to keep yourself physically fit? Wash your face carefully and then Use a common roller towel? Go to the drug store to buy a tooth brush and then Handle the entire stock to see if the bristles are right? Swat the fly and then Maintain a pile of garbage in the back yard? — United States Public Health Servive. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Fovth Annul Bulletin 11 SOME EXPERIMENTS WITH A INTERIOR POLIOMYELITIS. The epidemic of Infantile Paralysis that is now raging in the east need as yet have no terrors for the Nebraskan that does not go too far in that direction and voluntarily expose either himself or family. As announced in the daily press of July 12th, 1916, we have but three cases in Nebraska that have been reported to the State Health Department, and as it is a report - able and communicable disease which must be reported, we have no reason to believe in the existence of others. The present epi - demic as it exists in the east seems to be more murderous in type that the epidemic that we had in Nebraska in 1908. The epidemic at that time left many cripples but the loss of life was very infrequent. Up to date none of our scientists have posi - tively identified the germ causing the disease but it is known that there is one, and in this epidemic it seems to fulfill the law that nearly all other bacteria do of increasing in virulence as it passes through numbers of individuals. Right here is one of the great elements of danger in this as well as other infections disease; i. e., the mild case may be productive of many severe ones, and for that reason the mild ones should be handled as carefully as any of those that are more severe in type . As the pathology of the disease is purely degenerative, it renders it more difficult to handle as to the final outcome and final result. In the average inflamatory lesion we have a patient who either dies or gets well, while in Infantile Paralysis, they can die, get well or remain cripples either for life or varying periods of time. The mode of transmission of the infection is not as yet thoroughly understood but we know that it is contagious and follows defi - nite lines in its travels. For example, you will discover the dis - ease following one street in a town, or staying in one particular neighborhood. In the epidemic which we had in Nebraska in 1908. the towns that were successively visited followed the lines of railroad communication leading from the town where it first made its appearance. At that time the disease first made its appearance at Stromsburg. followed the line of the K. C. &amp; 0. to Benedict, then into York and from York went both ways over </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 m dal* ■_ — — j l**ltk the B. &amp; M. and the Northwestern. Leaving Stromsburg the other way, i. e., the Union Pacific, it went up and down the lines of that railroad and the cases as reported seemed to follow the transportation lines radiating from the various town where it had put in its appearance. One of the peculiarities of this disease is a tendency to variance in its manner of attacking different families insofar as the contagion seems to exist. For example, I have seen instances where there were five children in a family and only one have the disease and the rest seem to be absolutely immune. I had one instance where we had nine children in a family and they all had the disease in various modified forms. But just because it will at times attack but one member of a family is no argu - ment that it is not highly contagious and that it should not be be quarantined. The disease should be and is subject to the most stringent quarantine that the Board of Health can devise and, as in our previous experience, a rigid quarantine controlled the disease, we must insist on one for any case that appears at this time, as that is the only method whereby we may hope to control any epidemic that may appear or to prevent one if a case does appear in the state. The symptoms of the disease are many and varied, no two cases showing the same symptoms in onset and development. As a rule the child has many of the symptoms of a slight intestinal disturbance and the paralysis is only discovered when it is time for it to get up, and we find that the child cannot walk or is paralyzed in some of its muscles sufficiently to impair their usefulness. There are other cases that apparently have a great amount of meningeal involvment and begin with the average symptoms of anything, but suddenly discover that they are paralyzed in one or more groups of mus - cles having had no symptoms of any diseased condition prior to the onset of the paralysis. In general it is safe to say that where you have an attack of intestinal indigestion in a child that is slow in recovering the presence of a positive Eernig sign with the depression that seems to be in excess of what the symptoms warrant, that case must be watched closely for the advent of a paralysis. As to treatment, the greatest thing is prohhylactic </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Fourth Auul lulltlin 13 and is of great importance. If you can prevent the disease from obtaining a foothold you have gone farther in the treatment than can possibly be attained in any other way. Infantile pa - ralysis should be the greatest "Safety First" disease in the whole category of human ailments. Prevent its onset if pos - ■sible, but prevent its spread in any and every way possible. The treatment of the condition after it is present consists of general treatment to maintain nutrition in the muscles involved. In those cases with a larger or smaller amount of meningeal in - volvment a spinal puncture removing a portion of the spinal fluid will give quicker relief than any of the things advocated for the treatment that I personally have ever used. But what - ever else is done, n aintain the nutrition of the affected muscles in any manner that best appeals to you until some positive means of overcoming the paralysis is found. Personally, I do not see the practicability of the lately discovered Adrenalin treatment, but it may prove successful, so it is not for me to criticize it until I am better informed as to the results following such treat - ment. It is up to the local health afficers in the towns and counties to prevent, if possible, any invasion of our State with this dis - ease by insisting on the rigid observance of the laws, rules and regulations of the Nebraska State Board of Health when it does make its appearance and to prevent its appearance by destroy - ing the breeding places of flies and other vermin that are recog - nized carriers of the disease. Every doctor should see to it that his clientele have their children looked after and have their noses and throats in as good a condition as possible, as it is gen - erally believed that the infection travels by way of the air pas - sages. In conclusion, we wish to say that with any case that ap - pears suspicious we should not forget the great idea of every cor - poration and manufacturing plant in the country, but use "Safety First" to prevent the spread and consequent damage of this dread disease of childhood. L. STARK. M. D., Hartington. Neb. Treasurer Nebraska State Board of Health </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska SMe Board ol Icahh SEWARD COUNTY ORGANIZATION The County Board of Health of Seward County. Neb., was organized February 16, 1916, i naccordance with Rules and Regu - liitions of the Nebraska State Board of Health, and consists of one Registered Physician, the Chairman of Board of County Commissioners and County Sheriff. This Board adopted and is working under The Rules and Regulartions of Nebraska State Board of Health. In order to get the County to working in har - mony, the Health Officer has called upon all physicians in the County, and they have talked over the rules. Every physician in the county is following the rules, and all contagious diseases are reported to the County Health Officer, when within the juris - diction of the County Board of Health. Blank stamped cards have been sent to each physician, on which to report. Cards are also supplied to all physicians upon which to report funripation and disinfection, and all follow the same method of same. Quar - antine cards are also supplied to all hpysicians and they are in - structed to place same, and report such. Placards have been printed and will soon be supplied to all physicians, bearing the words. "Contagious Disease "Within," on one side and "Extracts From Rules and Regulations" on the opposite side. The "ex - tract cover such rules and regulations as parents and children should know. ''Extracts From Rules and Regulations" have also been printed on a slip, and the County Superintendent of Public Instruction has promised to send one to each school dis - trict with instructions to post in a conspicuous place in each school room, and instruct the pupils in same. This, the Health Officer feels will do more to educate the community than any other means we know of. There has been reported to this board 128 cases of reportable diseases, as follows: Measles, 91: smallpox, 24: diphtheria, 1; scarlet fever. 9. and tuberculosis. 3. The quarantine rules have been structly enforced, and while we have had very little bother in maintaining same, we have had two violations of same. These -were prosecuted in justice </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Fourth Anaial Bnlletin 15 court, and in each instance the parties pleaded guilty, paid their fine, and went away feeling that they had been honestly and fairly dealt with, and assured the Health Officer that they had learned something in regard to quarantine, and that they would never need to be called upon to answer such a charge again. The Health Officer has made a careful study of the Rules and Regula - tions of Nebraska State Board of Health, and feels that they have covered the ground thoroughly, and that if these rules are followed, nobody will suffer any hardship and the community will be greatly benefitted. "We surely are greatly indebted to our State Board of Health, and should do all in our power to assist them in their work. The Health Officer has also taken steps to have all villages in the county establish boards of health in accordance with Rules and Regulation of State Board of Health, and most of them have done so. The City of Seward also organized a board of health under the Rules and Regulatiosn of Nebraska State Board of Health. To this board reports are as follows : Chickenpox, 3 ; measles. 7 ; smallpox, 7 ; diphtheria, 1 ; scarlet fever, 18 ; and whooping cough, 6. There has been no violations of quarantine. Arrested for Practicing Medicine. Independent-Democrat, Seward, Neb. : Louis Sleich was ar - rested in this city last Friday charged with practicing medicine without a certificate from the State Board of Health. Dr. S. E. Ragan filed the complaint after securing convincing evidence. Sleich had been here several weeks and had secured several patients. Sleich was arraigned before Judge Gladwish on Friday, who, after hearing the evidence of four patients, bound the man over to the district court under $100 bond, which he could not furnish, in default of which he was remanded to jail. Evidence showed that Seich was a sort of chiropractor and osteopath as well as prescribing medicine for his patients. He claimed to have prac - ticed in several other towns in the state and admitted that he </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Ncfemka SMC Board •! Iraltk 16 knew he was doing so illegally. Seich is a middle aged man and claimed to have a family in Omaha. Saturday evening Judge Corcoran came down from York to grant Sleich a parole to Sheriff Niemann, so that Sleich is at liberty temporarily, with orders to report here at stated itnervals. Sleich paid the costs of the preliminary hearing and the judge's trip. He left town Sunday, telling Sheriff Niemann that he in - tended taking examination before the State Board of Health for admission as a legal practitioner. The work of prosecuting this case is to be commended as there has always been in past years laxity in the enforcement of laws affecting such cases as Sleich 's and the enforcement of health and quarantine laws. Under the present State Board of Health, who drafted the present health laws, conditions have improved to a great extent and will continue to improve. However, many counties in the state have no boards of health and many towns and villages are in the same fix. Since the appointment of a County Health Officer things have happened ; there has been sev - eral prosecutions and convictions for violation of quarantine, and he has urged the town boards of the county towns to either act as local boards or health or appoint such. This is a spirit we like to see in a public official, and when an officer has spent much time gathering evidence enough to convict a lawbreaker we want to see a sentence imposed sufficiently severe, fine or jail or both, to create in that lawbreaker a wholesome respect for the laws and the courts. Prevention of Infantile Paralysis. To control the present epidemic of infantile paralysis, accord - ing to a statement issued by the United States Public Health Ser - vice today, the chain of infection between persons harboring germs of the disease and the well members of the community should be broken. Infantile paralysis is probably caused by a very minute organism found in the nasal, mouth and bowel discharges of those who have the disease orw ho are carriers of the germ without themselves suffering from the ailment. All of the steps in the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Fourth Annual Bullf tin 17 spread of the infection are not known but if this germ can be prevented from passing from the infected to the well person, the disease will cease. Infantile paralysis is not a disease of recent origin. Sporadic or scattered cases have occurred throughout the country for many years but it is only during the last decade that the infection has assumed epidemic proportions in the United States. The present epidemic in New York City, on account of its magnitude and viru - lence, has awakened the residents of many communities to the danger of the importation of the disease into their own midst. This danger is real, but if due precautions are exercised it is be - lieved that the epidemic will subsidy. The actual control of the present epidemic must be left to the city, state and federal health authorities. These organiza - tions will properly quarantine and care for affected persons, prescribe sanitary measures and limit as may be necessary the travel of individuals in order to protect neighboring districts from the infection. Individuals and communities, however, can do much toward their own protection. Poliomyslitis is probably spread directly or indirectly, through the medium of infective secretions. Account must therefore be taken by communities of every means by which such secretions are disseminated. Promiscuous expectoration should be controlled. The common drinking cup affords a meth - od for the interchange of material of this nature and should therefore be abolished. Rigid cleanliness of glasses and utensils at soda fountains, in saloons and other public places should be enforced. Flies, roaches and other vermin, by coming in con - tact with infective secretions, may possibly convey them to our food and thus directly bring about the development of disease. Therefore eliminate insects. Street and house dust bear a defi - nite relation to the spread of many infections and it is not un - reasonable to presume that they may be a factor in the dissemi - nation of infantile paralysis. Maintain strict cleanliness of streets, yards and alleys in order to prevent the breeding of in- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 sects and other vermin. See that all garbage and waste are properly eared for and collected at regular and frequent inter - vals. Guard all food supplies, especially milk and other perish - able products. Digestive troubles of children arising from the indigestion of food of questionable quality may lower resistance. Assemblies of children in infected localities are to be discouraged, if not actually forbidden. While the above measures are in a sense general, and applicable to many . epidemic diseases, their importance should not be overlooked. Individual preventive measures may be thus summarized: Summon a physician at once and immediately notify the health officer of the presence of the disease. If the disease is present in the community, medical aid should be sought when - ever &lt;i child is sick no matter how light the illness; many cases of infantile paralysis begin with a slight indisposition. Should the illness prove to be infantile paralysis isolate the patient, place a competent person in charge, and reduce all communication with the sick-room to a minimum. Hospital care is preferable, not only for the childb ut in order to better safeguard against the spread of the disease. The sick-room should be well venti - lated and screened. Nasal and mouth sercetions should be re - ceived in cloths, placed in a paper ba&lt;r and burned. The clothing of the child, the bed linen, and the excretions should be disin - fected in the same manner as for typhoid fever, that is by boil - ing, the long continued application of 57, carbolic, or other well recognized disinfectant. The ssime is true for dishes and drink - ing vessels. Nurses should exercise the same precautions as re - gards clanliness of hands in caring for infantile paralysis pa - tients or for those afflicted with other infectious diseases. A child man convey the disease to others even after a lapse of several weeks. For this reason quarantine should be main - tained for a considerable period, usually from six to eight weeks, and the above precautions should be adhered to during this time. Disinfection of the room following recovery is advisable. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Fourth Aunal Bulletin 19 ATTENTION The day for the state conference of all local and state health officers has been set for February 20th and 21st, Lincoln Hotel, Lincoln, Nebraska. It is expected and urged that every municipal and county health officer be present, as matters of great import - ance are to come before the conference. Nebraska will doubtless have to cope with an epidemic of anterior poliomyelitis the earning year, as the contagion swept from the east to the west during the past summer and our past experience has taught us that the second year it is more prevalent in the central states after the disease has spent its ravages on the eastern coast one year before. This and other topics will come to the attention of the health authorities. We also have some legislative matters which will be in full bloom at this time and your presence is not only solicited, but urged. If we can look to you for an address or paper on any of the current topics, kindly notify the secretary at once and you will be given a place on the program. The custom that has worked so well in the past will be followed this year where in the State Board of Health recommends that each municipality or county shall pay the traveling expenses of their health officer or representative to the conference on the presentation of a certi - ficate signed by the Secretary of the Board of Health that said local health officer or representative has been i nactual attendance the whole time. To this end the roll is called each session. Local health officers will kindly take this matter before their municipal - ity or county board for action at once. Last year the federal government gave us the valuable ser - vices of Dr. Freeman of the Public Health Service, and this year we are assured that the federal government will be represented. DON'T forget the time and place, as every health officer in the state should be present. See tentative program, pages 53-55. E. ARTHUR CARR. M. D. Secretarv. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska State Board ol leaUh 20 ALL UNITED FOB NEW MEASURE. An important meeting took place at the Lincoln Hotel No - vember 9th at 80 'clock when the committees from each of the Medical societies of the state, together with a committtee from the Health Officers' Conference and the secretaries to the State Board of Health met to formulate a bill to present to the coming legislature hoping to reorganize the health and sanitary mat - ters of the state on a broader plane. Some of the best known and most influential physicians and health men attended the conference. The joint committee was presided over by Dr. C. T. Burchard of Falls City, and Dr. E. Arthur Carr ascted as secretary. Those present representing the different organizations were as follows: Health Officers — Conference of Local and State. Nebraska State Eclectic Medi - cal Society. Dr. F. L. Wilmeth, Lincoln. Dr. F. M. Andrus, Lincoln. Dr. E. J. Latta, Lincoln. Dr. Samuel Methany, Lincoln. Dr. J. R. Bell, Fairfield. Dr. P. F. Dodson, Wilber. Dr. S. E. Ragan, Seward. Nebraska State Homeopathic Medical Society. Dr. J. D. Case, Lincoln. Nebraska State Medical Society — Special Committee. Dr. C. A. Shoemaker, Lincoln. Dr. G. W. Collins, Pawnee City. Dr. R. W. Hufman, Dr. E. W. Rowe, Lincoln. University Place. Dr. J. P. Lord, Omaha. Dr. W. A. Cate, Nelson, Neb. Dr. W. H. Wikon, Lincoln. Secretaries of State Board of Health. Nebraska State Medical Society — Legislative Committee. Dr. C. T. Burchard, Falls City. Dr. H. B. Cummins, Seward. Dr. L. Stark, Hartington. Dr. E. Arthur Carr, Lincoln. Dr. Chas. L. Mullins, Broken Bow. Dr. H. E. Mantor, Sidney. After a full and complete discussion of every matter pertain - ing to better and more favorable laws, every principle of the new bill was approved by the joint committee, and a special Dr. A. I. Dillon, Auburn. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Fomrlh Aliul Bulletin 21 committee, consisting of one member from each of the organi - zations was chosen to complete the new bill. The special com - mittee is as follows: State Board of Health Secretaries Dr. H. B. Cummins State Health Conference Dr. Porter F. Dodson Nebraska Medical Society Dr. A. I. Dillon Nebraska Eclectic Medical Society Dr. F. M. Andrus Nebraska State Homeopathic Medical Society Dr. C. A. Shoemaker With every organization interested in health matters unani- mously in the support of the measure emanating from the physi - cians and those interested in public health, it is confidently expected that such a bill will readily be adopted in the coming legislature. During the last legislature when different factions submitted bills, all of which were killed, the medical and health men were assured that if they united on a progressive health bill it would be passed readily, as the legislators were anxious to assist in a bill which eminated from a united profession of medical and health men. Hence it is up to you individually to see that this matter is presented to your representative. This bill is the modi- fied Fox Bill. House Roll 245. EDITORIAL Since the last issue of the bulletin I have been re-elected secretary after an absence from the office of four years and as such officer I am supposed to be an editor. I assure the physi - cians and those interested in health matters it will be the policy of the editor to use the bulletin for the promulgation of up-to - date, modern health laws and measures and we invite those inter - ested in health matters for their criticisms and suggestions and any articles which bear upon the current health topics. Owing to the small appropriation we have been unable to have sufficient office help to get out the last numbers of the bulletin, but hope in the future to be on schedule time. We have placed on trial in our department an addressograph of the latest model, capa - ble of addressing 4,500 letters or periodicals an hour. This will </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Ncbrsski Slstf Bo&amp;rd of Hfiltb 22 expidite the issuing of our bulletins. It is embarrassing at times to be placed on a program for an after dinner speech following a recognized orator. It is equally difficult to follow in an editorial capacity a man especially gifted as we recognize our colleague, Dr. Cummins, to be along this special line. We can only assure the common - wealth of the State of Nebraska that they will get honest en - deavor. The bulletin has been in great demand by the teachers and county superintendents of the state for use in the public schools. We invite these requests. With compliments of the season, we remain Cordially, STATE BOARD OF HEALTH. E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Secretary. PLACARDS It has recently been discovered that our rules do not specifically state what shall be inscribed upon a placard for the placarding of contagious diseases which are not quarantinable. The State Board of Health at its meeting in November unanimously adopt - ed the following : That the placard shall be used on all diseases which are contagious, but not quarantinable, a card which shall read as follows : * » NOTICE CONTAGIOUS DISEASE WITHIN. or Name of the Disease KEEP OUT. The secretary was instructed to notify all health officers, so you will kindly take notice and govern yourselves accordingly. To the Municipality and County Health Officers of the State of Nebraska : A personal letter has been addressed to you as follows . We </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Fourth Amuil Bulletin 23 take occasion to publish the same in the bulletin that the above contract and the routine for applying said contract may be better understood and applied. My Dear Doctor: The Nebraska State Board of Health has made an arrange - ment with E. R. Squibb &amp; Sons to furnish their Biologies through the State Board of Health. Distribution will be made through depots which will be located at the County Seat of each County. In establishing these depots, of course they desire to give prefer - ence to their customers now hadling their line. They send these goods to the various distributors on consignment. They will replace all out dated goods with fresh, without expense to the distributor. A discount of 2o r /i will be allowed the distributor for work involved in the care and distribution of the stock. It is expected that a monthly statement will be forwarded to their office with a remittance covering the sales. Our former contract with another house worked a great saving to counties and municipalities in buying antitoxines for nidigent poor, but this contract also includes and permits physi - cians to enjoy these very much reduced prices. Our board desires to have the hearty co-operation of our Ideal health officers in all things. We therefore request you to recommend a druggist, in view of the above, who is best equipped to handle these Biologies in your County Seat. If you are not the Health Officer at present, hand this letter to the proper person or if this should be embarrassing, kindly return same to me. giving me the name of your present Health Officer. An early reply will greatly oblige Yours truly, STATE BOARD OF HEALTH. E. ARTHUR CARR, Secretary. Municipal and County Health Officers will immediately send in their names so that we can correct our directory. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Stale Boird ol leaMb HEALTH NOTES. By W. S. LEATHERS. Director of Public Health. The Mississippi Secretary of the Board of Health has found it necessary to change the contract which was made with Dr. H. M. Alexander Co., relative to furnishing biological products to the State Board of Health. After investigation of the mat - ter, it was found advisable to make a contract with E. R. Squibb &amp; Sons, of New York, N. Y., for antitoxins, vaccines, etc. This company is well recognized as producing a standard product along all lines, and the material which is made by Squibb &amp; Sons, can be relied upon as being the very best on the market. It may be of itnerest to know that Dr. Jno. F. Anderson, former Director of the T'nited States Public Health Laboratory, Wash - ington D. ('.. is now employed by this company as director of their laboratories. This in itself guarantees the product placed on the market by them. ONLY PURE WATER ALLOWED ON RAILROAD TRAINS." The following communication serves to show the public the routine in guarding the safety of the traveling public: Secretary of the State Board of Health, Lincoln. Neb. Sir: There is enclosed herewith for your information a copy of a letter addressed to Mr. N. Hughitt, Vice President of the Chicago and Northwestern Railway Company. Chicago. Illinois, directing the discontinuance of that company's drinking water supply at Superior, Nebraska, on account of contamination cer - tified bv the Nebraska State Board of Health. By direction of Surgeon General. Respectfully, A. H. GLENAN, Asst. Surg. Gen. Published in Falls City Journal, November 18, 1916. The Nebraska State Board of Health through its secretary, Dr. E. Arthur Carr, of Lincoln, has secured a contract with E. R. Squibbs &amp; Sons of New York City, whereby the biological products of that firm may be purchased at very much reduced </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 prices by any regularly licensed physician in the state. The products of the house of Squibb knows, and are so guaranteed ■ire standard, as every physician by the house. Following is a comparison of prices Diphtheria Antitoxin. 1,000 units $ 2.00 1,000 units same $ .50 2,000 units 3.50 2,000 units same 95 3,000 units 5.00 3,000 units same 1.35 4,000 units 6.50 4,000 units same 1.70 5,000 units 7.50 7,500 units 10.00 5,000 units same 2.00 7,500 units same 3.00 10,000 units same 4.00 10,000 units 12.00 Tetanus Antitoxin. 1,500 units Syrings Pkg. .$2.50 1,500 units Syringe Pkg. .$1.67 3,000 units Syringe 1'kg. . 4.25 3,000 units Syringe Pkg.. 2.87 5,000 units Syringe Pkg. . 6.00 5,000 units Syringe Pkg. . 4.00 4 Also special price on Typhoid vacine and Smallpox vacine and all products not listed above 50% off list, arrangements will be made to establish a depot in each county seat town for hand - ling. The place has not been decided for Falls City, but will be announced. This is a very great saving to the unfortunate sick of the state President State Board of Health. Clean Hands Disease germs lead a hand to mouth existence. If the human race would learn to keep the unwashed hand away from the mouth many human diseases would be greatly diminished. We handle infectious matter more or less constantly, and we con - tinually carry the hands to the mouth. If the had has recently been in contact with infectious matter the germs of disease may in this way be introduced into the body. Many persons wet their fingers with saliva before counting money, turning the pages of a book, or performing similar acts. In this case the C. T. BUBCHAED, </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Stale Board ol leal* process is reversed, the infection being carried to the object handled, there to await carriage to the mouth of some other care - less person. In view of these facts the United States Public Health Service has formulated the following simple rules of per - sonal hygiene and recommends their adoption by every person in the United States : WASH THE HANDS 1MEDIATELY Before eating. Before handling, preparing or serving food After using the toilet. After attending the sick, and Afater handling anything dirty. — Los Angeles Health Department. Simple Method of Water Purification. Take a level teaspoonful of chloride of lime and rub it up in a teacup with a little water to a thin paste free from lumps. This should then be made up to a cupful and diluted with three more cupfuls of water and poured into a bottle, then tightly corked. You have then a stock of solution that will keep for a week, if tightly corked. A teaspoonful of this solution should be added to each two - gallon pail of drinking water, thoroughly mixed, and allowed to stand for a few minutes. This will give about one-half part of free chlorine to a million parts of water, which will destroy all typhoid or dysentry-producing germs in ten minutes. With most waters in this locality ,this quantity will not make the water taste. If it does, in your case, use a little less, other - wise not. It is advisable to procure chloride of lime in the pound size metallic can ; the chloride of lime packed in cardboard cases usually becomes weak and ineffective within a short time. The above method of purifying small quantities of water was worked out by Dr. G. G. Nasmith and Dr. R. R. Graham, and was orginally designed for prospectors, campers and for use at sum- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Fourth A.noil Bulletin 27 mer cottages, and has been copied all over the world. It is esen - tially the same method that is now being used to protect the water supplies on the battlefields in Europe. The United States Public Health Service Asks DO YOU Think dog muzzling cruel and then marvel at the spread of rabies? Carefully select your brand of and then feed your chil dren unpastenrized milk t Repeat the Golden Rule and then sneeze in somebody's face? Go camping for your health and then place your toilet so that it drains into your water supply! — Los Angeles Health Department. WATCH FLIES, NOT BULLETS Doctor's Advice to Soldier Boys Now Leaving For the Boarder. "Never mind the bullets, but watch out for the flies," is the advice of an army surgeon, who served in the war in Cuba and who has recently been in service at the variou sarmy posts along the Mexican border, to the North Carolina boys now leav - ing for the banks of the Rio Grande. He says that there is more danger from flies alone in Mexico than from hot weather and bullets' combined and that there's safety to be had only behind screen and not even then unless the greatest care is taken with the food and water. As to anti-typhoid vaccine as a preventive against typhoid fever, he says that it is a great thing, a wonderful thing, but unless the boys take the utmost care as to their eating, drink - ing, their personal hygiene and their sleeping, that not even will vaccination keep off the typhoid fever, but that it will re - duce their chances against it over a thousand times. "Then, too," save he, "there's pneumonia to guard against, for the thermometer in Mexico runs to 160 in the sun and from 106 to 108 in the shade, while at nights it often drops so low as to bring on a sudden chill. This makes pneumonia dangerous, but </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nckrwka SUte U*ri odttlth 28 with the proper care of one-'s self, a man may keep fit and avoid Sickness. "Another health hazard," says the doctor, "that a soldier is likely to encounter down in Mexico is typhus fever. As you know, it is carried from one to another by the body louse just as malaria or yellow fever is carried by the mosquito. Care - fulness and good personal hygiene is again one of the best preventives. Frequent bathing and clean clothes do much to keep off the louse and down the infection, while naphthalene, kerosene and various powders are recommended for killing the lice and nits. "But," says the doctor, "if a soldier has been vaccinated against typhoid and smallpox and will guard against infection and will practice daily as much personal hygiene as is possible, these will give him his best chances for coming back home." — North Carolina State Board of Health. The State Board of Health approves the following poster, recently issued by the Health Commissioner, Dr. Ralph W. Con - nell, of Omaha : SCARLET FEVER AND DIPHTHERIA Health Office, Omaha. The Health Office issues the following circular of recom - mendations, with the hope that those not familiar with the care of Scarlet Fever and Diphtheria may be benefited thereby: Scarlet Fever and Diphtheria are like Small Pox in their power to spread rapidly from person to person ; they are highly contagious. Diphtheria is not only contagious, but is also in - fectious. Each disease shows its first symptoms in about one week after exposure, as a general rule ; and persons who escape the illness during a fortnight after exposure are comparatively safe from attack, but it may develop even three weeks after exposure. Scarlet Fever, Scarletina. Canker Rash and Scarlet Rash are names of one and the same dangerous disease. A mild case </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Foorth Anntl Built tin 29 may develop into a malignant one. When a case of Scarlet Fever or Diphtheria occurs in any family, the sick person should be placed in a room apart from the other inmates of the house, and should be nursed, as far as possible by one person only. AND IN NO CASE SHALL THE ATEENDING PHYSICIAN OR OTHERS DIRECT THE. RE - MOVAL OP THE UXINFECTED CHILDREN FROM SAID HOUSE TO ANOTHER FOR THE PURPOSE OF CONTINU - ING IN SCHOOL. The sick chamber should be well warmed, exposed to sun - light and well aired, though avoiding direct drafts, for four weeks; its furniture should be such as will permit of cleansing without injury, and all extra articles, such a window-drapery, woolen carpets and the like should be removed from the room during the sickness. The family should not mingle with other people. All visitors to the infected house, especially children, must not be admitted. No pet dog or cat, or valuable plaything, should be allowed the patient, as thus frequently has disease been carried to others. If either dog or cat is found in the house they must be excluded and thoroughly disinfected with formaline or destroped. The sick person should not mingle with other until four week at least from the first beginning of the attack. During this time the skin, naturally always wearing away, contains the germ of the disease, and for this reason cosmoline or some oily material should be kept on the s surface constantly and a slighly carbonized (one per cent) sponge bath used daily. All clothing and bedding worn or uped by the patient or the nurse should be cleansed by boiling for at least an hour; or, if that cannot be done, by free and prolonged exposure to outdoor air and sun - light. On revocery the walls of the room should be dry rubbed and the cloths used for the purpose should be burned without previous shaking. The ceiling should be scraped and whitened. The floor should be washed with soap and hot water, and car - bolic acid may be edded to the water (one pint to three or four </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Mrli|-a«lf ■ Cial* RjitiI nl Mj^yh gallons.) The infected clothing should be cleansed by itself and not sent to a laundry, using one pint of salt and one pound of white vitrol to tub of cold water. In case of death from Scarlet Fever or Diphtheria the fune - ral services must be strictly private, and the corpse cannot be exposed to view, and should be buried within 6to 24 hours after death. As children are especially liable to take and spread Scarlet fever and Diphtheria and because schools afford a free oppor - tunity for this the Health Department of Omaha excludes from school every child from any family in which a case of either disease occurs. The absence to continue in those afflicted with Scarlet Fever, four weeks from date of recovery and thorough disinfection of house; in Diphtheria ,three weeks from recovery and thorough disinfection of house. Chidren not affected, but having been exposed, are excluded from school for two weeks from date of recovery and thorough fumigation of house. Neighbor's children, or those who have beenexposed and not living in house with the disease, are excluded two weeks from school from time of last exposure. House must be disinfected by Board of Health, which will be done on receipt of notice from attending physician that case lias recovered. DO YOU KNOW THAT It's worry, not work, that shortens life! A cold bath every morning is the best complexion remedy? Poor health is expensive? The U. S. Public Health Service has reduced malaria 60% in some localities? The death rate from typhoid fever in the United States has been cut in half since 1900? Pneumonia kills over 120,000 Americans each year? Flyless towns have few funerals? The well that drains the cesspool is the cup of death? </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 OVER 1,300 VACCINATED IN BLADEN. Three-Month Health Campaign Gaining in Interest. Over 1,300 people in Bladen county have been immunized to typhoid fever during the past four weeks or since the health campaign has been in progress in that county, according to Dr. G. M. Cooper of the State Board of Health, who has just returned from Clarkton. This town, he says, is wide awake to health interests. As many as 300 people, which is practically the entire population of Clarkton. have already taken the im - munizing treatment to typhoid. The three-mouth health campaign under the direction of Dr. T. M. Jordan which hiis" been in operation now for four weeks is showing fine progress, says Doctor Cooper, and the people are manifesting an increased interest in all the health features of the campaign and attend well the lectures and dis - pensaries. Doctor Cooper believes this campaign will mean great good to the health and general prosperity of the county. —North Carolina State Board of Health. MANY DEATHS REPORTED FROM TYPHOID State Board of Health Advises Vaccination as Preventive of Typhoid. On account of the very large number of deaths from ty- I-hoid fever that has been reported to the State Board of Health within the last few weeks, the Board is urging the people to lose no time in taking the immunizing treatment agains this disease. It says that on account of every case being a new source of infection and its spread and contact so insidious and unsuspecting, that no intelligent person can afford to neg - lect taking this means of protetcing himself. Furthermore, the Board says that June is the month when the death rate fro myphoid fever begins to rise and that already the incom - ing death certificates are showing an unusually large number of deaths from this disease for this season of the year. ''Vaccination us &gt;n effective means of preventing typhoid </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Stale Board el lealth fever," says the oBard, "has been well established, but the main reason why people continue to get sick and die from ty - phoid is indifference and not ignorance. The indifference and neglect that tolerate Hies, filth and the spread of typhoid from individual to individual is that same indifference that makes a person neglect vaccination as a means of protecting himself. Indifference is now the cause of more deaths fro mtyphoid fever than ignorance." — North Carolina State Board of Health. DO YOU KNOW THAT One million two hundred thousand Americans die each year, it is estimated? Heart disease, pneumonia and tuberculosis cause more than 30' , of deaths? Sickness lowers the earning capacity? The U. S. Public Health Service is the nation's first line of defense against disease? Disease is the nation's greatest burden? Sunlight and sanitation, not silks and satins, make bet - ter babies? Low wages favor high disease rates? A female fly lays an average of 120 eggs at a time? —United States Public Health Servive. ON GETTING STUNG. "Eever get Stung? Or rather, who hasn't?" says the State Board of Health, "both with bees and otherwise. Hurts like the mischief, don't it — both petting stung by bees and getting stung otherwise. For either kind of "getting stung" preven - tion is better than cure and discretion is the best part of valor. "Tact, diplomacy and good judgment will ward off many instances of "getting stung," in the social world as well as in the insect world. We offer no panacea or remedy for the former, but for the latter, seriously speaking, much can be done. "The first impulse in the case of an insect sting is to strike the offending insect and in doing so in most cases we usually tear the insect away from its sting, leaving the sting in the flesh. It is the irritating poison on the sting that hurts so badly and causes such swelling, so the very first thing to do is to remove the sting it left in the flesh. Use a knife point or needle for this purpose. Then don't scratch or rub the sting. That only makes bad matters worse. Add a few drops </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Fonrlh Annnal Bulletin 33 of weak ammonia or spirits of camphor or ordinary tincture of iodine as quickly as possible. "The poison from hornet stinirs is soluble in alcohol and therefore if the spot is gently bathed or washed in alcohol tome relief is obtained. Finally if ammonia, camphor, iodine or alcohol are not available, gently rubbing a piece of wet soap over the sting helps the situation out somewhat. Always remember, however, that the most important first aid is to remove the offending sting and that prevention is better than cure." — North Caroline State Board of Health. CARELESS COUGHING AND SPITTING Don't Spit Laws Should Be Made More Than Jokes. The dangerous and dirty habit of careless spitting, cough - ing and sneezing is without doubt the most costly carelessness that civilized society indulges in. The saying, "No spit, no consumption," is literally true, and this means that the con - sumption that we have, with 5,000 deaths a year, would be largely avoided if this habit could be abolished. It has been shown by careful and scientific experiments that in the act of coughing or sneezing, unless a handkerchief or other object is held in front of the nose and mouth, micro - scopic particles of saliva and nasal secretion are discharged into the air which, even in a quiet room, may be carried a distance of from ten to fifty yards from the place where they were expelled. Many of these droplets can be seen if one will cough or sneeze in front of a mirror or windowpane. Most of them, however, are to small to be visible to the naked eye. One can now readily understand how very impolite it is to cough or sneeze without holding a handkerchief in front of his face, for such a person literally spits on objects and people, perhaps on food, within a distance of from ten to fifty yards about him. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 CAN THE STATE NOT AFFORD IT? To Aid and Give Treatment to a Tuberculosis Father of Six Children. A letter to the State Board of Health yesterday told the story of a man, a father of a family of seven, who is sick with tuberculosis and who is without means for defraying the expenses of care and treatment. He has a wife and six chil - dren and altogether they are living according to views of half a century ago, particularly as regards tuberculosis. That is, they do not know that tuberculosis is a germ distase, that it is contagious and that it is spread through the sputum. They do not know that consumption is not inherited but contracted, and that it is both preventable and curable. So, according to past experiences with this disease, one by one, all the family will become victims of dread consumption which they did not inherit but contracted from the father. And yet this is not all of the story. This household is a source of infection to the neighborhood and the whole com - munity. Neighbors visit, and friends and relatives come and stay to render whatever assistance they may to the sick man. They are conscious of their duty to the sick but not of the danger to which they are subjecting themselves. What is to be done about it ? Can the county of which this sick man is a citizen afford to let him remain in this con - dition with no effort to help him or protect his family and the people of the community from the same disease? Can the state afford to withhold the small sum of a dollar a day for treat - ment at the State Sanatorium which would not only give the sick man the care he needs but would give his family through him the instruction and protection they need regarding the disease ? Neither the state nor the county can afford from an eco - nomic standpoint alone not to care for this man and protect him as a dangerous citizen. Whatever this one case would cost the state now, in a few years seven cases of tuberculosis, </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Fourth Annul Bulletin 35 or in a few more years, seven times seven cases would cost the state a staggerig sum. Can it afford it? — North Carolina State Board of Health. A TOWN'S BEST ADVERTISING "A town without flies is the best advertising a town can have," said a business man the other day. And when he was asked why he thought so, he replied: "There are several rea - sons. First, everybody knows that a town without flies is a clean town, a healthful town, where health matters receive due attention. You would expect to find in it clean streets and alleys, clean food shops and markets, and clean grocery stores and restaurants. It is where you would feel easy to sit down and eat without feeling suspicious about the food that is served you. "In the second place, it is a town that has no filthy, fly - breeding stables and open surface closets. It takes care of its sewage and garbage and deems the health of its citizens worth protecting. For this reason you feel like such a town is a good place in which to live. "In the third place, it would be a town practically free from typhoid fever, infantile diseases, cholera and other fly - borne disease, to say nothing of other improved health condi - tions and the comforts brought about by cleanliness and the absence of flies." "But ho"* are you going to have a flyless townf" the speaker was asked. "By going after the stables first," said he, 'and then by cleaning up the rest of the town and keeping it clean. To afford flies no space to breed," said the speaker, 'is the only way not to have flies. Towns that have succeeded in controlling the fly menace went straight for the stables first and then for the open closets and other dirty places where flies find breeding places. Dr. L. M. McCormick, the fly-fighter of Asheville, says, 'There is no royal road to freedom from tfies but Clean Up and Keep Clean is the winning slogan.' " — North Carolina State Board of Health. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nekraslu Stale Baard ol Htalta VITAL STATISTICS In presenting its report for the past year, the State Board of Health, first of all, wants to thank its many co-workers who have assisted so materially in this compilation. A comparison of the figures presented herewith, with those of other years will show how standards are being raised. Physicians, undertakers, county officials and local registrars have our thanks for good work done. We hope, in time, every person who has to do with this work will be so impressed with the importance of his duties that our annual report will be an absoluetly accurate and complete record of the state's vital sta - tistics. While we have had intelligent and hearty support from most of our helpers throughout the state, we are not satisfied with the results of our labors. We are striving for a perfect record and can be content with nothing less. This will come only when every man is impressed with its necessity. It will be noticed that marriage and divorce records are more complete than those of borths and deaths. This, of course, is due in part to the stringent rules laid down for the guidance of those licensed to perform marriage ceremonies and the courts which are permitted to loose the marriage bond. While we are glad to obtain these reports, a little study of the situation will convince one that birth and death reports are of as much importance. The necessity of our vital records fol - low naturally the growing complexity of civilization. One needs but to answer a few calls upon this office to realize what a part a simple little certificate can play. Scarcely a day passes that we do not have one or more requests for certi - fied copies of birth reports. They are necessary in the comple - tion of legal transactions, the exercise of franchise, in some cities the securing of marriage licenses, for school records and for the determination of the right in child labor cases. Parents should insist on the filing of a birth certificate. A </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Fourth AmmI lull? tin 37 few moments spent in attending to the matter may save days and days of worry and effort later on. Physicians should regard as an important part in their ser - vices to humanity the proper registration of certificates. They above all others, should take upon themselves the personal obli - gation to make proper returns, to make them complete and to make them promptly. When a physician is not in attendance at a birth, parent! are required, by law. to file a report. Ignorance of the law explains some of their failures to do so. The physician does not have even this invalid excuse for neglect. Death certificate! are fully ns important. We are asked, constantly, for certified copies desired by life insurance com - panies, pension officials and the like. They often are necessary in the completion of business transactions. Vital statistics comprise the bookkeeping of public health. As demands for its services increase, the board of health must so keep its books that every item is easily accessible. Every per - son in the state is entitled to its services but calls for informa - tion often mean long hours of search through incomplete records. Appropriations for this work have not been sufficiently large to permit the retaining of a clerical force to do the work properly. The State Board of Health tries to do its work on funds smaller than those demanded in the ordinary city. We hope a persual of the statistics herewitli will bring to mind their necessity. We must have the co-operation of all to succeed fully. That is what we bespeak in submitting these figures. Health Inspector. J. D. CASE, M.D.. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Stale Board ol lealth REPORT OF BIRTHS BY COUNTIES FOR THE YEAR ENDING DECEMBER 1, 1916 TO DECEMBER 1, 1916. Counties Male Female White Colored Yellow Indian Adams 255 224 479 Antelope 143 109 252 Athur 14 14 28 Boone 158 173 331 Blaine 4 5 9 Box Butte 45 58 103 Boyd 86 77 163 Brown 75 63 138 Buffalo 25 I 230 480 Burt 143 139 282 Butler 178 198 376 Cass 186 184 370 Cedar 154 176 330 Chase 56 63 119 Cherry _.. 87 128 213 &gt; Cheyenne 58 51 109 Clay 147 149 296 Colfaz 105 123 228 Cuming 181 154 335 Custer 307 285 592 Dakota 56 54 110 Dawes 63 59 122 Dawson ... 14H 139 288 Deuel 21 21 42 Dixon , 134 106 240 Dodge 268 224 491 1 Douglas ... 1945 1725 3631 38 1 Dundy 54 44 98 Fillmorc 168 148 316 Franklin 113 102 215 Furnas 150 165 315 Frontier 92 82 174 Gage 305 276 581 Garden 33 30 63 Garfield 40 58 98 Gosper 54 50 104 Grant 26 24 49 1 Greeley 104 98 202 Hall 232 191 423 Hamilton 11/ 119 236 Harlan 109 99 208 Hayes 43 37 80 Hitchcock 39 25 64 Holt 199 165 364 __ Hooker 11 9 20 Howard 97 71 168 Jefferson 181 185 366 Johnson 119 98 217 Kearney 100 118 218 Kei h 33 24 57 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">rHnl Randal MllrXUi 39 Counties Male Female White Colored Yellow Indian Keya Palia 28 22 50 Kimball 12 6 18 Knox 219 178 m i Lancaster 988 927 1905 10 Lincoln 137 138 268 Logan 27 18 45 Loup 2 ■2 4 Madison 256 228 4S4 Merrick 130 101 231 Morrill 38 38 76 Nance 106 91 197 Nemaha 154 136 290 Nuckolls 117 113 SS« McPherson 3 e 9 Otoe 199 176 375 Pawnee 106 97 203 Perkins 16 19 35 Phelps 131 93 224 Pierce 142 148 290 Platte 250 226 476 Polk 100 109 209 Red Willow 117 82 199 Richardson 248 221 489 Rock 29 27 5K Saline 180 173 MS Sarpy 84 75 tit Saunders 254 217 471 Scotts Bluff 158 136 292 I Seward 159 182 341 Sheridan 100 77 171 1 Sherman 114 92 206 Sioux 24 24 4S Stanton 80 65 14.". Thayer 185 174 359 Thomas 2 •' 4 Thurston 126 113 MS 6 Valley 148 99 247 Washington 147 138 28f. Wayne 138 109 247 Webster 134 125 259 Wheeler 25 18 43 York 178 189 367 Total 14193 13075 27205 52 3 8 Twins 288 pair 576 white. Triplets 4 sets 12 white. TOTAL 27268. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Stair Board *i Health MARRIAGE REPORTS, 1916 Counties Counties No. No. Counties No. Counties No. Adams _ 243 Adams _ 243 Howard „ 74 Howard „ 74 Antelope _ 115 Antelope - 115 Jefferson 185 Jefferson 185 Arthur _ 16 Arthur _ 16 Johnson 64 Johnson 64 Banner Banner Kearney 67 Kearney 67 Blaine 17 Blaine 17 Keith 31 Keith 31 Boone 213 Boone 213 Keya Pah* 49 Keya Pah* 49 Box Butte 139 Box Butte 139 Kimball 67 Kimball 67 Boyd 56 Boyd 56 Knox 136 Knox 135 Brown 132 Brown 132 Lancaster 1096 Lancaster 1096 Buffalo 127 Buffalo 127 Lincoln „ 182 Lincoln „ 182 Burt 78 Burt 78 Logan 207 Logan 207 Butler 97 Butler 97 Loup 26 Loup If t'ass 31 ;'ass n McPherson 10 McPherson 10 Cedar 104 Cedar 104 Madison 133 Madison 133 Chase 34 Chase 34 Merrick 86 Merrick 86 Cherry 94 Cherry 94 Morrill 61 Morrill „_ 61 Cheyenne 140 Cheyenne 140 Nance 71 Nance 71 Clay 110 Clay 110 Nemaha .._ 86 Nemaha 85 Colfax 82 Colfax 82 Nuckolls 103 Nuckolls 103 Cuming 109 Cuming 109 Otoe 181 Otoe 181 Custer __ 153 Custer __ 153 Pawnee 100 Pawnee 100 Dakota 175 Dakota 175 Perkins 33 Perkins 33 Dawes 120 Dawes _ 120 Phelps 91 Phelps 91 Dawson 114 Dawson 114 Pierce 106 Pierce 106 Deuel 18 Deuel 18 Platte 219 Platte 219 Dixon 69 Dixon 69 Polk 44 Polk 44 Dodge 283 Dodge 283 Red Willow 167 Red Willow 157 Douglas 2479 Douglas 2479 Richardson 166 Richardson 166 Dundy 47 Dundy 47 Saline 134 Saline 134 Plllmore 123 Fillmore 123 Sarpy 265 Sarpy 265 Franklin 17« Franklin 176 Saunders 160 Saunders 160 Frontier 61 Scotts Bluff 139 Frontier 61 Scotts Bluff 139 Furnas . 176 Furnas 176 Seward 133 Seward US Gage _ 239 Gage _ 239 Sheridan 67 Sheridan 67 Garden Garden Sherman 58 Sherman 58 Garfield 37 Garfield 37 Sioux 26 Stoux 26 Gosper 28 Gosper 28 Stanton 68 Stanton 68 Grant 28 Grant 28 Thayer 104 Thayer 104 Greeley 51 Greeley 51 Thurston Jl Thurston 91 Hall 406 Hall 406 Valley 75 Valley 75 Hamilton 110 Hamilton 110 Washington 123 Washington 123 Harlan 75 Harlan 75 Wayne 106 Wayne 106 Hayes 19 Hayes 19 Webster 102 Webster 102 Hitchcock 30 Hitchcock 30 Wheeler 9 Wheeler 9 Holt 143 Holt 143 York 172 York 172 Hooker 28 Hooker 2S Total 11550 Total 11550 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Foartk AmmI Ballctia 41 DIVORCE REPORTS 1916. Counties No. Counties No. Adams 35 Howard _ 3 Antelope 28 Jefferson 20 Banner 2 Johnson 7 Blaine 2 Kearney 8 Boone 4 Keith 87 Box Butte M Lancaster _.. 210 Boyd 7 Lincoln 27 Brown 10 Logan 4 Buffalo 37 Loup 2 Burt 8 McPherson 6 Butler ._ 17 Merrick , f Cass _ _. 25 Madison 57 Cedar 7 Morrill _ _ 5 Cherry 26 Nemaha 1 13 Cheyenne 8 Nuckolls 15 Clay _. 10 Otoe 39 Colfax 14 Pawnee 3 Cuming 7 Phelps 11 Custer 19 Pierce 14 Dawes 16 Platte 16 Dawson 12 Polk 9 Deuel Red Willow 22 Dixon 12 Richardson 16 Dodge il Saline 12 Douglas ... 739 Sarpy 17 Dundy Saunders _ 17 Scotts Bluff 14 4 Fillmore 15 14 Franklin 3 Seward _ 24 Frontier Sheridan 13 5 Furnas 11 Sherman _ 5 Gage 36 Sioux _ 4 Garden 5 Stanton _ 2 Garfleld 2 Thayer _ 9 Gosper 1 Thomas _ 5 Grant Thurston 47 1 Greeley 1 Valley _ ( Hall „ _ 66 Washington g Hamilton 14 Rock _ 12 Harlan 10 Wayne 10 Wheeler 1 York „ Ik Hayes 3 Hitchcock _ 1 15 Holt _ 17 Hooker 2 Total 2i9j </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Slate Board ol Health 42 CAUSE OF DIVORCE AND PLAINTIFF. County Cruelty Drunkeness N-Sup. Desertion Adultery Husb. Wife Husb. Wife Wife Husb. Wife Husb. Wife Adams 2 6 8 9 2 1 7 Antelope 2 10 8 15 — 2 Banner 2 _ Blaine •j Boone 2 1 1 2 Box Butte 25 4 . 5 1 Boyd 3 4 _ 1 Brown 4 5 Buffalo 2 14 10 7 4 Burt 4 1 o 1 I 8 Butler 4 Case 1 5 14 6 2 Cedar 3 1 1 Cherry 12 1 5 3 3 1.1 Cheyenne 2 2 1 2 1 ? I Clay s l I Colfax Cuming I 1 Custer 1 4 .; 4 Dawes 2 7 2 12 1 Dawson •' 1 Dixon 2 4 Douglas 55 35 8 104 214 32 66 18 9 Dundy '&gt; 1 1 Dodge 1 18 r, 1" 2 2 3 1 Fillmore « 1 Franklin l 1 Frontier 5&gt; 9. 1 Furnas 4 12 12 1 Gage 5 10 10 1 4 3 Garden •&gt; Gosper 1 Grant 1 Greeley 1 Hall 4 15 9 1 5 2 Holt 1 6 4 Hamilton 5 4 4 1 Harlan 1 1 ■2 4 1 1 Hayes 1 1 1 Hitchcock 1 Howard 1 2 2 Hooker 1 1 1 Jefferson 1 6 2 5 2 4 i Johnson 2 13 1 Keith 1 37 11 23 6 5 4 Lancaster 12 80 1 14 78 8 17 1 Lincoln 4 10 2 4 3 3 1 Keith 4 10 2 Logan 2 1 1 _ Loup 1 i ' ' ...... McPherson 3 1 l l 1 1 _ </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 Fourth Annual Bullttin Madison 8 16 4 17 4 2 2 Merrick 13 4 1 ..._ - Morrill 1 2 11 Nemaha 2 4 113 2 Nuckolls 1 5 4 4 1 Otoe 3 13 19 4 1 1 1 Pawnee 1 ■&gt; 1 Phelps 1 4 1 Pierce 1 Platte 4 4 4 1 1 Polk Red Willow 10 I Richardson 1 15 11 Rock 1 ■i Saline 5 5 Sarpy 2 5 2 4 3 1 Saunders U Scotts Bluff 8 1 3 2 Seward 11 ■2 Sheridan 4 Sherman 1 1 3 Sioux 1 111 Stanton 1 1 Thayer 2 1 1 Thomas 1 1 3 Thurston 1 20 6 3 12 6 Valley 1 1 Washington 4 9 Wayne 2 113 3 ■' Wheeler _ 1 York 10 5 Total 80 836 14 230 546 137 191 35 24 THE ROAD OF THE HEALTH OFFICIAL. "The road of the health official is usually a dreary one, unlightened even by an occasional fringe of primroses in the way of public commendation, and is made bo by reason of the fact that it is is chief duty to prevent disease, and the measures of prevention are commonly distasteful to the public in whose interests he is acting. A successful year's campaign against filth in a city of 100,000 persons, resulting in the saving of a hundred lives, is publicly rewarded by a brief newspaper paragraph to the effect that the death rate has been reduced from 15 to 14 per thousand population, and is as promptly forgotten, if read at all." </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Suit Board •! Health CLASSIFICATION OF DIVORCES FOR 1915. County Length of Marriage Nature of Decree Grant- dis- Pend- Ink. 2 5 lo 7 13 25 40 45 ed missed ing Adams 2 12 10 2 1 1 1 25 2 8 Antelope 18 5 17 4 7 Banner 1 •&gt; Blaine •i ■&gt; Boone 2 1 1 4 Box Butte 15 12 6 ■&gt; 2y ■&gt; 5 Boyd 4 2 1 4 2 1 •_&gt;. ■' Brown 5 3 2 ■&gt; 1 Buffalo 17 10 10 24 11 2 Burt 2 2 3 1 8 •&gt; Butler ■I 4 6 1 7 5 5 Cass 1(1 4 I 15 4 Cedar 3 2 1 i 24 2 .... 2 7 Cherry 4 1 24 2 ■1 I Cheyenr.c&gt; 2 6 8 Clay 115 2 1 9 1 ■2 Colfax 1 3 4 Cuming 7 13 3 Custer ti 5 6 2 17 2 Dawes I 5 i 4 15 Dawson I 1 1 5 4 7 1 Dixon 3 •}. 3 4 X I 1 Dodge 21 I 9 7 1 28 ■1 13 Douglas 234 216 174 111 72« 11 3 Dundy 2 1 1 13 1 1 Fillmore 5 5 4 1 13 1 1 Franklin 3 1 2 Frontier 3 2 4 1 Furnas 2 4 3 10 .1 Gage 12 6 10 ,s 20 10 Garden 2 2 1 2 5 Gosper 2 2 Grant 1 1 Greeley 1 1 Hall 12 2 14 10 56 Hamilton 5 2 2 4 5 1 S Harlan 5 113 6 2 2 Hayes 2 1 3 Hitchock 1 1 Howard Ill 3 Holt 6 3 6 2 12 1 4 Hooker 1 1 2 Jefferson 6 4 4 6 1 „ 10 5 5 Johnson 12 3 1 6 2 _ Kearney _ 2 3 1 2 7 1 Keith 24 16 33 22 3 85 2 Lancaster _ 66 66 50 26 3 196 14 Lincoln _ 7 4 9 6 1 26 1 Logan 2 11 4 Loup 2 2 _ </seg>
            <seg id="p045">F^vrth AibbaJ Valletta 45 County Length of Marriage Nature of Decree Grant- dis- Pend - ed missed ing Unk. 2 5 10 M 4U 45 McPherson 1 2 3 McPherson 1 2 3 6 Madison 15 16 17 8 1 51 « Merrick _ 3 3 12 9 Morrill 12 11 5 I Nemaha 5 14 3 7 6 7 « Nuckols 2 5 6 2 13 2 __ Otoe Otoe 17 14 7 3 3 30 4 10 Pawnee 1 2 3 3 Phelps 4 3 3 1 9 1 l Pierce 5 6 1 2 10 1 3 Platte 6 3 6 1 5 4 7 Polk 5 2 2 14 Red Willow 6 6 3 6 7 10 • 4 10 t 4 Richardson 3 4 4 6 16 Rock 3 5 2 2 6 3 3 Saline 3 2 15 1 10 2 Sarpy 6 6 2 3 11 3 3 Saunders 5 2 6 4 9 2 6 •&gt; Scotts Bluff 2 4 5 3 14 _ 2 Seward 6 7 8 3 19 1 4 Sheridan 6 3 13 8 2 3 Sherman 2 2 1 5 Sioux 1 , 1 2 4 Stanton 1 1 2 „ Thayer 5 2 2 6 3 Thomas 1 1 3 6 Thurston 26 8 13 2 27 20 Valley 13 2 « Washington 2 13 2 8 Wayne 3 3 3 2 6 1 3 Wheeler 1 1 York 6 4 5 7 6 3 Total 7 683 608 484 368 36 8 1888 140 166 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 hraaJiB tlato Rjtard *l Health DEATHS BY COUNTIES. From December 1, 1915 to December 1. 1916. Counties No. Adams 417 Boone 126 Counties No. Antelope 122 Arthur 4 Box Butte 76 Boyd 83 Brown 46 Buffalo 193 Burt 132 Butler 1*3 Cass 183 Cedar _ 120 Cheyenne - 50 Clay 147 Cuming 135 Cherry 69 Chase Jl Colfax 109 Custer 159 Dawson 50 Dakota 67 Dixon 126 Dawson 141 Douglas 2754 Dodge 253 Dundy 41 Deuel 11 Fillmore 139 Frontier 47 Gage 318 Garfleld 21 Grant 7 Hall 332 Franklin 84 Furnas 129 Garden 28 Gosper 26 Greeley 39 Hamilton 135 Hayes 26 Harlan 94 Holt 127 Hitchcock 23 Howard 80 Hooker 16 Johnson 106 Jefferson 168 Keith 26 Kearney 95 Keya Paha 5 KimbaU 7 Lancaster 1146 Knox _ 146 Logan 19 Lincoln 122 Madison 273 Loup _ 11 McPherson 4 Merrick Ill Nance 54 Morrill 22 Nuckolls »7 Nemaha 132 Pawnee 93 Otoe 196 Phelps .-. 104 Perkins 21 Platte 231 Pierce - 89 Red Willow 112 Polk 77 Rock 5 Richardson 188 Sarpy 120 Saline 166 Scotts Bluff 121 Saunders 176 Sheridan 61 Seward 147 Stanton 55 Sherman 60 Thayer 136 Sioux 9 Valley „ 88 Thurston 112 Wayne 107 Washington 142 Wheeler Jl Webster 122 York __ 199 ToUl 11091 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 CAUSES OF DEATHS, 1916. Typhoid fever L 105 Small pox ." _. 5 Measles 59 Scarlet fever 112 Whooping cough 5 Diphtheria 101 Infleunza 271 Cholera Nostrae 9 Dysentery 40 Erysipelas 46 Other epidemic diseases 1 Purulent infection and septichaemia ._ 28 Tetanus 16 Mycosis 1 Tuberculosis of the lungs 419 Tubercular meningitis L 17 Pott's disease 1 Tuberculosis of the joints 1 Tuberculosis of other organs 86 Syphilis _ 22 Cancer of the liver and stomach „_ _ 253 Cancer peritonaeus intestines rectum (0 Cancer female genital organs 52 Cancer of the breast 36 Cancer of other parts 266 Other tumors 10 Acute rheumatism 16 Chronic rheumatism 11 Diabetes 166 Exophthalmic goitre 17 Addison's disease 2 Leuchaemia 17 Anemis Chloretes 87 Anaemia Chlorosis 87 Alcoholism 42 Meningitis 121 Locomotor ataxia 14 Other diseases of the spinal cord 21 Cerebral hemmorrhage, apor f ;' 659 Softening of the brain 16 Paralysis without specified cause 233 General Paralysis of the insane 39 Other forms of mental alienation 33 Convulsions _. 52 Epilepsy _. 41 Pericarditis 18 Acute Endocarditis 139 Organic disease of the heart 1139 Angina pectoris 51 Diseases of the arteries 226 Embolism and thrombosis 110 Diseases of the veins (varites hemorrhoids phlebitis) 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 M#krMlf ■ Clsl# Bj.»|-j |»altk Diseases of the lyphatic system 1 Diseases of the nose and throat _ t Bronchitis acute 41 Bronchitis chronic 60 Bronchopneumonia 343 Pneumonia 1048 Pleursy 10 Pulmonary congestion BO Asthma 40 Pulmonary emphysema .5 Diseases of the oesophagus 3 Ulcer of the stomach 38 Other diseases of the stomach (cancer excepted) Ill Diorrhoea and enteritis, under two years 234 Diarrhoea, two years and over 163 Appendicitis and typhlitis 131 Hernia, intestinal obstruction 140 Other diseases of the intestines 79 Cirrhosis of tho liver 69 Biliary calculi 18 Other diseases of the liver 63 Diseases of the spleen * Simple peritonitis 172 Other diseases of the digestive system _.. 2 Acute nephritis 233 Brights disease 369 Other diseases of the kidneys and annexa 26 Diseases of the bladder 28 Diseases of the prostate 36 Diseases of the uterus (non-cancerous) 7 Cysts and other tumors of the ovary 6 Salpingitis and other diseases of the female genital organs 6 Accidents of pregnancy 17 Puerperal haemorrhage 16 Other accidents of labor 11 Puerperal septichaemia 62 Puerperal albuminaria and convulsions 16 Gangrene 36 Acute abscess 7 7 Diseases of the bones (tuberculosis ezcepted) 6 Congenital debility, icterus, sclerema 872 Senility 67» Suicide by poison _ 66 Suicide by hanging SI Suicide by firearms _ 63 Suicide by other means tl Accidental poisoning t Accidental drowning „_ It Burns 45 Traumatlsm by firearms _ SS Traumatism by machines „ 62 Traumatism by railways, vehicles ate „ 18 Traumatism by fall _ 6 Injuries by w" |m »'t _. 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 Starvation 4 Excessive cold _ 4 Excessive heat 21 Lightning 10 Homicides _ 36 Other external violence 146 No cause _ 1M Cause of death not specified or ill denned 32 Hodgkins disease 4 Other diseases of the circulatory system 30 Other diseases of the respiratory system 23 Absorption of deleterious gases conflagration IS Diseases of the larynx _ 10 Other general diseases 22 Disuses of the pharynx 2 HI denned organic diseases 30 Encephalitis 23 Chronic poisoning 1 Furuncle 3 Other acute poisonings 2 Neuralgia and neuritis 5 Other diseases of the nervous system _.. 16 Fracture 23 Pellegra 1 Acute abscess - 3 Chorea : _ _.. 1 Poisoning by food 6 Malaria _ 3 Diseases of the mouth and annexa 1 Poliomyelitis 3 Congenital malformations 9 Abdominal tuberculosis _ 1 Other causes peculiar to early infancy 6 Other diseases of the skin and annexa 1 Other diseases of the heart _.. 3 Still birth _ _ 417 Total 110*1 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 N#hr*«bfl Ctal# Ra&gt;i*H a! Health REPORT OF J. D. CASE, M. D State Health Inspector. The report of the inspector of the State Board of Health, for the year 1916, is herewith presented. This enumerates only some of the most important features of the work done daring this period. There are almost daily demands for official aid.. information or advice, executive or advisory action relative to the management and prevention of communicable disease, the protection of water supply, unsanitary conditions, along with a few calls regarding the sanitation of summer resorts. Jan. 3 Howells Scarlet fever Jan. 4 Norfolk Scarlet fever Jan. 8 Wahoo Scarlet fever Jan. 16 Wahoo Scarlet fever Jan. 14 Ohiowa Typhoid fever and small pox Jan. 19 Fairtield and Edgar Chicken pox Jan. 22 Raymond Scarlet fever Jan. 23 Bethany Small pox Jan. 24 Grafton Small pox Jan. 25 Omaha Inspection Jan. 31 Plalnview Scarlet fever Feb. 2 Ashland Ccarlet fever and diphtheria Feb. 4 Schuyler Small pox Feb. 7 Omaha Scarlet fever Chicken pox Feb. 9 Fairbury Feb. 16 Fremont .Scarlet fever Feb. 17 Neligh .Small pox Feb. 24 Milford .Scarlet fever Mar. 1 Ravenna .. Small pox Mar. 9 Hartington Small pox and chicken pox Mar. 12 Loup City . Diphtheria Mar. 18 Harvard Measles Apr. 3 Beatrice Quarrantine Apr. 5 Weeping Water Sanitation Apr. 6 Courtland Small pox Apr. 6 Oretna Small pox Apr. 7 Plattsmouth Scarlet fever Apr. 13 Columbus Inspection Apr. 14 Grand Island Inspection sanitary Apr. 14 North Platte Inspection sanitary Apr. 15 Kearney Inspection sanitary Apr. 16 Hastings . Inspection sanitary Apr. 24 Seward Inspection sanitary May 3 Central City Sanitation May 7 Humboldt Small pox May 11 Bethany Small pox </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Fo«rth Aunil Bulletin 51 May 23 Fremont ..Sanitation -Sanitation -Small pox May n Fremont June 10 Havelock July 7 Mason City ..Small pox ...Small pox July 10 Weeping Water July II Aurora -Sanitation July 15 Auburn Infantile paralysis Sanitation July 20 Bethany July 21 South Sioux City -Sanitation July 24 Harvard Infantile paralysis Sanitation July 25 Hastings July 28 Peru ..Sanitation -Sanitation ..Sanitation Aug. 10 Crete Aug. 12 Ashland 16 Crete ...Sanitation Aug. Sept 15 Henderson -Typhoid fever Sept 20 Winnebago .—Typhoid fever .—Vital statistics Oct. 11 Hastings Oct. 21 Grand Island -Sanitation and sewerage -Infantile paralysis inspection Oct. 24 Hastings Oct. 30 Seward Water supply Nov 16 College View -Scarlet fever —Small pox Nov. 20 Auburn Nov. 28 Pender ...Infantile paralysis —Infantile paralysis Dec. 1 Crete </seg>
            <seg id="p052">M |j.w_ fc _i 1 , €•»•» Urn mr J aI ■*altk rtCVaBMLB 3UIX BWrl W BC9IUI THE NEWSPAPERS AND PUBLIC HEALTH The Doctors and the Newspapers to Clear the State of Preventable Diseases "The doctors and the papers 1 The health and happi - ness of the people of a great State are largely in their keep - ing. 'Together let us beat this ample field.' Combining their efforts to a common end — the education of the people in the sane and safe rules of good health, and to the import - ance thereof — they could in the course of time rid the State of all preventable diseases. There should be no reason why we could not have a State clear of disease of a preventable nature. But we should not be content to stop there. The newspapers and the physicians should set the higher mark of giving North Carolina the finest health record of any State in the Union. With the doctors leading the way and the papers urging the people to follow on, our State might easily be placed at the head of the list ' ' — From an address by Mr. Wade H. Harris, editor of the Charlotte Observer, at Durham, April 19, 1916. LOW PAT FOR SANITARY KNOWLEDGE "Some health departments are neither headed nor manned by persons well qualified by knowledge, experi- ence and energy to perform the highly responsible duties required of them. Unless a young man possesses independ - ent means, or is of a philanthropic turn of mind, the salaries offered in health department work are such as promptly to discourage him in any fond dream of speedily acquiring the competence of a millionaire ; but with the prevailing appro - priations it cannot be otherwise. It is a fact, certainly not realized by many, that few thoroughly competent municipal or state department heads fill such positions except at a personal sacrifice. Where an official possesses that knowledge and experience competently to fill the position as chief of such a department, the salary offered is but a comparatively small measure of the «n*n«»i»] return the same ability would command in private practice." </seg>
            <seg id="p053">FMrtfc Auaal Balktii 53 I LINCOLN HOTEL, FEBRUARY 21, 1917 Garden Room 10:00 A. M. Registration. 10:30 A. M. Address of Welcome — Gov. Keith Neville. Response to Address of Welcome — Robert McConaughy, M. D., Health Officer, York, Nebr. President's Annual Address — Dr. H. B. Cummins, Vice-President Ne - braska State Board of Health, Seward, Nebr. Paper — Edward H. McLean, M. D., Prof. Creighton Medical College. 1:30 P. M. Lagrippe Epidemics and Their Relations to Public Health — J. H. Mayhew, M. D., Lincoln, Nebr. Discussion — Dr. C. A. Anderson, Health Officer, Stromsburg, Nebr. Dr. C. A. Cate, Nelson, Nebr. Dr. J. R. Bell, M. D., Health Officer, Fairfleld, Nebr. 2:10 P. M. Need of More Urgent Laws for Reporting Venereal Diseases — W. L. Capell, M. D . Lincoln, Nebr. Discussion — R. W. Reynolds, M. D., Lincoln, Nebr. Geo. O. Remy, M. D., Health Officer, Ainsworth, Nebr. L. Fox, M. D., Chairman Board of Health, Nelson, Nebr. 3:00 P. M. Paper — Emergency Care of Passengers and Equipment for Handling Same — Dr. A. F. Jonas, Chief Surgeon Union Pacific R. R., Omaha, Nebr. Discussion — ■ Dr. Frederich Hoyer Millener, Surgeon U. P. R. R., Omaha, Nebr. H. J. Sloss, M. D., Health Officer, Blue Springs, Nebr. 3:54 P. M. Paper — Railroad Sanitation— Dr. A. R. Mitchell Surgeon C. B. ft Q. R. R., C. ft R. I. R. R., U. P. R. R., Lincoln, Nebr Discussion — Dr. E. S. Wenger, Burlington Relief Surgeon C. B. ft Q. R. R., Lincoln. Dr. Harry H. Everett, Surgeon C. B. &amp; Q. R. R., Lincoln. Dr. C. L. Fahnes Lock, Surgeon C. B. ft Q. R. R., McCook, Nebi C. T. Burchard, M. D., Pres. Nebr. State Board of Health Secre taries. Falls City, Nebr 4:30 P. M. Military Hygiene and Sanitation on the Border — Maj. J. M. Birkner, M. D. Discussion opened by — Roscoe Ozman, Y M. C. A. Secretary on Border, Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Nebraska State Board ol HtaHh WEDNESDAY EVENING, FEBRUARY 21, 1917 Lincoln Hotel, Garden Room The Public and Especially Members of Legislature Invited 1. Select Music. 2. Paper — Should Tuberculosis be Quarantined? — Mrs. K. R. J. Ed - holm, Executive Secretary Nebraska Association for Study and Prevention of Tuberculosis. Discussion opened by — L. S. B. Robinson, M. D.. Supt. Nebr. State Tuberculosis Hospital, Kearney. Frank G. Salter, M. D., Health Officer, Pierce, Nebr. W. A. Ackley, M. D., Health Officer, Juniata, Nebr. 3. Male Quartette. 4. Address — Sanitation of Public Schools — W. H. Clemmons, State Supt. of Public Instruction, Lincoln. Solo — Miss Fay Lichtenstiger, Lincoln. Address — Responsibility of Municipalities for Sickness and Death Resulting from Negligence — Hon. Dexter T. Barrett, Deputy Atty. Gen., Lincoln, Nebr. Male Quartette. Address — "The Appreciative Public" — Hon. Edgar Howard, Lieut. Governor, Nebraska; Columbus, Nebr. GARDEN ROOM Lincoln Hotel, February 22, 1917 Morning Sesaion 8:30 A. M. Paper — Duties of a Local Health Officer — Lucian Stark, M. D., Mem - ber Nebr. State Board of Secretaries. Discussion opened by— Hal C. Wilmeth, M. D., Lincoln. C. A. Shoemaker, M. D.. Lincoln. O. H. Hall, M. D., Health Officer, Elkhora, Nebr. 9:15 A. M. Paper — Urgent Need for Full Time County Health Officer — Dr. Geo. Shidler, Ex-Health Officer, York, Nebr. Discussion opened by — F. B. Slussen, M. D., City Board of Health, Polk, Nebr. J. H. Hall. M. D., Health Officer, Plattsmouth, Nebr. Irving S. Cutter, M. D., Dean University Medical College, Omaha. 10:00 A. M. Paper — Remeniscences of a Health Officer — S. T. Ragan, M. D. County Health Officer, Seward, Nebr. Discussion opened by — Jesse Hartman, M. D., City Health Officer, Crete, Nebr. James R. Bell, Health Officer, Fairfleld, Nebr. L. Phelan. M. D., Health Officer, Grand Island, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">FMrth Anna! Bulletin 55 10:45 A. M. Pending Legislation — Dr. F. L. Wilmeth, Lincoln, Nebr. Discussion — H. E. Hantor, M. D., Health Officer, Sidney, Nebr. W. H. Wilson, M. D., Ex-State Health Inspector, Lincoln. S. E. Hasan. M. 1) . Health Officer. Seward. Chas. L. Mullens, M. D., Health Officer, Broken Bow. Porter F. Dodson, M. D., Health Officer, Wilber, Nebr. John Prentis Lord, M. D., Surgeon State Orthopedic Hospital, Omaha. Robert McConaughy, M. D., Health Officer, York, Nebr. Clifford P. Fall, M. D., Ex-Secretary to Nebraska State Board of Health. 11:30 A. M. Paper — Sanitation as Relating to Institutional Life — W. S. Fast, Supt. Hospital for the Insane, Ingleside, Nebr. Discussion opened by — F. L. Beck, M. D., County Health Board, Geneva. Geo. Charlton. M. I) . Supt. Hospital for Insane, Norfolk, Nebr. W. Edmonds. M. D., Health Officer, Nebraska City, Ntbr. 1:30 P. M. 2:00 P. M. Paper — Public Health and Sanitation— Chauncey F. Chapman, M. D., Supt. of Health, Lincoln. Discussion opened by— J. W. Bozarth, M. D., Health Officer. Lexington, Nebr. F. E. Calkins, M. D., County Health Officer, Fremont. Hon. Harry D. Landis, Sec'y Public Health Ass'n., Seward, Nebr. Dr. Frederich Hoyer Milliner, Surgeon U. P. R. R., Omaha, Nebr. 2:40 P. M. Paper — Need Nebraska Fear an Epidemic of Anterior Poliomyelitis during 1917? — J. D. Case, M. D., State Health Inspector, Lincoln. Discussion opened by — Joseph Socrates Leisure, M. D., Pathologist, Hospital for Insane. Ingleside, Nebr. H. H. Thompson, M. D., Health Officer, David City, Nebr. L. Muir, M. D., Health Officer, Alvo, Nebr. 3:20 P. M. Paper— Proper Ventilation of Public Buildings— Chas. H. Arnold, M. D., Lincoln. Nebr. Discussion — Truman I. Wigim, M. D., Health Officer, Dorchester. G. A. Sloss, M. D., Health Officer, DeWitt, Nebr. F. M. Andrus, M. D., Lincoln, Nel.r. 4:00 P. M. Business. Adjournment. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nehr^u State tmri U ImM 56 REGARDING THE FOX LAW. LINCOLN, Neb., Jan. 27— To the Editor of the State Journal: Lincoln physicians who were first pleased with the action taken by the league of Nebraska municipalities, in jheir meeting at Hastings, whereby they endorsed the bill before the legislature based on the Fox report, havt discovered that in said bill, house roll 124, senate file No. 60, which provides for a wholesale reorganization of the state board of health, are not so well pleased now as they have dis - covered a joker in those bills which asks a democratic board of secre - taries by repealing the action of the statutes under which they were appointed. It is reported that Dr. E. W. Rowe of Lincoln is one of the doctors most active in pushing the bill and it is also claimed that he is taking this action as the small minority of three of the joint committee of the committte which recently met here in Lin - coln of the different state medical and health organizatiins ; repre - sented as follows: Conference of local and state health officers — Dr. F. L. Wil - meth, Lincoln; Dr. J. R. Bell, Fairfield; Dr. P. F. Dodson, Wilbur; Dr. S. E. Ragan. Seward. Nebraska state medical society — Dr. E. W. Rowe, Lincoln; Dr. J. P. Lord, Omaha; Dr. A. I. Dillon, Auburn; W. H. Wilson, Lincoln; Dr. Charles L. Mullen, Broken Bow, Dr. H. E. Mantor, Sidney. Nebraska state eclectic medical society — Dr. F. H. Andrus, Lin - coln; Dr. E. J. Latta, Lincoln; Samuel Metheny, Lnicoln. Nebraska state homeopathic society — Dr. C. A. Shoemaker, Lin - coln; Dr. G W. Collins, Pawnee; Dr. R. W. Hufman, University Place; Dr. W. A. Cate, Nelson. Secretaries to the state board of health— Dr. C. T. Burchard, Falls City; Dr. H. B. Cummins, Seward; Dr. L. Stark, Hartington; Dr. E. Arthur Carr, Lincoln. Many of those who have already announced themselves on those bills are now facing about and are endorsing the modified Fox bill, which is H. R. 245. At the late hour at which this communication was sent in, it was impossible to reach other members of the committees to obtain their signatures. DR. C. A. SHOEMAKER, DR. F. M. ANDRUS, DR. SAMUEL METHENY, DR E. J. LATTA, DR. F. L. WILMETH DR. R. W. HUFMAN, </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 (urn AmwJ Miietu FAILED TO HAVE LICENSE Gray Fined Fifty Dollars for Practicing Medicine Without Health Board Certificate. (Lincoln Evening News, January 22, 1917.) Charles W. Gray, pleaded guilty in Justice Clark's court Tues - day morning to a complaint charging him with practicing medicine without securing a license from the state board of health. He was fined $50 and costs, which was the minimum under the law. The fine and costs were paid. The complaint was signed by Dr. E. A. C'arr. secretary of the state board. Gray said that he supposed that he was registered. He stated that he was a graduate of the Lincoln Medical college, and after he received his diploma he understood that the college authorities had registered him with the state health board. While running a drug store in Chicago the store was destroyed by fire and Gray declared that his diploma and other papers were burned. Dr. E. Arthur C'arr. secretary of the state board of health, said that the question had been raised as to whether Gray had a license to practice emdicine and he had made an investigation. He under - stood that Gray had been called by another doctor into consultation in a very critical case and he made it his business to question Gray. The latter told him that he was graduated with the class of 1902, of the Lincoln Medical college. Doctor Carr said he had a roster of the students of the college and the list of graduates from the institution covering the year named by Gray but could not find his name enrolled. Doctor Carr recalled to Mr. Gray that at that time he, Carr, had lectured at the college, but Gray could not remember him. Secretary Carr said he introduced another doctor who was a student at the college during that time named by Gray, but the latter could not recall having heard of him or known him. Doctor Carr said Gray told him that he supposed that he had been registered for a number of years. Mr. Gray was recently engaged in the optical business. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">DON'T FORGET the Annual Conference of Local and State Health Officers LINCOLN February 21 and 22, 1917 Municipalities and Counties should mar Travel. Ing Expenses of their Health OMcurm or Representatives 8E£ TENTATIVE PROGRAM PAGES 33-55 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>