<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00003">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00003</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION HELD AT LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, January 15, 16, 17, 18, 1901</title>
		             <date value="1902">1902</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-12</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-07</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
or the 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL MEETING 

or tbs 

Nebraska State Poultry 

Association 

HELD AT 

LINCOLN, NEBRASKA 

January 15, 16, 17, 18, 1901 

FKIPARED BY 

AUERT Lkmsn, Secretary 


LINCOLN. MB. 
JACOB NOKTH * CO., FKINTIU 

ISO* </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL. 

Office of the Secretary 

Nebraska State Poultry Association, 
Lincoln, Neb., February 1, 1901. 

To His Excellency, Charles H. Dietrich, Governor of Nebraska: 


Dear Sir — In compliance wth the law in this case made 
and provided, I herewith transmit the Annual Report of the 
Nebraska State Poultry Association for the year closing January, 
1901. 

Very respectfully, 

Albert Lemen, 

Secretary. </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
OFFICERS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1900-1901 

CM. Lewkllino President Beaver City 

Frank Patton Vice -President Surprise 

Albert Lemen Secretary Lincoln 

E. A. Spencer Treasurer Cortland 

MEMBERS OF THE BOARD 

Johh Skinner Spiker 

L. W. Garroutte Lincoln 

Casper Dice Roca 

H. J. Smith Lincoln 

E. £. Greer Cambridge 

OFFICERS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1901-1902 

L. P. Harris President Clay Center 

W. A. Irvin Vice-president Tecnmseh 

L. W. Garroutte Secretary Lincoln 

E. O. Spencer Treasurer Cortland 

MEMBERS OF THE BOARD 

L. P. Ludden Lincoln 

O. D. Talbert ; Omaha 

T. L. Norval Seward 

Frank Patton Surprise 

E. E. Greer Cambridge </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
PROCEEDINGS 

OF THE 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 

OF TBS 

NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION 

HELD AT 

LINCOLN, NEB., JANUARY 15, 16, 17, 18, 1901 

Lincoln. Neb., January 15, 1901, 3:00 p.m. 

In accordance to the call issued by the Secretary and in 
conformity to the provisions of the statute the members of 
the Nebraska State Poultry Association met in annuaj convention 
in the Commercial Club parlors, Lincoln, Neb., with 
President C. M. Levelling in the chair. The President then 
delivered his annual address. 

PRESIDENT'S ADDRESS. 

Members of the Nebraska State Poultry Association, Greet- 

ing: 

Another year has passed into history, and we again meet 
in poultry convention to review the work of the past year, to 
interchange ideas, and map out the work for the future in 
which all, I am sure, will be willing to assist. 

Ke past year opened up discouragingly to many. Their 
refused to lay early, and after they did begin the work 
ling the egg basket they were off the perch early in the </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
6 


morning, their combs as red as roses., and they woe ;i t once 
into the scratching pen, making the straw fly, hunting for 
any stray kernel of grain they might have overlooked the 
day before. The most of them would deposit a nice, large, 
perfect egg in the nest box, taking their places on the perch 
again in the evening for another night of repose and slumber, 
never once noticing the frown that deepened each night 
upon the face of the owner, when it was discovered that not 
one of them felt the least inclined to set. Is it any wonder, 
then, that after the fancier had saved a bushel of those fine 
eggs, and with apparently no prospect of getting Biddy to set, 
an order should go forth for an incubator — something that 
would set or not, at the will of the operator? But even after 
the patent machine had done its work it was a cold, backward 
spring, and most of the chicks pined and died for want 
of the warm sunshine which no man can counterfeit. 

It was not any wonder, then, that the last of August, when 
the fanciers began to look in their flocks for chicks to exhibit 
at the state fair, at the same time remembering what 
fine, large ones they had in their coops on other years, and 
not realizing that their competitors had been obliged to meet 
the same difficulties and discouragement as themselves, that 
they should conclude not to exhibit at the fair, or at least 
only a few, and those mostly old birds. 

This cut down the poultry exhibit at the state fair, and 
has also been against all local shows I have attended this 
winter. Yet, in spite of the slow development of birds the 
past season, it is estimated that during the year 1900 onehalf 
more poultry and one-third more eggs were shipped to 
market from the state of Nebraska than in any preceding </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
7 

Cars loaded with poultry have become a familiar sight, 
whereas only a few years ago they were a thing unknown, 
and when you realize, in addition to this, that the express 
companies are tarrying to market in slatted coops stowed 
away in express cars and out of the sight of the public gaze, 
except as they are loaded and unloaded, fully three times as 
ninth poultry as they did a few years ago, you then have 
some idea of the growth of the poultry industry of the state. 

I would call your attention to the great improvement in 
t quality of the market poultry of to-day over that of a few 
rs ago, and please permit me to say that to you, my fellow 
fanciers, is due the credit for this advanced step in poultry 
culture, because from your yards of carefully mated 
thoroughbred fowls you have contributed to the world a 
better class of birds than it had before, and I am pleased 
that you are yet in line to carry still farther the good work 
of improvement. 

Since our last annual meeting some changes have been 
made, and it seems to me that others are needed in order to 
meet the demands of the times. At the semi-annual meeting 
held on the state fair grounds it was voted that the premiums 
be again raised from $4, $3, $2 on pens to $6, $4, |2, 
and on single birds from $2, f 1.50. f 1 to f3, |2, f 1, and some 
new breeds which are bred in the state have been added to 
the premium list. Belgian hares have also been added to 
our list, and the additions made have increased our liabilities 
over $400 more than they were last year. We are now 
offering in cash premiums f 1,512; besides this we must pay 
our judges $155, our treasurer $25, and our secretary $50, 
making a total expense of $230, besides the expense of printing, 
feed for the birds, an assistant secretary, and help in the </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
8 


show room. All this puts our liabilities at meat $2,000, and 
our show room is furnished us this year, otherwise it would 
be above that figure. We draw $1,000 annually from the state. 
Last year we received for entry fees #287, door receipts 
1102.80, and these, with the sale of stock, would put our 
assets at about f 1,400. With these figures looking me in the 
face, I see but one way of solving the problem. We must go 
before the legislature and ask them to increase our appropriation 
to $l.~&gt;00 jK'r annum. We should increase our premiums 
rather than cut them down, by offering premiums on 
dressed ptmltry, e^gs, etc. This matter, my friends, I believe 
to be worthy of your careful consideration. I wish to say 
that this year your board of managers has tried to exercise 
the most rigid economy. Tt was necessary to hold a board 
meeting in February to approve the bonds of your worthy 
secretary and treasurer. Each member who attended the 
meeting donated his time and bore his own expenses. 

t recommend that you so cfcapge your by-laws that the 
ident be required to approve bonds of the secretary and 
rarer instead of the board of directors as heretofore. 

E* a matter of economy I would respectfully recommend 
in the future you elect as officers a president, vice-presi, 
tertiary, treasurer, and sui&gt;erintendent, and that the 
officers named shall constitute the board of directors or 
d of managers. 

Five men can do just as much business as nine men, and 
do it with less expense. 

I recommend that no member of the board who receives 
from the association a stated salary, as does the secretary 
and treasurer, he allowed any further compensation as a 
member of the board during the annual show. And I urge </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
9 

NKRRASKA STATE 1*1 * l_ I/fK\ ASSOCIATION. 

Eyou take sjM-iial action on this, as a precedent has 
established that it seems to me is unjust and dangerous 
9 association. 

Early last summer I, as your president, made application 
to the railroad companies doing business in Nebraska for a 
general passenger rate of one fare for the round trip to Lincoln 
during our annual show and convention. 

The railroad companies declined to give the rate I asked 
for, but offered us a one and one-third rate on the certificate 
plan, and notified the agents over the state of such arrangement. 
.Members of the association, as well as of the Commercial 
(Mutt of Lincoln, assisted in continuing to ask for 
the rate of one fare, and finally, at a late date, round trip 
tickets to Lincoln from anv potel of the state were secured, 
without the bother of certificates. 1 recommend that you 
pass resolutions thanking the railroad companies for the 
concession and assistance to the poultry people in granting 
said rate, and also recommend that you instruct your officers 
for the coming year to respectfully urge the railroad 
companies to give us a flat rate of one fare for the round trip 
to our next annual show. 

Whereas, according to our by-laws, the newly elected ofti&lt; 
crs are inducted into office, and at the same time our old 
officers go owt of office, on Friday after the election, the 
annual poaltry show not yet being over, the door receipt* 
still coming in, yet the secretary and treasurer are required 
t report while their accounts are incomplete and without 
•ing any time to prepare their reports in a presentable 
shape. In this you change the business of the show from 
the old board to the new during the tiu.e of the show, which 
reminds me of the old story of swapping horses while cross- </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 


ing a stream. It might be a food change, but uot a good 
tiate to make it. 

I therefore recommend that the time for inducting the 
vlv elected officers into office be changed to a later date, 
that the old officers who have conducted the show from 
first lie permitted to continue the same to its close and 
n have a reasonable time to prepare a report. This will 
3 give the newly elected secretary and treasurer time to 
lire bonds. 

I recommend that a bill be prepared and introduced into 
the legislature requiring assessors to gather statistics of the 
Eltry and eggs marketed, also those consumed by the fainof 
each partv he assesses, that the people may know the 
jnitude of the poultry industry of the state. 

Find now, wishing for each of you a prosperous year in 
ltry raising, I close by recommending that a commit tee 
appointed to revise the articles of incorporation, constitution, 
and by-laws of this association, and that said committee 
be required to report Thursday evening. 

Immediately following the president's address, the program 
as arranged for was carried out 

Prof. John L. Sheldon, of Central Village, Conn., then ad-ed 
the association on "Poultry Shows as Educators." 

He spoke as follows : 

Mr. President and Members of the Nebraska State Poultry 

Association: 

t bring you the greetings of the poultry fanciers of the 
t. The subject assigned me on your program is "Poultry 
ws as Educators." 

The old-time notion that anybody and everybody can raise 
chickens, fancy ones. too. is gradually dying out. There are </seg>


            <seg id="p011">
11 

tijrh abandoned hen houses and dilapitated yards Mattered 
¦ the country to convince the most skeptical and verify 
statement. A glance at the advertising columns of some 
of the poultry journals for a scries of yean will reveal the 
beginning and closing out of several poultry establishments, 
claiming to be the largest of their kind in existence. It re- 
E*d whole pages of advertising space to let the public 
r about them. There were other one- and two inch adsements 
that will be found in the same papers to-day, 
ment is unnecessary. 

I People are beginning to realize that a large amount of ex"ience 
is more essential than capital. It is no small matter 
conduct a poultry plant turning out ten thousand broilers 
annually or perhaps caring for several hundred layers. The 
incubator and brooder are marvelous constructions, threatening 
to make it unprofitable for a hen to become broody. 
Like her, however, they require a certain amount of attention. 
The minutest details must be regarded in feeding for eggs. 
The hens must not become too fat nor too poor, but always in 
a good, healthy, laying condition. For the amount invested 
there is probably no live stock paying so large a dividend 
when properly managed. 

The average breeder who raises only enough pullets to take 
the place of the old hens, marketing the surplus cockerels, 
can allow his fowls greater freedom. They consequently keep 
in better health, and the loss from disease is trifling compared 
with when they are massed together. However, in large or 
small flocks, overcrowding invites disease and reduces growth 
and egg production. 

The breed i ng of fowls — fancy ones in particular — is more 
or less spasmodic. Every year just before the show season </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
12 


opens, there is a certain class that has a relapse of "hen 
fever"; just after the show a lot of beginnen come down 
with it. The "hen fever" is very contagious, often sweeping 
through whole communities within a short time. There are 
a few persons who are immune. They have no use for hens 
¦pt when they are chicken hungry, and probably could not 
tell the difference l&gt;et\veen lien and chicken unless they 
judged by the price of the meal or by the cooking. When a 
poultry show is mentioned in their presence, they ask with « 
sneer, "What is there to see in an old hen show but hens? We 
• an see hens anywhere." So they can, such as they are, but 
if they want to see hens, such as they don't see "anywhere,'" 
the only place to see them is at a poultry show. Their-curiosity 
knows no bounds when they learn that an exhibitor has 
refused a hundred dollars for a cockerel. ''Whew! You 
• lout say so? Worth H much as a good horse. Well, now, 
I guess I better go in a little while this evening and see what 
kind of hens they've got in there. Anyway, I don't take any 
k in this full-blooded hen business. They ain't a bit better 
than the old-fashioned kind. Maybe they do look a little 
prettier, but they won't lay any more eggs, and the color of 
their feathers don't cut any figure when they are on the 
table. But I wouldn't mind having one of their roosters to 
put with my hens. I like to chauge blood occasionally. I'll 
tell you what it is, though, T wouldn't give over a dollar for 
the l)est rooster they've got." 

Ehere are a few born fanciers. Those who are not can 
help it; they are not to blame. In my own case (pardon 
personality, for I know more about my own experience 
i I do about any one else's) what little talent I possess 
g that line was inherited from my mother through sev- </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
13 


E generations. It is a fact well known in our family that 
father has never been able to set a hen and not have her 
e the nest at the end of the second day — sooner, if she waa 
fastened on. While he can not set a hen, his coops and 
yards are models of neatness, and the chicks show in the 
fall the effects of his liberal feeding. 

My mother began training me at a very early age to take 
care of our common chickens. It was about the time that 
so much was being said about "full-blooded" hens, when the 
Red Leghorns were being "cracked up v as great layers. My 
annual trip to the county fair was a source of no small 
amount of inspiration. I had an attack of "hen fever," from 
Ich I have never fully recovered. I invested a few slowly 
led dollars, saved up from the earnings of the first hens 
rer owned, six of them, of as many shapes and colors, in 
oultry paper, and some "full blooded" eggs. Say, what 
es those were ! I furnished the theory, my mother the exience. 
A mixture of the two always worked well so long 
he theory was kept well diluted. I have always claimed 
tr I inherited the theory, along with several other things, 
n my father. The mating in this instance proved conlively 
that it was not done according to well established 
recognized principles of breeding, although it was a 
ural selection on the part of the two contracting parties. 

The successful exhibitor must be a successful breeder. Exhibitors 
who buy all of their birds instead of raising them 
are ruled out here for various reasons. They are a great help 
from a financial standpoint, and undoubtedly receive much 
pleasure from their investment when their birds win, while 
the breeders reap the profits. The breeder will furnish the 
birds if the other party will the cash. Let the good work </seg>


            <seg id="p014">
14 


II breeder must be a thorough student of poultry culture 
the game degree that the successful farmer is of agricule 
and the successful physician of medicine. He must be 
re than an ordinary student; he must be a specialist, for 
s only by patient and careful study of the "ins and outs" 
the variety that he breeds that he is able to mate his breed 
; yards intelligently. In other words, the breeder must be 
icated for his work. 

It has required years for Philander Williams to bring the 
ocrat strain of Light Brahmas to their present type. The 
eder also naturally becomes an expert judge of his variety. 
s specialty judge is being employed at nearly all the large 
ws. Those judges usin^ the decimal score card are recogid 
as being competent to do the work by a committee of 
estigation which grants them a certificate, sort of a dima. 
Poultry breeding and management is being introed 
into our agricultural colleges and experiment stations 
account of the importance of the poultry industry. The 
dents are receiving practical instruction under the guide 
of competent instructors. 

J?oultry breeding is often a means of obtaining a livelihood, 
is congeniar and affords a means of recreation to those 
ose brains become wearied from other duties. To the man 
the shop or store there is a real pleasure in caring for a 
7 thoroughbreds. He reads the poultry journals and benes 
a thinker along this line. He finally becomes an exlitor. 
His faculties of observation and judgment become 
ined, resulting in an increased breadth of culture and 
ntal development. 

K Breeding may be termed the science and exhibiting the art 
poultry culture. Results of breeding culminate in the </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 


show room. It is at the poultry shows where the breeders 
test their skill; where they find out in what points their 
birds are weak, and in what strong, by comparing them with 
»&gt;se of other breeders, and where they get new ideas, snch 
they can not obtain from any other source. Perhaps one 
of the greatest benefits they receive is the judge's unbiased 
opinion, for there is no one who does not become so attached 
to his fowls and therefore see fewer general faults in them. 
To the amateur it is at the poultry show that he finds out 
what a really good bird is. He is encouraged to keep on, while 
the veteran gains new inspiration and is forced to exert every 
effort to win, otherwise he is driven to the wall and must 
stop showing. His reputation as a breeder is at stake. His 
sales of stock and eggs are dependent to a large extent upon 
his success in the show room. 

No fancier can become so narrow that he is not interested 
in other varieties except his own. It does not follow that because 
he has Barred Plymouth Bocks that he can not appreciate 
an extra good specimen of the white variety or a Langshan. 
The new varieties always attract his attention. The 
breeder of Silver Wyandottes must have felt that the introduction 
of the white, golden, and black meant a diminished 
sale of the Silver. One question that would come to him 
would be whether the other varieties surpass his in points of 
excellence. Most of us remember with what curiosity we 
looked at the first Red Caps, Indian Games, Rhode Island 
Reds, and the other new breeds. They are the product of 
some one's creative imagination, brought out by breeding and 
came in with the others for recognition as thoroughbreds. 
Those that possess real merit will continue to be bred in 
numbers proportionate to their excellence and popularity. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 


All of our breeds are comparatively new. Back in (he fif- 
IBurnhani was breeding Cochin Chinas of all colors from 
ctically one mating. His yards were not mated with the 
e that we have at the present time. He did not have the 
•k in the first place, but he made a l&gt;eginning. If his 
•ks came black, they were Black Cochin Chinas; if buff, 
I Cochin Chinas. From these distinct colors came ouf 
ck and Buff Cochins by selection. Biirnham is only one 
he many who has helped develop our Asiatics. To-day we 
not satisfied if they breed true to color. It was not long 
e that a controversy arose M to what the proper shade of 
&gt;r is for a standard Buff Cochin. 

Ehere are proboMy breeds that will produce from seven tyto 
ninety ]M-r cent of exhibition stock. The progeny being 
so nearly alike that a person unfamiliar with fancy fowls 
might exclaim. "Why, I don't sec how you can tell them 
frt!"' It does not require very close observation to detect 
erences. It is a part of the breeder's business to pick out 
differences in mating his Hock. There are differences in 
the expression of the eyes, shape of the comb, general carriage, 
etc. One learns even to recognize them by the sounds 
which they make. 

A story is told of a man who became so well acquainted 
with his fowls that he could pick out a eeftaia rooster from 
a flock of over one hundred on a very dark night, without 
the aid of a lantern, merely by touch. Perhaps it ought to be 
added by way of explanation that this was the only rooster 
in the flock. 

f'hen we note the differences which characterize the varibreeds 
and varieties of thoroughbred poultry, we would 
for once imagine that they all came from two lines of </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
17 


ancestry, the jungle fowls of India, which are very similar to 
our modern Black Breasted Red Games, and the Cochin 
China type. It has beea suggested that the crest may have 
come from crossing with the pheasant Taking the Polish 
as an illustration of what systematic selection and mating 
has accomplished, we find the bearded and plain white, white 
crested black, black crested white, golden and silver spangled 
and penciled, bearded and plain, possibly others. They are 
rivals of the Hamburgs in both color and beauty. We need 
not stop here with the poultry, but take a look at the pigeons. 
Who would ever suspect that a pouter, jacobin, and fantail 
were of common parentage? Yet they are lineal descendants 
from the wild rock pigeon of Europe. Illustrations just as 
striking could be cited from among cattle, horses, sheep, 
swine, fruits, vegetables, and flowers. Plants and animals 
show natural tendencies to vary. The "survival of the unlike," 
as Professor Bailey of Cornell terms it in his recently 
published work by that title, is the foundation of our new 
varieties which in some instances are termed breeds. 

The public is always ready to buy that which is new. 
Breeders and exhibitors cater to the public, and new varieties 
are the result. One can be made in a few years. 

It is at the poultry shows that the new varieties make their 
debut. If they are attractive and of good size or supposed 
laying qualities, they are liable to prove more than a fad. In 
either case, they soon are dependent upon their real merits 
and fall into their proper places along with the other 
varieties. 

All standard breeds must come up to a fixed color test, 
while many must for weight. The weight requirements have 
placed larger and plumper poultry in our markets. It goes 

I </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 


iiout saying that thoroughbreds are superior to scrubs in, 
7 particular, whether it be for rapid growth, for broilers, 
eggs, or for eggs and poultry combined. They are bred 
these very purposes, as well as for fancy points; they are 
•efore more uniform. The utility side has in nearly ail 
js been of first importance. 

The public at large has not as yet been educated up to the 
point where it can appreciate the value of the thoroughbred 
fowls. It does not know the immense amount of labor and 
capital that has already been expended in improving them. 
People attend poultry shows largely out of curiosity. It is 
true they do carry away some new ideas. Are not most of 
the poultry shows for the exhibitors after all? They are the 
ones, then, that reap the benefits. In order for poultry shows 
to educate the public, they must make provision for exhibits 
of those things that are of interest to the public. I recall a 
valuable display of dressed poultry made by the Rhode Island 
experiment station at one of the shows held by the state poultry 
association. It was of great value from a market standpoint 
on account of the data accompanying each entry. The 
breed or cross was given in most cases; the age, and the live 
and dressed weights. The relative size and color of eggs 
from different varieties is another important factor. But 
few of us know much about capons except in name. Many 
have never seen the plump, good-natured, long-feathered fowl 
that they are. An old lady who purchased a few became disgusted 
with them after keeping them a few months because 
they did not lay. Evidently she mistoook the name for some 
new breed of hens. 

Ehe incubators and brooders attract the children. They 
stand for hours watching the little chicks kicking them- </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
19 


selves out of the shells or chasing each other about in the 
brooder in an attempt to get a supposed extra good morse) 
which one of their number is unwilling to give up. The 
other poultry appliances and fixtures, bone-mills, foods, medicines, 
etc., are of importance to the exhibitor. They help 
keep him up-to-date. 

In conclusion, then, poultry shows become educators in 
that (1) breeders and exhibitors have an opportunity of 
meeting each other and exchanging ideas, comparing their 
Kls, of seeing representatives of the more important breeds, 
xamining the different makes of incubators and brooders 
in actual operation, besides many other things; (2) the public 
is educated in that it is given an opportunity to see gathered 
together the best that is produced in fancy poultry for 
miles around, to form some conception of what is being done 
to place prime poultry and fresh eggs upon their tables, to 
make a comparison between thoroughbreds and scrubs, to 
learn something about the artificial methods of hatching and 
brooding, to form some conception of the importance of the 
poultry industry. 

Dr. I. C. Stephens, of Milford, Neb., pccMated the following 
paper, which was read : 

I the Officers and Members of the Nebraska State Poultry 
Association: 

VjENTLEMEN — I beg leave to submit the following relating 
"The White Wondor as an Egg Producer." 

The White Wonders were brought to my notice three years 
ago by Mr. P. H. Jacobs, editor of the Poultry Keeper, who 
recommended them as "grand layers and table birds, the beat 
combination fowl out." In October, 1898, I purchased a </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 


cockerel and four pullets to give them a trial. They were 
May hatched birds, and while they did not begin laying at 
as early an age as some claim their pullets do, they certainly 
made up for it after they did begin. They began laying December 
16, when about seven months old, and by the 20th all 
were laying, though I did not keep a record until January 1 
to 15, inclusive, 1899, and during those fifteen days they 
laid 53 eggs, an egg ever 27 hours and 10 minutes per pullet. 
You doubtless remember that the weather in January, 1899, 
was unusually and extremely cold for Nebraska, but it 
seemed to make no difference with those White Wonder 
pullets. Their house was 6x6 feet, one thickness of J-inch 
boards, covered on the outside with tarred paper, standing 
out by itself, unprotected by shelter of any kind. It was so 
cold that often a basin of water would freeze solid in twenty 
or thirty minutes. Their feed consisted of whole wheat in 
the morning, a few table scraps at noon, and whole corn at 
night. No cut bone, clover, nor prepared poultry foods of 
any kind. I did not feed them a warm mash during the entire 
winter. I mention this to show that these pullets were not 
pampered, and "fed for eggs," so called, but produced an egg 
every 27 hours and 10 minutes per pullet on the plainest 
kind of food, showing conclusively to me that they were grand 
winter layers. I have not been so particular about keeping 
records since the above mentioned time, but I have had other 
pullets do as well, I think, as these. In the spring of 1900 I 
set three of my White Wonder hens, giving the chicks, thirtytwo 
in number, to one of the hens to brood. The day her 
chicks were four weeks old she l&gt;e«;aii laying. She did not 
desert her chicks, but took the best of care of them as long 
as they needed her care (for White Wonders are good mothers), 
and laid an average of two eggs every three days dur- </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
21 


ing that time. A White Wonder hen is very gentle and becomes 
broody quite readily, but her broodiness is very easily 
broken up, and in a remarkably short time thereafter will 
resume her laying. &amp;hc is certainly built that tray. 

Es my experience with White Wonders is limited, I will 
te you what some of the New England breeders say of 
n ; that section of the country where they are best known, 
and where, I am told, they are very popular among the farmeA 
and poultrymen on account of their excellent table qualities 
and egg production. 

|[r. H. F. Corning, Hartford, Conn., says of them: "For 
ter layers they have nothing that can come near them, 
me tell you breeders of thoroughbred fowls what four 
ite Wonder hens did for me in a year (365 days). In a 
se so cold (it was intended only for summer use) that a 
[ of water froze solid several nights, with no hot mush 
no cut meat or bone, with only wheat for feed, they have 
i 576 eggs for the year, not a month but what they proed 
eggs, and two of them were set in March and hatched 
. raised their chicks. This was done by them on their 
it merit, not a favor shown them ; it was done for a test, 
it was a great one. A year ago last January (this was 
tten in 1897), with favors shown in a warm house, with 
meat and bone fed twice a week, with wheat only, no hot 
mush fed, twenty June hatched pullets laid 432 eggs, producing 
in one week 111 eggs, and three days during the month 
18 eggs per day. Since January 1, this year, up to February 
20, fifty June hatched pullets have laid 1,431 egijs." 

W. J. Gabb, Bloomfield, Conn., says : "Had my White Wonder 
pullets laid one more egg, their average for December 
would have been eighteen eggs apiece. Their January aver- </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 


age was twenty-two each. They were fed twice a day on 
wheat, buckwheat, hulled oats, and scraps from the table. 
They also had free access to groud shells. Taking into consideration 
their size, beauty, hardiness, excellent table qualities, 
and laying ability, as shown in the above test made in 
midwinter, in a cold climate like New England, without artificial 
heat, I do not think the breeders of White Wonders 
need allow their slumbers to be disturbed because they were 
refused admission to the Standard." 

I*. H. Jacobs, editor of the Poultry Keeper, Ilammonton, 
w Jersey, says : "In regard to the White Wonder fowls, I 
1 say that the hen began to lay as soon as she arrived, kept 
ing, laid when she was moulting, hatched a brood, and 
med to want to do nothing but lay, I will say that 
far I like the White Wonders more than well, and have 
n nothing to eclipse them for hardiness, egg production, 
1 market qualities oombmcd. They are cranks on laying, 
1 do not seem to be willing to rest over wLen moulting, 
n laying while the chicks are young, and caring for them 
the same time." 

IVm. N. French, New ITaven, Yt., the originator of the 
ed, said : "To give an idea of their laving qualities it may 
stated that from January 1 to May 1 of 1891 eighty of 
se hens and pullets laid 3,688 eggs." 

I have statements from White Wonder breeders in Illinois, 
Wisconsin, and South Dakota, showing remarkable laying 
qualities of their fowls, but this paper would become tedious 
were I to report them all, so will report but one more, a 
statement made by E. V. Stoekwell, Dodge City, Kan. He 
said: "The two pullets commenced laying in December, and 
they averaged 15 eggs apiece in December, 25 in January, </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
23 

NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION. 

{23 apiece in February. I set one of them and she 
•lied 9 chicks out of 12 eggs; another hen hatched 14 oat 
5 eggs. The White Wonder hen began laying a^ain when 
chicks were two weeks old, and laid an egg every day for 
weeks, besides brooding her chicks." 

I good iiwny prominent and influential members of the 
ricau Poultry Association have become sufficiently a&lt; 
inted with the White Wonders in the past year or two 
; they are willing, anxious in fact, to have them admitted 
he Standard of Perfection, and they would undoubtedly 
dmitted to the Standard this month had a petition asking 
their admission been filed with the secretary of the Amer- 
Poultry Association sixty days prior to its annual meetas 
its rules require. I propose to see to it, personally, 
: all the requirements of the American Poultry Associa. 
are complied with next year, and thereafter, I have no 
bt, the White Wonders will be recognized by the Aineri- 
Standard of Perfection. 

Skcretary Lemex — I move that a committee of live be appointed 
to revise the Constitution and By-Laws of this Association, 
the President to constitute one of the committee, and 
I would recommend that Judge Norval be made chairman of 
this committee. 

Motion seconded and carried. 

EB. Luddex — The other recommendation in that report 
that resolutions be'drafted. It seems to me it would be 
if we have a committee on resolutions to report here 
rsday evening. 

Motion seconded by Secretary Leinen. Carried 

K resident Lewelunc; — Kev. L. P. Ludden will be chairi 
of that committee. </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 


EK. Ludden — I would rather vim would put some other 
on on that committee; I waive that courtesy as the 
er of that motion. 

President Lkwklling — While we appreciate the amount 
of work you are performing, still 1 am satisfied it would be 
the will of the convention that you serve on this committee, 
if you please. I supj&gt;ose that committee should he three. I 
will add to that committee Mr. W. A. Irwin and David 
Lamm. 

President Lkwklung — I would name as the three members 
to be added to the committee on the revision of the Constitution 
and By-Laws, Mr. L. W. Garoutte, Mr. J. S. Bishop, 
and Mr. Albert Lemen. 

The convention then adjourned. 

The paper by Dr. A. Gaiser, on "The Utility of the Buff 
Cochins,'" was not read, owing to his absence, and was not 
handed to the Secretary. 

Also the paper prepared by J. Q. Gordiner on Belgian 
hares was not turned over to the Secretary. 

ADDRESS BY REV. LUTHER P. LUDDEN, 

LINCOLN, NEB. 

Mr. Chairman and Fellow-Workers in the Poultry Industry: 

I was not asked to prepare a paper, but to talk just a little 
while from my experience in the poultry industry in connection 
with the farmers' institutes. I presume because no individual 
in the state has had a larger experience with the 
farmers' institutes and the poultry industry than your </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
25 


speaker to-migkt. I was one of the committee that in the 
early nineties waited upon the state university authorities, 
who had charge of the farmers' institutes, and urged upon 
them the recognition of the poultry industry in the preparations 
of the programs for the institutes. We were received 
t- courteously and were talked to very nicely, but were 
"that the poultry industry was such a small business 
wny that it would hardly pay to j^ive it a plate on the 
itute program." That year we had not even an appeari 
at the farmers' institutes, but the Nebraska State Poul- 
Association was not to be outdone in this work, as they 
not in any other line of work. The next year we made a 
:wed application, and the Secretary found from the permce 
of the Association that he would have to say at least 
a "yes" to us, but that our program would have to be confined 
to some one of the evening meetings, and the first meeting 
he gave us to understand would come after 9 o'clock, and 
the address must be limited to twenty minutes. The Nebraska 
State Poultry Association turned the part of the address over 
to the speaker, and I made the journey and prepared to talk at 
I 'clock p.m. for twenty minutes upon "The Commercial 
ue of the Poultry Industry of the State of Nebraska." 
the time appointed on the program the chairman, in inlucinf,' 
the speaker, said, "We understand he is to talk 
y twenty minutes." It was the first poultry address to be 
given in connection with the farmers' institutes, and they 
fe afraid of it, and said we would be made a laughing 
k by the other states. I will never forget that first meetin 
Arcadia in the church, which was crowded to the doors, 
oke twenty minutes that night, because I timed my manupt 
until I knew I could say all of it in twenty minutes. At </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 


the end of that time the audience was not ready to jjo home. 
Kv a series of questionings they diacoawd the whole range of 
poultry work, and did not go home until near 11 o'clock. 
From that time, 1893, until this time the farmers' institutes 
have been recognizing the poultry industry. I have attended 
as high as fifty institutes in the winter to address the farmers 
upon the question of poultry raising in Nebraska. The 
question assigned to me to-night is 

rT IS THE EDUCATIONAL BENEFIT FROM POULTM DISCUSSION 
IN THE FAUMEKS' INSTITUTES?" 

The population of Nebraska in the past ten years has in 
creased very little, comparatively speaking, when we place 
the census of 1890 for the state with that of 1900, and yet 
after you have listened to the address of our President tonight, 
when he spoke of the large increase in the shipment 
of poultry within Nebraska, we find that the increase in the 
poultry industry has been far greater than the increase in 
our population. What has been the cause of it? 

(1) A live, active state poultry association that has put a 
spirit of enthusiasm in the poultry industry, that has led 
them to believe, and demonstrated to the world, that there is 
¦of any place in the United States where they can raise better 
chickens and better poultry than we can raise in Nebraska. 
Our mild winters, bright sunshine, unexcelled climate, our 
cheapness of grain, our nearness to the markets has increased 
the poultry industry in Nebraska. Yes, this has been 
one of the potential factors. 

K2) The second factor in the education of our people has 
a the farmers' institutes. One-half day and one evening 
r is given over to the poultry industry. Two earnest ad- </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
27 

NKRRASKA STATK Pun/TRY ASSOCIATION. 

dresses, two or more larefully prepared papers, until the 
[Hi)ple see thiit tlie poultry industry, instead of Mag small. 
is larger than many of our industries that have larger names 
and larger appropriations and a larger number of people engaged 
in them. It is the only industry in the state of Nebraska 
that does not have to bolster up its work. There is 
no imitation of the egg product, unless it is in the form of the 
dessicated or evaporated egg as it is now prepared for the 
&lt; old regions. When you come down to the new kind of food 
preparation in which the Belgian hare people are going t&lt;&gt; 
put up hare in that compressed form for us — they are the 
only people we have got to be afraid of in food imitations. 
It is said the Belgian hare will look like the finest white 
meat in imitation of our chicken. When you come to the 
chicken in the form in which we usually have them, there is 
no imitation of it. We don't have to petition the legislature 
or congress to grant us protection from food imitations. 

Phe farmers' institutes have been the second force that has 
eased the poultry profits in Nebraska. I will venture 
assertion that since the university authorities consented 
to the placing of the poultry industry on the farmers' insti- 
I programs we have more than doubled the number of 
kens; more than doubled our products of eggs in Neka. 
They go away from the farmers' institutes with the 
fever. They carry it out. As a result we see them comdown 
to our poultry shows. The first time, you know, 
go home with no premiums. Some of the best birds we 
; to-day in the show-room are from breeders who had 
s disqualified a year ago — splendid exhibition now. I 
I been greatly interested in the Nebraska State Poultry 
K-iation. We have taken the lead of all the states in the </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
28 


Union in holding poultry conventions. I don't know of an; 
state that holds an annual poultry ((invention. We take the 
lead in that. We were laughed at by other states eight o 
nine years ago; the idea of holding a poultry convention 
In spite of all that we have gone on with our convention year 
after year, and as a result of it the poultry men stand shoul 
der to shoulder, and we are producing a splendid financia 
object lesson for the state of Nebraska. There was a time 
when the poultry industry was like the colored boy. He 
wore his suspenders crossed in front and back, and the mas 
ter seeing him one day stopped him and said "You have go 
to stop that, you can not do that." The boy says: "I guess 
they are my suspenders ; I can do as I please." The master 
says : "When I look at you I can not tell whether you are 
coming or going." 

I remember in Nebraska when the poultry association was 
hard to tell whether it was coming or going. Go back fo 
1889, or a few years preceding that, when the association 
held its first meeting in Pawnee, and follow on the course 
and look at it to-day. Then it was one judge and a few birds 
now it is three judges and 1,400 birds. 

The farmers' institutes have been one of the means of 
crowding this work forward, until it is growing with tremen 
dous force; and I want to see it increase all over our state 
Nebraska is the home of the wild fowl. Our birds are jus 
a few generations removed from the wild fowl, and if the 
wild fowl could thrive in this state as in no other state in the 
Union, and all conditions connected with the bird industry 
obtain here, we ought to increase our poultry product. We 
ought to go forward in the next five years until chickens not 
by the carload, but they may have train loads. </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
29 


Earn a little fearful that with all the good we have acplished 
they are going to crowd us out again from the 
farmers' institute programs, l»e&lt;ause it has crowded out 
some of the other things that they wanted to talk about in 
the farmers' institutes. When they start the poultry discussion 
there are so many questions to be asked concerning the 
diseases, etc., that we always run over time. I believe the 
university has done splendid work in the work of the farmers' 
institutes along the line of diseases of poultry. What is 
the result? After we started in the farmers' institutes, 200, 
400, 600, were sent to the university to be analyzed and determine 
what was the matter with them and to receive in return 
free a prescription that would bring a cure to a whole 
flock. The farmers' institutes open the way of bringing the 
farmers and their poultry work in closer touch with the university. 
They began to send in their birds because it meant 
to save a flock of 50 or 100, and as a result of the farmers' institutes 
the farmers of Nebraska have been educated along 
this line, how they may preserve the lives of their chickens 
when disease sweeps in on them. I don't care whether they 
shut us out or not. We have simply to put our shoulders to 
the wheel and go back into the institute. This year they 
have not been putting out as many poultry addresses in the 
farmers' institutes, not because they could not get the speakers, 
but I presume because they thought other subjects more 
important. 

We have room for thousands of birds upon these prairies 
of ours, and our splendid sunshine and mild winters of ours, 
we ought to go on educating our people. 

tlook upon the farmers' institutes as one of the strongest 
ns within our power of reaching the farmers. Coming </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 


oat of these farmers' institute work will be the demand 
upon the university for the opening up at the experiment 
station work similar to that done in Khode Island, along the 
line of preparing poultry for market and the best results to 
be obtained therefrom. 

I am glad the subject was mentioned here to-night. I have 
l interested in seeing our university take some steps 
ig that line. For the past five years we have had one or 
lecturers. I have gone over and told them about our 
e as a poultry home. We want a regular course along 
line, a course that will teach them how they may tell a 
:erel from a pullet, and what a capron is, and especial 
;fits to be derived from caproniziug, not that they will 
2 to be bothered as our predecessors used to be. We want 
a educated along this line. We can not interest them too 
:h in these great industries, because the possibilities of it 
larger than the possibilities of the best cattle ranch we 
2 in Nebraska. 

I[ know how many thousands of dozens of eggs are carried 
t of this state every year ; how many thousands of pounds 
poultry, too. When you gather these statistics and look 
the 350,000,000 of ducks, chickens, and geese that go out 
o the great market centers of our world. Their average 
ce is 7 cents a pound. And more than 2,000,000,000 dozi 
of eggs, with an average of 6 cents a dozen to the farmer, 
I the great sum of money that that pours into the treasury 
jkets of the farmers, and think of the possibilities that it 
ans — the poultry cranks that they call us — we can afford 
to put our shoulders to the wheel. 

I want you, when you go back to your homes, if they are 
going to have a farmers' institute, to insist in that program </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
31 


the poultry industry shall be recognized as well as the 
swine and cattle, the alfalfa and clover, as well as the native 
grasses. Let us have our industries represented. Stand 
shoulder to shoulder. 

The time is coming when Nebraska will have all this down 
so that we may stand as Missouri, Rhode Island, and Connecticut 
stand, and tell just what this industry is doing for 
our state; not through the great express and railroad companies, 
but through our statistical departments in our state, 
with an accuracy that we can depend upon, and know the result 
that will come therefrom. (Great applause.) 

t Adjourned until Thursday evening for the annual meeting. 

Thursday Evening, January 17, 1901. 

ANNUAL MEETING 

OF THK ROCKHOLDEB8 OK THE NKRKASKA STATE l"OULTRY 

ASSOCIATION'. 

IPhe annual meeting of tin- stockholders was held this even; 
at the Commercial Club rooms, with President Lewelling 
the chair. 

The roll was called by the Secretary, and eighty shares of 
stock were represented and seventy-eight members present 

The minutes of the semi-annual meeting, September 6, 
1900, were read and approved. 

The committee on resolutions, through their chairman, 
L. P. Ludden, present the following report: 

Your committee on resolutions would report as follows: 

1. Resolved, That we extend to the Commercial Club of </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
32 


Lincoln our sincere thanks for the very courteous manner in 
which they have assisted in making this annual meeting and 
exhibition so great a success. Every pledge given by them 
has been fulfilled. They have not only kept their contract in 
providing the Auditorium for our annual exhibition, the 
stenographer, etc., but they have also very willingly tendered 
us the free use of their parlors for our business meetings 
and assisted materially in securing special rates on the 
railroads. 

II. Resolved, That we extend to the Wittmann Company our 
irty thanks for the splendid phonograph concert given in 
( exhibition rooms, thus adding greatly to the enjoyment 
visitors and exhibitors. 

I\. Rcsolrctl, That our thanks are due and are hereby exided 
to the railroad companies for the concessions made 
the way of reduced rates for the exhibitors. 

E. Resolved, That we thank the press for the many coures 
extended and the excellent reports given of our meetand 
the full reports of the exhibition. 

5. Rexolnd. That our officers be instructed to request the 
Commercial Club to assist next year in securing sj&gt;ecial rates 
for our exhibition. 

6. Resolved, That the Secretary be instructed to transmit 
a copy of these resolutions to the Commercial Club and the 
passenger departments of the several railroads. 

I Whereas, It is highly desirable that the Nebraska agri- 
Itural industry should be represented at the state capitol by 
i enterprising person, empowered officially to represent this 
industry and to use all possible means for the promoting of 
r various branches thereof, within the state, and properly 
represent this industry abroad by promptly publishing </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
33 


such information as the condition of the agricultural industries 
supplies, and 

('hebeas. The Nebraska state constitution forbids creatnew 
offices of government, such as secretary of agricul, 
who could best meet the duties above outlined, therebe 
it 

Resolved, That we favor the installing of an agent of the 
organized branches of agricultural industry in an office in 
»capitol building, with power to represent each society 
to do everything which may lawfully be done to promote 
.•ul tu nil industry in the state. 

Resolved, That the expenses of this work be borne by the 
tt contribution of all the state societies receiving aid from 
government and such voluntary contributions from the 
r societies and from individuals as may from time to 
: become available until the work is supported by the 


Respectfully submitted 

L. P. Ludden, 
David Larson, 

W. A. Irvin. 

The report was considered item by item, adopted, and the 
report then adopted as a whole. 

Hon. T. L. Norval, for the committee on revision of the 
constitution, presented the following: 

Mr. President and Members of Nebraska State Poultry 
Association: 

fur committee on revision report that they have carefully 
and considered the articles of incorporation and byof 
the Association, and have reached the conclusion 
the interests of the Association would be better sub- 

3 </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
34 


served by making the superintendent an officer elected by 
the Association, instead of being selected by the board of 
directors, as in the past; also by reducing the membership 
of the board from nine to five, thereby making it the easier 
to secure a quorum of the board for the transaction of 
business. 

IPo secure the objects stated, your committee recommend 
) That art. 9 of the Articles of Incorporation be amended 
read as follows: "Art. 9. The officers of this corporation 
ill consist of a President, Vice-President, Secretary, Treas&gt;r, 
and Superintendent, who shall constitute the board of 
ectors. The officers shall be elected by a majority vote, 
ballot, at the annual meeting of the stockholders, and 
til serve one year, or until their successors have been 
elected and qualified. Vacancies occurring in said offices by 
resignation, removal, or death of the incumbent shall be filled 
by the board of directors." 

K2) Your committee further recommend, in case of the 
ption of the proposed amendment to the articles of inporation, 
that art. 5 of the by-laws be amended to read 
as follows: "Art. 5. The board of directors will hold special 
meetings at the call of the president or of three (3) or more 
of its members. A quorum of the board of directors shall 
consist of three of its members. Said board shall control the 
affairs of the Association at all times except when the stockholders 
are in session, attend to all printing, give publicity, 
to secure suitable accommodations for all public exhibitions, 
appoint all judges; also provide suitable medals, diplomas, 
and such other awards as are advisable, and report its transactions 
at any meeting of the association." 

K3) Your committee further report and recommend that 
7 of the by-laws be amended to read thus : "Art. 7. The</seg> 


            <seg id="p035">
35 

semi-annual meeting of this Association shall be held on 
Thursday of the week of the State Fair, on the fair grounds." 

All of which is respectfully submitted. 

T. L. Norval, 

C. M. Lewelling, 

L. W. Gabouttb, 

Albert Lkmen, 

J. 8. Bishop. 

The report was considered item by item. 

Rr. Ludden moved, Mr. Lemen seconded, that item one be 
»ted. 

After a general discussion the committee asked permission 
to withdraw items one and two of the report. Objection 
being offered, the President ruled that the item of the report 
was still before the Association. 

er. Mickel moved, and Mr. Armstrong seconded, that 
s one and two be laid on the table. The motion was 
adopted. 

Item three. Mr. Ludden moved, and Mr. Garoutte seconded 
that item three be adopted as read. The motion was 
adopted. 

Mr. W. A. Armstrong offered the following, and moved 
its adoption : 

Resolved, That the President and Secretary of each local 
or district poultry association in the state be made members 
of this association ex-officio and have a vote on all questions 
coming before the Association. 

The motion was adopted. 

Mr. Ludden offered tb^e following: 

rat the President appoint a committee of three to confer 
the chancellor and board of regents of the state univer- 
</seg>
            <seg id="p036">
36 


sity to ascertain if it is not possible to establish a department 
of poultry industry at the experiment station similar 
to the work now inaugurated in Hhode Island and other 

The motion was adopted. 

ty informal ballot the Association then proceeded to the 
tion of officers for the ensuing year. 

The President appointed L. P. Ludden, L. W. Garoutte, 
and O. D. Talbert tellers. 

The informal ballot resulted as follows : L. P. Harris, 44 ; 
C. M. Lewelling, 33; scattering, 7. 

T. L. Norval moved that the informal ballot be declared 
formal. The motion was adopted. Thereupon the President 
declared that L. P. Harris, of Clay Center, was duly elected 
president for one year. 

tr. Gaiser moved, and Mr. Ludden seconded, that the rules 
uspended and that the secretary be instructed to cast 
84 ballots present for W. A. Irvin, of Tecumseh, foi 
president. 

The motion prevailed. 

The Secretary complied with the instruction, and the President 
declared Mr. W. A. Irving duly elected vice-president 
In a similar manner Mr. L. W. Garroutte, of Lincoln, was 
elected secretary, and Mr. E. O. Spencer, of Cortland, was 
duly elected secretary. 

Ehe following were nominated for the position of memof 
the board : Mrs. Blanchard, Lew Marshall, O. D. Tal, 
F. Patton, E. E. Greer, I. L. Lyman, T. L. Norval, L. P. 
den, Mr. Southwick. 

The ballot resulted in the election of the following : L. P. 
Ludden, Lincoln; O. D. Talbert, Omaha; T. L. Norval, </seg>


            <seg id="p037">
37 

Seward; Frank Patton, Surprise; E. E. Greer, Cambridge. 

fir. J. C. Seacrest, on behalf of the Commercial Club, exled 
an invitation to the Association to hold its next meetin 
this city, offering the free use of the Auditorium and 
same conditions as this year. 

By a unanimous vote the offer was accepted, and the show 
fixed for Lincoln, January, 1902. 

Mr. Lewelling offered the following, seconded by Mr. 
Lemen : 

Ehat a special committee be appointed to draft such measi 
as will be necessary to present to the legislature asking 
an increase in our appropriations, and, if deemed best, to 
Qge the general statute under which we are incorporated. 

The motion was adopted. 

Eudge T. L. Norval was made chairman of such special 
imittee, and he was given the right to call other memi 
to assist him in the work as the legislature progressed. 

A motion by Mr. Ludden that the Secretary be instructed 
to purchase the box borrowed for the use of the Secretary. 

The motion was adopted. 

The Association then adjourned. 

A. Lemex, 

SEMI-ANNUAL MEETING. 

Nebraska State Poultry Association held their semi-annual 
meeting on the fair grounds, September 6, 1900. 

Meeting called to order by the President, C. M. Lewelling. 

Elie following members responded to roll call : C. M. 
elling, A. Gaiser, Casper Dice, Wm. H. Chapman, J. T. 

Secretary. </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
38 

PROCEEDINGS OF THE 

r, I. L. Lynian, Avers &amp; Son, E. H. Eggert, A. P. Hollen- 
L. P. Harris, Ray Winslow, A. Lemen, T. L. Norval. 

Minutes of the board meetings January 19 and May 6 read 
and approved. 

Moved by L. P. Harris that all exhibitors furnish their 
own exhibition coops. Carried. 

tloved, that we offer $ 6, f 4, and f 2 premiums on pens, and 
f2, and f 1 prizes on singles. Carried. 

Moved, that we offer flO each in gold for four sweep- 
Ees prizes; flO for best pen, solid color with weight; |10 
best pen, solid color without weight; $10 for best pen, 
:i-color with weight ; f 10 for best pen, parti-color without 
;ht. Carried. 

Motion to adjourn. Carried. 

A. Lemen, 

Secretary. 

BOARD MEETINGS. 

Friend, Neb., January 19, 1900. 

The Board of the Nebraska State Poultry Association met 
in regular session, with President Lewelling in chair. 

Eie following were present: President Lewelling, Viceident 
Patton, Secretary Lemen, members E. E. Greer, 
i Skinner, Henry Smith, L. W. Garroutte, Casper Dice. 

It was moved that we employ as judges for the next show 
Messrs. Hitchcock, Itussell, and Harris. The motion 

A recess was then taken until 2 o'clock. 

Board met at 2 p.m., with the following present : Lewelling, 
Patton, Lemen, Dice, Smith, and Greer. </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
39 


Koved, that the entire Board be a special committee to rethe 
premium list for next winter show, and said comee 
meet at state fair Thursday 2 :00 p.m. Carried. . 

B[oved, that all applicants for superintendents of next 
ter show file their applications with the Secretary, 
ried. 

Moved, that the Secretary correspond with firms in regard 
to cooping the next winter show, including plans of coops, 
etc. Carried. 

Board adjourned. 

A. Lemkn, 

Secretary. 

BOARD MEETING HELD 

AT LIN DELL HOTEL. 

Lincoln, Neb., May 5, 1900. 

The following members were present : C. M. Lewelling, E. 
A. Pegler, Casper Dice, J. M. Armstrong, L. W. Garroutte, 
by proxy, held by H. C. Young; E. E. Greer, proxy, held by 
C. M. Lewelling. 

Moved that Secretary Lemen's bond be approved. Carried. 

Moved that Treasurer Spencer's Bond be approved. Carried. 
After which they took part in the meeting. 

Kovfed that the retiring secretary and treasurer's reports 
pproved and placed on file. Carried. 

Moved that the bill of Jacob North &amp; Co., for the printing 
&amp; proceedings of '99 convention, be allowed and warrant 
wn for same. Carried. 

Board adjourned. 

A. Lemex, 

Secretary. </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
40 


FINANCIAL STATEMENT 

Ok the Nebraska State Poultry Association from Janu 

KA STATE Poi'LTKY ASSIMIATI 

ary 18, 1900, to January 20, 1901. 

t 18, 1900, to January 20, 19" 
RECEIPTS. 

Received from former Treasurer, balance on hand.f 514 07 

reived from Secretary Lenien, entry fees and 
stock sold 47!&gt; »;. r &gt; 

Uweived from Secretary Lemen, door receipts .... 224 86 

Received per state warrant 1,000 00 

Received premium state warrant 9 25 

Total receipts |2.227 «2 

DISBURSEMENTS. 

State Journal Co, printing f 7 50 

L. P. Harris, judging :i5 00 

&lt; '. If. Lewelling, expenses on board 7 85 

\V. s. Russell, judging GO 00 

I". W. Hitchcock, judging 60 00 

( Super Dice, expenses on board .' 5 00 

( 'arl Andra, labor, annual show 7 50 

\Y. A. Irvin, labor, annual show 3 75 

l&gt;avid Larson, superintendent, annual show 9 00 

Theo. Larsen, labor, annual show 2 50 

Harry Gordin, labor, annual show 4 35 

E. S. Jennings, labor, annual show 5 00 

Frank Patton, labor, annual show 6 55 

J. S. Bishop, labor, annual show 4 00 

E. H. Wilkie, labor, annual show 8 75 

J. E. Megahan, labor, annual show 3 75 </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
41 


A. Lemen, secretary, stationery and supplies | 26 60 

A. Lemen, secretary, salary 50 00 

A. P. Hallenbeck, labor, at annual show 2 50 

L. P. Luddon, emtrj clerk and postage, etc 27 00 

L. W. Garroutte, expenses, member board 4 00 

E. O. Spencer, treasurer, salary and postage 28 00 

Jacob North &amp; Co., printing 38 80 

E. A. Pegler, straw, food, and supplies 15 55 

State Journal Co., advertising 59 00 

State Journal Co., printing and supplies 127 50 

H. A. Smith, labor, annual show 2 00 

Lincoln Sign Works, printing signs 5 00 

A. S. Godfrey, lumber 2 80 

A. Lemen, supplies 2 00 

A. B. Evans, premiums 3 00 

Anton Kopac, premiums 5 00 

M. M. Fox, premiums 9 00 

Jas. Craig, premiums 17 00 

E. B. Day, premiums 9 00 

G. B. Clary, premiums 10 00 

Orcutt &amp; Samuels 5 00 

H. C. Wittie, premiums 14 00 

E. H. Eggert, premiums 67 00 

Patton &amp; Steele, premiums 25 00 

J. S. Bishop, premiums 2 00 

Wallen Cameron, premiums 8 00 

Robert Black, premiums 28 00 

E. D. Van Court, premiums 8 00 

J. M. Armstrong, premiums 33 00 

Jennie Birdsell, premiums 15 00 

De Witt Yates, premiums 5 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
42 


Cottle Bros., premiums I ? 00 

1". Rademacher, premiums 10 00 

L. C. Huntington, premiums 11 00 

.1. &lt; \ Morford, premiums 11 00 

( '. M. Lewelling, premiums 7 00 

50 00 

&lt; 'asper Dice, premiums oO 00 
EL EL Cutpbell, premiums 2 00 

A. Hiatt, premiums 9 00 

Km C. A. Blanchard, premiums 11 00 

W. A. Kirkpatrick, premiums 8 00 

E. E. Smith, premiums 17 50 

E. M.*Crittenden, premiums 2 00 

Win. Miller, premiums 1 00 

I\ H. Brown, premiums 7 00 

E. E. Bowers, premiums 11 00 

W. A. Irvin, premiums 6 00 

1 &gt;avid Larson, premiums 29 00 

A. Gaiser, premiums 31 00 

L. P. Harris, premiums 59 00 

T. L. Norval, premiums 31 00 

E. S. Jennings, premiums 6 00 

A. Lemen, premiums 26 00 

L Marshall, premiums 7 00 

Kay Winslow, premiums 28 00 

D. W. Evans, premiums 4 00 

Wiu. Wilson, premiums 12 00 

A. P. Hallenbeck, premiums 8 00 

Ida Buehler, premiums 20 00 

Raymond Stryker, premiums 19 00 

E. H. Wilkie, premiums 2 00 

A. R. Carruth, premiums 12 50 </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
43 


Seth Abbott, premiums $ 15 00 

Geo. A. Hazlett, premiums 3 00 

Dr. I. C. Stephens, premiums 6 00 

Bert Overcash, premiums 2 00 

Aje &amp; McComb, premiums 1 00 

J. C. Kapper, premiums 8 00 

8. P. Knight, premiums 6 00 

W. J. East, premiums 6 00 

J. C. Nauman, premiums 6 00 

Geo. Galbraith, premiums 4 00 

C. A. Cook, premiums 22 00 

Sam. Gadd, premiums 7 00 

F. S. Slocum, premiums 8 00 

L. B. Arnot, premiums 4 00 

Sauerbier Bros., premiums 8 00 

Jno. A. Ling, premiums 13 00 

James A. Rudge, premiums 4 00 

D. Tipsword, premiums 8 00 

Hans Matthenson, premiums 4 00 

J. W. Gibson, premiums 1 00 

J. H. Oxman, premiums 2 00 

G. W. Hardin, premiums 1 00 

J. F. Uttecht, premiums 1 00 

Chas. B. Garrison, premiums ...... 6 00 

W. G. Hiltner, premiums 2 00 

R. Whitehead, premiums 3 00 

A. S. Godfrey, premiums 11 00 

W. H. Chapman, premiums 25 00 

H. J. Smith, premiums 3 00 

Ayers &amp; Sons, premiums 11 00 

G. A. Walker, premiums 4 00 </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
44 

KBR.VSK A ST ATt 1*0 L' I/TRY AchsOI I AT ION 

H. E. Stein, premiums $ 2 00 

M. M. Fox, premiums 10 00 

&lt; ' Kockhill, premiums 3 00 

J. A. Johnson, premiums 3 00 

EL A. Lamphre, premiums 5 00 

Dr. D. D. Potter, premiums 1 00 

H. C. Young, premiums 2 00 

Ithiel Payne, premiums 7 00 

Joseph Kay, premiums 11 00 

Emil Meduna, premiums 3 00 

J. Cook Johnson, premiums 2 00 

I. &amp; N. Connor, premiums 17 00 

•F. A. Johnson, premiums 3 00 

B. If. Coffin, premiums 2 00 

.1. North &amp; Co., printing 73 80 

Total disbursed |1,697 05 

Total receipts |2,227 62 

Total disbursed 1,697 05 

Balance on hand $ 530 57 </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
Articles of Incorporation. By-Laws, and Order of Business 

OF THK 

Nebraska State Poultry Association 

Incorporated September 26, 1892, 

Also a copy of the act of the Legislature granting aid to the Association, 
and legalizing the same as a State Institution. 

ARTICLES OF INCORPORATION. 

The State of Nebraska, ) 
Lancaster County. J 

Know all men by these presents, That we, C. M. Lewelling, 
Geo. W. Osterhout, John R. Megahan, Irving L. Lyman, J. 
k Armstrong, F. O. Yule, and Albert Lemen have associ-1 
ourselves together, and by these presents do associate 
selves together, for the purpose of forming and becoming 
&gt;rpo ration in the state of Nebraska, and do hereby adopt 
the following 

ARTICLES OP INCORPORATION* 

Article 1. The name of such incorporation shall be the 
Nebraska State Poultry Association. 

Art. 2. The principal place of transacting its business 
shall be in the city of Lincoln, county of Lancaster, state of 
Nebraska. 

Art. 3. The nature of the business to be transacted by said </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
46 


corporation shall be the encouragement of the interests and 
promotion of improvements in the breeding and management 
of poultry, by means of exhibitions, and the collection and 
dissemination of reliable and practical information relative 
to the utility breeds of poultry. 

Art. 4. The amount of capital stock, authorized, of said 
association shall be two thousand (2,000) dollars, which shall 
be divided into four hundred (400) shares of five (5) dollars 
each. Fifty per cent of each share of stock shall be paid in 
cash at the time of issuing a certificate for the same, and 
the fifty per cent remaining unpaid shall be due at the call of 
the board of directors, at any time after six months from date 
of certificate. 

Ekt. "&gt;. Each share of stock shall entitle the owner thereof 
ne vote at all the meetings of the stockholders, but not 
e than ten shares of stock shall be owned by any one 

{Lbt. C. The shares of any stockholder who shall neglect 
refuse to pay into the treasury of this association such 
tallments or sums of money due thereon as may be called 
by the board of directors as herein provided, within thirty 
•s after notice of such call, shall, if the board of directors 
iirect, be declared forfeited, and the same shall thereupon 
forfeited to the association. 

En. 7. The existence of this corporation shall commence 
ember 26, 1892, and continue twenty (20) years from 
date, unless sooner dissolved, or continued in accordance 
law. 

Art. 8. The amount of liability or indebtedness to which 
this corporation is at any time to subject itself is hereby limited 
to fifty (50) per cent of its paid up capital stock. </seg>


            <seg id="p047">
47 

Art. 9. The officers of this corporation shall consist of a 
President, Viee-President, Secretary, Treasurer, and Board 
of Directors. The Board of Directors shall consist of nine 
(9) members of the association, to-wit: the President, Vice- 
President, Secretary, Treasurer, and five (5) others. The 
officers shall be elected by a majority vote, by ballot at the 
tual meeting of the stockholders, and shall serve one year, 
ntil their successors have been elected and qualified. Varies 
in office occurring during the term, by resignation, 
oval, or death of any of the above-mentioned officers, shall 
illed by the Board of Directors. Until a regular election 
dicers the respective officers shall be as follows, to-wit : 
sident, C. M. Lewelling; Vice-President, Geo. W. Osterhout; 
Secretary, John B. Megahaa; Treasurer, Win. A. Armstrong; 
Board of Directors, C. M. Lewelling, Geo. W. Osterhout, 
John R. Megahan, Win. A. Armstrong, E. C. Blowers, 
s. S. Borton, I. L. Lyman, H. R. C. Montgomery, and W. C. 
Brown. 

Kit. 10. The business of this corporation shall be coned 
in accordance with the by-laws adopted by the cortion. 


In testimonv whereof, we have hereunto set our hands, 

this 25th day of October, A. D 

1892. 

('. If. Lkwklling 

Geo. W. Osteehout, 
John R. Megahan, 
Irving L. Lyman, 
J. M. Armstrong, 
F. G. Yule, 

Albert Lemen, 

In presence of 

L. Meyer. </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
48 


Thk State of Nebraska. 

Lancaster County. 

On this 25th day of October, A. D. 1892, before me, a 
notary public in and for said county, personally came C. M. 
Lewelling, Geo. W. Osterhout, John R. Megahan, Irving L. 
Lyinan, J. M. Armstrong, F. G. Yule, Albert Lemen, personally 
to me known to be the identical persons whose names 
are affixed to the above instrument as their act and deed, and 
they acknowledged the execution as their free will and deed. 

Witness my hand and notarial seal at my office the day 
and year above written. 

[seau] L. Meyer, 

Notary Public. 

State of Nebraska, 

Secretary's Office. 

Eseeived and filed for record this l. r &gt;ih day of November, 
'. 1892, and recorded in book "L," Miscellaneous Incortions, 
at page 455. 

John C. Allen, 

Secretary of State. 

BYLAWS. 

[Adopted by the Board of Directors, February 21, 1893.] 

DUTIES OF OFFICERS. 

Article 1. The President shall preside at all meetings, 
sign all warrants upon the treasury, cast the deciding vote 
in case of a tie, call extra meetings of the Board of Directors 
when requested in writing by five (5) or more members of 
the association, and shall exercise the usual functions of the 
presiding officer of a deliberative body. 

ss. </seg>

            <seg id="p049">

49 

Ert. 2. The Vice-President shall perform all duties inci; 
to the office of President in the absence of the regular 
iding officer. 

Art. 3. The Secretary shall conduct the general correspondence 
of the association, and have custody of the same, 
shall preserve all important letters received and a copy of 
the answer thereto, to be read at the meeting of the association, 
if requested, and keep the minutes of the Board of 
Directors; keep an account of all the expenses incurred by 
the correspondence. He shall keep the minutes of the meetings 
of the stockholders of the association, and have charge 
of all the books and papers appertaining to his office. He 
shall also issue certificates of stock in the association, and 
shall have his books and papers open at all times for inspection 
of the Board of Directors, and shall receive for all such 
services the sum of fifty (Si I dollars per annum ; and give a 
bond in the sum of one thousand (1,000) dollars, to be approved 
by the Board. 

Err. 4. The Treasurer shall have charge of all funds lx'ing 
to the assiM-iation and pay all hills per order of the 
ident, countersigned by the Secretary, as long as the 
association funds hold in hand. He shall keep his account* 
in proper form for the inspection of the Board of Directors 
and shall give a bond to the President in the sum of two 
thousand (2,000) dollars, to be approved by the Board of 
Directors. He shall also make a report at the annual meeting 
of all the receipts and expenditures for the current year, 
and shall collect all moneys and assets due the association, 
keeping a correct account thereof, and shall receive for all 
services a salary of twenty-five dollars per annum. 

Abt. 5. The Board of Directors will hold special meetings 

4 </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
50 


at the call of five (5) or more of its members, five (5) of 
whom shall constitute a quorum. It shall control the affairs 
of the association at all times except when the stockholders 
are in session, attend to all printing, giving publicity to and 
secure suitable accommodation for all public exhibitions, appoint 
all judges ; also provide suitable medals, diplomas, and 
such other awards as are advisable, and report its transactions 
at any meeting of the association. 

ANNUAL EXHIBIT. 

Akt. 6. The annual exhibit of the association shall be hel&lt; 
in January of each year, beginning with the third Tuesday 
on which day the annual meeting of the stockholders shal 
begin and continue in convention until the business of the 
association shall be concluded. The annual election o 
officers shall be held on Thursday evening of the same week 
beginning at 8 o'clock p.m., and said officers shall assume 
their respective duties on Friday next succeeding the annua 
meeting, when the Board of Directors shall meet, and al 
reports be audited, and accounts settled. All officers of thi 
association shall hold their respective offices for one (1) yea 
and until their successors are elected and inducted into 
office. 

SEMI-ANNUAL MEETING. 

Art. 7. The semi-annual meeting of this association shall 
be held on Thursday of the week of the State Fair, on the 
fair grounds. 

HOW AMENDED. 

Art. 8. These by-laws may be amended by a majority vote 
of the stockholders when in regular convention.</seg> 


            <seg id="p051">
51 

BOARD OF MANAGERS. 

Aht. 9. The Board of Directors shall also be the Board of 
Managers. 

ORDER OF BUSINESS. 

Abt. 10. Order of Business. — First, call to order; second, 
roll call; third, reading minutes of previous meeting; fourth, 
unfinished business; fifth, reports of officers; sixth, report* 
t special and other committees; seventh, communications 
d correspondence; eighth, new business; ninth, miscellaneous 
business; tenth, election of officers; eleventh, adjournment 


THE LEGISLATIVE ACT LEGALIZING THE NEBRASKA 
STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION. 

HOUSE ROLL NO. 388. 

rill for an act legalizing the Nebraska State Poultry Association; 
to define certain duties of said association; to 
make an annual appropriation therefor, and fixing a 
penalty for the misappropriation of any of the money 
hereby granted. 

[Introduced by Mr. Casper, of Butler.] 

Be it enacted by the Legislature of tlte State of Nebraska: 
Section 1. That the regularly organized and incorporated 

f'ety known as the Nebraska State Poultry Association, 
ise articles of incorporation are recorded in the office of 
secretary of state, be and the same is hereby legalized as 
ate institution. 

Sec. 2. The Nebraska State Poultry Association shall hold </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
52 


I invention annually, on the third Tuesday in January, at 
i place in the state as the board of managers may select, 
the purpose of gathering statistics and diffusing practiknowledge 
on subjects pertaining to the poultry interests 
be state, by addresses, piyn, discussions, and such other 
ns as the board of managers may direct. 

I ec. 3. The Secretary of said association shall preserve all 
ere read, and take a stenographic rei&gt;ort of all addresses 
discussions at said annual convention, and shall make a 
jrt of the same to the governor, together with a full re 
t of all business transacted, including an itemized stateit 
of all expenditures of money, and shall publish in 
iphlet form not less than two thousand copies of said ret, 
which shall be distributed according to the laws governing 
the distribution of the reports of the State Board of 
Agriculture. 

[ec. 4. The sum of $1,000 is hereby annually appropriated 
of any moneys in the state treasury not otherwise apjriated, 
for the use and benefit of said association, and 
state auditor is hereby authorized to draw his warrant 
the same upon presentation of proper vouchers therefor 
ified to by the President and Secretary of said association, 
said amount to be used only for defraying the expenses 
incurred in holding conventions, and in publishing and distributing 
reports and such other purposes as in the discretion 
of the board of managers shall l&gt;est subserve the poultry 
interests of the state. 

Sec. 5. If any officer or member of said association shall 
convert any of the moneys hereby appropriated to his own 
use, or suffer the same to be lost or expended in any other 
way or manner or for any other purpose than is designated </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
53 


by law, such officer or member shall be deemed guilty of em- 

bezzlement, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished 

by imprisonment in the penitentiary not less than one nor 

more than three years. 

LIST OF MEMBERSHIP. 

No. - SHA«ES 

1. Geo. W. Osterhout, David City 2 

•&gt; 

C. M. Lewelling, Beaver City 1 

•&gt; 

3. Albert Leinen, Lincoln 1 

4. Warren L. Mitchell, Table Rock 1 

5. W. B. McDermott, Omaha 2 

•&gt; 

6. I. L. Lyman, Lincoln 1 

K. Whithead, Lincoln 1 

i. 

9. J. G. Woolsey, Elk Creek 1 

10. R. R. Ellinwood, University Place 1 

11. Raymond Stryker, Lincoln 1 

12. H. C. Young, Lincoln 1 

13. O. C. Smith, Lincoln 1 

14. E. C. Blowers, Edgar 1 

l&amp; J. D. Brubaker, Sidney 1 

16. J. A. Howard, Edgar 1 

17. C. C. Branson, Lexington 

&gt;/ 

18. S. G. Palmer, Tobias 1 

19. H. J. Smith, Lincoln 1 

20. E. S. Jennings, Lincoln 1 

21. S. S. Borton, Beatrice 1 

23. L. P. Harris, Palmyra 1 

24. C. M. Lewelling, Beaver City 1 

•_'."&gt;. W. G. Gooden, Friend 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
54 


26. H. C. McArthur, Colorado Springs, Colo 1 

27. S. J. and H. Carpenter, Waverly 1 

28. Casper Dice, Boca 1 

29. James Heaton, Lincoln 1 

30. J. M. Armstrong, Greenwood 1 

31. H. R. C. Montgomery, Omaha 1 

32. Wm. A. Armstrong, Greenwood* 1 

33. Ira A. Draper, Dawson 1 

35. E. P. Mickel, Lincoln 1 

36. T. E. Wheeler, Bennett 1 

37. F. B. Donisthorpe, Geneva 1 

38. M. M. Aaron, Roca 1 

39. H. S. Thomas, Omaha 1 

40. L. P. Ludden, Lincoln 1 

41. G. A. Ashmun, Louisville 1 

42. P. T. Dean, Omaha 1 

43. E. C. Worden, Auburn 1 

44. J. F. Siems, Columbus 1 

45. H. M. Walker, Leigh 1 

47. Edwin Post, Havelock 1 

48. Joe C. Gerspacher, Grand Island 1 

49. Jacob Severns, Unadilla 1 

50. W. H. Chapman, Saltillo 1 

51. J. W. Deary, Bloomington 1 

52. Julius Boeck, Boulder, Colo 1 

53. E. C. Hills, Lincoln 1 

54. A. F. Coon, David City 1 

56. Mrs. Anna M. Bunting, David City 1 

57. A. S. Potter, Kearney 1 

58. E. H. Eggart, Minden I 

59. Mrs. Minnie Chandler, Kearney 1 </seg>


            <seg id="p055">
55 

60. W. A. Irvin, Tecuinseh 1 

61. Mrs. H. M. Crane, Blooniiugton 1 

62. S. Rhodes, Ulysses 1 

63. J. S. Bishop, Ul vsses 1 

64. O. P. Dovel, Auburn 1 

66. Wm. H. Harrison, Alda 1 

67. 0. H. Kent, Auburn 1 

68. A. 8. Brubaker, Lexington 1 

69. Wm. J. Palmer, McCook 1 

70. A. t&gt;. &lt;iodfrej, Lincoln 

1 

71. C. W. Jester, Deweese 1 

-¦&gt; 

A. Gaiser, Tecumseh 1 

i_. 

73. A. N. 1 )pfoe, Tecumseh 1 

74. W. H. Havens &amp; Son, Fremont 1 

75. E. O. BiK'mer, Cortland 1 

76. Nellie Hawks, Friend 1 

79. Wm. Wilson, Normal 1 

80. A. Cruikshank, Dorchester 1 

81. W. F. Cadogan, Omaha 1 

82. Chas. A. Cook, Salem 1 

83. A. W. Saultzbaugh, Auburn 1 # 

84. Wm. M. Clark, Lincoln 1 

85. Abbott Bros., Saltillo 1 

87. Geo. H. Lee, Exeter 1 

88. Jennie K. Warner, Lincoln 1 

89. Mrs. Nancy Watson, Lincoln 1 

90. W. E. Mickel, Lincoln 1 

91. W. H. Gardner, University Place 1 

92. E. A. Pegler, Lincoln 1 

93. E. W. Martin, Fremont 1 

94. H. E. Lemmon, Falls City 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
56 


96. &lt;iti&gt;. O. Monroe, Omaha 

1 

97. Thos. II. Wade, Rising City 1 

97. Thos. II. Wade, Rising City 1 

99. W. A. faggot, Lincoln 1 

99. W. A. Taggert, Lincoln 1 

100. &lt; ii&gt;o. A. Goodwin, Avery '. 1 

100. &lt;ieo. A. Goodwin, Avery '. 1 

101. W. J. Scott, Omaha . '. 1 

101. W. J. Scott, Omaha 1 

104. A. Soronson, Omaha 1 

104. A. Sorensou, Omaha 1 

1W&gt;. Magrane &amp; &lt; 'o., ( &gt;maha 1 

107. Bonthwick &amp; Barclay, Friend 1 

10v John Skinner, Spiker 1 

109. F. \V. fTrrpolshximcr, Denton 1 

110. Frank C. Richards, Lincoln 1 

111. (J. W. Randall, Newman Grove 1 

113. .Mrs. Eleanor Odbert, Lincoln 1 

114. J. \V. Sealn-ook, University Place 1 

115. F. W. Hudson, Saltillo 1 

ll*i. J. II. Swisher, Salem, Va 1 

118. F. F. Goodaon, Omaha 1 

119. Major J. T. Croft, Omaha 1 

120. Fred E. Mm-kett, Lincoln 1 

121. O. E. (Jaines, Elk City 1 

122. Geo. Van Houten. Auburn 1 

124. J. I). Currie, Lincoln 1 

125. L. W. and Scott ( Jarrouttc, Lincoln 1 

12(t. E. A. Vanderli]), Bennett 1 

127. L. L. Fisher, Genera 1 

1 M. Lew W. Mai-shall, Lincoln 1 

129. C. O. Harvey, Lincoln 1 

130. G. RiehardH, Omaha 1 

131. W. H. Bushell, David City 1 

132. D. K. Leard, Shelby 1 

133. A. S. Campbell, McCook " 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
57 


134. C. A. Chapin, Ulysses 1 

135. F. L. Esmay, Fremont 1 

136. E. H. Linn, Beatrice 1 

137. R. L. Newton, Bennett 1 

138. Frank Patton, Surprise 1 

139. Thos. K. ( )tis, Humphrey 1 

1 41) A. M. Heudee, Table Kock 1 

141. Aym &amp; Son, ( Jeneva 1 

1 4L\ C. B. Eckardt, Lincoln 1 

1 43. A. Upton, Tobias 1 

144. I. Payne, Lincoln 1 

1 4."». M. M. Fox, Geneva 1 

146. J. G. Foster, Hoskins 1 

147. Gallatin Ritter, Baltillo 1 

148. Sam Gadd, Lincoln 1 

149. H. H. Haines, Omaha 1 

LOO. Gould &amp; Richardson, Lincoln 1 

151. David Larson, Walioo 1 

152. Dr. Clyde Davis, Lincoln 1 

153. Wm. Foster, Saltillo 1 

154. Chas. Ross, Omaha 1 

IK 0. E. Boggs, Lincoln 1 

156. 0. D. Talbert, Omaha 1 

157. Aug. Seover, Edgar 1 

158. Dr. O. C. Link, Lincoln 1 

159. J. W. Ferguson, Lincoln 1 

160. D. D. Adams, Johnson 1 

161. M. H. Drollinger, Kenesaw 1 

162. J. G. Cordner, Lincoln 1 

163. H. J. F. Wert, Auburn 1 

164. H. J. Pegler, Palmyra 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
58 

PROOKKPIN liS Or THE 

MS. J. A. Alley, University Place 1 

1 •&gt;•&gt;. Ray Winslow, Lincoln 

1 

167. W. S. Hillis, Omaha 1 

1 ML James Glasgow, Cozad 1 

!«&gt;!». J. B. Brainerd &amp; Co., Olar Bluffs 1 

170. J. A. Wheeler, Bennett 1 

171. Daniel Allen, Fremont 1 

172. A. C. Killian, Wahoo 1 

173. J. B. Campbell, Hastings 1 

174. F. T. Wieuban, Madison 1 

175. Louis Jacobs, Wilbur 1 

176. Jno. A. Ling, Harvard 1 

177. D. H. Goodrich, Geneva 1 

178. Robt. Black, Raymond 1 

179. Mrs. A. B. Lathrop, Omaha 1 

180. John M. Landan, Jr., Walioo 1 

181. Dr. J. S. McCleary, Beatrice 1 

182. W. A. Melson, Lincoln 1 

184. O. B. Fraser, North Bend 1 

185. W. L. Sprague, Wood BItct 1 

186. P. R. Longfellow, Walioo 1 

187. Cherney &amp; Kavan, North Bend 1 

188. J. C. Blackburn, Craig 1 

189. A. Grant Musson, Ashland 1 

190. C. H. Roberts, Holdre-re 1 

191. W. B. Fuerst, Battle Creek . 1 

192. O. M. Tharp, Wahoo 1 

193. C. K. Olson, Omaha 1 

194. W. H. Powers, Clay Center 1 

195. J. C. Kapser, Clay Center 1 

196. J. J. Brown, Normal 1 </seg>


            <seg id="p059">
59 

197. Walter F. Saville, Saleui 1 

198. Geo. B. Galbraith, Janscn 1 

199. G. P. Whitham, Raymond 1 

200. Frank Scott, Surprise 1 

201. E. Brien, Jansen 1 

L'(I2. L. C. Huntington, Omaha 1 

203. Wm. Miller, North Bend 1 

204. H. C. Witte, Lincoln 1 

205. Ray Winslow, Lincoln 1 

206. M. D. King, Minden 1 

207. Geo. P. Meese, Ithaca 1 

208. A. P. Hollenbeck, Lincoln 1 

209. Jennie Birdsall, Greenwood 1 

210. Amos Vogt, Holdrege 1 

211. Jas. Kay, David City 1 

212. C. Rockhill, Harvard 1 

213. J. W. Holstein, Spiker 1 

214. A. R. Carruth, Lincoln 1 

215. T. L. Norval, Seward 1 

216. C. F. Hinman, Friend 1 

217. C. M. Sanders, Friend .1 

218. J. C. Morford, Beaver Crossing 1 

219. D. Tipsword, Beaver Crossing 1 

220. G. M. Whitford, Arlington 1 

221. C. A. Blanchard, Friend 1 

222. G. B. Clary, Fairbury 1 

223. A. B. Evans, Heartwell 1 

224. J. E. Athey, Fairfield 1 

225. W. S. Morlan, McCook 1 

226. E. E. Greer, Cambridge 1 

227. Kimball Bros., Beatrice 1 

ZZ\</seg> 

            <seg id="p060">
60 

I'K&lt;H'KKl)lN(iS OF THE 

228. E. M. Cottin, Lincoln 1 

I'LMi. E. B. Bowers, York 1 

230. if. \V. Lamphere, Seward 1 

231. E. B. Day, North Hend 1 

232. Anton Kopac, Wells 1 

233. Ida J. Buehler, Kenesaw 1 

234. D. W. Evans, University Place 1 

235. P. W. Brown, Lincoln 1 

236. W. H. Lake, Hampton 1 

237. E. E. Smith, Lincoln 1 

Alice Hiatt, Bennett 1 

239. V. A. Benway, Fairmont 1 

240. J. Cook Johnson, Omaha 1 

241. I. &amp; M. N. Connor. Ponca 1 

242. II. B. Stein. Friend 1 

243. 1 )r. 1 ). 1 ). Potter, Seward 1 

244. E. X. &lt; 'ritlenden. Lincoln 1 

24o. Emil Medium. Wahoo 1 

246. I. C. Stephens, Milford 1 

247. Hans .Matherson, Scribner 1 

M&amp; J. W. Hall, David City 1 

24!». E. D. Van Court, Nehawka 1 

2."&gt;o. Wallen Cameron, Sclmyler 1 

251. Stephen Norton, Davey 1 

1 

U.-&gt;2. Ttcater Supply &lt; '&lt;»., Lincoln 

2r&gt;3. Gottle Bros., Bdgar 1 

2."&gt;. Carl Andra 1 

¦ft P. E. Brown, Syracuse 1 

257. Mrs. J. E. Orcutt, Lincoln 1 

258. Peter Jaeoby, Atirora 1 

2.V.». E. II. \\ ilke, Lincoln 1 </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
61 

NEBRASKA STATE POULTKV ASSOCIATION. 

260. Geo. H. Dunham 1 

261. James Craig, Wahoo 1 

MS. J. 0. Starrest, Lincoln 1 

263. Mrs. Henry Shrader, Berlin 1 

264. O. A. Walker, Fairmont 1 

266. 0. E. Genoways, Aurora 1 

267. S. W. Postle, Aurora 1 

268. J. A. Johnson, Holdrege 1 

269. T. J. Cummins, Howe 1 

270. Nebraska Farmer, Omaha 1 

271. M. M. Johnson, Clay Center 1 
</seg>
         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>