<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0075.0001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1, 1932</title>
               <date value="1932-02-01">1932-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">PUBLIC DOCUMENTS OF NEBRASKA 1931-1932 VOLUME 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY 857571 A ASTOR, LENOX AND TIXDEN FOUNDATIONS Ft 193Q L </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS VOLUME 5 J. Agricultural Experiment Station, Annual Reports, 1931, 1932. a. Bulletins, Nos. 247-272. b. Research Bulletins, Nos. 49-61. c. Circulars, Nos. 40-43. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA FORTY-FIFTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF . . NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1, 1932 . LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL ■ •■■. ■ ■■■.....-_ ■ ■ . . ■ ■ ■ . - ■ The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly^ Ihe State of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing tolrS^T^f^T' * have the honor herewith to subnut the Forty-fifth Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. February 1, 1932. . . W^'SS-eftor. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Mr. W. W. Burr, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station: ■ ■ • . • . Sir: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Forty-fifth An - nual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. T . . L . Charles W. Bryan, Lincoln, February 1, 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA ••■'•"•; THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Stanley p. Long, Cowles, President Term expires January, 1933 Frank J. Taylor, St. Paul , Term expires January, 1933 Fred A. Marsh; Archer Term expires January, 1935 Marion A. Shaw, David City.... Term expires January, 1935 Earl Clinb, Lincoln ...Term expires January, 1937 Arthur C. Stokes, Omaha Term expires January, 1937 E. A. Burnett, D.Sc, Chancellor L. E. Gunderson, 1 Finance Secretary : • . THE STATION OFFICERS W. W. Burr, B.Sc., Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk I . THE WORKING STAFF _ C W. Ackerson, Ph.D., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry M A. Alexander, M.Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry Arthur Anderson, MiSc, Assistant in Agronomy M J. Blish, Ph.D., Agricultural Chemwtry (Chairman) , E E Brackett, B.Sc. in E.E., Agricultural Engineering (Chairman) e! M. Brouse, B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Substation, Valentine W. W. BURR, B.Sc, Agronomy (Chairman) M Ruth Clark, s Ph.D., Associate in Home hconomics H. P. Davis, M.Sc, Dairy Husbandry (Chairman) ; P. A. DOWNS, Ph.D., Associate in Dairy Husbandry. _ H* C. Filley, A.M., Rural Economics (Chairman) A. L. Frolik, M.Sc, Assistant in Agronomy • R. \Y. Goss, Ph.D., Associate in Plant Pathology H J. Gramlich, B.Sc, Animal Husbandry (Chairman) " I L HATHAWAY, M.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry HAROLD HEDGES, A.M., Assistant in Rural Economics J. A. Holden, 3 B.Sc, Supt. Experimental Station, Mitchell _? Nelson E. Jodon, 4 B.Sc, Research Assistant tn Agronomy, North Platte F. D. Keim, Ph.D., Agronomy (Associate Chairman) T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph.D., Agronomy ; &#132;'.„. • E B Lewis B.Sc. in A.E., Assistant in Agricultural Engvneenng W. J. LOEFFEL, M.SC, Assistant in Animal Husbandry W. E. Lyness, B.Sc. in Agr., Assistant in Agronomy ; C B McGrath, D.V.M., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene R F. Morgan, M.Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry F E Mussehl, B.Sc, Poultry Husbandry (Chairman) J F Olney, D.V.M., M.S., Assistant in Animal Pathology G L Peltier, Ph.D., Plant Pathology (Chairman). ■ Jo'hn F. PospisiL, Supt. Box Butte Experiment Farm, Alliance J. C. RUSSEL, M.Sc, Associate in Agronomy Rudolph Sandstedt, M.Sc, Analyst II Edna B. Snyder, M.Sc, Assistant in Home Economics L. B. Snyder, M.S., Assistant in Rural Economics ■ W P. Snyder, M.S.. Supt. Experimental Substqtwn, North Platte Coit-A. Suneson, 4 M.Sc., Research Assistant in Agronomy i Ry an act of the Lejrislature of the State of Nebraska, approved and in effect February 15. 1899, the State Treasurer became ex-offido custodian of the Experi - ment Station fund on and after July 1. 1899. ' Absent on leave, one-half year. . .'»,,. •Detailed from the Office of. Western Irrigation Ajtriculture. « Detailed from Office of Cereal Crops and Diseases. United States Department of Agriculture. Washington. D. C. ■ ■■■■ ■: .■ ■■■ ,■■.. ■t </seg>
            <seg id="p008">R." R ' T%I?JIJ L -%-l ! Eru! ? molo0 » (Chairman) t vi'»r v vPs Ass^tant in. Plant Pathology H E^s£ «'m &amp; A A^i r? 1 ? I *™ ™* HypZne (Chairman) M D W^ST -Mi 'a AB P? tant . Agronomist, North Platte h" n wS^' m"o C *' Assistant tn Agronomy Dov'r A * 8 °™*e in- Horticulture C r N i^rr C -r/ B^ ta7tt in Entomology W%r v^* 8 ' ?\P- Pomiculture (Chairman) T^'t vIPTiJ t M -\ Assista »t Horticulture L.. L. ZOOK, 0 B.Sc, Agronomist, North Platte .;'■-•■ CONTENTS Letter of Transmittal „ __ 2 Governor's Certificate _ Official Roster of the Station _ o Contents ...,., Introduction _ Investigational Work.. ....„ Agricultural Engineering: "'" Nebraska Tractor Tests ;...... . . • 7 Combine Harvester Study. "'" v I A Study of Wind^driven ElectricPiants"fbr"Farm"Use".!.' 8 ±*ump Irrigation ' S A Study of the Use of Electric Pff^'m'W^b^SSi'v^^Z'.ZZ 8 an/l^Li he r^ ar V &gt;US eth ° ds ° f Co °^e Milk on the Farm and ! Their Effect on Quality ■ 9 Animal Diseases: . '...-'•■ A Study of the Pathogenicity as well as Antigenic and Biologic An Morbfdit int ° tHe In * luence °* Environmenr'upon"Pouitry" Laboratory Diagnosis and Examination'of ' Specitjien's..'.'.".".'.".".".'.'.";! li Dairy Husbandry: A. Study of the Principles of Ice Cream Making........: 11 n»,w « Fat / ol £ b ! e . A " a ? Pr f? ent in the M " k of the Four" ' i? t Dair Y J"? ds&gt; Holstem, Ayrshire, Jersey and Guernsey 12 F - act °™ i^S* J he Quality of Fluid Milk as Show " by the a aifj* T ! S^! Sedlment Tes t. and Bacteria Count 13 A Study of Growth in Dairy Cattle. ]% Methods of Practical Control and Economic Effect "of Coti - tagious Abortion upon a Dairy Herd...... 14 The Vitamin Content of Field-cured and Artificially Cured" Hay 14 Field Crops and Soils: ■ ..• ■ A Study of the Principles of Corn Improvement through In - breeding and Hybridization.... &#132; 14 Variety Testing, Breeding, Acclimatisation, arid Cu'ltur'af""""" Studies m Small Grains • 1 K Forage Crop Investigations ".""'^"'"^Z^""" 16 A B 'ric e »Uu™. W. r iw n « C o e nr f D F C Ile ' e Cr ° PS *"* Di " aBe8 ' United SUteß Department of A^ D c e u^, W^hlS. °D f . C Ol7 LaD&lt;i Un "^ State. Department of </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Determination of the Relation of. the Characteristics, Com - mercial Grade, and Market Value of Alfalfa Hay to Cur - • ' ing, 'Stacking, and Baling Practices 17 '. - Crop Rotation and Fertilizer Experiments 18 . The Relation of Weather, Cultural Practices, and Soil Con - - ■ . ditions to Nitrification in Nebraska Soils 18 A Study of the Factors Which Affect the Tilth of Soils 19 A Study of the Restoration of Organic Matters in Soils 19 . Co-operative Fertilizer Experiments... 19 Fruits and Vegetables: Pruning Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits 20 Fruit Breeding Experiments ;.. 20 Orchard . Culture, Union Fruit Farm. 20 I. ' Vegetable Experimentation— Variety Trials and Cultural Tests.. 20 ■ Fruit Stock Investigations 21 • . . Orchard Spraying for the Codling Moth : 21 Home Economics: Cash Contribution of Farm Hqmemakers to the Family Income through Dairy and Poultry Products 22 Washing Machine Study 22 A Study of Electric Cooking Stoves 23 The Relation of Draft to Performance of Kerosene Burners on Kerosene Cook Stoves i 23 A Study of the Family History and Standards of Living of Farm Families in Selected Districts of Nebraska 23 • Insect Control: Investigation and Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds „ 24 Grasshopper Control 24 ; ■ The Life History and Control of Potato Flea-Beetles in Western Nebraska ~ 24 A Brood Study of the Codling Moth in Southeastern Nebraska.... 24 A Study of the Distribution,' Life History, and Means of Con - trol of the Cutworms Attacking Corn in Nebraska .* 24 Livestock Feeding : • Fattening Cattle 24 Forage Crops for H0g5...... .' ;... 26 Rations for Fattening Hogs „ 27 • Dairy By-products for Fattening Hogs... 27 Hard vs. Soft Endosperm Corn as Pig Feed.. 27 Lamb Feeding. 28 Factors Affecting the Quality and Palatability of Meat 28 Milling and Baking: • ■ Preparation and Study of the Cereal Glutelins.. 29 Standardization of Methods in Experimental Baking Procedure.. 30 Plant Diseases : A Study of Spindle Tuber and Combinations .of Spindle Tuber with Other Degeneration Diseases ; 31 An Inquiry into the Pathological and Physiological Aspects of Alfalfa Failures in Nebraska 31 A Study of Potato Scab and Fusarium Wilt of Potato in Re - lation to Infection from the Soil ;. 32 •• . Fruit Disease Investigations 33 ■Potatoes : ■ Potato Selection'for Seed Purposes 33 .. A Study of Degeneracy in Seed-potato Stocks 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Poultry: A Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry Feeding 34 Nutritive Requirements of Growing Chicks ..,' "" ""•' 35 Turkey Production ; ,;•; 36 Rural Economics : . Cost of Producing Farm Crops... '. 37 Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production, and the Pur - chasing Power of Farm Products. „ 37 . Cost and Standards of Living on Nebraska Farms "" 37 Nebraska Farm Land Prices 38 Market Costs . ;.. .;*(.„!„ 38 Farm Organization and Farm Costs :.".'.".'.'" ' '• 38 Transporting Livestock to Market ™"".38 State Serum Plant 39 North Platte Substation: Agronomy ' 40 Crop Rotation and Tillage Meth0d......... ......";"......".".."."."...." 40 Crop Improvement .'... ; "" 40 Pump Irrigation "" """ 41 Beef Cattle , ...•.."!'.!'."!""!"."""!!!!"! 41 ' Ho£ s • ■. ZZZZ!:™."".'.'"! 42 Sheep ...... ....„ ,-, ; 42 Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Lambs 42 Dairy ; „ ; ' 42 Poultry """"""""""""!!!" 42 Horticulture and Forestry ; !'.Z."!!!!Z!i!"!"! 43 Scottsbluff Substation : ... Crop Rotations ; .• ;."...„: -. 44 Lamb Feeding.. „.. • " ' 45 Beef Calves ....;.:J3.*!"!!.".""1 45 Dairying ...„ , 45 Hogs ;£..„..„.„:„„;.! 46 Poultry .„; _ 46 Valentine Substation: " • . Agronomy „ ; 4g Meadow: Investigation ;..,.; !!!!!!!'- 46 Trees ...........„;."•!"!!'!;"!" 46 Box Butte Experiment Farm 4g Changes in Staff ; ; 47 Legislation ; . 47 Additional Land, Buildings, and Equipment 47 Publications of the Last Fiscal Year 48 Financial Statement 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Forty-fifth Annual Report .This report covers the investigations, expenditures, and publications of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Sta - tion for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1931. During the year 68 projects have been under investigation at the main station. These have covered a wide range of subjects. At the various substations the work is planned to meet the needs of the different regions. The funds for carrying on the work of the stations are derived from federal and state sources. The work is carried on in definite projects according to the supporting fund. In this report no attempt is made to designate the projects under which the various funds were expended, but for convenience the projects are grouped as to subject matter. The intent is to show the progress made rather than to present a large amount of detailed information! The financial report of the receipts and expenditures of the Experiment Station has been prepared by the Finance Secretary and is given at the end of this report. Satisfactory progress wa&amp; made on the research program. During the year eight projects were completed and seven new ones added. The selection of new projects is on the basis of most urgent need, together with the ability of the Experi - ment to carry the project. The policy is to concen - trate on a few rather than many projects, and to keep the investigations along fundamental lines. Many problems are brought to the Experiment Station- which it is not equipped, in either personnel or resources, to undertake. The financial depression in which agriculture still finds itself has increased rather than decreased the demand upon the Experiment Station and the College for new and definite, information. This demand has been taken care of insofar as possible. " . ■ During the year covered by this report eleven bulletins, nine research bulletins, and one circular have been published by the Experiment Station. In addition 22 technical papers have been prepared by members of the staff and printed in various technical and professional journals, A list of publi - cations is given in the latter part of this report. AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING Nebraska Tractor Tests. — This work is in accordance with the Nebraska Tractor Testing Law. During the year 13 tractors were tested, eight on gasoline, two on kerosene, and three on "distillate" of about 38-40° Baume. The low-grade fuels available varied so much as to require trial in the engine as a means of selection. Four of the tractors tested were </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station of the crawler type; one was of the four-wheel-drive type. The general purpose tractor continues to receive consider - able attention by manufacturers, as evidenced by four machines of this type. "■••.■ J Experiment Station Bulletin 255, "Nebraska Tractor o/rIV 7 ar . ch ' 1931, presents in condensed form the reports of 65 tests ten of which were completed in 1930. Altogether, within W 6 H r n compe ! ed in the eleven y ears ending Ss bulfetin ° n ° b3Olete machin es were not included in ip£Ts" e rvest f r Study.— The only work under this pro - &lt;%££ unng *5 e P ast . year was a study of the draft of several combines. The project will be continued. v,^ tUd l ° f W™ 6 -^™ Electric Plants for Farm Use.— Further observations were made during the year It is ex pected that with the conclusion of this yea 's date the material will be assembled for publication and the project Pump Irrigation.— So field testing was done during the past year, but a portable power unit has been secured. This tests ° n Plants already estab : Tfeo'f^i^ the J Jse of Electric Power on Nebraska Farms. —The total number of farms connected with electricifv has risen from 2142 to 3,566 during the past tw6 years Tlisi" an increase of over 66 per cent. The average yearly consump^ tion per farm increased about 40 per cent The averX cost of current to the farmer from power Tries was aboufl cents per kilowatt-hour: A part of the data obtained were summarized and published in Bulletin No. 254 entitled "Rural Electric Service in Nebraska " ™" ™ In a study of the use of a 5 H. P. motor for filling silos at an average rate of 3.84 tons per hour, 1.17 kilowatShours of electricity were required per ton. The effect of excess?^ n?n? P r S^Tv? ned fr^ m data teken with the cutter riri - mng empty at the speed used in filling (460), and aeain empty with speed increased 41 per cent (650) The powe? S l^r f&lt; ]toS ei Ki?? 8 P eed WaS 8 ° PGr tha P n°Tor Ihl \?^ I* * kmves ' dr y corn, and low voltage on the hne aocunted for a doubling of cost of power ner ton The circular calls attention to the following: Ample tran? former capacity is necesafy for good peSorntnce of the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">• Forty-fifth Annual Report motor under heavy load. The transformer should be as near the load as practicable. Wires should be of ample size. Con - tinuous and even feeding is essential. The knives must be sharp if power cost is to be kept at a minimum. The bundles should be small if bands are not cut. . Some of the data obtained in the study of water systems for Nebraska farms were published as Experiment Station Bulletin No. 245 entitled "Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Systems for Farm Homes;" The study of small unit plants for farm use has been con - tinued. Experiment Station Bulletin No. 249 entitled "The Mechanical Dairy Cooler on Nebraska Farms" was published. In a study of four small dairy coolers of the walk-in type it was found that with electricity at 4 cents per kilowatt-hour the cost of power per gallon of milk cooled in the different units ranged from $.0035 to $.0112 during the hot summer period. This wide range, showing over three times the power cost in one as in the other, indicates the importance of good design, good construction, careful operation, and utilization of the space and refrigeration if economical results are to be obtained. A Study of the Various Methods of Cooling Milk on the Farm and. Their Effect on Quality. — This project is co-oper - ative between Agricultural Engineering and Dairy Hus - bandry. The work has been continued in a study of the most effective way of applying water as a cooling medium for milk. Water of varying temperatures and rates of flow has been applied at different angles and to different parts of the cream cans standing in cooling tanks. The amount of water needed for cooling milk in various types of tanks, when still and .agitated, has also been studied. Studies were made to deter - mine the influence of the temperature and length of time of cooling upon bacterial growth. ANIMAL DISEASES A Study of the Pathogenicity as- well, as Antigenic and Biologic Properties of the Organis-ms Belonging to the Hemor - rhagic Septicemia Group. — With the closing of the tubercu - losis project and the consequent release of laboratory animals, work under this project has been renewed. The recent work has consisted largely of a study of the immunizing value of so-called aggr.essins widely sold and used as a result of the claims of their value in prophylaxis. Probably this project will be brought to a conclusion during the coming year. An Inquiry into the Influence of Environment upon Poul - try Morbidity.— -During the past year the epizootologic be- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station havior of six different poultry diseases was studied under carefully controlled environmental conditions. These diseases are bacillary white diarrhea, blackhead (turkeys), tubercu - losis, fowl cholera, coccidiosis and fowl typhus. Definite con - clusions cannot yet be offered except for blackhead. It can now be definitely stated that blackhead infection is clearly associated with the soil, contaminated by the droppings of affected birds. In the yard in which the soil was covered with gravel and where the food and water supply was under sanitary control the incidence of blackhead as compared with the yard in which sanitation was not attempted was 6:81 for the year 1929 and 7:127 for 1930. The virus element for th.-. two yards was of equal volume insofar as it was possible to make it so. Further studies of blackhead are now in pro - gress, and from evidence thus far obtained it is becoming increasingly apparent that it is possible to create and main - tain an environment in- which blackhead cannot exist and in which turkey growing can be undertaken in a profitable man - ner. At the conclusion of the present studies it is hoped to test out these possibilities in an even more searching manner before making recommendations to the producers. In conection with fowl cholera, results thus far indicate that direct-contact infection may play at least as prominent a part in transmission as indirect, environmental infection. After the introduction of infected fowls an outbreak in both yards was experienced and sanitary safeguards proved of no value in the presence of fowls which had become virus, carriers. In a subsidiary experiment with a small number | of surviving, healthy birds it was ascertained that the virus ' was present in the mucus of the nasal cavity. This confirmed results previously reported by workers in the Rockefeller In - stitute for Medical Research. Nothing of a conclusive nature can as yet be said with reference to bacillary white diarrhea. The results thus far point toward the possibility that our present views pertain - ing to the prophylaxis of this disease should be subjected to careful revision. . Means have. not yet been found of obtaining outbreaks of tuberculosis and fowl typhus comparable with the ones observed in the field. The efforts in this connection are be - ing continued, but until these objectives are obtained it will, not be possible to formulate definite conclusions In the part of the project devoted to coccidiosis, difficul - ties were encountered, the principal one being associated with the fact that thus far it has not been possible to secure chicks entirely free from the causative microparasites. It also was found that microparasites seem to thrive in birds </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Forty-fifth Annual Report without becoming a cause of death in a conspicuous manner. It appears that much which is accepted as authoritative in connection with coccidiosis must be challenged anew. Some preliminary experiments are planned to find a base for such an undertaking. More light on the behavior of the disease is needed in order to find the influences having to do with its propagation. In this study there was not a single record where infection from one yard to another took place, a simple wire netting being a sufficient barrier.. Laboratory Diagnosis and Examination of Specimens. — This project is continued to take care of the many specimens that come to the Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene for routine examination and diagnosis. During the past year 10,367 specimens were examined. This kind of work continued to interfere seriously with the research pro - gram. DAIRY HUSBANDRY A Study of the Principles of Ice Cream Making. — Several phases of this work were carried during the past year. The scoring and analyses of samples of vanilla and strawberry ice creams submitted by manufacturers showed some slight improvement in quality of the different samples, strawberry ice cream frequently developing a stale flavor after being held in the hardening room. In a study of strawberries as a source of yeast and molds in ice cream, the method of Hood and White (Dominion of Canada, Dept. of Agr.,. Leaflet 92, New Series) was used and the berries included were frozen, canned, and sterilized. The canned and sterilized berries contained few yeasts and molds, indicating, that such methods are satisfactory. Frozen berries showed greater differences in yeast and mold content. The studies indicate that strawberries may not be the only source of yeasts and molds in the ice creams. Previous studies of the deficiencies of homogenization of the ice cream mix indicated that samples of ice cream made from a homogenized mix frequently show, evidences of churn - ing. Homogenization is quite effective in breaking up the fat globules, but churning tests of the homogenized mix and finished ice cream indicate that from 2 to 21 per cent of the fat can be recovered by churning. In a study of the factors affecting freezing conditions, a series of mixes were studied in which the length of time of pasteurization was the variable factor (30 and 60 minutes at 145° F.) . It was found that mixes pasteurized for the shorter - time reached the proper overrun in freezing several minutes quicker than those pasteurized for the longer time. Pro - longed pasteurization apparently has a retarding influence </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station upon overrun. Another series of trials was run with mixes which were pasteurized at 145° F. for 30 minutees, after which one-half the mix was heated to 175° F. and homogen - ized at that temperature. The mixes that were pasteurized in the normal way reached the desired overrun of 90 to 100 per cent in ten to twelve minutes, while mixes that had been heated to 175 °.F. after pasteurization reached an overrun varying from 75 to 80 per cent in the same time. A study of the factors affecting the accuracy of the stand - ardization of fat and 'solids, content of ice cream was also made. The results indicate that there is considerable varia - tion in the percentage of. fat in samples taken at different stages of the processing of the mix and that fat standardiza - tion of the mix m the ordinary way is not a guarantee that the same percentage of fat will be found in the finished ic« cream. There is little indication of fat migration to the sur- * C ? rt l n^ a "oroosenized mix held 24 hours in 10-gallon cans at 40 F. The variation in fat from the calculated percent - age appears to be due to various causes which will be studied further. .In testing the accuracy of the Nebraska procedure against the Mojonnier test it was found that there was a variation pf ±0.0708 per cent, while the Garrett-Overman test when read direct showed a variation of ±0.649 per cent and when read with glymol showed a variation of ±0.2946 per Studies of ''Fat Soluble A" as Present in the Milk of the Four Dairy Breeds, Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey and Guernsey 7^JT V nf?* St A dy £ the T Vitamin A content of milk pr£ duced by Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey cows was made by comparing the growth produced by 560 rats receiv- T&amp;- f F om these breeds as th eir only source of vitamin A Albino rats 24 to 28 days old, and weighing between 35 and 45 grams, were fed a vitamin A free basal ration composed of 18 per cent casein, 78 per cent corn starch, and 4 per cent salts. One gram of dried yeast daily was fed separately as the source of the vitamin B complex. The antirachitic factor was supplied by irradiation of the corn starch with a Cooper Hewitt quartz mercury vapor lamp run at 2.4 amperes, 250 volts. This ration was fed from weaning .until ophthalmia was incipient, or there was a cessation of growth When this point was reached, the basal ration was supplemented with one, two, and three cubic centimeters of milk. Negative con - tros received only the vitamin A free diet and positive con - trols received the basal ration supplemented daily with one - tenth of a cubic centimeter of cod-liver oil. In each comparison milk taken from two groups of four </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Forty-fifth Annual Report cows each represented a breed. The cows were selected for uniformity of age, stage of lactation, number of lactations, and stage of gestation. In general the cows in each group were milked the same number of times daily, and received the same feed. The results showed some slight irregular differences in the gains produced by the milk from the different breeds, but in view of the individual variation of the experimental animals, they appeared negligible. This conclusion was substantiated by a statistical examination of the data. From the results of this study, in which the experiments were duplicated, it was evident, that under the conditions of these experiments the difference in the vitamin A content of milk from Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, and Guernsey breeds is insignificant. A part of the data obtained is published in Research Bulletin No. 54, entitled "The Vitamin A Content of the Milk of Hol - stein, Guernsey, Jersey, and Ayrshire Cows." Factors Affecting the Qualtity of Fluid Milk as Shown by the Fat Test, Sediment Test, and Bacteria Count. — This study has been under way for seven years. Daily butterf at tests and weekly determinations of quality by means of sediment tests and bacteria counts by direct microscopical examination have been made. After the first three years, weekly reports were sent to each patron. At the end of four and one - half year.s a bonus was given for high-grade milk and dur - ing the last nine months a deduction has been made for low - grade milk. Up until the time the bonus system was inaugu - rated the improvement was comparatively slow as measured . by the sediment test and bacteria count. The inauguration . of the bonus arid the deduction for low-grade milk brought about a marked improvement in quality. In grading milk the use of the sediment test alone was found unsatisfactory and should be used along with some other quality test. The bacteria count and Methylene Blue reduction test were found satisfactory for the determination of quality in milk. There appears to be a very- close relation - ship between night atmospheric temperature and the quality of the milk delivered the next morning, indicating that the cooling on the farm is often inadequate. A Study of Growth in Dairy Cattle. — The collection of growth data has been continued throughout the year with all dairy animals born on the experiment station farm. The number measured monthly is now over 100 and approximately 75 of these are photographed monthly. A preliminary tabula - tion of the growth of Holstein and Jersey females for the first 36 months of their lives has been made. A' comparison of </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station the six-month intervals showed the skeletal growth of both Holsteins and Jerseys to be greatest during the first six years of age. Methods of Practical Control and Economic Effect of Con - tagious Abortion upon a Dairy. Herd, — This project is an at - tempt to obtain a herd free from Bang's disease as indicated by the agglutination test. The dilutions used are 1 :25 ; 1 :50 : 1:100; and 1:250. A separate group of buildings and yards is provided for the animals which are considered infected. The negative herd is tested each month and the entire herd every I three months. During the past year a Holstein heifer reacted positively. This has been the only reactor for 29 months. Although the disease seems. to be under control it is evident that so long as the positive herd remains there is the possibility of new reactors. Studies have been made on the effect of feeding sprouted oats as a cure for temporary sterility, but data are not yet available: The Vitamin Content of Field-cured and Artificially Cured Hay. — A comparison of artifically and field-cured alfalfa hay was made by feeding them to rats in conjunction with a basal ration devoid of vitamin A. The rats receiving artificially cured alfalfa made slightly greater gains than those fed field - cured hay, when the amount of alfalfa hay fed was taken into consideration. Both of these groups made materially more gain than the rats in the positive control group which received in addition to the basal ration 0.1 c.c. of cod-liver oil. The rats in the negative control group receiving only the basal ration died. . In a preliminary study, of the vitamin E content of alfalfa hays, 24 rats previously on a sterility-producing ration wer a fed for a period of 90 to 100 days. In continuing these rats on a sterility ration with varying amounts of alfalfa added it appeared that from ten to fifteen per cent of alfalfa would be necessary to overcome the lack of Vitamin E in the basic ration. FIELD CROPS AND SOILS A Study of the Principles of Corn Improvement through Inbreeding and Hybridization.— Because of extreme drouth m 1930 most phases of this project were almost a complete failure. -Drouth years have occurred so frequently during J^ e n \ &amp;at tv/ent y years ' namely 1913, 1918, 1919, J 925, 1926 and 1930, as to interfere decidedly with this type of corn breed - ing program. In 1930 a very poor set of seed was obtained in the control breeding plats. Including field and greenhouse produced seed, and seed remnants carried over from the pre - </seg>
            <seg id="p019">" ■ . Forty-fifth Annual Report vious year, about 600 self ed lines and 200 hybrids were avail - able for planting in 1931. The work is now facilitated by the availability of greenhouse space which makes possible the growing of two generations in one year. Aside from studies to determine what constitutes desirable qualities in selfed lines and practical methods of their recom - bination into productive hybrids, the corn breeding work of this station is centering upon the development of hybrids for commercial use. Material progress is being made in this direction. In these tests outstanding farm varieties, com - mercial hybrids from neighboring states, and experimental hybrids are grown in comparison. In four outlying tests, conducted in co-operation with the Agricultural Extension Service where Hogue Yellow Dent was used as a check, cer - tain hybrids were outstandingly good at all four points. The best of the hybrids averaged 26 per cent higher than Hogue. In rather widely separated co-operative &gt;tests of hybrids and local varieties of corn, the five highest-yielding hybrids gave 16 per cent higher yields than the best five varieties. With the advent and growing use of mechanical harvesters, a special demand is being created for productive lodge-resist - ant corn with ear shanks sufficiently strong to prevent the ear from dropping off. Some of the better hybrids are somewhat superior in these respects. Selection for these characters is being especially stressed in the present breeding program. During the year .the following publications were made: The Use of. Advanced Generation Hybrids as Parents of Double Cross Seed Corn, Journal of American Society of Agronomy, Vol. 22, No. 7, July 1930 ; and Progress Report on Corn Hybrids, 22nd Annual Report, Nebraska Crop Grow - ers' Association. . Variety Testing, Breeding, Acclimatization, and Cultural Studies witW Small Grains.— During the past year the several phases, of this work were continued. The name of the winter wheat known as Nebraska No. 50 has. been changed to Chey - enne. Further experimental evidence shows that this wheat is superior in strength of straw and shatter resistance, and fully equal or superior in yield to Nebraska No. 60. Several promising selections of hard red winter wheat have been made from the Turkey variety. These selections show satis - factory resistance to cold and to both species of stinking smut, and three of the selections are very promising from the standpoint of yield and early maturity. Nebraska No. 21 and Burt C. I. 293 continued as the most promising available varieties of oats for Nebraska conditions. Certified seed of both of these is available in large quantities. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station During the past few years the acreage of barley grown in the state has increased threefold. A number of relatively new smooth-awned varieties of barley are being tried out. This type now predominates in eastern Nebraska where har - vesting requires the handling of sheaf grain. Comfort and Glabron are the most common smooth-awned sorts, and have yielded approximately 20 per cent more than the common barley. Of the rough-awned sorts Trebi has given the highest yields during the past eight years. . Among the spring wheat varieties Ceres has given the highest average yield, the yields closely approximating those of the Durum varieties. The cultural studies with small grams have been continued. During the year the following publications were made : Breeding Winter Wheat for Resist - ance to Stinking Smut, Experiment Station Research Bulletin No. 51 ; and Variety Tests of Oats, Barley, and Spring Wheat Experiment Station Bulletin No. 253. Forage Crop Investigations. — During the past year all of the forage crops made excellent yields. The yields are all based on forage reduced to 15 per cent moisture content The annual yields per acre were as follows: common millet 2.7 tons, German millet 3.4 tons, sudan grass 3.4 tons, Black Amber Sorghum 3.7 tons, Early Sumac Sorghum 4.9 tons, Western Orange Sorghum 4.9 tons, Kansas Orange Sorghum 5.3 tons, and Honey Sorgo 5.4 tons. The later varieties of sorghum gave heavier yields than the early varieties. Heavy seeding produced finer-stemmed hay than lighter seeding. The yields of grain from the sor - ghums were unusually heavy, running from 32 to 49 bushels of seed per acre in comparison with but 9 bushels of corn, the season being very unfavorable for corn production. «- r £ he eld , of soy beans was unusually heavy, ranging from 21 bushels for Midwest and Ito San to 31 bushels for Manchu The average yield at Lincoln is approximately 17 busjiels per acre. The efforts of the past several years to grow soy beans in solid planting rather than in cultivated rows is considered a failure because of difficulty with weed control. From field tests, comparing seed from various sources it has been found that decided variation exists in the winter - hardiness of regional strains of Common alfalfa, while in 8e 2£ r £ ™ e . seed source has made relatively little difference with the Grimm variety. Alfalfa variety testing for yield, longevity of stand, and other agronomic, qualities has continued as usual except on a larger scale since this phase of the alfalfa investigations is now in collaboration with the U. S. Department of Agricul- </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Forty-fifth Annual Report ture. In a yield test including seven varieties planted at the Agronomy Farm in 1922 and continued to date, Cossack and Baltic have been outstanding, yielding respectively 12 and 10 per cent more than Common alfalfa 'obtained from cen - tral Nebraska. Extensive collections of varieties and regional strains have been made and a number of demonstrational plantings have been carried out in different parts of the state. In one of these tests at Cozad, where alfalfa wilt is preva - lent, a varietal series was planted two years ago. This test includes land not previously cropped to alfalfa and land which had just been broken up from a severely wilt-infected field. Wilt was decidedly more prevalent in the crop growing where infected alfalfa had previously been grown. There is great varietal variation evident in respect to wilt resistance. Two varieties, Hardistan and Provence No. 34886, have proved de - cidedly resistant to wilt in this test, just as they have in older tests at Lincoln. Several importations from Turkestan are proving fully as resistant. These three varieties should prove a good source for selection and breeding material. Six bushels of Hardistan seed were distributed to a number of farmers for seed increase during the past year. Ah alfalfa nursery has been planted at Lincoln, containing in duplicate some 300 new importations recently made by Mr. H. L. Westover of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Determination of the Relation of the Characteristics, Com - mercial Grade, and' Market Value of Alfalfa Hay to Curing, Stacking, and Baling Practices. — During the year investiga - tion of alfalfa hay stacking problems was begun in co-opera - tion with the Hay, Seed, and Feed Division of the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Records of moisture content and leafiness are kept in relation to the practices of the farmer co-operators. It was found that in general the curing practice should be so planned as to hasten curing to avoid rain damage and yet retain the leaves. This will ordinarily result in partial swath curing until the leaves are well wilted, followed by raking into medium-sized windrows. Raking immediately after cutting materially delays drying. Cocking the hay before it is fully cured delays stacking and does not materially improve the quality. Leaf shattering may result in a Very serious loss in that it lowers the yield and mate - rially reduces the feed value. A high correlation has beep found between leafiness and protein content. Leaves consti - tute about 45 per cent of the dry weight of alfalfa, and they contain about 28 per cent protein, compared with 11 per cent for the stems. It has been found to make little difference in the curing rate or hay quality whether side delivery or sulky </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station rake is used, provided windrows of about equal size are made Turning the windrows before it is fully cured hastens the drying a few hours. If the hay has overcured in the swath so that the leaves tend to shatter, such loss is greatly reduced by raking in the morning while it is tough from dew. Turn - ing or scattering partially cured windrows or cocks that have become wet from rain has shortened the period of curing 28 hours as an average of 33 trials. Such turning has had prac - tically no effect upon the color, leafiness, or protein content It has reduced, however, the number of sample lots which were graded down because of mustiness. So far as possible the final quality of the hay in the stack is being determined at the time of baling. The problem of stack spot is also being studied. The relation of stack preser - vation to stacking practices will be studied. During the year * bulletin U. S. D. A. No. 235 entitled "Quality of Alfalfa Hay in Relation to Curing Practice," was published. ■, n C X op Rotation an d Fertilizer Experiments.— The crop, of 1930 was the tenth since the general-fertility plats were started. The season was favorable for wheat and oats, but unfavorable for corn. The average yield of wheat was 41.3 bushels, of oats 58 bushels, and of corn about 10 bushels per acre. For the sixth time there was material response from applications of phosphate for both wheat and oats, the in - crease being 5 and 6 bushels respectively Manure likewise increased the yield of both wheat and oats the largest increase being 11.3 bushels per acre of wheat. For the first time during the experiments alfalfa was on land where it had not been previously grown and where subsoil moisture was not a limiting factor in production. Even under this condition consistent increases from applications of fer - tilizers were not obtained. The Relation of Weather, Cultural Practices, "and Soil Con - ditions to Nitrification in Nebraska Soils.— The work under this project was continued during the past year in a further study of the response of winter wheat to top dressings of nitrogen fertilizers. On four farms in Lancaster County seven mtrogent carriers were compared. The fertilizers were all applied inequalities to furnish the same amount of nitro - gen, 30 pounds per acre. a ,,St o inCreaSeS fr ? m nitrate, Calurea, and ammonium «5J ate , . were ,, c . onsistent ' both actually and relatively, with those obtained in previous years and indicate profitable usage «L^ n^ mt £ ate a ? d P ther avaiIabl e nitrogen fertilizers on some farms when wheat is normal in price. At the low prices now prevailing, such increases are not profitable. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Forty-fifth Annual Report \A Study of the Factors Which Affect the Tilth of Soils.— Under this project the study of the coefficient of friction of soils has been completed, and the data have been put into manuscript form. Recent work has been started to study the nature and modification of the tilth and other physical pro - perties of solonetz soil. Field studies have been laid out in which gypsum, sulfur, lime, treble superphosphate, and manure, and combinations of these, are being used in a rota - tion of barley, sweet clover* and corn. A Study of the Restoration of Organic Matters in Soils. — Studies of the decomposition of organic materials in soil under field conditions have been continued. It was expected that in uniformly mixed soil, changes in organic content could be followed by means of volatile matter determination, but difficulties have arisen in connection with the method. If the temperature at which the soil is ignited is carefully controlled, consistent results can be obtained, the time of ignition within the limits of one to four hours being unimportant. It appears, however, that soils exposed to weathering in the field vary in the amount of combined water present, so that the volatile matter determination is not a* reliable index of organic content from time to time. Other simple and depend - able methods of determining soil organic matter are being sought. The fallow, weeds, wheat, sweet clover, alfalfa, and blue grass frames to determine the loss or gain of organic matter and nitrogen are being continued. A new set of frames 24 inches square and 9 inches deep has been installed. In these will be grown several modifica - tions of a three-year rotation, with or without applications of fertilizer. It is expected that the experiment will show the effect of sweet clover, nitrogen fertilizer, manure, and superphosphate on the organic matter and nitrogen content of the soil and on yield and quality of crops. At the Box Butte Experiment Farm a series of plats have been laid out to determine what should be done with wheat straw in the prevailing systems of wheat production, and the effect of straw burning on soil organic matter and nitro - gen. Various treatments are being tried on land which has the straw and stubble burned off and also on land which has the straw and stubble turned under. Co-operative Fertilizer Experiments. — -During the year in Morrill and Scottsbluff counties phosphate was applied to alfalfa on a number of irrigated farms. On bottom land where the soil either contains alkali or is highly alkaline in reaction, increases in yield were obtained. This work is be- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ing continued both in the application of fertilizer and in a study of the residual effects. In a study of the effect of phos - phate on other crops, profitable increases were obtained on corn, potatoes, beans, barley, and sugar beets, under the same soil conditions mentioned above. The greatest response was from sugar beets. In eastern Nebraska, perhaps because of the severely dry season, corn yields were depressed by ap - plications of phosphate. ' . FRUITS AND VEGETABLES Pruning Apples, Pears, and Small Fruits. — Another year's measurements were made upon the growth made by lightly and heavily pruned Jonathan and Winesap apple trees. The trees lightly trimmed at transplanting time are still slightly larger in trunk diameter than those pruned much more heavily. The difference, however, is slight, as was the differ - ence in the growth during, the past year. There is a fair promise of crop for 1931 and the effect of various treatments may be noticeable later on. ; Fruit Breeding Experiments.— Of the many open-pollin - ated Omaha plum seedlings under test, few seem to offer promise. During the past year a large number of the least desirable were discarded. During the year additional vari - eties of apples and small fruits were obtained for study. These include the more deeply colored of so-called "Black" strains of Jonathan, Stayman, and Mclntosh apples, and some seedling gooseberries from the North Dakota Experiment Station. The unfavorable weather conditions of late summer during the past year so interfered with procuring a stand of the newer varieties of strawberries as to prevent a satis - factory comparison. Newer and better adapted varieties are still being sought as a necessity if the strawberry produc - tion of the state is to be increased very greatly. Orchard Culture, Union Fruit Farm. — The dry season of 1930 prevented much length growth, but a fairly satisfactory set of fruit was made in the spring of 1931. The previous light crops prevent drawing any conclusions from the block devoted to fertilizers. In the block under continuous clean culture considerable wash has occurred which may necessitate a change in the original plan. The study of the effect of the soil treatments on grape productoin was continued, the re - sults varying considerably from those previously obtained. A brief report of the results to date was presented to the Ne - braska State Historical Society, January, 1931. Vegetable Experimentation— Variety Trials and Cultural Tests. — Several phases of this project were carried during the year. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Forty-fifth Annual Report iJ? oil . Management.— During the very dry, hot season of 1930 irrigation was found to be the most outstanding single factor influencing vegetable production. Straw mulching was the next most desirable method of improving quality and yields. Paper mulching stimulated early production, but it is doubtful that yields were increased sufficiently to pay for the cost of buying and laying the. paper. Partial covering with paper was less desirable than complete covering Tomato Production.— A detailed study of the time and rate of development of tomatoes was conducted with two vari - eties grown under eight' different cultural conditions. Sig - nificant differences were observed but they do not permit general conclusions at this time. Asparagus Production.— The blocks planted with large crown sizes continued to give superior yields. A cutting season of tour and six weeks has resulted in decreased early yields as compared with one of eight weeks. A cutting seas - on of ten weeks does not seem to have weakened the plants appreciably by the end of the third cutting season. Shallow - planted crowns are yielding about 20 per cent more than deep-planted crowns. Straw and manure mulching are both retarding shoot growth and are reducing yields to a serious extent. Salt applications have reduced yields, possibly be - cause of adverse soil conditions (deflocculatioh) . Fruit Stock Investigation. — Work has been continued in a study of the effect of the use or different sizes of seedlings for grafting on nursery trees. A second part of the experiment is a comparison of wedge and whip grafting on seedlings. This is being carried on at Arlington in co-operation with the Marshall nurseries. The data indicate that the differences between the various types of grafts are so slight and so variable that there is no advantage for either. Orchard Spraying for the Codling Moth. — The past season was the third devoted to a test of summer oil sprays for codling moth control. The dry summer proved a severe test for summer oils. In fact it was a severe test of the spray schedule in general. The drouth which began about July Ist was favorable to the codling moth and there was little rain to wash off the spray materials. There was a well-developed second brood of worms and a partial third brood. In the young orchard, control of the codling moth was very thorough and uniform in all the plats. In the old orchard where the infestation was heavier, another late spray should have been applied for the third brood of worms. One definite con - clusion can be made with regard to the summer oil sprays: that is, that they are about as effective in controlling the </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station worms of the second brood as is the standard lead arsenate spray. The results from the two previous years point to this same conclusion. Oil sprays are used primarily to get away from excessive use of lead arsenate and to avoid a heavy residue being deposited on the fruit; Since oils cannot be used with lime sulfur they are not used until the second brood develops. With normal rainfall a large part of the lead arsenate . residue is washed off the fruit. Because of the dry season last 1 year ' the fruits showed more residue than formerly, several of the plats being above the recognized world toler - ance. It should be stated, however, that the samples were selected with the intention of getting the heavier residue, as that is the way government tests are made. It would seem from the three years' work that summer oils will con - trol worms as well as lead arsenate. They are, however, more expensive. If one is prepared to wash the fruit the lead arsenate may be used as late as necessary for control pur - poses. . HOME ECONOMICS Cash Contribution of Farm Homemakers to the Family Income through Dairy and Poultry Products. — Work was con - tinued in the analysis of the data contained in 159 records wherein the complete records of the value and cost of dairy and poultry products were kept. Analysis shows that 70 per cent of the total time spent on poultry and poultry products and 35 per cent of the total time spent on dairy products was spent by the farm women. After all expenses for the year were deducted, including a charge of 5 per cent on net working capital, the records showed an average hourly in - come of 44 cents from poultry and 40 cents from dairy pro - ducts. These figures represent the return from both sale and use of the products. The unit prices at which the various products were sold and at which they were valued for home use are given for every month of the year, so that this study can be used as a basis of comparison with other years. Dur - ing the last half of the year for which records were kept prices of both dairy and poultry products fell considerably. The results have . been published as Experiment Station Bulletin No. 258,. "The Contribution of Nebraska Farm Women to Family Income through Poultry and Dairy Pro - ducts." The project is now closed. Washing Machine Study. — This project is co-operative with Agricultural Engineering. Eight washing machines, repre - sentative of four types, were studied as to: (1) cleansing action and relation of cleanness of fabric to length of wash- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Forty-fifth Annual Report ing period, temperature of water,, and size of load, (2) wear on fabric, (3) heat retention^ and (4) constructional features affecting convenience of operation. The study has been com - pleted and the data published in Nebraska Experiment Sta - tion Research Bulletin No. 56, "Ai Study of Washing Machines." ■•• ■ • . A Study of Electric Cooking Stoves.— In this study four electric stoves of the various types of units and oven insula - tion have been purchased. The laboratory procedure has been determined to study the speed, thermal efficiency, and cost of operation of the different types of stoves, and to determine the best methods of handling and caring for them. The Relation of Draft to Performance of Kerosene Burners on Kerosene Cook Stoves.— The purpose of this study is to determine what factors are important in the construction of kerosene burners as related to time of heating and thermal efficiency. Most important are: (1) ■ draft, which is deter - mined by the construction of the chimney and the burners, and (2) shape and size of grates, distance of grate from chimeny, and framework of stoves around the burners. Results to date show that for any burner operated under standardized conditions the speed of heating is affected directly by the rate of combustion of the oil. The velocity of the air passing into the burner is regulated by the height of the chimney and the perforations for air in and around the burner and chimney. There appears to be one best chimney height for every burner. Carefully designed burners and chimneys allow for considerably greater volume of air than is necessary for combustion alone, and the openings must be adjusted both in size and arrangement to give the correct mixture of oil- vapor and air so that combustion is complete, as evidenced by freedom from soot and odor. The diameter of the chimney affects thermal efficiency. The ideal burner is constructed so that the draft is sufficient to cause a high rate of consumption of oil, which in turn in - creases the speed of heating. The chimney should be con - structed, to prevent heat loss and thus give a high thermal efficiency. ... A Study of the Family History and Standards of Living of Farm Families in Selected Districts of Nebraska. — Under this project 87 families in Cass and Fillmore counties are keep - ing both home and farm accounts for the year. Sometime during the year information on the family histories of the members of this group will be secured. A part-time field worker is in close contact with the home record keepers and the work is being done under the most careful supervision. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The records are being summarized and transcribed every three months. It is planned to extend this work into at least one other county during the coming year. INSECT CONTROL Investigation and Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. — Further work was done on the Hessian fly. A field observation station was maintained at Weeping Water during the past year. The annual survey to determine the presence and spread of the alfalfa weevil was made during the month of June. No new evidence was obtained. With the new insectary constructed last year, new phases of this project were undertaken in the study of the life history and control of the cherry slug, the imported cabbage worm, the egg-plant flea-beetle, the spruce leaf -miner, the boxelder plant bug, and house ants. Grasshopper Control. — This work naturally becomes more active when grasshoppers become prevalent. Grasshoppers were a serious menace in several sections of the state during the past year and work was energetically renewed. The Life History and Control of Potato Flea-Beetles in Western Nebraska. — Three years' work has been completed in a study of the life history and methods of. controlling potato flea-beetles. The data will be assembled for publication. A Brood Study of the Codling Moth in Southeastern Nebraska. — Work was continued during the past year. As in the past three years, the data will be prepared for publi - cation in the report of the Nebraska State Horticultural So - ciety. A. Study of the Distribution, Life History, and Means of Control of the Cutworms Attacking Corn in Nebraska. This project has been active, but progress has been slow during the past year. The portion dealing with the means of identifica - tion of the various kinds of cutworms known to attack field crops is now complete. It is expected that it will be pre - pared for publication soon. The life history studies and means of control will require the continuation of the project. LIVESTOCK FEEDING Fattening Cattle. — In a study of wintering rations for stock calves, ground corn fodder produced cheaper gains than silage but almost a fifth less gain per animal. Silage produced a larger daily gain and more gain per acre and kept the cattle in better condition than the corn fodder. In convenience of handling the silage was superior. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Forty-fifth Annual Report d.\ . Cottonseed cake as a supplement to either silage or fodder proved more valuable than double the amount by weight of alfalfa hay. The cake materially increased the gains and decreased the cost when fed, in conjunction with either silage or fodder. These results are comparable with those obtained a year ago. In this year's test alfalfa fed with silage was worth approximately 15 per cent as much per ton as cotton - seed cake." With fodder it was worth approximately 20 per cent as much as the cake. Corn vs. Wheat for Finishing Three-year-old Grass-fat Steers. — In a comparison of corn and wheat for fattening cattle, a group of three-year-old grass-fat steers weighing approximately 1140 pounds per head were divided into two lots, the first receiving a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay and the second cracked shelled corn two parts, cracked wheat one part, and alfalfa hay. Each lot was on full feed for 65 days. The average gain per steer was 196 pounds in Lot 1 and 231 pounds in Lot 2. The steers in Lot 2 were appraised at 25 cents per hundred higher than those in Lot 1. In the slaughtering test the steers in Lot 2 dressed slightly higher than those in Lot 1. The feed required to produce 100 pounds of gain was con - siderably lower for both lots than is ordinarily the case for steers of this age. The small feed requirement was unques - tionably due to the relatively short feeding period. Lot 2 produced 100 pounds of gain on 55 pounds -less grain and 12 pounds less hay than did Lot 1. If, grinding did not in - fluence the corn utilization in Lot 2, then 197 pounds of wheat replaced 252 pounds of corn, saving, therefore, 55 pounds of corn for every 100 pounds of beef produced. The Effect of Winter Rations upon Rate and Economy of Summer Gains. — In a second test- three lots of 14 steers each were placed on feed November 30th and fed for a period of 135 days. During this period they received the following rations. . Lot 1, Shelled corn and alfalfa (both full fed) Lot 2, Corn silage (full fed) and cottonseed cake (1 pound daily), ; Lot 3, Ground corn fodder (full fed) and cottonseed cake (1 pound daily). During the period the steers in Lot 1 made an average gain of 292 pounds, or 2.16 pounds daily. In Lot 2 the gain was 252 pounds per steer, or 1.86 pounds daily. The gain in Lot 3 was 186 pounds per steer, or 1.27 pounds per head daily On the appraised basis the steers in Lot 3 showed the high - est profit, those in Lot 1 the least. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station In order to determine the effect of the different rations mentioned above the three lots were thrown together at the end of the first 135-day feeding period and fed for another 100 days. All lots received the same ration, namely, a full feed of shelled corn and alfalfa hay plus one pound of cotton - seed cake per head daily. In the 100-day feeding period the average gam per steer for the various lots was as follows- Lot 1, 207 pounds; Lot 2, 227 pounds; Lot 3 t 244 pounds, lne cost of gain, which was in direct correlation with the ga l n S 2]v ade ' was as follow s: Lot 1 $10.76, Lot 2 $10.40, and Lot 3 $9.81 per hundred. These prices are based on corn at 70 cents per bushel, cottonseed cake at $50 per ton, and alfalfa nay at $15 per ton. Judged by the actual selling price, all lots showed a loss. In a study of the carcasses the dressing per - centages were : Lot 1, 55.72; Lot 2, 54.34; and Lot 3, 53.70 per cent. Forage Crops for Hogs.— In an effort to determine whether a combination of protein feeds actually was more efficient or whether it simply increased the feed consumption through greater palatabihty, four lots of 56-pound spring pigs were fed on sudan grass pasture for 140 days. Lot 1 was fed shelled corn and tankage. Lot 2 received shelled corn and a mixture of tankage and cottonseed meal, equal parts. Lot 3 received shelled corn and a mixture of tankage and linseed meal, equal parts Lot 4 was fed shelled corn and a mixture of tankage and shorts, equal parts. The four lots were hand - fed, receiving full feed throughout the experiment. The pro - tein mixtures were fed to the various lots in such amounts as to supply the same amount of crude protein in each case. The one year's study indicates that mixtures of protein sup - plements are of primary value from the standpoint of in - effiSf Payability of the ration rather than its A fifth lot was fed the same nation as Lot 1 exceDt thai - it was fed in a dry lot. It soon became aHtoifSSt corn and tankage would not meet all the requirements of young rapidly growing pigs. In order to avert disaster some alfalfa mea * in the ration of L ot 5 after t h e first month. The pigs gained 0.68 pound daily as compared to 1 16 pounds with a similar ration on pasture. The pasture in this S perfect * ° f producin * the P°'k approximately In^another test eight lots of 12 pigs each averatrinc- 7fi pounds were fed different rations whili on Judan £rfss nas W?flS!i fe T Hl S- pe r i 2? continuin * fi -°m June 28, Slo^fo; 105 days. In this test ground wheat proved islightly more </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Forty-fifth Annual Report palatable than corn. The wheat-fed pigs gained 1.19 pounds per day 33 compared with 1.06 pounds where shelled corn was fed. Ground barley was found to be only 84 per cent as efficient as corn: In a corn-and-tankage ration, replacing one - third of the corn with shorts caused the pigs to consume more %ttu not increase their gains above the check lot. Where one-fourth of the grain consisted of ground oats the pigs gained practically as much as where shelled corn comprised the entire grain ration. On a weight basis, ground ™l S P ro ™d t0 be 77 -5 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. Where 50 per cent of the grain ration was made up of ground oats, the. daily gain was reduced. The pigs lacked the finish shown by the other lots. As has been demonstrated in previous trials at this station a mixture of equal parts of cottonseed meal and tankage in - creased, the daily gain, although no material saving of feed was effected by the mixed supplement Rations for Fattening Hogs.— In a 121-day feeding test two lots of 72-pound pigs were used for a comparison of wheat and corn for fattening purposes. Lot 1 received yellow shelled corn and Lot 2 coarsely ground wheat, and the same supplements, namely a mixture of two parts tankage, one part a -it i' 3."? . one £? rt cot t o nseed meal by weight, were used with both lots. The pigs in Lot 1 averaged i daily gain of 1.24 pounds per day. Those in Lot 2 gained 1.32 pounds Dairy By-products for Fattening Hogs.— The : low price of dairy by-products during the year has raised considerable question regarding the fattening value of these feeds. In an attempt to determine their feed values jfchree lots of 71-pound pigjrwere placed on feed December 24 and fed for a period of 110 days. The rations fed were as follows: Lot 1, Shelled corn, tankage, and alfalfa hay, x °J o' Shelled corn, skim milk, and alfalfa hay, Lot 3, Shelled corn, whey, and alfalfa hay. All lots were self-fed; The average daily gains ner ttic- TTi W* X ' l- 5 \P ou " dS; f0r 1-46 pounds; and fof Lot 3, 1.19 pounds. In this particular trial with corn worth 32 cents a bushel, tankage $50 a ton, and alfalfa hay $1™ t sk ' m 1 P llk wa , s wo^h 24 cents per hundredweight and whey 9 cents per hundredweight. Hard l\Soft Endosperm Corn as Pig Feed.— In co-ooera tion with the Agronomy Department two lots of pijrs wero fed for. a period of approximately 70 days to determine the relative feeding value of hard and soft endosperm c™n Lot 1 received Reed's yellow dent corn in the self-feeder anda protein supplement made up of two parts tankage, one part </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station t^^J"^ 1 ' an - d M ne part cottOn seed meal by weight. Lot 2 2£Lf m * a Sim , lIar manner exc ept that they received the dimple dent corn known as cattle corn. The gains were 1 83 pounds per head daily for Lot 1 and 1.74 poundt f orlo?2 Lamb. Feeding.— Under this project two- lines of work Wfc n?K ned °?' T &gt; **? one was a comparison of wheat with other grain rations for fattening lambs Whole wheat was found to be almost as palatable a* slXd corn but^onfy made ?** ** effident as corn in the two feeding trials Ground wheat fed alone was distinctly less palatable than either shelled corn or" whole wheat. It was, hWever?more afaTeJ^rT^h 5?* !«"*&amp;*»* than shelled Torn as a feed for lambs. Grinding wheat to be fed as the onlv grain will be profitable if 100 pounds of it can be grounS S 3 *aS3Si hay. "' ° f 6 " 8 pounds of wheat a «d 8*4 pounds A mixture of ground corn, one part, and ground wheat three parts, produced just as rapid and as economical Tains as shelled corn Such a mixture "will be more prXbleSn shelled corn whenever 75 pounds of wheat is enough cheape? of the m?Se Weig ° f tO Pay f ° r * rindin * 10 ° P^SS In a detailed carcass study of three average corn-fed lambs fndrS 6 wh .°fe wheat -fed lambs, little difference wS &amp;S5 m dressing yields, carcass quality, or payability brPdM^S? S^ U H y 150 aged white - f aced western ewes were tw P ure 5fed Hampshire rams. After the breeding season S,2 dmded lnto three lots of 50 ewes each and fed rS I' n*** 7 F ai " ration before and after lambing. Lot 2, No grain before lambing and heavy grain ration I after lambing, Lot 3, No grain before and after lambing. snl^S+W? We n nin - g the ewes remain i«» in the lots were sold with the following average weights: 150 pounds. 100 pounds, and 91 pounds respectively for Lots 1, 2, and 3 the SSSf pri . c ?,, bein S. ? 2 - 75 ' ?2, and $1 respect ve y? and thl dressing yield varying from 50.2 in Lot 1 to 42.0 for Lot 3 &lt;3 o S. C «fi°T S £ff ectin 9 the Quality and Palatability of Meat — Prison of wCf e - C r pleted dUI J ns the past re™- In a Sn - parison of wheat and corn as a feed for lambs the m^at frnm lambs which received wheat instead of ground corn was fuUy ? i£f qU ? h &amp; S " d palatabilJ ty to that produced with corn BuSn'N? 25^ " in Nebra8ka Station </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Forty-fifth Annual Report In co-operation with the Bureau of Animal Industry, cer - tain lots of hogs were fattened on various rations, some of which contained wheat in comparison with corn. The meat from pigs which had been fattened on ground wheat and ground barley was firmer than meat from those which had been fattened on corn. Slaughter and cooking tests, chemical analyses, and careful tasting of roasts by a trained com - mittee of nine reveal no significant differences in palatability between wheat and corn fed pork: . A second year's work has been completed on a study of the effect of weaning upon the quality and palatability of lamb carcasses. In this study a number of lambs are slaugh - tered at weaning time and others at the end of a definite period and the carcasses from the two lots compared. This part of the project will be closed with the summarizing and publication of results. In co-operation with the Bureau of Animal Industry tests are being carried on to determine the effect of feeding grain to grass-fat two-year-old cattle. A preliminary slaughtering test of some of the grass-fat cattle was made and the car - casses were carefully scored. The remainder of the cattle were put on grain feed to be fed for definite periods. MILLING AND BAKING Preparation and Study of the Cereal Glutelins. — Activities on this project were maintained throughout the year and' consisted chiefly of continued eff ortts to establish reliably the identities and individualities of the several proteins of wheat' gluten, based largely upon the ideas presented in last year's report. It now appears certain, that gluten is composed of at least three types of proteins, instead of only two (gliadin and glutenin) , as has been the accepted belief ever since the pioneer work of T. B. Osborne. These proteins are so highly colloidal in their properties that it has proved extremely difficult to find reliable methods whereby they may be sharply, quantitatively, and reliably separated from each other without undergoing irreversible alterations in their original' properties. The main accomplishment thus far has been the recog - nition, and, within narrow limits, the identification of a third and hitherto unrecognized protein in gluten. This protein constitutes probably from 15 to 20 per cent of the gluten, and is intermediate between gji«din and "glutenin" in both physical and chemical properties. This new protein may, for purposes of cpnvenience, be designated as "mesonin," a term which suggests the "intermediate" character of the pro - tein. . r </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The identities and individualities, respectively, of gliadir and mesonin" may be regarded as established with far ' f^£ te r reliability than is true in the case of "glutenin" Both gliadin and mesonin can be prepared by different meth - ods and modifications of procedure that give, respectively preparations agreeing closely both in physical and chemical properties. With "glutenin," however, slight variattaS Tn procedure yield preparations of varying chemical constitu- Sw- Whether * n f se variations are due to difficulties in nfwwv, a c ? mpl( * 6 .reparation of glutenin from mesonin, or whether glutenin 1S in reality a mixture of several indi - vidual components (as has recently been found true of casein) is the problem now chiefly under consideration. The situa - tion is rendered difficult by limitations in our knowledge of S££; n methods ■«* criteria for establisM^Their A preliminary paper dealing with the general aspects of £r™T S n° f Si SS*1S T 8 g ublished^ Cereal cTelS: try, Vol. 7 pp. 421-427 (September, 1930). A large amount of material is now ready to-be prepared for publication , J/^w^f *°" . 0/ Method* in Experimental Baking Pro - 2SSf^°S T ler ? h ? Pr T Ct haS been acceleratecl by the assignment to this station of a research worker from the American Association of Cereal Chemists. During the vea • for^f- Udl6S h T ha l for their objective the seeding of in - formation regarding the extent to which some of the various factors in experimental baking operate, respectively in °a) influencing the characteristics of the experimental loaf, and (b) in contributing to the substantial variability thkt is generally encountered when different operators perform lab oratory baking tests on the same flour. Some of the more important factors thus far studied have been method ami degree of dough mixing, method of molding, and types o Snd g t°o Ve h nS -f J he m f hOd V - and **«e'of dough mixfng'va found to be the most critical factor, when all other con ditions are specified and controlled. An extensive report of these studies has been prepared and will be published at an S Vors^rf^^f/ reP ° rt SPPeared Cereal Chen? - istry, vol. 8, pp. 64-68 (January, 1931) During the past year a comprehensive study of m-oeressivp changes in pH, volatile arid non-volatile acidity £&gt;d afcohol concentration as produced by prolonged veast fei "mentation compfe^ 0^ ? ****"* T va completed. The purpose was to ascertain whether the rato of production of factors that are known to influence the physical properties of gluten is substantially affected by </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Forty-fifth Annual Report abundance or deficiency in the available supply of fermentable sugars. The data show the rates at which H-ion concentra - tion, volatile and non- volatile acidity, CO 2 , and alcohol, re - spectively, increase over a range of time from 1 to 24 hours, in doughs with initial sugar contents of 0, 2.5, and 10 per cent respectively. In all cases, the pH dropped from an initial value of 6*0-6.2 to approximately 5.0 in from 7 to 8 hour3, and showed no further significant change throughout the re - mainder of the 24-hour period. Conditions ranging from sugar deficiency with a very restricted period of active alco - holic fermentation on the one hand, to |sugar excess with a prolonger period . of active fermentation on the other, did not effect significant differences in the rate of increase in H-ion concentration in the dough. Total, volatile, and non - volatile acidity and also alcohol reached higher concentra - tions in the doughs containing excess sugar than in the ones to which no sugar was added. These differences, however, were of no consequence within the limits of time ordinarily employed for dough fermentation in commercial bake shops. The results indicate conclusively that under ordinary bak - ing conditions, "fermentation tolerance" in terms of time is a function of the gas production rather than of gas retention factor, and that the ability of a flour to withstand prolonged fermentation can be regulated by the amount of sugar used in the baking procedure. PLANT DISEASES A Study of Spindle Tuber and Combinations of Spindle Tuber with other Degeneration Diseases.— No experimental work was clone under this project, during the past year. The results of the data obtained thus far were analyzed and a por - tion of them published in Research Bulletin No. 53, "Infec - tion Experiments with Spindle Tuber and Unmottled Curly Dwarf of the Potato." This, together with Research Bulletin No. 47, issued last year, on the symptoms of these two dis - eases, completes the phases of the problem that were under ■ investigation. In Research Bulletin No. 53 the results of insect surveys and insect inoculation experiments are reported in addition to results of artificial inoculation, transmission by seed piece contact and cutting knife and the effect of various treatments both chemical and physical upon such transmission, transmis - sion by picker planters, the rate of spread of the virus through the tubers in storage, and the effect of dilution and heat upon the virus. An Inquiry into the Pathological and Physiological Aspects of Alfalfa Faihires ifl Nebraska. — A part of the work done </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ■I mmsm diseases. The soil of the farm I Practices upon these and heavily infested with both U " d *- 0 be uni formly </seg>
            <seg id="p037">. Forty-fifth Annual Report fection from the soil. Such seed-treatment studies cannot be conducted on this experiment farm. Treatment of the soil with a number of different chemicals and proprietary com - pounds failed to decrease the amount of scab even when applied at rates in excess of those that could be practically employed. A Fruit Disease Investigations.— The work under this pro - ject during the past year was largely confined to a study ot the cherry leaf spot disease caused by Coccomyces hiernalus. The effect of weather conditions upon this disease and the time of application and types of spray used to control it nave been studied by recording the percentage and severity ot leaf infection and the extent of defoliation. The results obtained to date were presented in a paper to the Horticul - tural Society of Nebraska at their annual meeting. POTATOES Potato Selection for Seed Purposes.— One hundred tuber lines of Triumph potatoes were increased to quantities rang - ihg from 5 to 50 bushels each. These strains were selected from individual indexed tubers because of differences in time of, maturity (a range of about 6 weeks for the extreme lines) Detail tests of 30 tuber lines were made by planting all in replicated plots during late May and June. Factors considered have been total yield, size of tubers, tuber shape, freedom from knobs and second growth, susceptibility to scab and other diseases, and susceptibility to cracking at harvest - ing time. Tests conducted at Alliance in 1930 indicated that in long growing seasons the later-maturing strains produce the greatest yield but the tuber type is not as good as in the early-maturing lines. Scab prevalence appears to be affected more by environmental conditions, when tubers are suscep - tible, than by inherited or tuber-line differences. Time of planting was a factor of far greater consequence with regard to scab than the tuber line. Early strains planted late gave more desirable results than" late strains planted early. A further study of seed-potato production in eastern and central Nebraska confirmed the earlier results that good seed stock can be grown from disease-free seed. The tuber-indexing work' is being continued with about 30 selected lines. These tuber-indexed lots are being increased at the Box Butte Experiment Farm. In a three-year study at Alliance, shallow planting, provided the covering is ade - quate, has given more satisfactory results than deep plant - ing. Further data on see'd-potato storage were obtained. A Study of Degeneracy in Seed-potato Stocks. — Several phases of this project were studied during the past year. At </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station North PJatte seed potatoes were produced by early plantings on dry. land in 1929. When this seed stock was tested fn SXSST PH H tS JP 19 i° the u^rly-harvest e d seed lots we re rnf nff nwS rOduCtlV 2 those from which the ™es were ?he fidd SnS e n, a f m h e dat Tvf n , d^ he tubers not removed from tne field. until October. The latter were in turn slieh'lv mnr P productive than the tubers harvested in Octobe? from v™es allowed to grow to full maturity. At Alliance with normal seed stock free from virus dis eases, t,me of planting, time of harvesting, Sid tTme of cutting off vines did not appear to be a factor of significant consequence insofar as yield from the tubers the followfn' S^TffiS^™ second SW £ffi£ 3S havSilp?^ 61181 ? tGStS - in Nebraska and southern states have failed to reveal any significant differences in vieldimr £rX,W f W6en dry - ] 2? d and irri^ted seed potatoes when produced from virus-disease-free seed 1 -vJ r i! UmP V^ bers are very sus ceptible to cracking while be - ing harvested, percentages of 5 being very common ami oV not infrequent. These cracks are very deep Tserxe L source of infection for rot-producing organisms J num ber of tests were made during the hafvestfng Son of S to determine when and where the most cracking occurs an how it might be prevented. Standard testing 1th were a r n eiul t r er l6ngth ° f Cracks we^Sd^ Immature and turgid potatoes were found more suscep - tible to cracking than more mature or less turgid tubers Large tubers cracked more easily than small tubers Tubers were more likely to crack if dropped on the edge than on thP apical end and least of all on theflat top or bottom " u, fac» rpste? eXP + ° Sed tO , - he air for a few hours developed mucb a sack the cracking increased rapidly as the heient of «,» drop mcreased Microscopic studies aiereveaHnf the fact face CUTS *" *"**" ap P arent^ ™ore slowly^thaS sur- POULTRY • \ Study of the Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins, in Poultry Feeding.— This project is co-operative between th« Departments of Chemistry and Poultry^Durlng Ihe past </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Forty-fifth Annual Report year the work has consisted of laying the ground work for comparative slaughter tests. These tests, which will serve as a check on results previously obtained, involve the determina - tion of total nitrogen, calcium, phosphorus, and crude fat of chicks at different ages. A sufficiently large number of individuals were used at each slaughter weight to reduce the variability to a minimum. To simplify the matter of analyses of individuals or to permit the accurate pooling of samples the procedure of hydrolyz - ing the entire chick by means of concentrated hydrochloric acid was adopted. This procedure permits a rough determ - ination of crude fat by a modified Werner-Schmidt procedure. Nitrogen can be accurately estimated on aliquots of the hydro - lysate via Kjeldahl, and other aliquot portions may be taken tor calcium and phosphorus after subsequent destruction of organic matter with nitric acid. The initial study was made on newly hatched chicks, sacri - ficed before food was taken. With respect to nitrogen, which is generally looked upon as a measure of the protein content, 54 chicks varying in weight from 31.5 to 44.1 grams contained an average of 2.55 per cent of nitrogen. The coefficient of variability was about 4.5 per cent, indicating that the amount of protein in baby chicks can be rather accurately calculated by assuming a nitrogen content of 25.5 milligrams per gram of live weight. A determination of fat on 43 of the 54 chicks showed an average of 7.4 per cent. For calcium and phos - phorus it is necessary to make analyses on composite samples because of the small amounts of these elements present. Pre - liminary work indicates that these figures will be around 0.25 per cent for phosphorus and 0.35 per cent for calcium. Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks. — This project is co-operative between the Departments of Poultry and Chemistry. Further work has been done in determining the calcium and phosphorus of the blood plasma and the ash content of the bones of chicks in the different experimental lots. A bulletin on "Protein Utilization by Chicks" is being prepared, and a" paper on "Effect of Yeast Additions to Cer - tain Rations for Baby Chicks" will appear shortly in Poultry Science. During the year a study was made of the growth-promoting value of several oat products for growing chicks. Two hun - dred chicks per lot were used in order to minimize the possible error of chance selection. For these experiments a standard chick mash formula, complete for all known vita - min, mineral, and protein essentials, was used. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station- To 80 units of standard chick rations 20 units of an oat product, adjusted with starch to a protein level of 11 per cent, were added. Each ration, therefore, contained 2.2 per cent of oatj proteins and a total protein content of 16 per cent. In the test pulverized oats, germinated oats (dried and pulverized)^ hulless oats, pulverized oat groats, and pulver - ized oat groats plus 2 per cent agar "agar were compared. A difference was found in the growth-promoting value of oat groats and I pulverized oats. The explanation is unknown at this time. The conclusion of the entire test was that as much as 20 per cent of finely pulverized oats can safely be included in rations for growing chicks and also that one is not justified in paying a premium for oat groats to be used for that pur - pose. In another study experiments were conducted to get more detailed information on the effect of varying the Ca-P ratio of a practical chick ration. The ration used contained 6.817 per cent of ash of which calcium represented 0.88 and phos - phorus 0.79 per cent. The Ca-P ratio of this ration was there - fore 1:0.9. The basal ration apparently contained sufficient calcium and phosphorus for normal growth and calcification, when chicks were provided with direct sunshine and vitamin D. Normal calcification occurred on a ration containing 0.88 per cent Ca and 0.79 per cent P when antirachitic essentials were pro - vided. A calcium-phosphorus ratio of 1 to 2 was evidently not read - ily tolerated by the growing chick even when antirachitic re - quirements were fully satisfied. In practical experience one would very rarely use a ration with a Ca-P ratio as extreme as 1 to 2. In a comparison of the nutritive value of dried buttermilk, dried skim milk, 'and dried whey, there was no evidence of special nutritive value to be accredited to dried whey as compared to dried buttermilk when fed to growing chicks at the same level of protein intake. A significant difference in the growth-promoting value of dried buttermilk and dried skim milk fed at the same pro - tein level was observed. The results are favorable to dried buttermilk. Turkey Production. — The study of the effect of variations in weight loss of turkey eggs on the growth rate of poults hatched was continued during the year. Three hundred and thirty-six turkey eggs of approximately the same size (80 to 90 grams initial weight) were incubated in a standard cabinet incubator with temperature, humidity, and air movement / </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Forty-fifth Annual Report under control. Each egg was weighed accurately at the be - ginning of the incubation period, and on the eighth, sixteenth, and twenty-fourth days of incubation. The first significant observation was that there is a great variation in the weight loss of eggs of the same size kept under the same conditions of humidity, temperature, and air movement. The eggs varied in their weight loss from 9.61 to 26.29 per cent of the original weight. Each fertile egg was basketed so that the poult hatched could be identified with the egg from which it hatched. The poults were carefully brooded and were given an excellent ration so that growth conditions were favorable. Weights on the twenty-eighth day do not indicate any correlation be - tween the weight loss sustained during incubation and the inherent vitality of the poult if the growth rate during the first four- weeks is the measure of this quality. RURAL ECONOMICS Cost of Producing Farm Crops.— This work is carried on in co-operation with farmers. Record books are furnished for keeping accurate records of costs. During the past year farm record books were kept by 176 farms on the cost of wheat production, 229 on the cost of corn production, and 29 on the cost of operating tractors. For 1931 the number is considerably higher in each case. Most of the records are being kept in eight counties. The farmer keeps a record of the hours of man labor, horse labor, machine labor, and other production costs. The charge for the use of the land is the share of the crop usually given for rent. These cost-of-pro - duction records are of value for comparing the efficiency of different methods and different farmers in any given area, and for comparing the cost of producing any given crop in different areas. Economic Studies in Price, Volume of Production, and the Purcfiasing Power of Farm Products. — Work was continued in a study of the prices paid for corn, wheat, oats, hogs, butterfat, eggs, and potatoes at different Nebraska points during the past 35 years. These data are being analyzed and prepared for publication. Cost and Standards of Living on Nebraska Farms. — During the past year data on some phases of this project were an - alyzed, and a bulletin, "Housing and House Operation Costs on Nebraska Farms," was prepared for printing. Another manuscript on standards of living has been presented for publication. With the publication of this material the project will be closed. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station date and have been SS to?S?r l-S Ve been brought U P to mation, as the basis for the ma w? ° Urrent market infor " the "Nebraska Economic SituSioS » P re f n * ed monthly in has been made to determine if Z^ihiP 'F 18 , ° f Such data operating costs and financial -reSit 4 4 f f qui P men t on mit an insight into the finn^-i e com P lete data per - vators since 1918 financial progress of farmers' ele- Farm Organization and Farm Cost* Tb* i ' Ji « Sj5^JS^jy£?r^-J^' «. project co-operating with the ExpertS StS S"? fa ™« are cords of Uvestoc* SSSS ™SuS </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Forty-fifth Annual Report state serum plant During the year hog cholera was reported from different parts of the state, but nothing serious developed. The prompt administration of serum and virus confined the disease to the immediate neighborhoods. The past twelve months have been about normal from the hog-chblera standpoint. The plant experienced no difficulty in filling all orders promptly and kept a liberal supply of serum in storage for an emergency. The policy of buying serum subject to retest and manufacturing most of its own virus has been contniued. The retail price for blood serum was 60 cents per hundred c.c. until May 1st, when it was reduced to 55 cents. Clear concentrated serum retailed at 75 cents unil May 1st, when it was reduced to 65 cents. Virus sold at $1.50 per hundred c.c. throughout the year. Following is a report of the serum and virus sales by months, and a statement showing- the financial status as of January 1, 1932. . . : Cubic centimeters Serum on hand January 1st, 1931 9,164,200 Serum purchased and delivered during 1931 4,154,87f&gt; Total serum handled for year 13,319,075 Serum and virus sold by months: ■ • Serum Virus c.c. c.c. January 196,700 12,425 February 104,200 , 6,535 March 79,975 5,670 April 174,100 12,670 ■•■I: May 762,150 55,520 ■■!'. June ...1,651,775 112,250 July 982,825 61,410 August 1,473,925 88,440 September 577,875 33,810 October 275,275 1 19,440 : November : 317,575 22,025 December 285,500 20,220 Total sold.... 6,881,875 450,415 Used by plant ■.: 33,925 5,000 Total 6,915,800 455,415 Serum on hand January 1st, 1932. 6,403,275 c.c. Total gross sales from all sources ., $46,680.26 Money collected and receipted for 49,647.87 Cash balance January 1st, 1932, according to re - port of bursar $ 72,434.61 Value stock invoice January 1st, 1932 :... 34,366.38 Accounts payable 250.00 Total assets ; $107,000.99 Pigs used in retesting serum and making virus 385 Number of orders for year 2,822 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station north platte substation . The work of the North Platte Substation has been con - tinued along the usual lines. With the addition of Mr. Marvel L. Baker to the staff of technically trained men, more emphasis has been placed on experiments with livestock. Agronomy. — The growing season of 1930 was unusually favorable for crop production. The amount of precipitation, both seasonal and annual, was well above normal, and its dis - tribution fair. Temperatures were above normal, but not excessively. Evaporation and wind movement were below normal. Yields of all crops, especially cereals, were well above aver - age. Winter wheat made the highest average yield on record. Yields of later crops such as corn, potatoes, and sorghum were somewhat reduced by the dry period extending from the last week in June to the third week of August. Some moisture was carried over from 1930, which, with timely rains, has given fair promise for the 1931 crop of small grain. The prospects for corn are not good. Crop Rotation and Tillage Method. — The crop-rotation anil tillage-method studies in co-operation with the United States Bureau of Plant Industry, Office of Dry Land Agriculture, have been in continuous operation for 25 years. A study of the records appears to justify the following conclusions. (1) Moisture is he chief limiting factor in crop production. (2) Tillage sufficient to control weed growth and to keep the sur - face broken enough so that moisture can penetrate readily. is essential. (3) Tillage in excess of these requirements may be harmful to root development of intertilled crops and may promote soil blowing in open areas. (4) Differences between good and poor tillage increase as the effects of weed control under good and weed infestation under poor tillage accumu - late. (5) The rate of fertility reduction is slow. (6) The effect of manuring with stable manure or green crops in - creases with the length of time the land is under cultivation. On account of vegetative stimulation and increased water re - quirements, grain yields are lowered when moisture later becomes inadequate and increased when moisture is plenti - ful. Crop Improvement. — Eight years' data covering the several phases of plant, breeding involved in the improvement of small grains, corn, and sorghum have been secured in the co-operative cereal project. The records show that while the majority of small grain varieties tested are inferior, there is little difference in yield among the better strains. A very high-yielding and stiff-strawed barley. has been selected and </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Forty-fifth Annual Report a pure-line wheat excellent in milling quality and yield has been produced. Adapted varieties of corn have given better results than hybrids under dry-land conditions. Under irri - gation, hybrids offer more promise. Pump Irrigation. — During- the growing season of 1930, 45 acres of land were watered by pump irrigation. A total of 761 acre-inches of water was pumped at an average of 57.62 cents per acre-inch. The increased yields from irrigation this year were: for corn 66 bushels, potatoes 105 bushels, anS alfalfa 0.72 ton per acre. Beef Cattle. — Purebred herds of both Hereford and Short - horn cattle are maintained. During the past year three ex - periments in feeding beef cattle have been carried on. Coi n, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Calves. — Five lots of twelve 327-pound grade Hereford steer calves were fed for a -205-day period. All lots received alfalfa hay. No diges - tive difficulties were experienced from including either wheat or rye in the ration. When ground these were equally pala - table, and about 90 per cent as efficient as shelled corn. A mixture of equal parts of shelled corn and ground wheat was practically equal to shelled corn in every respect. The results of this experiment have been published as Experiment Station Bulletin No. 263. This experiment will be repeated during the coming year. Creep-feeding Calves. — Six lots of ten calves each were on pasture with their dams from May 15 to October 9. Two lots of steer calves and one lot of heifers were fed shelled corn in creeps after May 23. The steer calves gained 37 pounds per head more than similar calves which did not receive grain. They ate 3.56 bushels of corn per head, making 10.39 pounds extra gain for each bushel of corn consumed. The heifers ate 2.6 bushels of corn each and gained 16 pounds per head more than the check lot of heifer calves, or slightly more than 6 pounds for each bushel of corn eaten. One lot of steer calves ate 0.9 bushel of corn per head and gained 7 pounds per head more than the calves in the check lot, or a gain of 7.7 pounds per bushel of corn. All of these calves were weaned October 9 and will be full-fed on shelled corn and alfalfa until ready for market. It is planned to continue this project. The Use of Alfalfa Pasture for Fattening Cattle. — This work was a continuation of the project begun in 1929. Year - ling heifers were full-fed shelled corn on alfalfa hay in a dry lot. The results indicate that it is entirely practical to feed cattle on alfalfa pasture. It is planned to continue this pro - ject for at least another year. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Hogs.— The station maintains a herd of purebred Durocs which supplies the pigs necessary for experimental work Studies on the feeding value of wheat, rye, and proso com - pared with corn for fattening hogs have been made during the past year. Ground wheat has proved to be slightly supe - rior to shelled corn for fattening hogs. Ground rye and ground proso were practically equal in efficiency, having ap - proximately 85 per cent of the value of shelled corn, pound for pound. Tankage or a mixed protein supplement con - taining tankage was used in all feeding experiments. Sheep. — A flock of about 60 grade Rambouillet ewes is maintained as a farm flock. Data on the cost of maintaining such a flock and the returns from it are being secured. Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Lambs. — During the year two tests were carried on in a comparison of corn, wheat, and rye for fattening lambs. The results of these experiments are published as Bulletin No. 256. This work will be con - tinued during the coming year. Dairy. — The dairy herd of Holstein cattle has been main - tained at its usual number of about 50 head with about 25 to 30 cows in milk. The last ten years have given, as the result of proper methods of breeding and handling, a herd of one-fourth fewer cows in number producing one-fifth morp milk. This demonstration in herd building and in the sani - tary production of milk has been of much value to both the producer and the consumer of milk throughout this region. The open-shed method of handling dairy cows, successfully used at this station for more than 15 years, is apparently gaining favor throughout the country. At North Platte the cows are stanchioned only while being milked and while eat - ing their ration of grain and silage. They have free access to an open shed kept, dry and well bedded, where there is ample room for all cows to lie down at will. Alfalfa hay is always available for them in the open. During a very stormy, cold day the doors of the shed may be closed and hay fed inside. This has not occurred more than twice during the average winter at North Platte. Poultry. — Flocks of White Leghorns, Buff Orpingtons, and Rhode Island Reds totaling 750 hens " are maintained as demonstration flocks. Mammoth Bronze turkeys are also pro - duced by the station. During the summer of 1930 young turkeys on alfalfa range gained 7.6 pounds per head in sixty - two days. During this period they consumed 10.24 pounds of grain and 7.0 pounds of mash per head. During the same period a similar lot of young turkeys confined in large runs </seg>
            <seg id="p047">» Forty-fifth Annual Report made a gain of 6.26 pounds per head on a feed consumption of 9.9 pounds of grain and 12.0 pounds of mash. Horticulture and Forestry. — Conifers. — Growing conifers from seed indicates that the source of the seed is more im - portant than the species and should be given careful con - sideration. Seed of the Western Yellow pine secured from native Nebraska trees has given much more vigorous growth and apparently a more desirable tree than much of the seed produced in other regions. The tip-moth continues as the chief enemy of this species and because of it Austrian and Scotch are more promising. Scotch makes faster early growth than Austrian but may not prove the better tree in the »nd. During the past year a few Black Hills spruce of the older plantings died. A very late severe freeze followed by an unusually dry season probably caused the loss. There was also some loss among the older Jack pines. About 17,000 three-year-old conifers were set in the canyon land. Owing to the extremely dry season, only a. small percentage of the spring's planting survived. Some four-year-old stock will be tried in 1932. .Deciduous Trees. — The Chinese elm has been under close observation on the station farm since 1915. The chief value of the Chinese elm lies in its quick growth, dense foliage, and habit of holding its leaves late in the fall. There is just enongh evidence of a lack of permanency to cause the con - servative horticulturist to proceed with caution. The late spring freeze that damaged other species did not injure this species. Evidence to date indicates that late fall irrigation should be guarded against. Forest Plantation. — The forest planting set on the table land in 1908 and the years following is assuming the appear - ance of the old "tree claim" plantings made many years ago. Probably a deficiency in moisture is the cause of the death of the trees. Black Locust, Catalpa, and Osage Orange have not proved worthy of consideration in this region. The Hackberry is quite satisfactory in favorable locations and is one of the best lawn trees. The Orchard. — During the past year all of the plum trees were killed back to the trunk or larger limbs. Many fruit spurs on the apples were killed. No fruit was produced. Ornamentals.-^New varieties are being tried as they appear. A few of the native kinds are quite promising. There is a rather wide range of evergreens that are ap - parently satisfactory for ornamental planting. The bush honeysuckle, considered one of the hardiest shrubs, was ' severely injured by the late spring freeze. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station scottsbluff substation The work at this station is carried on in co-operation with the Office of Western Irrigation Agriculture of the United States Department of Agriculture.. The crop year of 1930 was favorable for crop production and average yields were obtained. The spring of 1931 was decidedly unfavorable and gives promise of low yields. Many fields of beets and pota - toes had to be irrigated before the crops came up and many poor stands were obtained. One hundred sixty acres of ad - ditional land have been procured for the station. Sixty-three acres are irrigated land, 40 acres can be irrigated by the pumping system, and the rest cannot be irrigated Experi - mental work was begun on this tract in the spring of 1931. Crop Rotat ions.— The crop-rotation work has 132 one-quar - ter acre plats divided into 46 different cropping systems A part of this work was begun in 1912: In the older rotations the past year's work bore out the evidence of previous years The outstanding difference in yields is due to the beneficial effect of alfalfa and sweet clover in the rotatoin, or from applications of barnyard manure. These differences have been consistent throughout the experiment. The plats that have received no manure or have never pro - duced alfalfa or sweet clover gave much higher yields during the first three years than they did the last three years show - ing that fertility has declined. The manured plats and the plats previously in alfalfa or sweet clover yielded about the same, or a slight increase during the last period. The varia - tion in yields, therefore, from these differently treated plats is accounted for largely by a decreased yield from the plats n °t -having alfalfa nor sweet clover nor receiving manure rather than to an increase from manure, alfalfa or swee* - clover. If the results of the first five years of the crop rotations are omitted and the average yields for the later years are compared, the beneficial effect of manure and the legume crops is especially apparent. In many .cases the yields have been doubled by growing legumes or by applications of manure. • • ■ In the spring of 1931 work in horticulture was undertaken in a study of the possibility of growing canning crops. Sev - eral varieties each of sweet corn, tomatoes, peas, beans, spinach, and asparagus are being studied and also such garden crops as onions, cabbage, cauliflower, and celery. Additional varieties of fruit were also set in the orchard during the current spring. Some trees were lost from sun scald and some pear trees from blight. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Forty-fifth Annual Report Lamb Feeding.— During the year 13 lots of 25 lambs each were fed for a period of 70 days in a comparison of corn and wheat with various supplements. In addition to the grain ration the lambs were fed one pound of silage per lamb per day and as much alfalfa hay as they would eat. The gains during the 70 days ranged in the various lots from 22.1 pounds to 27.0 pounds per lamb and the feed cost from $1.13 to $1.49 per lamb. The market was such that all lots showed a loss at selling. This is the second year of work in this experiment. The summary of the two years' results show wheat, when fed alone, to be less effective for feeding lambs than corn fed alone. A mixture of wheat and corn was approximately equal to corn. Mixtures of wheat and corn were better than mix - tures of wheat and barley, or wheat and dried pulp. Beef Calves. — The past year completed the third year of study of the cost of wintering beef calves. The costs for the year are shown in the following table. | Gain | Cost of winter feed Lot per Pe^i Per~100~ No. Ration and amount fed per Calf | ca |f ca ]f ]b s _ gain 1 i 2044 lbs. alfalfa hay 125 $10.79 $8.64 2 1513 lbs. alfalfa hay and tops from | 5.9 tons of beets 190 9.93 5.22 3 I 1873 lbs. alfalfa hay and 329 lbs. pulp 177 ' 12.82 7.24 4 : 128G lbs. alfalfa hay and 2059 lbs. silage -. 172 11.05 6.42 5 1 4538 lbs. silage and 122 lbs. cotton ca ke 215 12.12 5.G4 A summer feeding test of three lots of steers is being carried on, to compare the feeding value of wheat in various grain mixtures. The grain rations for the various lots were: Lot 1, equal parts of corn and wheat ; Lot 2, equal parts corn, wheat, and barley; and Lot 3, equal parts wheat and barley. On full feed the steers received 15 pounds of the grain mix - ture, 1 pound of cottonseed cake and 15 pounds of silage per head. All received alfalfa hay. The steers in all lots are making satisfactory gains. Dairying. — The work with the dairy herd was continued along lines previously reported. The herd is divided into two lots, one receiving one pound of grain for each four pounds of milk produced, the other lot receiving no grain. The cows were divided as equally as possible according to age and pro - duction. The lot receiving grain has produced about 20 per cent more milk and butterfat than the other lot. When the </seg>
            <seg id="p050">NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION VALENTINE SUBSTATION years' work on the hard land twn S th^ Statlon and ei^ ht ||f° J5«2 &amp;ys ftias winter rye 8 6 bu ° ,,ri» S- r * n i ' ; spll " e whcat 5 - 8 &gt;&gt;u.; 6.8 bu.; ernme,. 56'b,, * ' ° b "- : oats I08 "■•! barley .mSiSta"^^ StK ?i VC " f «='-tu, ns than sag sand Hiits •■ fsi^^fasss: sS ,.ve youn8; fl . ui t trees l^^S'^^'gJgag^ BOX BUTTE EXPERIMENT FARM the couTtf Affi£2. ! of SS 1 R % in co -°P e^tion with missioners furnSSin? the ff n ?^ Pk**?, ,?° Unty ' the CO1" - was begun in the sSrinl of l^n , i buildl ?? s - The work study of the agroK? ptbSs SdffiW thT 1 " J? a </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Forty-fifth Annual Report Permanent plats have been laid out for certain studies of crop rotation and cultural practices. Varietal studies are also being made. The season of 1930 was favorable and good yields of all crops were obtained. CHANGES IN STAFF During the fiscal year a number of changes in the staff have taken place. Mr. O. J. Trenary was appointed Assist - ant in Agricultural Engineering, effective July 1, 1930. C. B. McGrath was appointed Instructor in Animal Pathology and Hygiene, effective October 1, 1930. Dr. McGrath took the place of H. M. Martin, resigned. A. D. Weber resigned eflective June 30, 1931, and M. A. Alexander was appointed in his place. L. B. Snyder was appointed' in place of J. 0. Rankin in the Department of Rural Economics. A. E. Ander - son was on leave during the entire year, T. H. Goodding for the second semester, and Professor H. C. Filley for part of the year. J. .0. Gulbertson was appointed temporarily in Mr. Anderson's place, and P. J. Olson in Mr. Goodding's place. LEGISLATION The legislature which met in January, 1931, passed no legislation affecting the work of the Experiment Station ex - cept in the matter of appropriations. The maintenance appropriation for the University was somewhat lower than for the previous biennium. The proportion of the reduction falling to the Experiment Station was approximately $4,000 for the year. The legislature appropriated $15,000 for permanent im - provements at the North Platte Substation, and $75,000 for rebuilding the Animal Husbandry building, which had been partially destroyed by fire, and the building of a fireproof seed house. " ADDITIONAL LAND, BUILDINGS, AND EQUIPMENT During the last year a dairy calf barn costing approxi - mately $12,000 was built at the main station at Lincoln. At North Platte a residence for the Station Agronomist was completed. This cottage cost approximately $6,000. Some new fences were built to provide experimental pas - tures, and a watering system was installed to provide water in them. At Scottsbluff, 160 acres additional land was procured. Of this approximately .65 acres can be irrigated from the ditch and 40 acres more by pumping. An addition to the superintendent's residence is being built at. a cost of approxi - mately $2,000. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station PUBLICATIONS OF THE LAST FISCAL YEAR +%£S3&amp;&amp;i£^^. for the \ fiscal year — l l.l^So^i 1 RePOrt&gt; Presented t0 th * Governor February BULLETINS w.t. 25 &amp; P "™f, ?s?» y 'ts s^" Wo » e ™ E ™- : a «■ 5,000 of pL B ""' S " H °« F »"- Wnv J. Looffel. October. 1 B30. Lewis. March, 1931. 5,000 copies. w ana r* u - T 2 55, Nebraska Tractor Tests, 1920-1930. Board of Tractor No. 257, "Wheat for Fattening Lambs. A. D Weber and Wm I Loeffel. April, 1931. 10,000 copies. ' ™' J - No. 258, The Contribution of Nebraska Farnf Women to Familv It, SXTef End ° airy Pr ° dUCtS - M - Ruth May f ll f93i: : RESEARCH BULLETINS 19?0°: toM S copL 0f Ker ° Sene C °° k StOVeS " Ed^B.Snyder. July, S^ne 49 i T v2n I pv d -iS e Ti f T^ V M n v Uber f uIosi8 in Mamm als other than w eM m nj n i^ M - Martln - August, 1930. 5,000 copies N.h 0 ,; t°' e « F °« d abit 5 Of t J le Rine-necked Pheasant in Central Nebraska. M. H. Swenk. November, 1930. 3,000 copies ,n$,?\- S1 : B . reedl ?e Winter Wheat for Resistance to Stinkine Smut d r e^ a fem a bfr, r i'^ A " Ki -lbach and Arth^ur 8^ No. 53, Infection Experiments with Spindle Tuber and Unmottled Curly Dwarf of the Potato. R. W. Goss. February, 1931. 3,000 copies: No. 54, The Vitamin A Content of the Milk of Holstein Ayrshire Se ?ooT d ?^ r n nsey . Cows - H - P - Davis and !• L. Hathaway. Febru^ &lt;*ry, ixtai. o,uuu copies. No 55 Utilization of Proteins by the Growing Chick. F. E. Mussehl and C. W. Ackerson. May, 1931. 6,000 copies. P N B°ru 5 n% A M^^il^OO^cS 1168 - Ed " a B " ™* M ° rt »" </seg>
            <seg id="p053">. Forty-fifth Annual Report circulars No. 40, A Manual for Hog Raisers. Wm. J. Loeffel. September, 1930. 10,000 copies. TECHNICAL PAPERS Blish, M. J. The Gluten and Non-Gluten Proteins. Cereal Chem. 7:421-427. Sept., 1980. . Blish, M. J. Report on Experimental Baking Tests. Jour. Assoc. Official Agr. Chemists. 13:458-466. Nov., 1930. Blish, M. J. Report on Glutenin in Wheat Flour. Jour. Assoc. Official Agr. Chemists. 13:442-443. Nov., 1930. Keim, F. D. Is There Anything Better Than Blue Grass for Lawns? Ann. Rep. Nebr. State Hort. Soc. Jan., 1930. Keim, F. D. Trends in Agriculture and Soil Fertility. Twenty-sec - ond Ann. Rep. Nebr. Crop Growers' Assoc. Jan., 1931. Kiesselbach, T. A. The Use of Advanced Generation Hybrids as Parents of Double Cross Seed Corn. Jour. American Soc. of Agron. Vol. 22, No. 7. July, 1930. Kiesselbach, T. A. .Progress Report on Corn Hybrids. Twenty-sec - ond Ann. Rep. Nebr. Corn Growers' Assoc. . Jan., 1931. Kiesselbach, T. A. and Culbertson, J. O. Analysis of the Effect of Diplodia Infection and Treatment of Seed Corn. Jour. Agr. Research. Vol. 42, No. 11, pp. 723-749. June, 1931. Merritt, P. P. Preliminary Report of the A. A. C. C. Research Fellow in Experimental Baking Test Cereal Chem. 8:64-68. Jan., 1931. Mussehl, F. E. and Ackerson, C. W. Anti-rachitic Value of S-l Lamp Radiation for Chicks. Poultry Sci., 10-68-70. Jan., 1931. Reichart, E. L. How Freezing Conditions Are Influenced. Ice Cream Field, p. 148. April, 1931. Reichart, E. L. Factors Affecting Freezing Conditions. Ice Cream Rev., pp. 52-53. May, 1931. Roberts, R. Seven New Names of the Genus Tiphia (Hymenoptera, Scoliidae). Canadian Entomologist, 62:189-190. Aug., 1930. Russel, J. C. Do Commercial Fertilizers Pay on Nebraska Farms? Twenty-second Ann. Rep. Nebr. Crop Growers' Assoc. Jan., 1931. •Swenk, M. ■ H. Codling Moth Investigations for 1929. Ann. Rep. of the Nebr. State Hort. Soc, pp. 27-46. Dec.,- 1930. Swenk, M. H. The Rose-Breasted and Black-Headed Grosbeaks Hybridize. Wilson Bulletin, 42:289-290. Dec, 1930. Van Es, L. Reflexions on the Diseases of the New-born. Rep. Eleventh Internat. Vet. Congress, London. 1930. Van Es, L. Remarks on Avian Tuberculous Infection in Mammals. Proc. Thirty-fourth Annual Meeting, U. S. Livestock San. Assoc, Chi - cago. 1930. Van Es, L. The Metabolic Diseases of Bone. Proc Nebr. Vet. Med. Assoc, Lincoln. 1930. Werner, H. O. Some Distinct Tuber Line Strains in Triumph Potatoes— A Preliminary Report. Proc. Potato Assoc. of America, pp. 132-133. Dec, 1930. Wiggans, C, C. Grapes in the Missouri Valley. Technical Paper No. 99, Ann. Rep. of the Kansas State Hort. Soc. 1930. Yocum, W. W. The 1929 Spray Experiments at Shubert. Ann. Rep. Nebr. State Hort. Soc, pp. 45-51. 1930. 857571 A </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT OF MONEY RECEIVED FROM THE UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal Ma a r r ch n 2 ded 188 U 7 e 81 -™*" act ° f Congress apVovel March 2, 1887. Total $15,000.00 _ , . Expenditures For salaries $15,000.00 Total ; ...: ....$15,000.00 ADAMS FUND Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1931, under act of Congress, ap - proved March 16, 1906. Total ..$15,000,00 Expenditures For salaries $15,000.00 f _ TotaI :■••■■•- ■■■■■■ $15,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON January 27, 1932. Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Forty-fifth Annual Report . purnell fund Receipts Received by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer of the University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal year ended June 30, 1931, under act of Congress approved February 24, 1925. Total "* $60,000.00 SALARIES . E*P«»*t»re. Regular :....$39,449.45 Temporary 3,153.66 Total $42,603.11 SUPPLIES Office supplies $ 68.35 Laboratory supplies '. 2,119.93 Educational and recreational 62.99 Janitor and barn supplies 16.35 Feeding stuffs _ 5,039.78 Agricultural supplies , 213.95 Total $ 7,521.35 EXPENSE Office expense and postage $ 10.53 Freight, express, and drayage 66.85 Water, heat, light, power and fuel... 90.98 Public printing, advertising, and photography 1,875.65 Traveling expense 1,800.07 Rentals 9.60 Special and temporary services 2,268.90 Miscellaneous , 1 4.07 Total : $ 6,126.65 REPAIRS Equipment $ 357.61 Total $ 357.61 EQUIPMENT Furniture and fixtures $ 724.99 Apparatus (labor and equipment).... 1,902.64 Livestock 304.50 Machinery .. ; ... ; 322.41 Books 49.91 Total $ 3,304.45 LANDS AND BUILDINGS Land improvements $ 86.83 Total $ 86.83 GRAND TOTAL $60,000.00 Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON, January 27, 1932. Finance Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ■ FINANCIAL STATEMENT Statement of expenditures for the Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of Nebraska for the year ending June 30, 1931 (exclusive of Federal funds), including expenditures for central sta - tion at Lincoln, and substations at North Platte, Scottsbluff, Valentine, Union, and Alliance. SALARIES AND WAGES Regular $82,313.47 Temporary 9,160.57 Total..'. • soi aha r\A ' SUPPLIES : $J1,474.O4 Office supplies 5 961,77 Laboratory supp'ies 5,476.75 Fuel coal. 1,718.95 Food stuffs 1,972.42 Educational and recreational.... '295.28 Janitor and barn supplies 325 97. Feeding stuffs 32,241.25 Agricultural supplies 7,827.81 EXPENSE T ° tal 7 $50,820.20 Office expenses and postage $ 1,382*23 Freight, express and drayage 1,297.05 Water, heat, light, power and fuel.. 5,190.43 Public printing, advertising and photography 4,688.40 Traveling expense 3,746.28 Rentals 224.73 Special and temporary services.: 29,582.04 Miscellaneous 1,279.75 REPAIRS T ° tal ' ■ 547,390.91 Building $ 5,008.22 Lands 547.27 Equipment 7,989.83 Total ; S13 545 32 EQUIPMENT *ia,040.3^ Furniture and fixtures $ 1,166.53 Apparatus (labor and equipment).. 5,898.31 Livestock 18,690.11 Machinery ; 6,687.57 Books ;.. 189.26 Total ssf&gt; f.Qi 70 LANDS AND BUILDINGS *M.bSl.7B Land purchase : •$ 3,360.95 Land improvements 1,581.38 Original construction.. 64.85 Total $ 5.007.18 GRAND TOTAL "$240,869.43 Dated at Lincoln,, Nebraska, L. E. GUNDERSON January 27, 1932. Finance Secretary. F2M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>