<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska NORFOLK, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">3 t. £ s c i | LU u. i % &gt; &lt; a: 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Thirteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska NORFOLK. NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 80. 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">300 KIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : In compliance with your request and the Statute of Nebraska, we submit the following : RETROSPECTIVE At the beginning of this biennium, December 1, 1912, A. Johnson, M. D., was Superintendent ; H. R. Carson, M. D., 1st Physician; R. H. Foster, M. D., 2d Physician; Mr. A. J. Gutzmer, Steward and Bookkeeper; Mrs. A. Johnson, Mat - ron ; Miss Elizabeth Leece, Superintendent of Nurses ; and Mr. D. C. Regan, Supervisor. Katherine Patrick, who was appointed by the Governor as bookkeeper, resigned in one month, April 13, and Nellie Quinn was sent to take her place The latter resigned October 14, 1914. On March 1, 1913, the Governor relieved Dr. Carson and Dr. Foster, appoint - ing Drs. W. D. Guttery and J. D. Case in their stead. Ow - ing to Dr. Case being unable to assume his duties at once, Dr. Foster continued as 2d Physician until the first of May, when Dr. Johnson retired by resignation and, by order of the Governor, his duties were assumed by W. D. Guttery, M. D., as Superintendent, pro tern. After communicating with the Executive office, the acting Superintendent moved Dr. R. H. Foster up to the position of 1st Physician and in - stalled Dr. J. D. Case as 2d Physician. On August 20, 1913, after visiting the institution, your Honorable Board relieved Dr. J. D. Case and appointed the following : OFFICERS W. D. Guttery, M. D., Superintendent; H. R. Carson, M. D., 1st Physician and Assistant Superintendent; R. H. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 301 Foster, 2d Physician and Pathologist; and A. J. Gutzmer, continuing under the Governor's appointment, as Steward. The Superintendent has installed the following sub - sidiary officers: Miss Elizabeth Leece, Superintendent of Nurses; Mr. D. C. Regan, Supervisor of Male Attendants; Mrs. Mary E. Herring, Assistant Superintendent of Nurses ; Mrs. L. M. Guttery, Matron ; Miss Laura Hill, Stenographer, Store and Bookkeeper; and Miss Jessie Church, Medical Stenographer, Postmistress and Usher. ORGANIZATION The Institution, for convenience of administration, is divided into departments, as follows : First: Medical Department, including (1) the Clin - ical division, (2) the Pathological division, and (3) the Nursing division, embracing superintendent of nurses, male supervisor, who directs the work of the male attendants, and, under the direction of the first physician, assigns male patients to their working tasks ; and the assistant superin - tendent of nurses, who performs a like duty on the female side. Second : The Physical or Steward's Department, in - cluding 1 the Agricultural and Horticultural division, em - bracing farm, dairy, garden and lawn, and 2 the Mechan - ical division, embracing ( 1 ) the engineer having charge of the power, heating, plumbing, lighting and water supply ; (2) carpenter in charge of repairs and construction; -i Store and Bookkeeping division ; and 4 Matron's or House - keeping and dietary division, embracing maid service, laundry, sewing room, dining rooms, and kitchen. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">FIRST BIEN RE "ORT OF 3 c c I a, • &gt;» « &lt; -a ? 5 m - c Q) - s. II ■ c X X K — &lt; r~ — X. E ■ O ~™^—^-^^-^— — fe ■8 2 = S = I 1 , c = S I I j ij I j £ A a I .2 --s | 1 1 !i &lt; S H c ■ t 1 /$ X -O I k o "a ■ Q I s w L 1 ■ 0) e | ■81 CA « S « on m c t c •S ■* .2 ■£ .2 t. ■ § S i I a o o. « b. I I ! c .2 8 DQ | | S 50 •a B ■ •21 fa — c | -i s s 2 r 0 ■ 1 «• cc t&gt; ■« S I I CO I ! « - — ctf — ■s. c s ■ 1 e C4 II ■8 a i c^ </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 303 The Superintendent does his work as far as possible through the departmental and division heads and, for this purpose, holds daily meetings with his fellow workers, as follows : I. STAFF MEETING The staff consists of the physicians and the superin - tendent. It meets in the first Physician's office at 8:00 a. m. and is presided over by him. The physicians present a report of their examinations of new patients, with the diagnoses. This is discussed, confirmed, or modified by those present. Then the conditions of the various wards are taken up and the whole institution reviewed. II. PHYSICAL CORPS The corps which consists of the heads of the various working divisions meets at 7:30 p. m. in the steward's office, and is presided over by that officer, the bookkeeper acting as clerk. Each man reports upon the progress of the work in his division and the work of the following day is outlined and a note made of the same in a book kept for that purpose. The Superintendent is usually present at this meeting and gives such general directions as is thought necessary. In order to carry on the work of repairs and improve - ments there have been employed for the most of the time during the two years, from one to three extra carpenters, one extra painter and one mason. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">304 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF It will be seen from the above that only about three - fourths of the patients are employed and it is much less than this when they cannot work in the garden and on the farm. One of the great needs of this institution is a work room where employment can be furnished the men when they cannot work outside and for those chronic or con - valescent patients who, after the acute stage of the disease has passed off, are left in a crippled condition mentally and need re-education. THE SPIRIT OF THE INSTITUTION Under this organization the officers and employees have worked with such unanimity of purpose that each seems to vie with the other for the good name of the hospital and the well being of the inmates. Dr. Carson deserves our grati - tude of the excellence of the records, the value of which will become more apparent as the institution grows. Dr. Foster is entitled to special mention for the interest he has taken in the amusements and physical exercise of his pa - tients and the perfection to which he has brought the lab - oratory department. Mr. Gutzmer, the steward, should have an increase in salary for he has surely given the State the best there is in him. His ten years' experience in this () ■■ iir Lj\j [ .ur r^.&gt; .■mi ur rAiiEiiNIO Employment S3 3 Employment 1 I 2 Emp. I). R F. Pat. D. R M. Pat. D. R Gen. Kitchen :)ff. Kitchen Laundry 3ewin(f room Bakery Veg. room Ens:, room Carpenter Painter Upholsterer Grand Total Idle 1 . ...... 5 . 17 . ...... . __. 2 1 2 5 20 1 1 22 &lt;&gt; 5 6 Farm 20 Dairy and Herd 11 Teamsters 6 Garden 1 Butcher 39 Mason 6 Poultry l| Store-room 5! Tailor 2|Wopd Chopper 2! Janitors llWard Workers 2|Art Class 1 . n 11 .. 8 8 6 ' 6 .. 18 18 .. 2 2 .. 7 7 .12 3 .. 1 1 - 2 2 1 I 3 3 '.'. 55 69 114 33 33 158 154 312 . 67 77 144 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">in £ O 1 u. 3 | ■* &lt; * w i c I </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 305 institution has been invaluable. Miss Leece's work is matchless for the skill displayed in re-organizing the Nurses training school, which had reached the vanishing point at the beginning of this biennium. So skillful has been the work of Mr. Regan, as male supervisor, that the task of supervision on that side of the house is nil. The matron is simply indefatigable and ubiquitous. The employees gen - erally have been so loyal, their conduct so good, and their work so skillfully that it has been found necessary to dis - charge but one man and to give one woman fifteen days to find other employment. The changes in help have been very few and those mostly voluntary resignations for more lu - crative situations. WHAT WE HAVE ACCOMPLISHED From what has been said it will be seen that this bien - nium was begun under a handicap, as the present superin - tendent had nothing to do with the administration other than the medical department until May 1, 1913. As "pro tern." he could not project his plans much into the future until August 20 and had, perforce, to accept matters as he found them. DISSATISFACTION OVERCOME His first task was to overcome the dissatisfaction and insubordination among the employees, especially the ward workers. Many did not stay long enough to learn the names of patients and, hence were of little use to the ward phy - sicians. They were called together, some abuses corrected, their duties defined and then told, "You work for Mr. , your division head, when he can no longer use you, we no longer need you." Then they were asked to consent or resign. All acquiesced and fell into line like soldiers. NURSING At the beginning of the previous administration there were eleven graduate nurses. At the beginning of this, there was one, they being replaced by attendants of the migratory class. These do well enough as watchers and </seg>
            <seg id="p010">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 306 guards but can not do constructive nursing. As to what is being done now, see Superintendent of Nurses' report. A well trained nurse, in treating the insane, is worth more than the physician. It is to be hoped that the legisla - ture will provide more pay for our graduates and put them on the same footing as to registration as other nurses, so as to induce them to remain in the service. CARE AND TREATMENT OF PATIENTS The treatment and care of the insane is the real work jf the hospital, the justification for these expensive build - ngs and the outlay of the sums of money which this State appropriates from time to time, yet, it is the least under stood of anything pertaining to these institutions and the hardest to properly report and put upon paper. No one can understand what goes on in such an institution without living in it. We found, as in most institutions of its kind, a ten - dency to make elaborate records of the physical and mental examinations, make note of their foolish sayings during their delirium, and then file them away much as a high school girl does her botanical herbarium, and forget them. We have tried to change this. The physician visits his wards twice during the day, (9 a.m. and 4 p.m.). and if a sick or acute ward once at night, (9 to 10). He takes each patient by the hand, speaks with him, examines his skin, pulse and tongue, notes if there are any foul odors, bruises, etc. He selects those whose convalescence indicates that they may be improved by gymnastics, employment, amuse - ment or personal conversation, then makes suggestions or prescribes accordingly. At irregular intervals he visits the bath, dining room, the amusement ground and work places to see that his directions are properly executed. Recognizing that every insane person is sick and that the physical condition is the basis of the mental state and seeing that they are all autotoxic our method is as follows : After a bath the patient is put to bed, given calomel in broken doses, followed in six hours by a purgative dose of Mag. Sulph. This may l)e followed by Abbott's Intestinal </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 307 Antiseptic or other specific treatment to combat the toxic condition, including hydrotherapy and massage, specifically applied on the ward. He remains in bed from one to two weeks, unless contra indicated, that diet may be properly regulated, for observation, examination and study, that the above therapy may be continued or varied as indicated, and for disciplinary purposes. This last is a very necessary and yet the most delicate^ dangerous, and difficult part of the management of this class of patients. The nurse substitutes her will for that of the patient, which is usually weakened or perverted. Thus his capacity for self -direction is re-established. I have known a chronic patient cured of the most revolting habits by a little judicious punishment. This must be frankly rec - ognized and its mode and limitations prescribed. Taboo this subject and we convert our ward workers into liars and sneaks. They are forced to take the matter into their own hands. Abuses arise which are handed down from one gen - eration of attendants to another. Thus their methods hark back to the iron manacle, chain and club. The last stage of our treatment consists in well directed gymnastics, amusements and employments. This work is done largely by nurses and attendants carefully trained and supervised by the ward physician. A FEW EXAMPLES WILL ILLUSTRATE Mr. L., a boyish patient with katatonia, sat upon the ward with his head constantly bowed upon his breast, drooling like a baby cutting its teeth, so that he wore a bib constantly. He also had pseudo contracture of the hands. Whenever the physician came upon the ward he was told to hold up his head and look the world in the face like a man. Also to straighten out his hands. Later he was asked to rise each time and perform some simple gymnastics, imitating the physician. He gradually improved until the bib was dis - carded and he assumed a very good carriage. He is now upon the open ward, carries himself erect, takes care of himself very comfortably and, while he will not recover completely, he will, no doubt, make a very good ward worker. He </seg>
            <seg id="p012">308 KIKST BIENNIAL REPORT OK never sees that physician without making a decided attempt to hold up his head and assume a dignified position. Little Mrs. A., a child-like young mother, who had be - come confused and somewhat maniacal after the birth of her child, was found constantly tied in a commode chair, constructed of 2x4's with the upper part of her body and arms in a straight jacket, her feet in leather manacles. After a few days of observation, the then acting First Phy - sician ordered her out of restraint. She was very mis - chievous and destructive at first. The female attendants of the class above mentioned protested, but the physician, who in her delusions she fancied was her "Grand-dad," went upon the ward and remained half days at a time and partly by suggestion and partly by encouragement, had her re - pair the dresses she had torn up and finally had her serve .\t the dining table. She gradually lost her delusions and oegan to talk of her child whom she had not seen and after a few weeks was sent home to her young husband and babe, in a cured condition. It mas like redeeming a human soul. Mrs. F. had been in a chronic maniacal state for five years, a part of the time tied with the most ingenious de - vices to a stationary bed, a part of the time enclosed in an iron cage, (the latter being abolished by the previous super - intendent). She was found confined constantly in the com - mode chair above described, not only in a straight jacket, feet manacled, but with a sole-leather bib, having a notch ~ut in it to fit her chin, the upper corners fastened to the :&gt;p of the chair posts, the lower corners to the arms of the •hair. In this condition she was kept from 12 to 14 hours •svery day. She was ordered out of this restraint, one of "he brightest pupil nurses instructed to take her out for a half day each morning and give her full liberty, simply keeping in sight of her. She was at first very active, rolling upon the grass, etc., but gradually quieted down and would :ake orderly walks with the nurse, conversing in her crazy manner of the beauty of nature and the joys of freedom after five years' imprisonment. In the afternoon, the nurse would take her back upon the ward and place her in a con - tinuous bath for the remainder of the day, after which she </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 309 would sleep quietly and soundly during the night. She was then placed upon the convalescent ward, went to the dining room for her meals and was able to assist in the dining room and other female employments of the institution. She is now at home caring for her family. Mrs. B., whose case was similar to Mrs. A.'s. was hypomaniacal. She had been in a private sanitarium at Kan - sas City and in similar institutions in this State, a mistake many people make, instead of bringing their afflicted friends at once where they can be properly treated, owing to a feeling of prejudice against State institutions. She was given packs, sprays, and sitz baths, as well as medicinal and hygienic treatment. Her physical health improved until she changed from an emaciated girl of one hundred pounds to a plump woman of one hundred thirty, but was still delusional and erotic. Having discovered that she was a fine musician, both vocal and instrumental, she was taken to the picture show and placed at the piano. At first her music was as maniacal as her talk, but after a few trials she was able to interpret the pictures and play very enter - taining accompaniments and later sang solos at our enter - tainments and lead the church choir. The case was finished up by suggestion, when she went home well, to the joy of her husband and little boy. Havin? had the above experience as a ward physician and realizing that the State would not consent to spending fifty dollar- a month on every patient, as in the case of Mrs. F., the Superintendent attempted to create a machine to do this work by wholesale. With this end in view he inaugur - ated a system of gymnastics in which the patients are drilled every afternoon, especially if they cannot be taken out of, doors. The grove north of the female wards was fitted up with swings, hammocks and croquet grounds. Here the convalescent ladies are taken every afternoon in good weather. When they tire of swinging and croquet they play "Drop the Handkerchief" and like games, under the direction of the nurse and 2d physician. Similar arrangements are made for the men, where they play at catch the ball, and pitch horse-shoes, and three </seg>
            <seg id="p014">310 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF days out of the week play base-ball with the attendants under the inspiration of the first physician and supervisor. It will be seen that our treatment is medicinal, hydro - therapeutic, hygienic and psychic. (For further details see 1st Phyician's report.) BUILDINGS AND GROUNDS While each of our predecessors has done much to keep the place in good repair we found much yet to be done. The roofs of several of the buildings were being damaged for want of paint. The woodwork on the cottages had not been repainted since their construction and some of it was fall - ing into decay. Many of the rooms, especially those oc - cupied by attendants, were in wretched condition, some fes - tooned with mold from leaking pipes. The walls of many of the wards looked like they were marked by small pox. In places there were large openings in the plaster, com - municating from one room to another. In the laundry the plaster had mostly fallen off. The cow barn was dark, un ventilated and, in every way, unhygienic. The wagons and farm implements were standing out exposed to the weather from one season to another. This has all been remedied. The grounds in front of and immediately surrounding the official building were in very good condition and much had been done to beautify them. The grounds immediately in the rear of some of the ward buildings were as unsightly as could be imagined. There was an old unused barn, un - sightly and unhygienic, adjacent to the ladies' hospital build - ing, and the grounds immediately back of this building were strewn with discarded boilers, cinders, and other refuse. These were all cleared away, the grounds graded up and parked, and a retaining wall, hidden by vines, placed around the cinder pile to hide it from sight. Now the ladies' ward has as pleasant a view in the rear of the building as they have in front. Many trees have been planted in var - ious parts of the grounds and especially a small orchard planted back of the ladies' hospital building. It will greatly improve the view as well as furnish fruit for the institution. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 311 ihe Male Ward No. 1 was built in a depression so that the steps leading to it were about five feet above the ground. This has all been filled in and graded up to correspond to the rest of the surroundings. The hog yards were so close to the female hospital that a wind from that direction car - ried the odors constantly to the sick ward. These have all been moved. The grove back of the building had been per - mitted to grow up into weeds, a dumping ground for refuse. This has been cleared out and converted into a play and exercise ground for the patients and fitted up with swings, hammocks, etc., as mentioned elsewhere. NEW BUILDINGS, BUILDINGS REPAIRED AND EQUIPMENT The disused ice-house has been raised and a new foun - dation placed under it, a cement floor and ceiling put in, divided into two stories, and otherwise repaired so as to convert it into an excellent carpenter and paint shop and cold storage. There has been an addition of 62 feet added to the cov barn and the old barn completely overhauled and converted into a modern barn with cement floor, steel stan - chions, steel pens for calves, lying-in pens for the cows constructed of the same material, and in every way fitted up as a modern barn. The open sheds for the dairy herd had been built up against the barn on the east side, shut - ting out the light and air. These have been removed so as to put the bain in a more hygienic condition. These changes about the stable and barn made it necessary to move several buildings and sheds and reconstruct them. This, with the building of the two sheds for cattle, one for hogs, and con - siderable new fencing, required considerable new lumber. We also had an eighty-foot addition to our green house built, which will provide for several years to come. A buggy shed and gran i ,y has been built, an inter-institutional telephone system installed, and a wagon and implement shed built. We have had constructed 16,598 square feet of cement walk and floor in various parts of the grounds, mostly in the rear of the buildings, for the use of the patients, and made many minor repairs too numerous to mention. Sev- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">312 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF eral buildings have basement rooms occupied either by pa - tients or employees. It was almost impossible to maintain the good appearance and hygienic condition of these rooms. With a view to correcting this the foundation of some of the buildings was bared and the wall coated with dehy - dratin. There has been added to the bakery one two-bar - rel bread mixer with motor. We have also purchased a hair renovating machine so that we now manufacture our own mattresses. This is a considerable saving to the institution since all worn and discarded mattresses may be rebuilt by - patients and new ones made at a saving of about $1.50 per mattress. Fifty have been rebuilt during the past two years. There have been 432 feet of water mains and four new hydrants added to our fire system. The new building which the legislature provided is in progress of building and promises to be, in every way, a model and will provide for about seventy-five additional patients. Thanks to the liberality of the legislature and the energy with which your Honorable Board has pushed the matter, our long-desired railroad spur has been completed so that now our coal is delivered directly to our coal sheds, which will result in a great saving to the State. In order to enable us to run cars into the coal shed it was necessary to make rather extensive changes in this building. LIVE STOCK We now have about fifty thoroughbred and graded Holstein cows in our dairy herd. It is our object to reduce these to about forty. Hence, we have about ten cows to dispose of which are being held at present for the use of the Board should they need them for other institutions. We had the herd tested for tuberculosis and only had one "re-actor." It is believed that our herd was more fortunate than other State herds in this matter because we stable them only when we are milking them. We have had excel - lent luck with our hogs, except this season when they were unfortunately attacked with the cholera and we lost about 130 out of the herd, notwithstanding they were all given the "simultaneous serum treatment." </seg>
            <seg id="p017">v l I 4 | m^^^^^2 ' f ui 1 - r J -I I 1 &lt; E S i a: ft 5 £ &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 313 With our poultry we have had only fair success. While one of our predecessors had built apparently a very fine poultry house, it is not successful for breeding purposes and we had but little luck in raising chickens until we built a number of small coops and scattered them about the grounds and put a brooding hen in each coop with the proper num - ber of little chicks and placed these in charge of a lady patient who was accustomed to raising chickens on the farm. Since we have adopted this method the number of chickens raised is only limited by our desires. During the summer we can see little chicks scurrying everywhere. This is not only good for the chickens, but it is good for the patient who cares for them. HEALTH OF INSTITUTION The health of the patients and employees has been re - markably good during this biennium, with the exception of a rather extensive epidemic of a mild type of small pox — so mild that many had the eruptions before it was discovered they were sick, and hence, made it hard to get it under con - trol. All have recovered or are recovering. We inherited four cases of typhoid fever from the former administration, which was possibly carried by Hies, owing to many of the windows and porches not being screened. This has been largely remedied. The epidemic did not spread. We have had two cases of malignant diphtheria. Both died. (For details see report of first physician.) HYDRO-THERAPEUTIC DEPARTMENT This is a valuable part of our treatment of the insane, but has been somewhat of a disappointment owing to its being quite remote from a large portion of the patients and owing to the fact that it requires the time of one nurse having a higher salary than the ordinary nurses and at - tendants. It would have been much better had arrange - ments been made for the application of this mode of treat - ment on each of the two acute wards, as we are now provid - ing on the new male building. Part of the apparatus is im - practical, especially that part stigmatized by Dr. Wood </seg>
            <seg id="p019">314 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Hutchinson, as a cross between the garden hose and Gat - ling gun. It is useless waste of time to apply hydro-therapy as a routine measure. It should be applied specifically, i.e., with a definite object in view, applicable to the particular patient. PATHOLOGICAL DEPARTMENT We found nothing in this department but a bare room, one microscope, a few test tubes and re-agents. We have added a working counter with a sink and water, shelves and racks for re-agents and appliances, and an electrical centrifuge and incubator. It is now in a very good working condition, so far as it can be made to apply to the class of patients here. Few instances can be recalled where it has been of value either to the physician or the inmates. But it is thought best to keep it and the physician in good work - ing order in case of emergency and also in response to a popular professional fashion. The class of work referred to as blood counts, routine urine analysis, which simply serves to encumber our records are of no diagnostic value as far as treatment is concerned. To the same class belongs the Wasserman test and spinal puncture for syphilis, except that the latter process is sometimes fatal to the patient and simply determines the fact diagnostically that the patient is hopeless. To this department has been assigned the Abderhalden reaction test and Lundval's Nuclein solution treatment for dementia praecox, which is expensive, takes too much time, and results in no material improvement to the patient. Also dicrotalin treatment for epilepsy has been tried out and found of little or no value. The above is not to be interpreted as any reflection upon the pathologist, to whose report I refer you. AMUSEMENTS, RECREATIONS, ETC. We have had during the biennium, a weekly picture show and dance. Beside the outdoor amusements mentioned elsewhere we have had four plays given by the employees. One by the male employees in the form of a minstrel and three by the female employees, under the direction of the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 315 matron. Our amusement hall is decidedly too small to ac - comodate our patients and is greatly in need of being en - larged or replaced by a new one. RELIGIOUS SERVICES We have had religious services for the patients every Sunday afternoon. Members of the ministerial association of Norfolk have taken turns in conducting the services. MEDICAL LIBRARY The Medical Library has been greatly increased. While there was a large number of books they were mostly ob - solete. We have purchased a number of books and journals that are up to date both in our specialty and general medi - cine. GENERAL LIBRARY The State Library Commission has furnished the in - stitution with about three hundred volumes, mostly of fic - tion, which our patients and employees greatly appreciate. Owing to the crowded condition of our official building we have been somewhat at a loss how to find a way and place to properly care for this library, but are having shelves placed in our reception room and will take care of them there. FARM AND GARDEN At the time of assuming control of this institution it was too late in the season to do much with the farm and garden except to continue what was begun, as the seeding, etc., had been mostly provided for. The planting was ample and the tillage good but in both departments the crops were considerably damaged by the drought in 1913. While the fruit crop was damaged, the apples which were procured from the rented Osborne farm were ample for the institu - tion. In 1914, the general crop and garden was much better but the apple crop was virtually a failure owing to the drought. However, our best crops are grown upon rented land as we have very little tillable land on the State farm </seg>
            <seg id="p021">316 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF and it is recommended that the State buy another quarter or half section, if possible, of good farm land adjacent or as near as possible to the present tract. RECOMMENDATIONS Prophylaxis It is well recognized that insanity is on the increase in the United States and, since there is no specific for the dis - ease yet known, those interested and informed upon the subject naturally turn to the question of prevention. With this object in view we held a Clinic at this institution in July, 1914, and invited the Elkhorn Valley Medical Asso - ciation to meet with us. They responded to the number of about seventy-five. The program presented was largely psychiatrical subjects and many cases were presented to the visiting physicians. This was done in the hope of reaching the public .through the medical profession and it is believed it would be profitable to continue such meetings. But if these meetings are to accomplish the most pos - sible good we must make psychiatry talk English. There are some things that the State can do directly to assist in this matter. First, alcoholism must be controlled and put under a ban. Second, every luetic person should be quar - antined and doctors compelled under a heavy penalty to re - port all cases of syphilitic infection. Then for the purpose of educating the public it would be well to encourage senior medical students and recent graduates to enter these insti - tutions for six months or a year as internes, that they might learn something practical about insane patients and their management and thus carry it into their general practice. It is not to be understood that these internes should be trained up into State hospital physicians, for no man should be entrusted with the medical care of this class of patients without first having had ample experience in general prac - tice. No man ever became a skilled physician by dancing attendance upon a great internist while nurses render all care to the patients or who has learned to idealize a surgeon who takes as many appendices annually as the game law will permit. Before a medical graduate is sent to one of these </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 317 institutions as physician he should be thrown on his own resources as a physician of the people until he has learned to take care of the sick and until he has trained his sym - pathies to respond to the sufferings of humanity as his conscience should respond to the voice of God. It is true these freshmen easily become psychiatrical pedants, but these institutions do not need alienists as much as they need physicians. They are too liable to be medical nihilists and have a notion that diagnosis is all there is to medicine and this of the mechanical type that involves the latest pseudo-science that enables them to name the disease only at the autopsy. They are too much inclined to spend their time in trying to prepare themselves for some spe - cialty or aping the Rockefeller institute. These patients do not need research. They need treatment of the kind that has grown up clinically under the practice of the Fathers of Medicine, of the kind that knows how to apply ther - apeutic remedies to the condition of the patient, as indicated by the symptoms determinable by the five senses of the trained physician. Lastly, the State can aid in disseminating knowledge pertaining to insanity by requiring all nurses who graduate in other institutions to spend at least six months in a State hospital before permitting them to register and at the same time permitting graduates of the State hospital to register i'?on graduation. Care of Paroled and Discharged Patients Approximately 75 r i of the patients of this institution belong to the dementia praecox group, i.e., insanity of youth, who after a period of mental disturbance, recover or pass into a chronic stage with their mentality very much low - ered. They are capable of re-education, much as develop - mental defects. They make very good working people under proper management, but are seldom capable of taking their places in society, but can be paroled or discharged provided they are sent into proper environment. Three such patients, iluriner this biennium, who appeared to be thoroughly capa - ble of li v in«r in the home environment were discharged at ihc earnest solicitation of friends and have since committed </seg>
            <seg id="p023">318 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF suicide tt home. Hence it is suggested that an employee preferably a physician &gt;:e assigned for the purpose of super - vising these outside patients and counseling with those responsible for them and, if necessary, visiting them oc - casionally, as is done in several of the older states, namely. New York. Mass., etc. To this additional employee might be added tV&gt; task of bringing the patients into the hos - pital. We are thoroughly convinced that many of the pa - tients are greatly injured mentally by injudicious handling in transit. This practice is also in successful operation in many states. We have cautiously worked out a few pa - tients who had, owing to domestic difficulties or other causes, no one to whom we could parole them — one a woman and the others men. By keeping them in constant touch with tin- institution they were able to make good and were final'.', discharged. With this same object in view we have employed in the institution two patients. One, the present gardener, vho had been in the institution ten years as a patient and vho, you will testify, will compare favorably with :i!iv K^rdener and florist in the State. The other is serving as fireman and is one of the most courteous and competent men in our employ. Dentist The inmates of the institution are constantly needing the sen ices of a dentist, which has never been supplied. During this biennium we have sent a number of pa - tient* to the dentists in Norfolk, whenever we could secure private funds from their friends to do so. In a few in - stances when the patients were old chronics who had ren - dered long service to the institution we paid the expenses out of the cash fund. We would recommend that a dentist be added to the hospita! staff. Possibly one dentist might do the work of the three hospitals for insane or a senior dental student might be employed during each vacation to put the patients' teeth in as good shr.pe as possible, which last proposition ought not to cost more than the services of an attendant. It seems needless to say that proper dental work is as necessary to the health of this class of patients as anv other class of medical service. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 319 Provision for Commitment of Defectives There are something like fifty developmental defec - tives, not insane, ranging from idiots to imbeciles and mor - ons in this institution. They can not be properly controlled and trained in this institution as it is not organized for that purpose. On the other hand, they take up the room and oc - cupy the physicians' time, which should be devoted to the care and treatment of the mentally sick. It is recommended that a change in the statute be made so that this class of patients may be sent to the institution for the feeble-minded, thus relieving the insane hospitals of their care. Postal Laws There is great need of a change in the statute with reference to the mail of the patients of these institutions. Much postage is wasted on useless and harmful mail sent out by patients. We often have complaints from friends and neighbors asking us to restrict the patients in their correspondence as their letters are often embarassing to relatives and a nuisance to others. Friends occasionally send money to patients without our knowledge and thus the patients are sometimes aided to escape. They also write harmful letters to patients. The statute makes it a penal offence for the superintendent or any employee to censor the mail of patients. The institution head who is unworthy to be trusted with that task is unworthy of being trusted at all. in order to enable us to procure the proper data for certain items in our statistical reports and also for properly making the required return in death certificates, the fol - lowing interrogations should be added to the Physician's Return in committing patients: 1. Date of patient's birth. 2. Length of patient's residence in Nebraska. 3. Name and nativity of parents — father and mother. Since these interrogations are prescribed by statute, an act of legislature is necessary to make the change. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">320 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEW BUILDINGS AND REPAIRS NEEDED The building containing the kitchen and employees' dining room, chapel and amusement hall, is greatly in need of being enlarged or replaced with a new one. To build a new one such as the institution needs, would probably cost in the neighborhood of $75,000. It could probably be enlarged and remodeled for something in the neighborhood of $25,000, if experts, on examining the building, find the old walls fit to sustain such repairs and enlargements. Four of our cottages are without proper ventilation as they were built for individual heating plants with ventilation in connection, but when the heating plant was taken out and these buildings heated by the central power house of the institution it naturally destroyed the ventilation system. This should be remedied. It would cost in the neighbor - hood of SI, 000. The remodeling of the toilet and bath room in the west win? included in the architect's designs for the new building now being constructed was cut out owing to limited funds. That, it seems, was estimated at a cost of $5,000. It is hoped this will be provided for in the appro - priations. Some changes are necessary in the physicians' quarters in the official building, which would cost about $200. Nurses' Home A nurses' home is very necessary for this institution in order to keep the proper help in the nursing department. In this respect see Dr. G. Alexander Young's report in mak - ing this recomrrendation six years ago. "The nursing force has been working under many dif - ficulties, the chief one cf which has been poor living quar - ters. For the proper development of an efficient and steady force of nurses and attendants, it is desirable that special quarters should be furnished for them to which they may be able to retire after their work is done and enjoy privacy and quiet, which is now impossible. The work of a trained nurse or attendant among the insane is, at the best, ardu - ous and wearing, and the hours are very long. If the hos- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 321 pital desires to keep the most efficient form of help in this department, it is necessary that it should provide comfort - able living conditions, which young women engaged in this work have a right to expect. For this purpose, I believe an appropriation should be made sufficient to build a nurses' and attendants' home large enough to accomodate at least thirty-five to forty individuals." This would cost about $30,000. Ceiling in Engine Room and Barn A small appropriation of possibly $240 is needed to put in a metal ceiling in the new cow barn and also in the en - gine room. Finishing Dining Room and Elevator in New Building Owing to the many necessary improvements in other portions of the institution, we have not been able to com - plete the dining room and elevator in the new stone build - ing as the legislature intended in their appropriation un - der that head, but, with the tacit consent of the Commis - sioners, we have done things which seem to be more urgent. We should have an appropriation of about $4,000 to com - plete this work. The Wing of the Laundry Building Should have a second story added and a new roof over the entire building, — cost estimated at $1,000. To enable us to take the best advantage of the railroad spur and handle the coal properly necessitates the building of a cement block coal bin. The institution can do the work at a cost of $1,025. Two New Cottages One for males and one for females will be needed if the Commissioners carry out the policy of increasing the capaoity of this institution to the size of the other State hos - oitals. They should cost approximately $60,000 each or $120,000 for the two. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">322 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF The Engineer's Department Will need, owing to the increased capacity of the in - stitution, several additional appliances, to-wit: 1 High Pressure water tube boiler, at 1 Exhaust water heater, at $5,000 300 1 350-hour ampere storage battery, at 3,500 Sewerage This institution is drained by an open sewer which discharges about a mile from the institution on the public highway. There has been much complaint by the citizens in the neighborhood and also a notice from the county that this be taken care of in such a way as not to continue a public nuisance. With this end in view a survey has been made with the intention of putting in a settlement tank and take care of the water in an underground irrigation system which will cost in the neighborhood of $2,000. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION There were in this institution November 30, 1912, 408 patients. There have been received since then 225 patients. Sixty-six patients have died, and there have been paroled or escaped from the institution 112 patients. There have been discharged from the institution 14 patients. Of those paroled or escaped there have been 16 returned, leaving the present population 457.. There have been discharged, in - cluding those on parole 98, showing an increase for the biennium of 49. For further information see statistical table. SYNOPSIS OF RECOMMENDATIONS Estimate of Appropriations for 1915-17 Salary of superintendent at $2,5000.00 per annum $ 5,000.00 Salary of first physician at Salary of second physician at Salary of steward at 1,500.00 per annum 3,000.00 1,350.00 per annum 2.700.00 1,200.00 per annum 2,400.00 Salary of bookkeeper at 900.00 per annum 1.800.00 salary of superintendent of nurses at 900.00 per annum 1,800.00 Employees' wages, increase of 6 attendants because of new " building 55 000 00 Maintenance, including everything except salaries, wages, new buildings, repairs and the up-keep of buildings and the p-ounds 125.000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 323 3. To commit developmental defects to the institution for feeble-minded. 4. To change the State postal laws relating to State in - stitutions. 5. To require all graduate nurses from other hospitals to take a post-graduate course in an insane hospital be - fore being permitted to register. 6. To permit nurses graduated in State hospitals to regis - ter without further training. To change the Physicians' Returns so as to require date of patient's birth and time of residence in Nebraska, rnme and nativity of patient's parents. 8. To provide for voluntary commitment of patients in insane hospitals. Repairs and Improvements: Up-keep of buildings and grounds $5,000.00 H. P. water tube boiler 5,000.00 Exhaust water heater 300.00 350-hour ampere storage battery 3,500.00 Minor buildings and repairs the work on which is to be Hone by the institution: Ventilation of cottages $1,000.00 Remodeling toilet in west wing 5,000.00 Modification of physicians' quarters 200.00 Finishing female hospital building 4,000.00 Metal ceiling in barn and engine house 240.00 Sewerage 2,000.00 New roof and second story to part of laundry 1,000.00 Coal bin of cement blocks .... 1,025.00 14,465.00 28,265.00 New Buildings Nurses home and work-room in basement 30,000.00 Building including kitchen, bakery, em- ployees' dining room, amusement hall 100,000.00 Two new cottages, lif it is the Board's policy to enlarge this institution) at $60,000 . 120,000.00 250,000.00 Additional farm land— 160 acres 20,000.00 Total $494,965.00 STATUTORY CHANGES 1. An employee to supervise outside or paroled patients and bring in patients. 2. To provide for a dentist. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">324 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF REPORT OF FIRST PHYSICIAN W. D. Glittery, Superintendent, Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk, Nebraska. Dear Sir: A first examination of the patient is made the day of admission and, unless it seems probable that more accurate information can be gotten by a brief delay, a report to the Board of Commissioners is made at once. The later de - tailed examination follows the general outline of Dr. H. D. Singer. The results of this examination are dictated to the stenographer and are made a part of the permanent records of the institution. An effort is made to get this ex - amination within two weeks after the admission. The case is then presented to the entire staff for discussion and a plan of treatment outlined. Bed-side records of the acutely ill are kept. Monthly charts of the acutely insane and quarterly charts of the chronic cases are written. These are filed with the records of the first examination. A permanent record is thus kept of the mental states, illnesses, and treatments of each pa - tient during his hospital residence. When he leaves the hospital permanently, a brief summary is written and again presented to the staff. We consider the most effective single method of treat - ment is hydrotherapy. This is not to be considered as a routine measure, but to be administered for definite re - sults, with a definite prescription considering time, tem - perature, and in some cases pressure. The following table gives an approximately accurate summary of the number treated for the biennium : The pathologist has recently checked the night reports for the year previous to the introduction of hydrotherapy Treated reated 40 40 78 25 26 10 219 Purpose Tonic Stimulation Sedative Analgesic Elimination Pelvic trouble Total Improved 28 20 57 25 21 10 161 Not Helped 10 14 15 1 44 Results in Doubt 2 fi 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THK BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 325 and those for the year following its introduction. Those of the succeeding year show a falling off of 50 f /r in the num - ber of sedative hypodermics given, notwithstanding a con - tinuous growth in population. An epidemic of smallpox broke out on the female side about July 24, 1914. Eleven female patients and four nurses were afflicted before Oct. 18, 1914. There have been no cases on the female side since then. In four female pa - tients the disease was diagnosed from the prodromal symp - toms. In the others the appearance of the pustules was the first evidence of the disease. The disease made its appear - ance on the male side in September and since then 21 pa - tients, five attendants and two others have had or have the disease. In the cases of six patients the first evidence of illness was the appearance of a few pustules. In one case there was no temperature and no pain but he appeared ill. He insisted, however, that he was not. In two female cases there has been marked "pitting." In none has there been a secondary temperature. In October, 1914, there were two cases of diphtheria. One was a man sixty years of age, subject to asthmatic attacks. He had a severe attack from which he did not re - cover and smears and cultures revealed the presence of the diphtheria baccilus. He was given antitoxin. The other was a man 2 1 years old who had been in continuous manic excitements thirteen days. He had been in the institution four days before the first symptoms. He was given 10,000 units of antitoxin within twenty-four hours and 7,000 units later. This loosened the membrane but the throat was gangrenous. Both cases died. During the latter part of 1912 and early in 1913 there were five cases of typhoid fever at the institution — one em - ployee and four patients. Of these one patient died. The Abbott Alk. Co. kindly furnished the institution a supply of Lundval's Nuclein Solution to use in the treat - ment of Dementia Praecox. The pathologist selected two female patients and two male patients were selected by the first assistant physician. Red and white cell counts were made before and after the administration of each dose, and </seg>
            <seg id="p031">326 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF there was always an increase in the number of leukocytes. The patients were fed an excess diet and slept out doors. There was an increase of weight in one female patient, case No. 461, of eighteen pounds during the period of treatment, but aside from this there was no improvement noted in any of the four cases. The dicrotalin treatment of epilepsy has received a trial. The pathologist selected two women, 315 and 423, for the treatment, as they came nearest to filling the re - quirements for those most amenable to treatment i.e., those who had both major and minor attacks. The third patient, 383, was an accidental choice, in that we decided to see what effect the drug would have on the condition of "status." She had fifteen convulsions in ten hours pre - ceding the administration of 1/100 gr. of dicrotalin. She had but four seizures in the twenty-four hours following. Two patients, 383 and 423, received a total of sixteen doses each. The first dose in each case was 1 100 gr. The dose was then increased to 1 25 gr. and nine doses of this size were given in each case. We followed carefully the sugges - tions as to elimination and general care. The drug was given hypodermatically deep into the muscles of the fore arm and calf, using a different site each time and using iodine to sterilize the site of injection. The interval be - tween injections depended on the recovery from the reac - tion to the preceding treatment. In neither of these cases was there ever any severe local reaction. Case 383 had twenty-five convulsions the three months preceding the treatment, thirty-one during the period of the treatment, including 15 during the period of the status, and twenty - one the three months following the treatment. Case 423 had eighty-two convulsions the three months preceding, one hundred three during the period of treatment and sev - enty-two convulsions the three months following. It was necessary to abandon the treatment in case 315, female, because of the exceedingly severe local reaction following the larger doses. She received but five doses in all. From our limited experience and our experiments to determine the coagulation time of the epileptic's blood, in </seg>
            <seg id="p032">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 327 which we have been unable to determine in a single case more rapid coagulation than normal, we believe the treat - ment has nothing to encourage its use. Statistical data tables accompany and are a part of this report. Yours respectfully, H. R. Carson, M. D. Norfolk, Nebraska, November 30, 1914 REPORT OF SECOND PHYSICIAN W. D. Glittery, Superintendent, Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk, Nebraska. Dear Sir: I submit herewith a report of the work done in the laboratory for the biennium ending Nov. 30, 1914. In spite of the law passed by the legislature in regard to the disposal of unclaimed bodies, we have made a total of twenty-nine autopsies. A brief synopsis of four of the more interesting autopsies will be given below. We have made a routine examination of urine of all cases admitted. We have not been making blood counts as a routine for the past six months unless there has been some special indica - tion for the same, as it has been our experience that we have a surprisingly large number of normal blood counts among those who are admitted. Before commencing the use of dicrotalin in epilepsy we made a series of coagulation tests of blood in the epileptics. This was done for the purpose of determining whether or not the contention of those who recommend the use of dicrotalin was correct, namely, that the blood of epileptics coagulates more rapidly than the nor - mal blood. We have been unable to demonstrate this in a single case. We have done a little work with the Abder - halden tests in dementia praecox, and hope to be able to re - port a series of tests later. The laboratory at present is well equipped with the exception of an accurate set of balances. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">328 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Urine examinations Male patients _ _ _ 123 Female patients _ 102 Male employees _ _ _ _ _... 5 Female employees _ _ 3 Total 233 Blood examinations including differential white cell counts Male patients ..._ _ 95 Female patients _ _ 75 Female employees _ _ 2 Total 172 Sputum examined for tubercle bacillus Male patients, present 1 Male patients, absent 3 Female patients, present _ 2 Total 6 Culture from throat for diphtheria bacillus Male patients, present 1 Male patients, absent _ _ _... 9 Female patients, absent _ 2 Male employees, absent _ 3 Female employees, absent _ _ 4 Total _ _..„ ___ 19 "Widal" reaction Male patients, positive _ _ 4 Male patients, negative _ _ _ _ 3 Female patients, negative _... 2 Male employees, negative _ 1 Total _ _.._ _.._ 10 Urethral discharge for gonococci Male employees present _ - 1 Vaginal discharge for gonococci Female employees, present _ 2 Determination of coagulation time of blood Female patients 35 Time from 2 hi to 5 minutes. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">329 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS as J I o a _-c i) £, .2 3 "JS.5 ■ .SS £.2 2 &gt;2.2 ** w •— •'« '5 '« 'x 'w m*m3w*»'« t3 S 2-J.2J22! 2 £££ £2 1 1-1 « o a a a a a «8 a a&gt; a a ______ 0.Z0.0.0.0, o. cua.u a, a. j&gt; _ I j j I Si :' -I i i i . 8 ,% ill :$&gt;■&amp; SIMM c «'-' i I i ■© 3 3 ; : : c 6C_ : : : :&lt;e a a -S g " « 01 ll Oif.fc be Tj 1 IHISHIIIli I o o o og £ 5 o o o o : a MZSsgtti 0J ZZZ Z i » ] | |"| | | j . i | ; j j "S -»-» *j -u&gt; a a ti c o o o o ? « o o o o ■ ? zzzzSS z zzz z ; :J ! j M i 1 3 ;S J &gt; oi oi « a) ■- ttiti o&gt;o&gt; S uS 1^ .tS.&gt;.&gt;&gt;.&gt;^ : ~ .&gt;.&gt;.&gt; &gt;&gt; E °3^ _ a _ -B _ _ x § .-55 .-S " 2 « o « 000 o — 1 * o o o o d c 0,Z 0.0. 0,0.x 0.0.0. 0.0. .S 1 1 s 1 1 i ] nr &amp; _ «^0S««K -g 05-o-c «^ g £ fc tc~ bt be tt tic -c st-c -5 fct-p 5 ■* — o*S^^« &lt;y •— v _2 cB wbSojccww as cgKoj xOS o « g I j| I if I if I I I 1.1 i I "sItbII "i ill ii £ "- 1 Sx S _js S »S S ™ 1o°» .-s _.»&amp;!.» i |.»5 Eb I |&gt;.s_ — t. 68 •* OJ £_■§-_ lunoo N -x^rxw-H n ujjquj oca "5 _8"g . — . J&gt; | § « § u« d Jijjgj 5 §§§ §§ icigf ZoSZZZZ; as ZZZ ZZ 5^^^° * x • oetoao « a&gt; • £ S fa „ </seg>
            <seg id="p035">330 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF POST-MORTEM SYNOPSIS W. D.— Case No. 680— Multiple sclerosis. Male, white, farmer, age 63; admitted Feb. 28, 1913; died Oct. 25, 1913, 10 :15 a. m. Post mortem Oct. 25, 1 :00 p. m. Pathological findings — Brain and spinal cord were re - moved. Slight evidence of Pacci meningitis in the cord. In several areas beneath the dura of the cord large white flaky deposits were found. Sections of the various levels of the cord from the pons to the conus-medullaris were made and stained by the Weigert-Pal method. The only area of sclerosis found was in the distal portion of the pons involving the nuclei of the fifth and sixth nerves and pyramids. G. L. — Case No. 612 — Tumor pituitary. Male, white, farmer, age 25; admitted March 25, 1913, died Jan. 6, 1914, 4:14 p. m. Pathological findings — The pituitary body was entirely replaced by a large friable mass, a prolongation of which extended into the center of the left hemisphere. Sections from the mass showed it to be a spindle-celled sarcoma. I. A. — Case No. 519 — Organic brain disease. Male, white, carpenter, age 50 ; admitted Feb. 6, 1912 ; died May 28, 1914, 10:00 a. m. Post mortem May 28, 1 :00 p. m. Pathological findings — The examination of the cranial cavity showed little save an old meningitis. The liver con - tained numerous gumma. Sections stained by evaditi method showed numerous spirochetae plapallidae. M. W. — Case No. 495 — Pulmonary tuberculosis and Glenard's disease with Katatonic symptoms. Female, white, school girl, age 27 ; admitted April 10, 1914 ; died May 21, 1914, 3:50 p. m. Post mortem May 25. Pathological findings — This case is reported because of the fact that there were no ante-mortem symptoms of the advanced stage of tuberculosis found post mortem. The stomach was vertical with the pyloric end in the true pelvis. There was about 20 inches of stenosis in the large intestine, the liver was enlarged, congested and fatty, the left kidney was larger than the right, pale, and microscopic sections showed many areas of small round cell infiltration. The </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 331 lower lobe of the right lung contained much blood, and with the exception of the upper lobe of the left lung there were many abscesses in the lungs. The right lung was much more seriously involved than the left. Sectioning the lungs showed no areas of calcification. We believe the multiple abscess indicate an acute tuberculous process though there were no clinical symptoms of the disease. Respectfully, Robert H. Foster, M. D., 2d Physician and Pathologist. Norfolk, Nebraska, November 30, 1914. REPORT OF SUPERINTENDENT OF NURSES W. D. Glittery, Superintendent, Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk, Nebraska. Dear Sir: I submit the following report of the Training School for Nurses for the years 1913-14. Nurses in school July, 1913 14 Admitted on probation 21 Applicants accepted 20 Resigned 12 Died 1 Time completed 4 Nurses in school November, 1914 17 Graduating Claw 1914 Helen R. Browne Mary B. Bagby Nellie Shannahan Margaret Bratton Nurswf Staff Superintendent of Nurses 1 Assistant Superintendent of Nurses 1 Charge nurses (graduates) 2 Charge art department (graduate) 1 Charge nurses (pupil) 4 Night nurses (pupil) 4 Day nurses (pupil) 9 Day attendants 2 The faculty of the school is composed of the Superin- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">332 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF tendent and Medical Staff of the Hospital, Superintendent of Nurses, and Assistant Superintendent of Nurses. Practical instruction is given in the best methods of the care of nervous and mental diseases together with med- ical and surgical nursing, dietetics, hydrotherapy, and mas- sage. Pupil nurses are changed from one position to an- other until experience has been had in the different depart- ments. An announcement of the Training School in this hospital has been printed which states the course for two years' work. This two years' course covers all the branches required by the Nurses' Registration Law of Nebraska, but, in order to meet the requirements of the Nurses' Examin- ing Board of Nebraska, six months or more additional train- ing in an approved general hospital is required. Two nurses of the graduating class of 1914 will take graduate service in the Illinois Training School for Nurses, Chicago, 111., January, 1915. The work of the pupils has been generally satisfactory both at the bed side and in the class room. The schedule of work with instructors for the junior year is as follows: Study of Pulse 1 hour Mental and Nervous Diseases 14 hours Hygiene and Sanitation '. 2 hours Anatomy and Physiology 30 hours Bandaging 6 hours Arrest of Hemorrhage 1 hour Nursing 30 hours Chemistry 10 hours Urinalysis 2 hours Materia Medica 16 hours The schedule of work with instructors for the senior year is as follows Arrest of Hemorrhage 1 hour Accidents and Emergencies 1 hour Study of Pulse 1 hour Mental and Nervous Diseases 14 hours Typhoid Fever 1 hour </seg>
            <seg id="p038">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 333 Tuberculosis 2 hours Diseases of the Digestive and Respiratory Tracts. 10 hours Dietetics 18 hours Massage 6 hours Household Economics 5 hours Obstetrics and Gynecology 8 hours Children's and Contagious Diseases 5 hours Bacteriology and Surgical Technic 6 hours Eyes, Ears, Nose and Throat 6 hours Diseases of the Circulatory System 3 hours Practical Points 15 hours Respectfully, Elizabeth Leece, Supt. of Nurses. Norfolk, Nebraska, November 30, 1914. MATRON'S REPORT W. D. Glittery, Superintendent, Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk, Nebraska. Dear Sir: I hereby submit my report as Matron of this institution from December 1, 1912, to November 30, 1914. CULINARY DEPARTMENT Apples canned 962 gallons 26 gallons Butter, apple 38 gallons Butter, plum 5 gallons Butter, tomato Butter! dairy, December 1, 1913, to November 30, 1914 1664 pounds Beans, canned 144 gallons 144 gallons 47 gallons Catsup, cold tomato 13 gallons Catsup, pepper 10 gallons Catsup, cooked tomato 1 gallon Chili sauce 295 gallons Cherries, canned Currants, spiced 12 glasses 38 glasses Currant, jam Cider 156 gallons Fruit juices, canned 16 gallons 5 gallons Gooseberries, canned 81 glasses Gooseberry jam 3 gallons Grapes, canned 299 glasses Jelly, apple 653 glasses Jelly, currant 330 glasses Jelly! choke-cherry 30 glasses Jelly, plum Jelly, wild grape 925 glasses </seg>
            <seg id="p039">334 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Mi^,S ■= - "6 gallons Marmalade, grape -— -IZZZLZZZT 11 quarts Mangoes, stuffed 65 gallons -,. , j , , wu uaiiuns Pickles, chopped 8 gallons Pickles, apple 36 gallons r^ « i r .*• »ju gallons Pick es, beet 127 gallons £ lck es - cucumber 7 ga i lon .s -v- . . ' .... • fioiu;ii&gt; Pickles, dill 120 gallons Pickbs. green tomato ZZZZZZZZZ 67 gallons Pickles, spiced Pickles, mustard 4 gallons 6 gallons Pickles, pepper ..ZZZZZZZ 4 gallons Pickles, musk melons 13 gallons Pickles, watermelons 4 gallons Pickles, onion 14 gallons Pickles, peaches 8 gallons Piccalilli 65 gallons Peppers, scissored 4 gallons Pepper sauce ZZZ 10 gallon's Peas canned _ 89 gallons Peaches, canned ."" 34 gallons Preserves, apple „ 15 gallons Preserves, musk melon 14 gallons Preserves, plum 2 gallons Preserves, strawberry 25 glasses Preserves, tomato _ 24 gallons Preserves, watermelon _ 5 gallons Relish, beet 11 gallons Relish, corn _ 18 gallons Sauer kraut 100 gallons Strawberries, canned 21 gallons Tomatoes, canned 202 gallons Wine, grape 3 gallons Wine, dandelion _ 5 gallons Wonderberries, canned 24 gallons DIETARY ONE WEEK'S MENU OFFICERS' Sunday Breakfast — Oranges, soft boiled eggs, toast, coffee. Dinner — Fried chicken, sweet potatoes, Irish potatoes, cold slaw, jelly, coffee, ice-cream, cake, bread and butter. Supper — Cold meat, potato salad, sliced tomatoes, sauce, cake, coffee, tea, bread and butter. Monday Breakfast — Breakfast food, pancakes, bacon, coffee Dinner — Soup, roast beef, turnips, potatoes, pie, coffee. bread and butter. Supper — Fried eggs, potatoes, tomatoes, sauce, cake, coffee, tea, bread and butter. Tuesday Breakfast — Cereal, toast, bacon, eggs, coffee. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 335 Dinner — Beafsteak and onions, baked potatoes, creamed carrots, graham bread and butter, pudding, coffee. Supper — Fried ham, eggs, gravy, marmalade, hot biscuit, coffee, tea. Wednesday Breakfast — Milk toast, biscuit, bacon, jelly, coffee. Dinner — Soup, beef loaf, potatoes, cabbage, catsup, bread and butter, pie, coffee. Supper — Frankfurters, creamed potatoes, graham mush, jelly, buns and butter, coffee, tea. Thursday Breakfast — Oatmeal, toast, dried beef creamed, coffee. Dinner — Irish stew, potatoes in jackets, boiled onions, corn bread and butter, apple sauce. Supper — Fried hamburger, potatoes, bread and butter, cin - namon rolls, jelly, coffee, tea. Friday Breakfast — Oranges, codfish on toast, potatoes in jackets, coffee. Dinner — Bean soup, baked mackerel, mashed potatoes, beets, bread and butter, pie, coffee. Supper — Scalloped salmon with tomatoes, potato balls, beans, tea, biscuit and butter, jelly, coffee, tea. Saturday Breakfast — Corn-flakes, hot biscuit, bacon, jelly, coffee. Dinner — Soup, boiled dinner (meat and vegetables), corn bread and butter, preserves, coffee. Supper — Corn fritters, potatoes, cold meat, bread and but - ter, cookies, sauce, coffee, tea. ONE WEEK'S MENU -EMPLOYEES' Sunday Breakfast — Breakfast food, fried ham, fried potatoes, gravy, hot biscuit, butter, coffee. Dinner — Pea soup, roast ribs with brown gravy, mashed potatoes, cold slaw, beet pickles, bread and butter, cof - fee, ice-cream, cake. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">336 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Supper — Cold meat, potatoes, catsup, sauce, bread and but - ter, cake, coffee, tea. Monday Breakfast — Oatmeal, toast, beefsteak, potatoes, butter, cof - fee. Dinner — Vegetable soup, pot roast with brown gravy, mashed potatoes, bread and butter, chocolate pudding, coffee, milk. Supper — Cold meat, fried potatoes, boiled rice, tea biscuit, butter, sauce coffee, tea, fresh buttermilk. Tuesday Breakfast — Corn flakes, bacon, potatoes, hot biscuit, butter, syrup, coffee. Dinner — Irish stew, potatoes with jackets, turnips, graham bread and butter, beet pickles, cottage pudding, coffee, milk. Supper — Cold meat, creamed potatoes, graham mush, buns, butter, sauce, coffee, tea. Wednesday Breakfast — Shredded wheat biscuit, beefsteak, hot biscuit, butter, gravy, potatoes, coffee. Dinner — Cream of tomato soup, roast duck with dressing, peas, mashed potatoes, jelly, dill pickles, bread and butter, coffee. Supper — Hash, fried potatoes, bread and butter, catsup, sauce, coffee, tea, milk. Thursday Breakfast — Cream of Wheat, hot biscuit, bacon, gravy, but - ter, fried potatoes, coffee. Dinner — Boiled dinner (meat and vegetables), curried rice with tomatoes, picalilli, bread and butter, jelly, coffee. Supper — Corn meal mush, hamburger steak, baked potatoes, grravy, sauce, buns and butter, coffee, tea, milk. Friday Breakfast — Breakfast food, codfish on toast, potatoes in jackets, coffee. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 337 Dinner — Bean soup, baked mackerel, cold sliced meat, gravy, potatoes, cabbage, bread and butter, lemon pie, coffee. Supper — Scalloped salmon, creamed potatoes, boiled onions, bread and butter, sauce, cookies, coffee, tea. Saturday Breakfast — Pearled barley, milk toast, bacon, fried potatoes, bread and butter, coffee, milk, syrup. Dinner — Mutton stew and vegetables, chopped pickles, bread and butter, corn starch pudding with cream, cof - fee, milk. Supper — Fried hominy, baked beans, brown bread, butter, potatoes, sauce, coffee, tea. ONE WEEK'S MENU-INMATES' Please take note under this menu that when meat is served three times a day, the working tables are meant, as the feebler patients have the milk toast, cream, puddings and soup. This does not describe special diet for the sick patients, prescribed by the physicians. Sunday Breakfast — Hominy flakes, milk and cream, milk toast, gravy, butterine, bread, coffee, sugar, syrup. Dinner — Brown spare ribs with peas, mashed potatoes, to - mato pickles, garden huckleberry pie, tea, sugar, bread. Supper — Cheese, bread, butter, cold meat, ginger bread, tea, sugar, milk, jelly. Monday Breakfast — Oatmeal, milk and cream, bread and butterine, gravy, syrup, coffee, sugar. Dinner — Corn beef with cabbage, steamed potatoes, beet pickles, bread, tea, sugar. Supper — Fried potatoes, meat, fruit sauce, bread, butterine, tea, milk, sugar, milk, toast, cream, pudding. Tuesday Breakfast — Graham mush, milk and cream, bread, gravy, butterine, syrup, coffee, sugar. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">338 K1RST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Dinner — Soup, mutton stew with vegetables (carrots, tur - nips, potatoes), dill pickles, pudding, milk, tea, sugar, bread. Supper — Corn meal mush, milk, sauce, buns, butter, tea, sugar. Wednesday Breakfast — Oatmeal, milk and cream, bacon with gravy, bread, butterine, syrup, coffee, sugar. Dinner — Pot roast with brown gravy, beans, steamed po - tatoes, bread, tea, milk, sugar. Supper — Cereal with milk, meat, radishes and onions, bread, butterine, sauce, tea, sugar. Thursday Breakfast — Milk toast, bread, gravy, butterine, syrup, cof - fee, cream, .sugar. Dinner — Soup, beef stew with tomatoes, brown gravy with potatoes, pudding, bread, tea, sugar. Supper — Hominy flake, milk, lettuce and onions, cinnamon rolls, meat, sauce, tea, sugar. Friday Breakfast — Oatmeal, milk and cream, bread, gravy, butter - ine, syrup, milk toast, coffee and sugar. Dinner — Creamed codfish, steamed potatoes, bread, tea, cof - fee cake. Supper — Cereal, milk, corn bread, butter, cheese, sauce, tea sugar, cookies. Saturday Breakfast — Graham mush, milk toast, gravy, bread, butter ine, syrup, coffee, sugar. Dinner — Soup, string beans with bacon, creamed beets steamed potatoes, pudding, bread, tea, sugar. Supper — Pearled barley, milk, meat, bread, butterine, sauce tea, sugar. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 339 SEWING DEPARTMENT Articles Made Mended Aprons, muslin Aprons, kitchen Aprons, gingham Aprons, rubber Bed pads 314 4S&gt; 372 -IX 3 4 Bibs, ward Burial robes 2(19 U9 26 Binders abdominal Bolster covers ... x 2 ( amisoles 16 214 Camisole strings Candy bags 232 8-15 Clothes bags Chemise IS 14 2fi I 171 Coffee sacks .. Corset covers Curtains, pairs Caps, baker 10 5 27 G Drawers, ladies Drawers, men Dresses, calico Dresses, wool Dresser scarfs Iron holders ... 16S 709 219 17 ■&gt; M HO Ice bags 4 9 Jelly bags Mattress ticks Muffs, pairs Napkins, table 28 a Iti4 197 Napkins, sanitary Night gowns 415 M Overalls u Pillow cases 1554 36 Rubber pillows Sheets, muslin Sheets, rubber. Stupe, wringer Strong dresses Straw ticks 6 1451 48 M •&lt; 229 42 10 87 Suspenders, pairs Shirts, men 36 453 1124 Skirts 224 68 Table cloths Table covers Towels, hand Towels, roller Towels, dish 68 17 1702 2o 596 3072 Tuwels. old linen Tray cloths 39 474 Window shades i-J 4 SO </seg>
            <seg id="p045">340 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ARTICLES MADE FOR PATIENTS AND EMPLOYEES FROM There are, in this department, three cooks, five dining room maids who are also maids of all work, distributed as follows : Two cooks in the general kitchen, one cook in the officers' kitchen, one maid each in the three officers' dining rooms, one maid in employees' dining room, and one maid in the female patients' dining room. These maids, aside from having charge of the dining rooms, do general house work and take their turn once each week in the vegetable room. Hitherto, an extra maid was employed for the vegetable room alone, but, as will be seen from the above, this extra help has been dispensed with. LAUNDRY By adhering strictly to the checking system, by means of printed slips, the usual confusion and vexation attending institution laundries has been largely eliminated. CONDEMNING DAY Once each month the supervisor, head nurse, and mat - ron condemn all worn out linens, making a tabulated report to the Superintendent. This has resulted in a great saving of linen and has also put a wholesome restraint upon des - truction and waste of State property. Articles Made 139 51 46 41 43 I 35 222 4 93 Aprons, patients. Aprons, nurses... Bibs, nurses Caps, nurses Cuffs, pairs Drawers, ladies Dresses, uniform Dresses, calico ... Dresses, wool Skirts MAID SERVICE </seg>
            <seg id="p046">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 341 BREAKAGE A report is required each week of breakage in the sev - eral dining rooms. This has led to greater carefulness, each employee striving to make the best showing, and the maids, with but one exception, have made truthful reports. Truly, Mrs. L. M. Guttery, Matron Norfolk, Nebraska, November 30, 1914 STEWARDS REPORT W. D. Guttery, Superintendent, Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk, Nebraska. Dear Sir: STATEMENT OF INCOME OF FARM, GARDEN, ORCHARD AND POULTRY YARD 1913 1914 Total Beans, string, bushel Beets, bushels 88 92 130 20% 57% 78 Cabbage, heads. Carrots, bushels 1415 1705 3115 22 145 167 Cauliflower, heads 270 270 Corn, Sweet, prepared in general kitchen, bu 155 182 337 Cucumbers, bushels 2 75 77 Egg Plant 399 399 Huckelberries, garden, bushels 37 37 Lettuce, bushels 66 107 173 Melons, musk 205 390 595 Melons, water 500 620 1120 Onions, bushels 226 10!) 335 Parsley, bunches 100 100 200 Peas, bushels M 59 118 Peppers, red and green, bushels 2 7 9 Potatoes, bushels 714 949 1663 Potatoes, sweet, bushels 10 2:; 3J Radishes, bushels 77 164 241 Rhubarb, pounds 475 125 600 Salsify .bushels _ _ 112 Spinach, bushels 2S 66 so 220 Squash Tomatoes, bushels 19K 567 Turnips, bushels 88 75 103 Corn, field, bushels 1973 995 2968 34 Corn, sweet, sold to canning factory tons... 17 17 Corn, pop, bushels 5 5 Oats, bushels 554 2626 3180 55 20 75 Hay, prairie, tons Alfalfa, tons _ 41 45 86 Millet, tons _ - - - 24 24 38 140 :S69 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">342 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF In conclusion, gentlemen, we hope you will not consider this report too revolutionary or iconoclastic and that we, like Alcibiades, have been destroying institutional gods out of sheer wantonness. We have simply tried to present things as we see them after nearly five years residence here, whether our views are in accordance with the prevailing mode or not. The care of the insane is in an undiscovered country beyond an uncharted sea. We have been clearing the deck and enlisting and training the crew for the voyage. Thanking you for your forbearance and support dur - ing the biennium that has just closed, Very respectfully, W. D. Guttery, Superintendent. Norfolk, Nebraska, November 30, 1914. Ensilage, tons _ 175 185 Ml Apples, bushels 1000 273 1273 Cherries, bushels 96 48 144 Currants, bushels 3 2 5 Gooseberries, bushels 1 l Strawberries, bushels 9 2 11 Beef, pounds 5060 1230 6290 Pork, pounds 18075 9455 27530 Veal, pounds 2015 2015 Chicken, pounds 1135 860 1995 Eggs, dozen 1104 897 2001 Milk, delivered to general kitchen, gallons.. .24592 27412 52004 Hops, 52, weight 17855 $1,371.06 Hogs, 83, weight 32393 2,608.44 3,979.50 Pig, 1, 3 months old 12.00 12.00 Calves, 28. 4 weeks to 11 months old. 720.00 Calves, 14, 1 week to 11 months old.. IS30.&gt;*5 1,050.85 Hides, 656 pounds B5.94 Hides, 215 pounds 25.22 91.16 Tallow, 218 pounds 8.72 8.72 Old iron, 46665 pounds 71.00 71.00 Rags, 2859 pounds 14.27 Rags. 1800 pounds 9.00 23.27 Respectfully submitted, A. J. Gutzmer, Steward. Norfolk, Nebraska, November 30, 191 h. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 343 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1, '12 July 1, 13 ending Total to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Present at begin ' ning of period 210 198 408 214 209 42;: 214 207 421 210 198 408 Admitted: For first time 37 29 66 13 11 21 60 43 103 110 83 193 •Readmitted 4 3 7 3 4 7 6 9 15 13 16 29 Transferred from other institutions 3 3 3 3 Returned from pa- role granted be- fore commence- ment of period 325 336 14579 16 Returned from es- cape made before commencement of period Total under treat- ment 254 232 486 233 227 460 281 266 547 340 309 649 Discharged: Recovered 4 4 8 3 2 5 9 12 21 16 18 34 Improved 10 5 15 5 7 12 13 3 16 28 15 43 Unimproved 7 2 9 3 2 5 8 4 12 18 8 26 Not insane 2 2 4 112 3 3 6 Transferred to oth- er institutions 112 Died 15 7 22 5 5 10 20 14 34 40 26 66 Committed suicide on parole 1 1 3 3 4 4 Paroled and not re- turned during per iod 22 13 35 14 13 27 12 11 23 48 37 85 Escaped and not returned during period Total removed 60 33 93 31 29 60 67 46 113 158 108 266 2! I CO &lt;;: 46 113 158 108 266 SI </seg>
            <seg id="p049">344 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION— (Continued) returning to hos - pital 20 10 30 12 9 21 12 11 23 44 30 74 'Includes patients who have previously been in this or a similar institution in Nebraska or elsewhere. TABLE II. AGES OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending r Ending r or i ear Dec. 1, 12 to June 30, 13 r dnaing July 1, 13 to Nov. 30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T Remaining at end of period Average number treated Absent on parole or escaped at commencement of or during period and later dis- charged without 214 209 423 214 207 421 226 231 457 226 231 457 213 201 414 215 211 426 221 214 435 216 209 42s For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 Dec. 1, '12 to June 30, 13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium AGES M F T M F T M F T M F T Under 15 — - - - ~ 15 and under 20 3 2 5 3 2 5 20 and under 25 7 3 10 1 2 3 8 7 16 16 12 28 25 and under 30 3 4 7 2 2 4 8 12 7 14 21 30 and under 35 6 5 11 4 2 6 11 3 14 21 9 30 35 and under 40 5 5 10 1 2 3 8 9 17 14 18 32 40 and under 45 527 123 3 10 13 9 14 23 45 and under 50 4 5 9 3 3 6 4 10 10 11 21 50 and under 55 4 4 224 459 10 7 17 55 and under 60 2 3 5 3 3 4 4 8 9 7 16 60 and under 65 3 2 5 3 14 6 3 9 65 and under 70 2 2 1 12 13 3 3 6 70 and over 2 13 3 3 9 1 10 14 2 16 Unknown ...- - 1 1 1 1 Totals 41 32 73 16 15 31 66 55 121 123 102 2: </seg>
            <seg id="p050">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 345 TABLE III. CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total CIVIL STATUS to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Single 24 5 29 7 6 13 38 19 57 68 30 98 Married 14 20 34 8 7 15 22 29 51 45 56 101 Widowed 246 112 57 12 8 12 20 Divorced 12 3 1 1 13 4 Separated 1 1 _ 1 1 Unknown 1 1 1 1 Totals 41 32 73 16 15 31 66 55 121 123 102 225 TABLE IV. EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total Nov. 30, for EDUCATION to to June 30, "13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Primary 9 4 13 4 4 8 4 12 21 8 29 Common School 29 26 55 10 12 22 46 42 88 85 80 165 High School 1 1 1 1 4 4 15 6 College or Univ 112 112 None ... 2 2 134 64 10 97 16 Unknown 6 17 6 17 Totals 41 32 73 16 15 31 66 55 121 123 102 225 The above report is approximately correct. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">346 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE V. NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 NATIVITY Dec. 1, 12 tT June 30, 13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total I for Biennium M F T M f M r T M F T Nebraska Arkansas Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Maine Michigan Missouri Minnesota New York New Hampshire New Jersey Ohio Pennsylvania South Dakota Virginia Wisconsin Unknown 5 4 5 t 1 _ 1 . 1 _ 1 .. i _ l .. l l I 3 1 I 1 i 2 1 1 1 10 3 6 9 17 1 1 1 7 1 1 5 1 1 8 2 2 4 7 1 3 1 1 1 . 2 13 4 1 1 1 1 1 1 3 1 1 1 . 1 1 . 1 1 1 2 1 1 2 1112 2 1 1 3 16 8 2 I 1 3 1 2 2 ....... 3 2 33 1 13 3 10 2 " 1 1 I 1 I 1 1 4 a 3 5 26 2 . I 1 1-1 1 2 1 1 1 2 5 1 2 1 3 1 3 2 5 27 12 3 x 1 1 1 s 1 2 1 3 1 -1 3 52 2 21 4 22 2 3 1 2 3 7 1 2 2 6 1 4 6 8 'otal native born 24 19 43 12 13 ■ 46 44 M 82 76 158 Austria Bohemia Canada Denmark England Germany Hungary Holland Iceland Ireland Norway Russia Sweden Switzerland . Wales 4 1 1 2 2 1 2 4 4 1 __ 1 1 1 1 3 1 5 . 3 2 3 8 1 1 . 1 . 1 1 I 1 '. i - "i'Z 2 i i l „ i 2 i i 1 2 1 2 1 2 1 2 4 2 __ 1 1 ~ 1 t 6 2 1 1 3 3 2 I t; 1 1 2 6 2 1 1 1 6 3 9 4 3 7 2 2 4 3 4 7 10 6 16 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 3 1 1 1 2 3 9 9 2 2 1 1 2 Total foreign i b. on ■n.. If 13 30 4 2 6 20 11 31 41 26 67 'otal foreifm born 17 13 30 Totals 41 H 73 16 In 31 66 55 121 123 102 225 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 347 TABLE VI. NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED NATIVITY OF PARENTS U S.. both parents Foreipn, both par ents Mixed Unknown Totals For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 Dec. 1,12 July 1,13 to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M F M F T M r T M F T 10 8 18 5 7 12 13 25 38 28 40 68 20 14 34 1 1 2 10 9 19 t 5 a ........ IS 7 27 1 25 21 I M 1 34 53 2 40 41 94 1 3 20 60 J -•. it; 15 Ml 66 55 121 123 102 225 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">348 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VII. PREVIOUS OCCUPATIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1, '12 July 1, 13 ending Total OCCUPATIONS to Nov. 30, for to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Artist-painter 1 1 1 1 Basket maker _ _ 1 1 1 1 Bartender 1 1 1 1 2 2 Baker 1 1 1 1 Brick mason 1 1 1 1 Bridge carpenter _ '. _. 2 2 2 2 Blacksmith _ _ 1 1 1 1 Carpenter 1 1 1 1 Cook „ 1 1 1 1 Court reporter 1 1 1 1 Chauffeur 1 1 1 1 Domestic ...... 2 2 5 5 13 13 20 20 Dressmaker _ _. 1 1 _ 1 1 2 2 Farmer 19 19 7 7 30 30 56 66 Fisherman 1 1 1 1 Housewife 24 24 9 9 35 35 68 68 Insurance agent _ 1 1 1 1 Laborer 14 14 3 3 13 13 30 30 Laundress 2 2 _ 2 2 Nursery man _ 1 1 1 1 Prostitute 1 1 1 1 Painter _ 2 ...... 2 2 2 Poor farm. _ 4 4 4 4 Real estate _ 1 1 1 1 2 2 Student _... 12 3 12 3 Shoemaker _ 1 1 _ „ 1 1 Sheep herder _ ..._ - 1 1 1 1 Tailor 1 ...... 1 -..- - __ 1 1 Telegrapher 1 1 1 1 2 2 Traveling salesman 1 1 1 1 Tinsmith - 1 1 1 1 Teacher 1 1 1 1 2 2 4 4 1 Teacher Teamster 1 1 - 1 1 Tramp 1 1 - 1 1 2 2 1 1 Tramp Weighmaster 1 1 1 1 1 1 Well man 1 1 — 1 1 Unknown - - 12 3 12 3 1 1 _ 1 1 Unknown Totals 41 32 73 16 15 311 66 55 121 123 102 225 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 349 TABLE VIII. COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year All Dec.1,12 Jul. 1,'13 ending Total Remaining COUNTY to to Nov. 30, for Nov. 30, Jun.30,13 Nov,30.13 1914 Biennium 1914 MFTMFTMFT MFT MFT Antelope 3 .... 3 .... 2 2 5 16 8 3 11 13 8 21 Boone 13 4 Box Butte _ 2 13 Boyd 1 1 2 415 527 95 14 Brown 2 2 1 .... 12 6 8 3 8 11 4 10 14 2 2 1 .... 12 6 8 3 8 11 4 10 14 Bart 2 .... 2 123 3 2 5 10 6 16 Caag 1 11 .... 1 112 _J 2 2 Cedar 2 13 1 .... 1 3 14 7 6 13 Cherry 415213448 10 6 16 4 10 14 Cheyenne 2 2 4 Clay _ 1 1 1 1 1 1 Colfax 1 2 3 .... 22112 2 5 7 5 12 17 Cuming 1 .... 1112156 3 6 9 12 13 25 Custer 5 2 7 Dakota 1 .... 1 .... 1 1 .... 22 134 28 10 Dawes 1 .... 1112336 5 4 9 7 6 13 Dawson 14 5 Deuel 1 1 Dixon 1 1 2 .... 1 1 .... 11 134 48 12 Dodge 1 .... 1 112 21 3 77 14 Douglas 13 4 13 4 4 6 10 Gage 1 .... 1 1 12 13 Greeley 112 Holt 2 .... 2 1 1 5 6 11 8 6 14 11 12 23 Hooker 112 112 112 Howard 3 2 5 Keya Paha 2 .... 2 2 2 5 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">350 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VIII. COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF* BIENNIUM— (Continued) For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year All Dec.1,'12 July 1, '12 ending Total for Biennium Remaining Nov. 30, 1914 COUNTY tu to Nov. 30, Jun.30,'13 Nov.30,'13 1914 M F T M F T M F T M F T M 11 F T 2 3 5 2 .... 2 3 Knox 1 4 4 11 9 20 Lancaster 1 1 1 1 1 1 McPherson 1 1 1 1 1 1 Madison 4 4 8 13 4 4 11 12 11 23 12 15 27 Merrick 3 :! Morrill 1 1 ...» I 4 4 3 3 6 Nance 1 1 2 Nemaha 1 .... 1 1 1 Pierce 1 .... 1 1 1 2 2 1 3 s 15 Platte 14 5 1 .... 13 2 5 5 6 11 13 14 27 • r i Rock 1 1 2 112 2 2 4 3 14 2 i Saline 1 .... 1 1 1 1 1 Sarpy 1 1 •&gt; 3 5 Saunders Scotts Bluff 1 1 Seward 1 1 Sheridan 2 1 3 S 3 1 6 3 5 8 .. 1 5 Sherman 4 Sioux 12 3 1 .... 1 1 .... 13 2 5 2 13 Stanton 1 .... 1112426 6 3 9 9 7 16 9 ;&gt; 1 1 1 •&gt; 1 Thomas 1 Thurston 2 3 5 112 3 1 4 •; 5 11 :i !• Valley 1 1 2 2 13 2 2 6 2 8 10 is 13 14 27 Washington Wayne 1 .... 1 :i 1 3 4 4 4 8 41 32 73 16 15 31 66 55 121 123 102 225 226 231 457 Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p056">: bo^ ARD OF COMMISSIONERS 351 I _ J - 2*1 fc s s E- h 1-H 1—1 : X W CO N i-t IC tH iH © CJ 5C '. 00 KW I H^HiH 1O ICO 1-H — . CROCOf fH — "- — — S 1 ■ ion : in coco:: es:N : : t* : :«:::: r-ieo:! r-i!t-i r. ■»O1 Wt-c ;os(N rt c 3 l_ _ I. I co m Is i4 fc « 2 I I a &gt;« &gt;" 2 r H 1 1 s — :NrtN:: ]~ \ \ Gt :m I : rt i ! ! : i : i ! N :N :M i : i-c j O) • i ! i i *" ! ■ ■ i - M : : I 0) : : »i"t- co s 2 ■ i • : I ; ■ i : : '■ ■ : : : : i ! i : : : '■ : : : : : ; ■ : : : : : : : c £ 3 oo ::•;:: : : ■ ■ ■ i • • • : i : i S : : : : : : i : : : : : • ■ » ;;■!:: i i I ! i : -S | ; » i J I I I i i I j j I !• j i i:!a 3 :o«J : i -2 : 'S : : : -a ; ; t wiii il IlllaeSSlJlliilllljgill « ri S &gt; &gt; t; </seg>
            <seg id="p057">! Fl IRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 2*1 - s - E- fc. TP — M!C U5 « Oil .-H-11-ieO Nt-BOf Tf : :« weo t- : .-i :»iei :oo&lt;-ii-i&gt;h ■ I ; r-c O-h&gt;h : woo «rt :« :rt NaNaog ■ I ) s B ■M 2 ■ S I i : ; e B r S S U9 H r- h to : i-t cc : ic co : : : : *-&lt; moohon i-i ; « QO : : co : *-» to : ■ i-t — : 1-4 r-t ! i"H t- ii-i ; :■» : : : : n^h«h ■4 1— s ■4 1— M s n 1 2 c, H .Sec ~S§ fe w~ -» z s .- h, M H ~. ■"8 I 1 : : : : : : : : : : : : : : •Vi-&lt; : : icec m &gt;-. hm :oi :tON : sj ■*■ : : rt _&lt; : •"-&gt; : : : 11 ■ : 1 I P a — P a — — 1 I I i ! t • ; 1 : : : • : : : • ' 1 ■ CO H ■ s i i i : c : i :' ! I I i ! : i : i : ! j ; ; : i I feL : ! 2 i j i j i if i lyjiii! ll^fljirll ilHtH : t; fills \'j\\ {lll|llipdl!ipiji 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 353 TABLE X. NUMBER OF ATTACKS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XI. PREVIOUS DURATION OF DISEASE IN THOSE ADMITTED For Yeai For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 r Ending ATTACKS Nov. 3C Dec. I, 12 to June 30, H 0. 1913 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending: Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M M F FT M F T T M f T First Second Third Unknown ... ... 23 21 44 9 10 19 ... 11 6 17 4 3 7 14 5 2 13 6 17 112 39 14 4 9 28 67 71 59 130 14 28 29 23 52 3 7 7 8 15 10 19 16 12 28 Totals ... 41 32 73 16 15 31 66 55 121 123 102 225 For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 ir. DURATION Dec. 1, '12 to June 30, '13 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 endintr Nov. 30, 1914 Total for Biennium M F T M F T M M F F 1 M F T M F T Under 1 year 1 year 2 years From 2 to 5 yrs From 5 to 10 yrs From 10 to 15 yrs From 15 to 20 yrs From 20 to 25 yrs Over 25 years Unascertained 19 9 % 1 1 12 3. 2 2 4.. 2 2 "T"_! i '.'. 2 13.. 13 18 31 6 2 2 1 ...... 2 1 ib 7 I i -t i 16 25 4 5 7 1 i . l . 22 19 1 I r, 2 1 24 44 I 8 12 3 ""i i i M 50 29 79 7 18 6 5 11 9 8 17 5 4 9 1 1 2 2 3 14 1 1 41 52 93 Totals 41 32 73 16 15 31 66 56 121 123 102 225 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">354 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF ' TABLE XII. HEREDITARY INFLUENCE IN DISORDER OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year HEREDITARY Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total INFLUENCE to to Nov. 30, for to Nov. 30, for to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Father or mother insane ..... _ 3 3 6 1 2 3 4 8 12 8 13 21 Gr. father or Gr. mother insane 1 1 1 1 1 112 3 2 Aunts, uncles or cousins 2 13 11 145369 Brother or sister 2 2 33 268 211 13 Mother and broth- er insane 1 1 1 1 Gr. father and uncle insane 1 I 1 1 Mother and sister insane _ _ _ I 1 1 1 Sister and father insane 1 1 ... 1 1 Uncle and sister insane 2 2 2 2 Father and broth- er insane 1 1 1 1 2 2 Aunt, mother and sister insane 1 1 1 1 Paternal uncle and mother insane 1 1 1 I Mother and son insane 1 1 1 1 "Whole family" 1 1 1 1 Sister and cousin 1 1 1 1 Unknown 34 25 59 14 6 20 48 33 81 96 (i4 160 Father and grand- father 1 1 1 1 Paternal Gr. father father, family 1 1 1 1 Brother and pater- nal uncle 1 1 1 1 Gr. mother and aunt 1 1 1 1 1 Brother and sister _ 1 1 1 1 Brother, sister, and brother's son _ 1 1 1 1 Totals 41 32 73 16 15 31 66 55 121 123 102 226 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">355 E •3 a 3 fee e2°S I E- E- fc T&gt;Mn i-i COCOrH C: IN •«• iH &lt;H 0) !-! &gt;H T : :»h : :e&gt; : c-eM^ : : :i-i.-i oo &lt;hC4 : &lt;-h nrtn CO : : MiH M : : &lt;O I I ! n ; « cc X pi s to — I HHn ih ih : : somn ;ih hhh ih in 2 E- E- H : :ih : : : iomn i : ;hh O) Mrt iTHrHiieo;; ;&gt;-iih::o&gt; S h W S C". &amp;. 0 - ■c--i !»&gt; I 8 M ■- s Eh h E- fc S • • j ; — ■ : I *-&lt; p&lt; j [ {It M fi : ih | j ft j ec : : t 4 '• ' ■ i" i n H "• ill I II! ||N| III u Mi! li J {llfillli 1= s| J3&gt;s|sSs| ||=£| | « a 5 £ &gt; &gt;&gt; &gt; m 3 I I </seg>
            <seg id="p061">356 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XIV. DURATION OF RESIDENCE IN HOSPITAL OF THOSE RECOVERED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total DURATION Nov. 30, to to for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Less than 2 months 3 4 7 3 4 7 2 to 4 months... 5 to 9 months... 10 to 12 months 13 to 18 months... 19 to 23 months 2 years and over. 1 12 13 1 14 15 2 4 6 1 1 12 3 4 6 10 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 S 11 2 2 4 2 3 5 1 1 1 1 12 3 12 3 Total* 4 4 8 3 2 5 9 12 21 16 18 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 357 TABLE XV. NUMBER OF ATTACKS OF THOSE RECOVERED For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total ATTACKS to Nov. 30, for to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT First attack 325 213 369 89 17 Second attack 11112213336 Third attack 2 13 2 13 Fourth attack 1 1 2 2 4 6 3 5 8 Totals...- 4 4 8 3 2 5 9 12 21 16 18 34 TABLE XVI. AGES AT ADMISSION OF THOSE RECOVERED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total AGES to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MPT 15 and under 20 1 1 20 and under 25 112 25 and under 30 112 1 1 213 224 649 1 1 112 3 2 5 _ 1 1 2 2 3 3 30 and under 35 35 and under 40 2 2 112 13 4 40 and under 45 3 3 3 3 45 and under 50 3 2 5 3 2 5 1 1 2 2 50 and under 55 1 1 1 1 1 ...... 1 60 and under 65 65 and under 70. 1 1 _ 1 1 Totals 4 4 8 3 2 5 9 12 21 16 18 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">358 riAAi DidnniAL niiruni ur I E-&lt; I Ml I 111 :: em 1*4 : i-h i-h : 1*4 ; | | : : : ; F- fc .2 m m inn eo : r* : t-i : |*4«4 : ih tn ih i^ rH »-i i-h s o C O.-C fe"Z OH M : : coin : : : iHih : : :i-ii^r-i 1*4*4 it Eh — 00 :; — — — j*4*4 — H fc s | ■Oil &gt;&gt; ■; CO ■ i 2 ik j 1 Mi H fc ■ &lt; \ h O I kg IS HI C C 3 c 3 : ih : : :»h ih : :»-h :ih : : :ih : : I fc :h Ml"*! r- h ~. 33 X 53 o 8 U &gt;&lt; "/. E I o 1 1 1&lt; j 1 1 k 111 ill lUuttlO iliisjlii lUrsiljlilli i • ■ : • I • fT i i ! j I 1 1 | , I | 1 1 j ,11 1 1 I ' r ih III* jfil i rA\\ a a a a a ft a a 0 - 1 o.oot~ . a .2" «c"«« </seg>
            <seg id="p064">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 359 C4 ii iH N .-Ci-H-I HHHH rHUr-l ii Is! b, " j •* ■- i r — • r -H i jO&lt;2 c : : : : g S i rt : M '"""' i | i — ! I j I •* •i j : ii ih :ih ;HH : i-irHiH : a t^o j i i &gt;J .s ". s t ~ 1 i j i"* I* i ••••H S"S§2 I'M ! i &gt;»&lt; v&lt;z S rt ** i i I i rt I i : : ii : : : . j \w* it! : « « E- : U, ~ H : i i i j i t3^h&gt;»^ ::: i::::: ;: = 2 "= o s : : i i i i i ! : I" M 2 H ---;;-; - } j | ; j j! - o~-. ill I ! i i i OZ -HO= fc - | - | j | j j j | j ; j *** o eu : : * : :::::!■ S J .■ ! - ! h | ■- ; c o - &gt; S — • H , i.i.:. i . i : : • ! • !i ! i ■ f c \M 4 j A ! c i : IJS { 5 :5 ;5 15 ;5 | j i| i I ; !* ; \ ;| j a "s i-s i*s i n i y" | i.p Mr g 1 1 1 1 1 111 ilill 111 iiJifililHlliiflliflU '.i.l, j , i A : I ; ; ; : i ; ; JS ■£ ■£ j^ ;« I « « hi « n| j if ii| I 11 111 ii H »l « S I I I I «l Us --1 a. : ft. if i£ :C ;. cc^ ? o o o o o oc5£ £=SS gSS </seg>
            <seg id="p065">360 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF Hrtri rH B H 3 y-&gt; rtrt Hh fc, i-t iM HHH £ S i-)HHHrt : wi iH i-H hhh : : *h th :»hihi-h r- i_ Ws ■&lt; I M fc, •a &gt;as i-i s 1H JfH »-■ — »-1 h &amp;. I J I u — ■ -sS »-. Is cos jn 3 O ~&gt; z s «S ■ «-l M E- Pi' B W a h 0 a U e SZ ~ fc. d V 1H rH y= a ! HI 1 1|4 0 a o ►&lt; E ul \ U Ul Ui N iiil! * &gt; 'S ii mi 11 ill I nun ■ itcUJ Jill J* MJ 1 1 In ; jj .s.s.a.2.2 s|o."g i ; o|| gssslii liili ilJIjljJl SSSiS If ccccc «5r333&gt;&gt;&gt;,3P m &lt; U •111 s5i|.^g.-s|i5SlllS|li -an. § -Sag = * g i ».£ SaaaSSil Shh wwQ Zaig mQ w wHHHC OgO I j j I j I : i ; ; ; I I ! I i I I I j [ j las I ! I lit I I I e I I I I I (■■■ill I 1 I t I I I I ■ I I I I I </seg>
            <seg id="p066">361 ** 1-1 m - j " " a « »h : : H p4 1— •— «h : : s § I &amp; mo h ! sS.s".s h ! - Si S3 i i — — : — «h : : : I g s s i" I ; : : 1 I I '1 I: c : 2 2^ £ -^ &gt; » », X ■ o e 5 d -j e o U I a a 1= COS ■ M i- I s ... I |M I 1 i a ? *" ! Z -»b h, j j i * J ■ I I I ; w* ; : *-( : 3 M H ■a its |B8 j M oi X : X ! O &gt; O : O : g II !|! £ 3-3-2 .h § £ £ £ SO Q I 2 c c a _c 1 _l_ d 111 ! 1 H i H , ! ! \ i _o o "3 "5 I sip "3 's'a'a «T3 i mi M a i i i MM hi I b I Mi kj i Mi! ii j i i i S-S §S d w | J O -2-2 .2 .! .21.! o " ■ » p. *3 "5 *a 1 o 3 ~m ! 3 «-O ,=3 9 : 2- 3 a-o a 2*1 1 siJi S&gt; «i • ; -o^» x&gt; j ■^cj P-e </seg>
            <seg id="p067">362 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XVIII. PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN HOSPITAL OF THOSE WHO DIED DURING BIENNIUM For Year Ending Nov. 30. 1913 For Year Dec. 1, '12 July 1, 13 ending Total to Nov. 30, for to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Less than 1 month 2 2 5 16 5 3 8 From 1 to 6 mos 2 13 11 5 3 8 7 5 12 From 6 to 12 mos 3 14 112 2 2 6 2 8 From 1 to 2 yrs 1 1 2 1 From 2 to 5 yrs 2 1 3 From 5 to 10 yrs 7 1 8 3 1 3 4 7 5 5 10 33 336 57 12 3 2 3 5 12 4 16 Totals 15 7 22 5 5 10 20 14 34 40 26 66 TABLE XIX. AGES AT DEATH For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, '12 I July 1, 13 ending Total AGE to to Nov. 30, for June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT 20 to 25 _..... 112 2 2 13 25 to 30 2 13 112112437 30 to 35 2 2 112 13 35 to 40 1 1 1 1 40 to 45 1 1 12 3 13 4 45 to 50 112 4 4 5 16 50 to 55 2 13 112 1 14 2 6 55 to 60 1 1 2 1 12 2 4 4 3 7 60 to 65 1 1 2 2 13 4 4 3 6 9 65 to 70 3 3 11123437 Over 70 2 13 6 17 8 2 10 Unknown 2 13 2 13 Totals 15 7 22 5 5 10 20 14 34 40 26 66 Suicide while on Parole SO - 1 .._. 1 1 1 22 _ ': 1 .._. 1 1 1 » 1 1 1 1 43 ..._ 1 1 1 1 Totals 1 1 1 3 3 4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 363 TABLE XX. AVERAGE NUMBER OF PATIENTS EMPLOYED Average Number Employed In Outside Aggregate Av'ge Pop- Per Cent Ward Ward ulation Employed ulation Employed MFTMFT MFTMFTM F T TABLE XXI. RATIO OF EMPLOYEES TO PATIENTS Male Female Total Number of physicians including superintendent 3 - 3 Ratio of physicians to patients 1:75 1:75 •Number of day nurses and ward attendants 17 18 35 1:75 1:75 Ratio of same to patients 1:13 1:13 'Number of night nurses and ward attendants 4 3 7 Ratio of same to patients 1:57 1:77 "Total day and night nurses and ward attendants 21 21 42 Ratio of same to patients 1:11 1:11 Total officers and employees 33 38 71 Ratio of same to patients 1:7 1:6 *Does not include Superintendent of Nurses, Assistant Superin - tendent of Nurses, Supervisor or General Night Watch. During year ending Nov. 30, 1913 62 58 120: 77 During year ending Nov. 30, 1914 |65 63 1281 90 Averages for bi- ennium 64 60 124 83 63 140|139 107 246219 208 427 67 157 155 130 285 221 214 435 58 141147 118 265 220 211 431 65 52 57 70 til 66 </seg>
            <seg id="p069"/>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>