<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  THE STORAGE AND USE OF SOIL MOISTURE.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION Volume XXVI, Akticle II. THE STORAGE AND USE OF SOIL MOISTURE Report of Experimental Substation, North Platte, Nebraska. By W. W. Burr. W. P. Snyoer, Superintendent E. A. Burnett, Director. Distributed March 12, 1914. LINCOLN, VEBRASKA OP NEBRASKA. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE GOVERNING BOARD. (tmi xiioti or thi umvEMmr) E ORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. ORABLE GEOROE COUPLAND, Elgin. OR ABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln. ORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE. Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICER8. SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. K. A. BURNETT, B. Sc. Director. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. Bead Wii.rox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. . Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. . Chase, B. Sc. M. E., Agricultural Engineering. Buss, B. S. A., Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Fkandsen. M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. La whence Briner, B. Sc., Entomology. T. A. Kiesseliiach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. C. W. Pdmur, B. St.. Farm Management and Agricultural Extension. W. J. Morkill, M. Fob., Forestry. Ekwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geology. G. R. Chatburn, A. M., Highway Engineering. R. A. Emerson, D. Sc., Horticulture. KP. Stoit. C. E., irrigation Engineering. Lovei .and. A. M., Meteorology. ■P. Snvdei:. M. S., Superintendent of Experimental Substation. North Platte. 1W. Bur.R. B. Sc., Associate in Soils and Crops, North Platte; Assist ant Agriculturist, Office Dry Land Agriculture, V. 8. Department of Agriculture. C. B. Lee, A. M., Assc-iate in Animal Husbandry. M. H. Swenk, A. M., Ai&gt;.sii( itilr in Entomology. George K. K. Link. A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. J. W. Calvin, B. Sc., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Barker. A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (8oils). Er\vi\ Horr. B. Sc.. Assistant in Aqronomy (Crops). i. A. Ratcutf, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. Howard J. Gsamlk-h. B. Si.. Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Horses). L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. U., Assistant in Animal Pathology. E. G. Woodwabd, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper, B. Sc., Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. Sc, Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. James Cowan. M. E.. Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fritz K-sorr, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell. S. V,'. Pkrin. Farm Superintendent. H. L. Nie. Foreman Demonstration Farm. Culbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">TABLE OF CONTENTS. Introduction 5 Type of soil 7 Storing water in the soil 7 Effect of the condition of the soil It tiie surface on water retention 7 Effect of the character of the rain on already water retention. . 8 Effect of the amount of water in the soil on water retention 8 Loss of water from the soil 10 Cultivation to conserve moisture 11 Summer tillage 12 Disking after the binder 14 Plowing versus disking 15 Artificial mulches 16 Depths to which crops have used moisture 16 Effect of weeds 18 Summary 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">BY W. W. BURR.* INTRODUCTION. Ifn this paper we have attempted to sum up the main fact* eated by the study that has been carried on at the North :te Substation for a number of years relative to the storage use of soil moisture. The entire discussion is based upon ilts of work which has been done in the field, exposed to the e climatic conditions to wiiich all fields in that immediate lity are exposed. The effect on the moisture content of the under a large number of different tillage methods has been lied. Accurate climatic records have been kept so as to jerly interpret the results. Much has been written during the last few years in regard to the storage of moisture in the soil, which is correct and well founded. Other statements have been made which were either incorrect or so stated that they allowed the wrong inference to be drawn. We have found that when the moisture comes in suffi - cient amount and is properly distributed we can store this mois ture in our soil in considerable amount. However, we have not ■ncceeded in storing enough moisture before seeding the crop to mature that crop. Whenever there is sufficient moisture present in the soil at seeding time, it gives an effect which might be termed overstimulation ; that is, it starts more growth than can be sup - ported thruout the entire season, the plants stool out, giving a heavy growth of straw which makes rapid use of the moisture which falls. If, then, a dry season comes, which is always accom - panied by other unfavorable factors, such as high winds, high temperature, and low relative humidity, the demand for water I* Detailed from the Office of Dry Land Agriculture, U. S. Department Agriculture Formerly Associate Professor of Soils and Crops at the rth Platte Substation. kThe data presented In this bulletin have been obtained by the North tte Substation in cooperation with the Office of Dry Land Agriculture I the Biophysical Laboratory of the Bureau of Plant Industry, D. S. mrtraent of Agriculture. A detailed statement of these experiments 1 be found in Research Bulletin No. 5. which can be had on application. ■ The author is indebted to Messrs. Fritz Ullrich, S. B. Noland, and V. Burr for assistance rendered in taking soil samples. BULL. 140, AGE. EXP. STATION OF NEBE. VOL. XXVI, AST. SL </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 The Storage and Une of Soil Moisture EKiich conditions is so great that the crops suffer. In the ountain country, where hot winds and increased wapof - &gt; not prevail, it is probably possible to produce a crop entirely on stored water. Our work has shown that when a moisture stored in the soil to be used in addition to the 1 which comes, we are much more certain of a yield of This has been especially true of winter wheat. On the other hand, we have found that we cannot store water excepting it come as rather heavy rains, or in frequent showers for a period if the rains are light. The isolated shower does very little good .for storing water, and even a heavy shower falling on a soil surface which is already dry and hot will be lost before it can get deep enough into the soil to be held by any cultivation. Cer - tain erroneous ideas in regard to the storage of soil water are still i|iiite prevalent. The idea that continued cultivation will ac - cumulate water in the soil has no foundation. The only thing that cnltivation can possibly do is to hold the water already there : it rannot create water. When there is sufficient water already in the soil to cause an upward movement of water to the surface, cultivation will check this movement, and there may be an accumu - lation of water just below the cultivated portion of the soil. The cultivation is, however, to prevent the escape of the water already there, and not by any mysterious means to create water. It is simply reducing evaporation from the surface and killing the weeds to prevent their use of the water. The fact that this water, already present in the soil, has been held, while in an adjoining field, where no cultivation was done, it has been lost, has been the basis of certain misconceptions. Some men have been led to think that the stations and dry farming men are trying to teach that by continued cultivation we can accumulate water in the soil even tho it does not rain. This has doubtless been inferred from the teaching of men who have used it to propagate certain so - called systems of dry farming. The fact is, if the soil is already dry and no precipitation comes, the moisture content of the soil cannot be increased by any amount of cultivation. We can, how - ever, by stirring the surface and killing the weeds, conserve moisture after it has soaked into the soil. The actual data upon which this discussion is based are pur - posely omitted, since it would require too much space to present them. A more detailed discussion and a presentation of the actual data obtained is given in Technical Bulletin No. 5 of the Nebraska Experiment Station.* * Anyone interested in the details of the work or in the actual data obtained will receive this bulletin by applying to the Director of the Agricultural Experiment Station, Lincoln Vpbraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The atmrmg* ami Uae of Soil Moisture 7 The soil on the Sulist:it ion farm is what is commonly known as hard laud. It is a very tine sandy loam of the loess formation. The native vegetation was mainly buffalo and grama grasses. The soil is free from gravel and is easily tilled. The mechanical character of the soil is qaHc uniform to a considerable depth, the most noticeable change being less organic matter in the subsoil, in - dicated by a change in the eolor. The most notable change in color usually begins in the third or fourth foot, the npper Boil being darker than the lower soil. I It is imjK'rafive that the type of Roil on which the work has n done be kept in mind. Any variation in the soil type is apt nodify the results which one will obtain. There is. however, lose similarity between the soils of the North Platte Station in and those found in large areas in various sections tliruout western half of the State. It is quite certain that like work ie on these soils will give results very similar to those obtained the Substation farm, if the work is done under like climatic ditions. STORING WATER IN THE SOIL. t Storing water in the soil consists in getting the water into the and then preventing its escape. There are a number of tors and conditions which modify or control the storage of ter. Tt seems best to divide these factors and to treat them ler separate heads so that the importance of each may be better lerstood. Only those factors which are largely under the con I of the farmer will be discussed. Getting the water into the soil dej&gt;ends upon — The condition of the surfaee soil at the time of the rain. The character and amount of the rain. The amount of water already in the soil. EFKKCT OF THE CONDITION OF THE SOU. AT THE SIKPACE ON WATKlt RETENTION. The condition of the surface soil has an important influence on the amount of water that will be retained from a certain rain. Water runs ofi' more freely from a smooth, dry surface than from a surface which has been loosened by cultivation. The snn &lt;&gt;th. compact, or dry soil offers more resistance to the penetration of the water than does a soil that is more open or more moist. Where the surface has been cultivated, the water runs into the openings made by the implement used, and is held until it can soak into the soil. Where the surface has not been stirred, there are no such open spaces to catch the water. As soon ;•» the soil </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Tlie Storage and Use of Soil Moisture at the surface has been filled It can hold no more water except as the water is removed from the surface by penetration to lower depths. The water which falls in excess of the amount that can readily be absorbed by the soil will be lost as run-off unless the surface is very level. Obviously the amount of run-off from an.v rain is governed largely by the type of soil and character of the rain. A loose, sandy soil offers so little resistance to the pene - tration of water that there is very little run-off even during heavy rains. The soil particles composing the sandy soil are larger than those of heavier soil and consequently the open spaces are larger and water readily penetrates into the soil. It is only dur - ing excessively heavy rains that run-off is seen in very sandy soil. The resistance to the penetration of water increases as the soil l&gt;ecomes heavier or more like clay. All gradations are found, from i lie sand, which offers so little resistance to the penetration of water, to the gumbo, where penetration is extremely slow. We have observed that water will stand for several days over a heaw gumbo spot, and he lost mainly by evaporation rather than inn served by penetration, often penetrating only a few inches into the soil. EFFECT OF THE CHARACTER OF THE RAIN ON WATER RETENTION. The character of the rain has also an important influence on the amount of water which will be retained from any given rain. The more rapidly the water falls, the greater the run-off. During heavy, torrential rains the water fa lift so rapidly that it does not have time to penetrate into the soil and is lost by run-off. The tM-ating drops of water often puddle or clog the surface, making it more difficult for the water to enter. The more open and j&gt;ormis the surface is. the more water it will admit from any rain. Thus a cultivated surface will retain more water from a heavy rain than an uncultivated surface. It is a matter of common ofceer vation that a heavy downpour of rain frequently does less good than a much lighter rain that falls more slowly. The type of rain that is really most l&gt;eneficial is the rain of sufficient amount and falling slowly enough to be carried into the soil to a depth where it will not be exposed to the rapid surface evaporation. rCT OK THE AMOITNT OF WATER AI.REAHY IN THE SOIL ON WATER RETENTION. Of equal importance with the two factors above mentioned in governing the amount of water held in the soil from any given rain is the amount of water present in the soil when the rain comes. A very dry soil offers much greater resistance to the downward movement of water than does a moist soil. In a very </seg>
            <seg id="p009">dry soil the movement is so retarded and the amount of water required to moisten it so great that the water from a single rain, coming alone, is generally held near the surface. From here it is soon lost thru the rapid evaporation which takes place at the surface. On the other hand, where the soil is already moist when the rain comes, it is much more quickly carried away from the surface. It is also distributed to lower depths in the soil and thus protected from the rapid loss at the surface. Frequent ob - sprvjitiors liiivc been made along this line on the native sod. This is tiMinlh hard and dry. It is seldom wet more than a few inches by the rains that come singly. The lower depths receive moisture only during "rainy'' or "wet" spells when a second rain comes before the moisture from the preceding rain is lost. I Our experience has shown us that we can seldom separate the ious factors influencing the storage of water so as to study ■ one factor as a single problem. All factors are important not all are equally under man's control. In almost every test made we have found that sod laml. which is usually hard, dry, and smooth at the surface, absorbs less water than a cultivated soil. The difference usually varies in direct ratio with the rate at which the rain falls. If the rain fall&gt; slowly lei-s difference will be found, because the slow falling rain has time to soak into the soil, even where the surface is smooth md dry. and there is little run-off. If the rain comes as a bear} downpour, the difference is greater, and the more the surface is tii-red and opened up the more water it will admit. Sod land which is supporting a large number of plants on a given arc a is usually drier than the cultivated soil, and as a consequence a single rain seldom wets the soil more than a few inches. As an example of this, during a certain rain in 1009 the brome sod land was wet to only three inches, while corn land adjoining this, which contained more moisture at the time the rain fell, was wet to nine inches. During another period extending thru several days, over three inches of rain fell ; the soil of a field of alfalfa on the table land was wet to a depth of only seven inches by the water it retained from the three inches of rain. A piece of wheat laml which had been spring plowed, and was almost" as dry as the alfalfa land, tho doubtless more open, due to its more recent plow ing. was moist thruout the entire first foot, and a small amount of water had entered into the second foot. An adjoining corn tield which was cultivated at the surface and already contained a considerable amount of water was moistened by the rain to the third or fourth foot. All of our experience shows that a culti - vated surface will absorb more moisture than a surface not </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 The Storage and Use of Soil Moisture t ion to the amount of water already in the soil when the rain LOSS OF WATER FROM THE SOIL. Ehere are three ways by which water may be lost from the First, escape downward by percolation; second, evapora - from the mmtmu. ; third, transpiration, or loss by being used lants. t)f the first named means of loss little need be said. It is &gt;m that we pet enough water into the soil to allow percola - beyond the reach of the plant. Percolation does not take e to any considerable extent until a soil is filled beyond its ying capacity. This point is very seldom reached, but when lied, the percolation is beyond our control. The second means of escape, that is. by evaporation from the surface, is to a certain extent under the control of the farmer. There will always be some loss even under the best system of cultivation, but it can be reduced to a minimum. The water that evaporates from the surface reaches the surface in much the same way that oil from the bowl of the lamp reaches the flame. The water passes from one soil particle to another until it reaches the surface and is lost by evaporation. This upward movement is quite rapid when the soils are wet and is retarded as they dry out. If the surface of the soil is cultivated it becomes loose and dry. Both the looseness and the dryness tend to retard the further movement of water to the surface. Water moves very slowly thru ■ loose or dry soil. In this section a rain is usually followed by a hot sun and wind. These cause a more rapid loss of water from the surface than can be supplied by capillarity from adjoin ing soil particles. The result is that the soil surface soon dries. This is of itself a check to surface evaporation. The water from below moves slowly thru the dry surface/ If the rain was of sufficient amount to make the surface smooth and connect with the under moisture it should be stirred as soon as practicable. In order to reduce evaporation from the surface to I minimum, it is essential to have on the surface not only a dry soil but a loose soil. Cultivation will stir the surface soil, causing it to dry out more quickly and leave the soil kernels not so closely in contact. The fewer the points of contact between the smail particles of soil and the drier they become, the more effective is the mulch in re - ducing evaporation. Another reason for cultivation soon after ■ rain, especially where a field is bare, is that a smooth soil blows much more quickly thnn a rough soil. This, of course, applies to the soils that are light enough to blow and in regions of frequent high winds. On this type of soil we feH thnt two or three inches is suffi- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Utoruge and Use of Boil Moittwe 11 ciently deep to make an effective mulch. Where the mulch is too shallow, there will be enough circulation of air thru the mulch to cause considerable loss. On this soil almost any implement that stirs the surface can be used if it does not pulverize the soil too finely. Where the surface has become so dry that the drag-harrow pulverizes, we prefer the disk. On still lighter soils the disk 111 ijrtit pulverize too much and make some other implement prefer able. The objections to a very fine or dust mulch are that it will blow and that it offers too great resistance to the penetration of rain water. IPhe third means of escape of water from the soil, that of being vn out by growing vegetation, is much more effective on this of soil than surface evaporation. Considering only the mois - content of the soil, the water used by any plant is lost. From standpoint of the farmer, only the water which is used by Is is lost. This is, of course, a real loss since the weeds have I i 1 1 It- pract ieal value. The little value they have is furnishing nic matter to the soil. The water that is taken up by the s of the &lt; -rops. passed thru the plant, and exhaled by the i's. has served its purpose. It is for this purpose that we re to store the moisture in the soil. i\s imich water is required to grow a pound of dry matter of Is as is required to produce the same amount of dry matter line of the farm crops. From the standpoint of crop produc - weeda are the worst enemy of the farmer who is farming er a limited rainfall. Any water used by weeds is lost to the i. It is hardly practical to keep all weeds down, but the crop snally cut short to the extent that it has been robbed of the IV by weeds. From a large number of tests that have been e, it is found that where weeds are allowed to grow thruout season they dry the soil as thoroly as does a crop of small CULTIVATION TO CONSERVE MOISTURE. Cultivation is the one practical means that the farmer has for conserving moisture over any considerable area of land. It is by cultivation that the surface is put in condition to catch and hold the water until it can soak into the soil. Weeds are killed by cultivation and thus prevented from using the water which falls. Cultivation also checks the loss of water from soils by direct evaporation. Stirring the soil loosens the surface, hastens the process of drying the surface layer, and decreases the points of contact between the soil particles, so that the water from below cannot so readily reach the surface by capillary action. In other words, we purposely sacrifice the moisture in the cultivated layer in order to conserve that in the deeper levels. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 The Storage and Vie of Soil MuUliue SUMMER TILLAGE. From the standpoint of storing moisture in the soil, we have found summer tilling, which is clean cultivation without any crop for a season, the most ideal way in which to store moisture. When the rainfall of a season is insufficient to produce a profit - able crop, it may be better to summer till than to crop every year, and thereby store a small portion of one season's rainfall to use with the rainfall of the following season for the production of a single crop. In other words, to use not "two years' rainfall for one crop," but rather a small portion of the first year's rainfall, added to a somewhat larger portion of the second year's rainfall for the crop. Our investigation shows that it is only under favor - able conditions that as much as 33 per cent of the rainfall of one season can be carried over to the next, and that during the most unfavorable season only 10 per cent was carried over. Probably not more than 60 per cent of the second year's rainfall is utilized l&gt;y the growing crop, and it is probably safe to assume that con siderably less than one year's rainfall is fully utilized for crop production under the best system of summer tillage. Summer tilling is a system that has been practiced for a long time in the drier sections of the country. Altho this method of utilizing moisture is seemingly an exceedingly wasteful one, it is l&gt;robably the best one yet devised for some crops, soils, and cli - matic conditions. It is obvious that it will hardly be profitable to summer till a shallow soil, for in such soils the effect of cultiva - tion is of little value in storing water. Where there is a layer of hard-pan, gravel, rock, or sheet water close to the surface, the amount of water which the shallow layer of soil above this stratum will hold is so limited that probably one good rain would fill it. It is useless, therefore, to keep it clean cultivated thru an entire •eason. Crops grown on this type of soil are almost entirely dependent on seasonal rainfall because of the very limited amount of water that can be stored in so shallow a soil. We cannot store sufficient water in such shallow soils to carry the crop thru a long dry spell. As soon as the moisture stored in the soil is and, crops will suffer or die according to the duration of the drouth. On the deeper soils, however, which prevail over the greater por - tion of the central and western part of Nebraska, it is possible under normal weather conditions to store a considerable amount of moisture as a safeguard to the crop against drouth. It must be borne in mind, however, that the bad effect of overstimulation, already mentioned, will sometimes more than offset the benefits of this stored moisture, and that in some seasons the increased yields due to summer tillage may not be sufficient to pay for the extra expense. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Storage and Use of Soil Moisture 13 IJonsiderable work has been done at the Station to test sum - tillage as a means of storing water. The results have varied the amount and distribution of the rainfall during the period ring the summer tillage. In years of normal rainfall, with nal distribution, we have succeeded in filling the soil with t to a depth of from five to seven feet. In the driest years, less total amount of rainfall, and the rain falling mostly as ited rains or light showers, we have not succeeded, even under best methods of summer tillage, in storing very much water, ing the past eight years the per cent of the total rainfall held iimmer tillage varied from 10 to 33 per cent for the various 9ns. iln the summer of 1908 there were eight rains of more than ■half inch each, three of which were more than an inch. There ■e also rainy jx'riods when light rains came so close together t the surface soil was wet from one rain until the next ; and, refore, even the small rain penetrated below the surface. Dur - that year we succeeded in getting into the soil all the water mu Id hold to a depth of six or seven feet. &gt;In 1909. five and one-half inches of rain, or about one-fourth he total amount of water which fell, was retained by summer ige and the soil was again filled to a depth of seven feet. In 1910, only three rains of more than one-half inch came. Only one of these did very much good from the standpoint of stor - ing moisture; the other two fell as isolated showers. The surface was so dry and hot that all the water was held within the first few inches of soil and did not get deep enough into the soil to be held !&gt;y surface cultivation, but was lost thru evaporation within a short time. During this season, only two feet of soil were filled to normal carrying rapacity. The third foot showed a slight in crease in water content. About 21 per cent of the total rain - fall of the season was held. Even with this small amount of stored water, this field and another that was summer tilled with much the same results in 1910. and both sown to winter wheat. were the only fields that produced small grain in 1911. This stored water, while only a small amount, was sufficient with the Hgtal seasonal rainfall to sustain the crop and make a yield of about twelve bushels per acre. In 1911 the total amount of rainfall was greater than in 1910 hut the distribution of the rain was not as jrood. Only about 10 per cent of the total rainfall was held. The trouble waB that either the rain would fall in such light showers that it was not sufficient in amount to soak into the ground deeper than the first few inches of the surface, or else the showers would come singly, - ] } I * y» fm j 4» | \\ f\^ (\ I 1 \" ui | f*f Q fiO TVd^ll \i\ \\t^ 1 4~tflt fit T*ll t" Vl a 1*41 T\l li I I 1111 1 4 1 111 tl^ ' IM \ 9M\~ I a^J , ** • * * ■ *™ ■ ■•V rf » %^ • </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 The atorayn and U$e of Soil Moiature i oration. The best distribution of rain for storing water is 1 the showers are so frequent that the surface does not dry thoroly between them. One such rainy season with several es of water falling during a period of several days will do i good from the standpoint of storing water than a much ier rainfall falling as single showers. It takes an inch of •r to wet the surface six inches. If, then, only an inch of ;r falls, the most of it will be lost in creating a mulch. If her rain conies while the surface is still moist it can be ied into the lower soil. I In 1912 conditions for storing water were favorable during a t of the season, and the soil was filled to four feet and some er entered the fifth foot. During this MMM 12 per cent of the total rainfall was held. A large portion of the seasonal fall was so distributed that it could not be gotten deep enough &gt; the soil to be conserved. From this discussion it will be seen that the amount of water - lored by summer tillage depends on the amount and distribution of the rainfall. In some years it is comparatively easy to accu - mulate the moisture in the soil; in others it is next to impossible to get it into the soil. Unless we can get the water deep enough in the soil we cannot conserve it. It is needless to say that we cannot conserve rainfall we do not get, nor can we hold water which we have not gotten: and no amount of cultivation will in crease the total amount of water in the soil. In fact, some men who have been practicing summer tillage put more work on their summer tillage than is warranted, and may get more labor costs involved in the actual operation than the crop is worth. Our aim at the Station has been to cultivate only so much as is absolutely necessary to keep the surface in shape and to destroy the weeds. A bare surface, such as is essential to summer tillage, must be cultivated after a hard rain, else it would blow, ruder our con ditions. a smooth surface will alwavg start blowing first. I At the Station a crop of winter wheat has been produced evcrj r on summer tilled land. The yields have varied from 12 to bushels per acre, depending upon the amount of water stored, seasonal rainfall, and the climatic conditions. For winter &gt;at, summer tillage has proved a practical and profitable hod during the eight years it has been tested. For spring in the results have been indecisive, some years proving profit p and ethers years not. No benefit has been derived from mier tilling for corn except in the seasons of worst drouth. DISKING AFTER THE BINDER. Tt is frequently not desired to pummer till in the preparation </seg>
            <seg id="p015">1 rtts OvOfiMf€ dftd (J 8fS Of OOtl JrJOiStUTC 15 Iie seed-bed for a crop. The same principles, however, should pplied as are applied in summer tillage; that is, keeping the ace in shape to catch the water and keeping the weeds from g the water. The preparation of the seed-bed should com - ce as soon as practicable after the preceding crop is off the ind. Usually the longer the seed-bed is prepared and kept in &gt;er condition the greater the amount of water that will be ed, and the firmer will be the seed-bed. A firm seed-bed is atial for all crops. After a crop of small grain has been n from the ground it usually becomes weedy unless it is ivated in some way, or unless it is so dry that weeds will not r. The weeds that grow on the grain stubble field, after the ious crop has been taken off, use the water and plant food. :h should be saved for the succeeding crop. Considerable work has been done to determine the effect of disking after the binder on the conserving of soil moisture. Wherever there was sufficient moisture in the soil to produce a crop of weeds and these were killed by disking, we found a sav - ing of moisture on disked land over land not disked. In some cases where heavy rains came during the test, some benefit was found by the disked land catching more of the water than was caught by the unstirred soil. We have not made actual test to determine the financial profit in disking, but from the moisture standpoint it will prove beneficial to stir the surface so that it can catch more of the rains that may come, and kill the weeds that are on the ground. The soil is frequently so dry and hard after harvest that it is necessary to weight the disk in order to make it do the work thoroly. PLOWING VERSUS DISKING. I From tests that have been made at the Station, plowing has n better for storing moisture than disking. The difference in ie cases has been very little. It is dependent on the amount of i that comes while the test is being made and the rate at which water falls. If heavy rains fall, the increase in moisture con - t of plowed land over disked land is greater. This is to be ex - ted, since the plowing stirs the surface of the soil more thoroly, I puts it in better condition to catch any rain that comes. The wing will also kill all of the weeds. The disk does not in all bs do this. It may be preferable — if a soil does not blow when s fall plowed — to plow the stubble fields instead of disking m. This, however, is frequently impracticable, due to the dry - si of the soil. K sting the soil has been almost as good as plowing. We have lowever, made many tests to determine the effect of listing. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 The Storage and Use of Soil Moisture ARTIFICIAL MULCHES. It is a coinninu practice to use artificial mulches among shrubs, small fruit, and in some cases vegetables. The Station has done some work to determine the value of artificial mulches from the standpoint of catching and holding the water that falls. These mulches are usually composed of old hay, straw, or manure. From the standpoint from which they are applied, that of retain - ing water, they are most efficient and have a practical applica - tion. Wherever it is &lt;1 ired to grow shrubs, ornamentals, or small fruit, the mulch can be used for retaining water. Against its efficiency in holding water, is sometimes advanced the opinion that it forms a harboring place for injurious insects. We have no data on the latter point. For storing water, a mulch of straw or hay has been found more effective than a soil mulch. The hay mulch is so open and porous that water falling as rain will readily penetrate into it without run-off. A hay or straw mulch is also more effective in reducing evaporation. The mulch itself quickh dries after a rain, but protects the water in the soil underneath from loss thru evaporation. The particles composing the arti - ficial mulch are so coarse and have such large spaces between them that water from below cannot move upward by oapil DEPTHS TO WHICH CROPS HAVE TSED MOISTURE. I The depth to which a crop will use moisture depends upon the t revelopment of the crop, the length of its growing season, its mal development, the type of soil on which it is being grown. I the location of the moisture in the soil. Some crops make more root development than others and naturally send their roots deeper into the soil to obtain water and plant food. An extreme example of deep feeding is seen in alfalfa. Other crops feed to a lesser depth. The length of the grow - ing season also affects the depth to which water is used. A perennial crop, such as grass, will dry the soil to a considerably greater depth in a series of years than it will in one year. It may he that there is some continued growth of the roots and that they keep growing so long as they can find water, or the drying of the lower soil may be due to the water being brought to the roots by capillarity during the greatly extended time. Winter wheat due to its longer growing season develops a deeper root system than does spring wheat, and consequently uses the water from a lower depth than does spring wheat. I During a very favorable season a crop may become so injured t it will not make normal development and consequently does use the water to as great a depth as it would had it developed </seg>
            <seg id="p017">The Storage ami Unc of Soil Moisture 17 normally. Indications of Mils were observed in a number of plats in 1913. The crops were so damaged by the hot winds that they died while there was available water which would have been within the reach of their roots if they had made normal development. The plants were so injured, however, that they did not send their roots into the lower soil. I The type of soil is an important factor in determining the th to which crops will feed. On a loose or a sandy soil that rs but little resistance to the penetration of the roots, a plant 1 send its roots to a greater depth than on a heavier soil that ts more resistance. A layer of gunibo or hard-pan near the face will prove more or less impervious to plant roots and Be the crop to feed in the soil above it. Shale or rock has the le effect but it is more marked. It is a matter of common ob - ration that during dry seasons the crop will suffer first on the ts in the field where an impervious stratum comes nearest the face. The feeding ground of a plant is limited to the contiguous area of moist soil occupied by its roots. This feeding ground may be larger or smaller, depending upon the character of the soil and its moisture conditions. Plant roots will not penetrate far into either a dry or an impervious soil. In a field where the surface layer of soil is moist, overlying a stratum of dry soil, which iu tarn overlies another stratum of moist soil, the plant may be unable to secure moisture from the lowest area because of the dry stratum which lies between the two. This condition some - times happens, even when the lower area of moist soil is easily within reach of the plants if there was no dry layer of soil be - tween to prevent the penetration of the plant roots. The surface layer may contain enough moisture to start the crop nicely, or, if rains conic f ,'quently, to mature the crop without increasing the thickness of the surface layer of soil in which the roots feed. If rain does not come at the right time, the plants may die while there is an abundant supply of moisture only a little way below the feeding ground of the roots, and easily within reach but for the layer of dry soil which the roots cannot penetrate. If at any time there is enough water to wet the dry stratum, then the roots of the plant may penetrate it and have access to the moisture in the lower area. This condition may exist in fields planted to HUM grain crops, hut it is especially noticeable in fields sown to alfalfa where permanent moisture is found at from 10 to 30 feet below the surface. This intermediate stratum of dry soil often prevents the alfalfa roots from reaching the moist soil beneath, especially where alfalfa is sown upon land in which there is but little moisture at the time the crop is sown. If con </seg>
            <seg id="p018">§D8 are such that Um plant can once reach the zone of per - :nt water supply, it will then continue its growth when the r areas of the soil are too dry to furnish moisture for th. It is therefore very important to have available mois - in the soil to a depth of several feet when alfalfa or other rooted plants are to be sown. (Averaging all of the results obtained on depth of feeding, we e found that oats, spring wheat, barley, and corn feed to a th of 4 feet ; winter wheat feeds to a depth of 6 or 7 feet ; per - iial grasses dry the soil out to a greater depth. Alfalfa will d its roots to greater depths for water than any other common m crop if water is available in all intervening portions of the to supply the roots while making this greater growth. In this oner alfalfa on the second bottom lands usually obtains manent water supply. The roots frequently go down to the et water where it is within 20 or 30 feet of the surface. EFFECT OF WEEDS. IAb above stated, weeds are the worst enemy of the farmer who arming under limited rainfall. All of our work has pointed to fact that from the standpoint of storinir moisture, the killing the weeds is even more bnportaat than cultivating the Boil, tivation, however, is the means &lt;&gt;f killing the weeds and serves ceep the surface soil in condition so that it will catch the water t falls, and not blow. In 1907 a small tract of land was kept thoroly cultivated until the middle of June; then one-half of it was allowed to become weedy, while the other half was kept cultivated. During the latter part of September, moisture determinations were made to a depth of three feet on each portion of the tract. It was found that three and one-half inches of water had been used from the upper three feet of soil by allowing the weeds to grow. The por - tion which was kept cultivated had at the eud of the season prac - tically all the rater it could carry, while the portion where the weeds had jjrown was as dry as it would have been had it pro - duced a crop of grain. Cases similar to this are sometimes seen where a tract is being summer tilled. The land is kept clean and water ston d during a portion of the season ; then other work be - comes urgent and the summer tilling is neglected. The weeds grow and use a part or all of the accumulated water, and the pre - vious labor is largely lost. iln 1908 a similar experiment was carried on thruout the entire son, and moisture determinations were made to a depth of 6 t at the close of the season. Where the weeds were kept down cultivation, five inches more water was found in the upper six t of the soil than waa found in the part where weeds were </seg>
            <seg id="p019">In 1911 a field on the Substation farm was being plowed in May. A portion of the field was free from weeds while on another [K&gt;rtion of the field Russian thistles were coming up quite thickly. Where no weeds were growing, the soil was in good condition to plow and was easily worked down into a good seed-lied. Where weeds were growing, the soil was very lumpy and hard when plowed, and was too dry to work into a good seed-bed. The wwil which had already used this water were quite small, averaging only two or three inches in height. Moisture determinations wen made from each of these portions, and on the average showed that the weeds had used over an inch of water from the first foot of •oil. When we consider that this inch of water already in the ■oil represents probably two inches of rain, the importance of killing the weeds liecomes more evident. Had the weeds l&gt;een killed early in the season, this water wolild have been saved for the use of the crop and less labor required to get a good seed-hwl. Similar conditions are sometimes seen during dry seasons in fields being listed to corn. Where the weeds have Iteen killed by preri - ons disking or other cultivation, the soil is in much lietter condi tion to list thiiii where the weeds are growing. In seasons of abundart rainfall the difference is less evident hMUK rreqnent rains furnish enough water to ipyly the weeds anil also keep the surface soil sulliciently moist to work easily. I In 1!M2 two small tracts of land were Rgaii used to determine effects of weeds. One of these was kept cultivated and the pr allowed to grow wed*. At the beginning of the season, "il l."&gt;. each contained practically the same amount of water. the close of the season, the cultivated plat contained fi inches re water in the upper 6 feet of soil than was found where weeds I l» en allowed to grow. I In 1013, moisture determinations were made on two plats of A being summer tilled. One was beiag worked according to usual method of clean fallow. The other was not plowed il after weeds had started, in order to save labor in the suni - • tilling process. On June 23, the date of plowing the latter I. a considerable growth of weeds had started and it was found t the soil was practically dry all the way down while the other t had already two feet of moist soil. There was a difference of i and one-half inches of water in the two plats, representing amount of water which had been lost by allowing the weeils to w. From the standpoint of storing water, keeping the weeds in is very important. SUMMARY. This piii&gt;er is meant to discuss the principles involved in stor - ing water, rathei- thai t" leach any actual farm practices. The </seg>
            <seg id="p020">application of principles To farm practice! must be left to the farmer. Our work lias added proof that a cultivated surface is more effective than one not cultivated in catching water from rains. AYe have found thai on this soil weeds are the ptilal agency for the loss of soil water. Not only liefore the crop is planted Inn after it is planted, wherever weeds are growing they ai-e using moisture. I It is left to ihe farmer to determine the most economical wa\ him to pat llie principles into practice. The problems differ h llie type of farming, but the principles do not change. One i wants to store water to grow grain for the market; another ires to grow more feed for stock. The returns from either will bably lie in proportion to the water supplied to the crop. unles* usual conditions, such as hail, come during the season. The amount of water available to the crop is the important factor in making the yield in the western half of the State. It is probably the most important factor in crop production in most of the State today. It is more important than any particular method of Ullage. We have found that tho some methods of tillage give belter average returns than some other method, yet Hm 1 method of tillage is overshadowed by the importance of the total amount of water supplied the Crop. Water stored in the soil Itefore seeding tends to insure the crop, but it is not sufficient to insure a profitable yield. The yield is influenced not only by the amount of stored water but bv the amount and distribution of the seasonal rainfall, and by other climatic conditions. 1'nder the same rainfall, the stored water tends to insure a higher yield from any crop. Moisture is the limiting factor of production under our conditions. The soils are still fertile and the replenish ing of their fertility is a question moi-e for the future than the p resent. E'he application of the principle* of storing water may be med up in a few sentences. The surface should Ik- kept in lition to catch the rains. It should l&gt;e cultivated to keep it ■ and rough, thus reducing evaporation and preventing blow The weeds should lie kept down as far as practicable both re and after seeding, to prevent their use of water. In order to bring farm practices up to the point of gi •cIV.ciency it is essential that the farmer understand the conditions under which he is fanning and the principles affcting the prac - tices. A thoro knowledge of the prevailing weather condit r: il conditions, and nature and requirements of crops are all ■iMal. lie can then work out lite practicis. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>