<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Pump Irrigation at the North Platte Experimental Substation</title>
               <date value="1936-06">1936-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 301 June, 1936 Pump Irrigation at the North Platte Experimental Substation Harry E. Weakly Irrigation for fall seeding of alfalfa after removal of corn for ensilage, 1934. Bulletin 39 of the North Platte Experimental Substation L. L. Zonk, Superintendent The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction 3 The Plant 3 Water Supply 3 Costs 5 Operating costs . 5 Fixed costs ....'■ 7 Crops Irrigated ■ g Corn for grain g Corn for silage . 9 Potatoes , 10 Alfalfa U Precipitation 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Pump Irrigation at the North Platte Experimental Substation Harry E. Weakly 1 During recent years, pump irrigation m Nebraska has increased greatly m importance as a result of the acute shortage of water for gravity irriga - tion and the unprecedented drouth of 1934. This bulletin reports the results of work dealing with pump irrigation m the production of crops, under conditions approximating general farm practices, at the North Platte Experimental Substation. The data presented have been accumulated under conditions which would make them of value as an indication of what might be expected from pump irrigation under similar conditions and general farm practices. The results from the earlier years of this work have been published previously m Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletins 227 and 271. THE PLANT The original equipment consisted of a six-inch horizontal, side-suction, centrifugal pump connected to three wells and powered by a thirty-horse - power kerosene engine. The average capacity of this equipment was from 900 to 1,000 gallons per minute. In 1925 the kerosene engine was replaced by an electric motor and the capacity of the plant increased by the addition of a fourth well. In 1930 a new double-suction six-inch centrifugal pump with direct-connected electric motor was installed. With the new pump and four wells, the capacity of the plant averages from 1,000 to 1,200 gallons per minute. The water table ordinarily stands at about 31 feet below the ground surface, and the pump is set m a pit at this level. The wells extend approximately 22 feet below this depth, and are of the open cased type. The casings are of metal, 24 inches m diameter with the lower 10 feet constructed of half-inch-mesh, heavy-gauge, galvanized-wire screen and the entire casing is surrounded by a three-inch screened-gravel envelope. The discharge pipe is constructed with two outlets, one at the ground level and the other approximately five feet higher. With an average draw - down m the wells of approximately eighteen feet and allowing three feet of additional head for friction m the pipes, the total head against which the pump must operate averages fifty-two and fifty-seven feet respectively for the lower and upper outlets. WATER SUPPLY The total depth of water-bearing material at the location of this pump - ing plant would indicate a plentiful water supply, but the greater portion of the water-bearing material is very fine sand mixed with some silt and clay. This fine material extends to within four or five feet of the bottom 1 lunlor Agronomist detailed hy DivUloti of Dry Land Agriculture. L". S. Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 301 of the wells and gives up its water slowly, so that the greater part of the water produced must come from the lower few feet of the formation, which is considerably more coarse and yields a large amount of water. Because of this condition, the average draw-down is greater than is usually con - sidered desirable from the standpo nt of operating economy. In .seasons when the water tatle is high and pumping is light, the amount of draw-down is correspo idingly less, while in seasons such as that of 1934 when the water table was very low and the demands upon it heavy, the draw-down amounted to as much as twenty -one feet. Under these conditions, it was necessary t9 regulate the discharge at slightly less than 900 gallons per minute by partially closing a gate valve in the dis- Table 1. — Power consumed, total power cost, and average cost pet \ilo - watt-hour ]or eleven years. Year Toul electricity Total cost Av. cost per used at pump kilowatt-hour Kilowatt-hours Dollars Cents 1925 10,820 S403.70 3.762 1926 9,560 373.82 3.910 1927 3,690 162.39 4.401 1928 5.760 251.31 -1.363 1929 7,880 284.20 3.607 1930 5,870 244.63 4.167 1931 5.080 192.57 3.790 1932 9,290 361.83 3.895 1933 5,396 152.49 2.820 1934 14,600 . 359.34 2.460 1935 8,920 225.06 2.523 Total 86,866 S3.011.25 Average 7,897 273.75 3.467 charge pipe, so that the pump could hold its prime and continue in opera - tion throughout the day during the most severe part of the season. Generally die amount of draw -down increases gradually throughout the season because of tJie temporiry lowering of the water table as the summer advances. This again may be illustrated by the season of 1934. At the beginning of this season, draw-down was not excessive for this plant, being somewhat less than seventeen feet, but as the season advanced and the water table receded, the dr aw-down increased to the unprecedented figure mentioned above. In the season of 1927, quite tie reverse was true. A relatively small amount of water was pumped anil the pump operated only intermittently throughout the season. This fact, coupled with an unusually high water table and plentiful precipitation, combined to keep the average draw-down at slightly over fifteen feet for the season. This low draw-down accounts for the high average delivery of water by the pump during this season. No permanent lowering of the water table has been observed. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Pump Irrigation COSTS The cost of pump irrigation is usually divided into two types of charges, operating costs and fixed costs. Items which make up the operat - ing costs are power, attendance at the plant, lubricants, and the cost of distributing the water; Fixed costs are charges made to cover the items of upkeep, depreciation, and interest and taxes on the plant and distributing system. As such, they are charged against the land irrigated rather than against the water pumped, as is the case with the operating costs. Operating costs. — Operating costs, total electric power used, and total cost and average cost per kilowatt-hour for each of the eleven seasons, 1925 to 1935, are shown in Table 1. Electric current rates are usually arranged on a sliding scale wherein unit costs decrease as the monthly use of current increases. Power rates have been revised several times during the period covered in Table 1. In each case, unit rates have been lowered, but increases have been made in the amounts of current required to be used at the higher rates before the succeeding reductions could be applied. The schedule last introduced, which was in effect in 1934 and 1935, is as follows: First 200 kw.-hrs., per month, 5.5 cents per kw.-hr. Ncxr 300 kw.-hrs., per month, 4.4 cents per kw.-hr. Next 500 kw.-hrs., per month, 3.3 cents per kw.-hr. Next 4,000 kw.-hrs., per month, 2.75 cents per kw.-hr. AH over 5,000 kw.-hrs., per month, 2.2 cents per kw.-hr. These rates would make power costs unduly high if a limited amount of pumping was done and no current used for other purposes. At the Substation an average of approximately 2,800 kilowatt-hours per month the year around is used for other purposes. When these are charged off first, there remains about 2,200 to be used by the pump motor each month at the rate of 2.75 cents before the 2.2-cent rate applies. At an average use of approximately 17.5 kilowatt-hours of electricity per hour, 12.6 ten - hour days of operation would be required to consume this 2.75-cent curient and any additional pumping would then be done at the 2.2-cent rate. Regular daily use of the pump for long hours per day makes possible the greatest use of the cheaper current and consequently tends to reduce the average unit cost of current. The variation in unit price of current as shown in the last column of Table 1 is due partly to changes in rates, partly to total amount of current used per season, and partly to monthly distribution of pumping operations. The latter is the more important of the three factors, as shown by the results of 1930 and 1931 when the rates charged were the same and the difference in amount of total current used was relatively slight, but because of the more intermittent use of the pump the unit cost in 1930 with the greater amount of current used was higher than in 1931. The same was true for the seasons of 1931 and 1932, when, because of the distribution of use of current, the unit price for current in 1931 was slightly less than it was in 1932 with almost twice as much current used in 1932 as in 1931. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Exieriment Station Bulletin 301 A summary of operating costs hours pump was operated, amount of water pumped, and average cost pe- acre inch is given in Table 2. During 1924 power was furnished by the kerosene engine, and for that reason figures for 1924 are not included in the averages. The per-hour cost of $1.47 for the engine is considerably higher than that for any year with the electric motor, but since 35 cents of this cost is charged as attendance at the engine and no attendance ct arge is made for the motor, the actual power cost becomes $1.12 per hour for the engine, which is just equal to the charge for the motor in 1928, but the additional three-fourths of an acre-inch pumped per hour by the motor would much more than offset this apparent gain. Since the a tendance charge is necessary with the Table 2. — Operating costs, numbe of hours pump was operated, number of acre inches of water pqmped, and cost per acre inch. a &amp; gi gjr It ii sir if n 1924 S 178.20 S 167.67 S 457.65 » 310.50 S 1.470 2M 621.00 $0 737 1925 404.74 187.60 592.34 469.00 1.260 2.20 103100 0 574 1926 381.72' 178.00 559.72 445.00 1.260 2.42 1.076.00 o'52O 1927 209.48 » 87.80 297.28 219.50 1.350 2.78 609.50 0 488 1928 251.31 139.20 390.51 348.00 1.120 2.75 957.00 0.409 1929 284.20 207.80 492.00 519.50 0.947 2.20 1,142.90 0 431 1930 244.63 120.90 365.53 302.25 1.210 2.52 76U60 0 479 1931 192.57 194.53 387.10 432.25 0.897 2.55 1,102 20 0 351 1932 361.83 183.49 545.25 524.25 1.040 2.48 1,300 14 0 419 1933 152.49 99.75 248.96 322.50 0.758 2.48 819 25 0 307 1934 359.34 255.90 615.24 853.00 0.721 2.20 1.919 32 0 321 1935 225.06 151.73 376.79 505.75 0.745 2.42 1,223.82 0.308 Total $3,067.47 $1,806.70 $4,870.23 4.941.00 $11,319 27.00 11,942.73 $4,607 Av.' 278.86 164.25 442.75 449.18 1.028 2.45 1,085.70 0.419 'This includes an attendance charge of $111.78. * Cosu of some irrigation the previous fall c larged to crops these two seasons • Average of eleven years, 1925-35. engine, it is a legitimate item in the cost of the water, and so we find that in this particular instance the engine was considerably more expensive as a source of power than the ele:tric motor has been. This engine used kerosene, a relatively high-priced fuel, but a more modern engine using distillate or some of the other cheaper fuels could be operated much more cheaply and on the basis of operating charges alone could probably com - pete successfully with the electric motor at the present electric rates as a source of power. The high first cost and high rite of depreciation of an engine as com - pared to those of an electric motor are also very important factors in choosing between the two sources of power, especially if the engine is to be used for nothing but irrigation. Where the engine is a farm tractor used </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Pump Irrigation also for other purposes, this disadvantage is largely offset by making the other uses of the tractor bear their full share of the cost of upkeep and depreciation. Fixed costs. — Fixed costs are based upon a fixed charge against the valuation of the plant and are calculated to cover the average amount of interest on the investment and upkeep and depreciation of the equipment. For the average plant powered with an internal-combustion engine, these charges run approximately as follows: interest 6 per cent, depreciation 10 per cent, and upkeep 2% per cent, or a total of 1814 per cent on the valuation of the plant. Because of the lower first cost and longer life of the electric motor, these charges are considerably reduced where this type of power is used'. Interest will remain at 6 per cent, depreciation about 5 per cent, and up - keep 1 per cent, or a total of 12 per cent. Table 3. — Total fixed cost, acres irrigated, and fixed cost per acre for the twelve years, 1924 to 1935. Year RatC «% h m 8&lt;: Total Acro I Fixed co« Y " r ?S ' , fixed cost irritated ! per acre — \rcr cent ) I 1924 18J/; $462.50 42.20 S10.96 1925 18'/, 462.50 74.20 6.23 1926 12 300.00 79.00 3.80 1927 12 300.00 61.00 4.92 1928 12 300.00 64.00 4.69 1929 12 300.00 89.90 3.34 1930 12 300.00 50.10 5.99 1931 12 300.00 78.00 3.85 1932 12 300.00 107.00 2.80 1933 12 300.00 70.70 4.24 1934 12 300.00 111.70 2.69 1935 ' 12 300.00 134.55 2.23 Average 1 .. 83.65 S4.O7 1 Year 1924 not included in the averages. As shown in Table 3, the fixed costs for irrigation operations are figured at the above rates. In 1924, when the engine was in use. the charge was I8V2 per cent of $2,500, the original valuation of this plant. This rate was continued in 1925 to take care of the additional cost of in - stalling an additional well and new motor. Since 1925 the fixed costs have been calculated at the rate of 12 per cent. The cost of adding one well has offset approximately the difference between the first costs of the engine and the motor, so that the valuation has been considered to remain at $2,500. Since the fixed costs are of such a nature that they are charged against the land irrigated, it is logical that the plant should be made to serve the largest possible number of acres consistent with good irrigation practices. Since fixed charges must be made every year, it seems quite obvious that it does not pay to have the pumping plant stand idle any more than is necessary. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 301 CROPS IRRIGATED Irrigation at the North Platte substation is confined to three crops — corn, potatoes, and alfalfa. These crops are all grown in units of one to fifteen acres, and thus the irrigaticn approximates general farm practices. " ..■ .--..__._.. Corn above and below a ditch immediately after that below the ditch had received the sec&lt; nd watering. Corn for grain. — Corn at the Substation is grown chiefly for silage. Usually, however, parts of fields are left each year for seed and to secure data on grain yields. Table 4 summarizes the results from nine years of irrigation of corn for the production of grain. Increased production has Table 4. — Corn for grain — acres i rigated, water used, cost per acre, aver - age yields on irrigated and dry' land, increased production, bushels per inch of water applied, and cost per bushel of increased production. . Av. inches , Av. yield Increased Increase Cost per Year Acres applied Av - cost '■ i yield P" lnch bushel irrigated pa me per acre Irrij ,, ted Dry hnd per acre "f!" increased I added production Bit. Bit. nn. Bit. Cents 1925 35.7 11.20 SI 2.65 4 .70 7.50 36.20 3.23 34.94 1926 39.5 10.17 9.09 40.50 2.50 38.00 3.74 23.92 1927 36.5 9.32 9.46 60.00 42.00 18.00 1.93 52.56 1928 31.0 9.80 8.06 60.00 32.70 27.30 2.79 29.54 1929 38.9 16.44 10.43 47.50 14.20 33.30 2.03 31.27 1930 33.0 18.34 14.84 9 5.64 30.00 66.64 3.64 22.27 1931 32.3 14.56 9.21 4J.07 14.00 35.07 2.40 26.26 1932 1 1933 42.9 12.78 8.14 5K86 24.00 30.86 2.41 26.38 1934 2.0' 21.07 9.44 :0.10 0.0 50.10 2.38 18.84 Average 32.4 13.74 10.15 5 i.82 18.54 37.27 2.58 29.55 'No yield in 1932 on account of hail. 'Total corn irrigated, 37.7 acres. Grain yielis secured on only two acres. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Pump Irrigation ranged from 18 to 66.64 bushels per acre at an average cost of 29.55 cents per bushel. The year 1932 is omitted on account of heavy hail damage. In 1935 no grain-yield records were secured. As corn is irrigated to supplement natural rainfall in supplying crop needs, the amount needed and used from year to year in a general way vanes inversely with the rainfall. The average amount used was 13.74 inches, and annual amounts varied from 9.32 inches in 1927 to 21.07 in 1934 The amount of water used per application varies with the slope of the land and length of corn rows, from about three to five inches. The usual number of applications has been two or three and occasionally only a single watering on some fields. The maximum was five waterings on one field in the dry, hot season of 1934. Pcr-acre costs averaged $10.15 and annual per-acre costs ranged from $8.06 in 1928 to $14.84 in 1930. On account of variations in cost of current, in operating costs and fixed charges as previously shown, there is only a slight relation between the amount of water used and the cost per acre. The large variations in acre yields are due to numerous causes, Table 5. — Corn for silage— number of acres irrigated, water used, total cost per acre, average irrigated yield per acre, pounds per inch of water, and irrigation cost per ton. Year .Acre. A : D ™ h " Cos, Average *»££ Irrigation Imgated Wh£ per acre Irrigated «JgP« cost lon , ''"" water used •" «'l»ge ,„,, Tom founds \Z " 932 S»-« 12.« 1.640 S0.7S 99 o , 9 /° 806 124 ° I ' 220 °« '" 389 &gt;«•« 10.41 9.70 760 0 75 930 33 -° 18-34 ,4.80 I2 .oo « 0 ,23 Hi u .f • 9 - 21 Ilfio ™ S 932 . 54 - 8 7.99 6.25 ' 4.25 820 147 " I 278 »■&gt;« «» L540 934 357 21.07 9.44 . 6.24 560 ,51 f 5 »•» 8-34 4.80 ,3.95 ,.900 rj Avmse 371 I3JI8 8.95 10.56 1.171 0.91 among which are differences in fertility of the fields used, variations in irrigation efficiency, timeliness of watering, and seasonal variations in the water requirements of the crop. Under Substation conditions, average yields of corn have been increased 37.27 bushels per acre. Each inch of irrigation water has on the average increased yields 2.58 bushels per acre. The average cost per bushel of increased yield has been 29.55 cents. Corn for silage.— Table 5 summarizes the results obtained from the irrigation of corn for the production of silage. As no comparable dry-land silage yields are available, no comparisons of irrigated and dry-land yields are possible. For this reason, costs per ton of silage are figured on the io« i? I Y rather tha " increased y« eld - Yields were reduced in 1932 by hail and in 1934 by high temperatures and drouth. These condi- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 301 tions were so severe that they could not be entirely offset by the limited quantity of water available for irrigation. The highest single yield of corn silage obtained to date was 20.3 to is per acre from one field in 1933. Potatoes. — Table 6 summarizes eleven years' data for potatoes grown under irrigation at the North Pla te Substation. In general, potatoes re - quire somewhat more frequent xvz tering than corn, and because of their slightly more shallow rooting habiis, do not require as large applications at any one time. Usually potatoes will do very well with from three to five irrigations. In extremely unfavorable seasons a greater number may be required, as in 1931 when potatoes required seven waterings and pro - duced the second-highest yield of he period. In 1934 they were watered eight times at weekly intervals and yielded but 290 bushels per acre, which shares third lowest place with the yield of 1927. The total amount of water used in 1934 is excessive as far as actual use by the potato crop is Table 6. — Potatoes — acres irrigate i, water used and cost per acre, com - parative irrigated and dry-land yields, increased yields, bushels of in - crease per inch of watei , and irrigation cost per bushel of increase. Acres Av - inch " Av cost AV " V ' cM Increased Increase Cost per Y " r irrigated applied pa- .ore 1 &gt; ieM p " lnch bushd per acre Irri "atcd Dry land per acre water increased . , I K added production Hi hels Bushels Bushels Bushels Cents 1925 3.50 19.00 S17.14 4:8.5 100.0 378.5 19.92 4.53 1926 4.50 26.70 15.68 2(3.0 102.0 181.0 6.78 8^66 1927 4.50 17.11 13.26 25 0.0 150.0 HO.O 8.18 9 47 1928 2.00 11.69- 8.84 4(0.0 255.4 144.6 12.37 6.11 IS 29 2 -00 16-30 10.37 3:7.0 100.0 227.0 13.93 4^57 1930 2.00 31.42 21.04 25.4 109.8 105.6 3.36 19.92 1931 2.00 36.46 17.29 4(8.0 78.0 330.0 9.05 5^24 1932 1.00 13.64 8.52 3! 0.0 97.0 253.0 18.55 3J7 1933 1.30 52.94 25.78 3:1.0 52.0 279.0 5.27 9.24 1934 1.00 33.75 13.51 2 0.0 0.0 290.0 8.60 4 66 1935 1.05 20.17 9.15 2' '3.6 50.0 243.6 12.08 3.76 Average 2.26 25.38 14.60 3.3.3 99.5 233.8 10.74 6.81 concerned, and probably should not all be charged against the crop. The last two waterings of this season were made quite heavy in order that considerable water might be got into the soil, as it was intended to plant this land to alfalfa the next season. Potatoes respond readily to irrigation and because of the relatively large yields and low irrigation cost per unit of increase, the crop may usually be produced at a fair profit. In litigating potatoes, certain practices are essential to best results. The potatc is much more sensitive to wrong irri - gation practices than corn. During the early growth of the tubers too much water will lower the quality and yield. During the later stages, the crop does not seem to be quite so sensitive to a small oversupply of water. When potato ground is prepared lor irrigation, it should be well ridged up, and care should be taken that ;he irrigation water does not reach the top of the ridges and come in contact with the base of the plants. This </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Pump Irrigation condition, when it is permitted to occufl, has a very undesirable effect upon the quality of the crop, as a result of the exclusion of air from the base of the plant and its roots. Sufficient water should be kept in the soil at all times, so that the crop will continue to grow vigorously without being checked by a shortage of moisture at any time. Even a short period of arrested development greatly decreases the yield and quality of the crop. The moisture in the soil should not be permitted to fall much below the point where the soil may be made to form a fairly firm ball by the pressure of the hand. If the soil becomes much drier than this, the growth of the potatoes will be checked and a large percentage of rough, knobby tubers will result. Alfalfa. — The greatest use of irrigation for alfalfa at the North Platte Substation has been for the purpose of restoring water to the subsoil pre- Table 7. — Alfalfa— acres irrigated, water used and total cost per acre, average yields with and without irrigation, increased yield due to irri - gation, pounds of increase per inch of water used, and irrigation cost per ton of increased production. Acres Av. inches Xv.cbil Av " yield Increased 'i cr . M « Cost per ton Year irrigated applied per acre i yield per inch increased per acre Irrical«i Dry land per acre waIer production I added Tons Tons Tons Pounds 1926 80 14.34 S11.26 3.80 1.50 2.30 321 $4.90 1927 3.0 9.87 9.82 4.00 2.00 2.00 405 4.91 1928 5.0 9.35 11.47 5.76 2.00 3.76 804 3.05 &gt; 929 4.0 11.30 8.18 5.60 1.00 4.60 984 178 193° 3.0 5.67 8.71 5.70 3.00 2.70 957 3.23 &gt; 9 31 -10 33.72 16.27 5.00 2.50 2.50 148 6.51 1932 11.0 29.87 15.33 5.50 2.00 3.50 234 4.38 1933 4.0 22.01 11.00 4.35 2.00 2.35 214 4^68 • 9 3-» 10.0 16.88 8.10 3.00 1.50 1.50 178 5.40 1"»35 2.0 28.44 10.99 3.50 2.00 1.50 105 7.33 Avenge 5.4 18.15 11.11 4.62 1.95 2.67 435 4.62 paratory to reseeding alfalfa on ground which has recently been in this crop. In such situations, subsoil moisture has generally been exhausted to con - siderable depths and it is almost impossible to replace it by natural means. On land where the ground water lies far enough below the surface that subsoil moisture cannot be replenished from below by capillary rise of ground water, irrigation is the only quick and economical means of re - plenishing it. On the very fine sandy loam soils such as those at North Platte, approximately two inches of water are required to penetrate the soil to a depth of one foot and 24 to 36 inches to wet the soil from the surface down to ground water on the bench land. Irrigation costs and yields of alfalfa hay for the ten-year period from 1926 to 1935 are sum - marized in Table 7. Alfalfa responds well to irrigation and usually gives very satisfactory increases in yield per unit of applied water. Its water requirements are </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Esperiment Station Bulletin 301 very high, however, and as a cons&lt; quence the acreage which may be satis - factorily irrigated by the limited an lount of water furnished by the average pump is relatively small. The srrall head of water available greatly in - creases the length of time requind to cover a given area and also cuts down the length of run, or the amount of ground covered from any one field lateral, thus necessitating a substantial increase in the number of field laterals, with attendant hampering of haying operations. These facts of necessity limit the use of any pumping plant for the irrigation of alfalfa. In general, the smaller the plant tie lower its efficiency for the irrigation of alfalfa. PRECIPITATION The amount of irrigation watei required by any crop during any given season is obviously dependent largely upon climatic conditions. During a season of high precipitation- and low evaporation, a very small amount of supplemental water will usually tide crops over any short, dry period which may and usually does occur :ven in the most favorable season in this section. In such a season a pumpi lg plant may be made to serve a much greater number of acres of crops t\ an in an extremely hot and almost con - tinuously dry season. The seasons of 1934 and 1935 at the North Platte Substation illustrate this point verf well. In 1935 the plant was made to serve 23 acres more land than it did in 1934 and with a considerably smaller total amount of water puriped. The results for these two seasons show that a much smaller amount of supplemental water in a relatively good season may be of considerably more value than a correspondingly greater amount in an extremely un favorable year. Table 8. — Monthly, seasonal, and annual rainfall for each of the seasons considered hi this publication. Year April May June j jly Aug. Sept. Seasonal Annual 1925 2.13 2.47 2.85 1.40 2.29 1.23 12.37 14.94 1926 0.47 1.50 4.31 ; .05 3.74 1.00 13.07 15.39 1927 3.72 2.38 5.07 (.88 3.63 4.03 19.71 22.45 1928 T. 3.93 4.86 ! .65 0.08 6.73 15.25 20.63 1929 3.51 2.47 0.93 .55 . 4.11 2.47 14.94 18.00 1930 3.73 6.76 4.14 H.85 2.65 1.73 19.86 27.15 1931 1.34 0.24 2.70 . .04 0.71 0.40 6.43 10.11 1932 1.95 1.77 3.94 &lt;1.51 1.66 0.26 16.09 18.73 1933 5.51 3.04 1.29 1.28 2.68 2.16 15.96 18.12 1934 0.40 0.62 2.30 (.72 3.89 3.19 11.12 12.49 1935 4.45 7.20 3.61 ; .47 2.44 0.78 20.95 23.17 Average 2.47 2.94 3.27 : .22 2.53 1.63 15.07 18.29 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>