<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>...22nd ANNUAL REPORT... OF THE Nebraska State Poultry Association Annual Convention and Exhibition...... Held in Lincoln, Nebraska, January 15th to 20th, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">..22nd ANNUAL REPORT... OF THE cHebraska State Poultry (Association Annual Contention and Exh ibition Held in Lincoln, 3(ebraska. January i5th io 20th, 1906 LUTHER P. LUDDEN, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Letter of Transmittal Poultry A. - mit the annual re; :ng Novembe- Very resp </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Offices of the &amp;&amp;bnsk* State Poultry (Association for the Ye*r 1905—1900 I I. Norval K i; l&gt;ay Krvmoni l.utht-r I'. I I I. I. \ in. in ! l.in.-.iln lloldrvirr Itrailshaw Offices of the £P{ebraska State Poultry cAssoeiz ion for the Yenr 190b 1907 I' I. ii. 1. 1. ; I I, l.vmnn. i;ii \i:n i'l II.K'II . . I Krutlsha « \\ . II &lt; itlumbuK K. l&gt; • ' inliinl.'ii I'lfiniint \ i &gt;. liurhanK. I'n-^ \jffn1 ...Lincoln .11 IMiKS K&lt;n: S Kiisscll IIOAKI) &lt;&gt;| I » 1 1 : Kt TOI!S Krvnn *n\ K\K&lt; ITI VK (&gt;|- I |i Kits T I.. Norval , .1 . .h Il~. Ml * &gt;ina ha dii:» toks I nivenot.v I'liirr &lt; II Kh. «l.-&gt; K II Hhfllalmryrr </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">TROCEEDINGS of the Twenty-Second (Annual Convention of The ch(ebraska State 'Poultry Association held it Lincoln, hnuary 16 and 18, 1906 I.I.Ni i il. N. NEKR. . .Ian order in the office of Secre - &gt;rval in the chair. md when the Secretary reached the 61st a quorum being present, id Mr. Bower- under the roll call be dispensed with. opted. l] announcement of the regular and such other irned until Thursday evening at LUTHER P. LUDDEN, Secretary. Room No niversity Building. Lincoln Nebraska, January 16th President Norval called the meeting to order and said: Ladies and Gentlemen: — \Vp are very fortunate in Nebraska this year, not only on account of the large yield of corn, oats, wheat and hogs, but we are fortunate in poultry matters. We all know what the old hen has done for us in the past and what she is doing now. We are fortunate for such a fine exhibit in our shoir room, but we are more fortunate this evening in having with us the greatest </seg>
            <seg id="p006">s poultry man in - Prof hrow ■ like him you have to ba man 1' aska man would want about ■11, then ) stand on if each represented $1,000. That v. Today poor did. man n </seg>
            <seg id="p007">I. THY ASS i li IATION products, and possibly more, be- nt tlie cities and villages. Oue other e dry and I will not dwell Ions upon them. (I have at our finder's ends some of these attlemen, sheepmen and other live stock t ir products and how much they are worth, we of what the American hen is doing. There liiUiM, farmers in the I'uited States, some 5,800,000, these farms of the United States have w 1 know that sometimes chickens have to take per cent of the farms of ihe United wing chickens today. That, Mr. President, seems to m to the boy and girl crop of the Tinted States i* t one not only in the. United States, but in the which p comes a close second. There are one or ' ittstics that we have from the United States m1 ih The." average production of the laying hen in the United lo/.en eggs in a year. Only 6G eggs tor one hen That is not a very large number. Another unpleasant iverage price of eggs In the United States is i- dozen. You and 1 like to. talk about the hen that t ioz.n eggs in a year. That would mean a doubling United States ,;even if it did not do more than re strains of poultry that, iay- 200 eggs a year. That he east, and 1 suppose it has been done in the i-lon hind the effete east. If, therefore, you are ,duci; of in i,- thai lay on the average - ■-.-* apiece in ■oducing more than the average lien in the i 1 gtati more than' 11.2 cents. They are have been selling for more than that. It is a good ;i dollar for your; eggs if you can. !i is possible to hat can be. said ia regard to oar business is Infancy, but it is growing wonderfully. It is a wood work and .we are in it as a life work'. 1 think we as poultry men Tlie evidence we can bring forward •an sa&gt; ii is ;i pood uusinc would include tho facts that cannot be gainsaid. While almost 90 he farmers' of the United Stales are raising chickens. ■r.'cei the other 10 per cent are raising chickens, not only out in the coun- try, but in the villages, towns, and cities; and the men who are igaged in the business today include clergymen, lawyers, business men. teachers, and in fact all of the professional men are engaged in it. If this Is true, then the keeping of poultry must be a very pleasant kind of business whether they are in i.t as an occupation or as a side issue -I n this business, of ours there is great competition </seg>
            <seg id="p008">NEBRASKA ri.TRV A- I think a poultry man is born and not made. A poultry man who takes a real live interest in his fowls and tries to make then *nd better i ir, is a man who has ambition, and ' do better each year than he did the year before, or tinner than his neighbor has done. In one sense he is like the gambler I heard about back in Rhode Island. This man had led a downward life for mam ltd had r and the spirit h hold of him m he wa: -. door. On his dea d in a friend of his and after talking with him a while and found a er, his friend said to him, "Had not II in a m v ill do me no good. I a man. Ti - ded him got hi:t me, salva talk i i the ii an a tion i prodih 'ird. Buff Wj Rock or any oilier .rhaps : You should She « il'ul and had one had pn her, and she wa.s Betting a n love </seg>
            <seg id="p009">IATION her to be his wife. ■ t know hardly how to manage will propose to -Miss lay he i; I Miss he way to some had the nerve of your in callin. 1 Johnson''" proposition tig in tha: r all. in a miin^ into I hlghwaya to carry convenience for ion — m in their hou of the I nation, draint md underneath the houses is well drained. Then of your houses with concrete, or whatever you wish, lly know how to express ho is this t;i! </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 11 Imilalii </seg>
            <seg id="p011">■ 11 I fresh ■ A'ben ill find i: ■ n corn If I « four ■ihinz is no !fa!fa ■limal food have roviding what ■ rin must </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 be provided. If you can obtain a rabbit an&lt;l cut the flesh into small pieces for your fowls to swallow they will take care that it is made into eggs. If you i I don't live n - slaughter hi lights an : "drown ' what is a su) Your ton rm of - is when you coi end of *ill find th.it j «&gt; that. The fact is the figures I ha\ this country, v I think it is a good problem fi </seg>
            <seg id="p013">SKBRA I I.TKV ASSOCIATION 13 ip this matter and get at the underlying principles of incu - in and put the knowledge into practice and have a better founda - tion for our I think these things will hold true if you You ought not to force your hens to lay througho ; them hare a rest through the fall when moulting and ha through the winter months. Then In the spring let them lay their eggs. You should not set your hens In this way you will be following nature, for o lay their eggs and hatch them is in the ill conditions are favorable and when everything Is Cand rearing of them. But so many -ire for the greatest success and the great - ve compel our hens to lay 200 or 250 eggs a year. tty who is trying to get his hens to he will be able to do it &lt;-ry much like a man in the east m easily it was for him to breed ook a Brahma, according to the standard and black hackle he finally produced a ler in them. I asked him why he could • until he gradually produced a strain on at all and thu that that would lie the thing to do i shipping our birds to market for our ta- f feed tli. ■i which they are intended. When operators a preparation ;ilbu- en and ■ vided for in the food. You know that It is one ur friends become sick the and milk are very much alike. The birth, for the reproduction of young of the em must be very active, and mperature and also produce jungle fowl of India, how many eggs do you fifteen or twenty, perhaps iore than 25 or 36 eggs in the whole ! it pro. I i and then had a ■aider of the year. We want our fowls to do ten and twenty times better than that and produce eggs. What for? &lt;*e chicki-: for us to swallow and we think we hav« • </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 and »■ ■ ■ fear H any d aiiim If 1 li.l'i lilll.' I Wl ■K'uliator litTii up that 1; and pan aJ animal an.! fed all grain ail die.l . it thoae fed all p anced ration of train aniinal .&lt; lived. onl&gt; t: iik. It ii ill ry men to aii.l these ihiuKK alihounh ih.- od practice on them to a reasonable ■ irv for </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 rinciple u boll bin :i that wi oial and corn. Kiiiuk that . ml .1 in hil qusJItii in who i, ii.' lias invested in his flock, in his buildings. and he knows books ■■ awls and il as the end ly how whether •ultrj man oimlit to have Kill. I wil , tlittes an. I ch.i -nil in any lii, n in havo wh&lt; in tin- eounti hi ought to have qualities of an old niaiil iltry order that !:■ ipou.tiynian must have the qualities tin quality thai qualities men poultry ' ll! I|l: " ls tht&gt; rt»mm they with chickens than men do. They have more till better The 8UCCP8 |M)iiliryinan must have qua! grandmother. That means that he has hail som&gt; experience in life in dealing with fowls: has also had ! " when sick oca, to provide a remedy. If you have these qaulitlea you will b -nil The question may Ih&gt; asked, What. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 IATION then, is the poor old bachelor going to do?" Th^rc is only one thing for him to do, and that is to marry the old m There is one little phase of this subject that I thought I would touch upon tonight. Some of you have boys and |fa Ms evening — I wish tli- ion is .isked by parents. What is the beat thing I can do for that boy or girl in life?" How often have I heard the remark. "I don't intend that m&gt; hard a time in life as I Kd. I intend that be, or she. shal; h ill the ances th. and an and every oppe boy a favor. T If yon »:&lt; i rough life, find out « It will be some him and know of an him a &gt;!■ boy i at the end of I man and help him &lt;mn&lt;t; who is full of lif' to do with himself. 1 »i - sonie chickens to U I know that that might be ti poultry keeping has a moral and soo: Mr. President. I think I will close and tunity to ask .: ion that (Applause.) </seg>
            <seg id="p017">NKHB.4 rXPOCLTI . ATION 17 :i — How would a curtain do in place of a straw loft? main has come to take the place d with it we can provide the heathl ■lan where the winter is severe is 8x9, ■ &gt;th in place of the glass window. the floor and have the perches and removable. In front of the platform hang lawn. This will provide against a cold sight and you want to guard urtain in front of the roosts. There the curtain in connection with that fresh air. I would not ■tain cloth will be all right. In this how me through then it nide boarding the hack part common iath and nail on. then stuff can ! burn it. which should iied with a free jirofits orawl 1 you .is if 2 Pe. If you •i in a Dry er tiouse D a bone a up finp not </seg>
            <seg id="p018">iQthing mixed uiiioriui . time. That condition should than horse maun fowls produ. top dressii Barrel "My fowls will not eat rjr&lt; on it " If chick. Another perha, Rape is an&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 and turnips? •• to be cooked. -ar beeet? I .inie eat them and some kins. rmilk" now that is siiiiii.i poultrynien h;, what the fowl rotein in the milk beinn i is manu- the Bner tion. If those her end of it and lose moi ng it and has it on lultry man will find have known of in this light ■xlucl Of ily obtainable and &gt;r you to find milk? in milk. milk' !iin&gt;; like that if the them sweet milk one day and sour milk the trouble If you make a efca '&lt;&gt; or thrc Iilenty of graves li. ■ &gt;n — No </seg>
            <seg id="p020">NEBRASKA STATF. POfLT; ATION Professor. Then you mi; o* form. I to buy grit I would rallies not buy i marke w (1 get the granulated boi of man it out. That - i har.l grit anil ana* gravel : at dp and repairii ( the fowl ■ your potatoes and nia&gt;hes hecanst- ' !.■: Qu&lt; aniiiKi anim edw- it. lm in ttai dry !■ it with it *: thonii Of d: it in it in !.' ■ foumi Mr. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">ATION 21 Th hid About I ■Hit m. and award ■ fQ in connection with Experiment • •&lt;i with Prof. Burnett so that you cafc tures. If convenient you can drop In •■•■ of the Association — provided you w member he wants you to register. For $2.00 • ctures. ' hat the Nebraska State Poultry Brigham our hearty thanks for the and thoroughly practical lecture he has nd ad Kooni 107, University Building. Lincoln. Neb., January 18, 1906. inn to order, and said I am glad ! poultry are present this evening. Not and exhibitors have done to make for the annual election of officers, and it Is um that you choose lhe best man to be how much of the sure • if the offtv :t 19 nan who is fit and qualified for the i ;ily maki I sacrifices to make the anil 1 hope at this time you will select the very ed, and there is plenty of It. mors you have conferred upon me, for I hope ut. who will make the poultry exhibit •all of the i otary. the roll until he had reached more than a ed that the further call of the adopted. lecretary then read the minutes of the last meeting, ami were duly approved. •d Bu- the only unfinished business is the awarding of the prize ( he committee. The committee iade its report The committee will try to make a report tomorrow </seg>
            <seg id="p022">REPORT OF OFFICERS The secretai : only that ))• iplied with all the rules and 1 on; publii thing I of managers hn This | unii in one volume. Your &gt; for the miserably I • roof. I did all I coulo d calls for our annual nich I have left. 1 are ob to say in tfc one ! want a send them out Mr. Norval extent and at f our ar MM under e of inc&lt; ■ authority, and if our ;. to it at the time it would not bavi any more stooK only two ti on, which will im and with the Cowl which It would i that if tthe stocV iu would have to amend the articles of incorporation. I think you cai. wthout this </seg>
            <seg id="p023">! ATION 23 ■-hip certificates which shall be issued to persons who may desire them for the same amount they • rsons the same rights and that means you eon - ■ ■fits. REPORT OF TREASURER Mr. Lyman Lincoln. Neb., January IS, 1906. • rs of the Xebru- Poultry Kpenditnrea Incident to he htmor to report at the Senii-Annual ■;• that there remained as -he sum of $203.29 ■ 'iichera drawn accout 1905 show' rrintiiiK account . . | ectfully submitted. I. S. LYMAN, Poultry Association. mi our Stati&gt; appropriation, anil if I had .1 it would have appeared In addition to i many thin:: my time had been up. I wil .red to uunis of the r, that we had a ndt'll Hotel since the semiannual meeting, and at thai examined the books carefully in detail and found that </seg>
            <seg id="p024">1 I'LTKV A-- they corres|&gt;onded and that the money had beei orders of tl and that their ai accura of the shall : be for The motion ».: such ii for !&gt;&gt; of dir&lt; It has I be accepted ;i Pres: Thi- up th- Mr. I. In certifit Mr ■ • remain; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">: VIION Mr. Seabrooke: incur? ich this incorporation shall tock. This and I move in order to annual meeting, rinted, • 1 by Mr. I.yrnan and carried that the rule that was adopted e. which has now reconsidered. id carried. 'i life Jo with the fair? tion and 1 think they I ;md take The office of the the State Eapil quicker than 1 ti « lain wha ,t by the ruling out of were like those roving ir last the </seg>
            <seg id="p026">No. Mr. Co;; class that go around I Eefourth of ih own. ■ up bes ■ and tli my bi. I woud - that they Incli Mr. Compton: I » eluded in tl to me tha* any 1 1 Mr. i ■ ■ and I Mr. QowV I would and I did nm think a bird that did </seg>
            <seg id="p027">mow wiiat they is been ■ hi tain the prize id will put in the premium to the show. I K added to our riibited in id which pro- for th- of poultry ■ oultry, ally apply th' on the iliffen- I tli would be had a magnificent il all kinds. It did not spoil in our show building \hibit of is in might encourage something alou- ipon. In Nebraska some of us H hicks. They are excellent .■I scratch for the little Tin d, that the premiums on the hea\ . »rd. Mr. Compton: I will accept the amendment. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 "LTKV ASSOCIATION Mr. Terwiliger What is to be gained by that amendment " I do not see how a proposition of that kind is p This association poultry, and it products. If you want it in that form on the product in it&gt; _!:• — irj Ludde practical m&gt; That ago, but di 1 d&lt; and a di thicki . 1'rof' 11101 inn « ried - I have anotli' ConRressman Pollard, ask: agricultural teaching in States, and I desire to ask the poultry people of ndorse </seg>
            <seg id="p029">SF.BR\ IATION this movement. 1 lit- matter to you in this form, and would mo\ the movement of the ir efforts to secure the elements of Schools ot the I'nited States.— bill that has been referred to in the other appropriating more money? (1 with some of us who are Normal School work. I am President of and the question has been agitated for gton, and they ha\ have requested our Attorney hill, and we will have Mr. Pollard introduce it. if manning the farm. We have been ity.. in our Experiment dong the wrong end of the ished what th. -t out to to reach or accomplish all that has ling with marvelous interest all Iling all about rW of th.: nal work in N within the tn: That we i few mil "llv tr cream. that. bird? Normal in this nor end nine r of the the Izlng iter making? We </seg>
            <seg id="p030">I AT It *N 30 want i ion and in line with the other industrial to endorse thi* I It ma In our poultry iska. The motion was an udden S( - I tl and « Whereas. Tli incel- Armory building for our annual poultry exhibit: therefore, be it Resolved Thii the ■ I • MISCELLANEOUS BUSINESS that I cided ' other committees, that. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">[ATION 31 ■■: Benjamin Andrews, iiown in enabling us to hold our building. our thanks rar ("lark and during oriutn I think we should hav.- ;i committee instructed Auditoriun of holding our next show. italning the . made bul I will be f xious in in Lincoln They saiil to &lt;n that orinm for yon. We '1 they They with the .ir. could • without o. but mgh they E_li our ;rkeys in one thibltor made Mr Turi If in all 1 hn Chinaman op having the picture of the hog and i Will e?" and he nodded to his com- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">SF.UK* II.TRV ASSOCIATION pinion and said ing to ma &gt; that They asked ip an incubai' thing u|&gt; a - who mold talk in t)i Mr. 1. . Thf » : ■ and the hard » </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 \T1ON lected for the en- I and carried that in for the ar. who are in favor of Phave K:ition: I certainly me, (nit I his matter past ident I bare uot made any here d to prici It my duty to from that ot I i and mal libit, ■one icy for a I would ap - for your :&lt;;nt. It is tary much other work as ! this a in Lincoln m 1 will be &gt;1 after that some other place" Many of the poul - with a typewriter on the railway train; ork. I is in the 1 1 prizes Ftemoon at 4 o'clock. This I. I am no could now of it I cannot on account of D "one ter it for me. ook: r did anything is I now do to cast the entire I ■ tion of the following named officers which I now do in the spirit of the motion, as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 NEIKA IATION For J Mr. T. ezhiln would ■ Th&lt; W. H nil t by 11, Mr Whit I ti to Mr. E. B. Day, our pri fficieut way he has mana^pd the aMmi show, and that the Board of requettri superintendent for the ensuing year. The motion was seconded and carried </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 'hat the matter of selecting left with the Board. iiion litoriuni can lie obtained the in. I mean this. talk, up with , ill lrishm one iially did sick -liual ■ u who look liis place fellow. In i the play Kian when he can down i down. I do not know ay further down. tilery who had brought his with him ami thinking to lose his fear that he would h;i :i[) with Mary Ann hanging im and palling bin Hoora, hel.'s full. 1 ' I La i I think ■ I pretty full tonight of poultry matters, by this time. A Voice: Tell us about the capons </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 That was what I have just been tell I want to say one thins, however, in • is to be ai B Breeders Associ.r different assix-i. 1 work and want to h;. woull •' tuch ■ ation and of can to help it a: I » You ii board do no* Ex-Cti capable mn about I am your ii so that wli. the re!' . will mai (Appln Now in called the Sou tli B and made in They an ed in the fall. I is of stu. down there. We found in I in of the country farms that had not been altogether profitable In past years and that the mortgages </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 had mm there splendid rolls' in the market, I speak of here in Nebraska. Do not I them in the ■ ybody else is il Christmas and take what - i down near Cape Cod, ill and raise them through the winter ing when everybody else id. That is 1 capons bring the highest price. : you all about it. The proper way ■ that I shall soon start here under L: rather in connection with the will have the privilege of asking only is it well to ■ ■ liings different fro iss of the the question of broilers and squab ising, pheasant raising. Don't do the is doing which brings the price below the up the question of feeding, it help beiiiK proti 1 the business loped that the I will tell you how the raising &lt;• Kit deal of trouble. out the broilers and the v I know you will do things every own hands." In that way we shall ■ n so in order that we may make I thank you. (Applause.) - hat exhibitors can have our orders on following the meeting Of the new Bo. i adjourned LUTHER P. LUDDEN Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 MEETING OF THE BOARD OF MANAGERS Th&gt; ation met ■ folllow;: - .- - ■ Tli - of No exhiln- SEMI-ANNUAL MEETING NEBRASKA STATE POULTRY ASSOCIATION. Unco held on i tif Fair (i: the chair. Th&lt; printed form and pi </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 d with dm on the under the ■I to I to ■ 11 Thursday. Amt. | H in premium list Ki.00 rial 1.00 ? I ha m follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Voucher AmL 1905. Jan. 20. To A. Wilson. Premium 23 *12.50 Jan. 20. To \V. Premium Jan. t I'remium Jan. 20. T Jan. K. To Jan. 20. T.. Jan. Labor . Jan. L'O. Ti Jan. 2 Jan Jan. z&gt; Jan Jan Jan Jan. 2 Jan. 2i Jan Jan. Jan. Jan Jan. ; Jan. - Jan. - Jan. 20. To J. \ Jan. ! Jan. . Jan Jan. . .1. H. H&lt; Jan. tO. To I. I" l.u L. I*. 1 . ■ Jan . .Tan. :_''&gt; To Fra </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 94 14.00 8.00 4.50 14.00 10.00 25.00 II 15.50 ■rniium.. 1.00 77 14.50 I 21JM 11.75 14L' Labor. 1.00 ■ [u Ibul ' • i ■ 7.00 16.70 17 10.50 10.50 .143 . . .144—1 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Jan. 28. To E. H. Wilkie, Pp Jan. I. To M. W. Failing. La* II. To .1. Jan. 31. To G. \V. h ■ ■ ■ Mar. Mar. V » ■ Ilalai K\[h nni~ Labor Around Show i; Suppll Supplies for Offlc Printing . Board JudjKs </seg>
            <seg id="p043">■ 43 $ 1917.51 iard with power to HER P. I.CDDEX Line ■ciation was nuts with roll call Lincoln, x oultry ot the treasurers ich time I In my hands JIOISG of January I have received cash - illows: cm band . $ 102. SG ■. Krom State Approprlatioo 1000.00 Jan. 19. Froni P. Luddeo ... 500.00 nice Jaii'. |lt84.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 N KHR A . Januar&gt; 1 out on voucher:- total sum of J follows: Jan. 19. To Jan. 19. To T Jan. 19. To David Jan Jan. 19. To Conra.: Jan. 19. To M Jan Jan. I'.'.To P. Jan. It. To F Jan. 1 Jan. I Jan Jan Jan. I Jan Jan. Jan. Jan. I Jan Jan. 19. Paid to () E. Henning, I&gt; Jan I </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 Jan I Hamilton, Premium 1.00 Jan Johnsoi on Board 12.05 i Johnson, Premium 11.50 Premium 1.00 Premium 18.50 reemium 2.00 11, Premium . 2.00 1.00 E. Bowers. Premium 22.50 on Board 12.45 Premium 5.00 Premium 10.00 100.00 Account .... 1.50 id to Ed 1 Printing 96.50 Paid to ' 25.00 ■ E r Morse Laboi 11.65 11.00 11.00 il to ,1. II Labor 11.00 ; . He Compton, Premium ■ • . Uourlay, Premium k, Premium 10.50 Ludden, Postage and expense 62.46 Thl. Labor 15.00 Labor . 5.00 Premium Premium ... 7.00 1. Supplies 2.39 lork and Judge 6.75 56.00 remium . ... E. Inim. Premium 16.50 2.00 •'an. ir r. Premium I Herzog. Premium Jan. 2-i. Paid 12 .50 Jan to J. W. Alden, Premlni 5.50 Jan. L'2. Paid to Paulin. 5 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Jan Jan id to I. • Jan SjM ■ • ■aid to T. J. Thorj. Paid to J A. .John*. Board . Mar. 10. Paid to A. J. K Mar. 16. Paid to State Journal Co., Printing 2».5O Mar. 2.'i. Paid to J. W. 10.0" Mar. 26. Paid to J. M. Armstrong, Premiui: </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 10.00 I STATISTICAL. ■ items, there was paid j lent ... If : $ 1 and •13.75 .$1,463.00 if that 1 of which ;i|&gt;roprta- |C00 in their generosity erous v demons I the iWation •;t side, my great y and Its officers have tern of apologies aiid discounted claimB Respectfully submitted. I. I.. I.Y.MAN. Trea* Nebraska State Poultry Association It was referred to the officers for auditing. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 NEBR.A \TII'\ In tl rium for the winter show the Mr !{• litorium '• ■ N ■ The i coin. i warrant f' Association th&lt; LIT, Secretary • </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 MEETINGS BOARD OF MANAGERS. January 15, 1906. ; the office of the Secretary with Smith, Johnson, Norval. Ludden. Kition of J. A jonnson, of from the state. Same was accepted but Ellison saying iden illness of his wife Impossible : that they would not fill the I opted: lirected to il but in no case to carry them was UTHER V. LUDDEN, fary. Januar ■ irval in chair. if Barrt-,1 Rod one JiidKO females. On the recommenda - .ving was adop other sex a suitable the - U'THER P. I.UnOEN. Secretary. January 17, 1906. Board B m. in secretary office, ail present except Campbell. Pret -val in chair. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 follow ■ ■ Boa i chair </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 bj to the lers directed hin. that mr show next January Br incoln wa e for Hows: h and iph the Judges and ask and the officers be dir. the next show he l;iy for his I.ITHKH P I.UDDEN Hiring that Dice anil the .ken. LTh^i rend Adopted. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">, The chair appointed Mr. Seabrook and Mr. Lyman. "That the secretary : / :&gt;e pigeon premium according to the rule." Adopted. "That the secretary window show cards. Adopted. •T) 'lubs that the Board will tier, and print their oftVi Th. 1 th« for the pn: 3:30 p. m The Board met pure ask for bids and the mi and ' Board then adji -tary All the ni&lt; Coun &gt; D . held •( th&lt; for $J cleared early B </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>