<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00018">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00018</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA BRANCH SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, MILFORD, SEWARD COUNTY, NEBRASKA.  BEING FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900.</title>
		             <date value="1901">1901</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-29</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Laura Weakly</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Validation</item>
				     </change>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-24</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
				     </change>

				     <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>

            <seg id="p003">i 

REPORT. 

To His Excellency, the Governor of the State of Nebraska, and 
to the Hon. Board of Public Lands and Buildings: 

Gentlemen— I would most respectfully submit the following 
&gt;port for the biennial period commencing December 1. 1898, 

[ind ending November 30, 1900. 

The legislature of 18W» appropriated fo.OOO for the erection of 

i hospital, which was complete in due time. It furnishes accom- 

modation for about twenty-two persons, and while it is not all 

that could be desired, it certainly satisfies, to a great degree, a 

long felt want in this Home. The sick and feeble are separated 

from the noise of the main building, and are very comfortably 

situated, with toilet rooms and baths on each floor. 

The health of the members is good, as the doctor's report, lierejnto 
attached and made part of this report, will show. 

.¦ well at the Home proved to be a failure, and last winter 

appropriated fKi.TDO. with an increase of one-fourth the num- 

ber of members and one-third more room to heat, light, and 

I w;ts compelled to dig and curb a new on&lt;&gt;. The smoke stack 

has Mown down Twice in t In- last two years, which necessitated 

the election of an entirely new stack. There being no emergency 

fund, these improvements, winch are permanent, had to be paid 

from the maintenance and clothing fund. These and many thiugs 

of this character, which have been paid out of this same fund. 

have increased the running expenses of the institution, and show 

that our per capita is higher than it really is. 

The legislature of isitT appropriated for the maintenance of 

the Home. Tin- sum of *1."&gt;.28O. This sum was inadequate for the 

running expenses of the Home for that time. We were conse- 

quently compelled to make a deficiency. The legislature of 189!) </seg>

            <seg id="p004">
500 

I.ANIf COMMISSIONER S ItEI'OHT. 

furnish. This extra expenditure of money is bound to make 
another deficiency, which I hoped could be avoided. With the 
additional building to heat, we will probably be in debt for 175 
tons of coal cm the first day of April, 1901, and it will probably 
i -list more than it would had we been able to pay cash. 

The legislature in the past has seemed to look upon this institution 
as a secondary matter and has not treated it as well 
.as others. It cannot afford to deal scrimpingly with the hoys 
who carried the flag daring the dark days from % &lt;il to "fi5. They 
are not in the home from choice, but from necessity, living out 
the last few years of a disappointed life. — only a few years at 
West, and the j&gt;eople of Nebraska should deal liberally with them. 

The needs of the Home are many, and having been here for 
the past three years and eight months, and knowing them. I 
take the liberty of mentioning a few. 

We are greatly in need of a water tank or standpipe. There 
is a small tank in the attic of the main building which holds 
about thirty barrels of water, but this is not sufficient for the 
uses of the Home. At present we should be wholly at the mercy 
of fire, if one .should break out. and as we use kerosene lamps, 
the property is not as secure as it should be. 

The roof on the main building leaks in many places, and by all 
mt^ans should be replaced by a new one. 

The attic of the main building should be finished, fur this 
would furnish room for twenty or thirty jM-rsons. I think this 
way cheaper than any other, for studding are already set and it 
is more than half lathed. 

The basement in the new building should be floored and 
plastered, as the room is badly needed for dining-room and 
kitchen purposes. 

A library would add very much to the enjoyment of the mem 
bers. There has never been anything appropriated for this pur 
po.se. and it surely should not be deferred longer. 

Another boiler is also another great necessity. We have but 
one. and if anything should happen to this one in the wintertime, 
we would be in a bad condition, with so many feeble old men on 
our hands. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
AND SAILORS' HOME. 

501 

BRANCH SOLDIERS 

A residence for the commandant and his family is a very necessary 
thing. He should not be compiled to take his wife and 
familv into the same building with the members of the Home, 
unless the building were differently constructed from this. There 
is no doubt but that the discipline of the Home would be better 
should the commandant live in a house apart from the main 
building. 

An adjutant at the Home, with reasonable salary, would be a 
great benefit. Also, the doctor's salary is too small for the 
amount of work he has to do. 

The Visiting and Examining Board has made a very full report 
of the Home, which is attached to and made a part of this 
report. The platting of the grounds, the clearing away of brush, 
pruning of trees, laying out of walks, and other improvements 
on the grounds. I need not mention, as their report includes them 
all. 

1 take great pleasure in saying that the discipline of the Home 
was never better than it is to-day. Drunkenness in and about the 
Home has pretty near become a thing of the past. 

The Visiting and Examining Board has always been painstaking 
with both the members and officers of the Home, trying 
at all times to deal justly with the state as well as the Home, 
making special effort to make the Home pleasant for all. 

To you. tin- Honorable Hoard of Public Lands and Buildings. 
1 am esj&gt;ecially thankful for your kind treatment. You have always 
treated us courteously, taking pains to find out the needs of 
the institution, advising with us as to the best in all matters of 
interest to tfie Home. 

Mrs. Fowler, the matron, has been very considerate of the 
needs of tlie members, and she holds the respect of all in the 
Home. 

Dr. Stevens has been with us but three months, but in that 
time he has gained the confidence and esteem of all the members. 


.). G. Perkinson. the commissary sergeant, has been a careful 
and conscientious officer, and has spared no trouble in making It a 
"home" for all. </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
502 

LAND fOM.MISSIOXEK's REPORT. 

The following is the member 
1, 1898. to November 30, 1900: 
Total members present and abi 

hip of the Home from December 

;eni December 1. 1898 

Men 

.).! 

Women 

Total 

Total applications approved f 
November 30, 1900: 

Mil December 1, 1898. 

Men 

Women 

Total 

Total 

Total members discharged from December 

November 30, 1900 
Men 
Women 

Total 

M 

Total members died from Dccenil 
30.1900: 

r 1. 1898. to Novenib. 

Men 

Women 

r&gt; 

Total T 

Total 

i\ 

Total present and absent November 30, 1900 : 
12") minus 43 by death and discharge. . 

*1 

Actual number of members present 66 

Actual number of members absent 16 

Total number present and absent 

&lt;-2 </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
1SBAXCH 

SOLDIKRS 

AND SAILORS' £OME. 

503 

The following deaths all occurred in the Home as follows: 
Thomas Witherspyon, oSth Ind. Inf. Band, buried in Lincoln. 

John McGivern. &lt; 'o. P. New York H. Art., buried in Omatfa. 
David Bowe, &lt; o. H, 8th N. H. Inf., buried in Home Cemetery. 
Joseph Littlefleld. &lt;"o. E. 3d YVis. Inf.. buried in Home Cem- 

•tetv 

John Slack. Co. H, 15 N. Y. H. Art., buried in Lincoln. 
Peter H. Johnson, Co. I. 11th Light Art., buried in Lincoln 

Daniel S. Lemou, Co. 1. 16th Pa. Cav., buried in Home Cem- 

Yours respectfnllv 

J. M. Fowler. Commandant. 

M. Fowler, Commandant 

Sir — I herewith submit The repvrt of mv department for the 

nnial period ending November 30, l!&gt;00. 

department September 17. 1900, but two 

and a half months ago, my predecessor, Dr. S. P. Tracy, having 
been in charge up to that time. 

* &gt;n entering upon my duties at this Home I was very favorably 
impressed with its general appearance, both indoors and out. 
The location is a very pleasant and healthful one, and the sanitai-v 
conditions are excellent. 

While there is not that variety of table delicacies which some 
of the older members should have, the culinary department is in 
first-class condition. The food, though plain, is of the very best 
quality and well prepared. Added to this the highly efficient 
manner in which the matron's duties have been performed, the 
old soldiers of the Milford Home can truthfully say they have a 
home. 

Referring to Dr. S. P. Tracy's files. I find he has made 3.281 
prescriptions from January 1, 189ft. to September 16. 1900. 

I have made 231 prescriptions from September 17. 1900, to November 
30. 1900. principally for chronic ailments, and have made 

SIK&lt; IKUX'S REPORT </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 

504 

83 visits to the Home from my residence, three-fourths of a mile 
distant. 

There are now none sick in the Home except the chronic ail 

ments. 

The following deaths have occurred 

Thomas Witherspoon, aged 56. died March 24. 1899; cause of 
death, locomotor ataxia. 

John McGivern. aged 64. died May 28. 1899; cause of death 
apoplexy. 

David Rowe. aped 75. died January 27. 1900; cause of death 
strictures. 

Joseph Littlefield. aged 69. died April 30. 1900; cause of death, 
heart trouble. 

John Stack, aged 58, died August 24. 1900; cause of death, 
heart trouble. 

Peter H. Johnson, aged 62. died November 12. 1900; can 
death, hepatic cirrhosis. 

David S. Lemon, aged 57. died November 13, 1900; cau 
death, hepatic atrophy. 

With an average membership present at the Home of 53, this 
makes an average death-rate of 6.66 per cent, or one in 15.14. 

All of which is respectfully submitted 

I.e. Stephens, M. D 

REPORT OF THE VISITING AND EXAMINING BOARD 

Milforp. Nek.. December 5, 1900 

To His Excellency, the Governor and the Board of Public Lands 

and Buildings 

Gentlemen — In accordance with the law governing soldiers' 
and sailors" homes, the Visiting and Examining Board beg leave 
to make the following report of the Milford Home: 

The Board has exercised the same jurisdiction over this Home. 
in conjunction with the commandant, as over the institution at 
Grand Island, and which has been.fully explained in the report 
made of that Home. The regular and quarterly meetings have 
been twenty-four in number, with no special meetings. </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
505 

SOLDIERS 

AND SAILORS' HOME. 

KRANCH 

111 order that your excellency, and all other persons interested, 
may have a better understanding of the institution, the Visiting 
and examining Board deems a history, in epitome, at this time. 

he proper. 

The Milford Home was provided for by an enactment of the 
legislature of 1895. accompanied by an appropriation of $8,000. 

The first acquaintance of the Visiting and Examining Board 
with the institution was at a called meeting, by order of the Commissioner 
of Public Lands and Buildings, holden November 22, 
1895. when the visiting and Examining Board were instructed 
by the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, with the advice of 
Attorney General Churchill, to take the same supervision of the 
Milford Home, in conjunction with the commandant, as evrstom 
and law had provided at Grand Island. 

At its first meeting the Visiting and Examining Board adopted 
rules and regulations for the government of the Home; elected 
th&lt;- subordinate officers recommended by Capt. J. H. Culver, who 
had been appointed commandant by the Board of Public Lands 
and Buildings, and admitted forty members to the Home. 

On January 30, 1896. the Visiting and Examining Board held 
its first quarterly meeting in the office of the Home and called 
upon the commandant for a financial statement, showing the condition 
of the funds, and learned from this first report made to it 
that not only had all of the $8,000 been expended, but that the institution 
was then in debt to the sum of (3.3S3.33. Bv order of 
the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, the Home was administers! 
to the end of the biennial period on a deficiency. 

The legislature of 1899 appropriated a sufficient sum to purchase 
the grounds, which was afterwards effected by the Board 

of Public Lands and Buildings, and also for the erection of a 
new hospital building. 

At the close of the biennial period, beginning December 1. 
189S. the total membership of the Home was 58, while there are 
now X(&gt; members on the rolls, an increase of :52 per cent. 

In addition to purchasing the grounds and buildings 'with the 
sum appropriated, the parties who sold to the state also painted </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
506 

LAXD COMMISSIONER S REPORT. 

the entire outside of the building as a part of the consideration 
much to the benefit and appearance of the same. 

The new hospital is a neat and handsome addition to tin- main 
structure. It strengthens the whole building and adds t&lt;&gt; rh( 
general good appearance of the Home. It^vill accommodate 
twenty-one patients and was a much needed improvement. 

The total amount which the state has invested in permanen 

improvements here is $27,000. 

The Visiting and Examinii 
against the Home the past tw 
877.01. As there is no promise 

Board have audited claims 
vears to the amount of *20. 

if a diminution of mem 

for the coming two years, it follows that the appropriatk 

be increased. The sums which the Board has audited, divided bv 

53, the average membership, foi 

two vears. nial 

cost per member $302.50. or $!!??&gt;. 2." per annum. With n&lt; 

of a decrease in membership 

future by the past, it will require $29.1 

for the next two years, beginnin 

1, 1903. While the per capita cost &lt;&gt;f livin 

$36.50 more than that at Grand Island, it is not iuap] 

note the fact that at Grand Island they produ 

own fresh meat and milk, which is not the case at the Mil ford 

Home, but the Board has not deemed it necessary to figure tlw 

difference out in detail. The cost of living in each report in 

eludes officers' salaries and all other expenditures paid by th 

state. 

The total amount appropriated for maintenance of the Home 

by the last legislature, not including permanent improvements, 

was fl6,790. There has already been expended fl4.304.4fi. or an 
average expenditure of $839.50 per month for the past twenty 
months, and as there is now remaining of all the appropriations 
the sum of f895.54, the management of the Home cannot avoid 
creating a deficit of two thousand to twenty five hundred dollars 
during the four winter months remaining of the biennial period. 
The increase of membership the past two years being 32 per 
cent, may well explain the cause of this increase, especially when </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
507 

AXD 

SAILORS 

HOME. 

AXCH 

niEits 

mbinrd w 

\ 

i 

\ 

1 author 

I 

the increased cost in nearly all food products, 

i ml Examining Board Takes pleasure in reporting 
harmony prevails among officers, employees, and 

le condition of the Home is neat and cheerful. 
&gt;f this Home is beautiful, and it is a popular re- 
D\v in importance as the years go by. As there 

e underbrush, dead and unsightly trees, as well 
tblc comments upon his efforts during the past 
injr and Examining Board would recommend that 
forester, like ex-Governor Furnas. be employed 
ie landscape plan which future commandants and 
rities can follow, as no two men can be expected 
the subject of tree-pruning, and yet, the grounds 

; neglected because pugnacious persons, with 
may have access to columns of newspapers to 

Tf nil v submitted by the undersigned, 

GrEO. N. Smith, President. 

Secretary. 

Mary E. Ward. 
Julia S. Bowen. 

J. A. Baird. 

miplaints because rff the commandant's efforts </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>