<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00002">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00002</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>INAUGURAL ADDRESS OF GOVERNOR CHARLES H. DIETRICH TO THE TWENTY-SEVENTH SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA, JANUARY 3, 1901</title>
               <date value="1901">1901</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-29</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Laura Weakly</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Validation</item>
				     </change>		
				     <change>
				        <date>2007-05-18</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
				     </change>
				     <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">(1OVEBKOB CHARLES H. IJ1KTXICH</seg> 

            <seg id="p002">
31 

INAUGURAL ADDRESS 

OF 

GOVERNOR CHARLES H. DIETRICH 

&lt;• 

TO THE 

Twenty-seventh Session of the Legislature of Nebraska. 

JANUARY 3, 19O1. 

To the Senators and Representative*, Twenty-seventh Bession of the Legis- 

lature of Nebraska: 

As your chief executive, I herewith submit for your consideration the 
following recommendations: 

By the Constitution, as adopted in 1875, prorision was made for six 
judges of the district court, which number, the legislature in the exerciaa 
of its constitutional authority has Increased to twenty-eight, at a cost to 
the state of about 1115,000 per annum. It is generally conceded by members 
of the legal profession that a material reduction in the number of 
dtstHct judges can be made without affecting the adjudicating capacity or 
the efficiency of the judicial branch of the government. 

There are nearly one thousand seven hundred cases ready for trial 
before the Supreme Court, and it is estimated that it will require about 
eight years before any new action brought can be prosecuted to judgment. 
It is well known that persons aiming at the adjudication of equitable claims 
are being made the prey of unscrupulous and irresponsible contestants by 
reason of the delay incident to the congested condition of the Supreme 
Court docket, thus entailing unnecessary hardship and less upon legitimate 
claimants, at the same time discouraging investment of capital, and making 
it difficult for the honest borrower to obtain loans. This is an abuse of 
Justice which Impairs the credit of both the state and the individual, aad 
which neither the state nor the individual can afford to license. Innumerable 
cases now pending before the supreme and districts courts would be 
dismissed if a speedy trial could be had, and knowledge of the tact would </seg>


            <seg id="p003">32 

t doubt greany restrain litigants In the future. I therefore recommend, 
n a view to temporary relief, that an act be passed empowering the 
ireme Court to. appoint referees whose duty it shall be to assist said 
rt, and whose tenure of office shall be for the immediate biennium. 
Iso recommend the submission to the voters of the state of a propoon 
to so amend the Constitution as to empower the legislature, under 
per restrictions, to provide for such an increase in the number of 
ges of the Supreme Court as shall Insure permanent relief. 

The laws of Nebraska need amendment in many essential particulars, 
and should also be codified. I recommend the creation of a commission of 
suitable persons, learned in the law, to submit for the consideration of the 
next legislature a codification of our laws and suggestions of changes 
where necessary, and to also prepare a revenue measure providing for an 
equitable taxation of all property throughout the state. 

Sec. 26 of art. 5 of the Constitution should be so amended that the 
legislature shall have authority to create a State Board of Control for 
the management of our state institutions, and I therefore recommend the 
submission of an amendment of that purport to the people without 
unnecessary delay. • 

Eour attention is directed to the Pan-American Exposition which is to 
held at Buffalo, N. Y., this year. A reasonable appropriation to be 
i for advertising the resources of our state will meet with my approval. 

Nebraska should be properly represented at the Exposition to be held in 
St. Louis in 1903, and a liberal appropriation should be made for that 
purpose. 

Your attention is hereby directed to the inadequacy of the law applying 
to the crimes of kidnaping and child stealing. I would recommend that 
the law be so amended as to make kidnaping or child stealing a felony, 
punishable by imprisonment in the penitentiary for a period of not less 
than five nor more than thirty years, that the age limit be removed, and 
that me unlawful or forcible nolding in captivity of any person at a place 
other than the natural or lawful domicile or abode of said person shall 
constitute the crime of kidnaping. I also recommend that an appropriation 
be made, to be placed at the disposal of the chief executive of the 
state, for use by him in apprehending such criminals and repressing this 
sort of crime. 

The state has several cases pending in the courts against sureties on 
official bonds. The prosecution of these cases has been attended with great 
expense, and has continued for several years. In the interim, some of the 
sureties have died, many have become insolvent, and the chances for ultimate 
recovery on the bonds seem to be growing less. It Is the exception, 
and not the rule, that personal bonds have been satisfactory. Private 
corporations deem It for their interest to buy surety company bonds for 
their employees. Our present state treasurer finds it impossible to furnish 

tl^fa^on' personal bond without subjecting himself to terms and 
Itions which have proven to be so annoying ana disastrous to others</seg> 



            <seg id="p004">:n 


who have held the same position, and he has been obliged, as was hU 
predecessor, to purchase a surety bond at a cost incommensurate with 
his salary. I submit that the law should permit corporate surety bonds 
to be given in all cases where a bond is required, and snould provide that 
any public officer may be compelled to furnish a corporate surety bond, 
the cost thereof to be defrayed by the state or municipality for whose 
benefit such bond is required. 

The game, song, and other insectivorous birds are the property of the 
state and are being ruthlessly slaughtered. I therefore recommend that 
the laws for the protection of these birds be so revised as to prohibit 
their exportation from the state, and to provide for a State Game Warden 
whose duty it shall be to see that violators of the law are duly prosecuted. 

The executive mansion should either be sold, or an appropriation made 
for its proper maintenance. It should be cared for as any other public 
property. 

Another matter to which your attention is called is the boundary line 
between the states of Nebraska and Iowa. The original intention undoubtedly 
was that the center of the channel of the Missouri river should 
form the boundary line between these two states. Owing, however, to 
changes in the river bed, the channel in many places has been so changed 
that Nebraska territory lies east of the said river, Iowa territory lies west 
of the river, while in some instances the question of jurisdicton is in 
doubt and dispute. This state of affairs leads to a condition of lawlessness, 
especially in the disputed territory, which should not exist. It is recom- 
Ktded that a boundary commission be provided for by joint resolution of 
two houses to act with a like commission from our sister state of Iowa, 
; shall have power, with the consent of the Federal government, to 
blish a permanent boundary line between the two states. 

Your attention will be called to the advisability of establishing a state 
circulating or so-called traveling library, which in other states has proven 
to be a great success. 

century just closed has been immortalized for all ages to come by the 
nt achievements on land and sea of the American soldier and marine, 
by the patriotic sacrifices of our American women. Let us, then. In 
this, the first year of a new century, show our appreciation of their deeds 
of valor and love for country and humanity by appropriating a liberal sum 
of money to erect a fitting monument to the memory of our heroic dead. 

Committees should be appointed at once to visit our various state institutions, 
with instructions to make an early report of their needs, so that 
the legislature may have ample opportunity to act intelligently in the 
matter of appropriations. 

In conclusion, I wish to state that every act of yours or mine should be 
governed by that same honesty of purpose and business tact and care 
as though our state and ter institutions were our own personal belongings. 

C. H. DIETRICH. </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>