<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eighteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT AND THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf For the years 1911 and 1912 TO THE Governor, HON. CHESTER H. ALDRICH</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Eighteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT AND THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf For the years 1911 and 1912 TO THE Governor, HOIN. C^ H k. 3 1 t. K ri. ALDixlv^ri </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Nebraska School for the Deaf, Omaha, Nebraska, Dec. 1, 1912. Honorable Chester H. Aldrich, I Dear Sir: In compliance with section 12, chap. 22 of the lplied Statutes, the Board of Trustees of the Nebraska x&gt;l for the Deaf has the honor to transmit herewith the teenth biennial report of this institution, embracing the jress and work accomplished during the period ending De- Very respectfully, H. H. Hanks, t). 0. DWYER, Mrs. Viola J. Cameron Board of Trustees. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">HON. CHESTER H. ALDRICH BOARD OF TRUSTEES H. H. Hanks, President Nebraska City, Nebraska D. 0. Dwyeb Plattsmouth, Nebraska Mrs. Viola J. Cameron, Secretary Omaha, Nebraska OFFICERS F. W. Booth, B. S Superintendent and Steward Zella E. Noe Matron and Housekeeper Jennie E. Jones Clerk ASSIGNMENT OF TEACHERS Head Teacher, Academic Department J. W. Sowell Head Teacher, Intermediate Department Alberta Regnier Head Teacher, Primary Department Emily E. Sauter Librarian Ota Blankenship Literary Society W. H. Rothert Boys' Christian Endeavor Society C. H. Eldridge Girls' Christian Endeavor Society Ota Blankenship Editor "The Nebraska Journal" . . J. W. Sowell Physical Culture and Athletics P. E. Seely ACADEMIC DEPARTMENT F. W. Booth, B. S. Principal Twelfth Grade J. W. Sowell, M. A. Eleventh and Tenth Grades C. H. Eldridge Ninth and Eighth Grades W. H. Rothert, B. A. Seventh Crade Ida Hendee </seg>
            <seg id="p004">368 INTERMEDIATE ORAL AND MANUAL AND PRIMARY MANUAL DEPARTMENT Eighth Grade, Oral Alberta Reginer Seventh Grade, Oral Ethyl Rogers Fifth Grade, Oral Helen Waite Sixth and Fifth Grades, Manual Mae Gregory Fourth and Third Grades, Manual Emma Anderson Second and First Grades, Manual Ota Blankenship PRIMARY ORAL DEPARTMENT Fourth Grade Edith Ross Third Grade ■ Lillian Bamford Second Grade Mary Woodson First Grade Emily E. Sauter First Grade Clara Worley First Grade Iilla Upsher Painting J. F. Rogers Printing P. E. Seely Manual Training and Carpentry Jesse W. Jackson Wood Carving and Clay Modeling Goldie C. Vawter Drawing Ota Blankenahip Sewing Edith Johnson Laundering Marguerite Field Farming W. H. Chapman Farming, Laborer Ralph Kirkpatrick t DOMESTIC DEPARTMENT Matron and Housekeeper Zella E* Noe Boys' Supervisor Ann Richards Assistant Boys' Supervisor William Claussen Boys' Supervisor (small) Mae Witmer Assistant Boys' Supervisor Henry Porter Girls' Supervisor Hester A. Gray Assistant Girls' Supervisor Milin Trentham Physician A. Jefferson Nurse .Mae Edwards </seg>
            <seg id="p005">369 Engineer H. E. G'adwin Assistant Engineer and Night Watchman Fireman Fred Krause J. A. Jensen John Stodola Mary Notter Janitor Janitress Cook Bertha Brown Anna Chizek Lillie Cooter Second Cook Laundress. . . Laundress Emma Lundberg Eg room girl g room girl g room girl Nettie Boon Emma Anderson Hazel Springer Maggie Mekkelsen House girl . House girl . Mabel Jamie Caroline Engel SUPERINTENDENTS REPORT To the Honorable Board of Trustees: II have the honor to submit to you the Eighteenth Biennial &gt;rt of the Nebraska School for the Deaf, covering the period December 1, 1910 to December 1, 1912, as follows: The number of pupils under instruction November 30, 1910 was one hundred seventy-eight (178), of whom ninety-four (94) were boys and eighty-four (84) were girls. Since that date forty-one (41) new pupils, seventeen boys and twenty-four girls have been admitted; and seventeen former pupils, twelve boys and five girls have been readmitted. Seventeen pupils, twelve boys and five girls, have graduated ; fifty-five, thirty-six boys and nineteen girls, have been furloughed, or honorably discharged, or have removed from the state, and two boys have died. The total enrollment for the biennium in 236, of whom 162, seventy - three boys and eighty-nine girls, are now in attendance. Since the founding of the institution in 1869, 853 pupils have received instruction, of which number 105 have been awarded diplomas of graduation. Of the 105 graduates thirty-one have taken more </seg>
            <seg id="p006">370 Washington, eleven of the number now being students at that institution. The movement of population for the biennium was as fol- Population 1910-1912 Boys Girls Total Pupils present November 30, 1910 94 84 178 Pupils admitted 29 29 58 Total enrollment for two years 123 113 236 Pupils graduated and discharged 48 24 72 Pupils died 2 9 Attendance November 30, 1912 73 89 162 The 162 pupils now in school have their residence as follows: Counties Boys Girls Total Adams 2 2 Antelope 1 1 Buffalo 1 1 Boone 1 1 Boyd 1 .. 1 Burt 112 Cass 1 1 2 Cedar 2 1 3 Cherry 1 -1 Colfax 1 .. 1 Clay 1 2 3 Custer 3 3 6 Dawson 2 1 3 Dixon 2 2 Dodge 2 13 Douglas 19 26 45 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 4 1 2 lllmore ranklin rontier urnas 1 £::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::: 3 1 [amilton </seg>
            <seg id="p007">371 Hitchcock 1 . 1 Kearney 4 3 Keith 1 1 Lancaster 6 8 14 Madison 3 4 Merrick 1 1 Nemaha 2 I Nuckolls 2 I Otoe 2 2 4 Phelps 1 1 2 Red Willow 1 1 Saline 2 2 4 Saunders 1 1 Scotts Bluff 1 .. 1 Sherman 2 . . 2 Stanton 1 . . 1 Thayer 1 .. 1 Thurston 1 1 Valley 2 Washington 1 1 Wayne 1 1 Webster 112 Wheeler 1 .. 1 State of Wyoming 1 1 Total 73 89 162 It is of interest to note that, while Douglas County, in which is the city of Omaha, had by the 1910 census but 14^ of the total population of the state, the forty-five pupils which the county now has in the school constitutes 28^ of the attendance. Were the rest of the state as well represented in the attendance as is Douglas County, the total attendance at this time would be in the neighborhood of 300 children, and without doubt there are that many deaf children of school age in the state who should be in school. As a matter of fact there are children known to be </seg>
            <seg id="p008">372 are doomed thus to grow up in ignorance, with all that that means to themselves and to society, because of mistaken feelings of kindness on the part of their parents. Every effort should be employed by town and county authorities to bring these children to school and such authorities are urged if necessary to bring to bear the provision of the compulsory education law relating to deaf or blind children (See Cobbey's Annotated Statutes, Section 11,819.) The following table gives the assigned cause of deafness in all pupils now attending the school. Cause of Deafness Boys Girls Total Abscess 2 1 3 Brain fever 6 4 10 Catarrh 3 3 Catarrhal fever 1 . . 1 Cholera infantum 1 1 Congenital 22 34 56 Congestion of the lungs 1 1 Diphtheria 13 4 Earache 1 .. 1 Fall 1 1 Fall and whooping cough 1 1 Fever 2 2 4 Grand swelling 1 1 Kicked by a colt 1 . . 1 La Grippe 2 1 3 Lung fever 1 1 2 Malarial fever 1 . . 1 Measles 2 ' 6 8 Measles and whooping cough 1 1 Meningitis 11 6 17 Mumps 1 .. 1 Overdose of chloroform 1 . . 1 Pneumonia 1 . . 1 Scarlet fever 2 7 9 Sickness 4 2 6 Smothered 1 1 Typhoid fever 1 1 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">373 Unknown ■ i Whooping cough 2 3 Hearing mutes 1 1 Total T.i 89 621 It will be seen that out of 162 pupils now under instruction very nearly 35*^ were born deaf. Other principal causes of deafness were meningitis 17, brain fever 10, scarlet fever 9, measles 8, sickness, nature not stated 5, and unknown causes, probably congenital, 14. The following table shows the ages at the time of admission of the forty-one new pupils received in 1911 and 1912 Five years . 1 Six years 8 Seven years 12 Eight years 7 Nine years 4 Ten years 1 Thirteen years 2 Fourteen years 3 Sixteen years 1 Nineteen years 1 Twenty years 1 The table following gives the ages at which the forty-one new pupils became deaf: Congenital 6 Under one year 6 Under one and one-half years 7 Two years 7 Three years 6 Four years 2 Five years 2 Six years 1 Seven years 2 Eight years 1 Unknown 1 The health of the school family during the biennium period has been generally good although one death among the pupils </seg>
            <seg id="p010">374 I be recorded, that of Paul McFadden, which occurred on lary 3, 1911. The infirmary records covering the term from mber, 1911 to June, 1912, show seventy -one cases of children ing infirmary treatment, and during the ten weeks of the it term there have been fourteen infirmary cases. The health record of the school is, I cannot but feel, due very y to the faithful attendance and the watchful care of our A Physician, Dr. Alfred Jefferson, assisted by the School &gt;, Miss Mae Edwards. The following table gives the in - ry record of cases treated during the school term, Septem - 911, to June, 1912: I One death among the pupils occurred during the summer ation of 1912, that of Glen Harris, who was killed by being lck by a motor car on the Union Pacific Railroad at his home lie he was walking alone on the track. Glenn was one of brightest pupils, and it is incomprehensible how, being deaf, could have taken the great risk of walking on the railroad :k. RThe death on November 20, 1911, of Mr. Lloyd Blanken - , of our staff of instructors, was a distinct loss to the work. Biliousness 5 Bite by dog 2 Boils 2 Catarrh 9 Coughs, colds, sore-throat 12 Cuts, burns 5 Diphtheria 1 Ear treatment 3 Eyes treated 5 Fingers cut in planer 1 Hives 1 Infection on face 1 Infection on hand or foot 9 Itch 4 Pneumonia 4 Shoulder hurt, fall 2 Sprain 4 Total 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">375 Mr. Blankenship graduated from this school in 1897, after which he took a special course in art in Chicago. In the fall of 1897 he was appointed instructor in art in this school and he held this position up to the time of his death. Mr. Blankenship was a man of fine character and was greatly beloved by his pupils and his associates on the teaching staff. The affairs of the household department have been since August, 1911, under the direction of Miss Zella E. Noe, the matron. All parts of the building are kept scrupulously clean and the children are carefully looked after in the matter of their clothing and personal health and cleanliness. Food supplies are purchased so far as possible under contracts renewed quarterly, upon bids submitted to and passed upon by the Board of Trus - tees. All goods purchased are of standard grades, and any goods received that are not satisfactory are returned and replaced by better goods. The aim is to provide the children with plenty of plain and wholesome food, in variety and well cooked. In the summer a large amount of fruit, mostly grown on the place, is put up, and in their season vegetables from the garden are served. More than 2,000 quarts of cherries, grapes, plums, etc., and over 3,000 glasses of jelly were put up in the summer of 1912 by the matron and her assistants for use during the present term. Many bushels of apples, likewise from our own orchard, were gathered and used. I Much has been done in the past two summers under the ction of Mr. W. H. Chapman, the farm foreman, in the way mproving the grounds. Shade trees have been trimmed, Is have been laid out and graded, and shrubbery has been ited. A substantial board fence has been put up enclosing orchard and garden, money for which to the amount of $500 appropriated by the last legislature. While we have a tract ut twenty-three acres, more than half of it campus, the returns i the land in the form of farm and garden products during two seasons have amounted to $2595.60 in value, of which 40.50 worth has been consumed, the remainder having been and the money used for various purposes of the school. It has been my desire and hope to secure an extension of the school area by the purchase of contiguous ground, this to afford a building site for a future manual department building for the accommodation of children who because of physical or mental </seg>
            <seg id="p012">376 incapacity cannot be taught orally, as well as to give additional playground and likewise additional garden, vineyard, and or - chard area. The last legislature made appropriation of $12,500 for the purchase of such ground, but as yet the state authorities and the ground owners have been unable to come to a mutually satisfactory arrangement for the purchase. The last legislature enacted the following law An act to provide for a change to the oral, aural and lip - reading method of instruction and training of pupils in the Ne - braska School for the Deaf and to provide for the education of those pupils qualified for such instruction and the training in other deaf schools pending the change of method in this state. Be it Enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska: I Section 1. All children hereafter admitted to the Nebraska ol for the Deaf and all children who have not advanced nd three years in the course under present methods in said al shall hereafter be taught and trained in said school by the aural and lip-reading method to the exculsion of the deaf abet and sign language, unless incapacitated by mental de - or malformation of the vocal organs and all pupils now meed beyond said three years in the course shall be taught trained in the oral, aural and lip-reading method in the regu - ourses of study and by means of special conversational courses e put into effect to the fullest extent which is feasible and ticable. Section 2. Pending the complete change of method in the higher grades as provided for in Section 1, upon application of any parent or guardian of any deaf child residing in the state of Nebraska, capable of being instructed and trained by such method, such deaf child may be placed in any other school teach - ing and training in the oral, aural, and lip-reading method, pre - ference being given as far as practical to school selected by the parents or guardian, and an allowance shall be made each year to such parent or guardian toward the expense incident thereto in such an amount as in the judgment of the Board of Trustees of said Nebraska School for the Deaf would equal the cost to have educated and trained such child at the Nebraska School for the Deaf during each year said child shall attend such other school, to be paid out of the general appropriations made for the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">377 maintenance of the Nebraska School for the Deaf and in the same manner other charges are met and paid. 1 Section 3. It shall be the duty of the Superintendent and d of Trustees of said Nebraska School for the Deaf to en - i the provisions of this act. In pursuance of the provisions of this act all new pupils en - tering the school during the past year and a half have been under oral instruction and have so continued except in instances of physical or mental incapacity. These new pupils form four classes, and with five other oral classes, making nine in all, they constitute the present oral department. The remaining seven classes of the school are manual taught and they constitute the manual department. The school as a whole, this consisting of sixteen classes, is under the immediate direction of the superin - tendent, assisted by Miss Emily E. Sauter, Miss Alberta Regnier, and Mr. J. W. Sowell, respectively head teachers of the primary - oral, the intermediate oral and primary intermediate manual, and the advanced manual departments. tit is a satisfaction to be able to report a marked advance - ; in the work of the school in all its departments during the and present term. This advancement is especially notice - in the more general use throughout the school of the English aage, either in its spoken or its manually spelled form as a lum of instruction and communication among teachers and Is. In all this the principle is recognized and applied, that iguage is best learned through its use and through exclusive ndence upon it for all its purposes in the varied activities emergencies of life. In the work of the nine oral classes speech and lip-reading, with written and prinfed language, are the chief means of instruc - tion, while in the seven manual classes the work is conducted by means of the manual alphabet and written and printed lan - guage. Thus the pupils have all the practice in the use of lang - uage, either spoken, spelled, or written, that existing conditions make possible. At present the higher classes of the school are taught manually, the pupils composing them having been taught in the greater part by silent or non-speech methods throughout their school course, and it being deemed inexpedient to change methods at this stage. However, even in the case of these older, manually taught pupils, the semi-mutes among them and those </seg>
            <seg id="p014">378 thave acquired in their school course some powers of speech, given, for a period of fifteen to twenty minutes daily, drill practice in speech and lip-reading. This brief practice is n with the purpose in view to keep up the speech possessed hese pupils and so far as possible to improve it. The second section of the law as above quoted relates to children of advanced standing, whom their parents desire to attend oral schools outside the state, in order that they may secure advanced oral instruction such as this school is not now in a situation to provide. But while, in the case of two children, former pupils of the school and now attending an eastern oral school, application has been made to the Board of Trustees for an allowance toward the expense incurred by their parents in sending their children to a school outside the state, no allowance has been granted. The Board in denying the application of these parents for an allowance did so on the ground of insufficiency of funds, the legislature having failed to make the necessary ap - propriation to carry out this provision of the act. In view of the plain intent of the law in the matter it would seem but right and proper for the legislature to make appropriation for the reimburse - ment of the above parents, within the limitations provided by law, for the expense to which they have been subjected. The course of study of the school carries the children from the kindergarten occupations and the primary lessons in lip - reading and articulation, through successive stages of advance - ment in the acquisition of speech and of grammatical forms em - ployed in spoken and written language, then on through the regular common school branches, including composition.geography, grammar, physiology, physics, arithmetic and algebra. The course covers twelve grades, and in the case of pupils of average intelligence it may be covered in twelve years. It will be under - stood that all studies are in their largest part language studies, and this regardless of their subject matter, and the chief aim in pursuing them is to give a command of the English language and fluency in its use. The following is an outline of the course of study as at present pursued in the several departments of the First Grade Sense training, lip reading, arithmetic, language, numbers, Sunday-school work. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF, OMAHA 379 Second Grade Speech, speech reading, language, numbers, Sunday-school Third Grade Speech, speech-making, language, geography, arithmetic, Sunday-school work. Fourth. Grade Speech, speech-reading, language, reading, geography, arith - metic, Sunday-school work. Fifth Grade 1 Speech and speech-reading, language, reading, descriptive ns, geography, (Local and Nebraska) nature study, arith - c, Sunday-school work. Sixth Grade t Speech, speech-reading, language, reading, descriptive les - s, geography (Nebraska and United States) nature study, arithmetic, Sunday-school work. Seventh Grade E Speech and speech-reading, language, reading, geography th America, South America, Europe) United States History, biographies, nature study, manners and morals, Sunday- Eighth Grade i Speech and speech-reading, language, grammar, composi - geography, United States History, local biographies, phy - gy, manners and morals, Sunday-school work. Ninth Grade Language, grammar, composition, reading, geography, Amer - ican Biographies, American History, arithmetic, articulation and speech-reading, manners and morals, Sunday-school work. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">380 Tenth Grade Language, grammar, composition, reading, geography, Eng- lish Biographies, American History, arithmetic, articulation and speech-reading, manners and morals, Sunday-school work. Eleventh Grade Language, grammar, composition, reading, physical geog- raphy, English History, arithmetic, physics, articulation and speech-reading, manners, and morals. Twelfth Grade Division A. Language, grammar, composition, reading, arithmetic, algebra (latter part of term) articulation and speech- reading, manners and morals, Sunday-school work. Division B. Same course in English as above, literature, algebra, articulation and speech-reading, manners and morals, Sunday-school work. Upon graduation from the school pupils may elect to con- tinue their education by taking the five year course at Gallaudet College, a national free college maintained by the government at Washington. Two classes have been regularly graduated during the bien- nium, one in June 1911, and one in June 1912. The 1911 class consisted of seven pupils as follows: Peter C. Anderson Kearney County Frank A. Andrewjeski* Howard County Gladys F. Clark Washington County Lydia H. Gaeth Dodge County George W. Leach Clay County Arthur G. Nelson Washington County George L. Patterson Boon County The 1912 class consisted of ten pupils as follows: Fred W. Brown State of Wyoming T. Scott Cuscaden* Douglas County Emil V. Hladik* Pierce County Sophia M. Macek Douglas County </seg>
            <seg id="p017">381 Charles C. Marshall*. Ellen A. Pearson* . Robert O. Thayer . Louise C. Thomsen . Oscar M. Treuke* Christie F. Wieseman York County Burt County State of Wyoming Saunders County Douglas County Polk Countv tAll these young men and women had completed the pre - &gt;ed course with credit to themselves, and they are well pped as we may feel for doing their life work. The names ked with an asterisk are of the graduates who have entered are now attending the college at Washington. In conjunction with the literary department, the school maintains an industrial department, in which the boys are trained in carpentry, printing, painting, and farming, and the girls in sewing, dress making, laundry work and house work. Both boys and girls are given preliminary courses in drawing, clay modeling, basketry, and wood carving, preparatory to taking up more advanced training in the grades. The school is far from being well equipped in its industrial departments for proper trades teaching, and I would urge es - pecially the needs of the printing office and of the wood working department, for machinery and tools for training the boys in their use and preparing them to enter regular shops upon finish - ing school. The printing office requires a modern cylinder press on which to print the school paper and such pamphlets and books as may be published by the school; the office also needs a new and large paper cutter. The cylinder press will cost $1,200, and the paper-cutter $100. The wood working department likewise requires a number of machines to make its equipment complete for teaching joinery, cabinet-making and wood turning; among these needed machines are a mortising machine, a surface planer, a wood trimmer, an universal saw table, an d si* turning lathes. This additional machinery will cost $1,500. In this connection it may be stated that the wood working department has this year been placed under the direction of Mr. Jesse W. Jackson, a graduate of the Normal Training School at Pittsburg, Kansas, with the result to introduce the latest and most approved methods of training boys in the various departments of wood craft. It is a tart of our plan for the future to have every boy who psssgs </seg>
            <seg id="p018">382 through the school take a course more or less extended in the wood working department, this in order that they may have a practical knowledge of tools with greater or less skill in their use. Under well-ordered methods and skillful teaching, the mental culture and discipline gained in our industrial department is of a very practical character, tending with the rest to the development of self-confidence, independence, and manliness. A boy or girl who can work and who takes pride in his or her work is advanced far on the road to useful citizenship. All the girls in the school except the very youngest, receive instruction in sewing, under the direction of Mrs. Edith Johnson. They are taught plain sewing, dress making, and fancy work. The department during the past term, covering the period from the opening of school in September, 1911, to the close in June, 1912, made up the following articles, 2,590 in number: Aprons 55 Pillow cases 156 Bed pads 10 Pin cushion 1 Boys' suits 2 Printers' aprons 6 Curtains 2 Sheets 270 Centerpieces 2 Skirts 17 Dresses 15 Suits, girls 1 Dish towels 264 Sanitary napkins 48 Dresser scarfs 27 Sanitary belts 24 Dust cloths 12 Table squares 14 Dolls 2 Towels 772 Gowns 6 Table cloths 82 Guimps 4 Window shades 49 Gymnasium suits 6 Wash towels 39 Ironing pads 130 Waists 4 Laundry bags 15 Waists, corset 12 Napkins 533 The material needs of the school are chiefly for buildings. The present buildings, with two exceptions, that of the school - house and the auditorium, are old, out of repair, and generally illy adapted for the purposes of a modern, progressive school for the deaf. Moreover, since the older buildings were erected the city has laid out its main thoroughfare to pass immediately in their rear, so the "back parts of these buildings with their accessories are the parts presented conspicuously to the view of </seg>
            <seg id="p019">383 the passing public. With the rest, the power house, with its coal and cinder piles, and its smoking chimney and escaping steam, is the building in the foreground closest to the street. Altogether these older buildings are not, either in their construc - tion or their location, such as the state can be proud of, and I would urge the adoption of a plan looking to their replacement in time by buildings better constructed, better placed, and better adapted to the requirements of a present day school for the deaf. The modern school plant is an aggregation of cottages or de - partments, in which is secured at once the best possible condi - tions for health, safety, and proper school grading, through the segregating of the children in comparatively small groups or families where the advantage may be secured to the children of close supervision and of individual care and attention, which supervision and care are impossible where children are cared for as they are now in one large group of children of all sizes and ages. The desirability of the segregation of children thus in small groups according to size, age and advancement, needs no argu - ment, and I would urge that the state in its future development of this school plant, shall aim systematically to secure such segre - gation in the adoption of the cottage or the department plan, and building to that plan in all cases of new construction. Such a plan will contemplate at least five cottages or departments, each to provide home conditions for from forty to fifty children. Thus there would be a primary department building, an inter - mediate department building, and two advanced department buildings, one for the older boys and one for the older girls, also later a department building especially for the manually taught pupils, each of the five buildings being a complete home for its group of children, with its house-mother in immediate charge, together with all necessary supervisors for the proper care and training of the children under their charge. The development of the above plan may well be a progres - sive one, the several departments to be erected successively, beginning this year with the primary department building and one of the advanced department buildings, that for the older boys. I would, therefore, recommend that the present legislature be asked to appropriate sufficient funds to erect these two cot - tages or department buildings, to be of a size to accommodate </seg>
            <seg id="p020">384 The primary department building I consider one not only desirable for reasons above given, but absolutely essential to the highest success of the work of the school. The last legis - lature in its wisdom passed a law establishing the oral method as the method of the school, without however, providing the neces - sary conditions for making real oral teaching possible. At present the conditions compel the new children entering school at the opening of every term to come into daily contact with the older, manually taught, sign using pupils, and mingling with them they learn the sign-language and use it among themselves as their vernacular, quite to the exclusion of speech and lip - reading, and thus continuously throughout their school course. This operates seriously to handicap the oral teaching in the school, as the chief element of such teaching is practice, the practice every - where and at all times of the speech and lip-reading that are being systematically taught. It may be safely enunciated as an educational principle that increase in practice in an arith - metical ratio results in an increase in attainment in correspond - ing geometrical ratio. Thus if we so condition the practice of speech and lip-reading as to doubt it, we do not merely double the resulting attainment, but we quadruple it, and by trebling the practice the increase may reach nine fold. Lip-reading especially needs practice, but it richly rewards it, as is demon - strated by results secured in the best schools for the deaf of the country, in which lip-reading is used and relied upon as the chief means of communication. It is therefore, the present problem cf our school so to condition teaching, care-taking, and in truth all the activities of the daily school and home life, as to enlarge practice among the pupils of lip-reading. Dr. A. L. Crouter, one of the highest authorities in the work of the education of the deaf in this country, has said that lip-reading is the corner-stone of the oral method, hence the need for its practice and for the adoption of every means to secure the highest possible degree of skill in the art by our pupils. The providing of a separate building for the primary children will ma've it possible to segre - gate them at once upon their entrance to school, and thereafter to control conditions to the giving of the largest amount of practice in speech and lip-reading through their constant use by teachers and care takers, and by the pupils themselves, in all the </seg>
            <seg id="p021">385 K provide a building such as is required for the housing and toling of fifty primary children, we ask an appropriate of 000. The need of a new Advanced Boys' Cottage or department building has been a pressing one for some years. The present building occupied by the older boys was originally of the cheap - est construction, and while needing repair in every part, it is hardly worth putting money into, to repair it. Besides, we have the gravest fears that it is unsanitary, inasmuch as the toilet and bath rooms are immediately off the study and sitting rooms, and the odors from them are in almost constant evidence. We ask $50,000 for an Advanced Boys' Cottage. A new power house is also a need. The present power house fronts directly on the main street and the four boilers are all old and liable to give way at any time. The new power plant would be located, at a low point in the present garden, and equipped with new self-stoking boilers it would in a few years save its cost in the lessened amount of coal consumed. We need for this building and for necessary tunnels, piping, and equip - ment, an appropriation of $35,000. tThe industrial department building standing next to the er house is likewise a building out of place. Originally of cheapest construction, it is at this time much in need of re - and a wise economy will be its replacement with a new modern properly located building. We ask for erecting this building pprbpriation of $30,000. I Our school house, while a welj constructed building, is not ?ether well planned in the arrangement and the size of its &gt; rooms. Some of the rooms are decidedly too small. These ild be enlarged, and the enlargement can readily be ac - plished by moving certain partitions, which will result in wing four small rooms into two good sized rooms. This will ice our present number of rooms by two, but they may be e than regained by the partitioning of the old chapel on the i floor, which partitioning will readily yield five good sized &lt;o\ rooms. We ask for an appropriation of $700 for making e changes that will give us larger and additional school m. The city has within the last year put in paving on Forty- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">386 I street immediately in front of the school and extending the re width of the grounds unpaved. The paving thus ending ur school gate should be extended along the entire front of grounds. The cost of the state's share of the curbing and ing, which will be for the part lying between the curb line and street car track, will be $3,300, and we ask for this amount to ised for such purpose. The bill granting the appropriation ild at the same time authorize some official of the state to the petition for the paving of the street as is required by city ordinance. The last legislature made appropriation • of $3,000 for the equipment of the new chapel and gymansium. The money has been expended in the purchase of 200 folding seats for the audi - torium and of a complete gymnasium equipment, including a double bowling alley. A moving picture machine has also been contracted for and will soon be installed. This will afford our children, who in the nature of the case are dependent more than normal children upon their eyes, much entertainment and like - wise in the use of educational films much instruction. The appropriation made by the legislature of $5,000 for securing connection of the school with the city water mains was, under the direction of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, expended to the amount of $3,800, and we have, and have had since the winter of 1911, city water throughout our school plant, and we have also four outside hydrants conveniently located for use in case of fire. A hose cart and 300 feet of 2\ inch fire hose have been purchased at an expense of $332.66, which amount has been paid out of the funds of the school. This expense being extraordinary and unprovided for, has contributed in so much to increase our maintenance fund deficiency. The connection of our water system with the city water works relieves us of dependence upon wells for our water. The well water was good, but more or less frequent breakdowns in the pumping machinery made this source of supply unreliable, and likewise expensive. A fire company has been formed consisting of employees, and a number of the larger boys, and we have had frequent drills in handling the apparatus. The several funds as appropriated by the last legislature have been sufficient for meeting the expenses incident to the carrying on of the school, with the exception of the maintenance fund, </seg>
            <seg id="p023">387 which will be approximately $4,000 short of the amount needed to carry the school to the end of the biennium closing March 31, 1913. A deficiency of $5,000 occurred in the maintenance fund, two years ago, which would go to show that the maintenance fund, in order to meet fullly the necessary expenses of the school, should be increased to $40,000. I would therefore ask that the maintenance fund be made this amount for the coming biennium. The salary funds have been barely sufficient to meet the requirements, in fact they may lack a small sum of carrying the salary roll to the end of the biennium. Our salaries as now paid are not high when compared with those paid in other schools for the deaf, of the country, or in the city schools of Omaha. Be - cause of the special training and high order of skill required in the teachers, and likewise because of the close and intimate associations of the officers and employees with the pupils, the salaries paid should be attractive in a measure to draw to us the best teachers in the country and to give to us, and to make it possible to retain, officers and employees of a high grade of character and intelligence. The teachers' and officers' fund, which the last legislature fixed at $33,000, and the employees' fund, likewise fixed at $11,000, we ask to have raised respectively to $36,000 and $12,000. Oral classes are of necessity smaller than manual classes, hence the school requires and will require as the oral work increases, more teachers than formerly when the methods of the school were largely manual. Then it is our de - sire to establish a department of domestic science for instructing our older girls in cooking, instruction that they greatly need to fit them for what will be for most of them their life work, house - keeping. The increase in the salary fund asked for will make possible the employment of the needed domestic science teacher. The repair fund as appropriated by the last legislature was $3,000. This was in part used in effecting changes in the repairs to the heating and power plant, changes that have without doubt resulted in an economy in the expenditure for fuel. The repair fund is already exhausted and many needed repairs must await another appropriation. We shall need at least $4,000 appro - priated for repairs for the coming biennium. An appropriation of $300 was granted by the last legislature to send graduates of this school to Gallaudet College for the Deaf </seg>
            <seg id="p024">388 transportation of students unable themselves to bear the expense, and the amount, $150 per year, has been sufficient thus to aid two students. But at present there are four of our graduates of the above class attending the college, and the amount needed to permit them to continue their course will be $300 per year, or $600 for the biennium; we therefore ask that the latter amount* be appropriated. I take great pleasure in reporting upon our school library relative to its recent growth due to accessions received from the Nebraska Public Library Commission, through the good offices of Miss Charlotte Templeton, Secretary of the Commission, and of Miss Florence Waugh, Librarian for State Institutions. In the two years the Commission has presented to the school some 250 volumes, all carefully selected with reference to subject matter and to attractiveness in illustrations and print. Miss Waugh has made several visits to the school and in collaboration with Miss Roath, the school librarian, and latterly with Mrs. Blanken - ship acting in the same capacity, she has carefully classified, rearranged, and catalogued the entire library, doing thus a service the value of which to the school it would be hard to measure. The deaf must in the nature of things, find their chief enjoyment in reading, hence, the special value of the commission's contribu - tions of books to our school, giving our children, as they do, not only a present pleasure, but also training them in the art and im - planting in them the habit of reading that will be a source of pleasure to them all through life. It is contemplated, as soon as our funds may warrant it, the replacing of the present book cases with modern library shelving. This will make possible a better and more convenient a'rrangement of the books, besides adding much to the attractiveness of the room. I Two professional meetings were held, one in the summer of , in July, at the school for the deaf at Delevan, Wisconsin, ;ing the convention of American Instructors of the Deaf; the other in July, 1912, at the School for the Deaf, Provi - e, R. I.; this being a summer meeting of the American Ac - tion to Promote the Teaching of Speech to the Deaf. Both ings were largely attended by educators of the deaf from all ons of the country. One or two foreign delegates were also &gt;nt. The program at each of the meetings was rich with things in the way of papers and discussions relating to the </seg>
            <seg id="p025">389 numerous and difficult problems met with in the work of the education of the deaf. Members present at the Delevan Conven - tion from this school were as follows: Mr. J. G. McFarlane, Mr. W. H. Rothert, Miss Alberta Reginer, Miss Ethyl Rogers, Miss Helen Waite, and the Superintendent. Members attending the Providence meeting representing the school were Miss Emily E. Sauter and the Superintendent. (In closing this my report I wish to express to you my deep reciation of your encouraging support during my administra - , and likewise my appreciation of the fine spirit and hearty •peration of the teachers, officers and employees in the carry - out of all plans presented by me. Respectfully yours, </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>