<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00013.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00013.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NINTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BUREAU OF LABOR AND INDUSTRIAL STATISTICS FOR THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1903-1904</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">— OF THK— BUREAU OF LABOR —AND— INDUSTRIAL STATISTICS —FOR THE— State of Nebraska 1«&gt;o:M&lt;k&gt;-4- BURRETT BUSH ty Commiwioner DON C. DESPAIN / Clerk Lincxjln, Neb., 1905. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">• </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSM1TTAL ■ Hix Excellency, Honorable John IT. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska : §Sir: — In compliance with tbe provisions of Section 10, &gt;ter 39b, of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1903, I the honor to present for your consideration the Ninth nial Report of the Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics. Very respectfully, Burbett Bush, Deputy Commitnontr. oln, Nebraska, June 1, 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Suggested Legislation </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">SUGGESTED LEGISLATION The following suggestions are prompted by the experience gained in the performance of the duties of this department during- the period of my incumbency. I respectfully request your consideration of them and earnestly urge their recommendation. Enactment of a law providing for the appointment of ad - ditional factory inspectors to make possible the 'thorough inspection of all factories. The growth of the manufacturing interests in the state, together with the multiplicity of du - ties In the Bureau at present, makes the present force entirely inadequate to the demands of factory inspection. This in - spection to be for the enforcement of child and female labor laws and for the thorough collection of industrial statistics. Amend the child labor and female labor laws to provide for the reporting the first of each year, by all employers, of the number of children and females employed by them. Amending the fire escape law to remedy certain possible weaknesses therein and providing for the installing, by all hotels, hospitals, dormitories and rooming houses of a fire gong system in each room for warning of inmates in case of fire. Enactment of a law compelling all employers to report to the Bureau of Labor all strikes which may occur in their establishments. This report to be made immediately after the calling of the strike and to give causes thereof and the number of persons involved. Amend the statute relative to securing information and data from corporations and factories through the medium of blank forms. Broaden the ground which the Bureau may cover in its investigations and provide greater penalties for refusal or neglect to furnish information called for. Amend the statute relative to duty of assessors to collect agricultural statistics in such a manner as to compel greater care and diligence in the performance of this duty, and pro - viding penalty for neglect or refusal to collect same. Enactment of a law authorizing the establishment of state employment bureaus in the business districts ot our larger </seg>
            <seg id="p008">B cities. These can be established In co-operation with the municipal governments and upon a fee system, which will entail but a small expenditure by the state. The location of a state free employment bureau in the capitol building is im - practical and Is of little benefit unless sub-bureaus are maintained in the cities. I would recommend that more liberality be exercised iu providing appropriations for the maintenance o£ this depart ment. The present extent of the Bureau's appropriations will not permit of the printing of sufficient copies of our quarterly bulletins to supply the great demand. More funds and morfi clerical force is imperative if the full benefits of the aims and objects of the Bureau are realized. Compulsory publicitj' of the business affairs and operations of corporations and in - dustrial interests, is the most powerful weapor which the people possess in regulating our large industrial organiza - tions. Adequate legal authority and sufficient facilities in the nature of funds and clerical aid should be supplied the office from which this work is expected. Respectfully submitted. BURRETT BUSH, Deputy Commissioner To His Excellency, </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Labor Laws of Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011">Chapter 6 — Wages Preferred — In Assignments. Section 585. Nothing in this act (regulating assignments) conta. shall be construed so as to prevent any debtors from paying or se&lt; to be paid any debt not exceeding the sum of one hundred dollars, for clerks' or servants' wages, or from paying or securing any debt which shall (have) been created within nine months prior to the date of such payment, or securing or to effect any mortgage or security made in good faith to secure any debt or liability created simultaneously with mortgage or security, provided any such mortgage shall be filed for record in the proper office within thirty days from its date. Chapter 14a — Examination and Licensing of Plumbers. Section 1501 (As amended by chapter 24, Acts of 1903). In all cities in the State of Nebraska, having a population of more than forty thousand (40,000) inhabitants there shall be a board of the examination of plumb - ers, of four (4) members, consisting of one member to be known as the chief health officer of the city and one member to be known as the plumbing inspector of the city, one journeyman plumber, and one master plumber, all of whom shall be. appointed by the mayor of said city, by and with the consent of the city council; the health officer and plumbing inspector to hold their offices during the term of office of the mayor, and all of whom shall be residents of the city, and the inspector, jour - neyman and master plumber, shall be licensed plumbers. All vacancies In said board shall be filled by the mayor and council as above. The chief health officer and plumbing inspector, if such office exist in such cities, shall serve without additional compensation; and any of said board may be removed from office for cause, by the district court of the county in which such city is situated, and each of the board shall give bond in the sum of one thousand dollars ($1,000.00), conditioned according to law. The term of office of the journeyman and master plumber shall be for one (1) and two (2) years respectively, to be deter - mined by the mayor at the time of appointing them. t Section 1502. The persons who compose the first plumbing board &gt;r this act, shall, within ten (10) days after their appointment, meet leir respective city building or place designated by the city council, organize by the selection of one of their number as chairman, and plumbing inspector shall be the secretary of said board. It shall he duty of the secretary to keep full, true and correct minutes and </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Eds of all licenses issued by it, together with their kinds and dates, the names of persons to whom issued, in books to be provided by city, for that purpose, which books and records shall be, in all less hours, open for free inspection by all persons. Section 1503. The said board shall have power, and it shall be its to adopt rules and regulations, not inconsistent with the laws of the state or the ordinances of the city, for the sanitary construction, alteration and inspection of plumbing and sewage connections and drains placed in, or in connection with, any and every building in such city, in which it shall prescribe the kind and size of material to be used in such plumbing, and the manner in which such work shall be done, which rules and regulations, except such as are adopted for its own convenience only, shall be approved by ordinance by the mayor and council of such and the said board shall have power to amend or repeal its said rules and regulations, subject, except such as relate to its own conven - ience only, to the approval of the mayor and council of such city. The said board shall have power to compel the owner or contractor to first submit the plans and specifications for plumbing that is to be placed in any building or adjoining premises to be first submitted to and approved by said board before they shall be installed in such building or premises. I Section 1504. The board shall fix stated times and places of meeting, :h times shall not be less than once in every two weeks, and may be oftener upon written call of the chairman of the board, and the d shall adopt rules for the examination, at such times and places, 11 persons who desire a license to work at the construction or repair - of plumbing, within the said city. I Section 1505. Any person, not already licensed as herein provided, ring to do any plumbing, or to work at the business of plumbing in city, shall make written application to the -said board for &lt;-\amina - for a license, which examination shall be made at the next meeting le board, or at an adjourned meeting, and said board shall examine applicant as to his practical knowledge of plumbing, house drainage, ilation, and sanitation, which examination shall be practical as well heoretical, and if the applicant has shown Limself as competent the ibing board shall cause its chairman and secretary to execute and r er to the applicant a license authorizing him to do plumbing in city. Section 1506. All original licenses may be renewed, and all renewal licenses may be renewed, by the board, at the dates of their expiration. Such renewal licenses shall be granted, without a re-examlnation, upon the written application of the licensee filed with the board and showing that his purposes and condition remain unchanged, unless it is made to appear by affidavit before the board that the applicant is no longer competent, or entitled to such renewal license, in which event the renewal license shall not be granted until the applicant has undergone </seg>
            <seg id="p013">18 Section 1507. All original and renewal licenses shall be good for one year from their dates, provided that any license may be revoked by the board at any time upon a hearing upon sufficient written, sworn charged with the board showing the holder of the license to be incompetent or guilty of wilful breach of the rules, regulations, or requirements of the board, or of the laws or ordinances relating thereto, or of other causes sufficient for the revoking of his license, of which charges and hearing the holder of such license shall have written notice. Section 1508. It shall be unlawful for any person to do any plumbing in any such city of this state, unless he holds a proper license. I Section 1508a. The fee for the original license of a journeyman plumb - he fee shall be $1.00. All renewal fees shall be fifty cents. All ise fees shall be paid, prior to the execution ami delivery of (he se to the treasurer of the district school within the city, for which license was issued, to be used exclusively for the support of the non schools therein. I Section 1512. Any person violating any provisions of this act, or my lawful ordinance, or rules and regulations, authorized by this shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be fined not ■eding $50.00 nor less than $5.00 for each and every violation thereof; if such persons hold a plumber's license he shall forfeit the same, it shall be void, and he shall not be entitled to another plumber's ise for the space of one year after such forfeiture is declared against by the board. Chapter 16. — Safety Appliances on Railroads. Section 1794. ... It shall be unlawful for any corporation, person or company operating any line of railroad in thi my car manu - facturer or transportation company using or leasing cars to put in use in this state any car or cars that are not equipped with safety or auto - matic couplers between the ends of such cars to couple or uncouple them. I Section 1795 It shall be unlawful for any corporation, pany or persons operating a railroad, or any transportation company g or leasing cars of any description, and using in the commerce of country or in the construction of railroads, to have upon any railroad lebraska, for use in the transportation of freight or passengers, any that is not equipped with such safety automatic couplers as provided In said section 1(1^ Section 179C. It shall be unlawful for any corporation, company or person operating any line of railroad in this state, to use any locomotive engine upon any railroad in this state, to run any train or cars that shall not have in that train a sufficient number of cars with some kind of efficient automatic or power brakes, so that the engineer upon the locomotive can control the train without requiring brakemen to go between the ends or on the tops of the cars to use, as now, the common </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Section 1798. Every railroad corporation, company or person operat - ing a railroad in this state, and every person, corporation or company using or leasing cars in the transportation business, or in building rail - roads, shall, and are by this act required to include in their annual report to the state railroad commissioners the number of locomotive engines and cars used in this state, and what number is equipped with automatic power brakes and what number of cars equipped with auto - matic safety couplers and the kind of brakes and couplers used and the number of each kind when more than one kind is used. Section 1709. Any corporation, company or person operating a rail - road in this state, and using a locomotive engine, or running a train of cars, or using any freight or way car contrary to the provisions of this act, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and shall be subject to a fine of not less than five hundred dollars ($500.00) or not more than housand dollars ($1,000), for each and every offense for the benefit of the school fund; Provided, that penalties and liabilities on this section shall not apply to companies in receiving and hauling cars delivered for transportation by railroads other than those of this state which are engaged in interstate traffic. . And any railroad employee who may be injured by the engine or train or cars contrary to the provisions of this law shall not be considered as waiving his rights, to recover dam - ages by continuing in the employ of such corporation, company or person running such engine, or train of cars contrary to this law. Chapter 16— Intoxication of Railroad Employees. I Section 1811. If any person shall, while in charge of a locomotive ne running upon the railroad of any such corporation, or while acting he conductor of a car or train of cars on any such railroad, be in - cated, he shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon con- Ion thereof shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars or more l five hundred dollars, or be imprisoned not less than six months more than one year, and be imprisoned until the fine is paid. Chapter 16. — Incorporation of the Knights of Labor. t Section 1S92. All organizations known as subordinate lodges of Knights of Labor, which have been or may hereafter be regularly ted by the respective grand lodge bodies of the several orders or nizations in the State of Nebraska, are hereby entitled to all the [leges and rights incident to bodies corporate, so long as they in their respective organizations and charters aforesaid. Section 1893. All subordinate lodges of ... Knights of Labor, t. shall be known by the name and title designated in their several ective charters, as issued by the said grand lodges, department, or nization, by which name they shall be capable of suing and being , pleading and being impleaded, in the several courts of this state, same as natural persons, and shall have power to hold and convey estate and personal property, and do any and all things usually dona »rpo rations. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Chapter 21. — Right of Action for Injuries Causing Death. I Section 2503. Whenever the death of a person shall be caused by wrongful act, neglect, or default, and the act, neglect, or default is i as would, if death had not ensued, have entitled the party injured taintain an action and recover damages, in respect thereof, then, and very such case, the person who, or company or corporation which Id have been liable if death had not ensued, shall be liable to an &gt;n for damages, notwithstanding the death of the person injured, although the death shall have been caused under such circumstances mount in law to felony. Section 2504. Every such action shall be brought by and in the names of the personal representatives of such deceased person, and the amount recovered in every such action shall be for the exclusive benefit of the widow and next of kin of such deceased person, and shall be distributed to such widow and next of kin in the proportion provi ! law in relation to the distribution of personal property left by persons dying intestate; and in every such action the jury my give such damages as they shall deem a fair and just compensation with reference to the pecuniary injuries, resulting from such death, to the wife, next of kin of such deceased persons, not exceeding the sum of five thousand dol - lars; ProvidBd, that every such action shall be commenced within two years after the death of such person. STATE OF NEBRASKA (House Roll 108, 1905.) An Act for the equipment of certain classes of private buildings, hotels. lodging and apartment houses, public halls, asylums, schools, fac- tories, etc., with fire escapes, under the supervision of the Com - missioner of Labor or his Deputy, providing penalties for the viola - tion thereof, and repealing section 15, chapter 30 of the compiled statutes 1903 as now existing. Be it enacted by the legislature of the State of Nebraska: Section 15. That within six months after the passage of this act, all buildings in this state which are THREE or more stories in height, excepting such as are used for private residences exclusively, but in - cluding flats and apartment buildings, shall be provided with one or more metallic-ladder or stair fire escapes attached to the outer walls thereof, and provided with platforms of such size and dimension, and such proximity to one or more windows of each story above the first, as to render access to such ladder or stair from each such story easy and safe, and shall also be provided with one or more automatic metallic fire escapes, or other proper device, to be attached to the Inside of said buildings so as to afford an effective means of escape to all occupants who, for any reason, are unable to use said ladders or stairs; the number and material, location, and construction of such escapes, to be subject </seg>
            <seg id="p016">to the approval of the Commissioner of Labor, or his Deputy; Provided, however, that all buildings more than two stories in height used for manufacturing purposes, or for hotels, dormitories, schools, seminaries, hospitals or asylums, shall have at least one such fire ecape for every fifty persons, and one such automatic metallic escape for every twenty - five persons, for which working, sleeping or living accommodations are provided above the second stories of said buildings; and that all public halls and theaters, which provide seating room, above the first or ground story shall be provided with such numbers of said ladders or other fire escapes as said Commissioner of Labor or his Deputy shall designate. Provided, however, that nothing in this act shall apply to buildings not more than three stories in height, which are used as store flats, and apartment buildings, where such building.-; have front and rear entrance and are supplied with porches in rear on each story, extending the entire width of the said buildings, with \ tending from the ground to the upper porch, offering safe and accessible opportunity of egrees and ingrt • Section 16. All buildings of the number of stories and used for the purposes set forth in section 15 of this act, which shall be hei - ■ d in thi -hall, upon or before their completion, each be provided with fire escapes of the kind and number and in the manner orth in this act. Section 17. It shall be the duty of said Commissioner of Labor or his Deputy to serve a written notice in behalf of the people of the State l&gt;on the owner or owners, trustees, or lessees, their agents or the occupant of any building within this state not provided with fire escapes in accordance with the provisions of this act, commanding such owner, trn &gt;&gt;r occupant, or either of them, to place or cause to be placed upon such building fire escape or escapes as is provided for in section fifteen (15) of this act, within thi i days after the oa of such notice. And the grand juries of the several counties of -tate may also, during any term, visit or hear testimony relatr uilding of buildings within their respective counties, for the purpose lining whether it or they are provided with fire escapes in accordance with the requirements of this act, and submit the result of their inquiry, together with any recommendations they may desire to make, to the district court, and said court may thereupon, if it find from the report of said grand jury that said building or buildings is or are not provided with fire escape or escapes, in accordance with this act, cause the sheriff to serve a notice or notices upon owner, trustee, lessee, or occupant of such building or buildings. Section 18. Any such owner or owners, trustee, lessee, or occupant, or either of them, or their agents, so served with notice as aforesaid, who shall not, within sixty (CO) days after the service of such notice upon him or them, place or cause to be placed, such fire escape or escapes upon Fiion bull die i£&amp; * • s rt*o u i r*t ' il bv this Pet 'in ■ 1 t ht* tpnns af mip^i &lt; tt ' ( ■&gt; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p017">IT shall be subject to a fine of not less than twenty-five (25) or more than two hundred (200) dollars, and to a further fine of fifty (50) dollars for each additional week of neglect to comply with such notice. I Section 19. The erection and construction of any and all fire escapes ided for in this act shall be under the direct supervision and control lid Commissioner of Labor or his Deputy, and it shall be unlawful for person or persons, firm, or corporation to erect or construct any fire pe or except in accordance with a written permit first had obtained and signed by said Commissioner of Labor or his Deputy, rmlt shall prescribe the number, location, material, kind and ner of construction of such fire Section 20. Any person or persons, firm or corporations, who shall liiired to place one or more fir* U|&gt;on any building or build - ings, under the provision or this act, shall file in the office of ttu- Coninibsiuiii r of Labor or his Deputy a written application for a permit to erect or construct such fire escape or which application sha'.l scribe the character of such building or buildings, the- 1 and number of stories thereof, the number of fire io be placed thereon, the purposes for which such building or buildings is or are used, and the greatest number of people who use or occupy or are employed in such building or buildings abov&gt; lereof at any one time. Chapter 3Sb. — Bureau of Labor Census and Industrial Statistics 1 Beetle There i created a bureau of labor c&lt; trial statistics, with headquarters in the capitol building, for •h stationery, postage, expressage, printing, and facilities for tran - ing business shall be furnished the same as for other irtments. Section 3311. The governor of th is hereby made commi r of said bureau. I; 12. Said commissioner shall have the power to appoint puty at a salary of fifteen hundred dollars per annum, who, ig for or instead of said commissioner, shall have and may exer - equal jwwer and authority subject to the approval of the comaiis- oner Section 3313. The duties of said commissioner shall be to col collate, and publish statistics and facts relative to manufac ial classes, and material resources of the state, and especially to examine into the relations between labor and capital, the means of m from fire and protection of life and health in factories and workshops, mines and other places of industries, the employment of illegal child labor, the exaction of unlawful hours of labor from any em - he educational, sanitary, moral, and financial condition of laborers and artisans I food, fuel, clothing, and building </seg>
            <seg id="p018">jecU and matters pertaining to the welfare of industrial interests and Section 3314. The commissioner or his deputy shall have power to enter any factory or workshop in which labor is employed, for the pur - pose of gathering facts and statistics, or of examining the means of escape from fire, and the provisions for the health and safety of operatives in such factory or workshop. He may also post in such factory or workshop the laws now, or hereafter to be, made in respect to child labor, fire escapes, hours of labor, or others pertaining to the health or safety of employees; and if the owner, manager or agent shall remove or destroy the same he shall, upon conviction thereof, be fined in any sum not to exceed fifty dollars for each offense. And in case the officers of the bureau shall discover any violation of, or neglect, to comply with, said laws, he shall notify the owner or occupant of said workshop or factory in writing of the offense or neglect, and if such offense or neglect is not corrected within thirty days after the service of notice aforesaid, he shall lodge formal complaint with the attorney of the county in which the offense is committed or the neglect occurs, whereupon said officer stall proceed against the offender according to law. Section 331C. At the time of the assessment of property for taxation for county and state purposes, it shall be the duty of the township and precinct assessors to enroll the names of all persons over 21 years of age in their respective township or precincts, together with their several occupations; if farmers or manufacturers, the products of their several farms or factories during the past year, and if wage workers, the time they have been employed during the past year and the wages they have received for the same. It shall be the duty of the county clerks on or before the first day of July in each year, to forward a summary of such reports of their respective counties to the state bureau of labor. The deputy commissioner of labor shall compile said reports and embody them in his biennial report to the governor. Section 3317. The said commissioner shall have power to prescribe blank forms and transmit them to employers, which shall be filled out clearly and completely under oath, by the person or persons to whom they are sent, with the facts, statistics, and statements asked for, anJ return them to him within such reasonable time as he may fix. In case any owner or occupant, or his agent, shall refuse to admit any officer of said bureau to his workshop or factory, when open or in operation, he shall forfeit the sum of ten dollars for each and every .offense, and if he shall, through his agent or otherwise, neglect, fail, or refuse to fill out the said blank forms, and verify and return them as required, he shall forfeit the sum of ten dollars for each and every day said blanks may be so delayed beyond the time fixed by the commissioner for their return. The forfeits named and provided in this act shall be sued for in the name of the state by the county attorney of the respective county where such offense is committed, upon the complaint of any offic - er of said bureau, or any citizen, and shall be paid into the school fund. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Section 3318. The commissioner of labor is hereby authorized and directed, within thirty days after the passage of this amendment, to es - tablish and maintain in the office of the bureau of labor and industrial statistics and in conection therewith, a free public employment office. The deputy commissioner shall receive all applications for help made to him by any person, company or firm, and all applications made to him for employement by any person or persons and record their names In a book kept for that purpose, designating the kind and character of help wanted or the kind and character of employment desired, and the postofflce address of the applicant. It shall be the duty of said deputy to send by mail to all applicants for help, the name and postofflce a&gt;i of such applications for employment as in his judgment will meet their respective requirements and such other information as he may possess that will bring to their notice the names and postoffic* m of such unemployed laboiers, mechanics, artisans or teachers as they may require. No compensation or fee whatsoever shall directly or indirectly be charged or received from any person or persons applying for help, or any person or persons applying for employment through the bureau of labor. Said deputy or clerk connected with the bureau, who shall accept any compensation or fee from any applicant for help or any applicant for employment, for services as provided in this act, shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be fined in a sum not less than twenty-five dollars nor more than one hundred dollars for each offense, or imprisoned not to exceed thirty days Any application for help or any application for employment made to said office shall be null and void after thirty days from its receipt by said deputy, unless renewed by the applicant. Every applicant for help shall notify said deputy commissioner by mail immediately after the desired help designated in his or her application has been secured, and every applicant for employment shall notify said deputy immediately after securing the same. Such notice shall contain the name and last preceding postoffice address of each employer or employee secured through such employment office, and any failure or refusal to thus notify said deputy commissioner shall bar such applicant from all future rights and privileges of said employment office at the discretion of said deputy. All applicants for help shall be construed to mean employers wanting employees, and applicants for employment shall be construed to mean persons wanting work to do. . . . Section 3319. The commissioner shall report biennially to the governor, accompanying his report with such suggestions and recom - mendations as may be deemed wise and proper. The said report shall be printed and distributed according to the provisions of the law gov - erning the printing of other state reports. I Section 3320. The commissioner shall be allowed a sum not to exceed hundred dollars per annum for traveling and contingent expenses, a further sum of one hundred dollars per annum for the purchase </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Poks and periodicals on labor and industrial matters for the bureau y. There is hereby appropriated annually, out of moneys in the ury, not other wise appropriated to carry out the provisions of this Chapter 47a. — Trade-Marks of Trade Unions, etc. Section 3549. It shall be lawful for associations, and unions of workingmen to adopt for their protection, labels, trade-marks, and othor forms of advertisement, announcing that goods manufactured by mem - bers of such associations or unions, as are manufactured. Section 3550. Any and ail persons using such union or association trade-marks, labels, or advertisements, whether exactly like such labels, trade-marks, or advertisements or not, if with the intention to, or likely to deceive the public, and every person who shall use any counterfeited label, trade-mark, or form of advertisement of such unions or associa - tions, knowing the same to be counterfeited, after having been notified in writing by the owner thereof, or his or its agents that the same is counterfeited, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, punishable by imprison - ment for not less than three (3) months or more than one (1) year, or by a fine of not less than one hundred (100) dollars, nor more than five hundred (500) dollars, or both: Provided, That such notice in writing contains a copy, counterpart, or facsimile of such genuine label, trade - mark or forms of advertisement. Section 3551. Every such association or union adopting a label, trade-mark, or form of advertisement as aforesaid, shall file the same in the office of the secretary of state, who shall, under his hand and seal, deliver to the association or union filing the same, a certificate of record, for which he shall receive a fee of twenty-five (25) cents. I Section 3552. Every such association or union adopting a label, trade- Is, or form of advertisement as aforesaid, may proceed, by suit in courts of this state, to enjoin the manufacture, use, display, or sale ny such counterfeits, and all courts having jurisdiction thereof shall ,t an injunction to restrain and prevent such manufacture, use, dis - , or sale, and shall award the complaintants such damages resulting i such wrongful use as may be proved, and shall require the ndants to pay to the party injured the profits derived from such lgful use, or both profits and damages; and the court shall also r all such counterfeits, in the possession, or under the control of defendant in such case to be delivered to an officer of the court or he complaintant, to be destroyed. Section 3553. In like maner such unions or associations shall be authorized to proceed against all persons who shall wrongfully use, or display the genuine labels, trade-marks, or forms of advertisements of the respective associations or unions not being authorized by such associations or unions to use or display the same. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Chapter 53. — Earnings of Married Women. I Section 3662. . . . The earnings of any married woman, from her e, business, labor, or services, shall be her sole and separate property, may be used and invested by her, in her own name. Chapter 54. — Security for Wages of Employees on Public Works — Con tractor's Bond. Section 3683. It shall be the duty of the board of public lands anl buildings, boards of county commissioner, the contracting board of officers of all cities and villages and all public boards are hereafter empowered by law to enter into a contract for the erecting and finishing, or the repairing of any public building, bridge or other public structure to which the general provisions of the mechanics' lien laws do not applv and where mechanics and laborers have no lien to secure the payment of their wages, to take from the person or corporation to whom the contract is awarded a bond with at least two good and sufficient sure - ties conditioned for the payment of all laborers and mechanics for labor that shall be performed in the erecting, furnishing er repairing of the building or in performing the contract said bond shall be to the board awarding the contract; and no contract shall be entered into by such board until the bond herein provided for has been filed with and approved by said board. The said bond shall be safely kept by the board making the contract and may be sued on by any person entitled to the benefit of this act. The action shall be in the name of the party claiming the benefit of this act. KThe sureties on the contractor's bond are liable to a sub-contractor, lebr. 816. t'To insert a covenant in a contract for the erection of a public ing, requiring the contractor to agree under the bond to » laborers and material men, is within the power of the »l . 220. Chapter 72. — Protection of Employees on Street Railways — Inclosed Platforms. Section 4044a. ... It shall be unlawful for any person, partner - ship or corporation, owning or operating a street railway in thi - for any officer or agent thereof, superintending or having charge or control of the management of such line of railway, or the cars thereof, operat - ing electric, cable or other cars propelled either by steam, cable or electricity, which require constant services, care or attention of any person or persons upon the platforms of such cars, to require or perm.i sucn services, attention or care of any of its employees or any other person or persons between the first day of November and the first day of April thereafter of each year, unless such person, partnership or corporation, its said officers or superintending or managing agents, have </seg>
            <seg id="p022">tsure, constructed of wood, iron and glass, or similar suitable material lent to protect such employees from exposure to the winds and in - ■ncies of the weather: Provided, That such inclosure shall be nstructed as not to obstruct the vision of the person operating the or to endanger or interfere with its safe management by the tor. Section 4044b. ... It shall be unlawful for any such person, partnership or corporation so owning or operating street railways using steam, electric or cable cars, or any superintending or managing officer or agent thereof, to cause or permit to be used upon such line of railway between said November first and April first of each and every year thereafter, any car or cars upon which the services of any employee, such as is specified in section one (1) of this act (4044a). Section 4044c. Violations of this act shall be punished as follows: If the violation is by a corporation it shall forfeit and pay the sum of one hundred ($100) dollars; if the violation is by a person or a co - partnership such offender shall be punished by a fine of not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100) or be imprisoned in the county jail not to exceed three months. Each day that any of said person or persons, partnership or corporation, cause or permit any of their said employees to operate such cars in violation of the provisions of section one (1) and two (2) of this act (sees. 4044a and 4044b), or cause or permit cars to be mod or operated in violation of said section two (2) of this act (sec. 4044b), shall be deemed a separate offense: Provided, That the provis - ions of this act shall not apply to cars used and known as trailing cars. I Section 4044d. It is hereby made the duty of the county attorney ay county in which any such street railway is situated and operated, i any information given him by any credible persons, or upon the fledge that he may possess, that any person, partnership or corpora - has violated any of the provisions of this act, to promptly prosecute person, members of such partnership or corporation for such viola- Chapter 78 — Employment of Intemperate Driver* on Public Conveyances. I Section 4562. No person owning any carriage, running or traveling i any road in this state, for the conveyance of passengers, shall loy, or continue in employment, any person to drive such carriage is addicted to drunkenness or the excessive use of spiritous liauors, if any such owner shall violate the provisions of this section, after hall have had notice and reasonable proof that such driver is addicted runkenness, he shall forfeit at the rate of five dollars per day for he time during which he shall thereafter have kept any such driver is employment. K Section 4563. If any driver whilst actually employed in driving any carriage, shall be guilty of intoxication to such a degree as to en - ter the safety of the passengers in the carriage, it shall be the duts </seg>
            <seg id="p023">signed by any one of said passengers, and certified by him on oath, forthwith to discharge such driver from his employment ;and such owner who shall retain or have in his employ, within three months after receipt of such notice, any driver who shall hav so lo - toxicated, shall forfeit at the rate of five dollars per day the time d which he shall have kept any such driver in his employment receiving such notice. Chapter 78. — Hours of Labor on Public Roads. K Section 4581. The overseer shall allow all persons who may api» uance to such notice and offering to pay their labor tax in labor :r his direction, the sum of $1.50 for every day he snail actuallv c eight hours on such road. Chapter 90. — Hours of Labor. K Section 5329. Ten hours shall constitute one day's labor, so far as mcerns laborers and mechanics, throughout the state. I Section 5329a. No company, corporation or person operating a rail , in whole or in part, within the State of Nebraska, shall permit or Ire any conductor, engineer, fireman, brakeman, telegraph operator ny trainman who has worked in his respective capacity for eighteen ecutive hours, except in case of casualty, or unavoidable emergency, gain go on duty or perform any work until he has had at least eight ■s for rest. I Section 5329b. Any company, corporation or person who shall vi ermit to be violated, any of the provisions of the foregoing section, ny officer, agent or employer who violates or permits to be violated of the provisions of the preceding section shall be fined not less fifty ($50) dollars nor more than two hundred ($200) doilai - every violation of this act: Provided, however, That the proceed - to enforce the penalty, as provided in this act shall commence in six month from the date of the violation of the same. Chapter 91a. — Anti-Trust Act — Labor Organizations Exempt. t Section 5342a. Nothing herein contained shall be construed to piv - any assemblies or associations of laboring men from passing an 1 ) iting such regulations as they may think proper, in reference to wages the compensation of labor, and such assemblies and associations shall in, and there is hereby reserved to them, all the rights and privileges accorded to them by law, anything herein contained to the contrary rithstanding. PART II.— CODE OF CIVIL PROCEDURE. Title 14. — Wages Preferred — In Executions, etc Section 6117. Nothing in this chapter shall be so construed as to </seg>
            <seg id="p024">BIENNIAL KKPORT OF exempt any property in this state from execution or attachment for clerks', laborers', or mechanics' wages. Title 14. — Exemption of Wages from Attachment, etc. Section 6118. The wages of laborers, mechanics, and clerks who are heads of families, in the hands of those by whom such laborers, mechanics, or clerks may be employed, both before and after such wages shall be due, shall be exempt from the operation of attachment, execution, and garnishee process: Provided, That not more than sixty -hall be exempt: Provided further, That nothing in this act shall be so construed as to protect the wages of persons who have or are about to abscond or leave the state from the provisions of law now in force upon that subject; Provided, further, That nothing in this act shall be so construed as to permit the attachment of sixty days' wages in the hands of the employer. I An exemption granted in another state by the laws of that state continue in this state in case of an action brought here. The exemp - of laborers' wages extends to non-residents. 19 Nebr. 181, A laborer may maintain an action against a creditor to recover wages wrongfully garaisheed. 17 Nebr. : Title 14. — Exemption of Wages — Unlawful Assignment of Claims. Section 6120. It is hereby declared unlawful for any creditor of. or other holder of any evidence of debt, book account, or claim of any name or nature against any laborer, servant, clerk, or other employe of any corporation, firm or individual, in this state, for the purpose below 1. to sell, assign, transfer, or by any means dispose of any such claim, book account, bill, or debt of any name or nature whatever, to any person or persons, firm, corporation, or Institution, or to institute in this state or elsewhere, or prosecute any suit or action for any such claim or debt against any such laborer, servant, clerk, or employee by any process seeking to seize, attach or garnish the wages of such person rsons earned within sixty days prior to the commencement of such proceeding, for the purpose of avoiding the effect of the laws of the State of Nebraska concerning exemptions. » Section 6121. It is hereby declared unlawful for any person or per - i to aid, assist, abet, or counsel a violation of section one of this 120) for any purpose whatever. Section C122. In any proceeding, civil or criminal, growing out of a breach of sections one or two of this act (sees. 6120, 6121), proof of the institution of suit, or service of garnishment summons by any per - sons, firm, qr individual, in any court of any state or territory, other than this state or in this state to seize by process of garnishment or otherwise, any of the wages of such persons, defined in section one ot this act (sec. 6120), shall be deemed as prima facie evidence of an </seg>
            <seg id="p025">BUREAU Bis of this act on the part of the creditor or resident in Nebraska ng the same to be done. t Section 6123. Any persons, firm or company, corporation, or business tution guilty of a violation of sections one or two of this act (sees. . G121) shall be liable to the party injured through such vi - act, for the amount of the dt ued upon, with all costs and expenses and a reasonable attor: to be recovered in any court of competent jurisdiction in I shall further be liable by prosecution to punishment by a fine not eding the sum of two hundred dollars and costs of pro- This act is constitutional. 39 Nebr. 679. IOne who assigns a claim contrary to the provisions of th able to the debtor for the amount so appropriated without his con - . 37 Nebr. 267. PART III.— CRIMINAL CODE. Chapter 23. — Sunday Labor. Section 6905. . . . And if any person of the age of four' years or upward shall be found on the first day of the week, commonly called Sunday, at common labor (work of necessity and charity only excepted), he or she shall be fined in a sum not exceeding five dollars nor less than one dollar: Provided, Nothing herein contained to common labor on said first day of the week, commonly called Bui shall be construed to extend to those who conscientiously obsen • seventh day of the week as Sabbath, nor prevent families emlgi from traveling, water men from landing their passengers, superinten or keepers of toll bridges or toll gates from attending and superint. - the same, ferrymen from conveying travelers over the water, or persona moving their families on such days, or to prevent railroad companies from running necessary trains. Chapter 23. — Employment of Women and Children Section 6942a. No female shall be employed in any manufacturing, mechanical, or mercantile establishment, hotel, or restaurant, in this state, more than sixty hours during any one week, and that ten hours shall constitute a day's labor. The hours of each day may be so arranged as to permit the employment of such females at any time from six o'clock a. m. to ten o'clock p. m. ; but in no case shall such employment exceed ten hours in any one day. Section 6942b. Every such employer shall post in a conspicuous place in every room where such females are employed, a printed noti&lt; the number of hours' work required of them each day of the wet - hours of commencing and stopping such work, and the hours when the time or times allowed for dinner or for other meals begins and ends. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Commissioner and the form of such notice approved by the Attorney General of this state. I Section 6942c. Every such employer in such establishment shall ide suitable seats for the females so employed, and shall permit the of such seats by them when they are not necessarily engaged in the ve duties for which they are employed. I Section 6942d. And employer, overseer, superintendent, or other it of any such employer who shall violate any of the provisions of thia shall be fined for each offense in a sum not less than twenty dollars more than fifty dollars; and it is hereby made the duty of the Deoutv jr Commissioner to enforce the provisions of this act: Provided, ever, That nothing in this act shall be construed to prevent any other on from enforcing its provisions. This act (sections C942a to 6942d) is constitutional. 91 N. W. Rep. KThat any male of female child under the age of ten ■s shall not be employed in any manufacturing, mechanical, industrial, tercantile establishment. Section C954. That any male or female child under the age of four - teen years shall not be employed in any manufacturing, mechanical, in - dustrial, or mercantile establishment, except during the vacations of the public schools; unless during the next year preceding such employment, said child has for at least twenty weeks attended some public or private day school where the English language is taught; nor shall such em - ployment continue, unless such child shall in each and every year attend school as herein provided, and no child shall be so employed who does not present a certificate signed by the president and secretary of the school board of the school district in which said child resides, of their compliance with the requirements of this section. Nor shall any owner, superintendent, or overseer of any such establishment, parent or guardian consent to or permit the employment of any child contrary to the pro - visions of this act. Section 6955. Any owner, superintendent, or overseer of any such establishment, shall require and keep on file, open to the inspection of the public, certificate of the age, place of birth and residence of every male and female child under sixteen years of age employed therein, so long as such child is so employed; which certificate shall also state, In case the child is under fourteen years of age, the amount of said child's school attendance during the year next preceding his emplyment, and such certificate shall be signed by the president and secretary of the school board of the school district in which such child resides, and the forms of certificate herein referred to shall be approved by the attor ney general of this state. K Section 6955a. Any person who shall be convicted of a violation of of the provisions of this act shall pay for every such offense a fine of not than twenty dollars nor more than fifty dollars; Provided, however, </seg>
            <seg id="p027">That no conviction shall be had under this act unless the procee therefor shall be commenced within one year after the offense shall have been committed. i Section 6955b. It is hereby made the duty of the Deputy Labor i ioner of this state, upon complaint being filed with him, to inspect and all establishments to which this act applies, and ascertain w iy of the provisions of this act have been violated. Whenever it shall e to his knowledge that any of the provisions of this act have been re being violated, it shall be his duty to cause the same to be enfo: ided, however, That nothing in this section contained shall be con - ad to prevent any other person from causing the enforcement of the isions of this act. Chapter 17. — Employment of labor on Public Works — Cities of the First Class. Section 123. In all cities governed by this act (cities having less than forty thousand and more than twenty-five thousand inhabit; where work is performed upon the streets, sewers, boulevards or in parks. etc., or by virtue of any contract with any person, company, or companies, or corporations, for such city, shall be done by union labor and be paid for at the rate of two (|2.00) per day: Provided, That when skilled labor is employed by the city, said labor shall be paid the current scale of union wages: Provfded that eight hours shall constitute a day's labor. </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
            <seg id="p029">Child Labor </seg>
            <seg id="p030">• </seg>
            <seg id="p031">CHILD LABOR What Constitutes Effective Child Labor Laws. Klrst among all the ends to be striven for is uniformity among the on the basis of the best that has already been accomplish most enlightened states. It is to be borne in mind in all discussions of child labor laws. I ire enacted in the interest of the weakest elements in the comnv It is the recently immigrated family in the north and the poor whites in the south whose children are found at work. It is, therefore, probable that a rigid exclusion of all work of children under the age ■ years, while inflicting hardship upon some families already here and in - volving, perhaps, some need of assistance for them on the part of the community, would act as a check upon the immigration of the lea - sirable foreigners, — those who come in the hope of exploiting their j children, — and would somewhat deter the migration of the moi) whites in the south to the mill towns. In Massachusetts, at the past four sessions of the legislature, a bill has been introduced which would raise the minimum age for employment to sixteen years ; and th&lt; no doubt that this bill will continue to be introduced until it final) v becomes the law. Meanwhile, however, in the interest of the effort for uniformity, it has seemed more practicable to adopt as the minimum age for beginning work, the fourteenth birthday, except in mines and dangerous occupations; while endeavoring to bring to this minim the children now engaged in street occupations hitherto exempt from restrictions in nearly all the states; and endeavoring also, to bring to this minimum the statutes of those states which as j ibe either no minimum age, or one set at ten, twelve or thirteen years. No one acquainted with the diminutive stature of children of the working clasa at the age of fourteen years, can regard the adoption of this standard minimum age for beginning work as final. It is merely the best attain - able for the present and the immediate future in the evolution of child - labor legislation. In the century since the movement for child-labor legislation begab with Sir Robert Peel's act of 1802, effort has ben devoted chief placing about the labor of children restrictions based upon age or school requirements but these have been found unsatisfactory in the United States by reason of the defective registration of births and the readiness of parents to perjure themselves. It is the tendency of the pres» consider the fitness of the child itself, and to establish an obj. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">test of fitness for the occupation which the child enters. This has taken primarily the negative form of prohibiting for all children certain Industries in Massachusetts and New York, and of prohibiting in general in Ohio, "any occupations dangerous to life and limb or whereby its health is likely to be injured or its morals may be depraved." In Illinois, the idea is expressed in the long list of prohibited occupations. A law enacted by the legislature of New York during 1903 provides that a child must be "of normal development and in sound health" before receiving the certificate of the local board of health enabling it to begin work. Effective legislation dealing with child-labor involves many differing elements including the child, the parent, the employer, the officials charged with the duty of enforcing the statutes, and finally the community which enacts laws, provides schools for the children when they are prohibite 1 from working, supports and authorizes officers for the enforcement of the laws, prescribes penalties for their violation, assists dependent fam - ilies in which the children are below the legal age for work. In the long run, the effectiveness of the law depends upon the conscience of the conj munity as a whole fa: 1 more than upon the parent and the employer acting together. I With the foregoing reservations and qualifications duly emphasized, following summaries are believed to outline the substance of the :tive legislation which it seems reasonable to try to secure in tho ent and the immediate future. They deal only with provisions for child as a child, taking for granted the provisions for fire escapes, guards for machines, toilet facilities and all those things which the I shares with the adult worker. BAn effective child-labor law rests primarily upon certain definite pro- Ions among which are the following: Labor is Prohibited. (1) for all children under the age of fourteen years. (2) for all children under sixteen years of age who do not measure sixty inches and weigh eighty pounds.* (3) for all children under sixteen years of age who cannot read flu - ently and write legibly simple sentences In the English language. (4) for all children under the age of sixteen years, between the hours of 7 p. m. and 7 a. m., or longer than eight hours in any twenty-four hours, or longer than forty-eight hours in any week. (5) for all children under the age of sixteen years in occupations dangerous, to life, limb, health or morals. *Tbis measure is not now specified in any statute thouirn it is implied in the stutute w York, enacted in 1908. Bills specifically embracing this provision were introduced </seg>
            <seg id="p033">The Child. Effective legislation requires that before going to work the child satisfy a competent officer appointed for the purpose, that it (1) is fourteen years of age, and (2) is in good health, and (3) measures at least sixty inches and weighs eighty pounds, and (4) is able to read fluently and write legibly simple sentences in the English language, and (5) has attended school a full school year during the twelve months next preceding going to work. The Parent. Effective child-labor legislation requires that the parent (1) keep the child in school to the age of fourteen years apd longer if the child has not completed its required school work, and (2) take oath as to th« exact age of the child before letting it begin to work, and (3) substantiate the oath by producing a transcript of the official record of the birth of the child, or the record of its baptism, ■ or some other religious record of the time of the birth of the child, and must (4) produce the record of the child's school attendance, signed by the principal of the school which the child last attended. The Employer. B Effective child-labor legislation requires that the employer before ng the child begin to work, (1) obtain and place on file ready for official inspection papers show - ing K(a) the place and date of birth of the child substantiate (b) the oath of the parent corroborated by (c) a transcript of the official register of births, or by a transcript of the record of baptism, or other religious record of the birth of the child, and by (d) the school record signed by the principal of the school which the child last attended, and by (e) the statement of the officer of the board of education designated for the purpose, that he has approved the papers and examined the child. rr permitting the child to begin to work, the emplo:&gt; required to produce the foregoing papers on demand of the school-attendance office, the health officer and the factory inspectors. (3) In case the child cease to work, the employer must restore to the child the papers enumerated above. (4) During the time that the child is at work, the employer 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">provide suitable seats, and permit their use so far as ttao nature of the work allows; and must (5) Post and keep posted in a conspicuous place, the hours for be - ginning work in the morning, and for stopping work in the I middle of the day; the hours for resuming work and for stopping at the close of the day; and all work done at any time not specified in such posted notice constitutes a viola tion of the law. The total number of hours must not exceed eight in any one day or forty-eight in one week. The Officials. Effective legislation for the protection of children requires that tho officials entrusted with the duty of enforcing it (1) give their whole time, not less than eight hours of e\nery working day, to the performance of their duties, making night in - spections whenever this may be necessary to insure that children are not working during the prohibited hours; and (2) treat all employers alike, irrespective of political considerations, or race, religion or power, in a community. (3) prosecute all violations of the law; (4) keep records complete and intelligible enough to facilitate tho enactment of legislation suitable to the changing conditions of industry. The School. The beet child-labor law is a compulsory education law covering forty weeks of the year and requiring the consecutive attendance of all children to the age of fourteen years, and until they complete a specified portion of the curriculum, as eight years in Colorado or five years in New York. It is never certain that children are not at work, if they are out of school. In order to keep the children, however, it is not enough to compel attendance, — the schools must be modified and adapted to the needs of the recent immigrants in the north and of the poor whites in the south, affording instruction which appeals to the parents as worth having, in lieu of the wages which the children are forbidden to earn, and appeals to the children as interesting and attractive. These requirements are so insufficiently met in the great manufacturing centers of the north, that truancy is in several of them, at present, an insoluble problem. No m of child-labor legislation can be regarded as effective which does not face and deal with these facts. The evolution of the vacation school and camp promises strong re - inforcement of the child-labor laws; which are now seriously weakened by the fact that the long vacation leaves idle upon the streets children whom employers covet by reason of the low price of their labor, while parents, gredy for the children's earnings and anxious lest the children </seg>
            <seg id="p035">ti be worse for the physique of the school child than being compelled ork during the summer; and the development of the vacation school vacation camp alone seems to promise a satisfactory solution of the lem of the vacation of the city child of the working class. The Community Effective child-labor legislation imposes upon the community many duties, among which are ( 1 ) maintaining officials — men and women — school-attendance officers, health officers, and factory inspectors, all of whom need (a) salary and traveling expenses, (b) access at all resonable times to the places where children are employed, (c) power to prosecute all violations of the statutes affecting working children, (d) tenure of office so effectively assured that they n&lt;?ed not fear removal from office in consequence of prosecut - ing powerful offenders; (2) maintaining schools in which to educate the children who are prohibited from working; (3) maintaining vital statistics, especially birth records, such that real age of native children may be readily ascertained; (4) maintaining provision for the adequate relief of dependent fami - lies in which the children are not yet of legal age for begin - ning work. More important, however, than the enactment of the foregoing pro - visions is the maintenance in the community of a persistent, lively interest in the enforcement of the child-labor statutes. Without such interest, judges do not enforce penalties against offending parents and employers; inspectors become discouraged and demoralized; or faithful officers are removed because they have no organized backing, while some group of powerful industries clamors that the law is injuring its interest. Well - meaning employers grow careless, infractions become the rule, and workingmen form the habit of thinking that laws inimical to their interest are enforced, while those framed in their interest are broken with im- IUpon parents there presses incessant poverty, urging them to seek )rt unities for wage-earning, even for the youngest children; and upon employers presses incessant competition, urging tbem to reduce the roll by all means, fair or foul. No law enforces itself ;and no officials enforce a law which depends upon them alone. It is only when they consciously the agents of the will of the people that they can make law really protect the children effectively.* *A portion of this introduction was printed in the Annals of the American A trad emy of Political and Social Science for May 1908. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Changes During 1904. ■During the year 1904 statutes were enacted by Massachusetts, Ken - y, New Jersey and Vermont. I Massachusetts extended to the month of December the restriction of hours of labor of women and children which formerly applied only to en months of the jnear. It will henceforth be illegal to employ any lan or minor under eighteen years of age longer than ten hours in day or fifty-eight hours in one week at any time during the year. I New Jersey extended to boys under fourteen years of age the pro - :ion which previously applied only to girls. Neither boys or girls now be legally employed in manufacture in New Jersey before the teenth birthday. Unfortuniately, the legislature repealed the statute •h had, since 1892, prohibited the employment at night of children sr eighteen years of age in all manufactures except glassworks, can - es and establishments for preserving perishable fruits. Children teen years of age may, therefore, be employed throughout the night ictories in New Jersey. » Kentucky extended to the entire school year, not less than five months, term of compulsory attendance at school for children under fourteen s of age. I Vermont enacted a new law, embodying some of the best features le laws of Illinois and Massachusetts. This is the first eastern state iopt the Illinois restriction upon the hours of labor of children under ?en; not more than eight hours in one day, nor more than forty-eight s in one week, nor after 7 p. m., nor before 7 a. m. The requirements [assachusetts regarding the age and schooling certificate have been ap - imately followed, with the addition of the passport for verification ge. The age limit has been raised only to twelve years, but no child sr flften may be employed while the public schools are in session. — &gt;m Handbook 1905 issued by National Consumers' League.) </seg>
            <seg id="p037">SUMMARY OF STATE LAWS (The following pages are devoted to an analysis of the various form* of child-labor legislation in the several stal SCHEDULE A— AGE LIMIT. iThe Age Below Which Child Labor is Prohibited varies from si\ en years. Nln have no restriction whatever. The number •mployments prohibite.l ries greatly — from all emplo&gt; Qg school hours to mine work 01 "es, factories and mines are places of employment usually - ral states in&lt; laundries, telegraph and telephone offices, and other lines of work rded as dangerous for children, including street trades. ! states which prohibit child labor in several occupations have more ;tive legislation than those which prohibit it in only one or two. i though the age limit be the same. Group I. — Age Limit for Employment, 16 Years Illinois — In dangerous occupations specified by law. (See Sched 1 : K Dangerous Occupations), lsylvania — In mines. Texas — In any mine, distillery or brewery. Group 11. — Age Limit for Employment, 14 Years. (Children may not be employed under the age of fourth In factories, stores or in any of the following places of employment: offices, laundries, hotels, theatres, bowling alleys, telephone or mes - senger offices— Conncticut, Illinois, Indiana, Massac): gan, Minnesota (except in vacations!. Nebraska (except in vacation, or unless certificate of twenty weeks' school attendance is presented). New York, Ohio (15 years in mines), 0 xcept children over 12 "necessarily employer &gt;, Wisconsin (children orer 12 may work in vacation in places not factor^ fn factories — Arkansas (if illiterate), Colorado, Kentucky (exemi may be granted for po\ county judge), Louisiana (apph to girls), Maryland (except In canning industries an&lt;i 'o or - phans or children of wrdowed mothers or invalid fathers), Minnesota, Missouri, New Jersey, Tennessee, Texas (if lllitera- In mines — Alabama, Arkansas. Colorado, Idaho, Illinois. Indiana, Ken - tucky, Minnesota, Mont Oregon, Ten - nessee, Utah, Washington, Wyoming. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">4. — In all employment during school hours — Colorado, Connecticut, Illi - nois, Massachusetts, Minnesota (except children "necessarily em - ployed"), Montana (to 16 years, unless studies enumerated in school law have been successfully completed), New Hampshire (to 16 years). New York, North Dakota (except when employed by parent or guar - dian or otherwise "necessarily employed"), Ohio (16 years, unless studies enumerated in school law have been successfully completed), Oregon, South Dakota (except when employed by parent or guardian and except when school requirement has been complied with), Ver - mont (to 15 years), Wisconsin. Group III. — Age Limit for Employment, 13 Years. In stores (or) factories — Pennsylvania (includes offices and laundries). Rhode Island (except in vacations). Group IV. — Age Limit for Employment, 12 Years. 1. — In stores or factories — California, Maine. In factories — Alabama (except orphans and children between 10 and are of widowed mothers or invalid fathers), Arkansas (excep - tions same as Alabama), Louisiana (applicable to boys), New Hamp - shire, North Carolina, North Dakota, Rhode Island, Texas (if able to read and write; 16 years in mines and breweries), Virginia, West Virginia. 3. — In mines — Iowa, Kansas (coal mines), Missouri, North Carolina, Vir - ginia, West Virginia. Group V. — Age Limit for Employment, 11 Years. In factories or mines — South Carolina (except children "necessarily em- ployed"), after May 1, 1905, the age limit will be 12 years). Group VI. — Age Limit for Employment, 10 Years. 1. — In stores or factories — Nebraska. tn factories — Alabama (orphans or children of widowed mothers or disabled fathers), Arkansas (orphans or children of widowed mothers or disabled fathers). Group VII. — Miscellaneous Age Limitations. Alaska — Under 21 may not be employed in bar-rooms. Florida — Under 15 may not be employed more than 60 days without con - sent of legal guardian. Mississippi — Under 21 boys, under 18 girls, similar to Florida. Group VIII.— No Age Limit, Arizona, Delaware, District of Columbia, Georgia, Hawaii, Idaho, Indian Territory, Maryland (applying to 20 counties, all canneries, and all children of widowed mothers and disabled fathers), Nevada, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Carolina (applying in June, July and August to all children who have attended school four months in the year). </seg>
            <seg id="p039">SCHEDULE B— HOURS OF LABOR. I Work at Night it Specially Prohibited in only 17 State*.— One state, bama, authorizes night work for children between thirteen and sixteen rs of age by restricting such night work to forty-eight hours in the ■k. Thirty-five states fail to prohibit work at night and vary widely heir usage. For instance, Connecticut enforces her restriction as to rs of labor by day, and usage prevents the employment of children at tit in factories and stores. In Pennsylvania, on the contrary, usage irds no protection; girls of thirteen may and do work the full maxi - m of ten hours, from 7:30 in the evening to G:00 in the morning. The :e of Washington expressly declares that "the hours of work may ire arranged as to permit the employment of females at any time, so t they shall not work more than ten hours in the twenty-four." Ob - isly, children cannot have certain immunity from night work, unless hours are positively stated between which it is unlawful to employ I Those states which fail to restrict the hours of labor allowed in one ■k !io well as in one day, invite the possibility of seven days' labor. Washington, for example, women and girls may not only work ten :rs at night, they may do this every night, including Sunday. In the last Group (V.) are comprised those states which do not limit the hours of labor at all, although they do restrict children's labor in various other ways, from Nebraska, for instance, which forbids all work to children under the age of 10 years, to Alaska, which prescribes an age limit only for minors employed in bar-rooms. Group 1.— Work at Night Prohibited, rn C p. m. — 7 a. m.— Michigan, children under 1C; Virginia, children under 14. From C p. m. — C a. m. — Texas, children under 14. rn 7 p. m. — C a. m. — Ohio, gir's under 18, boys under 1G; Illinois, child - ren under 1G; Minnesota, children under 1G; Oregon, children under 1C; Arkansas, children under 14: Alabama, children under 13. From 7 p. m. — 7 a. m. — Vermont, children under 1G. From 8 p. m. — G a. m. — South Carolina, children und&lt; From 8 p. m. — 5 a. m.— Washington, children under 16 in From 9 p. m. — 6 a m. — Wisconsin, children under 16. From 9 p. m. — G a. m. — New York, in factories: All women and children under 18. From 10 p. m. — 7 a. m. — New York, in commerce: Women under 21 and boys under 16. After 10 p. m. — New York, newsboys under 14 in New York City and Buf - falo. After 10 p. m. — 6 a. m. — Massachusetts, women and minors in manu- </seg>
            <seg id="p040">tm. — 6 a. m. — Indiana, women and girls In factories; Nebraska, women and girls. Group II. — Work at Night Authorized Ilt is restricted to a specified number of hours at night and to &amp; ifled number of hours by day. Night Restriction — 18 hours in one week — Alabama, children between 13 and 16. Day Restriction — 66 hours In one week — Alabama, children between 3 3 and 16. Group III.— Work Restricted by the Day and by the Week. It is restricted to a specified number of hours in the 24, and to a specified number of hours in one week. 8 in 24 — 48 in one week — Illinois, minors under 16; Vermont, minors under 16. £ in 24 — 54 in one week — New York, minors under 16 in commerce. 10 in 24 — 60 in one week — New York, women between 16 and 21 in com- merce. 9 in 24 — New York, minors under 16 in factories. 10 in 24 — 60 in one week — New York, women and minors under 18 in factories. ti 24 — 58 in one week — Massachusetts; women and minors under 18; Rhode Island, women and minors under 18. E24 — 54 in one week — California, minors under 18. 24 — 55 in one week — New Jersey, minors under 18. 24 — 55 in one week — Ohio, boys under 16, girls under 18. 24 — 60 in one week — Louisiana, women and minors under 18; New Hampshire, women and minors under 18. E24 — 60 in one week — Connecticut, women and minors under 16. 24 — 60 in one week — Michigan, boys under 18, girls under 21. 24 — 60 in one week — Indiana, girls under 18, boys under 1C; Maine, girls under 18, boys under 16. ■i 24 — 60 In one week — Minnesota, minors under 16; Wisconsin, min - ors under 16; Oregon, minors under 16. E24 — 60 in one week — Arkansas, minors under 14. 24 — 66 in one week — North Carolina, minors under 18. 24 — 60 in one week — Pennsylvania, women and minors. Group IV.— Work Restricted by the Day. It is restricted to a specified number of hours in the 24, but Is not restricted to a specified number of hours in one week. B24 — Arizona, Montana, Missouri, Utah, all persons in mines. 24 — Colorado, minors under 16. 10 in 24 — North Dakota, South Dakota, women and minors under 18. 10 in 24 — Washington, women and girls. 10 in 24 — Maryland, children under 16. 10 in 24 — Virginia, minors under 14. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Group V. — No Time Limit. Ika, Delaware, District of Columbia, Florida, Georgia, Hawaii, Idaho, Indian Territory, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Maryland (applying counties, all canneries and all children of widowed mothers and disabled fathers), Mississippi, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, Okla - homa, South Carolina (apply in June, July and August to all children who have attended school 4 months in the year), Tennesee, v. ington, West Virginia, Wyoming. SCHEDULE C— NO AGE OR TIME LIMIT BY DAY OR NIGHT. No restriction is placed upon the age for beginning work and the hours of labor of children in the District of Columbia and in eight states and territories. In some of these, it is true, there is little manufacture involving the labor of children, but in others industries are highly de - veloped and the consequent demand for child labor is not opposed by any restrictions. South Carolina and Maryland have laws protecting certain classes of children, but both of these states permit exemptions of an unusually wholesale character. Maryland explicitly leaving the children unprotected in canneries, an industry in which the hou: labor inevitably tend to become irregular and exhausting long. KThe pressure of competition of the cotton mills of Georgia and ~ jlina upon mills in northern states is frequently urged as a reason deferring much needed legislation in such states, until Georgia takes initial step in the direction of restricting child labor, and South Caro - increases her requirements. t Bills defining an age limit and hours of labor for children are pend - in the District of Columbia and Delaware. The prominence of the rict of Columbia as containing the capital of the nation, and the that many children are employed there as messengers and in the H trades, make it particularly desirable that it should speedily be jved from the list of states, which have neither an age nor a time t in the employment of children. Delaware, District of Columbia, Georgia, Hawaii, Idaho, Indian Territory, Maryland (applying to 20 counties, to all canneries, and to all children of widowed mothers or disabled fathers), Nevada, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Carolina (applying in June, July and August to all children who have attended school for 4 months in the year). SCHEDULE D— COMPULSORY SCHOOL ATTENDANCE. In respect to compulsory attendance laws, the points to be noted are: 1. The age to which attendance is required (which varies from six- teen to twelve years). ■ 2. The length of the annual period of attendance (which varies from whole school year to eight weeks). The most effective means of preventing the illegal employment of children is compulsory school attendance throughout the entire period </seg>
            <seg id="p042">during which employment is prohibited. Twenty-one states now have this requirement. If the law prohibits children from working under a certain age, it should require them to be in school to that age, during the entire school term of each year. In states where children under the legal age of employment are not obliged to be in school all the year, complications in the enforcement of the child labor law invariably arise, because it : s easy for parent.) to send their children to work under the legal age. Exemptions from the compulsory education laws are granted in many states for one or more of the following reasons: Physical or mental disability. Private Instruction. Distance from school (over two to three miles) Poverty. In a few states free books, free clothing or other aids are granted on account Of poverty. Group I. — Attendance Compulsory to 16, if Unemployed. Irado — Entire school year (exemptions granted to children over 14 it "necessarily employed," or if they have completed the eighth grade; illiterates under 16 must attend Jay or night school, whether em - ployed or not). Connecticut — Entire school year, 36 weeks Maryland — Entire school year. Massachusetts — Entire school year, at least ICO days (children over 14 may work, provided they attend night school). Biesota — Entire school year 12 weeks at least 6 to be consecutive, tana — Entire school year (illiterates under 1C must attend day school, K whether employed or not). Mexico — 12 weeks. I York — Entire school year between October and June (children over 14 who can read and write English may work, provided they have regularly attended school 130 days during the previous school year, receiving instruction in reading, spelling, writing, English grammar and geography, and are familiar with the fundamental operations of arithmetic, including fractions). Ohio — Entire school year. Insylvania — Entire school year (unless local school board votes to accept 70 per cent of school year. Children may work after 13th birthday). ■ main — Entire schcnl year. Wyoming — 12 weeks. Group II. — Attendance Compulsory to 15, Kansas — Entire school year (children over 14 who can read and write English and are "necessarily employed," need attend school only S weeks annually). Maine — Entire school year. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Michigan — Four months in rural districts; entire school year in cities (in cities exemptions may be granted by board of education to chil - dren over 14). Nebraska — Two-thirds of entire school year (exemptions may be granted to children over 14 "necessarily employed." Attendance at night school may be required). Kin — Entire school year (if unemployed), e Island — Entire school year (if unemployed) ont — Entire school year, 160 days. Washington — 24 weeks. Group III. — Attendance Compulsory to 14. Arizona — 12 weeks. Arkansas — 12 weeks, 6 to be consecutive. California — 5 months, IS weeks to be consecutive. Colorado — Entire school year. (To 16, unless employed). Connecticut — Entire school year. Attendance required to 16, if school committee decides child of 14 has not sufficient schooling to be em - ployed. District of Columbia — 12 weeks, 6 to be. consecutive. Idaho — 12 weeks, 8 to be consecutive Illinois — Entire school year, at least 110 days Indiana — Entire school year. Iowa — 12 weeks. Kentucky — Entire school year, at least 5 months Massachusetts — Entire school year (to 16, unless employed). »iesota — Entire school year (to 16, if unemployed, exemptions may be granted to children "necessarily and lawfully employed"). Montana — Entire school year, at least 16 weeks (to 16, unless employed). Nevada — 16 weeks, at least 8 to be consecutive-. New Hampshire — Entire school year (to 16, if illiterate). New Jersey — Entire school year. New Mexico — 12 weeks (to 16, unless employed) ■■ York — Entire school year (between October and June. To 16, unless employed). North Dakota — Entire school year (exemptions may be granted to children "necessarily employed"). Ohio — Entire school year, not less than 24 weeks. (To 16, unless em - ployed). Oregon — Entire school year. South Dakota — 12 weeks. Utah — 20 weeks. West Virginia — 16 weeks. Wisconsin — Entire school year, 8 months (to 16, If not employed). Group IV. — Attendance Compulsory to 13. Pennsylvania — Entire school year (to 16, unless employed). Rhode Island — Entire school year (to 15, unless employed; exemptions </seg>
            <seg id="p044">may be granted children over 12 "necessarily employed"). Group V. — Attendance Compulsory to 12. Maryland — Entire school year (to 16, unless employed; applies only to city of Baltimore). *Group VI. — Xo Attendance Laws Alabama Alaska Missouri North Carolina Delaware Florida Oklahoma South Carolina Georgia Tennessee Louisiana Mississippi Texas Virginia SCHEDULE E — EDUCATIONAL TEST FOR CHILDREN SEEKING EMPLOYMENT (Children under the ages specified may not be employed unless they meet the requirements indicated). An Educational Test before the child can be legally employed is found in states having the most advanced child-labor legislation. This test is usually ability to read and write, or a certain amount of school attendance, or both. The states having this test vary as to the age to which it is enforced, and as to the number of employments specified. The age ranges downward from twenty-one years (Massachusetts). The number of employments affected varies from all employments (Massachusetts) to mines only. &lt;.r&gt;. up I. — Children must be Able to Read and Write and must Attend tiool Before or During Employment (Night Schools are Usually Pennitted to Illiterates Employed During the Day). Colorado — Required to 16 years. Connecticut — to 16 years. Kansas — to 16 years (in coal mines) Illinois — to 16 years. Maryland — to 16 years. Massachusetts — through minority, if illiterate resota — to 16 years (exemptions may be granted to children "neces- Barily and lawfully employed"). Montana — to 14 years. B Hampshire — to 16 years (through minority, if illiterate). York — to 16 years (boys between 14 and 16 employed in New York City and Buffalo must show certificates of graduation from elementary school or must attend night school 6 hours a week during 16 weeks). Ohio — to 14 years. Ksylvania — to 16 years, e Island — to 13 years. South Carolina — Children may be employed at any age, in vacation </seg>
            <seg id="p045">if they present certificates showing school attendance for 4 months daring the year, and ability to read and write. Washington — to 15 years. GroupII. — Children must be Able to Read and Write Before Being Employed. Ensas — to 16 years (mines only), ina — to 16 years (except in vacations), igan — to 16 years. Missouri — to 14 years (mines only). Btana — to 16 years (for employment during school hours), i — to 16 years. Oregon — to 16 years. Texas — to 16 years (exemptions may be granted to children between 12 and 14 "necessarily employed"!. Vermont — to 14 years (for employment during school hours) Group III. — School Attendance Only Required. Louisiana — to 14 years Ee — to 15 years aska — to 14 years 4 Dakota — to 14 years l Dakota — to 14 years Vermont — to 15 years (in mills and factories ) . Group IV. — Xo Educational Test SCHEDULE F — PROOF OF AGE: CERTIFICATES OF AGE OR SCHOOLING. tThe importance of obtaining trustworthy proof of age is recog - [ in but few states. Twenty-two states require no proof of age at The mere affidavit of parent or guardian is often accepted, un - orted by futher proof. School records are also used for veriflea - of age, but the most relable sources of information are transcripts rth certificates, certificates of baptism, or passports. Alabama — Required for children over 12, affidavit of parent or guard- Alabama Mississippi Alaska Nevada Arizona New Jersey California New Mexico Delaware North Carolini District of Columbia Oklahoma Florida Tennessee Georgia Hawaii ah Virginia Idaho West Virginia Iowa Wisconsin Kentucky Wyoming </seg>
            <seg id="p046">ian, stating age and date of birth. Arkansas — Same as Alabama; for children under 14, in addition certi - ficate of school attendance. California — Required for children under 16, certificates stating age and place of birth, verified by parent or guardian or by minor himself. Connecticut — Required for children between 14 and 16, certificate of age, signed by the registrar of births, marriages and deaths, or by a teacher of the school which child last attended. If the child was not born in the United States and has not attended school in this state, one of the parents or the guardian of the child shall have the date of the birth of the child recorded by the registrar of births, marriages, and deaths, or by the town clerk, where such parent or guardian resides. When applying for a record of the date of birth the parent or guardian shall state under oath to said registrar or town clerk the date and place of birth of the child, and said registrar or town clerk shall demand of the parent or guardian any family records, passport or other paper showing the age of the child. Illinois — Required for children between 14 and 16 years, age and school certificate, approved by the superintendent of schools or by a person authorized by him in writing. An age and school certificate shall not be approved unless satisfactory evidence is furnished by the last school census, the certificate of birth or baptism of such child, the register of birth of such child with a town or city clerk, or by the records of the public or paro - chial schools, that such child is of the age stated in the certificate: Provided. That in cases arising wherein the above proof is not ob - tainable, the parent or guardian of the child shall make oath be - fore the juvenile or county court as to the age of such child, and the court may issue to such child an age certificate as sworn to. lie age and school certificate of a child under sixteen years of age shall not be approved and signed until he presents to the person authorized to approve and sign the same, a school attendance certificate, as prescribed, duly filled out and signed. A duplicate of such age and school certificate shall be filled out and shall be forwarded to the state factory Inspector's office. The employment and the age and school certificate shall be separately printed and shall be filled out signed and held or surrendered as indicated in prescribed forms. Register must be kept recording name, age and place of residence. rna — Required for children between 14 and 16 years, affidavit by parent or guardian or by minor himself, certifying date and place of birth. ras — Required for children between 12 and 16, certificate of school attendance during at least 3 months in the year from a school teacher (for employment in coal mines). Kentucky — Required for children under 14, certificate of age sworn to </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 by parent or guardian, unless employer shall know the age of the child. r?iana — Required for children under 14, certificate of school at - tendance during at least 4 months of the year preceding employ - ment, signed by the director of the school district or principal of a private or public school. re — Required for children under 16, certificate of age and place of birlh signed by school authorities; for children under 15, in addi - tion, certificate of amount of school attendance during year pre - ceding employment (16 weeks required). rland — Required for children under 16, certificate stating that child is more than 12 years of age, signed by the principal or head teacher of the school last attended and a like certificate of parent or guardian. Massachusetts — Required for children under 16, age and schooling certificate approved by the superintendent of schools or by a per - son authorized in writing by him or by the school committee. Employers must keep two complete lists of all minors employed under 16, one on file and one conspicuously posted near principal entrance of the building in which such children are employed, and he must also keep on file and send to superintendent of schools or to the school committee, a complete list of the names of all minors employed who cannot read at sight or write legibly simple sentences in the English language. An age and schooling certi - ficate shall not be approved unless satisfactory evidence is furnish - ed by the last school census, the certificate of birth or baptism of such minor, or the register of birth of such minor with a city or town clerk, that such minor is of the age stated in the certificate ex - cept that other evidence may be accepted in case the superinten - ent or other person authorized by the school committee, decides that neither the last school census, nor the certificate of birth or baptism, nor the register of birth is available for the purpose. The age and schooling certificate of a minor under 1G years of age shall not be approved and signed until he presents to the person who is authorized to approve and sign it an employment ticket duly filled out and signed. A duplicate of each age and schooling cer - tificate shall be filled out and shall be kept on file by the school committee. The employment ticket and the age and schooling certificate shall be separately printed, and shall be filled out, signed and held or surrendered, as indicated in forms prescribed. rigan — Required for children under 16, certificate sworn to by par - ent or guardian or by child himself, stating that child can read and write and giving age, date and place of birth. Register must be kept recording name, birthplace, age and place of residence. Kesota — Required for children under 16, employment certificate signed by the superintendent of schools or by some person author- </seg>
            <seg id="p048">tain a statement of the name, birthplace, date of birth and age of child at date of statement. This statement shall be signed and acknowledged under oath or affirmation before the person author - ized to issue the certificate. The certificate shall also contain a statement or certificate by the officer issuing the same that the child can read at sight and write legibly simple sentences in the English language, or that said child, if unable so to read and write, is regularly attending a day or evening school, or has been ex - cused by the school board, and that if under the age required by law for the attendance of all children at school said child has in the year next preceding the issuing of said certificate attended school as required by law. The statement in the certificate giving birthplace and age of child shall be signed by the father if living, or by the mother, or by the child himself. rtana — Required for children under 16, certificate approved by superintendent of schools or by person authorized by him, upon receiving satisfactory proof of age and of completion of required studies. raska — Required for children under 16, certificate stating age, place if birth and residence; for children under 14, in addition, certificate of school attendance during year next preceding employment, signed by president and secretary of school board of child's school distn. I Hampshire — Required for children under 16, statement of age, sworn to by parent or guardian before superintendent of schools or some person authorized by school board. Also certificate from superintendent of schools or authorized person that child can read at sight and legibly write simple sentences in the English lang - uage. New Jersey — Required for children under 16, I. Native born. Affidavit of parent or guardian stating name of child, residence, place and date of birth, name of father and maiden name of mother, church attended, if any, school last attended, if child was baptized, name and location of church where baptized. There must accompany affidavit, transcript of the record of the child's birth, or if it can - not be obtained, and child was baptized, a certified copy of the baptismal record. II. Foreign born children. Same affidavit as above, with an additional statement that child named in the affidavit is the same mentioned and described in the passport under which child was admitted to this country. A true copy of the passport must in all cases be attached to the affidavit. III. Other children. Commissioner of labor shall have power to issue permits of employment to children upon the production of evidence of the child's age satisfactory to him; provided, that he shall first be satisfied that the child cannot obtain a transcript of birth record, a baptismal certificate or passport. New York — Required for children under 16, employment certificate </seg>
            <seg id="p049">ssued by the commissioner of health or the executive officer of the oard or department of health of the city, town or Tillage where uch child resides or is to be employed, or by such other officer hereof as may be designated by such board, department or com - missioner for that purpose, upon the application of the parent, uardian or custodian of the child desiring such employment, uch officer shall not issue such certificate until he has rec« - xamined, approved and filed the following papers duly exec; 1) The school record of such child properly filled out and signed 8 provided in this article. ( 2 I A passport or duly attested trans - ript of the certificate of birth, or baptism or other religious record, showing the date and place of birth of such child. A duly ttested transcript of the birth certificate filed according to law with a registrar of vital statistics, or other officer charged with le duty of recording births shall be conclusive evidence of the ge of such child. (3) The affidavit of the parent, guardian or cus - odian of the child, which shall be required, however, only in case uch last mentioned transcript of the certificate of birth be not pro - uced and filed, showing the place and date of birth of such child; which affidavit must be taken before the officer issuing the em - loyment certificate, who is hereby authorized and required to ad- tinister such oaths and who shall not demand or receive a fee erefore. Such employment certificate shall not be issued until such child shall further have personally appeared before and been examined by the officer Issuing the certificate, and until such officer shall, after mak - ing such examination, sign and file in his office a statement that the child can read and legibly write simple sentences in the English language and that in his opinion the child is fourteen years of age or upwards and has reached the normal development of a child of its age and is in sound health and is physically able to perform the work which it intends to do. In doubtful cases such ph fitness shall be determined by a medical officer of the board or department of health. Every such employment certificate shall be signed, in the presence of the officer issuing the sam - in whose name it is issued. The school record required by this article shall be signed by the prin - cipal or chief executive officer of the school which such child has attended and shall be furnished on demand to a child entitled thereto or to the board, department or commissioner of health. It shall contain a statement certifying that the child has regularly attended the public schools, or schools equivalent thereto, or par - ochial schools for not less than one hundred and thirty days dur - ing the school year previous to his arriving at the age of fourteen years or during the year previous to applying for such school record and is able to read and write simple sentences in the English lan - guage, has received during such period instruction in reading. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">spelling, writing, English grammar and geography and is familiar with the fundamental operations of arithmetic up to and including fractions. Such school record shall also give the age and resi- dence of the child as shown on the records of the school and the name of its parents or guardian or custodian. ri Carolina — Required for children under 12, written statement of age of parent or guardian. ri Dakota— Certificate of school attendance, signed by the superin - tendent of schools, or if there is none, by the clerk of the school board. Ohio — Required for children under 18, register to be kept recording name, birthplace, age and place of residence. ran — Required for children under 16, affidavit of parent or guardian stating name, date and place of birth and school attended by child. rsylvania — Required for children under 16. affidavit of parent or guardian stating age, date and place of birth. If child has no par - ent or guardian, affidavit shall be made by the child. In order to receive certificate, child must be able to read and write the English language and must have attended school as required by law. Rhode Island— Required to 15, certificate made under direction of the school committee stating name, place of birth name and residence of guardian. South Carolina — Required for children under 12, affidavit of parent or guardian stating age of child. ressee — Required for children under 14, sworn statement of age made by parent or guardian, unless age of child is known by em - ployer. Vermont — Required for children under 16, age and schooling certificate approved by the superintendent of schools, or by a person author - ized by him or by the board of school directors. Employers must keep two complete lists of all minors employed under 16 years, one on file and one conspicuously posted near the principal entrance of the building in which such minors are employed, and they must also keep on file and send to the superintendent of schools or the board of school directors the names of all the minors under 16, employed who cannot read at sight and write legibly simple sen - tences in the English language. An age and schooling certificate shall not be approved unless satisfactory evidence is furnished by the duly attested transcript of the certificate of birth or baptism of such child, or other religious record, or register of birth of such child with a town or city clerk, that such child is of the age stated in the certificate, or in a transcript of its passport. The age and schooling certificate of a child under 16, shall not be approved and signed until he presents to the person authorized to approve and sign the same, an employment ticket as prescribed, duly filled out signed A duplicate of each age and schooling certificate shall be </seg>
            <seg id="p051">filled out and kept on file by the board of school directors. The employment ticket and the age schooling certificate shall be sepa - rately printed and shall be filled out, signed, held or surrendered as indicated in prescribed forms. West Virginia — Required for boys over 12, employed in coal mines in cases of doubt as to age, affidavit of parent or guardian. Wisconsin — Required for children under 16, affidavit by parent or guardian or if not living, by the child, stating name, date and place of birth, and name and place of school attended. Register must be kept recording name, age, date of birth and place of residence. SCHEDULE G — DANGEROUS OCCUPATIONS. tThe operation of elevators or of dangerous machinery by minors r certain ages is prohibited in twelve states. A large group of s prohibit occupations dangerous to health or morals: chiefly the oyment of children where liquors are sold, rope-walking and kin - exhibitions. This general provision is effective principally in case image suits, following upon accidents to minors. t Illinois and Ohio lead all the states in specially prohibiting the loyment of children under sixteen years In a list of manufactures in - ing fourteen different kinds of dangerous machinery, and in forbid - the employment of children under sixteen years in three special ufactures — paints or colors, and compositions needing acids, in 111 - i; matches and compositions needing acids, in Ohio. In Massa - etts, the state board of health is authorized to investigate and pro - : such manufacture of acids for minors under eighteen. In New c boys under IS. and all women are prohibited from operating ry, emery polishing, or buffing wheels. Group I. — Operation of Elevators is Prohibited. Illinois — to 16 years. Indiana — to 18 years. Massachusetts — to 16 years; for any elevator running at a speed of more than 100 feet a minute, to 18 years. Minnesota — to 16 years; for elevators running at a speed of more than 200 feet a minute, to 18 years. New York — to 15 years; for any elevator running at a speed of more than 200 feet a minute, to 18 years. Ohio — to 16 years. Pennsylvania — to 14 years. Wisconsin — to 16 yeara Group II.— Operating or Cleaning of Dangerous Machinery is Pro- hibited. Illinois — to 16 years; 14 different machines specified. (See Standard Eild Labor Law, Sec. 11, p. 37). ma — boys to 16 years; girla to 18. — boys to 16 years; girls to 18. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Louisiana — to 12 years. , Massachusetts — to 14 years. Michigan— boys to 18; girls to 21 New Jersey — to 16 years. New York — boys to 18; girls to 21 years. Ohio — to 16 years, 14 different kinds of machinery specified. Pennsylvania — to 16 years. Group III. — Specified Manufactures are Prohibited. r)is — to 16 years in manufacture of paints, colors or white lead, or compositions needing acids. (See Standard Child Labor Law, Sec. 11, p. 37). Ohio — to 16 years in manufacture of matches, paints, colors or white lead, or compositions needing acids. Massachusetts — to 18 years in manufacture of acids (upon complaint and after investigation by state board of health). fYork — to 18 years for boys, and total prohibition for women, in operation of emery, tripoli, rouge, corrundum, stone carborundum, or any abrasive^ or emery polishing or buffing wheel, where articles of the baser metals or of iridium are manufactured. Group IV. — Employment Dangerous to Health or Morals is More or Leas Completely Prohibited. California. Montana Colorado New Hampshire Connecticut New Jersey Deleware New York District of Columbia Ohio Georgia Pennsylvania Illinois Rhode Island Indiana South Dakota Kansas Texas Kentucky Vermont Maryland Virginia Massachusetts West Virginia Michigan Wisconsin Missouri Wyoming riEDULE H — EXEMPTIONS FROM THE CHILD LABOR LAWd. The most important exemptions from the child labor laws allowing work under age have been embodied in the schedules on the age limit. (Schedule A). There remain to be noted the officials authorized to grant such exemptions, in so far as they are specified in the laws, and the reasons for granting such exemptions. Exemptions for work over time are allowed for various reasons In thirteen different states. A. — WORK IS ALLOWED OVER TIME. I. — On Saturdays or for Certain Days Preceding Christmas in: Colorado, where children under 16 may work more than 8 hours </seg>
            <seg id="p053">in the day, in the week before and following Christmas Day. New York, where persons of 16 years and upward may work in mercantile establishments more than 10 hours a day on Saturdays, provided that the total number of hours of labor in a week of any such person does not exceed GO; such persons may also work more than 10 hours a day between the 15th day of December and the following first day of January. Minnesota, where children not less than 14 years of age may be employed in mercantile establishments on Saturdays and tor 10 days each year before Christmas until 10 in the evening; provided that this permission is not so construed as to permit such children to work more than 10 hours in any one day or over 60 hours in any one week. II. — For the purpose of making up lost time due to some accident of breakdown in the machinery in: New Hampshire, where women and children under 18 may be employed for this purpose more than 10 hours in a day. t South Carolina, where children under 12 (whose labor is permiss - only till May, 1905, unless they are allowed to work because they children of widows or of disabled fathers or are orphans), may be loyed for this purpose after 8 P. M., provided that under no cir - stances a child below 12 years of age shall work later than 9 P. M. III. — When a different apportionment of the hours of labor is made for the sole purpose of making a shorter day's work for one day in the week in: tN'ew York, where women, and boys between 16 and 18 years, may in factories more than 10 hours in one day in order to make a er workday on the last day of the week; and women between II 21 may work more than 10 hours in any one day in mercantile lishments for the same purpose, provided that they do not work than 60 hours in any one week. I Indiana, where for the same purpose boys under 16 and girls under may work more than 60 hours in one week or 10 hours in one day: not more hours in any one week than would make an average of hours per day for the whole number of days which such persons ivork during such week. -Either (a) when a different apportionment of hoars is made for the sole purpose of making a shorter workday for one day of the week, or (b) when it is necessary to make re- pairs to prevent the interruption of the ordinary running of the establish - ment, in California where minors under 18 may work more than 9 hours in one day, but in no case must the hours of labor exceed 54 hours in the week. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Maine, where women and boys under 16 may work more than 10 hours in a day, but in no case must the hours of labor exceed 60 hours in the week. New Hampshire, where women and minors under 18 may be em ployed more than 10 hours a day. Rhode Island, where women and minors under 16 may work more than 58 hours in one week and 10 hours in one day. Connecticut, where women and minors under 16 may work more than 10 hours in one day, for these two causes. t Michigan, where women under 21 and boys under 18 may be em - id more than 60 hours in one week for the second cause (b), and e such persons may be employed more than 10 hours in any one for the first cause (a). B. — Work is Allowed Under Age; Authorities for Granting Exemptions r'ado — Exemptions for children between 14 and 16 years, granted by the Judge of the county court of the county in which the child resides, if it would be, in the opinion of said Judge, for the child's best interest to be so employed. rucky — For children under 14, granted on account of poverty by the county Judge, of the county in which the child resides, sub - ject to the approval of the county Attorney, in the event of any complaint. Minnesota — For children under 14 and illiterates under 16, granted on account of poverty by the school board or board of school trustees. ri Dakota — For children under 14 years, granted on account of poverty by the school board of the district or by the board of edu - cation of the city or village. rle Island — For children over 12 years, granted on account of pov - erty by authority of the school committee upon the written recom - mendation of the overseer of the poor. ri Carolina — For children under 11 years^ granted on account of poverty provided that the guardian of such children shall furnish an affidavit duly sworn to before the magistrate or clerk of court of the county, stating the need of the child's support, and provided that the officer before whom the affidavit is subscribed shall en - dorse upon the back thereof his approval and consent. Texas — For illiterates under 14, whose parents are incapacitated to sup - port them. riington — For children under 14, granted on account of poverty by any superior court Judge living within the residence district of any such child, for any occupation not in his opinion dangerous to the health or morals of such child. Wisconsin — For children over 12 years, in vacation, granted on account of poverty by the county Judge of the county in which the child resides, or by the commissioner of labor, or by any factory inspector </seg>
            <seg id="p055">» IILKEAl' OF LABOR SCHEDULE I — ENFORCEMENT I. THE CHILD LABOR LAWS. tThe states provide in various ways for the enforcement of the labor laws. Five states have made no provision for enforcement. iolation of the law may be prosecuted by the County Attorn&gt; - ilaint is made to him by any interested person. Some of the states entirely given over to the school authorities the enforcement of labor laws, and in many others the truant officers as well as the ry inspectors are authorized to enter places of employment, to de - 1 certificates of age or schooling, to make arrests and to enter rut ions for violation through the Prosecuting Attorn- In seven states Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, New Jersey. New York, Oregon and Wisconsin, the factory- inspectors may demand a cer - tificate of physical fitness from some regular or county physician in the case of young persons who may seem physically unable to perform the labor at which they may be employed and shall have the power to pro - hibit the employment of any minor that cannot obtain such a certificate. In New York the physical fitness of a child apparently 14 years old is determined by a medical officer of the board or the department of OFFICIALS FOR ENFORCEMENT OF THE CHILD LABOR LAW Alabama — No special officials for inspection or enforcement. Arkansas — No special officials for inspection or enforcement Iornia — Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor Statistics^ salary $3,000; Deputy, salary $1,800; Assistants not exceeding 3. salaries not to exceed $4.00 per day, all expenses allowed. Krado — Truant officers appointed and salaries fixed by the board of school directors; vested with police powers and with authorr enter workshops, factories and all other places where children may be employed, in the way of investigation or otherwise. Iiecticut — Agents appointed by the state board of education fo terms of not more than one year, salaries not to exceed $5 a da&gt; including expenses. The school visitors or the town school com mittee in every town, shall once or more in every year examin into the situation of the children employed in all manufacturin establishments, and ascertain whether all the provisions of th law are observed and report all violations to the proper prosecu ing authority. Kb — Chief State Factory Inspector, salary $2,000; Assistant Chief Uary, $1,250, and 18 deputy factory inspectors, salaries $1.' ppropriation to cover all necessary expenses. $10,000. Ea — Chief Inspector of the Department of Inspection, salary $1,800 id actual expenses and a sufficient number of deputies not to ex - ed 5. Iowa — Commisioner of the Bureau of Labor Statistics, salary $1,500 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">and Deputy); and one deputy. Also mayor and chief of police of every city and town. Kansas — Inspector of Mines, salary $2,000 fucky — Labor inspector and one assistant labor inspector, salary $1,200 and $1,000 and traveling expenses. "The grand jury shall have inquisitorial powers to investigate violations of this act and judges of the circuit courts of this state shall specially charge the grand jury at the beginning of each term of court to investigate the violations of this act." rsiana — Superintendent or chief officer of the police in cities; in towns the Mayor shall detail what portion of the police force is nec - essary. (e — Inspector of Factories and Workshops, salary $1,000 and reas - onable expenses; and a sufficient number of assistant deputies, salaries $2 per day and reasonable expenses while engaged in duty. For violatioin of the section requiring childern under 15 to attend school for a required period during employment, school commit - tees and superintendent must report to the county attorney who shall prosecute therefor. Maryland — Attendance officers, not more than 12 to be appointed for the city of Baltimore by the board of school commissioners, their compensation to be paid and fixed by the mayor and the city coun - cil of Baltimore city; and not more than three for any county, ap - pointed by the several boards of county school com missi oners, their compensation fixed and paid by the county commissioners. The police commissioners of Baltimore City shall cause to be made annually a full record of each child between 6 and 16 years ot age in each precinct of the city, the place where and the year and month when such children last attended school, with name and ad - dress of parents, or guardians, and of employers of such children, to be furnished to boards of school commissioners, of Baltimore City. rachusetts — Chief of the District Police, salary $2,500; deputy chief, salary $2,400 and 28 factory inspectors, salaries $1,500 and all necessary traveling expenses. Truant officers appointed by the school committee of every city and town, to receive no fees. Iigan — Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor and Industrial Sta - tistics, salary $2,000 and expenses; Deputy, appointed by the Com - missioner, whose term of office shall continue during the pleasure of such Commissioner, salary $1,500 and expenses and such assis - tants as shall be necessary, at least one of whom shall be a woman. (Total appropriation about $35,000.) [esota — Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor, salary $2,500 and expenses; assistant commissioner and factory inspector, salaries $1,500 and $1,200, and two deputies and two assistant factory in - spectors, salaries $1,000 each and expenses, (total appropriation $12 200) </seg>
            <seg id="p057">r&gt;uri — Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor Inspection and Statis - tics, salary $2,000 and such assistance and expenses as may be essary, not exceeding $2,000 per year. ftana — Truant officers, appointed and salary fixed by the School Board. Vested with police powers, with authority to serve war - rants and to enter workshops, factories, stores and all other p where children may be employed. The Inspector of Mines, for mines. Nebraska — Deputy Commissioner of Labor, salary $ i f Hampshire — State Superintendent of Public Instruction, and dep - uties appointed by superintendent, necessary expenses to be allow - ed by Governor and council. Also truant officers appointed b: trict school boards and paid by the towns. r Jersey— Commissioner of Labor, salary 91,500; assistant commis - sioner salary $1,500 and 11 inspectors, two of whom shall be women, salaries $1,000 and all necessary expenses allowed. fYork — The Board or Department of Health or Health Commission - ers, for emyloyment in mercantile establishments ; in fac Commissioner of Labor, salary $3,500 first deputy commissioner of labor salary $2,500 and 38 deputies, salaries $1,000, 9 of whom are women. North Carolina — Commissioner of the Bureau of Labor, salary $ 1 rh Dakota — Truant officer appointed by the board of education in any city of more than i ha bit ants, or the president of the school board of any district. — Chief Inspector of the Department of Workshops and Factories, Balary $2,000; three district inspectors, salaries $1 000 and additional district inspectors if necessary; all expenses allowed. Inspectors have same authority as truant officers to enforce school attendance of any child found violating the school laws. ron — The Board of Inspectors of Child Labor^ composed of 5 per - sons, 3 at least of whom shall be women, to serve without compen - sation. rsylvania — Factory Inspector and 39 deputy factory inspectors. 5 of whom shall be women, at salaries of $1,200, traveling expenses allowed. For mines. Chief of Department of Mines and 30 inspec - tors. rle Island — Two factory inspectors, one of whom shall be a woman, all necessary expenses not to amount to more than $1,200. One or more truant officers, appointed by the school committee of each town or city and compensation fixed by the same. South Carolina — Xo special officials for inspection or enforcement. rh Dakota— District School Board or the Chairman of the board of education in independent districts^ or the county superintendent. Tennessee — Grand Jury has inquisitorial powers to investigate viola - tions and judges of the circuit courts of the state shall specially </seg>
            <seg id="p058">charge the grand jury at the begining of each term of the court to Investigate violations. rmmi88ioner of Labor Statistics and Mines, expenses of the depart - ment not to exceed $4,000 per year; commissioner to act as inspec - tor of mines. Texas — No special officials for inspection or enforcement riont — Town Superintendent, appointed and compensation fixed by the boards of school directors. Truant officers two to be appointed by selectmen of a town and the Mayor of a city; salary at the rat© of $2.00 a day for time actually spent. Virginia — So special officials for inspection or enforcement. Act passed April 16, 1903. No prosecution lodged up to Dec. 12, 1904. Washington — Commissioner of Labor. West Virginia — State Commissioner of Labor ronsin — Commissioner of Labor, salary $2,000; deputy commis - sioner, $1,500 and 7 factory inspectors, salaries $1,000; 1 factory - inspector salary $ 1 . PEXALTIE9. I The penalties for infringement of the Child Labor Laws fall under heads: penalties for the employer and penalties for parent or guard- rty for Employer for Employing Child I'nder Ago (a) and Over Time (b) Alabama — Fine of not more than $200. Arkansas — Fine of not more than $500. rornia — Fine of not less than $50 nor more than $200, or by im - prisonment of not more than GO days, or by both such fine and imprisonment for each offense. Connecticut — Not more than $20 for each offense r'ado — Fine of not less than $50 nor more than $500 and imprison - ment in the county jail not less than 30 days nor more than 3 months. Applying to (a). Illinois — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100 for each offense and to stand committed until such fines and costs are paid. rna — Fine of not more than $50 for the first offense, and not more than $100 for the second offense to which may be added im - prisonment for not more than ten days and for the third offense a fine of not less than $2 50^ and not more than 30 days im - prisonment in the county jail. Applying to (a). Kentucky — Fine of not less than $25 and not more than $250. Ap - plying to (a). Maine — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50 for each offense Eachussets — Fine of not more than $50 for first offense, and who - ever continues to violate the law after being notified by a truant officer or an inspector of factories shall for every day thereafter </seg>
            <seg id="p059">that such employment continues, be punished by a fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20. rland — Fine of not less than $100 for each offense and pay for the cost of prosecution, one-half to go to the informer, and one-half to the school fund of the county or city in which the offense shall have been committed. rigan — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100, or by im - prisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 90 days or by both in the discretion of the court. Minnesota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each offense. riuri — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $100 or im - prisonment in the county jail for not less than 2 nor more than 10 days or both, for each offense. Applying to (a). Montana — Fine of not more than $1,000 for mines or any similiar business. Applying to (b). raska — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each offense, provided that no conviction shall be had under this act unless the proceedings shall be commenced within one year after the offense shall have been committed. Applying to (a). New Hampshire — Fine of not more than $50 for the use of the dist - rict for each offense. New Jersey — Fine of $50 for each offense. r liana — Fine of $100 for each offense or imprisonment in the parish jail not more than 30 days, or both, in the discretion of the court. fYork — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $100 for a first offense; for a second offense not less than $50 nor more than $200 or by imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or by both: for a third offense not less than $250 or by imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or by both. North Carolina — Punishment at the discretion of the court. North Dakota — Fine of not less than $10 and not more than $100 Ohio — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 or imprisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 30 days. Fon — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $25 for the first offense, not less than $25 nor more than $50 for the second and imprisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 30 days for the third and each succeeding offense. Pennsylvania — Fine of not more than $500. re Island — Fine of not more than $500. Applying to (a). N'ot more than $20 for each offense. Applying to (b). ri Carolina— Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $50, or imprisonment for not more than 30 days at the discretion of the court. South Dakota — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $100. Tennessee — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than | </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Texas — Fine of not less than $50 and not more than $200, each day of violating act to constitute a separate offense. Applying to (a). Virginia — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $100. rhington — Fine of not less than $50 nor more than $100, or im - prisonment in the county jail for not more than one month for each offense. Applying to (a). rt Virginia — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $20 for each offense. For employment in coal mines, fine of not less than $50 nor more than $500. In default of payment, in the discretion of the court imprisonment in the county jail for not more than 3 months. onsin — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $100 for each offense. Penalty for Employer for Kmploying Child During School Hours. Connecticut — Fine of $20 for every week such child is so employed. rrado — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50 and all such fines to be paid into the country treasury and placed to the credit of the school district in which the offense occurs. Illinois — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100 for each offense and to stand committed until such fine and costs are paid. rachusetts — Fine of not more than $50 for the first offense and for every day thereafter, after notification by a truant officer or by an inspector of factories, a fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20. Minnesota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each of - fense. Montana — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50 for each offense. New Hampshire — Fine of not more than $50 for each offense, for the use of the distri. York — Fine of $50 for each offense. rh Dakota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 and costs for each offense. — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 or imprisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 30 days. ron — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $25 for the first offense, not less than $25 nor more than $50 for the second, and imprisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 30 days for the third and each succeeding offense. tth Dakota — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $20 and costs for every offense. riont — Fine of not more than $50 and for violation after notification by truant officer; fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20 for each day of such violation. Penalty for Employer for Neglecting (a) to Keep File of Age and Schooling Cert ideates and (b) to Produce Them for the In ispection of the School Authorities or Factory Inspectors, bama — Fine of not more than $200. Applying to (a). </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Arkansas — Fine of not more than $500. Applying to ■ornia — Not less than $50 nor more than $200 or by imprisonment of not more than 60 days, or by both fine and imprisonm&gt; Connecticut— Fine of not more than $100. Illinois — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $50. §.na — Fine of not more than $50 for the first offense and not more than $100 for the second offense to which may be added imprison - ment for not more than 10 days, and for the third offense a fine of not less than $2 50 and not more than 30 days' imprisonment in the county jail. Kansas — For coal mines, fine of not more than $50 for each offense. Louisiana — Fine of $100 for each offense or imprisonment in the parish jail not more than 30 days, or both in the discretion of the court. Maine — Failure to produce age certificate is prima facie evidence that the employment of the child for whom it is demanded is illegal. Massachusetts — Failure to produce or to have listed age and schooling certificate, shall be prima facie evidence of the illegal employment of any child whose certificate is not produced or whos not so listed. fland — Fine of $100 for the first offense and for every day thereaf - ter, after notification by an atendance officer, fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20. Failure to produce age or schooling certifi - cate shall be prima facie evidence of the illegal employment of the child whose certificate is not produced. figan — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100, or b onment for not less than 10 days nor more than 90 days, or both in the discretion of the court. resota — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50, for each offense. Failure to produce age or school certificate shall be prima facie evidence of the illegal employment of the child for whom it is not produced. Montana — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50 for each offense. raska — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each offense, provided that no conviction shall be had under this act unless the proceedings therefor, shall be commenced within one year after the offense shall have been committed. Applying to (a). New Hampshire — Fine of not more than $50 for each offense, for the use of the district. Applying to (a). New Jersey — Fine of $50 for each offense. I York — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $100 for the first offense; for a second offense not less than $50 nor more than $200 or by imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or by both^uch fine and imprisonment; for a third offense not less than $250 or by im - prisonment for not more than 60 days or by both fine and impris - onment. Ohio — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50. Oregon — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $25 for the first </seg>
            <seg id="p062">offense, not less than $25 nor more than $50 for the second, and imprisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 30 days for the third offense and each succeeding. Pennsylvania — Fine of not more than $500. Applying to (a). Rhode Island — Fine of not more than $500 riont — Fine of not more than $50; for violation after notification by truant officer, fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20 for each day of violation. Wisconsin — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $100 for each offense. rty for Employer for Employment of Illiterates who do not go to Night School. Colorado — Fine of not less than $25 and not more than $100 Connecticut — Fine of not more than $50. Illinois — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100 and to stand committed until such fines and costs are paid. rland — Fine of not more than $100 for each offense; such fines to be paid to the school commissioners for use in supporting even - ing schools in the city or county, in which the minor resides., rachusetts — Fine of not more than $100 for each offense to the use of the evening schools in the town or city in which such minor resides. rigan — Fine of not less than $5 and not more than $100 or impris - onment for not less than 10 nor more than 90 days, or both in the discretion of the court. Minnesota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 New Hampshire — Fine of not more than $20 for the use of the evening schools of the town or city in which the offense was committed. New York— Fine of $50 for each offense. Penalty for Employer for Refusing Entrance to or Obstructing Factory Inspectors or School Authorii I California — Fine of not less than $50 nor more than $200. Illinois — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100 for each offense and to stand committed until such fines and costs are paid. rina — Fine of not more than $50 for the first offense and not more than $100 for the second offense to which may be added imprison - ment for not more than 10 days, and for the third offense a fine of not less than $250 and not more than 30 days' imprisonment in the county jail. Iowa — Fine of not more than $100 and costs of prosecution or by im - prisonment in the county jail not exceeding 30 days. ftucky — Fine of not more than $100 or to be imprisoned in Jail not more than 6 months or both to be so fined and imprisoned in the discretion of the jury. Maine — Fine of $50. Maryland — Fine of not less than $50 for each offense Michigan — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than J100 or by impris- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">onment for not less than 10 days nor more than 90 days, or both, in the discretion of the court. Missouri — Fine of not less than $2 5 nor more than $100 Massachusetts — Fine of not more than $1,000. New Jersey — Fine of $50 for each offense. I York — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $100 for a first offense, for second offense not less than $50 nor more than $200 or by imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment; for a third offense, not less than $250, or by imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or by both such fine and imprisonment. Pennsylvania — Fine of not more than $ Rhode Island — Fine of not more than $10. unsin — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $100 for each offense. Penalty for Parent for Allowing Child to be Employed antler Age (a) Alabama — Fine of not more than $200. Arkansas — Fine of not more than $ rornia — Fine of not less than $50 nor more than $200 or by im - prisonment of not more than 60 days or by both, for each offense. Connecticut — Fine of not more than $60 and every week of snch em - ployment to be a distinct offense. Illinois — For each offense fine of not less than $5 nor more than $25 and to stand committed until such fines and costs are paid. r.na — Fine of not more than $50 for the first offense and not more than $100 for the second offense to which may be added imprison - ment for not more than 10 days, and for a third offense a fine of not less than $250 and not more than 30 days' imprisonment in the county jail. Maine — Fine of not less than $25 nor more than $50 for each offense. rachusetts — Fine of not more than $50 for the first offense, and for every day thereafter that employment continues, after notification by a truant officer or by an inspector of factories, a fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20 for (a) ; fine of not less than $50 nor more than $100 for (b). rigan — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100. or by im - prisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 90 days or by both in the discretion of the court. Minnesota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each offense. rmri — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $100, or by Im - prisonment in the county jail for not less than 2 nor more than 10 days or by both, for each offense. Applying to I Nebraska — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each or. Over TiiiH 1 (h) </seg>
            <seg id="p064">ceedings therefor shall be commenced within one year after the offense shall have been committed. Applying to (a). New Jersey — Fine of $50 for each offense. Oregon — Fine of not less than to nor more than $25 Pennsylvania — Fine of not more than $500. r« Island — Fine of not more than $20 for each offense. Apply - ing to (b). rth Carolina — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $50, or im - prisonment for not more than 30 days, at the discretion of the court. Applying to (a). riont — Fine of not more than $50, and for violation after being notified by truant officer, fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20 for each day of such violation. rty for Parent for Allowing Illiterate Child to !&gt;&lt;■ Employed With - out Attending Day or Night School. rland — Fine of not more than $20 to the use of the city or county in which the offense occurs. rachusetts — Fine of not more than $20 to the use of the evening schools of the town or city in which such offense occurs. rigan — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100, or imprison - ment for not less than 10 nor more than 90 days, or both, in the discretion of the court. resota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each offense. r Hampshire — Fine of not more than $20 for the use of the even - ing schools of the town or city in which the offense was com - mitted. Penalty for Making any False Statements in an Age or Schooling Certificate. rama — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100, or hard labor for term not exceeding 3 months. To be tried before some justice of the peace or other court or officer having jurisdiction for trial. tansas — Usual punishment for perjury, necticut- — Fine of not more than $20. rois — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $100 for each offense and to stand committed until such fine and costs are paid. - K tacky — Usual punishment for perjury, ne — Fine of $100. Massachusetts — Fine of not more than $50. rland — Fine of not more than $50 or imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or both in the discretion of the court. Minnesota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50. New Hampshire — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each offense. New Jersey — Fine of $50 for each offense. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">fYork — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $100 for a first offense;for second offense, not less than $50 nor more than $200, or by imprisonment for not more than 30 days, or by both; for a third offense not less than $250, or by imprisonment of not more than 60 days or by both. North Carolina — Punishment at the discretion of the court. North Dakota — Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 and costs. fh Carolina — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $50 or im - prisonment for not more than 30 days in the discretion of the court. South Dakota — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $20. Tennessee — Punishment usual for perjury Vermont — Fine of not more than $50. SCHEDULE I. (Continued)— ENFORCEMENT. 2. THK ( OMI'l I,S()HV KM CATION LAWS. Almost all of the states having compulsory education laws, pro - vide for their enforcement by authorizing the appointment of one or more truant officers in each school district. These officers are usually appointed by the school authorities: they must notify parents of the violation of the compulsory education laws, and are given police powers for the arrest of truants. Their salaries are usually fixed by the boards appointing them and vary from no compensation as in Massachusetts to $2 for each working day. Penalty for Parent for Failure to Send Children to School. rornia — -Fine of not more than $10. or imprisonment for not more than 5 days for the first offense, for subsequent offenses fine of not less than $10 nor more than $50, or imprisonment for not less than 5 nor more than 25 days, or both fine and imprisonment. rrado — Fine not less than $5 or more than $20 or the court ma quire parent or guardian to give bond in the penal sum of $100, with sureties to the approval of the judge of the county court, con - ditioned that he or she will cause the child to attend some recog - nized school within 5 days after and to remain during term pre - scribed by law. Upon failure to pay fine or furnish bond, said parent or guardian shall be imprisoned in the county jail not less than 10 days nor more than 30 da recticut — Fine of not more than $5. each week's failure to be a distinct offense. District of Columbia — Fine of not more than $20. ro — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $25 for the first offense, not less than $10 nor more than $50 for the second and each sub - sequent offense, besides costs. Illinois — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20 and costs and to stand committed until paid. Indiana — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $25, and in the discre- 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">tlon of the court imprisonment in the county jail for not less than 2 nor more than 90 days. Iowa — Fine of not less than $3 nor more than $20 for each offense Kansas — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $25 Maine — Fine of not more than $25 for each offense. Maryland — Fine of not more than $5 for each offense Massachusetts — Fine of not more than $20. rigan — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $50, or by imprison - ment in the county or city Jail for not less than 2 nor more than 90 days, or both fine and imprisonment. Minnesota — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $25 for the first offense. Montana — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20. Nebraska — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20 rda — Fine of not less than $50 nor more than $100 for the first offense, not less than $100 nor more than $200 for subsequent offenses, besides costs. New Hampshire — Fine of $10 for first offense; $20 for each subsequent offense. New Jersey — Punishable as a disorderly person New Mexico — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $25, or by impris - onment for not more than 10 days in any county jail. rYork — Fine of not more than $5 for the first offense and for each ubsequent offense fine of not more than $50, or imprisonment for not more than 30 days or both fine and imprisonment. rh Dakota — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20 for the first offense, not less than $10 nor more than $50 for subsequent of - fenses and costs. Ohio — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $20. or imprisonment for not less than 10 nor more than 30 days. Oregon — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $25 rsylvania — Fine of not more than $2 for the first offense and not more than $5 for each subsequent, and in default imprisonment for not more than 2 day for the first offense and not more than 5 days for each subsequent offense. Rhode Island — Fine of not more than $20 for each offense. ri Dakota — Fine of not less than $10 nor more than $20 for each offense and to stand committed until fine and costs are paid. Vermont — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $25. riington— Fine of not less than $20 nor more than $50 for each offense. West Virginia — Fine of $2 for the first offense and $5 for each subse quent offense. Wisconsin — Fine of not less than $5 nor more than $50 for each offense A STANDARD CHILD LABOR LAW </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Illinois have been included in the Standard Child Labor Law which follows. Attention is asked for the provisions covering street occupa - tions for children. BE IT ENACTED. ETC.. AS FOLLOWS Compiled from Kew York Factory and Mercantile Establishment* Laws of 1003. Child under 14 Years. I Sec. 1. No child under fourteen years of age shall be empl' nit ted or suffered to work in or in connection with any fa&lt; kshop, mercantile establishment, store, business office, telegraph e_ restaurant, hotel, apartment house or in the distribution or trans - lion of merchandise or messages. It shall be unlawful for any per - firm or corporation to employ any child under fourteen in any business or service whatever, during any part of the term ng which the public schools of the district in which the child re In session. Vork Compulsory Kducation I.a» of IWW. Sec. ."&gt;. . Compiled from Massachusetts Law and New York Factory Law of 1»M&gt;:t. . Child Inder 1« Years. KXo child between fourteen and sixteen years of age shall mployed, permitted or suffered to work in any factory, workshop lercantile establishment unless the person or corporation empl' procures and keeps on file and accessable to the truant offic • ttown or city, and to the inspectors of factories, an employment ficate as hereinafter prescribed, and keeps two complete lists of uch children employed therein, one on file and one conspicuously 3d near the principal entrance of the building in which such chli - are employed. On termination of the employment of a child so stered, and whose certificate is so filed, such certificate shall be lwith surrendered by the employer to the child or its parent or dian or custodian. Massachusetts Law. . F.niployment Certificate, By Whom Approved. Sec. 3. An employment certificate shall be approved only by the intendent of schools or by a person authorized by him in writing, or, where there is no superintendent of schools, by a person authorized by the school committee: provided, .that no member of a school com - mittee or other person authorized as aforesaid shall have authori approve such certificate for any child then in or about to enter his own employment^ or the employment of a firm or corporation of which he is a member, officer or employee. \«w York Factory Laws &lt;&gt;f 1JHKJ, Chapter 1K4.. Kniployment Certificate. tSec. 4. The person authorized to issue employment certificates not isue such certificate until he has received, examined, appn filed the following papers duly executed: (1) The school record ich child properly filled out and signed as provii! </seg>
            <seg id="p068">REPORT O» (2) A passpor or duly attested h f or baptism or c i, show he date a i of such child according to la ed with the duty of recording births, shall be conclusive evidence of y age of such ct d rhe affld vit c todian of a ch Id, which shall be i w i last mentioned transcript of filed, showing the place and date of birth of such child; which affld w must be taken before the offl is herebv authorized and required to ad shall not dema hell not be issued until such childs father has persor before and x ff such officer st fter m onic6 s tences in the English language and that in his opinion the &lt; JW of a child from the *■ whi^ nds cal fitn Ever he off h r Contents &gt;f ( rtiti&lt; ii« V the child, and lit and ,• distinguishing f: I by the preceding papers requir proved and t peared before Seer signii School Record Wh Contain. at to Sec. 6. The school record required by this article s has attended and shall be furnished thereto. It shall contain a statement certifying that the child has reg ularly attended the public schools or schools equivalent theret parochial schools for not less than one hundred and arriv or during the year previous to app able to read and write simple sentences in the E has received during such period ins n in reading, spelling, w English grammar and geography an i.. amiliar with the fundai operations of arithmetic up to and including fractions. Such schot record shall also give the age and residence of the child as shown c records of the school and the name of its parent, guardian or custodiar ins ther religious reco A duly, attested trans- w with a resistrar of vit; irt&gt; id or rece describe tt d and that the by the principal or chief executiv the school year preyiou </seg>
            <seg id="p069">BUREAU OF LABOR Report of Certificates Issued. Illinois Factory Laws of 19O3, Sec. 10. Hoars of Labor Compile Truant Officers to Inspect Work Plac* v Vli ft its, sha ider thi off* 1C h Massachusetts Law.. Failure to Produce Certitleat* </seg>
            <seg id="p070">Sec. 11. No child under the age of sixteen years shall be employ - ed at sewing belts, or to assist in sewing belts, in any capacity what - ever; nor shall any child adjust any belt to any machinery; they shall not oil or assist in oiling, wiping or cleaning machinery, they shall not operate or assist in operating circular or band saws, wood shapers, wood-joiners, planers, sandpaper or wood-polishing machinery, emery or polishing wheels used for polishing metal, wood-turning or boring machinery, stamping machines in sheet metal and tinware manufactur - ing, stamping machines in washer and nut factories, operating cor - rugating rolls, such as are used in roofing factories, nor shall they be employed in operating any passenger or freight elevators, steam boiler, steam machinery, or other steam generating apparatus, or as pin boys in any bowling alleys; they shall not operate or assist in operating, dough brakes, or cracker machinery of any description; wire or iron straight - ening machinery : nor ghall they operate or.assist in operating tolling mill machinery punches or shears, washing, grinding or mixing mill or cal - endar rolls in rubber manufacturing, nor shall they operate or assist in operating laundry machinery; nor shall children be employed in any capacity in preparing any composition in which dangerous or poisonous acids are used, and they shall not be employed in any capacity In the manufacture of paints, colors or white lead; nor shall they be employed in any capacity whatever in operating or assisting to operate any pas - senger or freight elevator; nor shall they be employed in any capacity whatever in the manufacture of goods for immoral purposes, or any other employment that may be considered dangerous to their lives or limbs, or where their health may be injured or morals depraved; nor in any theatre, concert hall, or place of amusement wherein intoxicating liquors are sold; nor shall females under sixteen years of age be em - ployed in any capacity where such employment compels them to remain standing constantly. THE NEBRASKA CHILD LABOR LAW An act to regulate the employment of children in manufacturing, mechanical, industrial, or mercantile establishment, to provide a pen - alty for its violation and the enforcement of its provisions, and to re - peal sections 245aa, 245bb, and 245cc, of the" Criminal Code of the State of Nebraska. That the provisions of this Act shall be known as sections 255aa, 245bb ( M5cc. 242cc-l, 245cc-2, and 245cc-3, of the Criminal Code of Nebraska. I Section 24 5aa.— That any male or female child under the age of years shall not be employed in any manufacturing, mechanical, strial. or mercantile establishment. Sec. 245bb. — That any male or female child under the age of four - teen years shall not be employed in any manufacturing, mechanical, industrial, or mercantile establishments, except during the vacations of the public schools; unless during the next year preceding such em - ployment, said child has for at least twenty weeks attended some pub - lic or private day school where the English [language] }s taught; nor </seg>
            <seg id="p071">f BIREAU OF LABOR 71 hall such employment continue, unless such child shall In each and every year attend school as herein provided, and no child shall be so employed who does not present, a certificate signed by the President and Secretary of the School Board of the school district in which said hild resides, of their compliance with the requirements of this section Nor shall any owner, superintendent, or overse«r of any such establish ment, parent or guardian consent to or permit the employment of an hild contrary to the provisions of this act Sec. 245cc. — Any owner, superintendent, or overseer of any such establishment, shall require and keep on file, open to the inspection of the publics a certificate of thee age place of birth and residence of ever male and female child under six so long as such child is so employ in case the child is under fourtei n years of age employed therein, 1; which certificate shall also sta i years of age, the amount of said child's school attendance during the year next preceding his employ ment, and such certificate shall be signed by the President and Secretary of the School Board of the school district in which the child resides and the forms of certificate herein referred to shall be approved by the Attorney General of this state Sec. 245cc-l. — Any person who shall be convicted of a violation of any of the provisions of this act shall pay for every such offense a fine of not less than twenty dollars nor more than fifty dollars, Ih-ovidttl. However: That no conviction shall be had under this act unless the pro- ceedings therefor shall be commenced within one year after the offe shall have been committd Sec. 24 5cc-2. — It is hereby made the duty of the Deput Labor Commissioner of this state, upon complaint being filed with him. to inspect any and all establishments to which this act applies, and ascertain whether any of the provisions of this act have been violated Whenever it shall come to his knowledge that any of the provisions of this act have been or are being violated, it shall be his duty to caus the same to be enforced, Provided, However: That nothing in this section contained shall be construed to prevent any other person from causing the enforcement of the provisions of this act Sec. 245cc-3. — Sections 245aa, and 2 4 5bb, and 24 5cc, of the Crimi- nal Code now in force are hereby repealed, and the provisions of thi act shall be known as sections 245aa, 245bb 245cc-l. 245cc-2, and 45cc-3, of the Criminal Code of the state of Nebraska The effort to restrict the labor of children on the streets is so re- cent, and the measures hitherto adopted are so largely experimental. that it seems best to print in full the newsboy law how in force in New York, followed by a brief statement of the substance of the provisions in which it is excelled by the Boston law LAWS OF NEW YORK An Act to amend the labor law relating to children working in </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 streets and public places in cities of the first class. Became a law, April 8, 1903, with the approval of the Governor passed three-fifths being present. 7 4. Prohibited Employment of children in street trades. — No male child under ten, and no girl under sixteen years of age shall in ■ city of the first class sell or expose or offer for sale newspapers in street or public place. Permit any Badge for Newsboys, How Issued. 175. No male child actually or apparantly under fourteen years of age shall sell or expose or offer for sale said articles unless a permit or badge as hereinafter provided shall have been issued to him by the district superintendent of the board of education of the city and school district where said child resides, or by such other officer thereof as may be officially designated by such board for that purpose, on the applica - tion of the parent, guardian or other person having the custody of the child desiring such permit and badge, or in case said child has no parent, guardian or custodian, then on the application of his next friend, being an adult. Such permit and badge shall not be issued until the officer issuing the same shall have received, examined, approved and placed on f51e j in his office, satisfactory proof that such male child is of the age of ten or upwards. No permit or badge provided for herein shall be valid for any purpose except during the period in which such proof shall remain on file, nor shall such permit or badge be authority beyond the period fixed therein for its duration. After having received examined, approved and placed on file such proof, the officer shall issue to the child a permit and badge. ( ■'•nt fiitx of Permit and Badge. 176. Such permit shall state the date and place of birth of the child, the name and address of its parent, guardian, custodian or next friend, as the case may be. and describe the color of hair and eyes, the height and weight, and any distinguishing facial mark of such child, and shall further state that the proof required by the preceding sec - tion has been duly examined, approved and filed; and that the child named in such permit has appeared before the officer issuing the per - mit. The badge furnished by the officer issuing the permit shall bear on its face a number corresponding to the number of the permit, and the name of the child. Every such permit, and every such badge, on its reverse side, shall be signed in the presence of the officer issuing the same by the child in whose name it is issued. Regulation* Concern In b Badce and Permit. 177. The badge provided for herein shall be worn conspicuously at all times by such child while so working; and such permit and badge shall expire at the end of one year from the date of their issue. No child to whom such permit and badge are issued, shall transfer the same to any other person nor be engaged in an : the first </seg>
            <seg id="p073">73 class as a newsboy, or shall sell or expose or offer for sale newspapers in any street or public place without having upon his person such badge, and he shall exhibit the same upon demand at any time to any police, or attendance officer. Badge and permit to be surrendered. 1178. The parent guardian, custodian or next friend, as the case be, of every child to whom such permit and badge shall be issued surrender the same to the authority by which said permit and e are issued, at the expiration of the period provided therefor. Limit of hours. §179. No child to whom a permit and badge ar« issued as pro - 1 for in the preceding sections, shall sell or expose or offer for sale, newspapers after ten o'clock in the evening. Violation of this article, how punished 179a. Any child who shall work in any city of the first class in any street or public place as a newsboy or shall sell or expose or offer for sale newspapers under circumstances forbidden by the provisions of this article, must be arrested and brought before a court or magis - trate having jurisdiction to commit a child to an incorporated charitable reformatory or other institution, and be dealt with according to law; and if any such child is commited to an institution, it shall, when practicable, be committed to an institution governed by persons of the same religious faith as the parents of such child. 12. Nothing in this act contained shall be deemed or construed to .1, amend, modify, impair or in any manner affect any provisions e penal code or the code of criminal procedure. ADDITIONAL PROVISIONS IN FORCE IN BOSTON. KThe following provisions of the Boston law excel the New York law should be incorporated in any statute hereafter adopted. I No child shall work as a bootblack unless he is over ten years of and he shall not sell any other article except newspapers, unless he er twelve years of age. Every permit shall be issued on the condition that the holder there - of shall, so long as he continues under the age of fourteen years, attend, during every session thereof, one of the public schools, or some regular - ly established school in the city of Boston^ approved by the committee on licenses of said city. Any minor who violates any of said terms will be deprived of his permit and badge, and be fined. </seg>
            <seg id="p074"/>
            <seg id="p075">Strikes </seg>
            <seg id="p076"/>
            <seg id="p077">STRIKES During the biennium of 1903 and 1904, three strikes of importance occurred in Nebraska as follows: — The Union Pacific Railroad strike, involving the boilermakers, machinists and blacksmiths employed in the construction and repair shops af that system; the Teamsters' strike in Omaha, in which were engaged all the union teamsters in that city, and the Packing House strike of South Omaha, which involved and was call - ed by the Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workers of America. This latter strike was a part of the general strike of packing house em - ployees which prevailed throughout the United States in all meat pack - ing centers. The total number of employees involved in these three strikes was 7,050, fifty of these being female workers in the packing I'nion Pacific Strike. The strike of the boilermakers, machinists and blacksmiths in the Union Pacific Railroad service was declared July 3rd, 1902, as the re - sult of an effort to institute the "piece-work system" throughout the shops. The employees had been working under a per hour schedule of thirty-two and thirty-four cents. The Nebraska points affected by this strike were Omaha, Columbus, Grand Island and North Platte. The strike, however, extended to all points touched by the Union Pacific Railroad. The number of men affected was 1,400. I The question of the number of hours constituting a day's labor was an issue, as an eight hour schedule was effective prior to the strike has been since. The employees won the point at issue, being suc - ful in securing the acceptance of an agreement which abolished the ce work" system. An increase in wages of seven per cent was also ited. The Company retained such of its present working force as »sired upon equal terms with union men. Every striker was rein - ?d upon application within sixty days of date of agreement. Teamsters' Strike. The teamsters employed by all coal, brick and lumber dealers^ all mercantile establishments, and transfer and express lines in Omaha went on strike May 1st, 1904, upon the refusal of the employers to grant an increase in wages as demanded by the Team Drivers Interna - tional Union. The number involved in the strike was 550: Employees were out of employment one month and three days, the strike being settled and declared off by the union June 3rd. 1904. The strikers gain - ed their contention for an Increase in wages, but conceeded to employers the right to maintain open shops. The wages prior to calling the strike </seg>
            <seg id="p078">Ee from $9.00 per week to $45.00 and $50.00 per month. In - ies were granted which fixed wages at from $12.00 per week to $50 $60 per month. Ten hours constituted a day's work prior to the e and since. All employees returned to work. Parking House Strike. The Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workers I'nion of America called a strike July 12, 1904, of all members employed in the packing houses of Armour and Company, Cudahy and Company, Swift and Company and the National Packing Company located at South Oma - ha. This strike resulted from a reduction in the wages of common laborers. The wages of the latter prior to the strike, were 19 cents per hour with hours of labor per day irregular, depending upon amount of slaughtering done. Hours per day ranged from two to tei&gt;. This strike was but an extention of the general packing house strike which existed in all packing house centers in the United States. In South Omaha the strikers numbered about 5,000, fifty of whom were females. The period covered by the strike was two months, dur - ing which time several violent demonstrations occurred, directed most - ly against imported non-union strike breakers. During the last two weeks of the strike period the packing houses closed. On September 10, 1904, the Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workers union call - ed off the strike and submitted to the terms of the packers. About three hundred employees lost their situations and those common laborers who did resume work did so under a reduction of wages from 19 cents per hour to 17% cents Der hour </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Fire Escape Enforcement </seg>
            <seg id="p080"/>
            <seg id="p081">In the enforcement of the fire escape law an official comes into .full realization of the value that the average citizen places upon human life, and to what extent the commandment "Be thy brother's keeper" secures practical application. It is a surprising and greatly to be regretted fact that the ordinary owner of public buildings in the erec - tion of the same_ and in supplying it with modern conveniences, never gives a moment's thought or attention to providing even the minimum of protection against fire to the lives which may inhabit his building or buildings. In my enforcement of this law, I have had to deal very much with those who in the past have opposed it and have refused com - pliance therewith. Since the horrible catastrophy resulting from the burning of the Iroquois theatre in Chicago, it might be supposed that the minds of men might be compelled to appreciate the value of the lives of the public that gather in their public meeting places, and that they would realize the absolute necessity of surrounding their build - ings with every possible means of protection and safety, but it is hard indeed to move men's minds when it means the expenditure of the ■"Almighty Dollar." I During the past biennium every city in this state, which contains dings subject to the present statute, has been visited, and the law irced in every possible case. Especially have I made effort to secure proper protection of all hotels, theatres and public halls. During the nium I have ordered fire escapes constructed an one hundred and ty buildings in the state. Seventy-seven buildings have been &gt;erly equipped and the fire escapes approved, and I have escapes on ■n buildings now in course of construction. </seg>
            <seg id="p082"/>
            <seg id="p083">Female and Child Labor Law Enforcement </seg>
            <seg id="p084"/>
            <seg id="p085">In the enforcement of the female labor law I have found the prin - ciple violators to be laundries and the large department stores In our large cities. Practically all of my notices of violations have been to such establishments. Other mercantile establishments have also re - quired notices and visits, but in the majority of cases this is all that has been necessary to compel compliance with the law. As required by statute large notices giving the provisions of the law and the penalty for violation of the same, have been posted in every business establish - ment in the state which employs female labor. I have given formal notice of prosecution, in case violation did not cease, to nineteen estab - lishments. Thus far this has been sufficient to cause the suspension of long hours, and I have, therefore, not been compelled to ins - legal proceedings. The six o'clock closing scheme customery in Omaha and Lincoln eliminates, to a great extent, violations of this law. I The packing houses of South Omaha constitute the greatest ground infractions of the child labor law, and I have made annual insepec - 8 of these establshments in 1903 and 1904. Careful search into status of all children employed has been made, and great num - i have been prohibited from working. The difficulty in the majority •ases in enforcing this law does not come from the operators of le establishments, but from the parents of the children, who persist orcing their children to work, and very often resort to falsehood irding age, period of school attendacne. etc., in making it per - sable for them to be allowed to work. There are approximately two thousand manufacturing establish - ments of large proportions in Nebraska, and it is conservative to pre - sume that twelve hundred of these employ child or female labor. Be - sides this number there are forty-five steam laundries in the state, all of which employ female labor to a great extent. It will, therefore, be seen that a stringent and proper enforcement of the child and female labor laws is not an easy task, for to secure proper compliance with the law, frequent inspections of each establishment is imperative. These in - spections should be made each quarter. The personnel of the Bureau of Labor as now constituted by statute is absolutely inadequate to make such inspections. The force numbers three persons. The statistical work of the Bureau requires double this number, yet it has been per - formed thus far, as well as possible under the circumstances, by two per- </seg>
            <seg id="p086">sons and the Deputy Commissioner has attempted to attend to child and female labor enforcement together with the enforcement of the fire - escape law. Twelve hundrd and fifty establishments or factories to be inspected, and the law enforced therein, by one official. A performance of this duty would require the inspection of four establishments each and every day, a feat absolutely impossible, to say nothing of the prepos - terousness of expecting an inspection each quarter, which would demand the inspection of fifteen factories daily by one official. Other states throughout the Union have awakened or are awakening to the im - portance of efficient factory inspection and to the irristible demand for child protection from the mind stunting and physical ruin resulting from constant employment in factories. It is to be hoped that Nebraska, the foremost state In the Union in the literacy of her people, will soon take steps to properly deal with this great question. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">The Value of Statistics </seg>
            <seg id="p088"/>
            <seg id="p089">THE VALUE OF STATISTICS The Value and Influence of Labor StatiMii -. " There are now in the United States, besides the Federal Department )f Labor, thirty-three state bureaus or departments devoted to the col - ectiok of statistics of labor by means of original investigations. Beside* hese. tSe^Federal Census Office, the Bureaus of Statistics of the Federal rreasury and Agricultural Departments, the Bureau of Foreign Com- &gt;f the Department of State, the departments and boards of agrl - of the various States, and various other offices may be consld- n d as publishing labor statistics in some degree. But I speak here of he value and influence of those offices first mentioned— those devoted peciflcally and technically to the investigation of social and industrial onditions and to the publication of distinctive labor statistics. These &gt;fflees had their foundation in the establishment of the Massachusetts bureau in 1869. Gradually other states created bureaus of statistics of ibor, and in 1884 the United States government added its own office o those already in existence. All the offices, together, have published r er 460 octavo volumes, covering a great variety of topics and the suits of investigations relative to almost even- condition and environ- ment of the workingman The character and quality of the work of the different offices varies in some degree, due to a considerable extent to the short tenure of the heads of the different bureaus. Where the governor of a State has allowed himself to ignore politics and insist upon scientific work, the bureaus have achieved the greatest success; but as a rule a governor feels that the office of the chief of the bureau of statistics of labor of his State must be filled by somebody from his party, without reference to the skill, the experience, or the integrity of the Incumbent under the previous administration. Yet I am glad to say, as the result of pretty careful study of the reports of all the officials who have done the duty in this country during the past thirty-two years, that no matter for what reason they were appointed^ no matter how inexperienced in the work of investigation and of compilation and presentation of statistical mat- ter, no matter from what party they came, and whether in sympathy with capital or labor, and even if . holding fairly radical socialistic views — the men have, almost without exception, at once comprehended the sacredness of the duty assigned them, and have served the public faithfully and honestly, being content to collect and publish facts with - out regard to their individual bias or their individual political senti - ments. As soon as a man realizes that he is giving to the world a fact. By Hon. Carroll D Wright </seg>
            <seg id="p090">he feels the necessity of accuracy, and tt collected would be to comi h because is would mislead legislators at the history of the State. Many men the statistical bureaus feeling that th but almost always with failure, t * nish infor That what I t Province of Ontario Canada hav their duties very closely those assigned \ and departments. In Germany, I the same character are published distinguished member of the Hous me a few years ago that, whenev w to workingmen before his colleagues, he carried into the Houj *K American report on the statistics of labor. In the Chamber^jf D« of France, in the German Reichstag, and in the legislative jp&lt; other countries the American labor reports have been free/fj a economic discussions. Had not the work of the American on highlv regarded, these things w course, that the sentiment of the tin altruistic sp i know how best to expend its eff question is being constantly asked: "What do social classt each other?" and that any on or magnitude of its de nust tu situation The question is often asked, and by very intelligent people, O good is a bureau of statistics of labor? Does the workingman any direct benefits from its existence? This question cai 4 answered very specifically, any more tt benefits of the public school. It w( T how a dollar more is made to enter th w through the existence of the put institution, andyet all men will admit that the sum of ben« increased by the existence of schools. P w tended that the bureau of statistics of labor, wt ply a part of the educational machinery establish through which" it is enabled to know more of itself. "Know is an injunction which should be applied to communities as well as individuals, and it is only through rigid impartial, and propagandism in some way, and in few lowing the example of the American gium, Austria, New Zeland, New cessful operation of bureaus of tion paid to social and ind the environment of men I </seg>
            <seg id="p091">EAl i *, t: *• A A A SV ff tv </seg>
            <seg id="p092">of lacts the influence of the reports of the bureaus has been enormous the value of their statistics cannot be expressed by figures. The first ten-hour law in this country was passed by the Masschu - setts legislature in 1874. The statistics published by the bureau of that State helped the passage of the law in a marked degree, and saved its repeal in later years. The manufacturers, finding that they were brought under the ten-hour law so far as minors and women were con - cerned, felt that the manufacturers In surrounding States ought to be brought under like laws or the law of Massachusetts should be re - pealed, for they claimed, as was claimed in England years ago, that in working under a ten-hour law the manufacturers of Massachusetts were placed at a decided disadvantage^relative to the manufacturers in the surrounding states. The legislature therefore directed the Bureau of Statistics of Labor to investigate the subject of the hours of labor in that State and in the other New England States. The result of the investigation showed that, under a ten-hour system, the Massachusetts manufacturers paid more wages than those in the other States, where eleven and twelve hours were the rule; that they produced more goods on any basis that could be named^ whether per individual or per machine; in short that in every respect the Massachu - setts operatives were under better conditions than those of the sur - rounding States. There has been no attempt since that report was published to repeal the ten-hour law of Massachusetts. On the other hand, other States have followed suit, until now that system prevails generally in the United States. The bureaus have been very influential in securing a modification of the old common-law rule relating to the liability of employers for -nts occuring to their employees. Under this rule a workman cannot recover damages for injuries received through carelessness or negligence of a coemployee, although a stranger might recover damages for an injury following the same carelessness or negligence; as for instance, under the old common-law rule, a brakeman on a train running perhaps 500 miles could secure no damages from a railroad corporation in consequence of injuries received through the carelessness or negligence of a swithohman along any part of the line, although the brakeman knew nothing of the switchman, had no knowledge of his skill or capacity when he engaged with the company, and in no sense of the word, so far as reason is concerned, could be con - sidered the co-employee of the switchman; yet, although that com - mon-law rule grew up before great industrial enterprises were estab - lished, judges had adhered to it and had ruled that in such a case as that just mentioned the switchman and the brakeman were coem - ployees, and therefore the employer could not be held liable. The agitation for a legislative change in this common-law rule in England resulted in the enactment of a law in 1S80 changing or modifying the rule, and, in this country, the matter being taken up by the bureaus of statistics of labor, several legislators have been convinced of the </seg>
            <seg id="p093">I:e of a change, and have therefore made it; the dire results which predicted as sure to follow the change of the rule have not ved. In this direction the bureaus have done a great service, not to the employees of railroads and corporations engaged in pro - ve industry, but in securing the public against the employment of apetent men. Another very emphatic influence which the bureaus have ex&lt;' is In the abolishment or modification of what is known as the "truck store" system, or, as it is more popularly known in some parts of the country, the "pluck-me" method of store trading. This system con - sists in the establishment of a store by the proprietors of a works for the supply of its employees. Formerly, in many instances, the p charged at these stores were much higher than those charged at other places, and so the employee of a concern having a truck store was almost compelled, and in many instances actually compelled, to pur - chase the necessaries of life for his family at an exhorbant price, whereby the employer made a second profit on the labor of th&lt; ployee. In very many instances the workmen of such an establish - ment never saw any money from one year's end to another. The pay for the goods purchased in the store was secured by the payrolls, and the debts and credits left no margin on pay-day. Early in the • of bureaus of statistics of labor this system was the statistical method, and the result has been that ii laws have been passed making it a criminal offence, in some carry on such a system, and in other cases making it the duty of the proper officers to see to it that they are regulated. The evils of the truck-store system have not yet been entirely eradicated in this country, but the change has been great, and the value to the wage receiver of the greatest importance. In this connction I might mention the influence which the bureaus have had in securing more frequent payments for the workingman. Formerly the payments were monthly. Under this system the credit system grew also, because without ready money the wage receiver must secure credit of his grocer, and the grocer, under such circumsnt looks out that the charges are sufficient to cover the delay in reoe his money or the losses which may come through his endeavors later on to collect the amount of his bill of the employer through the tr or the garnishee system. Weekly payments have been shown by va - rious bureaus to be beneficial in eradicating some of the evils of the credit system. Iln some of the western states there have grown up during the past years some of the most rascally practices on the credulity of the kingman that have ever been known. They are robberies of the nest sort, for they not only rob a man of his money, but in many ances of his manhood. The practice I refer to is that of a certain b of employment offices, located usually in the rear of some beer on, which advertise that a large number of men are wanted for labor </seg>
            <seg id="p094">in a certain city, but almost always at a distance. In a western city one of these offices advertised for one thousand men to proceed imme - diately to Washington, D. C, where employment would be furnished at $1 per day. Hundreds of men responded to this advertisement. were obliged to pay down $3 or $4, as the case might be or as the rascality of the manager might demand, and then the men were put off by various excuses for several days, until fhey began to clamor for their contract. When they became too demonstrative, the manager would pay back part of the sum advanced, for the sake of integrity. Meantime, however, these hundreds of men, loafing about his beer - saloon, had expended more or less money for beer, in addition to the aid for the supposed employment. In one city an advertisement appeared for a large number of men to be shipped to Iowa, while in Iowa an advertisement appeared for a large number of men to be shipped to the very place of the first call. The bureaus in some of the states where such practices have been carried on collected the information relative to these offices, and exposed the swindle perpetrated upon the wage receiver. Much good was derived from these reports, and in addition to the laws in existence, others of a more stringent nature followed. I These instances of the direct influence and value of bureaus of of labor are sufficient, it seems to me, to prove beyond any stion their right to exist, their right to the sympathy and support he public, and their right to ample equipment and means for carry - on their beneflcient work. But they have another office to perform, eh is one of the leading offices of statistics in every direction, and : is the correction of false impressions and the removal of apprehen - , and two or three instances of this kind may perhaps be of service. The statement is usually made by writers on the labor question from the capitalistic point of view that the prosperity of the savings - banks of the country represents absolutely the prosperity of the work - ingman — that the total amount of savings in such banks clearly indi - cates the prosperity of labor. -I am not disposed to question this state - ment, so far as it applies as a principal, but I question the degree of accuracy contained in it, for the investigations have clearly shown that only about one-half of the deposits in the savings-banks belong to men and women engaged in manual labor or in the toil necessary to the pro - duction of goods. Such a fact properly brought out, simply sets people's thoughts in the right direction, although it does not disprove the sentiment underlying the erroneous statements regarding the con - ns involved. In 1878 a great deal was said about the unemployed in this country. It was reported, and the report was very industriously circulated, that there were from 2* people out of employment in Massa - chusetts, 4(^000 in the city of Boston alone, and I in the United States. These figures were quoted in newspapers, works on political -my, speches in Congress, political resolution intil they </seg>
            <seg id="p095">came to be believed everywhere and yet no attempt was made officially or otherwise, to ascertain the real facts. The Bureau of Statistics of Labor of Massachusetts undertook to make an investigation of the sub - md this it did at two separate canvasses, one in June, 18 78, and the other in November of the same year. The result showed that in that Commonwealth, on June 1, there were I i lied and unskilled laborers, male and female, out of employment, seeking and in want of work, and that in November there were not more than 23 000 of the tame class. On th&gt; uld not have beon ovt-r 460.UH0 un employed able-bodied men and women in the United States, ordinarily having work, out of employment at the time mentioned. The report further showed that in the State mentioned there were in 1875 only 316.450 persons engaged in manufactures and mechanical indu* in occupations upon which they depended for support, whether actually employed or not, and the whole number actually employed in the manufacturing and mechanical pursuits of the State wa 13. If. therefore, there had been 2iH),oon oi I persons out of employment In the State in .In is the alarmists were in the habit of stating. there could have been hardly any left in the factories and work-shops of the community. The figures published by the report were used all over the country, and completely reversed the popular belief relative to the vast number of the alleged unemployed in the country. But I think one of the most striking instances of the removal of false impressions from the public mind relates to mortgage in.: on real estate. In a speech made in Congress in May, IMS, the statement was quoted from an agricultural paper that the estimated mortgage in - debtedness of all real estate in Ohio at that time was $7' Indiana^ $39s : in Illinois, | onsin. t 00;* in Michigan. $#&gt;&lt;; in Iowa. $3ol.0H0.&lt;)0&lt;&gt;: and - nients were made for other states. The Ohio and Michigan Bureaus of Statistics of Labor undertook to investigate this subject, through the offices of the registers of deeds, the boards of assessors, etc.. and in these two States the mortgage indebtedness, as established and estimated by the Commissioners of Labor, was, for Ohio, $330,999,205^ and for Mich - igan, $129,229,553, instead of the amounts popularly claimed. Under the Federal cencus of 1890 an investigation was made relative to mortgage indebtedness, and the facts established with remarkable accu - racy for the other States just named. By the investigation of tht sus it was shown that in Indiana the mortgage indebtedness is $11". - 730,643; in Illinois, $384,299,150; in Wisconsin, 111 nd in Iowa, $199,774, 171. It is a little remarkable that the sums accepted in a popular way for the mortgage indebtedness of the States named were in some instances exactly the valuation of all the property of the State. The extravagant figures quoted were used all over this country and in Europe, wherever capitalists were seeking investments in this country. The figures did immense harm; the wrong cannot be calculated; but </seg>
            <seg id="p096">labor and from the Census Office are removing the apprehension which grew out of the original statements. Another feature relative to mortgages relates to the causes for which mortgages are placed upon farms in the western country. It has been claimed in recent years that the great mortgage indebtedness of western States is due largely to disaster or adversity. The Commis - sioner of Labor of Nebraska undertook to satisfy himself, by positive investigation, as to the truth or falsity of such claims, and he took as the territory for his investigation the county of Sarpy, covering the period from December 31, 1879 to January 1 is one of the oldest counties in Nebraska, and it therefore offered the best opportu - nities for investigation in that State. The result, as to the causes for the creation of the mortgage indebtedness of the county, is shown in the following statement, taken from Commissioner Jenkin's report for --90: Purchase money per cent Permanent improvements I per cent Purchase stockk per cent To meet personal obligations ' per cent To invest in real estate 7.00 per cent To invest in mercantile business ■ per cent Sickness ■ per cent Unknown causes ■ per cent Allowing that all the mortgages from sickness and from unknown causes were the result of misfortune or of adversity of some kind, the foregoing table shows that 92 % per cent were for legitimate causes. ■ such causes as indicated prosperity rather than adversity. The investigation under the eleventh United States cencus compre- hends the object of indebtedness for 102 selected counties in several States, the results being obtained by personal inquiry through the experts of the office. That investigation is a clear and emphatic cor - roboration of the results arrived at by Commissioner Jenkins of Ne - braska. It shows that to legitimate objects, indicating clearly pros - perity and advancement, 94.37 per cent of all the mortgage indebted- ness of the 102 counties considered must be attributed. The convict labor question is one that has attracted a great deal of Iition during the last quarter of a century, but it was not until jus State bureaus and the United States Department of Labor cted exhaustive statistics relative to productive employments in tentiaries and other penal institutions and showed the effect of rent systems of employing convicts that the discussion took intelli - shape. There has been much reform along the lines of convict r. Many States have made experiments which have been aban - sd, while others have established new systems which are progress - favorably; in the whole work the contributions of labor statistics have been of the greatest possible value. • </seg>
            <seg id="p097">ated by the exhaustive publications of different departments and bureaus of statistics of labor relative to industrial education. It is only recently that the different States of the Union have felt it incumbent upon them, through their legislatures, to study all the phases of industrial training, consisting of manual training, trade school instruction, and the higher technological or university work which is done in our institutes of technology. The United States Bureau of Education has aided the dis cussion and consideration of such matters, and its work has been grandly supplemented by the State bureaus and the United States De - partment of Labor. It is now possible to discuss the question of industrial education in all its phases not only intelligently but on the basis of practical experience in this and other countries. I These few instances show the enormous value of statistics in remov - apprehension and in correcting erroneous views. The money e of such information is not easy to calculate. In September, 1883, the heads of the few bureaus of st labor then existing met at Columbus, Ohio, and organized onal Convention of Chiefs and Commissioners of Bureaus of Statistics of La - bor. Since then these officials have met annually for the purpose of dis - tig statistical methods and the best way of collecting information and of tabulating, analyzing, and presenting it. It was of the early dreams of the founders of this convention that some uniform contem - poraneous work could be undertaken by all the bureaus in co-operation, but this dream was fraught with many difficulties. States did not or - ganize their bureaus at the same time. Many of the subjects which had been covered by those organized at early dates formed the subje&lt; investigation of those which had been established at later dates, and hence there was conflict; for the earlier bureaus did not wish to ■ again what was new and important to the more receni ished ones. Another difficulty arose in the fact that the industries and con - ditions of one State were not common to all States having bureaus of statistics of labor. Notwithstanding the fact that the original idea has not been and cannot be carried out, the convention has been of the greatest possible value to the different States. At each annual meeting each Commissioner of Labor reports the investigations he has had in hand, the methods he has adopted for obtaining the information desired, and all the difficulties and complications attending his work. These mat - ters are then discussed and the experience of older Commissioners brought out for the benefit of those who have more recently come into the work of gathering statistics of labor. Thus great advantage is given to even the older Commissioners to gain fresh inspiration from, the troubles and difficulties of those who are new to the work. The conven - tion also helps to call public attention not only to the value but to the methods of the work being conducted. &gt; Notwithstanding all that I have said relative to the value and influ - e of the statistics of labor, I am perfectly well aware that they could made of far greater value; but that greater value can only be se- 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">cured through the direct action of the legislative bodies behind the bureaus. They are very poorly equipped. They need more men and more money. They need experience, which can only come through the influence of the executives of the States. With a longer tenure of office and an increase in the equipment and means of the bureaus, their future usefulness can be made to far excel that of the past and of the present. The lines of work which they can undertake are numer - ous and inexhaustable. Knowledge of production is absolutely essential for the adjustment of many of the difficult questions we are facing to - day, and any contribution, through statistical Investigation or other - wise, that will enable both the capitalist and his employee to more clearly understand the real conditions of production should be welcomed by all elements of the comumnity. The bureaus must be kept in the future, as in the past, free from partisanship. The statistician is not a statistican when he is an advocate, no matter how skillful he may be In the manipulation of figures. He must be impartial, he must make his Investigations without any reference to theories to be proved or dis - proved, and give to the world the actual results of his inquiries. This country lacks trained statisticians. We have no means for training them, except in the practical work of the statistical offices of the State and federal governments. These offices, therefore, become a school for the future, and the statisticians of this country that» are to be of great service to the government must acquire their knowledge through the statistical offices; but no work can be accomplished successfully with - out money and without men. We must look, therefore, to the legisla - tive branches of our various governments for the increase of the useful- </seg>
            <seg id="p099">The Value of Statistics to Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p100"/>
            <seg id="p101">THE VALUE OF STATISTICS TO NEBRASKA The Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics seeks, by the dissem - ination of official to the world the commercial, .'. and labor conditions of the commonwealth and the resc ■which we have, not only to support, but to further increase the indus - trial enterprises within our borders. Its reports and various publications are for the purpo - veying to the people of our eastern states, the information I aska compares well with the leading states of this republican Union of ours and to dissipate the many laughable and ridiculous impressions which exist concerning the state's primitiveness. It desires to enlighten eastern capital to the fact that the buying of Nebraska real estate is a safe and extraordinarily paying investment. It wishes to inform the farmer not entirely satisfied with his lot in the congested farming communi - ties of the east that here in Nebraska we have lands which may be pur - chased at a much cheaper price than that which he now possesses, but which can be excelled no where in fertility and produi The reports are desired to herald to the higher class of foreign immigrants that the land of freedom and plenty, in search of which they bade fare - well to a land of monarchial institutions and peonage, can be found upon the broad valleys and rolling uplands of a country, of which a I traveler once said "The Sun and Moon conceived and the issue was Nebraska." To the lawyer and physician, the merchant and bu - man, the writer and teacher, the mechanic and laborer, in fact all endowed with brain and brawn and with the attributes which would contribute to the upbuilding of a high standard of citizenship, a: tended inducements, which the natural qualifications of Nebraska hold forth, together with the hearty welcome of the people of Nebraska. The bureau desires to attract attention to that "Star of En. which, to the easterner, is perched upon the western horizon and which impresses all with the unquesionable truth tha ward Ho' Star of Agriculture has taken its wa -aska today ranks third in the production of corn. Yet little more than a biennium has pinned since a high official of the U. S. Department of Agriculture refused to include Nebraska within the corn belt and it necessitated the pressure of statistics and a trip of observation to convince him of his error and compel his withdrawal of the embarge placed upon the state's agricul- </seg>
            <seg id="p102">tural standing. If such an opinion could exist in th whose duties should necessarily ecquaint him with status of states, what must be the opi of easterners less qualified to judj education of the east to the advantages and There lies the great duty of the Bureau of Statistics. When conscier P educational medium than statistics. When official and impregnated throughout with the seed of truth The statistician in charge of the coi other aim or object than to have exl out with truth and reliability. For v great a crime and felony upon his part, as is the misappropriation of as TV and robs the state of p repaired and reimbursed by him and his bondsmen; the on name of a state can only be regained in its former wortt w effort and diligent use of the truth once assaulted. Theref&lt; ician when once the statistics of his department have esta bility, has resting upon him a spons at as any other servant of the peopk From the many misleading rep&lt; institutions having p« for hone s wealth and which he knows v w of the educational machine pose of educating the resid of people without tt industries of the stat v may exist t fast. Its in \ w r th n in •• t i than Kai is $1,000 i tv ier ven t The sta Illinois and Iowa on od ar z. corn, wt princip al nd ranks second only to Iowa among the states comprising the Trans-M tiously and honestly collected and public funds by a trusted serva boards of trade, grain associatio to the figures prepa with $14 Nebraska While these figure sister states in indi </seg>
            <seg id="p103">i •r *• *• </seg>
            <seg id="p104">representative persons of good judgment and intelligence. It is necess - ary to have those whose judgment can be relied upon to give accurate reports and estimates. Second, it is hard to secure those who will take an interest in the work and who will continue to act year in and year {It is also of prime importance to secure men for this duty who will : have an interest in the character of the report sent in. The Bureau Is that in the year and a half's efforts it has succeeded in overcoming i difficulties and has established a splendid service of correspondents the number of nine hundred in the state. Ten reporters have been ured in each county; in some of the larger counties more were secur- These are located in various localities and are authorized to esti - mate and report crops within a radius of ten miles of their residence. Tin- Bureau during 1903 and 1904 has issued eight reports and Bulletins aggregating 30,000 copies. These have found their way to all parts and corners of the globe. The reports have dealt with both industrial and agricultural matters giving statistics upon the volume of business in all industries and the agricultural production in all the countidft. An idea of the ground covered can be obtained from the fol - lowing statement of the various channels in which our investigations are made: Manufactories and Wage Meat Packing Industry. Railroad Statistics, The Diary Industry, Flouring and Grist Mills Labor Organizations, Reports of Strikes and Lockouts Municipal Statistics, Ecclesiastical, School and Professional Condition Criminal Statistics, Lodges and Fraternal Societies, Charity and Charitable Institutions, Nebraska's Surplus Products, Crop Production and Crop Conditions Quarterl General Agricultural Conditions, Land Values and Conditions The results of these investigations and enumerations are published quarterly in bulletins which are given as wide distribution as possible. Eastern real estate and investment interests especially are anxious for them as they are invaluable in giving a detailed resume of each county. Without them an investment may&gt;go elsewhere for want of information. It is our aim that the information therein may be the means of attract - ing investments and imnifpration. If the state produces so much of some crop and it shows good for the state we want the world to know about it. If we ship out of the state more than some European nations we want to let the world know about it and cause people to realize that </seg>
            <seg id="p105">liDBEAl- OF I.ABHK we have an inland empire here in Nebraska with an agricultural wealth of unlimited proportions. In the past the Bureau has done much In supplying the great demand for statistical literature but vastly more coTild be done were the office equipped with greater facilities for work on a larger scale. The western half of Nebraska is showing wonderful improvement. It is imperative that the east be kept fully informed and impressed with this development if we expect to obtain those mediums of greater de - velopment — capital and settlement. In Nebraska we have no vast fields of mineral wealth which in themselves are sufficient attraction for investments, but we do have a marvelous agricultural wealth and we nave an area of 29 000,000 acres which has laid dormant but which today shows its value under the tutoring hand of irrigation. The entire area is rapidly undergoing a natural conversion from semi-aridity to productive fertility. As our agricultural resources and productivity increase, as it is doing each year, there must needs be opportunities for iring the location of manufacturing enterprises adapted to agrieui pamphlets have proven of great interest in inducing immigrants to their states. I especially refer to tb* state of Kansas. Nebraska has been very much behind in this important department in the past. "The effect of such statistics on the prospective immigrant or land purchaser is to give him accurate data from which he can determine the advisability of locating in Nebfaska, by comparing what she has to officer with that of similiar statistics of other states. "I think nonresidents, who are seeking information regarding western states, are especially anxious for such information. »"The further increase in the duties, powers and resources of the reau of Labor and Industrial Statistics of this state would certainly - very beneficial. tural communities and dependent upon agricultural products. Dissemi- nation of official literature giving full and detailed data relative to these products, the country which produces them and the industrial possibili- ties throughout the state will be an important factor in accomplishing such a purpose. The following voluntary indorsements and expressions are given publicity .here in order to give those, who may not come directly in con- tact with the good done by the Bureau's publications, an idea of how the latter are appreciated by the interests that know, by experience, the good accomplished. G. W. WATTLES, ESQ., PRESIDENT OMAHA GRAIN EXCHANGE, OMAHA, NEBRASKA: — "I deem the disseminating of statistics and other information re- garding the State of Nebraska of great value. Other western states have for many years been very acUxfi in securing and publishing accurate statistics regarding crop conditions, values of products, etc.. and their </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 NIAL REPORT OF h VJ \J W t\ l\ t \ ,"i \\ _■ 1 Aj\ r J ■ fc" 1^7 | ■*■ * I i I ™ * J J I * ■ »' li U 1' ("We desire to thank you for your kindness in sending us copies of Lugust bulletin from your bureau giving statistics as to the pro - ons in the state, acreage and yield of crops, and other valuable in - ation. Rest assured we appreciate the work of the bureau for we a not know of any other source from which to obtain the informa - and in such concise and correct form. We have been greatly bene - thereby. »"We believe these bulletins have a salutary effect upon newcomers, prospective purchasers of land. Recently we had an inquiry for this niation from parties as far east as New York State, and a few days we handed a copy to the editor of a financial journal in Chicago, seemed delighted to get it in the columns of his paper. In this way nformation would be dissiminated over a large area." 0. J. MILKS. MAYOR CITY OF HASTINGS HASTINGS, NKB:— t"I want to thank you for your letter giving me the yield of the sev - ils in the counties comprising the Fifth Congressional District ebraska. I appreciate fully the privilege it was to be able to call for receive so quickly, reliable information along this line. Undoubted - our Department is valuable in furnishing accurate memoranda to pectlve settlers and enterprises." MR. BERNARD MONNICH, REAL ESTATE &amp; MORTGAGE LOANS HOOPER, NEBRASKA: — I "To a State whose resources are as undeveloped as those of Nebras - e sending out of statistical and other information is greatly beneflc- It would be more generally used by those interested in the devel - ient of the state if at all times readily obtainable. The prospective investor or home seeker is always on the alert for reliable information. Statistical matter of an official nature issued by a State Bureau created for that purpose is considered by immigrants and prospective investors the best information that can be obtained. It is dered reliable and carries more weight than any other kind of ad - vertising matter. "The Kansas State Board of Agriculture has been a greater factor in developing the state of Kansas than any other. It ought to be a source of pride to any one interested in the developement of the state of Nebraska to have the powers, duties and resources of the Bureau of Labor increased so that it will be more efficient than that of any other R. C. PETERS &amp; CO., INVESTMENT BANKERS, OMAHA, NEB: — "We have used to good advantage the reports and buletins of the Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics in the way of sending them to our investors. We have a large number of clients as you probably know. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 having loaned about 1 6,0 00 000, largely for private clients. We send these reports to them and think they have done a great deal of good and been the means of bringing a good deal of money into the state. I note in the different places where we lend they have these reports and refer to them and think it has been of considerable assistance to us. Of course the more money brought into the state the cheaper the rates and the better it is for the farmers." STULL BROTHERS. OMAHA, NEBRASKA: — "We believe the value of the Bureau of Labor and Industrial Sta - tistics is greatly under estimated by most people. The bulletins issued by your bureau have been of great value to our office which you can readily see from the many requests we have made for additional copies to be sent to our eastern correspondents. Some of our eastern clients. who are most all investors, have requested to send them soon as your bulletins are isued, a copy of same and we know they are referring to them right along. We believe that the more concise statistics your bulletin contains the better it is. It has aided us greatly in our ability to dispose of loans to eastern parties." r. CHARLES F. MAXDERSON, GENERAL SOLICITOR B. ft M R. R. CO., OMAHA, NEBRASKA: — I "Suffice it for me to say that the Bureau of Labor and Indus - 1 Statistics seems to me to have justified its existence in this state, s resources and capabilities of the state should be truthfully and care - y investigated and information thereon should be given to the world arge. Unquestionably there is a desire, not only in the eastern coun - i but abroad, for accurate information with reference to the ; ties of the life in the state of Nebraska, and with the new conditions are being taken under because of the Kinkaid bill and the irrigation ernes, it is of prime importance that these statistics should receive le circulation. "In the past the main work in setting forth the advantages of the state has been dony by the railroad companies, and they are still per - forming great service in that direction. It certainly is the duty of the state to join in this effort." I No class of citizens are more interested than those whom we find le various commercial bodies generally denominated "Commercial is." Each club is a community builder. Each is making every effort ible to develop, advance and promote the interests of the commu - in which it exists.. Therefore it is reasonable to believe that the sus clubs are entirely competent to determine the channels through ■h the state as a whole and the communities separately derive ma - il benefit. It is therefore not out of place to append the following lutions which were adopted at the state meeting of the State As - ition of Commercial Clubs held in the city of Fremont, February </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 BIENNIAL REPORT OK 6th and 7th. 190D. The resolutions are conclusive of benefits haying been accomplished in the past by the Bureau and are worthy of consider- ation in connection with what may be done in the future. rlREAS: It is the sense of this Association that sufficient efforts and means are not being expended in portraying the resources, ad - -es and opportunities of the State of Nebraska, and I It is fully impressed upon th&gt; ion that this com - monwealth should follow the policies of in the matter of education along statictical and industrial lines which have brought within their boundaries increased population, capital and other economic benefits, and WHEREAS: The State of Nebraska has a State Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics which embodies the Association's idea of the^ form and methods of industrial and agricultural education, and while we endorse and commend the work of the Bureau in the past as having performed great good for the state, it is the opinion of this State Association of Commercial Clubs of Nebraska that the powers and means of this Bureau be Increased sufficient to allow of more extensive work along statistical lines commensurate with the demands of our industrial conditions, therefore, be it RESOLVED: By the Nebraska State Association of Commercial Clubs that we urge and petition the Legislature of the State of Nebraska the advisability of appropriating as large a portion as necessary of the unexpended balance of the St. Louis Exposition Appropria - tion, amounting to approximately $16,000, or from other funds, for the purpose of placing before the people of the Eastern and Central states the resources, wealth and opportunities of Nebraska. That the appropriation be expended in the direction of more ex - tensive statistical investigations, as conducted by other states, and the dissemination of official liturature, supplemented by a cam - paign of illustrated lectures in the east with the "Moving Picture Exhibit" used by the Nebraska Commission at the St. Louis Expo - sition and which is now in the possession of the State of Nebraska. Adopted unanimously at Fremont, Neb., February 7, 1905. Committee, MR. JOHN F. FLACK of Omaha, MR. J. P. HANSEN of Fremont, MR. W. C. KERR of Central City. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">Statistical Tables </seg>
            <seg id="p110"/>
            <seg id="p111">raoisno A\i\ -pnioaj 'saonp -oij jo ani«A » cix ■ ©26 * 1- r-i — « ss i-5 • ■-0CM pasn s[«u*iBHJO1soo S3^ as * S3^ i- e «s oc o&gt; "9«"-c £25=° sasuadxa -"1-" « — X SSg rr £ - 8 1 z s H c: o 1- B « X t- erf pi" re 1- • non epfeo" 5 « SI I3qran}i 3 Sod OONO SS 3 o| Hog 3=n'a - -^—•35 83IJU[BS ?S* — s* laqnmii ~ ?l 3, N v2 Ui -r O 3. &gt;M • t— r- as c: O t- X -^ o t— 35 oic- 1-5; • 00 «~ « S O f^5 r*5 CO O (M O co — &lt; 35 f.t- ■ — ifl 35 S3 as -sg jo jaqumjj — ■"-," 85^ a s 0Ct;O ■•• S r: J«9A r^ I&gt;H r-t &lt;— • — — i-H s as GC i B O ■ hi p "o 3 ! I ■ fc-. p e9 o I o I 3 "5 a r 3 X OS 8 V- I • </seg>
            <seg id="p112">8aui«daj DUB 5(JOM IUO) rfll I pil[DUl '8}.llip -oj«£ jb 8ni«A MO »^ 00 c*5 ?4 S3 ■ « as-* «» paao O CO f! CO ■" 2^ « -r as -«■ CM 33 CD to 1 B9BaddX3 snoouvn I- CD si si Kg 5^1 — 9 r i-- 838«A §5 00 00* O ~— —&lt; J.XHUIlly So ao « N II jaqti trTcT SI s's" 2S US ss" if 3 * lO0O_ ao 33 i s 3 C5 t e rft« e»fcf jo aaqur ns gs 88 "^ -^ OS -• S3 eao a »— FN — — *^ — — — di I -tf ■ as • -2 ; L. • 0 e if 1 u I B It i O OQ • o o, K 4* o c .£ C c 3. -a* B O I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p113"/>
            <seg id="p114">114 -91 pav hiom. raoasno 8uj •pnioaj -sjonp 8 2 • i-i« on n-.-on 35 t- 8 2S2 CO — 00 pasn — -- r— •&lt;• ® — &gt; x co s us" ♦ no ♦ ■MO 89SU9dX3 g 8 iD^at * — !*^ 7»? 3S O i — i- c c J CO 8 if** N " S CM a 10s! *4 ,1 I I 4fr » M *r rt &lt;* o r- CD SO 8 cc q r— O O S S sato.u a 8 »o n f 3» w - CO CD 30 "^ co oo c3 o "• •&gt;»• Is 2§g S3I«I«S s 8* S~ *O Cb tr- —* *D C-i ■Z&gt;?S ?* •^ e^ •**« f^ o *m — 1-TiH • SO 00 00° aoqum^ — -IOJCC "8" '" 1 - - o — &lt; -r — ■ !■■■ *C o«r 8 CM M « N r— r— US "~ r^ c^ ?o ffinaraqsiiqw} g ="* -8a jo aaqranjii « — &lt; s&gt; oc xi M g^O - 3 ■^ I ?! - i II J * ill 111 &amp;3 r^-f - § s|3a^ J *g Si g « J </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 ■ go" *- ©*k~ r:".-' — "^~ aT r -J o n n ■ as n sc® ooow gjajMicja -; r~. -r — ~ — - ■» »- S RN — 3C &gt;.-; *■) c — t iao_ rt irf r-T ag^sT ifl'r-'ao'iff cf^«^»f =TsT us" or « io &lt;s — a&gt;»t)« t — &lt; — ao — n ■» — i — .- S ICO *A 00r- DOM® C^OQ»C'M» -f Mt"NI9OOt *1 J6 -h O » r-n 3i O -^ — ■• qp— »^X— — — — t . -^i -i" irT 0 HiiHlHfff iiffiillliil liliiiii Q fc. i,5M iiiSc iSB^hU iJ SSSSCP-3- a&lt; a« H — « 3» S i- f r- — . ® — — r- ■ -«. -m O6*-h ;e Fi ~* 00 M -* Or— r™ O &amp;&gt; rr^-r-— OOt^ 00 S«. «5 © « o» &lt;- - S5 ao W — • W Ob ■ 35 35 © © © t- X »-C O * C-1 © -r-H -r 3 x-m r «ri-f ~ £ — ~* -^ 3c a? ST~1 5 f^ CC -S C-IM 3D » M t-M 3&gt; 5S O 115 -t I ?1 t- O O ?5 O O a © te ?j :iioxS — M— &lt;» — i o— . •«&lt; - C4 — "■■ 30 C*3 i-^ CO - 1 Or- © co **o sco^»cd oc5po:occcd n io c x o n r: c© o j» *-»»-H CJCQ W »-- CJ n — — i- ,.-3 Kl ife: :J: :j:i: : : : : :|itrf: •■Bil: :i:$:*i |li I I 1 I Jig. Ifff 1 I 11 IH li ft !i ill ! i: Hililu 1 »tel I' 35" 3- :* •^ O »« 3b • ?J . — 00 r- S"5 . « 3&gt; «r S3 r- r- g" • A t^ • CO w* ei ® ao »o co • o CO • M CO 0» "I </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 SB -8J piIK JiJOM luujsno u I -pniouj 'sionp pasn °o StlO3U l El[H jaqtnnfj OD © B *»an,ii x — — 3C •r — efa» — — ■ — — 3C •r — a» 8 s OD O i— •» w -*■ o o I s " • • e '. '. " jh li] hi ill US' mo s: i - i - US' MSMCJ * t- as tC — ri oo 8" CD*"* ■ : : n II |1 S '■»&gt; It :i; X — 3i — »l §sa tftf i 3 1 2 M ac I ISM 00 IO oc r- ei as — ■ P : : B 1 : :» l • • e i : j] J | ;■; 111' 'II ~5| |f| PiPiP !! IlliBtliillfl * : •-l«gM|Bl-ia ? I liifii pHhl Sis §islSr.sis5si- ™ J3qmn&amp; C. f- 31 00 lit- P5 r- 00 I s " S.r.2 8" »-&gt;*• oc ■»• i— i ■sg ;o j»qian(j x ■• «■♦•«&gt; ■a °°8 as D Q i— i : :S : : -± : :E : : : :g : : :j? : :&gt; : : I 11 M ijf j|li|H|!! flfl*filie§= sSl IIS 5£ ? </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTIONS, 1904. . ndustrial and agricultural, in 19&lt;&gt;4 ap. proxiruat d $500,000,000, being the highest annual output in ti of the state. The following tible gives the detailed valuati tons of the state's productions. At this date it is ini(&gt; give exact figures on all items, consequently estimates are ne&gt; some items, and the same have been obtained from the most autl. sources. The 'imates: VALUE OF NEBRASKA'S PRODUCTIONS, 1904. NEBRASKA'S SURPLUS COMMODITIES, 1903. t following table shows the principal surplus commodities of Nebraska shipped during the year 1903 : Corn Wheat Oats Barley 1 . 1 Hay Potatoes •Sugar Beets. . •All other soil crops •Dairy Products 11 •Poultry Hi Live Stock •Manufactured Products? 175.000,000 00 Total »501, 582,190 83 Whe»t, Bushels 27,327 365 Corn, " 42.4 OtU. " 15,1' Barley, " 509 7» Rye, "" 3,051,030 Hay, Tons l Cattle, Head 9«y.li9 Hogs, '• 2,1 Sheep. " 870,495 Horses and Mules, Head Flour, Pounds 313,334,674 Mill Feed, Pounds 90,4 Potatoes, Bushels Butter Pounds Eggs, Dozens Live Poultry, Pounds 9,580,600 r\rnf-nafl Vniilfrvw PnnnHa * ..■ * - . to L/reaaea jruuiirj, ruuuus. 4,ooo,U3o </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 CORN IN S" ijli RASK.A . Acreage and Production for Ten Years. Year. Acreage. At. Yield Per Acre. Production, Bushels. 904 903 9t&lt;2 901 900 699 898 897 1896 1895 6 173,984 6,130.369 5 516,801 5,853,967 6,291.050 6,436.918 i.746 36.7 27.6 32.0 12.37 22.83 27.3 21.0 30.0 37.5 16.1 226.959 194 169,693,965 176,537,632 72,445,227 143.650,317 175,816,641 158,754,666 241,268.490 298,599,638 125,685,069 WHEAT IN fEB BASRA. Acreage and Produi .ion for Ten ' ears. Year. Acreage. Av. Yield Per Acre. Production, Bushels. 904 903 902 901 900 899 81* "97 *96 895 2.024,667 *.592 ".,043 1,232,252 15.7 18.3 20.9 20.4 16.2 9.8 16.4 14.5 14.0 12.0 31,825,850 43,660,318 53,468,472 50,227,484 37.748,24 ,-%100 34,679,309 27.4 19.39C.6O2 14,787.024 OATS IN N EBUASKA. Acreage and Product tion for Ten ears. Year. Acreage. At. Yield Per Acre. Production, Bushels. 1904 1903 1902 1901 1900 1899 1898 1897 !S 2,146,324 1,958,721 1,638,647 1,577,936 1,424,948 1,628,501 31.12 34.0 32.0 17.92 23.49 31.7 32.1 31.0 19.0 23.8 52^436*704 28,287,707 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">BCRKAU OF LABOR RYE IN NEBRASKA. Acreage and Production for Six Years. Av. Yield Production, Bushels Acreage Per Acre 16 6 29.4 18.0 2,035,802 10,1c 8,7c 2,3:; 15.0 14.2 16.0 997,104 BARLEY IN NEBRASKA Acreage and Production for Six Years. Av. Yield Per Acre Production, Bushels Acreage 27.9 5,50'- 25.0 1,9* ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 BIENNIAL REPORT OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTIONS — Corn, 1904. COUNTY Acreage Ay. Yield PerAcre Production, bushels Farm Value ope banner Bla i ne Box Butte Brown Buffalo liUl ICl • • ••••■■• ■ ry Dakota l)awes I &gt;awson Dixon . . r&gt;ouglas ly Fillmore Frontier Greeley Hvaiiion........... ...... Hdrlan Hitchcock Hooker Kearney ■■ imja •••••••• *•••• 57,948 115,486 2,333 5,214 103,109 5,188 51,480 31,597 126,739 84,068 117,145 145,091 29,280 19,381 100,594 103.122 152,955 43,343 3,372 115,690 14,«33 113.1HJ4 73,072 168,489 14,346 68,908 47^498 81,104 101,116 - 39,349 26,070 93,599 1,425 77,053 100,722 63,511 78,251 9,160 28,3*9 566 103.171 30.7 38.2 2.i.0 22.0 34.3 16.0 30.1 28.3 38.3 43.2 35.2 19.0 17.0 19.0 41.8 39 2 37.7 38.0 40.8 22.4 32.6 33 6 39.7 38.8 23.0 40.7 39.4 31.6 37.8 40.3 23.0 36.3 2,300,535 4,411,606 53,659 114,708 3,536,638 83,008 1,415,700 853,119 3,804,843 2, 37M24 4,486.653 6,2e&gt;7,931 3,972.425 556,320 329,477 14' 4,204,828 2,223,110 3,887,699 5,812,290 1,768,394 75,532 3,771,494 ".,586 2,768.774 4,010.216 2,701,644 643,908 4,601,704 2,879,036 3,491,199 3,461,937 6,790,106 329,958 2,501,360 1,544/ l,57o!328 55 2,193. 1,380.' 194 ~ 115. 1,477,' 680 15 2&gt; (VIA r J&gt; 618,937 90 26,436 20 1,320,022 90 103,455 10 969,070 m 1,403." "&gt;75 40 :i67 80 1,610., 1,007,' 1,221,919 65 1,211,677 95 2,»76,537 10 115,485 30 875,476 00 31.4 41.9 42.6 38.8 28.0 28.2 31.3 22.0 38.4 42.2 41.5 3V.2 20.3 20.2 16.0 35.5 1,491,437 3,39S 4,307,541 5,006.t',74 1,101,772 735.174 2,929,648 31,350 2,958.836 4,250,468 2,635,706 3,067,439 185,948 572,447 9,056 3,662,570 522.002 95 .535 90 H20 20 257,310 90 1,025,376 80 10,972 50 1,035,592 25 J, 487, 663 80 922.497 10 1,073,603 65 65,081 80 200,356 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 AGRICULTURAL PRODDCTIONS-Corn, 1904.— Concludfd Acrpairp Av - Yield Production _ „ . Acreage Per Acre buahe|s Farm \ aloe NTY Lancaster I 24' 36.6 9,024,645 $3, 168,6: Lincoln 23 0 1,2 in 24.3 14:;. ip . 10 I son M ick re aha 102, 33.6 3,444. ... .... 36.4 1,575,110 82,430 --.381 Nemalia :olls vOllS Otoe Pawnee Perkins 14.771 14 •■ - 3,034. 4,l«0. Phelps 8&lt; Plat' 4.1K0,2(m 1,4 Polk Red Willow I «•■ Willow ardson . . Richardson .470 ' e r ders 28.0 Scott's Bluff ,rd 1(H Sheridan ; 1 18 0 34.4 1 Sherman Sioux Stanton j 81,718 "Ihayer 109.710 1 4,300,- Thomas 3,096 19.7 Thurstoo ■ ington 78 37.8 ie .'.'. 13, 36.0 3. Webster 9- 38.6 3. Wheeler 11,729 20.0 4,354. York 101 6,17:&lt; Total 36.7 194 l «79.4 </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTIONS— Wheat, 1904 At. Yield Production, Per Acre bushels Farm Value COUNTY Acreage Adams. 64,472 15.0 967,080 1802,676 40 158,7 11.956 16.0 191,296 Antelope 2,261 11.6 26,2 36 12.5 2,261 11.6 26,227 21,7 373 50 Banner '* 12.5 450 Blaine 36 Boone 22,304 15.2 339.020 281,38b 60 15.2 339.020 1.330 12.0 15.!*i0 13,1-46 80 12.0 Box Butt«. 12,700 12,700 16.3 207.010 171.818 30 16.3 207.010 5,908 16.0 168 24 5,908 16.0 Brown. Buffalo 421 16.2 651,068 60 16.2 13,109 13.109 15.0 163.207 05 15 0 Burt. 4H.217 14.0 647. 537,041 54 Rut Icr 14.0 20.725 16.8 34&gt;- 989 40 16.8 7.737 15.0 116,1 96,325 65 15.0 Cedar. 7,737 4.*25 13.0 62.: &gt;tU 75 13.0 62.725 831 12.7 46,113 J73 79 12.7 Cheyenne •74 13.0 116,662 96,82!) 46 13.0 17.0 1,442,943 1,197,642 69 17.0 14.578 14.578 15.0 219,670 182,326 10 15.0 219,670 306,195 130,052 58,903 610,995 U3 15.0 306,195 254.141 86 Cum ing. 20.413 15.0 36.053 16.0 576. 478,783 84 36,053 16.0 10,004 13.0 130,052 107,943 16 Dakota 10,004 13.0 r.i22 ,M22 11.5 58,903 11.5 389 49 507,125 85 40,733 15.0 610,995 507,125 85 40,733 15.0 2,287 13.0 29,731 24,676 73 13.0 29,731 24,676 73 139,283 13 255,774 46 10,621 15.8 167,811 139. - 15.8 167,811 Dixon 21,107 14.6 308,162 255,774 46 Dodge 14.6 308,162 2,376 13.9 33,026 27.411 58 2,376 13.9 Douglas J10 15.0 33,150 27,514 50 Dundy . 15.0 79.660 16.8 1,338,288 1,110,779 04 16.8 Fillmore. Franklin 41,063 16.7 685,752 569,174 16 16.7 41,071 15.9 653,028 542,013 24 15.9 Frontier. 63,135 16.8 1,060,668 54 44 Furnas 16.8 63,413 17.2 1,090,703 905,2*3 49 17.2 1,720 13.3 22,876 18,'- 13.3 22.876 Garfleld Gosner. 33,218 33,218 15.0 498,270 413,564 10 15.0 498,270 Grant. ' 7^782 14!6 108^948 "90,42$ M Greeley 7,782 14.0 32.089 32.089 16.2 519,841 431,468 03 16.2 Hamilton. 71.611 16 8 1,203.064 "43 12 71,611 16 8 68,457 16.0 1,095,312 909. 10« 96 16.0 3.361 ;61 12.0 40.332 33.475 56 12.0 Hitchcock 27.392 15 0 410. 341/ 5,121 14.3 73.230 60.7 15 0 5,121 14.3 80 13.0 1.040 13.0 1.040 80 Howard 26,479 26,479 14.8 391,889 325/267 87 14.8 391,889 Jeff- rson 35,167 16.2 569.705 472,856 15 35,167 16.2 569.705 22.310 15.9 354.729 294.4 \'5 07 Johnson 22.310 15.9 354.729 1,081,973 Kearney 70.268 15.4 1,081,973 898.' 1.860 12.8 23,808 19.760 64 70.268 15.4 23,808 Keith 1,860 12.8 Kera Paha 5,067 5,067 11.5 58,270 MM 10 11.5 58,270 694 12.0 8,328 6,912 24 12.0 8.328 Kimball 694 2,112 13.8 138,730 35 - </seg>
            <seg id="p123">123 AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTIONS-Wheat, 1904.— Concluded COUNTY Acreage At. Yield Per Acre Production, bushels Farm Value Lancaster Lincoln I _ nf tn •••••••••••■•••••••• Madison Me Pherson Nemaha Pawnee Perkins Phelps Richardson Saunders Seward Sheridan Sherman Stan ton Thtyer Thomas Thurston Washington Wayne Webster Wheeler 6,000 7,107 893 2,780 9,015 7J6O9 19,326 28,648 30.869 15.124 3.239 71.211 34.92:5 779 58,426 4H.722 19. (Kk) 23.173 1.32S 40.714 9J605 14,660 13.456 44,005 1,485 83,193 15.9 14.2 15.0 14.0 14.7 95.400 100,919 13,395 38,920 132,520 •79. 83,7 11,117 85 32,303 60 109,991 60 14.8 15.2 16.0 17.0 16.8 15.7 12.8 17.0 13.6 170 15.8 11.0 16 2 13.7 14 3 10.0 15.0 11.0 13 9 10.4 13 2 15 0 112,613 293,755 458,364 4,773 684,690 237,446 41,459 1,210,587 94,587 357,643 551 79- 316 914,101 32,770 70" 209,660 322,104 13.811 111! 700,710 93,468 70 243,816 65 380,445 44 197,060 18 758 " 18U«0 40 12.5 14.0 13.9 14.0 16.0 13.0 16 5 120,062 298,900 '..774 -.384 704,080 19,305 1,372,684 If 1«K7. i 2,024,667 15.7 31,825,850 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">AGRICULTURAL PRODUC1 IONS— Oats, 1904. Av. Yield Per Acre Pr a c ie r- itanv.i» COUNTY Acreage Aotelope Box Butte Brown Buffalo ng i r Dmkota Dawson i as &lt;&gt;re L lin 20,572 61,414 1,127 501 63,178 1,462 22,045 12,265 44,465 25,571 50,010 65,279 960 3,210 2,213 Mi 32.8 32.5 21.0 22.0 33 0 19.0 30.1 32.3 3(1.5 31.2 35.0 23.0 26 0 32 7 32.6 34 0 3i.O 31.0 31.2 31.5 761 :, fe 74 27, t 78 . 17ti 1.4.1' 480 :&gt;38 7:iti,14O 11.198 1 . 4L"J 431. •168,940 25 417 " !22 00 14,384 50 1-4. '35 (10 2,7 740 00 349 : itier.. ! ........ 29.1 145,120 Furna&gt; 31 5 «ajr- 31.7 8.1 - ilt m : • an 31.9 27.6 k !!;;!!!!!; 27.0 35. 2ti 9 14 Howard Jefferson 31 t; Joh: h ." a Paha 194. Kiii ball Knox.... ..I - i 1,7: 430.6W 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">125 AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTIONS— Oats, 1904. . . At. Yield Production, Vnm — --- Acrea^ Pcr A ,.,... h,, fi v,«u iarm\alue N'TY Per A' bushels Lancaster ■oln p ............... 1,701 210, 67,701 lierson iek 14,*13 31.0 I 31.6 171. 44 nee ti7 1.742 21. ................ Willow ardson 31 4 ardson 314 &lt; ' Saline 33 2 y.... ........... i Huff 114 ders 34 6 114 Huff 29 2 ,rd 42. 1,44" ,rd 42. 34.2 1,447.727 113,124 irian 4,1 idan 4,1 113,124 man x ton 40. 1 , ■ver 31. mas 110 110 | 24. ti Tluirston 19.114 I 122 ! lin'trton ! . ne 44. 31.6 14.- J10 24.0 Tori ... 35.3 1 3'i2.0o&lt;) 2,146.324 I 31.12 $16,7 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTIONS i— Barley, 1904. At. Yield Production, Per Acre bushels COUNTY Acreage 335 23.4 Antelope 1,035 29.5 » 345 20 0 1,581 27.8 Box Butte. 1,648 26.2 1,277 30.7 Brown. 1,175 30.4 Buffalo 1,056 28.3 ■j 3,961 31.0 Butler 570 250 123 26.2 7,751 31.4 27.0 Cherry. 1&lt;2 24.6 enne. 486 23.0 Co If ax 991 24.0 2,081 29.4 2, 142 30.3 CjUst^ r Dakota 886 29 5 2rt.2 27.0 Deuel 220 1,916 sssr 391 l,72.-&gt; ! Fillmore Franklin'. 142 24.0 137 24.5 Frontier. 1,4*1 25.0 2,903 42 26.0 Garfield 3-tf Gosper. 441 24.8 uTPtK') . 1,070 27.2 25.0 Hamilton 344 25.3 Harbin 713 2r,.4 ■,cock 26.1 28.6 Hooker Howard. 806 Jefferson 8 V6.0 Johnson 34 Kearney 204 24.0 23 7 Keya Paha Ki in ball UM 7.643 3u.3 S ! r Farm Value 7,839 t 2,586 87 30,632 10,075 56 6,900 2,277 00 43,951 *i4,*503 83 43.177 14,248 41 39,203 12,936 99 35,720 11,787 60 29,884 9,861 72 122,791 40,521 OS 14,250 4,702 50 3,222 1,063 26 243,381 80,315 73 30,240 9,979 20 2,509 827 97 10,488 3,461 04 23,784 7,848 72 60,181 19,n 64.902 21,417 H6 31i',252 102,383 16 137 8,625 21 51,692 17.058 36 141,210 m 30 19,470 6,42 &lt;S9 18,146 :&lt;7 ".72 6, 1 2 10.126 3,34 41,745 13. 7 3.408 1,124 t&gt;4 156 1,1' 025 12,218 2&amp; 74.607 24,620 31 1.0H2 360 36 T77 3 16 41 10,936 3,608 88 '29404 "9,*604 32 20,175 167 75 8,703 2,871 99 325,791 107,511 03 18.110 76 30 360.702 lKU 43,071 14,213 4J 'ffi^Oe "7;393'98 68 64 286 11 "96 1.H15 68 .71 38 43 24,992 8,214 36 126 767 58 231,582 76,422 06 I , 4*11 1,120 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">AGRICULTURAL PRODUCT • \.S *■' * &amp;\fj % COUNTY * c -*« fcl£? Production, bushels Farm Value Madison McPherson *ha Pawnee Perkins Phelps Saunders Seward Thayer Tbnrston Washington Webster W heeler 2.50 2.047 16 2,454 "309 390 4 85 40 53 141 504 8,556 5,317 46,0H5 10-' 12a 100 518 1. 3,631 93 60 6," 1,663 1,075 8,538 503 259 937 24.9 25.' 6 24.0 24.7 24.9 31.2 30.4 27.6 27 0 24.0 24.6 24.0 28.6 29.7 25.0 121 :, mo 1,(124 i IB] 1,27- 2,163 103 1,572 23,987 23, u 13 Total 196, S44 5,502,725 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 AGRICU LTURALi PRODUCTIONS — Bye. 1904. COUNTY Acreage A v. Yield Per Acre Production, bu&amp;l Farm Value Anttlope 1 ■■anri Blaine Hour if Box Butte Urown Buffalo Butler . . Cuming . Dakota Dawes Dawson Dixon Douglas Flllmore Frontier Furaas Harlan Hitchcock Hooker Howard Jefferson 1 3.796 164 508 2.120 1(»7 3.14ti 414 39 244 217 4,678 13. (i U.5 17.0 17. K 17. « 15.3 16.9 17 0 16.6 13.0 21.0 17.4 18.0 17.5 17.0 lrt.7 17.2 16.9 15 4 14.0 17.5 1,732 13.479 14,076 11,903 4,728 35,192 1,301 11,970 139, 188 58,629 4.270 1,105 6,379 41.230 « 1,03 4,93 15,19 27.4! 1.1' 7,1- 5.151 00 21, li 83, .V 35.177 40 421 20 57 40 18,041 00 333 14.9 17.(1 17.2 17.5 19,206 81,445 •90 40 87, t 45.181 £0 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">129 AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTIONS— Rye, 1904. COUNTY Acreage Av. Yield Per Acre Production, bushels Farm Value Lancaster Lincoln Madison McPherson Nemaha Pawnee Perkins Phelps Richardson Saunders Scott's Bluff Seward 5her&lt;dan Stanton Thayer Thomas Thurston Washington Webster Wheeler 2,000 4,791 301 519 1,710 i.ns 653 77 416 462 45 209 1,307 1,845 1,997 427 3,530 219 679 499 290 1,714 95 431 6,607 2,369 1,649 1.684 719 190 154 2,038 254 486 586 1,408 372 121' 15.2 15.6 14.0 15.0 17.2 15.6 16.2 16.7 15.8 15.0 16.2 13.0 16.0 18.8 15.7 15.9 16.0 16.2 16.5 16.6 15.7 15.5 14.0 16.0 15 2 IS. 4 14 6 18.0 16.3 13.0 16.4 15.1 16.0 18.3 15.2 14 6 15.8 30,400 74,739 4,214 7,785 29,412 26,800 10,428 1,285 6,572 6,930 729 2,717 20,912 34,6«i 31,3C2 56,480 3 547 11,203 26,567 1,330 100, 4:^ 24.075 30.312 11.719 2.47(1 2,o25 30,773 •18,240 00 44,843 40 2,5. 4,671 00 17,647 20 16,080 00 6,256 80 771 00 3,94 4,158 00 4(7 40 16.6 2,035,802 </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 BIENNIAL REPOET OF Principal Farm Crops lor 19O4. .CORN. Productiou, State. bushels. Acreage. niinoia 344,133,880 9,428,^30 Iowa..'.'.!!!!!!!'.!'....! 303,039,266 9.295,683 &gt;"ebra»ka! .".!!!!!! 226,969,194 6,173,984 Mto»uri .'!.'! 161,522,643 5,783,307 Indiana ..." 143,396,852 4,552,281 Texas ..!'.!!!!...! 136,702,699 6,048,792 yunrar 134,609,669 6,440,664 WHEAT. Production, State. bushels. Acreage. Minnesota 68,344,256 5,339,386 Kansas 65,019,471 6,231,152 Korth Dakota 53 4,667,135 Nebraska 31 2,024,667 South Dakota 31 3,287,165 Missouri 27,1«3,141 2,3L Pennsylvania 21,857,961 1,660,210 OATS. Production, State. bushels. Acreage. Iowa 122,3^3,200 3,822,600 Illinois 117,341,952 3,666,93* Wisconsin 86,734,515 2,478,129 2,172,921 2,146,324 1,215,979 1,245,752 1,279,720 Acreage. Minnesota 32,123,041 1,131,093 California.* 28,091,999 1,237,533 North Dakota 17,518,074 623,419 Wisconsin ....; 14,941,290 498,043 Iowa 13,552,945 487,616 South Dakota 9,787,624 349,568 Washington 5,824,198 167,382 Nebraska 5,502,725 196,844 1W.M4 RYE. Production, State. bushels. Acreage. Pennsylvania 5,367,108 346,266 • State. Wisconsin 4,905,263 302, 7»4 New York 2.177,761 147,146 Nebraska 2,035,802 122,565 Michigan 1,752,590 132,772 Minnesota 1,648,967 93,162 lllinnic 1 2ft3 ftfift EesoU 85,178,503 iska 66,810,065 49,733,541 York 42,480, 143 na 42,358,732 L BARLEY. Production bushels, t* 32,123,041 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">BUBBAU OF LABOR Comparison of Leading States in Acreage and Production of the Principal Farm Crops for 1904.— Continued. HAY. k Production, ;. to i Acreage. Fork 6,480,800 's294 iska 5,308,970 State. &gt;,.WO, Iowa 5,074,362 3,1 &gt;,«!■», PennsylTania 4,449,425 Missouri 4. Illinois 3 Comparison of Total Acreage, Production and Value of Corn, Wheat, Oats, Barley and live for 1904, in States of Trans-Missouri Region. Total Production, Total Total State. bushels. Acreage. Iowa 451,241,254 14 635.059 $146,238,190 i«'i Nebraska 333,133,636 10. Minnesota. 229,103,850 Kansas 220,751,097 Missouri 195,274,337 South Dakota 113,583,122 5,944,712 51,124,326 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 BIENNIAL, HEPORT OF ACREAGES OF PRINCIPAL CROPS — 1903. COUNTY Winter Wheat Spring Wheat Rye Corn Oats Barley Banner 76,128 1.9M 151 II 15,721 47 1,067 56.857 505 50,275 15,527 461 995 156 1,147 14,665 2,355 63 9,006 1,549 8,536 5,88« 2,9M 16,716 358 3,889 10,815 5,043 4,087 521 3,881 730 596 3,442 1.9W6 1,376 1,966 14,349 2,473 970 629 1,305 58,929 85,749 3,235 5,008 40,708 27,836 119,601 - 125,028 153.982 108,974 25,781 19,229 4,013 04,460 1,459 867 48.97(1 1,783 14,845 8,3ft2 38,924 32,552 53,562 32,420 57,265 570 3,070 I I 2,354 365 46 10,626 300 84 Cheyenne Colfax Cuming Ouster Douglas. 1 'UI1Q V •■■■••••••• Fillmore Frontier Furnas Garfield Gosper Greeley Hitchcock Hooker Jefferson Kearney Keya Paha ! ' 97*2«i' V.1I5 666 23,383 14 1.679 59,051 631 145 11.4:5 464 569 77,000 50,766 47,388 81,988 67,359 706 43,790 528 9,271 33,311 23^12 14,897 4,176 1,422 1,349 16,382 1,588 2,371 22 37 15,063 4,317 110 632 2,594 "z,3So' 148 2,159 3,155 1,036 34,170 124 9,627 28,131 4,249 231 838 511 477 1,113 1.671 21.073 11,047 840 807 9,375 '9»,643 108,464 224. 43.550 85,687 8,506 88,191 108,154 75,185 122,005 70,036 87,659 70,948 202,134 9,495 51,292 14 6(1.250 78,864 104,615 71,302 59,932 23,880 87,183 817 74,747 97,805 72,687 79,803 7,737 24,053 610 88,897 25,184 3,143 50,593 41,175 9,232 2,483 17,761 4G2 35,954 42,72ti It, 6% 193 39,201 11,798 2,248 53,790 2,727 3,906 15 20,724 36,335 33,050 5,747 280 170 32,407 2,819 2,618 979 3,540 810 I 195 152 8,390 34,233 86,956 66,958 1,791 16,082 1,222 2,374 2, T&gt;( «5 7,73« 4,537 3,467 7,204 1,254 8,666 3,115 5.901 13,187 A 10,825 559 205 1,317 637 903 320 2,054 408 487 1,504 1,159 417 7,853 649 21,857 88,260 25,527 75,139 952 136 213 758 5,369 25 15 4,711 1,241 4,921 691 13,328 20,134 119,798 18,815 20,058 403 6,541 94 (9,068 531 29 123 152 S33 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">acres; Timber 311,215 acres. ACREAGES OF PRINCIPAL CROI .—1903.— Concluded COUNTY Winter Wheat 8 iffi2 Rye Corn Oats Barley Logan..!!!.. 360 Madison!!!!!!!!! 2,' 342 Mcrtierson Nemaha. !..!.!!! 25*457 kolls Pawnee 16^036 Perkins ps 84,154 Pieioe 791 Platfce 27,768 Polk 35,104 Red Willow 5.: Richardson . . saline'!! !!!!!! !!!i 60,500 launders 20,915 Scott's Bluff Seward 49,594 Sheridan 386 Sherman 16,21« Stantoa !!!!!!!!! 1.415 Thayer 46,277 ThurstOH 22« Washington 2,706 Havne l,0U 7 4,458 1,450 2,017 16,222 6 320 4 37 396 1.4:10 9,479 13,932 562 35 955 662 854 699 14,897 1,978 574 3,629 7,556 3,824 267 2,149 718 142 79:1 7,501 3,431 2.103 15,701 BOB 3,819 69 1,025 6,648 10,294 1,003 2,962 110 109 6,694 1,007 1,717 1 729 164,970 52,408 10,074 7,687 09,023 66,027 89,859 ti71 106,331 143,580 91,208 12.977 75,714 155 122,453 72.804 55,775, 99,938 14.236 119,452 :$94 176.422 3.214 120,383 13,132 67,471 2,264 80,157 114,719 2,506 56,167 &gt;*»2 17,859 103, 166 81,177 12,693 123,899 I 44, S41 3,047 617 2,319 66,710 21,192 15,996 14,043 14,191 44,986 19,748 155 14,991 49,536 67,782 29,560 722 22.608 3,592 40,054 17,327 56,655 2,240 43,558 721 15,749 941 36,700 3O,15« 15,943 40,003 47.234 13,301 6,161 41,533 44 2. M*ri 2,513 M 2,810 227 487 14 16 71 6 190 278 8,595 5,326 453 1,507 199 154 97 111 13,729 8,218 10,751 183 120 373 273 2,637 56 10,652 19,369 27 1,044 20 2! 853 1,057 144 930 Totals ll, 933,467 439.542 345.602 6,130,369 L,ot,ta 113,717 No returns from 1 fcPhewon and Cheyenne Counties. ACREAl 5ES OF OTHER CROPS. ;res; Timothy 238,041 acres; Sorghum Cant :oes 69,102 acres; Broom Corn 2,373 acres; rass 172,881 acres;Other Tame Grass 298,51s Sugar Beets 11,160 a&lt; 128.598 acres; Irish Pota Clover 54,635 acres; Blue G </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 ACREAGE OF MISCELLANEOUS CROPS , 1904. Cni T VTV IrUh Sweet Sorghum LXJUJN1Y PoUtoei Potato* Cine Sugar BMW Millet and Hungarian 692 1 080: 2 786 18 Antelope 33 202 &gt;s 2 6S9 1 005 81 banner . mi 100 30 Blaine. 97 359 Boone 109 186 2 182 9 Box Butte. 30 2 2 287 573 P 133 23 1 872 3 BuE '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 1 429 547 2 2 433 983 593 192 2 609 •47 625 212 •2 403 "Rii t Ipt* UU11C1 ■ 694 150 25 326 909 600 Cedar eitii 176i 1 660 275 3 700 2 160 Cherry 1 485 180 2 095 Cheyenne 1 149 1 181 15 1 502 2 217 6 1 428 60 1 519 497 2 6 671 Sfc::::: 1 451 1 196 39 2 859 1 O'Jf 8 783 Dakota. 1 04:! 9* 35 1 567 5 ] 172 54 1 541 1 114 2 062 390 2 75» 358 597 1 396 567 31: 15 1 M6 9 1 038 1 917 3M 81 15!. 391 2 031 132 2 449 5 Oundy. 188 5 403 92 2 025 25 Fillmore Franklin 816 2 1 407 47* 38 974 35 771 358 2 433 i 22y 138 Frontier. 887 8 0o4 4 Ml 100 S5T::::::::: 947 10 785 93 2 540 923 2 2 365 2 2 814 Gartield 312 73 3 455 7 Gos[&gt;er 503 3 597 2 353 Grant 3 Greeley. 587 127 14 1 721 1 201 1 297 6« 1 06! 1 196 Hamilton Harlan 759 1 307 2* 840 30 784! tJTV 1 959 2 260 32 32s 5 164 11 2 736 Hitchcock 257 10 188 586 I 402 850 1 879 2X 1 163 H 2 062 K;er • rd 62 486 146 836 901 14 1 680 675 Jefferson Johnson 2 405! 3 706 383 1 7 418 5 1 262 i Kearney. 668 1 698 2 552 112 710 Keith 191 175 770 Keya Paba 401 402 2 1 8361 Klmball 1.31 12 345 1 048 2 OOOJ 4 50 41« 3 778! 3 976 6 025 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 Irish Potatoes SlYMt PoUtOM . COUNTY Sorghum (June Sugar JJe«t» Millet and Hungarian Broom Corn Mad is id McPherson Nemaha Pawnee Pent ins Red Willow!!.!. Richardson oftllno »■•••■••&gt;■ Saundere Scott's Bluff . . . Se ward Sheridan Sherman ....... Stau ton Tnayer Tbumas Thurston V ill ley. Washington .... Wayne Webster Wheeler 1 112 9 2 135 2 853 2 14 10 1 214 211 1 950 2H 2 : i ■ B 409 177 7 3M 1 67« 10 411 MM MO TM 1 142 465 3 713 5 X 769 1 ( 3 1 1 3 1 32* 1 0 10 3 832 584 264 640 853 36 376 620 1 298 874 H 187 179 845 208 245 6 2 ." 1 27 7 1 609 45 156 154 488 8 41b 690 1 333 1 4 2 3 2 !' 23 895 3 17» 218 100 169 30 2 271 4 125 139 6 53 13 146 41 15 94 4 396 32 35 7 961 1 3 208 2 544 1 249 2 04 i 914 3 2 17 3 • 10 7 1 679 1 513 51 200 567 3 327 5 1 t 1 061 2 205 20 1 645 2 646 453 ... 74 562 118 574| 10 194 </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 BIENNIAL BEPOBT OF ACREAGE AND YIELD OF HAT. creage Tame Grasses 1904 Tons of Hay Cu COUNTY Tim- othy Clover Blue Grasses Other Alfalfa Tame Grasses Tame Hay Wild Hay Antelope x*ui. ic r. ••••■•■ enne Cuming Dakota Dawes Dawson Dlxon Dundy.. Flllnat-re Franklin Front!* r Furnas Gosper Grin t Hitchcock Booker Howard Jefferson . Johnson Kearney 940 49 1 068 294 1 637 392 20 151 65 78 42 9 11 9 999 1 364 9 (&gt;• 207 18 088 1 947 8 111 1 055 1 1 3 134 4 371 127 1 601 169 8 &gt;60 1 356 136 1 : 186 •7 6 : 661 8 999i 3 738 3 0 49 294 392 65 42 11 1 364 207 1 947 1 055 "3 127 169 1 356 186 967 498 "788 "28 N 3 704 3 821 13 015 25 495 488 5 109 30 5 40 2 168 ia o.iT 9 863 4 432 289 6 516 6 166 4 034 632 7 889 39 575 198 290 1 «40 125 165 13 785 4 476 556 6 691 19 040 79 216 3 022i 9 472 549 73 960 23 380 258 31 2 260 2e 085 16 379 1 502 33 251 25 138 845 5 292| 8 398 17 882 1 612 9 689 13 275 476 7 558 9 793 la 167 1 341 3 540 7 441 42 269 86 340 3 500 1 084 86 2 901 i 229 338 50 7 4»il 31 065 5 251 8 67 13 503 714 435 2 Olti 17 434 29 907 42 150 1H7 12 718 1 8871 II 410 16 0«7; 18 212 1 07H 3 !i4H 2S 1 73 7 11 Oil 675 3 125 4 711 5 62* 7 137 6 142 2 617! 3 222 6 558 li 37 10 768 I 11 351 : 10 :&lt;59 25 372 5 996 2 198 11 * 1 343 19 200 15 962 1 258 7 562 «&gt;"T*T •••■... ....... Ou OOU 1 363 68 1 821 17 765 12 284 22 832 25 868 5 193 2 470 14 651 6 637 11 683 27 706 15 977 30tt 7 745 4 100 553 1 9 194 1 838 991 729 2 331 163 135 2235 3367 21 476 2 979 290 4 367 16 897 633 6 218 4 256 5 313 6 7371 10 499 "i'8 "548 80 8 8 616 1 164 48 41 4 678 18 8 12 570 147 56 766 628 1 261 35 605 70 174 4 12H 5 371 306 105 117 202 2 119 140 </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 ACREAGE AND YIELD OF HAT. Tons of Hay Cut Acreage Tame Grasses 1904 1903 COUNTY | y | Clover | G B^ | AMUfc | J^ | Tame Wild Keith Keya Paha... Lancaster Lincoln Loff iin • • Lo&lt; &gt;p . . . . . • ■ Madison McPherson... ick Neniaha Pawnee Perkins Platte. Red Willow!! Richardson. . . S3 line ....... Saunders ... . Scott's Bluff. Seward Sheridan man Stanton Thayer Thomas Thu'Bton Washington.. Watne Webster Wheeler 1 113 1 3 3 1 825 1 800 2 000 8 1 4 &lt; _ _ I ■•• _ 305 1 4 9 322 1 085 3 932 18 699 2 4T 719 2 531 ""49 ...... ' 5 -4 560 295 4 61 499 1 8 (•• 887 4 17 454 8 017 21 740 8 5 611 1 005 5 539 4 !• 70 431 4 103 4 807 Id .... 10 ■ 272 3 1 5 20 3 i&gt; 244 822 686 27 189 3 4 414 20 750 145 70 105 16 177 1 0«0 4 514 28 241 719 110 29 84 40 101 16 544 1 688 503 648 «&lt;V4 IK 136 1 185 2 325 1 943 1 142 8 178 644 615 12 3 644 410 3 497 1 619 6 956 3 187 246 1 548 967 426 8 855 1 (Mo 1 563 2 635 647 1 729 4 366 50 87 7 771 1 553 482 10 166 1 014 4 318 34 ••••:_ 180 135 461 72 24 "*8 804 146 412 12 981 117 516 222 363 1 189 1 378 1 925 13 972 257 1 678 4 319 4 H23 1 097 30 1 163 10 500 23 140 175 6 261 9 HI 408 484 2 415 8 754 1 737 2 374 6 097 12 000 6 830 611 7 103 3 445 4 801 8 214 13 102 11 230 6 026 2 158 3 794 4 196 8 917 6 502 8 985 27 698 774 6 394 5 83« 6 416 12 184 7 946 409 2 896 9 029 6 152 135 3 933 13 194 4 743 15 210 20 451 Ma 14 871 24 871 33 311 1 749 51 7 «48 22 449 13 148 8 792 7 306 27 138 23 075 12 915 4 «24 2.", M 8 419 49 811 IS 23 *« 11 616 9 210 13 601 15 603 7 306 Total 408 733 41 120 Jo 321 307 857 683 057 .'102 12. </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 SURPLUS COMMODITIES— 1903. COUNTY Cattle Head Hogs Head Sheep Head Horses and Mulea Adams Antelope Banner Blaine Boone Box Butte Brown . Class Cedar Chase Cherry Cheyenne Clay Colfax Cuming Cosiei Vaiiiita Dawes Da»son Dlzon Douglas Dundy Fillmore Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage GarBeld Grosper Giant Grer ley Hall Hamilton Harlan Hayes Hitchcock Holt Hooker Howard Jefferson JohnsoD (Kearney Keith Keya Paha Kimball Knox 4 975 10 252 No railroad . 3 J25 15 900 4 700 3 5oO 8 650 13 lu2 17 164 15 950 11 12t&gt; 23 411 4 800 29 400 17 950 5 806 19 21 i 21 8 728 12 200 16 4 35U 22 32 25 614 28 293 2 970 405 2 080 119 41 956 14 775 7 053 41 24* 65 525 42 780 41 !&lt;12 56 H2«j 4 050 90i 30 814 61 341 64 620 38 346 20 756 95 46 594 3 3S0 48 75 173 270 5 670 2 835 1 080 810 14 615 20 52&lt; 1 3o( 6 34, 5 42. 1 76 1 75 13 50 221 11 34&lt; 3 51&lt; 10 12 23 2» 2ft 364 494 78 650 1 174 838 390 496 390 2mj 1 4S2 3 484 780 113 442 1 06» 26 1 950 884 104 233 1 118 8 1(H 24 574 7 875 4 700 9 026 3 600 8 477 13 426 5 900 1 375 23 150 12 600 12 025 10 501 4 526 . No railroad 4 42o 19 257 7 850 7 751 11 102 6 875 3 776 9 225 . No railroad 4 700 24 300 4 578 20 947 28 813 i 10 575 34 467 I 46 429 I 6 828 i 6 027 4 590 4 59t 4 845 1 084 2 700 2 02c" 2 160 260 651 338 208 626 012 166 78 156 614 1 120 1«S 442 t 24 977 i 25 774 1 33 626 J 17 537 675 91 667 4 995 11 340 I ) 7 804 n 27 505 ) L 29 127 I 34 569 5 25 439 5 17 550 5 150 4 3783 2 970 21 061 15 845 3 240 810 442 648 130 312 598 364 494 364 a 0 0 72 098 12 690 3 375 494 8 924 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 SURPLUS COMMODITIES-1903— Continued. COCHTY Cattle Head Hogs Head Sheep Head aDdH03Seg T ipgan ................. Madison lierson Pawnee Phelps Richardson. Saline Scott's Biuff^!!'.!!!!! Stan ton Thomas Thurston Washington Wayne 12 193 - 213 14 45u 11 025 No rai i road No railroa r 59 68! No ra 10 - 34 153 9 i 37 2-'9 4 e 5 2 9 604 27 179 15 0 55 017 7 '.'. 31 340 4 750 14 114 14 602 53 927 8 475 6 159 9 604 37 403 3: 10 670 17 10 • 1 57^ 9 8: 28 i 5 050 15 006 100 10 : 18 600 6 1 - 34 400 10 ■ 675 8 8 16 276 10 - 25 058 15 " 48 101 21 650 39 616 10 400 27 717 2 c 1 200 11 551 39 027 22 550 1 228 2 I 67« I 20 MB 858 22 Ml 4 5 M 10: MK) 2 2 6 210 1H2 5 400 279 28 002 3 240 4 321 300 5 H70 Ml 270 M 5 67*. 626 5 4&lt;H 546 14 Mrt 41 04 1 587 ■a. 's 7 15 Ml 81' 130 1.1 79." 131 15 12' 2:u 94: Ml 54t 54 *50 Totals. 655 263 2 161 511 680 T6 M 9 23 680 7: </seg>
            <seg id="p140">SURPLUS C IOMMODITIES— 1903. QBJ lIN AND HAT COUNTT Wheat bu. Corn bu. Oats bu. Barley bu. Rye bu. ss Adams Antelope Bannei Box Butte. ..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.' Brown Buffalo Uhejenne., Cuwlng Dakota ..'.'.'. Dawion Douglas '. . Dunoy Flllmore Franklin Frontier Vn rpQg Garfleld........ !!!!.. Greeley HmBiltonV. '.".'. *.".* *.****' Hitchcock Howard Jefferson Kearney Keya Paha. . . . '.'.'.'.'.'..' Kimball. 961 619 312 369 106 919 65 049 346 766 471 558 S0R.K No R.B 165 999 782 122 790 874 62 000 6 621 108 062 31 .; .53 000 642 1 it) 813 'r! 500 '7 999 17 938 ii" 3 III^ 2 000 41 333 I 187 1337 199 601 4.i7 53 427 54 25«i 52 4: 19 . 614 « ,4 625 44 666] 2 409 •4 9IS 98 7 120 1 m: 1396 667; 12 04 700 400 248O 467 549 821 ■00 81 103 30 376 260 000] 73 876 3 760 1 142 "i'875 ' 2 500 23 750 J62 377 T 1 •&gt; : : "i7'566 J4 «4i I 343 25 572 17 985 2 685 6 714 169 190 2 014 22 157 2 685 "irnb "2 685 1 342 241 714, 8 057 320 271 '671 2 685 50 346 "io 70 I :! 21 2 280 3 800 340 ' 2 940 8 057 11 414 123 543 26 u; 4 028 10 071 95 343 iio 510 20 2 100 100 10 20 95 3341 161 403! 282 595 -11 109 3' 1 187 No R. R 124 667 9 838 40 631 6 879 18 128 102 855 17 456 56 364 "220 2 020 "ioo "V376! 11 414 29 648 28o 34 816 I 276 667! 132 495 89 062 166 331 1186 731 133 099 325 660 844 766 72 437 1384 667 383 834 45 125 4 000 3 218 . . . NoR.R 3 330 50 000 82 709 608 000 466 933 2374 471 265 499 "2'5o6 625 625 63 714 2 014 671 8 043 177 928 290 300 40 860 2 650 128' 125 "j'686 2 014 40 i MO </seg>
            <seg id="p141">SURPLUS COMM&lt; )DITIES — 1903 — Continued. Mi IN AND HAT ~ COUNTY Wheat bu. Corn bu. Oats bu. Barley bu. Rye bu. as Lincoln. «.... 59 337 27 484 625 57 743 22 Logan. No R.B Loup No R.R Madison 80 000 557 282 790 829 3 750 13 428 flM McPheraon No R. R Merriok 224 668 66 649 93 812 627 714 11200 Nance 123 333 248 930 lho (*&gt;:$ 20 143 Nemaha 214 199 994 114 Nuckolls 152 21 &gt;9 551 661 Otoe 1196 599 3187 818 17 456 110 Pawnee 166 800 949 949 81937 Perkins 3 333 Pnelps 3125 331 724 306 ! 106 81 Pierce 59 558 208 Platte 161 334 963 Polk 402 000 516 329 429 875 Bed Willow - l 140 Richardson 286 «:« 1128 213 53 625 Rock 4 &lt;&gt;&lt;* 13 M Saline 78 2 886 Bauoders ""!.'.'... 264 6612991175 491 624 !".*.!I!I M 4K§ 4*.i Scott's Bluff 8 070 Seward 12 108 360 Sheridan l-i Sherman 24 938 139' 170 Sioux 50 Btanton lhayer 363 467 1238 044 1«7 438 »5 :, 40 Thoiuas Tburston 62 000 26S&lt; 10 000 " ........ Valley 209 66» 140 Washington »■ 4 038 60 WajDe Webster 517 331 118 041 4 750 13 70 Wheeltr 4 000 2 412 1 90 York 1426 667 766 401 225 625 1260 12 091 60 Total ! 26633: ■ .&gt; 333| </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 JiS : Sir:' so" '^aoan t- r. ,S 3.2 fJ : : '• ** ■ -- 9$ N .T. : S3 53 "O 88 j"S S2|5 n" : • 82 8S." ~SS r- t- 1-H.-1N — . s s I *;- o — S X .... r- «r- . . . .S^&gt; 5 5 S * g • • • • •»_ • oi . . . .m&amp;i o S3 C5 W 5 M i | :|| :|| : :g 5S3 :^S .^5 : :* fc-i u — B 2 0 a * 3 ";:" £ = £J?; s I ssf 3g|a83' £3 I : i ■§§£%% §1 : I !| ill .| d : i !-«-"-"« s rf : 8 :g : : : : : -r -i- ■ r — ac </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 i*oo -cim-h-h — « •t-ooaoaoo • i— r-t-qp • • ••»• ■ -m ;r — ■if* •- hoJS • •— e-i r - oo i— oo • &lt;o -# 35 &gt;-&lt; e-j • &gt;e oo — os ■ • •-• •ss^Oi.'jo ■_•■■• ©.•■*© ■ io ce ocq ■ i— ir- -C4 » © o o ottaa; ! S •» 2«op*-ji;ia r-i»»xiN 'Moon ti:i o-cnoe ■ 1-4 C4 w$ &gt;a ■ •! ar-fiS'jixifl -H -*« . &amp;* . r^-H • CD • r1 • ■-• — a •mim-*n -mil 'Siooohh • r~ as n ■ ■ t- •»- — a '. '. '■ :«••"• 7 - ~ l ao n : ?p 00 qp 00 oo r5 • &lt;© «o 3i as O er-xr- ffiLOC O O r - jr—&lt;»O • •wriest-- -5:-^« • -* ;c r- -m r- . -ift-HOQ • -m ■ r- — -X - rtri-^fjT—( • • r i r 1 r^ c • &amp;} ~* •-t-nsir' -i-*©o&amp;« • ■© ■ m o t i j? C*J • ■ CD 00 op 00 oo r5 • &lt;© «O 3i os O Cr-ocr- ffiLOC O Q t- o ■:-H • • ?l N !&lt;1 &lt;B •«« • — r-csror- -i-iO*« • O ; M O f I «D35!O • &lt;O ■«■ •MOBOO^'CO • -I O r- ■ •«? • I— tt '-Z ~C rio-^-s • -can •«o^ 1 •nasoo^eo • -^»t- ■ -cp -r-M-.c:pgc: — r— • . c? • o • o* • • •— co -^ n • ; • • -&lt; : N : i ': M • • • • r* M (M • to . . •i-ltN • • -tN -CO — • • •N«r- • • IO • «-•— C — • • • . . • f* • f^ ..... *- — . .,... .... •* .*•■• . • •■a. .... ■ . ■■•■• * (o t%%t* \ ;§ :s« ji i is § ia 1 : is ill :1 s s? •— : : : : : : |S : : £C 2 : B^O -30 • • • L* ■ CO • CO *P • • QQ iO CO ■^ i&gt; - t i -*^? *^ -^) --i*"^ ■?44 • • • eMooS -3S ■ — i •♦ •♦ •* . -SS-o 2 -iTi— -"ri OD Q0 • • • i.* ■ . tf|l *p * • QQ 4rt QQ *^ 25 O -^ 63 • • • NflOW '^i-^ -^H^t^^* • 'SOWS w- ! • • • -^ j NfiN- * • 'HOJM ....-«■ . :i?im- • ---(Osjo « -*io ■-. • •••••••••••••••• ::::::::::::::::■■:: ej ■ - ■• : : = </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 ScoiO «M a o«5oo«o n»n«hw i-^ -^ an i— ■ 3O CM —i »-^ r- « 00 *i-4 if! fHCQ f CO CO C^ ■— &lt; • O &amp;3 il n — ri ■♦ 3 — m o 7-i o oc — Mi- CM U3 • I - • c:k-. ao *-f coa-cwn ■ 'Oh • • •« u II 5 \ I. i -f 3aS -Sap -SSS •* • • • 8 ■ eo • § « oc ao-»&gt;i-i . 2 -rt &lt;o -o • ; • •&lt;* • -as ■ i-c e 1H «O &lt;-c •» N . .... . . . . . -r h rj -m -r i oc -r to • 'Oa • -ac» •» .ao &lt;o 03S ■ -Mr- • -«« -t- •* ao x f^ r- ?i o x •« u5^nec • *ioao • »-^r- -»o «i-i rt »-l ■?&lt; ■ . ■ ■ . . 1— . . . . . (Q H Z • ••■••••"•••«•*•*■ *•##■ ttiiiiilili o </seg>
            <seg id="p145"/>
            <seg id="p146">146 RANK OF LEADING COUNTIES IN SHIPMENTS OF COMMOD- ITIES FOR YEAR 1903. CATTLE First Dodge County 32,476 head Second Cherry County 29,400 head Third Sheridan County 28,025 head 29,400 head X iiiru &gt; Fourth Knox County 24,300 head Fifth. Cedar County 23,411 head Sixth, Grant County 23,150 head Seventh Morrick County 23,077 head Eighth Dixon County 22,779 head HOGS First Dodge County 75,173 head Second Koox County 72,098 head Third Burt County 65,525 head Fourth Saunders County 64,36» head Fifth Madison County 59,t&gt;62 head Sixth Cedar County .*. 56,326 head Serenth Platte County 55,017 head Eighth Cuming County 64,620 head Ninth Richardson County .53,927 head Lancaster County 52,213 head SHEEP First Hall County 91,667 head Second Cuming County head Third Seward County 41,042 head Fourth Platte County 19,001 head Fifth Dodge County 24,574 head Sixth Dawson County 2. Seventh Lancaster County Eighth Sheridan County 22,545 head HORSK A!fD MULES First Knox County 8,924 head Second Cheyenne County '. .3,VU head Third Adams County 2,080 head Fourth Dawes County 1,950 head ii Seward County 1,587 head Sixth Cherry County 1,482 head ith Lancaster County 1,228 head h Sheridan County 1,222 head h Buffalo County 1 174 head head </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 RANK OF LEADING COUNTIES IN SHIPMENTS OF COMMOD- ITIES FOR YEAR 1903— Continued. WHEAT WHEAT First Phelps County 3. 125,331 busb 1 Hamilton County 1,429.330 Phelps County 3,125,331 bushels d. ...... Hamilton County. .'.". .' l.429.:«0 " Third Yor 1,426,068 " Third Yor l.-i: Fourth Fornas : Fifth inty 7 " Fourth Fornas Fifth inty 7 " Sixth « th Otoe County 1 , 1W. SM ' ' Eighth.. ........ ..'.'.'...'.....'..Franklin Guanty .'.'.'.'....'.. V; . .t CORN First, Cass County 4 bushek Second! . Otoe County ! . . . Third Saunders County Fourth Gage County Firth 'inty I " SUth Bui Kith th, Thayer County 1,2.;- OATS First Cedar County 1 ,117, 938 bushels Second Platte County Third .' Boone County t " F'urto &gt;s County 608,000 " Fifth Butler County 60:,999 " Sxth Pierce County 606,771 " Seventh. Gage County 549,821 " BARLF.Y First. Cedar County 1«2.377 bushels nd Knox County Third Pierce County 69,558 " Fourth Wayne Councy 55,(00 " Fifth hurt County .&gt; " Sixth Dawson County 17,.t00 " 17,500 Plllll ■••• •• •••• 1'on.^'ii \ ..\j\j ii ijr ••••• XI) Seventh Dlxon County 14, RYK E,t Merrick County 65 ind Dawson Con my M: rd Coster County 241.714 rth Pbelps County 241 ,043 ;14 bushels - 241,043 " Fifth Keito County 177,928 " Sixth Huflalo County 169.190 " Seventh. Sherman County. 13JJ brt •• </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 BANK OF LEADING COUNTIES IN SHIPMENTS OF COMMOD- ITIES FOR YEAR 1903— Continued. HAY First Holt County 34, 815 tons Second Lincoln County .'. 22,490 Third Rock County J2J590 Fourth Merrick County ".!!".! 11 '200 I". 1 ™" SSl'" 0^™^ :•••: •'•'•••'••• »!sao Pi Scotts Bluff County. '.'.'.'.'..'.;i'/.;; 8.'o7O " nth PlatteCounty 7,223 " FLOOR First. . P 3 ,? 801^ C 000^ 39,984,000 lbs Second Colfax County. . . 37,408,000 " Third Sail ne County 21 Je"7!375 ' ' Fourth Antelope County 18,480,780 " 18,480,780 " Fifth Buffalo County 14,832,000 ' ' 8l«,h •• --Clay County 14,395,190 " Seventh Pierce County 13,373,230 " Eighth Gage County 11.228.790" Ninth Fillmore C &gt;unty 9,184,000 " Tenth Larcaster County 9,025,600 '• Eleventh Dodge County 7,672,000 " Twelfth York County 7,168.000 " 11.228.790 " Hinth. 9,025,600 " Eleventh. 7,168.000 " Thirteenth Boone County .'.'.'.'.'. e' 6,832,000 " Fourteenth Kichardson County e',808iooo Fifteenth Sauodere County 6,552,000 '« Sixteenth Cumins County 6,160,000 Seventeenth Nuckolls County ..." s', 624*. 271 Biteenth Hamilton County 4,8~2'000 " iteenth — Adams County 4 827 020 " ntieth Nance County 4.256000 " 4.256,000 Twenty-first Furnas County ..'. 3.4 3.416.000 " Z m , ~ — v ••• •• ii.iiu.yw Twenty-second Johnson County 2,496,000" MILL FEED f lrs *.. • Otoe County 48,120,000 lbs •nd fceward Couoty 9,090,000 " Third Saline County 6,331 620 Fourth Lancaster CouDty 4,570,685 4,570,685 n Filla.ore Couuty 3,39o!ooo " n .-_ Buffalo County 2,970.000 " 2,970.000 P'« """•'« v/uuijuj Z,i)iOA*M nth Nuckolls County 1,796,203 " ith Bichardson County 1,587,000 " POTATOES First. *rSheridan County 129,000 bushels Second. Box Butte County 64,(X)0 '• Third Butler County. . . . .'.'.'.'. ! .' .' .' .' .' 2^500 Third Dodge County 29,500 Fourth Kiobardson County 18 000 Fifth Dawes County 15,500 Sixth Saunders County 14.000 Seventh Buffalo County 13,500 Eighth Cass Count? 12.660 12,660 .Ejigimi \jaaa 12,660 Ninth PlatteCounty 12,500 Ninth Custer County 12,600 12,600 i.i iuuii muster i_x)unty 12,500 Tenth Adams County 11.004 Eleventh Johnson County 11 Twelfth : Seward County 10,600 Twelfth Guming County 10*500 '• Thirteenth .. Cherrv CounfcT * in'(V¥i •* </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 BANK OF LEADING COUNTIES IN SHIPMENTS OF COM MOD* 1TIES FOR YEAR 1903— Continued. BUTTEE Flrat Gage County 2,715,659 It*. Second Lancaster County 2, 7e9,K- 2,7B9.- Third Douglas County Fourth Jefferson County Fifth ..Saline County Sixth Buffalo County 37 Seventh Adams County Eighth Thayer County i 1 Ninth Tenth Saunders County Eleventh Platte County 1 ECUS First Douglas County Second Gage County Eh Adams County 2; in Seward County Madison County th Nuckolls Connty Eighth Platte County 6-t Ninth. Dodge County 63 Tenth Nemaha Couoty 5- Eleventh Jefferson County 44 Twelfth Thayer County 4. Thirteenth Knox County 364,380 L1VB POULTRY First Lancaster County 789,1' Second Colfax County 61 Third Polk Cuunty Fourtu Dodge County 2. Fifth Seward CouDty 2 Sixth Gage County 2 Seventh Hamilton County Eighth Buffalo County I </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 NUMBER HEAD OF LIVE STOCK, APRIL 1, 1004. COUNTY Cattle Hogs Sheep Horses and Mules An te'ope! !!'.'. '..'.'.'.. Banner Box Biitte. ........... enne (Turning Filmore. rnmklln. Frontier 11 176 43 434 13 200 6 493 35 149 26 776 16 170 16 7h8 38 607 30 048 42 869 144 993 33 098 18 534 18 509 43 798 69 459 13 622 16 266 38 540 49 Ul at 043 32 844 10 959 15 677 18 808 24 926 22 715 33 238 29 119 9 254 19 736 35 825 41 427 80 B01 24 865 26 402 15 419 13 995 79 222 3 287 26 243 26 064 17 141 19 948 22 408 19 060 7 736 38 306 5« 560 15 833 34 536 322 1 128 35 515 10 740 6 49H 32 416 46 751 36 104 31 96S 48 380 5 736 3 344 2 223 26 244 57 4:id 30 031 4 156 32 176 41 223 12 870 5 002 23 922 25 876 17 972 29 888 44 246 3 383 13 945 172 16 806 29 348 39 134 4 254 18 162 146 18 5H2 27 218 2.1 266 1 167 6 138 26 37 845 43 321 12 419 7 713 23 195 10 819 30 875 6 070 3 743 666 321 832 5 500 4 995 3 389 768 167 1 163 54rt 85 8 936 6 876 4 731 112 4 113 2 064 218 199 428 49 588 7« 52 4 36 398 11 205 1 604 7 480 23 268 3 217 5 954 9 376 2 630 908 9 334 3 693 4 319 3 387 11 175 11 650 9 369 10 1",9 1 040 5 441 19 721 6 376 9 628 4 813 10 691 13 512 4 144 3 020 10 252 6 334 7 209 10 232 5 419 2 708 9 233 7 732 8 475 11 307 13 072 1 560 6 083 2 445 4 810 8 719 8 919 8 546 4 085 3 549 14 403 425 6 862 8 303 6 080 7 314 2 374 4 171 2 427 8 876 Greeley '.'. Hitchcock ! . Hooker ... Jefferson. Kearney ± Paha. 24 7 158 4 371 1 610 544 6 31 636 913 </seg>
            <seg id="p151">151 BUREAU OF LABOR NUMBER HEAD OF LIVE STOCK, APRIL 1, 1904.— OonHmmtd. COUNTY Cattle Hogs Sheep Horses and Me Pherson Saunders t's Bluff . rd 37 459 3 510 4 4**!' 23 635 36 154 33 867 17 663 31 634 22 010 23 311 ■ 2 11 961 40 731) A30 23 102 31 782 43 607 16 566 13 160 i 3 952 4 182 7 7 977 43 2 Oil 177 830 250 738 3 371 14 621 514 2 246 4 907 3 239 437 935 8 689 327 41 2 412 111 1 742 47 7 277 758 1 229 10 213 2 195 7 083 6 473 6 731 10 399 - M8 ii 9 6W9 6 yo.J 4 501 9 332 3 811 9 776 4 692 12 919 40 061 10 031 11 060 5 39« 4 561 5 604 11 487 M 6 lv*J Total 2 4'J5 814 1 870 616 667 637 </seg>
            <seg id="p152">BIENNIAL REPORT OF MEAT PACKING INDUSTRY— Table No. 1. !! Date of Establishment Date of Value of Establishment CapiUl Invested Incorporation jSept. 14, 1887 Sept. 14, 1887 $882 645 54 $7 000 000 00 Sept. 1883 ban. 1887 100 000 00 100 000 00 !•••••••• 955 000 00 Branch of 111. Corporation March 12, 1901 March 12, 1901 250 000 00 250 000 00 Jan. 30, 1888 </seg>
            <seg id="p153">1 if i i s a 7. 5 3 ao s o o CO 5 CD 3 8 S •* .6 3 1 _2 3 I 3 ! en h o | « ? I ■2 (2 5 j 1 S 3 s a i 3 u b o o Pi — 5 1 Ph n. | en 1 = Cm « IS '. Is. t 00 s CO ■ 8 — 8 s 3 • S3 SB O 2 3 8 8 8 8 til 3 3* i — s Ob 8 « 3 00 • </seg>
            <seg id="p154">i"25 fill 5"S8« i I • I S. I 2 d — a 3 o (X&gt; s 8 to I I" 1— * oc 5 r— o C 1 ! CO CO 1 I CO I 8 8 w o I— 5? g S S2 IN i at » CO - i. o 8 5 o i s I — a o s 00 » t- us cs * (H M 3 i a o 55 ! £ a 1 I ! BB I i CD as 2 i F-( : o w 1 w 3 I 2 • 6 P I i i </seg>
            <seg id="p155">- II r— S I 00 M 01 : 3 I 1 5 B § 33 I m 3 CD I— CO s 8 o I S3 S r - o 2 §1 8 S M I s 00 — t ■ &gt; .= I 9 8 S s o a « CO 3 o E ■E « 1 ill s 8 8 S § 5 ~? — « i-H § «o s i 5 1 3a s r- S L 1 § g u s s s s 8 9 S T-t j is c o «•£ rf.£ SS Cfl CO 1 1 s eft a CO I 1 i i - </seg>
            <seg id="p156">i I = 0 W5 s s S I 8 8 S ! 8 s § a 8 s C-J 04 CO C4 - 0» If b S © &lt;" S a i i I K | 6 c s © 3 5 o 2 I © 3 N ! = S -o r^ ao « ■85=2 3 s *•* 1-H P4 N a 9 o e ° I 2 3 £ o a I i— &lt; Ik ¥ 3 S s 8 g I H « 33 § s i— t «•- ii i i ! i I </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 BUREAU OF LABOR uajoqvn F: "■: IS,J ra^jj ¥ 1-5 »l«H 5 ... « • «8« : OTM s I S spj«.\ H»l- I uadooo 3 s s ¥ ¥ lu^*&gt;i f: S 8 1 r I pir» »oi|».T. . uan»»|0 i ?5 s ¥ s uatiao J8»H I 5cS8 8o3 ■M**«» i s S S 2 8!? 2 S IJ»[OO0 5(JO,I JS uafooo^oH I i ¥ — ■&gt;■— c&lt; s 11 a»H a*wnts n»K taaj-i^M 8 « 1 B»S8 I I - ■• uaogan 3 o 8eS P Q S 9 a. O o uaddtqs I ¥ 5? asM »noa : s naH adi'U 3 ?. nan aS^anoj, 3 U3H J»7Ttlli»&lt; g 8 s s — i ¥ M W i a»H HO w — i tSuitvn i K u»qotng *&gt;H ¥ 8=53 £=8S 3 £ «j-.tl-Tin!i daaqs I g=g^ c^ eo so J5 M "■"IOTH I*»H If 3=38 «__3««a ■i" n.mi«i(«s 8=SS CO 30 BO til ■m»A ¥ Cl 2 3 *x S 3 3 ' ~&lt; SO »I»H ¥ s T r M ma* •r»n ¥ M SoSS w indaa^^oofl ¥ S.8S m 8=83 ¥ jaqoin&gt;i ' </seg>
            <seg id="p158">i»anoo ,O« ■* — ia = &gt;c — cici— !«•* i — fatnN-!t-.SJ-gSi T»'unu...|. «q«aio i 1 1 II! I!;; i ill Mi I iii i ;; ;;; M : : : s :::::::::::::!: i : :::::::: ■ . : : : i ::::: I : I :::::::::::::::::::::: oguKH .3 :::::::::.:::: :g :..:.:::.:::: = 23 .:..:.::.:::. M :■'.:::::::::: s m :::::;: ...-. !!!!!! '. '. '. '. '. I niilimlillll-'llillllijiili - •9ii S V i -V £ : : : :::: ::::::::::::::;••:• j • • • i a ■ i i i i ; : ; ; js j : i : ; : is j ! is : • : ; : ;■•••• .O • • • • • ■ • r- . . . s I;:::::::::*::::::::::::::'-::: i-a o j j • j • 55 : • '• ■ • : :: ! ! : rs : " | ::::::: i i : :S ::::: i ::: i :: i :'::: » ::::::;:::: :::::::::::.:: ; : : OTH I : i i i i • ; i i« ; : s I ; i i i 00 i« i i i« i- i i ! A H .22 : :8 :SS : S . j |P :SSS : :S : : g§8 :5 ": . : : : :£ : : :g :£ : : : S :3 :2 : :8S :*§:.: I : : : :« j j JS « ! j | I* |S '?5 : :§S :SS? i : : .8 : :$ -2 : ;3 -gsg $ — oo • • oo oa -w cf ao Jf . -r-( .^i . -M COM i-i oa a ;d -ia -o a&amp; • •8383 r as •* ■ ■"(Da •*■•••••••■••.. lllilgliili 3|||||sf^ii1 </seg>
            <seg id="p159">159 Jii|j|ijii!lII=!lgSii.|l!il!iliii t'ti-i^ooevsHMai-o-aooo-" • :c to — «o • *oo • oo e*; m — n t- - ■ rH — Sh • • -H -« miMiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiUiiiiiiiiHii : :s :;;■::;::::::•■:;; iTTTTTTTT] -;i jjimjjjjjijjj ill j U. h" 1 i nit! IO • in :S :::::: S :::::: J :::::: i 3S • liiliiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiijiijii; N : : : : : ■ : • : . . . .::..:] iiifi an • ■ . • S •• • O) OS III! 3 i ! : i : i : § ■ I \ \ \ s I ! : ! I i : : : : : !« ! ! ! : : JS j j j j | j j |S : S iililillillNllli!!! 8 ::: : s ::::::: a III! ;;;;;ii; : K'. '. '. '. . S ■ « • • • • -HO ■ • S ! ! : i ! I* : i « I !!:::::•■; I .■:: I ■S : : . S : : : ■ : :§S3S . . : : • j | 9 j ! ;a« ! ! j j i •3 : : -3 S : : :5 eM-ioto- 3 -Sa ■••••'•• « 'HO • S -3c&lt;? T . .... «-:5oao §S»nSqo«^" -nonit- • • • S3S2 : : . :&amp; SiSSSS : SS : : : :S 3138^33 i </seg>
            <seg id="p160">160 |5c3SSS52$SS^PE5i3SS2S2SS* &gt; S 1 |«aimji.i. V tfpiifl iqmd I ::::::::::::::::::::::: I co lihiiililiiiiililiNli:: illhUliiiliiililnn puwf) V qdMOf - »8 illllHIl^Hi! I X T ilililiillliillllilhilil' liiiiPMiiiiiiiiiiiiii! 2 s 1 1 1 ;« Sit- • ■ 0000 S3 ::::::;::::::::: » linottfH ( I H"0 O *- t— ■ CO o I I, ... ........ .o • -oo t-3 • • • e :::*:::::::: ■ •» •■♦lo • I • ■ :::::::::::: ■ :- :«■• . : : - O T K 5 •A M vail |S? : -S3 : : 5 :«s SS^ : : :S : : : S S 1 OBTMd | x if;_ : ; . .&lt;joS • • -Si • ■ • • =S2 : : : :25 : : : 2 i : i i S : : : : : 5 I •H» a L3&amp;38 -§SS§SS2K .J2S :s : .S3S3 « I if ::::::: *y ::::::::::::: g : • s a : : : 2 :::.::::: fl ::: 3 sjis £ l;ilf.iliil&amp;li|l, : : : </seg>
            <seg id="p161">161 |"5i Amount Date of % . i t ipanded In incorpontioD z 1 May 12, 1869 2,610.62 193.' N T one Nonet 2,540,447.13 2 Jan. 24 1.42 Nm None • 923,059. 88 i *590,» 3. J*n. 20, 1869 1,070.08 None! 59.77 None Nor Jet Eug. House 4. Nov. 15, 1871 273.41 Nor None June 2, 1880 250.4 Not; None .2.00 Non 5,700.00 portant 1880 284.93 None Mar. 6, 1886 128.1!* None 29,491.06 ' 2.50 •Improvements during year 1903. X » /\ I I a H^^^^ 1 J?y 1^1 r* ti w%^ J LX&amp;tC XVO* li 5«S tiS n buildings, eiptnMli I B • I ooutmaUoD: durt» t 1MB. 2i ■** ■■« HI I A .us i^t r EBRASKA— 1 T,i. 'e No. 2. BULLING STOCK OWNED. IN i|j I J 8 c £ ■j s 9 — a 11 i ■ I. . . . 4 725 2 251 794 1C: 50 .... 6 782 2 464 238 107 51 .... 2 701 6901939 55 9 ....1353 66 194 19 0 8 18 3 031 414 52 768 6 191 527 1 621 532 180 • • • • I 279 J « ■ • ■ • 00 120 5 653 57 H 278 33 36 - .... 5 18 949,3 58' 15 53 17 4 084 A 077 100 H - L. 14 953 658 81d ::::::::::: N 707 - . 17 _____ i i ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p162">162 E 3 is 8 s 3 © 5 a CD « •o «» A&gt;p j»d sa3^M aUraaAV © ■♦ S — *-i paXofduie jaqmntf § 8 IQ 3&gt; (M s 3 i a 8 00 r- S I 2 E e Si •» 3 § §s 8 a ivpiad sa^BM aftuaA v 1~ 3 ' 1" 8" s N n SM N M 4 paA'ojdiua jaquinif *- m n S 3 35 « I i s 9 3 i § M if|i|i s S 8 §3 8 s S I "Si a § ■M 74 s s I— S i — «• .icp jad 8 S ss I— ( I "I 2 M » •&amp; M eo p8Xo(dai3 jaquin&gt;t n 5 _ 09 S a 2S 8 fi s I S a I I « S»S«M 3JSBJ3A V 5C ao $ §1 5! S3 a 9 3 S i-H 94 S4 M N « ps\'o[dma jaqmnjt 3 S 9 CD e|»|l|S s 8 s ~8~ I a E 3 § I S s O9 i (M 3 8 ?i 8 S3 •» s § 30 2 as ao B •_ « «O « C4 idcaa jaqmn^i a 5 S * ■ 9[npaqDS « J J </seg>
            <seg id="p163">163 Xvp ja&lt;I t-t TCuta.u ■— 1 O pa.Coidma 8 — s 8 5 • I i JO B 9 ?i | s a H CO if IS re 3 is — Iff i 9 A»p s 5? 2 n C5 § ri - ilma | JaqoitiK P, — z a 2 S 2 — 111 iipf «»- s ■ 8 S d a •» jo 71 g ■9 5 P2 r iui* fH a 5 '"^ «» a ID 9 g • 5 35 = 9 3 3 — -. iad s^km aim»\ v a» CO ■ 5 34 "3 "3 ItUrt 00 *— » — 3 3 111 2-3 i m s — I — IT 3 m H 8 a 1 2 a S 5 M CO - - "[data 2 3 ?3 m *• •* lii •ainpaqag *i ,a » - </seg>
            <seg id="p164">164 ° c *™-i— S* rt&lt; S§. s 3 §e &lt; 1 — «► o 04 Kcp iad pa£o|rtuid jaqmnfj I s — co CO IM Si C "Co 3 — O A § s 8 g 5 QU *-4 I— 4 I— 2 1 a 1 s r- S3 a&gt; K o A'np J3d S3J§T!.» 3*U3AV S5 s — psA'oiriiua jaqninjj CS s n io - J ? 5 is c ° * — — *-* 5 a E "E 0 «» ~ AV|) Jr&gt;(l Sa8T!M 93&amp;I3AV 10 g a « re paAO|dina jagoinM 5 s 4- o a 3 8 GO I - 1 fi o a M ta s a •*- S» Si pH 5 8 i— * -■5 paAoidtaa jaqinrifj s •a ao -r ill be 5i C es se =3 c — i^ cr yi cr ■O "C "O 2 2 5 "3 13 "3 i - x be i 3 S S 3 ~8" 00 a | I •o ao s ao «» UAiip aad S 2 g CO 4» CO c-i N N rH pa^oidoia jaqninjj I i s -s CM E C t 113 ainpaqos </seg>
            <seg id="p165">165 § I limits » Si.»s4» fi fi A*«p jad saihs.* aftuaAV * f r r - jagmn •• </seg>
            <seg id="p166">« b Seises 3 2 8 g S •O r; N us 06 CJ t- •♦ C4 r- r- — ? i g" i 11 •o C paXoidma 3 iaqinna |i|&lt;nio; imp Jjd ■»&gt;»«. »iun»AY s 04 3 1-4 T 1 p8.fo[dui9 J9q -rnna i^oi paMf) r- 1 | X T —I 5 8 2 8 a 3 3 O 00 M a &lt; ./fop isd B3^«m aS«a3Av CO 1-H s "S" "5 m" 1 M _=_ - paA0[dma jaqianji: I A 7 j S I O o I • • X«p iad T " " paA'oidina jaqmny a&gt; i &amp; * " "" / J Z n m '• s I Asp j.id 00 I — . o pa.foidraa jaquin^ 3 ! i s 1 I Q *-3 r^ O g^ *-• O 3 *"* ~8~ r- s I 1 "S. K s GO A'td isd saiteM ajipjaAv 8 N s C4 T "1 jaqainjj: i ko • i Schi T 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p167">RAILROADS IN NEBRASKA — Table ffo. 4. CASUALTIES ON NEBRASKA RAILROADS. 1902. n I Numb« Number | Passengers | Enipl. puxnpn wraokt, 1 j SSffiS * 0C «« nU Killed Injured Killed *On road, in shops, etc., causing personal Injuries. r—r .... 2 650 671 no record 1 32 20 934 036 *382 4 33 14 .... 606 416 1 3 4 441 218 24 0 6 0 • .... 246 189 87 none 9 3 .... 42 645 70 none none 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p168">168 -NIAL REPORT O» S|S sjaqiuan : : : : : : • : : : : S5 • • • • • • ■ • •ok ;;;;;;__ ;i-i M ii,ii In I siaqcaai^ ; ; ; : . : : : r :::::•■; :~* . JJiiiJJJiLLHJjJ ; M MM •ok • m ■ ■ • « Ills siaqoidH '::::::::.: j ::::":. . ! ::::: •on: ** • - • » • ■•••(■! : iiii SJ^qm*K LJil N I i I! I •oti m « ; ; •N!D'^&lt; CMr-l •Set: 5^1 j-t-ejjM»ct-aoc-3-«MSf m sjaqniajv »■* i-H •ok ~ S ! iifi IIil siaqcnaj^ rtto • ■o»»iggt':i-si.;ii-o".'5t( wh • ok siaqmaw :3S •ojj M "^ ; ;M • -IM^ • M • i-t 1 itiiiiiil^iilliifliyii </seg>
            <seg id="p169">169 BUREAU OF LABOR O • • HJ r- ••'«•• ic -fi - - iR n N f-;j M • — in -. rt M I I " I « * 1^ . I •&lt; 2 :::;•• *- -■; 2 3 '£ !5 2 r2 X n ~~ -&gt;■■&gt;»• n«»Mc-inxHi- -e»5 -r ao n~ — i-icocNHrtF&gt;na»io«'»i- lOsnoxNHiijHii) &lt;cni-«iao rU 2 £3 '-° "*■ r * '~ iZ — tj — — Tfz xi — r-o — as • «Mion«io or* — »«-*rtrt-«j«ei5 -eo » • — m^n-* i &lt;rr-H-&lt; r^j; moo — : • »-4 j j j j i s j ; ; ; ; i ; ; ; : = ; ! : : : ; ; : \ : : ! : i i ; ; . ... — | 5 f 1 1 1 5 1 1 1 =— 5 iiiiiinniiiiiiiNiNrijniiiiii — -■ • . -^- . - .^j .-* . . . .— • i 2£gs«g« • • O • -P&gt; 3&gt; » CD— &lt; M — • -r : : - : : : : : : : : — NM • . tH </seg>
            <seg id="p170">170 BIENNIAL REPORT OF o a uaqoreH • •• **»•««*'»« s •OH • *+ • rTTnTTnTTTTTTTTTTTTT III! soaqmaK fflWHB •on • . • • I ■ . ■ &gt; I C a) o «-fc&gt;T3 S SiaquiaK '•-••••• • 5 — •os sjaqradK ■ S i m«i -»"O— •?£ • •« ■ mm -a • ceo •ON. M 'NMM cfjrt m • N • i-l • m :|« oe^nesonoo-HM-fa- • d » oo r-- 3! S3 9B 2 3 £J saaqraaps ■ a *3^_ C E •ok S = •lOOt-CHIH-O^tONTl' ■ 1« 00 • •* OB ■* 30 •* •» - Z. — ri— ?; — T) 04 — . S . m — m • sjaq&lt;D3H : : : : : a t»s i—« — etS-ff^i^ii-NiO— Tj-Mrt -I-14.-5 . — C&lt;iO(Mn ;N • g 5 c« I : :|S :::::.: :s . : . . .2 . : : : : : 2 8iaqm)H : : :::::.:: :::::::: :::::: M •ON •(N ■ • • ii-H.L-iil? i j II i|i ! 1 1 :| j j j i i I i • ij H 1 1 i jiiJiitljfijjj! 2. 2 o ■r </seg>
            <seg id="p171"/>
            <seg id="p172">172 w u9qm»K S :S -S3 :? : :3S :8 : : : 8S : : : : :9 : : : . : ;;;• ;^;« ; ;• ; ; J !*X • • • " * • • * * • • ••••• ■ ■ • •• . • • • ■ •■&gt;■• ■•■■« ■ ■ . • . ■ . . • «■ • .... •••■■ •».•• • •OK I i uoqm*n p 1 1 1 1 1 ! I i ' i ! 1 1 ! :* i I ! I ! • I* ! i i 1 ; !• ! j 1 1 1 i •°K m I':::::::::::::'*.::::: : rt : : : rt ::*:::;:: Hl B I.::::::::::::.*::::::::.* :a« :«| ::::* uaqmaK ::::::::::::■:: ::■::::: :" : s : : : :" •OK b«-i s uaqmaR ; ::"••* :^ :;;: i ;; : s ;a ; ;g| ;■;;;;;; ;« ; •ok P4«^ ... »4 ■•*« a «« ■•••&gt;• *M •«•• *«^i .**. S§ :• ;' ;S=S||SS£5| 2 CS382 B§|«gggsg j j ;S| ■on ;.-«iOMt-* • • ■ T* ::::: :S :»::::»::•:;::: .85232 :.§::::: uaqm : : : : : : ::::::: s : •■ : M *qm, K i j j j j j 1 1 j j I j j j j : j* j : | j i I I** I : I ! I : I 1 I* : or ;;:;;;_;; ;•■ ; • » • • • ;C1to m • - — ' — : \ '. . » . . • • : ] '• ] \ • ] '■ : : : : : i :::::::::::::::•::'•:: liiiffiilililiiiiiililiiii </seg>
            <seg id="p173">173 "•»—•♦« •a m 9 * «.- o »•*«■»— . — -410«0 ; ;•• «rt«eSC1««HxlO»f«e»OM!0 ■« &lt;O NN- r« -". ■ Tr: •* : :3 : : ; : : ;g : ; .IITTIT: : ;* j j [S ;« ;=2 \t jjg !;;* .; t ! r *. t ; • • • ..i r ;;; ! '. '. i t * t;;;!." ■ . .H . .«« . ■ ec . rs, . - ec c* • ■ -&lt;h . • c« -a* &gt;i-4^ •«••/••• .**" 4 • • • |8 i§ i i I i i i ; 8 ::.;: .2 :§:::: :g :: :| :::::::: 88 :S : : §S !i|l •«• :,•;*: ;™ ;■■■;■: "^ *••••:;;;••;: ;•• ::;.:::;; ;*"** :-« : : 3 : : ; K :: ; ::*:: :R :t *:•::■:::::::::::::•":::: i* i iiiiiiffiiiiiijiii \uu : ■ • . . . « • . w ::::*::::*::*". • •« • ::::::§: :S ::: :5 ::::::: :88 :::::::::::: :S ::::::. .83 nijjj H [HI liliiili liHHiijhh iljjjjj r • .{.«.*.•*«. ::&lt;*::::;:: :—-• MiMMiriiMinr-'iiir s*§s ;s§Ss s :§=is i is sr^as :• ;8 : : :*S3 : : : jS* : : B : : : :g : : ; : :S : . : : : ■::•:: - • W* ■■** • • .Mil— • • ♦ ■ .** ........ ..... .go : :•• :::::••:: |$ :::•::::::"::::::::::::: |« : : : : i| I:::::::::::: • •••••••■•■•■••a. .... .^ .... .go </seg>
            <seg id="p174">H uaqn»H ; — — — ro 'OJi I esimi-i TT^i-i fijQ^T-n • — -^fM^rN n» wnt-n ••::ii:i5i:i!::!i:ii:l!:::! ■°n : ::::.:::::::: : : : : : — © &lt;o — 35 " «o opno S5 ra-t o • tiaqmaH ; ; ; •ON I « ■°K : : : : •OK ■ -^N ——i « • — — i-H • « -&lt; i-c OJ N OJ Tl !-!»»•»«• • "I • • : : M .... r^&lt; ........ uaqraaK I I i I ! ! ! ! ! usqmaH "M hiih!iiiMi!;i = = iij!J!i-"| :° H •OK • • - . &gt; - 1— 1 Fi • • •••••• • &lt; • &gt; • — n - ioo-cn»a»h'3C]c»33-.a3!r-ont-t-n NM • • i-i NMNf M -&gt;NN CO W N4M uaqauH : : ON uaqmaR ■*•" CD • ;;;;;;;;;;; j • • • • j • 2 • •OK »h • ■ • a • 8 111111 </seg>
            <seg id="p175">175 **■♦ «r- rr ci - •i.::--!: ;• •«::!j;.:-l::S Pil o Ii|iJii!,!iilji1l!li!l^i|iill!iI^Il ■ lows . . -for-r- • • • •e*a»o&lt;M-H»»&lt;M-^'M • to M«35Sfl f~^»-^»30C^i oc-i 1 :c e&lt;i ■*»• o&amp; -f :o T. ~ ;c t o • lowtx o ci-rjsioeoc^i- Tiot-tcm r.ai-aoxr- i ■ r- s — «c « i N — -&gt;C4^&lt; • m — m •*••« ■ ■ cm re cm -^ n — — M ■» t». sj -^ ■♦ io .NnN«-&gt; • e*r-N« «a &gt;a w* ia m «-. P5 - &gt; . _* *^ — 4 . . . •— C*5 •&lt;*• «^ »^ r^ M • • 00 CO ©* C* «0 •"* IO • lii: — ■ • ■ rr 3 : . : |SS jl j • eg o a-j • ■ • : g~i S S S .2 . : ci — • — ■ ; ■n — N •« •-&lt; • — . « ; I :8 i : i ;* ! ! C3 O • s: N • ; ; : : - : «S : 2 S» : N~* •♦ ■ •MN «d^« - . . '■ '. I '. I . I I . • O5 ■ • -^ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p176">176 -NIAL REPORT OF H h^ »^ • 94 3^ * • ■ ** — • u*qm«H '. II! ■ « s •: o* I NnnNHN -toeMo -i-i M mm .^-&lt;M«»je^ uaqmsH I:::::::::;:::::::::::. on I- u»qra»n S5S-3 § ft 1^ »C •on — • -* ci rc ~- 01 &lt;M .»O • I : : 8 : uaqmait | ; ; ; .m O JS N — o« • •— O&gt; - ix -i-l "II*" • N uaqmaii J: OM I — — Cl 55 1— I S • C1 — C-l — T I uaqm3H ; ; : uaqmaK OJJ I \* s : i ; igg i ; ; ;l : i ; • • ; ; ; = : ; ; ; : : : : =| \ ': is" . : gg :J : »§ .% :JJ : !ii££sil!f!lll!lf!iifjl« I </seg>
            <seg id="p177"/>
            <seg id="p178">178 » I8S :S :ffiS5SS SS :8*SSS2S5 -62? :2S SSSS8 S5S : o« II p*&gt;qui»ii : ::: :j i j:::::::::::::::::: i ::::]:: j : : : OH iiiliii ill I ::::::::::;::::.::::: : : : . :S t»qni»ic I;::::::::::::::::::::::::::;:: OH ! S Ioco«^c^C4io*9Mr~o:r-xoot&lt;'toec»^&gt;^«iab&gt;^roiOk9 w or- 5cxt^^c4«^t-*«»^l I : : : : 8 : :g« -223 . -Jg :£S8 .1288 S a fe :S s . .2 ■ s : r om . . 1-1 .«« ■ « C4CCM iOMM — — -OS • -*-* • •«•"• ■ P I^tr^ . . - -t» ; i*^"! • MOO | •.-••_. :::::: : : : : : : : [ : : . aC : 2S . i i .8^3 j TT^- ■3 a IS • : -SS - 8 : • • : : 83 R . : 8 :gu : .8 S . : : .^23 : usqmaR : : : : : :::::: : : : : :•":•; \ | • • :" : oil I asiiiiisiii </seg>
            <seg id="p179">179 •~ ' *+ *T mm • * rm) ■ ?4 ~* r+ • w4 ' • ?4 i- • • • &lt;^ • t+ Tl • t 82 .2 .« i .53 .2 : ;8|2 00 » i* ■♦ « cHT r* ** • • -H •• . •• .^^- ■ .mm • . • 1 • SO - c — r — l« 3 ; » . I : p p, e» : -i so . N " -c* » liTl 1 : fes8 :::: :Bi ::*:: : 2 .•::: : a S a : s :: :S ::::::::«:: : 2 ' 8 : : : : : : : : : : : : : 00 ; • ■«-• ■COrt -fi - ■* • « 0» i « </seg>
            <seg id="p180">180 ; : ;3 i ;6 :::::: :S • • • • . ■ • ■ • • • • OH I c*ta c* ■ -c*^ ■ -o • .^ -o • M •«■ ■ • •■ ■!O« if! uaqmait : : : : : : : : : • : '. : : : : : j : i : i : : : : : j : : : : ; : : . •OR m 1! u&gt;qa»H ! i i : i ::■•:: ! ::■ i i i • i :::! i : • I : : I : • I ! : I \ I \ OK l:!!!i . -c« ■ : : A % a fj«qm»ii : : : j : . •ok I *•* -»W»«iO iO-*» -?&lt;..--.-ic o«-» — ••» -n X — r* -r. x • • II usqm»K I::::::?;!::::::::::::::!!::!:::;-::: OH ! ! i ! :• ! ! i i ! |S j j I i ! i I j ; i i ; i s « ; i i • i a ; j : ! i i i ; «aqm»K • • • ■ :::::! : : :::::• : ::::-!•••: : ' : : or 1 5 1 1 n i s s i r ■ ;^«c 1 ::: .5 ::.;. .8 :::.»::»:::.;: .S'SS : ;B : : : : .3 : : uaqtnaii : : i : : : r ; : : : : : r : :::::: : : : : : j : : '. OH " ii ;T ii!ir i j H iTii -ii i " i ; " i i 1 5 • 23 S -a *£~2 .• &lt; 5 fc " | *i g Sm-o a "a a 3 »« S. = |-p ■* • </seg>
            <seg id="p181">181 BCEEAU OF LABOR ililiii II " ; 3 * a ! : i • i ■ 1 1 i i ;S SS i ; j ; j i j ; i j i s ; : S£ \ \ \ ;s j :s \ \ \ |» is -oo« • • • • • *W ; ■ c&lt;^-* • ■ ■ — t — km ■ • - M i-TTTTT i : : i : s : : : i :§::::: ::* :S :::: i i i ::: i j :::::!::::: i : i : |8 : ;^* :°° ; ; TTTTTTi i . ■ ■ x .o 1 1 r rS2 S :S52 : :£ SSgSSS S8333SSS :» :zau SS gig • •* tonr* - «?*.■* — deoeo-* m • •&gt;... ::.: :5 .::::::: ■«::::: iiiiiiilii :::::::::: :S :: : 3 :::: : s ::: : 8 :::::: i ::::::::: : a :::: IS :::.:.«::; .5 :.:. :5S :« :: .1 :::!;;. ;S S .:..:...: : 5 : . • I *• :** i • </seg>
            <seg id="p182">B • — SIS : : :S§SSSSS"?? :2g :fi uaqmaK : : : : : : oo 'H«gt . ok i nim ■ ■ -h n -&lt; ■-! m &gt;o &lt;•• n ■•-&lt;-&lt; nM »-* i^ -CO t~ *-t u»qai9|C :::::::: :5 ::: i :* C4f-l ; • • • • Sag • •OK I . • i-» »H ■Hrt • • • • C4-- • • •••••• *-H « ■iaqman : : : : . S -9 SR : - : : .SS : : : • . -85J : ci &lt;-iio» ■OK N i-i • OH - * tC • • -0400 • « V uaqmaH T^i : : : o . ■ • • • • • • '■ • "• • '• '• '• r-^i . : i i z I . i i i i i i i i i ' '. ! : : : i -o— •ok i-t • 1-H • • = i 1 1 = I j i i 1 1 ! ! r- •o K &gt;•••••■• ■ -* *«■ • ■ &lt;&gt;•■•&gt;••■*&lt;■•■• * ..&gt;.■••■..••■.•• * • •. ■••••••■-*• « uaqman on . .*• ••.*■ . • . . . • ■ 2 ■ ' « « » « • uaqman '! ■OH t~ ■ ■ «•* « • •* — » • O(l I I e* • e^&gt;-i : — eocj ; • ... ■ ■ • |!i||in|ii|l|||||ii|i|nm Uii!#iiii!iliiJliiiiiiiIiii lliii-'sl2slilisl&amp;3ail|Iis|l| </seg>
            <seg id="p183">183 '. — — !Z HZ ~ — — — — ■J- ~— — • ••■: — :■ : : :': s 3g^ ;■ 3 ■ ■ t-t-rt • ■ «o ...tai.".3 •55 ?) • w eMCNeo -^ • &gt;u3eoc&lt;i "r&lt; -t:i»- ■" s&gt; • • • • t— * • - •*•••••« 1— t • W* ?*s : N : : . « : S : " fl ■jji 18 ! j i i' ijiHlii* II 1 1 1 1 1 § : « • CJ CO « * r-t ... . ?q . ■ • • •••••••••••••••••• *•■• ■••••■ • • •• •&gt;■■&gt;•■••••.■•&gt;■■• ••■■ •••••• • .... S ........... 55 T» ■ ■ * - p4 • . • • « - — — . • • • 53 : . : .8 "::::.:::: §77^*7777" f_i . . . . ,_, . . . - • • »■* • • • mmmmmmMnn Si! ■ ~- -HfO C4 • — to «n | i ! j | ! | ! i | ! i { j j j ! ! ! ; ! ! j ! 1 1 ! ! ! { i ! ! ! | :;:::::::- !!!! CO 1—1 X tl m $ ; • !!M = s:i 1HH • N • </seg>
            <seg id="p184">184 :2^S • • O) • • 00 W O 30 ' :' u»qm»H ■_- "OK rt — m .-.® -aoiM 3&gt; ■ ci-* •■-&lt; • •« — o»-h« n I u«qa»it : : : . ■* I3 N^ 2 : : . i . fl — . ...... lm^ on • • - T-* n uaqa»H ; ; ; ; ; ; ; — . n n ■ ■ ■ t. « ok W4 CO • N - n s « . i H «aqra»n MliiiiiMiiiiliMMifiHI 11 OK ill! uoqmaii :::::::::::::::::::::: ■OK J I— 1 • ■ .::::::.:.:::::::: I " uaqrasji •ok fien ■ • .««« -n • 'Nh .^irt-«^"^ i-i I 1 * •••••••• ; • ; • : • • • • : ! ;■.■■;: *~ uaq««K II OK a&gt; a&gt; en • • •■♦ ■ go • -to • • &gt;-&gt; • .„...•* !!!!!!!! II. I II • • i h : : . "=» ! uaqmaii «K • »"^ C5 ••■■•••• C4 ■ • " CO ■ ■ • • CO • • • ... ... •■ .. ...en : : : :*s : : : il : : : : : : : : ijj : : j j iiiiiiiJiijjsii i ! H O i </seg>
            <seg id="p185"/>
            <seg id="p186">186 I I d i SSff .- 8 » 2 o i^Sa M 22 :2i •■ :g r.Sr«« 3i5 a * ■• - -* c _ ;&lt; ii liitiliiiliiiiliii • ■•-.- 2 ""■="• : asoa«i&gt;« w : r.« ; «coe&gt;- «&lt;o«ti --.kso-»«-c3» • B f i I [tometHf-NO »o» -o*-:io*i«h 1 I • "•ro.-ic^rJM — eo —■ '^-— is p — ■* e»^-tir*c— r - o ! S*^ 6 * '8212 1010 -.i^^JJ ; o »g5 tc rT=K| — x ®^^«* . ~ — — — . — , — . — . . . — , — __ — __ — __i </seg>
            <seg id="p187">187 • xn«aociHHM io-Nri-"«*?cr:t'X«'C?ici.^?i*M t«N?::in?i-:»»c WQ Cl 71 v* ' m *^ OO Ot t » • P* C*&lt; m v* c: : 2h0«n»h loMH^oo^aaHOHavgoieohxiOO ■ * l- -• :&lt; c y z c « ic » c . o 3 ■i tS iH i l|Ii ! jl.lJin A j tilti i MA ill J I IH^lJ33IIillllII1lll!iilIiIllisIlfsl3Ji£s| S"" 0l 5S t *" c *'*8 : »-&lt;^(gjo-j-;ooog«^?jocg02;5rigoD ;"Og — oc o i- jj D t- o • ©donc^'OeoocQ 'p4O^&lt;e0i-nD^c&lt;«»^i0«O'»"*'«o?«M-« i * -c*--: - r*si«o^ : •I «fH »* • Cl i-^ p^ OQ « M W • </seg>
            <seg id="p188">188 ojwfiaig jge weoeoN 'oohho-n *oo •© ■ ©© ooo« 'o&lt;-*«ooooo psniaa «(ocom«oh isiid«H O «O -W-i — •* ■O«0-*O — OCC« t^doMida noom- oet .no-^o^m '*^«h &gt;o s*o ■ i-* e» -- 1-( '-^— -vooo^r* B«qiO t^ «» i I nusqini i i : ; i i u»u3jXqsi»ja *«ochnoo ■^•v«c»Mv4w4 *.»*- ••wo Im&lt;^«ci •o«r«oooe«e« o!i&lt;Hn«o _ , a . 3^- | s . j. U ;.,.. h I«non«8»J*aoo -INOHYHON ■C-CMOOO tc4CC jo « O '«OO« N N ■* " O — © "* n^o3wh«- ■Ntt-- ■ o — w '.-«© [o jetooo-r '-4NiaH^ooii jfipoman _ ;.„-,. u j. j,. %.. h= ™.. </seg>
            <seg id="p189">189 ODONOO--«^M-0 3r»M09: o ~- I^CHnofOv^ofSMHCtfHioBinH .hoc^owmoohosib «ons»-4S O C O ?• © — © — — — S »■• « '-OOHO^HSlOnOO-K^aH-HSJH M = O£C» KMf OSM -•M^OhMN- — ■* oi « im r; -c n-M3O333-^HO • z&gt; --«fXN*4^L-:o?:xfOt*N or-oo© o-n ■© o w* c« i- • »HO«ONc«&gt;c«*oonNCH-?:oon '•?*•*•-&lt; r*« o oca « — — •• &lt;*r OOtfS-fM-rO?) — O — — X — — — -J-rSOOi— </seg>
            <seg id="p190">190 BIENNIAL REPORT OF BANK DEPOSITS OF NEBRASKA, 1903. ( BY COCNTIES ) rom reports !or quarter en ng J ov. i, «. COUNTY SUMi Prirate National Total AT*-*-* Per Capita Deposits Brown Buffalo. $ 162 236 78 423 36 340 39 14 142 36 255 826 12 34 1 304 : 132 628 1 673 835 00 716 4S3 63 920 35J* 99 f.75 777 68 104 I 109 757 94 303 302 H 149 "t 219 020 42 69 322 06 966 885 65 1 344 139 41 1 183 711 68 78 66(1 48 806 - 481 394 29 421 694 571 20 88 639 42 53 116 90 137 671 77 307 537 53 596 187 52 534 118 65 300 539 06 $ 1 500 042 11 138 130 12 536 960 38 303 - 14 200 70 t 1 662 278 89 562 120 11 36 340 39 14 142 :i&lt;» 792 786 50 337 997 73 318 757 23 132 555 87 908 555 77 1 154 806 98 1 394 830 57 1 839 032 11 856 026 58 104 020 -S3 29 I *4 1 04-- 1 (&gt;!■ 1 23 707 838 48 303 302 64 453 461 806 43f&gt; S2 0« l o:; 36 2' • 29 1 s .i 1 1!*?5 1 1&gt; 88 639 42 53 116 90 137 671 77 307 537 53 1 383 100 11 984 517 45 300 539 06 t 88 22 49 56 32 62 23 4a 47 81 60 66 43 41 38 20 44 86 88 61 88 83 ► 6 22 68 66 40 65 39 41 32 32 53 48 50 91 51 15 48 00 180 43 379 783 43 580 971 98 678 376 94 818 676 12 280 248 90 Cfierry — Cheyenne Co i fax ....... Dakota Dundy Flllmore Frontier Furnas. Garfleld. .!!".!!. Gosper &amp;mnt •••••■■«••■■ Greeley Hamilton Harlan J J y £ iy Hitchcock Hooker Ho*ard Johnson Krarnej 148 015 35 49 ma 79 225 00« 05 329 763 58 709 804 37 183 628 93 "Ml 073 53 587 415 27 72 318 44 1 884 «74 87 35 094 532 81 "i72'607'95 1 444 390 52 [ !H2 59 450 398 80 I 311 . 1 022 583 13 354 238 949 56 87 484 24 W 086 13 "380 727 81 «3 024 57 170 462 15 316 515 00 155 701 93 148 479 85 623 284 00 22 581 56 374 280 96 1 193 045 28 670 908 35 394 «fil 48 87 484 24 if 69 91 HS .... </seg>
            <seg id="p191">191 ijAJSK DEPOSITS OF NEBRASKA, 1903. Continued. ( BY COUNTIE8 ) From bank reports for quarter ending Nov. 17, 1903. COUNTY SUU Prlrmte National Awrtf Per C»plt Ltopoiiu Totel KimbaH 54 112 44 Knox 1 133 6: Lancaster. ....... 1 255 &lt;~ Linooln Login 33 122 12 Loup 87 750 73 Madison 708 033 52 ilcPberson Merriok 660 426 06 Nance 34 8' Nemaba 425 873 48 Nuckolls 178 700 46 Otoe 958 149 07 Pawnee 373 I Perkins Pbelp* 107 266 77 Pi*fce 598 430 01 Platte 605 403 30 Polk 618 074 &gt; Red Willow 478 330 96 Richardson 1 284 436 74 Rock 99 331 02 Saline 804 § ar PT Saunders. . 17 Scott's Bluff 127 231 m Seward Sheridan 3*?3 Sherman 79 1 Sioux 158 Stanton 56 1 lhayer 630 597 22 Thomas 14 191 62 Thurston Valley 227 82117 WMhlngton 1 154 230 75 Wayne 527 - Webster 312 Wheeler York 58O7O9'i4 20 333 18 4 669 724 85 349 356 92 "91586678 88 248 90 404 413 23 566 434 41 414 103 18 1 366 42.1 86 507 330 84 '"568" TIM 10 674 I 79 0" 333 810 52 54 112 44 1 153 959 02 5 915 362 65 644 636 02 33 122 12 87 750 73 1 623 900 30 ' 648 674 96 675 987 97 1 45 10 SO 33 1 02 383 79 194 95 158 537 60 349 201 42 896 ; 14 191 6-2 1 191 598 47 937 831 61 464 291 64 95 66 70 09 53 43 47 75 104 31 80 16 SS 66 13 79 48 35 36 698 '755 84 916 413 71 566 416 «8 oas'ii 266 153 07 382 646 72 204 661 54 37 181 72 409 151 704 42 i 084 i 665 691 21 •■„» Total $37 073 882 24 !$37 073 88 l$65 106 913 57 $102 180 rse per capita for state Deposit* and depjslts of . S. disbursing officers . SI </seg>
            <seg id="p192">192 MUNICIPAL STATISTICS— Table No. 1. City City Popula - tion. TOWN COUNTY. Value. Indebt - edness. Hall? Boone. Aurora . No 1,269 $12,000 19,000 Box Butte.. Saunders . . . Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No •15.000 •4,000 2,535 1,477 None None 28,000 25,000 None Nemaha 2,000 2,M4 Hamilton... Gage 1,921 7,875 Washington Custer 2,000 2,970 B rot en Bow. Central City. Chairon 200 1,375 Merrick. Dawes . . 2, (HJO 1,571 26,liOO 62,000 45,000 27, 000 13,000 15.000 1,665 Platte Saline butler Clay . . Columbus. Crete No Ye* No 5,000 2.199 Fafrbury .. Fremont. . . 1,845 No Yes No No 1,140 Jefferson Clay 5,000 3,140 1,203 None 34,500 209,000 14,000 15,000 25,000 141,000 277,400 Richardson . Dodge 3,022 Iont Dodge Yes 10,000 7,241 209 000 Yes Yes No 7,241 saline Yes 1,500 1,200 14 000 .-aline Nance 1,200 Fullerton. Geneva . . . rton Nance No 1,464 15,000 1,464 n Fillmore \es 400 1,534 25 000 Fillmore. Hall Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No 1,534 Grand Island. Hastings i Island Hall Yes 25,000 7 554 141 J 000 7,554 ings Adams Yes 8,000 7,188 277 400 Adams 7,188 lock Lancaster... Yes 3,500 1,480 5 000 Lancaster . . Thayer 1,480 »n Thayer Yes 2,000 1,511 2o',&lt;xk) 1,511 fege l 1 ?^^ 6,000 3,007 46 000 Phelps. 3,007 holdt Eichardson.. Yes 500 1218 12 500 Richardson. Buffalo 1,218 ™J Buffalo Yes 25.000 5,634 176!ooO 25.000 5,634 &gt;lfton S*T^ n ,, Z™ 2 '°°° i- 343 28 500 Da « son 2,000 1,343 ', ok Red Willow.. Yes 1,500 2,445 ioooo Bed Willow. Madison 1,500 2,445 son Madison Yes 1,000 1,479 19 000 1,000 1,479 e n •••■ Kearney No 1,238 25,000 Kearney Otoe ... iska City. iskaCity Otoe No 7.. 300 000 No h Antelope.... Yes 2,000 l ]:« 8 000 Ante'ope Madison . Dod;. Yes Yes Yes No 2,000 1,1*5 &gt;lk-... Madison Yes 8,000 3,^-83 61,000 Kend Dodge Yes 6,000 1,010 18 600 folk. 8,000 3,^-83 h Bend . . h Platte. Oakland 6,000 1,010 Lincoln. Burt 3,640 Yes 2,000 1,008 7,000 O'Neill Ora . . . . Holt 1,107 Valley No No No No No 1,372 2,270 28,000 140,000 Pawnee City. Plattsmouth. Ponca Pawnee. Cass .... l.ytw 5,496 Dixon 1.043 8,500 ■i Cloud. Paul .. Webster Howard Colfax . . 1,564 20, 000 20,000 32,000 43,000 1,475 KSSf: No No 2,175 Seward 1.970 Stanton Cheyenne . . . Stanton Yes Yes Yes No 1,000 1,001 1,200 HOO 1.052 7,500 Hromsburg. Superior Polk 1,000 1,154 13,000 » Nuckolls Clay 1,577 43,400 No 1,365 15,500 </seg>
            <seg id="p193">STATISTICS MUNICIPAL Table No. 1.— Concluded. city City Hall. Popula - tion. TOWM. COUNTY. Value. Indebt - edness. Tecumseh Tekamah . Johnson Burt ... Yea No 5,000 2,005 45,000 15,000 1,597 » University Place Lancaster ... Saunders Yes Yes No 500 1,130 19,000 10,000 20,500 14,000 2,100 Wayne Wayne Casa .. 2,119 Weeping Water. Point Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes 1,156 8,000 » Cuming. Saline .. 14,000 1,054 51,000 Wi.ber.. Wymore York... 1,500 1,000 12,500 fiage. York 2,626 10,000 5,132 j 30,000 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p194">gsa j jg'saWssas j :ss§ is^Jffg" 10 "^^ s 4 ax. t&gt; 333,O333t,333333~^°33 -3333 = 3333«H ---^--^--&amp;,2H-s-CL,eM&amp;,^p,i^ : c, ft, c-^. i, i. a, s, t, in N I &gt; :»' :Ss : :2Sg« : : :g^§ ;S :SS is* :§ « i 3 O el a 5 *n "c "c t; "c "C "s : : - cn3i3 -"c ■aa'C '•'E ;- C3 '"cccn 1 o '■ '. '■ '. o '■ *o :::::::: ©■ 1 • • • -lO • i-( -H : : :«" :«" : : :S S 5| |iMi|!|iNMMM| "C : : : :"E :~"n ::::::: :"c p- • : • : p4 :^iCh ■••:::::* i j ]2SS ': i :S : : « ss a : : : « ...&gt;■&gt;&gt;...(► : . :£££ : • : p* ::::: i jkij • ••••::: • iliifiJilJMl '. : '. c :::::: . ..*.::.^ . t:^ 5 C «,*.• o a © </seg>
            <seg id="p195">195 2 :a*3|'S8958iS»S8^^aSS : ° r S*8Saf85SS^2SS • ■ * © © CD © m -j - J ""* "~ '"" *^ ZH ~* ~ — "ZZ i)"^ ""* -j — m — — (^a&lt;a,P^pL«P4A*Pkft«P&lt;PkPHPHti&amp;*PHp4(l(KiiSPiftft &lt; PkPifcfi(E^pHa &lt; • ©©©©•©•© © • • • o ■ o a a ■ © • aj - a&gt; m - ~ -3 * ?&gt; ■■*■ *~ ?*■■■—- ■- rt • rt— ■ rf— c5 — Ph Ph Ph :-i : Ph Oh Ph : : : :-, &amp; : — £ z~ : s- =, : £ a* : o* a. p&lt; iiimmmmmm : : : :S :«2 : :S :S :::::: : i i : : : : : : :5 :£3 ■ • i •£ : : : : ... .1-1. ■— 3 '. '. U, . I* . . .'.'.'.'.'.I'. m j r n r r 1 1 i i i ; j m uimln ►JSSSZf5ZZKOCft&lt;a&lt;i&lt;PSMxx»!iBM!BM [ -('HD&amp;^^fti{^ </seg>
            <seg id="p196">196 MUNICIPAL BTATISTICS-Table No. 3. Value of Property of Expenses of Police Force Police Officers. City Jail? TOWN Fire Department. 1902. Albion. 1 Yes Yes Yes Yes No $ 750 Alliance 2 $i,r.r.o 300 Ashland 1 2,500 1,200 Auburn. 4 1,HH) Aurora 1 420 Beatrice 3 Yes Yes No 3. "00 3,000 Hlair 2 Broken How 2 TOO Central City 2 1.140 No 1,000 Chad ron 3 1. 100 Yes Yes Yes No 2,000 Columbus. 3 3,(MK) 1 2,000 David City 2 2 Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No 1,IMM) ■rbury rtield 2 ],2lKI l.(HM) 2 2.000 Falls City Fremont 2 2,500 3,000 5 7.5O» Friend. 1 1,600 Fullerton Geneva 1 1,000 1 400 Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No 600 id Island 5 3.700 10,0(10 ings 4 3,000 Maveloclc 2 230 l,;"&gt;00 Hebron 1 600 l.UOO lioldrege 2 l,2i&gt;o J Kiboldt rney 2 540 1,000 5,000 2 1.200 Lexington McCook 1 420 2 1,400 Yes Yes No 1.500 1,500 Madison 2 1,000 Minden 3 1,800 «oo Nebraska City 4 2,500 No No 5,000 Neligh. 0 1,000 Norfolk. 3 1,680 Yes Yes No 2,5i»0 North Bend I 1 360 1,500 North Platte Oakland 2 1,200 2,500 » 1 G00 Yes 600 O'Neill i too No 3,000 Pawnee City Plattsmouth 2 WO Yes No Yes No 2.000 3 1,560 2.500 Ponca 1 600 1,800 Red Cloud. 2 750 1,000 Paul 2 500 i No 1,500 Srhuvler. 3 1,400 1,000 Yes Yes No 2,500 * 2 2,500 J Sidney Stanton 1 180 1,700 ! 1 358 Yes Yes 800 Stromsburg 1 300 1,000 2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p197">197 MUNICIPAL STATISTICS- Table No. 3. TOWN Police Officers. Expenses of Police Force 1904. City Jail? Value of Property of Department. Button Tecumseh Tekamah University Place . . . Wayoe Weeping Water West Point Wilber Wymore 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 500 600 540 160 600 600 300 "00 420 Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes INo No Yes Yes "t 'ijooo Yes </seg>
            <seg id="p198">MUNICIPAL STATISTICS-Table No. 4. TOWN Churches Schools Public Halls Parks Saloons Albion Aurora Broken Bow Chadron Columbus Fafrbury Fremont j ricrid. ••••••••• •■■ Geneva Grand Island Hastings Humboldt Kearney Lexington Minden Nellgh North Bend Oakland Pawnee CitT Plattsmouth bchuyler. . f Stan ton !!!!!! Stromsburu 8 6 I 7 8 18 12 7 7 7 9 7 5 6 7 5 10 12 5 5 6 13 15 I 5 9 5 14 5 1 6 7 18 5 10 4 7 5 7 7 8 5 7 5 7 8 4 6 7 7 2 1 2 4 2 10 5 2 3 I 6 5 4 2 6 1 3 8 1 1 B 2 2 2 1 7 3 3 2 2 7 2 6 2 5 1 1 4 a i 2 1 3 6 1 1 1 3 2 4 2 3 1 1 3 2 3 2 1 1 3 2 3 1 1 1 7 1 3 2 3 2 1 2 1 1 1 4 2 2 0 1 1 2 'i 1 1 1 1 2 3 1 1 1 1 3 1 1 1 ■i i ■'- ■i 1 1 5 1 2 1 i 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 4 i 1 4 I 2 2 1 i 3 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p199">BUREAU OF LABOR 199 TOWN Churches Sch ola Pnbllc Halls Parks Saloon. Suttoo. • Tecumseh Tek imah Uniyersitj Place Wayne Weeping Water Wilber Wymore 10 8 6 1 11 7 4 7 6 2 4 2 2 15 2 1 3 2 1 1 1 4 1 i 2 1 1 1 ' 3 i i l 1 1 1 1 ii 'i i 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p200"/>
            <seg id="p201">Index </seg>
            <seg id="p202"/>
            <seg id="p203">I N I &gt;EX. Child Laoor Laws ... 81 Female and Child Labor Enforcement 84 Fire Escapes Enforcement Labor Laws of Nebraska . . 1) General Statutes ... 11 Code of Civil Procedure Criminal Code Municipal Statistics 192 Gas Plant, Electric Light Plant. Water Works 194 Police Officers, Expenses of Police Department, City Jail, Prop - erty of Fire Department . .196 Churches, Schools, Public Halls, Parks, Saloons 198 Statistical Tables. Acreage and Production for ten years 118 Acreage of Principal Crops . . 132 Acreage of Miscellaneous Crops • Acreage and Yield of Hay 138 Agricultural Productions ...117 Bank Deposits ..190 Barley Productions in 1904 Census o&lt; Manufactures ...114 Comparison of Leading States 130 Corn Productions in 1904 Ecclesiastical Statistics Fraternal Organizations 188 Meat Packing Industry 152 Number of head of Live Stoc k Oat Production in 1904 Professional Statistics Railroad Mileage in Nebraska . Railroads in Nebraska Rank of Leading Counties in Shipments . .146 Rye Productions in 1904 Statistics of Manufactures Ill Surplus of Commodities ■ . 138 Wheat Productions in 1904 </seg>
            <seg id="p204">Suggested Legislation ' CummaviT nf Sltoto T Q us 37 / ■mary of State Laws •• A .1 A ifinna 1 Pphi- ia inno in Fnrftp in Rnflt.nn .. • Additional Provisions in Force in Boston ' Age Limit 37 Dangerous Occupations «&gt;1 Educational Test ** 55 Enforcements Exemptions "* Hours of Labor '- 39 71 Laws of New York. Nebraska Child Labor Law "° No Age or Time Limit * Penalties Proof of Age 45 Standard Child Labor Law Value of Statistics 89 Value of Statistics in Nebraska 101 Voluntary Indorsements and Expressions 105 </seg>
            <seg id="p205"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>