<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Twelfth Biennial Report OF THE Commandant OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">'■f. ■ \ /' a s. r ? K s 5 d c a-. ' M 8 M s I P. ' s. c ■ ■ V=3 ■••; — , ; -- </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE OF NEBRASKA Twelfth Biennial Report OF THE Commandant OF THE Soldiers' and Sailors' Home MILFORD, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Bicnnium ending November 30, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">198 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Howard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and Silas A. Holcomb: Gentlemen : KI have the honor to submit the twelfth biennial report the Soliers' and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska. I In beginning this report I wish to express my gratitude the all-wise Providence for His goodness in preserving the moers of this "Home". tThe conditions existing in the "Home" and among the bers are the best. The food is of high quality and very cooked. We have done quite a bit of work in improving the Main Building. It has been painted from the top to bottom and new floors laid in all halls and rooms. An elevator also has been installed which runs from the basement to the top floor, saving many steps for the inmates. tThe new Hospital Building has been completed and has 1 occupied for the past six months. A new walk has been t around the new Hospital Building. kThe new Laundry Building is about ready to be occupied when completed, will be one of the best laundries in the institutions. tThe institution does not attempt to do much farming out - of gardening truck, such as green corn, field corn, po - !S, cabbage, cucumbers, beets, onions, radishes, etc. The en truck, fruit, etc., is used for the "Home". In favor- Milford, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 199 &gt; I able seasons we have fruit, such as apples, cherries and plums. The pigs eat the refuse of the tables which is almost enough to keep them. When hogs are sold the money received is credited to the institution cash fund of the "Home". List of garden truck and other products raised the last two years: Cora 380 bushels @ $0.65 per bushel $247.00 Potatoes 750 bushels @ .70 per bushel 525.00 Cabbage 500 head ® .05 per head 25.00 Cucumbers 30 bushels © .60 per bushel 18.00 Beets 50 bushels @ .40 per bushel 20.00 Onions 50 bushels @ 2.00 per bushel 100.00 Total Hogs sold and now on hand: 32 hogs sold at $610.08 36 hogs on hand now, value about 70949 One old engine and parts sold to the Nebraska Soldiers' and Sail - ors' Home, Burkett, Nebraska for $213.00 One Generator sold to the Nebraska Corn Mills 100.00 Cinders sold to the amount of 11.25 I recommend that the following amounts be appropriated to meet the necessary expenses of the institution for the next biennium : I— Maintenance $ 70,000.00 (a) Salaries and Wages , _. 30,000.00 (b) General Repairs _ 15,000.00 II — New Equipment and Furniture 2,500.00 III — Permanent Improvements to Buildings and Grounds 1,000.00 IV— New Buildings and Grounds _ 15,000.00 Total _ $133,500.00 I have asked for $15,000 for new buildings for barn place to put wagon, machinery, hog shed, and ice plant, which. I think, would be a saving. Buildings and equipment would not cost much over $5,000. The old Hospita 1 Building needs repairs very much, should be plastered or some kind of cealine material put on and also needs painting. The porches on the Main Building need repairing and painting. In closing this report I wish to thank the Governor of the State, John H. Morehead, for the courtesy he has at all times shown me as Commandant of this "Home". I also </seg>
            <seg id="p005">200 wish to thank the members of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions for looking after the supplies that have been furnished and in granting every request that I have asked at their hand. I am also under obligations to the W. R. C. of the state for the many beautiful and useful gifts received from them. I have the honor to be, Yours very truly, D. C. Rowden, Commandant. Milford, Nebraska, November SO, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">V- i; ;f x ■s. M Q ■ B s. - ■i. 'X E I Z - X Si x s &gt; M Q a </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 201 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For T«r For Ye«r en.liiii: ending ToUl Xot. .10, Not. 30, for MOVEMENT for 1915 1918 Biennlum M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T Present at beginning of period.... Admitted : U« 11 137 110 S 118 114 19 135 For first time-. » « t« a 7J n a 12 Transferred from other institution* Returned from furlough before rotn 3 5 8 3 5 8 mencement of period » 5 14 21 8 27 30 11 41 Totals.. 1T4 16 WO 182 44 126 24« W M Discharged : No longer requiring institution care.... Pied Id lnstitt.tion 30 2 32 26 4 SO 56 «C2 12 12 17 4 21 2» 4 3J On furlough not returned during period 21 6 27 28 10 :M 10 M &lt;S Total ». n » h ii is &lt;-o r.4 V, im Remaining at end of period... Average number In institution 110 8 118 111 10 121 111 18 129 131 14 14.'. l.» -I" ir&lt;» 270 M 304 TABLE II. AGE OF THOME ADMITTED For Tear For Year ' ending ending Total Not. .TO. Not. 30, for 1915 1910 Biennlnm i ' For Tear For Tear ending ending Total Not. .TO. Not. 30. for for M F. T. M F. T. M. F. T I 2 , 1 2 4 » 2 « 40 npil under 50. 40 hd(1 under 50 VI and UDder 00. DO .iml under 7&lt;&gt; 70 and under Si'. SO and i.uder W&gt;. VI and under 00. DO .iml under 7&lt;&gt; 10 ..... 10 10 20 30 » M 40 70 and under Si'. K 33 33 5 .11 11 1 70 SO and i.uder W&gt;. 5 5 « 3 • 11 III ID — 4* SI 30 81 100 W 130 4» — m SI 30 81 100 .10 130 TABLE III. CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Ye«r For Temr ending ending Total CIVIL 8TATT8 Not. 30, Not. SO, for 1915 1916 Bien ilium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Single *&gt; W 7 ..... f\ 17 IT Married - 1» 15 14 12 M » 12 41 Widowed *« — 24 » 18 48 M 18 71 Total* 49 4» 51 SO 81 100 SO 130 Foi ei X&lt; AGE M 10 K 5 Mk_ hi- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">i TABLE IV. NATIVITY OF THOME ADMITTED For Year For Year ending •■inline Tot.i! NATIVITY Nov. 30, Not. 30. for 1!)].". 1916 Blfiinhim M. F. T. M F. T. M F. T Vnlted States otlier th«n Nebraska.. 45 43 46 28 74 91 28 119 Total native born 45 43 4« 28 74 91 28 110 England _ - 1 II. 1 1 Uermaiiy . - 1 1 3 3 4 4 Ireland _ 1 1 2 2 3 3 Norway 1 1 1 11 1 2 France 1 1 ' 1 1 France Total foreign liorn j 4 4 5 2 7 1 9 2 11 Totals 49 ■» 51 30 81 100 30 130 TABLE V. PREV1OI K OCCUPATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year ending cndinz Total Nov. 30. Not. 30. for OOTPATION for ISIS 1916 i Biennlnm M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T i-arpenter 2 _.... 2 ; 2 2 Farmer - 23 23 26 26! 49 49 Laborer 21 21 20 20 ; 41 41 No occupation.. Painter 1 1 1 1 Physician Publisher - 1 1 1 1 Salesman — 1 — 1 | 1 1 Teacher - 1 1 1 1 Housewife - 30 30 , 30 30 Totals 49 49 51 30 SI ! 100 30 130 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 203 ! TltiLE VI. (OINTl OF FKSIDEX'E OF I HOSE ADMIT(KI) \NT&gt; CI THOME KKM MMM. AT END OF KIKNMI M For Year ending For Tear All ending Total Remaining cor xt v Not. 30, Not. 30. for Not. 30, 1915 1918 Biennium 1918 Buller Buller 2 2 _ 2 2 3 3 t 2 2 S S Adams i Adam* 2 2 2 _ ? Boyd — 11 1 Bovd — ; 1 1 2 ...... 2 3 _ 3 » _. S 2 __. 2 J _.. 3 3 - ... S I Burt Burt ! _ i i if t i a i "1 s Buffalo Buffalo Tinning _ 1 1 Cnming 1 1 1 _ 1 2 2 2 2 &lt; 'uRter ' Cunter .. 1 ...... 1 1 _.... 1 1 1 1 ..- 1 1 1 1 1 C»M ...L i 1 1 it.catBlati Cans | 1 1 ( I I' | 3 2 5 Cherry Cherry i i i i i i 1 1 1 1 1 1 I'ouclaK 10 10 Douglas 10 10 7 S HI 17 3 20 » 3 M Hi 17 3 20 33 3 M Podge _ 1 1 Podge _ 1 1 1 1 2 2 2 _.. 2 1 1 I 2 2 2 _.... t ■ Gait* 3 S Gage .1 3 « ft 3 9 B 3 0 fi 8 .1 9 8 3 • &lt; innlpu 1 — 1 1 .... 1 1 _... 1 Garden 1 — 1 1 1 1 _.. 1 Fillmore Fillmore _ 2 2 _ 2 2 ._ 2 2 ■• Hall 2 2 Hall 4- &gt; ««L'8«2S 1 I _.. 1 1 _.. 1 1 4L-88l'8«28 Kearney Kearney 1 I ! 1 1 i _ .. 1 1 Lancaster 1!» IK Lancaster 1!» IS 14 .". l!l X\ 5 38 3» It) 4'.. 3473473 47 14 .I IS 33 5 38 SO 111 4» 3 473473 47 Neiuaba N'eiuaha pintte 1 1 piatte 1 1 1 1 2 _.. . 2 1 1 Pnelpa _ Phelps 1 1 1 1 1 -.. 1 1 1 1 1 1 _... 1 Richardson 1 1 lltfllS|«t1 Richardson 1 1 i i 1 1 s a ■ I 4 i Seward S S Seward 4 4 R 7 4 11 11 8 17 Salne 2 2 Salne 3 3 .'. 5 5 S 1 1 1 _ 1 Sarpy 1 1 Sarpy , 1 1 ;;; _..:: s ... I Thurston * Thurntnn .. ; 3 t York _ York 1 2 .T 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 Si 1 2 3 M'nyne 1 1 M'jiyne 1 1 Total* | 40 49 „ l 12 2 4 1 1 I 2 2 4 TntaN •» 49 ■ 30 »l 100 30 130 136 39 178 ■ 30 M 100 30 130 139 39 178 TABLE VII. NATI'RE OF SEKVIC K ON WHICH ADMISSION 18 BAHKD For Tear For Year SERVICE M. F. T. I M. F. T. M. F. T I. War in which enlisted: Civil War Spanish-American War I. War :n which enlisted: CItII War 42 47 4!) SO 79 9« SO 12*1 2 2 2 2 4 _... 4 42 47 ! 4!) 30 79 98 SO 1M Spanish-American War j 2 4 _.... 4 Totals Totalu 49 . 4» 51 .TO 81 100 30 1»&gt; 40 . 4» 51 30 81 100 30 l.tfl II. Dkkki of service: fa) Volunteers - II. KMnlon of aerTice: fa) Volunteers 40 48 ■ 51 100 _.. 100 « (h) Artillery 5 5 8 CaTalry Infantry t 4 14 14 18 18 40 40 32 32 72 72 Navy and marine. 46 49 51 31 100 MO Totals. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. K. T. ending --fl i-iir T.til Xrv. SO. Nov. *&gt;. for IMS 1O1B Ripnniuni ToUli.. « tt 51 51 100 __.. 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">204 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABU Till. 8TATE OF KM.lSiT.MI-.XT OF MEN ADMI ilHI For Year For Year eniiluc Hiiitiii; T&gt;AMt STATE Xov. 30, Not. 30, for 191* ' Birnnium 191. r &gt; M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T IlllnoU _ 13 IS 13 5 IS M .1 31 Indian. _._ _. 3 SO 1 10 12 1 13 Iowa :. 10 10 IS 7 20 23 7 30 Kuni - _ 2 ..._. 2 ! 3 S 3 .1 Mmaaacbnaetta 1 1 1 1 Minnesota _ - 2 2 3 1 4 5 1 • Maryland „ ' 1 1 1 1 Miasourl .- 3 3 1 1 S 1 4 »w Hampshire _ _ 1 1 1 1 New York _ 5 _ 5 2 2 7 7 N. ■« Mexico-. _ _ 1 1 1 1 Ncl.raaka _ _..- 4 __.. 4 1 2 J 5 2 T Olilo _ _ 5 3 7 !i 2 7 F&gt;nnijlT«iiii _..._ — | 5 5 4 4 5 4 » Vf rmont ..._ ! ..._ _ _.... 1 1 1 1 Wisconsin ..._ % 3 _ 2 2 3 2 •* I J 2 2 3 Total*. 4» m m. so si i loo so im i TABLE IX. AGE AT DEATH For Year ending For Year end in-; Total Not. 30, for a&lt;;f Not. 30. 1915 1916 Biennlum M. F. T 11. P. T. If. P. T I and under 70.... and nnder 80-... and nnder 90. 2 2 t 2 7 18 • i io is a is S 3 2 IO 11 2 13 Totals 12 1 13 IT 3 20 29 +33 </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 205 TABLE X. PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN HOME OF THOSE WHO DIED DIKING BIENMI'M For Te«r For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30. Xnv. 30. ror 1915 1910 Blennlum PERIOD M. F. T. Jl. F. T. SI. F. T L F. T. M. F. I. II. F. T. 1 . i i i Leas than six months... _ _ _ _ 1 — 1 ! 1 — 1 From « to 12 months. _. I I 2 •_' 2 2 2 4 2 2 •_• 2 2 2 4 From 1 to 3 year*-. 3 3112415 3 ■ 1 1 4 15 From 2 to 5 years-. From 5 to 10 years.. From 10 to 16 years... S 3 3 3 6 • 3 3 3 2 2 4 1 5 1 « 1 7 4 1 5 « 1 7 2 2 8 8! 10 18 2 2 8 Totals.. 12 ...... 12 17 4 21 1 29 4 SS TABLE XI. CAUSE OF DEATH For Tear For Tear ending ending Total Not. SO, Not. SO, for CAISE OF DEATH for Ml 1916 Biennlum M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T 1st tuna 2 _ 2 Apoplexy — — ~ 1 — - 1 1 1 Bladder trouble _ 1 1 1 1 Bronchial- tronl.le - 1 -.... 1 1 _... 1 firrnhoBis of liver 1 _... 1 _ _ II 1 Congestion of lungs _ 1 II 1 1 Chronic bronchitis- - 1 — 1 . _ i 1 1 Dropsy - ...- - i — 1 1 1 1 General debility 1 1 ! 1 1 General senility I 1 — ' ll 1 1 Olflngreen j 1 1 1 1 Heart trouble . S .11 1 23 1 4 Liver trouble.... Old age 1 1 _ ! 1 1 2 2 3 1 4 5 1 • 3 S 9 2 Pneumonia Paralysis 1 li ill i 2 Pectoris (angina) Stomacb trouble I'lcer of the stomach.. 1 i _ l i 1 _.. 11 _.. 1 S J ; 3 J Totals... 12 1 13 IT S 20 2* 4 33 </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>