<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00092.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0092.0014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Wound Healing in Potatoes (Triumph Variety) as Influenced by Type of Injury, Nature of Initial Exposure, and Storage Conditions</title>
               <date value="18??">July 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OE AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 102 Wound Healing in Potatoes (Triumph Variety) as Influenced by Type of Injury, Nature of Initial Exposure, and Storage Conditions - V H. O/Werner Department of Horticulture ¦'¦.'¦'•".¦' ' - ; .". :¦' \ ¦ I¦' ¦ :. " . ¦ .¦¦¦']¦ ¦ .'•¦ ¦ '". - ¦"¦' . •¦¦ ';' ¦ ¦ j '¦ : ..: ... '.-. ' " ..' . '.' i ¦ ¦i' ¦ ¦¦""¦• ' - ¦ ; ¦.'¦¦. : ¦;¦' ¦ : -¦''.'¦']¦ ¦-¦:¦¦'.'• ':- r ¦ :.¦¦ .¦".'. '.'•¦¦¦¦¦'! LINCOLN, NEBRASKA j ! JULY, 1938 ; </seg>
         <seg id="p002">i ¦ CONTENTS l.mr.iturc Review 3 ¦ )blccls. Procedure 7 Rale .in.l I-Akni of 1 ic-jling of Tyi&gt;c\s of Wounds 9 Hkct "I Tuuper.mirc .mil Light ltcforc Storage Hi I Ilict "t 1 tm l-'ormaldcmdc on Tangential Cuts 37 I -lit r.iiurc Cited 39 SUMMARY 1. 1 numpli tubers that were subjected tn tangential and railial cuts and "feather - "'.- (removal of pcridcrmj were exposed tn sunshine for varying periods of time .mil \ure lit Id under di/Terent storage conditions. Sections were cut from samples taken a! intervals from rive tn 265 days after injury to determine the rate and extent til [lie several wound-healing phases. 2. With tangential cuts in tubers held in humid-cellar storage, typical of the type available in western Nebraska and adiacent states, subcrization of parenchyma beneath rlie cut surf.ue occurred between the third and fifteenth day, phcllngcn activity was .ipp.mnt Ix-nveen the twentieth and fortieth days, and phcllcm cells (subcrized wound - o.rk perulernu were first apparent on the fifteenth day with the differentiation of tins region practically completed by the fortieth day. i. Healing lit radial nits into tubers dilTered from tangential cuts by later anil li~- extuiMvi Hiberi/ation, which always was sparse and sometimes absent inside the wli-m. but with an earlier and more persistent phcllogcn and earlier formation of a phelkm, which seemed to be thicker. The inner portions of a radial cut healed much more vlmvlv than the |»irtion close to the old pcridcrm. 4. Under "leathered" wounds (removal of periderm) subcri/Jtinn .started earlier Inn w.is slower and less eMensne than under radial cuts. Periderm formation seemed to -t.irt l.itt r and was less e\tensi\c. x With .ill t\pes of wounds a "wound periderm" was never observed to have diuloped across the cells immediately under the old periderm (probably outer cortical ii IK;. alihiun.'h the cell- in this region were the first to be subcrized. &lt;&gt;. As the se\irn\ ot the i\|K&gt;sure of tangential wounds was increased, there was in UKH..IM in tin thickness ol the false cicatrice (consisting of layers of dead cells) .mil .ipparentli i.irlier initiation ol and more prolonged and extensive suberizatinn of pariiKlnma. l'lulloi;en activity was delayed and was less extensive, resulting in later formation ol a thinner phcllctn. 7 1 Aposun ol radial cuts to sunshine resulted in less damage and less retardation nt uoiiml-lu.ilmi: processes than with tangential cuts. As the severity of the exposure iikn.ised the cracks became wider, the false cicatrice became wider and extended further—though to a greatly reduced thickness—into the deeper portions of the cuts, suUcn/ation of parenclnma occurred earlier, was more prolonged, and more extensive, Inn the wound periderm which developed later was less extensive. 5. I'eathereil tubers alter c\|x&gt;sure to sunshine healed in very much the same manner as did wounds of tangential cuts. H h». Wounds of tangential)) cut tubers, and also radially cut and feathered tubers, : Kcnm suberi/.ed and developed a wound periderm much more quickly in a warm j humid room t/i.in when heM in a humid cellar. In dry cellar storage the process was Mill slower. In cold storage suherization \\;is greatly delayed and a phcllogcn never i developed. Exposure to sunshine did not materially alter the effect of various storage i conditions u|xin the wound-healing process. ; Id. Treating freshly wounded tubers with hot formaldehyde was found to cause : much damage to unprotected tissues anil a consequent increase in mold and rot in ! storage. I i. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">Wound Healing in Potatoes (Triumph Variety) as Influenced by Type of Injury, Nature of Initial Exposure, and Storage Conditions H. O. WERNER! .. '&lt; ' Tul)ers o£ the Triumph variety of potatoes, the one most extensively grown in western Nebraska, are more susceptible than those of other varieties to the various types of injury that occur at harvest time. This greatei suscepti )ility is chiefly the result of long stolons, unusual tender - ness o:: skin, ai d ease with which the tubers crack. The two latter char - acteristics have been accentuated by the custom of late planting adopted genera! Iy throughout the region in recent years. '¦:'., In western Nebraska from 9 to 35 per cent of the annual crop of potatoss raised Ifor certification from 1928 to 1935, have been rendered unfit for U. S.hNo. 1 grade because of mechanical injury (22).-' Probably mechanical injury is more serious throughout the entire region than these figures indicate! since most growers do not handle' potatoes as carefully as do the growers of certified seed. More than 95 per cent of the potatoes upon which these data are based were of the Triumph variety. Many of the difficulties could be avoided by growing another variety. However, as. there now seems to be no other variety as well adapted to the growing conditions of the region and.because of the established special market for seec and table use over a wide area it is inadvisable to con - sider a change :o any other variety. Thus for the near future and possibly for a ronsiderable period of time the most logical procedure is to use methods by wh eh such damage will be avoided. Much progress has been made n.this d rection, but serious damage is frequently unavoidable be - •cause cf uncont ollable atmospheric and soil conditions just previous to and during digging time (6, 7,17, 21). It is to the advantage of the grower to salvage these d; maged tubers as best he can in order to be able to market them as a lower grade or to hold them over till planting time as seed potatoes for his, own use. In order to do this intelligently it is desirable to know the extent to which field exposure of Wounded potatoes will in - fluence the rate of wound healing. It is also desirable to know the extent to which the healing process is inhibited or expedited by different types of storage conditions which might be provided when tubers have suffered different types of wounds. : • LITERATURE REVIEW The earliest studies on the wound healing process in potatoes seem to have been those o' Hcrchtolil (3), DeVrics (5), Kny (JO), Prunct (16), Olufscn (11), and Appcl i 1). The 'mast complete study as to the nature of the process was reported by I'rie.'tley and Woflcndcn (15) in 1923. Under conditions favorable for rapid heal - ing, the process is quite generally understood to involve: (a) color changes at the sur - ' 'The author acknowledges Ilic coitjicralion «f Milrofan Afana&gt;icv ami George SchmM iir &gt;cciir - . inj* hijlo bfical samples al proper intervals anil of -Mary Sclirocilcr, who prepared slidci used in tins investigation. . -' . ' ' ¦¦.. . '. ¦ :,' ¦' :, ° Publ cations arc lislctl at ilic liack of the 'bulletin. </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 f,nc which ;irc of no material consequence; (b) the deposition, on the walls of outer alls, nt a (ally "subcrin-likc" layer resulting from the oxidation and condensation (if tarn substance deposited by the sap as it dries up in the tissues at the injured surface; (c) the dcvolupmcnt under this subcrized layer of a cork mcristcm or phcllogcn, the cells of which arc converted into phcllcm cells by subcrization. The development of this wound jK-ridcrm is accompanied by the disappearance of the starch grains in the dividing cells. The range and extent of these processes is principally dependent upon the variety jKculiarilics, oxygen supply, temperature, and humidity. The necessity of oxygen for subcrization was early shown by DcVrics (5) and Kny (HI). Kabus (')) founii that when cut surfaces were pressed together no subcrin was formed except where an air bubble had been caught. Priestley and Woffcndcn (15) round that oxygen was essential for the subcrization process, but that while it was not necessary for the formation of a cork mcristcm the latter did not develop unless the surface was blocked off by a layer of subcrized tissue or by some artificial means. Olufsen (11) reported that the larger the cell complex in relation to the lesion, the more favorable were conditions for pcridcrm building. However, Habcrlandt ' (ia) stated that the si/c of the wound in relation to the amount of tuber tissues did not seem to alter the healing power materially, except that healing did not occur when pieces were so small that the) did not contain any phloem vessels. Priestley and Woffcn - ilen reported that the first cork mcristcm developed in the immediate vicinity of ihc \ivcular bundles, suggesting that this was due tti the bathing of these tissues with the substances diffusing under the suhcrized layer of cells from the phloem. Kabus rc - ixirtcd greatest wound healing activity in cuts near buds. Kny and Olufsen reported prompter healing by unripe and undeveloped tubers than by old tubers. Chcvclcy (as reported by Priestley and Woffcndcn) found that im - mediately after harvesting, small tubers were more active in cork formation than were large tubers. With mature tubers which had been in storage over winter, Priestley and Woffcndcn found no appreciable difference between small and large tubers. Shapovalov and Edson (IK) found that badly shriveled tubers did not heal under any conditions as well as firm ones. Their work thus confirmed the very early report by Berchtold that the healing power waned with the advance of germination, and by DcVrics, who reported lack of wound cork formation in seriously shriveled tubers. When partly shriveled |v&gt;tatocs were permitted to absorb water they were capable of forming wound cork (Shapovalov and Edson). Priestley anil Woffcndcn found that the rale of formation of subcrized cork mcristcm ivjs prac'ricifly doubled when the temperature was increased from 15° to 25° C. Artschwagcr (2) found that in Irish Cobbler potatoes subcrization of parenchyma cells under a cut surface was evident after the eighth day at 2/¦ ° C, the fifth day at 5° C, and after the first day at 21° to 35° C, and that temperatures over 30° appar - ently limited subcrization. He found that cuts in Rural New Yorker potatoes subcrized very slowly at temperatures below 10° C. In the Irish Cobbler potatoes the first pcridcrm cells appeared after the ninth day at 7° C. but none were ever observed be- Imv that temperature. At H)° C. they appeared after the fourth day, at 15° C. after the third clay, and at 21° C. after the second day. With the Rural New Yorker^ ami other varieties pcridcrm formation was much slower at temperatures below 21° C., at which temperature there was no apparent difference traceable to varieties. Smith (I'l; reported that with Rural New Yorker tubers stored on the clay of harvest, subcrization occurred on the second day when stored at 68° F. but not until the j sixth day in A(\° K. storage. Wound pcridcrm was observed first on the third day at i 6H° F. but none at all was found in twelve days at -)6° F. When the wounded j tubers were transferred from -)6° F. to storage averaging 56° F., they developed a ¦ wound pcridcrm within six days after the transfer. i Very recently Singh and Malhur (17a) reported that subcrization occurred on the ¦ third day with a 12-day prcstoragc temperature of 1«° C, but not until the ninth day j. with 7° C. Wound pcridcrm was noted on the sixth day at 18° but at the end of » 12 days more had occurred at 7° C. With the higher prcstoragc temperature, storage f losses were much less than wilh the. lower temperature. |. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Kny (10) and Olufscn (II) each concluded that moderate humidity is an essential requirement for wound pcridcrm formation but Olufsen reported that an excess hindered the process anil caused cell proliferation. He reported that the larger the wound, the moistcr it must be kept to enable healing. Artschwager (2) found that at all tem - pcraturt| the relative humidity exerted a very-noticeable effect upon both subcrization and pcridcrm development, the rate increasing as the humidity increased. He observed no unfavorable effects of high humidity with temperatures ranging from 2'A ° to 35° C, even though the humklit&gt;- closely approached saturation at the lower temperature. Arbthwagcr has reported that tubers from which the skin had been removed by peeling ir which were injured by contusion did not heal like those with cut and stab wounds. He also reported an irregular.development of. peridcrm below the margin of. injury erased by a blow that broke the original peridcrm, but only a slight develop - ment or none at. all beneath the tissues that were merely crushed, or else the wound pcridcrn formed in several tiers with crushed nccrotic tissue intervening. New pcridcrm cclh de\ eloped within one cell layer of the surface when potatoes 1, were peeled with a sharp knife but when the surface was much abraded in peeling,a deep-seated perulerm resulted. 1 Cut surfaces exposed to sunshine or dry air have been found to subcrize in irregular patches. Appcl ascribed this to lack of oxygen because of the difficulty of diffusion through the drying surface. Priestly and Woffcndcn concluded that the rapid drying of. the sap prevented uniform distribution of the fatty substances over the cut surface. Gmscqucntly the wound mcristcm occurred in patches—form - ing only under the cells previously, blocked by subcrization. The unprotected areas between these- healed patches exposed the tubers to the possibility of infection by rot - producirg organisms, as the hard dry shell-like layer of collapsed tissues (which formed in sunstinc or dry air) cracked very easily and was of np protective value. Werner (23) reported in 1936 that when cut surfaces of tubers were exposed to sunshine the rate of Weight loss, total weight loss, andi final total amount of rot increased as the duration or severity of the exposure increased. ; Appil reported that the subcrization which occurred within 24 hours after cutting protcctci the tuber against infection by B. phytophthonu. Weiss, Lauritzcn, and Bricrlcy (20) did not consider subcrin (through which fungi entered by mechanical penetration) an effective barrier against all species of Fusarium but they report that a wound jeridcrm excluded all Fusarium species tested as well as docs a normal pcridcrm. Since wsund cork formation was greatly delayed or never occurred at a tempera - ture of 5.7° or below, infection occurred at any time that moisture conditions at the surface vcrc /avorab/c for mycelia/ growth. Their work showed that wounds should be well wotcctcd with a pcridcrm before they arc subjected to temperatures which will be too low for wound cork formation but not too low for the growth of fungi, as was ihej case with F. cocrnleiini. Werner (23) found that storage losses and final total amount of rot were very much greater with damaged tubers placed in cold stor - age immediately after being injured than if stored in the cellar. Frorrl inoculation tests with four species of Fusarium, including F. trichothecioides (the molt prevalent potato storage rot-producing organism in western Nebraska), Weiss, Lauritzc i, and Brierlcy. reported that a protective layer developed more quickly with tangcnti:l cuts (almost passing through or just outside the vascular ring) than with tubers c it "through the middle" when Russet Rural and White Rural potatoes were used. With the four other varieties (including the Triumph) the trend of evidence was less marked. When the time-temperature factor was favorable to healing, infection did not occur in the tangential cuts but some occurred through median cuts. Below Jo° C there was no evidence of difference in infection in the two types of cuts. However, in their summary table No. 12, they report that with the Triumph variety, the total number of infections at all temperatures and at all intervals was considerably greater with all tangential than with the: median cuts, with each of the four species of Fusarium. As the differences were smaller and generally in the other direction with the other varieties used, this suggests that in the. Triumph variety the healing of these two types on wounds may not proceed in the same manner as with the other varieties. Werner (23) reported losses in storage following various types.of wounding. Cuts into </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 lulurs anil bruises caused least loss, tangential cuts caused much less loss than trans - verse c.r longitudinal halves, anil tubers completely feathered lost most of all. Pi-.u-iH.-k (12) observed macroscopically the effect of exposure of "skinned" areas upon the healing as indicated by color changes and skin replacement. He reported that skinned potatoes were severely injured when exposed during the middle of the day when the solar and sky radiation (gram calorics per square centimeter) was high, but others were not injured if exposed to low radiation even if the air temperature was high. The air temperature increased as solar radiation increased and at the same time the humidity decreased. The combination of all these resulted in increased water loss I nun skinned areas, which soon turned a brown to black color. An exposure of a half. hour in a clear mid-September midday sky did not cause much discoloration of skinned arc-as or appreciably disturb the healing of the area, but exposure of one hour caused J light-brown discoloration, while dark brown or black areas developed with exposures "I I - I" 2 huur&lt; and m these blackened areas "skin pcridcrm /ailed to develop." K.irl\ -morning* and late-aficmnnn exposures did not appreciably affect normal healing. Wlicn skinned areas were turned down onto the moist ground, the surfaces healed normally regardless of the length of time the tubers were left in the field. When placed in storage ranging from 32° to 90° F. all skinned areas that were injured by cx - [¦murr in the field turned dark, but those not injured in the field remained light colored. Later Peacock, Wright, and Whitcman (13) reported that with tubers skinned in the ixtcnt &lt;il about 1(1 per cent of the surface, shrinkage as measured by weight loss dunng 12 weeks of storage varied from 1.8 per cent at 60° In 16.3 per cent at :2 ]¦'.. as compared with comparable losses of 2.S and 5.1 per cent with uninjured tubers. This great loss of weight from skinned tubers ami dark discoloration oi the miureil .ireas at the lower temperatures were attributed to the prevention of the for - mation &lt;t n wcund pcridi-nn. lor the healing "I wounds or protection of them against rot-producing organisms, tin use nf various siccatives and disinfectant treatments have been recommended. Wil - i»N. Link, and Pool (2-1) secured some control of the dry rot in storage by means of. a formalin dip (cnMj. formalin vapor, and lime-sulfur wash, but little or none by t)ic use of flowers of sulfur or air-slacked lime. The combination of three parts of lime and one nt flowers of sulfur may have increased the amount of rot. Pralt (14) rc - (iirtid lhat badly bruised tubers kept without decay after dipping for two hours into tidier furniaUkhydc (cold) or mercuric chloride, provided the application was made within -fN hours after digging. Neither lime nor sulphur was effective when applied as (lust. Apparently no histological studies concerning the effect of these treatments were nude prior to those reported by Shapovalov and Edson (18), who reported sulphur to be lit no consequence in the healing process. Priestly and WofTcndcn (15) reported that neither caustic nor air-slacked lime seemed to aid the formation of a normal subcrin dc|visit. l.iiile suberin was found in limed potatoes, probably because the fatty acids wire prci.-ipit.itcd at the surface as calcium soaps instead of condensing to subcrin. I hey reported greater water losses per unit of cut surface after dusting with lime than wlu-n not dusting. Clavton (4) reported that none of a number of treatments had any visible effect on corking of cut surfaces except that a dust of equal weights of flowers of sulphur and air-slacked lime caused the development of a "thicker, tougher protective layer." Hcrklots (H) concluded that alkalinity at the cut surface (pH 7.5) promoted suber - ization but retarded meristematic action, tvhercas acidity promoted phcllogcn activity I in the subcrized block but retarded subsequent subcrization of tissues thus formed. ], Werner (21) found that the standard hot-formaldehyde disinfection treatment applied }' 1. 6, and 24 hours after cutting caused the destruction of numerous layers of cells under || the cut surface and delayed the rate and extent of the wound-healing process but by j the end of 3 days the healing process was so far along that no damage was done by r the treatment. i Appel (1) and Priestley and Woffcndcn (15) reported that varieties differed greatly t in the rale at which they deposited subcrin on walls of injured tissues or laid down f { </seg>
         <seg id="p007">• ' . Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes a would pcridcm. Weiss, Laurilzcn, and Bricrlcy (20) reported that the considerable diftcrerccs which they found in the rate at which subcrin was deposited in injured tissues, or wound cork was established, were followed by similar differences in resistance to infection by Fusaria. The Spaulding Rose and Irish Cobbler healed most quickly and were the most difficult to infect. The wounds of Russet and White Rurals healed most slowjy and were most easily infected. Green Mountain and Triumph occupied intermediate positions with regard to both wound healing and infection. In 4 recent publication dealing with a storage study parallel to the one reported in this bulletin, the writer has considered storage losses with sound and damaged Triumph potatocj that had been exposed in various ways before storage and that were stored under two different conditions (23). The results reported show greatly increased losses due to injuries, the extent of the losses having been in proportion to the extent of the injured | areas. Losses with cut potatoes.were increased in proportion to the severity of exposure to. the sun. With cold storage in the fall, weight losses were greater than when cellar storage was used. These losses were reduced by an initial week of cellar storage prior to cold storage. Rot-producing organisms which entered the tubers be - cause oi. the lack of a protective barrier across wounds, were responsible for the greater part of the weight losses encountered when damaged tubers were stored. OBJECTS OF THE INVESTIGATION Th: objectives of this investigation were: (1) to determine the rate.and extent of the wound-healing process with different types of wounds in Triumph potatoes, when (2) exposure to different atmospheric conditions (typical of commercial procedure) immediately after injury was followed by (3) different types of storage, and also to determine (4) the effect of the hoi: formaldehyde treatment and (5) the effect of light of various types upon the healing of cut potatoes. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE In arder to attain these objectives, freshly harvested Triumph potatoes grown on dry land in western Nebraska (near Alliance) were injured by: (a) cutting-off tangential slices similar to those made by a digger, (b) makinfe radial cuts into the tubers so as to simulate the cracks which fre-. qttentl* occur in harvesting and (c) by "feathering" (removing the outer skin o: periderm from about one-third of; the tuber surfaces) so as to simulate the partial skinning suffered by potatoes as they rub against each other cr against the sack during harvesting. After being subjected to these injuries, some of the injured tubers were exposed to sunshine for variou - periods of time with wounds placed in several positions with regard to ex - posure to the sun, while others were placed in storage at once. In all in - stances the check tubers (wounded potatoes not exposed to the outdoor air after wounding): were wounded when the sun-exposed tubers were placed in the jseveral storages. AH tubers of one treatment (one type of wound, exposure, and storage) were placed in a paper bag with wounds toward the top and with the tops of the bags left open. More details concerning the exposure treatments and types of storage are supplied in the several sec - tions where experimental results dealing therewith are supplied. : . . Reords of atmospheric conditions, before and during storage were obtained at as frequent intervals as the nature of the conditions warranted. Temperature records were secured by thermographs and thermometers. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nlbraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 Atmospheric moisture conditions were determined by a sling psychrometer (tor relative humidity) and spherical white atmometers (for evaporating power ot the air). An approximation of the solar radiation on the day the potatoes were exposed to the sun was secured by determining the ratio of the evaporation from a black spherical Livingston atmometer to that Irom a white atmometer (Table 1). Weight losses etc. for sound and in - jured potatoes stored under similar conditions are reported elsewhere (23). Tabli. 1. — Atmospheric conditions on September 22, 1934, during the time when m)ured portions oj tubers were exposed to the rays of the sun. ('••n.liiuin .11 be- '¦""of '&lt;"s°f ..„,„ Ra'i" Kirniincofcach &gt;"'" »«« h " "." lo» from 1V",i,l &#132;1 HcriiKl from frora nooriy lilackto ...¦.ct&gt;.iii.iii I Mark while '.""• while Tcniiut- t Relative atmom- almom- white at- almom- amrc I luimidiiy clcrs clers mnmctcrs c[crl °F P.ct. cc. cc. cc. 10:05 to lll:.ii A. M. hi 48 4.9 2.') 5.8 1.67 111:11 tn llr.ill A. M. hi -15 5J 5.X 3,1 MO 11 :SU vi 12:25 I. M. fi'i 43 5.4 4.0 4.4 1.34 12:25 tn 2:10 P. M. 7i j(l H. 4 11.1 7.0 1.29 2:10 to 3:.M) P. M. 77.5 2i 11.8 10.0 7.5 1.18 5:311 to 4:25 P. M. 77 2f. 4.0 4.4 4.8 1.12 4:25 in 5:15 I. M. 7-1 42 5.1 3.0 4.7 1.51 5:15 to 6:05 P. M. 71 44 3.1 2.5 3.0 1.23 1:05 (W 50 111:115 A.M. in 4:25 P.M. 4(i.7 36.2 5.7 ... Blocks of tissue of appropriate size which were cut out of three tubers in all treatments at appropriate intervals were fixed in formal acetic alcohol. Sections cut by means of the paraffin method were stained with ammon - iacal gentian violet according to Artschwager (a fresh lot of gentian violet made each day) and then counter-staining with Orange G. Types of wounds and of exposure after wounding are identified by the tirst number as follows: 1. 1 .injzcntial cuts not cximsctl tn sun (check) 2. Tangential cuts t-xjioscil tmvartl sun 6 hours (10:45 A. M.—4:30 P. M.) 4. Tangential cuts cxposal toward sun 1 hour (11:20 A. M. — 12:20 P. M.) 5. Tangential cuts exposed toward sun 1 Vi hours (4:25 P. M.—6:00 P. M.) f&gt;. Tangential cuts c.x/iosed away from sun ] V: hours (4:25 P. M. —6:00 P. M.) 7. Radial cuts not exjxised to sun (check). X. Radial cuts excised to sun (&gt; hours, cracks north to south. l. Radial cuts excised to sun 6 hours, cracks cast to west. Ml. Radial cuts exposed to sun 1 hour, cracks north to south. 11. Feathered tuhers (periderm rubbed off) not exposed to sun (check). 12. Feathered tubers exposed to sun 6 hours (10:20 A. M— 4:30 P. M.) H. Feathered tubers exposed to sun I! 4 hours (11:05 A. M—12:20 P. M.) Types of storage are identified by letter in the middle of each number complex: A. Warm humid room in carl) part of storage season. 15. Humid cellar. , C. Dry cellar. ', 1). O&gt;ld storage. </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Nu nber of days after injury when the section reported upon was securec is reported after the letter indicating type of storage. Eximple: 4820 designates a tangential cut exposed to midday sun one hour a id then stored in the humid cellar, the section reported on having been secured on the 20th day. (The series numbered LI to L 7 comprises the tangentially cut tubers exposed under various types of glass at Lin - coln in 1929.) Data for the various tables depicting extent of wound healing processes were secured by counting number of cell layers in each stage at various places throughout the sections, cross checking with all sec - tions involved with each factor in each series. The sketches were secured by tracing the outlines of each region as projected in a greatly enlarged image. Thus although the regions are shown diagrammatically their out - lines are based on the actual sections studied. . ; RATE AND EXTENT OF WOUND HEALING WITH DIFFERENT TYPES OF WOUNDS The general wound-healing procedure was much the same with various types cf wounds but the rate and extent of the different processes varied because of (a) the type of the wound, (b) atmospheric conditions im - mediately after wounding, and (c) the type of storage. As humid cellar storage appears to be the most desirable for wound healing and is suit - able for commercial practice, it seems desirable to consider first of all the healing processes which occurred with different types of wounds when they were exposed continually only to the atmosphere of a humid cellar. Details concerning the /atmospheric conditions in this cellar are presented in Tab c 6. Observations indicate that the air was considerably more humid in this cellar than is the^case in most commercial cellars in western Ne - braska .¦.';'-'• ;'/:'- - ;•¦..' ''• ¦¦.*¦¦. -';¦.¦ -.¦'. ¦"¦"¦¦.. '¦;•: - :- )¦¦ -'¦ '':' , ¦ ]¦¦¦. TANGENTIAL CUTS •;:..': :' ¦'.-,' ". ¦ . Tangential cuts were made on September 22 with a sharp knife so as to lea^e a wounded area about'one inch in diameter. The center of this tangential cut was generally sufficiently deep to involve the inner phloem or in a few instances a small amount of pith. The sampling blocks were cut so as to extend a short distance across the center of the cut area. When tangential cuts were exposed only to the atmosphere of the humid cellar (IB), a very thin false cicatrice consisting of a portion of one to all of one or two cell layers was developed during the second and third days (Table 2). These cells seemed to be quite completely dehydrated and as a result they collapsed. The starch grains in these cells appeared to remain intact throughout the entire storage period. This false cicatrice was most extensive in; the cortex arid pericycle, diminishing through the phloem and xylem toi practically complete absence in the perimedullary and pith regions. Suberization of cell walls began the third or fourth days. By the end of five days cells were suberized to a depth of about one layer throughout the cortex and three-fourths of a cell layer in the pericycle and one-half cell </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Ac.kl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 Table 2.— Extent of wound healing in tangential aits exposed for various lengths of time immediately after cutting, as observed at intervals after storage in a humid cellar (cellar B'J, stated in terms of number of layers of cells involved. I I'ri.iimcnt number and nature of exposure of cut surfaces Time ; .——— — ader fiH. I 1: hours SR, I'-hoitrs 4ft, 1 hour 211.6 hours ¦njury ! "*. notcv- away from sun toward sun toward sun toward sun I"""1"""" -I :*iVnl&gt;P. M. 4::&lt;i-fi:nri I. M. 11 ;2D-ll:2&lt;&gt; P. M. ln : 4v4::"H'.M. False cicatrice 40li.»ur« I) .5-10 3-10 ... 10-20 i,1.,,s ' -2 h-7 7-X 8-12 15-20 + 10 cl.iU 'j-2 fi-H 8-15 10-15 20-25 Sulkti/cil parenchyma 5 daw IM. GO-' 0-2, GO 0-2, GO O-'A, G'A 0-2 10 (lavs 1-3. Cillj 1-1.G2 1-3, (.2 1-3, G1 + '/:-4 2(Ula\» 1-1 2 2+ 1-3 1-4 411.1avv 1 l-.i 2 2+ 3 2-4 Phtllojicn (o( wound pcriclcrm)"* Hlilavs 11-1. (ill : » ? 0-1, GO 2(1 .lavs 1-i 1-4 0-1 0-i 0-2, GO 40.1.11. l-fi. 04 1-2 1-2 0-3 2-3 rs.by, M.C! 1-2 IM 0 0-2 12»il.i\- H-4. Gl 1-2 IM 0-1, GO 0-1, GO I'lOtl.iv. i)-4. C7II . . ¦ • •• 2f.0.1..V-. ii-^ U-2.G1 0-1, GO 0-3 0-2, GO PhcHcm 1(1 J.n&gt; 11-l 20 .lav. .'--I 2-i 0-2 1-3 0-2 40&lt;l:n« &gt;-5. (H+ -t-i 4 -1-5 3-5 , 75ila\N 1-6, CJS 4-5 -1 5-6 2-6, G4 12O.lay&lt; 4-7,05 4-5 3-5 4-5 2-6 l'lO (lays 4-7. Gfi ¦ • 2-6, 04 2("iO.lavv 4-8, Gfi -W 3-5 4-5 2-6, G4 I 1 For .nmi.splieric conduions during exposure period sec Table I; for cellar conditions Table 6. - Swiil'ul (', u&lt;fil to designate the most prevalent or "general" number or condition. " D.im cm suK-n/cd parenchyma not reported afler a phellcm had developed across all ot the cut lurf.icc. 'inr vLitiincnt enmerning usage of terms "phcllogcn" and "phellcm" sec footnote 3, page 11. layer in the outer phloem, while only the outer cell wall or part of it was suherized in the perimedullary or pith. By the tenth day there were from one to two suberized layers of cells across all tissue regions. Next to the old periderm. especially when it was partially torn loose by the cutting knife, least suberization occurred and more cells disintegrated, forming a false cicatrice of rather limited extent. Suberization continued a short time beyond the tenth day, and there were generally two to three suberized j cells in all regions by the twentieth day (Fig. 1, 1B20). j Phellogen activity, which was apparent at only a few places on the tenth | day, was most conspicuous between the tenth and twentieth days. \ </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Table 3. — Extent of wound healing in tangential cuts that were exposed to the sun at Lincoln on September 16,1929, tinder various types of glass for tight hours, as observed at intervals after storage in a cellar. ] ' . . : '-Treatment number ami type of glass used ¦ £ X^ Sl . L6SJ £1 L 3 L2suJ £ hs,Ll l 7" •»J«O Cl f, s Red; lucent Cello. Th,,.,. | k one Direct down E'"V ghis glass layers I layer sunshine ' False cicatrice . ¦ Iday . «-8 ¦ 7-10 7-12 12-15 12 16 17-25 I . " .Subcrizcd parenchyma Iday . C'-'i ' ... ... ¦¦'¦ . Q-Yi -..:¦¦ ..." .. 2days .. !•&gt;-! ... ... K-2 ... Gl/10 0-1, GO 3 days . 1-2 2-3, C2H \-2&lt;/i,Gl&gt;4 &gt;/,-3, GIJV:: .. : Gjj 0-1 GO "days . 1-2,Gl'/. 2-6.G3 IVI-4.G3 1-5.G3 2-4.G2 lVi-4,C2 1-4.G2 14 days . W, 02 2-6, C 3 lJi-5, G3 1-5, G-l 2-C, G3 HH, G2 M,G2 ¦ . 1 : . l'licllogen (of wound pcridcrm) 3 days . 0 Oi 0 (?) . 0 0 .0 0 7 days.. 0-3, GI 0-2, GO 0-2, GO 0-2. GO 0-3. G2 ¦ 0-3, CO ? 14 days . 1-3, G2 0-2, Gl, 0-3, G2 0-3, Gl 1-3, G2 1-3 1-3 21 days . 1-2, G2 0-3, G2 0-2, GO 1-3, G2 1-3, G3 2-3 1-3 28 days . 1-3, G2 .. , .. 2H, G2 .. 2-3 l-t,G3 35 days . 1-3, C 2 ... . :. 0 : 2, GO &#132; ... M 1-2, Gl ¦. ' , . ¦ riicllem ¦ .; ..': . ; 7 days . 0-2 0 (t) O-I.GO ' 0 0-2.G0 0-I.CO 0 Hdays . 3-C, G3+ 0-3,02 2-5, G3 1-3, G2 0-3, Gl 1-4, G2+ 2H, G2 21 days . .3-6, C\ 2^, G3 3-5, G4. 2-4, G3 2-5,03 2-5, G2 3-5, G3 28dajs . 4-6.G5 .. .. 3-7, Ci ¦ .. . . 3-fi, Ci -t-6, G-l 35 days . 4-fi, G5 ... 3-6.G4 .. .. 3-6,G-t 4-6, G5 SampWs were not secured when data are not- tenoned. . :. On th^ twentieth day a phellpgeri two to three cells thick 3 was iEound throughout most of the tissue from the pericycle through the perimedul - lary region. In the cortex and pith it developed later and to a less degree than ir the other regions, being least extensive in the cortex. It never developed in-those cells which might be considered as either the outer cortical cells or the phelloderm o£ the original periderm of the tuber— the san c region in which suberization of parenchyma cells was found to be less extensive than in the inner cortex. Greatest phellogenic activity was obierved between the twentieth and fortieth days when the phellogen was three to six!cell layers thick in the perimedullary and pith but only one to thrfet cells thick in the pericycle and generally absent in the cortex. By the 75th day the phellogen activity had diminished considerably, being faund only in regions inside of the pericycle where it was three or four eel layers thick. By the 120 th day there was a phellogen of one to three ctll layers at a few places in the perimedullary or pith but at all other places the cells were seldom found in the cortex or pericycle, but as many as three or four were found .it numerous places in;the vascular parenchyma region. There appeared to be a reactivation of the phellogen with the * In ih is. bulletin the term "phcllogen" is used to designate'both the true phclfogen or layer of dividing cells and the¦ mcristematic. cells derived therefrom but which did not stain with gentian violet as did the more mature phcllem cells. "Phellem" is used to designate'only the cells that did stain wilh gentian.-violet. ¦. . ; ' . .-. . -'¦ . \ '. . . </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Xi-.braska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 slightly hijjrhcr spring-time temperatures preceding the 260 th day, for then there were more phellogen cells in the vascular zone than earlier even though some phellogen cells had been converted into phellem since [he I'Klth day. Phellcm cells Here differentiated from the phellogen about the fifteenth day. Ky the twentieth the phellem was generally two cell layers thick throughout the entire cut surface except for the outer cortex. By the fortieth day, when most of the phellem had been differentiated, it was lour to seven cell layers thick with four in most places (Fig. 1, lEMO). At this time new phellogen cells were apparently being differentiated only across tissues inside the pericycle, but the walls of those previously formed were being suhcrized so that by the 75th day phellem was at least four cell layers thick in all except the outer cortical portions. The layers of phellogen cells differentiated before the 75th day were almost all suberized by the ] 20th day, but a tew layers of phellogen cells were observed on the l'Hlth day. mostly inside the pericycle. With a rise in the temperature after the 2lM)th day, walls of a few of these late-formed phellogen cells located in central tissue were suberized, so that by the 260 th day the number of lau-rs of phellem cells was slightly greater and more uniform throughout than at earlier dates. RADIAL CUTS OR CRACKS INTO TUBERS Radial cuts were made by cutting into the tuber to a depth of one centimeter with a thin knite blade, the cuts being three to five centimeters long, depending on the size and shape of the tubers. The healing problem presented by such cuts differed in several major respects from that with tangential cuts. The two sides of the cut remained relatively cloJe together, thus providing Jess opportunity for loss of mois - ture by evaporation and also inhibiting movement or exchange of gases. Relatively less cortical and pencydic tissue and more phloem, xylem, and pcrimedullary tissue were involved for a given area of wound in cracks than in tangential cuts. With radial cuts the false cicatrice was of more limited extent than with tangential cuts (78, Table 4, compared with 18, Table 2; also Figs. i and 5). It seldom involved more than one cell layer and rarely occurred inside of the cortex. Suberization occurred more extensively by the fifth day in the cortical region of the radial cuts than in the tangential cuts. Although there was little or no evidence of suberization in tissues inside the pericycle in the radial cuts, there was some evidence of suberization on the outer wall of practically every intact cell that was adjacent to the surface in the tangen - tial cut. By the tenth day one or two layers of cells were suberized across all tissue regions of the tangential cut, whereas in the radial cuts the suber- . ization inside of the pericycle never involved more than one complete eel! layer and was generally less, with no suberization at all on some ¦ cells located toward the apex of the crack in the perimedullary region. i I </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes '.' Table A.—Extent of the wound healing in various tissue regions of radial crates (cuts into tubers) that were exposed to the sun jor various' lengths of time immediately after cutting, as observed at intervals after • storage in a humid cellar (cellar B), stated in terms of number of layers ' of-Cflls involved. ..-."' .¦' ¦'.; - - - Treatment ¦ -.-'- ¦ Tissue regions - . Days I ¦ - i ; : —— alter . * ¦ ¦ : Pcnmcd - iniurv No. Type of- Outer Inner Perl- Outer X) .| cm „„.,„. ¦. . . exposure coucx concx cycle pWocm . or pj, n &gt; . l:alsc cicatrice -.-.'... ¦ 5 .7B . None :- ' O-'.i •' 0- 1/, ¦¦:!".. I 0 0 " TO 1 lir., NS- 4-6 4-6 1-10-1 0 0 Ml 6 hrs., NS 20 18-20 ' 15 .' .10 5 0-3 ¦ • 9B 6 Hrs., EWV 33 20-3(1 15-20 ,8-12 J-5 OH - ¦¦.;.- Sulicrizcd parenchyma. .;. . ¦ ''. 5. 7ft None .: 2+ !'j-2 '/. J-J-0 - •? 0 108 ¦¦¦: 1 he, NS 2 . Pi 1 'A 'A .0 &gt;« 6 hrs., NS 3-ft '.. 3-t .3-1 3 2 &lt;A 9B fi hrs., EVV 3-D '- 3-1 2-4 2-3 1-2 0-|.i 10 Trl None 3-5, C 3 IJ4-2 " l-l'/j « »-!¦• D"!i 108 1 hr., NS .3-5 !'/• 2 . :1. . .1 W-l ftH f&gt; hrs., NS 3-« -. '4 ¦.'..- : 4 3-4 3 1-3 'Jn 6hrs.,F.W 3-8 3-4+ 3-1+ 3-1+ 3 1-3 : ¦. . Phellugen (of wound pcriilcrm) .- . ¦ . : ¦ 10 TB None .- 0 -0-1: 0-5 .' (t-2, GO 0 P JOB 1 hr., NS O 0 0-1 lh-3 II .? HB (i lirs., NS U 0 0 0-1 0 0 : ..:. !»» 6 lirs., EW 0 . ()• -.:.( &gt;. 0 0 " 20 7B None i.: ¦•'¦¦¦ 1-2 .4-7 3-7 2-3 2-3, 108 1 hr., NS : 2 2-3 2-4 .1-3 2 HH 6 Urs., NS -2 2 2 1-2 1-2 9B 6 hrs., r.W ? ? • . 0-1 . 0 ? . 4J 7H None ? -...-¦ o^l 3-4 3-6 5 4-6 108 1 hr., NS. 11 0-1 3 3-5 5 8 611 (i hrs., NS ¦ ¦ :'. ¦ 0 ¦ 0¦ , O-l 0-1 0-1 0-3 9B f&gt;h«., EW I) 0 •.'_¦ 0-1 0-1 0-1 0-2 75 rii .None 0 0 0-2 2-6 4. 2-6 i 108 1 hr., NS 0 0 1-2 3-5 3-5 1-2 SB 6 lirs., NS (I ,0 0-1 0-2. 4-5: .4-5 9h 6hrj., EW (I . 0 (»-.' 0-2 .0-2 0-3 . 120 7B None : - II U 0-1 2-3 2-3 2-3. . . 108 . 1 hr., NS 0 ? 2 t 2-3 3 3-5 811 6 hrs., NS . .. • .. .. "¦ • .. . .. 9B Chri.,EW 0 ' ¦ 0 • • 6-1 0-2 260 7B None 0 1-2 2-4 1-5 3-« 2-fi : 8t 6 hrs.. NS . 0 0 00-1 1-2 0-3 . ¦ . ¦ -'¦¦ I'liellem.. ¦ . ' . .: . '¦- - . 20 7B None ? ¦ ;:•¦ 3 3 : 2-3 .0-2 1-2 108 I hr., NS •' 2 2-3 2-3 1-3 1-2 8B 6 hrs, NS f 2-3 2 2-3 2-3 &gt; 1-3 9H 6 hrs., EW I 1-1 ' . I ¦'.'!¦¦¦¦¦ '¦&gt; },: . 40 "B None 0 • 3 3-5 4-5 5 2-3 . ¦ 108 1 hr., NS 0-2-3 ' 2-) 3-5 4 0-3 8B film., SS 0 M ¦ M : 2-3 ! 2 2-4 9H 6hn.,EW .0.: M I-l 1-4 2-4 1-2 "5 "B None (I 3-4 I 4-« 4-8 5 3-5 108 1 hr., NS 0 '3+ :' 3-5 3-6 3-5 2-3 8R 6 hrs., NS 0 3 3-4 3-5 3-1 2-4 ' 9B 6 hrs., EW 0 1-4 2-12-4 3-5 2 120 . 7B None 0 4 . ¦ 4-7 ¦ 4-7 ' 5 - 4-5 JOB 1 hr., NS 0 - 3 3-5 +-5 4-5 2-t 8B 6 hrs., NS 0 -... ¦ 3 3-6 3-6 3-5 4 9B 6 hrs., EW 0 2-4 ; 3r4 2-4 3-5 3 : 260. -B " None -.0 5-(i 5-7 5-7 5-7 4-7 «B 6 hrs.. NS . .0 3-4 3-6 4-« +-7 3-1 1 "Pci medullary" as here used rcferl to phloem parenchyma between outer phloem and primary xylem. ' ¦ ¦'¦-'. ¦¦¦ ¦--'-- ' : . ¦ ' . -Letters NS indicate north-to-soulh position and EW east to west. Exposure of 108 was from 11:30 A. 11. to 12:25 P. M. </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nlbraska Ac;rl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 However, on the tenth day suberization was much more extensive in the cortex of the radial than of the tangential cuts (Fig. 3). There was very little suberization of parenchyma in radial cracks after the fifteenth day. On the tenth day there was very scant evidence of a phellogen, but immediately thereafter pheUogenic activity was very great, for by the Lwcntieth day a very thick phellogen and one to three layers of phellem cells were observed across practically all regions, including the very apex ol the crack. The wound periderm was considerably further advanced in the radial than in the tangential cuts on the twentieth day. In the inner phloem and perimedullary region of the radial cuts the phellem was formed either directly at the surface of the cut or separated from it by only one cell layer of subcrized parenchyma. After the twentieth day there was little further difference between these two types of cuts except that more phellem may have developed in the radial cuts and more layers of phellogen cells may have been in evidence as late as 120 and 190 days than in tangential cuts, especially in the portions most remote from the original periderm of the tuber. The slightly greater development of periderm in radial cuts may have been due to much of the cut surface being closer to more phloem vessels. There was a distinct increase in number of layers of phellogen and phellem cells after the temperature rose in the spring, as shown by in - creased numbers of cells on the 260 th day in most tissue regions but espe - cially in the inner regions. With tangential cuts there was less definite evidence of similar spring reactivation. In the radial as in the tangential cuts, no periderm developed in the cuter cortex immediately under the original or true tuber periderm. In this region as many as six or seven layers of turgid suberized cells were' found after 75 days. Sometimes three to five additional layers of pre - viously suberized cells, lying toward the surface, were found to have collapsed, thus adding to the portion of the false cicatrice that had been formed before suberization started. The outstanding differences in the healing of radial and tangential cuts seem to have been that in the radial cuts (a) suberization of paren - chyma cells occurred later and was less extensive both as to areas and depth, amounting to a very thin layer inside the xylem, (b) a phellogen developed earlier and persisted longer, and (c) the phellem was formed a trifle earlier and was a trifle thicker and continued to be added to for a longer time. FEATHERED TUBERS In "feathered" portions of tubers, where the periderm was removed by friction, a dense false cicatrice made up of two to four layers of the tangentially elongated cells of the outer cortex covered the entire surface (Table 5). In the walls of the cortical cells beneath this false cicatrice slightly more suberization appeared to have occurred by the fifth day than in tangential cuts. By the tenth day more suberization had occurred in the tangential cuts than in the feathered portions (which seldom had </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Table s.— Extent of the wound-healing process in "feathered" tubers that were exposed to the sun for various lengths of time immediately after injury as observed at intervals after storage in: a humid cellar, stated id terms of number of layers of cells involved. (AH data based on observations made on injured area between 5 and 10 mm. from edge of\old periderm.) \ . • :'-.." | Treatment and extent of exposure of feathered surface ¦¦-¦.P»y». afw , 13B(l&gt;/ 4 hours) 12B(6hours) m)Ury not exposed in sun 11:05 A- M- in sun 10:20 A- M - . not exposed , 012 ;20 P .M. . -. m 4:30 P; M. False cicatrice 2 days ............... : ;.. ... 15-28 .5 di&gt;;s .......;,;..... 1-3 , , &#132;:¦ 9-12 30-35 Subcrizcd parenchyma ¦ ' 5 days ............... 0-1 &lt;A-V/, * O-ty. 10 dsys ..'....¦ 0-I'/. I—l l4 , 2-3 40 days ....;..,....... 1-3;GI G2 2-4.G3 ¦'..'; ¦ ¦ '¦".'-.¦'¦.'¦ Vhcliogcn (of wound pcriikrm) '¦'¦ ¦ 10 days ............... ()' ¦ ..: ' -\^'"¦ 20 days ............;.,' ? • 40daW; 0-2 1-2 y,-l 75 daYs ....¦.-.. 0-I.GO IH,GO'v; 0 120 days 0-I,GO 0-3 . .: 0-3 190 days ..,.;.:......,.... ... i : 0 . ¦ . ;¦ ¦ -.' ¦ :". ¦'¦ Phcllcm '.¦:¦... ': &#132;: 10 dais ...!.,. '¦'¦.. . 0 :.'..¦¦• ¦¦¦'..' ¦ : 20 daYs ....;.......-.. 0 '¦;.-. .......•".•¦ '"..' ¦10 daYs :.............. ' 2-1.G3 G3 . i-3 ' 75 dats ..............;. ,3-5,G3 G3 -3-» 120 daYs ............:.. 3-5.G3 4-6 I: ' .' 3-5 190 days ....;...,.. ¦.¦•.'¦..¦. ¦¦.¦¦¦'-¦ .;.--: ¦'"-. &#132;'¦„¦¦ .''¦¦¦¦¦¦¦ 5-6 more than one layer of cells suberized) and a phellogen was just starting in the former but not in the latter. From the 40th to the 120 th day, whenever observed, the feathered areas generally contained from two to four fewer layers of cells of both phellem and phellogen than the tan - gentia cuts (Fig. 6). : : ; ¦ : In feathered tubers the wound healing was of necessity limited to cor - tical tissue and on and after the fortieth day it was found that starch grains were quite consistently absent from practically all of what remained of unc ifferentiatcd parenchyma of the cortical regions and also from several of the pericyclic cells beyond. However, with tangential cuts the starch grains generally had disappeared completely from only one or two cells beneath the wound phellogen by the fortieth day and later. There seldom was ary evidence of disintegration of the starch grains in cells lying further away :xcept where the wound traversed the cortex. In this region starch grains were generally absent under the cut surface after the twentieth or - fortieti days. .. ; </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska A&lt;;rl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 The principal differences in healing between feathered and tangentially cut tubers seem to have been that with the former a heavier false cicatrice was developed, suberization of parenchyma cells started earlier but was much slower and much less extensive, and periderm formation started later and was less extensive. EFFECT OF TEMPERATURE AND LIGHT CONDITIONS BEFORE STORAGE The wounded areas of tubers with the three different types of wounds were exposed to the outdoor atmosphere with various degrees of exposure. The temperature was typical for the warmer days during the average western-Nebraska late-potato harvesting period (Table 1). The wind movement was somewhat above normal. The intensity of the light was normal from 10:30 A. M. until about 11:00 A. M. when the air became very hazy because of dust which increased until midafternoon. Conse - quently, the solar radiation was below normal from about 11:00 A. M. to 4:HI P. M. Some idea as to the effect of this dust upon solar radiation is conveyed by the constant decrease in ratios of water lost from the black to that lost from white atmometers between 10:30 A. M. and 4:25 P. M. This occurred in spite of the decrease in relative humidity during that time. During late afternoon as the wind decreased and the dust settled, the light was much brighter and the solar radiation increased for a short period Irom sundown, at about 5:15 P. M. TANGENTIAL CUTS The series ot tangentially cut tubers which were exposed to the sun lor six hours Irom 10:15 A. M. to 4:30 P. M. (2B) 4 were subjected to some - vvhat more severe treatment than potatoes are likely to receive in com - mercial practice (Tables 1 and 2). On this particular day the tubers ex - posed to the sun for Wi hours at the end of the afternoon (5B) were subjected to slightly less severe conditions than those exposed for an hour over noon (4B). However, during the noon hour conditions were not as severe as those encountered from 2 to 3 P. M. except that (because of dust) the light was not as bright in midafternoon as at noon. For checks some tubers were cut tangentially at the end of the day and these wen never exposed to anything except the air of the humid cellar. The earliest and most conspicuous difference observed in tangential LUts alter exposure to sunshine for different periods of time or at different times of day, from cuts not exposed, was in the development of the false cicatrice (Table 2). This comprised various numbers of cell layers (ad - jacent to the cut surface) that were killed by cutting and subsequent ex - posure. At first the cells in this layer differed from the others by being slightly shrunken. Next they appeared to be devoid of practically all cell contents except starch. Finally the layer appeared as a dense, more or less amorphous mass of collapsed cell walls and numerous apparently nor - 'rironlictk.il numlirri .-icuimpjnkil hy Icticri refer to treatment numbers. ¦I i ¦ . fi </seg>
         <seg id="p017">¦-.•¦ ' ;. , - f Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Table 6.—Temperature, relative humidity, and evaporation jrom atmometers in different storages. ' Storage pcijiod B. Humid cellar C. Dry cellar I, *'?" . Evaporation ~ "*i™ Evaporation Dj K , D:|)')| "om No. ol Mean JJ.*' from alraomeler (aa rs| l- from almomerer «|ury da V s temp. hltmid . Period I Mean 'temp. humid- Period I Mean I- i'y tor.il | 24nn. ity - total |¦ 24 hrs, °F- % ' &lt;•&lt;•&lt; ••.-: cc. °F. . ¦¦% cc. ¦! «. t. 22 Starlit g time '62 59 .. • '. : 64 . 52 t.22-23 OtoKhrj. 57 65 , &lt;i.3&gt; .5.59 56 61 V.22 668 «¦ 23-24 26-44 &gt;rs. X 50 71: ' 4.03 6.05 .4" I 68 372 558 t. 24-27 44 hrs. to 5 days 3U 45.0. "9.6 10.18 3.22 47.6 66.6 16.10 SJO ict. 2 sto 10day» 5 53.2 ¦ 74.0 10.94 . 2.19 51.4 68.6 17.85 357 .2t012 lOto 20oays 10 53.9 86.1 39.8 3.98 54.4 67.5 63.8 6.38 1.12 to . ...--¦"¦ ¦ . ' ov. 1 20 to todays 20 48:5 84.3 61.5 3.(18 48.6 71.0 91.7 459 ».¦! lo . ¦ - ¦ • ' ' ¦¦.'.-. • . ¦ ¦ kc.s 40 to 75 days 35 39.7 84.77 .79.2 2.26 39.0 70.3 124.6 3.56 ". 5 (o . ¦- . . ¦ '¦¦¦¦ ' ¦. in. 19 75 to 120 days 45 38.2 89.5 36.6 0.81 : 37.7 64.3 105 7 235 .19 to ... ... .-"'-¦ : - . • - ¦ - ar.29 120 to 190 dats 70 37.4 88.5 83.3: 1.19 37.9 63.1-202.4 2.89 inclO 19Q| O ;«days .74. 43.1 91.4 . 72.3 ,1.03 44.2' ' 78.6= 110.0 1.66 .¦¦/¦¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ . ¦ - . . ~ Slora g e | period | P. Cold storage . ;¦ | A. Warm humid room I ' ' ¦':'. V. .¦••%:¦¦ re. .. ¦ cc: °r. % . cc. &lt;r . 1.22 SuttiriEiimc ;35 . 73 ... ¦• . ..: 73 '. 78 t. 22-23 oto 2flnrs. 35 73 1.23 1.14 68 76 '357 331 t.23-24 26-14r.rs. Vi 38 79 . 2.71 5.03 f.5 75 1 c- 241-27 44hr5. losda)j 3\i 39.3 78:0 5.32 1.68 [M 77 } 26-&gt; 7-08 a.2 sto 10 days 5 38.5 77.8 4.71 0.94 63 S3.fi 15.4 31 2t012 lOto 20days .10 .40.3 83.3 20.1 2.01 62 78.8 28.fi 2'sO .12 to . '.-"¦¦.'¦ . . ¦•¦'.' ' ' j ¦ ¦¦'¦'¦' ov. 1 2Q to 40 days 20 39.9 86.0 37.1. 1.86 .-. ... . .lio :¦..-'.¦¦¦ '- -.-¦ . . ¦ ¦ ¦ .•• ¦." . - ¦ 'j ' ¦ • -. ¦ . ¦ . cc.s 4.0t0 75days 35 38.3 84.7 -68.9 • 1.97. .. „. . 5 to : :/ ' .¦'!•¦-" . -.; ¦ ¦¦-'-. ' " n. 19 75tol20days 45 37.9 88.6 39.4 1.13 .. .. 1910 . .I-: . ¦..'¦¦ '. ¦¦¦¦"• ar.2? 120tol90days 70 ¦ 37.5 . 87.7 67.6 0.96' ;.. ' . ... .1 to ¦.'¦¦' '¦ . ¦ ¦[' - ¦ :. ¦ . ¦ ¦'¦¦¦.'¦ ' " inclO I9oto&gt;64days 74 40.1 .' . 90.8. 68.0 0.97 Mean lemperatire from May 16 to June 10 »as 50.5" P. in humid cellar and 52.5° F. in dry cellar. Because at cice isivc rain and a leaky roof, the relative humidity rose in the "dry cellar" in May and averaccd 83 5 ncr from May 2to /unc 12. '. .I .¦ - - ¦ .. .* mal si arch grains. In a very thick false cicatrice the outer cells frequently had collapsed to minimum dimensions, while the innermost ones were just beginning to show evidence of abnormality/This false cicatrice involved the sr tallest numbers of cells in the cortex and most in the pericydc and outer phloem. The number of cells involved again decreased perceptibly where the wound cut across the xylem region (Fig. 1). When cuts were exposed'to field air but away from the sun for one and one-half hours, in late afternoon, the false cicatrice involved 6 to 8 cell layers (6B), 8 to 15 cell layers when toward the sun for the same late afternoon time [5B), 10 to 15 cell layers when toward the sun for one midday </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 Table 7. — Total weight loss with sound potatoes held in crates in the different storages jrom September 26, 1934j, to three dates, jor which losses were calculated as percentage oj the original weight. Warm humid Djte Humid Dry Cold room 15 days weighed cellar (B) cellar (C) storage (D) then dry cellar (A) P.cl. P.cl. P.ct. P.ct. OctoUr II 2.2 3.6 1.9 3.1 April I 11.7 IJ.U 11.6 13.2 June 12 13.6 H.O 16.2 14.9 Per aiu &lt;&gt;l June weight Jimun.u 1r..-c il.im.i)!i' -I.N -1.2 5.j i.6 hour (4B), and 20 to 25 cell layers when exposed for six midday hours (,213). When not exposed to the field air at all, the false cicatrice was practically inconsequential, being present only over some parts of the cut and then seldom involving more than two layers of cells (IB). The number of layers of cells involved in this false cicatrice increased wkh lime until checked by the deposition of subcrin on the outer walls of some of the parenchyma cells. The longer and more severe the exposure the thicker was the false cicatrice and the earlier were its inside limits definitely defined. With the most severe exposures, cells were killed rapidly to a considerable depth. These dead cells probably constituted a barrier to loss of water from the lower or deeper cells comparable to the action of a litter mulch over moist soil. The region of high humidity thus provided probably brought about slightly earlier suberization than when wounds were not exposed before storage. With the less severe exposures, the cells were damaged beyond recovery but water loss was so much slower that they did not collapse as rapidly as did the cells in wounds subjected to more severe exposures. With these milder exposures the maxi - mum damage to the tissues was not apparent as early as with more severe exposures. Suberization of parenchyma cells occurred earlier and seemed to in - voke more cell layers in those cuts which developed a thick false cicatrice than when a thin one or none at all was produced. As the severity of the exposure was decreased the beginning of suberization was delayed a few days and the thickness of the suberized layer was less. With time the subcrized layer was always the thickest in the most severely exposed cuts, yet it gradually developed to almost the same thickness in cuts exposed to the other conditions. Phellogen activity commenced earliest in the unexposed cuts, was most active there, and continued to be most active for the greatest length of time. In general, it appeared that as the severity of the exposure was increased the initiation of a phellogen was delayed, and it was more limited in extent and its activity was terminated at an earlier date. With the more severe exposures very few or no layers of phellogen cells were observed on or after </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes : IBM 4820 282° IMO « 2BW Fig. I.—Extent of the wound healing under tangential cuts with Triumph potatoes that were stored in the humid cellar (B) con - tinuously: 18, into cellar at once, not exposed to the sun; 48, exposed to noonday sun one hour after cutting; 28, ex - posed to midday sun 6 hours. Numerical suffixes 20 and -!0 indicate number of days after tubers were cut when samples were secured. '• Dotted jxirtion designates false cicatrice consisting of dead cells; cross hatching designates subcrized parenchyma; solid black area adjacent to subcrized parenchyma indicates phcllcm of wound pcridcrm (cork cambium); and white space between line to left and phcllcm designates the phellogcn or cork cam - bium of the wound pcridcrm. The black band at the top represents the original pcridcrm o£ the tuber. In this figure approximately one centimeter of the sliced surface is shown. '¦'Mark x designates location of xylcm vessels. All drawings were made from slides by tracing the outlines of the various regions in a projected image. " . ¦ . 19 </seg>
         <seg id="p020">NI.BRASKA A(iRL. ExP. STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 102 the 75th day, yet with wounds not exposed or those given mild exposure •¦ numerous phellogen cells were observed as late as the 190 th and 260 th d;.ys. As a consequence of this delayed and restricted phellogen activity, :¦, the phellcm was developed later and was less extensi\ re when cuts were exposed to the more severe conditions. ¦ Meets of exposure to the drying conditions of the field atmosphere j might lx- summarized as follows: that as the severity of the exposure in - creased, there w.is (a) an increase in the destruction of tissues under the ¦ exposed area and a consequent increase in the thickness of the false cicatrice, (h) the interior limit of this false cicatrice was definitely defined .it an earlier date, (c) suberization of parenchyma cells was initiated at an earlier date, continued for a longer period, and involved more cell layers, Id; development of the phellogen was delayed, its activity was more re - stricted, and terminated earlier, and (c) the phellem or wound cork was ilex eloped later and was not as thick. EFFECT OF EXPOSURE TO DIFFERENT TYPES OF LIGHT On September U&gt;. 1929. at Lincoln, Triumph potatoes dug in western Nebraska on September 14 were cut tangentially xvith a dull corn knife and the cut surfaces were exposed to the sun for eight hours immediately after cutting. After this they were moved into a cellar. In addition to those exposed directly to the sun, some cuts were exposed to sunlight under one and three thicknesses of ordinary window glass, others under cilloglass. and some under glass whitewashed with lime so as to be about as translucent as the celloglass, and some also were exposed under led glass. The cut tubers were about six inches beneath the glass and air circulated freely over the cut surfaces. The control tubers were placed in the sun on a coarse screen with cut sides down and about two inches &gt; Irom a cement walk, thus being exposed to much the same conditions as } those with cuts toward the sun. The light was of average intensity for j September, the radiation in gram calories per square centimeter totaling j -)X0 for the day, of which 404 gram calories occurred during the eight hours ot exposure (4 A. M. —5 P. M.)." The greatest amount per hour was 71 j.ram calories from 12 to 1 V. M. During this period of time the cloudiness averaged about 4, being only 2at midday. The temperature rose from 70° ? F. to HO F. and decreased to 74° F., and the relative humidity decreased ! from 55 per cent to 32 per cent, then rose to 47 per cent. The cellar £ temperatures were relatively high, having averaged 63", 69 =, 62% 55", ir 55 for the five successive weeks involved in the observation period. The | relative humidity of the cellar ranged from 69 to 89 per cent but generally [ averaged around HO to S5 per cent, sufficiently high to permit considerable £ growth of molds on the debris in the false cicatrices of the cut surfaces. j; The vapor deficit of the atmosphere was sufficient to cause the death \ ot six to eight layers of cells when the cut surfaces xvere turned doxvn |, ( L 5. Table .?). [n this lot the outer cells were noticeably shriveled at the £ end of the outdoor exposure, but after 24 hours of cellar storage suberiza- | ¦ I rum I v. Wciihrr Huuju Sution .ilicui U*\ fci-t ilitl.uu. |': </seg>
         <seg id="p021">¦ Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes tion vas already under way on the outer wall of many cells and no additunal layers of cells were brought into the false cicatrice. With direct expostre the false cicatrice involved 17 to 25 cells in a hard dry layer and suberization was delayed till about the fifth day (L 7). In this test the false cicatrice was less extensive but suberization was earlier than in the 1934-1 :sts at Alliance, for the reason that at Alliance the light on the day of expwure was brighter and the entire cellar temperature was lower than in the Lincoln test. .' . As the intensity of the light was cut down by the different types of glass cavers, the thickness of the false cicatrice decreased and suberization occurred earlier. Differences in thickness of false cicatrice and time and extent of suberization suggest that the quality of the light rays as.well as the amount of radiation may be factors of consequence to the healing proces:. However, each type of exposure used retarded the healing pro - cess.- ¦;' ..'¦,•¦;• ..';. •:,; :•-¦--'..¦".¦ ;'.'¦;¦ .'.-. .'. .::i.L" '- . ¦¦¦ ' Th: development of a cork periderm was delayed by exposing the cut surfacts to the sun and perhaps it was not quite as thick as in the cuts not exaosed, but under, these very favorable storage conditions the event - ual differences were not very great. ¦";:.- : ',¦:¦¦'.. RADIAL CUTS OR CRACKS INTO THE TUBERS At Alliance some tubers with radial cuts were exposed to midday sun for on: hour (1 08, Table 4) before being placed in the humid cellar, and others were exposed to midday sun for six hours with cracks in the north - to-south position (8B). With the checks (7B) the cuts were made in'the cellar ;it the end of the day and never exposed to outside air. Th: two sides of the radial cuts or cracks that had been exposed for six hoirs separated much further than those of cracks not exposed. With one he ur of exposure the separation was intermediate in extent, A differ - ence in crack width occurred during the first few hours after the cuts were made and was very pronounced at the end of 40 hours. This greater openine of the crack was due to the greater tension placed upon the periph :ral tissues of sun-exposed tubers due to the. more rapid and greater loss of water.which they suffered. The greater shrinkage of cortical and pericydic tissues, because of their more exposed position, together with the greatei circumference of these regions, resulted in a relatively more rapid separation of the walls of the cut traversing these regions than where it travers:d the phloem and xylem. Consequently during the first few days the an;le of the crack was much greater outside of the xylem than inside but as the cells readjusted themselves to the altered moisture supply, ten - sions were probably equalized more and later there was much less differ - ence ir the slope of the crack walls in the different tissue regions. Because of constant loss of water, the width of the cracks increased throughout the entire storage season (Fig. 3). With unexposed cuts shrinkage was much slower, the cracks being about as wide (2-3 mm.) on the fortieth day as expose] cracks were at the end of 40 hours. However, by the 120 th day </seg>
         <seg id="p022">22 Fie. 2.—Extent of ihc wound-healing process with radial cuts into tubers that were stored in a warm, liumitl jilacc P (A) immediately after being cut (Treatment 7), as shown by samples secured 5, 10, and 20 days after cutting pj and those that were then stored in the cold-storage room (D) after 20 clays, as shown by samples secured HU g and 265 days after cutting (the latter group arc referred to in tables and discussion as 7AD-10 and 7AD265). Cuts were about one centimeter deep. o Dotted portion along cut surfaces designates false cicatrice; cross hatching indicates subcrized parenchyma; solid black, phcllem of wound pcridcrm (at top of figures it indicates original tuber peridcrm); white space inside of phcllem delimited by thin line is phcllogcn or cork cambium o£ wound pcridcrm. </seg>
         <seg id="p023">5 '¦,¦;' '.'0 '¦.'¦-'• 20 . ¦ .¦'••'¦'¦ ¦¦¦¦¦"40 '.¦'¦¦¦¦'¦¦¦..'¦ 7-5 . '¦;.¦'¦ 260- ¦ O Fig. 3.—Extent of the wound-healing process with radial cuts into tubers that were placed in the humid cellar (Treatment 7B) ' g immediately after being cut and stored there continuously. Sketches illustrate conditions at end of 5, 10, 20, .40, 75, and 260 days jj as indicated. ....;¦¦ Dotted portion along cut surfaces designates false cicatrice; cross hatching, suberized parenchyma; solid black, phcllcm of wound periderm (at top of figures indicates original tuber pcriderm); white space inside the phcllcm delimited by thin line is phcllogcn or cork cambium of wound pcriderm. Cuts were approximately one centimeter deep. ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p024">4 5 10 2o 40 75 265 CB Flc. •).— Extent of wound healing wilh radial cuts into tubers that were placed in cold storage immediately after being cut anil r hcltl there continuously (Treatment 7D). Sketches illustrate condition at end of 5, 10, 20, 40, 75, and 265 days. h Hotted portion along cut surface designates false cicatrice; cross hatching indicates subcrizcil parenchyma, 'flic wound- 2 healinjj process iliil not proceed beyond the stage of subcrizalion of parenchyma. Cross hatching across the dotted area mdi- — cates portions where suheri/.cd parenchyma cell cullapsrd and appeared as part of the false cicatrice. Cuts were approximately f3 one centimeter deep. </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes 7620 10820 : &gt;.•••.. 9BSO . Fig. s.—Extent of wound healing at the close of 20 days in the.humid cellar n ith radial cuts that had been treated in various ways immediately after cutting; 78, not exposed to sun; 108, exposed to sun one hour, cracks north t( south; 98, exposed to sun six hours with cracks east and west, north side a left. ; : :¦¦;¦:• ¦-;. ¦ . ; ...v . - ¦ Dotted portion along cut.surfaces designates false cicatrice; cross hatching slows subcrized parenchyma; solid black shows phellcm of wound pcriderm (it top of figures indicates original tuber pcriderm); white space, inside of picllcm delimited by thin line is phcllogcn or cork cambium of wound j] ridcrm. Cuts were approximately one centimeter deep. there \\ as little difference and on the 245 th day unexpqsed cracks were open about as wide as exposed cracks, about 5 to 6 millimeters at the top midway between the ends of the cracks. This opening up of the exposed cracks lot only was a factor in subjecting outer tissue regions to more direct exposure but it also increased the aeration to all injured tissue regions and thus may have been a factor in expediting suberization. Win the unexposed tubers (7B), the false cicatrice was relatively small but with cracks exposed to the sun for one midday hour (10B) there was a definite collapse or caving in of exposed cortical tissue so as to form a false cicatrice four to six cells thick (Table 4 and Fig. 3). This false cicatrice tapered down to about one cell layer in the inner pericycle and very little more was formed inside the pericycle. The inner limits of the false ciratrice were definitely determined before the fifth day, for then suberization was well under way. '"- . : : ' ' When cracks were exposed north to south for six hours in the midday sun (8B) much damage occurred to the tissues, for at the end of 40 hours therewas a false cicatrice 10 to 12 cells deepacrpss the cortex and peri - cycle. This diminished across the outer phloem to a thickness of about four eels in the xylem region, inside of which it had not yet developed. By the fifth day this false cicatrice had developed to a maximum of about 20 cells and extended as a layer a few cells thick for about 10 cells beyond </seg>
         <seg id="p026">NEBRASKA AcRL. F.XP. STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 102 .1 the xylem vessel region. There was some increase in the false cicatrice be - tween the fifth and tenth days. When cracks were exposed east and west so that the rays of sunlight ixuld strike the north walls quite directly for the entire six-hour exposure period (9B), a false cicatrice was formed that involved about 33 cells oh the north wall of the crack as compared with 20 to 25 on the south wall. On the north or sunny side the false cicatrice extended well into the peri - medullary as a two-to-four-cell layer (Fig. 5). As the severity of the exposure increased, the suberization processes started earlier and continued longer and were finally more extensive. With the more severe exposure the tips of cracks (toward center of tuber) were protected earlier by a deposition of suberin than were those of the less severe exposures. The cracks exposed six hours (88, 9B) had as much suberization at the tips by the end of 10 days as the tips of unexposed cracks had at 20 days. The tips of cracks exposed one hour were most like those not exposed. With six hours' exposure there were generally three or more layers of suberized cells in all parts of the cracks, but in those not exposed and those exposed one hour there was never more than one layer of suberized cells across the tissues inside the pericycle. This more extensive suberization of tissues near the apex of cracks exposed to the sun or dry air may have been partly the result of better aeration of the tissues as permitted by the widening of the mouth of the crack due to tensions resulting from the desiccation of the adjacent cells. The less the exposure the earlier was a phellogen formed, the more active it was, and the longer it persisted. Likewise with less exposure a phellcm was formed earlier and was heavier (contained more cells). A /ihellem was never developed across the outer cortex. In the portion of a crack on the shady or south side, the phellem developed earlier and more extensively than on the north or sunny side (98, Fig. 5). In all cases it continued to develop till the 120 th day. Then further development seemed rather improbable with severe exposures, but the number and general prevalence of phellogen cells in the less severely exposed cracks indicated , that still more phellem development was likely to occur. This was observed to have occurred by the 260 th day with unexposed tubers. After the 20th day there was little additional phellem development in the cortex and &lt; pericycle —but inside of that region a phellogen was observed throughout • all of the storage period. ; Another set of radially cut tubers was stored in a warm dry place j (74±4° F., -15±8 per cent RH) after being exposed to sunshine at Lincoln I for six hours (in 1929). There was less moisture in the air than in the. Alliance tests. With this set of tubers the false cicatrice was not extensive in the cortex and did not involve any cells beyond the pericycle. Suberiza - tion was delayed a day or two by the dry atmosphere, but phellogen activ - ity occurred earlier and was more general than in some tangential cuts i held in more humid storage. In the exposed cracks a phellem did not ? line the cracks completely quite as early as in those not exposed to the I </seg>
         <seg id="p027">i Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes : t complete protection by a phellem was attained earlier than with exposed! tangential cuts. ; Briefly stated, radial cuts exposed to sunshine or dry air, when com - pared with similarly exposed tangential cuts stored in a humid cellar, were fsund to have had: (a) a much less extensive false cicatrice which decreased rapidly in thickness from the mouth or cortical portion to the apex o • perimedullary portions of the cracks, (b) earlier and more extensive suberhation of parenchyma.cells, (c) possibly slightly earlier development of a piellogen which did persist later, and (d) a slightly more rapid and wider development of phellem in all tissue regions. As the exposure to which radial cuts were subjected was increased from rio exposure to six hours of exposure to the sun, it was found that: (a) The cracks were opened up more widely and more quickly. (b) The false cicatrice became much wider and was present—though to a reduced degree—across the crack apex or perimedullary tissues. (c) Suberization started earlier, continued longer, and was more ex - tensive. ¦ ' /.-.A - - ¦ '..•¦ [¦ ¦ ' ¦ ;•.:.'. ..¦;¦.' (d) The development of a phellogen was delayed and seemed to per - sist for less time. ;¦,,. (c) The phellem developed slightly later and was not quite as wide. FEATHERED TUBERS "Fothering" or the removal of the periderm was accomplished as previously described. The most extreme sun exposure was for six hours (128, Table 5), the other was for VA hours at midday (13B). The check ; (11B) was never exposed to outdoor air after being injured. Fe« thered portions of tubers not exposed in the field generally developed a false cicatrice of two to three cells. This false cicatrice generally com - i prised the phellogen of the original periderm and the few starchless cells ' beneati. With feathered areas when exposed for one hour, the false ! . cicatri c finally comprised about 9to 12 cell layers but 30 to 35 cell layers ll when exposed six hours. At the end of 40 hours' storage, the maximum I ." depth had been attained near the periphery of the feathered regions but in the central portion it was not attained until about the fifth day. ! With übers that were exposed to the sun for six hours the false cicatrice i involved more cells at a distance of 10 to 15 millimeters from the edge of } the-.wound than with tangential cuts. . f In the feathered areas of the tubers exposed one hour, one-half to one ! and a half layers of cells were generally suberized over the entire area by the end of five days (13B); With six hours' exposure one and a half layers of cells in the peripheral region of the feathered area were suberized but in'the central portions where maximum .'kitting was occurring, cells were still being added to the false cicatrice arid suberization was delayed considerably. By the tenth day when suberization was completed, there ! was generally one to one and a half layers of suberized cells in tubers not | exposejd or in those exposed only one hour, but with those exposed six </seg>
         <seg id="p028">' ( Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 hours there were generally two or three layers. The phellem which developed under this suberized layer was seldom over four cells thick in the feathered portions of unexposed tubers, in con - trust wuh phellem ot five or more | cells in those exposed 1(4 and 6 hours. 1 \ About half of this phellem in the 9 A' - exposed tuhcr had developed by the jl V¦. Jfl 40th day (Fig. 6), the other half de- j \ \ 9¦. veloping between then and the 120 th g, \'. || \ or even l'JOth days. As late as 120 |' \'. A&gt; i days two or three layers of phellogen I l I, ¦ II \ v cells were observed in several portions I ! -I '. &lt;§ ; ol exposed tubers, but very few I •; '• | j phellogen cells were observed in the ¦ i 1 ! i non-exposed tubers after the fortieth j ' 1.. : ] day. Then new phellcm at the per- ¦; : I• j i iphcrv of the feathered area seemed ! §\ ,' ,' to connect directly with the old per- i \ |.-.: j ] iderm in contrast with cuts in which t-.'J ' the new pcridcrm did not develop , . . ¦ I2B")O HO4O .icross what appeared to be outer cor- » [ex. fi neto The healing of feathered areas m which had been exposed was much the same as with exposed tangential F'fi. fi—Extent of wound healing at the cuts; that is, those exposed generally cl? &gt;c of W lla &gt;s wilh "fa*«cd" ¦ , . . '.„ &#132; '. (übcrs: No. 118 not exposed to sun, tended to sulxnze a trifle earlier and &#132;&lt;.,,, in humid cc] | ar . ]2B cxpoxii to develop a phellem or slightly less lo sun six hours, held in humid extent at a slightly later time. Possibly cellar; 12D exposed to sun six hours, the false cicatrice was a trifle thicker hcl&lt;! in c°l', l. storaSe- &#132; . r , Dotted line at extreme right is an in portions most remote from the per- estimation of rf^ OUKr lphery ot the in)ury. The healing edge of the cortex when the pcridcrm response in feathered areas varied was removed. Intervening white with the different degrees of exposure s Pace , indjc:l«:s shrinkage that oc - ii i currcd before checked by subcriza - in about the same manner as w.th -„ Cuts were appro!t i y matcly one tangential cuts. centimeter long. EFFECT OF METHOD OF STORAGE Cellar storage was provided in a typical western potato cellar or cave j with dirt floor and straw and dirt roof. A tight partition divided the j cellar into two halves. One of these was maintained as a humid cellar I by saturating the dirt under the bins and in the driveway, before storing any potatoes and by keeping the driveway damp continuously (B). The oiher half was maintained as a dry cellar (C). This was dried out |i thoroughly by leaving the doors and ventilators open for several months j before the storage season, by never adding any water to the Roor, and by i. t I </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Wound Healinc in Triumph Potatoes ventihting whenever it was possible to do so without causing a divergence in teriperature from that of the humid cellar. In order to avoid complicating fluctuations in. temperature during the time i he cellar was being filled with the farm potato crop, the ventilators of bolh cellars were kept closed most of the day time and doors were kept closed day and night except when opened for bringing in a load of potatoes. For a week, before this experiment was started the temperature was un - seasonably low so that the cellar temperatures were lower during the first week or two than those generally prevailing in western cellars at harvest time. As a matter of fact, during the first 20 days the mean tempera - tures for various short periods ranged from 45° to 57° F. (Table 6) and genehlly were 2 to 10 degrees below 55°, which has been-suggested by Artsciiwager (2) as a minimum temperature for wound cork formation. Thermographic records show that temperature fluctuations were rarely over three degrees in any 24-hour period so that these means depict the tempera - ture situation quite accurately. The mean daily temperature rose above 45° F. in both cellars on May 16 (236 th day) but never rose above 55° F. until June 10. ':¦:'•¦ '-'':; - '¦;'¦ •; . ; ... Drsired differences in humidity were not secured during the first 10 days aecause of the inability to maintain a sufficiently high humidity in .'.' the humid cellar (while it was. necessary to open the door to haul in potatoes in day time, when the humidity of;outdoor air was very low). After the tenth day this situation was rectified and differences in relative humidity of 14 to 25 per cent were maintained from the tenth to about the 225 th day. After that date the relative humidity was increased greatly in the dry cellar because of roof leakage following a late and very wet deep mow. The humidity in the dry cellar throughout most of the season was very, close to that which Artschwager observed, to have greatly delayed suber zation and apparently prevented periderm formation. The moisture i defici; or evaporating power of the air as measured by spherical white atmometers was generally 50 to 60 per cent greater in the dry than in the | humiJ cellar during the first 40 days. After that, with the temperature 'j.. below 40° F. till spring, the evaporation difference increased from 57 to 1 190 percent more| in the dry than in the humid cellar. : . j'j- . Inj a well-insulated room built in the cellar, temperatures between 35° | and 40° F. were maintained by artificial refrigeration (D) all the time except during the last three weeks when, because of failure of automatic 'j control, the daily range in temperature was from 36° to 44° F. The rel - : ativc humidity in this roorri was generally as high as in the humid cellar. I The evaporation from atmometers was generally only 40 to 50 per cent as great, during the early months in the cold-storage room as in the humid .•' cellar ¦¦-;.' ¦'{ '":' „ . ¦• ¦ ¦ ' .• ¦ " ¦ ;• •: ') '.. In' view of the beneficial results secured in healing wounds by the use of high temperatures (2, 19), especially when combined with reasonably high humidity, some wounded potatoes were stored for 20 days in a six - .; foot cubical box which was placed in a house basement (treatment A). ! ¦ ¦¦[¦¦: ¦.¦.;,:¦¦•.:•¦ ,¦¦¦¦ " •.-¦¦:.-.. ¦:.:,. / . </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 During the period the mean daily temperature decreased from 68° to 62° F. and relative humidity ranged from 75 to 84 per cent. During the first 10 days when the temperature was highest and relative humidity at times not higher than in the humid cellar, the evaporation from atmometers was 40 to 80 per cent higher than in the humid cellar but from the tenth to the twentieth day it was about 30 per cent less. Some estimate of the quality and relative desirability of these differ - ent types of storage may be arrived at from the records of weight losses suffered by a number of crates of field-run potatoes which were stored in each storage (Table 7). Tubers with severe mechanical injuries were dis - carded before storing but probably 20 per cent of the tubers had more minor injuries which might have been sufficient to permit decay under poor storage conditions. These potatoes were all harvested after two severe field frosts, and in spite of all precautions some frosted potatoes were included in these lots. Such frosted stock must have amounted to between 6 and 8 per cent of the stored weight, for on June 12, 3.6 to 5.3 per cent of the ; weight consisted of potatoes showing some frost damage —some tubers i having been completely destroyed. The percentages of frost reported for the different storages are not to be considered as differing because of the storages, since they probably merely represent chance differences; however, under some storage conditions a wound-cork formed more quickly under portions damaged by frost than under other conditions and in those cases j excessive weight loss, due to evaporation of water or rot, was prevented. TANGENTIAL CUTS NOT EXPOSED TO SUNSHINE With tangential cuts the wound-healing process proceeded most rapidly in the lots stored for 20 days in the warm humid storage (IA, Table 8), followed closely by those stored in the humid cellar (B) and those in the dry cellar (C). The process was very slow and never proceeded be- | yond the parenchyma suberization stage when cold storage was used con - tinuously. A false cicatrice was not developed in the warm, humid storage (1A), and in the humid cellar (IB) it was of little consequence. It was possibly most noticeable in the dry cellar (IC), whereas in cold storage (ID) it involved three to five cell layers before suberization was observed. With warm humid storage immediately after injury, suberization was well under way on the second day and was practically completed by the fifth. In humid-cellar storage the same amount of suberization was not in evidence until about the fifth and tenth days respectively, and even a little more time was required in the dry cellar. In continual cold storage suberization was greatly delayed and there was no perceptible change in j ihe cut surface until about the tenth day, when the cells in several of j the outer layers appeared slightly shrivelled, forming a false cicatrice. : Even though the weight loss was considerable, the cells did not show any ( volume loss prior to about the twentieth day, because at this low tempera- • ture the slight amount of water lost from the cut surfaces could be re- j placed with sufficient rapidity from the interior. Suberization of the outer | !. </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Tabu 8. — Extent of wound healing in tangential cuts of tubers that were fiiced under different storage conditions immediately after cutting, as ok ervedat intervals after cutting, stated as numbers of layers of cells in - vo* ved. (For atmospheric conditions in storages see Table 6.) '.:¦"¦¦ Treatment number and type of storajjc Days "'. • ¦ . ¦¦¦•¦• IAD ~ ~I alter :1B 1C Warm humid ID nut treament Humid Dry: room 20 days, Cold if' dstor?S c cellar cellar then cold storagefd^sse n •-•¦;. - : . storage .. humid cellar ¦.'¦'.¦' False cicatrice sdays 14-2 , &gt;/,-2 0-2 0 ... 10 da;-s ......... Vi-2 1-2 GL'/z-l ¦ ... 20das ......... :'A-2 2 . Gl 1-3 ... 40 da-s ......_,.;.- K-2 2 Gl 3-5 ; _. ¦ '¦¦&#132; •:';.-. Suberizcd parenchyma 2 da&lt;s &#132;.'....., .... ... 0-2 / ... &#132;: 5 daj¥...:....... 0-I,GO O-'A, GO 1-2^ F .;. lOdajs ......... 1-3.G2 1-3.G1 1-2 ? ; 20 days ..::..... 2-3 . G2 1-2 0-K ... 40 das ......:. 1-3 , G2 1-2 G3l 4-5 . 75 das ......... 1-3 ' G2 1-2 4-8 4-5 ' . 120 dais ......:.. 1-3 ¦! G2 1-2 ¦'[ 4-8 ¦¦'. 4-5 190 da}s ...;.,... 1-3 : G2 1-2 4-8 4-5: 260 dajs ......... 1-3 : .. G2 . 1-2 4-5 ... . . . Phellogcn (of wound pcridcrm) ¦; .' sdajs ..:...... 0; 0 . 0-2.G0 V. 0 ... 10 dajs ..:..;... Orl 0- 2-5.G3 0 ... . 20da 5 5.. 1-3 ¦"¦¦! (M 2-5' 0 ... 40 tlajs ......... 1-6 ! 1-3 O-3,G0 0 1-2 75 daj5;.,....... M 0-4 0-2 . 0 0-2 I 120 da 4 ......... 0-4 0-4 0-3 ¦ 0 0-I.GO 190 dajs 0-4: | 0-3 0-20 0-I.GO I 260 da 5 s ......... 0-5.G3-4 ...; 0-4.G2 ; 0 . ... i;' .:- V:.;. ' : .-; / y. .: I/'.:'-- Phcllem &#132; / ' . .•' _''' ; '" 10 da&gt;s ......... 0-1 ' ! 0 1-3 0 ... : 20 dajs .......... 2-A ':¦'¦.'; ¦¦ 0-2 ; - 3-5 0 ... f 40 dajs ...;..... 3-5 2-4 3-«,G4 . .0 0-2 . : 75 day 5;...:.... 3-6 3-5 3-6.G4 0 3-5 120 daj5i......... 4-7 j 4-6 3-6.G4 0 3-5 ¦ 190 days ....:.,.. 4-7 I 4-6 3-6,G4 .0 3-5 ' . 260da\|s... 4-8.G61 ... 4-B.G4' 0 ; ... I l Afta -!0 days, in cold storage cells in a number of layers under subcrizcd cells had shriveled con* - sidcrab)}' and many subcrized cells no longer remained turgid but also shheled, many to a corn. ' pletely c&lt; Uapscd condition. . ,: . '.;•. ¦. ' j walls &lt; f some outer cells had occurred by the fortieth day. ; Suberization { of add tional layers of cells appeared to be occurring continuously as long j as thes: wounded tubers were in cold storage because the number of layers I of suberized cells was increasing constantly. However, as time continued </seg>
         <seg id="p032">NhBRAsKA ACRL. Exp. STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 102 the only turbid subenzed cells were those in the three or four layers most recently suberized, whereas those suberized earlier had collapsed more or less completely and constituted the inner portion of the false cicatrice. The cells in several layers immediately under the most recently suberized cells did not appear fully turgid. Apparently this suberization of walls ol parenchyma cells was not very effective in preventing water loss in cold storage. When cut tubers were transferred from cold storage to the humid cellar on the 27th day (DB), suberization was greatly accelerated immediately. An active phellogen developed in the warm humid storage just after the tilth day. in the humid cellar about the ninth or tenth days, in the dry cellar between the fifteenth and twentieth days, and never in the cold : storage. When cut tubers were transferred from the warm humid stor - age to cold storage (AD) phellogen activity was checked promptly but the phellem continued to increase in width because of the suberization of cells differentiated earlier by the phellogen. Phellogen cells observed for some time alter the transfer were probably differentiated before the trans - fer but were not completely suberized at the low temperature. With the cut tubers transferred on the 27th day (Oct. 19) from cold storage to the humid cellar (DB) a phellogen was developed quickly; but as the tem - peratures then prevailing in the cellar (generally 45° to 52° F.. Tabje 6) were too low tor very active cell division but not too low for suberization ol cell walls, [he phellogen was not very thick, the neivly differentiated cells being converted into phellem cells rather quickly. In all storages ex - cept continual cold storage some phellogen cells were observed at each date, even on the 2n()th day. Observations made were not sufficient to determine whether these were formed before the low midwinter tem - peratures occurred and then remained unsuberized or whether they were formed during the winter, but the former seemed most likely. There was some indication that phellogen activity was revived in cellar storages by the slightly higher temperatures alter the 220 th day. Phellem cells were developed across the entire wound with warm stor - age by the tenth day and shortly before the twentieth day in the humid cellar. In the dry cellar considerable phellem was present on the twentieth day but the layer was not yet complete. With the tubers transferred on the 27th day from the cold storage to the humid cellar (DB) there was some phellem on the 54th day but it was not continuous but by the 75th day it was practically complete. Throughout the winter and at the close of the ¦ storage period the phellem development seemed to be slightly greater in the humid cellar than in the dry cellar. With tubers that were removed from \ cold storage to the humid cellar on the 27th day (DB), the phellem was more irregular and generally not as thick as with continual cellar storage (j (B). ' ' ,i In all storages the first phellem appeared in the cortex and pericycle '. and the last in the inner phloem or perimedullary regions. When the stor- [ age conditions were most favorable for wound healing the phellem de- </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes veloprd over all regions within a few days. Under the less favorable con - ditions the development across the inner regions was considerably delayed but eventually it developed to about the same thickness throughout any one tuber. .: ¦ . . These results show that a very effective wound-cork barrier was de - velopid across tangential cuts in 10 to 15 days when warm humid storage was used, whereas in humid-cellar storage a barrier of about the same extent was developed in 20 to 25 days and somewhat-later in a dry cellar but never at all when in cold storage continually: But if decay did not set in, an effective wound cork was established when cut potatoes were transferred from cold storage to cellar storage.: ".'&gt;.; ¦'¦':¦ : ¦¦;.'. TANGENTIAL CUTS EXPOSED TO SUNSHINE Tie effect of different storages was much the same upon the healing of tangential cuts that had been exposed to the sun for six hours as upon tubers not exposed to the outdoor air (Table 9). During the first live days he false cicatrice involved about the same number of cell layers in all storages and in all except the cold storage it did not increase in width after hat date. In the cold storage it gradually increased till 25 or more cell layers were involved between the twentieth and the fortieth days. Su bcrization was initiated in all storages a trifle earlier with exposed than with unexposed cuts. Differences in rate of suberization due to stor - age were about the same with exposed as with unexposed cuts, except that tlie shriveling and collapse of suberized and unsuberized cells in tubers held in cold storage was more severe in exposed tubers. Exposure to the sun did not materially alter the effect of the different storag:s upon the development of a phellogen and phellem..'" RADIAL CUTS OR CRACKS INTO TUBERS ::'¦'¦''¦'- \ ¦-¦-. ' ( :. '¦'¦. . ¦¦&gt;• ¦ ¦ ¦.¦:,.: ' '¦-¦ Tre healing of radial cuts into the tuber was influenced by different storag: conditions in much the same manner as was the healing of tan - gential cuts. With tubers not exposed to the sun the healing procedure in all except cold storage was essentially the. same as that reported as . occurring in humid-cellar storage; that is, all processes were initiated in the cortical or pericyclic regions and then progressed inward toward the peri - medulkry and inner phloem or pith tissue (Table 10, Figs. 2, 3, and 4). A fals: cicatrice developed in all storages but injcracks it was never as ex - tensive as with tangential cuts. Suberization of the interior portion of a crack was delayed more in cold storage than was the suberization of the tissues at an equal distance from the periphery of the tangential cuts. However, the collapsing of suberized parenchyma was less extensive than ; when jtangentially cut tubers were placed in colid storage. ' . Tne healing of radial cuts that had been exposed to the sun for six hours was altered by different storage conditions in about the same manner ; as the unexposed radial cracks (Table 11). ' ¦¦'.'¦ ¦ ¦¦ . ,'¦.;-¦.' : { ¦. ' . .'.•¦" " '¦'.'-.¦ '.•'. ; . ¦. . ¦ . :'¦'."'.- : '. 1 ' ' . " ¦• " : - . ' . .. ¦ ¦¦¦¦ ' I ¦'¦'¦¦ '''"':. ' '¦¦¦•:' ¦¦' :¦¦'¦"¦ •¦¦-¦.:' ' ¦•:• ¦¦''¦¦¦:¦¦¦ ¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 Table 9.— Extent of wound healing in tangential cuts of tubers that were placed under different storage conditions after six hours' exposure to sunshine immediately after cutting, as observed at intervals after cut' ting, stated as numbers of layers of cells involved. (For statement of at - mospheric conditions at exposure time and in storage see Tables 1 and 6.) Treatment number and type of storage Days Tad ~ alter 2 B 2 C Warm humid 2 D „ .". injury Humid Dry room 20 days, Cold If 1(1 Storage cellar cellar then cold storage 7.' .*?' &#132; storage humul cellar False cicatrice 2 clays 10-20 20 G2O 15-20 5 clays 15-20 20 20 15-25 10 days 2U-2S 20 20 20-25 20 clays 20-25 20 20 20-35 Suhcrized parenchyma 5 days 0-2 0-2 0-4 0 ID days !.--) 0-3, GO )-3, Gl 0 20 days I--) 3-4 2-3 0-1, GO 4ii day* 2--) 2 1-4 2-5 3-6 75 clays 2-4 2-4. G3 1-4 4-5 G8 120 days 2-4 2-4 1-4 4-5 G8 I"U dais 2-4 3 1-4 -f-5 Phclln^'cn (of wound pcridcrm) 5 days 0 &gt; 0 111 days 0-1, CO 1) 0-3 0 20 days 0-2, GO 0-2 0-2 0 41) .lays 0-i 1-3 0-2 0 0 75 clays . . . 0-2 GO-1 \-i 0 : J2O days IJ-I.GO 0-4 0 ? 0 0 l') 0 clays . 0-2, GO 0 0 2f.0 clays 0-2, GO ... 0 0 Phcllcm 10 clays . 0 0 2-4 0 20 .lays ... 0-2 O-2, GO 1-6 0 411 days 3-5 2-4 1-6 0 0 75 clays 2-fu G4 2-4 3-6, G4 0 0 120 days 2-6, G4 3-6 4-rt 0 lvo days 2-&lt;i,G4 3-6 -Mi,G5 0 260 clays 2-6, G4 4-7, G6 FEATHERED TUBERS The healing of feathered tubers was altered by storage in about the same manner as with tangential cuts. The principal difference observed j was the development of a somewhat more extensive false cicatrice with ] feathered than with tangentially cut tubers when both were held in cold j storage (Table 12). [ </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Table 10.— Extent of wound healing in various tissue regions of radial cracks in tubers that were placed tinder different storage conditions im - mediately after injury, as observed at intervals after injury, stated as nupibers of layers of cells involved. " Dayj ¦-¦ . ¦ '¦ ' Tissue region ... - after Lot Type of r —— i injury No.-, storage . Outer. Inner Peri- Outer Xvl , m IS.™ | . | cortex . cortex . .cycle phloem X"m "'%%« . " ¦ J False cicatrice . ¦. . . '".'¦. 5 7B Humid cellar 0-! i O-'/S 1 &gt; .. ? ? "A Warm room 1-2-1 ?¦":--?¦¦ ? j 70 Cold storage 0 0 0 0 0 0 . Suucrixcd parenchyma .. ' . ' 5 7B Humid cellar 2 V/.-2 ;i fr-JJ.'GO' -I 0 7A .Warm-roam 3-) 1-2 1-IIS li ft- 1/ 0 7D Cold storage : 0 Of 0~ 0 Or 0 10 7B Humid cellar 3-S,G3'l&amp;-2 ¦ 1-I'i '/, U-u n_i&lt; 7A Warm room .2-3 1-2 1+ 0-10-1 t'l 7D ¦ Cold Horace I. 0 ..-, ? -0 0 0 0 20 7B Humid cellar 3-5 1-2 1-2 &gt;/, &gt;(-V, o_i - .7A ¦: Warm room 5-7 3-5 ; . 2-3 1-2 'i-2 Xl 71) ¦ Cold storage ¦ 2-S 1-3. :: r . '¦• - ; ¦¦¦ ¦ j HO . 7D CiiW storage 6-7 .3-5 .2-3 lj^-2;i l&gt;]-2 H-l'/i 75 ¦ 7D Cold storage 6-7 4-5 ¦) v) .: s_) . J-2 260 7D . Cold storaijc 0-7 4-5 4-5 4-5 4.5 3.5 1 .';¦'¦ ¦ I'l&lt;clloKcn: (of wound.|ictiderm) Ifi 7B Humid cellar .I 0. U-l ¦ 0-5 . 0-2, CO 0 0 7A Warm room 0-1 1-3 1-3 1-3 1-3 j_j 7D Cold storage '-0 0 '. 0 . (}¦ ¦ 0 0 20 711 Humid cellar : ? 1-2 4-7 3-7 2-3 2-3 7A Warm room 0 0-2 1-3 5-fi 3-5 2-3 7D Cold storage - 0 . . 0 0. . Q " 0 0 40 7B Humid cellar f 0-1 3-4 3-6 5 4-6 7AD' Warm room '• 0 O-I 1-2 1-2 1-3 1-6 7D Cold Jloragc 0 : 0 0 / 0 0 0 75 7B Humid cellar 0 . 0 0-2 2-&lt;i 4 2-&lt;j ' 7D Cold storage ¦ 0.. .-'¦ 0 0 • 0.. ¦ ¦? a 120 7B Humid cellar 0 . 0 .0-1 . 2-3 2-3 2-3 260 7B Humid cellar 0 1-2 2-4 1-5 3-6 2-6 7AD - Warm room 0 0-1 lj-4 - 1-3 1-3 1-4 265 ' 7ADA 2 Warm'room .0 - Qrl. 0 1-3 2-4 3-4 ¦ ;¦ . ¦' ' ': ; ' Pliellem- \ .-,:[. 10 7A Warm room 0 1-3 0-2 0-1,00 0-2 0-3 20 7B Humid cellar .1 3 3 2-3 0-2 1-3 7A Warm room 0 ¦ 0-2 3-t 3-4 2-4 1.5 7D Cold storage 00 0 0 0 0 40 7B Humid cellar JO 3: 3-5 '; 4-5 5. 2-3 7D Cold storage 0 • .2-1 '3-5 .3-5+ .3-5 3-6 75 7B ¦ Humid cellar ' 0 3-4 - 4-6 ¦ 4-8 .5 3-5 7D Cold storage ;'..( 0 0 0 0 0 0-2? 120 7B Humid cellar .i 0 4 . 4-7 4-7 ,5 4-5 260 7B Humid cellar 0 5-fi 5-7 5-7 5-7 4-7 7AD&gt; ¦. , 0 ' 4 3-5 ' 3-5 ''.. 3-5 3-« 265' 7ADA 1 Warm-cnld . .10 4-5 5-6 ... 4-6 3-5 3-6 1 AD= warm humid room 20 days then moved to cold storage. : . 1 ADAt=same as described in footnote I, but back to warm room for five days on 260 th day. </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Nebraska A(;rl. Kxp. Station Research Bulletin 102 Tabli. 11.— Extent of wound healing in various tissue regions oj radial cracks into tubers that were placed under different storage conditions alter six hours' exposure to sunshine immediately after cutting, as observed at intervals after cutting, reported as numbers of layers oj cells involved. Tinmii- region hkV i '"' I T\|v..i Pcrimed - ¦ v, &gt;i,.,.,;,- Outer Inner Vcti- Outer Xylcm &#132;|iaiy or | iiirirt cortex cycle phloem | pj,^ l.ilsc cicatrice 5 SB llumul lll.it 20 llf-20 li in 5 0-3 hA W.inn r.«.m 111-12 7-9 1-5 1-3 «I) .1,1,1 mirage "12 Ml) S .f-8 1 0 Sul&lt;eri/ed parenchyma &gt; SB llumitl &#132;ll.n (-» 3-4 3-4 3 2 '4 M Harm r,,..iu »-l" 5-fi .M 2-t (M'j JHM hi. fulil niu* : : I) II 0 0 , 1(1 SB Kumiil cellar .&lt;¦&lt; J i 3 2-1 1-3 8A ".arm n»uir 12 3-.I 2 ¦( 2-1 1 2 81) C.1.l uuMtt 5 »(:l .M • » 0 0 ;¦( k|i i i,h! miMiw -I &lt;¦ H 2-' " 0 « i, Ml c ..1.1 M « 4-1, &lt; i H 1-2 • 3-5 2-3 -i 81) ( &#132;1,l &#132;,,r. 4-(. 1-1 i-i 1-1 3-5 2-3 l'hclliiKrn 1" mi llumn\ irlUi n " " "-1 0 ° »A ttjrm Mi « I»-J »-i l&gt;-l 0-2 0-i HP c,,1(1 &gt;l,ir.(iii- " " (I (I 0 0 'ii Mi Humid hllji ; 2 2 2 1-2 1-2 KA Warm r ii ii ¦ (HI 1-2 2 2 81) ( r.M &gt;Kirji!t " « II II 0 0 + i MB Humid x-ll.ir " 'I "-I 11-I 0-1 0-3 SM&gt;' Warm t',"in " 'I "• : 0-1 0-1 8U ( "Id .("(•.,„¦. (I (I I) I) 0 0 "5 8B Humid .ell.i H 0 IH 0-2 +-5 +-5 81) ( old »mr.(i;i- II IP 0 II 0 0 I2D Ml llumul cellar II U-2 11-I 0-2 1-1 3 !,n »H Humid ,ell.ir li Ii » 0-1 1-2 0-3 «\IV Warm r,«.m II (I II (I 1-3 0 HUB* I'nkl MtirjiK " 1-2 1-2 (l-l. GO 0-1 1 Vtwttem ID Ml llumul cellar II 0 0 0-1 0--1 0 KA Warm r.«,m II II 0-2 0-2 0-2 0-1 HI) (nl.I Mur.ise II 0 U 0 (I 0 2u »B Humid ellar : 2-3 2 2-3 2-3 1-3 HA Warm t.«.m « 0-1 2-3 3-t 2-3 3 81) ((,1,1 ,i.,r.,(e II I) U 0 II 0 4(1 »B Humid .rlbr II 2-f 1-t 2-3 3-1 2-4 BAD 1 Wirm n»im « 1-2 2-J 3-7 4 81) lolil iioratc (i U I) 0 0 0 " KB Humid .ellar II 3 3-13-5 3-4 2-t 8D (old mirage li 0 0 0 0 0 120 KB Humid cellar II 3 3-6 3-6 3-5 4 260 8B Humid cellar II 3-1 3-* 4-6 4-7 3-4 HAD Warm r.»,m I) 1-2 !-5 3-5 4-&lt;i 4-5 »1)B: I'o'.d M,,ra ß e (I \-2 2-3 4 4-5 3-4 — Al) = warm humid room 2u iljyi. llien to cold storage. ¦llrl = enlil &gt;l.,ra«e 27 ilayi. llieu humid cellar. ¦ I j </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes Table 12.— Extent of woiind\heaUng in "feathered" tubers that were placed uni'er different storage conditions immediately after injury (Lot 11) or afttr six hours' exposure to sun (Lot 12), as observed at intervals after injury, reported as number of layers of cells involved. ( Days Not exposed to sun. . Exposed to sun six hours .. after I 11.8 11 ADI 11 D . 12 B 12 A 12~D injury Humid Warm i Cold. Humid ¦• Warm Cold _| cellar room storage cellar cellar storage False cicatrice 2 1-3 3 .4-6 15-28 V 35 20-25 5 1-3 2-3. j 4-6 30-33 32-38 20-28 10 3-5 3-5 4-7 30-35 : 35-45 ..... 75 3-5 ... ¦'¦ ¦ ! 8-13 ..... ..... 46 120- 3-5 ... i 10-15 ..... ..... ..... : Subcrizcd parenchyma 5 1 2-3 0 IMJS 0-3 0 10 0-VA 2-3 . :? 1-2 1-3 0 20 0-3 2-4 1-2 .2-3. . 1-3 0-2 40 2-3 2-4 1-5 2-4, G3 1-3 0-4 75 0-1 ... 4-7 2-3 ... 2-3 120 0-2 • ... 8-9 2-3 ... 190 0-1 2-3 :.'•¦¦"' Gls 1-3 1-3 260 ... ... . Gl5 . . 1-3 1-3 ... Phcllogcn (of woum pcridcrm) 10 0 1-2 i : 0 0 . 0-1 0 20 ? 2-5, G2 0 0 0-2 0 40 6-2 •¦¦¦"¦ 0 ¦ i . 0 'A-l 0-2 0 75 o-i.go ••• '0 o • : ¦..;. o 120 0 ... . &gt; ¦ 0:; &lt;ir-l : ... :.. 190 o? . o ¦. o ¦"..-¦ 0-2 : o-i 260 O-3,G0: .:; 0 0-1 . 0-I.GO 0 :¦; .;¦ PhcHcm io o :¦¦? o o ' o o 20 0 2-4. , ¦ 0 0-2 0-3 0 40 2-4.G3 G3 . 0 2-3 1-3, G3 0 75 3-5.G3 ;.. ; 0 3-4 ... 0 120 3-5.G3 ... ." o 3-5 ... 0 I'JO 3-5.G3 2-4 0 5-6 " 3-4 0 2GO 4-5 ... ' , 0 5 3-5 0 'Warn humid room 20 days, Ihcn into colj storage.' 1 ." '-¦ . ¦• . ; Ex{ osure of feathered tubers to six hours' sunshine did not alter the relative effect of storage, upon the healing process. , . EFFICT OF HOT FORMALDEHYDE ON TANGENTIAL CUTS The results of Pratt. (1.4) in preventing' decay of bruised potatoes by treating them with disinfectants within three days after harvesting are suggestive of possibilities. When disinfecting potatoes in the fall it is not safe to use mercuric compounds because of the danger of poisoning people </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Ni.braska A&lt;;rl. F.xp. Station Research Bulletin 102 01 animals il the potatoes would lie used as food. As cold formaldehyde i« no longer in lavor as a potato-seed disinfectant it seemed advisable to determine the effect of the standard hot-formaldehyde method upon the healing of wounds. freshly harvested lots of Triumph potatoes were cut tangentially at \arious intervals hctore the time at which they were treated with hot for - maldehyde (1 to 120, at 124°-126° F. 4 minutes, then drained and covered lor one hour). They were then held in the dark at a temperature ranging between 6K' and 84° F., with the relative humidity from 30 to 60 per cent. When the potatoes were dipped in hot formaldehyde before suuerin had been deposited on the walls of the outer cells, some damage was done lv the unprotected cells adjacent to the cut surfaces. The earlier the treat - ment occurred after cutting, the greater was the damage as measured by the number of layers of cells in the false cicatrice. The damage may have ken a [rifle less when the treatment was delayed for one or six hours and it was definitely Jess when dipping was delayed until 24 hours after cutting. The hot formaldehyde brought about no damage when used three days alter potatoes were cut, the cut surfaces apparently having been quite lully protected by the suberization which was well under way by the second day. r.ABLt 13. — Growth of molds on the cut surfaces — tuber halves treated with _ hot formaldehyde. Time after cutling when as in severity of mold growth on sur - inatcd with hot taa' ' cl" tu"lT!&gt; "n December H)lh fonml.Uhy.lc None or mil.l j Medium or severe Per cent Per cent 1 AI once- iC, 64 2 Two hours -IS 55 i Not treated . Sfi H ¦&gt; One clay ... i} 67 i Two days -U 54 '. Three dais Hi tf 7 Two weeks 'IS 2 X Nm treated . . . 82 18 1...- 1 I i..t, &#132;n &#132;,i,l |&#132;,i. \-l ,r,.,,,,l .„ h.,,,,.,, linn- ,ii Alliance, on ihc Mine iliijr, Sipl. 27. 1928. I ..i, &#132;. h «rre mi &#132;n Scplcm)&gt;c&gt; 2~ an.l l..iii 4 1,, 7 were Irealcil i.n ihc gli-en numlirr of ilays ihcrc - .iiirr. Ml urn- lurid in sl.it traiei in a Ik-UI liuuk from Sew. 27 in Scot. 29. then in a frciriil cir iriim Sepr. 2') 1.1 (hi. 4, and in mid ilci'a-c from (Kl. 10 lice. 1(1. Suberization was delayed when potatoes were treated one day or less alter cutting but it apparently was not affected by treating three days after cutting. The development of a phellogen and phellem were likewise de - layed by early treatment of cut potatoes, but their subsequent development was not greatly altered by the treatment. Mention has been made elsewhere of the more extensive collapse of the unsuberized or outer cortical cells just under the old periderm and of the very general lack of development of a wound periderm across these j I </seg>
         <seg id="p039">i Wound Healing in Triumph Potatoes ortical cells. These tissues appeared to have suffered great injury in „ tially cut potatoes that were treated with hot formaldehyde six hours ar less after cutting. In such Jubers outer cortical cells were found to havi:; collapsed for a distance of 20 to 30 cell layers back from the edge of the cut under the old periderm, while in the inner cortex 15 to 20 cell layers were found to have' collapsed. There was seldom any wound periderm across the cortical regions. There seldom were over 8 or 12 layers if dead cells in the pericycle or outer phloem when dipping occurred at one: after cutting and in that region a wound periderm developed shortly before the seventh day. This more extensive killing of cortical tissue was observed, but to a lesser degree in potatoes treated 24 hours after cutting; but not when treatment was delayed until the third day. ;¦: Th:se observations indicate that the treating: of freshly wounded potatoes with hot formaldehyde is destructive to surface tissues and delays wound healing. With the lower storage temperatures prevalent in western storage cellars in the fall, the delay in establishing a wound cork would be greiter and there would be a prolongation of the time during which infection might occur with a rot-producing organism that grows at these low temperatures. Such delay might be serious in: view of the findings of Weiss, Lauritzen, and Brierley (20), to the effect that infection with some Fusaria may occur at any time through an uncorked surface and that these organisms are capable; of growing at temperatures too low for phello;;en development. 7- In jsome experiments conducted in 1929-30 it was found that many cut and tr:ated tubers became very moldy in storage and rotted (Table 13). In vie v of these facts disinfecting with, hot formaldehyde does not seem promi: ing as a means of preventing storage losses. LITERATURE CITED 1.. Ajipcl, Olto '. ";: . ¦ ¦"'¦ " ' L .',:,. : - .;. '."'¦ '¦: IS 06. ZuM KEXNTNISS DKS \VuNDVERSCIII.USSES BEI KaRTOITELV. Her. «lcr Dot. Ges; 24:118-122. . ' . 2. A tschwancr, Ernest : . . ]!27. Wound' Pekiderm Formation i.v the Potato as An krted. iv Tempera - ture and Humidity. Jour. Aj;r. Res. 35:995-1000. 3. ]!&lt;rchtokl, Fricclrich, Graf yon •-.¦•.¦ IH2. Die Kartoi-i-elx, Chapter XVI, Prague, 18-12. Literature ilcr KartolTcl - pllanzc, 542-16. ¦). C ayton, E. 13. -IS 32. Dust Treatment of Cut Potato Seed. N. Y. (Geneva) Agr. Exp. Sta. Hul. 610. . 5. D r Vrics, Hugo ¦-.; ¦ :.•: : .. ';.::• . 1178. JiKITRAfiE ZUR SI'KCIELLEX PIIVSIOLOGIE I.AXDWIRTSCIIAFTLICIIER KULTUR - PI-LAN7.KN—IV, Khimux(is(!E(:iiiciite der Kartofielknolles, Land. Jahrb, '-. .- ¦;. 7:217-19. . • -. ¦ \ sa. Hibcrlandt, G. ¦ ; 1913. Akad dcr wiss. Iltrlin, I, 221-234. From Priestley and Woflcnden (15). 6. Hardenburg, E. V. '.'"¦ &#132;.." . ; 1931. Field Study of Potato Tuber Defects is Western New York. Proc. 18th Ann. Meet. Potato Assoc. of Amcrica&gt;3l-40. • </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Nebraska Acrl. Exp. Station Research Bulletin 102 7. lhsiiivs. R. C. I'*Sv Mh iiiMiAi Injikps. \ SorHii ni Loss is Potatoes. N. D. State Seed Commissioner. Bui. 13. s. Hcrkl.its. (J. A. C. \ {&gt;2-\. Tin-; I'hmts 01 a\ Artimciali.y Controlled Hvdrio.v Concentration i ion Woind Hi.him. in tiik Potato. New Phytologist 23:240-55. ''. Kaltus. Bruno \'i\l. Nm 1 I'nii rsi 1111 ni.in ii nhii Rkcenlrationsvorgange bei Pflanzex. lln. lliol. l'llanz. 11:1-52. 111. Kny, 1.. ISK'I. I'llllß 1)11 Hlllllvi. HIS Wl NDPI RIDIRMS AN KSOI.I.EN IN HIRER AbHANCIG - kiit \dn usmhin V.iNurssiN. lk-r. Dcut. Bnt. Gcsell. 7:154-68. 11. OlulVn. 1.. 1().). I'vTHmill'VU V l-KHh.R WINnpmiDMMIIILDLNG AN KaRTOFI-ELKXOI.I.E.V. Biitan, t&gt;ntr.. lk-ihcftc l"-.[2fi9]-3O8. 12. I't.ic.wk. \V. M. ]''_&gt;]. Hj.m.inc, (ii Potato!s Skinnid DrßiN'fj Harvest as Affected by Tem - pi KATIRF, HI.MIDITY, AND SoI.AR AND SKY RADIATION. ProC. Am. SoC. Hurt. Sci. 2H:2Mi-6'&gt;. li. Pijcuvk. \V, M.. Wright. R. C. anil Whitcnian, T. M. I"S2. IJiNIHOII INI. THE SIIRINK.U.K OF SKINNED POTATOES IX STORAGE. PfOC. Am. Sue. ll.irl. Sci. 2 C':-!15-I». H. I'r.iit. (). A. l'Mfi. ('.oNiiuii. in tiii I'nwni.RY Ouv Ror of Westers Potatoes Caused by Vn/tmiiiu trichuihreioiiles. Jour. Ajjr. Res. fi:Sl7-32. 1=;. Priestley. J. 11.. ;&gt;ml WuficmU-n. I-. M. \'&lt;li. Tin- lliai i\(. in- Wra-vns in Potato Ti'iii-rs and Their Propagation 1 ny Ci i Sits. Ann. App. Hi»l. M):%-11". \i&lt;. Pruncl. A. I &gt;&lt;l|. Si R I A PI HI-ORATION 1)1 S TV HI -RCI'I.KS 1)1- I'OMME DE TERRE PAS LE RIIIZOMIS nr (iiii\DiNi-. Rc\. (Icn. Hot. 3:166-75. 17. Schrumpf, William V. l'l}3. Till 111 IH T OF IIINDI.ING MuMODS ON QUALITY OF MAINE POTATOES. Maine Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 3fis. 17a. Sin^li- B. W- and Mathur. P. B. V'iS. Sll 1)11 S l\ PIITATO STORU.F. —11, IXFU'FXCt OF (1) StM.E OF MaTUKiTV oi the Tibirs ano (2) the Storage Temperature for a Brief Dura - tion IMMI.Dt.Vn I.V AMIR DIGGING ON PIIYSIOLOCICAL LOSSES IS WEIGHT OF PoTvints Dt'RiNG Sroß\r.E. Ann. App. Binl. 25:68-78. Is. Sharxnalov, M.. ami Edsnn, H. A. lv|'». Writ vu ('-(irk Formation in the Potato i.n Relation" to Seed Piece Hkay. Phytopathology 9:-183. I l'. Sni'uh. (^ra I'iii. Stidiis oi Poiato Storage. Cornell Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 553. Jll. Weiss. I-'.. I.aurilzcn. ]. 1., and Bricrlcy. Philip. l ll2S. l-VCICIRS IN Till KcH'TION AND DEVELOPMENT OF FuSARIUM ROT IS STORED PoiAiofs. U. S. J^. A. Tech. Bui. 62. 21. Werner, 11. O. ] {&gt;il. Tin Cac-se and Privfntion oi Mechanical Injuries to Potatoes. Ncbr. .\);r. hsp. Sla. Hul. 260. 22. Werner, 11. O. Viti. (iRADK Di.ihts: Tmur Prevalence in Nebraska Potato Stocks and MtTiions of Ki.iminating TmM. 17th Ann. Rcpt. Ncbr. Potato Imp. As - soc. I=s-2-1. 2! Werner, H. O. I'i36. Cellar and Gold Storage of Sound and Mechanically Damaged Tru-mvh Seed Potatoes. Ncbr. \y.r. Exn. Sta. Res. Bui. 88. 2-1. Wilcox E. M-, Link, G. K. X., and Pool, V. W. 1913. A Dry Rot of tiif Irish Potato Tuber. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Res. Bui. 1. [2J4M] </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>