<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Second Biennial Report OF THE Board of Commissioners OF STATE INSTITUTIONS TO THE GOVERNOR AND LEGISLATURE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Second Biennial Report OF THE Board of Commissioners OF STATE INSTITUTIONS TO THE GOVERNOR AND LEGISLATURE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA For the Birnnium Ending November 30, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATE OF NEBRASKA BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS LINCOLN MEMBERS OF THE BOARD Howard Kennedy, Chairman Term Expires July 1, 1917 Second Congressional District Henry Gesdes Term Expires July 1, 1919 First Congressional District Silas A. Holcomb Term Expires July 1, 1921 Sixth Congressional District OFFICE STAFF Leo Matthews, Secretary Pearl Bemis Leonard George Weidenfeld, Accountant Vera A. Bonekf.mper, Bookkeeper Voucher Clerk Jessie L. Alley, Stenographer and Clerk Mary E. McDermott, Stenographer and Clerk </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 3 NAMES OF INSTITUTIONS AND ACTIVITIES I'nder the Jurisdiction of the Board of Commissioner* of State Institutions Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, Beatrice, Nebraska D. G. Griffiths, M. D., Superintendent Girls' Industrial School, Geneva, Nebraska Lyda J. McMahon. Superintendent R. V. Clark. Superintendent Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Burkett, Nebraska J. F. Walsh, Commandant Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Milford, Nebraska D. C. Rowden, Commandant Ingleside Hospital for the Insane, Ingleside, Nebraska W. S. Fast, M. D., Superintendent Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln. Nebraska B. F. Williams, M. I)., Superintendent Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk, Nebraska George E. Charlton, M. I)., Superintendent Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska L. S. B. Robinson, M. D.. Superintendent Orthopedic Hospital, Lincoln, Nebraska H. Winnett Orr, M. D.. Superintendent State Penitentiary, Lincoln, Nebraska W. T. Fenton, Warden Nebraska School for the Blind, Nebraska City, Nebraska N. C. Abbott, Superintendent Nebraska School for the Deaf, Omaha, Nebraska F. W. Booth, Superintendent Nebraska Home for Dependent Children, Lincoln, Nebraska Etta Caton, Agent Commission for the Blind, Nebraska City. Nebraska N. C. Abbott Superintendent Board of Examiners of Defectives B. F. Williams. M. D.. Chairman, Lincoln, Nebraska W. S. Fast, M. D., Secretary, Ingleside, Nebraska State Industrial School, Kearney, Nebraska Nebraska Industrial Home, Milford, Nebraska Lena E. Ward, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 5 REPORT OF BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS TO THE GOVERNOR AND TO THE LEGISLATURE OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA : The Board of Commissioners of State Institutions begs to present herewith for your consideration its second bien - nial report for the period beginning December 1, 1914, and ending November 30, 1916. PERSONNEL By the re-appointment of Silas A. Holcomb, one of the members of this Board, upon the expiration of the term for which he was first named and which expired July 1, 1915, the membership of the Board during its entire existence and the period covered by this report has remained the same and as originally constituted and its work has continued along the lines and according to the principles and policies adopted immediately after its organization under the law creating the Board and under which it has been operating since the beginning. An earnest effort has been made to improve wherever opportunity presented itself, not only in the general man - agement of the institutions under the control of the Board but with the view of more efficiently carrying on the work pertaining thereto and to safe-guard and promote, wher - ever possible, the interests, comfort and welfare of the charges of the State maintained in the several institutions referred to. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF From the first, it has been the policy of the Board to make no change in the personnel of the officers of the several institutions unless such change should seem to be required in order to promote efficiency and good service. Where vacancies have occurred for any reason they have been filled so far as practicable by appointments from among those already in the service of the State whose qualifications were such as to entitle them to recognition and promotion. EXECUTIVE AND STAFF CHANGES »Dr. E. R. Van der Slice, after serving a little more i a year as superintendent of the Hospital for Tuber - &gt;us at Kearney, retired from the service of the State November 30, 1915. I He was succeeded on January 14, 191G, by Dr. L. S. B. inson, who came to us from Minnesota, of whose State itorium he was assistant superintendent. During the interval between the going of Dr. Van der Slice and the coming of Dr. Robinson, the needs of the hospital were well cared for by Dr. L. M. Stearns of Kear- IDr. W. D. Guttery, formerly superintendent of the pital for the Insane of Nebraska at Norfolk, was relieved n duty on January 15, 1916. I Dr. M. W. Baxter, formerly superintendent of the leside Hospital for the Insane, retired therefrom on uary 31, 1916. The vacancy created by the retirement of Dr. Baxter was filled by the transfer of Dr. W. S. Fast from the super - intendency of the Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth at Beatrice, where he had made an admirable record of efficient and faithful service. tDr. D. G. Griffiths, then pathologist of the Nebraska pital for the Insane at Lincoln, was appointed superin - lent of the Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded th, to succeed Dr. Fast, on February 1, 1916. Dr. G. E. Charlton, second physician of the Ingleside Hospital for the Insane, was transferred to the Hospital </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS for the Insane of Nebraska at Norfolk to become the suc - cessor of Dr. Guttery on March 18, 1916. Mrs. Grace Baxter and Mrs. L. M. Guttery, who re - signed their positions as matrons of the hospitals for the insane at Ingleside and Norfolk, respectively, were suc - ceeded, the former by Mrs. Libbie Thordson and the latter by Miss Bertha M. Ludwig, each of whom had long served the State efficiently in positions of less responsibility. In this connection it seems proper to state that it is the policy of the Board not to appoint as matrons the wives of super - intendents, and that there are now but two instances in which the wife of the superintendent is the matron of the institution. The vacancy created by the promotion of Dr. Griffiths was filled by the appointment of Dr. F. S. Marnell, who had previously served with credit in similar institutions in Iowa ; and that created by the promotion of Dr. Charlton was filled by advancing Dr. C. A. Oaks, previously third physician at the Ingleside Hospital for the Insane. Dr. Oaks was succeeded first by Dr. G. C. Rice, who remained but a few days ; then by Dr. W. A. Danielson, who resigned after a few months to accept a better position in Illinois ; and finally by Dr. Ward W. Hedlund of Lincoln, the present incumbent. Col. Ferdinand Zimmerer, formerly commandant of the Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home at Burkett, was suc - ceeded on March 15, 1915, by Col. John F. Walsh, of Hum - boldt. Adjutant J. T. Lane of the same institution resigned February 23, 1915, and was succeeded by E. J. Maxwell, of Nemaha City. Dr. Clyde P. Fordyce, after more than two years ser - vice as physician of the Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home at Burkett, resigned to re-enter private practice and was succeeded on October 18, 1915, by Dr. J. A. Waggoner, of Humboldt. INVESTIGATIONS Among the duties which devolve upon the Board is to investigate and report any abuses or wrongs alleged to exist </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF I any institution under its control. Complaints are fre - ;ntly presented to the Board, often anonymously, and se no matter what their source, have always received care - consideration and, wherever sufficiently definite to afford asis for such action, have been personally investigated by Board or some member of it. Beside instances which e been called to its attention by others, the Board has on own initiative investigated matters which seemed to need ention. Some of these investigations have been quite in - mal; others were attended with many of the formalities a court proceeding. (The more important of these investigations disclosed gularities in the business methods and management of Hospital for Tuberculous, resulting in the retirement of Van der Slice ; irregularities in connection with certain Dlies and other matters in the management of the Ingle- Hospital for the Insane, resulting in the resignation )r. Baxter; and an ineptitude of management and de - alization of the working force of the Hospital for the me of Nebraska at Norfolk, resulting in the retirement )r. Guttery. In many instances complaints were found to be without any substantial basis and in most cases where some ground for complaint existed the facts had been greatly exaggerated and colored. Each case was carefully considered and such action taken as seemed to be required by the facts estab - lished. I The Board has at all times encouraged the retention ill employees who have proven themselves efficient, well lifted, and conscientious in the discharge of their res - tive duties for such period of time as their work proves sfactory ; and with a view of keeping in the employ of State the very best class of service that can be obtained required that no one be discharged from his or her )loyment except for cause and for reasons which are sfactory and for the betterment of the service, and that jport be made to this Board monthly of all such dis - rges and the reasons therefor. We feel that it is now I understood among the larger number of employees in </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 9 these different institutions that their continuation in the service of the State depends entirely upon the merits of the service rendered to the State and the faithful and efficient discharge of the duties which they are required to perform while engaged in such employment. In general, it should be said that conditions in the several institutions have been excellent. STATE INSTITUTIONS The several institutions managed and controlled by the Board consist of three hospitals for the insane ; two homes for ex-soldiers and sailors; two industrial schools, one for boys and one for girls; an institution for feeble-minded; a hospital for tuberculosis; an orthopedic hospital; a state penitentiary; an industrial home for women; a school for the blind ; a school for the deaf ; and a home for dependent children, making a total of fifteen. POPULATION The average daily inmate population in the different institutions of the State for the year ending November 30, 1914, was 4305. The average daily inmate population for the biennium covered by this report, being for the two years ending November 30, 1916, is 4526. The average daily inmate population for the month closing the biennial period, that is, November, 1916, is 4864. In the above summary of the population there are not included those who were not actually present in the institu - tions but were on parole or furlough or for other reasons temporarily absent from the institutions in which they were inmates or held membership. This absent population in - cludes those committed to the different hospitals for the insane who were deemed by the authorities of such insti - tutions sufficiently recovered to go to friends and relatives or to those who took friendly interest in them on parole for brief periods of time or for so long as their conduct was such as to warrant them in having their liberty, some of whom were finally discharged and others from time to time </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF returned to the institutions from which they were paroled. The same rule holds good as to the institution for feeble - minded and the industrial schools. At the soldiers' homes and the penitentiary a large number are constantly out on parole or furlough. Temporary free homes are also fre - quently found for many of those committed to the home for dependent children. This absent population will average altogether approximately ten to twelve hundred. The aggre - gate absent population for the month of November, 1916, in all institutions numbers 1001, thus making a gross total population under the control of the State, directly or in - directly, at the close of the biennium of 5865. The total number of officers and employees as shown by the reports for the month of November, 1916, aggregates 718. I It will be seen from the above that the total population intained in the different institutions and present therein the close of the biennial period numbers 5582, and if to s is added the number on parole and furlough or who, for ler reasons, are temporarily absent, the grand total of the pulation of all of the institutions reaches in numbers 6583. I It is to be noted from the foregoing that there has n a steady increase in the population of these several titutions and, judging by the past, it is not to be doubted that this increase in the growth of the population will tinue for some time to come. Based upon the experience the past, the capacities of the different institutions to ivide for the accomodation of those seeking admission, increased facilities by the completion of new buildings v under construction, and additional buildings which are ommended in our estimate of appropriations needed for coming biennium, it is estimated that the average inmate mlation for the coming biennium will be at least 5031 and which provision will have to be made for their proper e, support and treatment. For some time past and at present the greatest demand for additional room and facilities for caring for the inmates or those seeking admission exists at the three hospitals for the insane, the institution for the feeble-minded and the two soldiers' homes. We have found ourselves unable to </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 11 provide promptly for the reception of all those who have been legally adjudged insane and regularly committed to one of the three hospitals maintained by the State. Every effort possible has been put forth to accommodate this un - fortunate class of citizens of the State and to receive them promptly in one of the different hospitals as they are found to be entitled to admission and committed by the proper authorities thereto. By transferring from one institution to another and crowding to the utmost limit commensurate with the safety and welfare of those already under treat - ment, we have been enabled to care fairly well for all those who have been committed to the custody of these hospitals and in this we have received the hearty aid and co-operation of the superintendents; but notwithstanding the utmost efforts we have been able to put forth, there are a large number that for a shorter or longer period of time have to be detained in the counties of their residence, in the jails or other places of restraint until a place can be found in which to receive them in one of the hospitals where only can they be given the care, attention and treatment their unfortunate conditions demand. The Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth has outgrown its capacity and is now unable to receive all who are committed thereto and who should have the intelligent and humane care and treatment that can there be given and of which they are deprived because of the lack of facilities to receive them as rapidly as application is made therefor. At the two soldiers' homes the applications for admis - sion are greater than the two institutions can provide ac - commodations for and a waiting list has been necessary for some time in the past. By the construction of a new build - ing at Milford and other improvements there made which increase the facilities of that institution to care for a larger number, and contemplated further improvements at the soldiers' home at Burkett, it is hoped and believed that all those applying for admission hereafter can be with reason - able promptness provided for and accepted as members in one or the other of the two homes. In this connection it is to be noted that those who are admitted to these two homes </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Pg i&gt;lder and more infirm, more come in the class id hospital cases requiring the increasing of the nd the increasing expenditures in the way of and proper help for this class of members espe- With reference to the congested condition existing at the hospitals for the insane and the institution for the feeble-minded, recommendation has been made for new buildings with the view of more promptly receiving and more adequately caring for all those entitled to admission in such institutions. FINANCE We are transmitting herewith a full, complete and de - tailed statement of the appropriations made by the Legisla - ture for and on behalf of the Board in the prosecution of this work and of all expenditures made therefrom and show - ing the purposes for which made ; and also our estimate of the appropriations needed for the coming biennium. tin order that a more intelligent understanding may be regarding the expenditures of the public funds for the ort of the different institutions and the purposes for h expended, the Board has classified or grouped all of its expenditures under two principal heads, as follows : First, the ordinary expenditures required in maintain - ing such institutions and which under the heading "Mainte - nance," are divided into twenty-two sub-heads, many of which are again sub-classified or divided so that there are fifty-three classifications and sub-classifications under this heading, such as salaries and wages ; transportation, tele - graph and telephone ; articles of food ; clothing ; dry-goods ; hardware; fuel, light and power; machinery, tools and sup - plies ; general repairs ; etc. Second, in addition to expenditures under the head - ing of maintenance which includes the ordinary running, every-day, current expenditures, there are further divisions denominated extra-ordinary, including furniture and equip - ment of all kinds, permanent improvements to buildings and grounds, and new buildings and land. These are all </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 13 sub-divided or sub-classified under different titles or head - ings so that for all institutions we are enabled to determine the monthly and annual expenditures of all kinds, both the ordinary and the extraordinary, and to have them prop - erly classified as above outlined. For, the purpose of determining the per capita cost of maintaining the different institutions the same has been based upon the current or ordinary expenditures as the extraordinary expenditures fluctuate very greatly as to the different institutions and also as to the different biennial periods for each of the institutions and depend largely upon appropriations made for permanent improvements, new buildings, furnishing and equipping the same, the purchase of land and other like expenditures of extraordinary char - acter. A detailed statement of all such expenditures prop - erly classified and showing the per capita cost will be found among the tabulated statements herewith submitted as a part of our report and which will disclose fully and in an itemized form all of such expenditures and the pur - poses for which made. During the biennium there was expended for mainten - ance in all of the institutions under the control of the Board $2,125,351.98; for furniture and equipment $62,068.94 ; for permanent improvements to buildings and grounds $144,460.94; for the construction of new buildings and the purchase of land $359,522.09; for miscellaneous purposes 35,969.66. The principal expenditure making up the item last mentioned was for the purchase of the equip - ment and material of the Handcraft Furniture Company at the State Penitentiary, and of new machinery, amount - ing to over $23,000; and personal damage claims for in - jury and death of those connected with the services of the State and which were made by the last Legislature under special enactments made for that purpose, making a total expenditure for extraordinary purposes of $602,021.63, or a grand total of expenditures for all purposes for the bi - ennium of $2,727,373.61. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF EXTRAORDINARY EXPENSES IThe expenditures made during the biennium covered this report were distributed among the different state ;itutions and generally for the purposes as follows : Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth There was expended for extraordinary purposes a total of $56,986.16. This sum was in the main expended for the purpose of constructing, furnishing and equipping a new school building with auditorium on the third floor, rooms Eie basement for industrial training and other purposes, at a total cost of approximately $40,000 ; also to con - it and equip a modern dairy barn capable of housing about 36 dairy cows; also a vitrified hollow tile silo of 135- Ii capacity and a hay barn holding a large tonnage of hay which the herd of cattle is fed during the winter season ; o an expenditure of $9,600 for the purchase of 80 acres land which has added greatly to the crop producing capa - y of that institution and is believed to be a very excellent r estment. Some extraordinary expense was also incur - 1 in extending heating mains, constructing a new well and }viding for a greater supply of water which at no time s been very abundant at this institution. Girls' Industrial School A total extraordinary expenditure of $26,679.64 was made at this institution, principally for the purpose of fin - ishing and furnishing a new auditorium and dormitory building with kitchen and dining rooms on the basement floor, and remodeling and changing the interior of the old building, which became advisable upon the occupancy of the new, especially with reference to re-arranging some of the rooms, the laying of new floors and extensive repairs and changes in the heating and plumbing system which were found to be sadly in need of the same. State Industrial School There was expended for extraordinary purposes $6,741.59. The improvements were in the main of a general </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 15 nature, in adding to the appearance and preserving the structures already in existence, but also including the con - struction of a new ice- house, some new hog houses and a hay barn for the storing of hay and feeding of cattle therein. There was afso purchased some additional laundry machin - ery and equipment for the several trade departments main - tained at this institution. No extraordinary appropriations were requested of or made by the last Legislature and the expenditures above mentioned were made from available funds found to exist including the institution cash fund de - rived from the sale of farm products, live stock, etc., pro - duced at and sold by the institution. m Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Bnrkett The soldiers' "Home" expended during the biennium for extraordinary purposes the sum of $10,669.65. This sum was used for the purchase of machinery and equipment for the laundry, to replace equipment which had become old, worn out and of no further practicable use, the construction of a building principally for the care and protection of farm machinery and .for storage purposes, the extension of the heating plant by the laying of additional mains to other buildings, and for painting, re-wiring, re-plumbing, the lay - ing of floors and other such general repairs throughout the different buildings which have been constructed for a long period of time and are in constant need of repairs and im - povements in order to preserve them and keep them in a comfortable and sanitary condition. The "Home" has made a total expenditure for the bien - nium for the purposes under consideration of the sum of $34,056.81. This sum was paid for the furnishing of the new hospital building completed during the biennial period, for laundry machinery, the finishing of the new hospital building and the construction of a new laundry building with sleeping rooms above for employees, and some expen - ditures for repairs generally. Soldiers' and Sailor. 1 Hone, Milford </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Ingleude Hospital for the Insane rAt this State hospital a total expenditure of $17,711.33 extraordinary purposes was made and principally for purpose of re-shingling several of the mfcin buildings with asbestos shingles which are fire-proof, thus decreasing materially the fire hazard there existing also the laying of the necessary cables and erecting a complete system of elec - troliers for lighting the buildings and grounds and which have added greatly to the convenience and appearance of that institution. Out of this sum there also was paid a death claim of $2,000, allowed and appropriated by the last Legis - lature. This institution is the largest in the state and the gen - eral repairs constantly being carried on in all parts of the institution amount to no inconsiderable item. By constant Eition, however, to the subject the institution is kept in llent condition, in a good state of repair ,and deteriora - is reduced to a minimum. No special appropriation made for any expenditure at this institution of an aordinary character, and the amount expended was found to be available from funds of the regular appropria - tion and from the institution cash fund, a statement of which appears in another part of this report. There is also contemplated the erection of a new gen - eral kitchen, modern in all respects and of sufficient capac - city to provide for all of the inmates as well as the officers and employees, and also to furnish dining-rooms for all of the employees, with a dormitory which will accommodate 75 to 100 of such employes on the third floor. The construc - tion for a building of this kind will probably require an ex - penditure of from $40,000 to $45,000, all cf which is now available or in sight and can, with profit to the State and advantage to the institution, be used for such purpose ; after which, according to present indications, a large sum will lapse into the state treasury at the end of the biennial The old kitchen building has been carefully examined by competent architects at our request with the view of </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 17 remodeling and enlarging the same rather than to build a new structure, but such examinations disclose that this building is structurally unsafe and cannot be depended upon for the purposes for which used but for a short time, and that safety, business prudence and to properly prepare for the future require the construction of a new building and the destruction of the old. There will, of course, be much salvage in the old building which will be put to the best pos - sible use and no useless waste or destruction of any kind will result from the improvements thus to be made and as above outlined. Nebraska Hospital for the Insane A total of $51,842.84 has been expended at the hospital at Lincoln for extraordinary purposes. Included in these expenditures are the erection and furnishing of an addition to the main building which, when occupied in the near fu - ture, will provide additional facilities for 50 or more pa - tients, and will also afford a general dining-room for male patients much more convenient than the one now in use. This new addition has been connected with one of the de - tached buildings by a permanent structure serving the pur - pose of an enclosed walk or passageway on the first floor to be used in inclement weather and an open walk from the second floor of the two buildings thus joined, and permitting the passage conveniently of attendants and employees from one building to the other at all times and at all seasons. There have also been constructed sun porches on the east of the building thus connected for both the second and third floors, these porches from experience having been found to be a great convenience and adding greatly to the comfort and welfare of the inmates. An officers' kitchen has been constructed and new tunnels built to connect the new addi - tion containing the dining-room with the general kitchen, and there has also been a general overhauling, changing and extension of the mains for heating and for water supplies, as well as the installation of additional plumbing required by reason of such changes. The entire main building has </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF also been re-wired for purposes of safety at an expense of approximately $3,000. While there was appropriated but $30,000 for new buildings at this institution we have been able to make the improvements above refewed to by finding other available funds at our command, including the institution cash fund. Hospital for the Iniane of Nebraska At the Norfolk institution a total expenditure of §►3,877.82 of an extraordinary character has been made •ing the biennium. This expenditure was for the purpose finishing a new extension or annex to one of the ward buildings for male patients ; also the construction of a new ward building for women patients which is nearing comple - tion ; and other improvements in the way of remodeling and adding to the laundry building so as to increase its capac - ity ; constructing a small cottage for the residence of one of the physicians ; a considerable extension of the system of tunnels and of heating mains, and of a sewer system for the purpose of properly disposing of the sewerage at this institution. Other improvements seem to be required in the way of a new ward building for male patients, increasing the capacity to properly house and care for 100 more in - mates than is the capacity at the present time or will be when the womens' ward is completed, and which will per - mit a total population at this institution of 750 to 800 in - mates; also extensive repairs in the way of remodeling or constructing anew the power house and installing therein new machinery and boilers, all of which are imperatively necessary in order that the work may be carried on economi - cally and satisfactorily. Hospital for Tuberculous I At this hospital a total of $61,588.55 has been expended the purpose of furnishing and equipping, as well as for construction of a new hospital building which is now ipied and accommodates 50 additional patients; a new er house and laundry building, together with laundry </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 19 machinery and equipment ; the extension of the heating sys - tem to connect the power house with the new laundry build - ing ; also additional sewerage necessitated by these improve - ments. Further changes, improvements and repairs are con - templated for the coming biennium and are referred to in our estimate of appropriations required for this insti - tution. Orthopedic Hospital A total of $25,859.29 has been expended at this insti - tution for furniture and equipment, permanent improve - ments to grounds and buildings, and a new building con - structed thereon. The principal part of this expenditure is for the completion, furnishing and equipping of the new hospital building which has been completed during the cur - rent biennium and which has been occupied for something over twelve months, and which has added greatly in facili - tating the work carried on at this institution and increas - ing the capacity to properly care for those who come there for treatment. Extensive repairs also have been made in other buildings and especially in the power house in the way of enlarging and installing additional boiler capacity; also for the purpose of purchasing additional laundry machin - ery and equipment. State Penitentiary There has been expended at this institution for pur - poses of the kind under consideration $92,831.87. Of this amount $5,000 was expended by reason of an appropria - tion by the last Legislature on account of a death of an em - ployee occasioned at the time of the outbreak occurring at that institution in 1912; and $23,969.66 for the purchase of machinery, equipment and stock, manufactured and un - manufactured, of the Handcraft Furniture Company, the business of which has been acquired by the State and which is now being operated on behalf of and for the benefit of the State. There was also expended $59,352.80, which was </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF chiefly for the purpose of enlarging the power plant, buying new machinery and providing for the generation of elec - tric current sufficient not only to supply that institution but also the State Capitol Building, the Governor's Residence, the Orthopedic Hospital, the Nebraska Home for Depend - ent Children and the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, all of which are now provided with electric light and power from this central location. While this work is not quite complete it is nearing the end and it is believed that with the facilities thus provided by the State and for the pur - t mentioned, the work and result will be found satis - ry as well 'as economical and that the State is now to generate its own electric current in sufficient quan - tity to meet all of the requirements of the institutions re - ferred to for a much less sum than it could possibly hope to do from outside sources. Nebraska Industrial Home The sum of $11,380.38 was expended for extraordinary purposes at this institution, the main part of which was for the purpose of covering the two main buildings with a coat of stucco with a view of preserving each of them and pre - venting further deterioration of the brick of which the original construction is made and which shpwed plainly indications of disintegration and decay. The improvement has greatly added to the appearance of the buildings as well as, it is hoped, to render them safe, durable and inhab - itable for generations to come. There has also been con - structed an addition to one of the buildings in the way of a nursery, a sun porch and an extension to the kitchen which has greatly added to the convenience of the work carried on as well as the comfort of inmates and employees. Nebraska School for the Blind $3,602.11 was expended at this institution in the way of furniture and equipment, and improvements to build - ings which were of a general character and serve the pur - pose of keeping the institution in good repair and prevent </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 21 unnecessary deterioration. No extraordinary appropriation was made nor was any required to keep the buildings and grounds in a satisfactory condition. Nebraska School for the Deaf $73,626.06 was expended at this institution for extra - ordinary purposes, $5,000 of which was appropriated for the purpose of paying a personal claim for injury and the remainder of which was used in the construction and fur - nishing of a new primary building, remodeling and enlarg - ing the power plant, extending the heating and water mains, the building of an ice house and refrigeration plant and general repairs in the way of painting and improving other - wise the buildings already constructed ; also a complete re - wiring of the main building has been made as the old wiring was condemned as unsafe and liable to result in a fire which might destroy the entire building. With the removal of the old and the construction of a new barn, and some re-grading the physical condition of this institution will be placed in a very complete and satisfactory state. Nebraska Home for Dependent Children The sum of $24,567.53 has been expended for the con - struction of a new building near the Orthopedic Hospital and for the purchase of the necessary land, with a view of bring - ing together all of the dependent children until temporary or permanent homes can be found. These now number 80 or more. 'These wards of the State are at present being boarded at the expense of the State in private residences throughout the city and its suburbs. It is believed that when this building is ready for occupancy and the children brought together therein that the new arrangement will greatly facilitate the finding of homes, which is the ulti - mate object of the law for these homeless ones, and will also permit the carrying on of the work and administering of the affairs of the institution much more economically than can be done at the present time. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF INSTITITION CASH FUND We present with this report a detailed and itemized statement of the amounts received in the institution cash funds of the different institutions and deposited in the State Treasury to the credit of such institutions, the amounts expended therefrom and the balance on hand November 30, 1916, the end of the biennial period. These funds accumulate from time to time from different sources in the different institutions and are reported monthly by the sup - erintendents showing in detail from what sources received and the amounts going to make up the total which consists of various items of many different characters but which in the main represent the proceeds of the sales of farm prod- Ei, live stock, old and discarded machinery and supplies other property of no further use to the institution, h funds are, after being so reported, immediately de - posited in the Treasury to the credit of the institution pro- King them and for its benefit in the general support and ntenance and carrying on of the work generally and for which no specific provisions have been made by an appro - priation by the Legislature There are also included some other sources of revenue hereafter specifically adverted to. From the attached report it will be observed that the total receipts for the biennial period from all sources belonging to the cash funds of the different institutions amount to the sum of $258,565.25, and that the total expenditures for the same period amount to the sum of $130,710.06, leaving a total balance on hand to the credit of these different insti - tutions November 30, 1916, of $149,069.44. In addition to the sources from which these funds are received as above noted, it should be stated that of the in - stitution cash fund received by the Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth, a large amount thereof, as shown by the table presented herewith, was received under the provisions of the law from the different counties from which the inmates were committed to that institution, and from the relatives of such inmates who are legally chargeable, and which are paid in for the purpose of supplying such in - mates with clothing and which is denominated a ''Clothing </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 23 Fund." Under the law the counties or individuals properly chargeable are required to pay annually for each individual the sum of $40 or such a part thereof as may be necessary to supply such inmate with clothing, the State thus being relieved of that portion of the expense necessary in the maintenance of the inmates at that institution ; and, while heretofore this fund has been under the control of the au - thorities of the institution and purchases from time to time made as needed and separate from the general business of maintaining- the institution out of the appropriations made by the Legislature, this board on May 1, 1916, adopted a policy of having this fund deposited to the credit of the institution cash fund and denominated a "Clothing Ac - count" and the purchase of clothing for the inmates placed upon the same basis as like purchases for all of the other institutions, the payment therefor being made out of this identical fund and not otherwise. While the method of do - ing the business has been thus changed and modified to the advantage, we think, of the inmates of the institution and while under the present rule every item of expenditure for this as well as all other purposes is required to be drawn from the State Treasury on properly executed and verified vouchers fully itemizing the nature of the purchase and the amount of the same, it still leaves the situation as it has heretofore existed in that in making up our estimates for the necessary sums for the maintenance of this institution no account has been taken of the amount required to pur - chase the clothing needed by the inmates, this being pro - vided for as above stated and thus reducing to that extent what would otherwise be necessary to be included in the general appropriation for maintenance. Also with reference to the three hospitals for \he in - sane there is collected and paid into the respective institu - tion cash funds from relatives and friends and thode leg - ally chargeable under the law passed by the last Legislature, being Chapter 134 of the Session Laws of 1915, mainte - nance charges for such inmates as have the means to pay the same or whose relatives who are legally liable for the support and maintenance of such inmates possess 9uch </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF means ; and also as to the hospital for the insane at Lincoln the collections made pursuant to Section 7288 of the Revised Statute of Nebraska called "Receipts for the Care of Dipso - maniacs." While these laws have not been in force for a sufficient length of time to estimate with a reasonable de - gree of certainty what would be the probable income annu - ally on account of collections from maintenance and for the care of dipsomaniacs, a careful and conservative estimate leads us to believe that we can safely count upon at least $60,000 for the coming biennial period which, to that ex - tent, reduces the necessity for that amount of approQria - tions for maintenance generally. We have accordingly in our estimated expenditures for these three institutions for the coming biennium reduced the total sums, which seemed to be necessary, by the following amounts: For the Ingle - side Hospital for the Insane, $30,000; for the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane at Lincoln, $20,000; and for the Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska at Norfolk, $10,000; or a total of $60,000 for the three institutions. It is also to be observed that with reference to the in - stitution cash fund of the State Penitentiary there is paid therein besides the funds derived from the ordinary sources the proceeds of the labor of the inmates of that institution where they can be put to profitable employment, a portion of which goes to the permanent benefit of the State in re - ducing expenditures generally and a portion to the individ - ual, whose labor resulted in the receipt of the money, for the support of those dependent upon him or to create a fund for his benefit held by the Warden as trustee and fixed by rule of this Board to be paid under the provisions of the law after the time of the expiration of fiis term of service to the State., There is also included in this fund the proceeds of the sale of all of the manufactured materials produced by the Handcraft Furniture Company and sold to the trade generally, amounting in the aggregate on November 30, 1916, to $46,802.56, and in this connection it is to be said that, while all of the proceeds of the sale of the output of the business carried on at that institution under the name of the Handcraft Furniture Company is deposited in the </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 25 State Penitentiary institution cash fund, when so deposited it is immediately resorted to and used for the payment of the running expenses of that industry including salaries and wages of employees, a percentage paid to the inmates who are employed therein, and for the purchase of raw material out of which are manufactured the articles produced and sold, and for machinery and supplies of all kinds necessary in carrying on the business so that, as to this fund so de - posited in the institution cash fund, it really and in fact constitutes a working capital and is used as occasion re - quires for carrying on the business generally connected with that industry. For a detailed and itemized statement of all of the re - ceipts of all kinds including the appropriations made by the Legislature and all of the expenditures of every description and which have been heretofore referred to in a general way, we refer to the tabulated statements hereto attached consisting of several different tables which by study and comparison will disclose very fully the financial workings and conditions of the several institutions mentioned therein. INCREASED COST OF SUPPLIES At the very threshold of the biennium just passed the Board was confronted with the increasing cost of the ■sup - plies and materials required to be purchased by it in the prosecution of the business connected with the management of the several institutions under its control. Later on this tendency toward higher prices grew at an astonishingly rapid rate and it soon became apparent that the total outlay compelled to be made for the support and maintenance of the institutions, if such prices continued, would be in a very appreciably larger sum than that which has heretofore been required ; in fact, when in many instances the Board was met with quotations -fifty to one hundred per cent higher than it had been paying in some instances, in amounts that were really prohibitive, the members felt quite apprehen - sive of their ability to get through the biennial period with - out creating in the aggregate a very substantial deficiency. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 26 To meet this extraordinary situation the Board adopted a policy of substituting lower priced articles where it was be - lieved it could get substantially the same service or benefit, and refraining as far as possible from the purchase of larger quantities than absolutely necessary of the more costly sup - plies and altogether wherever possible. Upon the whole we are glad to note that even though we have been com - pelled to pay much higher prices than what would be re - garded as normal, yet we will, we think, be able to get through the biennial period with a substantial margin yet remaining to the credit of the State as to the aggregate of all appropriations and other receipts, and all expenditures required to be made. It is quite true that as to four of the different State institutions deficits will appear but in no in - stance in a very large or unusual sum; in fact, the total of these deficits for the biennial period will fall far snort of those we had to contend with two years ago. It is also interesting to observe that where these deficits have oc - curred they are generally at institutions where opportuni - ties and facilities for raising produce and foodstuffs for the benefit of such institutions are altogether absent or in exist - ence only in a small degree; while at the other institutions where we have been enabled to employ the inmate labor in farm and garden operations, in caring for livestock, keeping up dairy herds, etc., we are enabled to get through the bien - nium without deficits which otherwise would undoubtedly FARMING OPERATIONS At all of the institutions where the inmates are able to labor to a greater or less degree much of such work is utilized in the raising of farm and garden produce and other articles for food and forage consumed at the institution, and with, a view of obtaining the best results it has been the policy of the Board to encourage in every way within its means the careful, intelligent and scientific use of methods and labor to the end that the largest possible output be made of those things so useful and common in the support of the institutions, and thereby in a large measure avoiding </seg>
            <seg id="p027">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 27 the necessity of buying the same supplies in the open mar - ket. Two years ago the Legislature made provision for the purchase of additional farm lands for the Nebraska Institu - tion for Feeble-Minded Youth, the Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska at Norfolk, and in a smaller way at the Hos - pital for Tuberculous at Kearney. All of these investments, we are confident, have proven profitable to the State and have been the means of enabling these institutions — and especially the two first named — to increase the production of farm and garden to a very appreciable extent. At the other institutions, notably the industrial school for boys, the hospitals for the insane at Lincoln and Ingle - side, the penitentiary, and the home for soldiers and sailors at Burkett, farming operations, the caring for dairy herds and the feeding of live stock, especially hogs, have all been engaged in on a large scale and have been the means of bringing in large returns to these several institutions, far more than paying the costs of the operation of such indus - tries. Over and above this the employment of the inmates in the manner now under consideration is believed to be more healthful, wholesome and beneficial than almost any other way in which their labor can be utilized. Farm lands are growing dearer in Nebraska from year to year and it is hardly to be hoped that the State will ever be able to purchase farm lands adjacent to these institutions for any less than will now have to be paid and the prob - abilities all are for increasing prices as time goes on. At the penitentiary especially is there pressing necessity for additional farm land on which the inmates of that institu - tion can be profitably and beneficially employed. We have been compelled, in order to carry on these farming opera - tions in a small way, considering the labor at our command, to rent high priced land and for which a high cash rent is required to be paid, and sometimes a share of the crop or a crop rent which yields to the owner as high as $20 to $30 an acre as rent for the land thus used by the State. With the view of improving conditions at that institution in this respect, the Board found itself enabled to secure an option on a good piece of farm land convenient to the penitentiary </seg>
            <seg id="p028">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 28 at a very reasonable figure and by the payment only of a nominal sum, viz., $100, for such option which will expire April 1st, next. There are in this tract of land 120 acres ; the same is in a good state of cultivation and can be secured for the sum of $20,000, and we have recommended in our estimate an appropriation with a view of obtaining title to such land for the benefit of this institution. I Notwithstanding the acreage owned at the Hospital for Insane of Nebraska at Norfolk and that acquired two irs ago, that institution in order to put to useful purpose : labor of the inmates, is required annually to rent farm - ; land convenient to the institution and for which in many tances a very high rental is paid especially where a share the crop is received by the owner. On one piece of land, •ecially well adapted to the purpose, a large acreage of :atoes was planted and cultivated by the institution, the ner receiving a share as rent, the result being that with I extraordinarily good yield and the high price of this pie article, the state could have applied a very substan- I payment on the price of the land out of the proceeds the crop which it delivered as the owner's share for rent. tThe Ingleside Hospital for the Insane can also utilize dvantage additional farm lands and some steps were n by the last Legislature looking to that end but this not result in any appropriation for that purpose. tAs to - both of these institutions, we are not in a posi - to recommend specifically the purchase of any partic - tract of land and yet, should we find an opportunity ng the sitting of the Legislature, we would feel it in - bent upon us to call to its attention the desirability of purchase of any such lands that may be found conven - ly situated and offered at a reasonable price. In the reports of the superintendents of the different institutions will be found a resume of the products of the farm and garden, stock raising, dairy farms, etc., the aggre - gate of which amounts to a surprising figure, and we espe - cially call attention to these reports, disclosing^as they do, the work accomplished along these lines. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 29 PENITENTIARY FURNITURE INDUSTRY On the 24th of May, 1915, the Legislature having pre - viously made provisions therefor, the Board acquired the business, property and good-will of the Handcraft Furni - ture Company which had been carried on in this institution by a private corporation for several years and in the opera - tion of which the labor of a portion of the inmates of the penitentiary was utilized in the manufacture of the product put upon the market by this company. The consideration paid for all of the property thus acquired including machin - ery, equipment, raw material and the manufactured articles on hand amounted to the sum of $21,043.75. The amount paid in acquiring this plant was more than one-half less than the amount asked for at the beginning of the negotia - tions for the purchase of the same. In obtaining the business the Board proceeded to take a full and complete inventory and after ascertaining as well as it could the fair value of all of such property, proposed to acquire the same from the company then owning it by the payment of the amount thus found to be its value which was finally accepted and the property turned over to the State. After the acquisition of the property many changes were made, some much needed machinery and equipment acquired, facilities for operating the business improved and the work since carried on by the State for its own benefit has gradually grown in proportions and volume until the present time. The principal part of the business thus carried on is the manufacture and sale of furniture of many kinds, con - structed chiefly by the use of reed and fibre which is ob - tained in the market as needed and at prices as advanta - geous as can be found. At the beginning there were employed in this depart - ment the first month of its operation 52 men which number has gradually increased until the month of November, 1916, shows the employment of 115 men who are inmates of the penitentiary, and in addition to the number mentioned there are an average of 15 apprentices per month who do not appear upon the pay-roll. The men are paid a small stipend </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF for the work performed by them which is used for the support of those dependent upon them or is saved as a fund for their own benefit when they are discharged from the institution. The total sum thus paid to the inmates working in this department to November 30, 1916, or for a period of eighteen months, aggregated $5,659.68. In addition to the amount thus paid the men in the employ of the State who are inmates of the penitentiary, there is a pay-roll made up of a general manager, a book-lreeper and three foremen of the three different departments, amounting to the sum of $525.00 per month, and all of which has been paid out of the earnings of the business. Manufacturing conditions for twelve months and more havo been unfavorable and difficult by reason of the con - stant advance of nearly all of the raw materials used in the manufacture of the output of the plant. In fact these ad - vances have been so marked and persistent that selling prices have had to be correspondingly advanced by an in - crease of 10 r /r on two different occasions, the last of which, however, not taking effect until January 1, 1917. tThe products of the department are shipped into ;een various states but particularly into the states of ■aska, Iowa, Illinois, Kansas, Colorado, Missouri, Okla - i and Texas. A special effort has been made not only to prosecute the work diligently and promptly meet all demands for the pur - chase of the output of the department, but also to give espe - cial attention to the quality of the article produced in order that merit and quality shall be leading features in the dis - posal of the manufactured article to the public generally. tThe wages paid to the men thus employed have helped tly to bring about a satisfied condition and to encourage ough work of the best quality and to make them satis - and contented. A complete inventory taken during the month of No - vember discloses that the State has on hand at the present time in this department property in the way of equipment, office supplies, supplies generally in the way of raw material and finished stock, of the value of $38,447.69. It is also </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 31 disclosed by the report of the general manager that for the period of eighteen months during which this department has been operated by the State and after paying all expenses of operation as above narrated, there was a net gain in the business of $10,071.74. The showing of the work thus done and under the circumstances, is regarded as reasonably satisfactory and it is believed that so long as the State may go into the market generally in order to dispose of its pro - duct that the business can be carried on, furnishing em - ployment for 175 to 200 of the inmates of the penitentiary at a profit; that the employment will be beneficial to the inmates by reason of the character of the same and that it is found agreeable and pleasant and of such a nature as that by applying oneself diligently the necessary skill to perform the work satisfactorily may be obtained by an apprenticeship of from 15 to 30 days. It is also found that many become very proficient in the work assigned to them and to such there is paid in accordance with the graduated scale adopted by the Board a larger wage than that paid to the beginners or those showing only ordinary skill and ability in the work in which they are engaged. In connection with the reed and fibre department there is carried on a hard wood department employing only a few men and engaged particularly in making chairs, tables, cabinets, etc., which may be used in the other institutions of the State. No attempt has been made to manufacture furni - ture in this department to be placed on the market gener - ally. It furnishes employment to those who are especially skilled in cabinet and hard wood work. In determining the amount that should be paid by the institution receiving the benefit of work of this department, the Board has endeav - ored to fix a price at about the same figure it would be com - pelled to pay were it to purchase, as it does other like sup - plies, from wholesalers and jobbers. The operation of this department shows a loss of $944.22 but it is to be noted in this connection that, while this is the loss as shown by the books, yet the State has found useful and profitable employ - ment for a few who were especially well equipped and has expended a considerable sum for machinery and equipment, </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 and that the institutions receiving the output have been benefitted to the extent shown by the books to be a loss in its operation. REFORMATORY I The Legislature of 1913 provided for the establishment a reformatory for first offenders and appropriated 0,000 therefor. During the period which intervened be - en the organization of this Board on July 1, 1913, and assembling of the Legislature in January,1915, members ;he Board had visited a large number of proposed sites had secured necessary information preliminary to locat - the institution, but had not in fact selected a location. i Board therefore reported to the Legislature its doings this behalf and recommended that the said sum of 0,000 be re-appropriated and that $50,000 additional be ropriated for equipping and maintaining the institution, s Legislature, however, thought best not to follow this jmmendation and the original appropriation meantime *ed. The State is, therefore, still without a reformatory. I It is understood that the Legislature which will as - ble in January, 1917, will be asked to provide for the blishment of one or more State custodial farms for the &gt; of mis-demeanants. Such a measure meets with our lial approval. The weakest and least creditable of all machinery connected with the administration of justice le prevalent system of jails and lock-ups. It is an iilogi - and pernicious survival from the dim past and should ! way to a more rational and constructive method. Such an institution as is proposed will help to solve the problem of the dipsomaniac and will relieve the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane at Lincoln, from the custody of such alcoholic and drug addicts as have no desire to secure relief from bad habits and need disciplinary no less than hospital tWe suggest that in the establishment of such a custodial i provision be made for the admission thereto both by mitment and by transfer of such persons as would be </seg>
            <seg id="p033">65 rT KKPORT AND I&gt;KT All.KI) STATEMENT OF KSTIMATKI) APPIO- I-KI \TIO\s FOK THE RIKNMI M BEGINNING APRIL 1, 1K17. AND ENDING MARCH 31. 1*19 KKCAIMTILATION— (Continued) If— Nebraska School for the Blind. Nebraska City, Nebraska: Estimated ordinary expenditure _ _ i 54000.00 Total - I 5CMuW N— Hospital for the Insane or Nebraska, Norfolk, Nebraska: Estimated ordinary expenditure $241000.00 Estimated extraordinary expenditure _ _ _ _ 117000.00 $i&gt;«ooo.on Total _ flX«W.0O P— Nebraska School for the IK-uf, Omaha. Nebraska: K-tiuiHt.-.l oriliuary expenditure 1117900.00 Kxtimateil extraordinary expenditure 0000.00 Tottl 1 1 "HOt. 00 8— Nebraska Home for Dependent Children. Lincoln, Nebraska: Estimaneri ordinary riiienditure _ _ 4 4«SO0.O0 Kstimated extraordinary ex|&gt;eiidltiire „ _ 2500.00 Total exiimaieil ordinary expenditure)) 12356770.00 Total estimated extraordinary expenditures 154800.00 Crawl Total _ .-- «3MOO7O.0O Total estimated expenditnre. for the Board of Comml. - ■toncri* «'f Stult* Instit n tit'ii^ _„ ( 444*m).0u </seg>
            <seg id="p034">FINANCIAL TABLES SHOWING Statement of Expenditures from Legislative Appropriations Analysis of Balances in Appropriations Made by the 33rd Session of the Legislature Statement of Cash Receipts Credited to the Institution Cash Funds, Disbursements Therefrom, and Balances Therein Statement of Daily Average Inmate Population Explanatory Outline of Distribution Statement of Expenditures Comparative Distribution Statement of Annual Expenditures for Mainten - ance Only (Institutions Only) Comparative Distribution Statement of Annual Expenditures for the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions and the Nebraska Commission for the Blind Distribution Statement of Biennial Expenditures for all Purposes (In - stitutions Only) Per Capita Biennial Maintenance Expenditure (Institutions Only) Per Capita Annual Maintenance Expenditure (Institutions Only) Per Capita Monthly Maintenance Expenditure (Institutions only) </seg>
            <seg id="p035">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 67 KTATtXKM Or K\rKM&gt;lllKKS I KllM LEGISLATIVE APPROPRIATIONS NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR KEEBLE-MIXDKD VOUTII, Beatrice, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1016 Expend- Amount Kxpmd'd fd De«\ Total Ex- Balance &gt;. \ppr ti&gt; 1. "14, to ix'tulfil tii of Appro- Name of Appropriation Thirty -third SeasiM, 1»1J — S;ii:ll\v lit' supf I'llltf lltlflll Salary of steward UU * :sl-.».:k x HM1.M x .-•iwimw $ 11WU.U0 .T0O.00 J4W.00 LMOIMIM Salaries of teachers Salary of chaplain Wages of employees Maintenance ia«»i.i» Jim.Ki ao.ou 5.oo '.o.tw lifi.ou .37 3*70.80 dUI General repairs Dairy ■£M*)M 2-Mtl.Ttl MUO.'Jl -'4U97.4N Ml iuwm«i lmm.ool ltioo.uo Constructing sewer 3000.UI 80M.M Misrellaueous apprupiia - tions to specific claimants, account of deflriencjr In M1-bVH iip)iro|iri:itt&lt; us Iiistitiition cash Total.. Thirty-fourth sm.l.n, I»I5— Current exiM'iise. II. K. 7"»1 New buildlnfrs and improve- $I.VkI:».II&gt; *ll»»iV..;tl *1I«.&lt;«K.»1 t V.744.O* ment«, H. R. 6»K. Lauil. H. K. Mft 4S00U.U0 4O155.2S i 4O155.23 7M4.77 •JOIIO.OO 9600.00 9WO.0O •Ioue Storey, H. R. 199. •Dorothy C Falk, II. R •O. D. Langley, II. R. 7: Institution cash 731.00 ! 731.00 731.00 ublw uiuio lao.oo »2.oa i3i'.uo jxi.oo 19423.49 | (B77.76 6577.76 12845.73 Totnls •Not rx|M'inle«l l»y Ittiiinl of ('•aimlmioam of stjit** laalllBtto— . |.ri»ti,m lHH-.l.Hj Ile&lt;-.l.'l&lt;l Ikr.l.'ltt priatlou 4S3&amp;.79 1M125 r«K.(H 7.M 30OUIUJ0 LTaW.lU 7-.T7.3T :(*7G.t» h»»JU.UII H8LT4.U7 MiaUi HS8W.0B xsta» SKM&amp;a 1 :uaiu.-A umM .i»a;iu aio.47 29W.S7 m*M IMUHM $1040CS.M f 3121S.93 $VKO2l.&gt;» * SO34.15 tmaafc* nrmiM « ittuti.uo % smmm </seg>
            <seg id="p036">68 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES FROM LEGISLATIVE APPROPRIATIONS GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. Geneva, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1. MM Name of Approprimioii of Apiir. to 1. 14. to pended to of Appro- Thlrty-ltaird ScraUn. 1»1S— Salary of superintendent * 3000.00 * 2375.00 * 62.Y00 * 3000.00 * 8«l«r.T of matron _ 1000.00 Salary of matron __ : 1000.00 780.96 300.00 989.9C ia04 780.96 200.00 989.9C ia04 Salaries of three f.imil.v Salaries at tbrw family manawrs 36U0.0U maiiHicfis '. 38W.0U -■OSM.tH 775.00 34W.64 130.36 J694.tH TT5.00 34W.64 130.36 Wages of employees 7900.00 Wages of employees I 7900.00 5730.1$ 1789.75 7499.93 .07 5730.1S 1799.75 7499.93 .07 Maintenance 27000.00 Maintenance 27000.00 26W8.4S 1.50 26896.98 .02 3973.37 26.81 3869.98 .02 •000.00 9000.00 I MM 1.50 28900.98 .02 General repairs 4000.00 General repairs 4000.00 Land _... 0000.0(1 Land 6000.00 New building 5000O.00 New building 50000.00 32202.U0 17797.4(1 50000.00 Miscellaneous appropria - tions to fpi'ciflc claimants. avaWM "f deficiency in 1811-1913 appropriations ... 11143.62 Miscellaneous appropria - tions to specific claimants, -H-4-oui-t of deficiency in 1911-1913 appropriations ... 11143.82 11143.02 11143.82 11143.82 _ 11143.82 Eatimated deficiency in 1911 - 1913 appropriations 1200.00 Estimated deficiency in 1911 - 1913 appropriations 1200.011 1190.97 1199.97 .08 1199.!I7 1199.97 .08 Transferred from "Miscel - laneous Expenditures." Board of Commissioners &lt;&gt;r state Institutions ap - propriation for mainte - nance use 8792.71 Transferred from "Miscel - laneous Expenditures." Board of Commissioners of state Institutions ap - propriation for mainte- nance use - ! S792.71 0925.56 1867.15 8792.71 8925.56 1867.15 S7S2.71 Institution cash — i 2272.42 Institution casli ', 2272.42 1205.04 375.57 158(1.61 691.81 1205.04 375.57 1580.61 891.81 Totals - i $126508.75 Totals - $126508.75 *101 238.42 » 23437.98 H24876.40 » 832.35 I10123S.42 I 23437.98 $124876.40 ; f 832.35 Thirtj-fourth Sniltii, 1»15— Thirt j -fourth S«»l»n, Ml*— Current expenses, II. K. 7T.1 $ SB4O.00 Current expenses, II. K. Mill »t540.0fi * f 51746.90 f 51746.90 ' $ 779.1.10 * f 51746.90 f 51746.90 ' $ 779.1.10 Sewage disposal plant and laundry equipment, H. R Sewage disposal plant and laundry equipment, H. R 088 _ ! 5500.00 688 5500.00 5484.75 5484.75 5484.75 5484.75 15.25 15.25 Estimated deficiency, H. R. ! 000 I 7124.00 Estimated deficiency, H. R. 660 7124.00 7M&amp;21 7108.21 16.70 7W&amp;21 7108.21 16 TO 728.54 T»M 1782.24 Institution cash _ 2510.78 1782.24 Institution cash _ 2510.78 728.54 73S.54 ________^_ _ | ( 85068.40 $ 65(168.40 t 960B.38 Totals * 74874.7R Totals f 74674.78 * 85068.40 * 65&lt;I6S.4O t U60R.38 Expend- Amount Kxpend'd imI Dec. Total Ex- Balance priation Deo.l.'14 Dec.l,'l« , Dw.1.16 iirlatiou </seg>
            <seg id="p037">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 69 I »l \THMKNT OF EXPENDITURES FKOM I.E&lt;ilSI.ATl V K AI&gt;PKUPRIATIO» STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, Kearney, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1. 1916 Expend- Amount Expend'd , ed Deo. ToUl Ex- Balance peml'd ed Dec. Total Ex - to 1, '14, to pended to Name of Appropriation of Appro- to 1. '14, to pended to of Appro priation Der.1,'14 Dec.l.'K Dcr.l.'lS prlatiou w.l. 14 Dccl.'K Dec.1/16 Thlrt&gt; -third ItHlH, 111*— Salary of superintendent _ Salary of assistant superin- 28SO.O0 * 7B0.00 I 3000.00 f .-wuu.uu * ■M * 780.00 I 3000.00 , tendent 3».(IP 1741.IH . 4.&gt;.:«J -'jm.UM Salary of steward Salary of cbaplain Salary of physician Salary of matron Wanes of employees Purchase of land ... Maintenance UWO.(I) iitw.Chj £«.:»; imiu.ix: MJI ao.00 358LS0 9oa.ni JSO.UO lajo.uo 450.00 12S.0O 575.00 IS0O.0O 241.50 12(10.00 H6u.no jso.uo 1200.00 OUU.00 32000.00 24944.27 0B50.14 318B4.41 106.59 14944.27 OB50.14 318B4.41 «»»»l.00 MH.1I j 1- 38B8e.T» I 10US.21 MM.TB 1- 38W8.79 *WI.» «ff7.5S 5WW.44 um»»i.i»&gt; 538O1.W (UW7.56 9MW.44 X Permanent anil general re pairs V. im.i jittkm.HK 5NH5.3O .rV4&gt;6.1« 1951S.S4 r.x»»&gt;.&gt;* .-.ss.-,..i() ,rv4&gt;6.1« MMI , 4M.51 1043.72 Equipping and running trade department 3500.00 M9.21 , 494.51 1043.72 145C28 Machinery and farm equip - ment 20UM«&gt; W4.9O 535.30 920.80 lir7V.2O W4.9O S3S.90 920.80 Band instruments limo.oo wb.81 -.tr.4.-. '.M.oa ;.-. m '.MICt.KI •-11.4.*. '.C4.0B MiscellniuMtus appropria - tiouh to specific claimants. account of deficiency In 1911-1913 appropriations.-. .13302.42 333B2.42 333K.42 , S3S2.42 33302.42 isiu-j ;:: 6763.48 7O66.JH 14469.29 Institution cash Totals t25t.-m.7f&gt; |lfl»«1.21 * 2B786.38 $22»*47.» $ 276H7.1H Thirty-fourth sm.i.n. 1»1»— Current expenses. H. K. 751 Estimated deficiency, H. R. $117720.00 _. f M1S4.82 I 94KM.82 f T— T.IB M 5720.00 4545.10 4645.10 1174.40 Institution cash 2O16&amp;96 I 4808.80 4808.00 1535O38 tl433S8.9e »10«.-,ls.3? »10851SA; $ +OIB0.4« Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p038">70 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES FROM LEGISLATIVE APPROPRIATION.* NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, Burkett. Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1U14S December 1, 1914, to December 1, lUlti Expend- Expend- , Amount Kxpend'd : ed Dec. Total Ex- Balance Amount Kxpend'd ed Dec. Total Ex- Balance Name of Appn piiiiii. i or Appro- I to | 1, '14, to pended to ofAppro- Name of A|i|&gt;n pi i:iii' &lt;■ or Appro- to 1, '14, to pended to of Appro- ' priation Dec.1,'14 Dec.l.'16 Dec.1,'16 prlation priatioD Dec.1,'14 Dec.1,'16 Dec.1,'16 prlation Thirty -third Scion, IMS— Salary of ciiuiinaiidaht t :WU)).U) * 3»7.-&gt;.(W i * UiVi.iX) S raJOO.OO $ Salary of adjutaut 1800.00 1312.50 U1.07 1-KB.57 390.4.1 Salary of surgeon 3400.00 1UOO.0O 500.00 2400.00 ' Salary of matron 1000.00 756.97 -JO&amp;M 9tB.31 34.86 Salary of engineer * 1«W.UO ] 435.00 365.00 1800.00 I Salary of night cnginiH-r.. la moo Salary of farm manager 12UO.00 !»75.00 LSK.OO 1200.00 . 1H5.(» aso.oo 1195.00 i 5,00 Salary of bookkeeper and KteuoKrapber ' 9U0.00 786.00 19&amp;.00 900.00 Service* of chaplain 000.00 386.00 100.00 485.00 115.00 Waves of employees - ' 30000.00 wumM 110902.25 14308.91 2086.00 M M .64 Maintenance 125000.00 14397.O4 V1V.W -.• .71 (ieneral repairs - 15000.00 Q&amp;2JX 149»e.lU .^1 Building and equipping new laundry 3000.00 iWT.flT 2S12.33 3000.00 , Miwrellaneous appropria - lioiis to specific claimants, account nf dettcipiM-y in 1911-1»13 appropriations 23».4B IT!', i. 4'.' 3BB3.64 •j:w.4it Institution caah 8001.73 3S71.» 7763.92 837.81 Totals ! *195801.2-.&gt; I18T911.79 * 264»8.34 $194410.13 $ 1391.09 Thirty-fourth SmUn, 1I1C — t-urrent expeimes, H. R. 751 «2130L&gt;0.00 $136440.47 $156440.47 $ 56579.53 4834.20 3165.80 Sew buildings and Improve - ments, H. R. 6«7..._ 8000.00 4SM.20 Estimated deficiency, H. R. IM0 ' 25743.00 22257.01 12(12.43 22257.61 34S5.39 Itistitiitlmi cash 11727.23 1202.43 10624.80 *1S47.!4.71 * 7.t7.V,..-c' *1K4734.71 Totals _ $2tW490.2n </seg>
            <seg id="p039">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 71 STATEMENT OF EXPENDITI Ht:&gt; FROM LEGISLATIVE API-KIIPRI A I Inv - SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS HOME, Mllford, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Expend- Amount F.xpendd ed Dec. Total Kx- Halance Name of Appropriation to 1, '14, to pended to of Appro- \ i priation Dec.1,'14 Dec.l.'lS Dec.1,'16 priatlon Thirtr -third SCMira. IMS— Salary of commandant _... ! * anxi.U) * l.W&amp;Xi * 416.0H t -JOOO.OU $.. Salary of surgeon 100(1.01) 791.68 308.32 1000.00 Salary of engineer 1680.00 MU0 310.00 1273.00 406.00 Salary of matron JWO.OU 715.00 186.00 MM Wages of employees 10330.00 8818.71 1*75.25 CTIMt 1U104 Salaries of nurses and chap- lain „ _.. 2400.00 14.14.00 391.00 1820.00 BT6.00 Maintenance 48000.00 MMK1S 10078.07 44SW.42 M Central repairs I HSno.OO 4282.37 7438.31 11700.68 MM New huildings 25UIO.0O 61ST.31 18812.dD 25000.00 Misi-ellaneoiiK appropria - tions to specific claimants, account of deficiency In 1911-1913 appropriations BT67.86 0787.86 «T«T.» Estimated deficiency in 1911- 1»13 appropriations 0000.00 2804.04 2894.01 3106.98 150.00 54.36 304J5 7M.M Institution cash _. 994.51 Totals »1138«2.3« t 07490.0(1 $ 3B870.27 $107340.30 f WK.0t Thlrtj -foarth S&lt;-..l.n, 1»15— Current expense*, H. R. 751 I 86*0.00 « 50634.44 « 50634.44 I MMtM New buildings and improve - ment*. H. R. «M ! 10000.00 0643.09 0B43.0B UHM Ilistitutloi. ..i»i 187M.4K Totals ■ % 97H8.48 4T7.33 477.33 1J01.15 * 08364.80 $ 03664 80 f 34008.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">72 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATKMKKT OF KXPBMDITCKK8 FKOM LEGISLATIVE APPROPRIATIONS INOLESIDE HOSPITAL FOE THE INSANE. Iipgleside. Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 E i pcnd Amount Kxpend'd ed Dec. Total Ex- i Balance Name of Appropriation of Appro- to 1, '14, to pended to of Appro- priation Dee.1,14 Dec.1,'16 Dec.1,'16 ; priation Thirty-third 8 «»»!»■, 1*11 — Thirty-third 8 «»»»»■, 1111 — * 3068.33 * 1041.67 $ SOUO.OO [l ars.oo aas.oo snou.no 1857.20 825.00 2482.28 517.74 Salary of superintendent. t 90)10.(10 Salary of superintendent. * 90)10.(10 $ 3956.33 * 1041.(17 * 3000.00 * Salary uf assistant physi - cian _ _.. .1000.00 Salary of assistant phyai rtan 3000.00 2375.00 625.00 3000.00 Salary of pathologist 3000.011 Salary of pathologist 3000.00 1857.26 625.00 2482.26 817.74 Salary of second assistant physician 24(10.00 Salary of second assistant physician 2400.00 1900.00 900.00 ; 2400.00 j 1MOU.00 500.00 jjiipiii Salary of third assistant physician . 2000.00 alary of fourth assistant physician 1800.00 alary of steward _.. 3000.00 Salary of third assistant physician __ 2000.00 1583.33 418.67 2000.00 1083.33 416.87 2(100.(10 Salary of fourth assistant physician 1800.00 1425.00 375.00 1800.00 2375.00 628.00 3000.00 '.(0551.19 ' 15448.S1 108000.00 1425.00 375.00 1800.00 Salary of steward _.. 3000.00 2375.00 628.00 30110.00 Wages of employees 10DOUO.OO Wages of employees 10B0U0.00 [aintenance J900HO.OO •J0551.19 ' 15448.81 108000.00 Maintenance 29001 10.00 215749.68 U8M4H.70 284596.38 .X03.62 215749.68 UHH4W.7O 284996.36 j 5403.62 Miscellaneous appropria - tions to specific claimants, account of deficiency In Miscellaneous appropria - tions to specific claimants, account of deficiency In 1911-1913 appropriations-.. 21331.83 1911-1913 appropriations-.. 21.131.83 21331.83 _ ; 21331.88 21331.83 _ 21331.88 Estimated deficiency in 1911- Estimated deficiency in 1911 - 1913 appropriations 26000.00 1913 appropriations 26000.00 17579.40 _ 17579.40 7420.60 175TO.4O _ 17579.40 7420.60 Institution cash 15563.U1 Totals *478OU5.74 Institution cash 15563.91 10771.31 1473.18 12244.49 i 3319.42 10771.31 1473.18 12244.49 3319.42 $371497.33 ! f 89V77.O3 , (461134.36 $ 16081.38 Totals *478OU5.74 $371457.33 $ W977.(IS $461434.36 $ 1A661.38 Thirtj -foorth Hrttlom, IMS — Thirty-fourth *&lt;-«.lo», IMS — ■arrent eiprnwi. H. H. 731 *41«2U&gt;.00 Cnrrent eiprnwa. H. H. 751 $41«2OO.OO $301073.38 $30107:1.38 ♦11.M2I1.62 $301073.38 $3O107:t.38 ; $115126.«2 Sanitary sewer. H. R. 142... -mnhmki Sanitary sewer. H. R. 142... 44X11.00 , _... 4000.00 8415.00 8415.00 amo.(» 20oo.no «7.00 87.00 1087.70 1OS7.7O 450W.S9 A 000.00 Estimated deficiency. H. R Estimated deficiency. H. R. «ao mi.-i.ihi Lucy A. Talbert. H. R. 639 24JO0.0O M. OMeara. H. R. 7S3 , 87.00 nstitution cash 48M7.0B Totals $478749.0B «0 8415.00 M1.-i.iip 8413.00 axio.oo 2000.00 "Lucy A. Talbert. H. R. 639 2000.00 •SI. OMeara. H. R. 753 , 87.00 87.00 67.00 Institution cash 46087.09 1057.70 1067.70 I 45009.39 l$312«13.(« $312613.08 | $164130.01 Totals $4767*9.09 I $312013.(16 $312«13.(p« ] $184136.01 •Not expended by Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 73 STATEMIXT OF EXPENDITURES FROM LEGISLATIVE APPROPRIA TlOXft NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE. Lincoln, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Expend- Amount Expend'd ed Dec. Total Ex- Balance Name of Appropriation I of Appro to 1. 14. to pended to of Appro priatlon Dec.1/14 Dec.1.16 Dec.l.'l* prfation Thirty-third s&lt;-».lon, ltlt — Salary of superintendent Salary of assistant physl * 5000.00 * 3958.33 * 1O41.«; S 5000.00 $ clan 3000.00 30UH.II0 .im.Ki 2375.flO 625.00 3000.001 Salary of pathologist.. Salary of steward _ 2375.00 025.00 3000.00 2375.00 • «er&gt;.oo 3000.00 Salary of second assistant physician _____.. 2+0O.0O MM 500.00 '.'400.00 Salary of bookkeeper Salary of matron isno.o) i4-jr..m 375.01) lMMLW 1200.00 H3O.00 25O.0O 120a00 Services of chaplain. \» ages of employees Maintenance 300.(10 225.00 75.00 300.00 75000.01) 59306.12 15633.86 75000.00 44086.67 170000.00 170000.00 123B14.33 Ueneral repairs 10000.011 !M*.7.«3 512.07 10000.00 Purnitnre and equipment new building 20000.00 6000.00 L1KKI0.00 20000.001 ConstrtK'tlug steam, sewer, etc — ___ — Appropriation Increased, State Treasurer's receipt No. 9556S, Oct. 14. 1H14 tiOU).50 _ 60no.,'i&lt;» .50 J l-:i|iii|i|&gt;inu- hydriatic rooms .... Buildings, repairs and im- .-rfilKI.UI .-■0HH.UI 5000.00 1 proreuients 73000.01' weau.it 5040.24 75000.00 Estimated deficiency In 1911 - 1013 appropriations 1!)1S).OO 1U19.00 1919.00 2K76.VI 11709.14 MM Institution cash 15704.52 **fc\31 Totals ■■■Mi tsmiuo $ 722«tT&gt;.3« *3M378.64 * MM Thin&gt;-fourth ScMtoa, 1115 — Current expenses. II. H T.'.l New building and improve- »2«2OU.U) $228412.53 $228412.53 $ 5*787.47 ments. H. R. 603. Institution cash ... 30000.00 29013.95 29013.H NUt 33925.92 9W55.57 9955.57 2I0VMS Totals I349UB.92 $367382.06 , $3C73K.0B I « 8174S.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">■4 STATKMKXT OF BXFKNDITl RES t'ROM I.K«.1SI.AT1 \ Jfc AITKIIIKII I ln\ - HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA, Norfolk, Nebraska December 1, W14, to December 1. l'Jlti Expend- Amount Kxpend'd ed Dec. Total Bx- Balance Nainc of Appropriation or Appro to ; 1, '14. to peuderi to i of Appro prlationi Dec.1,'14 1 Dec.l','16 Dec.l,16| prUtioll Thirty-third MeaiWa, 1DIS — Salary of superintendent * 50KMKI * UKfeXI * 1041.07 * ftUIO.UO I « 828.(10 WKM.U0 Salary of assistant phyal- .iau - _ :«MMft) Salary of second assistant physician 2400.00 Salary of bookkeeper 1M00.O* 2400.00 1U12.S0 4-7 Vi 24OO.UO 1426.00 375.00 1800.00 l'.IOO.OO 500.00 -J44IO.0O Salary of steward J4IKMJ0 Salary of inperinteiKlent of nursea 1800.00 UiYOO 375.00 18U0.00 nurd's \V«Bei&lt; of eniployif* StOIO.O)) :i?.tKl.»*4 10147.50 4M2S1.34 l«70.«« Maintenance - lUOOOO.OO «6.1tS3.78 3O*W.24 'J6K4.1.02) 3156.HS UepairK. improrements. new buildings, and elevator 14000.00 8471.61 5478.03 13»4t).S4 ! 50.36 Constructing and furnishing 5(04.80 40MB.20 550011.00 new building 55000.00 Side track _ 70(11.00 '.M3.31 4!)73.U) 5908.40 10t3.«0 Institution cash __ j 64«V.83 5785.24 106.60 6291.84 173.99 *137S86.41 *l(H!»:i.l.si «242XW.24 * 634S.9U Totals _ _ — I tumrnm Thlrtj -fourth goaalon, 11)15 — Current expenses, H. R. 751 |18:t700.00 I15863S.27 j *158838.21 I « 251)61.73 Constnwtias and furnishing new baHdlBK. H. R. 44:i .... aiooo.OO 23527.64 23B27.64 36472.36 58S0.O0 5850.00 Land. H. R. 380 5860.00 1793.14 1793.14 14946J2 Institution cash 16739.46 ToUls | $2«*»t.4« «)«8f».»5 : tlHOflOU.O.-. | 1 7I-.4SI.41 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 75 STATEMENT OF BXPKNDITl RKH FROM LKUIH1.ATIVK \ I'HKdl'K I \ I !•&gt;&gt; * HO8PITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS, Kearney, Nebraska December 1. 1»14, to December 1, 1»18 ! Expend - Amount ' Kxpeudd ; ed Dec. ToUl Ex Balance Name of Appropriation of Appro- ti&gt; ' 1. 14, toj pended to , of Appro prlation Dec.l.'14 Dec.1,'16 Dec.l.'M priatlou Thirty-third Mr»lsa. 1*13 — Thirty-third Sniloa, 1*13 — 1360.U0 * 835.00 * 2175.00 t 2B.0O Salary of superintendent $ 3400.00 lseaoo * oas.oo * 2173.00 $ 225.00 jso.00 aoaoo »8o.on Salary of superintendent » 34WMIO Salary of physician 12U0.U) Salary of physician 12UUK&gt; 250.00 WL«i MM Maintenance 32000.(10 Maintenance 3200O.(l&lt;) 26736.76 8204.24 33000.00 2«B.0O 723.00 S8S.00 14.00 _ 3W2O.36 ' 3009O.3C T».O4 «*»U2 «KW.ia hn«.w lcxn.is liwri.'.ut n-.v 26736.76 03M.24 33000.00 Laundry machinery, etc: lOliO.Ud Laumlry machinery, etc: lOHO.Uti JM3.0U 723.UI 888.00 14.00 ■mo. ii ; mmolm t».«4 New iMiildlng and furnishing 40nm).IIU New l.uilding and furnUhing 40nw.UU MiMvllaiienus appropria - tions to specific claimant". account of deficiency In 1911-lUl.t appropriations.... isihi.I" MiMvliaiienus appropria - tions to specific claimants, account of deficiency in l!Ml I'.m:: apprupriaiions .... iMH).U: OltHii.12 WNI.1S IiiKtitmtnn cush 1NI1..".: 1 ToUls . * 85441.84 IiiKtitntldii iiish 1NJ1..".: 1 ToUls . * 85441.84 ISS6.K1 i 1UI7.1S iiltl.'.'.i 107.5-; 3&amp;H&amp;M $ 4S638.78 * 84005.47 &gt; 1438.17 JUmM $ 48BW.7S * 84005.4T * 14M.17 Thlrt&gt; -lo.rth srn.ion, Ills— Thlrt, -fourth Sm.ion, 191.%— &lt;iirrent expeliws, II. U. 751 * -HMOO.OO riirrent exi&gt;eime», II. U. TT&gt;1 * 4»4«&gt;O.I)I&gt; « M046.27 * M048.2T I 11303.73 * :«».:■! » W046.2T $ 11363.73 I-and, H. R. 572. 28U0.1HI Uind. H. R. 572. _. 28UO.UU 2800.00 2800.0* 2808.00 2800L0* New buildings, improve - ments and equipment. H. k. oar. _ 162GO.00 New buildings. Improve- ments and equipment, H. r. aan isjso.uo 1411S.73 14113.73 213&amp;2T 417.K «nM, N8J1 14113.73 14113.73 tUU WtX I 417.82 956.91 Institution cash 1378.73 Institution cash ' 1378.73 Tot«U * «W6.7J * 6M77.82 I* 53377.82 i * 144OM </seg>
            <seg id="p044">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 76 STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES FROM LEGISLATIVE APPROPRIATIONS ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL, Lincoln, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1»1« Expend - Amount Expendd i ed Dec. Total Ex- Balance Name of Appropriation i of Appro- to 1, '14, to : pended to of Appro priation De.-l.14 Dec.l.'l* Deo.1.16 priatirm ■1 Thirty-third 8e»tea. UK- Salary of superintendent. t 3000.00 S attO.OO \t 7.T0.00 * 3000.00 S salary of chief surgeon 4000.00 salary of chief surgeon 4000.00 3166.64 833.36 4000.00 3166.64 ' S33.S6 40110.00 Salary of bead nurse 2200.00 Salary of bead nurae 2200.00 1464.46 ; 375.00 Isat 46 .170.64 1464 46 j 375.00 1820.46 370.54 Salary of first assistant Salary of first assistant nurse ..___.. i 1200.00 nurse rJOO.UO S80.00 200.00 lOKt.dO 120.01) 880.00 200.00 10MMITV 120.00 Salaries of teachers 4800.00 Salaries of teachers 4vm.u&gt; 3636.76 1086.94 4722.70 77.30 3838.76 1086.94 4722.70 77.30 Salaries of pnpil nurses 0000.00 Salary of stenographer 900.00 Salary of matron 900.011 Salaries of pupil nuraes 8000.00 4110.20 1092.15 5202.66 797.35 4110.20 1092.15 5202.86 797.35 Salary of stenographer 900.00 765.00 195.00 U6O.00 765.00 196.00 960.00 Salary of matron ' M0.00 746.00 200.00 O4S.00 15.011 746.00 200.00 046.00 15.011 Emergency 15000.00 Emergency 15000.00 149US.49 14909.4S .51 149W.49 I 14M0.4S .51 Wages of employees 11500.00 Wages of employees 11500.(10 9117.61 2382.S9 11500.00 _ _.. 8117.61 2382.S9 11500.00 Maintenance 38000.00 Maintenance 38000.00 33840.40 4159.14 3T9S0.M .46 33840.40 • 4159.14 37999.54 .46 Alteration and repairs 10000.00 Alteration and repairs lOOtnon 9484.90 515.10 10000.00 9484.90 515.10 10000.00 Hospital supplies 5000.00 Hospital supplies 5000.00 4!lV, fis 38.65 m*.Xi 4.67 mmm 38.an 4f.rM.Xi 4.67 Office expenses 2000.00 Office expenses 2000.00 1566.10 416.73 «*«.« 17.17 1580.10 416.7:i tWSJI 17.17 Paving South street ' 1725.00 Paving South street ' 1725.00 _ 1725.00 1725.00 New building and equipment 45000.00 New building and equipment 45000.00 30872.00 ■ 14128.00 4SO0O.OO _-. - 543.99 I 470.74 1014.73 384.66 :$0872.00 14128.00 45000.00 Institution cash I 13W.3U Institution cash I 1360.3a 543.99 I 470.74 1014.73 384.66 Totals $163344.39 S122W8.23 * 26843.50 *149831.73 « 3612.66 Thln&gt; -fourth Sndon, 1*10— i*urrent expenses, n. K. 751 * !»!*62O.00 - # 89512.22 i $ 8B012.J2 $10107.78 Furnishing new hospital building. H. R. 641 6000.00 ._ — .. 4322.18 4322.18 1077.82 Estimated deficiency, H. R. an 6392.00 _ 6392.00 092.00 .._ Institution cash 1022.44 800.86 880.86 161.58 Totals -. $113054.44 j ,.! $101087.26 $1O1OS7.2« $ 11947.18 10C2.44 800.86 880.86 161.58 Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p045">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 77 STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES FROM LEGISLATIVE APPROPRIATIONS STATE PENITENTIARY. Lincoln, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 1 1 Expend- I Amount Expend'd ed Dec. Total Ex- Balance Name of Appropriation of Appro- A 1. 14. to pended to of Appro prlation DecT,'14 Dec.1,'16 Iter.l.'lS priatlon i Thirty-third Be»Ua, 1*13 — Salary of wanlen * 4CXU.UO f :il«3.«4 * ssxtH » 4UIJO.00 $ Salary of deputy warden 2300.00 1S60.O4 520.95 247O.8» JH II Salary of chief clerk 2400.00 1XT5.00 375.00 2250.00 150.00 Salary of steward 24CM.00 1*00.00 ■ 500.00 3MM0 Salary of physician 24O0.0U 11100.00 j 500.00 2400.00 Salary of deputy chief clerk 1 1 and uaber 1800.00 J75.00 i 375.00 1«M» Salary of chaplain _ 1200.00 750.00 250.00 1000.00 200.00 Salary of matron 1200.00 980.00 250.00 1200.00 Wages of guards and em- I ployew .-Vi'KJO.OO .14492.17 81*6.52 ! 42690.86 UMi.Sl Maintenance - 73740.00 7573»J» 757».» .01 General repairs 120U0.00 S10S.02 , 2780.14 88«8.16 &gt;UUI Office and contingent ex - penses 3000.00 2812.01 21H.1.77 4.22 Buildings. improvements . I and repairs - tiOOOU.OO 55800.37 &lt; 3453.54 .'0262.91 737.08 Constructing and equipping binding twine factory 35000.00 School and reformatory..- 25(10.00 805.50 1000.28 1805.78 SM.2Z 50000.00 Emergency - 5(1000.01) 50000.00 Transferred from "Miscel - laneous Expenditures," Board of Commissioners of State Institutions appro- priation for maintenance ose 12464.BD UO48.24 use 3416.42 2595.08 1 2464X6 Institution cash -_ 19126.08 12308.46 14904.48 4220.55 »8«82«.J4 * 578BS.SB Totals *34+0W8.t» *269»89.43 * MNM Thirty-fourth Session, ltlS— Current expennps. H.' R. 751 *185920.00 ■MU 115901623 I 24MB.T7 7S451.74 mwm Industrial equipment, H. R. »i«l _ — 118000.00, 78451.74 Estimated deficiency, H. R. 660 _ 17640.00 176W.91 Vim*! M 5000.00 9000.00 SHXM 2012.54 •Elizabeth D. Davis, n. R. 91 5000.00 •Sarpy County, H. R. 192__.. 2012.54 -■•ri-'.M •Cornell-Wigman-Searl H. R 753 35.00 : -". .m 35.00 852.70 •W. T. Fenton. H. R. 753 &gt;.52.70 852.70 •H. W. Jchns-Manville Co. H. R. 753 4,\00 i 48.00 48.00 Institution cash — 386B6.95 - MBUI T3384.3* 15311.56 Totals _ HV8204.19 «»SB440.51 $336440.51 18176MB I 4 "Not ex|&gt;ended by Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">♦ 7^ STATEMENT OF KM'KMHTl'KKs KKlIM I.K&lt;iISI.ATI VK APPROPRIATION* NEBRASKA IXDISTUIAL HOME, Milford. Nebraska Iieceiuber 1, 1914, ti&gt; I&gt;e&lt;-einl..&gt;r 1. ■ 1916 _^^ Expend EX|KMI&lt;1- Anuunt Expend'd ed IK&gt;&lt; . ' Total Ex- Halain-e Name of Appropriation oi.Ml 1 " &lt;&lt;• ! 1. '14. t •• pemleil io of Appro- Anunnt Expendil ed Deo. I Total Ex- Haliniv Nime of A|i|&gt;ri:|n'i:iiii'ii m .vQi' &lt; i M I 1. '14. to printed to of Appro- priation Dw.i.'H Dec.1,'16 Itor.l.'ltt prbtiou priation Dec.l.'H I)«.U6 Dw.l.'M iiriatton , ' ; : Thirty-third gestion. itlS— Thirty-third gMilan. 1*13— i Salary of superintendent Salary of mntrnii Salary of superintendent * -JOOO.OO * 1SKS.XI t UUK * MM * * 2U0O.0U UMJi * * MM * -.1KKI.U- I Salary of matrnii _ lOOO.UI TWMKI LOMIO UtW.no lll.Ui uioo.uo Tmt.iMi aon.oo wmm io.wi Salary of pliysiiiuii 1«»&gt;.(»&gt; OttM a»1.97 1400.00, Salary ami teacher and ser - rrtary lOOO.OO T'.U.tXi WtM ]i«».00 ; Salary ami teaihrr and sec retary HKKI.ON Tlll.lW LWi.34 1(100.00 | Salary of hen. I nurse K4O.0U «rj.4&lt;i ITUi 777.8B &lt;P-'.:tl Salary of licnil nurse Salary of wwiim Teacher Salary of farmer _ Salary of mmtm leHc-her HIKlOd «23.:i4 l«6.IKi T'.IO.OII 10.00 HlKMHP (KSt.:i4 KS6.IHi 7110.01) 10.00 Salary of fanner MO.OO B81.J*. 17V1J WO.UJ MO.00 (Ml.Wi 1T8.H (M0.0U Salary of ciifciiift-r Salary of engineer ia0(l.0l&gt; 1223.70 :161.5s 1.1R5.28 , 14.7J 1000.0" 1223.70 .'M1.3H 1W5.28 , M.H Malary of night n reman MtMl fftM MM ltHHT 33.33 Kalary of night flreiimn \l:lillli'li;l in »• MHllitenillire l-OOOROIt 174;!7.lll 25fl2.(t I'.WHB.tt! .37 i;enernl repairs QwMnU repairs rjWO.OI itt-JS.."*.! L'44Vi.7.'. Il!l!t464 5.36 Misifllaneniis appropriiltion to &gt;|w-&lt; itli- claiDiants. ac .ount of (leflcieiicy in 1011 - 1!»13 appropriatious 47."&gt;:; 47..V1 : 47., Institution cash 1O82.7&lt;; 2HO.O0 H18.«l 1018.61 UM Totals $ 42780.29 t 34077.45 , * 7930.40 * 42006.0G * 182.24 Thirty-fourth BcmIsb. 1815— Carrent expenses, II. H. 7-"&gt;l Omtl ttrtlng and equipping t 454flO.l«) ; * 3(634.36 * 3M24.3A ! f 5B25.44 ■l.lrv liarn and silo. II. It. 2SO0.0O i ' 2300.00 Estimated ileflriehry, H. R MO -... 2M4.00 2W4.00 2K44.mi 8W.75 :»!.."&lt;• M.20I TKJB Institution i-aah. Totals * 51712.75 .._ ' $ 42804.76 t 42804.78 $ 8007.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 79 STATEMENT OF EXPKND1TI KKS FROM LKUI8LATIVE APPKOPKIATIO&gt; IS XKBKASKA SCHOOL KOK THE BLIND Nebraska City, Nebraska December 1, 1!&gt;14. to December 1, 1U16 Expeud- Amount Expead'd ed Dec. Tuul Ex- Balance Name of Apipr.ipriaiiini | tt \pprw- t» 1. 14, to peuded to I of Appro primtiou Dec.1,14 Dec.l.'M Dec.1,18 priatimi Thirty-third Snitei, 11113 — Salary of principal - f 3»«M«&gt; * jxjo.uo » 730.00 * aooaoo wan ao.oo ijoo.oo Salary of matron iji«mi&gt; Institution i-ai.li ...._ 461&amp;15 Totals — $ 5671S.15 I l.irli-fnurll, xmIiid, !•!&amp;— Current expenses. H. R. 751 * 49000.00 I 38681.79 * 38681.76 $ 11018.24 Institution cash _ _ 3»2&amp;3» 81.94 M1.94 3844.4S f 3MM.TO S 38M.T0 t 14M2.OB Totals- _ S 5352C3V SnliirieH of teachers rjUMMJU 88M.17 3000.00 11083.17 IMfll Wages of employee* 8500.00 «H».O8 1838.07 xl'-THi OtM MaiiifpiiaiMi- _ MW0U.UO 13144.W SIKM 1W27.52 »T2.46 General repairs IWMlOB I MM.WI 2MSJ* a»42.«8 30B7J4 Institution ca»k ...._ 4B18.15 341&amp;87 734.75 4153.02 444 53 * SHH4.40 * 14SM.S7 $ 540*4.07 * 5*H.0B </seg>
            <seg id="p048">80 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF HTATKMKNT OF EXPENDITURES FROM LKOISI.ATIVK APPROPRIATIONS NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF, Omaha, Nebraska December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1910 Expend - Amount Expend'd ed Deo. Total Ex- Balance Name of ApprupriMiimi or.vppm to ] 1. '14. to paadcd to of Appro- priation Dec.1,'14 Dec.1,'16 Dw.l.'M prliitton Thirt) -third Session, 1»1«— Thirty-third Session. 1»1S— Salary of superintendent t :iauo.(» Salary of superintendent * :tauO.(HI * 2850.00 * 750.00 * 3800.00 111)0.01) 333.32 1533.32 WtM 23254.38 U43O.6S 33885.06 ai4.!H 9582.41 2808.10 12386.51 611.4!) 32219.1" 7780.83 40000.00 5000.00 5000.00 ' 550.90 28.11 578.61 21.30 Salary of matron 1000.00 Salary of matron 1000.00 Salaries of teachers 36000.0U Salaries of teachers 36000.00 Wages of employees 13000.00 Wages of employees 13000.U0 Maintenance 40000.00 Maintenance - 40000.0" Repairs and improvements... 5000.00 Repairs and improvements... 5000.0U Gallaudet students OOO.U) Gallaudet students eoO.OO Erecting new building 600WUHI Erecting new building «0O0(M«l 27315.06 32861. 7T .V.W. IV. 23.37 Power house - 35000.00 Power bonse - 35000.00 24.00 27242.03 ZIMMi 77X!.'J.-, Changes and Improvements.. SOOO.ou Changes and Improvements.. SOOO.on 3878.23 1065.00 4'.K3.73 57.27 3878.23 1065.00 4943.73 57.27 Emergency _ 4200.00 4200.00 | ! 4200.00 4200.00 : 4200.00 Emergency 4200.00 Transferred from "Miscel - laneous Expenditures," Board of Commissioners of B 8tate Institutions appro prlation for maintenance use _ 38.S0 Transferred from "Miscel - laneous Expenditures," Board of Commissioners of B 8tate Institutions appro prlation for maintenance use _ 38.S0 36.30 36.80 30.*) .. 30.80 use Institution cash _ 2772.90 Totals $205809.76 Institution cash _ 2772.90 1231.64 1284.44 2516.08 296.88 12.-U.et 1284.44 2516.08 256.88 $111305.39 * 83419.40 I $im724.T"J * 110*4.97 III I Mi ■ * S1419.40 IV.H724.7y * 11084.97 Totals $205809.7* Tklrty-f mirth Session, IMS- Current expenses, H. R. 751 *10«iiio.(i&lt;&gt; _. $ 8414«..t2 % 84146.32 % 21!Ht!.«s 3103.19 3193.1!" S08.S1 $ S41«.:e $ fM146.:C $ HMLM Grading grounds and fur- Grading grounds and fur - nishing new primary buildtntr. H. K. 68B 4000.01) nishing new primary ' buildlnc. H. R. «f» 4O0O1M1 3193.19 3193.19 S06.S1 Estimated deflciencv. H. R. Estimated deficiency. H. R. aao _ '.»4«.on - 041.51 W1..M 4.49 i 5000.00 5i«0.00 2804.17 2804.17 1136.95 mir.i i'4i..-.i 4.49 660 - ' 94«.m •Cassle Dyer. H. R. 242 _ 6000.00 •Cassle Dyer. H. K. 242 _ 5(100.00 5000.00 5000.00 Institution cash ■ 3941.12 Institution cash ■ 3W1.12 2804.17 : 2804.1T 1136.95 Totals ! I11M87.12 I * M085.10 $96086.1* $ 23.S51.93 $ 98085.19 $ 96085.W $ 23S31.93 Totals I $119987.12 •Not expended by Board of Commissioners of State Institutions </seg>
            <seg id="p049">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 81 STATEMENT OF Y. \ I'KMiI II K K- I KoM I Hl.lsl ATIVK A 1IROIR1ATION H XKBRASKA HOME FOIt DEPENDENT CHILDREN Lincoln, Nebraska Keceuilwr 1, 1!»14, to December 1. 1»16 Expend- Amount Expend'd ed Dec. ToUl Be- Ralance Name of Appropriation ofA»|&gt;r. to 1. 14. to printed to of Appro ■ prlation Dec.1,14 I&gt;ec.l.l« Itw.1,16 priation Thirl.t -third &gt;&lt;-..lon, 1»IJ_ Salary of placing oat agent Salary of assistant agent... Salary of second assistant.... % 3000.00 * 2375.011 * B25.00 $ 3000.00 ; -"OOO.UO 1583.33 416.6T 2000.00 agent 1800.00 144O.U0 1200.00 iooo.no _ 1000.00 iwaoo Salary of secretary. Salary of matron .. Salary of governess Salary nf pkfaMM Waifejs of 'empioyees Office and telephone Traveling expenses Maintenance MO.00 1 300.00 1300.00 240.00 M&amp;W MO.00 114O.00 Mi Mil.'" iooo.ou MJO.OU 8*5.00 1 175.00 8«0.0() m»j»\ sw.28 .n *».47 177.IJG MUI mil mi MM i7ono.no MM -J61.00 581.2S 18.T2 26».28 j 345.24 ■M ■'-■ 17588.8B 11.10 nmtM Transferred from "Miscel - lanettus Expenditures." Board of &lt;'nminissloners of StatP Iimtitutions appro - priation for maintenance use 4VJ.56 412.5B 412.5* ! Institution cash MMI 2flB6 M ' 2225.15 4883.51 Totals * MM ■ * :«2&amp;».SP $ 513S.77 $ 37M8.W $ W!M Thirty-fourth Urnion, 1»1S— Current expenses, B. R. 751 Constructing and furnishing J 35020.00 » 33080.91 « a«o.»i $ now i.iiiMniL:. II. K. 004 Land. H. R. 640 •jTaoo.ni) 2300.00 220*0.13 22040. IS 2500.00 2300.00 Estimated deficiency. H. R. OHII •_'7:m.(Mi •-TSfl.On 2730.00 •J. H. Graham. H. R. 763 •Iner C. Philtirick, H. B. 7S3 ♦S. K. Cook. H. R. 75.1 25.50 173.00 213.50 25.50 25J0 173.00 173.00 -'13.50 213.50 i •H. A. Oraham. H. R. 753.... •Drs. Bentley and Lewellen, 5.00 5.00 5.00 H. R. 753 20.W 2O.00 20.00 Drs. Angle and Snipes. H. R. 753 MM moo 230.00 230.00 •J. M. Mayhew, H. R. 753. Illstittltii'II rush io.oo lo.on 14M.29 240.21 240.21 1243.08 Total* * 8W10.29 I 618BS.25 f «18SS25 f 8O42.Ot •Not expended by Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">8TATKMKNT OF KXPENDITI'KKH KKOM l.KI.IM.ATM K UI'HIII'KI V I H&gt;\ &gt; NKIIHASKA REFOHMATdHY (Cn located). ADVISOItY BOAKD, AND KKLIEK OF THE BLIND December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Kxpeml- Ainiiiiui i:\|.fi,,i ,1 ,-,l De«\ | Total Ki Ilalaure Name of Appropriation of Appro- to II. '14, t» I pendetl to of Appro- priation IfcH-.l.'U Iwc-.i.-i.i I Dec.1,16 priiition Thlrlj -third Nr.ilon. MIS— NKHUASKA BKTOUI Katalilixbiueiit ami nuiintr ATOHY (L'nlocated) nance .&lt; irrfMHMt.ixx f 1.-|HMM).00 Thlro -fourth 8e»l«B, 1K1S— lleUrt of the bliud, II. It. .T&lt;»* L-OUO.UV $ IS:K;.!»l|t 1S32.U1 * HB7.W ADVISORY BOARD Kxpenwi. of advisory I | lM&gt;nr.l &gt;* :««)0.0l&gt;(* 1634.80) * 1084.81)1* !Sa5.3O </seg>
            <seg id="p051">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 83 STATEMENT OF EXPENOITl'KKH FROM MSUINI.ATIVK APPROPRIATION* BOARD OK COMMISSIONERS OK ST.VTK INSTITUTIONS Lincoln, Nebraska December 1. 1!&gt;14, to Decemlier 1, l»ltt Expend- Amount Kxpend'd , ed Dei'. Total Ex- Balance Thirty-third &gt;r,,»i. &gt; n. 1*11 — of Appro- to 1. 14. to pvliilfil to of Appro priation Dee.1/14 Itec.1,'16 ! Dc.-l.lti prlation Salaries of three commis- sioners ! $ \7,~MM&gt; * IJXi.ui * .T73O.ni $ l.-.-rm.oo ! $ Kitting and equippiug rooms irM)0.&lt;)0 14«».7S 14MI.73 Miscellaneous expenditures 40000.00 Transferred to maintenance use from "Miscellaneous Kxp**mlltures" for: (ilrls' Industrial School — WTNS.T1 ', 1.1100.61 51W.W 1K.-.KI. State Penitentiary — 12464.DA Nebraska School for the Deaf - -3R.H0 Nebraska Home for Depend- put Children — 113.56 J I'niform system of hooka. blanks, etc. .TOO.OO 4UB.S7 _ 4WI.S7 .13 t »t!O4S.27 * 7100.21 * smj.m » M»q.0B f .42 Total Thirty-fourth s».hIob, 1115 — Salaries of three commis- sioners, h. It. ~io * ikiiiii).i» * 14M0.00 * 14J»).OO $ ."73a00 Salary of secretary. H. K. 750 - -1600.(10 LM50.00 •JSOO.00 760 Oil Salary of bookkeeper, H. It. ~Ut 2!4o.i)0 2343 00 ; MB.*0 Salary of assistant book keeper. II. R. 750 1785.00 1410.110 Salary of stenographer and file clerk. II. R. 780 1920.00 1530.00 1520.00 tmm Salary of estimate clerk, H. R. 750. 1920.00" 1520.00 1520.011 400.00 Salary of statistical clerk. H. R. 730 - 1665.00 131.-..O0 1315.00 '• 360.00 For Incidentals, books, etc. oTSO.flb .._ 3145.78 3145.76 2«34.24 H. R. 751 :U 45.76 Railroad fare and traveling allroad fare and traveling expenses. H. R. 731 1130.00 tW0.35 (WO..V&gt; «MR expenses. H. R. 751 1150.00 (W0.:f. Extra help, H. R. 751 510.00 xtra help, H. R. 7.-.1 510.00 230.06 230.06 3»JB 230.05 Totals $ 39900.00 9 29MS.1S f 2MW.lt I $ If II </seg>
            <seg id="p052">84 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF RK( WITM.ATION OF EXPKNDITl'KKH FBOM LKUIKLATIYE AITKOPBIA - TIONS OF THK Thlrt.v-thlrd Mul», 1*11, for all 1 lift it ut inns. BoariU and Activity Under the Jurisdiction of tbe Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions. December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 of Appro- ' to i 1, 14, to pended to of Appro- Name of Institiiti.ii. Board prtatlon Dec.1,14 Dec.1,'16 ] Dec.1,'16 prhition and Activity Expend- ' Amount Kxpend'd ed Dec. Total Ex- Balance Bonders' and Sailors' Home, Milforil ...._ _ ll:US62.36 Bonders' and Sailors' Home, Milford 113862.36 Ingleslde Hospital for the In IiigleKide Hospital for the In Mine, lagleside 47X0U5.7-1 sane, iDgleside 47*095.74 Nebraska Hospital for the In Nebraska Hospital for the In MBe, Lincoln 3W324.O2 sane, Lincoln 398324.02 Hospital for the Insaue of Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk 248865.83 Nebraska, Norfolk 248863.83 Hospital for Tuberculous. . S5441.64 Hospital for Tuberculous .... KH41.A4 Orthopedic Hospital.. 153344.3S1 Orthopedic Hospital.. 153344.3S1 State Penitentiary 34MW.W State Penitentiary 344fl»».W Nebraska Indnstrlal Home MMJi Nebraska Industrial Home 42TUO.2U Nebraska Schorl fur the Nebraska S.lic 1 fur the Blind 58718.15 ::ium.»ii 1 4.-'.m.ti7 540S4.07 5634.06 1113O5.M) *t419.40 194724.79 11084.97 ::ium.»ii H.-mi.iiT 540K4.O7 5434.06 Blind 59718.15 Nebraska School for the Deaf 2O580U.7ii Nebraska School for the Deaf 206809 .7« 111305. fit SI419.4O 194T24.T9 11084.97 Nebraska Home for Depend Nebraska Home for Depend - ent Children....- 38446.2S ent Children. 38446.2* 32309.88 5138.T7 37448.6* 907.62 32300.!* 5138.77 37448.66 997.K Nebraska Reformatory 13(1000.(10 Nebraska Reformatory 13(1000.(10 150000.00 150000.00 MS34.8O _..._ 1«S4.8O 13«.2O MI34.SO 163480 1366.20 Advisory Board 3000.00 Advisory Board 3000.00 Board of Commissioners of Board of Commissioners of State Institutions...- WO43.i7 Totals 3135032.18 State Institutions I W043.27 IT 100.21 8IM2.C4 36042.8B .42 100.21 8842.04 36042.85 .42 21H3«20.r. 1 $040(06.19 2833856,31»l»301375.87 Totals 3135232.18 2193620.12 $(H«i3«.19 2833836.31* I $301375.87 While there was actually ox|&gt;ended from all appropriations made by the Thirty-third Session (or all Institutions and boards under the total sum of.... 42833856.31 jurisdiction of this board tbe tbe sum of. was actually expended for relating to tbe period covered hy n|i items propriations made by the Thirty second Session and, hence, properly rhariceable thereto. Thus, there was actually expended from appropriations made by the Thirty-third Session and chargeable thereto the sum of 26S8589.26 To this, however, must be added actnal additional expenditures as per appropriations made by tbe Thirty-fourth Session, not properly . liaruealile thereto, for ordinary expenditures 74999.08 and for extraordinary expenditures. - 14743.54 Thus, making tbe true expenditures for all purposes for the period covered by tbe appropriation made by tbe Thirty -third Session charge- .12718341.88 ■jo"»^."&gt;7.nf. Nebraska Institution for Fee- hle-Minded Youth SJUl l.TOJM $10400T&gt;.tttt * 3121J.M3 fl!K&gt;221.8» * 0834.15 ErU 1 Industrial School 12550K.75 lOl^W^L' iBttT.at* 12487*40 832.38 ite IndustrUl School 254334 75 1IWW1.21 LWs«.38 i-_1»47.5e 27887.16 Nebraska Soldiers' and Sail- iors 1 Home, Burkett... 185801.22 167W11.78 2640K.34 l»4410.13 ' 1391.09 IS74UO.O.1 :stK70.Ji | 107360.30 1 .t714.7T.:i3 H9W77.08 461434.3« 1«S81.3S S3113.28 ■Rssan.ae 3»437s.tH MU y i:r7M6.41 :i5+6.-&gt;.«» MMuM tmnm IMMBJi 4853U.T8 1*0843.30 l"&lt;w:(«.'.ii 7930.40 2426^0.34 8M05.47 14W.Sil.73 JMOiS.34 42608.05 0346.56 1436.17 3512.66 •37&gt;«3.35 182.24 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">85 KK&lt; ll'lill \Tlll\ OF KM'KMHTl KK.X FROM LKG ISI.ATI &gt; K APPIOrRIA - TION8 OF THE Thirty-fourth gnsloa. INS, tor ail Institutions, Boards and Activity Under tbe Jurisdiction of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions. December 1, 1914, to December 1, IMS Expend- Amount Kxim-ihI'iI «*&lt;1 Dec. Totnl Ex- Balance of Appro- t.. 1. 14. tn peuded to i of Appro - priation Dee.l.'U Dec.l.lt; In-.-1.16 priatlon Name of Institution. Board and Activity NHirasku Institution for Fee Me- Minded Yontb t-jx»ia.4ii tmorUt $1771171.90 $ .VH34.W Cirls' Industrial School 74K74.7S 85068.40 80068.40 98MJB State Industrial School l-l.1ftU8.9ft 103518.52 108518.52 4O08O.44 Nebraska Soldiers' and Sail iors' Home, Burkett -j.vmn.-jn 184734.71 1S47M.71 T3TSMK Soilders' and Sailors' Home, Milford 97368.4* 6KVM.8S tB.V4.S6 3400t.« Ingleside Hospital for the In sane. Ingleside ___ 47«T4H.(«t 312613.08 312813.08 164138.01 Nebraska Hospital for tbe In sane, Lincoln — 34!&gt;1-JS.»2 2673S2.05 2A7382.O5 81 743.87 Hospital for tbf Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk MM. ■ 189S0B.O5 1S9809.05 ! 7M80.41 Hoiipital for Tuberculous flOK26.73 55377.S2 55377.82 14448.91 Orthopedic Hospital.. ll.'*«4.44 101087.20 101087.2S 11947.18 State 1'enitentiary. 41«2lkt.l!» 396440.51 336440.51 S17«3.« Nebraska Industrial Home Nebraska School for tbe Blind Nebraska School for the Deaf 51712.75 42804.78 +2STH.76 8M7.M .-A-»Lf..31t 38868.70 3.NW3.70 148BB • i mum-' 9406S.19 M08S.19 ?S861J« Nebraska Home for Depen ent Children _ •msuo a «1H68.% «1S«R.25 SH2.04 Board of Commissioners of State I nstitutions _ J&amp;266.1B 2*266.16 1 10HLM 1332.»1 1332.91 687.00 MM MM Relief of tbe Wind.. .12837446.34 - 212««79.13 &lt; l212«679.13«|$71076«.21 Totals 'Inasmuch as $74999.06 for ' ordinary expenditures and $11743.54 for extraordin I expended during the period covered by the appro - fourth Session for items relating to the period cot - ide by the Thirty -third Session and, hence, properly and true expenditures to date from the appropria- ary expenditures were actually prlations made by the Thirty ered by the appropriations made chargeable thereto, the actual tion* made by the Thirty- fourth Session and properly chargeable thereto arc It may also be stated that of tbe expenditures made out of appropriationa made by the Thirty-fourth Session of the Legislature listed under certain lnstitn- tions. there are some which were not expended by antbority of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, but by the Legislature directly authorising the Auditor of Public Accounts to Issue warrants npon properly executed Touchers. Nevertheless, tbe claims referred to grew ont of tbe existence of the several Insti - tutions affected and, since allowed, are properly chargeable to the respective in stlrntions Involved. The total of the sums thus appropriated and expended In fall Is $1B775.24. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF SUMMARY OF EXPENDITURES FOR ALL PURPOSES December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 As per "Recapitulation of Expenditures from Legisla- tlative Appropriations of the 33rd Session, 1913" $ 640,236.19 per "Recapitulation of Expenditures from Legisla - lative Appropriations of the 34th Session, 1915" 2,126,679.13 Total $2,766,915.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 87 &lt;MM-I- OF II VI VM K» IN VI- PKOPRIATIONS M Vlil- BY I III- TH1BTY- THIRTY SKHHION OK THE INK I H.l-l V ri KK OF THE NKBRAMKA, l»l&gt; HTATE OF ., I»IJ • I 5 - i. = » I , life ill 1 x i X sis *«£ JIM lul Xaine of Iustltutiou and Buanl Naine of Institution and Hoar. I »• - apt » I || I If SI =5 Kg 331* j *| 511 1*5] =5 = - ] \i-l.raska Institution for Keelile-Miudeil Youth, I-l*»Ht ri«*e. Nebraska . . Nebraska Institution for Feel.le-Miiided Vmitl), Beatrice. Nebraska . . * .1000.00 * WM.3S * 239.77 | $ W34.15 * .1000.00 * WH..V. * 2H» .77 I $ 5034.15 for const. for const. sewer flBl.Sl 140.54 8KJS 4iNn.&lt;&gt;4 jri.vvi.i2 ntm.u S37.S1 553.28 13B1.08 TflO.16 5711.90 1 «HB.« 3.119.42 13341.96 14M81.38 sewer &lt;iirl&gt; Industrial School. (leneva. Xelir (Mils' Industrial School. (leneva. Xelir Staff [nilustrinl Sa'hoiil, Kearney. Nelir W1.81 140.54 8KJS State Industrial School, Kearney. Nelir 41NH.IH 13504.12 -.TOW.W Nebraska Soldiers' ami Sailors' Home Burkett, Nebraska _ Nebraska Soldiers ami Sailors' Home Burkett, Nebraska _ WIM 553.28 1361.OB Soldiers' and Sailors' Home. Milford, Xebraska _ Soldiers' and «ailor»' Home. Mil'i.rd Nebraska 7!W.16 5711.90 ! 6502 08 liik'lt'slde HoHpital for th«- Insane, Injrle wide, Nebraska Inglesldr Hospital for the Insane, Injrle side, Nebraska 3.119.42 13341.96 | 14MM1.38 Nebraska BaapMal for the liiHaue. Lin '•olti. Nebraska _ Nebraska H.ispltal for the Insane. Lin coin. Nebraska _ 39«.38 3MS.3B 173 99 (SlTl.ao CMMt l«..-« 1J70.64 14M.17 Hospital fur the Insane of Nebraska, Norfolk. Nebraska _ Hospital fur the Insane of Nebraska Norfolk. Nebraska _ Hospital for Tuberouloos, Kearney, Nebraska Hospital for Tuberoulous, Kearney Nebraska Orthopedlr Ho«pit«l, Lincoln Nebraska Orthopedlr Hospital. Lincoln Nelmiskii OUi 384.HS 1403.00 »12«S for pav- for pav ing South street V«0O.K&gt; 4220.5S 1WH2.SU 57MS.35 Ing South street Stnti' Penitentiary. Lincoln Nebraska State Penitentiary. Lincoln Nebraska S.TOOO.(« 4220.55 1SB4--.80 578*3.35 for tilnd - ing twine for iilnrt- ing twine fai-tor.v 44.15 138.08 UtM 464.53 5MW.55 m*M sm.m 10KS4.U1 uom.»7 70.21 927.41 m.«2 130000.00 160000.00 For Nc- fai'tor.v Nebraska Industrial Home. Milford. Nebraska Nebraska Industrial Home. Milford Nebraska 44.15 13K.OB 1«24 Nebniska School for the Blind. Ne - braska City, Nebraska NebniKka School for the Blind, Ne braska City, Nebraska 404.53 5MB.55 StUM Nebraska School for tbe Deaf, Omaha, Xebroka Nebrasku School for the Deaf, Omaha Nebr«»ka iifl.SB 1«K!S.I«» 11OS4.97 Nebraska Home for Dependent Chil - dren, Lincoln Nebraska... Nebraska Home for Impendent I'hil dren, Lincoln Nebraska... 70.21 927.41 WIM Nebraska Reformatory, (nnlocated) Nebraska Reformatory, (nnlocated) 15OUO0.0O For Ne - braska 160000.00 l&gt;ra«ka Keforma tory Hefnriua tory 134B.20 134B.20 Adyisory Board - AdTisory Board 11BB.20 • IMUt Board of Commissioners of State Instl tntlons Board of Commissioners of State Insti - tutions .43' .42 42 .42 *l»1725.l»l * 2OLM2.5U $")940S.37 «S01&gt;MJT TOTAL •Eliminating entirely from consideration the appropriations for in the first column, in amount of extraordinary purposes listed in $191,725.00, and also the Institutic Institution Cash Fund balances, which were Session of the Legislature . 1915, re-appropriated by the Thirty-: ■fourth it is of interest to note that, notwithstanding a total balance of $89,408.37 in appropriations for purely ordinary purposes, it was necessary for the Thirty-fourth Session of the Legislature to appro - priate $79,686.70 for deficiency expenditures of an ordinary character, of which only $74,999.06 was actually expended. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">88 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF KTATKMENT OF CASH RECEIPTS ( REDITEI) TO THE INSTITUTION t'ANH rirXD*, DISBI KSKMKNTS THKREFROM. AND BALANCE* THEREIN The Institution Cash Fnmls represent the cash incomes of the institutions from all sources with exceptions and ampliflcations noted below. Total Received Received Receipts Expended Balance XAMK OK INSTITITION Dec.l.'H 'Dec. 1. V. Dec.l.'H Dec. 1, 14 on hand Nebraska Institution for Fee Nebraska Institution for Fee - ble-Minded Youth $ iscj 77 hle-Mtnded Youth $ iscj 77 Girls' Industrial' School MST38 * lWtt.02 * lsv-,i7!t J 6&lt;-7:t."3 * 12H4.-..7:: 1181.S4 284».L &gt; 2 1104.11 1782.34 * imra.02 * i.w-,i7!t x e«-7:t."a * 13s4.-,.t:: Girls' Industrial' School Ill [W l«i7..V&gt; 1181.64 2840.22 1104.11 1782.34 Stare Industrial School lflU0K.iti Stare Industrial School MWtts.02 ■Ml 24333.66 12508.41 16360.38 i:B«5.0« 24353.66 12508.41 16360.38 Nebraska Soldiers' and Sail - ors' Home, Burkett ."Kr.'4.,)&lt;i Nebraska Soldiers' and Sail ors' Home. Burkett 1 ."Kr.'4.,)&lt;i 654O.2S 12464.S4 50T3.71 10524.80 MM 12464.84 5073.71 10524.80 Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Soldier!-' and Sailors' Home, Milford _ MLM MUford _ MUt SCi^L' 1513.88 531.68 1201.16 532.32 1513.66 531.88 12O1.16 Ingleside Hospital for the In - sane, Inpleside. _ H677.62 Ingleside Hospital for the In s«ne. Ingleside. 6677.62 :ti:!7ri.lO 44052.72 2630.88 45009.39 :I7375.1O 44052.72 2530.S8 45006.39 Nebraska Hospital for the In - sane, Lincoln sxx;.&lt;i-"i Nebraska Hospital for the In- sane. Lincoln sNXi.&lt;i."i £(i&gt;m.r*&gt; 3-J309.15 126S2.4O 23870.36 237MUO 32S6B.15 12S32.4O 23970.36 Hospital for the liiMine of Nebraska. Norfolk OMJM Hospital for the lnsmic of Nebraska. Norfolk 9fMJM Hospital for Tulieriuloiis 74.".. 42 1+445.S8 1«716.42 2299.74 14SMti.3l &gt; KW.7O 1814.12 1425.00 968.91 1444.1.N* 16716.42 2290.74 14!I4H.3J Hospital for Tulieriuloiis 74."i.4.' 1IW.7O 1K14.12 1429.00 968.91 Orthopedic Hospital 474.7« Orthope&lt;lic Hospital 474.7« 361.68 836.39 1331.80 161.5« 361.63 8M.3B 1331.00 161.5« State Penitentiary -J-xso.m Nebraska Industrial Home 124. ."&gt;1 Nebraska School for rbe Blind 24O4.3S Nebraska School for the Deaf 1108.32 State Penitentiary 3-HKt.m ti^i«».:!7 0117(1.23 7.Tt»7K.SS 15311.56 6228B.37 9117(1.23 7.Tt»7K.S3 15311..V1 tWl.27 81S.T8 854.81 782.55 Nebraska Industrial Home tUM 6U1.27 815.78 854.81 782.55 Nebraska School for rbe Blind -'4OI.5S ICJl.lr. 4O2f&gt;74 816.69 3844.46 m I II 4035.74 816.W :I844.46 Nebraska Hrhool for the Deaf 1108.3^ 11277 .92 4446.24 4088.61 1136.96 WtrtM 4446.24 4088.61 J136.95 Nebraska Home for Depend Nebraska Flome for Depend ent Children 14B6.9S ent Children 1456.98 803.31 2260.29 2466.36 1243.08 803.31 2260.29 2466.36 1243.08 TOTAL I 172551.51 $1S«O13.74 *25W«5.25 J130710.06 $149089.44 This statement does not include the balances N linn. I in '.he institution cash funds. Dec. 1. 1914. and hence, the "Balances Ml Hand. Dec. 1, IMC" plus the "Total Expenditures Dec. 1. 1014, to Dec. 1. 1916." exceed the -Total Re i-eipls. Dec. 1, 1914. to Dec. 1, 1916". The following are to be noted : 1. The tntal cash receipts at the Nebraska Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth include the sums received pursuant to Section 7224. Revised Statutes of Nebraska. 1913. commonly called the "Clothing Fund ". Beginning May 1. 1916. this fund was transferred to the Institution Cash Fund of said institution. L' The total cash receipts at the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane include the sums collected pursuant to Section 72K«, Revised Statutes of Nebraska. 1913. commonly called "Receipts for Care of Dipsomaniacs". 3! The total cash receipts at the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane. Ingleside Hospital for the Insane, and Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska Include the sums collected pursuant to Chapter 134, Laws of Nebraska. 1915. com - monly called "Receipts for Maintenance". 4. The cash receipts of the State Penitentiary from the sale of articles manufactured hy the Handcraft Furniture Company and also the cash receipts for labor of inmates are Included in the total cash receipts of said Institution. 5. The total cash receipts of the Nebraska School for the Blind and the Nebraska School for the Deaf include tuition charges for pupils from other ■tatec. 6. The total cash receipts of the Nebraska Soldiers' and Sailors' Home and tfie Soldiers' and Sailors' Home do not include the sums receiTed from the Tanked States government. ST. Tho toul cash receipts of the 8tate Penitentiary do uot Include the earnings for electric current furnished to the Orthopedic Hospital, Ne- Hospital for the Insane. Governor's Mansion, and State House. Demnbrr 1, 1914, to Deonnferr I, lillft Dec.l.'13 1KH-. 1.1« IMh\ 1, 16 Deo. 1. 16 Dw.4, *M </seg>
            <seg id="p057">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 89 3 ! /. . £- H II !^ i , vi oxlli!li!i!ill|ii||] mnu MH'miMW 1 1 S Hi iiiioh ' : 1«»-"W\ E. e = irs is s if! pailH »m Joj •* J« »moH i»i-m 1 SSSSSSpSSKSS i 2 , * S £ E i i hi «*»« mum |ii A] wl d.. H SS8SS22g|Sgg S S |||^ 0!p*doq»JO ■ B 3J» «noinaj*qnx JIS^SSsSS^SSS E « J H.-5 Jjo; i»i|ilso|i fcJCj *qj 4OJ i«i|daoH Si B |UI(J«oh HiuqJS Ee« = »Pi"i*«&gt;i ?.?.SSSSSSSS8S | 8 I*a5 •" '.iiisiiui jqj jo; — — — — — — — ~ — — — — • -_■= j | l«|d«o H apiMiani " '""" " 1&gt;1M 2 " » HS I 1 p-io,,,k =SSRSg58£S2£ g 2 jjI-bJ WJ5S 5WH5588MS g 3 £|I ::;:i:in-i/:c.-/ r- * fc ■£&amp;. ,oo MJ8IW SI8SS||i£|gS g S f||| -«npui .8|ajo » =■■ qjno.1 papniK 8?:S|¥Si = 5isS5 8 9 tl's a|((*»j joj ao|j *V»i*5i*$*KS »#-=.■; ■ninsui n««q»x " o * J' 1 1 Miii nil I iii ;f ? l in {I «ft*!w I ! ill 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 90 ujjpim.)| P?5SSSSt$SSS IS Z )u&lt;&gt;pil&lt;Kl&lt;HI J"J S dUlOH B!|1IIIJ&lt;I&gt;».V | 111 M S".fc |h looqjg wj|««j&lt;i*\ ; a * i I •; puna siii -""i *■ I I I 1 _ ii £. el e |I B - &lt;1 &gt; v - I &lt; - — .ii|i Ml 1V)!' |K "H ti| ...iii'i SjfiJg-sjtjJtg-* n m Tpiwiiii «S25?.5SS S^tfcS SIS ■,.in:sil| am JUJ ~^^^~~~SS^ —^ « 5 imidsoH »|i|iw|*ni ■ .IlllilH .KJ»U»W ------------ ft - po« .sjaipios I I TO^T[lB£saHS==£S*|S|s ..|l...cl,,IUJ(l - I s noi ii^iiuTSWS Vii s = 5i.'V;^S= S I S JOJ |Vlt&lt;lK»|l __________! Ii nil S-sI IK* «a: |J,J = i = I ell- ni 1 ,ooqo« ...a, usiminiOTi -snpui al*lH ** Nlipill .B|J|{&gt; " | 5 | qjn«i l»pn| K JJga S = f 3CSKP, Illllslll 1!&gt;(&gt;I1UC|.I\ •3 § - I I </seg>
            <seg id="p059">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 91 ■ I i I •ivxoxj J S S uajpnuj S Z |£ )a»pnada&lt;j J "J JUiOH ||!||IWJ&lt;H\ n ? ? j«a&lt;l aqt joj i i I I i — I i~ puHH aq) jo; |'i"i|-iS unmi4na.v m m = — \\- ■"""II 1»H) i s - = iJViiiirfiiiiri,! T ft § X M ! &lt; - _3 . |«}|(lson .•|p«iiil|UI&gt; T T = J - w~ r J — i — E 3 &lt; - 2 a M -" 1l"iJ"\ I ,t I JMJ JOJ ihiiiNiih | | ll|n.ill|'I f! ■MI &gt;:- II 1 -•■11 j..j i'- |i:iiil&gt;o|l K!1!(II4&lt;|*.N; _j s Si "A fi a .. 3 | \ * ' ap|«aiSai 'rtllHHlll .&gt;l|l Jo; |»J!d«on j|)|Ka|3ni 9 | _3 I'JOJIIH •* I &gt;-n&gt;[|«« Ihiij *j.»|pii&gt;« 8 I Kt !i I; ■ ■ _ s ll I! UrfVtiti »n»H .sjo||«tj pnii .sjji|'I"S ■umiJiHx; 5 I $ |oo M .) S i^jj | | j -nopal .«|JIf) T n — s- I ■IIIIIKIII ll!|«lMi|,t\- J~ | "I ' S~^ 4 £ 2 * 2 5 2_-- 2_-u r«-u f] * i * i •l! "If "|f I Ik I! </seg>
            <seg id="p060">92 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF EXPLANATORY OUTLINE OF DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES FOR ALL STATE INSTITUTIONS UNDER THE JURISDICTION OF THE BOARD OF COMMIS - SIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS f December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 I. Maintenance NOTE: — Covers all for which there has been an original purchase or which in the nature of the classification is properly chargeable hereto 1. Salaries and Wages — a — Officers, employees, and teachers b — Extra labor or professional services 2. Transportation, Telephone, and Telegraph (official trips) a — Railroad fare b — Traveling expenses, other than railroad fare. (Includes hack and automobile livery, street car fare, hotel and meals) (For inmates discharged or returned) c — Railroad f«t*e d — Traveling expenses, other than railroad fare. (Includes hack and automobile livery, street car fare, hotel and meals) e — Express, freight, and drayage f — Telephone and telegraph 3. Articles of Food— a — Flour b — Sugar c — Coffee and tea d — Canned goods e — Other groceries, fruits, and vegetables. (Includes bread, yeast, vinegar, etc.) f — Meats. (Includes live stock purchased expressly for this pur - pose, fresh and salt fish and oysters) g — Lard and butterine h— Butter i— Eggs j— Milk k — Cheese and other dairy products 4. Stock Feed 5. Tobacco </seg>
            <seg id="p061">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 93 Maintenance — (Continued) 6. Clothing — a — Boots and shoes, shoe brushes and polish, lacing, etc. b — Men's clothing and furnishings c — Women's ready-made wearing apparel d — Repairing Dry Goods. (Includes all goods by the yard, bed and table linen, combs, hair brushes, etc. and notions) 8. Hospital Supplies. (Includes drugs, disinfectants, surgical instru - ments, crutches, laboratory supplies and kindred articles for the especial car of patients.) 9. Soap, i For all purposes — includes cleansers, starch, bluing, etc.) 10. Hardware. I Other than builders') 11. Queens ware and Glassware 12. Furniture. (Includes shades on rollers, mattresses, [no other bed - ding], refrigerators, stoves, carpets, made-up curtains and draper - ies, etc.. and all repairs thereto.) 13. Stationery, Books, and Paper — a — Office supplies. (Includes printing, stationery, postage, ink and kindred office supplies — furniture excepted) b — School books and supplies c — Books and periodicals d — Miscellaneous. I Includes toilet and wrapping paper and paper bags) 14. Brooms, Brushes, (Radiator, floor, etc.), Polish (Furniture and metal), and Dusters 15. Fuel, Light and Power — a — Coal b — Oils and lubricants. (Includes packing and compounds) c — Electricity d_Water 16. Machinery, Tools, and Supplies — a — For industrial departments. (Such as printing, shoe and broom manufacturing ) b — For institution in general. (Includes parts and repairs to fore - going, blacksmithing and horse-shoeing) 17. General Repairs — a — Engineers' supplies. (Includes steam fittings, engines, boilers, and their accessories and plumbing supplies and their acces - sories) b — Electrical supplies. (Includes lamps, fixtures, wiring, motors and their accessories) c — Builders' hardware d — Paints, oils, glass, paint brushes and wall paper, and moulding e — Building material. (Includes cement, brick, lime, plaster, lumber, structural steel, stone, etc.) f — Labor. (Professional and otherwise, other than I. — U) </seg>
            <seg id="p062">94 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Maintenance — (Continued) 18. Live Stock. (Includes horses, mules, cows, hogs, poultry, etc.) 19. Seeds 20. Entertainment 21. Burial Expenses 22. Miscellaneous. (Not classed in foregoing) II. Furniture and Equipment NOTE: — Refers to all new furniture and equipment used to furnish and equip in whole or in part new and older buildings such as completely outfitting a room or rooms. 1. Furniture. (Includes freight, if any) 2. Equipment. (Includes freight, if any) — a — For institution in general. (Such as boilers, etc.) b — For hospital. (Such as hydrostatic, Roetgen rays equipment, etc.) c — For farm. (Such as binders, etc.) d — For industrial departments. (Such as printing presses, etc.*) e — For laundry. I Such as mangles, etc.) III. Permanent Improvements to Buildings and Grounds NOTE: — This refers to improvements which have not existed before, made to buildings, — such as sleeping porches to present building, etc.; new cement walks not replacing old walks; grading of grounds, etc. 1. Labor. (Includes supervising and architect fees) 2. Lumber. 3. Brick and Stone. (Includes common, face and fire brick and stone, crushed and otherwise) 4. Cement, Fire Clay, Sand, Plaster and Lime 6. Paints, Oils, Glass, and Paint Brushes 6. Structural Steel 7. Engineers' Supplies. (Includes steam fittings and their accessories and plumbing supplies and their accessories) 8. Electrical Supplies. (Includes lamps, fixtures, wiring, etc.) 9. Hardware. (Builders') 10. Miscellaneous. (Includes all not otherwise classified, such as freight </seg>
            <seg id="p063">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 95 rv. New Buildings and Land NOTE: — Refers to new buildings and buildings replacing those de - stroyed by any cause whatever. 1. When Erected by Contractors 2. When Erected by State — a — Labor. (Includes architect and supervising fees) b — Lumber c — Brick and stone. (Includes common, face and fire brick and stone, crushed and otherwise) d — Cement, fire clay, plaster, sand and lime e — Paints, oils, glass, and paint brushes f — Structural steel g — Engineers' supplies. ( Includes steam fittings and radiators, plumbing supplies, and their accessories) h — Electrical supplies. I Includes) lamps, fixtures, wiring, etc.) i — Hardware. (Builders') • j — Miscellaneous. I Includes all not otherwise classified, such as freight, etc.) 3 Land V. Miscellaneous All items not properly classified under any of the foregoing four main divisions. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">96 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE 1IISTKIBI TION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL lAI'KMllll Kl&gt; FOR MAINTENANCE ONLY NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH, BEATRICE, NEBRASKA Dewiuber 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Kailroad fare — official.. 86.53 67.44 153.97 4.41 , 4.56 8.98 1.42 9.32 10.74 4.75 2.75 7.50 Transport- Traveling expenses — official atlon, I Kailroad fare — inmates _J telegraph, 1 Traveling expenses— inmate*— -J and telephone I Express and freight _ i Telephone and telegraph .". -I Total.. I Flour I Sugar I Coffee and tea.. I Canned goods.. Articles I Ot-er groc., fruits and vegetables of food •! Meats _ .: I Lard and butterine. I Butter EBR8 ! Milk I Cheese and other dairy products. Total. Stock feed. Tobacco... [ Boots, shoes, sboe brashes, lacing. etc. I Men's clothing and furnishings... Clothing ___ -i Women's ready-made wearing ap- pnrel 881.64 881.64 OOA.m ooi.w » 376^7 377.42 I Miscellaneous (includes repairs) Total. Dry goods.. Hospital supplies Soap, cleansers, starch, etc.. Hardware (other than builders').. Q&lt; eensware and glassware. Fu rnitnre (Includes repairn i .. CLASSIFICATION ; Total Dec. 1, M4 ; Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, 14 to to to Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, '16 Dec. 1 '18 Salaries and wages 1 Officers, employees, etc _ I Extra labor or services _ ... $ 2439S.K9 $ 24658.25 i 49053.14 325.50 150.34 475.84 Xotal _ 2471U.S* ' 24S0U.5M l'JoliS.iM* 1.SU.4G 3UU.S1 -*-U.-O 131.72, 179.63 311.35 390.28 ! 864.50 923.78 3944.80 732.23 911.00 1021.60 4886.37 4340.15 1951.87 !»4.S5 520.51 «1.75 149.86 3850.45 1058.06 864.80 812.86 .1834.01 5384.42 2522.97 M4T..1K 553.79 81.75 230,98 7795.25 1790.2K 1775.80 1834.29 8720.38 9724.57 4474.S4 USO.flR 1074.30 143.50 ■Ml 19454.79 20039.10 39493.*! 1322.96 792.14 2115.0H 179.90 153.01 153.01 332.91 332.91 8.25 7.50 1583.00 2504.72 1591.25 3UU2 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 33 eligible to the reformatory were it in operation — that is, persons not less than sixteen nor more than thirty years of age at the time of sentence, convicted of felony for the first time. The prison population of Nebraska is not large, com - pared with that of other states. The number of those eli - gible to a reformatory is relatively small. Yet there should be proper provision made for these, however few in number. Such provision, it seems to us, could well be made, for the present and for several years to come, in connection with the establishment of the State custodial farm, and we so recommend. COMMISSION FOR THE BLIND The Legislature at its last session appropriated the sum of $2,000 for the relief of the blind and provided that the money so appropriated as well as any funds contributed for such purpose, should be expended only under the authority and supervision of the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. The Superintendent of the Nebraska School for the Blind and the Executive Board of the Nebraska Association of Workers for the Blind were constituted an Advisory Hoard to carry out the purposes of the act. The statute specified the following lines of work to be undertaken : (a) To collect, interpret and publish data relating to the cause, prevention and cure of blindness; the means employed or advocated for ameliorating the condition of the blind ; the number, location, character and condition of the blind of this State. (b) To provide home teaching for the blind. (c) To encourage home industry by assisting the workers in obtaining supplies and in finding a market. Cd) To assist worthy and competent persons in finding remunerative employment suited to their needs and capacities. (e) To assist worthy and talented persons in pur - suing studies more advanced or more technical than those offered by the Nebraska School for the Blind. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">34 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Pory Board organized under this statute and mperintendent of the Nebraska School for the e officer of the commission and Lyle A. Har - of the school and himself totally blind, field Mr. Harris entered upon his duties August 1, 1915, and has traveled over a large part of the State, securing infor - mation concerning the blind and those whose vision is seri - ously defective, and making a census of their number, loca - tion, character and condition, as prescribed by the statute. He found a total of 404 blind persons, of whom 129 are self-supporting, 121 partially self-supporting and 154 en - tirely dependent. Of the total number 76 are minors and most of these, of course, are dependent. I Through his instrumentality several have been enabled enter the Nebraska School for the Blind and are now ■oiled as pupils. To a limited extent Mr. Harris has also ie some home teaching of the blind, and with the co - iration of women's clubs and other associations and in - iduals has accomplished something in the way of provid - : a place for the sale of articles made by the blind. tn one instance a loan of $75 at a nominal rate of ;st has made it possible for a blind man to start a little for the making of brooms. The Advisory Board was organized to solicit and re - ceive contributions either for immediate use or for endow - ment, but the receipts from this source have been insignifi - cant, amounting during the biennium to only $12.05. The work is evidently regarded as a matter of public duty rather than of private charity and no substantial sums may be expected from voluntary subscriptions. tWe feel that considerable good has been accomplished that there is a field for further activity which will fit not only the blind but the State at large. The statistics have been gathered for the most part, and future efforts should be directed chiefly toward bringing to self-support the adult blind who are now wholly or par - tially dependent. This may be done by providing home teaching of a practical and vocational sort for those who </seg>
            <seg id="p067">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 35 may be unable or unsuitable to enter the school at Nebraska City ; by assistance in securing them employment ; by aid in obtaining a market for the articles made by them; and by small loans of money, on proper conditions, for the pur - chase of tools, machinery and material to enable worthy and capable persons to start in business. To accomplish any appreciable results along these lines will require the services of two persons — a woman who could teach cooking, sewing, weaving, basket-making and other household arts, and a man who could instruct in broom-making, net and hammock making, piano-tuning and other occupations adapted to the blind. We therefore recommend the continuance of the com - mission for the blind and an appropriation of $4,000 to carry out the purposes outlined. STERILIZATION LAW Among the preventive measures enacted by the last Legislature was a law authorizing the sterilization, in proper cases, of certain classes of state wards. The law itself is very conservative. It recognizes the fact that there is no need of such a procedure in the case of any person who requires permanent custodial care. It applies, therefore, only to those who may be eligible to parole or discharge. Neither is it compulsory. It presents as an alternative a continuation of institutional custody. It applies only to feeble-minded and insane persons, in what - ever State institution found. After the bill became a law a Board of Examiners of Defectives was appointed consisting of the superintendents of the three hospitals for the insane, the institution for feeble-minded, and the orthopedic hospital. This Board organized with Dr. B. F. Williams as chairman and Dr. W. S. Fast as secretary, and adopted suitable rules to govern their procedure. The board of examiners has held several sessions and has investigated and passed upon the cases of 89 persons, of whom 40 were men and 49 women. Of the total number examined, 46 were authorized to </seg>
            <seg id="p068">36 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF be paroled without sterilization ; 35 were ordered to be ster - ilized as a condition precedent to their parole; and 8 were held for further consideration. Of the 35 persons, in whose cases it was ordered that no parole be granted unless after sterilization, 15 were operated upon. Of these 9 were men and 6 women. No operation had been performed upon the remaining 20 on November 30, 1916, the close of the period covered by the report. Of this latter number it was considered that several were not suitable to be paroled and hence that an operation was not advisable nor proper. kit is gratifying to learn that good results have been ined in all cases operated and that in no instance have ulties or complications arisen. ■ tThe Board of Examiners has acted very conservatively considerately, as its report transmitted herewith shows, h the thought of protecting the individual and safe - •ding the interests of the State". I The feeble-minded are recognized "as the most pro - class and potentially the most dangerous from the ldpoint of race standards". The Board therefore "un - itatingly authorized the sterilization of the male feeble - ded wherever application was made" in proper cases, but ng to the more complicated surgical procedure and the ger of prostitution and the spread of venereal disease vocated custodial care rather than sterilization in the &gt; of the feeble-minded female". In case of insanity the ird was guided largely by the wishes of the patient and itives. I The examinations were confined to wards of the State the several hospitals for the insane and in the institution • feeble-minded. I The law is applicable also to persons who are inmates the penitentiary, industrial schools and industrial home, such persons are found to be either insane or feeble - nded and are in other respects fit subjects for such a pro - lure. We believe the law is a wise one and that, administered conservatively and rationally as is being done by the pres- </seg>
            <seg id="p069">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 37 i ent Board of Examiners of Defectives, it will prove a val - uable factor in diminishing, in some degree at least, the enormous burden of insanity and feeble-mindedness which the State must bear. VISITS The Board has kept in touch with the several institu - tions not only by means of frequent official visits by the members of the Board but also through visits by the secre - tary and accountant of the Board who have been sent from time to time to inspect supplies and to audit accounts, to the end that the Board and the institutions might co-operate more effectively in carrying on the work. A detailed state - ment of the visits made by the Board is attached to and made a part of this report. CONFERENCES Semi-annual conferences have been instituted whereby the executive and other members of the staffs of the several institutions may meet with the members of the Board to discuss the affairs and the work of the institutions. Such conferences were held in Lincoln October 27th and 28th, 1915; May 25th and 26th, 1916; and November 15th and 16th, 1916. Papers were read covering a variety of topics, profes - sional and administrative, and interesting and profitable discussions followed. The meetings were helpful in many ways and have manifested a gratifying spirit of unification and mutual co-operation in our common task. It is expected that these conferences will become a permanent feature of the work. Superintendents, members of the medical staffs and members of the Board have participated also in meetings of several of the medical societies of the State, thus bring - ing the work of the institutions into a better understanding and closer relations with the medical profession. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 38 ADDITIONAL RECOMMENDATIONS It is made the duty of this Board, among other things, to study " the conditions, causes, prevention and cure 01 crime, pauperism, insanity, epilepsy, imbecility, evil home conditions and environment" with a view "to diminish pauperism, defectiveness and degeneracy." Society has been aroused to the necessity of the repres - sion of the traffic in alcoholic liquors and in harmful and habit-producing drugs and drastic restrictive legislation has been enacted to check these evils. There is another fruitful source of physical and mental degeneration which likewise, should receive attention — the venereal diseases. tThe extent to which these diseases are prevalent, as ■d by the highest authorities, is almost unbelievable and • terrible consequences are manifest in our hospitals other institutions. I It would seem not unreasonable to subject these ail - ts to at least as close supervision as other and less dan - us infectious diseases. We accordingly renew our ler recommendation that physicians and druggists be ired under severe penalties to report to the Department ealth all cases of syphilitic and gonnorrheal infection ng under their observation and that authority to en - &gt; quarantine against infected persons should be lodged le proper medical authorities. The proposal accords the views expressed by the best alienists and neuro - ts of America. A further consideration of the subject leads us again to recommend an amendment to our statutes whereby the age when a girl attains her majority should be raised from eifirhteen to twenty-one years. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 39 There is no sufficient reason why a girl should be eman - cipated and become her own mistress at eighteen while her brother must remain a minor until he shall become twenty - one. Indeed, the girl of eighteen, nineteen or twenty is at a peculiarly critical period of her life and often stands in special need of wise over-sight, careful protection and par - ental authority. INSTITUTION REPORTS We are transmitting herewith biennial reports made by the superintendents or chief executive officers of the differ - ent institutions covered by the foregoing report. These reports show with considerable fullness and in detail the workings of these several institutions, the conditions pre - vailing and what has been accomplished in general by the work thus carried on. Much that is of value and interest concerning each of the institutions will be found by a close examination of these reports, which also give the views of the different heads as to the future needs and requirements in the further prosecution of the work and the, carrying out of the purposes and objects of the law creating the same. ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS 'We wish to express our appreciation to the Governor for the interest manifested by him at all times in the work connected with these several institutions, his valuable sug - gestions and counsels regarding many of the multifarious matters that are constantly arising, and the earnest support and hearty co-operation given in rendering the work suc - cessful in the greatest possible degree. The officers of the different institutions have at all times manifested a zeal and deep interest in the work under their charge and have responded cordially and promptly to the suggestions of the </seg>
            <seg id="p072">40 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Board and to its efforts to improve wherever improvement could be made. We note with pleasure a spirit of good fellowship and co-operation between the officers of the diff - erent institutions and a determined effort to reach higher standards and greater efficiency in carrying forward the work thus assigned to them. The office force working with the Board in the prosecution of its business has remained pactically the same since the organization of the Board and we are indebted to each and all of them for the faithful and efficient service rendered and the assistance given in the performance of their respective duties, involving, as the work does, a high degree of accuracy, application and skill in order to overcome and avoid irregularities and mistakes and render the record of our transactions comprehensive and complete in all its details. All of which is respectfully submitted. BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS, HOWARD KENNEDY, Chairman. HENRY GERDES, SILAS A. HOLCOMB. (SEAL) Attest: Leo Matthews, Secretary. November 30, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 41 OFFICIAL VISITS TO STATE INSTITITIONS December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Institution Date of Visit By Whom Made 1915, February 27, Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes April 7 April 30 June 24 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes August 26 October 2 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Nebraska December 31 Institution for 1916, February Kennedy Feeble-Minded I March 22 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Youth, May 3 Beatrice June 6 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy June 23 July 1 Gerdes July 11 Kennedy Gerdes August 29 October 3 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy November 14 1915, January 8 Gerdes February 22, 23 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes April 8 May 4. 5 June 21 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes June 30-July 1 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Aug. 31-Sept. September 7 Gerdes November 4. 5 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes Girls' Industrial School, Geneva .. 19K&gt;, February 18, 19 March 14, 15 Gerdes Gerdes April 11 May 5 Gerdes Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy June 1, 2, 3 July 4. 5 July 18 Gerdes Gerdes Gerdes Gerdes August 1, 2 August 15, 16 September 6 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy 1915, January 20 April 15 June 15 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes. Kennedy August 17 Gerdes, Kennedy Nebraska October 14 Soldiers' and November 8 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Sailors' Home, 1916, March 16 Burkett May 18 Gerdes, Kennedy June 21 Gerdes. Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy July 22 October 12, 13 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy November 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">42 OFFICIAL VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS— (Continued) April 14 June 16 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy August 18 October 15 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney November 19, 20 November 27, 28 1916, February 25 Gerdes March 17 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy May 16, 17 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy June 20 July 21 Sept. 2-5 '■&gt;rde8 October 11 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Institution Date of Visit By Whom Made Insane, Ingleside 1915, January 12 Jaunary 22 April 13 May 18 June 17, 18 August 19 November 3, 4 December 20 1916, January 27 February 26 March 18 April 5 June 19 July 19 July 20 October 10 Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy State Industrial School, Kearney 1915, January 11 January 21 April 14, 15 June 16 August 18 October 15 November 20 November 28 1916, February 25, 26 March 17, 18 May 17 June 20 July 21 September 2-5 October 10, 11 Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kolcomli. Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Ifolcomb. Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy 1915, January 11 January 21 Kennedy Gerdes </seg>
            <seg id="p075">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 43 OFFICIAL VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS— (Continued) Institution Date of Visit By Whom Made 1914, December 24 Kennedy December 29 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy 1915, January 6 Gerdes, Kennedy February 6 [ Gerdes, Kennedy March 10 Gerdes April 12 Kennedy May 11 Gerdes, Kennedy June 28 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy July 5 Kennedy July 17 Gerdes, Kennedy August 9 Kennedy September 3 Gerdes, Kennedy Nebraska September 16 Gerdes, Kennedy Hospital for the September 30 Gerdes, Kennedy Insane. Ocotber 8 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Lincoln November 12 Kennedy 1916, January 11 Gerdes, Kennedy February 15 Gerdes March 7 Gerdes, Kennedy April 14 Gerdes, Kennedy May 22 Gerdes, Kennedy June 26 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy July 14 Gerdes, Kennedy August 10 Gerdes. Kennedy August 27 Kennedy September 13 Gerdes, Kennedy November 15 Kennedy 1914, December 20 Kennedy December 29 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy 1915, January 1 January 27 Kennedy February 9 Gerdes. Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy February 26 April 19 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy May 10 July 5 Kennedy July 24 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes September 3 Orthopedic October 6 Gerdes. Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy Hospital, November 2 Lincoln November 23 Kennedy 1916, January 12 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes March 8 April 15 May 23 Gerdes, Kennedy June 27 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes July 25 August 22 Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes September 14 October 4 November 16 ! Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy </seg>
            <seg id="p076">44 OFFICIAL VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS— (Continued) Institution Date of Visit By Whom Made 1914, December 20 Kennedy December 29 uerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy 1915, January 1 January 27 Kennedy February 9 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy February 26 April 19 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy May 10 July 5 Kennedy July 24 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes September 3 October 6 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy State Novemhpr 2 Penitentiary, November 23 Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes Lincoln 1916, January 1 February 10 March 9 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes April 7 May 12 Gerdes June 26 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy July 13 July 24 Gerdes. Kennedy Kennedy August 18 September 16 Gerdes November 16 Kennedy 1915, February 18 I Gerdes, Kennedy April 24 Gerdes May 8 Gerdes June 25 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Aufrust 10 Kennedy October 26 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy November 11 Gerdes Vohrsickn ixovemDer . Industrial Home, 1916 ' J"™"* 18 Gerdes Miifnr.i April 8 Gerdes Mlllorn »__;i an /- i._ April 27 Gerdes, Kennedy June 16 Gerdes. Holcomb, Kennedy July 22 Kennedy September 15 Kennedy September 17 ! Kennedy September 28 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy November 29 | Gerdes </seg>
            <seg id="p077">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 45 OFFICIAL VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS— (Continued) Institution Date of Visit By Whom Made 1915, January 11 Gerdes February 1 18 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes April 24 May 8 Gerdes Gerdes June 12 June 25 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy August 10 August 24 October 4 October 26 Gerdes Gerdes Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes November 10 December 14 Milford Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes 1916, January 4 January 18 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy April 27 June 16 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy September 15 September 28 November 29 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes 1914, December 16 Kennedy December 30, 31 1915, February 24, 25 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy April 30 Kennedy June 8, 9 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Nebraska School for the Blind, August 13 Gerdes, Kennedy December 28 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Nebraska City.. 1916, February 11 Kennedy April 28 Gerdes, Kennedy June 13 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy August 15 Kennedy October 27, 28 I Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy I Gerdes, Kennedy I Gerdes, Kennedy April 28, 29 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy June 9, 10 June 11, 12 Kennedy July 11, 12 Gerdes October 20-23 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Hospital for the I November 16, 17 Kennedy Insane of December 16, 17 Gerdes, Kennedy Nebraska, 1916, January 14, 15 Hordes, Kennedy Norfolk February 1-6 Gerdes, Kennedy April 17, 18 Kennedy June 9, 10 Gerdes. Holcomb, Kennedy July 17, 18 Kennedy August 3, 4, 5 Gerdes October 31 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Nov. 22, 23, 24 Gerdes, Kennedy 1915, Jan. 17, 18, 19 I Gerdes </seg>
            <seg id="p078">46 OFFICIAL VISITS TO STATE INSTITUTIONS— (Continued) Date of Visit Institution By Whom Made 1914, December 31 1915, February 26 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy March 17 April 16 April 23 April 28 ■"Jerde Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy May 4 May 29 June 5 June 9 June 21 Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy Nebraska School for the Deaf, August 12 Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy August 24 August 26 Omaha Kennedy September 8 November 1 December 7 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy 1916, January 20 March 24 April 12 June 12 August 31 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy October 6 Kennedy November 2 Gerdes, Holcomb, Kennedy 1914, December 18 1915, Februrary 27 June 22 June 29 July 28 Gerdes, Kennedy Kennedy Kennedy Gerdes. Holcomb, Kennedy Kennedy Kennedy Kennedy November 2 November 13 Nebraska Home for Dependent Children, 1916, January 12 Gerdes, Kennedy Gerdes, Kennedy March 8 | Gerdes, Kennedy j Gerdes. Holcomb, Kennedy ' Kennedy May 23 Lincoln June 27 September 14 September 26 Gerdes. Kennedy November 15 Kennedy </seg>
            <seg id="p079">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS BUDGET REPORT AND DETAILED STATEMENT Estimated appropriations for all Institutions and Board. Under the jurisdiction of the Board of Commissioners of State In - stitutions. Biennium beginning April 1, 1917, and ending March 31, 1919. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 48 HI IK. I I REPORT AND I&gt;K I \ 1 1 . K I • KTATKMENT OF ESTIMATED AI'I'Kcl FRIATIONS FOR THE B1KNMI M BKIilNMMi APRIL 1. 1*17. (Ml K\I)IN«. MARCH SI. IKI9 A NBHltASKA INKTIT1TION FOIt FKKBI.K XIINIlKIl YOITH BEATRICE. NKKKASKA rtaily average inumii' population IH-i-vimIkt MM Pally average inmate population No'einlier. l'.Hti I»nil&gt; average Inmate population. IMS Hally average inmate popu 1» t i&lt; i u . lllll' Mf n«il&gt; average inmate population fur the l&gt;ic miiuiii ending »ln«Wl :«•. !»!«.. 4M Dally average number m officers anil employees November, luir .-,1 1M1-"V nppropritition for- current expeimei* *1VhI«i).(&gt;(I i:\peinifii to \. He in'., i :ui luKi I1IMIRL91 Ilnhilii-e nn**xpeiH&gt;(1 % 35744.1* Salaries and Wape* Kxiienileil for tip veiir emllng |T»» —111 I :'i '. 1!&gt;ir. » ?471»J!I Kx|mmiiIi-iI fur the year ■■inline NVvi'HiIht :',i nil '4xtm.r,:&gt; •4X«l..7i Kxpended for the hiennlnni enilini; Novemlter :tl). 1&lt;n&lt;; * 4»rc&gt;8.!W General Repairs — Kx|&gt;en&lt;le&lt;i for the yt.ir emlllia Noven'ier .1' VIV- &lt; 17&gt; .'1 Kxpenileil for the y^:ir t-i ilinu NoxeuilH-r .{i Till "J4."V1.:!1 ■J4.-,i.:u Kxpemleil fur the hieiiiiiuin ending Ni veinltcr :ttl. \'Mt\ * 4171".. T i: other Malutenaiii-e - Kx|»eiHie&lt;l for the year ending Noven*l»er W llll.". * 43191 HI KxjM'nde&lt;! for the ytar ending Novetnlier .Kl. Wl&lt; ♦ ,v.'4«'l.::i: I^'sn ilothiiiK fund iimh m-iount .VWri 'B 471 1.-.4:: Kxpendeil for the liienniiini ending Noveinher 30. I'.Mti % !»2247.24 Total rxprnditarr far tbr hirnBlum rndin- November S*. Itl* *14".H."-,.74 * 147 "Mi Ininnti' MMl per rui»lta i-ost for tbe vcar i'H"v Inmate annual per i^ipita i-ost. exrluding WM4B.WI. rlotklng fund i-nsli iicfount. for tht- year MH6 14&lt;!.7O Inmate Itieiii^iil per «-a l ■ i t-i &lt;*ost. exrltldhlg .&lt;-V14ri.'.t:t. rlntking fund f-iiMh nct'ount. for the hienuiuui 94.31 K.tlmatr&lt;l expendlturr far the kirnnlum Iwiinnln. April I. 191* Salaries and wages * Mnrw.on General repairs lUNH.m. Other iimintHiiHtii-e ULtMnni Total $177&lt;iO«M*t Kase&lt;l &lt; ii e»tiinated average dally population or ."►47 for the liielllifuln. Kxtniordlnary appropriations for the current lilen - i) 1 ii in : For new l.uildingx. eto * 4Snm.(K&gt; Expended to Novemtier SO. 1K16 4"iv..j:: Ralanoe unexpended J$ 7H44.77 Appropriation for purchaae of land _ 4 »MO.0ll Expended - ••00.00 BalalKV Uliexpelliled f KaMaaated extraordinary expeadltarr far Ihr lii»n - nlom fcrilnnln. An- II I. 1*11: For new rottage for girls $ 40000.01 Addition to hospital 1l«yx).(ici Furniture and equipment for cottage and hosnttal SQOO.nti Improvements and equipment for power house and construction of new well 8000.00 Tot ii I K.llm»l&lt;-d Cirmml Total </seg>
            <seg id="p081">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 49 HI IX. KT KKFOKT \M&gt; I)KI \IIKI&gt; HTATKMENT OK EMTIMUEU VITRO PRIATIONM FOB THE BIIWMM BBIIINMMI APRIL I. 1M7. AND KMIIMi MARCH SI. lll&gt; H &lt;;[RI.S- IXIMSTH1 AI. SCHOOL. OEXKVA. XKUKASKA •■'- Ihilly averajre inmate population for the hlenntum ending NoveinlH*r ■*&gt;. Dally imw mini her &lt;if u Hirer** mid employees Nnveiulier. 1W. IT I'.ji hi In f 11 rc\ |»t 1 i'i-i! f TTU3.1I) Salaries nnd WaKf* F:x|K*iMle&lt;l ftir llie re:ir eiHlinv Noveuilwr •'*'. 1 ' • 1 "■ * TTl'l.T Kxp«'rni«»*l ftT ll 1 * 1 yfjir ending Noveiul»er '-UK V.»1C 7rtT."i.7 7B7.-.T: Kxpt'tiiled for tit* tiiciMituni ending Ntivrinlier :&gt;". l'.lKi $ IMUI (■eiieral Kepuir&gt; Expended for the ye»r endinu N"oveml&gt;er 'V&lt; l!»1"i « HW..TI Bxpendfd for the year ending November -to. 1010 1714(4 1714 14 Kx|H-i.d&gt;'d fur the liiennirni enillni.' Nnvenilier :u '. I'.MH * MU other Maintenance — Expended for the year endini.' Nnveint.er :«i. l'.M.I « ZnTINJV Expended for the year ending X.nemWr *i. !!•!« ■J-J4.*!.nL&gt; ■m&amp;.rri Kxieli«led for tile liiertiinni erdl.-g NoAHinler rv», tftltt Tola! rxpeadltarr far the blraalmn frtl t Navembrr W, l»l« ( MMM Inmate nnnual per capitn io»t for the yen"- VI" * aot!.."&gt;" Inmate annual per capita cost for the year Ml :t)n .V Inmate hienninl l»*r inpitn 10M fur tie liieunluui fCS.14 K&gt;timalr&lt;l r«nr&gt;dllarf far the biranlum brslauii.-.c »pril I. III! 1 !: Salaries and watcea $ 1KKIUIXV Oneral repairs inclndlne repainting of main hnildlng and porch 4.'»»U V &gt; Other maintenance 4**X)«n Totnl « i:.SOXH0 Ilil-wil ■■•! e"tim;ited average dally population of 114 for the hienniuin. Extraordinary appropriation for the current lilen ilium : For sewage disposal plant anil laundry equip - ment '■ -f .V»*Kt ()») Expeniled to Xoremlier ». 1»1C MHl.TTi Kalam-e unex|iended * l.'i.ii Rsllmated extraordinary rxaradlturr far the Men. nium hellnnirr '"'" '. '*■''■ For rattle anil hay Imrn. Img house, chliken hoiuu-. new holler and other permanent improvements «. * tHiOlino Estimated Graad Tatal * 74l»»nO Dnllv HVt-ra^t* inmate population lK*&lt;t*in)»t*r. H'11 1 » h i I &gt; ;iviTii«** Inmate population Xoveml&gt;er. l«.»lt; Daily iivpraire ininnte population, ltU;~» Dally :i\tT:i^H Inmate populatUm. 191tt I'.IW :i|iprii|irl:itloii for riim-nt f\|iensfs * WM0.0 Kxiieiiiiwl la Hmatii :«&gt;. 1011; .-ii74«.»i « MM </seg>
            <seg id="p082">50 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF HI MET RBPORT AND DETAILED MTATEMKNT OF KSTIVATI.I) AFI'KU PBIATIONS FOB THE BIKNMIM BKUINMNU APRIL I, 1»17, AND ENDING MARCH SI, 1»1» &lt;■ NKliHASKA SUMMERS' AND SAILORS' HOMK, HCltKKTT, XKHKASKA Daily average inmate population December, 1W4 _ tttt Dally average Inmate population November, lMft. 417 Dally average Inmate population, 1915 _ 443 Dally average Inmate population, 1U16 407 407 Dally average Inninir population, for the bienniiim ending November 30. 19 HI MB Dally average number of officers and employees November. Wlti 1915 appropriation for current expense* XJKaJCum K\p.-iiiletl to Nuveml&gt;er 3D, 191« _ 1.VM4O.4T IiiilMiii-i' unexpended f S6579.5.'! Salaries and Wages — Kxpended for the year I'liding November 30. IMS-. $ 3S423.K Kxpendeil for tilt- year euiling November 30. 1918. l"T548i4t! K\|&gt;eii&lt;lfd for tlie hieiiiiluin ending Novemlier '■'•». r.ili! $ i'SiTJ.irj lieueral Repairs— Kxpeuded for Hie year ending November 30, MI * 142US Kxpended for the year ending November 3&lt;&gt;, HUB ■'■"« m Kx|&gt;ended for the Wieunltitu ending Noveml&gt;er .'W. V.*U\ .&lt; Wl'T uttuT Mflinteuance Kx|&gt;ended for the year eliding Novenil»er 3tl. r.M."i $ 6S7T^.K7 ?:xpended for the year ending November 3(), 1!&gt;1« 7«3Sm.!t!i Kxpeuded for the Meniiilini ending Novemlter 30, 1910 $14Olti3.S&lt;) Total expenditure for the biennium eading November 3», 1»1B «»i:iti:i.4ii Inmate annual per i-apita cost for the year liil.'i 4 2ICI.H1 Inmate annual per capita cost for the year 1916. L1f7.S&gt;&lt; Inmate biennial per capita cost for the blennluui 4TUH KMimatsd expeBditarr for the hieanlum beclMlag April I. 1»I7 Salaries und wages _ $ MOOO.U) (ieneral repairs, plumbing, wiring, painting. etc 1SO0O.WI Other maintenance lMGOO.tK) Total JjaaiO.iw Based on estimated average dally population of 425 for the bieunium. Kxtranrdinary appropriation for the current bien - nium : For new buildings and Improvements J$ xukmhi Expended to November 30. 1916 _.... STJI 37.-.0 Halanoe unexpended f 7!16L'.44 KatlmMed extraordinary expenditure for the blen - nium beclaalag April 1, Mil For addition to boiler house and new machinery % 13000.00 KMimaled Grand Total CSTiMMH! </seg>
            <seg id="p083">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 51 H M SEFOIT VM&gt; DETAILED STATEMENT OK KHTI'M ITKD APPRO - PRIATIONS FOR THE BIKNMl M !(!■(. ISMM. APRIL' 1. 1»I", AND ENDING MARCH SI, 1*19 I&gt; INfiLESIDE HOKI'ITAI. KOK TI1K INSANE, INGLJCSIDK, NEBRASKA Daily ■Ttragja iiiiiuiif population I &gt;i-«-i'in &gt;i«t. r.'ll Dally average Inmate population November. MM Daily average inmate population I'M". Daily ;i\«t:il* Inmate population l'.uc Daily ■rrracc luattt MtMiM fur the hiennium ending Noveuilier 30. Daily average uuin)x*r of oflWrs ami employees Novemtwr. 1'Ot; .. 196 1915 appropriation (or current expenses MUfOMUt Expeucfeil to November :1O, 101C 3M073.3R M:i l:tn&gt;T nnexpenileil .$11." 12«.«E Salaries and Wages Expended for tile year tmUmg Novemlier .1). RW * WMAO Expendeil for the yeiir eudintr N'ovenitKT m&gt;. HUH ■an i • Expended for tlie l»teiiiilnra ending Nnveinl»er •*¥). 1!&gt;16 MMUI Qeueral Repairs- Expended for the year ending N»veinl&gt;er M). MI * :&gt;41.7) Kxpended for the year ending Noveint&gt;er :m». li»l»!. XII. SK Expended for the bieiinliini endine NovemlMr SI). 1916 * rM ■ Other Malntenanre- Expended for the year •nding N.nenilier :«, 1»15 $iaK»2« Expended for the year ending November .*M), ll»m. U9S13.M K\p&lt;-iidccl fir the bleniilnm eudiiiE Novemlier :M. lOltl KMOO72.12 Total rxpriwliturr far the hlrniilym rndiag Xivraikrr M, 1»1« $3S4S7S.7S Inmate annual per capita cost for the year 1»13 $ 1TO.&lt;B Inmate nniiunl per capita io»t for tliu year l!Mi; _ 14B.M Inmate biennial ]ier capita cost for the bienniuu) 33B.TO Estbnated rxprndltarc for the hu-nnlum Ixginnlng April 1, 111" Salariew and wages. *144i«»i.l»- General repairs K.(WM«) Other maintenance. le*s eitimated receipts from patients, *300no.OO. y«800n.0(&gt; Total «:CK*«Mt.)M&gt; Btsed on estimated average dally population of 1130 for tbe biennium Extraordinary appropriation for the current bien - nium : For septic tank and sewage disposal Expeuded to Novemlier :«&gt;, 1(118. $ »4JUH«. | I'Knai Rniance unexpended K.lim.ted extrmordlBary expmdltyiw far the blea - nlum brginniag April 1. 1*11: For sanitary sewer and sewer work, addition to power house, and for boiler, pumps, ct&lt; . K»tlmated &lt;irand Tola! </seg>
            <seg id="p084">52 SECOND BIENNIAL REPOkT OK HI IMiKT KKI'OKT AND HKI All Kll STATEMENT OK KsTIMAIKI) AITKU - PMATIONN FOR THK BIKNMI M BK«.I\N1N&lt;. APRIL I, 1*17. AMD ENDING MARCH tl, ■•!• R STATK IXIUSTKIAL SCHOOL. KKA11XKY, XK1U1ASKA BiVHM0B illllliite ]io]iuhit it M Dei-elulier, 1!U4 JW'I average inmate i&gt;o|iti lutlon Xoveinlier. MWO M average Inmate population. I'.*!."* "Ji&gt;» -I'.' B average inmate population, litlli 1** infill iinn.-itc population for tlit* liieuniiiui eiulhiK NoreinlM*r -Mi. l'.tlfV... 11H&gt; tniTHire ihiiiiIht of ol!i&lt;t»rs mikI *»iuploytH*s Xmawr. ISM— M M IMS appropriation for rnrreat hxih-iuk-s fllTTJU.im l.\pi-ml.-.| to XovpihIht :«(. 1!H« W1W.S-J ltltlHIIre UIM'XIWlMlfit # £tVki.lS snlnrl«&lt; and Wages K\|H-inltHl for rhf venr cncliim Xuwhi M, IMA * 22T/£!»! Kx|m»imIh&lt;1 for tin* y«*jir immUii^ NoveinUt-r :M». 1'JUi 'J|:C!K.4)1 Kxpeiiilcil for iIk- i.iHiiiihiin .-iHlinir Novi'ihIht :;i . I ■ 1 1 &lt; ; * 4:«K&gt;u.!tl li.neral lii-pair&gt; — Kv|(.iiiifd for the .vein iikIIiik Novftiilx-r W, MIS. * M87.43 Kxjgpnded for the year eiiillnit XoyeinlH-r :*&gt;. Ml 11IKX7 Kxpemlt'4l for the lileiiiiiuin Hiiiltim Xttveiiilier *U'. r&gt;lti f 4i7*i.-12 '"Iiit Mainteuauee Kxiwinlfil for tilt- y«ir puiIIuk XoveiiiUer -io, lMl"i * 4"c'&gt;1.4." Kxpiridfil for the year enilinn Xoveinlier :to. MM :t:i&gt;4.iu: Kxprnileil for the liielinlam enilinj.' Xovcml&gt;er Ml * Ts'iUa.lK Tata! i-»iM-»di«urr far th«- blrnnium rn.lin« NovrntM-r U. l»l« &lt;r.1i-*:!.:il liini.ite iimiual per capita iwt for tlie year ML * rlx.'A". {innate aiiuaal per rapita cost for the year I'.tlo. JlHi.:Bi innate lilennial |&gt;er i-apltn i-ost for the Ipiennlliui Mil K.llmalrd rxprndllurr far Ihr blrnnium breinninie April I. Itli SularteK mid w«ires * &lt;»*»uerHl repair* I It her in.-iinteiiiiiic-e l..|iil|.in&lt;'iil and mipplies f&gt;ir trade ilepurlmeins I 4-MMHI.IMi 4IKN&gt;.IK&gt; smrilO.IKI J.MXMHI Kaavd on eRtimated average daily popiiliitlnn af M for tbe biennium. *!S»WW«l.t»! Kxtriinrilinjiry itppmpriatioii for current bk»n- iiiiini . N"»&lt;- r:»&lt;lm»trd rxlraordiury rxpendltan for tkr Mra- nlum iH-nlnnin, April 1. l»17 : Fc r hay »n&lt;l cattlf hnm. anil hot' honne f .VMM MX «14&lt;*««l.l« K.limalrrt &lt;.r«»d T»t«l </seg>
            <seg id="p085">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 53 HUJH-KT BBPOBT AND DETAILED STATEMENT UF KMTIMATKD VI'I'Kil PBIATIONH FOB THE BIF.NNUM BEGINNING . APKIL I, 1»17, AND ENDING MARCH SI. l»l» F— HOSPITAL FOR TlBEKCVUtlS, KBAKXIJY, NKBKASKA Daily average inmate |mi|iuIh1 l.m Decemlie*. l'.»14... n Daily average Inmate population Xuvemhor. WW. I Hilly nver»Ke Inmate population \\*\~&gt; n daily average iimiati- population UN liiiily average Inmate |&gt;i&gt;|&gt;u In t Ion fat the Mennluni fluting November .10, 1»1« .14 1 &gt;Hil y aygraajt aMahaf of crttiirs anil employees Novemlier. l'.tlti 14 M I'-'l"' appropriation for current excuses * 4i&gt;4OO.I» KipnM t" Novpiiilicr :U). MM .DAMI.-.T HilhllMT UIIH\|N &gt; IMlfll * iiast.n Salarien aud Waiftt Kx|M&gt;n&lt;lfil for the year Mattes N'ovhiiiIht :»■. 1MB * itTi"-' 11 Kx|i«-uilfil for tllr rear ■■iiiIIiik Nonibtl M, l'.tlti T3B8 »:. Kxiifliiltxl for Hit- lili'iiiiillin hikIIiii: Xovi'iii!»t II. l!H"i II..-.* ... * Central Repairs— K\|&gt;fiiileil for th'e year ciiilinu XovciiiIht IB, |M&amp; % 336.(11 Kxpen&lt;le&lt;t for the year ciiilhit; Novemlx-r :i'i. I'.'U. MtM !»14.!H K\lH-liili'&lt;l fur Hie liielinillin I'liililiu- Novelnlier M. 1'Mli * other Maintenance- Kxpeuded for the year ending Noveuilier :ti». I'M'. * ll.1IKl.!ICi Txpenrted for the year ending Xorvaihn 10 V.tU- i:.4&lt;»!4tl i:.4&lt;»!4tl Kxim-imIpiI for the Itit'linitllll endinie Niivenitier -'til, l'.llrt * total r\|&gt;rnililurr fur the birnnium rndlnn Nntrmkrr *l, l»l« * Inmate annual per i-apita rost for the rexr Mil $ .; .i '■■: Illlimte anilllill per capita &lt;*ONt for the rear !*• 1 ** •V.-.7 To li'lnate liletinial per raplta rost for the Menninni 1J44.97 K»timated r&gt;p«-nditurr for the birnnium hminninK April I, III* Salaries and wages. * lirroow sini.n farm ma si.vi.tri imwoo Total Biiseil on estimated averflge daily population of MO for the liiciiiiiniu. Kxtraordiliary appropriations for the iiirrent bleu nhim: For liew imildings. ele * ««S».«i Expended to Xovemlxr SO, 19W 141M.T1 italaiK^ unexpended * :!l.Tft^ For laud * Kxpended to November SIK WW .•M.M.I Halnnce uuexpendeil * K.limst.'d extraordinary eipMldllora for fclea - nlam lx-«innln« AprH I. l»11 : For extension of he»t&lt;ug and water mains : re - modeling old pavilion : extension of sewage .lisposal system and water system inrlnd - ing stand-pipe: laying walks: construction and furnishing residence for »u|ierlntendent * l«««l«i J.VKT.IKI For X Ray apparatus &lt;J**"t*nil repair** Furniture, ktt&lt;*ht*u t.&lt;|iif|&gt;iiipiit ami chiuery Other ninltitenuiH*** . * '.14VKUO K.llmalrd &lt;.r»n&lt;i Total f!14MM&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p086">54 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF HI IM.FT BirOIT AMD DETAILED STATEMENT "I KttTIMATKIt M'l-Ri) PK1ATIONS t'HK TNI BIKNMt M Bt(,lN\IM, tl'KII. 1. 1M7. AND EMUMi MAJtTH SI, lilt G— NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOK THE INSANE. LINCOLN. XKBHASK.V Dally average inmate population Deeeiiiher. 1!»14 71s r«aily average inmate population XovemtxT, l»ltt. T.%4 LHiily average inmate population. I'M.". Dally average inmate population, 11*16. 743 Dally average inmate population for the hleiiniuin emling Xovemlier '■*&gt;. l'.'ltt. . 733 Dally average number of officers and employee* Xoveniher. MM 108 I»15 appropriation for current expenses *"&gt;52tKI00 Expended to November so. lftlC L&lt;-JS41L'..Vi Balance unexpended $ SCT^T^T Salaries and Wage* — Expended for the year I'liding November 30. W1.1 f K".!«i .') Expended for the year ending Xi vember 3&lt;&gt;, 1M6. _... 4KiMi.1iii Expended for the hlennliim endlni; Xoremlier '!0. I'.tlu * 'isr.ffl.14 &lt;&gt;&lt;-nvrml Repair* — Expended for the year ending Noveuiher .10. l'.lli'i $ tKEKl.Ts Expended for the year ending Xoveinliir :!&lt;), 1!H6 :3I!IO.:!1 Expended for the Mennium endine Xoveml&gt;er 90. 1016 $ MN1.0U Other Maintenance — Expended for the year ending Xovenilier HO. 1915 * Wi.TlT.iM Expended for the year ending November 30, 1916 WB0-J..MI Expended for the Meniiium ending November 30. 1016 HMUI Total riprndilurr far thr hironlum rndlnn Navmbrr SO, 1*111 *J-7sm ." Inmate annual per capita cost for the year 1M5 H L"im.:tl Inmate annual per capita cost for the year 1916 V.r.'.~it Inmate biennial i&gt;er capita cost for the bieniiiura .'BfJ.IH K&gt;tlmslrd rxpemliturr for the blrnnlum beclnalac AprU 1, Ifl7 Salaries and wages _. *102000.(»( Oeneral repairs lOOOO.io rher maintenance, less estimated receipts from patients and &lt;■,, unties KOOnn.OO 196000.01) Total - *3&lt;iHI»«1.(»i Baa^d on estimated avernge dnlly popuiatliui of H00 for the hiennium. Eitraordiuary appropriation for the current Men nium: For new building : $ 301X10.00 Expended to Noveinl.er 311, Wl« :. 29013ft", Balance uuex|iended 4 986.0fi K&gt;ttmatrd rxtraordlnary expenlltaire far the him nlam bectaniac April 1. 1*11: For construction and furnishing of new hos - pital liuilding _ flOOOOO.OO For removal and reconstruction of green -house 301)0.00 For construction and furnishing of building to house employees 40000.00 Total K.llm«trri Grand Total </seg>
            <seg id="p087">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 55 Bl IX. KT KKI'OKT AND DETAILED STATEMENT U&gt; E8TIMATKD APPRO - PRIATIONS FOB THE BIENNUM BEGINNING AI'Bll. I, 1»17, AND ENDING MARCH SI, ltl» H ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL, LINCOLN, NKBItASKA Daily average inmate population December, imi XCB » average inmate population. November, 191S _ _ _ IX average inmnte population. l'Jir&gt; _ 10* D«lly average inmate population, l'Jl« tt» r&gt;ally average Inmate population for the liteiinium ending November .K&gt;. Hill... lt» Daily average number of officers and employees Noveiulier. 191(1 4fl 1915 appropriation for rurrent expenses 4 SOttSUKi Expended to November 30, 191« 9tBl2;£i • MBM unexpended 4 10107. 7 1 - Kalarles and Wages — Kxpendeil for the year ehillui: Novfinlier :». 1»15. * 1NM.;; Expended for the year ending November 30, M&gt;18 1877V.35 K\| fiiileil Tor the liielllilum eiiillng NovhiuIkt 30, 19141 9 SSTMLflR tit neral Repairs Kxpendeil for tile year eiiiliuir Noveiulier :«&gt;, 1!&gt;1.\ 4 UR« Expended for the year ending November .«». 1!»1« 1338.37 Kxuended Tor the tileiiniuin emlinir November 30. 1016 $ MMJB Other Maintenance — Expended for the year endini; November 30, IMS * 27437.00 Expended for the year ending November 30. lUld 3MB.M Kxnended for the btennhim ending Novemlier .10, I'.itr, $ (SJ^m.04 T.l.l rxprndllare far Ihe blranium r.dl»« Xnnatai M, lilt $103071. 47 Inmate annual per capita cost for the year 1!H5 4 430.58 Inmate nitiiunl \n i r &lt;apltn &lt;-osi for the year 191*1 ■■ — 41*7.4." I ii mn tf hieiiiiltil jN»r cupita msi for the Menniuin S." 74 K.llm»tr&lt;l exprnditorr far the hirpnium WiinnlDK April I, 1117: Salaries and wage* 4 37300.«&gt; (ieneral repairs (WOOOtl Other maintenance 80Ti«0.()il Total $ia»»*&gt;.nn Based on estimated average daily population of 140 for the blenninm. Extraordinary appropriation for the current blen - nioin \ For furnishing new hospital building 4 naai.iai Expended to November 30, 1916 43K.1S Balance unexpended ♦ MR7.X! K&gt;tlnuUed extra«rdlaanr n t n«tiiT for the Me» - nlum beslBBlnc April 1, Itl7: For fire escapes and fire protection $ OnOO.00 For laundry and kitchen equipment— 3.100.00 Total ....- — « MOO.00 Estimated Ciravnd Total $135n«)(l0 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">56 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF HI I" t r KKI-OKI AMU DKTA1I.KI) NTATKMKNT OK KMTIM %TKI&gt; VI'I'Ku PKIATIONH FOR THE RltNMI M BKUINMMi M KM I. 1117, AND KMHXi MARCH SI. 1*111 I STATE I'EXITHXTIAUY. 1.1 X&lt; ( H.X. NEKICASKA Da'h" ii*ernire i innate |m |Milat i&lt;m I iei-eml»er. V.I14 X I lially average Inmate population Xoveinlier, V-Mii Ml Daily njpi-.'ik'i- inmate population. I'.'l." :;4* Dally average Inmate population. BMB I &gt;a l» nviTii^** tniuiite popvlatftoa for the Meniilum ending Xo*eiul»er :m i'.ti«. ... :mr Daily average numlter of oltt&lt;*ers and employees XuivmIwi. l'.'lt 1 :hi MS appropriation ftir rurrent expeiiMPK tlHMrjDM Kx|M-nileil to NoVHinlM-r :N&gt;, l'.tlii \M:lt:;s: llnhil'f li lif\|M*nileil * lilENtt.77 Salaries ami Waves kx|HMi(leii for tl «* ye«r emllug NnveinlK-r 'M . VM'i &lt; 21MKI.2h K\pi-inlei! far Ik* jeiir enilini.' jlwirtu H. Itlfl 2B73X.("i ■anauM K\|hmm1hiI for . lu' liiennium enili:'^' Noxemlier '.'•' l'Mli * .7.IT.H. liencral Ut-piiirs Expended for the year ending; Noveinlier IB, llil."i f ££.'4.W Expended for the year eudinu Nnvemlier M. I'.Hl IK» Flx|teri1ed for tile Itiehlilnm en&lt;lin»: N» vemlier :ll . l'.lili * ::;i. -.-.■'» t&gt;ther Malntenam-e — Expended for the year ending Xoveinlter :u&gt;. IMS X r.iri-,4.41 Expended for the year endinic Xoveniher :to, 1!»1I' titis.-m !&gt;:, Kxpeitilt'il ftT the liien ilium cinliftv Novt'inher :: : t IBM ssi-jtri "•"..:!•; l.t .1 rMiimlilarr far thr I Irnninm tndiac Ntvrmkfr M. l*l« *|s'.l-.1.-...V.l iTuin does not iiH-inde the expelulitnres of the I la nil Irraft Furniture t miipany, a prison in&lt;ln&gt;try. These amount to *ML':tti.'.Ml. mtii were met in part from the apei-lal apprt'priation for the estaldishinent of prison industries. II. R. Ift'l. and In part from receipts of the business, turned into the institution rush fund. I Inmate annual per rapita rosi for the year l'.il.'i Inmate annual per capita roxt for the year I'.ilil ,'.M Inmate biennial per rapita rost for tin- liiennium 1 t»t'matrd &gt;x::erdlturr far Ihr hlrnnium brciBBlnc AprH I, ISli Salaries and waves $ IL1XI.IXI Ueiieral repairs SO»I."(P Parole* and disrba rges. oUtre ami ■rhmil nap pile* and rontintfent !i|4l I I Other maintenance ir&gt;4iim.(N Total Cscrj-Jii.mi ItasiMl on estimated average daily population of 400 for the hienuiuiu. Extraordinary appropriation for the rurreut liieu - nium: For prison industries and new power plant HHJM'l Ex|iended to Xovenilier :«). HUB 7H4.M.74 Balance unexpended f »%4Klii Kattmatrd exlrmardlaar&gt;' rxpeadltarr far Ibe biea - nimn tx-cinninc April 1, 1*1 &lt;: For farm machinery $ 12UI.UI For new laundry building and equipment UXIuO.lli: For new dormitory llMOO.OO For purchase of 130 acres of farm land a lmni Total * toaaja ■estimated GraMl Total * m&gt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p089">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 57 lil IM.KT KKI-OKI AND MM Ml H. STATEMENT OK K- I HI \ I H&gt; VlfKO PKIAT1ONN FOR TIIK BIKNNUM BKIilNNIM. AI'RIl. I, 1M7. AND KNI1IM, MARCH SI, lll» I »n il v average inmate population, l'.tl'i Daily average inmate population. wit; •&gt; Ihiilv average iiinmn- p« m 1j»u&lt; n for tl'e liietinitiin himIIhk Xoveinlwr 'M:. IVM_ 94 Daily average huiiiUt of officer** ami employnes, Xurpmbrr, IWM . !• 1'ilJ appropriation for current ex|&gt;en&lt;es * +."VJ.*il).txl Kxpended to Xoveniber «), l»l« :»»ti4.."i»i HiiU&gt;»cc imrxi^niliMl i $ tVEM.44 Sufariei! and Waifeo Kipemleal for the year ei'ilinu' NotmuIw "■&lt; . 1*13 * .VM.ia Ki|M*nile«l for the yeiir eniliiiK Noveinlier It, l'.'K' STMJt! Kspendi'il fur the liienniuiii &lt;-ii&lt;liii&gt;; Xovemlier ."10, Ml * 111144. if. General Repairs Bxpeiid«l for tlie year eudiliK XoTeiulier -Ml, 1»1"V * I.'r.-O.sl Kxpended for the year enilini; Xonabn :». 1»1« 2M3.M Kxpended for the lilellliilliu ellillUK Noveinl&gt;er '■*'. Ml * XH2JV other Maintenance- Kxpended for the yeiir eliiliuu Noveinlicr 3D. 1WIS-. * I IO'iT.'.'-" l:ti«)..w r/xpende&lt;l for the liienniuiii elidiliK Xoveinl&gt;er :t&lt;). 1!»1« * IMJWT.'JI Tatal ripriulltarr for Ihr Hirnniun, rndinx VovfmWr M. ■■■• * WHUM &lt; !t:r^ a Inmate annual per capita cok! for the year HM * ■*-'•"? Inmate annual |»-r enpita cost f. r the year IHi a SSK !•■ X\- I.', iMMti lilenulnl per enpita i-ost fir the liieiiniuin IH4.!rj K-timatrd r&gt;prnditurr far tkr blnilm ImiI.dIde April I. M*1 Salaries and wa)fex * 1 'V«!.&lt;M lienentl repairs fKII"! other uiiiiliteiiiince - :B«riO.O!l * 4ir«i.iii Total Bawd on estimated average dally populiitio.i of TO for the blennlum. Kxtraordiuary appropriation for the current Iden ninm: For new ilnirv liarn and silo , Kx'pended to Xoveniber 3&lt;&gt;, lilltt * -sayaa &lt; 3M10.MI Balanaf iinexpende«l K.linvncr.i extraordinary rxix-ndilurr f»r tkr bi*» - nlum brarlnninc April 1. Mil For tire escnpes and fire protection, well. puni|i. boilerR. machinery and lmproreineiit-&gt; ti&gt; |&gt;ow it house Kslimatrd Urmad Tatal K — XKBKASKA I NIM S rill A I. HOME, MII.KOKl). NKBHASKA ]&gt;nily average inmate population D*M*Miil»er, 11*14 4B Iiail.v averajre inmate population Xoveiul»er, 1H1C _ . •* ExprnuM for thr veiir wttttmm No\ciiiI»t linn. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">58 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Bl IX. KT KM'iiKI AND DBTAILBD kTATKMBNT OF EHTIXATED APPRO - PRIATIONS FOB THI B1KNXUM BEGINNING APRIL 1, 1»17, AND ENDING MABCH SI, 1»1» L— SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, Mil. FOUR NEBRASKA Dally average inmate population December. 1!&gt;14 _ Ill Dally average Inmate population November, r.tltj. „ 133 Daily aiciaur inmate population, 191."i 115 Daily average Inmate population, 1916 116 IHilly average inmate population for the Mennimn ending Noveinli-er -'M&gt;. MM— 113 Daily iivern;re number of officers ;iih1 employee*. November, l*!Htf 26 1915 appropriation for current expense* * BMO.M Expended la Novellllier :t(l, 1916 ."ifiri;V4.44 llnhiuce iihi'Xpfliileil * J934Ti.!Mi Salaries and Wages — Kzprnited f.-r the yr»r cikIIhc NoviMiii.cr .K). MM * 8411.1.* Hxj»elHlt.il for lh«* ye:ir etuliim N&lt; i vi&gt;uiln'r 'MK 1!»HI „ B324. !'■' Kxpendpil for the liieniiiillli cnillne N'c veiulier 30. 1916 $ 177.TS..14 Oeneral Repairs — Kxpciidol for the year endlni.' November .10, l»ir&gt; * L'lw Expended for the year ending November .10. 1916. k 74.3i I:\|i.t.1.,i far thr Mnrln rrnMca November ::i&gt;. 1!»16 * :a»l'!.::i Other Malntenaui'e- Expended for the year endini: Ililfsii M, 191."5 1 2L'412.Os t^xpended for the year imhIIiiu Nuv«&gt;inf«*r 3(&gt;, li»1«[ 26157JRI Expended fur the l&gt;ieli liilltn e 1 1 1 1 i 1 1 u' November .U). 191)1 * 4fCiOn.*"r T»lal rxiM-mlilurr for the klraalam radiac Nnvrmbrr M. 1»1« $ rtl.TflS..",; Inmate annual per capita cost for the year 191.1 .-. f •-irj.14 Inmate annual per capita cost for the year l»lfl :tV( 4J Inmate bienninl per capita cost for the biennium I10VJ0 Kstimnlf.1 rv|M-nillturr for thr hlrnrium IxclnninK April 1, l!il": Salaries and wages f ilflOMKt Oeneral repairs _ _ 5W0.00 Other in:iinten:iiice fi.VXXI.C&gt; Total _ $ »!&lt;rMMI Based on estimated avernire daily population at 140 for the biennium. Extraordinary appropriation for the current bien - nium: For nen* laundry building nud fi-uipuient t imMltl.oo Expended to November 30, l!»Ht HM3.011 Balance unexpended $ 34*4M&gt;1 EMImstrd rxlraardinary rxprnditurp for thr lilrn - nlum hneinnlnic April 1, I*!': For ii.irn. — rfcl-n ak*4 tmt I ■• ■ taaa Kutimatrd C-raad Total </seg>
            <seg id="p091">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 59 HI IM.KT RKI'OHI AND DETAILED STATEMENT OF ESTIMATED APPRO - PRIATIONS FOB THE BIKNNH M BEGINNING AI'KII. 1. 1WJ. AND ENDING MARCH SI, !•!• M— NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND, NEBRASKA CITY. NEBRAUU Daily average inmate popnlatiou December, 1914 ■ Daily average inmate population November, 1916. H Dally average Inmate population. 1915 — M Dally average inmate population, lUlti ■ Iiullv iivithbc Iniiintc poinihii fir The bu-iiniiim ending Noventlx-r :tt). l'.Hi. Daily average number of officers and employees) Novcinlier, r.'ltl 1915 appropriation for current expenses J$ 4BGMMNI Expended to November 30. l»lft 38381.78 Expended to November 30. 191ft 38381.76 Balance unexpended $ 11O1&amp;24 It.ihiin •- Unix pen Jed _ 4 11O18J4 Salaries and Wages — l-Apt'iiilcil for the year ending November 30, 1915 $ ISS-M.*) Kx|iemle&lt;l for th» year •■inline November 30, 1916 li564.70 Salaries and Wages — Kxi»'ii&lt;leii for the year ending November 30, 1»I5 4 l^:'.4&lt;i.-Hi KxiK-uiioi fir th« year cjnliii).- November 30, 1916 12364. 7«S Expeudetl for the biennluui ending November :»&gt;. Ml $ JV.xil.lG General Repairs — Expended for the year ending November 30, 1915 4 K£I*.U Expended fur the year ending November 30, 1916. _ 9M.7A Expended for the biemiimu ending Nuremlier :!0, ISM f 2MKJK General Repairs — Expended for the year ending November 30. IMS * 1238.41 Kxpendeil for the year ending November 30, 1918.. 884. ."H Kxpendfil for the bieuuiuui ending November :'J&gt;. 1918 f ZMKJll 1 Other Maintenance — Expended for the year ending Noveml&gt;er .Hi. IMS I 11011. T:t Other Maintenance — Expended for the year ending November 31), MM ll«4.-..:t!» Expended for (he bienniiim ending November .10, 1MB $ 228B7.12 Tot»l rxpciKliturr for th» birnnium rndlni Noumkrr M. ltl« * 49R61.M Inmate annual per capita cost for the year 1915 V Vtl^it Inmate annual per ca~plta cost for the year 191tt — VM. 4*i Inmate biennial per capita cost for the Meuniuin IVS.1I 491.441 975 h.limutril rxprndltnre far thr l.irnnium krsiaaix April I, l»l" Salaries and wages * STiOmoO General repairs 4CIU0.(«&gt; Equipment and supplies for vocational depart Equipment and supplies for vocatl KOOOO ments _ _ 1OT10.00 ther maintenance - - 280U0.W Other maintenance K»lim;i|p&lt;l l.ranil T.itnl - * Ml '• Bn»e«l on estimated average daily populntinn of ■ for the bienniiim. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">60 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Bl IX. KT KKIOK1 AMI DKTAU.KI) M ATKMKN I Of h.MHIM I l&gt; APPRO - PRIATIONS FOB THE BIKWIIM BK(il&gt;MN(i XI'KII I, 1117, AND ENDING MARCH SI. !•■» X— HOSIMTAL FOB TIIK INSANE OF NKBUASKA, XOltKOI.K. XKBRAHKA Daily average inmate population DiMMhtr, I'.tl4 tM Daily average inmate population Noreti»lx&gt;r, 11116 HT Daily average inmate population. IMA 47^ W Itsifv average inmate population. 1016 Daily average inmate | opuiation for the liifiiniiiin fiiilinir Xoveinliei SO, mm lot: Daily average number of oflii-ers and employees. November. KM .-.7 181."&gt; appropriation for current excuses *1S-,7(I: '.I-' Bxpended to Xoveuil»er :S0, lttiti. 1.1MKW.2T MiWV uni\pfliile(l * anosi: Salariex and Wages- K\pei!cifd for thf v&lt; :ir eiidiui.' Xoveiiilur :«&gt;. I'.H.'i $ :l+4:t7.!&gt;7 I ■ \peiiili-il for tlif vc.ir t'liiiilin Xi veiulipr K&gt;. l'.'ll' :t"i(l &lt; -H.74 XKKH.T4 Expended for the liieuniuin » TiM-^^l Kxi'tMiiled for the hieiiniuiu ending Xoyemlier :v. 11116 * MKJM Other Maintenanre — Ex|»ended for the year endinj; Xovenilier :W), HM.V * .VViCN. ■ar.ur.1 js Expended for tl:e Itieniiiitin eudh.tr Xoveinlier '■'•!' l'-'it; *lir)477.rj Total r \p&lt; -illiurr for the birnnium rndinjt Nntfaibrr M, 111* flMNfB.MI liunati' annual |tr i-apita i-ost for the year l'-M-'i * I'.M.fJ lKvai Inmate biennial |ter i-apita rost for the hieiitiinin Kutlmatrd r xp. ..ililure for thr hi. nnium brclnninK April I, 1DI7 Salaries and wages Genaral repairs lltlier niahit. Maine, lexs eitiuiateil recelptx from patients (iriM'.MU Total KaMMl on estimate*) average daily population of 650 for the Mennium. Extraordinary appropriations for the enrrent liien nir in: • ■onstriK-tint- and furnishing new building $ ttmoii.uo Expended to November 3(1. MM j:!T.^7.iH j:!T.^7.iH Balance unexpended t r*t7-.'.:«i For SO acres farm land .* aaaou ♦ Expended to November 'Ml. l'.HH. WiO.Cll Kalam-e unexpendeil * K.llm.lr.l exttaardiaar&gt; rxpeadltarr far thr hlrn - nlum hrirlaniBK April 1. 1*11: For extension and impruvement of newer k.vh tern For new bake-shop and store-room For remodeling power plant anil bojler house .VHiKl.iy For ronstrueting and furniabing new buildiug &lt;KM iim Total General Repairs — Expended for the year ending November JD, IBM » SW3 Expended for the year ending November 'MK 1MI I'.KW KxpfhiltMl for the year i-nililin NovellllMT :IT 1!M( hiiiiiite iiiiuiiiil iH-r &lt;»|&gt;ltH &lt;-ont for the year lillti :!T!».4". $ .*MKri.(i&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p093">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 61 HI IX. KT KKI'OKI AND DETAILED STATEMENT Ul KMIUtlKli \!-IK&lt;&gt; PRIATIONH FOR THE BIKNMIM BECilNMM. APRIL I. 1M7. AND KMIIM. MARCH SI, l»l» r XKIlliASKA SCHOOL KOK THK I&gt;KAK. OMAHA. XKBIIASKA Iinilv average inmate population I ten-mber, l'.»H 1***» iHlll.T HVf THKe imitate population N&lt; &gt;VC1I1 lie]*, l'.'lt! MM Daily average inmate population. Wfi tT:: Pally nvernite Inimite population. Will -. 174 Dall'v incratp i iitf \« imlntli'ii for the l.iei'niuni . .uliau Xamahrr •«■ HM IT* Daily averape nuinhrr »f officers anil eiuployi e&gt;. Nomibtv, 1!&gt;1fl Inmate iinnual per nHMMl i"O"*t for tin- veur tWk * l *-u • - Imiuite itnnnal |H"r i-apltH Mai for the year r.'Ui .T'4 i»» ll'llllltc liivl'll'ill I'er t-jiltlljl rr-it fi-r tVe liielltlil'lt' IMlK.-'ii) h.linmfil rxix'ntllturr f.r th&lt;- hlrnflnm krsiaala* April I. l»l^ Salaires anil wanes * MM General repairs Kouiiiniei't for trxilr ilvnartMrutii :iml kltrheu «on.ne Other niaiutennnm .VMtfXI.m Tofal *117!i«M»^ Raoed on -fti'iint-Ml average ilally raanriaHaa •' ISO for the hlenniuiu f*xtraorillnary appropriation for the i-urreut Men &gt;'or {rrartinc Kronnilx ami furnisliini: new p r i mary iMilliline $ 4om)."i&gt; Rjpenileil to Xoveinlwr 3D. 1»W Ilalaix-e unexpenileil siin.ni » ~-n\ si K»linmtril rxtraardlnarv rxprnilltarp for th» bi&lt;» - nlum brciBBinc April 1. 1(11: For new harn. Krailinu irronmU iml i-onstnnt int- \Milk» im -trim * Ml KatlmaKil (.runil Total !lir» iiiitiroprifltion for current ex|HMises *ll*V'."i&lt;(.li&gt; Kxpcniipd to NoremWr 30. 1»1« MltUI l';l';ll!'»* 111 t \ |it lldrd $ JI'.K^.W* Salaries anil \V;i*re» — ttpr»*rt for tl-e veiir e.idip;." VovhiiiI er :•). I'.ll.'. * Jtmsi ir; Jlxiwii'le'l for ; lit- ve:ir finlii'y Nnvt'inlifr -"'0. l'.tUi HHUI i:&gt;-.-iii..i f. &gt;■ ii.- i.i 1 11 in wmUmm 9mm0m ••». i!»t« * .VkV.l.» ;»-ntT;il H.'|.:iir* F.\|iemle&lt;l fnr thp y»»ar .-inliiii.' Xovpnilw*r 'Ml. 1!H."» . t :*CC ?\ Kx|hmii1«»i1 for the ye«r eiiilin^ Nnveinlier '■'&lt;*' litlti 1301.-11 l&gt;|iiiiliil fcr the lleiMiliim emlhru Niivemlier :d). Mi * mmM Other MiliuteiijilM-** — Kxpendeil for the venr emliiiB Xoveinlx-r :■&lt;&gt; t'.H." * LSHat.SH K\|»-n.l.-.l fwr the yenr eiiilln« \ovenil&gt;er :u&gt; Ml Utttft KxpHinleil fir lie liinniili'in nidi, z NiveinWer •'»&gt;. Ml * +M7J.&lt;*. I t.tnl ' \r-in'itirr»- fir thr hlfnrhini rmlirn NnirmWr M. !•!• *1.«K7»..Vl </seg>
            <seg id="p094">62 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Bl [ll.KT KKI'OKT AND DETAILED STATEMENT OF ESTIMATED AI'I'KO - PRIATIONS FOR THE BIENNIl'M BKUINMMi Xl'Kll. I. 1»1*, AND ENDING MARCH 31, 1S1U S— NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT (IIII.DKKX H:i*eil on eitiirsteil average dully population of HI for the Metiiiluni. Extraordinary appropriation for the current hien- For"'new building - * 2T.TKH.CK) Expended to November 30. 1016. £»!4&lt;).1S Balance unexpended * MBlM For land _ * jTi«l(io Kxiwnrle.l to Xovenilier *\ 1»1«- *in0.00 Hiilano' Uliexpelnleil 9 „ Kitimalrd exlrsardlaarj rxpendilurr far the hlen - mlmm d&lt;«IbbIb( Aprli 1. ItI7: For fencing, grading and improving grounds uuil lnyliii.' ■Mtwaft $ 2500.110 K.llra.lM Ormnd T»tal f 49000.011 i^i .&gt;» iji^.-n, j\r.niiA."*lv.v Haily average Inmate population Keoemlier. 11M4 '" Daily average inmate population November, IMA : °.&gt; Daily average inmate population. liO."i 6S Dally average inmate population, ll»l« M Imilv arrruB* Irawtf fmim l«tt«B fc r tin- I'ieiinltim cniiinir Xiivi-iiiInt SO, l'.nr, V' Dally average number of officer** and employees Xoveinber. 1 i » 1 1 ' . "i 1915 appropriation for current ex|&gt;ense*&lt; _ . * WUKkSR ' Expended to .November »), HUB MAM Halllir nnrxneliilril _ _ Jf l.XTt.O) Salaries and Wagea — Kxpeuded for the year emtiiiK N'ovemlier .*M\ l'.»l«&gt; f SM3.1] Kxpelided for the year enilini: N..veml&gt;er 'M. li&gt;l«. Mlfl Kx|&gt;eiiile(l fir the biennium enilltiK Noveinber ;m. 11*10 * HUI General Repairs- Expended for the year eniliut' NoveinluT M. IMS t 1.7*\ Expended for the year ending Xovenil^r :ui. 1!&gt;H! ' 4&gt;."&gt; Ki|H-nded for the liienniiim ending Xoveml&gt;er 31). 1016 $ 7.3T. K Maintenance — pended for the year ending Nnvemlier .1". I'.UI * 1-MWn.iti pended for the year eudine Xoveinlier .Ml, 1!»HS ITIKLMn Expended fur the hieunluni euilinn November •'»». 1916 * 31S4S.37 T..l«i rxprndilurr f.r t h» Itirnnium f«dlD| Ntvrmkrr XII, IMIli X 4-J4SA.49 Inmate annual per capita co»t for the year l!M-"&gt; X :Ui&lt;J.Hi Inmate annual rer capita &lt;*&lt;igt for the year l'.ilii 264.06 Inmate biennial per capita cost for the Meiiniuiii 5HTi.S4i Estimated rxiH-nditurr for Ike birnnlum Wciaainc April 1, I«I7: Salaries and wsges $ i:«nn.i«i General repairs .VXJ.tli" Traveling expenses :tCKlO.Oi&gt; other maintenance .10000.01) Total - - * MBMMMI </seg>
            <seg id="p095">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 63 III 1M.KT REPORT IMI IlKTMI.Kli STATEMENT OK KMIHATKIl APPRO- I'RIATIONH FOR THK B1KNMIM BK.IWIM, \IKI1 1. Kill. \M&gt; KXIIIM. MARCH HI. i»l» HOAKI) OK COMMISSIOXKltS OK'STATK I XST1TI TI( INS LINCOLN. NKKKASKA 1915 Appropriation: For salaries $31860.00 For incidentals, books, printing, telegraph and telephone, postage, office supplies, furniture and repairs, etc 5780.00 For railroad fare and traveling expenses 1150.00 Extra help _ 510.00 Total $39300.00 Expended to November 30, 1916: For salaries $25210.00 For incidentals, books, printing, telegraph and telephone, postage, office supplies, furniture and repairs, etc 3145.75 680.35 230.05 For railroad fare and traveling expenses For extra help $29266.16 Total Balance unexpended niiw.il Estimated expenditure for the biennium be - ginning April 1, 1917: For salaries : For incidentals, books, printing, telegraph $.56,920.00 and telephone, postage, office supplies, furniture and repairs, etc 5780.00 1250.00 For railroad fare and traveling expenses For extra help 500.00 $44450.00 Total Note: The above estimate includes the salary and traveling expenses of a consulting en - gineer. Increase for 1917-18 over 1915-16 $ 5150.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">64 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF HI IX. KT KM'iiKI AMI I&gt;K1 IILBD KTATKMKNT Ol KSTIMATKI) \1IKII I-RIATIONH I'OK THE B1KNMI M BKC.INMNt. APRIL I, IVI* AMI KM)IN(i MARCH SI, HtlU RECAP1TI LATION A IMwaafea Institution for Krehle-Mlnded Youth. Heat rice. Nebraska : Estimated ordinary expenditure Estimated extraordinary t-x (m-jmI i i in &lt;■ Tot»l *2Miti:.t B Olrls' IniliiKtrial Si-IhmiI. (it-neva. fihmlri KsthuHtt*&lt;l 4&gt;r&lt;linnry f xpciulftiiiv KstluinlPil extrnonlinury cx|»Mnliini.- * cvr uiu (KXXI.I ToUl * T+OIKl.tM* C NVI.raskH Soldiers' »ml SBilor*' ll&lt; nif ■■ttasIM ordinary exiMMHiitur** ..... KxlhuHted f xlmoniiiinry «*\ |winlilurt' Hurkrlt NVIiru Ifel .K2SJUI.MI r.imn.m Total KX-cim.Ul D liik-lfsidf Hospital for the lii»niic, Initlt-siili-. NHira E»tlmate&lt;l ordinary cxiieiiditurf . Kftimated extraordinary ex|&gt;eiHliture ika »:|!«»-:.l«i 11MKI.C '■ Total *41'-&lt;«M«. K Slate Industrial Sth.H.I, Kearney Neliraaka : Kstimated ordinary ex|w*nditiire KMimated extrnnrdiiiHry expenditure 41-1KUM.O XWO.II Total si in •■ ■ F Hospital for Tuberculous, Kearney, Nebraska: Kgrlmated ordinary exitenditure Estimated extraordinary expenditure * IM:UU.I- 3H00.I Total nutAi.w 8 Xeliraska Hospital for the Insane. I.iin-.iln. Nehru ika Estimated ordinary ex|&gt;euditure Eatiiuate&lt;l extraordinary ex|M*iulitiire *Iimi(:o.«i 1W»m:&lt;i Total *4."ili:im.l&gt;:i II &lt;)rtlio|iedii' HoapHal. l.iii.nln. Nebraska Kstimated ordinary exiteudlture Estimated extraonliuary ex|&gt;enditure ♦IJI1.K1.I Mi.111 Total fl3.VrtHI.tlU J State IVnilfiiliiirv, Lincoln, Nebraska: Estimate«l ordinary ex|&gt;en(liture K&gt;tiuiated extraorillnary ex|&gt;enditiir&gt;' 41:11x1.1-: ToimI ■STB K Nebraska Industrial Home. Milfc.nl. Nebraska Estimated ordinary ex|&gt;eiiditure Estimated extraordinary exiienditure &lt; MCW).! T.'iUUHl Total * ."•«K«l.l^ I. Sol.liers iin.l Snllor»' Home. Milford. Nebraska : K^tiuiHti'il ordinary ey*&gt;einliture. Estimated extraordinsVy expenditiire $ »ieni.m lU-KXKI.MI </seg>
            <seg id="p097">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 97 IllUI'tKlllVK I'l-I KIHI THIN STVIKJlt.VT Of ANXIAI. hAI'KMIIII Kt- IIIK ■IHIBIWI ONLY [ Kll(.'ln«T B - supplies 148N.17 1«S4.«4 2M2.81 I Klr.liiiiil (appUn 482.M AM.84 113LSS Cienertl re- &lt; Riiililrrfl' hardwHrr 114.14 4S.M 3*8.11 114.14 4S.M 9M.U pairs I I'iiinis. . ils. iclHHti. paiut l&gt;rnabes .'.] 9M.81 38UB tM«.M I Building material __ • 8W.0B 1512.T2 SMB.TT I ouiiuiiik uiaieriii ' irwiim , wii.n --w.il I Labor I MSJB I 882.04 7»7 J» Total I ST73.21 5380.78 !OB.«t S A INSTITITIUN FOR FKBB1 MEATHUK. XKHKASKA— (L t'MtillUt'il cuaypRum Total Deo, 1. 14 lie.-. 1. 15 Dec. 1, H to to to Dec. 1. '15 i Dec. 1. '16 I&gt;. Stationery, hooks, and paper [ Utfic* 1 KUP|&gt;llt*&gt;4 I Srhiiol hooks ;iinl supplies - \ Hooks, |x*rioiliitils anil ucwsp*- i iters „ —„_. I MisivllHlieous « 54S.T5 skim M.SO fiJM 18.00 hi 1 - 30.00 2T7.42 10tl.M -M Total 1041.M Brooms, hrusheg, polish, and ■iliiMt-r-v J06.+4 107 J» 107 J» Fuel, light and power | Cixi i Oils mid luiiri. ant* 1 Klwtrl.ity I Water _ — — IMMM IMJI 11919.07 21W.4S MU ses I . ( Total 13913.50 148LM.W Machinery, tools, and supplies f For iudustriul tit-part im'iit&gt; - - , For institution in g?u- [ eral I ■Ml ~Zm\ ~=S Tol»l _ j r.ao.M ■■J'M «13MH •73.M8 I Lire atotk _.... Mil Tn.HH ::4!i..-.7 ■Mil ■ta MMi 3mm 24.SU 233.37 M Kntertaiiiiiient ; I _^_^_^_ Rurial expenses.. 73.14 TJ.M MiKrcllaneous .. J mUt --"B1.37 11S3.4* GRAND TOTAL |* 715TK.41 * TW22.M »151301 87 Dally arerat*e number of Inmates Inmate per capita 486 " tl47.i» sat *£ </seg>
            <seg id="p098">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 98 COMPARATIVE IHSTRIBIT1ON STATEMENT in FOB MAINTENANCE GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. GKXEV \'\. NEBRASKA 1, 1916 December 1, 1914, to December 82.06 80.73 142.78 55.84 lmVtr. 161.50 Ruilroad fare — offtVinl. Transport- Traveling expenses — official ation. I Railroad fare— inmates 8.44 38.24 46.6K telegraph 1 I ravelins expenses — Inmates and telephone | Express and freight 6.00 57.T7 68.77 159.52 178.88 .T38.4O 19S.5U 186.13 384.72 [ Telephone aint tfleirrH|»h Total. [ Flour I Sugar I Coffee and tea... Article* I Other groc., fruit" nnd nf food •{ Meats - veyMtnldt 1 I Lnnl and butterinc I Butter I Emca I Milk I Oheeae anil other dairy products. Total Stock feed. Tobacco... I Bigots, sboes, shoe brushes, lacing. etc i Mm*! cluthing and furnishings.. CMMaj ...._ I Women's ready-made wearing ap 177..VI 388.«K 586.27 114.15 1O8.6T. WUK parel I Miscellaneous I includes repairs)... ANXIA1. l\ll.\ kt&gt; &lt;&gt;M.\ I Canned (T"&lt;*1«- 4««K Bt.41 7(10.77 Fnrnltoif (Inrlndw r»p«lr«&gt; KA.21 1TS.15 11O4..KJ CLASSIKK'ATION Total Deo. 1. 14 Dec. 1, 15 I Dec. 1, "14 to to to Dec. 1. '18 Dec. 1, '1«| Dec. 1 '1« | 7501.00 $ 1W73.86 * 14ST7.W 287.88 flOl.87 SW.53 7TO1.T5 TB75.T2 13467.47 Salaries and wages S OflWrs. employees, etr I Kura labor or services. ... Total 488.45 750.55 1!«'.-"U au» 417.2.1 11W.59 L-:if.7.t&gt;&gt;. 4.1H41 526.29 188.39 10.75 36.91 4*v4.-| 64U41 1137.86 4SB.48 1240.04 534.76 734.2W •jm.X 496.75 540.23 957.4 1 * 1401.58 2601.17 29M.O7 5311.75 726.27 1161 .&lt;W 719.06 1240.34 29S.09 484.42 .70 11.45 16.97 53.88 M13.S6 7884.64 MMJi .11 97K.S1 ■_'■" I Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p099">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 99 COMPARATIVE DISTBIBl'TION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL I \ II M.I 1 1 K K» ONLY KUK MAINTENANCE GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, GENEVA, NEBRASKA— (Continued Brooms, brushes, polish, ami dusters. 147.35 1W.39 -J71M I Coal un&amp;K «tra.M 8M&amp;* 50.96 142.48 1M.M Fuel, light I oils and lubricants and power 1 Klectricity 1015.35 U3T.06 MK.4* 4«T.O1 UDX 10CT.M ( Water Total... tools, and ! For institution in gen- supplies ( eral Total 282.04 247.37 529 41 Kngineers' supplies Klei-trlral supplies 6.80 IUI MM 2M88 W.43 MUD 49» saua S8U3 1101.Se 1084.10 2UBJB General re- ■; Builders' hardware palra I Paints, oils, glass, paint brushes Huililine material I Labor 18(4 22 2085.35 4BM.TT ToUl 9» 104 10S Dally average number of Inmates |f MBJtt t »Ha I MC14 Inmate per capita jflW.M ! &lt;S1.1.«4 1/12S.** Machinery, i h&lt;&gt;r nniiistrlal deiutrtnienti-. 282.01 247.37 329.41 301.11 WHO 8ST21 JOK.ls XU.X1 471.38 CLASSIFICATION Deo, 1, H Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1. 14 t* to ;o Dec. 1, "15 ' Dec. 1, "1« Dee. 1. 'M Stationery, books, and paper I Office supplies School IiooIck ami .supplies -; Books, periodicals and newspa- pers ___________ I MiHcellaneouH 2S3.M 538.41 72.28 358.0* 45C.y3 37.73 72.01 6U.«0 wot 110.01 Total — »l».l- ■_n Lk_U- Live stock- BAM 305.00 143.23 197.S6 Seeds... Entertainment. ■J2 13 ix-r..-&gt;3 Burial expenses- 5.00 5.db Miscelliineoua 4-3 ■ «tun GRAND TOTAL...- $ 2M4&amp;M * 31877.7S * S1SK74 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 100 COMPARATIVE lil-TKIBl TION MTATKMKNT OK AXMAL hM'KMMII K»&gt; FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY STATK INDUSTRIAL BCHOOL, KKAKXKY. XKBRASKA December 1, 1»14, to December 1, l'.HG Salaries* \ Officers. *Mnpli&gt;y**«'s. Me. and wnjjes I Kxtra lalior or service. 1154.71 •rj-.Tft; HffJ.Ul Total i.Til'-.'.'JO il32».()l 4:W.'«.!M IIiiilrotMl fiirc— offioial. ■-•71. 41' :f.T.:tO 3W.TS Transport- I TrHv*'linir expeaan ort1&lt;i:il jtlou, I K«llroa«l fare^ -lnmatcK I*.-".* 14:i.l'.i 3^8.4H 171.SS MS.07 3W.0U teleprnph. Tr:ivrliin.- i-xpenses — initiate* anil telephone i Kxpres* iiml froliiht S4.U L-V.U", 6J.JU 4o&lt;».ir.' W.7.41 'IVli'plioiif aud tHli-irnipli 181JW Hrj.Tii :i44.6e Total lan.i:; 1IW4.4J ::uv- 1 FI..U1 J71DUW 147!t.l(l 41N«.41&gt; i."«2S.l.". V^xi.'.rj 2811.00 SKL2S STj^.au ."■«l.*t 16M.A* ■Kfl.ihle iH7.'-(i i4Oi.:n Itutter Km MM.IK 14..-4 17».4il Milk Him ...i ujd I riitw and other dairy •diirta. 34.74 :BS.S*t 73.TJ pr Total l.-tSMt.til VtSMM 24UM6 Stock feed. UXJ2.U4 J7(fi.!M UST.M Mmm l.oi 1 i»' I'.nols. Kboes, shoe lirushes. iaoinK 4471 44.31 SB.*-' Mr, 1333.90 9H&gt;M ■.•.•U4.",4 Men's I'lcitlihiu and furnishings Clothing ! Wiiinen's ready-mail* 1 wearing ap pnn-l ; Mistfllnnetius &lt; include* repairs)... :i2«.i"!l 44.90 .174.13 T.ital I&gt;w. l.'H Deo. 1, 15 Dec. 1, 'H M to t" Dec 1, 'IS Dec. 1, 16 Dec. 1 'It. CLASSIFICATION $ JH-Ul.'.tU * W1TU0 $ -llttB.JSI I &lt;"oir«" mill ten I Cdiin**«l en&lt;wli« Article" i Htlier jiriN-., frultw «n«l v of taut MmM I I.iinl nmi tmtterine S&lt;!().35 ll&lt;n.7!l Z73A.1G l.-,17.tn 4L'TJ.T&gt; J!«'..».-, :ittl.-,.:!&gt; 7538.83 n .-.-. :so.&lt;k-&gt; 4T.:«&gt; Tulnl i:t7s.-.' r.T.l I.. -i i..: ■ &gt;ry trnod«... :!TT4.ti:i V.TO.ttt ■*rj.-. -J4 Hoopitnl supplies MUM l'.M.Tl 507.08 ' I Soap, clemiwrs. slarrb. et&lt;\ 747.33 MMI 1190.88 H.ir&lt;l«iire lothfr limn tmlldfrs'i. 238.(H S78.M 818.08 Qurranwarr »n&lt;l itlmwware. mm +4.37 132.4l&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p101">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 101 COjrrAIATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF iXNIAL EXPENDITI REM KOR MAINTENANCE ONLY STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. KEABNEY, NEBRASKA (Continued) "Total Dec, 1, -U Dec. 1. '15 Dec. 1. '14 to to to CLASSIFICATION to t" to Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1, 16 Dec. 1, '16 Dec. 1, 15 IK* 1, 16 Dec. 1, 18 I Offlce supplies 370.73 ' 3»1.8» 7«2.«Z Stationery, I School books ami supplies 238.22 : 143.11 378.3T. I Offlce supplies 370.73 391.8B 78B.«2 Stationery, I School books ami supplies 238.22 : 143.11 378.3H hooks, and ■! Hooks. periodicals and newspa- hooks, and ! Books, periodicals and newtpa - paper ners ! _ 3R.63 25.23 83.8K I Miscellaneous - 15.00 200.32 215.32 paper pern ! _ 3R.63 25.25 83.8K I Miscellaneous _ _ _ 15.00 200.32 215^2 ToUl - «R7..V« T«0^7 ~~M18,13 15.00 200.32 213.32 Total «r.7..V&lt; 760.07 HIS.IS Brooms, brushes, polish, and dusters_ 131.80 SS.7S ■ X, (Co«l 5MB.80 5MO88 ll.t]O.4A Brooms, brushes, polish, and dusters_ 131.80 83.75 \vc X, ( Coal - I 54«.«0 S8ML88 1131O.4S Fuel, light J Oils and lubricants _._ 158.64 388.87 42T. :.) and power 1 Kle.tri.ltv 3W3.« 4400.52 and power 1 Kltntriiltv Water .' 585.00 _ _ 525.00 *W8.11 M73.40 18e«1.51 Tota :r717.:i« l«i'..79 5643.17 Mju-hinerT. f For Industrial departments. tools, and I For institution in kpii- supplies ( eral 307.53 431.85 739.18 4034.01 357.44 C382.35 Total I KnKineers' supplied _ *•*•*» 341.1* 838,07 I Blertrical supplies Z—-" ««•« 1£-12 292.5S l r-ie.Tri.-iu supplies !2Z?JZ i-.i- _.-f...». Ceueral re- i Builders 1 hardware _ .3£?5 •¥?? 41812 pairs I Paints, nils, glass, paint" brashes '22- 40 4S8.73 1513.13 I Buildiiiic material _ tmM 11S.87 M4J1 Building material Lat.or . _ 1011.51 288.36 130OM Total _ 3857.TO 1887.15 MMM Live stock 1785.02 3002.56 4787.56 Daily average number of Inmates 308 188 tts&gt; Inmate per capita _ $ 3S8.S6 f 296JB f 08.00 Seeda 411.34 lte.os 182.06 5731 Entertainment.. 51S.S4 ■Mi loa&amp;i Burial expenses- ... Mi«&lt;*llaneou8 .. :ils.-« .W.10 GRANT) TOTAL. I * 70641.80 $ 55721.51 $12«S«3 .3 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 102 ( OMFABAT1YE D1MTR1BI T1ON M ATKMKNT OK AXMAL KX PKMMTl Kt&gt; NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AXD SAILORS' HOME, BIRKETT, NEBltASKA December 1, 1914, to December 1. 1916 Total Dec. 1. '14 Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, '14 to to to CLASSIFICATION Salaries \ &lt; Mean, employees, etr.. and wages I Extra lubor it services Total. ... .. "TCT f Railroad fare — official. TTanaport- Travelinc expenses- -offirial atlon, I Railroad fare — Inmates telegraph, 1 Traveling expenses — Inmates and telephone j Express and freight Telephone and telegraph Total. Flour Sugar Ii'offee and tea. Chimed goods. Article" I Other groe., fruits and of food \ Heats vegetables I Lard and hutterine I Butter Milk [ Cheese and other dairy products... Total. Stock feed Tobacco^ Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing, etc. * -.'.-.7:14s 1547.20 4128.8S Men's clothing and furnishings.... 300B.lft 4891.71 8800.87 333.40 358.90 f92.30 Clothing ; Women's may-made wearing ap parel Misoellaueous (includes repairs) 4.00 4.00 Total 6826.04 6797.81 13623.85 Dry foods — 2640.78 2580.86 5221.43 FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1, '16 Dec. 1 '16 $ 34387.1S $ 25543.33 t 4!IH30.r.l 2036.38 2005.13 4OU.51 26423.56 27548.46 ' .V!«7'-'.'rj 16£2 23.28 38.80 2.75 10.00 13.36 •-T548.46 577.2B 3M.M " 834."l8 •Ji'4 :,_• 238.67 443.19 821.01 528.51 1390.52 2108.66 1827.50 3806.15 2182.66 2KW.96 4579.61 33TS.1O 3467.98 &lt;LS41.O8 1681.47 2440.12 41^1.5U 39CU3 4684.01 8051.94 1Z17B.31 13448.«; 25«27.2:i 2478.1S 3105.85 .V£3.96 465.58 641.85 11O7.43 1850.60 1537.65 S38&amp;25 1.80 ««&gt;v 10.4» 306.46 538.M S44.40 2We8.6B 34098.45 64092.14 29903.69 1!«7.75 4484.33 (»422. Hospital supplies 1221.08 1238.W L'MO.O: Soap, cleansers, starch, etc :«i&gt;7 806.96 Hardware (other than builders') 900.19 308.82 Queeujware and i1inwir_ 227.57 S12.80 Furniture (Include* repairs)-. ■Ml TBJ8 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 103 COMPARATIVE Ills I RIBl TION STATKMKN T OK \SM \l (M'l.MllIIRI.. FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY NKBRASKA ■OLDIBWT AND SAILORS' HOME, I, Bl'RKETT, NEBRASKA ae.M i«7.w aut Brooms, brushes, polish, and dusters.. 1MM.94 11960.14 IIIW 5M.42 MH3.91 M42.SS [Coal Fuel. light j oils uml luUiieanti and power I Klwtrloltjr Water Total.. MaohinerT, I Kor industrial departments.. toolB. and ! Kor lustitutlon in fen - siipplies I eral Total. linn.iw 54O4.NT i tBBLM 514.46 4270S 941A1 &lt;*.IM J38.82 MM 86.S1 1541.01 1«3S.«.' 4«.13 1000.4ft 1XS.9B 872.78 2404.53 3IT7J1 [ Engineers' supplies Klectrirnl supplies General re- •{ Builders' hardware uT.r, I Faints, oils, glass. paiDt brushes I Building material ; Labor 3100.96 11004.54 14170.40 Total. CLASSIFICATION Dec. 1, '14 Dei-. 1, '15 Dec, 1, '14 to to to Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1. '18 Dec. 1, 16 Stationery, books, and p«per ( Onlc-e supplies I School books and supplies -I Books, periodicals and newspa- pers I Miscellaneous 3OT.10 3M.58 591 74 "188.17 2B.W " 4G8.78 Total - vm.x: SS7.M Live stork ltiao.oo 806 00 Seeds M6.34 ■KM l«7.0O m.m Enterttinment.. Burial expense*. 17ZV8C 13K.16 30CW 773.26 Miscellaneous _. GRAND TOTAL % 91*1793 1108946.45 HHML40 D»ily «Terage number of inmates Innate per capita * 443 20*8] $ M7.« $ m «5 </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION 8TATBHENT OF AXMAI. K\ I'KMH I I Kt.. FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, MILFORD, NEBRASKA December 1. 1914, to December 1, 1916 Total Dec. 1, '14 Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1, '14 to to to Salaries 1 OlMcerB. employees, eti - and wages ( Extra labor or services Total. ( Railroad fare — official. Transport- i Traveling expenses- t&gt;tri&lt;-i:il stlon, j Railroad fare — inmates telegraph. | Traveling expenses— Inmates and telephone I Express and freight I Telephone and telegraph Total.. I Flour I Sugar j Toffee and tea I Canned goods Articles I Other groc.. fruits and of food ■{ Meats vegetable* Lard and hutterlne. I Butter ?.W« Milk Cheese and other dairy products .... Total. Stock feed. Tobacco— I Boots, shoes, shoe brashes, lacing. etc. I Men's clothing and furnishings... Clothing •! Women's ready-made wearing ap- parel I Miscellaneous (Includes repairs) ToUl.. Dry (sods Hospital supplies.. Soap, cleausers. starch, etc.. 352.53 2OO.3S «42.91 Ilaidware (other than builders'). 104.21 314.41 41S.S2 Qneeiisware and glassware... 28.94 286.74 OMB Furniture (Includes repalra)- 351 14 2S2.7.1 583.SB CLASSIFICATION ■jau.m 3*7.03 ««2.«s 2-JO7.IK 1770.23 398&amp;31 .-«.** 43.50 77.38 66.5(1 TV!.'. 144.6S J«B.(m *M7.91 4870.97 »7.M '1WJ0.9K 1306.44 37«.!» 406.30 7*1.52 lee. 1. '16 Dee. 1, '16 , Dec. 1 °1« 8231.77 * 9003.14 * 17254.91 179.38 301.06 480.43 8411.15 9324.19 17735.34 41.92 34.70 76.C2 3U.0S 13.25 33.30 140.37 632.88 773~35 127.46 156.05 | 283.51 ■Mi 836.88 ; 1166.78 418.10 438.40 896.50 788.95 877.3S 1466.08 661.24 401.00 1152.24 883.46 988.14 1S71.60 MBB.70 2170.98 .t2Oa.6(. 3197.66 4172.59 7370.24 142.23 34B.93 4S8.16 1522.32 864.75 S187.07 80u.96 ioi5.i:; mi.ot&gt; l:M7.10 1766.05 3113.15 70.18 110.21 1S0.3H 10062.59 13040.5U 24003.15 13040.5U 1IW ■ «B «1 .tUtt &lt;W •mAi </seg>
            <seg id="p105">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS » 105 COMPABATIYB DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OK ANNI'AL (XPODITI'UI* FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY SiiLIHEKS' AND SAILORS' HOME. MILKORD NEBRASKA (Continual i j Total I OBn 1 supplies Stationery, School books and supplies. hooka, and \ Books, periodicals and newspa paper per« _ — Miscellaneous Total Brooms, brushes, polish, and dusters. ■J--..4.-. 42.75 1 *.■_•.. f Coal Fuel, tight J Oils and lubricant* ami power I Kleitrii'lty - I Wster Total ■U -.1.1.44 ; 1MB.* Machinery. ( Kor industrial departments. |a«ll and : For institution In sen - supplies ( eral Total Enirineers' supplies General re- ■{ Builders' hardware pairs I Paints, oils, glass, paint brasbei I Ruilillnic material Labor Total :k»*1 :« 23O1.«Z 9MU* 26.00 25.00 Live stock.. 3.93 'VI B flT ■ Reeds Entertainment.. WIM 134.75 3M.T5 Burial expenses-. Miscellaneous 125.44 CBS 132.3* f 33OU.9A f 30356.37 S MK8 ORAND TOTAL.. Daily average number of inmates. Inmate per capita 113 11« IIS S2P2.14 $31.1.42 MMI l*-&gt;: 1.14 Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, '14 to to to Ix-c. 1. '15 , Dec. 1, •!« Dec. 1, 'M "I. OSSIFICATION MM.80 133.M tmM 49.27 «.74 Mi 154.2* 183.38 ! 337.84 4MH.0B 4237.86 8«(H.»1 44.15 MJ» &lt;•» M S77.8O 887.» UOilO 1W.20 116 jo MH.17 mu» mam 103.17 238.W 42T2* I Klwtrirltl supplies jmm 1IV1.7J mjm 255.70 1XM.96 714.73 TOJ0 1O4.6R 101.88 151.UB 516.90 144S.C MT4.O! 16K.00 357.* ■M 1-41 &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL EXPENIMTI Kts FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY INGLE6IDE HOSPITAL FOB THE INSANE, INtJLKSIDE, NEBBA8KA December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Dec. 1, '14 | Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1, 14 to to to Dec. 1, 'IS Dec. 1, '16 Dec. 1 '16 CLASSIFICATION Salaries i Omcern. employee*, etc... and wages I Extra labor or services. $ tti7.x7.47 . $ t)94«1.15 $13TMft.C nu wanes xtra labor or serv: vices • &gt; Totsl -8491.401 69672.14 Railroad fare — official Transport- Traveling expenses — official atlon, Kailroad fare — inmates telegraph. Traveling expenses — inmates snd telephone 1. -press and freight Telephone and telegraph 123.00 138.37 82.54 38_3 A48.96 M M MM 201.78 50.82 _:i.4« 28^1 7M.23 1493.4U J Total l.Xi.M Articles of food Flour ..........„..__.. Kuysr _ Coffee and tea Canned goods _ I Other groc., fruit* and vegetables i Meats I Lard and hutterine _ I Butter I Eggs Milk I Cheese snd other dairy product*.... 7382.38 7752.00 15154.38 2-Ki.oi :tu_i.is auoB.r.i 2UW.5O 25W.37 5648.87 -Ml.W .386.0- 45O0.H 10B86.'.il !&gt;7.X.U6 20145.86 -'4712.50 27194.76 51007.26 4781.03 5649.85 10430.8s -S12.49 2W6.20 5778.78 1415.74 13UU.S2 2716.5S 240.33 3WL16 576.49 5WO4.58 63807.40 123711.98 Total - Stock feed-. Ml 3895.13 11317.75 Tobacco 1743.30 1444.11 3187.37 Booti, shoes, shoe brashes, lacing. etc Men's clothing and furnishings... Clothinz Women's ready-made wearing ap- parel _____ Miscellaneous (Includes repairs) 3062.66 4465.29 2706.87 2557.14 5758.52 781.% 6.90 6.25 57.14 W Total mmm 5326.40 Dry goods MM MM Hospital supplies.. 3411.90 I 3383.16 Soap, cleansers, starch, etc 1753.38 19S5.06 Hardware (other tbsn builders') 846.55 5S7.33 ... Queensware and glassware 286.75 208.51 Fan-ttm* (Incudes repairs).. 8-5.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 107 &lt; "Ml' \K \ I l\ K IMSTKIBl TION STATEMENT OF AXMIAL I M'hMiin Kl&gt; FOB MATNTENANCE ONLY INGLE8IDE HOSPITAL FOB THE INSANE, INGLE8IDE, NEBRASKA (Continued) Dec. 1. '14 Dec. 1. '15 Dec. 1, '14 CLASSIFICATION to to to Dec. 1. 'IS Dec. 1. 'Id Dee. 1, '!• [ Office supplies 'JUCH.l.') 1291.53 339B.K Stationery, i School books and supplies- books, and ; Books, periodicals and newspa paper pers 140.60 306.52 «46 .12 3K.J0 488.04 «UI I Miscellaneous ToUl 2770.04 tamm aatsx Brooms, brashes, polish, and dusters. 418.81 344.4* 7«4.2» . lsl.yt.TT : 20W4.IH 3MM.T1 f Coal Fuel, light I oils and lubricants - and power I Klectrlclty AW.2S «7S.33 1MH •B.TO m.n [ Water TotaL 1861O.7L- 21623.27 44BSSJ* 43.!* _ _. 43J« MHihinerjr. ( For industrial departments tools, and ' For institution in gen- 114A.M «B6.TS 1M3.34 supplies (. eral ToUl 1190.12 1 m*.T9 1MM 1134.93 1«B.«3 2T»8.5« Engineers' supplies 9SLM M6!42 1227.3* S73.53 3S3.84 707.17 I Elcftricnl supplies General re- ■; Builders' hardware palrs I Paints, oils, glass, paint brashes 1492.7S 1073.10 2MS.K I Building material — 14BS.10 1333.se 3tK7.dK NPB.1V AOOd.OV iWal.V Mt r, 60.75 34S.0B I Labor Total 53S8.M 3310.43 1MW.OT lliC'.V. 422.0S 1584.40 Live stock-.. SWHiS. 803.75 550.00 13M.C Entertainment.. 582.48 817.12 13W.«0 Burial expenses 7fln.0O 163.75 8M.1S Miscellaneous 541.70 345.36 787 03 GRAND TOTAL GRAND TOTAL .M83191.4'-' $191«8C36 |*«4«T8.TS 11S2 I 1134 US htm 1 n»M pa».io $183191.42 $191687.36 $384878.78 Dally average number of Inmates-. Daily average number of inmates-. Inmate per capita ~- 1132 1 1134 1133 Inmate per capita ~- </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL t:\HtMll I I Hl&gt; FOI MAINTENANCE ONLY NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOK THE INSANE, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Dec. 1. '14 Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1, '14 to to to Dec. 1, US Dec. 1, 16 Dec. 1 16 Salaries \ officers, employees, etc... and wages I K\ira Inbor or service Total. [ kailroad fare — official.. Transport- Traveling exjHMises — official atlon, I Hallroad fare — Inmates telegraph, 1 Traveling: expenses — inmates... and telephone Express and freight [Telephone and telegraph Tottl CLASSIFICATION" * 47WO.U2 * 4VK4H.41 $ •.KH.tl.M 10HK:il' 7o«.4« 1T64.S1 ■»k:iu».:m 4itntw;.&lt;.Hi dsiuh.h »2.90 &lt;^.i:j 1B1.08 *).34 -&gt;VM 10U.18 36S.9B IW.T:! «38.71 TH-1 -JS.IJ6 101.8K tUS.W 1W.«8 S76.73 476.25 4:!0.0B ;&gt;06.31 '&lt;&gt; 1783.3* 10110.44 Articles of foixi [ Flour _ _ I Sui-ar _ ! CoWet- and tea . Canned goods _ I other gr&lt;x\, fruits and ve«etalile« •! Meats I Uird and liutteriue I Butter - _ - I Eggs ..._ | Milk (Cheese and other dairy pr&lt;xlii&lt;-rx ... 5123.70 431.1.23 1T47.54 44XK.13 1W47.73 l'ietf.25 lll»*.3&gt;i 12O4.7SI K314.32 73W7.19 1 39XI.2N 13*40.18 4CCM.S.-&gt; 4304.31 i-.77.43 2W7O.S3 958.20 963.94 1.30 86.25 144.91 212.64 ! 38Htil.44 40476.74 W38.9S 0770.67 &amp;OM 2408.17 13711.51 S1763.4O W28.9« .V148.2»; r.iH.H 87.56 ■Mi 79138.18 Total -..._ 38Htil.44 Stock feed 37B8.25 3728.25 3497.12 7226.37 Tobacco 14TO.9S 1032.06 2503.08 f Boots, shoes, shoe brashes, 'm-ing. etc I Men's clothing and furnishings.... Clothing j Women's ready-made wearing ap- parel _ m L Miscellaneous (includes repair*) 1928.83 24B4.4S 4413.31 2272.45 4319.95 6592.40 587.88 388.8S ■ 954.73 44.34 107.30 ' 151.84 4883.50 7278.58 12112.08 Total _ Dry goods 4301.56 4934.62 (I23S.1X 4.a&gt;i 56 ... Hospital supplies 2164.75 2074.1K 423S.W Soap, cleansers, starch, etc 2080.82 1346.88 i .'.446.68 Hardware (other than builders')... 730.91 563.80 ' 1344.51 Queensware and glassware 889.13 470.08 1338.19 221.35 i </seg>
            <seg id="p109">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 109 .VI 1O106.49 tWW.55 1M52.O4 Live stock- NkVS.85 1230.05 2396.70 k«d«_ 770.30 r.19.70 12*0.00 — R*itprt*l"fTM*Ht in i laacoi ni2.29 ssobso | lorial expenses 247.00 122.00 MM* Miscellaneous , , ,, , ,,, 9K.33 922^4 GRAND TOTAL.. $144425.08 fl43179.3i HMWHT Dally average number of Inmates Inmate per capita 722 « ... 743 *l»2.70 ■■M COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANM.U EXPEND1TI RE 8 FOB MAINTKNANtK ONLY NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA t&lt; "uutiuued) Dae. i. "U I Dae. i. II Dw. i.-m ri.ASSlPICATIO.N to tu to Bet 1, - 15 | l&gt;ec. 1, '16 ' Dec. 1, '16 [ OIBce supplies WM.S4 1114.06 2BI9M Stationery. | School books aud supplies... books, and ■; Books, periodicals and newspa- i»aper Ders qi id '«■ *± i»i »;i '"'™ I •""* ..-— **" V+.W i^/._t 1O1.V4 ■ Mlscellauvoiis 2*3.28 3S&amp;28 81&amp;M his.;* Total... _ _ 131»..f 1557.21 JS7&amp;T3 Brooms, brushes, polish, and dusterx 471.95 250.40 7_"J « [OMl .... _ 158KS.2* 16408.07 3Xmjt Fuel, light i Oils and lubricant.- 1O71M4 TO1.96 lWlS and power 1 Electricity Water I " "JTiio ToUl....- - l«W4.70 17300.02 34174.75 Machinery, (For industrial departments 1015 tools, and ) For institution in gen- 10.1ft supplies L ««' ■•■- 1384.4« 1226.37 r,».TI ToU1 1534.55 122B.37 27S6.82 I Engineers' supplies 1B1.HK 2972.00 MM Electrical supplies 17H?')B ~vu*a »!St&lt;5 General re- Builders' hardware mil TU14O Sin ■•alrt Paints, oils, glass, paint brushes 230007 iii"iC anu - Building material SaSSlSr ! «35.?8 S».» L""" 0 ' 13«3.23 428J7 178».» 3812.M ■M 178».» </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL KXPENOITIME8 FOR MAINTENANCE ONLY HOSPITAL FOB THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA, NORFOLK, NEBRASKA December 1, 1914, to December 1, 191« Tot»T Dec. 1, '14 Dec. 1, 13 Dec. 1, '14 to to CLASSIFICATION to Dec. 1, 16 Dec. 1, '1« Dec. 1 16 Salaries ) Otflcerx. employees, etc... and wages I Kztia labor m services. t MU % 34511.2:! $ 674M.42 1478.51 2!M&lt;S.2y 1467.7* Total.. :H4:i7;i7 358N9.74 70427.71 I Railroad fare — official.. 79.43 81.58 161.01 saw i -smvs, 17.13 48.77 Transport- Traveling expenses— official 175.39 atlon, I Railroad fare — inmates 29.W telegraph. 1 Traveling expenses — Inmates 1U.UA 1.46 20.51 172.22 MM :c!i.57 mm and telephone ] hxpress and freight [ Telephone anil telegraph. 515J3 171.40 Total 1WO.54 854.si \m:,m.- f Flonr 3800.50 25a*.!B 208S.95 2S4JM «IM.M 8712JH 1W1.83 1133.39 I Coffee and tea Canned goods. 1 Other groc., fruits and Articles ■! Meats of food I Lard aiyi butterlne vegetables Butter.. I Egirs I Milk I ilieese and other dairy prodncts. aes.m Total.. 24904.51 Stock feed.. 1752.56 Tobacco 583!&gt;1 i Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing. etc Men's clothing and furnishings.... Clothing Women's ready-made wearing ap .--t::.iJ 1708.SE ! . .P 1 "?! 70. VI 141.75 65.75 1.T0.26 I Miscellaneous (includes repairs) 2324.62 4S9(uM Total.. 2531.02 Dry roods 3266.30 M17.51 2161.16 Hospital supplies.. 1442.40 1287.58 27S8.M Soap, cleansers, starch, etc- 964.53 1066.43 2030.96 Hardwflre {other than bnilders').. 28&amp;S4 380.28 . 669.13 Qneensware and glaswware. 117.15 &gt; 261.83 STUB 87JSI 657.36 715J4 1866.53 5G82.0CS 2704.51 528H.4* 1204.25 3-J90.20 363.63 598. lit 41GO.0U 8189.SS 9B1O.4S 1I-O22..S:! 2331. »l 4L«23.0f&gt; 1354.M6 24S8.21 2SS.18 48B.S0 376.78 " «4o!s3 23965.41 48HMC 1070.90 2823.40 472.38 1006.29 1148.44 lfl»1.5« 1120.43 28B7.0S </seg>
            <seg id="p111">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 111 COMPARATIVE DISTKIBl TION STAT-Uf-ENT OF ANNUL HPENDITIIKH FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA NORFOLK. NEBRASKA (Continued) Dec. 1, - 13 | Dec. 1. '16 Dee. 1, '!• ( Office supplies 719.75 906.99 ! 16Z3.74 8.35 32.51 I 38.7* Stationery | School books and supplies books, and &lt; Books, periodicals and newipa- 86.33 S7.O2 17I5.3&amp; 116.11 188.10 MUQl noner nfrg „ _____ [ Miscellaneous 931.44 1211.62 2143.08 Total. Brooms, brushes, polish, and dusters 130.96 198.41 123 Tfk [ Coal 130B9.7O 14894.72 -7724.42 526.03 588.18 H1SJ2S «f3.9O 790.80 148S_M&gt; Fuel, light j Oils and lubricants-, and power 1 Electricity [ Water Total i4_&amp;4.«&gt; i«07i.o0 aam_» Machinery, f For industrial departments - tools, and •' For Institution in gen - supplies (. eral _ Dec. 1, '14 Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, '14 to to .to CLASSIFK'ATIOX suppl ersl . ToUl 72S.W 936.53 728.M IMS* 1655.17 General re- pairs Engineers' supplies ,, Electrical supplies Builders' hardware Paints, oils, glass, paint brashes.. Building material I Labor 8*4.08 1087.98 20U» •mil 1MB.0&amp; ir:-.'- Z712.13 M2.14 M0.7» 740.78 «B&amp;73 2S6.O2 Hi 7^* Total r«6.5« 5300.90 100W.1B Live stock 3800 106&amp;00 loee.oo 646.2» .W1.06 1087.36 Seeds 343.S* 192.37 43121 Entertainment 243.S* 192.37 I ' ~~~™ Burial expenses 207 SO 2O7» 340.00 447.80 Miscellaneous S86.2S 584 JX GRAND TOTAI * MQ29.72 $ 97835.M tl«MB-« Dally average number of Inmates — Inmate pet capital -5 6B8 — </seg>
            <seg id="p112">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 112 COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL EXPENDITl RES FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY HOSPITAL FOR TUBERCULOUS, KKARXKY, NEBRASKA Deceml&gt;er 1. 1914, to December 1. lftlii TotTl Dec. 1. '14 - Dec. 1, 15 ' Dec. 1, '14 to to to I'LASSIKH'ATION Dec. 1, 'IB Dec. 1, '16 I»ec. ] '16 Salaries I Office™, employees, etc and ma I Kxtm lHlior at servlivs. It 6409.94 * atria*! $ rs.-rrs.4u 389.43 681.611 292.17 681.611 Total 6702.11 7355.S9 14O.VUPO ( Railroad fare- offlcial ixA-2 m.m :rr.»% Traosport- I Travellnit expenses official ation. I Railroad fare Inmates 12.25 17.40 2H.7O ati.uo 20.60 leleerapb 1 TianIlM expense* — Inmates and telephone I Kxpress anil freight 6.00 B.ai W.-ft 40.47 1011.74 Telephone and tcWgiapli 86.61 12*.63 £94.^4 Total 1M«..Vi •sum 419.10 Fl.mr .KMVi *4.'.»a 115.W oa».!»:t I Snt-nr 2321* 2l»7.00 Coffee and tea 107..VI 40.65 14*. 1.1 Canned j;&lt;»ods :i52.79 -.L'T.OB «».«■. Articles I otlier ltck-.. fruits and of food Meats veitetiililer mvi.ni 1471.71' 2522.2K 140R.9S M03.26 3207.1!! Ijinl nnrl Imtterine. 75.25 10U.8S 178.1.1 I Butter 51».5H 771 .U«" VJMO.67 Kcbr HW.7S 13S6.15 2111.93 Milk 1K2O.O7 17rHt..f. 2759.42 I i !«■«■ mill ntner dairy prodnctx 21.43 .14.77 56.20 Total .-■flrti.r 812S.04 i:r79K.?.i Stock feed.. 231. :w 2-2S.24 4.-.1...&lt;i Tobacco .Hi 1" I Knots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing. I etc. S.OB .-..or. I Men's clothing and furnishings... Clothing &lt; Women's ready-made wearing ap parel I Miscellaneous (include* repairs).... Total n.or. Dry goods. 447.02 m*M Hospital supplies mmM 2099.06 Soap, cleansers, starch, etc? M 4-s 441.42 Hardware (other than builders'). 22O.3S 67.12 ■Ji MM 118.2B Queeneware and glassware. Fnrntture (Includes repairs).. 91.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">Knginwrs' supplied 18&amp;50 M4.41 TtO.ll Electrical supplies _ M 273.78 334.76 I iMwinrm supplies — — tmj.iw -i.i.i- jwi.iw General re- ', Biillderf"' hardware 2.15 S7.9n ».«&gt; runnier!* naru*»iirt* _.i.» -m .«■ w.v«# Paints, oils, irlass. paint brushes 4048 16V' K.M palm I I .UI11S. UIIJ*. KiaBK. [milll I»U»IK».. W.W l»r.T». fv.n I RniMliiR materUl J4 44 M.« nS^» L Labor J 288.K 7M.14 1«H.T( Total - «U? 1708.33 2308^1 3M.7S 386.75 LtTe ttook. 35JS TIM H3J1 See&lt;l» 4.00 ru.^ J4&gt;,- Entertainment. Burial expenses. m ■ M8-76 «■.« Miscellaneous » 186B1.7S f 23«77.2» $ 42».0B GRAND TOTAL. SI 3« Dally average number of inmates Inmate per capita •6OI.S7 I6BT.70 VMA.W1 COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT 0 FOB MAINTENANCE O] IF ANNUL t .M-KMil ri KK HOSriTAI. KOK III— 1IIHWI1. KKAHXKY . XKBR.\SKA— (Continued) t I.ASSIKK'ATIOX 1 Total Dec. 1, '14 Dec. 1, '15 Dei. 1. 1 to to to Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1, 16 Dec. 1, II Statimiery. hook*, and paper ( Office supplies ?. I Srhuol lu&gt;oks and Hupplies m I Books, perioilirals and newspa- pers Miscellaneous — ( OfBce supplies ?. 1 — » I »...„!... ...... ....nnlln. 300.20 .T21.SU 022.10 Stationery. I School hooks and supplies J RiMtka twrliuhnfl la mil ii.j\v&lt; books, and paper I Books. |n-ri»ilii':i!&gt; and newi pers „ Miscellaneous Total rspa- i3jn iw 78.1U 141.78 M».« " Z»\M MM 8SSJ» Total - Brooms, brushes, polish, and cluster*.. Brooms, brti ishes, polish, and duster* 41.1S MM 14tt44 Fuel, light and power Fuel, light and power | Coal j Oils and lubricants _ 1 Klectriclty ..._ _ I Water „ Total | Cciill j Olla and lul&gt;ricanU 1 Klectrlcity - Water - 2375.35 1824.17 42W.K 23.81 MM MuB tttm 4M.MI 98T.«» ™ 5? ani.M 244O..T7 5312.SS Total — - Machinery, tools, and supplies f For induHtriHl department* &lt; For Institution in gen- t eral ToUl ■Ji BUI 317.57 91.13 224.42 ST7.57 </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE 1HSTKIBI TION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL EXPKMMTl KES FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 ToUl Dec. 1, 14 I Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, 14 CLASSIFICATION to to to Deo. 1. 15 Dec. 1, 'If j Dec. 1 '18 Malariev I Officers, employees, etc $ 17058.40 * 18357.0fi * 38O1S.46 and wages I Extra labor or service* _ _ M2.83 4£&gt;.S0 786.13 iA-2.83 i 42L-.3O 786.13 Total 1M DL23 ISTIMS :M780.5K I Itallroail fare official.. Tranaport- Traveling expenses — official 30.00 :!5.UU 55.0U atlon, I Railroad fare — inmates telegraph | Traveling: expenses — inmates 4.92 4.92 and telephone I Express ami freight 337.07 483.06 800.1t t Telephone and telegraph 3B2.79 476.40 S88.W Total - 790.48 , 96B.4O 1749.8C Furnltnre (inclndes repairs) 1 224.74 188.59 3»3J» Articles of food | Flour . . I Sugar ..._ _ I &lt; 'oftVt* and tea | Canned goods I Other groc.. fruits and reg-ptnblt-K i Meats I Lard and butterlne _. I Butter , I Ecars I Snl — [ Cheese and other dairy product*.... 120.15 444.50 137.96 m m swe.24 2224*1 134.90 174(1 '..J 1C86.22 2178 M _m 229.33 349.48 792.58 1237.08 179.50 317.45 1038.58 1698.41 5400.77 9388.01 2478.97 4701.88 «04.79 739.89 1513.26 3254.18 1560.06 2668.28 2554.37 473026 53.33 94S3 Total ! 2752.10 18423.54 29176.84 12752.10 Itock feed 13.15 .. 13.1S 'obmcco.. Kf Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing. I etc. _ I Men's clothing and furnishings.. . 'lothing ; Women's ready -m a de wearing ap- parel „ „ I Miscellaneous (Includes repairs). 5.26 5.25 11.00 .._ 11.00 Total I m 11.00 sis 16J6 .... _____ 'ry goods 1883.54 1655.85 3489.38 i ; [ospltal supplies 2913.31 4133.90 7047.21 p. cleansers, starch. etc_. 723.48 712.60 1436.08 [ardware (other than builders') 416.30 140.68 Ml ■■■.....■I lueensware and glassware. 117.84 148.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p115">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 115 COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANMAL KM'KMHTI RK - FOR MAINTENANCE ONLY ORTHOPEDIC HOSPITAL, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA— (Continued) "Total Deo. 1, '14 Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, 14 to to to Dec.l, - 16 Dec. 1, '1« Dec L It CLASSIFICATION f Office supplies 447.06 477.87 934.76 219.68 154 37 S74.OS Stationery, Scbool books and supplies books, and { Books, periodicals and newspa paper I pera 14.20 18.9.% 33.13 •0.88 17JJ6 .33.14 Miscellaneous Total.. 7*1.88 82B.2S 15*5.08 Brooms, brushes, polisb, and dusters... 110.41 97.ae ma f Coal 2883.57 5400.32 8283.6* 10B.T9 W8.12 2«1.!«1 10.48 911» KU 831.W 119».« MUR Fuel, light I Oils and lubricants., and power I Electricity - i Water Total. 3D3B.33 7tS».J6 11«8.«8 ♦ _^^___^__ 11.10 U.M 211.86 54.15 MM* 222.79 54.15 27«.K S01.7'&gt; 428.87 1230.62 Machinery, I For industrial departments, tools, and ', For Institution In gen - •upplies l^ era] „- , 11.10 11.10 211.99 54.15 MUt ToUl. 222.79 54.15 Z76.J4 ( Engineers' supplies I Electrical supplies S3S.S3 294.55 M1.38 General re- ■; Builders' hardware 144.&gt;ff ■ -1 MlM pairs I Paints, oils, glass, paint brashes 470.42 3J1.57 80TJ» I Building material 4i7.ro lai.na 5T7.«r. I Labor 4».00 TOM 1214iB Total. jsai.oe xm.n mm.x Live stock. Seeds Entertainment.. Burial expenses Miscellaneous GRAND TOTAL.. Daily average number of inmates-. Inmate per capita io» m m S430.56 I42T.4S 1867.74 </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF &lt; IIMIMKAT1VE DISTRIBUTION HTATKMK.NT O* ANM AL K\ PKMII I I K K- FOB MAINTENANCE OM.i STATE "PENITENTIARY, LINCOLN. NKliltASKA December 1, 1814, to December 1, 1916 Total Dec. 1, 14 CLASSIFICATION Dec. 1. '14 Dec. 1, 15 Dw. 1. H to to to Dec. 1. 15 Dec. 1, 16 Dec. 1 '16 Salaries and wages ) offlceris, employees. He ( Kxtra labor or services I .11755.30 * 30170.81 * 07K26.11 537.16 386.24 W3.40 32392.46 ~3655tT(6 68846.51 Total ~ f Railroml far** official Transport- I Traveling expenses— official atton, I Railroad fare-inmate* _ telegraph (Traveling i'X|&gt;eni«s — inmates and telephone Express nuil freight { Telephone miri telegraph :32.7b 27-4.3K .i07.08 l.-.l.i-, 1«.8O .116.06 ■LM 96.63 itiO.W KM Si.iO W.1B 771.7.1 :I7«.27 1151.01) 372.01 381.SM 753.96 tStHM . ~~{a&amp;M JU80.22 358.00 KU vmJTi «MB 657.(1.' 1150.87 2116.5(1 1640.00 1756.50 4:!J.'.«( LTd.or. 7(ti.ttr. .i340.42 4O8B.5O 741.-).!CJ VJS6.94 7003.56 1.T20H.3O H82.94 1110.5B 1H93.50 «!23.06 805.10 142s. 1.". 1776.73 3041.97 :Wl&amp;70 2&amp;20 23.20 61.14 105.23 1«6.37 21484.47 20596.40 ~42080.87 Total - — — .. Articles of food ( Flour _ I I Sugar | i 'off**** it ml t&lt;?8 ...... I ( 'jiiiiipiI jjoo&lt;ls .„ I other ltim-., fruits him) vegetables ■I Meats — | Lard and Butterlne - I itutter _ I Eggs ...::::::_;:i..::_.::: Milk _ I Cheese and other dairy product*.. Total - - ! , Stock feed... 2523.19 2419.11 4942.30 Tobacco UB1.00 S47.24 1498.24 f Boots, shoes, shoe brashes, lacing. etc I M*Mi s clothing and furnishings.... Clothing ■( Women's rendy-made wearing ap- parel __„_„„„_— . I Miscellaneous (includes repairs) . 1339.78 18»8.&lt;« 3238.40 MMf xm." 3708.14 8.50 5B.94 06.44 Total 3678.85 4333.19 7012.04 1765.16 5152.38 0817.54 Dry goods I_. Hoapital supplies. 861.80 139C.0O 2288.7S Soap, cleansers, starch. etc_ _ _ 1134 6.} 948.76 2083.42 Hardware (other than builders').. 511.61 MLM 847.87 Qneensware and glassware... 264.35 338.48 mm ■Ml 492.! </seg>
            <seg id="p117">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 117 COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION 8TATEMJOT OF ,WM\I. K\ I'KMllTl K»&gt; FOR MAINTENANCE ONLY ( Office supplies •j3-.m r.N-.ti- Stationery, I School books and supplies. books, and -J Books, periodicals and newspa 2.00 I 93.73 paper pers I Miscellaneous 14.1.4»; 1M.H7 ■Ml 13KM7 JXW.77 mm 281.04 MBfXM i.m n -•10.40 .-.iiv, u&gt; 41888.38 [ Engineers' supplies : Klei'trical supplies General re- I Builders' hardware pairs I Faints, oils, glass, paint brushes Kuilding material I Labor Total. Live stock. .■as.oo MMi I— ■Mil 348.20 140.34 iun.4i 1451.70 Kntertainment. 41.48 I ■ m&gt; Burial expenses-. Miscellaneous •4420.18 •llflM.83 •18108.W GRAND TOTAL-. $11238»64 *13«O*1.91 $270445.56 Daily average number of Inmates.. Inmate per capita— — 348 3T8 3m (322.88 $418.21 $74&amp;0&gt; ♦l'rlmarily Inmates' pay in industrial departments. 8TATK PENITENTIARY, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA— (Oontiuu&lt;-&lt;i &gt; Total Deo, 1, 14 De&lt;\ 1, 15 Dei. 1. 14 to to &gt;o Dec. 1, '15 ' Dec. 1. 18 Dec. 1. 'I* CLASSIFICATION '.►42.71 347.43 41.-iKi.S0 5MT4.79 8H8.1* 1183.40 421»1.» 5«858.1» 151A.S1 18M.31 MOtJC ■LM V»M 1712.10 +4«&gt;J 137.S6 SM.4T WT.« 412.19 134»J0 M7.» NOa.«B 1M1.6M 712.40 SO30 292.96 4974.07 427S.86 *H63.»2 '" :a 143T.W roomi, brutbea, polish, and dusters 190.44 ■uel. light lud power ICoal — _ Oils and lubricants Electricity _ .. Water 1.-KK.N6 *&amp; 1VM0.8B Machinery, tools, and supplies [ Fur industrial departments... ; For institution In gen- [ enil - 141T1.W 4!»V11 14087.10 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPABATIVE IIIMKIBI TION STATEMENT OF ANM AI. KI'IMilll Kt« FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL, HOME, MILFORI). NEHItASKA December 1, 1914, to December 1. Ml Total Dec. 1. "14 Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, 14 CLASSIFICATION to to tu Dec. 1, 15 Dec. 1, 16 Drt. 1 16 Salaries I &lt; (Ulcers, employees, etc. and wages ( Extra labor or services.. • ,* 4802.34 f JKtl.tH i MM 484.99 [ 736.2S 1220.17 Total... 6287.13 5756.92 11044.05 I Railroad fare — official. 98.18 S7.76 70.86 44.76 UU1 115.61 Transport- I Traveling expenses — official ation, I Railroad fare — Inmates 8.06 3.64 telegraph 1 Traveling expenses — Inmates 7.80 8.26 mill tolpnhrtn* tWnreKM Htul frfitrlit 19»&gt; «.i •Mill 11.72 1«jM and telephone Express ami freight 686.99 244.70 Telephone and telegraph Total UMM I Floor (H0.5« 251.55 664.72 1597.8.-1 12«).73 452.07 274.14 288.72 [ Suvnr I Coffee and tea... I Canned goods - Articles I other gnx-.. frnits and of food i Meats _ vegetable! I Lard and Hutterine... . I Rntter ■IBP Milk 1.80 { (Tieese and other dairy pro'lurt 72.51 Total.. MM Stock feed. 9TO.08 9M.14 1932.17 Tobacco r Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing, .etc. 99.38 97.13 muu I Men's clothing and furnishings... Clothing ■! Women's ready-made wearing ap- l ..P't. 1 208.10 108.73 6.55 17.30 311 .83 1MB I Miscellaneous (includes repairs) 122.16 122.54 *2».9O 801.00 1S5.48 23T.2O •JK1.23 32K.33 1H.12 168.43 258.83 404.89 5G6.70 lOOl.Otj 48T.S4 801.8B 22O.ffi; 23i.UCi 118.80 15.1.54 118.26 170.46 1.80 3».£1 33.20 L'410.119 352n.W ToUl._. 30U.U3 ■UI .132.1! Dry goods 78B.S6 1070.39 isse.: &gt;-. Hospital sappliea ■ui ■Mi ■MJi Soap, cleansers, starch, etc... 477.24 382.30 839..M Hardware (other tban builders') lll.flS 154.63 2«6.29 Qutcnsware and gla«rw«re 31.40 68.42 S9.I — I Fqrnltnre (Includes repairs) </seg>
            <seg id="p119">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 119 COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANSI \l K \ I- ► Mtl r I KK - FOK MAINTENANCE ONLY NEBRASKA IXDISTRIAL HOME, MILFOBD, NEBRASKA— (Continued i Total Dec. 1, '14 Dec. 1. '15 Dec. 1. '14 to to tn Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1. '16 Dec. 1, - 1« Office supplies Stationery, School books and supplies... hooks, and -{ Books, periodicals and newspa 17.34 :4 ■ ■ OC 1.32 10.58 11.M paper pers Miscellaneous 194.88 3O7.ST7 5O2.SS ToUl.. Brooms, brushes, polish, and duwers.. [Coal Fuel, light I Oils and lubricants, and power 1 Electricity — _ 1 Water Dally average number of Inmates... Inmate per capita — fiS *0 M 202.73 3WS.15 0MJH CLASSIFICATION 157.80 i.T.35 38B.1C 18.12 35.35 W77 M.12 M.iS 47.57 .W83.5S 3M1.M ftTOLK 12S2.-. mx nut &lt;so.«o sow ToU! ■M ss .1775. jr. .1775. •_'."&gt; IW7.08 Machinery, tools, and iupplieH ( For industrial departments i For institution in gen- [_ eral 1«.3» 127.28 28».«7 ToUl - Mi ■ 127» 2SB.87 General re- pair* | Engineers' supplies ......____.. I Electrical supplies i Builders' hardware I Taints, oils, glass, paint brashes I Building material 1 Labor «is.si ten.m 1115.W 46.38 IV.M 243.00 74.02 40.03 1X4.06 4S.53 A4».9» S06JE i-.K'.Wi 577JS0 1104.44 784.30 10S4.49 1838.7* 2184.88 3318.74 5401.41 X otal 70.26 145.00 21SJB Lire stock... 70.26 I Seeds COS 38.38 1U.M Entertainment... 5.90 23.78 2MB Burial expenses. 110.00 86.00 Miscellaneous . 241.90 183.34 GRAND TOTAL f 17805.87 » 214S6.»1 * 38964. </seg>
            <seg id="p120">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 120 COMPARATIVE DI»TKIHl TION STATKM KNT OF ANMAL EXPENDITl RKN FOB- MAINTENANCE ONLY NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE BLIND. NEBRASKA CITY. NEBRASKA December 1, 1914, to Deeemlwr 1. 1916 Total BM, 1. '14 Dec. 1.13 Dec. 1, 14 CLASSIFICATION In to t" Dee. 1. 15 Dec. 1, 18 De«. 1 - 16 Salaries 1 Officers, employees, etc. and Wages I Kxtra liilior m ankM * OmiM * 124HII.7H * M-MJ.-tl :t.-.s.'.«i 2SH.1K! 64.0CI Total. 12348.40 12SM.76 ! 41X11. 1« I Railroad fare— official. 44.WI 20.8* 85.74 frausport- I Traveling expeuses-- -official atlon, I Kallrond fmc lnniatra 19.43 9.73 29.1K 2.M 1&gt;.»S telegraph 1 Traveling e\|«ense» — IninateH and telephone ' Express am! freight .7.1 .75 64.M 81.8C 146.4U Telephone uud telegraph •8.32 77.-JI u:i..-)j Total ■Ml MM I Klmir I Sutrar 2»l.:i6 LtOI.NII 23».4.-. 177.1:: VB.YJ 3013.97 27HO.21 31O.«3 tSU.ST. I I'offee Mini tfH I &lt; aimed goods 81.50 J3S.W iam.tt 1-JU.82 M.a .(40.UU lt!64.5.1 isx.se JI.-...VI BM.T* xe,.&lt;x, Articles I Other gnx-.. fruit* and ves;i*talile&gt; of food •! Me«ts I Lard and tMittcrine •TO.1S .tlrt.-n | Butter ¥**• I Milk I ( lieew and other dairy product 2O.«I 5K.M -4.#l Total. 4541.12 *M&gt;m •I771.V.I Stock feed.. Ml. 51 5W.« 134!l.9fi fob* ceo.... ( Boots, shoes, shoe brashes, lacing, etc 1.63 l.BT, I Men's clothing and furnishings. .. nothing ■; Women's ready-made wearing ap parel I Miscellaneous (Includes repairs) Total. 1.8B ! 1.85 Dry goods.. 104.38 34632 MaVN Hovpital supplies.. 1S4.S7 20K.S1 ■BJi Soap, cleansers, starch, etc. ILV.'.M 137.50 264.44 Hardware (other than builders').. 63.21 134 .53 W7.74 Queeutware and glassware.. 20.15 .'.7.37 77.52 .1 1«L» SJ8J» Fnrnltnre (Includes repaint </seg>
            <seg id="p121">COMPAHATIVE DI9TR1BI TION STATEMK.NT O FOR MAINTENANCE l&gt; IF \NM \l KXPE.N'DITl'KBH NLY NBBHA8KA SCHOOL I-X)K THE BLIND. NE1 (Continued) BKASK CITY. NKBKASKA 1 TToli— Dec, 1, '14 I Dec. 1, '13 Dn-. 1. '14 to to to Dec. 1, IS , Dec. 1. 18 Dec. 1, lti CLASSIFU'ATKIN" Stationery, books, and paper I otllce supplies _. I School books Mint supplies •| Books, periodicals and newspa- pers I Miscellaneous _ 1.-B.43 mm 'JQR.S6 1 LI «.( 34.W) 1»16 m 7.-..(«l 7.» ■■ Total - 4T4.1» • --T'.' '.U ' T54.1O " : Brooms, brushes, polish, and fluster*.. J&lt;&gt;.io 3b 3046 Kuel. light and power f Coal I oils and lultrii-aiits 1 KlM'triclty - I Water mm 2425.» ttm.m mm *?.&lt; mm sT&amp;wi socau aaotM 44X77 MtiM *S».m ■Mii.m 3194.40 0077.48 Total Machinery, tools, and supplies ( For industrial departments ! For institution in uen ( ernl ToUl .... ST2.88 mm — m&amp;.si 512.46 ■MTU 412.lt mm ■■»1.*7 - ' i — ( Engineers' supplies - — 273.03 *0.44 M 47 I Kleetrlcal supplies C3.0B 77 40 14O..V&lt; 273.03 «.44 3«.4T General re- &lt; Builder* 1 hardware 88^35 6.«0 74.» pairs I Paints, oils. plas*. paint brushes 3W.83 54.08 4MA1 I RnildinK mntprlal -. 1M.9O 7S.M M 4.1 1 Labor _ 75O.3« 7-.'4.43 1474.7* 1374..-KI 1081.47 2*08.08 Total Dally arera^e number of inmates 51 51 Innate p«r opltt...- - - I **g» ' «*»■■«• W 7 ** [,lTe Mock. 1S3.S6 anc.no 24.02 K.47 ■ BnterUlnnwnt -... .-■II.IO :t.i.4.-, lurlll expenses 218.47 183.20 ■ «T !i»c*llineous .. GRAND TOTAlu. j* J4.TSt6.ri7 $ 2S(M4.flB * MW1W I . </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE I»1*TK1BI TION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL E\ I'KN DITl RE8 FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF, OMAHA, NEBRASKA December 1, 1914, to December 1. 1916 Total Dec. 1, '14 Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1, '14 to to to tl.ASSIFICATION Salaries and wages ) (itUcers, employees, etc... I Kxtrn lnlxir cr services.. Dec. 1, 'IS Dec. 1, 16 Dec 1 '16 * 28233.28 « 26604.62 % 52S27.90 23« ■ 4K7.64 724.03 26469.67 27082.M 53T»HK ToUl I Kallroail fare - official Transport- I Traveling expenses— official ation, J Kailroad fare — iumates airgraph 1 Traveling e xpenses — inmates and telephone I Kx press and freight I Tele|&gt;bune and telegraph 71 .22 36.40 140.92 eiil* 2-/7.4i 28.U6 64.O5 664.80 69.05 88O4 226.28 99.28 100.40 806.72 69.05 148.72 453.73 Total _ 536.37 1140.38 1078.96 :**.*+ lm.til 168.05 553.07 543.90 1096.97 199.25 159.25 358.5(1 862.19 906.31 1617.50 2941.50 3718.79 «660.2!&gt; 1765.67 1917.46 3083.13 515.35 631.64 1146.99 490.90 610.53 1101.43 459.70 501.72 061.42 2612.43 2547.61 3160.04 46^3 47.91 94.74 MMJI 1175:i.73 22049.00 Articles of food [ Flour - — I Sugar I (offe«- and tea | Canned goods I other groc.. fruits and vegetable* j Meats I Lard and Butterine..._ _ _ I Butter _ I Eggs _ - I Mm I iliecsc and other dairy products... Total — Stock fecd- arj.'.ir 142.55 350.52 f Boots, shoes, shoe brashes, lacing. et c . I Men's clothing and furnishings... Clothing •( Women's ready-made wearing ap- parel _ _____—_—— I Miscellaneous i includes repair!) — 11.95 7.20 MM 28.80 U 3.ao 3.oc 1.70 1.70 42.45 10.80 53.25 Total - - Dry goods.. w ■ ■ -■ 223.07 1046.1.'. 1269.22 Hospital supplies it»i.'.rj 375.30 982.22 Soap, cleansers, starch, etc.. 407.45 560.64 974.OH Hardware (other than builders'). 205.40 263.20 467.6C Qi.eenswire and glassware 2M.7O 216.92 468.62 UK. 44 124.97 277.41 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 123 COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANNl VI. K\ I'KMH r I Kt ■ FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY XEBKASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DEAF, OMAHA, NEBRASKA!— Cootluued) Brooms, brushes, polish, «nd duster*.. 114.87 I 173.35 SMlS 3OB«.ss asarao nnu.« aOLTT I 284.88 ::»i.7« ( Co«l Fuel, light I Oils and lulirirants. and power 1 Electricity mix arias shjs 761.12 844.W m*Xl t Water 4W0.57 7833.41 UMBJS Total Machinery, [ For industrial departments tools, and ■; For Institution in gen- supplies [ eral «T.O8 ■JUW.-J SMUT Total ( Engineers' supplies LTfi.lO Its.sl «15.00 ir*:« uou.w 1MMB MM ".Tir. «.•• 421^4 3IR9» O.« 34K.4A 44..t; 3W.T7 "J06X.IIT Mtl.35 3bM.«Z Sa87.3S 2M2.O1 5829.27 Live stock.. Seedx. 12.32 16.15 27.#I Rntertainment. Burial expenses.. 812.33 407.86 KE0.22 Miscellaneous $ 4WJ2.16 I MSM.37 IIMCTSJB GRAND TOTAL.- 17:i 174 174 1-jxK.iih S324.06 Wit Daily average number of inmates... Inmate per capita — 455.34 I 1WB.IK 3WJI 171.74 ! 1M.27 M8.01 I Electrical supplies General re- \ Builders' hardware — pain I I'ulr.ta, oils. glass, paint l.-usuen I Building material I Labor Ill .OS »51 130.57 &lt; I.ASSlPIfATIOX Dec, 1, tt to Dec. 1, - t5 , Total Dw. 1. 15 Dec. 1, U to to Dec. 1. 16, Dec. 1, 1 stationery, books, and paper ( Offlce supplies 300.23 1SJ7.37 MUM 1 School books and supplies 128.81 381 .W WSt \ Rooks, periodicals and newspa- |H-rs It »T -"4.00 "*' 47 [ Miscellaneous 2.18 'fTTT 134.41 ToUl 48T.T0 744.80 12KJ0 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF COMPARATIVE D18TKIBITION STATEMENT OF ANNUAL lAn.MMIIKK FOB MAINTENANCE ONLY NEBRASKA HOME FOR DEPENDENT CHILDREN. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 Total Dec. 1. '14 Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1. '14 to to to Dec. 1, 'IS Dec. 1, '16 Dec. 1 16 CLASSIFICATION Salaries and wiiuf« \ Officers, employees. et&lt;- I Kxtra labor or service* « 4336.11 f 3880.91 * S22U.02 1203.00 1154.75 2357.73 5542.11 3044.66 10586.77 Total _ -. I Traveling expenses — official _ Transport- I Railroad fare — official ation, j Railroad fare— inmates t&lt;*lri;r»i'h I Traveling expenses — iuiuatt-» t telephone I Express and freight I Telephone and telegraph 4*6.31 165.08 V.t.M 34.75 51.23 UV. ill 458.38 1057.04 447.36 982.67 139.(15 -MH.r.: 10-J.57 152.56 9.04 43.79 47.46 98.69 1208.87 25§8.88 Total Articles of food f Flour _ _ _ 23.95 9.25 I Sugar _ _ 48.70 34.76 coffee and tea 22.31 141.30 I Canned goods 4l.rts 34.81 I Other groc.. fruits and vegetable* 284.38 221.«4 Meats 139.43 107.39 I Lard and Butterlne 9.19 7.00 I Butter - _ 129.15 1*7 44) I Eggs »«.:«l 26.4* I Milk 17SI.2S 408.21 Lflieese and other dairy products !».9tt 9.75 Total 924.53 963.04 33.20 83.4.1 38.81 76.4H 508.02 244.82 16.19 216.61 62.K7 587.46 19.65 1887.57 I Stock feed .ao; .30 _ Tobacco "L i Boots, shoes, shoe brushes. lacing. etc — - ' 2«»» .v&gt;o I Men's clothing and furnishings. -j 288.17 Clothing ■( Women's ready-made wearing •p-| [ parel 2^4-5* I Miscellaneous (Includes repairs) 3B.il Total - 858.30 ' 329.1.*. 566.73 340.21 629.3$ 286.48 561.32 WkM 8«.9O !««.(« 1884.33 ! Dry goods... 72.80 84.44 157.1H 1 Hospital supplies.. - 14409 lOK.Tti 313.45 Soap, cleansers, starch, etc ... 21 .95 24.00 46.00 Hardware (other than builders'). mm 2.16 12.74 Qv.eensware and glassware. 1.30 .60 2.10 J 54.06 M 54.80 l'arnltnre (Includes repairs).. </seg>
            <seg id="p125">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 125 COMPARATIVE DISTRIBUTION STATEMENT OF ANSI M EXPEND1TI RES FOR MAINTENANCE ONLY NKBltASKA HOME FUR DEPENDENT CHILDREN. LINCOLN. NEIUCASKA ii'nntlnued) "ttT Dec. 1. 14 Dec. 1, ! 1S Dtr. 1, '14 CLASSIFICATION to to to to to 'o Dec. 1. '15 Dec. 1. '!« ! Dr.: L p l« Dec. 1. *M Bi» 1. 16 De.-. 1. "1« f Office supplies 125.98 129.07 M IK Stationery. School hooks anil supplies....- tM 12.18 ' 14.43 Stationery. I School hooks anil supplies....- tM 12.18 14.43 hooks, and I Rook*.- periodic*])* and newspa- honks, and ' Bimks,* periodic!!]* and newspa- paper I pers ... X&gt; 7.75 - i»i I MiMvllaiH-ous 8.70 4.4« : 11.U paper I pera .W 7.75 « '"i { Misavllaiivoiix 6.70 4.4K ! ll.M Total 136.18 147.4»j MM Total IK. IK 147.44 ; MJI Brc&gt;&lt; ms. I. rushes, polish, and du»ten&gt; 4.00 2.0B Mi i m i«4o i«w» mum Uri" mis. hrnshes, polish, and du»tpn&gt;. 4.110 2.00 Mi 1W.40 1««.X ■*■ i 'fill Fuel, light I Oll» and Inbrlcanta «0 .06 M Fuel, llirht I Oll» and hlbrleutalllZZZZ- ••&gt; ■« .« and power 1 Electricity +4.7S UJi 7*» I Water _ 6.75 6.00 12.7R Total 212.M 2OM0 416.41 44.7S 31 M 7« 3« and power 1 Electricity Water - I «.75 Ml 12.7S Total 212.53 208.88 416.41 ; I Machinery. ( Kor Induntrial department* Machinery, I For Industrial departments — tools, nnil ! For institution in gen- tools, nnd ', For institution In sen- supplies I er«l - ■*»' M 3.3B Total S-SO ■*» L» ( Knglneers' supplies __ — — — ~~~ — — I Electrical supplies *■ 'M »M .1311 M 3.SB supplies I era! tM Total Knsineerk' supplies _ — - — — — — — Elertrli-Kl supplies 2.IR ..»1 •.•.». Electrli'Bl supplies General r»- &lt; Builders' hardware - pairs I I'a'nts. oils, (class, paint hmabc* - I Building material ■■■ ■■-■ — -~- -j - | Labor . _ _ - x *■* 7 -* pairs I I'nints. oils, glass, paint hrnsbe* Total - *•» I*.™ 17J1 Live itock ■m* tut Entertainment 8400 06.00 18000 Burial expenses. 1073161 Miscellaneous (primarily hoard I r*^.* t 2B2S1.W * 4243».4S ORAND TOTAL. Daily average numher of Inmates — ••' Inmate per cplt. 1 I**-" •»•«••• »•■» </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF lllMKIBl TIO.N 8TATEMEKT OF EXPKND1TI KKK tUK THE BUAKU "I COMMISSIONERS OF MATE 1&gt;!&gt;TITI TION *, FOB THE PERIOD DECEMBER 1. 1*14, TO DECEMBER I. 1S1« Total N CLASSIFICATION Dec. 1, 14 Dec. 1. 13 Dae. 1,14 Dec. 1, 14 Dec. 1. 15 Dee. 1. "14 to to to to to to Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1. - 1« Dec. 1. '1« Dec. 1, '15 Dec. 1. '16 Dec. 1, '1« Salaries of members of the board $ 9000.00 $ 9OU0.nu $ 19000.0U Salaries of members of the board _ $ 9000.00 * 9O0O.OU $ 18000.00 Salaries of officers and employees of tbe board..- 7UW.B7 696U.O0 1 :«W.»°.tfT Salaries of officers and employees of the board... 7099.67 8960.00 lSWit.OT Extra help in office of tbe board Ml!*) »!o0 S46ia&gt; Postage _ 1 Stt.00 6S0.0U J175O0 Telephone and telegraph _ 325.41 M &gt;H Tl«!o5 Extra help Id office of the board 311.30 36.00 346.3U 346J0 Postage - 1 Stt.00 650.01) j 175 00 Telephone and telegraph _ 325.41 NMt 711»!oB Railroad fare of members of the board, officers and employee* 305.82 448.17 733.79 Railroad fare of members of the board, officers and employees 305.82 448.17 753.79 All otter traveling expenses of tbe board, officers All otter traveling expenses of the board, officers and employees _ __ 134.66 134.81 Jtf'46 and employers _ __ IMJi 134.81 -ttt.46 Advertising ...". _ »J8 OJB 127.78 Advertising _ 86.28 42J0 127.7* Binding and lettering books _ 20.75 117". IUB Binding and lettering books _ j»75 n 75 sj.ou Printing _ _ _ 626.03 336.35 UH2.38 Printing ... . _ 026.08 338.35 UH2.38 Foldfng cartons 12.50 ..!.... 12.50 Foldfng cartons „ 12.50 12.50 stationer* i itiHuilft* the follom'iug only: Blank paper and books, carbon paper, wrapping pa - per. nrlilinK machine paper, rubber bands, pens, penholders, ink, pencils, erasers, mucilage, paste, rubber stamps, stamp pads, blotters, typewriter rililMiiiN. stencil*, derinax, guide sheets, index sheets, folders for flies, tabs, desk calendars, clips, blank envelopes, letter opener, staples, map, spindle, twine, finger protectors, ink wells, paper file, mimeo varnish, eyelets, tags and hinders I - _ - 411.01 336.66 746.87 stationer.* i iiiHuilft* the follom'iug only: Blank paper and books, carbon paper, wrapping pa - per, ndiling machine paper, rubber bands, pens, penholders, ink, pencils, erasers, mucilage, paste, rubber stamps, stamp pads, blotters, typewriter rililMiiiN. stencil*, derinax, guide sheets, index sheets, folders for flies, tabs, desk calendars, clips, blank envelopes, letter opener, staples, map, spindle, twine, finger protectors, ink wells. paper file, mimeo ' varnish, eyelets, tags and binders) - 411.01 336.66 746.67 Benslne _ .23 ! .25 Benzine _ &amp; \ .25 Mimeograph machine 166.00 155.00 Mimeograph machine 16600 15500 Typewriter _ ; s.1 &lt;n .13.(13 lieio* Typewriter 83.08 t3.(B 116.06 Rent of typewriter ' 6.00 15.35 21.26 Rent of typewriter - ' 6.00 18.35 21.26 Repairs to typewriter, mimeograph, adding ma- Repairs to typewriter, mimeograph, adding ma - chine and numbering machine _ l» 40 6.81 17.2J chine and numbering machine „ 10.40 6.81 17.21 Filing cases and repairs thereto [ ll».*0 264.10 388.50 Filing cases and repairs thereto ltt.40 264.10 388.50 MLM Chair . 6.75 18.50 25.25 Chair 6.75 18.50 25.25 Table _ 11.00 8.00 l!»!oo Table _ 11.00 8.00 19.00 Waste paper basket snd filing basket..... .00 1.85 2.75 Blue print case _ 20.00 82.15 102.15 Waste paper basket and filing basket..... .90 1.85 2.75 Blue print case _ 20.00 Telephone arm - — _— 4.00 Blue print ease _ 20.00 82.15 102.15 102.15 Telephone arm 4.00 4 00 4.U) Paper rack 1.50 ._ 1.50 Paper rack Rubber stamp rack 1.50 ..._ 1.50 Rubber stamp rack _ . _ 1.5* _ 1 50 1.J0 1.30 Copy holder _.. 3.50 3.50 7.00 Copy holder _.. 3.50 3.50 7.00 Door in basement 4.36 ..- 4.95 Batteries and repairs to buiaer system 4.50 2.75 7.25 Door in basement 4.36 ..- 4.35 Batteries and repairs to butser system 4.50 2.75 7.26 Towel service ISjM 12.00 24.00 Towel service 12.00 12.00 24.00 Cash box - - .'. 2.00 2.00 Cash box ' 2 00 ° 00 Lock and bolt - - - 1.90 1.90 Lock and bolt _ _ 1.90 1.90 Klectricxl supplies and lamps for electric lights... 19.04 2.0U 21.04 KlectricRl supplies snd lamps for electric lights.... 19.04 2.00 21.04 Oak cabinet for cstalogs _ 21.75 21.7B Oak cabinet for catalogs _ 21.75 H.H Cork carpet for vault _ 14.40 14.40 Cork carpet for vault _ 14.40 14.40 F.iroleuin H»il lii&gt;i&gt;lenin cement 6.55 6.55 I ii'olenti' H»il liri'lei'in cement 6.55 6.55 Rubber Underwood typewriter key» _ 7.00 7.00 Rubber Underwood typewriter keys 7.00 7.00 Pencil sharpener _ 2.50 2.50 Pencil sharpener .". _ 2.50 2JS0 Hotchkiss stapler _ 3.00 :{.00 Post binder _ „. _ - 1.41 1.41 Moistener __ „ 3.00 3.00 Stenographers' desk and chair _ 4.1.00 45.0TI Punch 2.00 2.00 Electric fan _ __ 39.13 39.1S Oak leg and brace* for bookkeepers' desk 1.00 LOO Totals I 19264.24 $ 18044.56 S 3S2IW.8U </seg>
            <seg id="p127">127 DINTRIBITION STATEMENT OF EXPENDITURES FOX THE NEBRASKA COMMISSION" FOR THE BLIND, FOR THE PERIOD DECEMBER 1. 1*11. TO DECEMBER 1. 1»1« CLASSIFICATION Dec. 1. '14 Dec. 1, "15 Dec 1. f 14 to to t.&gt; Dec. 1, -15 Dec. 1, '1« Dec. 1. T« Salary of field agent Commission of field agent on sums collet-ted Railroad fare of field agent All other traveling expenses of Held agent Postage Express charges Printing Stationery linclndes the following only: receipt books and folders) Telephone Totals _ * 130.00 S 480.00 | «HL» _» .40 1.2ii 13.S2 200.50 214.3- 7-.06 3W.M 4... . .40 4.0B 4.45 .15 ._ J8 WOO 20.00 30.00 9 70 9 to 1.05 MB </seg>
           
            <seg id="p128">Repairs Paints, oils, glass, paint brushes... Building material I Labor _ 986.36 2396.77 797.39 390.30 586.12 2185.95 1513.13 944.21 1300.86 1626.62 1523.59 3277.31 1QO.W, 357.651 695.81 1841.85 2565.85 3027.08 343.02 3812.14 3589.55 1789.80 44Z.48 1326.89 2261.78 928.79 w.uo 55.94 115.89 1038.76 807.99 577.65 1214.53 BU4.47 1849.80 1461.68 292.96 114.UO 895.52 1194.46 1838.79 74.95 454.81 98.43 1474.79 80.90 629.83 .... 393.77 .... 3049.42 7J5 4:{22.H" 16772J3 18865.79 21381.56 Total 9033.99 4529.77 5294.94 14170.49 5382.95 10669.07 16652.04 10596.15 2308.51 4992.85 8853.92 5401.42 2606.03 5829.27 17.31 MM ;: Live Stock 349.57 519.98 4787.5H 2465.00 25.00 1584.40 2286.70 1099.00 366.75 1439.00 215.25 3Ho.:i« tmmm ■m* 580.00 341.09 574.37 663.04 67.22 1 1354.65 1290.00 1037.35 113.31 67.11 1451.70 101.46 50.39 27.47 7719.16 Entertainment 257.X7 279.66 1006.65 446.69 . J 1399.60 2508.30 436.21 34.86 92.45 182.00 mm MM 150.57 ia.n MU Burial Expenses.. 73.14 5.00 2975.77 391.75 863.75 369.00 447.50 165.00 180.00 5470.91 Miscellaneous 1183.49 1104.43 626.86 1080.24 132.39 787.03 1515.87 1170.81 488.43 2466.20 •16106.99 425.14 398.67 1020.22 t24000.75 MM ■ Grand Total $151301.67 $ 61826.74 $126563.31 $200663.40 $ 69368.32 $ 384878.78 $287804.57 $190865.06 $ 42329.06 $102071.47 $270445.55 $ 39354.78 $ 49661.26 $106878.53 $ 42439.49 2115361.98 II— FURNITURE AND EQUIPMENT Furniture (includes freight, etc).... * 2109.28 $ 1646.40 $ 352.00 $ 1437.82 $ 1519.17 $ 1270.60 $ 2829.24 $ 3236.08 $ 1104.30 $ Z109M $ 1661.13 $ 463.85 $ 881.23 $ 1484.13 $.... $ 22704.32 ( For institution in general...- Equipment I For hospital 'includes j For farm freight, etc.i ! For industrial departments I For laundry 1628.41 '.'' 894!50 589.78 10.20 ... 41.00 75.00 2526.36 414.50 764.89 iti'M 809;08 979.11 5490.67 . 1942.53 341.03 12.00 i "' ***l 1850.37 833.75 402.00 '""H&amp;J8S . 1984.42 1277.39 109.68 39.54 1066.20 137.61 549.30 48.00 . 498.84 718.10 740.56 12.25 ... 1298.06 649.85 686.57 195.86 176.00 312.04 38.00 85.14 18.50 20.50 637.49 43J0O 66.05 mm 4389.28 54.95 1738.18 666.00 17.40 ib.bb 179SLM 4166.39 3021.2O 3031.02 11162.15 1195.75 HoM Total I 1922J1 1922.91 3242.34 3242.34 1637.01 7064.64 2295.56 3101.97 3411.03 2299.95 2066.66 2588.79 1178.25 254.36 836.34 6837.41 27 40 MNbM Grand Total t 4032.19 $ 4888.74 $ 1989.01 $ 8502.46 $ 3814.73 $ 4372.57 $ 6240.27 $ 5536.03 $ 3770.96 $ 5297.881 t 2839.38 $ 718.21 $ 1717.57 $ 8321.54 $ 27.401$ mm i III— PERMANENT IMPROVEMENTS TO BUILD- INGS AND GROUNDS Labor _ Lumber _ Brick and Stone .i- _ Cement, Fire Clay, Sand, Plaster and Lime Paints, Oils. Glass and Paint Brushes Structural Steel _ Engineers' Supplies _ Electrical Supplies _ Builders' Hardware .... _ _ _... Miscellaneous (includes freight, ete.) $ 174.40 $ 3584.87 $ 485.90 $ 334.88 $ 1362.20 S 125.00 74.50 415.30 575.56 „ _ _ ] 169.46 - 7.00 18.00 79.20 274.28 ,,,. 46.90 "" 1582.40 _ 1112.49 56.75 557.00 49.91 15.46 3.90 9.70 35.55 27.45 916.15 2389.08 278.30 106.56 2083.01 1216.65 $ 11388.89 $ 64.26 607.28 350.30 351.15 651.26 563.97 237.09 35.70 18.00 2159.43 2204.03 1498.25 497.22 5008.21 36.00 606.94 $ 999.90 $ 395.12 279.46 1360.54 S1.62 14.50 1641.34 694.70 5296.35 758.31 ... 144.60 _... 6882.76 4.00 ; 2589.89 196.30 840.12 473.33 10.25 99.04 401.80 67i6 922.85 * 9195.90 $ 8366.22 $ 888.82 59.38 194.76 1203.14 28.45 260.19 2.40 308.48 15.85 14357.20 1620.72 31987.12 43.57 381.45 67.33 1 625.75 77.09 754.83 $ 2879.31 $. 380.40 4.78 414.00 101.66 3900 26.40 12.69 1.06 106.57 9066.00 ■ _ t 434*0.78 8736.70 14S9:.i4 MLH M.N 4M71.17 2747.14 21501.33 Grand Total $ 3629.18 $ 6052.35 $ 2355.59 $ 544.90 $ 4368.07 $ 11185.45 $ 15702.24 $ 16659.23 $ 2456.91 $ 5601.1 $ 59352.80 $ 10968.01 $ 1834.54 $ 4450.14 $ $1444*0.94 IV— NEW BUILDINGS AND LAND When Erected by Contractors.. $ 36076.13 $ 16564.90 . $ 25296.27 $ . $ 28145.00 $ 71392.72 $ 60443.17 $ 14245.42 $ f 124.40 $ $ 56132.38 $ 20879.76 $317800.15 When Erected by State Labor _ _ Lumber _ _ _ Brick and stone _ _ Cement, fire clay, sand, plaster and lime Paints, oils, glass and paint brushes Structural steel _ _ Engineers' supplies - Electrical supplies „ Builders' hardware _ Miscellaneous (includes freight, etc) 1601.15 157.66 670.10 363.19 866.96 1897.12 1696.47 393.6", 630.00 2157.94 111.12 29.20 677.08 U7.00 _ 42.76 49.20 11SJ1 — 361.20 18 50 27 23 40 00 23 00 - ..„ 33.80 808.70 : _.._ 128.77 - - • 18.60 _ 49.68 .. i 589.38 16*1.48 877.23 226.06 256.41 - _ 49.40 TjA _ _ ■ 7.«6 - 54.91 UM 28.40 — ■ 1«O-M - - 386.69 16.00 143.64 636.79 'SB 24.00 18.80 4*81 94.76 17.60 _ 684.90 719.78 6*7.52 73.96 122.80 : last- 37.75 81.66 JK 24.30 4.00 _ „ 624.44 _ 38.98 . i 10.96 5.25 11.00 . " UMLS2 57.72 8.46 . 284 07 Wit 194.35 1 62.10 962.91 2927.86 44CM 344.68 1879.10 Total _ 44H9.K4 2117.51 1570.03 269.76 1160.37 3648.66 173.65 2396.99 1622.29 577.74 153.31 1480.33 714.. Land 9600.00 275.00 5850.00 2800.00 100.00 ..._. 50.00 21175.00 Grand Total 49824.79 15738.56 2396.99 1622.29 25874.01 153.31 $ 29900.33 $ 81682.56 $ 55360.68 $ 1 $ 1670.03 $ 394.16 50.00 $ KM1.M $ 24540.13 $359521.09 *" V— MISCELLANEOUS Miscellaneous * $..._ $ .. $ $ . „... $ 12000.00 9 * ■ 9~ ■■ $ $ t$ 5000.00 t 359696*! RECAPITULATION MAIN GRAND DIVISIONS .... $ 151801.67 $ 61826.74 4888.74 6052.35 15738.55 $126563.31 $200663.40 $ 69368.32 1989.01 8502.46 3814.73 2366.69 544.90 4368.07 2396.99 1622.29 25874.01 $384878.78 $287804.57 4372.57 ' 6240.27 11185.45 16702.24 153.31 29900.33 $190866.06 $ 42329.06 $102071.' 6636.03 3770.96 5297.1 16659.23 2466.91 5601.1 R1682.56 66860 68 14M#J 1 170445.56 2839.58 MHJJ t 39364.78 718.21 ioaw.01 $ 3629.18 r EXPENDITURES FOR ALL INSTITUTIONS UNDER THE JURISDICTION OF THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS OF STATE INSTITUTIONS DBCUIBSR 1»U TO nm &gt; mm . iExpfdiiv*, «f tfc. Bmri «f Co««Uwo,,r. of 8UU UttfU— . iW Rritrf «f tW BW Exctafed HmftM.) |E(n ;:.;;:. 1074.30 484.42 179.4» 3388.25 1911.09 2716:56 19U.U 48S:50 211i:93 2666:28 381870 28872 •Site Itil 2U^t! Milk _ 143.60 11.45 12.00 10.48 3113.15 87.56 2759 42 4730 26 23 20 lan -?5i 42 tt87 «*»«-« I Chee« Mother dairy produrt. 380.64 63.88 73.72 844.40 180.39 576.49 357.55 MUM. Se^ Sw 1MS7 72:" ii« «4M 1»« 1^- 1 T *d S949389 1429822 g* 139^ M092.14 24003.1C 123711.98 79138.18 48869.92 13798.79 29175.64 42060.87 6936.93 977^ £MH9.(H iggTl? 64»447 4&lt; Engineers supplies 3102.81 857.21 826.07 6605.80 1445.62i 2798.56 4603.86 3606.19 703.11 1230.62 3402.92 1115.60 362.47 615 00 Electrical supplwi 1153.53 471.38 292.55 941.51 874.02 1227.39 2367.09 2030.12 334.76 931.38 1742.10 243.00 140.58 106035 Builders' hardware 098.13 38.81 418.12 295.66 168.00 707.17. 489.60 442.38 60.05 230.68 604.47 114.06 74 95 80 90 4603.86 3606.19 703.11 1230.62 3402.92 1115.60 362.47 615.00 31175A4 2367.09 2030.12 334.76 931.38 1742.10 243.00 140.58 1060.35 »JM 13819:72 - 1153.53 471.38 292.55 941.51 874.02 1227:39 •M 13819.72 General CLASSIFICATION si In 9 U CM r ,11 ill P til B 3 ill i HI H Is ill k { mt V U He m w I— MAINTENANCE I Average Daily Inmate Population.. 102 199 426 116 1133 733 119 ■I 174 Salaries and Wages ) Officers, employees, etc „ ..... ( Extra labor or services j t 49063.14 f 14677.94 $ 41623.29 $ 49980.51 $ 17264.91 475.84 889.53 2227.62 4041.51 48U 4:i $137248.62 $ 96481.33 S 67481.42 S 18876.40 $ 36015.45 814JTC 1764^1 1 2946.29 681.60 766.13 I 67926.11 923.40 * SOM8 $ 24642.20 $ UM7J0 $ 1290.17 368.96 724.08 mr.75 'mrnji Total L... 49628.98 16467.47 43860.91 53972.02 1773o.:i4 138163.54 98196.14 70427.71 14058.00 36780.58 MMLH 11044.05 24901.16 58651.93 10686.77 7071 U. 11 | Railroad fare I __, . \ rranaporU- Traveling expenses J umc »*' i tkm. Telegraph ) Railroad fare ( , . J tnd Telephone | Traveling expense* J 'a™* 1 ** ( i Express and freight I Telephone and telegraph 4—\ 163.97 8.96 10.74 7.50 431.26 311.36 142.79 161.60 46.68 63.77 338.40 384.72 698.72 39.80 76.62 328.48 13.35 33.30 337.02 .... 1. 62.20 ' 687.47 834.18 77s!36 344.66 463.19 283.61 324.78 1H9.19 106.00 66.84 1106.78 1289.62 161.03 109.18 688.71 101.86 876.73 906.31 161.01 238.25 46.77 20.51 687.75 493.06 37.88 29.70 55.00 20.60 4.92 6.00 100.74 820.75 224.24 869.19 507.08 316.06 160.99 91.16 1151.00 753.95 166.91 116.61 11.72 16.06 686.99 244.70 66.74 29.18 £9« •76 146.48 143.52 MJ* 100.45 806.72 69.06 148.72 463.73 1067.04 HX.91 304.13 152.56 43.79 98.6» 3.S«1 H MHJ7 8884.40 7W4.44 h- TotaL 923.78 923.78 1137.86 1137.86 2368.65 1360.52 1166.78 2368.55 1350.52 1166.78 MM 2783.82 1645.35 419.16 1749.86 2980.22 1230.99 388.64 1676.95 iS4-+4.- Articles of Food I Floor _ I Sugar Coffee and tea Canned goods Other groceries, fruits and vegetables. i Meats Lard and butterine „ „. I Butter . Eras 7795.26 1790.29 1775.80 1834.29 8720.38 9724.57 4474.84 1780.03 1074.30 1240.04 734.26 496.75 957.48 2601.17 5311.75 1161.68 1246.34 484.42 4189.40 2811.05 852.60 1613.65 4272.78 7638.83 2549.11 47.30 179.49 3936.15 4679.61 6841.08 4121.59 8061.94 25627.23 5583.98 1107.43 3388.25 866.501 1466.03 1152.24 1871.60 3206.68 7370.24 488.16 2387.07 1911.09 15134.38 6903.19 5648.87 4569.71 20145.86 .-&gt;1907.26 10430.88 5778.78 2716.56 9438.93 6770.67 3813.98 2403.17 13711.51 26763.46 8328.96 5548.26 1914.14 5662.03 5289.46 3290.20 598.19 8169.58 18022.83 4223.05 2488.25 485.50 115.04 529.93 148.15 879.85 2622.28 3207.19 178.13 1290.67 2111.93 349.48 1237.08 317.45 1698.41 9386.01 4701.88 739.69 3254.18 2666.28 6466.21 1150.87 8756.60 702.95 7415.92 15259.50 1893.50 1428.15 3818.70 432.68 610.56 261.56 664.72 1597.85 1289.73 452.67 274.14 5&gt;KS 79 289.46 580.36 177.13 666.19 3013.97 2780.21 310.63 1266.94 £R9 AK. 168.06 1096.97 358.50 1617.50 J««. 13 1146.99 1101.43 OMt At* 3SJ0 88.45 SU1 76.19 MU 16.19 216.61 MM6.79 28818.61 24274^ WMI.14 1834J4.6:i 41»78.4« 23214..&gt;» Stock Feed 2115.09 2290.01 8927.98 6422.08 398.86 11317.76 7226.37 2823.46 459.60 13.15 MMI 1932.17 IMMI 350.52 .30 ■MMI Tobacco . :i.',2.91 3187.37 2503.06 1056.29 .10 1498.24 ..._ mm 9i Clothing Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing, etc Men's clothing and furnishings Women's ready-made wearing apparel I Miscellaneous (includes repairs) I... 1591.25 700.77 89.02 2512.22 2314.34 881.64 566.27 377.42 222.80 4126.68 8800.87 692.30 4.00 662.63 3986.31 77.38 144.65 5758.52 7022.43 788.10 64.04 4413.31 6692.40 954.73 161.64 1691.56 5.06 5.25 2887.08 136.25 11.00 141.75 .. 1 3238.46 3708.14 ... 65.44 196.61 1.66 "' 3li!83 _ 23.86 _ _ 19.15 ■lM 3.60 1.70 586.73 6»J8 561.32 86.80 23006.54 ■•JH481.97 604&amp;M ltl&amp;7i Tof | 5362.53 1489.84 2403.36 5362.53 I4Hy.H4 2403.36 13623.86 13623.86 4870.97i 4870.97 13633.09 13633.09 12112.08 12112.08 4855.64 5.05 16.25 4855.64 5.05 16.25 7012.04 7012.04 532.19 1.65 63.26 18*4.33 S7x.i« H Dry Goods • 4959.77 2683.75 5025.24 5221.43 13008.44 13114.64 9236.18 5417.51 HS5..S4 3489.39 6917.54 1859.35 45:(.7O IMMI 157.13 ■U7-W*.; Hospital Supplies 1105.03 336.30 597.03 2460.02 786.52 6797.06 4239.69 2739.98 2069.06 7047.2r 2288.79 544.55 393.18 HM2.2-J US. 45 32&amp;*&gt;.i* Soap. Cleansers, Starch, Etc 2333.58 862.26 1190.86 1917.83 642.91 :&lt;7OX.4J 3446.68 2030.96 441.42 1436.06 2U*s.42 839.54 iH4.44 ■J'i.W 46.00 mmut Hardware, (other than builders' i 768.71 414.55 616.08 1062.01 418.621 1383.88 1344.51 r&gt;H9.l:i 284.90 566.18 847.87 266.29 197.74 4-i7 r*i 12.74 9320.87 {ueensware and Glassware. :i2fi.7:i 188.53 132.42 540.37 295.68! .Vi4.2&lt;: 1339.19 :i7K.;m 118.29 MMi MM 89.82 77.52 iM.62 2.10 ml Furniture (includes repairs) 885.09 1104.36 374.19 1693.45 583.89 1516.76 1083.95 715.34 •UH 393.33 492.93 933.78 505.69 277.41 :.4.hi) wma Stationery, Books, and Paper 1 Office supplies J School books and supplies Books, periodicals and newspapers I Miscellaneous 1234.09 37.50 57.00 313.12 611.60 994.34 110.01 126.88 762.62 591.74 376.33 63.88 215.32 468.75 238.63 99 01 3325.68 646.12 881.33 2079.53 181.64 615.56 1623.74 622.10 38.76 m.35 13.26 304.21 219.93 !*24.76 J74.O6 33.13 233.14 1880.60 544.11 95.73 299.33 385.15 53.77 52.02 11.91 292.96 324.89 53.7.-» 82.50 507 M 5M.82 80.47 134.41 249.06 14.43 11.16 15330.06 1571.16 40M.M Total 1641.71 IMMI 855.28 1418.15 1050.49 337.64 4853.13 irra.n 2143.06 1565.08 2819.77 502.85 754.10 ■u 2*2.rf4 .'4i::,J Brooms. Brushes, Polish and Dusters 313.03 277.94 195.35 236.35 C8.20 1UM 722.44 323.39 140.44 208.03 261.04 47.57 30.4.-! 288.22 %m ■a i Fuel. Light, and Power f Coal I Oils and lubricants Electricity Water 23843.15 1260.43 3434.38 8950.48 193.34 1952.40 1027.26 11310.48 22348.68 425.51 1642.33 4400.52 525.00 8401.91 99.54 1705.10 116.20 19104.71 1363.58 65.70 . 32298.33 1871.39 5.W ... 27724.42 1115.23 1486.50 4269.52 50.21 937.60 65.00 8393.69 261.91 922.36 1990.72 38834.14 6704.92 2836.97 211.56 210.40 50.60 4.87 4601.32 $gJK 580.66 829.63 10113.68 436.76 308.33 1606.21 :!2«.*5 .66 7rt..i« 12.75 247116.08 11836.28 16190.91 6181.64 Total _ 28537.96 12123.48 16661.51 23991.01 10322.75 40533.99 34174.72 30326.15 5312.33 11468.68 41886.38 6967.08 6077.48 12523.98 416.41 281323.91 Machinery. Tools, and Supplies t For industrial departments i For institution in general Total 1194.82 529.41 5643.17 739.18 1128.60 429.26 43.56 IM4MJU 10.15 2749.77 1655.17 3i7;57 11.10 265.84 56674.79 .. 1183.40 289^67 685.39 291.97 2387.36 298.01 3.M 84456.52 1M19.6O 1194.82 529.41 6382.35 1128.60 429.26 1886.90 2759.92 1655.17 317.57 276.94 56868.19 ■Ml 977.36 &gt;&gt;^:-, ;: 3.59 77375.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">A BIENNIAL AINTENANCE EXPENDITURE BASED ON EXPENDITURES FOR MAINTENA CE FOR PERIOD December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 CLASSIFICATION Average Daily Inmate Population Salaries and j Officers, employees, etc Wages ( txtra labor or services Total 59 1 r • " a - - • a _- S§ 2 ?■ § Sr.g •_ •_■*. |53g jl I ft» J 496 102 199 * 98.89$ 142.92 $ 209.16 $ .96 8.72 11.20 99.85 151.64 220.36 . si III 425 117.48 * 9.51 126.99 -— — _&gt; — — * * 115 1133 150.04 $ 12L~ 4.18 , 154.22 121. l5 ,S J 111 I 733 .14 $ 131.55 .81 2.41 .95 133.96 144 Hi I si |i: _-£.= 603 B~$ 134.16^ 1 5.86 6 140.02 III 84 * 393.42 20.05 I 413.47 S = So I* 1 31 i! 00 ■ U fli ?«§ £*3 V_L I ft ill I 1133 733 503 34 119 363 64 51 174 75 121.14 $ .81 131.55 $ 2.41 134.16 $ 5.86 393.42 % 20.05 302.65 6.43 $ 187.10 I 2.56 153.50 $ 19.06 481.21 $ 7.03 303.61 I 4.16 109.72 31.44 220.36 126.99 154.22 121.95 133.96 140.02 413.47 309.08 189.66 172.56 488.24 307.77 141.16 I Railroad fare ( , Traveling expenses ) Tiansporta- Railroad fare ( tion.'lcle^raph Traveling expenses ) and Telephone . Kxpress and ireight I telephone and telegraph Official j Inmates \" .30 .02 .02 .02 .87 .62 1.39 1.58 .47 .63 3.32 3.77 3.01 1.65 1.69 . .31 . 3.47 1.73 .09 .03 .67 .29 .29 .17 .09 .06 .98 1.14 .22 .15 .85 .14 1.20 1.23 .32 .47 .09 .04 1.37 .98 1.11 ... .87 .61 .18 . 2.96 6.60 .46 .04 1.40 .87 .44 .25 3.17 2.07 2.44 1.81 .18 .25 10.73 3.82 1.29 .57 .06 .01 2.87 2.82 .57 .58 4.63 .40 .85 2.61 14.09 12.44 4.06 2.03 .58 1.32 L96 1.09 £72 2.46 6.89 7.31 Total rf .__. 1.85 11.16 11.86 11.86 3.17 10.14 2.73 3.79 3.27 12.33 14.70 8.20 19.23 7.62 9.64 34.52 Articles of Food j Fiour Sugar 1 Conee and tea , Canned goods Utner groceries, fruits and vegetables Meats Lard and butterine Butter if*** 1 Mnic I Cheese and other dairy products 15.72 3.61 3.58 3.70 17.58 19.60 9.02 3.58 2.17 .29 .76 12.16 7.20 4.87 9.39 25.50 52.07 11.39 12.21 4.75 .11 .53 21.05 14.13 4.28 8.11 21.47 37.89 12.81 .24 .90 .06 .37 9.26 10.78 16.10 9.70 18.94 60.30 13.14 2.61 7.97 .02 1.99 7.45 12.75 10.02 16.27 27.88 64.09 4.24 20.76 16.62 27.07 1.57 13.36 6.09 4.90 4.03 17.78 45.81 9.21 5.10 2.40 .51 12.87 9.23 5.20 3.28 18.71 36.52 11.36 7.57 2.61 .12 .49 11.26 •10.51 6.54 1.19 16.24 35.83 8.39 4.95 .97 __ 3.38 15.59 4.36 25.88 74.18 94.33 5.24 37.96 62.11 81.16 1.65 2.93 10.39 2.67 14.27 78.87 39.51 6.22 27.35 22.41 39.75 .80 17.81 3.17 10.35 1.94 20.43 42.04 5.22 3.93 10.52 .06 .46 6.76 9.54 3.93 10.39 24.97 20.15 7.08 4.28 4.51 .03 1.13 4.70 11.38 3.47 13.04 59.10 54.51 6.09 24.84 12.80 L66 .97 6.30 2.06 9.29 38.28 21.17 6.59 6.33 5.53 29.66 .54 .44 1.11 .52 1.02 6.75 3.29 .21 MM M 7.83 M • ■ I —— Total 79.61 79.61 140.18 140.18 121.31 121.31 150.81 150.81 208.72 208.72 109.19 107.96 97.15 405.84 245.17 115.93 92.77 191.59 126.72 25.16 Stock Feed 4.25 22.45 44.87 15.11 3.47 Ml 9.86 5.63 1.-S.52 .11 13.62 30.19 26.47 2.01 _... Tobacco - .H7 2.81 3.42 2.10 4.13 Clothing I Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing.etc Men's clothing and furnishings Women s ready-made wearing apparel .Miscellaneous (includes repairs) 3.19 5.07 . 1.78 .76 " 6.87 5I55 . 2.19 .. .45 11.64 9.71 20.71 1.63 .01 5.76 34.66 .67 1.26 5.08 6.20 .69 .06 6.02 8.99 1.30 .21 3.36 5.74 .27 .28 .15 .05 .09 8.92 10.22 .18 3.07 4i7 _____ .38 .03 .11 .17 .02 .01 1.82 7.4» 1.16 Total 10.80 14.61 12.09 32.06 42.35 .31 24.86 14.61 42.35 12.03 16.52 9.65 .15 .14 19.32 8.32 .03 .31 Dry Goods - 9.99 26.31 25.26 12.29 11.42 11.58 12.60 10.77 19.27 29.32 19.06 29.05 8.90 7.29 '.29 2.10 Hospital Supplies 2.42 3.30 3.01 5.79 3.01 6.84 6.00 5.79 5.45 60.56 59.22 6.31 8.51 7.71 5.65 &gt;.66 4.18 4.69 5.99 4.51 soap, Cleansers, Starch, Etc 8.45 5.59 3.27 4.70 4.04 12.98 12.07 5.74 13.12 5.19 5.60 .61 Hardware, (other than builders')... 1.54 4.06 3.11 2.50 3.64 1.22 1.84 1.33 8.38 4.76 2.34 4.16 3.88 2.69 .17 jueensware and Glassware M 1.85 .67 1.27 2.57 .00 1.83 .75 3.48 2.24 1.63 1.40 1.52 2.69 .03 Furniture (includes repairs). 1.78 10.83 1.89 3.98 5.07 1.34 1.48 1.42 2.70 3.31 1.36 14.59 9.92 1.59 .73 Stationery, Books, and Paper I Office supplies j School books and supplies 1 Books, periodicals and newspapers... 1 Miscellaneous 2.49 .07 .11; .63 5.99 9.75 1.08 1.24 3.84 1.89 .32 1.08 1.39 UM 2.08 .86 2.93 2.83 .57 J25 .78 .84 3.23 .08 ..35 I .flO 1 18.29 6.47 7.77 3.14 .28 1.96 5.18 1.50 .26 .83 6.02 .84 .81 .19 5.74 6.37 1.05 1.62 2.92 2.93 .46 .77 3.32 .19 .11 .15 Total 3.30 4.28 3.92 3.77 18.06 7.13 2.47 2.94 4.2.; 25.15 13.15 7.77 7.86 14.78 7.08 Brooms, Brushes, Polish and Dusters ... M 2.72 Ji .5»; .59 .»;: .Hit .64 4.13 1.75 .72 .74 .40 1.66 Ox Fuel, Light, and Power I Coal j Oils and lubricants 1 Electricity I Water 48.07 2.54 6.92 87.75 1.90 19.14 10.07 56.84 2.14 22.12 2.64 52.59 3.86 73.06 .86 14.83 1.01 34.51 1.20 .06 44.06 2.55 !6i 55.12 2.22 2.95 125.28 1.48 27.58 1.91 69.69 2.20 7.75 16.73 106.98 7.82 .58 .01 104.76 3.31 .79 90.22 1.29 11.39 16.27 58.12 2.51 2.12 9.23 4.35 .01 1.02 .17 Total 57.53 118.86 83.74 r&gt;tu:&gt; 89.76 35.77 46.62 60.29 UM_K 96.37 115.39 108.86 119.17 71.98 5.56 Machinery, Tools, and Supplies t For industrial departments I For institution in general 2.40 5.19 28.36 3.72 .04 1.63 .02 3.75 Si® 9.34 .09 2.24 153.37 : 3.26 4.53 13.44 5.72 13.72 1.71 M 2.M 3.73 Total 2.40 5.19 32.08 2.66 3.73 1.67 3.77 3.29 9.34 2.33 156.63 4.53 19.16 15.43 .05 General Repairs i Engineers' supplies | Electrical supplies 1 Builders' hardware ; Paints, oils, glass, paint brushes Building material 1 Labor _ 6.24 2.32 1.21 1.99 4.83 1.61 8.40 4.62 .38 3.83 5.75 21.43 4.15 1.47 2.10 7.61 4.74 6.54 15.31 2.22 .69 3.83 3.58 7.71 12.57 7.60 1.46 3.11 6.05 16.02 2.47 1.08 .62 2.26 2.68 .30 6.28 3.23 .67 5.20 4.90 2.44 7.17 4.03 .88 2.64 4.49 1.85 20.68 9.84 1.77 1.65 3.41 30.55 10.34 7.83 1.94 6.79 4.85 10.21 9.37 4.80 1.66 3.72 4.03 .81 17.43 3.80 1.79 13.99 18.66 28.73 7.10 2.76 1.47 8.92 1.93 28.92 3.54 6.09 .IS .46 3.62 2.26 17.53 .10 Total 18.20 44.41 26.61 33.34 46.81 9.41 22.72 21.06 67.90 41.96 24.39 84.40 51.10 33.50 Live Stock .70 5.10 24.07 5.80 .21 1.40 3.12 2.18 10.79 ... 3.36 7.66 3.96 Seeds . 1.16 3.34 2.90 1.56 M 1.20 1.76 2.06 3.33 .56 4.00 1.59 .99 .16 _ Entertainment ..-)] 2.74 5.06 1.05 1.24 3.42 .XI 1.03 .78 .50 .46 1.70 Burial Expenses .1-1 .05 7.00 3.40 .76 .50 .89 1 2J&gt;8 2.40 Miscellaneous.. 2.38 10.83 3.16 2.54 1.15 .t&gt;9 2.07 2.33 14.37 20.72 44.37 6.64 7.82 J2O.01 Grand Total 305.04 $ 606.14 % 636.00 $ 471.91 % 003.20 379.45 $ 1244.97 $ MOM 339.70 * 392.64 $ 857.74 $ 745.03 $ 614.92 $ 973.75 S 608.50 $ NOTE: Blanks represent either no per capita expenditure ir a per capita expenditure of less than five mills. </seg>
            <seg id="p130">NOTE: Blanks represent either no per capita expenditure or a per capita expenditure of less than five mills. 3 CAPITA ANNUAL IN NTENANCE EXPENDITURE BASED O IND1TI ilES FO! INANCE FOR PERIOD December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 CLASSIFICATION a i c ' X. £ ■ 5 c. c 5 7 ii L m f *&gt; I*' ill J * C •I p - I- — 1*1 1 ill I « w m hi PI a 3 I 3 *» II ;2| la r. ■ - - P «, L. ■ a h Hi Hi U I:! VI Average Daily Inmate Population 496 •2 199 425 115 1133 733 I 503 «* ,-_, 34 119 363 51 174 75 Salaries and Wages J Officers, employees, etc t txtra labor or services $ 49.44 .48 a.46 $ 4.36 104.58 $ 5.60 58.74 $ 76.02 4.76 2.09 60.57 I .40 65.78 * 1.20 67.08 % 2.93 96.71 $ 10.03 151.32 3.22 93.56 $ 1.28 76.75 $ 9.53 240.60 f 3.52 151.80 $ 2.08 54.86 15.72 • Total _ 49.92 60.97 75.82 110.18 63.49 77.11 66.98 70.01 106.74 154.54 94.83 86.28 244.12 153.88 70.58 I Rjulroad fare ( odkuU j I Traveling expenses j v/un-«u f ransporta- j Kailroad fare I i )un ates ) uon, i elegraph 1 I raveling expenses. ) I and Teiepnone | Express and ireignt..... I leieptione and telegraph. _. .15 .01 .01 .01 .43 .31 .69 .79 .23 .32 1.66 1.89 1.51 .83 .84 .16 1.73 .86 .06 .02 .33 .15 .14 .08 .04 .03 .49 .57 .11 .08 .43 .07 .60 .61 .16 .23 .04 .02 .69 .49 .56 .44 .23 .30 .02 .09 1.48 3.4C 3.30 3.65 .70 .44 .22 .13 1.58 1.03 1.22 .90 .09 .13 5.37 1.91 .65 .28 .03 .01 1.43 1.41 .28 .29 2.32 .20 .43 La 7.06 6.22 2.03 1.01 .29 .66 .98 .54 3l36 1.23 - Total .92 .58 5.93 1.59 5.01 1.35 1.90 1.63 6.17 7.36 4.10 4.10 9.62 3.81 4.82 4.82 17.26 17.26 Articles of Food | Flour I Sugar _ I Coaee and tea _ I Canned goods I Otner groceries, inuu and vegetables i Meats I Lard and buttenne I Butter ,. I i!*«s _.„ I Mil* _ _ I Cheese and otner dairy products 7.86 1.81 1.79 1.85 8.79 9.80 4.51 1.79 1.08 .14 .38 6jM :.60 2.44 4.69 12.75 i 2H.04 5.69 ri.10 2.38 .06 . .26 10.53 7.07 2.14 4.06 10.73 18.94 6.41 .12 .45 .03 .18 4.63 5.39 8.05 4.85 9.47 30.15 6.57 1.31 3.98 .01 .99 3.73 6.38 5.01 8.13 13.94 32.04 2.12 10.3* 8.31 13.53 .79 6.68 3.04 2.45 2.02 8.89 22.90 4.60 2.55 1.20 125 6.43 4.62 2.60 1.64 9.35 18.26 5.68 3.79 1.30 .06 .25 5.63 5.26 3.27 .59 8.12 17.92 4.19 2.47 .49 !63 1.69 7.74 2.18 12.94 37.08 47.15 2.62 18.98 31.05 40.57 .82 1.47 5.1S 1.34 7.14 39.44 19.76 3.11 13.68 11.2C 19.87 .40 8.91 1.58 5.18 .97 10.21 21.02 2.61 1.96 5.26 .03 .23 3.38 2.35 4.77 5.69 1.97 1.74 5.19 6.52 12.48 23.55 10.08 27.25 3.54 3.04 2.14 12.42 2.25 6.40 .02 .56 .83 .49 3.15 1.03 4.66 19.14 10.58 3.30 3.16 2.76 14.83 .27 22 M .26 .51 3.37 1.64 .11 1.44 .42 3.92* .13 Total 39.80 70.09 60.65 54.58 53.98 48.57 &gt;2.92 122 5i 57.96 46.38 95.79 63.36 I1H 75.40 104.36 Stock Feed. 2.12 11.22 22.43 7.55 1.74 4.99 4.93 2.81 6.76 .0t 6.81 15.10 13.24 1.00 Tobacco . .33 ... • 1.40 1.71 1.05 2.06 Clothing I Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing.etc I Men's clothing and furnishings. ; Women's reauy-made wearing apparel Miscellaneous (includes repairs) 1.59 ■s .38 3.44 2^77 1.09 .22 5.82 4.85 10.35 .82 .01 2.8£ 17.33 .33 .63 2.54 3.10 .34 .03 3.01 4.50 .65 .10 1.68 2.87 .13 .14 .08 M .04 4.46 5.11 .09 1.54 .02 143 .19 :::.....::..::.:::. .06 .09 .01 .01 3.91 4.20 3.74 .58 Total 5.40 7.30 6.04 6.01 8.26 4.82 .08 .07 9.66 4.16 .02 .16 12.43 16.03 21.17 Dry Goods. 5.00 13.15 12.63 6.14 5.71 5.79 6.30 5.38 9.63 14.66 9.53 14.52 4.45 3.64 1.05 Hospital Supplies 1.21 1.65 1.50 2.90 3.42 3.00 2.89 2.72 i0.28 29.61 3.15 4.25 3.86 2.82 2.09 Soap, Cleansers, Starch, Etc 2.35 4.22 2.99 2.26 2.79 1.73 2.35 2.02 6.49 6.03 2.87 6.56 2.60 2.80 .31 Hardware, (other than builders') .77 2.03 1.55 1.25 1.82 .61 .92 M 4.19 2.38 1.17 2.08 1.94 1.35 mt (jueensware and Glassware .33 .93 .34 .84 1.28 .25 .91 .M8 1.74 1.12 .81 .70 .76 1.36 .02 Furniture (includes repairs) .89 5.42 .115 1.99 2.53 .67 .74 .71 1.35 1.65 .6« 7.30 4.96 .80 .37 Stationery, Books, and Paper | Office supplies. j School books and supplies _ _ ; Books, periodicals and newspapers _ [ Miscellaneous _ 1.25 .03 s 2.99 4.88 .54 .62 1.92 .96 . .16 . .54 .70 1.04 1.46 728 .39 1.42 A2 .42 1.62 .04 . .17 .30 '.15 .20 23 3.88 1.57 .14 .98 2.59 .75 .13 .41 3.01 .42 .40 .10 2.87 3.18 .53 .81 1.46 1.46 .25 1.66 .10 .06 .07 ..54- M Total 1.65 9.03 3.57 1.24 1.47 2.13 1.96 2.13 12.58 6.57 3.88 3.93 7.39 3.54 1.88 Brooms, Brushes, Polish and Dusters. .31 1.36 .42 :2H .30 .33 .50 .32 2.0« .88 .36 :m .20 m .04 Fuel, Light, and Power [ Coal ..: _ j Oils and lubricants _ | Electricity _ _ I Water 24.04 1.27 3.46 43.88 .95 9.57 5.03 28.42 1.07 11.06 1.32 26.29 1.93 36.53 .43 7.41 .51 17.25 .60 .03 22.03 27.56 1.27 1.11 1.48 .01 62.6-4 .74 13.79 .96 34.86 1.10 3.87 8.36 53.49 52.38 3.91 1.65 .29 .40 .01 45.11 .64 5.69 8.14 29.06 1.25 1.06 4.62 2.18 .01 .51 .OS Total. _ _ 28.77 59.43 41.87 28.22 44.88 17.88 23.31 30.15 78.13 48.18 57.70 54.43 59.58 35.99 2.78 Machinery, Tools, and Supplies J For industrial departments ( For institution in general _.... Total _ _ L» £b9 14.18 1.86 tm l!86 .02 .81 .01 1.88 1JS5 .Of 1.12 76.69 1.63 2.26 6.72 2.86 6.8« .86 .02 ..„.„„ 1.20 2.59 16.04 1.33 1.86 .83 1.89 1.65 4.67 1.17 78.32 8.32 2.26 9.58 7.71 .02 7.71 General Repairs ( Engineers' supplies Electrical supplies J Builders' hardware _ ; Paints, oils, glass, paint brushes Building material _ [Labor _ 3.12 1.16 .61 .99 2.42 .80 4.20 2.31 .19 1.92 2.87 10.72 2.08 .73 1.05 3.81 2.37 3.27 7.65 1.11 .35 1.92 1.79 3.85 6.28 3.80 .73 1.56 3.0? 8.01 1.23 .64 .31 1.13 1.34 .15 3.14 1.62 .33 2.60 2.45 1.22 3.58 2.02 .44 1.32 2.24 .93 10.34 4.92 .89 .82 1.70 15.28 5.17 3.92 .97 3.39 2.43 5.10 4.69 2.40 .83 1.86 2.02 .40 8.72 1.90 .90 6.99 9.33 14.36 3.55 1.38 .74 4.46 .96 14.46 1.77 3.06 M .23 1.81 1.13 8.76 .06 Total 9.10 22.21 13.31 16.67 23.41 4.70 11.36 10.53 33.95 20.98 12.20 42.20 25.55 16.75 .11 Live Stock _ .35 2.55 12.04 2.90 .11 .70 1.56 l.W 5.39 . 1.98 1.68 3.78 . Seeds . .58 1.67 1.45 .78 .29 .60 .88 1.03 1.66 J| 2.00 .80 .08 Entertainment 2.53 .53 . .61 1.71 .44 .52 .39 .26 .23 .44 .12 .26 1.37 Burial Expenses 1.70 .38 .25 .45 . IJ» 1.20 .07 .03 3.50 Miscellaneous.. 1.19 .5x .34 1.03 1.17 10.36 22.19 3.32 3.91 2.93 1*0.00 5.42 1.58 1.27 Grand Total 152.52 * 303.07 318.00 I 235.96 $ 301.60. 169.85 $ 196.32 % 189.72 % 622.49 $ 428.87: 372.51 % 307.46 | 48.V88 $ </seg>
            <seg id="p131">NOTE: Blanks represent either no per capita expenditure or a per capita expenditure of less than five mills. '1TA MONTHLY INMATE MAINTENANCE EXPEND! TURE BASED ON EXPENDITURE FOR MAINTENANCE FOR PERIOD December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1916 n ii I 1 A P 1 P £3 . l|j is] hi Id I si ' ~ - H HI -i f. I r CLASSIFICATION ■ II mi II £ I T hi ft ill Average Daily Inmate Population.. 496 496 102 199 199 425 425 ii 115 1133 733 503 34 119 363 H 174 75 Salaries and Wages J Officers, employees, etc ( Extra labor or services... 4.12 % .04 5.96 $ .36 8.72 $ .47 4.89 * .401 6.25 .17 5.05 $ .03 5.48 % .10 5.59 I .24 16.39 $ 12.61 .84 .27 u= 7.79 ' $ .11 6.40'$ .79 20.06 $ .29 12.65 $ .17 4.57 1.31 Total _ 4.16 6.32 9.19 5.29 6.42 5.08 5.58 5.8;! 17.23 12.88 7.90 7.19 20.34 12.82 Mi | Railroad fare ) rt-s • , 4 i Traveling expenses ) Offi&lt;lal ( Transports- J Railroad fare ( , f«= J tion, Telegraph | Traveling expenses ) inmates. ( and Telephone j Express and freight [ Telephone and telegraph _ .01 !04 .03 .06 .06 .02 .03 .14 .16 .13 .07 .07 .02 .14 .08 .07 .05 .03 .01 !28 .10 .01 .01 !04 .05 .01 .01 .03 .01 .06 .05 .01 .02 M .04 .05 .04 .02i .02 .01 _ .12 .29 .27 .30 .06 .04 .02 .01 .13 • .08 .10 .07 .01 .01 .45 .16 .06 .02 7l2 .12 .02 .02 .19 .02 .04 .11 .59 .52 .17 .08 .02 .06 Total .47 .50 m .13 .42 .11 .16 .13 .51 .61 .34 .so .32 .40 1.44 Articles of Food ( Flour „ I Sugar _ _ | Cotfee and tea | Canned goods I Other groceries, fruits and vegetables \ Meats I Lard and butterine | Butter _ I Eggs | Milk (. Cheese and other dairy products .65 .15 .15 .15 .73 .82 .38 .15 .09 .01 .03 .51 .30 .20 .39 1.06 2.17 .47 .51 .20 .01 . .02 .88 .59 .18 .34 .88 1.58 .53 .01 .04 .02 - .H9 .45 .67 .40 .79 2.51 .55 .11 .33 .08 .31 .53 .42 .68 1.16 2.67 .18 .86 .69 1.13 .06 .56 .25 .21 .17 .74 1.91 .38 .21 .10 M .53 .38 .22 .14 .78 1.52 .47 .31 .11 .01 .02 .47 .44 .27 .05 .68 1.49 .35 .20 .04 !05 .14 .65 .18 1.08 3.09 3.93 .22 1.58 2.59 3.38 .07 .12 .43 .11 .60 3.29 1.65 .26 1.14 .93 1.66 .03 .74 .13 .43 .08 .85 1.75 .22 .17 .44 .28 .40 .16 .43 1.04 .84 .29 .18 .19 M .20 .47 .15 .54 2.46 2.27 .25 1.04 .53 .04 .26 .00 .39 1.59 .88 .28 M .23 LM .02 .02 .05 .02 .04 .28 .14 .01 .12 .04 .32 .01 Total 3.31 5.34 5.06 6.28 8.69 4.55 4.49 4.04 16.91 10.221 4.83 3.86 7.98 5.28 1.05 Stock Feed.. .18 .94 1.87 .63 .15 .42 .41 .23 M .01! .57 1.26 1.10 .08 Tobacco _ _ .03 .12 .14 .09 J .17 . Clothing: f Boots, shoes, shoe brushes, lacing.etc | ; Men's clothing and furnishings. I Women's ready-made wearing apparel _ I Miscellaneous (includes repairs) .13 3X .08 .03 .29 .02 .49 .23 .09 .40 .86 .07 .24 1.44 .03 .05 .21 .26 .03 .25 .38 .05 .01 .14 .24 .01 .01 .01 .37 .43 .01 13 ..... .01 J» - _ .02 _ .33 .35 .31 .05 Total „ _ _.._ .45 .61 .51 1.34 1.76 .50 .69 .411 .01 .01 .81 .35 ... .02 1.04 Dry Goods - „ .42 1.10 1.05 .51 .48 .48 .53 M .80 1.22 .79 1.21 .37 .30 .09 Hospital Supplies .10 .14 .13 .24 .29 .25 .24 .23 2.52 2.47 .26 .35 .32 24 .17 Soap, Cleansers, Starch, Etc „ .20 .35 .25 .19 .23 .14 .20 .1? . r -4 .50 .24 .55 .22 .23 .03 Hardware, (other than builders'). .06 .17 .13 .11 .15 .05 .08 .06 .35 .20 .10 .17 .16 .11 .01 Queensware and Glassware.. .03 .08 .03 .05 .11 .02 M .03 .15 .09, .07 .06 .06 .11 Furniture (includes repairs) .07 .45 .08 .17 .21 .06 .06 .06 .11 .14 .06 .61 .41 .07 .03 Stationery, Books, and Paper [ Office supplies. _ J School books and supplies I Books, periodicals and newspapers. I [Miscellaneous .10 .25 .41 .04 .05 .16 .08 ... .01 .. .04 .05 .09 .12 .12 .14 .76 .33 .13 .01 .08 .22 .06 .01 .03 .25 .03 .03 .01 .24 an .04 .07 .12 iS M .14 .01 "m .05 .03 .02 .03 '.oi .03 .03 02 .27 .01 Total...- .75 .29 .13 .10 .12 .17 .16 .18 1.06 M .32 .32 62 .29 .lfi Brooms, Brushes, Polish and Dusters .01 .11 .03 .02 .03 .03 .04 .03 .17 .07 .03 .03 .02 .07 Fuel, Light, and Power (Coal _ „ J Oils and lubricants _ I Electricity I Water _ _. 200 .11 .29 3.65 .08 .80 .42 2.37 .09 .92 .11 .. 2.19 .16 3.04 .04 .62 .04 1.44 .05 1.83 .11 T5!- .09 .12 5.22 .06 1.15 .08 2.91 .09 .32 .70 4.46 .32 .02 4.36 .14 .03 3.76 .05 .47 .68 2.42 .10 .00 .39 .18 .01 Total _ _ 2.40 4.95 3.49 2.35 3.74 1.49 1.94 2.51 6.51 4.02 4.80 4.53 4.96 3.00 Machinery, Tools, and Supplies j For industrial departments '( For institution in general Total _ M .22 1.18 . .15 ........ -a ;67 :a ! "" :i4 .39 S 6.S9 .13 "l9 .56 .24 .57 . .07 . .10 .22 1.33 .11 .16 .07 .16 .14 .39 .10 6.52 .19 .80 .64 General Repairs f Engineers' supplies „ Electrical supplies _ J Builders' hardware | Paints, oils, glass, paint brushes | Building material I Labor _ _ .26 .09 .05 .08 .20 .07 .35 .19 .02 .16 .24 .89 .17 .06 .09 .32 .19 .27 .64 .09 .03 .16 .15 .32 .52 .32 .06 .13 .25 .67 .10 .06 .03 .09 .11 .01 .26 .14 .03 .22 .20 .10 .30 .17 .03 .11 .18 .08 .86 .41 .06 .07 .14 1.27 .43 .33 .08 .28 .20 .42 .39 .20 .07 .18 .17 .03 .73 .16 .07 .58 .78 1.20 Ji .12 .06 .37 .08 1.21 .15 .26 .01 .02 . ._ _ .15 .00 .73 _ Total 1.10 1.39 .75 1.85 1.95 .39 .95 .87 2.83 1.74 1.02 3.52 2.13 1.40 .01 Live Stock..... .03 .21 1.00 .24 .01 .06 .13 .09 .45 . .17 .14 M -..._ _ Seeds .05 .14 .12 .07 .02 .05 .07 .09 .14 .02 .17 .07 .04 Ml Entertainment .02 .11 .21 .04 . .06 .14 .04 M .03 .02 .02 .07 .04 .01 Burial Expense* .01 .2-.) .14 .03 .02 ■&lt;* Tx ZZZZ ■ , Miscellaneous..... _ .10 .45 .13 .11 .05 .03 .00 .10 .60 .28 .24 13.33 Grand Total ~ _ _ 12.71 $ 25.26 % 26.50 $ 19.66 $ 25.13 14.15 $ 16.36 S 15.81 $ 51.87 $ 35.74 31.04 S 25.62 % 40.57 $ 25.35 $ </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>