<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves</title>
               <date value="1935-04">1935-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 295 April, 1935 The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves MARVEL L. BAKER Bulletin 37 of the North Platte Experiment Substation L. Li Zook, Acting Superintendent ■ U . : ; ■ ■ j L:... r jj ■" J I ! Ti PH.. Bj f; - j:,. i Experimental Calves at the North Platte Substation THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Introduction ■ 3 The Use of Wheat for Fattening Calves. . ., 4 Complete substitution of ground wheat for shelled corn, 5 Partial substitution of ground wheat for shclcd corn 7 Ground wheat vs. rolled wheat ' 9 The Use of Rye for Fattening Calves : 9 Complete substitution of ground rye for shelled corn 10 Partial substitution of ground rye for shelled corn. . .- 12 Supplemental Feeding Period in 1 933 13 Ground Wheat vs. Ground Rye 14 ■ ■ . '. ■ ■'■ 1. :•'■••.• . ' ; ■ ' ■ . ; : , ■;■'••. ."■'■•;■ SUMMARY 1. In three trials, each approximately 200 days in length, ground wheat, ground rye, a mixture of equal parts by weight of ground wheat and shelled corn, and a similar mixture of ground rye and shelled corn were compared with shelled corn for fattening calves. In one trial ground wheat was compared with rolled or crushed wheat. Alfalfa hay was fed to all calves. 2. It was observed that for the best results the wheat and rye should be as coarsely ground as possible and that alfalfa hay should be fed according to the appetite of the calves. 3. No difficulty was experienced in feeding either ground wheat or ground rye, bur calves fed cither of these grains as the sole concentrate did not consume as much grain as similar calves fed shelled rorn or mixtures containing shelled corn. ■1. More alfalfa hay was consumed by the calves fed cither ground wheat or ground rye as the sole concentrate than by the other calves. 5. All rations fed produced satisfactory gains, but the rations containing corn produced somewhat better finish than the ration in which ground wheat was the sole concentrate and decidedly better finish than the ration in which ground rye was the only concentrate fed. 6. Calves fed shelled corn or the mixtures containing shelled corn required more grain but less alfalfa hay per unit of gain than the calves fed cither ground whr.u or ground rye as the sole concentrate. 7. Both ground wheat and ground rye were entirely satisfactory from every standpoint when frd as one-half the grain ration in these trials. Ground wheat, as the sole concentrate, was satisfactory from the standpoint of rapidity and economy of gains but produced cattle with slightly less finish than those fed corn or rations con - taining corn. Ground rye fed as the sole concentrate produced satisfactory and eco - nomical gains but calves fed this grain for 200 days were decidedly less attractive from a market standpoint than calves finished on rations containing corn. In order to pro - duce calves with acceptable market finish, corn should be added to a ration of ground rye and alfalfa for at least 60 to 90 days before the cattle arc marketed. 8. In the one trial in which the comparison was made, ground wheat was superior to rolled or crushed wheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves MARVEL L. BAKER The experiments reported m this publication were undertaken to se - cure data on the value of wheat and rye in ' the ration for fattening calves. Three tests were conducted, the first from November 25 1930 to June 18, 1931; the second from December 1, 1931, to June P 193?' and the third from October 18, 1932, to May 2, 1933. These three"periods were respectively 205, 194, and 196 days m length. Calves used.— Grade Hereford steer calves of good quality divided into experimental lots of twelve calves each, were used. These were native Sandhill calves from Hayes, McPherson, and Lincoln counties and aver - aged approximately 370, 420, and 440 pounds at the beginning of the three trials. They were March and April calves. Feeds used.— Yellow shelled corn was used. In the first test the mois - ture content of; the corn varied from 14 to 22 per cent with an average ot 17.6 per cent. In the second test the corn averaged 14.9 per cent mois - ture and varied from 13 8 to 16.5. In the third test the moisture content varied irom 12,8 to 16.5 per cent with an average of 13.1. For ease m making comparisons, the corn is reported on a basis of 14 per cent mois - ture. Ihe whe&amp;t used was hard red winter wheat with an average mois - ture content for the three years, respectively, of 13.7, 11.0, and 12 4 per cent. Rosen rye with an average of 13.1, 12.2, and 12.0 per cent moisture The wheat and rye were ground as coarsely as possible m a burr-type mil The shewed corn was fed whole. In the first test, second-cutting alfalfa hay vvafc used. In the second and third tests considerable first - cutting alfalfa was also fed. In general, the hay was bright, leafy, and or good quality. " Shelter and lots.— The calves had access to a shed 32x120 feet m size divided into five equal parts. The doors of the shed were kept open at all times except during the most severe weather when they were partially closed. Lots 24x150 feet m size were provided directly south of the shed. Feeding and watering.— ln general the calves were fed all of the grain and hay they would clean up readily after they were on full feed. During the first test an attempt was made to feed alfalfa hay at the same level to all lots. The theoretical advantages of this method of feeding from an experimental point of view are admitted and it was with reluctance that it was abandoned It was observed, however, that the appetites of calves ted either ground wheat or ground rye remained unsatisfied after the calves had consumed their allowance of hay and all of the grain they would consume.! Increasing the allowance of alfalfa hay resulted m an increased consumption of grain, m greater contentment on the part of the calves, and, as is pointed out later, m increased gains. From the stand - point of sound feedlot practice, the change m the method of feeding was fully justified. During the latter part of the first trial and during the </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 295 second and third trials all lots were fed both grain and alfalfa hay accord - ing to appetite. Hay and grain were fed regularly twice each day in the open. Salt and water were before the calves at all times, except that dur - ing the most severe weather the waterers were covered at night to reduce freezing. Rations used. — All lots were fed alfalfa hay. Each year the following grain rations were fed: Lot 1 — Shelled corn. Lot 2 — Ground wheat. Lot 3 — Ground rye, Lot 4 — Equal parts by weight of shelled corn and ground wheat. Lot 5 — Equal parts by weight of shelled corn and ground rye. Weighing and marketing. — Individual weights were taken on three consecutive days at the beginning and end of each trial. The averages of these three weights were considered as the initial and final weights re - spectively. Indhidual weights were also taken during each test, in general at 28-day intervals. In marketing, the cattle were trucked to North Platte and shipped by tiain to Omaha. Shrinkage was calculated from the final experimental weight. At the dose of the third test, the cattle were not sold. They were appraised by a representative of John Clay and Company of Omaha. All of the lots were then placed on a ration of ground corn, alfalfa hay, and linseed meal. Four of the lots (1, 2, 4, and 5) were marketed after they were on this ration for 29 days, and Lot 3 after it was on this ration for 55 days. The data on these cattle for the entire feeding period are presented in Table 8 and discussed later. Slaughter data. — Slaughter data for the first two trials were secured through the courtesy of Armour and Company, and for the third trial through the courtesy of Wilson and Company. These are presented in the various tables and are discussed later. Pork produced. — In only one trial was it possible to make a satis - factory comparison of the amount of pork produced by pigs following the five lots of calves. In this trial more pork was produced in the lots in which corn was fed. The pork production per bushel of grain fed to the calves was 1.27, 0.29, 0.29, 0.89, and 0.89 pounds for the five lots re - spectively. THE USE OF WHEAT FOR FATTENING CALVES At various periods the price relationship between wheat and corn has stimulated interest in the value of wheat as a feed for cattle. Weber and Connell x and Trowbridge and Moffett 2 in reporting work done at the Kansas and Missouri stations have presented summaries of much of the work that has been done in this country and there seems to be no good reason for detailed reference to the literature cited by these workers. 1 A. D. Weber and W.. E. Connell, Wheat .is a Fattening Feed for Cattle, Kans. A|;r. Exp. Sta. Bui. 261, 20 pages. 1932. • E. A. Trowbridge and H. C. Moffett, Wheat as a Cattle Feed. Mo. Agr. Exp. Sta. But. 325. 18 pages. 1933. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The\Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves V The complete substitution of ground wheat for shelled corn. — The data for the three trials in which ground wheat was compared with shelled corn for fattening calves at the North Platte Substation are presented in Table 1. In each case the calves in Lot 1, fed shelled corn, ate more grain and less alfalfa hay than the calves in Lot 2, which were fed ground wheat. For the" three trials respectively, the wheat-fed calves ate 83.9, {)5.4, and 88.6 per cent as much grain and 106.2, 121.8, and 112.4 per cent as much alfalfa hay as the corn-fed calves. The most probable explanation of the relatively greater feed consumption on the part of the wheat- fed calves during the second and third trials lies in the fact that during the first 140 days of the first trial, alfalfa hay was "fed at the same level to all lots. For the 1 last 65 days of the first trial and during the second and third trials, alfalfa hay was fed according to appetite, for reasons which have already been given. Observations vindicated that calves fed ground wheat not only ate more total feed (when fed alfalfa hay according to appetite but ate more grain than if their allowance of hay had been restricted to that given similar calves fed shelled corn. As might be expected, the wheat-fed calves made more rapid gains when compared with the corn-fed calves during the latter part of the first trial and during the second and third trials than during the first 140 days of the first trial. For example, during' the first 140 days of the first trial, the calves in Lot 1 made an average daily gain of 2.36 pounds and those in Lot 2 made an average daily gain of 1.98 pounds. During the last 65 days of the same trial, the corn-fed calves made an average daily gain of 2.55 pounds, while that for the wheat-fed calves was 2.67 pounds. During the second and third trials the corn-fed calves made an average daily gain of 2.13 and 2.26 pounds per head. In the/ same trials the wheat-fed calves gained 2.31 and 2.29 pounds per day. Especially in the second and third trials the calves fed ground wheat made a better showing in average daily gains, when com - pared with the calves fed shelled corn, than has been generally reported by other investigators. Aside from this difference in average daily gains, results secured in' these trials were in essential agreement with those re - ported by the Kansas and Missouri stations, previously referred to. It may be that the relatively greater feed consumption by the wheat-fed calves under discussion accounts for their relatively larger gains. No difficulty was experienced in getting the wheat-fed calves on feed, no digestive troubles were encoontered because of feeding wheat, and in all three trials the average daily consumption of wheat for each 2S-day period was greater than for the preceding period. The maximum average daily grain consumption by 28-day periods was 13.88, 13.33, and 13.44 pounds of ground wheat for the three trials respectively. For the corn-fed calves the maximum average daily grain consumption by 28-day periods was 15.28, 15.21, and 15.33 pounds for the three trials. In each of the three trials, less grain and more alfalfa hay were re - quired per unit of gain by the calves fed ground wheat than by those </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 295 I k ** ■2- ~7 . -o- a °K : : : : : : :S! 3L £■ -s« s»5~ =&gt;ft k§ i i i : : - •: ; K ! 5 i 1 ! 'C °i^ « =• *• -•« § 5 *».■-"■■ '-Jan 3 = ■ :' S If- 3 i "5 hi 2 SH S u-.x; S M *• o— *a m en ri ; — ***■ i^ir&gt;&lt;*o c* i - "■"'rc&gt;o #- *^ S M t&gt;c iT;,?.-!: — &lt;*•. -r i^»n "*- •»■ v&gt; „ s^^- u — ~ p- -r -^-. t- ■ U"\r^ «*2 V3 O Ij C ; &lt;SS ™ «g'- ' ' « " s b S i i «* | a .- R s||l|ss?" *? ssr sK ftj-=s - s *t S-l" ' . gs 5 ~S ""'2 "I S 'f -n_ S SS S ..«» 88 H IS ill 635 *s — K - gs s; .2 — o 2 it = T S **: c . "5 Ret 2 MM ii HI; :i MM; I! 1 a ; f •• : ri S ' ' ' ■ * o *^*^ : : : . . . u . . -^ . .....; b O w' p - ■" ie ■. . j, ; ; ; ; ; : ° : : » "j 5 i ill ;;:;„;§: 2 - tliil \\zi\ !|» K yii^ E ' E - SjlliiilHi ■!!■!!* ii Ju u u v o e «2 u c «2 &lt;s m «f jC „ m vi m m M.5-3 '•■S-5 j&lt;.= B u S . . tt£H 2 2JS2 !SS-,2£ =!35 3ddod= .« r* SSJS SO&lt;; 8C&lt;sJBa gZZZ2 = " &lt;&lt;&lt;&lt;&lt; a. «C u vi </seg>
            <seg id="p007">ThejUse of Wheat and Rve for Fattening Calves fed shelled corn. For the three trials respectively, 92.5. 78.7, and 87.5 per cent as much grain and 116.8, 112.2, and 110.9 per cent as much alfalfa hay werej required per unit of gain by the wheat-fed calves as by the corn-fed calves. Table 2 shows the approximate price per bushel based on the average of the thiee trials under discussion, which could be paid for ground wheat for fattening calves with shelled corn and alfalfa hay at the prices indicated. It sKould be borne in mind that these values are for ground wheat, that they probably are somewhat higher than values indicated by the work of others, and that they are based on averages and on the as - sumption that finished cattle fed giound wheat sell at the same price Table 2.— Replacement value per bushel of ground wheat for fattening calves when\ ground wheat was substituted for all of the shelled corn in the ration (average of three trials). 1 Price of shelled corn per bushel Replacement value of pround wheat at varioui prices of alfalfa hay per ton 1 S5.00 S10.00 SI5.00 S20.00 *° 2 ° i 50-24 $0.23 SO.22 $0.20 f n 36 .35 .34 .33 •S 49 .4* .47 .45 •!° 61 .00 .59 .58 ■"} 74 .73 .71 .70 ■'1 86 .85 .84 .83 •5" ■• -99 .97 .96 .95 ■ •?5 MI 1.10 1.09 1.08 '•°° 1.24 1.23 1.21 1.2f 1 See text for discussion. as those finished on shelled corn. As shown in Table 1, there was no Significant difference in the selling price or appraised value of the calves at the close of the three trials under discussion. Market conditions are not always the same, however, and an examination of the slaughter data which were obtained for the first two trials indicates that the corn-fed calves should have been somewhat more attractive from the buyer's stand - point. In the first trial the wheat-fed calves shrank 4.13 per cent in ship - ment, compared with 2.88 per cent for the corn-fed calves. Based on the selling weight, the corn-fed calves dressed 58.0 per cent, compared with a yield of 57.2 per cent for the wheat-fed calves. In the second trial shrink and the dressing percentages were practically the same for the two lots of cattle. In general the corn-fed calves produced the higher grading car - casses, although the difference was not great in the second trial. The partial substitution of ground wheat for shelled corn. — The data for the three trials at the North Platte Substation in which ground wheat replaced one-half of the shelled corn in the ration arc presented in Table 1 under Lots 1 and 4. Calves fed the mixture of shelled corn and ground wheat ate more grain than calves fed ground wheat as the sole concen - trate. On the average such calves ate less grain than calves fed shelled corn. In one trial, however, more of the mixture than of shelled corn was consumed. For the three trials, respectively, the calves fed the mixture </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 295 ate 95.2, 92.5, and 100.8 per cent as much grain and 98.3, 115.5, and 109.0 per cent as much alfalfa hay as the corn-fed calves. There was no appreciable difference in gains in any of the three trials. Neither was the difference in the feed requirement per unit of gain in any of the three trials marked. For the three trials, 96.1, 91.2, and 100.0 per cent as much grain, and 99.1, 113.9, and 108.3 per cent as much alfalfa hay were re - quired per unit of gain by the calves fed the mixture as by the corn-fed calves. Table 3 shows the approximate value of ground wheat per bushel when substituted for one-half the shelled corn in the ration. As might be expected from a study of the gains and feed requirements as given in Table 1, these values are not as high as those given in Table 2. From Table 3. — Replacement value per bushel of ground wheat for fattening calves when ground wheat was substituted for one-half the shelled corn in the ration {average of three trials). Replacement value of xnnuui wheat at various Price of shelled corn per bushel prices of alfalfa hay per ton 55.00 SIOJtQ 515.00 ~ $20.00 *°- 20 $0.22 $0.21 S0.20 S0.19 ■f. ••■•••■ -34 .33 .il .30 ■f n 46 .44 Ai .42 •50 ■ .57 .56 .55 M •S2 • 69 .68 .66 .65 •'&lt;•••• .81 .79 .7H .77 -&gt;&gt;0... 92 .91 .90 .89 •90 1.04 1.03 1.01 1.00 100 i.i6 1.14 1.13 1.12 the standpoint of the livestock feeder, they probably are more nearly cor - rect because on a market with considerable spread, calves fed the mixture oi shelled corn and ground wheat are more likely to sell in line with those fed shelled corn than are those finished on ground wheat as the sole concentrate. Shrink in shipment was considerably higher for the calves in Lot 4 in the first trial but somewhat lower in the second trial. In both cases the calves in Lot 4 dressed somewhat higher, the difference in dressing j-ercentage based on the selling weights amounting to approximately 0.5 per cent. Based on the final experimental weights, there was practically no difference in the dressing percentage. Carcasses from the corn-fed calves graded somewhat higher than those from the calves fed the mix - ture of shelled corn and ground wheat. These two lots of calves sold or were appraised at the same price, except for the second trial when the calves fed the mixture outsold the corn-fed calves twenty cents per hun - dred. It seems from the slaughter data that if either lot of calves possessed any advantage over the other from a market standpoint, the advantage rested with the corn-fed calves. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves Ground wheat vs. rolled wheat. — An attempt was made to increase the palatability of the ration, the grain consumption, and the finish of the calves by feeding rolled or crushed wheat instead of ground wheat. One trial was conducted com- _ paring wheat prepared in Table wheat vs. rolled or these two ways. Data for crushed when t for fattening calves, this trial are presented in December 1, 1931, to June 12, 1932 (194 Table 4 days, twelve steers per lot, both lots fed »ii i alfalfa hay). Apparently the ground — wheat was more palatable Lot 2 Ro'ikd'or than the rolled or crushed '«"&gt; G X"t "" shcd v. lira i wheat wheat. More of it was con- ~ ~~~. — ~ — ~ Average inin.il weight 422 423 sumed and more rapid and Avcra B c final weigh wo «44 economical gains were A A Zl% £$ Bain /..•.y.y//,-// "Ln made on it. Calves fed on Average &lt;&lt;aii&gt; ration: ground wheat shrank less, °"*" . 9 /\ 2 . l\l b , 1 . 1 ill- Alfalfa hay 6J6 /.15 dressed higher, sold tor a 7 ; : T, 7ZTZ ', '■ ,° reed required tor KMJ lbs. 01 gain: higher price, and produced &lt;;™in 421 432 ,.°, r V r Alfalfa hay 275 329 higher grading carcasses - i i r i ll l Shrink in shipment I per ccntl.. 3.26 4.24 than those fed on rolled i, rcil \ nK percental or crushed wheat. In this iw on veiling weight .... 59.2 5s.i Based on final experimental wt. 5/. 3 55.6 one trial, ground wheat ~ ; 7 . ° iti Carcass grades: was superior to rolled or No. 1 (per temt 25 0 , j • No. 2 (Per cent) 42 42 crushed wheat. s,,. ? , rrr «,,,, 25 50 The wheat used in this *'- &lt;"" ""•&gt; JL^ Selling price, per cwl. Sfi.hS 56.50 test averaged 11.0 per cent • moisture. It is possible that with wheat containing more moisture, or where facilities for adding a slight amount of moisture are available, roll - ing or crushing wheat might be advantageous. THE USE OF RYE FOR FATTENING CALVES Inquiries directed to the experiment stations of twelve of the more important rye-producing states disclosed that nine of these had done no experimental feeding of rye to cattle. Wilson and Wright 3 fed rye, both ground and whole, with alfalfa hay in comparison with shelled corn nnd alfalfa hay to two-year-old steers lor 90 days. The steeis fed rye ate less grain and more hay than the steers fed corn. The corn-fed steers gained more rapidly and carried more finish at the conclusion of the experiment than the rye-fed steers. According to these investigators, it was impossible to keep the steers on a full feed of rye and they ascribe the relatively poor results to unpalatability of the rye. Riser, Christgau, and Peters 4 fed calves rye in comparison with wheat, and a mixture of equal parts of rye and barley in comparison with a similar mixture of ' James W. Wilson and Turner Wright. Rye as a Fattening Feed for Cattle and Swine in South Dakota. S. Dak. Agr. Ezp. Sta. Bui. 271. pp. 3-5. 1932. *O. H. Riser, R. J. Christgau, and W. H. Peters, Wheat and Rye as Feeds for Fattening Cattle, Mimeographed Report of the Minnesota Northwest Station, 5 pages, 1932. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 295 wheat and barley. In addition to the grain, the calves were fed 1.5 pounds of linseed meal daily and sweet clover hay. The calves fed wheat ate more grain, made larger gains, and were valued at a higher price at the close of the test than the calves fed rye. For the same reasons, the ration in which one-half the wheat was replaced with barley was superior to the ration of rye and barley, although the difference was not so great as when wheat and rye were compared as the sole grain rations. In a later trial by the same authors 5 steers fed a ration of ground rye, linseed meal, and sweet-clover hay made larger and cheaper gains and were valued at a higher price than similar steers which were fed a ration in which rye was replaced with barley. The substitution of molasses beet pulp for one-half of the rye in the same trial resulted in a slight in - crease in the rate of gain and produced a more desirable market finish. In the same trial the combination of 50 per cent ground rye and 50 per cent molasses beet pulp produced larger and cheaper gains and more finish than a like combination of ground barley and molasses beet pulp when both were supplemented with linseed meal and sweet-clover hay. The Montana station 0 . fed calves three parts of ground rye and one part of ground oats in comparison with a similar mixture of ground barley and ground oats, alfalfa hay being fed as the roughage. The calves fed the barley and oats combination ate more grain, made faster gains, and were appraised at a higher value than the calves fed the mixture of rye and oats. The complete substitution of ground rye for shelled corn. — The data for the three trials at the North Platte Substation in which all of the shelled corn in the ration was replaced with ground rye are presented in Table 5. In each of the three trials, the calves in Lot 3, fed ground rye, ate less grain and more hay than the calves in Lot 1 which were fed shelled corn. For the three trials, the rye-fed calves ate 83.9, 86.5, and 88.0 per cent as much grain and 103.8, 134.1, and 118.2 per cent as much alfalfa hay as the corn-fed calves. No trouble was experienced in getting the rye-fed calves on feed. They apparently ate the rye with relish, but would not consume as much grain as the calves fed corn. In ' each trial, less grain and more alfalfa hay were required per unit of gain by the rye-fed calves. For the three trials, 93.6, 82.4, and 90.0 per cent as much grain and 115.5, 127.8, and 121.1 per cent as much alfalfa hay were required for each 100 pounds of gain by the rye-fed calves as by the calves fed shelled corn. Table 6 shows the approximate replacement value per bushel of ground rye for corn with shelled corn and alfalfa hay at the prices indicated. It should be remembered that these values are approximate, that they are based on averages, and apply only to the ability of rye to produce gains. Because of difference in the finish of calves at the end of the 200 - 1 O. H. Kiscr, R. J. Christgau, and W. H. Peters, Molasses Beet Pulp and Rye for Fattening Steer Calves, Mimeographed Report of the Minnesota Northwest Station, 5 pages, 1933. "Louis Vinlce, G. W. Morgan, and E. H. Sandberg, Mimeographed Report of the North Montana Branch Station, pp. 5-7, 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Table 5.— The use of rye for fattening calves, three trials {twelve steers per lot, all lots fed alfalfa hay). 1 «-} Hirst trial: Nov. 25, 1930, to Second trial: Dec. I. 1931, to Third trial: Oct. 18, 1932, to June 18, 1931—205 days June 12, 1932-19-1 days May 2, 1933—196 days C it-.-m I Loi 5 Lot 5 Lot 5 w Lot 1 Lot 3 Slicllril Lot I Lot 3 Sncllcd Lot I Lot 3 Shelled O Shelled Ground corn-1. Shelled Ground corn-1. Shelled Ground corn-1. "" corn rye ground corn rye ground corn rye ground &lt;; ryc-2 rye-1 ryc-1 J" Average initial wci^lir ~~.~. 372 372" 372 423 422 422 ~ 439 438 437 in Average final weight 869 H18 844 836 855 854 H82 870 887 &gt; Average gain 497 446 472 413 433 432 443 432 450 "* Average daily gain . .;.........■ 2.42 2.18 2.30 2.13 2.23 2.23 2.26 2.21 2.30 &gt; Average daily ration: d Grain 10.62 8.91 9.78 11.38 9.84 11.03 11.51 10.13 11.50 &gt;_. Alfalfa hay „. 5.33 5^53 5J6 5^22 7^0 5M 5^99 7_M 5.91 £? Feed required for 100 lbs. of ,;.iin: • &gt; W Grain 438 410 424 535 441 4% 510 459 501 Alfalfa hay „ . 220 254 228 245 313 253 265 32J 257 O Shrink in shipment (permit) " 2.8S 4.52 4.50 3.24 4.39 3.67 Dressing percentage: ? Based on selling weight ' 58.0 56.6 58.0 59.5 59.3 59.7 5 Based on final eiperimcntal weight.... 54J) 55^4 57J1 56.7 5^5 H Carcass grades: V. No. 1 (per cent) 42 0 20 33 8 8 H Ko.l (per cent) 50 75 70 42 42 33 g No. 3 (per cent) 8 17 10 25 50 59 No. 4 (per cent) 0 li &lt;&gt; 0 0 &lt;&gt; £3 Selling price, per cwt.' |~ $8.00 $7.75 $7.85 $6.65 $6.50 $6.85 $5.90 $5.50 $5.90 P 1 In the first trial two steers were removed from Lot 5. Results were calculated on a calf-day hasis. IJJ J The selling prices given for the third trial represent an appraised value rather than the actual srlling price. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 295 day feeding period, the values given for rye in Table 6 are too high if tye is fed for the entire feeding period. It is believed that they are ap - proximately correct if corn is substituted for the rye during the last 90 days of the feeding period. The gains themselves were satisfactory, being slightly larger in the rye-fed lot in the second trial and somewhat smaller in the other two trials. The greatest difference was in the first trial, in which the corn-fed calves made an average daily gain of 2.42 pounds and the rye-fed calves made a gain of but 2.18 pounds per head per day. Table 6.— -Replacement value Oer bushel of ground rye when substituted jor all of the shelled corn in the ration (average of three trials). 1 Replacement value of ground rye at various ,. , , prices of alfalfa hay per ton Price of shelled corn per bushel , S5.00 S10.00 S15.00 S20.00 $(;.2O S0.21 S0.19 S0.17 S0.16 .30 32 .31 .29 .27 .40 ... . .44 .42 .40 .38 .50 55 .53 .51 .50 60 «6 .64 .63 .61 70 .77 76 .74 .72 t0 .89 .87 .85 .84 90 1.00 .98 .97 .95 lioo.;;; i.n \jo los u* * See text for discuuion. The explanation for the relatively poor performance of the wheat fed calves in the first trial doubtless applies to the rye-fed calves as well. For example, while the corn-fed calves made an average daily gain of 2.36 pounds for the first 140 days of the first trial and 2.55 pounds for the last 65 days of the trial, the calves in Lot 3 made an average daily gain of 2.05 pounds for the first 140 days and 2.45 pounds for the last 65 days. No digestive troubles due to the feeding of rye were experienced. For about the first four months of each feeding period, there was no apparent difference in the sleekness and attractiveness of the rye-fed calves and the corn-fed calves. During the latter part of each trial, however, it was ap - parent that the calves fed shelled corn were carrying more finish and were more attractive from the buyer's standpoint. This was reflected in the valuations placed on the two lots of calves at the close of each trial. In 1931, the calves sold at $8.00 and $7.75. In 1932 they brought $6.65 and $6.50, and in 1933 were appraised at $5.90 and $5.50. In the two trials in which slaughter data were obtained, the corn-fed calves dressed somewhat higher, especially in 1931. Carcass grades were also higher for the calves finished on corn, thus justifying the higher price paid for them. The partial substitution of ground rye for shelled corn. — From even a casual consideration of the data pertaining to Lots 3 and 5 in Table 5, it is apparent that a ration of equal parts of shelled corn and ground rye is superior to a ration of ground rye. More of the mixture than of a straight rye ration was consumed, and in two of the trials more rapid gains were made by the calves fed the mixture of shelled corn and ground rye. In fact, the ration approached shelled corn in palatability and in two trials out of three produced more rapid gains. The grain consumption </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves for the three years respectively was 92.1, 96.9, and 99.9 per cent as much in the lots fed the mixture as in the corn-fed lots. For alfalfa hay the figures were 98.7, 107.9, and 98.7 per cent. In economy of gains, the calves fed the mixture of shelled corn and ground rye compared favorably with those fed shelled corn. For the three trials respectively 96.8, 92.7, and 98.2 per cent as much grain and 103.6, 103.3, and 97.0 per cent as much alfalfa hay were required per unit of gain by the calves fed the mixture as by the calves fed shelled corn as the sole concentrate. Table 7. — Replacement value per bushel of ground rye for fattening calves when ground rye was substituted for one-half the shelled corn in the ration {average of three trials). Replacement value of ground rye at various prices of alfalfa hay per tun Price of shelled corn per husliel ; . i 55 ,»n SI'UX) S15.00 S2O.OQ sSlii S0.22 S0.21 S0.21 S0.21 .30 32 .32 .32 .32 .40 43 .43 .43 .« .50 54 .54 .54 .54 .60 65 .65 .65 •- .65 .70 .76 .76 .76 .75 80 87 .86 .86 .86 90 . .98 .97 .97 .97 1.IK) '.'.'.'.'.'..'.'.'.. 1 .08 1L08 hm L03 Table 7 gives the approximate value per bushel of ground rye in the ration when it is used to replace one-half of the shelled corn and fed under the conditions of the trials under discussion. Shrink in shipment was somewhat greater for the calves fed the mixture of shelled corn and ground rye than for those fed shelled corn. There was no difference in dressing yield in the first trial and very little in the second. There was no difference in ihe selling price or appraised value of the two groups of calves except in the second trial when the calves fed the mixture outsold the corn-fed calves by twenty cents per hundred. The market at the time these cattle were sold was demanding weight and the reason given by the buyer for the slight discrimination in favor of the lot fed the mixture of shelled corn and ground rye was its greater weight. Since this difference actually amounted to only 15 pounds per head and in view of the higher carcass grades obtained from Lot 1, it is doubtful if the corn-fed calves should have sold at a lower price than the others. SUPPLEMENTAL FEEDING PERIOD IN 1933 At the close of the third trial in 1933, it was decided to continue the experimental cattle on feed. All five lots were placed on the same ration. Ground shelled corn and alfalfa hay were fed according to appetite and linseed meal at the rate of one pound per head per day. Lots 1, 2, 4, and 5 were shipped after 29 days on this ration. Because of lack of finish, Lot 3 was fed for an additional 26 days, making a total supplemental feeding period of 55 days for this lot. As a matter of possible interest a summary of the data for this period combined with those for the regular experimental period is presented in </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 295 Table 8.— Data from third trial, Tables 1 and 5, combined with data from supplemental feeding period, which was 29 days in length for Lots 1, 2, 4, and 5, and 55 days in length for Lot 3 {all lots fed ground shelled corn, alfalfa hay, and one pound linseed meal per head daily during the supplemental periods and the rations listed below, with alfalfa hay, during the regular experimental period). Lot 4 Lot 5 I Lot ' L °' - Lot 3 Shelled Shelled " em Shelled Ground Ground corn-1. corn-1, corn wheat rye ground ground , whcit-I rye-1 Average initial weight -139 438 438 43* 437 Average final weight 971 968 1,029 967 961 Average gam 532 530 591 519 514 Average daily gain 2.36 2.35 2.35 2.35 *2.33 Average daily ration: Grain 11.60 10.85 11.27 11.55 1184 Alfalfa hay 6.00 6.61 7.07 6.'-, 5.87 Linseed meal 1 .95 .95 .99 .95 .95 Feed required for 100 lbs. of gain: Corn 499 81 143 291 ■'93 Wheat ... 350 215 R&gt;e ,...;. ... 336 ... 215 Total grain 499 461 479 506 503 Alfalfa hay 254 261 300 271 252 Linseed meal * 5 5 955 Selling price, per cwt.» S7.00 $7.00 56.65 S7.0v $7.00 J For last 29 days for Lots 1, 2, 4, and 5, and for last 55 days for Lot 3. : Fcd last 29 days to Lots I, 2, 4, and 5, and for last 55 days to Lot 3. "Lots 1. 2. 4, and 5 were sold together at S7.00 per cwt. They shrank 4.54 per ce.-.: in shipment and dressed 61.8 per cent. Lot 3 shrank 4.54 per cent and dressed 61.2 per cent. Table 8. Average daily gains for the five lots as shown by Table 8 were practically the same. Variations in the feed required per unit of gain were not great. The four lots of cattle shipped after a supplemental feeding period of 29 days sold at $7.00 per hundred, the top price at Omaha for a considerable period in 1933. The other lot sold 26 days later at $6.65, which was the extreme top for the day. The first four lots were slaught - ered in one group and dressed 61.8 per cent with a shrink in shipment of 4.54 per cent. The last lot marketed also shrank 4.54 per cent, and dressed 61.2 per cent. It is clear that if price conditions or available feed supply render it advisable, calves may be satisfactorily fed on ground wheat or ground rye for a considerable part of the feeding period and then finished on corn. It is apparent that calves fed ground rye as the sole concentrate require a longer supplemental feeding period than calves fed ground wheat or mixtures of ground wheat or ground rye and corn. Taking finish, attractiveness, and probable carcass grades into considera - tion, it is the opinion of the author that corn should be added to the ration of calves fed rye as the sole concentrate after a feeding period of approximately five months and for at least 60 to 90 days before market - ing the calves. GROUND WHEAT VS. GROUND RYE The three trials under consideration afford a direct comparison of ground wheat and ground rye fed with alfalfa hay to fattening calves, </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 The Use of Wheat and Rye for Fattening Calves both as the sole concentrate and in mixtures containing 50 per cent corn. As a matter of possible interest the data from the comparison will be briefly discussed. Table 9 presents the data for ground wheat and ground rye fed as the sole concentrate. There was little difference in the palat - ability of the two grains, as judged by the average daily grain consumption for the entire feeding period. In each trial, however, the wheat-fed calves Table 9. — Ground wheat vs. ground rye (all lots fed alfalfa hay)?-- First trial: Nov. 25. Second trial: Dec. 1. , Third trial: Oct. 18, 1930, to June 18, 1931, to June 12, 1932. to May 2, j 1931—205 dayt 1932—194 dayi 1933—196 dayi Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 2 Lot 3 Ground j Ground Ground : Ground ' Ground j Ground wheat I rye wheat i rye \ wheat I rye Average initial weight I J72 372 422 422 438 438 Average final weight ' 823 818 I . *70 655 886 870 Average giin : .1 451 446 448 433 448 432 Average daily gain \ 2.20 2.18 [ 2.31 2.23 | 2.29 2.21 Average daily ration: Grain K.91 8.91 9.72 9.84 | 10.20 10.13 Alfalfa hay j 5.66 5^53 6M 7.00 | 6.73 7.08 Feed required for 100 lbs. of gain: Grain 405 410 421 441 446 459 Alfalfa hay 257 254 275 313 ! 294 321 Shrink in shipment (p. ct.i ' 4.13 4.52 j 3.26 4.39 | ... "~ ... Dressing percentage Baied on selling weight ... 57.2 56.6 59.2 59.3 Based on final experi - mental weight | 54.8 54.0 ] 57.3 56.7 ... ... Carcass grades: No. 1 &lt;r- "■&gt; I 9 0 25 8 No. 2 Ip- ct., :.., 73 75 42 42 No. 3 ip. tt.t I 9 17 25 50 No. 4 If. n.) I 9 8 ! 8 0 j ... .Selling price, per cwt.» j S7.85 S7.75 | S6.85 56.50 j S5.90 $5.50 1 In the first trial one steer was removed from Lot 2. Results were calculated on a calf-day baiii. 3 The selling price given for the third trial represents an appraised value rather than the actual selling price. ate less grain than the rye-fed calves in the first part of the feeding period and more grain in the last part of the period. It was apparent that the rye was relished to a greater extent in the early part of the feeding period but that the wheat-fed calves maintained or rather increased their grain consumption, as the feeding period progressed, somewhat more than the rye-fed calves. In each of the three trials the wheat-fed calves made slightly larger gains than the rye-fed calves. There was less difference in the gains made in these trials than in the work reported by Kiser, Christgau, and Peters, formerly mentioned (page 10). The calves fed rye by these investigators did not consume as much feed in comparison with the wheat-fed calves as calves fed at the North Platte Substation. These authors ascribe the somewhat more favorable showing made by rye in their later wrok (page 10)) to the fact that the rye in their first trial contained more ergot. Another factor which may account in part for the relatively better showing made by the rye-fed calves in the work at the North Platte Substation was the much greater hay consumption. Feed requirements per unit of gain were slightly but consistently higher for the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 295 ryc--fed calves than for the wheat-fed calves. A study of Tables 2 and 0 shows that ground wheat is worth more than ground rye when each is red as the sole concentrate to fattening calves. The difference is greater than that indicated by the two tables, as in each trial the wheat-fed calves were appraised or sold at a higher price than the rye-fed calves. The market and slaughter data in Table 9 indicate that this discrimination in price was fully justified. Table 10. — A mixture of shelled corn and ground wheat vs. a similar mixture of shelled corn and ground rye {all lots fed alfalfa hay).' Fint trial: Nov. 25, Second trial: Dec. 1, Third trial: Oct. 18, 1930. to June 18, 1931. to June 12, 1932, to May 2, 1931—205 days 1932—194 days 1933—196 dayi Item Lot 4 Lot 5 Lot 4 Lot 5 Lot 4 Lot 5 Shelled Shelled Shelled Shelled Shelled Shelled corn*l, corn*!. corn-1, corn*l, corn-1, corn-1, ground ground ground ground ground ground : whcat-1 rye-1 wheat- 1 rye-1 whcat-1 rye-1 Average initial weight I 372 372 120 " 422 438 437 Average final weight I S64 M4 H39 854 885 887 Average gain | 492 472 419 432 447 450 Average daily gain | 2.40 2.30 2.16 2^ T2&amp; 2.30 Average daily ration: Grain 10.11 9.78 10.53 11.03 I 11.60 11.50 Alfalfa hay 5.24 5.26 6.03 5.63 | 6.53 .5.91 Feed required for 100 Ibl. | Grain ..." 421 424 488 496 510 501 Alfalfa hay 218 Z2S 279 253 287 257 Shrink in shipment (p. cl.) . 4.58 4.50 3.07 3.67 Dressing percentage: Based on selling weight... 58.4 58.0 60.0 59.7 ... ... It :sctl on final expert- i '. mental weight 55.5 55.4 1 58.2 57.5 1 ... Carcass grades: | No. 1 &lt;p. cl.) 37 20 | 0 8 No. 2 ff oj 54 70 67 33 No. 3 (p. a.) 9 10 33 59 No. 4 (p. ci.) 0 0 0 0 LL: ... Selling price, per cwt. 3 | S8.00 57.85 | 56.85 S6.85 | S5.90 55.90 1 In the first trial one steer was removed from Lot 4 and two from Lot 5. Results were calculated on a calf-day basis. s The selling prices given for the thiid trial represent an appraised value rather than the actual selling price. As might be expected, when a ration of equal parts by weight of shelled corn and ground wheat was compared with a similar ration of shelled corn and ground rye, there was less difference in the relative value of wheat and rye than when they were compared as the sole concentrates iri the rations. No significant difference in average daily gains is shown by the data in Table 10. Neither was there any consistent difference in the apparent palatability of the two rations, in the feed requirement for 100 pounds of gain, or in shrink in shipment. The wheat-fed cattle dressed slightly higher and yielded carcasses of somewhat higher average grades, although there was no significant dif - ference in selling price or appraised value. Ground wheat a/id ground rye were of approximately equal value, pound for pound, for fattening calves when each was used to replace one-half of the shelled corn in the ration. [5M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>