<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Thirty-Seventh Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1924-01-01">1924-01-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA fHIRTY-SEVENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor February 1 , 1 924 LINCOLN. NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL The University of Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station To His Excellency, Charles W. Bryan, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the General Assembly of the State of Nebraska, approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor herewith to submit the Thirty-seventh Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. E. A. Burnett, Director. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE State of Nebraska, Executive Department Lincoln, February 1, 1924. Mr. E. A. Burnett, Director Nebraska Agricultural Experi - ment Station: Sir: I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Thirty-seventh Annual Report of the Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. Charles W. Bryan, Governor. February 1, 1924. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska Till-: I.(I\KKMM. BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) Hon. John R. Webster, Omaha. Term expires January, 1925 Hon. Frank W. Judkon, President, Omaha Term expires January. 1925 Hon. William L. Bates, Lincoln Term expires January, 1927 Hon. George N. Seymour, Elgin, Vice Pres Term expires January, 1927 Hon. Harry D. Landis, Seward Term expires January, 1929 Hon. William P. Warner, Dakota City Term expires January. 1929 Samuel Avkrv. Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor I III: STATION' IIIIIUIK E. A. Burnett, D. Sc Director W. W. Burr, B. S&lt;\, Assistant Director W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Berriet R. P. Crawford, B. A . Agricultural Editor W. W. Marshall, Executive Clerk I Ml HIIHhIM. NTAFK C. W. Ackerson, M. Sc. Assistant m Agricultural Chemtstri, Arthur Amiermin. B. Sc., Assistant in Agronomy M. J. Bi.ish, Ph. D., Agricultural Clninistry E. E. Brackett. B. Sc. in E. E., Asaocmte in Agricultural Eng E. M. Broi.se, B. Sc. Superintendent Experimental Substation. V il W. W. Birr, B. Sc. Agronomy /Chairman) H. P. Davis, M. Sc, Dairy H usbamli n /Chairman V. A. Downs, Ph. D., Aamtdate in Dairy Husbamlri H. C. Filley, A. M., Rural Eeonomu s /Chairman) H. D. Fox, M. Sc., Assistant in Animal Husband) R. W. Goss, If. Sc, AsMoriati in Plant Pathology H. J. Grami.icii. B. Sc. Animal Husbandry (Chain, 3. A. Holde.n, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental subst R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture (Chairman T. A. Kiehhelbaoh, Ph. D., Agromtmy W. J. Loeffel, B. Sc. Assistant m Animal Husbi G. A. Loveland, A. M., LL. B., Meteorology W. E. Lyness, B. Sc in Agr., Assistant in Igi H. M. Martin, V. M. I).. A. M.. Assistant in Animal I'atholoyi, R. F. Morgan, B. Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husband F. E. MrsNi:iu . B. Sc., Poultry Husbandry F. R. Nohavec B. Sc in A. E., Assistant in Agricultural Emt G. L. Peltier. Ph. D.. Plant Pathology J. O. Ra.nkix, A.M., Associate in 1'ural Economics J. C. Russkl, M. Sc, Assistant in Ayrono Rudolph Saxdsteot, B. Sc, Analyst O. W. Sjogren, B. Sc. in A. E., Agricultural Eni/im « nnu (Chain W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North FiatU M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology /Chairman) L. Van En., M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene /Cha E. E. Wehr, M. Sc, Assistant in Entomology H. O. Werner, M. Sc, Assistant m Horticuitur C. C. Wiggans, Ph. D., Associate in Hortirultun ♦♦L. L. Zook. B. Sc, Agronomist. North Platte •By an art of the Legislature of tht- Stat.- of Nebranka. approved and February 15. 1899. the State Treasurer became a «0M* cuModian of thi E if.. pt-rimen Station fund on and after July 1, 1899. ••Drtailwl from the Offic.- of Dry Land Axrirulturr. United Staten IK-u 1ment of AKrieulture. Washington. D. C. ♦L. E. GrxDEnsoN, Finance secretary B. I. Masc bovsky, M. So., Qmduatr Axxixtiint in hmrn Hu*b </seg>
            <seg id="p005">CONTENTS 5 1 ( etter of Transmittal lovernor's Certificate Official Roster of the Station 4 5 nt~ vestigational Work 7 Agricultural Engineering: Tractor Testing Plow Draft Investigation Fuel Saving Devices 7 8 8 Poultry House Ventilation and Construction \ in ma I Diseases 8 I Hemorrhagic Septicemia Important Poultry Diseases in Nebraska Relation of Avian (Poultry) Tuberculosis to Tuberculosis of Swine !" Other Animal Diseases 10 Husbandry: A Study of the Weight of Dairy Cattle The Principles of Ice-cream Making.. Ill 10 Acidity Phase 10 The Effect of Aging on Viscosity and Texture of the Ice cream Mix 11 Study of Gelatine II 12 National Egg-Laying Contest Field Crops and Soils: Corn Breeding II 14 11 l« 17 17 II lit Water Requirement of Crops Small Grain Forage Crop Investigations isoil Fertility Co-operative Experiments Factors Influencing Nitrification in Nebraska Soils Soil Acidity Fruit Production : .19 Winter Injury Investigations Pruning Apples, Grapes, and Small Fruit Fruit Breeding Investigations 20 21 Insect Control: Life History of Several Common Cutworms Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. Grasshopper Control 21 21 .21 22 Hessian Fly Livestock Feeding: Beef Cattle Baby Beef n 2^ Rations for Fattening Lambs Rations for Fattening Hogs.. Feed from Pasture 24 24 25 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">CONTENTS Continued Page Milling; and Baking Qualities of Wheat Nutrition : 25 Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks 26 Comparative Efficiency of Various Proteins in Poultry- Feeding 2&lt;; Studies of Fat Soluble A Present in the Milk of Different Dairy Breeds Plant Diseases: Studies of Stem Rust Fusarium Wilt and Stem-End Rot of Potato Jv Effect of Environment on Potato Degeneration Diseases Potatoes : Potato Selection Seed Potato Certification Degeneracy in Potatoes _'!' Rural Economies: Farm Management Survey Cost of Producing Beef Cattle Farm Tenure Cost of Production of Farm Crops Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains Farm Land Problem Serum Production North Platte Substation: Experiments with Hogs Dairy Cattle Poultry Plant Horticulture Field Crops Union Fruit Farm Valentine Substation Forage Crops Silage Crops Grain Crops Annual Legumes Scottsbluff Substation Field Crops Pastures Sweet Clover and Native Pasture Lamb Feeding Experiments Hogs- Summer vs. Winter Finishing Self-Feeder Compared with Limited Rations Comparison of Tankage and Alfalfa Hay for Feeding Changes in Station Staff Hogs Publications M Acknowledgments Financial Statement 4(1 41 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">in 1" THIRTY-SEVENTH ANNUAL REPORT the year covered by this Report satisfactory pro - &gt;een made in the investigational work carried on Experiment Station. Quite a number of problems under igation have been brought to conclusion and the results oled and published. A number of new lines of investi- •en added. ir a number of changes have taken place in Experiment Station staff. In each case the place has been . and two additional appointments have been made. Some equipment has been added for investigational work. is an increasing demand from the public for in - along many lines. This is evidenced not only correspondence received, but thru the number .nd animal specimens received, with requests for rmation. The receipt of such specimens has been y heavy in the Department of Animal Pathology equired for taking care of this routine work is rable. It is felt, however, that it is a proper function Experiment Station staff, and all such inquiries have ire of when they properly fell within our field. i\\ i:stk;ationai. woiik estigational work of the Experiment Station is by both Federal and State funds. A financial nt. showing the expenditure of various funds allotted Experiment Station, is shown later on in this report. lowing brief summary shows most of the problems investigation and records the progress made dur- nast fiscal vear. 7 Testing. During the past year a number of / bictors have been tested and notable improvements noted in i&gt;st of these as compared with previous models tested. The ost outstanding improvement noted was the ability of speed ntrol devices, or governors, to perform their functions more ;rfectly than has been true in former years. ?knowletlffment {■ «*n«* tn Assistant Director W. W. Burr for the preparation of the dwltafr with th. Experiment S%-iti.»n \&gt;.&gt;.' &lt;t The report of the Atrrioilturnl Ext. n»ion Service is published in a separate bulletin \i.i;i&lt; i i 1 1 i; \i K\&lt;;i\KKltl\(. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 8 Plow Draft Investigation. This work has been continued and considerable data have been obtained during the past year. However, results which have been so far secured are not sufficient to warrant definite conclusions. Fuel Saving Devices, and treatments, for internal com - bustion engines. During the past year a number of repre - sentative fuel treating materials were tested with the object of determining whether the saving in fuel claimed by the makers of these materials could actually be made. Results obtained have led to the following conclusions : The same results can be secured by proper adjustment of the carburetor without fuel savers as when these are used. Gasoline improvers do not in general give a marked sav - ing in fuel nor increase the mileage per gallon. When any improvement was noted it was so slight that it did not pay for the added cost of the improver. Poultry House Ventilation and Construction. The pur - pose of this project is to secure data which will yield infor - mation for the proper design of poultry houses best suited to Nebraska conditions. This work is just being started. \\IM\I. IHSKASKS Hemorrhagic Septicemiu. This investiga deavor to determine the organisms belonging to the \ hagic septicemia group and their development. It incl well a study of the antigenic and biologic properties organism. During the year covered by this Report it has been dosm - ble to produce a highly potent immune serum against the fowl cholera organism. It was also found that the immunity offered by this serum was of short duration and that it was not possible to lengthen or to activate this immunity by the introduction of virus during the immune period of the test animals. The department also attempted to determine to what extent the apparent immunizing properties of this serum can be utilized in field outbreaks. For this purpose a number of flocks in which there were more or less acute outbreaks were treated by members of the department. Some data were obtained but not yet in sufficient volume to warrant con - clusions. After some 2,000 fowls had been treated, outbreaks ceased to occur in this vicinity. For this reason the project has become temporarily inactive, but will be resumed as soon as material will again become available. In the meantime, </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report ii care is being taken of the serum-producing horses and a stock of the serum for field use is being collected and tested. Important Poultry Diseases in Nebraska. The investiga - tion carried under this heading has been brought to comple - tion and a summary setting forth the causes, nature, and prevention of the most important poultry diseases occurring in the State, has been made in Experiment Station Bulletin No. 195. It was found that the frequency of diseases is to a large xtent dependent upon the density of the livestock popula- tion ; that there has been a steady increase in the diseases of domestic fowls as their numbers have increased upon the farm. Stress is laid upon the fact that the problem of poul - try diseases will be more largely solved by preventive rather than curative measures and, as a means to this end, the fol - lowing are mentioned: (1) Selection of sound breeding stock, orrect and adequate feeding methods, (3) sanitation, 4) the eradication and control of transmissible diseases. lit lation of Avian (Poultry) Tuberculosis to Tuberculosis Swine. This line of investigation has been actively pur- sued during the past fiscal year. Material of tuberculous swine of Nebraska origin was received from the South Omaha and Nebraska City packing establishments and a study was made of the type of bacilli responsible for the lesions. Tho laboratory examination of 26 consignments of tuberculous swine is now complete. In none of these could bacilli of mammalian origin be demonstrated, but in 21 of the speci - mens it could be quite definitely shown that the infection which gave rise to the lesions was caused by the avian strain. Thru the co-operation of the local representatives of the I*. S. Bureau of Animal Industry, it was possible to secure a complete survey of the animals on 14 of the farms from which the tuberculous swine originated. On all of those farms the poultry flocks were found to be infected with tuberculosis, but on onlv one were the cattle also found to suffer from this infection. On 10 of those farms swine were also tested and on 5 those animals were found to be tuberculous. It is significant that many of those swine, tested simultaneously with mamma- lian and avian tuberculin, reacted only to the latter. This project is far from complete, but the results thus far obtained warrant the prediction that the current views on the origin of swine tuberculosis will require thoro re- vision. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Other Animal Diseases. In addition to the above men tional projects, a study has been made of such diseases a; "Hog flu," abortion in swine, coccidiosis in sheep, but as ye; this work is not sufficiently advanced to warrant a definitt report on these subjects. DAII5Y HISISANDKY A Study of the Weight of Dairy Cattle. The purpose &lt;&gt;i this project is to determine the average gain in weight of both males and females of several breeds of dairy cattle. All the calves are weighed at birth and for 3 days each week up to the time they are 6 months old, after which they are weighed for 3 consecutive days in the middle of each month. Males aiv weighed up to the time they are disposed of, while females will be weighed regularly as long as they remain in the herd. The following table gives the weight results obtained so far: w Breed No. Birth N /./, Holstein Male 1» S*l '. 1 Av. daily aain Holstein Fem. 13 90.1 tS 2M.&lt; Av. daily sain 1.4 Jersey Male 5 55.4 S Av. daily feain Jersey Fein. 11 49.9 10 118 Av. daily (gain Guernsey Fem. 6 66.8 4 148 Av. daily gain Ayrshire Fem. 5 67.8 Av. dally gain The Principles of Ire-Cream Making, During the yea several phases were studied, including the acidity as affec ing quality, yield, and viscosity ; viscosity as regards the effe&lt; of aging ; and comparative tests were conducted with differei grades of gelatine. Acidity Phase. Experimental mixes were made up with a composition approximately as follows: butterfat 14 per cent, sugar 14 per cent, gelatine • ■_. per cent, milk solids-not - fat 7 1 •_&gt; per cent, or a total solids content of 36 per cent. The ingredients used as standardized cream were skim milk, skim milk powder, gelatine, sugar, and flavoring. The entire mix </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 11 was pasteurized at 145 degrees F. for 30 minutes, after which it was homogenized at a pressure between 2,000 and 2,500 pounds per square inch, and then cooled to 45 degrees F. Aging took place at temperatures between 40 and 45 degrees F. Experimental mixes were divided into 3 groups. Group I mixes were aged from 2 to 3 hours, Group II mixes from 19 to 48 hours, and Group III mixes for 72 hours. One-half of each group of mix was acidified by the addition of 15 per cent of a lactic acid skim milk starter. An equal amount of fresh skim milk was added to the check mix. Viscosity read - ings were made with a Scott's Viscometer, and overrun was determined by using a De Raef overrun tester. Hydrogen-ion concentration was determined on a Leeds and Northrup Type K Potentiometer. In brief the results so far indicate : That the addition of the starter to the homogenized mix nds to increase viscosity. Comparing results obtained from a mix of high viscosity to acidity ana aging, with those from the check having lower viscosity, aged the same length of time but of lower idity, no decided differences were apparent in the yield of ream during the freezing process. No change was apparent in the hydrogen-ion (P H) value ormally handled ice cream mix during aging varying from i I") hours. rhe frozen cream from acidified mixes tends to retain the ic acid flavor of the starter and is consequently objection- aciditv is objectionable in frozen cream and does not ceably affect the physical make-up during the aging and zing of the mix, it serves no useful purpose and is not ?commended. The Effect of Aging on Viscosity and Texture of the Ice ■am Mix. The influence of aging upon viscosity and tex- ture was studied with 8 emulsified and 24 homogenized batches. Samples were taken from each batch immediately after prep - paration and before aging and kept in the aging room. Vis - cosity readings were made at intervals ranging from 2 to 72 hours and microscopical examinations were made at the same time. The results so far indicate: That excessive aging tends to decrease the viscosity of the mix and cause a decrease in its ability to preserve a smooth texture. That homogenized mixes appear always to have a higher viscosity than emulsified mixes, both before and after aging. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station That the optimum aging period for a normal mix is be - tween 24 and 48 hours. Study of Gelatine. It is believed that the foremost func - tions of gelatine in an ice cream mix are to prevent the crystallization of the sugar and the formation of large ice crystals. With this in mind the following test has been worked out, which it is believed will indicate the effectiveness of dif - ferent grades of gelatine for the purposes mentioned. A "gel" is prepared from 4 grams and 120 c. c. of dis - tilled water, to which is added 12 grams of bichromate (K.CrXK). After the gelatine and bichromate are dissolved, a test tube is filled half full and set away to congeal. After congealing, 5 c. c. of an 8 1 ;&gt; per cent silver nitrate solution (AgNO,) are poured on top of the "gel." The tube is al - lowed to stand for 24 hours. A comparison of different grades of gelatine can then be made, one "gel" being made for each grade. The sample that exhibits the greatest amount of brick red stratification appears to have the greatest protective powers. Microscopical examination of the crystallization that took place in 5 per cent milk sugar (lactos) solution contain - ing 1 per cent of gelatine of different grades shows a co- ordination between stratification and a compact, smooth for of crystals. NATIONAL KAMi l.AYIN*. (OMI^I A total of 272 birds trapnested in the Egg Laying Contest have made records of 200 eggs and better. These birds have been returned to their owners and are being used in breed - ing pens for the development of better laying strains of poultry. The publicity which the breeders of these birds have given their records has helped to emphasize the importance of egg production, on which the development of the poultry business depends. The egg records of birds at the Egg Laying Contest have varied all the way from 2 to 275 eggs. These birds were all housed in the same kind of houses and had exactly the same feed and opportunity to produce. The average production of all birds finishing the contest each year has been better than 150 eggs per bird, which is approximately twice the average for the whole state. The number of hens making records of 200 eggs or better each year is as follows: 1920-21—76 birds 1921-22—77 birds 1922-23—86 birds 1919-20—33 birds </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 13 Birds representing nearly every breed and variety of standard bred poultry are included in the list. A breeding program which is based on the use of the best layers in each entry is being carried out by most of the breeders. Trapnesting during at least a part of each year is now also being practiced by an increasing number of breeders who are wanting more accurate information on the laying ability of their birds than the physical characteristics tests give them. A study of the trapnest records made at the laying contests shows that intensity of production for at least 2 suc - cessive months quite accurately measures egg-laying ability. Hens which have laid 50 eggs in any successive 60-day period are usually the outstanding individuals judged by one-year records. Annual records are of course more desirable but more costly because of the labor required. Ml. I. It CROPS AND SOILS Corn Breeding. This project has been carried for a num - ber of years, the purpose being to determine methods for im - provement in the yield and quality of corn and to establish general principles of corn breeding. Many of the proposed earlier methods of corn improve - ment, such as the detasseling and ear-to-row methods, have failed to produce beneficial results. The favorable hybridiza - tion of pure lines that have been reduced to a homozygous state by prolonged inbreeding seems now to be the most promising procedure for corn improvement. Certain pure line first generation hybrids have indicated superiority over the original corn but new hybrid seed must be produced each year rather than to select from the hybrid progeny. Very material reduction in yield has resulted in all cases where the seed was selected from the first year cross. Investiga - tions are under way to determine the possibility of weeding out undesirable characters by inbreeding and then recombin - ing a relatively large number of pure line selections in order to obtain a corn that will continue to give relatively high yields. In this study many combinations are being made. Fertilization by foreign pollen has failed to give a ma - terial increase in kernel weight of commercial varieties of dent corn. The increase from heterosis is very marked in the case of selfed strains, amounting in these tests to an average of 11.8 per cent. The increase due to a change in endosperm type which occurs with sweet corn when fertilized by a starchy type is also marked, amounting to an average of 19.9 per cent for 6 sweet-dent combinations. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Seed corn from various sources and germinator selections for freedom from root rot diseases confirmed earlier indica - tions that these rot diseases are not serious in Nebraska and that nothing is to be gained by such germinator testing for disease provided usual precautions are taken to select seed of satisfactory viability. The question of regional adapted - ness is involved in all such tests and is regarded the out - standing factor in relative productivity. An Experiment Station Bulletin, No. 188, entitled "Pro - ductive Seed Corn," was issued in April, 1923, and summa - rizes many of the problems under consideration. Additional data are reported in Vol. 15. No. 5, and Vol. 16, No. 1, of the Journal of the American Society of Agronomy. Water Requirement of Crops. This work was continued with some 400 potometers, the purpose being to study correla - tions between the use of water of the corn plant in relation to climatic factors, soil fertility, variety, plant characteristics, and source of seed. Homozygous inbred strains were also compared with their hybrids. Increasing the concentration of the soil soli thi the addition of various rates of either manure or artificia fertilizer has failed to reduce the total amount of water us". per corn plant during its growth to maturity. On the othei hand, the amount of water transpired per pound of dry matt; i has decreased somewhat with such applications until a poim is reached where the added fertility results in decreased yields Concerning 8 standard varieties of field corn during a 7 - year period representing types adapted to various regions, the extreme range of water transpired per pound of dry matter was 260 pounds for a variety obtained from New York and 279 pounds for a small early maturing variety from South Dakota. The total water used per plant for these same 2 varieties averaged 235 and 135 pounds, respectively. In com - parison with these the variety known as Esperanza, which is not grown commercially, was extreme in the amount of water used per pound of dry matter, — namely, 317 pounds. The water requirement per pound of dry matter has" varied for corn grown under similar soil and moisture conditions during the 13-year period, 1910-1922, from 192 pou ids in 1915 to 445 pounds in 1913 ; 218 pounds were used pev pound of dry matter in 1922. The variation from year to year has been found to correlate rather closely with the evaporation rate from a free water surface, which in turn varies with the seasonal climatic conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 15 t The transpiration data as a whole suggest that any soil treatments which result in more favorable plant development tend to increase the dry matter produced per unit of water ranspired. Small Grain. This work was continued in the study of variety testing, breeding, acclimatization, and cultural studies with various small grains. The outstanding factor in the oat production is the rela - tive vields of early and late varieties. A summarization of 18 years of work, 1905 to 1923, shows that the 3 leading early varieties, — Kherson, Texas Red, and Burt, — have given an average of 54 bushels per acre. The 4 most promising late varieties, — Swedish Select, American Banner, University No. 6 (Minnesota), and Lincoln, — have averaged 45.3 bushels, or an average of 8.7 bushels per acre in favor of the earlier varieties of oats. This difference in yield is not as wide as has been found between the early and late varieties at the North Platte Station, indicating that earliness is even more important as one goes westward in the State, except where it is grown under irrigation. Several selections of Kherson have continued to give higher yields than the original strain. One of these, Nebraska 21, is now widely distributed thru the State. The work in the improvement of Texas Red and Kurt varieties has been continued. Commercially these varie - ties are mixed in color and a number of strains true to color of grain, ranging from black to white, have been selected. Four hundred pure line strains of the original 1,200 selected were grown this vear. Karly Java and Marquis spring wheat have continued to give the highest yields among the varieties of common spring wheat tested. Kota has been inferior under our conditions; while Acme and Monad Durum yielded highest of all spring wheat varieties. The last 2 named have been declared in - ferior and undesirable in quality by the U. S. Department Agriculture. Winter wheat varieties of the hard winter type have very definitely outyielded those of the soft to semi-hard winter types. Kanred, Nebraska No. 6, and Nebraska No. 60 have surpassed all sorts commercially available, tho strains from several other sources have given about equal results. Kanred is unsurpassed as an all-round wheat. Blackhull gives in - dications of lacking winter hardiness this far north. Chemi - cal analyses indicate that some of the Turkey Red strains are fully equal to the original Turkey Red in protein a , well as being high in yield. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station The testing of a large number of Crimean selections has continued in the nursery. Special effort will be made to select for resistance to disease and winter killing. Delay in planting winter wheat after October 1 results in receding grain yields as the delay is extended. Winter wheat planted under conditions of delayed germination so that growth does not begin until spring has its yield greatly impaired irrespective of the character of winter weather in this section of the State. Early planting has proved equally important with oats and spring wheat. Rate-of-planting tests indicate there may be a wide divers - ity in planting rate with any of the small grain crops with - out material effect upon yield. Forage Crop Investigations. Annual forage crop investi - gations consisted largely of varietal studies of the sorghums, millets, and other annual crops adapted to Nebraska condi - tions and of cultural studies of ordinary amber sorghum and sudan grass. During a 4-year period amber sorghum yielded 5.15 tons per acre, whereas sudan grass yielded 3.31 tons, or 64.3 per cent of the sorghum yield. Of the 10 sorghums grown in the variety tests there has not been much difference in ton - nage per acre when sudan grass is excluded. Black amber was found to be one of the earliest maturing and best yield - ers of the group. During especially long growing seasons later varieties, as Red Amber. Orange, Sumac, and Honey, may yield more than Black Amber. German Millet was the highest yielding foxtail millet and has yielded 79 per cent as much as ordinary amber sorghum. Japanese barnyard and Pearl millets have given satisfactory yields, but have been later maturing and the forage produced has been coarser and less palatable. Six dates of seeding amber sorghum and sudar grass. ranging from May 15 to July 5, have been practiced. The first 4 seedings have given but little difference in yield. Based on the average yields from the first 4 dates, the fifth and sixth dates of seeding amber sorghums have yielded only 74 and 58 per cent of the earlier dates and for sudan grass 71 and 51 per cent. Amber sorghum seeded at 6 rates, varying from 25 to 150 pounds per acre, has given relative yields of 100, 110, 107, 111, 116, and 115, based on the thinnest rate as 100 per cent. Similar results for sudan grass seeded from 10 to 80 pounds per acre have been 100, 96, 103, 106, 108, and 110. Harvesting at 3 stages of maturity have been followed for both crops, — i. e., heads appearing, fully headed, fully </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 17 ripe. Based on the first stage as 100, the yields for the sorghum have been 100, 108, and 113 and for the sudan grass 100, 112, and 89. Amber sorghums drilled, broadcast, sur - face planted in rows, and listed have yielded 100, 85, 67, and 49 respectively, based on 100 per cent for the drilled. Similar yields for sudan grass have been 100, 90, 82, and 67. Three years' results have been secured from studies deal - ing with cultivation, application of fertilizers to, and dates of harvesting of alfalfa. The evidence obtained is not yet sufficient to justify conclusions. An exhaustive study of alfalfa varieties and regional strains is under way; also a study of date of seeding, rate of seeding, and time of harvest - ing of sweet clovers and a study of the more important perennial grasses and red clovers. Sail Fertility. The work at the main station has been continued at the Agronomy Farm. These experiments have been in progress for only 3 years and have not run long enough to allow definite statements of results. Applications of manure have given small but consistent yields on all crops. The largest increase on wheat and oats comes from the heavi - est application of manure and in the year following its ap - plication. With corn the largest increase comes the second year after application. Applications of phosphorus show in the early growth of oats and wheat but have failed to give consistent increased yield at harvest. The effect of applications of nitrogen on oats and wheat is seasonal. Small increases have been obtained in seasons unfavorable for the development of nitrates in the soil. No commercial fertilizer has given consistent increases of corn. The yields of alfalfa have declined each year since the first year's crop. Applications of manure, lime, and various com - mercial fertilizers have failed to increase yields, which indi - cates that on this soil the yield is determined largely by the moisturp supply and not by fertility. After alfalfa has been grown for a term of years the supply of moisture in the sub - soil becomes exhausted and the crop is entirely dependent upon rainfall. Co-operative Experiments. Work has been continued in co-operation with farmers in the State. The plan has been to carry these co-operative experiments 3 years in a county, on all of the important soil types. The experiments are limited to a study of the effects of manure, acid phosphate, and potassium chloride on wheat, corn, and oats During the past year, work was carried on in Washington and Gage </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Counties. Up to the present no soil types have been found which are so deficient in nitrogen, phosphorus, or potash that these elements can be supplied economically as commercial fertilizers. Factors Influencing Nitrification in Nebraska SoiUs. The purpose of this project is to determine the importance of moisture, temperature, aeration, and organic matter on the rate of nitrate accumulation in the soil and to establish a rational basis for systems of tillage, rotation, and soil im - provement with respect to nitrate elaboration. Laboratory studies on average soil from the Agronomy Farm have shown that the rate of nitrate accumulation under temperature conditions that might obtain from late fall to May 15 is not sufficiently high to meet the needs of wheat or oats, but the rate at which nitrate accumulates at summer temperature is sufficiently high to meet the demands of the com plant. The limited moisture conditions that obtain dur - ing the large part of the seed-bed preparation season for wheat also seriously reduce nitrate accumulation. Laboratory studies show that aeration is probably not a serious factor in nitrification under Nebraska conditions. The most im- portant development of laboratory studies has been the very low rate of nitrate accumulation on soils which have been depleted of their organic matter. Correlations between crop performance in the field and nitrate production in the field and incubator indicate that there may be soils in Nebraska which have been so depleted of organic matter and nitrifiablc material, either by erosion or by long continued grain farm - ing, that nitrate production is the limiting factor for wheal and oats. Soil Acidity. The purpose of these investigations was to determine the approximate extent of acid soils in Nebraska. whether or not the problem at present had serious aspects, and the probable cause for acidity under Nebraska conditions. During the past season the work on the samples obtained from the fields has been completed. In all more than 550 samples of soil were collected from more than 160 areas. The information obtained shows that acid soils are more widely distributed thru Nebraska than was commonly thought. The Drift Hill reg?on in southeastern Nebraska is the most acid region. The Shelby and Carrington loam types in Johnson, Pawnee, and Gage Counties are the most seriously acid soils in the State. The Loess Hills soils are very slightly to medium acid, depending upon the extent to which erosion has laid </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 19 bare the underlying calcareous subsoil. The Loess Plains soils grow less acid and the calcareous horizon in the soil comes closer to the surface as rainfall decreases westward across the state. The acidity found in Nebraska is due to leaching. Rain water carbonated by organic decay leaches the lime out of the surface soil, carrying it to a lower depth. The factors determining acidity are rainfall, original supply of carbonates, age of the soil information, the extent of percolation as de - termined by texture and structure, and extent of vegetable decay both in the virgin state or under cultivation. Ninety-five per cent of the samples collected for this studv showed less than medium acidity by the Truog method. A few samples gave strong reaction, indicating strong acidity. The lime requirement of the most strongly acid soils is not higher than 3,360 and 760 pounds calcium carbonate per acre, by the Veitch and Hopkins methods, respectively. Kill IT PROMOTION Winter Injury Investigations. The purpose of this in- vestigation was to determine the effect of low soil tempera - tures on root injury of the apple. Investigations have been under way since 1915 and are being summarized for publica - tion, the following conclusions having been made: Individual French crab seedling stock is rather easily in - jured by severe winter temperatures. Many of them will be killed or severely injured by an exposure of -10° C. for two hours in an air chamber. Scion roots of most varieties are hardier than French Crab and seedling roots. Small, young roots are more susceptible to cold than large, )lder ones. Varieties of apples differ in their tendency to form roots from scion wood. Scion roots are produced by some the first year in the nursery, while others have none at the end of the third year. The tops of some varieties are more subject to winter in - jury in the nursery than others. Apple twigs taken in late winter became calloused read - ily, but they did not form any roots. At 7'^ inches depth the temperature under bluegrass sod was from 2 to 7 degrees C. higher in midwinter than that in a clean cultivated plat. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Moisture content of orchard soil used did not greatly in- the minimum temperature that was reached in mid - er at several inches below the surface. The dry soil, however, responded more quickly than the wet one to at - mospheric changes. Freezing temperatures were reached somewhat sooner in early winter in the dry than in the wet. soil. In early spring the wet soil remained at or near the freezing point for 12 days while the dry soil had a mean temperature of 34 degrees F. If there is less injury to roots in a wet than in a dry soil, it is probably due to protection afforded by the moist medium and not to higher soil temperatures in the region of the roots. Occasionally in midwinter soil temperature of eastern Nebraska gets low enough to kill tender apple roots to a depth of 6 to 12 inches. Pruning Apples, Grapes, and Small Fruits. This study is undertaken to determine the influence of different methods of pruning upon the fruitfumess and growth of the plant. With apples, work is being done on the "filler" trees at the Union Orchard and includes a study of several pruning methods ; also the effect of light and heavy pruning during both the growing and the dormant season. These trees are just be- ginning to bear, and data on the relation of different ods of pruning to yield are not available. Pruning experiments with grapes are being cond determine the relative merits of the "cane renewal" systen as compared to the "spur renewal" system. A portion of t vines are trained to a single trunk and the remaind double trunk. Fifty-three plants were pruned to the cane system and 61 to the spur system. The cane pruned plants had an age of 96.6 buds per plant, in 1923, and produced 6, grams of fruit. The spur pruned plants had an avera 62.1 buds per plant and produced 5,974.2 grams iit. There was a difference noted in the two plats in the percent - age of buds that produced fruit, in the number of clusters produced, and in the size of the clusters. Theie wore 73.94 per cent buds on the cane pruned plants which were produc - tive, while only 66.6 per cent of those on the spur pruned produced fruit clusters. The number of clusters from each producing bud on the cane pruned plants was 2.53, while the number on the spur pruned plants was only 2.26. The aver - age size of clusters from the cane pruned plants was 62.64 grams and from the spur pruned plants 60.99 grams. It </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 21 should be remembered that these vines are only 7 years old and are therefore very vigorous. Fruit Breeding Investigations. In these investigations 762 new strains of strawberries were produced by crossing and inbreeding a named variety. Ten of the hybrids have been retained after 7 years' testing. These promising hybrids have been selected largely upon their ability to outyield Dunlap, the standard variety for this section. They also produce larger berries thruout the season than either Dunlap or War - field. Bulletin No. 189 summarizes this work. IXSMT CONTROL Life History of Several Common Cutworms. Work on this project for the past year was confined largely to gathering additional material on the Western Army Cutworm. Control of Injurious Insects, Mammals, and Birds. Dur - ing the past year the work along this line was confined largely to a study of the Plains False Wireworm (Eleodes opaca). This worm seriously attacked the wheat crop of 1922-23 in several counties in western Nebraska. Experiment Station Circular No. 20 gives the life history and proposed control of this worm. Reports on the gadflies of Nebraska, an important group of insect pests of livestock, and upon the syrphus flies, a group that contains a number of useful enemies of aphids. were completed during the period covered by this report and have recently been printed. A report was also completed on the June-beetle family, which contains the very injurious white grub and its relatives, and this report has also just been pub - lished. Grasshopper Control. This project has received consider - able attention during the past season. Field experiments were conducted at the Scottsbluff Station from June 13 to August 17, 1922, and the results obtained were summarized in Bul - letin No. 183, on "Experiments with Poisoned Baits for Grass - hoppers." This work also formed the basis for the working out of a formula for preparing poisoned baits for use against grasshoppers in the North Platte valley, where these pests have been quite injurious for a number of years. Efforts to improve this formula were continued during the summer of 1923 and the further results obtained will be summarized in a bulletin now in course of preparation. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Hessian Fly. Considerable damage was done by the He.s - sian Fly during the past year. An increasing number of flies have been noticed for the past two or three years. The fall brood of 1922, favored by the dryness of the season, developed more widespread infestation. A survey in the spring of 1923 showed Hessian Fly present in all counties south of the Platte River and west to Frontier and Red Willow Counties and north of the Platte to Dakota, Wayne, Madison, Boone. Howard, Sherman, Buffalo, and Dawson Counties. Serious injury was done to the 1923 crop in a number of sections. Realizing that the large number of Hessian flies present in 1923 were likely to cause large and unnecessary losses to the following crop, a field observation station was established in the heart of a heavily infested district along the Missouri River, in order to determine from observations made at t point the safe date for planting wheat. The most satisfactory known method of combating tl Hessian Fly has been to delay seeding of the winter who until the danger of fly infestation in the field has passed; ar in a number of sections where the damage has been heavy 1923, the farmers agreed to delay seeding until the obaerv tions showed that the danger of infestation had passed, \vh&lt; the County Agent would be notified and h urn w notify them. r, emergence of the adult flies, their movement in the field, th&lt; egg-laying, and the decreasing presence of the viable or Hvii puparia in the stubble. The daily emergency of the adi the flies was determined by the flies emerging from about 3 bushels of heavily infested stubble placed in a tight wooden box. Tin daily movement of the flies in the field was measured h\ counting the flies caught on two large wire •i in the stubble field and painted with a sticky 1 p t The egir-laying each day was measured by the number o1 eggs laid on 100 wheat plants, selected in a small plot oi wheat, which was seeded on Aueust 20. The decreasing pres - ence of viable puparia in the stubble was determined by count ing and examining the puparia contained in 100 old stubbU plants each day. The observations made showed varying bui large activity of the flies along the several lines included ir the studies, the activity increasing rapidly toward the firs! of October. On September 29, when the date of safe seeding for Cass Countv " r as noted to be almost at hand, the date of safe seed - ing for Douglas. Saunders, Colfax, and Buffalo Counties was announced for that day; then when it was announced for Arrangements were made to make dail </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 23 ( County on October 1, it was also announced for Seward ind Fillmore Counties; for Otoe County the date of October I was announced ; for Johnson and Furnas Counties, October &gt; ; and for Richardson County, October 3. The co-operating •ounty agents immediately notified the farmers in their coun - ies that it was now safe to go ahead and seed the winter .vheat as rapidly as possible without any fear of injury to by the Hessian Fly. The results of seeding on the announced safe dates have been checked up in several counties, from data secured in co - operation with the Federal Bureau of Entomology Laboratory at Wichita, Kansas. In Cass County wheat seeded September 17 was 27 per cent infested; that sown on September 24 was 2 1 per cert infested ; while that sown on October 1, 8, and 15 was absolutely free from infestation. In Richardson County, wheat seeded September 24 was 72 per cent infested ; that sown October 1 was 16 per cent infested ; while that sown on October 6 and 10 was absolutely free from infestation. In Fillmore County, wheat seeded September 19 was 19 per cent infested; that sown September 24 and 26 was 2 per cent in - fested, while that sown on October 1 and 8 was absolutely free from infestation. In Furnas County wheat seeded on September 29 and on October 2 and 8 was absolutely free om infestation. The co-operation of the farmers in the .arious counties varied from 70 per cent not seeding their .vheat until on or after the announced date of safe seeding. p to 95 per cent in Cass and Richardson Counties awaiting date of seeding. As a result, Hessian Fly damago the co-operating counties was relatively unimportant dur- ng the fall of 1923, while the counties that were not badly nough injured in the fall of 1922 and spring cf 1923 to be sted in the campaign became the more heavily infested untios in the fall of 1923. MVKSTCM'K FKKIHMi H&lt; it Cattle. Effect of (i(i&lt; upon rate and economy of gain. Four lots of 10 steers each, ranging in age from calves to 3 or 4-year-olds, inclusive, were put on feed October 31, 1922. The cattle were all of the same breed and were similar in duality. They were purchased from the Young ranch near Valentine, Nebraska. Each lot was fed for a period of 200 days upon a ration of shelled corn and alfalfa hay. The results concur closely with those secured in the 2 previous trials. All groups gained slightly over 2 1 -. pounds per day. The calves consumed much less feed than the older </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station cattle and made much more economical gains. They, like - wise, gained consistently thruout the period, while the older cattle gained rapidly at first and very slowly toward the close of the period. Baby Beef. Beginning November 17, 1922, six groups each containing 16 calves were fed for 175 days at the Ex - perimental Agronomy Farm, near Lincoln. The objects were to ascertain the advantages of using various rations; also to compare steer and heifer calves. Shelled com and alfalfa hay proved to be the cheapest and most profitable ration used. The addition of 1.1 pounds of lin - seed oil meal daily increased the gain and selling price, but decreased the profit. Oats returned a value below existing market price. Ground corn did not produce the finish that shelled corn did. Heifers gained more slowly than steers and sold for low price, hence showed less profit. Rations for Fattening Lamb were fed for 84 days commencii rations were used, shelled corn most profitable. The addition quantities increased the daily resultant lower profit. Adding c est gain, but. likewise, it was Ten lots of 30 lambs eac October 17, 1922. Varioi *nd alfalfa proving of linseed meal ii ?ain and cost jttonseed meal gave t\ the most expensive. prairie hay instead of alfalfa hay. with corn and lowered the rate of gain, increased the cost, and r this being the lowest profit lot. Rations for Fattening Hogs. Beginning F 1923, six groups of fall shotes averaging 110 ] fed for 70 days. There were 15 hogs per lot. Yellow corn and tankage gave better results than either white or mixed corn and tankage. Three hundred and seventy - one pounds of yellow corn and 41 pounds of tankage produced 100 pounds gain, while 393 pounds of white corn and 52 pounds of tankage were required to produce the same gain. It required 383 pounds of mixed corn and 51 pounds of tank - age to produce 100 pounds gain. Ground barley and tankacre produced the highest daily gains, but the most expensive gains, because of feed necessary to produce 100 pounds gain. It re - quired 454 pounds of ground barley and 50 pounds of tankage. The cost of 100 pounds gain with ground barley was $7.56. with yellow corn $6.16, with white corn $6.84, and with mixed corn $6.70. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 25 Beginning October 25, 1922, six lots of twelve pigs each were fed for 76 days. These pigs were raised on the United States Experimental Farm at McNeil, Mississippi, and shipped Lincoln for fattening. The trial consisted of a comparison of yellow and white corn. Yellow corn produced an average daily gain of 1.47 pounds, while white corn produced 1.36 pounds. To produce 100 pounds gain with yellow corn, 3.88 pounds of corn and 1.05 of tankage were consumed. With white corn it required 1.29 pounds of corn and 1.01 of tankage. On yellow corn the feed cost of 100 pounds gain was $6.25 and on white corn $6.45. Feed from Pasture. Work was commenced in the spring 1928 in testing the efficiency of sweet clover as pasture dairy cattle. Only a limited amount of data has been secured and the work is being continued. During the past year some work was done in a compari - of sudan grass and sweet clover as pasturage for beef ittle on full feed of com. In this season's work the sudan rass showed up very favorably in comparison with the sweet ind the work will be continued to obtain further evi- Mll.l.l\&lt;. AM) r.MvlM. QUALITIES OF \\ III \ I A survey of the Nebraska wheat crop of 1922, with respect chemical composition and baking quality, has been com - ted and the results tabulated and interpreted. This survey luded milling, baking, and chemical analyses of 112 samples »\vn origin and from different parts of the State. Samples Elected for a similar survey of the 1923 crop. n the material used in the survey of the 1922 crop lected 9 or 10 samples showing widely different char- it ic-s. These were subjected to a wide variety of chemi - i physical-chemical tests, in an effort to find any possible relationships between baking quality and chemical properties. Nearlv all of these tests resulted in negative correlations. A fairly close correlation between baking quality and water soluble ash was noted, however, the higher baking qualities being associated with the higher percentages of water soluble ash. Since the viscosities of acidified flour and water suspen - sions have been recently suggested as a valuable index to the colloidal properties of flour, and, since gluten quality is fre - quently said to be dependent on colloidal property, this de- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station partment has made and is making a rather detailed study of the relation of the baking qualities of Nebraska wheat flours to viscosities of their acidified suspensions in water. Enough evidence has been obtained to warrant the conclusion that for Nebraska wheats such relationship exists only within limited groups of samples grown under the same (or at least very similar) environmental conditions. Furthermore, we have noted a number of exceptions to the idea that high bak - ing quality is necessarily associated with high viscosity in the acidified flour and water suspension. Individual proteins are being prepared from flours o widely different baking qualities, with a view to comparinj some of their chemical and physical properties. Studies are in progress which have to do with th of aging on certain chemical and physical properties o and flour. M ii ITION Nutrient Requirements of Growing Chicks. Th undertakes to determine the effect of environ Comporatire Efficiency &lt;&gt;t Feeding. This is a study of when various proteins are fed Various P P the actual nit at varving pla chickens. The nitrogen retention is established by determin ing the nitrogen elimination on a nitrogen free diet and apply ing this figure as a correlation to the figure obtained from th&lt; determination of total nitrogen elimination when knowT amounts of protein are fed. A considerable amount of data bearing on the nitrogen elimination of chickens on a nitrogen free diet have been published in a preliminary paper entitled "The Endogenous Metabolism of Hens and Capons," which w r as recently pub - lished in "Poultry Science." Data are now accumulating with reference to nitrogen retention when the source of nitrogen is restricted to the proteins of corn. tions, — especially the influence of sunlight, on the p and cure of rickets in chicks. It is observed that chicks on a standard ration exposed for an average of less than an hour daily unfiltered sunlight are developing normalh . where exposed to sunlight which has passed thru commoi glass develop rachitic symptoms. It is supposed that the ultra-violet rays, which a out when sunlight passes thru common glass, are 1 agents which influence calcium and phosphorous ass i ' • t ea &gt;n in 1)i sii </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 27 Studies of Fat Soluble A Present in the Milk of Different Dm, a llrt nls. The purpose of this investigation is to deter - mine whether or not Fat Soluble A is present and to the same amount in the milk of the principal dairy breeds, in - cluding: Holstein, Jersey, Guernsey, and Ayrshire. The method involves the development of a considerable ny of rats of the same breeding, which will have received tome time a basal ration in which Fat Soluble A is ab- When the weight growth of these rats shows that the Fat Soluble A in the body has been utilized and the weight is decreasing, then different pens of rats will be fed the milk ht&gt; different dairy breeds and in varying amounts, in to determine not only the presence of Fat Soluble A 1 lilk, but the quantity of milk to give sufficient Fat \ so that the rats will resume normal growth. The s not yet progressed sufficiently for a report to be I'l.ANT niSKASKS Studies nt Stem Rust. This project is a study of the en - &gt;nmental conditions influencing the development of stem st of wheat in the absence of the barberry. During the .st 1 years a detailed study of 2 biologic forms of Puccinia i tritiri was undertaken to determine whether or not action on the differential hosts remained consistent inder various environmental factors. At the same time the nfluence of environmental conditions on the growth of the iifferential hosts and on the disease was determined. The factors controlled in this investigation were soil tern- are, soil moisture, air temperature, and relative humid- ity. Sunlight was a variable factor, but the total hours of sunlight was recorded during the experiments. It was found that the general type of infection of a bio - c form on a differential host could not be changed: 1, by any of the environmental factors to which the differential host and biologic form were submitted ; 2, by the source of the inoculum ; or 3, by the source of the seed of the different - ial hosts. The differential hosts at the various stages of growth from seedling to heading occurred at 15 and 20" C. Temperatures of 10 below resulted in a slow growth, while temperatures of 25 and 30 C. inhibited the growth of the plants. The optimum temperature for the development of the disease at all stages of growth was between 20° and 25° C. In general it might be said that the temperatures at which the plants id&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station 28 make their best growth are generally the same as those at which the best development of the disease takes place. A progress report of this phase of the project has been published as Research Bulletin No. 25 of the Agricultural Experiment Station. Fusarium Wilt and St( m-End Rot of Potato. Fusariunt emruirtii is the cause of potato wilt and stem-end rot in Ne - braska. The disease causes a reduction in germination, an increase in the number of barren plants, and a high percent - age of stem-end rotted tubers. Infection occurs chiefly from the soil rather than from the seed. Infected seed does result in an increase of disease due to seed rotting in the ground and the production of weak plants more susceptible to infection from the soil, either thru roots or seed piece. The organism produces a toxic substance, capable of killing the host tissue in advance of the organism. The optimum temperature for the disease is 20 -24 C. Soil moistures favorable for the host are favorable for infection. After infection occurs, wilt- ing is favored by low soil moisture, while tuber infection favored by increased moisture. The only practical cont is the prevention of the disease by use of healthy seed ; long rotations. Effect of Environment &lt;&gt;» Potato Degenerwi The mosaic diseases of potatoes result in dec with all forms of the disease but only slightl mosaic." Combinations of mosaic and spindlt the most serious losses. Mosaic symptoms are masked at mean temperatures a 70 F., and are increasingly evident as the temperature d The effect of temperature decreases with the age of the ] and the severity of the disease. High sunlight inter low moisture are also correlated with the masking id- toms. Such masking makes it impossible to det&lt; amount of disease present in the fields under certain condi - tions often present in Nebraska. This is probably a greater factor than insect transmission in the yearly increase of the disease. The planting of representative samples of all certi - fied seed under conditions favorable for the disease is neces - sary in making estimates of the amount of disease present. POT^TOKS Potato Selection. This project has been continued since 1919. Some of the results secured during the first 3 year 1 ; have been presented in Experiment Station Bulletin 182. This </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 29 work is being conducted at the several State Stations and on the farms of a number of co-operators. It has included a study of several of the most promising varieties under differ - ent conditions in Nebraska. A large number of strains of most of these varieties have been planted for comparative trial purposes for the purpose of determining the variation exist - ing within varieties and to determine to what extent the vari - ous diseases are prevalent in Nebraska seed stocks. During the 1923 season approximately 110 lots of potatoes were as - sembled from that many growers in western Nebraska. These lots were grown in comparative trial plats. The results secured show that some farmers were planting potatoes which produced as low as 15 bushels per acre of U. S. No. 1 grade potatoes, whereas other farmers were raising potatoes of the same varieties which were capable of producing practically 400 bushels per acre of the same potatoes under the same snowing conditions. The importance of developing some means of eliminating these poor strains and replacing them with the superior strains is quite apparent. Similar trials were conducted during the past years on a less extensive scale but with similar results. Seed Potato Certification. In view of these great differ - ences found in various lots of potatoes during the period that this project has been in force, a system of seed potato inspec- tion and certification has been developed for the purpose of locating the best lots of seed and organizing a system of pro - cedure to encourage the improvement of these better lots. During the past year 121 fields of potatoes with an area of 2.419 acres and a production of approximately 200,000 bushels marketable potatoes were certified for seed purposes. During a 5-year period, which was concluded in the sum - mer of 1923, thru co-operation with the Bureau of Plant In - dustry and Experiment Stations located in 4 southern states, co-operative tests have been conducted of certified seed po - tatoes grown in this state as well as in other states which produce Triumph seed potatoes. In all of these southern trial plats the Nebraska lots of potatoes have consistently been quite superior. A very extensive demand now exists in all of the Gulf Coast states for western Nebraska certified seed potatoes, largely because of their relative freedom from the mosaic disease, which is one of the most serious factors affect - ing the early Triumph potato industry in the south. During the 1923 season potatoes from every lot of potatoes which was certified in Nebraska were planted in a trial plat at the Louisiana Experiment Station for the purpose of de- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station termining the efficiency of the certification service and to supply advance information which would be of value during the current season in Nebraska. A similar comparative trial plat was planted at an early date in western Nebraska. This feature of the work is being continued in 1924. By this means the certification work is considerably strengthened. The effect of the size of seed piece and distance of plant - ing under various climatic conditions is also under study. Degeneracy in Potatoes. Summarization of some of th work done so far on this subject is presented in Experimen ner Station Research Bulletin No. 24. The conclusions t\ a been drawn are as follow The soil and climatic conditions in the high a'.titud of western Nebraska are suitable for the product perpetuation of high-yielding seed potatoes. Many lots from isolated fields in the newe growing sections are relatively free from t\ This type of degeneracy causes very aerie tubev yields till eventually no marketable tuber Seed stocks produced on dry land at the highes proved to be superior in point of quality and yield produced, when planted in comparative trials. Rt'RAI. ECONOMICS Farm Management Survey. The principal study in this proiect is the effect of diversity of business i income. During the past vear about 80 addition records were obtained from Scotts Bluff Countv. volved laboi farm Tuber line studies with numerous lots of differ* ties revealed early and late maturing strains as well of degeneracy very similar to, or identical with. " tuber" (recently described by Schulz and Folson degeneracy manifests itself by a stiff, upright habit r and by an elongation of the tubers. Strains .irt»&gt;&lt; never recover, but become progressively weaker. The degeneracy most common in western Nel perpetuated thru the tubers and appears to Ix tn from plant to plant in the field. Irrigation produces conditions more conducive to increase of this degeneracy than dry land culture cent of the degeneracy increasing and the yield d with each additional year of irrigation. This type of degeneracy has been studied in 10 varieties. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 31 Pr&lt;xtnrin(f Beef Cattlt . This projest is co-opera - i the College and the U. S. Department of Agricul- ( 4 years' work has now been obtained. The data are direct from farmers upon cattle fed in the usual A final report is expected within the present year. mi* This work is carried on as a survey in al communities. During the past year the follow - itions have been made: n ISO, Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes. n 18"), The Nebraska Farm Family. Hi tin 191, Nebraska Farm Homes, tin 196, Nebraska Farm Tenancy. Product ion of Farm Crop*. This work is con- co-operation with the farmers. Record blanks are on which the farmers keep an accurate record of of producing the various farm crops. The attempt in the number of hours of both horse and man labor, han the value of the labor. /' hosing Power of Nebraska Grains. During the past llotin 187 was issued on this subject. In this bulletin dered the relative purchasing power of wheat, corn, s, at a given point in Nebraska for the past 45 years. purchasing power was taken as the year 1913. An - luscript on factors affecting the price of farm pro - lmost complete. n La ml Pmbh m. This projest is being carried in co - n with the U. S. Department of Agriculture. During A year the gathering of basic data on land price was ly completed. Further investigation on farm mort - d taxation is being carried forward. skkim puonriTiox The same policy of buying and retesting serum that has 'act iced for the past 2 or 3 years has been continued. ict as it has proved to be very satisfactory. The demand for serum from the State Serum Plant has been very heavy dur - ing the late summer and early fall months, but all orders were filled promptly and a sufficient reserve was on hand at all times. All virus put out by the State Serum Plant was pro - duced by it with the exception of a small quantity which was purchased to meet a rather sudden heavy demand. Particular pains have been taken with the virus produced, in order thai: </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station a pure, fresh, virulent virus may be sent out, as that is the key to successful immunization. Judging from the amount of serum issued, there were ap - parently not as many pigs vaccinated in June this year as in 1922 ; but as the outbreak of cholera was more serious in the late summer and fall months, it caused more vaccinating than perhaps otherwise would have been done, and as the pigs were larger by that time more serum was required to vaccinate them, consequently the heavy demand for serum came at that time. Serum sold for 90 cents per hundred c. c. until June 6. 1923, when the price was reduced to 80 cents per hundred c. c. Virus sold for $1.25 per hundred c. c. thruout the year. The following is a complete report of the activities of tht plant for the year beginning January 1, 1924: January 1, 1923, and closing Serum on hand January 1, 1923 Serum bought and paid for taring 1 1,110.635 c. i H."ii1.2imi &lt;■. « 1 1' Total.- Serum and virus sold, by months, as follows: Virus Serum January _ 21,104 c. e. February l",i&gt;5(i o. &lt;• March ._ _ 1M7« r. «• April __.... _ 9,980 c. c. May 24.380 c. c. June _ _ _ _ 88,910 c. c. July _ _ 77. sou c. c August _ _ltl.(4fl r. ' Septemb€r _ 122.250 c. r. October _ itt.iiln e. e. November 47,21" c. &lt;■. December 41.280 c. c. Serum used by Plant .ip'i.tinii &lt;-. r 183.0(111 c. c. ■ ■ , , I»i4.:: 4»n.r. 1.H17.:: •■ &lt;•. S,93i,20Q c. c. Z,CS«.57ti c. c. 2,OOti.2OG iv , 815,35" &lt; , 7112.750 c. o. I'l-'J'.-.II C. C Total __ _.699,070 c. c. 1 i-:.:r,\,2--.'&lt; c. c. Serum or. hand January 1, 1!I24 _ Collections from all sources __ Total expenditures _ _ _ _ Money in revolving fund January 1, 1924 Inventory and other assets Number of pifts used in retesting serum Number of pigs used for simultaneous virui Number of pigs on hand January 1, 1924 Number of orders for 1923 1,353,605 c. n. $12S »».] 122.564.9 — 54.761.1 lfi. 640.0 77 74 ..._ 25 ...._ 3.13 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 33 NOKTH PLATTE SI B.STATIOX Experiments with Hogs. During the winter of 1922-23 iwo lots of 10 pigs each were fed on white corn and tankage, against two similar lots on yellow corn and tankage and two other similar lots on yellow corn, white corn, and tankage. Alfalfa hay was fed in racks to all lots. Self-feeders were used. The daily gain on white corn was 1.61 pounds; on ellow corn, 1.58 pounds; and on a combination of white and el low com, 1.63 pounds. The corn and tankage required for 100 pounds gain for the first group was 340.4 pounds ; for the second group, 338.9 pounds, and for the third group, 347.9 |K&gt;unds. In the summer of 1923 for a period of 60 days (with fif- een 80-pound pigs in each lot) tests were made on relative alue of white and yellow com for pigs running on sudan miss pasture. Self-feeders were used for the com. The iaily gain per pig in the lot receiving white corn was 1.28 &gt;ounds and in the lot receiving yellow ccrn, 1.30 pounds. Three hundred eighty-one and nine-tenths pounds of white corn and 102.2 pounds of yellow corn were required to produce 100 pounds gain. In the comparison of sudan grass and alfalfa as pasturage nd a ration of yellow corn, hogs on alfalfa showed greater gain. The daily gain on alfalfa pasture was 1.51 pounds, and for pigs on sudan grass 1.30 pounds. The corn required for 100 pounds gain was 359.3 pounds with alfalfa and 402.2 IMiunds with sudan. In other tests where the sudan grass was allowed to make sufficient growth to make cutting for hay ■cessary the sows lost weight after the sudan was cut. In a test of sudan grass pasture, yellow corn, and tankage, as compared with the same ration without tankage, the daily gains per pig were 1.54 and 1.30, respectively. Dairy Cattle. During the past year all grade dairy cows were sold from the herd, leaving a purebred Holstein herd, consisting of 25 cows and heifers producing milk and 26 younger females. The average production of these cows (30) finishing a lactation period in the 12-months period ending June 20, 1922, was 10,781 pounds milk and 462 pounds butter. For the year ending June 30, 1923, thirty cows produced 12,231 pounds milk and 532 pounds butter. A mature cow in the herd, Rag Apple Blaske, in a 2-day test gave 5.76 pounds of butterfat. In a 10-months test as Junior 3-year-old, she made 449.97 pounds of butter and 10.885 pounds of milk. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station ! Tests to determine the effect of feeding silage or not feed - ing silage to dairy cows receiving grain and alfalfa hay were continued during the winter of 1922-23. Two lots of cow. - were fed silage (or no silage with an extra portion of com to replace the corn which would have been in the silage) dur - ing five 20-day periods, with 10-day periods intervening. Dur ing the periods while on silage rations, the cows gained :&gt;&lt; pounds in weight; gave 1,444 pounds milk containing 50.11 pounds butterfat, while on the ration containing no silage they lost 12.6 pounds in weight and produced 1,474.5 pounds milk containing 53.15 pounds of butterfat. Poultry Plant. A poultry plant containing 1.0(M) \ maintained at this Station; 3 breeds, namelv. Single Oats on fall plowing produced H:&gt;.7 bushel comparison with 52.1 bushels per acre on spr The average gain in favor of fall plowing for th period is 1.3 bushels per acre. The benefits of practices which maintain fertility apparent in years like the present when moisture is plentifu In 7 rotations, in which bamyurd manure, green manu sod crops were used, the average yield was 5S.5 bushels pt acre. In 15 rotations in which no manures or sod crops wet used, the average corn yield was 1 1.4 bushels per acre. Th gain for the more fertile plats was thus 9.1 bushels per acn Rhode Island Reds, Haired Plymouth Rocks, and Single Com White Leghorns, are kept. No experimental work u reported Horticulture. Some work of a demonstration characte in varieties of apples, cherries, and plums is undertaken. Th orchards are now of bearing age and have produced considei able fruit. Several acres of forestry plantations were set ou about 12 and 17 years ago. A report of the growth of th different varieties will soon be made. Field Crops. Field crops work has Ween continued alon the same general lines as previous years. Much of the wor is in co-operation with the V. S. Department of Agricultur and this has been extended thru additional help to includ small grain breeding and improvement. The grow mg seaso of 1923 was unusually favorable for practically all crops e&gt; cept winter wheat, which was seriously injured by an epidemi of rust. The average yield of corn in one of the crop rot; tion fields, upon which accurate records have been kept fo 17 years, was 47.3 bushels per acre. This is 11. « bushel above the 17-year average and 13.1 bushels above the higher previous record. •i r &gt;i x ;i i •I a </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 35 In (i vears Kanred has yielded above Turkey Red 3 times d below Turkey Red 3 times. Its average yield is 1.1 bushels r acre above Turkey Red. In the oats variety test the ghest yield was made by Burt which yielded 83.1 bushels t acre. The next highest yield was 5 bushels less, made Kherson. The average yield of 5 early varieties was 74.7 ishols per acre and of 3 late varieties 50.6 bushels per acre. of corn varieties the highest yield was 63.6 bushels made by Red Flour. The flour varieties yielded ushels per acre more than the dent varieties. he dates-of-seeding test of 4 spring grains, — wheat, irley, and rye, — each seeded on 4 different dates, the yields were secured in all cases from the second date ?ding which was made on April 9. The first date of ■eding, made on March 29, produced the second highest elds. The yields from April 21 and April 30 seedings were IMON KltriT KAKM tisfactory progress was made with the work along this he purpose of which is to determine some practical i of fruit production on a commercial basis. The 40- hard at Union is being used in this experiment. This was planted in the spring of 1918 to 9 commercial ics. Twenty acres of this orchard is divided into 5 at right angles with the varieties. The entire 20 acres ded to clover in 1919 in order to make soil conditions The entire orchard was cropped to corn in 21. In 1922 one plat was given clean cultivation, another Itivated to soy beans drilled in rows, and the remaining mted to corn. this orchard not included in the cultural ) ac ginally set with "fillers" of early maturing varie- \\ The object of this method of planting is to compare the is from the filler trees with the returns from the farm &gt;ps from the other 20 acres. Measurements are being taken each year of all the trees, inning with the spring of 1923, certain blocks will be iven particular cultural treatments, including clover crops, lean culture, inter-crops, and fertilization with manure. VAI. i:\TI\K SI "IISTATION Trie year 1923 entered with the subsoil very dry, having &gt;een depleted during the dry weather of the previous late ;ummer and fall. The total precipitation of the growing &gt;wer than from the earlier seedings. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station season was 2 l _&gt; inches below normai. Its distribution, how - ever, was favorable for such crops as corn and forage. Forage Crops. The average yield of 11 sorghum varieties was 6,275 pounds of forage per acre. The saccharine (sweet) sorghums averaged 565 pounds more forage per acre than the non-saccharine (grain) group. Sudan grass produced about one-half the yield of forage that cane did and about two-thirds that of corn. Planting in rows and cultivating gave a slight increase over drilling. Seven acres of sudan grass furnished pasture for 12 winter calves, 3 sows, and 18 spring pigs for a period of 2 months. Siberian millet outyielded common and Proso varieties Silage Crops. Corn produced 3 tons of ensilage, sun flowers 3.3 tons, and amber cane 5 tons per acre. The flov of milk was decreased about 10 per cent from heavy-produc - ing cows immediately following the change to sunflower silage Sunflowers must be cut early in this localitv to avoid the los of leaves from blight or rust Grain Crops. White flint corn gave a yield &lt; per acre. The local dent corn gave 35 bushels pel are the highest yields ever obtained on the uj Station. i Winter wheat varieties gave a yield of 2.5 to 10 per acre. Rosen rye gave 1 bushel per acre more 1 mon rye and 5 bushels per acre more than Kanred, est yielding winter wheat. In the following tabular statement is a comparisoi yields obtained on the upland at the Station farm harder loam land on the table north of town : Oats { 4 varieties Barley, Common Emmer — i» V 4 Rye bu. per A t Spring wheat (3 varietie A Annual Legumes. Soybeans made a good growth but the yield was low on account of a poor stand. Ito San and Manchu have matured for the past 3 years with an average yield of 8 bushels per acre. Spring vetch sown with rye was not satisfactory, due to insufficient moisture it obtained when competing with rye. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 37 A study of clover and alfalfa production in the wet val - leys has been undertaken during the past year to determine the proper depth of water table for the satisfactory produc - tion of alfalfa and clovers; also methods of soil preparation and seeding and the fluctuation in the height of the water table. SOmSBLVKK SI BSTAT1ON The weather conditions for the season of 1923 were not entirely favorable. The spring opened early with plenty of moisture in the soil. A freeze on May 16 did severe damage, especially to beets, necessitating the replanting of a large acreage. The total rainfall from April 1 to October 1 was 16.6 inches, — considerably above the average. There were several heavy downpours that caused considerable damage by soil washing. The fall freeze was earlier than usual and caused considerable loss in potatoes that were not yet dug. Field Crops. The work of the past season bears out re - sults obtained in previous years, an outstanding feature being the increased yield from the inclusion of alfalfa or sweet lover in a rotation or the use of barnyard manure. The ollowing table shows the average of yields obtained for the st vear Yields on an (ten basis from crops gron-n in rotation ex - imi ntx showing effect of manure, alfalfa, and sweet clover &gt;f different crops for the season 1923. Sweet In- Alfalfa clover nured Manured Alfalfa manure pastured Potatoes.... Itn. 74.4 117.0 154.5 / Oats Iln. 45.8 69.3 67.1 Wheat Kii. 7.4 S.£ As an average for 12 years' work those rotations contain - ing alfalfa, sweet clover, or barnyard manure have been profitable. The rotations not containing one of these have been unprofitable. The use of commercial fertilizers has not materially influenced yield, indicating that the increased yields resulted from the increased organic and nitrogen content of the soil. &gt;8 18.83 16.95 19.21 18.50 2 60.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Pastures. Some further work was done during the season on the effect of manure on the carrying capacity of tame grass pastures. In a comparison including no manure, 10 tons per acre annually, and 20 tons annually, the pasture receiving the applications of manure had twice the carrying capacity of the one not receiving manure. Lambs were used in this pas - ture experiment. Sweet Clorii ami .Xatir, Ptuture. In this lest :&gt; lots o 25 steers each were pastured, — one on sweet clover alone, on on native grass alone, and one on sweet clover plus coin, giv ing first a comparison of native grass and sweet clover am second, some information on the possibilities of fattenir cattle on sweet clover pasture by coin feeding. All the stee were 3-year-olds and averaged ToT pounds per head at beginning of the test. The corn ration for the lot r corn was increased until they were receiving 20 pour corn per head per day. At the end of the period th IK weight of the steers was 1,040 for the corn and swt 971 for sweet clover alone, and 1,012 for those on native pasture. The steers were all shipped to Omaha ar weighed there in the older named. — 1,012, 8&lt;&gt;0 pounds, the greatest shrinkage being on th« sweet clover alone. The total i pounds for corn and sweet clover, 13 and 225 for native grass past tinued during the following y&lt; i Lamb Feeding Experiments. Di of lambs were fed on various rations. This season's v is completes 3 years' work along this line and is summariz* and published in Bulletin No. 194 of the Agricultural I ment Station. Further work is contemplated Hogs — Summer vs. Winter Finishing. A test winter finishing and summer finishing of fall farrowed was conducted with 4 lots of 10 shotes each. The cost of LOO pounds of gain was $7.74 for those finished in the winter and $6.88 for those finished in the summer. The market value per hundred was $6.50 for the winter-finished hogs and $8.40 for the summer-finished. Those finished in the winter gav a loss of $3.00 per head, while those finished on pasture in the summer made a profit of $3.08 per head. Self-Feeder Compared with Limited Fiat ion*. For a period of 136 days 2 lots of hogs consisting of 37 head each were run on alfalfa pasture. Both lots received rations of corn </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 39 and barley, one lot being fed from a self-feeder where they had a continual supply of grain, the others receiving an amount of grain equal to 2 per cent of their live weight. During the 136-day period the lot on the self-feeder made a total gain of 4,095 pounds. Those on a 2 per cent ration made a gain of 2,995 pounds. The cost of the grain fed for the lot on the self-feeder was $262.55 ; for the lot on 2 per cent ration, $155.84. Figuring the gain at $7.15 per hundred the lot on the self-feeder showed an average loss of 25 cents per hog. while those on limited ration showed a profit of 50 cents per ho^ Compmriton of Tankage and Alfalfa Hay for Feeding Hogs. In a 57-day test 2 lots of hogs containing 35 each were fed, one lot receiving corn and tankage, the other lot corn and alfalfa hay. During the period the lot on corn and tankage made a total gain of 2,210 pounds and the lot on corn and alfalfa 1,645 pounds. The cost of 100 pounds of gain was $6.7K for the corn and tankage and $6.72 for the corn and alfalfa. Bulletin No. 187. Purchasing Power of Nebraska Grains. By H. C. Fillev and E. A. Frerichs. March, 1923. 7,000 copies. Bulletin No. 188. Productive Seed Corn. By T. A. Kiesselbach April, 15(2:',. 10.000 copies. Bulletin No. 18fl. Some New Hybrid Strawberries. By R. F Howard and C. C. Wiggans. April, 1923. 4,000 copies. Bulletin No. 190. Crop Rotation Under Irrigation. By James A Holden. April. 1923. 5,000 copies. chamjkk in station stakf Mr i! \\ Dawson. Assistant in Entomology, resigned May :'. 1, 3. Mr. J. A. Luithly, Associate in Dairy Husbandry, resigned June 1 41 •&gt; " 1923 Mr \V H. Savin, Assistant in Animal Husbandry, resigned July 1923 Mr. V A. Downi was appointed Associate in Dairy Husbandry us! 1. 1!I2I{. Mr. H. D Fox was appointed Assistant in Animal Husbandry ember 1, 1823. Mr. E. O. Andersen was appointed Assistant in Dairy Husbandrv nat 1. 1922. ITBMCATIONS The publication! of the Station since those named in the last ual Report are as follows: Thirty-sixth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor February •»23. 2,000 copies. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin No. 191. Nebraska Farm Homes: A comparison of souk living conditions of owners, part-owners, and tenants. By J. O. Rankin May, 1923. 4.000 copies. Bulletin No. 192. Dry Farming Investigations at Soottsbluff Sub station. By L. L. Zook. July, 1923. 4,000 copies Bulletin No. 193. Sixteen Years' Grain Production at the Nortl Platte Substation. By L. L. Zook and W. W. Burr. July. 192:1 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 194. Lamb Feeding Experiments in Western \i braska. By James A. Holden. August. 1923. 5.000 copies. Bulletin No. 19 5. The More Important Poultry Diseases. B L. Van Es and H. M. Martin. October. 1923. 10.000 copie Bulletin No. !!•♦&gt;. Nebraska Farm Tenancy: Some co poniin phases. By J. O. Rankin. October. 1923. 5,000 copies. Bulletin No. 197. Winter Lamb Feeding: 1919-20. 1920-21 22. By W. H. Savin. October. 1923. 5,000 copie Competition as a Source of Experimental Krror in Corn Y Tests. By T. A. Kiesselbuch. Jour. &gt;air Soc. Agron. January is Endogenous Metabolism of Hens and Capons. By c W .\^k^ man, M. J. Blish. and F. E. Mussehl, Poultry Science, Vol. II. St-ptei ber. 1923. ACKXOW l,KIXi&gt;IK\TS The agricultural press and the daily and weekly newspapers, especially those papers located within the state, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Station by giving liberal space to experimental work reported and in every way facilitating the extension of useful agricultural knowledge. Bulletin No. 198. Factors Affecting the Price of Farm Prod' By H. C. Filley. November. 1923. 5,000 copies Research Bulletin No. 2 1 S^ed Potato Investigations By Ii Werner and R. F. Howard. December. 192:!. 5,000 copies se 'sir 'rod Research Bulletin No. 25. A Study of the Environmental Ct tions Influencing ihe Development of Stem Itust in the Absence n Alternate Host. II. Infection Studies with Humuiti yramini* tritii -i. I III and Fonn IX. By Georsp L. Peltier. December, 1923. 3,000 00 il ) r Experiment Station Circular No. 20. The Plains False Wirew and Its Control. Dy M. H. Swenk. July. 192:: I,*M copies Experiment Station Circular No. 21. The Abortion Problen Farm Live Stock. By L. Van Ks. September. 192:! 10. 0M em Experiment Station Circular No. 22 Ice Cream Ingredients. H. P. Davis. Benjamin Masnrovsky. and John A. I.uithly. Jam 1924. 5.000 copies AKT14I.K* IN KK*KAK&lt; II M&gt;lll\\l&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 41 THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA I IWVriAl STATEMENT OK MONEY RECEIVED FROM THK l.MTED STATES GOVERNMENT HATCH FUND !:«■. ,-i|.i&gt; ■d by the State Treasurer, who is also the treasurer &lt;• (Diversity of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal ended June 30, 1923, under act of Congress &amp;d- i by the State Treasurer, wno is also the treasurer ■ University of Nebraska, installment for the fiscal ended June 30, 1923, under act of Congress, ap - •d March 16. 1906. Total _ $15,000.00 Expenditure Ko $15,000.00 T $15,000.00 L. E. GUNDERSON, At Lincoln, N'ebrask January 26, 1924. Finance Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station FIXAXOIAIi STATKMK.XT OK MOMKY RKCKIVKD FROM THK STATK OK N Kim ASK A Statement of expenditures for the Agricultural Experiment Station of the University of Nebraska by accounting classification units, and from all State funds' (exclusive of Federal funds). MATERIALS, PARTS AND REPAIRS FOR UPKEEI Buildings $ 4.249.0 Grounds II Autos and trucks II Upkeep of property Total S 8.271 S.i SALARIES AND WAGES Regular employes _$61, 726.89 Temporary employes - 1,548.39 Fees, claims, etc 63.22 Total - $ 63,338 SUPPLIES Office supplies $ 926..!? Laboratory supplies 4,479.7« Fuel ... 1,528.43 Food 1,452.03 Educational supplies 296.23 Janitor supplies 238.95 Feed _ 2X.436.58 Agricultural supplies 1.539.92 Total I 38.898 EXPENSE Office expense and postage $ 235.67 Telephone and telegraph Freight, express and drayage Water, heat, light and power Publishing, printing and advertising 251.09 938.59 2.981.31 K. 406 41 Traveling expense t.MS.SS Miscellaneous 16,632.38 Total $ 30,441 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Thirty-Seventh Annual Report 43 FINANCIAL STATKMKXT — Continued MEN fixturt 571.83 4,020.40 17,142.58 7,129.06 289.20 $ 29,553.07 Buildin 5,634.91 Tot * 8.270.34 ED CHARGES is and r* Total $ 7.50 * 7.50 Grand Total $178,780.24 jdes expenditures for and the substations the central station at the Agricul - at Scottsbluff, North Platte, and L. E. GUNDERSON, Finance Secretary. Ni-braska, 1924. I2M1 \DS AND BUILDINGS $ 2,635.43 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>