<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00068.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1930-06-30">1930-06-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Biennial Report OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE OF THE State of Nebraska FOR TWENTY-FOUR MONTHS ENDING JUNE 30, 1930. Frank Marsh, Secretary of State TO THE GOVERNOR </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Office of Secretary of State Lincoln, Nebraska Jane 30, 1930. To the Honorable, The Governor, Arthur J. Weaver, State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. My Dear Governor: Conforming to the statutes of the Commonwealth, I have the honor to present herewith, my report as Secretary of State, for the State of Nebraska, for the twenty-four months ending June 30, 1930. This report contains an exhibit of the affairs of the office and the method of conducting same during the term now closing. It also sets forth the amount of moneys expended by this depart - ment, a classified statement of all moneys received by the office as fees. It further sets forth a statement of the number of corporations incorporating, qualifying, withdrawing or dissolving, the registration of trade marks and trade names; the registration and renewal of stock brands, the granting of charters .to chattel loan, organizations under the provisions of Section 2846, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1922, and a report of the Board of Pardons. In the interests of economy, we have abridged the report as much as possible, eliminating several features that heretofore have been embodied, which would increase the cost of publication, and are. m themselves not of vital public interest. Respectfully submitted, FRANK MARSH, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE SECRETARIES OF STATE Territorial 1. Thomas B. Cuming, August 23, 1854, to March 12, 1858. 2. J. Sterling Morton, July 12, 1858, to May 6, 1861. 3. Algernon S. Paddock, May 6, 1861 to Feb. 21, 1867. State 4. Thomas P. Kennard, from Feb. 21, 1867, to Jan. 10, 1871. 5. Wm. H. James, from Jan. 10, 1871, to Jan. 12, 1873. Acting Governor, from June 2, 1871 to Jan. 13, 1873. 6. John J. Gosper, from Jan. 13, 1873, to Jan. 11, 1875. 7. Bruno Tzschuck, from Jan. 11, 1875, to Jan. 9, 1879. 8. S. J. Alexander, from Jan. 9, 1879, ta Jan. 4, 1883. '•■ 9. Edward P. Roggen, from Jan. 4, 1882, to Jan. 6, 1887. 10. Gilbert L. Laws, from Jan. 6, 1887, to Nov. 20, 1889. Resigned to fill unexpired term in Congress caused by the death of James Laird. . . ■ 11. Benjamin R. Cowdry, from Nov. 20, 1889, to Jan. 8, 1891. Appointed by Governor Thayer to fill vacancy caused by resig - nation of Gilbert L. Laws. 12. John C. Allen, from Jan. 8, 1891, to Jan. 3, 1895. 13. Joel A. Piper, from Jan. 3, 1895 to Jan. 7, 1897. 14. William F. Porter, from Jan. 7, 1897, to Jan. 3, 1901. 15. George W. Marsh, from Jan. 3, 1901, to Jan. 6, 1905. 16. A. Galusha, from Jan. 6, 1905, to Jan. 3, 1907. 17. Geo. C. Junkin, from Jan. 3, 1907, to Jan. 5, 1911. 18. Addison Wait, from Jan. 5, 1911, to Jan. 7, 1915. 19. Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 7, 1915, to Jan. 9, 1919. 20. Darius M. Amsberry, from Jan. 9, 1919, to Jan. 4, 1923. 21. Charles W. Pool, from Jan. 4, 1923 to Jan. 6, 1927. 22. Frank Marsh, from Jan. 6, 1927, to — </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THR-J5HORETARTv.aF STATE" STATE OFFICERS CURING BIENNIUM "1929-1931. Arthur J. Weaver, Governor : .Palls City Geo. A. Williams, Lieutenant Governor :.....-....Fairmont Frank Marsh, Secretary of. State ...:...Norfolk- ■■ L. B. Johnson, Auditor . ..... Omaha' Dan Swanson, Commissioner of Public Lands &amp; Bldgs •..•i.Fremorit W. M. Stebb.ins, Treasurer i Gothenburg C. A. Sorensen, Attorney General .Lincoln John H. Miller, Railway Commissioner '.Newman Grove John E. Curtiss, Railway Commissioner.. Geneva Charles W. Taylor, State Superintendent Lincoln, . UNITED STATES SENATORS George W. Norris .".McCook 1925-1931 R. B. Howell ........: ....Omaha 1929-1935 •"■'■• ■ . CONGRESSMEN John H. Morehead .Falls City .....First District Willis G. Sears Omaha Second District Edgar Howard Columbus Third District Charles H. Sloan... Geneva Fourth District Fred G. Johnson Hastings Fifth District Robert G. Simmons .....Scottsbluff Sixth District ADMINISTRATIVE BOARDS . Of Which the Secretary of State is a Member. Board of Equalization and Assessment. Board of Educational Lands and Funds. Board of Canvassers. Board of Pardons and Paroles. Board of Depository Bonds. OFFICE FORCE OF THE DEPARTMENT OF STATE Frank Marsh, Secretary ..Norfolk G. B. Thomas, Deputy:. Omaha Pauline Hill, Corporation Clerk. Lincoln Clare M, Sellers, Bookkeeper.. .Hastings Roberta Johnson, Recording Clerk.... .Omaha Lydia Hill, Stenographer. Lincoln Lydia Schessler, Extra Clerk . Seward </seg>
            <seg id="p006">REPORT OP THE SECRETARY OP STATE CORPORATION DEPARTMENT The following: tablie sets forth the number of articles of incor - poration, amendments to articles of incorporation, appointment of agents, dissolutions, etc., handled during the past twenty-four months: Total number of domestic corporations registered , 4,467 Number domestic corporations incorporated during biennium.... 995 Number domestic corporations filing amendments 332 Number domestic corporations voluntarily dissolving 251 Number domestic corporations dissolved for non-payment of .taxes 441 Foreign Corporations ■ &gt; " Total number foreign corporations registered .. 820 Number foreign corporations qualified during biennium..... 304 Number amendments to appointments filed... 122 Number foreign corporations voluntarily withdrawing 116 Number foreign corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes 32 Non-Profit Corporations Total number non-profit corporations registered &#132;. 821 Number non-profit corporations incorporated during biennium 97 Number non-profit corporations filing amendments 94 Number non-profit corporations voluntarily dissolving 21 Number non-profit corporations dissolved for non-payment of taxes . 41 Grand Total all -corporations, domestic, foreign and non-profit engaged m business at. this date m Nebraska 6,108 TRADE MARKS Total Number of Trade Marks 1,188 Number of Trade Marks filed during Biennium 221 STOCK BRANDS This department is charged with the assignment and registration of brands used for the purpose of marking live stock, as by the statutes so provided. The year 1927 was the year m which all stock brands were required to be renewed. This renewal comes but once m five years, and the year 1927 being the five year period since 1922, all stock brand owners were renewing accordingly. A summary of the business for the past twenty-four months. is as follows: Total number of brands registered ....: , 8,798 Number of brands issued during past two years 1,877 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OP THE SECRETARY OP STATE FINANCIAL STATEMENT This office collects fees for filing articles of incorporation, cor - poration permits, notary public commissions, registration of brands, certificates of transcripts, trade marks, loan licenses under provisions of House Roll No. 44, Session Laws of 1915, etc. The following is a true and correct exhibit of moneys received during the past twenty four months from all sources: Receipts July 1, 1928 July 1, 1929 June 30, 1929 June 30, 1930 Corporation Filings, Domestic $ 20,976.01 $ 30,670.10 Corporation Filings, Foreign 7,824.75 8,355.45 Corporation Permits, Non-profit 667.00 708.00 Corporation Permits, Domestic 109,755.75 77,495.75 Corporation Permits, Foreign 49,198.25 23,970.50 Notary Public Commission Fees 2,562.00 2,574.00 Brand Registration &amp; Sale of Brand 800k5.... 1,569.32 1,500.35 Loan Company Licenses.. .' 1,860.00 2,100.00 Miscellaneous Fees 2,334.03 5,239.92 Total $196,748.03 $152*614.0.7 Total Receipts for Biennium $349,362.10 Expenditure* Salary, Secretary of State $ 5,000.00 $ 5,000.00 Salary, Deputy Secretary of State 2,640.00 2,640.00 Salaries, Clerks \ 7,130.00 5,870.00 Maintenance ; 2,166.28 2,090.30 Administration of . initiative and 'referendum ] aws 595.16 Expended from receipts of Brand Fund........ 1,612.73 459.80 Total ,$ 19.144U7 $ 16,060.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE ■■•■• '•■■ ■ ". ■ Loan Agencie* Section 2846, Compiled Statutes for 1922, provides for the licens - ing of loan agents or agencies, and is designed to regulate the loaning of money in small-, quantities upon chattel securities, salaries etc. The bond to be given by the company is in the sum of $2,000.00 to be renewed and filed annually on March 1st. The companies now oper - ating, their places of business, and amounts of money loaned are as follows: . . - Peoples Loan Company Omaha $ 115,011.95 Motors Finance.... _.. Lincoln 34,128.99 The Omaha Loan Company... ; Omaha 549,095.00 Valley Finance Corporation." Lincoln No Loans Farmers Loan &amp; Investment Co Lincoln 158,522.20 Community Finance Corporation Omaha 151,836.95 Industrial Loan &amp; Investment Co ..Lincoln 81,909.00 United Loan Company Omaha 84,179.67 Phoneix Finance Co Lincoln 3,375.00 Provident Loan Society of Omaha Omaha 301,675.59 The Lincoln Finance Co... Omaha 568,923.89 Omaha Wimsett System Co Omaha , 91,622.00 Rex Finance Co Omaha 97,764.30 Western Finance Corporation.... BuTwell . North Platte Loan &amp; Finance Co North Platte 23,530.00 Federated Finance Lincoln 2,929.30 City Loan Company '. Lincoln 49,832.16 Austin Credif Company Lincoln 24',370.21 Lincoln Finance Company :.... Lincoln 30,919.31 Globe Finance Co Lincoln 151,852.16 Equitable Finance Co Lincoln 2,848.28 ' Miller Allied Securities Co Columbus Allied Securities of Norfolk :....Norfolk Gering Finance Co : Gering 4,783.40 Loup Valley Finance Co Ord The Weller Company Ord General Finance Company ..Lincoln 7,017.83 Total Moneys Loaned ': $2,636,833.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE TOTAL COMPANIES LICENSED THIS YEAR AND NOT MAKING REPORTS TO DATE ARE AS FOLLOWS: Nebraska Finance Company Grand Island The Auto &amp; Finance Company Lincoln Saunders County Finance C 0..... Wahoo Equitable Finance Corporation Omaha F. R. Hussong Finance Co Lincoln United Finance Co Lincoln Hastings Loan &amp; Finance Co Hastings McCook Finance Co ,-McCook Companies which have been licensed the required length of time have been 1 examined annually, as provided by law, and reports of ex - amination are on file m this office. Respectfully submitted, FRANK MARSH, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE BOARD OF PARDONS Below is a list of the number of applicants heard by the Board of Pardons from the penitentiary; the Reformatory For Men; Refor - matory For Women, and the State Industrial School. The release of boys committed to the Industrial School for violation of state law was taken over by this Board during- the current biennium, the first meeting having been held there m December, 1929. This report covers the period June 30th., 1928, to June 30th., 1930. Total Number of Cases heard 553 Total Number of Cases denied : 184 Penitentiary Discharged by Expiration of Term 444 Pardons granted 0 Commutations granted 73 Paroles granted I 130 Number of violators ; 28 Violators returned 1. 18 Violators m custody (awaiting return) 0 ■ ■ .-■-.■.. ■ . Reformatory For Men ■'.-.' Discharged by Expiration of Term 297 Pardons granted , 0 Commutations granted ... 14 Paroles granted : 127 Number of violators 12 Violators returned 8 Violators m Custody (awaiting return).... 0 Reformatory For Women Discharged by Expiration of term 72 Pardons granted 0 Commutations granted.. , 0 Paroles granted „..■ 12 Number of violators 2 Violators returned 2 State Industrial School 1 ~ Paroles granted ; 20 Number of Violators ' 2 Violators Returned : 2 The Board is composed of the Governor, Secretary of State, and Attorney General. Meetings are held at the penitentiary the second' Tuesday of each month, except m the month of August. An occasional meeting is held at the State Industrial School at Kearney. During this bi-ennium the per centage of violators was 15.2. In </seg>
            <seg id="p011">: REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE other words approximately fifteen out of each one hundred violated the trust imposed in them by the Board, and the great majority of those who did violate were apprehended and returned. Respectfully submitted, FRANK MARSH, Secretary, Board of Pardons. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>