<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00041">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0041</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Your Pressure Cooker</title>
               <date value="18??">June 1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001"/>
         <seg id="p002">Your Pressure Cooker •HOW TO CHOOSE IT •HOW TO USE IT FOR CANNING CIRCULAR 57 JUNE 1938 THE UNIVERSITY M : NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT/STATION LINCOLN, NEBRASKA W.VV BURR. DIRECTOR '- '¦.•¦ • .'¦'¦' . i ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Page How to Choose the Pressure Cooker 3 Size and shape 3 Kind of material 4 Sealing and clamping 5 Pressure gauges 7 Safety valves and petcocks 9 A thermometer for pressure cookers 10 Using the Pressure Cooker for Canning 12 The reason tor using the pressure cooker 12 Altitude correction 12 Correction tor faulty gauge 12 Temperatures 13 (ieneral procedure tor processing 13 </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Your Pressure Cooker How to Choose It and How to Use It for Canning ARNOLD E. BARAGAR Department of Home Economics TFROM years of experience and research, authorities on canning are of ¦*¦ the opinion that for safety all nonacid foods, such as meats and vege - tables, should be processed at temperatures of at least 240 to 250 degrees Fahrenheit. For this reason the steam pressure cooker becomes, an im - portant piece of equipment, because by using steam under pressure these higher processing temperatures can be attained; However, it is essential that both old and new cookers be in perfect condition or they may have no advantage over the other types of processing equipment. Old cookers should be inspected at the beginning of the'canning season and any faulty pans either repaired or replaced. New, cookers should be closely inspected to determine their proficiency as canning equipment. Perhaps more people would be willing to use pressure cookers if they knew more about them and the way.they should be operated.. Briefly discussed in the following pages are some of the pertinent facts relative to the choice of a new cooker and to the operation of both old and new ones. For specific procedure pertaining to the preparation of foods, packing of cans, size and'kind of containers, etc., and other methods of processing, consult Farmer's Bulletin 1762. 1 HOW TO CHOOSE THE PRESSURE COOKER The choice of a pressure cooker should be based upon the following: (1) the size arid shape, (2) the material from which it is made, (3) the method of sealing and clamping, (4) the type of pressure gauge, (5) the type of safety valve, (6) the type of petcock, and (7) the possible use of a thermometer. ; j Size and Shape | The size of the pressure cooker should be governed by how it is to be used — whether primarily for cooking or primarily for canning. If it is to be used mostly for the cooking of meals for the average-sized family, a cooker with a capacity of 11 or 12 quarts will be found easiest to handle. The small-sized cookers are not as satisfactory for canning because they" hold such a small number of jars at one time. This makes it necessary to reload the cooker more often and hence less food can be processed in a day because of the extra time necessary to heat and cool the cooker. For the average-sized family an 18-quart to 25-quart cooker should be ade - quate for canning. When a great amount of canning is done at one time it might be necessary to use a 40-quart canner; however, the 25- and 4 0-quart cookers are very heavy to handle when filled. The size of the cooker is usually given in terms of its liquid capacity; that is, a 12-quart 1 "Home Canning of Fruits, Vegetables and Meats," Farmers' Bulletin 1762, U.S.D.A. This bulle - tin may be obtained from the Superintendent oE Documents, Washington, D. C, for five cents. </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 57 cooker will hold 12 quarts of water, an 18-quart cooker will Hold 18 quarts, etc., but in selecting a pressure cooker for canning, the important thing to know is how many cans or jars may be processed at one time. The approximate capacities of various sized cookers are listed below: Size in Pint Quart N0.2 No. 3 quarts jars jars cans cans 40 24 16 30 21 20-25 17 7 18 10 18 9 7 15 8 12 7 4 10 5 9 5 3 5 3 Slight changes in capacities from those above may be expected for cookers of different makes because of variations in dimensions and shapes, especially for cookers in the 20-to-25 quart sizes. Typical pressure cookers of various sizes and shapes are shown in Figures 1 to 8 inclusive. I llw_ ¦'H R lil Pa _M_F'l ¦____-__________[ ____l __ _¦ ¦__£*'$_______ Fie. I.—Cooker I, eleven-quart aluminum Fie. 2.—Cooker 11, twelve-quart aluminum with central scaling device. Satisfactory conventional-type sea) using yoke bolts dial on pressure gauge. The petxock and wing nuts, Satisfactory dial on was improved in the laboratory by add- pressure gauge. Safety valve and pct - ini; a small bar which made closing cock combined. Small knob at left of anil opening easier. pressure gauge is a safety plug. Kind of Material The majority of pressure cookers are made of aluminum, but house - hold cookers which are made of steel and are designed primarily for canning may also be obtained. Whether the aluminum cooker is cast or stamped, the side walls and bottom should be of even thickness so that </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Your Pressure Cooker the expansion due to heat will be uniform. Both the inside and outside of the walls should be smooth and free from pits. Steel cookers should be heavily tinned or finished in some manner that will make them rust - resistant.' Steel cookers such as cooker V finished in porcelain enamel must be handled-with care because porcelain enamel will chip. Steel cookers are lighter in weight than aluminum ones of the same size, because they can have thinner walls and still have the same strength as the aluminum cookers. Another advantage of the steel cooker is' its lower initial cost. An aluminum ."' - ' '•••¦.. : ¦"¦ - ' •¦..'¦' may cost from $2.00 to $7.00 fl H more than a steel one similar I With respect to price, keep in mind H that as with all other equipment, H _n_ I some manufacturers ask exorbitant I B__l for cookers which are I X'__ I to those a lower ¦ B__ HI I mi I all-purpose cooker, alum- I _____¦__! I seems to have an advantage lie- H ____ il cause the steel cookers cannot be as H ¦ ____?__! where only ______________¦___¦_____¦ water is. heeded. This would be I II true for the ______! cooker if it were used for searing ¦ __¦__ H meat, because it would be more than _ '¦ , probable that the intense heat would F'&lt;\3--Cook« '"• etghteen-quart alum - r i j &#132; , , _—"•."-¦""*.. mum, bcad-and-groove-type seal using crack and chip the porcelain enamel. » C " damps. Pressure gauge dial un- As far as kind of material is con- satisfactory because pointer movement is cerned, both types of cookers have ,0° small. Combined safety valve and advantages and disadvantages, and a tcoc^ not the best because petcock choice between them will be gov- &gt; H,.^ °PC" ,0 " erned by factors other than material. J Sealing and Clamping The method of sealing and ease of clamping are important. Experience in the laboratory has shown that cookers IV and V were the easiest to clamp; that is, they required the least effort to make a tight seal. Next in order of ease of clamping is cooker 11. It should be noticed on cooker II that the Wilts swing away from the cover and that the wing nuts furnish a fair grid. In contrast to cooker II is cooker 111, which has three dis - advantaged. First, the "C" clamps are hard to arrange so that they will not be in (the way while one is removing the cover; second, the round knobs are hard to grip for tightening the cover; and third, the bead on the cooker could be easily dented, which of course would spoil the seal - ing qualities. The bead and groove are shown in Figure 4. </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 57 mgM k i»f iffl____B_l TV Titt _________TT ~~ _~"' —i^_—————l __3 lliv^ »' "'' ' _^___i _¦__! ICSS _^^-~^?_____j ___r H HUH HRm l^^_ -•'^tsWm wm H*-____! ________________________________________________P_____l M_ —P/'—H ______________________________________________r * &gt;'______i _____________________________________________r-' ______¦ ¦ Pv ____ I _l wEr' '___! _¦ _______ Fir.. •) — Giokcr 111. showing bead on body of cooker and groove on cover. This type of seal is unsatisfactory because the bead can be easily damaged. Cooker [ is convenient, because it is necessary to tighten only the one central handle, but it has been observed that this type of clamping is subject to excessive wear, causing the cap under the handle to catch. Both cover and body of all cookers should be marked clearly with arrows so that the cover can always be fitted in the same place. This is essential for good sealing. On steel cookers the seal between the body and cover is accomplished by means of a rubber gasket which may have to be re - placed occasionally with a new one to keep the seal in good condition. Of the two cookers V and VJ, the seal on cooker V was found to be the better, because it has been observed that the rim on the cover of cooker VI is in some cases likely to spring enough to develop a leak, no matter how tightly the clamps are adjusted. With the type of damp - ing on cooker VI it is essential that the rim of the cover remain absolutely rigid. This cooker would have a better seal if at least eight clamps were used instead of six. These clamps would be easier to operate if the handles were two inches longer. At present, clamping can be made easier by using a piece of one-half inch gas pipe four or five inches long as an extension handle. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Your Pressure Cooker 7 I_^_^_^ __^_H _¦ _K^^^^^^^ _E^ *^;_^_l _F_____H_. v_ -_______^:fl _________________________Frr_____E_____P ***__B ¦__ _?§_ _l _K^l_sl I _________________________t?~ ____________________________L, Fig. s..—Cooker IV (left), nineteen-quart aluminum with band-type clamp. Pressure cooker dial unsatisfactory. Safety valve easy to clean but spring characteristics ' can be changed. Petcocjqsarhc type as shown in Figure 13. Fig. 6.—Cooker V (right), fhurtecn-quart enameled steel body, tinned steel cover. Band-type clamp. Canning! capacity equivalent to 20-quart cooker. The pctcock on the combined safety valVe and pctcock must be held open to release air and steam. Dial on the pressure^ gauge unsatisfactory. The band on this cooker is supposed to act as a safety plug letting steam escape at 30 pounds per square inch pressure. ;."¦ Pressure Gauges The pressure gauge is the heart of the pressure cooker, for it is the instrument that indicates the pressure within the cooker and consequently when correctly used it indicates the processing temperature for live steam. 2 AH gauges on household pressure cookers operate on the same prin - ciple, but they differ in the manner of coupling the internal mechanism to the pointer. In Figure 9 the dials on two gauges have been removed so that the internal mechanism is shown. The center gauge has a gear coupling so that for the same pressure its pointer moves almost five times as far as the pointer on the gauge at the left. This is evident by compar - ing the pointer positions in Figure 9 with reference to the white marks on the glass. With the gear-coupled pointer the dial can be marked like the ' dial on the gauge at the right in Figure 9. This dial is graduated in ¦ intervals of one pound of pressure per square inch. With the other type of coupling the dials are graduated in five pounds per square inch intervals and readings of one pound per square inch are * "The Accuracy of Pressure Gauges Used on Household Steam Pressure Cookers," Research Bulle- . tin 99, "Agr. Exp. Sea.; University of Nebraska. ¦'.' </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 57 __^______H _K_l _l ¦_________. __i _Si_K_fl __l Fm. 7. —Cooker V (left), showing inside of cover. The rubber gasket can be re - placed when the old ones become imperfect. Fie. S.—Cooker VI (right), cightccn-quart tinned steel cooker. Pressure gauge dial satisfactory. Combined safety valve and pctcock satisfactory. The seal on this cooker would be better if at least eight clamps were used instead of six. ___.__(__________¦ mm ___¦ vr \ m\ __f_________ m mWß^mW^mWi^T^y-^mm ¦1 B| MtPilß] ___¦ _¦ Itff '" T '•"'V ~\B __ m\ _Wn^^Br. __Lwfe''J'ißl BWj I n 1 'i' !¦ B ht^^-^J __¦_¦____! i_S_'"'' ______ Ik v"-™ __K*^__l _lT'«_l ¦' H', '^"^_H ___PflBT _HPrT____ ____L- --H ¦ K-ii/'-C-f Bls__i__li______i_i.^;.^ rSS '^¦k^i^*,ia^-^^^"*^rai^^=S_____yii?^^ Fie. 9.—Pressure gauges with dials removed to show internal mechanism. The pointer on the cenrer gauge has moved about five times as far as the pointer on the left - hand gauge, as is shown by the distance the pointers are from the white marks on the glass. The dial shown on the right-hand gauge is satisfactory. Temperature readings on the dial should be disregarded because they arc only true for average barometric pressure at sea level. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Your Pressure Cooker 1 * - - ¦ ' .: ¦ ¦' hard to estimate. Such dials are shown on cookers 111, IV, and V. For ease of reading, the dial on the pressure gauge should be at least two inches in diameter. It should be ¦ clearly, marked in one-pound-per - square-inch divisions and have the markings from 0 to 20 spread over at least half of the dial face. How - ever, it should be noted that gauges with either type of pointer move - ments are liable to become inaccurate after they have been used, and con - sequently gauge accuracy will de - pend on more than pointer move - ment. Refer to the section on gauge corrections. '. Safety Valves and Petcocks The safety valve on a pressure Fie. 10 —Ball-and-socket-type safety valve, cooker does just what its name im- This type of valve is easy to clean. The plies; it releases the steam if. the steel ball and valve scat should be pressure goes beyond a certain point, kept shining clean. Usually safety valves are adjusted to "blow off" at pressures of about 22 to 25 pounds per square inch. A ball - and-socket type valve is shown in Figure 10 and a modified needle valve type which is also a combined safety valve and petcock is shown in Figure 11. With the handle in the a needle I raised. This portion the H valve the petcock shown ¦ H removed in Figure 12. This valve I ¦ a good example combined H H valve and petcock, but it has J __W__ B the drawback that the valve is diffi- I B^H I cult to remove for cleaning. The I K^_| H safety valve and petcock I Xl shown on cookers in- H mW use because is ¦ H necessary to the petcock open I BUI release steam. H Safety valves must be kept clean and I free corrosion. They should I H always be chosen with this fact in H mind. Also the spring should be H heavy enough to prevent distortion I by pressing or stretching with the " ',~, .., _•'' &#132; , &gt; , iL, suL such distortions will J___ change the blow-off characteristics Thi _ is _ at __f ac , ory but has the draw - of the Valve. back thar the valve seat is hard to clean. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 57 As an added safety precaution it is well to have the cooker equipped with a safety plug. These plugs release the pressure in case the safety valve becomes injured and usually act at pressures of 40 to 50 pounds per square inch. H II Brv^___ I H F;:_fl I W _B^__hl w 'JKk Eflfl II wr:' _M I' ____! Ht''_l _F . ~jW-jm\ _H_i mW _____ wF-' v_r__s__r_l _H____b_H_H. _l__ _H_H _E__H __________________________ __________Pvfl__________________l Fir. 12.—Combined safely vahe and pctcock (left) showing pctcock portion removed. Fie. 13.—Needle-type pctcock (right). This pctcock would be better if the knob were larger and made of wood or other nnn-hcat-conilucling material. Caution! To keep your safety valve in good working condition, \eep till parts shining clean, and do not tamper with the spring. Where the petcock is not combined with the safety valve, petcocks like those in Figures 13 and 14 are commonly used. The petcock in Figure 13 is easier to close and open than the petcock in Figure 14. The plug in the petcock in Figure 14 must be kept tight, and this makes it difficult to turn the handle with the fingers. However, aside from ease of operation, either type is satisfactory. A Thermometer for Pressure Cookers While it is not necessary that a pressure cooker be equipped with both pressure gauge and thermometer, it will be found that the thermometer is a worthwhile instrument to add. At present the cost of adding a thermometer is about $5.00. With the thermometer all processing can </seg>
         <seg id="p012">V Your Pressure Cooker ¦-...: Bbc done direcdy in terms of temperature ) and this will eliminate the uncertainty of j processing with a faulty pressure gauge. It is possible that the mercury column in the thermometer might be separated when it is first received but this can be easily rejoined by putting the bulb of the ther - mometer in an ice and salt mixture. After leaving it there for a few minutes a gentle tapping of the thermometer frame will rejoin the mercury. I The usual household pressure cookers do not have the necessary hole for adding a thermometer but any plumber can easily Fig. R-piug-type petcock install lt The thermometer used on house - showing plug valve. Be- hold cookers requires a hole tapped with cause the plug must be %-inch pipe threads. A cooker equipped ¦sr&amp;tiK'S-r r h a. prT urc ™ker &lt;hermometef is and close. shown in Figure 15. '.....'¦ Fig. 15.—Pressure cooker equipped with a pressure cooker thermometer, </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 57 USING THE PRESSURE COOKER FOR CANNING The Reason-for Using the Pressure Cooker With the water bath and oven methods of processing it is impossible to obtain a higher temperature than the boiling point of water and canning authorities agree that nonacid foods should be processed at higher temperatures than 212" F. to eliminate the common causes of spoilage. These higher temperatures can only be obtained by using steam under pressure. In the pressure cooker when the water first begins to boil the temperature will be the same as it would be in an open kettle, but since the steam which is formed cannot escape from the pressure cooker, the pressure above the water will be increased and consequently the boiling point will be raised. As more heat is added this process continues until the pressure is sufficient to raise the boiling point of the water to any desired temperature. For processing food the desired temperature is usually 250° F. At sea level a temperature of approximately 228° F. can be obtained by raising the pressure 5 pounds per square inch and a temperature of 240° F. will be obtained if the pressure is raised 10 pounds per square inch and similarly the temperature will be 250° F. if the pressure is increased to 15 pounds per square inch. These are the pressures that are read on the pressure gauge of the pressure cooker. Altitude Correction Everyone knows that it takes a longer time to cook food by boiling in the mountains than it does at sea level. This is because the barometric pressure in the mountains is less than at sea level, and consequently the temperature of boiling water is less. Likewise when the pressure cOoker is used in the mountains the water starts to boil at a lower temperature than it does at sea level and to raise the temperature of the water or steam lo 250° F. the pressure as indicated by the pressure gauge must be greater than it was at sea level. For instance, at an elevation of 5,000 feet this gauge pressure would have to be 17!/ 2 pounds per square inch to give a temperature of 250°. Many people forget that in using the pressure cooker any decrease in barometric pressure must be compensated by increasing the pressure shown by the pressure gauge. It should be remembered that when the processing is being done at altitudes of 1,000 feel or more the gauge pressure should be increased a half pound per square inch for each additional 1,000 feet in elevation. This correction is commonly called the altitude correction. Correction for Faulty Gauge If the gauge is accurate the altitude correction is the only one that is needed, but unfortunately many old and new gauges are inaccurate and a gauge correction must be added to the altitude correction to obtain the pressure that will give the processing temperature desired. Sometimes there is an error in the gauge that is obvious. This is the case when the pointer does not rest upon the zero mark when the cooker is not being used. Since some new gauges are faulty when purchased and others </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Your Pressure Cooker develop an error with use, it is recommended that the pressure gauge should be checked at the beginning of each canning season. The recom - mendation is based upon a study of both old and new gauges which showed that only 25 per cent of the gauges tested were correct to within one-half pound per square inch. Gauges may be checked by removing and mailing them to this Experiment Station, Household Equipment Laboratory, or, by returning them to a manufacturer who advertises such service. Whenever a gauge has been sent away to be checked there should . be returned with it a statement showing what dial readings correspond to actual pressures of 5, 10, arid 15 pounds per square inch. Temperatures The temperatures indicated on the pressure gauge should not be used as indicators of the processing temperatures, because these temperatures are correct only for processing at sea level with an accurate gauge. It is best to follow the policy of doing all processing in terms of the correct pro - cessing pressure. If it is desired to process in terms of temperature read - ings, the pressure cooker should be equipped with a pressure-cooker thermometer. General Procedure for Processing The general procedure for processing food in a pressure cooker is well standardized but certain instructions should be emphasized, A brief outline of procedure is worth repeating. Amount of water needed;— Remember that water is necessary for the production of steam. The canner should contain boiling water to a depth , of about one inch or at least to a level just below the canning rack. After processing each load, replace the water lost by evaporation so that the cooker will not boil dry. Loading the cooker.—A free circulation of steam around the containers is essential. The method of placing the cans will depend upon the shape of the cooker. Tin canis may be arranged in tiers if a wire rack is used. Sealing the cooker.—After loading, the cover should be fastened securely. Both the cover and cooker body should be marked with an arrow to make sure that the cover is always adjusted in the same place on the cooker. For cookers of the type shown in Figures 2 and 3, start clamping by moderately tightening opposite pairs of clamps and then repeat until each opposite pair is tightened securely. The method of sealing will do much to prevent the escape of steam from around the rim.. There should be no escape of steam from a new cooker except from the petcock.; However, where there are small leaks from around the rim or from the safety valve, add extra water to compensate for this vapor loss, so that the cooker will not boil dry. Small leaks will not interfere with the processing if the/correct pressure can be maintained. Exhaustion of air..—lt is absolutely essential that all air be exhausted from the cooker. With air in the cooker, even though the correct pressure is maintained, the temperature of the steam may not be uniform because of air-pockets. Until an automatic air-release valve is designed for </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 57 pressure cookers it will be necessary to let steam escape from the petcock for at least four minutes in a steady stream. After all the air is exhausted, close the petcock and let the cooker come to the desired processing pressure. Processing period.—Begin counting time at the moment" the desired pressure is reached. Regulate the heat so that there will be no fluctuation in pressure, because a variation of from three to five pounds per square inch may cause some loss of liquid from glass jars. Be particularly care - ful not to let the pressure reach the point where the safety valve will re - lease or "blow off," because the resulting sudden rapid decrease in pressure will cause even greater loss of liquid from glass jars. Releasing pressure after processing.—When the processing is com - pleted, remove the cooker from the stove but do not open the petcock if using glass jars and No. 3 or larger tin cans. A rapid release of pressure might cause a loss of liquid from glass jars and a buckling of large tin cans. Let the pressure come to zero by natural cooling of the cooker and then open the petcock gradually so that a vacuum will not be created. Do not hasten the cooling by using cold water or wet cloths, because there is a possibility that such cooling might warp or crack the cooker. For No. 2'/i or smaller tin cans the pressure may be reduced by gradually releasing steam from the petcock. Cleaning the cooker.—After use it is essential that the cooker be thoroughly cleaned. Special attention should be given to the rims of the cooker and cover, which make the sealing joint. Besides being kept clean these surfaces must not be dented or marred in any manner, because this will injure the sealing qualities. Make sure that the valve seat on the safety valve is clean and free from corrosion, because it is at this point that most serious leaks in the cooker start. Also, it must be remembered that dirt in the safety valve might cause it to stick and thus fail to release if a critical pressure is reached. Silver polish may be used to keep valve and valve seat shining clean. After cleaning, the valve should be thoroughly dried to prevent the rusting of any steel parts. Keep the petcock clean and working freely. Keep the opening into the pressure gauge clean and do not immerse the pressure gauge in water. The cooker should be stored with the cover turned upside down with a paper over the top to keep dust out of the openings. This will insure air reaching the inside of the cooker and prevent a stale odor from forming. [10 M) </seg>
         <seg id="p016"/>
         <seg id="p017"/>
         <seg id="p018"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>