<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Key to the Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms that Attack Corn</title>
               <date value="1935-06">1935-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 81 A Key to the Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms that Attack Corn DON B. WHELAN Department of Entomology LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JUNE. 1933 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Pace Introduction &#132;.....■ 3 Description of the Head Setae and Pun&lt; turcs . 5 The Body Setae and Punctures 8 Key to the Cutworms and Armyworms 8 Descriptions of Species Corn-ear Worm, Heliothis obsolcta ( -abricius) 11 Pale Western Cutworm, Porosagrotis orthogonia (Morrison) 11 Small Striped Cutworm, Etixoa nivei inea (Grote) 12 Sandhill Cutworm, Etixoa dctcrsa (\ talker) 13 Dark-sided Cutworm, Etixoa messoria (Harris) 13 Striped Cutworm, Etixoa tessellata (t [arris) 14 Red-backed Cutworm, Etixoa ochrogc ster (Gucnee) 15 Army Cutworm, Chorizagrotis auxili ris (Grote) 15 Clay-backed Cutworm, Feltia gladiari t . (Morrison) 16 Dusky Cutworm, Feltia venerabilis (\ talker; 17 Dingy Cutworm, Feltia subgothica (Ha worth) and F. ducens (Walker) 18 Granulated Cutworm, Feltia annexa (Trcitschke) ; . . . . 18 Greasy Cutworm, Agrotis ypsilon (Rntemburg) 19 Spotted Cutworm, Agrotis c-nigrum Jnnaeus 20 W-marked Cutworm, Agrotis tmicoh r (Walker) 20 Variegated Cutworm, hycophotia mat garitosa form saucia (Hubner) 21 Bristly Cutworm, Polia renigera (Stc jhens) 22 Bronze Cutworm, Nephelodes emme, lonia (Cramer) 22 True Armyworm, Cirphis unipuncta (Haworth) 23 Wheat-head Armyworm, Neleucania albilinea (Hubner) 24 Glassy Cutworm, Sidemia devastator (Brace) 25 Fall Armyworm, Laphrygma frttgipeida (Abbott and Smith) 25 Cotton Cutworm, Prodenia omit/toga 'li Guence) 26 Bibliography ' ; 27 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A Key to the Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms that Attack Corn DON B. WHELAN " The following key to the Nebraska cutworms and armyworms injur - ious to corn is based upon structural characters supplemented in some instances by color. Color characters alone cannot be depended upon in all cases, as there is at times a wide variation even among individuals of a single species. Such color-markings as the stripes on the Bronze Cutworm (Nephelodes emmedonia) are quite constant and can be used in a key for the separation of the species. Such marks, however, often disappear in the last larval instar. Structural characters are more stable, but even with these there may be some variations. The location of certain setae and the relation of other setae and the punctures accompanying them are examples of this instability. Cutworms may have abnormal characters at times. In one specimen of the Dingy Cutworm (Fellia subgothica) there was a normal spiracle on the right side of the fifth abdominal segment while on the opposite side of the same segment the spiracle was entirely miss - ing. A similar omission of a spiracle on one side of the seventh abdominal segment of a specimen of the Pale Western Cutworm (Porosagrotis orthogonia) was also noted. Both of these cases were plainly abnormal. By the use of a combination of both structural characters and color the different species usually can be readily separated. One using this key should bear in mind that inflated specimens may have their pattern of skin granulation modified by stretching so that it is quite unlike that found on living or alcoholic specimens. Not all of the species in this key have been found in Nebraska; some are included because they are to be found in near-by states to such an extent that they probably are present in this state. For example the larval stage of the Pale Western Cutworm (Porosagrotis orthogonia) has never been found in Nebraska, although the type locality for the species, based on the moth, is within the borders of this state. The Red-backed Cutworm (Euxoa ochrogaster) has not been reported or identified from this state, although it has been found in both Colorado and Missouri, which join this state on the west and east. With the description of each species is included its seasonal abundance, which will also, in some cases, help to separate the species. To better describe the injurious habits of cutworms and armyworms, they are divided into four kinds. The climbing cutworms are those that climb trees, vines, and shrubs, usually in the spring, to feed upon the buds and leaves; the army cutworms are usually found in large numbers feeding on the tops of the plants; the garden, or solitary, cutworm is one 1 Acknowledgment U made to Mr. S. E. Crumb, author of Technical Bulletin 88 of the U. S. Department of Agriculture on "Tobacco Cutworms", for the helpfulness of the terminology used by him in that publication and also for suggestions in simplifying the key and for specimens for study; also to Messrs. W. C. Cook, T. H. Prison, R. W. Harned, I. H. Hawkins, Kenneth M. King, and Roger C. Smith for furnishing specimens; and to Mr. M. H. Swenk for cooperation in the work and suggestions during the preparation of this bulletin. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebr. Agr. Exp. StA. Research Bulletin 81 .^occipital /^!^ *-*"\ OCCIPITAL «IMIIg Fig. 1. —^Front views of heads of cutwortis: A, Euxoa auxiliaris; B, Ncphclodcs emme - donia; C, Cirphis unipuncta. Side view of a typical cutworm, D. __ Fie. 2. — Ocular areas of cutworms A, Cirphis unipuncta; B, Polia renigera. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms that cuts off the plant near the surface of the ground; and the subterranean cutworm feeds on the plant below the top of the soil. Any cutworm may and often does belong to more than one of these groups. DESCRIPTION OF THE HEAD SETAE AND PUNCTURES A cephalic view of a cutworm (Fig. 1, A, B, and C) shows a median triangular-shaped sderite, the front, and parallel with its two upper sides are two long, narrow sclerites, the adfrontals. Just below the front is the /v-'-V '{2r r &gt;\)C' K \'t&amp;V E v^*" $% V * J l»» mm tm Fig. 3. — Labra of cutworms: A, iMphrygma intgiperda; B, Chloridca obsoleta. /* — "\ „„ *?~#j f ;t rp ~^ -p Jr. I — )/ fp^f 1 *\ v \ I IT' / I .-'''' I W- I J ' 6/6PIRACLE "f XT\ / \ T C/ / "SI \ SPIHACU I A 1^/ A. I l/\y^—^B Fig. 4. — Prothoracic segments: A, Laphrygma frugiperda; B, Prodenia ornithogalli. epistoma and below this is the upper lip, or labrum. The mandibles and the other mouthparts He behind the labrum. The remainder of the head is called the epicranium. Near the base of the mandibles are the antennae and above these antennae are the simple eyes arranged in the form of an arc (Figs. ID and 2). The simple eye farthest from the antenna, on the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebr. Agr. Exp. StaI Research Bulletin 81 side of the head, is ocellus I, while the one closer to the antenna, and just above it, is ocellus IV, with ocelli I and HI between them. Ocellus V is close to and just below the antenna and ocellus VI is located behind, both ocelli IV and V. Near the lower edge of the front is located a pair of frontal setae F 1 and between them a pair of fror tal punctures F a . On each adf rontal sclerite are two setae and a punctu "e. Adfrontal seta Adf 1 is located at a point slightly above the middle of the front, adfrontal seta Adf 2 is located near the apex of the front, and tl e adfrontal puncture Adf a is situated between them. There are two paiis of setae on the epistoma: the outer and lower pair are epistomal setae E 1 and the inner and upper pair are 'SPIRACLE Q !Q I SPIRACLE &gt; 3 \ I -jf /proles Fig. 5. — Third abdominal segments: A, Feltia subgothica; B, Agrotis ypsilon. epistomal setae E 2 . The posterior g oups of setae and punctures are located near the upper part of the adfronfc 1 sclerites. Each group is composed of two setae and two punctures. Posterior seta P 1 is closer to Adf 1 and nearly as close to Adf 2 , while P 2 is located above and posterior to P 1 . The posterior puncture P a is to o le side and posterior to P 1 while the posterior puncture P b is situated between and nearly equidistant from P J and P 2 . Above and back of this group is a series of ultraposterior setae and punctures all shown at X. Between the lower part of the front and the ocular area is the anterior group of setae and punctures. A 1 is located just above the antenna, A 2 is abovt A 1 , and A 3 is close to and in front of ocellus II. The anterior punctiire A a is located just above a line be- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms tween A 2 and A :l and nearly equidistant between them, and the anterior puncture A b is just in front of ocelli III and IV and almost touching them. Between ocellus I and the ultraposterior setae and punctures is the lateral seta L 1 and its closely associated puncture L a . The ocular group is closely associated with the ocelli: O 1 is just back of and very close to ocellus IV, O- is back of and fairly close to ocellus I, O :l is to the rear Fie. 6. — Highly magnified portions of the skin: A, Agrotis ypsilon; B, Polia rcnigera: C, Feltia annexa; D, Feltia gladiaria. of and below ocellus VI, and the ocular puncture O a lies between it and this ocellus. The subocular group (Fig. 2) lies below ocelli V and VI with SO 1 close to the lower articulation of the mandible, SO 2 very close to ocellus V, and SO :I back of a line between SO 1 and SO 2 . The labrum (Fig. 3) bears six pairs of setae and one pair of punctures. At the middle there is a pair of setae, which are the median labial setae M l with their closely associated punctures P. These are located above M 1 in some species and even with them in others. Slightly below and to the side of M 1 are M 2 and below these are M 3 . On each lateral margin of the labrum are two </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebr. Agr. Exp. StA. Research Bulletin 81 f setae; the upper or outside one is tLa 1 and the lower inside one La 2 , while La :i is usually located in the lower margin. On the mandible are two setae, Md 1 (not shown) situated nearer to its base and Md 2 I (Fig. ID) closer to the teeth. a , THE BODY SETAE AND PUNCTURES subgothica; B, Prodema ornithogalli The prothorax bears the cervical . or prothoracic shield dorsally and / the oval-shaped spiracle laterally. JsQ^k \ Near anterior edge of the shield ' ~\ /^\ F&gt;S ' are l^ e tWO setae w ' t * 1 1&lt;l \ I ] t ' le more median and I b lateral to / 1 / it, with the puncture Z between / I \ them. Close to the posterior margin I 11 r^—A °^ £^ e sn ' e^ are the two setae II a , /V- -} /a — | [q ] nearest to the median line, and II b ' I I j below it. The two punctures X and F,c. 8.-Second antennal segments: ft, Y " f T situ f^ed between the setae I" Nephelodes emmedonia; B. ProdAia and ll • At) ove the spiracle are the ornithogalli; C, Euxoa messoria. two closely associated setae I c and II C , while in front of the spiracle s are the two setae IV and V. Below /y^^ // it and above the leg is seta VI. \l \\ / A dorsal view of the third ab - yl___^jtf \\l Jlf dominal segment (Fig. 5) shows / \ /*"■ — J. setigerous tubercle I the more an - / 1 / terior and closest to the median line I \ I WiX^ setigerous tubercle II below / 1 / and posterior to it. On the side, I J I J: above the spiracle, is setigerous I A / B / tubercle III and anterior to its up- V ;/ \ y/ ' per edge is the puncture III a . Seti - — gerous tubercle IV is posterior to F'o- 9- — Prothoracic claws: A, Fe, tia the spiracle while setigerous tubercle gladiaria; B, Euxoa niveilinea. 1 V is below the spiracle. KEY TO THE CUTWORMS AND ARMYWORMS 1. Occipital sinus extending nearly or quite to a line which would connect setae P^ — P"; epicranial suture less tian half as long as height of front and usually about one-fourth as lond (Fig. 1A) 2 Anterior apex of cccipital sinus Jnot extending to a line between P 3 — P* (except sometimes in the Variegated Cutworm); cpicranial suture at least half as long as the height of front (Fig. IB or IC) 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms 2. Skin granules conical or upright (Fig. 6B or 6C) . Granulated Cutworm (Fellia annexa) Skin granules convex, flat or wanting (Fig. 6A or 6D) 3 3. Skin granules convex (I : ig. 6A) 4 Skin granules flat or wanting (Fig. 6D) 7 4. Prothoracic spiracle oval, about one and one-half times as long as wide (Fig. 7A) Dingy Cutworms (Vcltia sitbgot/iica and /•'. dttcens) Prothoracic spiracle elongate, about twice as long as wide (Fig. 7B) 5 5. Setigcrous tubercle II on abdomen larger than tubercle I; anal proleg with more than 20 crochets 6 Sctigerous tubercles I and 1! on abdomen the same size: anal proleg with 12 to 16 crochets Sandhill Cutworm (Enxoa detcrsa) 6. Skin granules strongly convex with small secondary granules (Fig. 6A); ocelli IV, VI, and V forming an acute angle . . . .Greasy Cutworm (Agrotis ypsilon) Skin granules small, slightly convex, without secondary granules; ocelli IV, VI, and V forming a right or obtuse angle '..... Dark-Sidkd Cutworm (Enxoa messoria) 7. Spiracle on prothoracic segment, round, or but slightly oval (Fig. 7A); second segment of antenna about twice as long as wide (Fig. 8A or 81$) Pale Western Cutworm ( Porosagrotis ort/iogonia) Spiracle on prothoracic segment an elongated oval (Fig. 7B); second segment of antenna less than twice as long as wide (Fig. HC) 8 8. Coloration like that of a white grub; prothoracic claw without distinct notch (Fig. 9A); skin granules obscure; ocular seta O 2 distinctly more than width of ocellus from ocellus I (Fig. 2A1 Glassy Cutworm (Sidemia devastator) Coloration normal, usually brownish; prothoracic claw with a distinct notch (Fig. 9B); skin granules distinct; ocular seta O 2 about the width of ocellus from ocellus I (Fig. 2B) 9 9. Ocular puncture O° situated distinctly posterior to a line between the center of ocellus VI and ocular seta QP (Fig. 2B) 10 Ocular puncture O a situated nearly on or slightly in front of a line between the center of ocellus VI and ocular seta O-' 1 (Fig. 2A) 11 10. Head markings back of ocular area heavy, more stripe-like, not arranged in isolated s|xhs Stripf.d Cutworm f Eitxoa tcsscllata) Head markings, if any, as faint isolated spots Army Cutworm ( Chorizagrolis anxiliaris) J 1. Epicranium with brownish, frccklc-Iikc spots (Fig. 1 A) 13 Epicranium with brownish markings but not arranged in spots (Fig. 1C) 12 12. Crochets on anal proleg about 12 in number: mandibular teeth serrate; anterior puncture A a about equidistant between the anterior setae A 2 and A 3 (Fig. ID) Clay-Backed Cutworm (Fcltia gladiaria) Crcxhcts on anal proleg 18-20 in number; mandibular teeth not serrate; anterior puncture A B closer to A :l than to A 2 (Fig. IB) Dusky Cutworm (Feltia vcncrabilis) </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 81 13. Freckles on cpicranium distinct; ocellus II closer to III than to I; body length about 25 to 30 mm.; head about 2.5 to 2.H mm. wide Small Striped Cutworm ( Etixoa nivcilinca) Freckles on cpicranium not distinct; ocelli I, II, and III about equidistant; body length 36 to -10 mm.; head about |3.2 mm. wide Red-Backed Cutworm I Etixoa ochrogastcr) H. Skin granules upright or conical (Fi;. 6B or 6C) 15 Skin granules slightly convex, flat, cr wanting; not as above (Fig. 6A or 6D) 16 15. Ocular puncture O anterior to a line from the center of ocellus VI to seta O*; median seta of labrum M 3 situated even with or higher than M 1 (Fig. 3B); a line between the centers of ocelli IV, VI, and V forming a right or obtuse angle (Fig. 2A) Corn-Ear Worm (Heliol/iis obsoleta) Ocular puncture O* posterior to a line from the center of ocellus VI to seta O* (Fig. 2B); median seta of labrum M 3 situated below M 1 (Fig. 3A);a line between the ocelli, as above, forming an acute angle (Fig. 2B) Bristly Cutworm (Polia renigcra ) 16. Spiracles yellowish or whitish withii i 17 Spiracles brown or black within ... 19 17. Dorsum with paired triangular, blac It ', spots, largest posteriorly 18 Dorsum without triangular spots; body striped or not .... Wheat-Head Armyworm (Neleucania albilinea) 18. Second segment ot antenna less than twice as long as wide (Fig. 8C); without black spots above spiracles; blacl subdorsal spots not including sctigerous tubercle I except on some poster or segments Spotted Cutworm ( Agrotis c-iiigrum ) Second segment of antenna more thin twice as long as wide (Fig. HA or HB): usually with black spots above spiracles; black subdorsal spots with an angular extension, including seticcrous tubercle I , . . .W-Marked Cutworm (Agrolis unicolor) 19. Mandibles with not more than one or two obscure teeth; a line between the centers of ocelli IV, VI, and V forming a right angle (Fig. 2A) 20 Mandibles with four or five distinct teeth; a line between the centers of ocelli IV, VI, and V forming an acute jngle (Fig. 2B) 21 20. Head brown with few markings aliove the eyes; prothoracic claw with little or no notch (Fig. 9A); body rotust, bronze or brownish with one median stripe and two lateral light stripe , on each side Bronze Cutworm (Nephelodes emmedonia) Head with net-like regulations above the eyes; prothoracic claw with a distinct notch (Fig. 9B); body more slender, striped, but not as above. . , True Armyworm (Cirphis tinipimcta) 21. Body marked with four to six yellowish or whitish dots on dorso-incdian line, more distinct on third thoracic and first and second abdominal seg - ments i. Variecated Cutworm ( Lycophotia saticia) Body not marked as above 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms 22. Skin granules |] at or pavcmcnt-likc (Fig. (&gt;D); setae tubcrculate; on first thor - acic segment a line through setae II C and Ic would meet a line drawn through setae V and IV in an acute angle (Fiji. 4A); cervical shield usually black or dark brown; nub of prothoracic claw acutely angled (Fig. c &gt;Ii) Fall Armvwohm (Laphrygma jrugiperda) Skin smooth, apparently not granulate; setae not tuberculatc; on first thoracic segment a line drawn as above would form an obtuse angle (Fig. 4E&gt;; cervical shield light brown or concolorous; nub of prothoracic claw rounded, not angled (Fig. 9A) Cotton Cutworm (ProJcnij ornirhosnlli) CORN-EAR WORM, Heliol/us obsolete (Fabricius) Description. — Body length about 32 to 38 mm. Head 2.8 to 3.2 mm. wide. Color variable, head usually tan, smooth, and unmarked, the darker individuals with freckles; body sometimes light green or pink to brown or almost black, usually with a double mid-dorsal line the length of the body. Some individuals arc concolorous, while others arc more or less striped. Cervical shield varies with color of larva. Ocular area light. Adfrontal sutures do not extend to the occipital sinus. Anterior puncture A* about equidistant between anterior setae A 2 and A s , a line through A 3 to A 2 to A 1 forming a right or slightly acute angle. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line drawn between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a anterior to a line from the center of ocellus VI to seta O 3 . A line between the centers of ocelli IV to VI to V forms a right or obtuse angle. Mandibular teeth pointed and acutely angled at their base. Median seta of labrum M- situated even with or higher than the first seta of labrum M 1 . Second segment of antenna not more than twice as long as wide. Setae of abdomen tuberculate, setigerous tubercle II larger than I, setiger - ous tubercle III larger than spiracle. Spiracles white within. Skin gran - ules thorny. Anal proleg with 18 to 20 crochets. Distribution.— Occurs throughout southern Canada, most of the United States and Mexico. In Nebraska it has been reported abundantly from all parts of the state and is probably present wherever corn is grown. Seasonal Abundance. — The corn-ear worm usually begins to injure the corn about the latter part of June, and from then on until frost. Habits. — The later broods of this pest usually attack the corn cars, but the first brood usually eats through the curled leaves of the plant, in a manner similar to that of some species of cutworms. Food Plants. — Besides corn, it is known to attack tomatoes, cotton, to - bacco, a large number of other cultivated crops, and weeds. PALE WESTERN CUTWORM, Porosagratts orthogonia (Morrison) Description.— Body length about 32 to 38 mm. Head 2.8 to 3.0 mm. wide, shining light brown, with a dark band extending from the edge of the clypeus up and back along the adfrontal sutures and through the ultra-posterior setae. Body a sordid whitish or grayish color with no mark- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 81 ings. Cervical shield a light shining brown cut by a light median line. Ocular area dark. The adfrontal sutures extend to the occipital sinus. A line through anterior setae A 3 to A 2 to A 1 forms an acute angle. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line drawn between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a posterior to a line from the center of ocellus VI to ocular seta O :l . Ocellus II closer :o ocellus III than to I, ocellus III closer to IV than to II, a line between- the centers of ocelli IV, VI, and V not forming a right angle. Mandibul: r teeth prominent, triangular, their bases acutely angled. A line from maidibular seta Md 1 to Md- prolonged would not bisect the teeth. Seconc segment of antenna not more than twice as long as wide. Setigerous tubercle II larger than I, IV larger than III. Spiracles light brown within. Skin finely granulated with flat pavement - like granules. Anal prolegs with 12 to 16 crochets. Distribution. — The distribution of this species is mostly western, extend - ing from Canada south through Montana and Wyoming to Colorado and northern Arizona and Nev t Mexico, and touching western North Dakota, South Dakota, Nebraska and Kansas. The species was originally described by Morrison in 1876 from Glencoe, Nebraska, which is therefore the type locality. Seasonal Abundance. — In Caiiada most of the damage is done during May and June. Habits. — The larvae work mostly underground, cutting off the roots. Food Plants.— It is known lo attack wheat, oats, corn, barley, flax, alfalfa, and beets. SMALL STRIPED CUTSVORM, Euxoa nivcilinca (Grotc) Description. — Body length absut 25 to 30 mm. Head 2.5 to 2.8 mm. wide, cream to light brown with dark freckles, no reticulations or dark bands. Body a dull brownish color. Cervical shield conspicuous, shining, light brown, cut by a light median line, a row of black dots along its posterior edge and a cluster of b ack dots posterior to seta I b . Ocular area light to dark. Adfrontal sutures reach the occipital sinus. Anterior setae A 3 , A 2 , and A 1 form an icute angle. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line drawn between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a about on a line between ocellus VI and ocular seta O 3 . Ocellus II closer to III than to I, ocellus III close • to IV than to II, a line between centers of ocelli IV, VI, and V forming an acute angle. Mandibular teeth prom - inent, their bases not acutely an§ led. A line through the mandibular setae Md 1 and Md 2 prolonged would not bisect the teeth. Second segment of antenna not twice as long as wide. Setigerous tubercle II larger than I, IV larger than III. Spiracles brown within. Skin granules small, flat to slightly convex and closely set. Anal prolegs with 14 to 16 crochets. Distribution. — This species is mostly western in its distribution, having been reported from Nebraska. Kansas, and Colorado to Texas and New Mexico. In Nebraska it has been reported from such widely distributed </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms localities as Cheyenne, Franklin, Hamilton, Antelope, and Lancaster counties. Seasonal Abundance. — This species has been collected mostly from May 27 to June 30, nearly all individuals pupating between the middle and the last of August. Habits. — Similar to the Dark-sided Cutworm. Food Plants. — It attacks sweet clover, corn, and wheat. SANDHILL CUTWORM, Euxoa dctersa (Walker) Description. — Body length about 23 mm. Head 2.5 mm. wide, smooth and usually unmarked, sometimes with faint freckles, small fuscous flecks just below the posterior seta P 1 . Cervical shield with fuscous flecks sim - ilar to those of Euxoa messoria. Ocular area light. Adfrontal sutures reach the occipital sinus. Anterior puncture A a closer to A :l than to A-, a line from A 3 to A 2 to A 1 forming a right angle. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocelli IV, VI, and V forming an obtuse angle, ocelli III and IV approximate. Mand - ibular teeth pointed, acutely angled at their base. Second segment of antenna not more than twice as long as wide. A line from seta I a ot prothorax to punctures Y and X form an obtuse angle. Setigcrous tu - bercles I and II about same size, IV larger than III. Spiracles black within. Skin with closely set convex granules. Anal proleg with 12 to 16 crochets. Distribution. — This species is found in eastern Canada, Nova Scotia, and in the United States in the northern, eastern, and central parts at least as far west as Nebraska and Colorado. In Nebraska it has been re - ported or found in Loup, Holt, Wheeler, Antelope, Pierce, Madison, Stan - ton, and Cuming counties. Seasonal Abundance. — Most of the damage is reported during the last of May and through June to early July. Habits. — The larvae cut the corn plant off at the surface of the ground when the weather is cool but after a warm spell they will go below the ground to do their injury. The injury is confined to the light, sandy soils. Food Plants. — Grasses and corn are readily eaten. DARK-SIDED CUTWORM, Euxoa messoria (Harris) Description. — Body length about 28 to 37 mm. Head about 3.0 to 3.2 mm. wide, creamy to tan with groups of freckles. Cervical shield light brown with several dark brown dots along its posterior edge and bunched behind seta I b . Ocular area light to dusky. Adfrontal sutures reaching the occipital sinus. A line from anterior setae A 3 to A 2 to A 1 would form an acute angle. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocellus II closer to III than to I, ocelli IV, VI, and V form a right or obtuse angle. Mandibles with at least five distinct teeth, their bases acutely angled. A line through mandibular setae Md 1 to Md 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebr. Agr. Exp. krA. Research Bulletin 81 prolonged would not bisect the' teeth. Second segment of antenna little longer than wide. A few scattered dots between setae I a and II a A light median line extends faintly to rear of body. Dorsum of body brown The sides darker, a dark band extending from seta II to and including the spiracles. Setigerous tubercle fl larger than I, and IV larger than II. Spiracles black within. Skin granules minute, convex, and contiguous Anal proleg with 20 to 24 crochets. Distribution.— This species occurs in Canada and in the United States north of a line between New Jirsey, Tennessee, Nebraska, Colorado and California In Nebraska it has been reported from Lancaster, Hamilton, Mernck, Hall, Greeley, Antelore, Madison, Buffalo, Cherry, and Dundv counties. ' Seasonal Abundance.— These cutworms are most active in May and June. Habits.— It is a garden type of cutworm but is often very destructive as a climbing cutworm feeding on the buds of fruit trees. Food Plants.— It attacks corn tobacco, onions, tomatoes, sweet potatoes cabbage radishes, spinach, beans, peas, lettuce, sugar beets, turnips, straw - berry plants, flowering plants, cWr, and grasses as will as the buds of apple, currant, soft maple, and grape. STRIPED CUTWdRM, Euxoa tcsscllata (Harris) Description—Body length l\ to 38 mm. Head 3 mm. wide, creamy to tan with groups of freckles similar to Euxoa messoria, only heavier markings back from eyes stripi-like. Body color pale, dorsum dull fer - ruginous a mid-dorsal and a pa r of supraspiracular pale lines present as a white subspiracular stripe. Cer-ical shield same color as head but with brown clouded areas and a few fuscous flecks. Ocular area black A line between anterior setae A\ A* Lnd A' forming an acute angle. Ocular seta O anterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI Ocular puncture O» posterior to a Him between ocellus VI and ocular seta O :t Ucellus II about equidistant between I and III, ocelli IV VI and V not forming a right angle. Second segment of antennae about VA times ?i°" S th aS Yu wi , de T r IT at u distal &gt;an proximal end. Sctigerous tubercle II larger than I II and III about trie same size, and IV distinctly the largest. S eS cf laCk W f ln { Prot M racic Claw dee P'y notch &lt;^ nub acutely ■Ifi \ r "'P ■ y P avem f, nt S ranulose - Anterior proleg with about 16 crochets and anal proleg wijh about 22 crochets. Distribution—This is a morfc northern species, occurring north of the Ohio river and Virginia and mtjstly east of the Rocky Mountains It was reported from Sioux City, lowajby Crumb, and the Nebraska records Hst disXed in y th n e ZT" " " "^ "?" Habits—It has been reported as climbing trees and also as a regular £tirg et L CU day ng ° ff Pl T JUSt ab ° Ve gr ° Und 3nd feedin * « </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms Seasonal Abundance. — This insect is probably one-brooded, passing the winter in the larval stage. They do the greatest amount of damage dur - ing late May and early June. The moths are found from early June until early August. Food Plants. — This species has been reported eating the leaves of apple, cherry, and pear as well as bean, beet, cabbage, celery, clover, corn, cu - cumber, flax, grass, flowering plants, lettuce, melon, onion, parsnip, plum, Polygonium, potato, radish, Rumex, rhubarb, squash, tobacco, and tomato. RED-BACKED CUTWORM, Enxoa ochrogastcr (Gucni-c) Description.— Body length 36 to 40 mm. Head about 3.2 mm. wide, smooth- shining, a dirty brown color with a cloudy appearance, a broad dark stripe along the adfrontals and through the ultraposterior setae. Body light brown to gray, the dorsum with a light median stripe bordered by two broad, reddish bands on cither side, brown below the spiracles and the venter lighter. Cervical shield a shining light brown with fuscous spots along the posterior margin, some posterior to I b and a few scat - tering. Ocular area darker. Adfrontal sutures reach the occipital sinus. Anterior puncture A a closer to A :l than to A". A line between anterioi setae A", A 2 / and A 1 would form an acute angle. Ocular seta O 1 anterior to a line between the corners of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a nearly on a line between ocellus VI and ocular seta O :l . Ocelli I, II, and III about equidistant, III closer to IV than to II, ocelli IV, VI, and V forming an acute angle. Mandibular teeth bluntly rounded, not acutely angled at their bases. A line through the mandibular setae Md 1 and Md 2 prolonged would not bisect the teeth. Second segment of antenna not much longer than wide. Setigerous tubercle II larger than I, IV larger than III. Spiracles brown to black within. Skin granules flat and pave - ment-like. Anal proleg with 12 to 14 crochets. Distribution. — This species is found throughout Canada, where it is numerous and very destructive, and in the United States south to Missouri, Colorado, and California. Seasonal Abundance.— Most of its damage is done in May and June in Montana and eastern Canada, the moths flying in July and August. Habits.— It works mostly underground, cutting off plants beneath the surface. Food Plants. — This species attacks corn, wheat, oats, barley, and such garden vegetables as peas, beans, cabbage, cauliflower, beets, radishes, and potatoes as well as flowering plants. ARMY CUTWORM, Clwrizngrotis aiixiharis (Grotc) Description.— Body length about 40 mm. Head 3.2 to 4.0 mm. wide, light brown with brownish freckles, dusky along adfrontal sutures and on front. Cervical shield with dusky areas' and dark brown dots, cut by a median line which is lost on the abdomen. Ocular areas dark brevvn. Adfrontal sutures variable, cither reaching the occipital sinus or not. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Si a. Research Bulletin 81 Posterior epicranial puncture P b distinctly closer to posterior seta P 2 than P 1 . Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line connecting the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a does not lie directly between the third ocular seta O 3 and ocellus VI. Ocellus IV closer to VI than to V, the three not forming a right angle. Ocellus II about equidistant between I and III, ocellus III closer to IV than to I. Mandibular teeth prominent and at least five in number, a line throi gh the mandibular setae Md l and Md 2 prolonged, not bisecting the teeth. Second segment of antennae but little longer than broad. Ground colo ■ of abdomen yellowish with indefinite markings, a dark broken line run ling through seta II. Setigerous tubercle II at least twice as large as I and setigerous tubercle IV over twice as large as III. Spiracles brown to black within. Prothoracic claw little notched. Skin finely pavement glranulose. Anal proleg with about 20 to 22 crochets. Distribution. — This species occurs in the United States, mostly in the plains states from North Dakota to Texas and New Mexico. In Nebraska the moths have a general distribution, while the cutworm reports have come chiefly from western Nebraska. [The Nebraska reports are from the fol - lowing counties: Boyd, Knox, Cedar, Pierce, Antelope, Wheeler, Madison, Platte, Merrick, Howard, Hall, Buffalo, Custer, Butler, Polk, Hamilton, York, Lancaster, Otoe, Jeffersorl, Thayer, Nuckolls, Webster, Kearney, Furnas, Hitchcock, Hayes, Chase, Perkins, Keith, Lincoln, Logan, Arthur, Deuel, Cheyenne, Kimball, Banner, Morrill, Garden, Dawes, and Sheridan. Seasonal Abundance. — The cutworms of this species are injurious from early March until the latter part! of April. The moths are generally most numerous during May. Habits. — This species when abundant goes in armies, devouring the plants above ground, not cutting them off. They are distinctly a surface feeder, burrowing very little. At |:imes they climb trees and eat the buds. Food Plants. — Because of the early season when this species is abundant, they usually injure only wheat, grasses, rye, oats, barley, and alfalfa, al - though in gardens they feed on cabbage, horse-radish, turnip, beet, corn, pea, celery, tomato, potato, onion, rhubarb, and strawberry. CLAY-BACKED CUTWORM, Fellia gladiaria (Morrison) Description.— Body length 371 to 38 mm. Head 3.1 to 3.2 mm. wide, light brown with dark brown arcs along and back from the adfrontal sutures, reticulations present between the ocelli and the ultraposterior setae. Body light with brownish or reddish markings on the dorsum, extending to setigerous tubercle II, the sides brownish. Cervical shield dark brown, slightly rugged, with three ligl|t stripes. Ocular area dark, front with a dark central spot. Adfrontal jsutures reach the occipital sinus. A line from anterior seta A 3 to A 2 toj A 1 would form an acute angle. Ocular seta O 1 on or slightly posterior jto a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a nearly on a line between ocellus VI and ocular seta O 3 . Ocellus II about equidistant between I and III, ocelli </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Key to Nebraska Cuiworms and Armvworms IV, VI, and V not forming a right angle. Mandibular teeth distinct, pointed and slightly serrate, acutely angled at their base. A line through the mand.bular setae Md&gt; and Md* prolonged would not bisect the teeth becond segment of antenna not much longer than wide. Setigerous tubercle II larger than I, IV larger than III. Spiracles black to dark brown within. Skin granules round, flat or slightly convex, of about equal size, but slightly separated from each other. Anal proleg with about 12 crochets. Distribution.— This species is found generally distributed in the United States and n Canada east of the Rocky Mountains. In Nebraska it has been reported only from Dodge and Lancaster counties. Seasonal Abundance.-They are generally found during the latter half ot May, being dormant during the summer and pupating about the first of September. The moths are found late in September. arm^lk^hTbit"* "" ° &amp; PlalUS abundant ""? Jssume an Food Plants.— Among the crops it is known to attack are: corn clover, tobacco potato, tomato, sweet potato, bean, onion, raspberry, strawberry oats, and grass as well as aster, goldenrod, and pansy. DUSKY CUTWORM, Feitia vcncrMlis (Walker) Description.— Body length 40 to 43 mm. Head about 3.0 to 3.5 mm wide shining cream color, with a dark band extending from the sides of the clypeus along the adfrontal sutures and through the ultra-posterior setae, reticulations extending from this band to the lateral seta L l and puncture L* front with median dark spot. Body mottled brown color. Cervical shield conspicuous, shining brown cut by a median light line. Ocular area dark. Adfrontal sutures reach the occipital sinus. A line between the anterior setae A 3 to A 2 to A 1 would form a right angle. Ocu ar seta O 1 posterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI Ocular puncture O* on a line between ocellus VI and ocular seta O\ Oce Ui IV, VI and IV do not form a right angle, ocellus II closer to 111 than to I. Mandibular teeth triangular, their bases acutely angled. A line through the mandibular setae Md 1 and Md 2 prolonged would hardly bisect the teeth. Second segment of antenna less than twice as lone as wide. Setigerous tubercle II larger than I, IV larger than III. Spiracles 20 c^hets" 1 ' Pavement granulose. Anal proleg with 18 to Distribution.— Found in Canada and the United States from Nova fnr°n *l m to J e ™™&lt;*&gt; Nebraska, Colorado, Texas, and Cali - f 1 H M 1 i ebra * ka ll has been re P°«ed f™m Red Willow, Dawson, Buf - falo, Hall, Hamilton and Lancaster counties. Crumb lists it from Sioux City, Iowa, a short distance from the northeast corner of this state Seasonal Abundance.-Our records show damage by this species from May 2 until June 6. Habits.— It has the cutting habit well develoDed. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebr. Acr. Exp. &lt;ta. Research Bulletin 81 Food Plants.— Reported food plants in this state are corn, alfalfa sweet clover, garden vegetables, and gUss pastures. ' DINGY CUTWORM, Feltia s,,b i0 ,hica (Haworth) and F. duccns (Walker) Description—Body length va ying from 22 to 32 mm. Head 2.5 to 2 7 mm. wide, shining biown with darker submedian arcs. Bodv color a dull dingy brown, each abdominal segment cut by two transverse light Hnes X re^\ C T 1C t 1 Shidd brm T"' CUt a faint "-dian light 1 nc a few eicS h tS i e ' ng PreSen - Adfr ° ntaI SUtures varia ble, sometime" reaching the occipital sinus and sometimes not. Ocular seta 6* posterior to a line between ocelli IV and VI. Ocelli IV VI and V fnrm P ° StCnor angle Mandibular teeth bluntly rounded and n^utdy a^d" S bfse'ct the rth S UgH , mandibuhr / etae Mdl and Md2 Ponged would bisect the teeth Second segment of antenna about one and one half times as long as wide. Setigerous tubercles I and II about the same size 7v 4 to 12 crochets, anal prolegs wi«jh 20 to 21 crochets. a d a D h S ! ribUti0n T OC 1 CUrS widcI y distributed in the United States and Can - ada but more abundant in the Urthern part of its range In Nebraska Habits.— This cutworm usually works in small numbers in cultivated areas but at t.mes may climb fruit trees to feed on the buds. CU ' mated Food Plants.— It is a general feeder, eating corn, wheat, grasses, clover, " strawberry, beans, peas, squash, cucumber, tomato, cabbage, horse-radish, GRANULATED CUTVORM, Vcltia anncxa (Trcitschkc) _ Description.-Body length 3C to 37 mm. Head 3.0 to 3.2 mm. wide, light brown, slight y roughenecl, shining, submedian arcs present with obltT l ° nS e u° W - B ° dy C f l0r a dark « ra y with a P air of Yellowish oblique hnes on each segment, venter a pale greenish gray. Cervical shield sutures t? Wn T V a u faim m£dian Hne - ° Cular areas dark - Adfrontal P'^o~VnnM na H C m , u OCCI PT sinus - Po «erior epicranial puncture from , ?•? bCtWCen "P icranial s etae P- and P*. A line drawn nZturl O°a f SCtae , 'Z A l ° A1 W ° UId f ° rm an Obtuse a "g Ie - Ocular puncture O« on a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocelli han I \Z II i° "^u 1™ a Ht anglC) OCdli IH and IV closer aether Alb 1\ tt teeth] triangular, their bases not acutelv angled. Lond sea 8 /? 6 d and ,^ d P rolon ge d would not bisect the tfeth. Second segment of antenna at least twice as long as wide, its sides slightly </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms rounded. Setigerous tubercle II larger than I, IV larger than III. Spiracles black within. Prothoracic claw with a deep acute notch, nub pointed. Skin granules upright, conical, somewhat retrorse, many secondary gran - ules present. Anterior proleg with 8 to 12 chochets, and anal proleg with 18 to 20 crochets. Distribution. — Occurs from Massachusetts and New York westward to South Dakota, Arizona, California, and southward through Mexico and Central and South America. It probably does not breed regularly in the northern part of its range. It has been reported from Lincoln, Lancaster county, in Nebraska. Seasonal Abundance. — This species probably winters as a pupa, the moths emerging early in the spring, the cutworms reaching maturity by early June. A second brood appears in July. Habits. — It is a general feeder, usually cutting off the plants and feed - ing on them by day but it will climb plants and feed on the leaves. Often it will gnaw the epidermis from the stems at or below the surface of the ground, or even at some distance above the ground. Food Plants. — Among its food plants are pepper, tomato, potato, sweet potato, cabbage, pea, bean, turnip, corn, wheat, grasses, clover, cotton, tobacco, and pepper grass. GREASY CUTWORM, Agrotis ypsilon (RottcmburK) Description. — Body length 30 to 45 mm. Head 3.5 to 4.0 mm. wide, dull brown, rough with darker brown markings, darkest adjacent to the adfrontal sutures. Body nearly uniformly dark grtasy-gray to a dull leaden-brown color with an indistinct mid-dorsal yellowish line and two faint lateral stripes, venter a dark greenish yellow. Cervical shield brown with dark mottlings. Ocular area dark. Adfrontal sutures terminate in the occipital sinus. Epicranial puncture P b anterior to a line between the epicranial setae P 2 and P 1 . Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line between ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a posterior to a line between the centers of ocellus VI and ocular seta O :t . Ocelli IV, VI, and V form an acute angle. A line through the mandibular setae Md 1 and Md - prolonged would hardly pass thrugh the teeth. The second segment of antenna at least twice as long as wide. Setigerous tubercle II much larger than I, IV larger than III. Spiracles black within. Skin granules strongly convex, rounded, coarse and interspersed with smaller granules. Anterior proleg with 16 to 21 crochets, anal proleg with about 28 crochets. Distribution. — Found practically throughout the United States, Canada, and south to Mexico. In Nebraska it has been reported from Dawcs, Daw - son, Buffalo, Valley, Harlan, Hamilton, York, Clay, Fillmore, Thayer, Lancaster, Johnson, Otoe, Dodge, and Douglas counties. Seasonal Abundance. — These cutworms have been injurious in this state from the middle of May until the middle of August. Pupation takes place in the last of June and in July. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebr. Agr. Exp. ;&gt;ta. Research Bulletin 81 the burrows dunng the day. T L climbmg habit is littfe developed* s^rry'tb^ -' «-* ««*» SPOTTED CUTWOtM, Agrotu cnignw, Linnaeus Description.— Body length about 30 to 36 mm. Head 8 to 3 0 mm vv.de cream to light brown, shining, with dark brown submedian ZTs two brown marks posterior to the ocelli, remainder of head re .culated Genera color of body a dull brown with brownish and Wackfsh fle Ss' paired triangular spots just anteriior to seta II on each abdomS lm n ' rn-ss,ng on thorax. Cervical shield a dull reddish-browncuT by a median line Adfronta sutures do not terminate in the occipital sinus Sar vi. ucelli IV, VI, and V do rot form a right angle ocelli III anH IV nearly touchtng. Mandibular t«th prominent^ theiAases^acutely ang l J Second segment of antenna not tlvice as long as wide. Setigerous tuSS Ten^™ U K O a n n*~° CC 7A in Canida a " d U " ited States south l ° Virgin, ir h I ' KansaS 'J f nd Arizona, more abundant northward. In Nebraska it has been reported only from Lincoln, Lancaster county INebraska W-MARKED CUTWORM, Agrotis c-ni S rum Linnaeus </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms A 1 would form an obtuse angle. Ocular seta O l just posterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a just posterioi to a line between the center of ocellus VI and ocular seta O 3 . Ocellus II closer to I than to III, ocellus III closer to IV than to II, a line between the centers of ocelli IV, VI, and V would nearly form a right angle. Mandib - ular teeth prominent. Second segment of antenna two and one-half times as long as wide. Setigerous tubercles minute. A light band below the spiracles. Skin smooth. Anal proleg with 34 crochets. Distribution. — This species is found in Canada and in northern United States as far south as Kentucky, Missouri, Kansas, Colorado, Utah, Nevada, and California. In Nebraska it has been reported only from Lincoln, Lan - caster county. Seasonal Abundance. — The Nebraska specimens have been collected between April 22 and May 23. Habits. — According to the literature this is a climbing cutworm at - tacking apple, currant, and gooseberries and at times is also a garden type. Food Plants. — The larvae are general feeders, attacking a wide variety of plants such as apple, asparagus, bean, boxelder, buckwheat, corn, clover, cabbage, currant, celery, cauliflower, chicory, gooseberry, grasses, lettuce, soft maple, peach, pumpkin, plantain, tobacco, wheat, and wild endive. VARIEGATED CUTWORM, Lycophotia margariiosa form uitidti (Hiibncr) Description. — Body length 35 to 46 mm. Head 3.0 to 3.2 mm. wide, smooth, shining, light to dark brown in color with variable markings, usually with dark brown submedian arcs adjacent to the adfrontal sutures and often extending posterior on either side of the epicranial suture, reticu - lations usually present. Body color varies from pale gray to a dark mottled brown intermixed with red and yellow, yellowish mid-dorsal spots visible on the third thoracic segment and at least the first four abdominal seg - ments, a velvety black spot on the dorsum of eighth abdominal segment, a yellowish area following it. A black dash anterior to seta II on each segment, less distinct on thorax, below this an orange dash, then a dark band extending to and including the spiracles, a yellowish or orange band below the spiracles to and including seta V, venter pale flecked with white. Cervical shield brown, heavily mottled with dark brown intermixed with yellow. Adfrontal sutures do not terminate in the occipital sinus. Epicranial puncture P b anterior to a line between the epicranial setae P- and P l . Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. The ocular puncture O a variable, either on or posterior to a line between ocellus VI and ocular seta O :t . Ocelli III and IV closer than I and II, ocelli IV, VI, and V forming an acute angle. Mandibular teeth bluntly rounded, their bases not acutely angled. A line through the mandibular setae Md 1 and Md- prolonged would not pass through the teeth. Second segment of antenna from two to three times as long as wide. Setae not tuberculate. Spiracles black within. Skin smooth. An - terior prolegs with 18 to 23 crochets, anal prolegs with 28 to 30 crochets. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 81 Distribution. — It occurs throughout the United States, Canada, and into Mexico. In Nebraska it has been found practically all over the state, most abundant in the southern and eastern portions. Seasonal Abundance. — Damage in this state has been reported chiefly during the month of June and agai 1 in July. Habits. — Most of its feeding is above ground. It may assume an army - like habit when numerous or it may climb trees. It prefers moist locations. Food Plants. — In Nebraska it his been reported from corn, alfalfa, sweet clover, potatoes, peas, and otb;r garden vegetables. Other states re - port a long list of food plants. BRISTLY CUTWORM, Polia rcni s era (Stephens) Description. — Body length 25 mm. Head 2.0 to 2.1 mm. wide, brown in color, rough in texture with dark brown submedian arcs. Dorsum a dull brown bordered by a narrow ight band just below seta II, then a darker band with a lighter band bdow the spiracles, venter a dull gray. Cervical shield brown and cut by ii faint median and two lateral lines. Ocular areas dark with reticulations extending up and posterior. Adfruntal sderites darker than front, adfront'l sutures not terminating in the oc - i cipital sinus. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line drawn between ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a pDsterior to a line between the centers of ocellus VI and seta O :l . Ocelli IV, VI, and V form an acute angle. Mandibular teeth distinct and not acutely angled at their base. A line drawn through the mandibular seta : Md 1 and Md 2 prolonged would not bisect the teeth. Second segment of antenna about twice as long as wide. Spiracles black within. Skin granules composed of low horny or bristly plates. Anterior proleg with 7 to 13 crochets, anal proleg with about 26 crochets. Distribution. — Its general distribution is in the United States east of the Rocky Mountains. In Nebraska it has been found only in Lancaster and Madison counties, although the moths have been captured in Douglas and Cuming counties. Its range is probably quite general, as others have re - ported it from Kansas, Colorado, and North Dakota. Seasonal Abundance. — Our reports of damage by this species have all come during May and early June. Habits. — It is chiefly a grass and garden pest, usually feeding on the roots. Food Plants. — It feeds on corn, clover, alfalfa, grasses, turnips, cabbage, tobacco, weeds, and garden flowers, BRONZE CUTWORM, Neihelodes emmedoniz (Cramer) Description. — Body length 35 tc 45 mm. Head 4.2 to 4.5 mm. wide, smooth, shining light brown with few markings. Labrum, antennae and adfrontal sclerites light colored. Eody color dark bronze-brown, cut by five pale stripes, the mid-dorsal one distinct throughout its length, on </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms either side a bronze-brown stripe containing seta II in its lower edge, then a light stripe followed by another dark stripe with the spiracles in its lower edge and another light stripe below this. Cervical shield bronze - brown cut by five pale lines. Adfrontal sutures do not terminate in the °A C 3 ipJt^ f mUS - Anterior seta A 2 about equidistant between A 1 and A-. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line drawn between ocelli IV and VI Ucular puncture O a anterior to or on a line between ocellus VI and ocular seta IV, VI, and V form a right or obtuse angle. Ocelli HI and IV widely separated. Mandibles with two median, rounded tC f xii 1 ™ JViYf P °,° rIy defined ones ' A Hne throu e h the mandibular setae Md» and Md* prolonged would bisect the teeth: Second segment of antenna about twice as long as wide. Setigerous tubercles minute Seta II on prothorax missing. Spiracles black within. Skin smooth, apparently not granulate Sides of prolegs with a brown patch. Anal proleg with lo to 20 crochets. ° Distribution.— Occurs throughout the northern United States and Can - ada east of the Rocky Mountains. In Nebraska it has been reported from Dixon, Otoe, Lancaster, Valley, Hitchcock, Cheyenne, and Morrill counties MavTnTh 31 A .^.? dan , ce T '- T h«=y have been reported from the middle of May to the middle of July— one generation a year with the moths flying in September and October. B treef abitS "~ USUaUy f ° Und °" the gr ° Und but at times wiU climb Food Plants.— They prefer grasses and cereal crops but sometimes as - cend fruit trees and feed on the buds and leaves. TRUE ARMYWORM, Cirphis tmipuncta (Haworth) Description.-Body length 30 to 35 mm. Head 3.0 to 3.5 mm. wide, smooth, cream to light brown color with dark reticulations giving a honey-comb-like appearance. A band of dark brown bordering the ad - frontal sutures and extending back along the ultra-posterior setae. Body brown with fuscous markings, cut by one median and two lateral white lines, the median line distinct on the thorax but interrupted on the ab - domen. On either side a broad band of mottled brown, darker at the edges and extending to seta II, a narrow white line below this, followed by a band of orange or brown edged with white, then a dark brown stripe to the spiracles edged with white. Below the spiracles an orange stripe edged with white, venter gray to cream with fine brownish mottling! Cervical shield brown with fuscous markings. Adfrontal sutures do not reach the occipital sinus. Posterior cranial puncture P» almost on a direct hne between the posterior setae P* and P* and about equidistant Detween them. A line drawn between the anterior setae A 3 , A 2 and A 1 would form an obtuse angle. Ocular seta O* nearly on a line between ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O» between ocellus VI and ocular seta O 3 A hne between ocelh IV, VI and V would form a right angle. Mandibles with one or two obscure teeth. Second segment of antenna at least three </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebr. Agr. Exp. StA. Research Bulletin 81 times as long as wide. Spiracles lark brown to black within. Skin not noticeably granulated. Prolegs with a brown lateral patch, anal prolegs with about 24 crochets. Distribution. — This species occurs throughout the United States east of the Rocky Mountains. In Nebiaska it has been reported from most of the counties in the eastern third or the state, and fewer towards the west. Seasonal Abundance. — Armywcprms are usually most abundant from the middle of June to the middle of| August, although they are frequently found both earlier and later than these dates. The second brood probably does the most damage. Habits. — When abundant they go in large armies, eating nearly every - thing as they go. Food Plants. — They prefer grasses and cereals but will eat almost any - thing in their paths when on trie march. They have been reported at - tacking a long list of vegetableSj some fruits, and many weeds. WHEAT-HEAD ARMYWORM, Nelaicania albilinca (Hubncr) Description.-— Body length 25 :o 30 mm. Head 3.0 mm. wide, smooth, dull cream color with two broad, light-brown stripes extending from the dypeus up and back along the adfrontal and epicranial sutures. Three dark lines extend up and back irom the oculars with fine cross reticula - tions. Body color a grayish or gre ;nish-gray, with a broad stripe on dorsum to and including seta I, cut by a narrow light line throughout its length, a broad, pale stripe with tubercli: II at its upper margin and tubercle III in its lower margin, the lower ha f of the stripe mottled with red or brown, a broad, brownish stripe including the spiracles, and a pale subspiracular stripe. Cervical shield concoloro is with remainder of body. Ocular area light. Adfrontal sutures do no: extend to the occipital sinus. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O a anterior to a line drawn between ocellus VI and ocular seta O 3 . Ocelli I, II, III, and IV aboit equidistant, ocelli IV, VI, and V form - ing a right or obtuse angle. Mandibular teeth bluntly rounded, their bases not acutely i angled. A line through the mandibular setae Md 1 and Md 2 prolonged would not pass through the teeth. Second segment of antenna not more than twice as 1 &gt;ng as wide. Spiracles white within. Skin very finely granulate with minute, flat, pavement-like granules. Anal proleg with 28 to 32 crochets. Distribution. — Occurs throughout eastern United States north of the Tennessee river and west to Colorado, New Mexico, and Arizona. In Ne - braska it has been reported frori Kimball, Box Butte, Morrill, Cheyenne, Garden, Hooker, Chase, Hitchock, Valley, Kearney, Saunders, and Lan - caster counties. Seasonal Abundance. — Damage in this state has been reported usually rrom the last week in June to the middle of July and again from the middle of August until the last of September. Habits. — It climbs plants ami eats on the heads of its food plants. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms Food Plants.— It feeds on various grasses and cereal crops, showing a preference for the heads. It is known to attack timothy, wheat, barley rye, and clover. " GLASSY CUTWORM, Sidemia devastator (Brace) Description.— Body length 35 to 40 mm. Head 4.0 to 4.5 mm wide smooth, shining reddish-brown with no conspicuous markings. Body a dirty whitish color with a greenish tinge, no markings. Cervical shield conspicuous, shining brown cut by a light median line. Ocular area not darker than adjacent areas. The adfrontal sutures reach the occipital sinus. A line through the anterior setae A 3 to A 2 to A 1 would form a right angle. Ocular seta O 1 posterior to a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocular puncture O* on a line between ocellus Z !?u , Vl? ° Celli IV ' VI ' and V £orm a ri g h t angle. Mandibular teeth blundy rounded, their bases not acutely angled. A line through the mandibular setae Md 1 and Md 2 prolonged would pass through the teeth. Second segment of antenna less than twice as long as wide Spir - acles narrow and long, white within. Skin not distinctly granulate a glassy shining appearance. Anal prolegs with 12 to 14 crochets. Distribution.— Widely distributed in Canada and in the United States from the Atlantic to the Pacific, more abundant in the northern part of its range, less abundant southwards. In Nebraska it has been reported from Grant, in Perkins county. Seasonal Abundance.— They winter as larvae, doing most of their injury in April and May, and then pupate in June and July. Habits.— This species seldom comes to the surface even at night It works below the surface of the ground in burrows, eating off roots and cutting underground stems. Food Plants.— It feeds on various kinds of grasses, wheat, oats, barley corn, cabbage, beans, radishes, strawberries, hollihocks, and lettuce. FALL ARMYWORM, Laphrygma frttgiperda (Abbott and Smith) Description.— Body length about 25 mm. Head 2.6 to 2.9 mm. wide, with heavy dark-brown reticulations leaving areas from brown to cream colored, lightest areas above and posterior to oculars and along the epi - cranial suture. Body dark brown cut by one median and one lateral light line, the median being faint on the abdomen. On either side of the median line is a broad, light-brown band with brownish and reddish-brown mottlings, laterad a narrow yellowish line just below seta II, then a broader brown line and a reddish line of the same width, the two merging on the thorax. A yellow band with reddish mottlings just below the fpiracles, the venter a cream color with reddish patches. Cervical shield dark brown cut by one median and two lateral light lines. Adfrontal areas cream to white The adfrontal sutures do not reach the occipital sinus. Ocelli IV, VI, and V form an acute angle. Mandibles with at least five distinct teeth. Labial puncture L a situated even with the second median </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 81 ! . ; seta M 2 , labium with lateral grooves. Second segment of antenna more than twice as long as wide. Setigerous tubercle III much larger than IV, tubercles I and II about the same size. Spiracles light to dusky within. Skin granules Bat or pavement-like. Anal prolcg with 20 to 24 crochets. Distribution. — This species occurs from New York to Florida and west to Nebraska, Kansas, Texas, and New Mexico. In Nebraska it has been reported from Cass, Pawnee, Ga^e, Lancaster, Dodge, Seward, Saline, York, Jefferson, Thayer, Clay, Meirick, Dawson, and Boyd counties. Seasonal Abundance. — It is usually reported from the middle of Sep - tember to the latter part of October. It seldom winters in this state. Crosby and Leonard state that "Recent observations have shown that in southern Nebraska there are three generat ons a year." Habits. — This species assumes an army-like habit and devours the en - tire plant. It climbs trees when asundant. Food Plants. — It is a general feeder, eating garden and field crops very readily. It is fond of bent-grass. COTTON CUTWORM, Prodenia ornithogalli (Gucncc) Description. — Body length 20 to 36 mm. Head 2.6 to 3.0 mm. wide. Color variable, the light form with a brown head and white adfrontal sclerites, the dark form with nearly all black or dark brown. Cervical shield brown, faintly cut by a me dian line which terminates on the second thoracic segment, and two latera lines, a row of lateral dots, distinct on the second thoracic segment, fairt on the third, larger posteriorly. Seta I located in the apex of the triangular dots and seta II in the lower posterior corner. Between these the dorswm is either a light reddish brown band or dark colored, below these triangles is a cream to bright yellow band sometimes with four narrow brown lines in it, and below this a dark band with the spiracles in the lower edge. Ocular area light. Adfrontal area white. Adfrontal sutures do net reach the occipital sinus. Ocular seta O 1 anterior to or on a line between the centers of ocelli IV and VI. Ocelli IV, VI, and V form an acute angle. Mandibular teeth prominent, bluntly rounded at their base. Second segment of antenna about three times as long as wide. Spiracles light brown with a black rim. Anterior prolegs with 17 to 25 crochets, anal prolegs with 32 to 36 crochets. Distribution. — Occurs from Massachuestts to Florida and westward to Minnesota, Nebraska, New Mexico, Arizona, and California, but usually common only in the south. In Nebraska it has been reported from Cass, Gage, Lancaster, Polk, and Cldy counties, while moths have been cap - tured in Cuming and Johnson counties. Probably fairly common in the eastern part of the state. Seasonal Abundance. — Our species has been caught in July and the remainder in September and early October. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Key to Nebraska Cutworms and Armyworms Habits. — They generally feed on many wild and cultivated plants. As a climber it attacks fruit buds. Food Plants. — It attacks corn, wheat, cotton, tobacco, beet, cabbage, potato, tomato, salsify, asparagus, watermelon, alfalfa, clover, and buds of peach, raspberry, and grape. BIBLIOGRAPHY Crosby, C. R., and Leonard, M. D. 1918. Manual of Vegktablf. Gardkv Insects. The Macmillan Company, New York. P. 293. Crumb, S. C. 1915. Tobacco Cutworms. Jour. Econ. Ent. 8:392-96, illus. 1926. The Bronzed Cutworm. Ncphelodes emmedonia (Cramer) (Lcpidoptera). Proc Ent. Soc. Wash., 28:201-07, illus. 1927. The Army Worms. Bui. Brookl. Ent. Soc. 22:41-55, illus. 1929. Tobacco Cutworms. U. S. Dept. Agr. Tech. Bui. 88, pp. 1-179. Dyar, H. G. 1895. A Classification of Lepidopterous Larvae. Ann. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 8:194 - !S95. Additional Notes on the Classification of Lepidopterous Larvae Trans. N. Y. Acad. Sci. 14: 49-62. 1896. Note on the Head Setae on Perophora mefsheimerii. Jour. N. Y. Ent. Soc 4:92-93. 1901. On the Fluctuation of the Post-Spiracllar Tubercle in Noctuid Larvae. Proc. Ent. Soc. Wash. 4:370-73. Forbes, W. T. M. 1910. A Structural Study of Some Caterpillars. Ann. Ent. Soc. Amer 3-94 - 143, 11 plates. 1916. On Cfrtain Caterpillar Homolocies. Jour. N. Y. Ent. Soc. 24:137-42. Fracker, S. B. 1915. The Classification of Lepidopterous Larvae. Uni. Illinois Biological Mono - graphs 2 (No. 1):1-169, 10 plates. Garman, H. 1920. Observations on the Structure and Coloration of the Larval Corn-ear Worm, etc., and a Few Other Lepidopterous Larvae. Ky. Agr. Exp. Sta Bui. 227, pp. 55-84, 11 plates. Gibson, Arthur 1915. Cutworms and Their Control. Dom. Canada Dcpt. Agr. Ent. Branch Bui 10, pp. 1-31. Hampson, George F. 1903. Catalogue of the Lepidoptera Phalaenae in the British Museum. Heinrich, Carl 1916. On the Taxonomic Value of Some Larval Characters in the Lepidop - tera. Proc. Ent. Soc. Wash. 18:154. 1919. Note on the European Corn Borer and Its Nearest American Allies, with Description of Larvae, Pupae and One New Species. Jour. Aer. Res 18(No. 3):1-12. Luginbill, Philip 1928. The Fall Army Worm. U. S. D. A. Tech. Bui. 34, pp. 1-91, illus. Mosher, Edna 1919. Notes on Lepidopterous Borers Found in Plants, with Special Refer - ence to the European Corn Borer. Jour. Econ. Ent. 12:258-68. T3M| </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>