<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Comparative Study of Pneumatic Tires and Steel Wheels of Farm Tractors</title>
               <date value="1934-09">1934-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 291 September, 1934 A Comparative Study of Pneumatic Tires and Steel Wheels on Farm Tractors C. W. SMITH AND LLOYD W. HURLBUT Deportment of Agricultural Engineering A good use for rubber tires. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Farm Operation Tests ...; g Tire Inflation Pressure Te5t5....... j- ErTeet on fuel consumption - jq Ettect on speed 2J. EiTect on travel reduction oj Relation to drawbar pull 03 Relation. to horsepower '■■ 03 Weight Trar.sfer and Trave; Redaction 05 Wheel Effdency Tests 2 i The Efett of Acdir.e Weight on tqe Traction of Pneninatic Tire 5....35. ...35 Srabb^e Field and Tractor Testing Course Comparison Tests 37 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A Comparative Study of Pneumatic Tires and Steel Wheels on Farm Tractors C. W. SMITH AKD LLOYI, vr. KVP.LEUT The adaptation of pneumatic tires to farm tractors is a development of recent origin. Considerable publicity wa= given to it m 1931 and 1932. so much that the Agricultural Engineering Department received a steadily increasing stream of inquiries. In order to answer them it was necessary to engage m a study of the problem. A set of tires was secured during the summer of 1932. with which investigational work was carried on during the fall and winter and the spring of 1933. In June. 1933, a co-operative project was arranged with _ four rubber companies : for the purpose of securing additional data. Several phases of experimental work were carried out and the results are reported m this bulletin. FARM OPERATION TESTS One very important phase of these studies is the farrr. cperation tests. The purpose of these tests was to do a large number of the most important farm operations requiring tractive power, recording from such the data of rr.ost interest to farmers, pounds of fuel per acre and acres per hour. Where such data were not practical, as m sweeping" hay, pounds of fuel per hour were recorded. Ir. picking corn*, further data reflecting the character of the work were secured. The genera] behavior of the wheel equipment was closely observed under all circumstances and those observations were carefully recorded. The_ general plan of procedure, as conceived at the outset. was that two tractors of the same rr.ake and mode] were to be run m the same field at the same time, each to pull, as nearly as possible, equal loads. One tractor was to be ecuir^ed with pneumatic tires and the other with steel wheels and sijade lugs. When half the work was finished, the whee". ecuiv^rr.en: was to be interchanged and the work comp'.et-ed. In this way comparable data could be secured for the two types of whee] equipment on two similar tractors under the same weather and soil conditions, and also comparable data for the same tractor and two types of wheel equipment m as short a time as p&lt;&gt;ssiole. Tnis plan was adhere-d to m the main. 1 but m _ 'T M JR«BB«» TSjj vxti Bi:i&gt;er O~- &amp;* B 7. C--.0i.-iti Co. -it Ovjirtz-r 72* tz.i ri-::«r Co, tad tit V^z-jni Su.-j&amp; 7:rt Co - *" !r -'-7 '=■'■ B&amp;-opma5cm :■; At ASSt-daOmot Kit.. O:. -it Jtia Deert Kit™ ' : rreztLZ i Hirllt lafc. il: -it lz.-*rz-f^: r.i.. B*meUß O:.. r. irti jiaa&amp;k •--. b*jtj -. .-. ?•&lt;&gt;•«;■s or :-.Tr-L ;.: Eer; is -^t •*=■• it,: n-.it ; .t=.t r=.t Hu-.i 3rj&gt;Jita.T« 'wnsvtonr. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 several instances circumstances arose which made it advisable to report the data as two separate tests instead of as one averaged test. 3 The operations selected for study were 1. Cultivating listed corn, first, second, and third times, 2. Mowing alfalfa and prairie hay, 3. Sweeping alfalfa and prairie hay, 4. Binding oats, 5. Combining wheat, 6. Plowing barley and wheat stubble 1 and sweet clover and alfalfa sod, 7. Drilling wheat, 8. Picking corn. The land and crop facilities for this plan were not available at the Experiment Station, nor on any concentrated area nearby. To secure them it was necessary to co-operate with farmers over a territory extending from 115 miles southwest and 120 miles northwest of Lincoln, Nebraska, to 95 miles east of the same city. Twenty-four farm operation tests were run. The results from these, so far as fuel consumption and acres covered per hour are concerned, are shown graphically in Figure 1. A description of each test follows. To avoid repetition of the wheel equipment, this has been tabulated for all tests in Table 1. Test No. 1, Cultivating corn the first time over. — This test was made with one Farmall 30 tractor and a four-row listed-corn cultivator. Pneumatic tires were not used on the front wheels. The land was rolling, the soil a silt loam and very dry. When equipped with rubber the tractor used 88.95 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 10.31 per cent 3 A plowing test was planned with a field of approximately twenty acres of alfalfa sod, two Allis-Chalmers Model "U* 1 tractors, and two three-bottom plows. The field was carefully divided into four equal lands so that each tractor would have one land for steel wheels and one land for rubber tires. Preliminary arrangements, such as assembl - ing the equipment, making plow adjustments, and getting moldboards to scour, had taken more than one day. All such preparations having been completed, the tractors were started off on their respective lands at approximately the same time. No sooner had a couple of rounds been made than it could be seen that high speed was too fast for the land beings plowed with rubber tires, although the tractor could handle the load almost as well in high as in intermediate. A strip of blue grass sod had worked its • way out into this land and. when plowed in high, the sod rolled completely over, landing right side up. This made it necessary to complete this land in intermediate gear although the data were wanted in high if within the power of the tractor to (to in high. On the other land plowed with rubber tires, it was possible to travel in high and do a good job of plowing. This was done and it was not deemed advisable to average the rubber tire data. Therefore the data are reported as two tests, each with one tractor, although taken in the same field at the same time. Another instance is the data reported as tests No. 23 and No. 24. Two Farmall tractors of about the same age and general appearance were secured. Plans were mapped out and both outfits started. The tractor with steel wheels could not pull the corn picker and wagon in intermediate gear so was driven in low gear. However, the other tractor, when equipped with steel wheels, could pull the load in intermediate gear and did throughout the test, with the exception of a few short shifts into low gear. Since one tractor ran in low gear and the other in intermediate gear when equipped with steel, it seemed advisable not to average the data but to report as two separate tests although run in the same field at the same time. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors Table 1. — Tractors and wheel equipment used in farm operations. Rubber-tired wheels Steel wheels Name of Operation Rear Rear Front Rear I Rear Front xrac or tire wheel tire wheel lug wheel s Y li v.ize wta. size size I aize size "ng In. No. In. In. In. In. Allia-Chalmers U Plowing ll l /4x24 3 6x16 42x11^ 5 28x6 Yes Farmall 20 CultivatinK 0 x36 2 Steel 42x12 6 25x4 Yes Farmall 20 Combining 11 '.4x24 2 Steel 42x12 5 26x4 Yes Farmall 20 Picking corn HV4x24 0 6x16 42x12 5 25x4 Ye; Farmall 20 Plowing 9 x36 2 0x16 42x12 5 25x4 Yes Farmall 30 Cultivating ll'.ixiM 2 Steel 42x12 5 25x4 Yes John Deere G.P. CultivatinK Il 1 ,4x24 2 Steel 42%xlO 5 24x6 Yes John Deere G. P. Mowing alfalfa 11*4x24 2 6x16 42-%xMJ 0 24x6 No John Deere G.P. Mowing native grass il',x21 2 6x16 42%xlO 5 24x6 Yes John Deere G.P. Sweeping Il'4x24 2 6x16 42%xlO 5 24x6 Yes John Deere G.P. Plowing lUix24 2 6x16 4294x10 5 24x6 Yes John Deere D Plowinsr 12?4x2H 3 7%.xl8 46x12 B 28x6 Yes CaseCC Drilling wheat 0 x36 2 Steel Open 4 25x4 Yes CaseL Discing 12%x28 3 7',-jxl8 48x12 5 30x6 Yes more land per hour. The speed of the tractor was less in any one gear than when equipped with steel wheels and lugs. However, it was possible to drive the tractor in high with rubber tires but only in intermediate otherwise. It was harder to keep the rubber-tired tractor on the lister ridges. Part of this difficulty was due to the tread having been widened by eleven inches when rubber tires were installed, and this made them run on the outer portions of the ridges instead of on the centers as the steel wheels did. There was less dust about the tractor and operator when the rubber tires were used. Test No. 2, Cultivation of corn the second time over. — This was the average of three runs made with two Farmall tractors and International two-row cultivators. The two tractors were first used in the same field, each using both types of wheel equipment according to the general plan. One of these tractors was then run in a second field first on rubber and then on steel. The soil was a silt loam and quite dry. The first field was rolling, the second level. When equipped with rubber tires the tractors used 80.9 per cent as much fuel per acre as when equipped with steel wheels and covered 6.24 per cent more land per hour. There was less dust about the tractor and operator. The pneumatic tires left a track in the first field which might have been detrimental had there been more moisture in the soil. A set of sweeps or duck feet was installed for the work in the second field and they defaced the track completely. Test No. 3, Cultivation of corn the third time over. — This was made with one John Deere General Purpose tractor and a three-row John Deere cultivator. The tractor was run in </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 high gear. The field was largely level and the soil a black silt loam. The tractor when equipped with rubber used 82.1 per cent as much fuel per acre as with steel wheels and covered 9.25 per cent more land per hour. The rubber-tired tractor was more comfortable to ride, just as easy to handle, and made less dust. The standard equipment on the three-row cultivator completely obliterated the wheel tracks. Test No. 4, Combining wheat. — This test was made with one Farmall tractor pulling a 12-foot International combine in wheat making about 25 bushels per acre and having a heavy growth of straw. The field was level and the soil a sandy clay loam. The test with steel wheels was made in the afternoon of one day and that of pneumatic tires in the after - noon of the day following. No change in conditions occurred between the two days except that the field was smaller and more turning was required the second day. With pneumatic tires the tractor required 78 per cent as much fuel per acre as with steel wheels and covered 27.61 per cent more land per hour. While the steel wheel equipment was being used it was necessary to run the tractor in low gear; with the rubber tires it was run in intermediate gear and throttled when necessary. Test No. 5, Binding; oats. — This test was made with one Farmall 20 tractor pulling a seven-foot ground-drive binder. One-fourth the acreage was first cut with steel wheel and lug equipment, then one-half the acreage with pneumatic tires, and the last fourth with steel wheels and lugs. The field was rolling and the soil a silt loam. The oats were short, light, and greener than when usually cut. The tractor was driven in intermediate gear throughout the test. When equipped with rubber tires the tractor used 80.7 per cent as much fuel per acre as when equipped with steel wheels and covered 14.22 per cent more land per hour. Test No. 6, Mowing alfalfa. — This test, which was made in second-cutting alfalfa making about three-fourths of a ton per acre, is the average of three runs. Two Farmall tractors and power mowers working simultaneously cut thirty acres. Then one of these tractors was used in the usual manner to cut a second field of 15 acres. With rubber tires 85.14 per cent as much fuel per acre was used as with steel wheels and 94.73 per cent as much land per hour was covered. Test No. 7, Mowing alfalfa. — This was made with two John Deere General Purpose tractors and seven-foot power mowers. The tractors when equipped with steel wheels had neither lugs on the rear nor skid rings on the front wheels. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">7 Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors jB • HmBm • ■-' I &lt; s^35Sb"- '■ ■■■ ■■■' 1 s la - •^^^■■.-■'' ;:' : - f '.' "^^nI^SB ■ '■ i </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 Sam H SaKftv w&amp;Si r I :jy ' mP Ww-' ° VBM kSpk»" fc«w-!? ■ks5vT-fex5.fi c </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors IT '^B [TTljfi. 'jRy - V ',. J * 1 ;., £§01 ! ? C </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 Both tractors were run throughout in high gear. The meadow was level. The rubber-tired tractor used 94.35 per cent as much fuel per acre as the steel-wheeled tractor and covered 1.45 per cent less land per hour. The rubber-tired tractor was much easier riding. Test No. 8, Mowing prairie grass. — This test was made with two John Deere General Purpose tractors and two power mowers. High gear was used throughout. The meadow was level but rough. Each rear steel wheel had one row of 24 five - inch lugs. The rubber-tired tractor when compared with the steel-wheeled tractor used 88.61 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 4.95 per cent less grpund per hour. The rubber-tired tractor was somewhat easier riding and made better corners. Skid rings on the front wheels hindered the steel-wheeled tractor in making corners. The steel lugs poked hay into the ground, which was objectionable. Test No. 9, Plowing barley stubble. — This test was made with two John Deere General Purpose tractors and two-bottom plows. Wheel equipment was not interchanged during this test. Fuel consumption was corrected according to the fuel - consumption characteristics of the two tractors, which were known at this time. The rubber-tired tractor traveled in high gear, while the steel-wheeled tractor was compelled to travel in intermediate gear. The rubber-tired tractor used 87.14 per cent as much fuel per acre as the steel-wheeled tractor and covered 25.69 per cent more land per hour. It was easier to ride and steered as easily. When rubber tires were installed on the general pur - pose tractor, the tread was widened. This made the furrow wheel, when equipped with rubber, run on some of the loose dirt instead of directly on the bottom of the furrow. Test No. 10, Sweeping alfalfa hay. — This test was made with two John Deere General Purpose tractors and two tractor sweeps. Neither lugs nor skid rings were used on the steel wheels. No wheel weights were used in conjunction with the pneumatic tires. An attempt was made to load both sweeps heavily and alike, but owing to the limitation in traction of the smooth steel wheels, the rubber-tired tractor moved more hay. Both tractors were driven in high gear. The rubber-tired tractor when compared with the steel - wheeled tractor used 94.12 per cent as much fuel per hour. Had they moved equal amounts of hay, the results would have shown a greater advantage for the rubber-tired tractor. Turning and steering were unsatisfactory with 15 pounds of pressure in front, but when the inflation pressure was raised to 26 pounds it was quite satisfactory, much better than </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors i with smooth steel wheels. The rubber-tired tractor was more comfortable to ride. Test No. 11, Sweeping prairie hay. — This test was made with two John Deere General Purpose tractors equipped with power sweeps bucking hay to the same stacker at the same time. In mowing with the general purpose tractor and power mower it was necessary to confine the lugs to one row per wheel. This lug arrangement was not changed for sweeping. Both tractors traveled in high gear. The personal element of the driver entered here more than in most other tests, and where it was the aim to have both tractors move the same amount of hay, it was thought that the steel-wheeled tractor moved a little more hay than the one equipped with pneumatic tires. This was no fault of the wheel equipment. Both moved all the stacker was able to handle most of the time and more part of the time. No change in wheel equipment was made for this test but the fuel consumption was corrected for the difference in the two tractors, the characteristics of which were known at that time. The rubber-tired tractor used 92.05 per cent as much fuel per hour as the steel-wheeled tractor. It tore up the meadow much less where it approached the stacker. Test No. 12, Plowing barley stubble. — This test was made with two John Deere General Purpose tractors and two-bottom plows. Lugged chains were installed on the pneumatic tires and used throughout the test. The tractors when equipped with pneumatic tires and chains traveled in high gear but were compelled to travel in intermediate gear when equipped with the steel wheels and lugs. The rubber-tired tractor, compared with the steel-wheeled tractor, used 91:05 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 19 per cent more land per hour. The lugged chains made the tractor rough riding. When plowing in sandy soil, a rubber - tired tractor having no chains keeps the plow running at more nearly a uniform depth than a tractor equipped with steel wheels and spade lugs. The steel wheel with lugs running in a furrow in sandy soil digs up the bottom of the furrow con - siderably. The furrow wheel of the plow and the plow are lowered by this action. Consequently, as a steel- wheeled tractor strikes a sandy spot where its going is hardest, it automatically aggravates the situation by sinking the plow deeper. The tires with lugged chains were not as good as the plain tires in this respect, but better than the steel wheels and spade lugs. The chains were used on the tires for 10 hours of plowing and no appreciable wear could be noticed, attributable to the chains. The chains were tight and crept but little. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 Test No. 13, Cultivating corn the third time over. — This test was made with one John Deere General Purpose tractor and a three-row cultivator. The tractor was compelled to travel in intermediate gear with steel wheels but traveled in high gear with pneumatic tires. The rubber-tired tractor, compared with the steel-wheeled tractor, used 6.53 per .cent more fuel per acre and covered 1.55 per cent more land per hour. This tractor was in poor mechanical condition and was over - loaded when driven in high gear. It would have been better judgment to travel in intermediate gear with both types of wheel equipment in this instance. This is one of two times encountered in this work where the rubber-tired tractor used more fuel than the steel-wheeled tractor. Test No. 14, Mowing prairie grass. — This test was made with two John Deere General Purpose tractors and power mowers on a meadow that was unusually rough. Where mowing was usually done in high gear it was thought better to do this in intermediate gear. Time was also taken to make square, clean corners. This procedure cut down the acreage and increased the fuel consumption. No change in wheel equipment was made in this test. The fuel consumption was corrected to account for the difference in the tractors, their characteristics in this respect being known at the time. The rubber-tired tractor, compared with the steel-wheeled tractor, used 89.7 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 11.68 per cent less land per hour. Test No. 15, Cultivation of corn the second time over. — This test was made with two general-purpose tractors and three-row cultivators. The wheel equipment was not inter - changed for this test. The fuel consumption characteristics for the two tractors were not known at the time of this test and, consequently, no fuel consumption data are given. The rubber-tired tractor traveled in high gear, the other in inter - mediate gear. The rubber-tired tractor, compared with the steel-wheeled tractor, covered 2.21 per cent more ground per hour. The rubber-tired tractor could not be steered satisfactorily with pneumatic tires in front inflated to 15-pound pressure. Steel wheels with skid bands were used in front on both machines. Test No. 16, Plowing -wheat stubble. — -This test was made with one John Deere Model D tractor and a three-bottom plow. The tractor was driven in high gear and the depth of plowing was six inches. A dense growth of grass and weeds covered the field. The tractor when equipped with rubber used 91 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors II _ ZZ2ESZ25 m/tlfma alfalfa hatt ■■■ STEEL WHEELS i '^■■■■■■■B »test Kin.ii ~- G 223 RUBBER TIRES - J -j-j- - - I- ■'"fl 1 '! Y'j {'fTTf W ""' N ° "*"" " AT * FUEL-POUNDS PER HOUR I |_FUEL-POUNDS perACReI Ai-^J " * ** * " « 4 — I I ACRES PER HOUR </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 90.96 per cent as much land per hour as when it was equipped with steel wheels and lugs. Test No. 17, Plowing wheat stubble. — This test was made with one John Deere Model D tractor and a three-bottom plow. The magneto gave some trouble during this test, not enough to interrupt it yet noticeable to the driver. For this reason it was not averaged in with Test 16 but the two are reported separately. It was run in high gear and the depth was six inches. The tractor when equipped with rubber and compared with steel wheel equipment used 97.71 per cent as many pounds of fuel per acre and covered 93.02 per cent as much land per hour. Test No. 18, Plowing sweet clover sod. — This was made with one John Deere Model D tractor and a three-bottom plow driven in high gear and plowing six inches deep. It has been contended by some that a tractor can be run with a leaner carburetor setting when equipped with rubber tires than when equipped with steel wheels. The idea was given a trial in this test. The rubber-tired tractor when compared with the steel - wheeled tractor used 84.71 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 85.97 per cent as much ground per hour. It was the opinion of the driver that the rubber equipment did permit using a little leaner mixture. Test No. 19, Plowing alfalfa sod. — This test was made with one Allis-Chalmers Model U tractor and a three-bottom plow. The tractor was driven in intermediate gear. The depth of plowing was four inches. The rubber-tired tractor when compared with the steel-wheeled tractor used 87.27 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 87.4 per cent as much land per hour. The rubber tires slipped enough one or more times on each round to make it necessary to raise the plow to get through. When using the steel wheels it was necessary to shift into low gear once each round and the wheels slipped con - siderably at such times. The steel wheels gave less trouble in the tough spots than the pneumatic tires. Test No. 20, Plowing alfalfa sod. — This test was made with one Allis-Chalmers Model U tractor and a three-bottom 14-inch plow. When equipped with rubber the tractor was driven in high gear; when equipped with steel wheels and lugs it was driven in intermediate. The pneumatic tires slipped enough to make it necessary to raise the plow one or more times each round to get through the toughest spots. The pneu - matic-tired tractor when compared with the steel-wheeled tractor used 1 per cent more fuel per acre and covered 13.60 per cent more land per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors Test No. 21, Plowing wheat stubble. — This was made with two Farmall tractors and two-bottom, 14-inch plows. The field was nearly level and plowed to a depth of six inches. Intermediate gear was used. Comparing the pneumatic-tired tractor with the steel-wheeled tractor, it used 83.3 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 8.22 per cent more land per* hour. Test No. 22, Drilling wheat. — This test was made with a Case CC tractor and a ten-foot press drill. The field was level and had previously been plowed, disked, and harrowed. The tractor was run in intermediate gear with steel wheels and in high gear with pneumatic tires. When equipped with rubber as compared with steel, the tractor used 74.82 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 36.30 per cent more land per hour. Table 2. — A comparison of pneumatic tires with steel, wheels on Farmall tractors carrying two-row cornpickers and pulling wagons — October 20 and 21, cloudy, cool, and dry, south wind, St. Charles White Corn, 25 to 35 bushels per acre, stalks tough and standing well. I Ears Rows Length Wheel Gear Ears missed Ears of rows equipment I per row per row missed No. Ft. No. No. P.et. 14 1,764 Rubber Intermediate 7S8.6 26.0 S.S 8 1,764 Steel Intermediate 712.0 80.5 4.3 16 1,764 Steel Low 762.0 23.6 8.1 8 1,764 Rubber Intermediate 666.0 30.6 4.6 Wheel equip- Gear Percentage of ears in wagons having these numbers of husks ment 0123456789 10 Above Rubber Intermediate 43 10 5 12 7 0 2 0 0 0 3 18 Steel Intermediate 43 1 10 7 9 1 12 2 4 0 0 11 Steel Low 54 3676332200 16 Rubber Intermediate 43 3 10 26992520 10 Test No. 23, Picking corn. 4 — This test was made with one Farmall tractor and an I. H. C. two-row picker mounted on the tractor. The tractor was driven in intermediate gear. A careful check was made on the percentage of corn left in the field and also on the quality of the husking done. This is re - corded in Table 2. In comparing the rubber-tired tractor with the same tractor equipped with steel wheels, it used 89.20 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 89 per cent as much 4 As part of the corn-picking tests No. 23 and No. 24, data were taken on the character of the work done. This has been tabulated in Table 2. It was thought that different speeds of operation might affect the quality and quantity of work done. Every ear in 46 rows, each 1,764 feet long, was counted before the rows had been touched by the machines. Every ear left was counted after the corn had been picked by the machinc3. Bushel-basket samples were taken from the wagons as the tests progressed* and the character of the husking done was recorded. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 ground per hour. In Table 2 it is evident that no significant difference occurred in the character of the work done with the two wheel equipments. Test No. 24, Picking corn.— This test was made with one Farmall tractor and one I. H. C. two-row corn picker mounted on the tractor. This tractor was run in low gear with steel wheel equipment and in intermediate gear with the rubber tires. Data are recorded in Table 2 relative to the character of the work done and other conditions of interest in inter - preting these results. The pneumatic-tired tractor when com - pared with the steel-wheeled tractor used 66.30 per cent as much fuel per acre and covered 32.60 per cent more land per hour. OBSERVATIONS FROM FARM-OPERATION TESTS A rubber-tired tractor is harder to hold on listed corn ridges when cultivating the first time over than a tractor equipped with steel wheels and spade lugs. The difference is less notice - able if the front tires are inflated to 25 pounds or higher and if the installation of the rear rubber-tired wheels has not changed the tread of the tractor. There was little difference in the ease of handling or of riding qualities between tractors equipped with rubber tires and those equipped with steel wheels when cultivating corn, except in handling when on the ridges. The riding qualities of a tractor equipped with rubber tires are very much better than those of one equipped with steel wheels and lugs when going to and from fields and when traveling on the road. The rubber-tired tractor is considerably better all around for haying operations than the tractor equipped with steel wheels and spade lugs. It does not punch hay into the ground. It does not tear up the ground when approaching the stacker with a sweep. In general the riding qualities of the rubber - tired tractor are much better on a meadow. However, on meadows that are very rough, an oscillating, bouncing motion is given to the rubber-tired tractor that not only affects the driver, but, when mowing, is reflected in a rough job due to the up-and-down movement of the sickle bar. A rubber-tired tractor has less traction on firm soil than a tractor with steel wheels and spade lugs but in loose, sandy soil it has more. 5 5 This observation is based on an experience with a ground-drive binder in a very sandy field of oats, for which the rejjular data on fuel per acre and acres per hour were not taken. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors __ A saving in time and fuel can be made on most farm opera - tions by using a tractor equipped with pneumatic tires. This savin? becomes less significant, and may become negative, as drawbar pulls increase, necessitating low gear. This saving increases for those operations which make a relatively light load and permit the use of higher gears. Necessarily the tractors best adapted to rubber tires are those having suf - ficient speeds to utilize this advantage. Front-tire inflation pressures as low as 15 pounds were found to be unsatisfactory. Twenty-six pounds inflation for front tires proved very satisfactory. It would seem that the design of tread on a front tire should be different from that on a rear tire to correspond with the difference in duty of the two. Field conditions were encountered following rains that caused a tractor equipped with pneumatic tires to slip when pulling a combine and also when pulling a plow. Although steel wheels and lugs gave some trouble under the same cir - cumstances, they were more satisfactory than the rubber tires. In applying rubber tires to tractors it was necessary in some instances ,{0 widen the tread (the distance from the center of one rear tire to the center of the other). This handi - capped the rubber tires when comparing them with steel wheels in some row-crop operations. There are many instances where rubber tires would be better on a tractor than steel wheels and lugs from the driver's standpoint and from that of the immediate job at hand. The economics of such installations will necessitate individual de - cisions on the part of purchasers. Brakes on tractors need to be improved if rubber tires are used. This is made necessary by the increased road speeds and the tendency of a rubber-tired tractor to coast at the ends of rows after implements have been raised. TIRE INFLATION PRESSURE TESTS Not only is the adaptation of pneumatic tires to tractors an innovation but at the same time low tire inflation pressures have been recommended, pressures considerably lower than those in common use on automobiles and trucks. An inflation pressure of 12 pounds has been generally recommended for the rear tires, and where the greatest possible traction available was desired it has been suggested that the pressure be reduced to eight pounds. This would lead one to think that the ability of pneumatic tires to secure traction is dependent on low in- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 * flation pressures. Since lowering the inflation pressure in - creases the area of contact between the rubber tire and the ground it seems logical to infer that in some way traction is dependent on area of contact. This seemed to demand that tests be run to determine the experimental answers to several questions, and work on this subject became the second phase . 1 I 1 I I "*M I li TttTTl L I jfe to III u t — r ill i * I § 1 \ | - a &lt;—-zi- S i -h 8 : m n !--^ --&gt;C?:l h- h\ 0 « ft ° _ 1 1* 2 p 1 ~°^ ft Hi £ _^| i ff u fe. ? i— y — I— Mi i! l— jt L \r/—\ I* -***— — l i I l*yr 1 3 N 1 % 5 Si 3 3 3 n S 2 3 ** 52 «nOH 'd'H MvaMVMQ U3d SONHOd - 13HJ tn </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors of this investigation. The work was done on the tractor test - ing course of the Agricultural Engineering Department. The drawbar equipment used in making official tractor tests was used for this and, in addition, some special equipment de - scribed more in detail in a later section on "Wheel Efficiency Tests". Tire inflation pressures were secured by means of a mercury manometer, low-pressure tire gauges not being suf - ficiently accurate for this study. The investigation included 100 individual tests involving five inflation pressures, five drawbar loads, and four gears. Each one of these 100 tests consisted of four separate runs, each for 500 feet, the results of which were averaged. Data were obtained for time, draw - bar pull, fuel consumption, and travel reduction. 0 The results of this phase of the work are reported in the following five sections. THE EFFECT OF TIRE INFLATION PRESSURE. ON FUEL CONSUMPTION The results of this work are shown graphically in Figure 2, in which pounds of fuel per drawbar horsepower hour are plotted against drawbar pull in pounds for each of four gears and five inflation pressures. The fact that the curves lie so closely together for each of the four gears shows that tire in - flation pressure makes no significant difference in the fuel re - quired to do drawbar work. This should not be interpreted to mean that tire inflation pressure has no significance and can be treated carelessly. It may have considerable to do with the length of life of the tires. It should prove conclusively that poor fuel economy on a rubber-tired tractor can not be charged to tire inflation pressure. THE EFFECT OF TIRE INFLATION PRESSURE ON SPEED The results of this work are shown graphically in Figure 3, in which speed in miles per hour is plotted against drawbar pull in pounds for four gears and five inflation pressures. In studying these curves the reader will notice that for any draw - bar pull the speed in miles per hour is greater for an inflation pressure of 16 pounds than for an inflation pressure of eight * The term "travel reduction" is one of our own coining. It means nearly the same as slippage and was synonymous with the customary use of the term slippage up until the time of this investigation. It is secured by determining carefully the number of revolutions made by the drive wheels in traveling) 500 feet with no load. Then the number at revolutions made by the drive wheels in going 600 feet with load are de - termined. The difference between the distance the tractor would have gone under no load and the distance it did go under load is called "travel reduction". Percentage of travel reduction is determined by dividing the travel reduction by the distance the tractor would have traveled with no load. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 pounds, and that intermediate pressures gave for the most part intermediate speeds. This is logical, for when the tire inflation pressure is decreased, the effective diameter of the wheel is decreased and this in turn decreases speed. A lower - ing of inflation pressure is accompanied by a loss of speed. il I 1 k- 1 I |— J-J — |i jfjHLL . — * — n i-«i 2 -I 1 1 | j O M S2 •* s t"~~ZZZZ~Z"Z 8 fJ ff ill * £ , . jl (| R | " «». a anoH us" saniTi- O33ds ' </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors THE EFFECT OF TIRE INFLATION PRESSURE ON TRAVEL REDUCTION Travel reduction is calculated in the same manner that slip - page is calculated for official tractor test reports. It is in large measure slippage, as will be shown later. It is of im - portance to a tractor operator because slippage always means wasted energy. The results of the tests to determine the effect of inflation pressures on travel reduction are shown graphically in Figure 4. If the reader will turn to Figure 4 and choose that part representing any one gear, say low for example, then choose some percentage of travel reduction, 16 per cent for instance, and follow that line horizontally across the drawing from the left toward the right, the first curve touched will be that for the tire inflation pressure permitting the most travel reduc - tion, and continuing across the drawing, the last curve touched will be for the tire inflation pressure having the least travel reduction. In this case the eight-pound inflation pressure gave the most travel reduction ; the 16-pound pressure gave the least. This relationship is nearly enough consistent through all the data plotted to warrant the generalization for the con - ditions under which this work was done that lowering infla - tion pressure was accompanied by increased travel reduction. In other words, more slippage was experienced with very low pressures than with pressures somewhat higher. This fact should be helpful to those who have been led to believe that they can secure more traction by lowering the pressure in the tires. There are undoubtedly times in very loose, sandy soil or other similar soil conditions where more traction can be secured by lowering inflation pressures but such a condition, where it is the soil that is slipping and not the tires, should be realized. THE RELATION OF TIRE INFLATION PRESSURE TO DRAWBAR PULL In Figure 5 it can be seen that for all gears the curves slope downward from left to right. Further examination will show that this fact means that travel reduction decreases as tire inflation pressure increases up to a pressure of 16 pounds, at least. Examining each gear-group of curves from bottom to top brings out another fact, namely that the slopes of the curves increase as the drawbar pulls increase. Where the slope of a curve is very small, it means that tire inflation pressure is of very little consequence. Where the slope is large, tire inflation pressure is of considerable consequence. The large slopes occur where the drawbar pulls are large. Therefore a relatively high tire inflation pressure (16 pounds) is desirable for large drawbar pulls (1,500 pounds and above) but has little significance so far as travel reduc - tion is concerned for low drawbar pulls. The practical point </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 of this is as follows : for heavy drawbar loads, such as plow - ing, it is important to keep tire inflation pressures relatively high. For low drawbar loads, such as road work, low tire in - flation pressures are permissible so far as travel reduction is concerned, and may be very desirable from the standpoint of riding qualities. x oyy «« I • a "3 : §jl t V\\ 8 a il iliiii— f i 3 \ \ o (h W~ 3 -S i *_8 Is T ji« as la ? 1 ® « r*i lil ( r *** -| JL 1-4-iiJI .§ * 5 d I! •§ B — 5*4 . 3 I'l 8 -2 ijL • Si" n w * 2 ~2 « S fi Jf 2 S &amp;» -IN33 U3d-NOU.3n03U 13AVUX </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors T I I ' — i — ' — ' — I — i — i — I — I — I — &gt; — &lt; — ' — ' — ■ — i — i — i TRAVEL NCDUCTION TRAVEL AtDUtTION COW CCA* ' ' IMTCMMCDMTC CCAK " "~ * ■ L»«» MMI ■ S**^. _ — W ' \. , t#— rojim fit* H^= m , O M« Q HJCM SIM ~ ' »W»CKHICM CCAR o &gt;m« o o mi e _ . * ■ • *•• A ! k^. '. __ + »•• i * m i mi • \s^^ m ■■ ■ »»• in i i^ § H f , i I 11 I I I II T&gt;-C MC1SVKC fOWDJ TIME F«tiW«[ — »OUNO» Fig. 5. — The relationship of tractor travel reduction in percentage to. tire inflation pressures for several drawbar loads. THE RELATION OF TIRE INFLATION PRESSURE TO HORSEPOWER An examination of Figure 6 reveals the fact that the curves for 16-pound inflation pressure extend further to the right than the curves for smaller pressures. The greater the dis - tance to the right, the greater the developed horsepower. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 Therefore the highest pressure plotted (16 pounds) seems to be most favorable for maximum drawbar horsepower. Pre - vious analyses lead to the same conclusion. There are two variable factors in horsepower: speed and pounds of pull. An increase in either or both of these factors increases the — -^=^ 1 nni— ■ 1 AW\ flfi - A \ "** Ja. iT "c jS sj S . o «l 2 it 5 u (- it p if ff c m I T *iis j 1 -i| LJ II in cu C3 t- f, q, C8.J3 IM |j^j 0) b &gt; 2* u §3^-= * -^^S§^ l_|" o 1 i: y. a_ \M &gt;- 5 a s a S * ! ° iii 8 a 2 55 o~ 2 -IN3D U3d- Houanaaa 13av«i « </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors horsepower. It has been shown that speed was higher for 16 - pound inflation pressure than for anything lower. It has also been shown that drawbar pull in pounds is greater for 16-v pound inflation pressure than for any lower pressure. Since 16 pounds is favorable for both factors entering into horse - power, it is certain to be favorable to the development of drawbar horsepower. The question most naturally asked at this point is : if 16 pounds is good, why won't high pressures of 25, 30, or 40 pounds be still better? These pressures take the tires out of the realm of low pressures. Our study indi - cated there was little to be gained by going above 16 pounds. It has been claimed that the extremely low pressures lessen dangers of punctures, add to riding comfort, and lessen strains on the machines. These characteristics, if such there are, are sacrificed by carrying inflation pressures very high. CONCLUSIONS FROM TIRE INFLATION TESTS Changing the inflation pressure carried in tractor tires causes no appreciable change in the fuel consumption of the tractors on which the tires are used. Increasing tire inflation pressure causes an increase in speed of the tractor on which the pneumatic tires are used. Travel reduction is less for a tractor equipped with pneu - matic tires when the tires are inflated to 16 pounds pressure than when inflated to lower pressures, and this difference in - creases as the maximum drawbar pull is approached. For the conditions of these tests, greater drawbar pulls were obtained with an inflation pressure of 16 pounds than with lower inflation pressures. The most horsepower was developed when the pneumatic tires were inflated to 16 pounds pressure. WEIGHT TRANSFER AND TRAVEL REDUCTION In the first studies made with pneumatic tires on tractors, the same procedure was used in calculating slippage and per - centage of slippage as was customary in calculating the slip - page of steel wheels. Many objected to this procedure, saying that what was designated as slippage was not all slippage but partly due to the fact that when a tractor is pulling on the drawbar, weight is transferred from the front of the tractor to the rear; this additional weight on the rear flattens pneu - matic tires appreciably and thus decreases the effective wheel diameter. The smaller wheel diameter lessens the distance covered on the ground, and the decrease in travel under load </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 can not all be attributed to slippage. This doubt seemed to be a license for minimizing slippage, and it seemed necessary to analyze the decrease in travel into its component parts!rS the decrease in travel under load, as explained before, the term travel reduction" was applied. No mistake can be made n its meaning. To determine what part of travel reduction nltwT ? I and what part is due to weight transfer from the front end of the tractor to the rear when it is pulling, the crankshaft of a tractor was locked, the gear shift placed SjoJ'h ? win ? 1 , as * chai u n hoist and hydraulic dynamometer p aced between the drawbar and a post, and a platform scale placed under the front end of the tractor, all being iStodon se C at nC ThP r/V \ 175 -* ou + nd we ;e h t ™» placed on the tractor Sf-* Ti A gM * ank ™ as three-fourths full and the radiator was full A series of increasing drawbar pulls was applied to the tractor until the wheels slipped, readings being taken on ' I WCIGHT TRANSrCR y^^\ | IH I I 1 .*&amp;3C''' ' I L^&gt;r ! — —^ — M— i... i^t j i i T^~~r 1^^ I I | ! DKWSAK PULL — POUNDS *^ "' Fig. 7.— The relationship of weight transfer to the drawbar pull of a tractor. A second set of data was secured by attaching three dif - ferent sizes of weights, 422, 561, and 700 pounds, to each rear wheel of the same tractor and then, with each weight and seven different inflation pressures, determining the ef - fective circumference of the wheels for zero draw-bar load on the tractor testing course as previously described. These data are shown in Figure 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors From the weight I ' ' r&gt; — i 1 1 transfer curves (Fig- errtcTive tire circuufcrcugc ure 7) the weights — transferred for dif- l&gt; ;»"•" -»"^-""' I I 1 I ferent drawbar pulls „"*"*- — 1|| 1 were found. These t,,,_J '» ■ | -^ ; weights were added to I. the static weight of 3 iM i /\' ' the rear end of the \ y ' r s''\ tractor and the total \, a J / v^ '\ divided by two to give % // XK the weight on each \.., I /S'/' rear tire. These fig- u /./I'' ures were taken to the \ , u __ /yV' . effective tire circum- u //)&gt;''' f erence graph, Figure I ... y/'l 8, and by interpola- £ &gt;/ I tion the effective cir- £«• - t f. — . 1 cumferences were de - termined. Results of ■»• these calculations are shown in Figure 9. iu i i k — A k k h — £ — :, The effect of weight TIRC pr " surc - tou »°» «&gt;»»"»• Lonofo. imn-n i._*i Fig 8. — The relationship of tire inflation transfer upon travel pressure to the effe p ctive tire circum . reduction for two f erence of a tractor tire. ■*ti !!• crrccnve tirc circumfcrgncc I i * IMFLATIOH MCStU»C — P0UN01 s j rr" *j~ — ~~s a iu . ' &gt;*" - — f—^- „ | * C "^ ' * "™ "~~ * ~"~ k^~ * ~~^ ' • — r-i. U IU nmm —^ -A- "" — —^— tnr' ■" ■ I I 1 I I I I 0 90O *O0 « o mo 1000 1200 1*00 i«00 1*00 1000 DRAWBAR PULL POUNDS Fig. 9. — The relationship of drawbar pull to the effective tire circumference of a tractor tire. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 inflation pressures is shown in Table 3, which covers a series of drawbar pulls largely within the practical range for the tractor being used in securing the data. It can be seen that with data showing first the amount of weight transferred from the front to rear of a tractor when pulling and, second, the effect that weight has on the effective diameter of a pneu - matic-tired wheel, the exact amount of travel reduction due to weight transfer can be determined, and anything aside from that must be slippage. CONCLUSIONS TO TESTS ON WEIGHT TRANSFER AND TRAVEL REDUCTION In no case calculated did the weight transfer account for more than one-half of one per cent of the travel reduction. Therefore travel reduction, for all practical purposes, can be considered slippage, for it can be shown by computations for Table 3. — The effect of weight transfer upon travel reduction, low gear. _ . . Circumference of tire Travel reduction baaed on revolutions .^ . Drawbar of tlrivers Corrected Difference pull in 500 ft. No load for weight No load Corrected transfer circum. circum. No. Ft. Ft. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. 16 POUNDS TIRE PRESSURE 1977.5 54.85 11.42 11.368 20.18 19.81 0.37 1764.2 60.08 11.42 11.374 12.58 12.22 0.36 1494.2 47.23 11.42 11.380 7.30 6.96 0.34 975.0 45.44 11.42 11.393 3.66 3.42 0.24 498.8 44.88 11.42 11.406 2.44 2.31 0.13 8 POUNDS TIRE PRESSURE 1918.2 70.04 11.02 10.952 35.23 34.82 0.41 1742.2 54.98 11.02 10.958 17.48 17.00 0.48 1518.0 51.23 11.02 10.964 11.43 10.97 0.46 925.0 47.29 11.02 10.982 4.06 3.72 0.34 505.0 46.38 11.02 10.994 2^17 1J&gt;3 0.24 the same tractor, and Figures 7, 8, and 9, that if the entire weight on the front wheels of this tractor were transferred to the rear wheels, it could not cause a reduction in travel of more than 2.5 per cent. From tire deflection data taken from an isolated wheel and tire of different make from those used on the tractor to secure the weight-transfer data but of the same size, theoretical calculations showed that by adding weight equal to the front end of this tractor to the rear tires, the percentage of travel reduction caused would be 3.98 per cent. While these two percentages are not in very close agreement, they do empha - size the fact that weight transfer can account for only a small part of the travel reduction experienced with pneumatic tires. WHEEL EFFICIENCY TESTS The efficiency of tractor wheels and transmission can be expressed as the ratio of the drawbar horsepower to the engine </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors horsepower. This varies with the condition of the road or soil on which the tractor is traveling and with the gear in which the drawbar test is made. It is a common and custom - ary procedure in engineering tests to determine engine horse - power and also to determine drawbar horsepower, but to secure both of these at the same time is unusual and little experimental work has been done with this aim in mind. To secure the ratio representing wheel and transmission effi - ciency was the primary aim in conducting the tractor-wheel efficiency tests. Since the same transmission was used with both wheel equipments, differences in efficiency were due to wheel equipment. There are several approaches to the problem of determining engine horsepower in the field while carrying on drawbar operations. One is the construction of special equipment to measure the torque transmitted to the wheels by the engine. This method is time-consuming, is confined to a very narrow field of application, and is very expensive. A second method is to calibrate the engine by fuel consumption; that is, plot fuel consumption against horsepower for various engine speeds. This method has considerably more promise for lab - oratories limited by funds than the first, but has several serious drawbacks. Results secured by it are averages and the momentary changes in drawbar loads that occur in all field operations cannot be observed or measured. A third method is one in which the engine is calibrated by means of a manom - eter attached to the intake manifold. This method takes ad - vantage of the fact that the vacuum in the intake manifold is greatest at no load and closed throttle, and gradually de - creases as the load increases and the throttle opens. It has the advantage of a relatively low cost in application, and variations in engine horsepower can be observed as they occur in field operations. The greatest drawback to it is a treach - erous inconsistency due to several factors, such as fuel tem - perature and the changing behavior of the fuel mixture, which require long and tedious calibration runs and checks. In spite of its limitations this last method was chosen for this work. A double manometer was constructed, one U tube of which used mercury, the other water. The plan was to use the mer - cury manometer for the relatively high vacuum conditions and the water for the small vacuum readings which could then be read with greater accuracy. It was found in practice that the water manometer was not needed and this part of the appa - ratus was filled with mercury and used for measuring tire pressures. Tests were made with an Allis-Chalmers Model U tractor. When equipped with pneumatic tires, weights totaling 425 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 J3!f 7tl e + adC l ed rear whee1 ' making the static weight of the tractor with driver 3,430 pounds at the rear and 1,570 pounds in front, a total of 5,000 pounds. When equipped with steel wheels and lugs the static weights of the i°^n ncludl^ g - th | dr . iver ' were 2 ' 895 P° und s at the rear and 1,650 pounds m front, a total of 4,545 pounds Fuel consumption for drawbar tests was secured by means of a calibrated 500 cc. burette. Engine R. P. m. were taken by means of a flexible shaft one end of which was attached to the end of the pulley shaft and the other end to a tachometer mounted on top of the fender. While calibrating the engine on the brake by means of the manometer, the governor was disconnected and the throttle controlled directly from the dash. The governor was in opera - tion on all drawbar tests. The brake horsepower readings were corrected to standard conditions by the formula B.H.P.(cor.)=B.H.P.(obs.)X-i^i-X V "* -K**- temp, degrees F. " Obs.bar. 520 Figure 10 shows the calibration curves. It was originally planned to plot a curve for 1300 R. p. m. but the engine reached a stage of unstable operation at this speed and data taken there were unreliable. This chart was used to determine -^- ; I ■ ~1 fc* _SS^_ _ UAfOUE'ER (ALIBRATDN duRv'f S h -§^I3Z i ~~~ Os s^ &amp;ore -nor Curry - ; 5x25. ZZZZZZ \ 1 Z\\N% I, ~\\^S^ 5 ~ vs^^x v — 5 " '" '* '* '» '« " M Jr4 yi Ii Jt Si M M tNOINE HORSEPOWER Fig. 10. — The manometer calibration curves showing engine horse - power plotted against intake manifold vacuum in inches of mercury for five engine speeds. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors engine horsepower for drawbar operations. Two readings taken during drawbar operations made this possible: engine speed and the manometer reading. Figure 11 shows drawbar horsepower plotted against engine horsepower. A reference line on this chart designated as 100 per cent efficiency shows the ideal, or no loss between the engine and the drawbar. Those curves which most nearly approach this line indicate drawbar conditions having higher efficiencies than the curves which are farther from it. Take, for instance, the curve representing steel wheels in low gear and a point on that curve representing 18 engine horsepower. The drawbar horsepower is approximately 10. The efficiency is 10/18 or 55!/^ per cent. Efficiencies for any points on any of the curves may be secured by placing a straight edge on the chart so that it passes through the origin and the point of interest. The point of intersection of the straight edge and the scale on the right-hand side of the chart gives the efficiency in percentage. The chart shows that drawbar efficiencies for pneumatic-tired tractors are higher than those for steel-wheeled tractors. This is due to the fact that the rolling resistance of a tractor equipped with lugs is greater than for one equipped with rubber tires. It takes engine i i I i i 1 i i i i i i i i i I i/f ———————————————— z~^- • z — &gt; £ w ,,/_ g * Tx Supirhiql ,'^^ i £ 2* -**_ ffu tber. -&gt;-q !&gt;■ u Tjj^ y' ' y^-Hn}h Rubit'r i | I" S" 1 7Z*' Z? — id -6 i:z==t zz-z-z^;^^ *&gt; Seco/ d Ru bber. l^-^ ' ' £yS &gt;^ \ jjjc ". T"^^^''^&lt;!^ ~ — — I ' ~^z * ~T~ I ?**% — ]f — % — i — is — 71 — n — a — n — » — n — n — n — n — w — a — " ENGINE HORSEPOWER Fig. 11. — Drawbar efficiency curves for both rubber tires and steel -wheels. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 energy to drive steel lugs into the ground and pull them. out again. Energy dissipated in this way is no longer available for useful work. Figures 12, 13, 14, and 15 are charts which show data in graphic form relating to tractor speed, drawbar pull, drawbar horsepower, fuel consumption, and travel reduction, for both steel wheels and rubber tires. To one interested in the subject of tractor traction these charts can serve as a basis for a con - siderable amount of study. A detailed discussion of them, while interesting, would add too much to the volume of this bulletin. From Figure 12 it is apparent that practically the same drawbar pull can be attained by rubber in low, inter - mediate, and high gears. With steel wheels and lugs the draw - bar pull decreases rapidly with increases in speed. Figure 13 is, in fact, a second efficiency chart expressed by fuel consump - tion. It supplements Figure 11. Figure 14 is of interest in determining the best drawbar pulls to use in loading a tractor for efficient operation. Figure 15 compares the travel reduc - tion of the two types of wheel equipment, steel and rubber. Figure 16 is a drawing of the manometer used in measuring intake manifold vacuum. a, 1 . 1 1 ___________________________ 10 I :=: __, I Izzzzzizzzzzzzzzzz 1 * b ' Hi 9* r * c ' O A — - — — n -___ *.„__ — / ta/t / k/SSt r id \ -it ,__ ' i *~~ _~2 "»"■• —-—■ — ,._ _. J*^-- . — &lt;3 •cone Rub &gt;er __ Fig. 12. — The relation of speed to drawbar pull. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors iiiiiiiiiiiiiiiiniir i" — ' Vn — -a !-HWr 5,, — . -V\l\ !s_ 2 Wl\ \ L I &gt;,.-^i KkS^ 5L §„ [—JiS^^V J^L^ 0.// bji, -Sjiv^. . *^- &gt;. y, -low Jrw ' It 1 _Z -. _^ *V^ *v. -^«^ rA*f&gt; #vt ***- Vjrt HvU W^ 5~ f4£ ■"i ' — i x f a s — 7» — » — » — a A — is n — it 7i'~"liJ /» "v — jt — 3 DRAWBAR HORSCPOWtR Fig. 13. — The relation of fuel consumption to drawbar horsepower. ?"— — Ljzzi i&gt;* \ i iS«&lt; oiy^ bier. .^\ «l\ tt / 7 — — — — _^ _ \ 1 __^_ _____ _____ _____ _^^_ tf" \AA r o.,, \__V — -X 5y--^ \ i ■. • "^ " —^ ~io, ' or *l &lt;Sup rfylyh ffuU tr-^ n^ \ &gt;mmm * ' ' •«a jJo *m jm — ate — ;&lt;Kfc wu ;J« ;i'm /J*&gt; *j« mm tin tit ttu liu Jin l**o DRAWBAR PULL — POUNDS Fig. 14. — The relation of fuel consumption to drawbar pull. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 _*, . 5« 1 _.« V a.eo ; 1 z"- f £„ 1 1 d« .L^li — T^HX ia -^- -,£*— -t '*- — A ™-e ii [ ~» " ' i J i J- J »»/»«/*&lt;»/+ /i /• /V /i JU . t DRAWBAR HORSEPOWER Fig. 15. — The relation of travel reduction to drawbar horsepower. CONCLUSIONS DRAWN FROM THE TRACTOR lf^»fnnH^ - WHEEL. EFFICIENCY V, r- JJ &gt; -*"t» TESTS ■ | ffl Under favorable n v jfi operating conditions . , rip^T 1 1 - pneumatic- tired LJ : ; . . wheels transform a ?*&amp; alB bM '° c ** cc *^"* greater proportion of \ ~t W engine horsepower i ] into drawbar horse- /nwy^twrn^^i : -* power than do steel £ ■ -. "V. wheels and spade £ ] i T lugs. i \ i\_ m Under favorable : -_, conditions steel - ? "^ ~*o*rMma~f, wheels and spade c 1 lugs attain a greater »«?•*«««, = I drawbar pull in low t ? ■ \ gear than can be at- #w^tt | x^*"*'" E ; = tained with rubber T&gt;B-rK&lt;n 31H1E tires. i | g g| I There are two ways - — —3&gt; v^ =K of increasing the drawbar horsepower Fl0 16 _ A drawing of the manonl eter which OI a tractor : by in- was use( j j n reading the intake manifold creasing the drawbar vacuum for the wheel efficiency tests. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors pull and by increasing the speed of travel. The drawbar pull of pneumatic tires is limited by traction in the first three gears. The drawbar pull of a steel-wheeled tractor is usually limited by engine horsepower in any gear. The maximum drawbar horsepower of a rubber-tired tractor in various gears covers a much wider range of values than that of a steel wheel and lug tractor. Horsepower values for rubber tires at high speeds exceed any de - rived for steel wheels and lugs. At low speeds the horsepower for rubber tires is less than that for steel wheels and lugs. Maximum economy was secured for the rubber-tired tractor when the drawbar pull was slightly more than 50 per cent of the static weight of the rear of the tractor. Maximum drawbar horsepower values were secured for the rubber-tired tractor when the travel reduction was about 16 per cent. No such point is found for steel wheels and lugs. The percentage of travel reduction is less for steel wheels and lugs than for rubber tires and decreases as speed increases. THE EFFECT OF ADDING WEIGHT ON THE TRACTION OF PNEUMATIC TIRES In the use of pneumatic tires on tractors, operators have been advised to add weight to the rear tractor wheels. The amount of weight to add has been a question ; also the amount K EFFECT OF WHEEL WEIGHTS ON x | DRAWBAR PULL n a x _ \ O U » ■ D o t Tl_tJlrj 2 L L.A a _Ll L~f 7_ Sis"? 7 J I I I I I I M I I HI IT ' *"* *°° *°° ' z °° "° o 'l"&gt; VOO JtCOO Itoo *t°O DRAWBAR PULL POUNDS Fig. 17.— The effect of additional weight on drawbar pull as de - termined by using the following total numbers of customary cast-iron wheel weights on the rear wheels: 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12, and 14. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 of traction gained by adding weight has not been definitely known. To throw some light on this latter question has been the aim of a portion of this investigation. The same Allis- Chalmers Model U tractor as previously described was used in this study. A series of drawbar runs was made on the tractor testing course with first one weight on each rear wheel, then two, three, etc., until seven weights were used on each wheel, or a total of 14 weights was added to the rear tractor wheels. The engine speed was controlled by the gov - ernor, for in none of these tests did the traction pull the engine speed down appreciably below governed speed. The data taken in these runs are plotted in Figure 17. It will be noted that a fairly regular increase in drawbar pull accom - panies the addition of weight to the rear wheels of a rubber - tired tractor. Previous work had indicated that 16 pounds of air pressure seemed desirable and that about 16 per cent travel reduction gave very good drawbar pulls and drawbar horsepower values. Consequently, using 16 per cent travel re - duction, values were taken from Figure 17 and plotted on Figure 18. This chart shows that there is a straight-line re - lationship between increase in drawbar pull and weight added to the tractor wheels. No attempt has been made in plotting these data to take into account the effect of weight trans - ferred from the front of the tractor to the rear on drawbar IUC INCBEASeO DRAWBAR PULL SECURED BY WHEEL' WEIGHTS //« . S lice I I I I I I I I 1* __). i r &lt;L £ n&gt; I g wo : /L , | *, __ L,_j a-H -zA- in / &lt; «_^ I ~ *-. 1 « I / M I I I M I I I I I I I I 0 ISO MO SAO //to I4OO IttO /MO *U0 .0 Z 4 .WDOHT^AOOED— POUNgS „ „ TOTAL WHEEL WEIGHTS Fig. 18. — The relationship of the increased drawbar pull secured to the increased weight added to the rear wheels of the tractor. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors pull. The increased drawbar pull is approximately 53 per cent of the weight added to the tractor drive wheels. It would seem that if this relationship were true, it would hold for the entire rear weight of any rubber-tired tractor. The weight of the Model U tractor on the rear or drive wheels with driver and three weights per wheel was 3,430 pounds. The drawbar pull at 16 per cent travel reduction was 1,850 pounds, or 54 per cent of the rear weight of the tractor, which checks fairly well. ' ij . These tests with the Model U tractor were made on tires that had had a great amount of service. There are factors which may be used, such as the hitch, to raise the percentage of drawbar pull to rear tractor weight. From some general observations it seems possible to raise this percentage as much as 10 per cent. Despite the limitations of the data presented on this phase of the subject, to date they are the most specific available and therefore are included. CONCLUSIONS ON THE EFFECT OF WEIGHT ON THE TRACTION OF PNEUMATIC TIRES The traction of a pneumatic-tired tractor, that is, the pounds of pull at the drawbar, can be increased by adding weight to the rear of the tractor. This weight is usually added to the hubs of the drive wheels. The increased drawbar pull will be slightly more than 50 per cent of the weight added to the wheels. STUBBLE FIELD AND TRACTOR TESTING COURSE COMPARISON TESTS A considerable amount of the data reported in this bulletin has been taken on the Nebraska tractor testing course. Some have questioned results secured on the tractor testing course, saying that they are not comparable with the results secured under actual field conditions. While it is realized that the tractor testing course is different from actual field conditions, it must be realized that this course is the same as field condi - tions in this neighborhood in the following respects : The soil is identical with that in adjacent fields, it is unprotected from sun and rain, and there is no material other than soil on it. It differs from field conditions in the following respects: It has been driven over many times and during long intervals between rains the surface becomes very dusty and the subsoil very hard and compact. To throw some light on this question and to make compari - sons, a stubble field was found which was practically level, had a considerable after-growth following the wheat harvest, and was being pastured lightly by a few cows and horses. Some maximum drawbar tests were run in it. Three different </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 7( i travel reduction -rubber tires ~j 3 f stubble field* tractor testing course t 6(j low gear ' \ 5q _____ INFLATION PRESSURE I POUNDS 5 A AC O- 12 -O ' / t * / f g tt ~~ * FIEI -D ' / so //, y » r — p- a. COORSJJ.--- — a o ° 2 INTERMEDIATE GEAR 1 ~ « fr 1 — I — h- *-4- . J_, _ J \ hi |so ; I \ I- FIELD T I ; zzzir »_; // 10 COURSE^^^'" ' O O 20 ' HIGH GEAR Tl FIELD ,jSS#^ ' „* 10 J .&gt;^* &gt;* ! COURSE. t^l. "" I I I 4 f -f -t— T soo 400 600 Sco io^ i35o^ J3&amp;5 B35 — B5!5 — 2iW iS6(, in DRAWBAR PULL - POUNDS FlG " co ? 1 P arison of the maximum drawbar pulls made by a rndira'stbbTeteld? 11 *«** t-ting co/rse </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Rubber Tires and Steel Wheels for Tractors 70 TRAVEL REDUCTION - STEEL WHEELS STUBBLE FIELD &amp; TRACTOR TESTING COURSE LOW GEAR .— 1 I I i 1 1 1 )-- FIELD/ AC ■ ■/- 3t \ 1 — 20 : k fqjRsS. 0 I o " 0 5 INTERMEDIATE GEAR «*&gt; 1 1 1 K i« : , O u gso bl m _j40 LJ a: 1-30 20 FIELD - ;£■ COURSE (j_ o--— — ~---~ HIGH GEAR ' „ FIELD | Q5 g-O— | °COURSE I 55 1000 1200 MOO 1600 1800 2000 2200 2400 2600 2800 3000 DRAWBAR PULL-POUNDS Fig. 20. — A comparison of the maximum drawbar pulls made by a tractor equipped with steel wheels and lugs on the Nebraska tractor testing course and in a stubble field. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 291 tire inflation pressures, three different loads in the vicinity of maximum, and three different gears were used, making a total of 27 individual runs. Courses were laid out for these tests so that the tractor and testing equipment never followed the same track twice. These data are shown graphically in Figures 19 and 20. For purposes of comparison curves were plotted on the same figures with data secured on the tractor testing course with the same tractor earlier in the year. An examination of Figui'e 19 shows that the maximum drawbar pull secured on the tractor testing course can not be increased appreciably in the stubble field, even with extremely high travel reduction, and that for the same travel reduction a higher drawbar pull was secured on the testing course than in the field. An examination of Figure 20 shows that the steel wheels and lugs made a much larger drawbar pull on the testing course than in the stubble field, and that drawbar pull on the testing course was limited by engine power, while in the stubble field it was limited by traction. CONCLUSION TO STUBBLE I FIELD AND TRACTOR TESTING COURSE COMPARISON TESTS These tests were very necessary and essential in removing doubts from the minds of readers who may have fe t other - wise that some data submitted in this bulletin were taken under conditions not comparable to those a farmer meets in the field. These tests show that for at least one field condition the tires did as well on the tractor testing course as they could do under this field condition ; in fact, just a little better. In other words, it would most certainly be inexcusable on the part of a farmer to buy rubber tires expecting much more from them than the tractor testing course results show. On the other hand, it is evident that where a tractor equipped with steel wheels and lugs on good footing in low gear will pull more pounds than the same equipped with rubber tires, this difference is considerably less under field conditions, and while only one field condition was used for this test, observa - tions under other field conditions indicate that there are places where the rubber tires will actually pull as much as the steel wheels and lugs and more. [5M] </seg>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044">CONDU TRACTOR ENGINE i Ca jl **VVm Weight § Bore Rated f&lt; o NAME RATING as "§ and b. p.m. Make Fud « ~ - Tested ==&gt; Stroke Used o 2 : »_ _m i 1 : ! g__ 1 3 I 4 I 5 6 ~7 I 8 I 9J_1 28 I BEEMAN"G" 1 1 JN4 650 I 1 I 31x41 I 1,500 I Own i~Ga 29 I LA CROSSE "G" 1 1 __12-24 4,670 | 2 | 6 x7 | 900 | Own | Kero. . . . 73 | WETMORE.I ■ I 12-25 I 3,000 | 4 | 4 x51 | 1,265 | Weidely |Kerb.|... 117 I McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL i 4400 I 4 3ix5 I 1,200 I Own Krol — 118 I MINNEAPOLIS "B" ■ 1 17-30 | 7,550 | 4 4jx7 | 825 | Own Kerolj.'!! 121 TWIN CITY "TY" • • ■ 17^28 5,895 4 4?x6 1,000 Own Kero 122 TWIN CITY "AT" 27-44 10,657 4 5ix6f 900 Own Kero 126 HUBER 20-40 9,336 4 5jx61 1,100 Stearns Gai ..'. 135 HUBER "SUPER FOUR" 4&lt;W52 9,910 4 61x61 1,100 Stearns GaS 137 SHAWT45" -1| 437 1 2}x3 1,600 Briggsestr. Gai 141 OIL PULL "W" 20-30 6,776 2 6Hx7 850 Own Kero 142 McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20 6,028 4 4Jx5 1,025 Own Keio 143 OIL PULL "X" 25-40 9,440 2 6H*8i 725 Own Keio 144 ROCK ISLAND. 18-35 5,740 4 41x6 1,100 Buda Dis. '" 145 OIL PULL "Y". .. • 30-50 13,207 2 7«x9J 635 Own Keio '" 146 JOHN DEERE,"D" ■ 15^7 4,917 2 6}x7 800 Own | Keio. .' 1 1 148 LAUSON "S_12" 20-35 6,228 4 4ix6 1,100 Le Roi GaJ 9&gt; 149 CLETRAC "40" 1 40-55 12,038 6 41x5 1,575 Wisconsin Ga» 9 151 ALLIS-CHALMERS 20-35 7,095 4 4Jx6J 930 Own Ga« 9 152 TWIN CITY "FT" 21-32 6.463 | 4 41x6 1,075 Own Gai 9 155 CASE "L" 5,307 4 4fx6 1,100 Own Kero. 9 156 McCORMICK-DEERING "15-30". 22-36 7,486 4 4Jx6 1050 Own Ke-o. 9 157 ROCK ISLAND "G2" 15-25 5,070 4 4}x5J 1100 Waukesha Dirt. 9 158 ROCK ISLAND "G2".. 18-30 5,380 4 4}x5} 1,100 Waukesha Gai 9 161 BAKER 43-67 10,575 4 51x7 1,100 Le Roi Gas 9 162 MINNEAPOLIS 27-42 8,373 4 4ix7 925 Own Gas 9 163 MINNEAPOLIS 39-57 9,695 4 51x61 1,000 Stearns Ga» 9 164 WALLIS* 12-20 3,893 4 3ix5J 1,000 Own Dist. 9 167 CASE"C" 4,155 4 3|x51 1,100 Own Kero 9 168 HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36 6,725 4 4}x6J 1,150 Waukesha Gas 9 169 CASE"CC" 4.240 4 31x51 1,100 Own Kero. 9 170 ALLIS-CHALMERS (UNITED)' 4,821 4 4jx5 1J200 Cont, Gas 9 By Mfr=. By Codo 173 FORDSON "F" Not Rated 11.03-21.58 §7820 4 ijil ITIoO Own Kero 9 174 FORDSON"F" NotRated 14.92-26.01 3,920 4 4ix5 1,100 Own Gaa 9 175 TWIN CITY "KT" 11-20 14.70-23.23 5,060 4 4Jx5 1,000 Own Kero 9 176 OLIVER HART PARR ROW CROP" Not Rated 18.29-27.60 4,650 4 4ix5J 1,150 Own Kero' 9 177 MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PURPOSE". . . Not Rated 15.47-22.20 4,100 4 4 x4J 1^200 Hercules Gas " 10 180 OLIVER HART PARR "2-3 PLOW" 7 Not Rated 18.43-28.22 4,420 4 41x5} 1,190 Own Kero. 9 182 CLETRAC "80-60"" 60-80 59.96-81.91 22,840 6 51x64 1,050 Wisconsin Gas 10 183 OLIVER HART PARR "3-5 PLOW"' NotRated 28.54-44.63 6,415 4 43x6} l|l25 Own Kero. 9 184 EAGLE "6A".. Not Rated 22.17-37.09 5,670 6 4x41 1.416 Hercules Gai 9 183 RUMELY "6A" Not Rated 27.65-43.20 6,370 6 4}x4J 1,365 Special GaT" — S 186 BATES STEEL MULE "35" 35-45 32.91-46.90 11,218 6 4}x4} 1,500 Waukesha Gas 10 187 BATES STEEL MULE "45"«&gt; 45-55 40.07-60.38 13,509 6 4|x5i 1,500 Waukesha Gai 10 189 ALLIS-CHALMERS "ALL CROP" NotRated 18.21-31.34 6,965 4 4}x5 1,200 Conti'tal Gai 10 190 JOHN DEERE "GENERAL PURPOSE" . NotRated 15.52-24.30 4,925 2 6x6 950 Own Dirt. 9 191 MASSEY-HARRIS "GENERAL PURPOSE" NotRated 13.02-20.31 4,120 4 4x41 1,200 Hercules Dist 9 192 BRADLEY "GENERAL PURPOSE" NotRated 15.89-22.93 4,150 4 3}x4J 1,250 Waukesha Gai. 9 193 ALLIS-CHALMERS "EK" Not Rated 27.16-42.58 7,200 4 6 x61 1,000 Own Ditt 9 194 McCORMICK-DEERING INDUSTRIAL "20" NotRated 17.27-27.51 M15 4 4}x5 1150 Own Ga 9 195 CLETRAC "40-30"" 30-44 31.17-42.44 9,700 6 4}x41 1,450 Hercules Gas' 9 197 MINNEAPOLIS-MOLINE UNIVERSAL "MT" NotRated 13.81-25.17 5.235 4 4ix5 1,000 Own Kco 9 198 McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F30" ... Not Rated 20.27-30.29 5 990 4 4}x5 1 150 Own Keo 9 199 McCORMICK-DEERING TRACTRACTOR" . . Not Rated 18.33-25.31 7^10 4 3 jx5 1,250 Own Keo." 9 20C» ALLIS-CHALMERS MODEL "L" Not Rated 60.02-80.48 22,027 (5 5}x6l OB0 Own Ga — 9S 201 CLETRAC "25" NotRated 21.52-30.35 7,275 6 3Jx4} 1,250 Hercules Gai 9£ 202 CLETRAC "15"" Not Rated 17.75-24.44 6,100 4 4 x41 1,250 Hercules Gai 9£ 203 CATERPILLAR 25 "....: 2M0 22.07-29.94 8 087 4 4x51 1100 Own Ga 92 204 CATERPILLAR "50" Not Rated 38.96-51.64 18)245 4 51x61 850 Own Ga 9t 206 CATERPILLAR "35" Not Rated 29.15-39.58 12,830 4 4}x6i 850 Own Gai 9E 210 McCORMICK-DEERING "W30" NotRated 19 69^3131 5 575 4 4}x5 1160 Own Keo 9= 211 McCORMICK-DEERING TRACTRACTOR T40 NotRated 33.24-43.53 10.790 6 3|x41 1.600 Ow^ gI [ ll 212 McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F-12". . . Not Rated 9.74-14 68 3 280 4 — 3~x4 1 400 Own Gai &lt; 213 CATERPILLAR "SEVENTY" NotRated 58 28-7744 30 800 4 7 xti 700 Own" Gi 214 CATERPILLAR "DIESEL FIFTY" Not Rated 4012I5574 20 125 4 5ix8 850 O™ FCilli ££ 01^"^'"- • •• ate^ 35:51-49.2! IIS 4 r% IS oZ of 1 ! 216 ALLIS-CHALMERS "M" NotRated 21.81-31.81 6,620 4 4fx5 UOO Own Gas 1( 218 C A^II ; | n A4ST?.^ E 3 L^K NTY " FIVE " 1 '- Vf-- : 62.18-83.22 32.050 6 6}x8 820 Own F.Oil . . 219 MASSEY-HARRIS "3-4 PLOW"" Not Rated 26 44-41 01 5 385 4 4ix5* 1 200 Own Dirt ! 220 McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F-12"... NotRated lutlS 45 IS 4 3 x4 1,400 O™ K?o. j 221 McCORMICK-DEERING FARMALL "F-20". . . Not Ratid — 12 68-21 93 4545 4 — 33^5 1 200 Own KfeS — 222 JOHN DEERE GEN. PURPOSE "MODEL A" Not Rated 16 22-2352 4 059 2 5*x64 975 Own" Dfc %l 015^ &lt;&lt;WC '" 8 - --■-• S°^4 12lIJo:?? t% 4 HI* iJSS 8wn Sfe Hi o^SSS^S-Si" S°*5 at€d 41.24-54.64 13,675 4 5Jx6J 950 Own Gtt. 225 CATERPILLAR "R-2" NotRated 21.48-29.11 7,420 4 4x5 1,250 Own Ga. 22f CATERPILLAR ;;TWENTY-TWO" ...NotRated 18.86-26.75 6,605 4 4x5 1,250 Own Dk. 227 CATERPILLAR R-3" NotRated 27 47-37 33 10 291 4 4^ e ii 110ft Own On. 228 CATERPILLAR "TWENTY-TWO" NotRated 1934^717 6 605 4 4x5 1250 OwS GaT 229 McCORMICK-DEERING "W-12" Not Rated 9 5^1388 3 360 4 3 x4 1 700 OwS Etao 230 McCOR'CK-DEER'GTracTracTor"T40 Diesel"" NotRated 336W312 12 625 4 4*x6* 1100 OwS FGl 231 McCORMICK-DEERING "W-12" NotRated IOaUJoI %S 4 3x4 So oZ Gat •Now called Modd "M". , 'Now known aa Cletrac "80". «Nnw ™ll,.fl Alii« rknim,,™ "if" l%ZS2?a££*B5" B ''- »ffi« I «Ki " °" Ver Hart PW 28^ 4 M»»^turer-. 2nd. Ge«. fund. &lt;$£%*!«&amp;£&amp;*. "Model 12". »Mod5 2 ctSied to Bate. Steel Mule "60" ' tode^dXthf^m^^dfled 0^^ SSS'SS •RoaMdAUla-Chalmen Model "D". uRenamed CTetimc "86". 1 " lltli wWSed 5iroMhoS^tW?tS^ 7 faCtU t£32SS&amp;S!£ltt£Ska M .^S««*-^^TracTn l cTor.-T-20". XZE3£°*a2Sf&amp;? t ~' Manufacturer's rating: 18-28. "Now known as "Caterpillar" "Twenty-Eight". </seg>
            <seg id="p045">SUMMARY OF RESULTS OF TK CONDUCTED BY THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA, DEPARTN __ INCLUDES ONLY TRACTORS OP&gt; GINE BELT TESTS i RATED LOAD-TWO HOUBS I MAXIMUM-ONE HOUR C A$; j I^L 1 Water I Temp. -JT i^i I Water I Temp for Total Av. H P LVn I « „ i , Make Fud % Hrs. H. P. Eng. Gals. Hre? G als Bp * v - „ , £• P. Lbs. Used of Run B.P.M. per lfp H£?" " Abn P.* H ' P ' t&gt; E £ g ™ Gals. Hours per Gals. 2£L R - P - M - H P o e ur 85. lo£ H^ur ! 8 I 9 1 10 I " 12 I 13 1 14 | 15 16 17 18 ~19~ 20 21 22 23 I 24 25 "~26~" £*- I aj: :::::! SlJgl'glfcS 1 Sfllig I SS~| 2 | {g|jj{ | jjg | g " Veidely | Kero.l | 32 j 25.27 | 1.253 | 8.65 | 6.9S | 0.98 | Q.QQ | 72 1195 127.94 1 1.264 | 3.46 | 8.08 i 0.84 | 0.64 l^oT SS I SJ: : : : : :l % I SS 1 1 S3 1 Sfl I iff I &amp; 1 2 9 ° 6 1 gff 1 *■% 1 |j| | a | }g 1 tiTTST S£ :::::: S Sfl Too £5 tS 8:8 ifcg S ffl 8S 'ffi KS |g 8g i-S g i fo,— , /-•_, jit inno i tnQ yi on ana «itc « XU S. " lu *s»-uo otfs* o.oa o.oS O./o 0.89 85 ; Gai 1 47 40 - 28 1&gt;1()3 4 ' 89 8.23 0.75 0.00 75 167 50.05 1,104 7.08 7.07 0.87 0.00 83 teams Gas 48 62.42 1,100 6.45 9.39 0.65 &lt;M)0 79 190 69 76 — TTnn — sbb sns niR nnn i 77 — i riggsestr. Gai 31 1.51 1,611 0.32 4.73 1.30 0.00 81 168 1610 035 Ho 128 nnn II lwn Kero 41 30.24 848 3.14 9.62 0.69 2.47 64 iso" WM 'SB 4!48 IS 0*.ll ill 76 i •wn Ke?o 35 20.46 1,028 2.04 10.05 0.68 0.00 63 206 24 81 1 023 2 72 9 12 0 75 n is ra. 9 »wn Keo 34 40.50 724 3.63 11.15 0.61 2.90 80 201 50 26 725 577 871 078 5^ tI ? iuda Dis^ 37 35.32 1,094 3.92 9.02 0.76 0.96 76 186 3650 1094 4 74 770 089 ill il \ 'to Keio 33 50.36 632 4.67 10.79 0.63 359 69 217 6332 635 7 16 885 077 RQR In 9 'wn Ito 35 27.45| 802 2.56 10.74 0.64 0.97 92 210 SI 801 IH HI QM £ 9? 1 &lt;e Roi GaS 97Tb" 46 35.24 1,099 4.419 7.97 0.778 5!22 61 191 ib~88 — TTTi — Tfi2Q — « fti n in? — KvZ an 1 i Tisconsin Ga, 98.5 37 5554 1 577 7.816 7.07 0.874 0^0 67 178 6300 l'579 g'S? 746 0829 000 67 1 wn Ga. 99.0 39 3559 933 4526 8.35 0.741 0.00 86 179 4459 931 5018 883 0701 000 85 1 &gt;wn Ga. 98.0 44 32.37 1,075 3.539 9.15 0.678 OJOO 73 192 39J4 1.075 I MM Illl o!631 0.00 68 1 jwn Kero. 95.0 58 4052 1,102 4.123 9.76 0.701 &lt;h00 62^ 183 44.01 1,099 4.461 9.87 0.693 — 000 61 — I )wn Ke.-o. 97.0 48 36.15 1,055 3.898 957 0.740 1.80 82 185 40.66 1 050 4.070 999 0 687 256 76 1 gaukesha D^. 97.0 30 25.36 1,102 3.014 8.41 0.825 0.00 56 161 29.00 1 100 3.620 8 01 0.866 000 54 1&lt; Vaukesha Gai 97.0 25 30.16 1,102 3564 9.24 0.668 0.00 67 168 35.69 l|lO2 3.906 9JL4 oil?! o!oO 66 1' /eRoi Gai 99.4 85 67.37 1,101 7.236 9.31 0.661 0.00 80 206 75.88 1,101 8567 9.18 0.670 0.58 74 2) )wn Gas 99.6 39 42.30 926 4.240 9.98 0.617 0.00 66 165 48.42 925 5.133 9.43 0.653 0.00 58 li ■teams Gas 98.9 40 57.39 997 6.445 8.90 0.692 0.00 72 185 64.55 1,004 6.367 10.14 0.608 0.00 72 1 )wn Dirt. 96.7 48 20.32 1,001 2577 8.92 0.778 0.00 72 203 24.16 999 2.467 9.79 0.709 L06 90 2: l^ 11 ! 1. ero - S!'f B 27SS 1 ' 100 2 * 472 H- 06 °- 621 °- 76 90 212 29 - 8 l LI© 2 2.624 11.36 0.604 0.89 89 2 7aukesha Gas 98.8 36 36.05 1,148 4.625 7.79 0.793 0.00 95 182 4256 1152 5507 8.12 0.761 0 00 96 1! wn Kero. 94.3 40 27.37 1,098 2.601 10.52 0.652 0.00 70 202 28.97 1101 2.880 10.06 0.682 0 00 79 2 iont, Gas 99.3 35 3057 1,200 3.671 8.25 0.736 0.00 | 63 1 185 35.04 1 1500 1 4.181 | 8.38 0.724 0.00 63 1} j™ Kero. 94.0 65 21.05 1,100 2.689 7.83 0.855 2^90 48 212 23.24 1,104 3586 7.07 0.853 OBT) 48~2l )wn Gas 98.0 68 26.12 1,102 2.741 9.53 0.637 0.000 48 191 29.09 1 100 3.059 9.51 0.638 0.000 45 1! )wn Kero. 98.0 64 19.99 1,001 2.037 9.81 0.687 0.000 65 162 25.83 1,000 2.585 9.99 0.677 0.000 66 1! t 1 Kero - ,n«'2 f 7 27 ' n 1 ' 160 2 - 749 9 ' 86 °- 684 °- 000 S 3 I 78 29 - 72 1,148 3.064 9.70 0.695 0.000 71 1! lercules Gas 100.0 61 22.10 1,201 2.707 8.16 0.743 0.000 71 182 24.84 1,198 3.008 856 0.735 0.000 66 li ■ Kero&gt; ,2H 6l 28 - 30 1 ' 191 2- 831 100 ° °- 674 !- 285 105 213 3059 1,192 3.042 9.96 0.677 1.645 101 2 Wisconsin Gaj 100.0 45 79.96 1,041 11.380 7.03 0.870 0.000 90 175 9053 1,047 12.077 7.47 0.818 0.000 85 1« )wn Ka-o. 96.0 60 44.29 1,125 4.252 10.42 0.655 0.000 58 186 49.04 1,132 4.906 10.00 0.682 0.000 68 1 lerculea Gai 96.9 50 37.14 1,428 4.047 | 9 18 0.674 0.000 72 181 40.36 1,417 4.300 1 9.39 0.660 0.000 71 1, Special GaT" 99^0 88 4353 1,366 5.008 8.63 0.718 O0OT 76 187 48.37 1,362 5.502 8.79 0.705 (Tool) 74 II Vaukesha Gaj 100.0 47 45.18 1,500 5.863 7.71 0.788 0.000 65 180 52.68 1,498 6.395 8.22 0.738 0.000 72 11 Vaukesha Gai 100.0 65 65.60 1,501 6.834 8.14 0.746 0.000 78 174 66.53 1,601 7.815 8.51 0.713 0.000 91 1« Gai 100.0 46 31.11 1,199 3.253 9.56 0.632 0.000 61 185 36.09 1,198 4.093 8.82 0.685 0.000 54 li </seg>
            <seg id="p046">NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS OF AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA . MARKET JANUARY 1, 1935 . DRAWBAR TES /arying RATED LOAD— TEN HOURS " " Load . 1 1 — 1 1 . . . neHour Slip of Fuel Water Temp.°F. FimtGear Draw Dnvere . , ; — r . t. P. M. Draw Bar Mflea Av. Per Cent Type D. B. Lbs. Draw 1 Bar Pull per Eng. ■ — of Gear Gals. H. P. per Gal. Draw Bar Mil H. P. Lbs. Hour R.P.M. Point Face Lug Used per Hours D. B. per Atm. Rad. Bar Pull pe' en Low Lugs Rim Hour p'r Gal. H.P.hr. Hour H. P. Lbs. Hoi 3 I 29 | 30 I 31 | 32 I 33 1 34 1 85 1 86 I 37 j 38 39 j 40 41 42~ 43 " 44 45 46 93 1 9511 1.08 1 188 2.17 1 1,334 12255 1 1 Angle 1 059 I 8.78 I 1.62 oWl 1 204 I 0.78 187 156 25| 896 1 13.63 | 1,859 2.75 | 821 | 7.90 |. .... .| Spade |. ." . .\ 2.86 | 4.76 | 1.41 frsO I 87 1 198 | 17.83 2,155 3.10 {80 I 1,246 1 1358 | 1.477 | 3.37 | 1535 | 14.00 | 5.60 | Angle | Int. | 2.88 | 4.61 | 1.48 I 0.04 | 62 | 176 | 11.36 | 2,525~jT6S J88 1,197 I 9.35 I 1,114 3.15 I 1507 1 10.17 I -5.71 I Angle Intl E79 653 159~TTl6 91 I 210 1 12.70 I 2.727 1 74 i9l 822 1 18.33 I 3,118 2.21 | 839 | 7.75 | 055 | Angle Low | 2.94 | 653 1.09 | 0.14 59 | 166 1 22.37 | iflU lift! SLIPPAGE __^__^__ 05 993 17.30 2,927 252 998 JMO Spade Low 27J6 636 O6 0l&gt;3 71 190 22.50 3.778 25S 53 895 27.17 4.368 2.33 904 7.66 Spade Low 4.37 6.22 1.09 0 59 82 194 84.65 J640 2 3C 57 1.098 22.12 3,233 2.57 1,111 5.57 Cone Low 4.01 5.51 1.12 oll7 85 186 40.79 tjlm III? 95 1,093 40.26 4,442 3A0 U13 11.44 Spade High &lt;U2 6^68 0l&gt;3 &lt;U4 84 184 49.44 7.607 2 43 95 1,519 0.53 145 1.37 1,627 28.64 Spade High 0.30 1.77 8.47 .. 82 0.55 222 0 93 66 841 20.96 2,455 3.20 844 6.93 Spade Int. 3.46 6.06 1.09 ' 2.29 63 183 24.89 3395 2.34. 76 1,022 10.90 1,196 3.42 1,026 4.19 Spade Int. 1.78 6.11 1.12 0.05 61 204 19.60 2355 2 49 45 720 26.42 3,276 3.02 724 6.24 Spade Int. 3.34 7.91 0.86 1.97 56 182 37.79 6385 222 G9 1,073 18.77 1,928 3.65 1,105 2.82 Spade Low 2.66 7.07 0.97 0.00 72 174 80.42 8190 3 58 57 626 30.38 3.504 3.25 634 4.19 Spade Int. 4.49 6.75 101 3.45 76 204 4718 6965 2 54 45 796 115.38 1,577 3.66 796 3.85 Spade High 2.30 6.69 1.02 0.64 78 210 28.53 4462 2M 59 I 1,071 20.04 2,201 Ol 1,101 JT37 Spade High 8^939 5l)9 1519 055 63 188 28.53 — 6140 2 08 24 1.565 40.74 4,317 3.54 1,571 0.62 Aigle Int. 6.231 6.54 0^44 o!o5 88 193 65.51 9725 2 14 •01 923 21.25 2572 3.51 925 3.54 Spade High 4.014 5.29 1.169 0.00 84 166 33.20 4400 2*83 10 1.070 1 22.58 2.499 3.39 1,075 5.42 Spade Int. 3.440 6.66 0.945 olo9 | 85 174 29.16 4716 2J32 .54 1,095 2658 2,855 3^45 1,095 9^71 Spade Int. O28 6\52~ Ol9 0J3 65 185 30.02 4555 2 47 ;87 1.062 22.78 2558 3.78 1.058 4.56 Spade Int. 3.688 6.18 1.111 o!64 68 184 30.07 3 912 HI , l3 2 J'Sfi 1 S-! 2 5«2?2 S-S 4 H? 3 8 -5 5 s P ade Low 2 - 934 5 * 2 i- 829 0.00 67 m 22.0s 2880 2.88 113 1,089 18.68 2,389 2.93 1,110 6.96 Spade Low 3.262 5.73 1.077 0.00 70 175 25.50 3,549 2.69 H? X -2I2 iHl i%ll 2-S 1 »22I 4 - 60 Spade m * h 7 - 812 5 - 58 l - 108 01 ° 86 19 » 55 - 72 1 7,840 2.67 m 920 27.79 2,956 3.53 926 4.78 Spade High 4.190 6.63 0.929 0.09 94 186 33.99 4 918 2 59 131 995 39.84 3,723 4.01 992 4.03 Spade High 5.878 6.78 0.909 0.19 91 187 47 77 5950 301 393 990 12.34 .1,232 3.76 1,007 5.60 Spade Int. 2.079 5.94 1.169 0.05 81 192 18.07 sloifS 254 214 1,101 17.41 1,856 3.52 1,100 8.76 Spade Int. 2.479 7.02 0.977 0.00 78 195 19.60 3,289 2.20 214 1.142 20.35 2,191 3.48 1,153 7.06 Spade High 4.035 5.04 1.225 0.00 91 166 27.25 4 482 2.28 203 1,099 17.88 1.599 4.19 1,104 8.01 Spade Int. 2.377 7.52 0.912 0.00 72 190 22.70 2950 2 88 253 1.187 19.28 1 1.934 3.74 1,192 5.33 Spade Int. 3.114 6.19 0.980 0.00 40 | 186 1 25.63 3J679 2J61 226 974 10.67 1,212 3l$6 1,102 7^9 Spade Int. 2421 136 1.532 0.727 71 197 13.60 3289 1 65 243 1,070 15.52 1,813 8.21 1,106 5.15 Spade Int. 2.628 5.91 1.028 1.362 86 207 16.14 3,202 1.89 085 839 11.87 1,327 3.35 1,003 6.32 Spade Int. 2501 5.40 1549 0.032 78 172 18.80 8,334 2.12 i\i H 2 J JH9 2 '2SI S* 28 1 ' 162 6 ' 66 S P ade 2 - 852 7 - 70 °- 876 °- 065 63 178 22.69 3,664 2.32 329 1,148 15.64 1,622 3.62 1508 2.75 Spade Int. 2.581 6.06 1.008 0.022 86 187 19.91 3,247 2.30 261 1,166 18.99 2,031 3.51 1,188 956 Spade Int. 2.436 7.80 0.865 0.135 89 199 23.56 3,241 2.73 i 3 , 2 . J'?iS 51-TT &amp;V1 2&gt;5 ° 1&gt;049 8 - 14 **&amp; ***■ 9 - 521 fi 58 °- 973 °- 075 52 188 83.63 18061 1.74 I™ Y 'l Q l S5- 44 2&gt; ? 40 8 - 63 1 ' 128 8 ' 89 S P ade 8 - 974 7.16 1.049 0.113 67 185 28.86 6,116 2.08 596 1.347 2250 2.422 3.44 1,418 9.80 Spade Int. 4.235 554 1.181 0.132 48 186 27.87 | 4£50 255 ■29 1,340 27.10 3,263 331 p64 636 Spade 1st 47762 {£69 O67 (MJO 76 183 33.57 4;73 2.95 31 M22 ?f #4 2 t»?fg 3 -°i 1 ' 496 °- 89 Cleats 2nd 5.556 6.38 0.947 0.00 73 190 43.73 8.J75 1.96 1= J-fff 4 5-i2 MS f-2! H2J 1&gt;07 Cleats 2nd 6 - 691 6 - 74 °- 896 °- 067 75 181 54 - 43 10 » !12 i- 98 lf lZS IVTl J'SiS f-gf 1.W8 4.83 Spade 2nd 3.334 5.33 1.133 0.045 72 170 24.98 3/63 2.49 •90 926 15.84 1,702 3.38 950 253 Spade 2nd 2.426 6.32 1.096 0564 75 202 18.86 2,553 2.48 : U \'\ll J 2 -Il 1'fJf i'5I h%&amp; H 7 S P ade 2nd 2 - 478 5 - 10 1 - 352 0-014 80 186 16.79 2/64 258 11 h lSS li-% i'SSf l-£ J-2SS f-55 Spade 3rd 2.553 5.81 1.057 0.075 90 202 18.45 4,40 1.67 «a i? 7 , 4 . ?Z-H ?'I2I iH J'922 !-7J Spade 2nd 4480 6 - 18 !-l° 7 0-037 91 180 33.82 4,33 3.07 §2 Hoi JHI £■£[? HI Hi? «2?. S? ade 2nd 2 - 917 6 - 09 1 - 003 °- 747 94 212 23 - 01 3^ 2 - 74 78 1,435 30.44 3,741 3.05 1,451 0.99 Cleats 2nd 6.482 5.55 1.097 0.078 87 192 40.66 7J80 2.01 tl i?Ii ll-ll J'ioS I-? 4 ,?IS 1-29 ■ i pa^ e 2nd 2 - 424 6 - 64 1Ji02 °- 000 66 195 i 8 - 17 89 2 - 36 m Ho2 ?2'S 8 2'f22 HI J'ifS ?- 44 . §,? ade 2nd 8 -!52 6.62 1.024 0.053 69 175 24.85 4157 2.24 96 1527 18.04 2,528 2.68 1,253 1.42 Cleats 2nd 2.481 7.27 0.932 0.138 77 180 23.33 5156 1.70 32 1.024 61.69 9,562 2l2 Oil O| Cleats 2nd &amp;24X 7^ OW! 0.000 65 172 75.66 15,186 1.88 ?1 Hq? ?i'2I MH %%, \'¥&amp; ?•!? S eats 2nd 3326 6 - 94 °-875 0.000 68 182 2652 5 06 1.89 \\ H5? Wlh ?*Si HI 1'5^2 HI 91^^ 2nd 2.949 6.35 0.956 0.000 77 182 20.97 *m 1.77 s ■« &amp;3 as a '« m ss a ts&amp; a &amp;s s s i?f as z\ \-m § -1 11 |«i |?f j-1 a sa isf urn ?:5i s as n s as ts at 45 1.573 33.69 1 4,668 2.71 1,599 | 1.11 Cleats 3rd 4.371 7.71 0.797 0.000 52 | 177 41.78 9199 1 1.67 70 1,356 10.09 1,172 353 1,401 2.61 Spade 2nd 1.608 657 0 986 0 000 48 191 n 68 S7?) 2sT % % M ffi HI '28? 8-?i 6 $*? ? nd &gt;P° ™l 0.918 oS 74 174 S?! mil ill 28 836 40.17 6,160 2Ao 851 0.71 Cleats 2nd 3.668 11.26 0 640 0 000 77 1 G9 52 61 1J7RS 1 S&lt;5 53 1,002 35.70 4,304 3.11 1,050 0.81 Cleats 2nd 5 000 7.14 0 846 0000 65 188 4787 fell 203 44 1.155 22.98 2.714 3.18 1502 2.06 Cleats 2nd sioee 7M oilol o'.145 60 198 29.65 SSS III! 82 801 63.62 10,455 258 820 1.19 Cleats 2nd 5.167 12.31 0 590 0 000 76 170 80 51 1&amp;97 1 61 44 1.184 24.92 2 714 3.44 1500 9.83 Spade 2nd 3 680 677 1 028 0000 54 183 2645 '501 220 26 1.370 9.71 1J122 355 1,401 | 2.69 Spade 2nd | 1.363 7/J8 0.945 0.000 38 199 11.81 ;814 2.44 '•36 1,169 12.61 1,524 Oo" 1503 2^67 Spade 2nd 1.906 6^62 L02l 0~013 67 206 15 38 2S3 2~4T »57 947 16^1 1,839 3.33 976 3.33 Spade 2nd 2.219 7.35 0 958 0071 53 203 1872 923 240 .77 1561 12.16 1,201 3.79 1599 7.80 Spade 2nd 1.870 6.50 1069 0100 77 189 12 84 921 251 •97 935 4159 5.649 2.74 950 1.30 Cleats 2nd 5.511 7.49 0824 0000 103 187 4893 1^84 1 77 !14 1505 21.87 3516 2.55 1,249 1.81 Cleats 2nd 3.109 7.03 0.873 oioOO 74 163 27il5 ill :l0 1,178 19.08 2,806 2.55 1550 1.75 Cleats 2nd 2.855 8.10 0.858 0 000 68 188 23 43 534 1 94 01 1.059 27.80 4,180 2.49 1,101 3.79 Cleats 2nd 4.034 6.89 0.891 0 000 76 182 33 88 622 167 27 1.194 19.55 2.870 2.55 1.249 1.50 Cleats 2nd 2.862 6.88 0.899 0 000 54 180 25 26 900 193 19 1.636 9.90 1,195 3.11 1,701 2.19 Spade 2nd 1.988 4.98 1.367 0.053 53 195 12.56 998 2 36 tlO 1.079 33.79 4,663 2.72 1,099 0.91 Cleats 3rd 2.628 12.86 0.588 0 000 55 196 43 05 528 169 12 1,633 1 10.52 1550 3.16 lffOQ 2.19 Spade 2nd 1662 6.33 0.972 0.064 52 190 13 52 MQ 2J37 .KA TRACTOR TESTS, JANUARY, 1935 i -■■■ ■ -. ■ ■ .. ■ ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p047">ASKA DRAWBAR TESTS = r_ MAXIMUM LOAD FhtGear ■ q^. I q^ V-gj^— -.j i5^^ S5^S Draw Draw Draw "n I i 1 H^J^^^j^J^^j^^^j^^ H Bar Pull &amp; Bsr Pull &amp; * -^ « | 46 | 47 1 48 I 49 I 50 51 | 52 Egj^ 5? 66 | 57 j 68 59 | 60 | 61 | ** 0.78 I 187 11.56 I j j r— i : r , - 17.83 1 2,155 1 3.10 28 c ' * ' -j^jj^ | | | | 29 11.361 2,52511.69 116.10 1 2,260 | 2.67 1 1 | I--ITJ^7...| [ | , , , , , 73 12.70 I 2,727 1.74 1 13.27 1^325 8.06 I 10.41 I 868 I 4.60 I. .. 1 i j j rjyf 22.37|&lt;,374 i.92 { 23.18 3,040 1 2.86 I ..... .1 | |...;^; ;;;;; ;|;;; ;;; ;;; ;;; ;;;;;;|;;;-; | | }}J 22.50 3,778 2.23 21.47 2^41 8.17 : r-^r 84-65 .640 2.30 32.63 3 992 8.06 .. ' *fi 40.79 t,933 2.57 37.78 3,931 1 3.60 '••'••* ••'liji"!!! '-'.'.II! ll'.'.ll llll'.l i!'.!!! !:i'.'.'. ill! | 126 *jJH 2.43 50.03 6l$55 3.50 ~ ToE 0.55 222 0.93 0.71 160 165 JoS 24.89 3395 2.84 26.10 3,007 sJI 'Hm 2.315 • v.06" vs.:: \:\:\\ \:":: :\:\:\ \:^ \\:\\\ \\\- -y.: : ::::: iS 19-gg 2^55 2.49 17.92 1,937 8.47 19.08 1,436 4.98 M2 Wit Vlll 2 - 22 88 ' 66 4 ' 787 3.02 84.58 3 477 8.73 \% 50.42 8,190 3.58 28.12 1,995 5.29 ' ill SHI 5-2^ S-5 4 **- 10 W 52 8 - 15 5 4 ' 025 8 - 99 •• •" ' 145 28.53 6.140 2.08 29l6l O59 8.41 " ~ — -~ TaZ ofoi ?T55 2 - 14 51 - 67 5 '*3 7 8 - 56 89 -6i 2,687 5.68' ::::.:::::': ul 33.20 4,400 2.83 32.37 8,488 8.48 . it? 29.16 4,716 2.32 30.20 3,336 | 3.40 27.78 1 2,176 4.78* Y.WW '.'.'.'.'.'. '.'.'.\Y.\\\\ Y. YYYYY. Y.Y.Y. YYYYY. YYYYY. Y.Y.Y. 152 S f.555 2.47 29^6 3,427 8.25 30.08 2,645 4.26 155 2-27, Ml$ Fl 2803 2 ' 8 * 6 3 - 69 26.46 2190 4.36 156 J2.08 2,880 2.88 18.66 1,627 4.28 157 25.50 3,5492.69 22.91 2,079 4.13 Y.YY. YYYYY. YYYYY. Y. \Y '.Y YY. '.Y. '. Y. '.'. YYY. '.Y. Y. Y.Y '. YY. ill 55.72 I 7,840 2.67 54.61 5,324 3.85 161 )3.99 4,918 2.59 34.30 3,693 3.48 ]ro 17.77 6,960 3.01 47.57 4,356 4.09 ?cq 18.07 3,018 2.24 17.25 1,784 3.62 16.59 1,293 4^i" '. Y.YY. YYYY. '. '. Y. Y. '. '. Y. Y. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. YY. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. 164 19.60 3,289 2.20 21.41 2,358 3.40 20.20 1,525 4.97 167 27.25 4,482 2.28 29.18 3,298 3.32 igo £H2 i- 950 2 - 88 20 - 91 2 » 038 3 - 85 i8 - 84 W87 5.79 :::::: .::::':::::: ::::;■ :::■; t&amp;l 25.63 3,679 2.61 24.62 | 2,466 | 3.74 | 2(h39 | M14 5.82 \ | '. .. YY. . YYYYY. YYYYY. YYYYY. YYYYY. 170 M 8^ 89 1-55 18^58 1,614 3.14 8A8 881 8.35 ~ 173 3202 1.89 18^0 2,226 3.08 12.66 580 8.96 . 174 18.80 3,334 2.12 18.89 2,076 8.41 16.67 1,408 4.41 : 175 52.69 3,664 2.32 24.40 2,894 8.16 23.65 2,076 4.26 ! 176 L9.91 3^47 2.30 19.65 2,050 8.58 1952 1,694 4.62 YYYYY. YYYYY, YYYYY. YYYYY. YYYYY. 177 23.S6 3,241 2.73 21.86 2,303 8.56 2252 1,781 4.68 180 83.63 18^61 1.74 77.92 11,469 2.55 81.13 8,250 8.69 . . 182 11-1% 5 Al$ 2- 08 U£1 8 ' 650 8 ' 61 31.18 2,412 4.85 183 27.87 1 4^50 2^5 29.52 3,282 8.87 25.75 2420 4.55 11 YYY. Y. Y.YY. . YYYYY. YYYYY YYYYY. YYYYY. 184 J3~57 4;73 2.95 291J0 2J3l 4.06 29.10 2,060 5.30 185 13.73 8.J76 1.96 41.83 5,147 3.05 39.19 3,475 4.23 186 54.43 10,!12 1.98 52.22 6,371 3.07 49.63 4 547 4.09 187 £2S 2»;S2 Ml 51-12 2 - 3 52 H 8 i 8 - 84 M«g 5.59 1 .lllll llllll llllll llllll .lllll lllM lllli: is? </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>