<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00017.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00017.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE NORMAL SCHOOLS</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
          
           
            <seg id="p001">Lincoln. Nebraska. January 1st ncy. John H. Mickey. Governor of Nebraska )n Iiehalf of the Nebraska State Board of Education and in with the law, creating said Board, herewith please find d statement of the expenditures of the several funds under , from the beginning of the present Biennium to December 31st, original vouchers are regularly filed with the Auditor, while properly filed in the office of the Secretary. ml ,l.-iai Very respectfully </seg>
            <seg id="p002">&lt; BOARD OF EDUCATION Ex E.I Majors. IVr dent, James E. Detaell, U Luther P. Ludden. D. D. xiir-Uon Lineoi x-Off ex-Off CO^flMITTEES. C'hilds. Delz itive — Maj xldei Finn B. Lndden I'riniinj; — Childs, Mortensen. McHrien .1. \V. Crabtree. Be. I).. I'linripal. l'« A 0 Thomas, Ph. D., Principal. K ■ (liiids. York .1 I. McBrien. Lincoln, in. Line i iid Employes — McBrien, Tex! and Lihrarj Hooks and i Study </seg>
            <seg id="p003">v 1 I i joy BIENNIAL REPORT H I- STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION GOVERNOR JOHN II. MICKEY ars of your adm at as Governor, now closing arked with many Intereslln ialth to which you can loi \\i in the years that i. Few, if any. ait 1 more epoc iking than those of the Normal ;hool we DIFFICULT PROBLEMS. t ration you were confronted with al School work. The I. nal School at Peru new and n&lt; ae tim&lt; mating a new Normal ;i vf ry careful considera placed your official approval upon riticize at the time, the wisdom of t The rounding out of your four both acts. Wh on is now abundan Cov, !•• acknowledge their v tions to you in these p&gt;! tus your action .nave educational nire has entered into the given by your Excellency in the Normal and other school n and to admit the splendid &gt;rk No better help or more hool work of Nebraska than the u t you have approved touchi two biennium Appended to this report you will ru and Kearney. We call special d the details of the advance a: :ention to the tables thai work in thi OUR ADVANCEMENT. One of the strongest reasons for tl that it affords an equal opportunit public or State normal eda to all in the state. Bqaa i by those of the remote rural d ely populated centers. The rema well as those of the more able growth of our Normal School unparalleled in the In- In the beginning of your admi problems touching the No lassed bills granting to the N of the Sta;&lt; advancement made in Normal Schc ttendanee during the past four d in the history of an I the I'nion. The rritii - .lishin </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 &lt; ■lormal would mean the crippling, if not the death, of the Normal • in The most sanguine advocates of additional Normals were only M to your Exn Henry the hope that when the buildings were ileted and the school in opentka we might see. as other states had in their new normals, from one hundred and fifty to two hundred and nients in the first two or even tour years of their history. What Are the Facts? Witn lh( 'I' the hill mating another Normal School and its |teol location at Kearney. Peru began a new life. That year Peru had a total enrollment of 7M. Last year the total enrollment at Peru was of gain would give us this year as an en - rollment 1 .T.rjT. The indications are at this writing. November M, IMC, Miniated attendance will be fully realized. The attendance at rtod IH114 was IM, last year it reached 655 while this year Today the students are simply up to the limit of the capacity of elty of lie buildings with many applicant till coming in The new Normal at Ktarnev has had almost phenomenal growth atrifiilated in the first full year of her history, thus break - of ali new Normals in the Ualted States. She starts out &gt;l her history to eren surpass the splendid record made Why all this advancement: whv all Why all this advancement; why all in enrollment?" Simply because Nebraska has been .litiou to her Normal School wor'i and because the State has ,uirements and ■ demand for better teachers. and be "' led. We are just in the beginning ol The educational pr will depend largely uiwn the of our teachirs. Our Normal Schools thus become educational They furnish trained teachers, better educated and at the same ne a source of inspiration to other teachers all over the State, irmging them to pursue ttndiei .&gt; aspire to nobler aims in life come in contact. in the higher institutions of learning for teachers and students with whom Kl r&lt;al value of the Normal Schools of the State can not be meas - the number of grata ,,se from the undergraduate classes u OUI • ■'■ a large number, not as well equip|&gt;ed as they be. but better equipped than when they entered the institution, actual work of teaching, so that the good accomplished can be •d only by considering the entire number receiving instruction for f the com Bof this ad\ in Normal School work means also a direct equipment, for sufficient money to pay good u '•■ **■ i" ;ikt&lt; a backward stei </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 i consideration that w. rtion ■idered. Good salaries for itutions of our State is truly i nt attention A mi! w nade by Sui&gt;erintendent Carr of National Su Ing of 19(14. He r« a m&lt; to purchase an organ ■cted and put in a pipe on began to worship in the w church it was found that Sister Jones, the old organist, could not i nere was too much machinery about it for ker. S to do with it. Then tni ,,f the dau «nred, and the failed to produce satisf.. icons w Idow'i daughter, w 's daughter, who was a good musician and who was a good musician and who eded the place, was persuaded to try and play: but she could not get persuaded to try and play: but she could M he pipe organ. There was great dissatisfacn mmitiee were charged with mismanage was great dissatisfaction in complicated machinery, the congregation seemed to bt icated machinery, the congregation seemed to be a the committee secured from the city, at a good m the city, at a good splendid organist. When the master musician began playing mist. When the master musician began playing fa such music as they had never heard befo lls with such music as they had never heard bef. ick to the old reed organ or the old organist. 11 or the old organist ool work, with all of its enrichment in the I al bohool work, with all of its enrichment in the gnized as a new instrument in our school « rument in our school in Normal School work, a few years aL-o, h;\&gt; vork, a fev r-iHldiini is now swinging another way, an.; nother way, and the 1 directors are recognizing that, like the organ in ton a Izing that, like the organ in S . it takes a mast.-!- teacher to operate the in. er to operate the modern In fact, .Nebraska schools are the desire. i [ n fact, Nebraska schools are he d« those who operate the machines, and it is an im- machines, and it is an im- qow ho &gt;w how and where to secure a sufficient nn i secure a sufficient number Public sentiment has line, but it now has reached wt aught, well-d ht. well-directed teachers. Public sentiment education alons; this line, but it now ha~ enianding good results from our schools. I it is den suits from our schools. It is the proper means of securing the good tear the proper mea peled to show that they can do good tear! it they can do good teaching. ;o and are employing noi; w i are recognizing tr dless of whi aiizing the fact also and are employing noni live, so long as they are properly freely a few years ago— the lack of pn hers — will soon pass away if the State will ;i tic-ism offered fr. art of the teachers — wil .v ;o — the lack of | soon pass away if the Sta er State Xormal Schools. There roper su| per support to her State Normal School up and ind call you blessed in the years to come beet i took such a great step forward in i CBlstag the fact that tie -r prepar- sed in the years to come !&gt;• h a great step forward in were Governor, you thus i- - r reat rk </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 each year. We uze thai educati i lion, but a careful combination of the two, and t into the teaching practices is doing wont a&lt; if our State THE ADVANCE SHOULD CONTINUE. Our State should continue the advance step taken during your ad ration and commit herself more fully to a bitter Normal Sch a .1 In the matter of buildings and equipment ■ av irward but are not now able in either school to handle all th« forward but are not now able in either schc for us to secure. Xor have we tht sible for us to seem n a idents now in the school. Our teachi iiltnts now in the sc two inst inn ions are among the very best wo instiii? ■ scholars in the land .11:' high ideals and splendid high ideals and splendid teaching i&gt;ow teachin in each sc in each school ano rtment, iidua and training departm nal of any schoo and training depart n qual of any school. At the same ti al Schools abreast of the ?hools abreast of th mand made for the teaching of indu i made U&gt; ling of industrial subjects i cl a! su OUR SUMMER SCHOOLS. OUR SUMMER SCHOOLS mum Normal School work shows a very i that the Hoard now make policy of the State Normal work ratle of work in the Summer N&lt; ititutioB in this country along the li d \V anent ft-ssional. academic or truly pt work. The is lo bring to out Summer Normal Schools the v itain, in addition to the • r Normal School work is growing in atten ii Summer Normal Schools the v b itain, in addition the regula Normal School work is rowing in atten y a :u and increasing in popularity. The attendance last : to the capacity of the building*. Scores of t ■ irk could not l and in popularity. Th attendance n w ,i ■ apacity of the build &gt;res of teachers who wan le work could not 1 jmmoi THE STUDENTS. THE STUDENTS. noted du liiennium i roll for the full years work and thus n ■ /f instruction .: the ten n jrk and iction throughout the ten months of the schoAt fear. The aver;. mi life in our Sts ar The a\' -ion of studi lif \ery 1. r studies. This indicates that they realize tl al with a problem that is worth studying ry high. Left to the nil studies. This indicates that they realize that they ;i ■ ith a problem that is worth studying show a laif </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 iwn personal effort to pay tie nt in part for their devotion in Of course they have all sig hools of our State. I doubt npan\ ness of the situation N'ormal School stu DO WE NEED NORMALS? I* Normals?" If all Normals. Junior Normals :»nd private Normals entered inks on graduation each aching force required annually he vacancies caused by resigna -. withdrawal! and deaths year by year. Quite a large perce: l the entire body of teachers in Nebraska are untrained as teachers le entire body of teachers in Nebraska are untrained as teacher Ve need more trained teachers and we need them badly, and the want ■ ■bras'ia in this direction is the want of every state in the I d them badly, and the want of every state in the 'he only way we can meet it in this State is to maintain our present em of Normal schools that we help supply the ever increasing de - i of all our public schools for better teachers. The Normal Schools can lite is to maintain our present Normal schools that we help supply the ever increasing de achers. The Normal Schools re the only schools in which the history, the philosophy, the theory and practice of education can be taught to any considerable number ol the only schools in which the history, the philosophy, the theory and ca nsiderable number of young men and women, and they are the only schools in which the sub are studied and ex|«&gt;unded in the manner in which they ought to eaented by the teacher in the school room. At the same time they the only schools in which the teacher, while belag trained, actually only schools in which the sub Ire studied and expounded in the manner in which they ought to iclx torn. At the same time they while being trained, actually practices teaching while being trained. There are other institutions de- while being trained. There are other institutions de voting part of their courses, of study to this specific work, they are doing ■ lid work but they still lack the particular application of the prac - work under the eye of a master teacher. The Normal School de io&gt;v course to this especial work of furnishing thoroughly educated technically trained hers who can give value re&lt; ■ of their courses, of study to this specific work, they are doing vc icular application of the prac work under the eye of a master teacher. The Normal School devote a mas ■i jf furnishing thoroughly educated a cial w who can give value rec in instinct ion for the money expended. INDUSTRIAL SUBJECTS. INDUSTRIAL SUBJECTS. The demand tar teaching certain industrial subjects in the noil schools of our State is upon us. Our Normal Schools have n the demand thus made as jusr and right. Just as fast as po&gt; e putting them on a m sound, nedasroirical liu«i« 9n H .,*. 3 fur teaching ustrial subjects in the great ind right. Just as fast as po ■ sound, pi |j a an( j ar€ these great lines. Yes, we hildren in their schools I </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 AGRICULTURE. •tody dubbed "agreii ments of agriculture, with a definite object ar ments of agriculture, with a definite object and i in view. Thus w. ratlve demand fron Thm »i demand from the r ■•immunities for teach. d along th - that will be able to bl d along these lines. We will that will be a sentimental at first. isly. until we arc beginning to realize i i.msly. until we are beginning to realize in oui this kind of teaching. We are not for 01 kfiicaltnraj College connected with our spit &gt;al value of this kind of teaching. We a Agricult ni inn our ( instruction in the Xt it our course of instruction in the Xorraal Schc and will prepare the teacher in the work of agriculture ? in the public schools of our States. The rank and tor many generations past h. .1 of much of handed down from generation to gensnti nd will pn her in the work of agriculture as it w in th ather educating tin way from the heart of nature and it of nature and the soil. Many, many d what an unguided observation would give ther what an imgaMed observation would give them; if working with the To nianv y of them soil was nothing and farm labor a drudgery and agricultural work generally illy for those who knew but little and cared to know abor a w a ho kn &lt;1. it is at ion the newe riculture and that it is ide of life into the farm and the rur &lt; ure. to keep r I rural life, to build up a sentiment s [culture and that it is no r mi ind rural life, to build up a ■ untry life and of agricultural pursuits. The com and of agricultural pursuits. The comii lit oral education in the si w ie problem ami the Normal Schools of our Ij to do their part i: lines DOMESTIC SCIENCE. DOMESTIC SCIENCE with the foregoing subject is the inal Schools of Nebraska ar ist of the Normal Schools of the country in taking very advar particular line of teaching. We are increasing our equipment ai K&gt;ts how to schools. Thus we lead th&lt; ind Hi teach domestic science to the chi m to an intelligent appreciation o </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 PERU. MANUAL TRAINING. An. &gt;iems is manual training, and the Normal Schools of Nebraska are hard at work along this line. knf manual training will ct he children with, in a real Beta of the world. It puts them in touch in a peculiar bly it will lead ibilities unities that are just before tin bject ol all ial work in our Normal Schools )lic schools how he bienneum for each school THE NEW CHAPEL AND GYMNASIUM. iK the biennium the New Chapel and Gymnasium building, out ngs on the campus, has been completed. The It is provided with bath 18, sanitary closets, locker rooms and quite thoroughly equipped for ihvsical training and indoor athletics. The first or main Hoor i - v far the largest and I ably hall owned b&gt; comfortably seating 1.M8 people. In this building are also In. jckt idoor athletics. The first or main Hoor is the best assembly hall owned b- n this building are also lo iffleea of the President of the school and the registrar. The bui President of the registrar. The building was completed and equipped, except decorating, within the appropri. led, ex ating, within the appropriation i THE NEW LIBRARY BUILDING. THE NEW LIBRARY BUILDING. During this biennium the new Library ISuilding, for which the Legis- dture o! 1901 made an appropriation of $32,000, has been com|. a an on of $:'.2,ooo. has been completed ud is now housing the M.MM volumes comprising our Normal School il is now housing the 20, lies comprising our Normal School ibrary. It is a plain, substantial, fireproof building 85x70 feet, Librar ii i 11 . substantial. fireproof building 85x70 feet, two ories high, giving ample room for X"&gt;,oimi books and reading and ri living ample room &gt;oks and reading ami nice rooms to accommodate 1 nee rooms to accommodate 1,000 students. The equipment is modern, Jdents. The equipment is modern. p-to-date, steel shelving for 2O,uo»i volumes and so arranged that as the jlunies and so arranged that as the ibrary grows, shelving for the addit ional 15.UU0 volumes can readily be THE NEW SCIENCE HALL. library building ha and brick ited into a modern ..ill. The building i nn&gt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ion to do thorough and more efficient w PRESIDENT'S RESIDENCE Ea great many years the President of the School has lived in a the main building. The great increase in attendence has com sident to vacate this part of the building. He was com i go outside of the campus to get rooms. These rooms and the ffice of the President and Registrar have now been fitted uj purposes. RENTING OF TEXT BOOKS E experiment started by the Board in the previous biennium of d books, at wholesale prices, and renting them to the stu - r a nominal fee each semester has been continued during the biennium. The results are all that we could wish. We charge EM each book for a seme f the books at the actual cost 100I year the student deposits he deposit is returned lei ist the student from one dolla 3ter. or if the student wishes they to the school. At the beginning of three dollars. At the end of the is the rental fees. By renting books to one dollar and a half per year To pu from $12.00 to $18.00 per year FEES i'.itard ha\' y eliminated all fees save the unusual brt she laboratory. SELF BOARDING. Iiring this biennium plans for self boarding have been very care - onsidered and perfected. In connection with the Domestic Science ment and under the direction of the special Domestic Science r, many of the students are boarding themselves. It affords an unity for actual exemplification of domestic science. It provides eation, adds to the pleasure of school life. The expense in self- boarding is very nominal, about one-half of that regular boarding wide, and two stories high. All of this changing, enlarging, brick- made without a special appropriation. Instead hat the Legislature gave for repairing and re- m to meet the increased demand of the science departments, the Hoard made the changes above indicated. Tak- he old science rooms for additional and much-needed class rooms. ment occupy the first floor and the physical letonce de|&gt;artrnent the second floor. This places these important depart- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 t ( t REQUIREMENTS Moaiti have joined with tl requirements. I quote fro e faculty in gradually raising the n Peru Catalogue (1904 and »re advised to fini h their high school before coming to ska are doing most thorough and ef- is hardly work, w xc a normal schools. It seldom pays one mastered thoroughly the work offered ichool until he has hon Th nts ha been made just as rigid as the law he State will permit NEEDS OF PERU For the biennium. yean ending M arch II, 1908 and March 31, 1909 the xpense items to-wit: Board estimates the following as th Estimat aries for memb&lt; of the faculty and assistant teach - for the biennium: r: 'or the Peru State Normal School For salar J92.930.00 For Current Expenses. For wages, janitors, engineer, an ;r employes $ 4,57 For fuel and light For repairs and improvement For commencement expenses and inc dentals 800.00 For physical trainin 800.00 For aKricultu For manual trainin For domestic scienc For principal's traveling expense For new engine and machinerv rr painting, frescoing new chapel, library building gymnasium and the new New Buildings. heating plant and connections $25,0' Briefly in regard to some of the ppropriations We ask for a small increase in h alary appropriation to meet the lew conditions upon us practically an increase of 500 students and no in - crease in faculty. Fully 300 students could not be taken into the school his past year because we did not have the funds to employ the needed eachers to instruct them. We continued to receive pupils so long as It n Peru. The high schools of Nebr •d or even equaled in the prepar- &gt;artments of cc t or printing and office supplies 2,500 . 00 For apparatus and laboratories 1,500.00 For postage, telegraph, telephone, freight, express and drayage. . l]500.00 For furniture and cases 1,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 iuch 100 large for good and efficient work. E us to make the needed increase in the faculty and to pay the wage ble to Kike c knocking al our doors striving to fit themselves t Fuel and Lights. We have so greatly increased the cubic feet of our building that four boilers to do the heating wr w iighted Printing Office Supplies. and offic. kindred printed supplies has i a » il heretofore. POSU Postage, Etc. wl in ool nurr xjdains the increase in this department. It is simply surprising tht ins the inn-ease in this &lt; • in« t the la lence owing n ling of the letters that run it ■ ring of the letters that run i he th - hool and the conditions, etc Repairs and Improvements. Id or main building is getting Into such a condition that auite :. I immedia i e made — a new new floors, new doors and in addition w 'I plant for twc xplains this itt Traveling Expenses of Principal. It is n. iv to go int ny details on thi Th n«- the school comi&gt;el him to travel a make these trips as formerly with. deal. It is no now 1UI xpens&lt; New Engine and Machinery E furnish our own electric ely four &gt;■ We mils to repair ii pull one half of the load lights, etc. The old er ked for a new one the now it has given out ag We are only able to fu n It is not r its that v.. ["hat is we cannot pr Ulildini: in darkness while we list urnish lights for the new library build </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 A new engine is mm "&lt;•» engme is one of the Imperative needs or else we will have limllar amount to be added to the fuel and lights fund In- similar amount added to the fuel and lights fund, in- «atag that to $14,00(1 dollars and thus enable us to buy our light from ■« that to $14,0o(i dollars and thus enable us to buy our light from ier people. Painting and Frescoing. Painting and Frescoing Ue ' " tifl11 "» chapel building and a splendid new library Ue h " itl " "» chapel building and a splendid new library Iding and the interior of both bull , t to be painted and the in) •if to be painted and the III tinted. New Buildings. New Buildings. We really need two new buildings— a new model school building to .irtments out of the basement of the main building and a ing plant. The Board decided to ask only for the new heat- We really need two new buildings— a new model school building to it of the main building, and a ln« Plant. The Board derided to ask only for the new heat- it plant. At present we are running two heating plan; :iirm i - aml the main building. This makes twi The old boiler iant. At present we are running two heating plants at the * n building. This men. The old boiler se with its smoke stuck is far too small. This winter with the in- w mall. This winter with the in- ised building! on the campus we have not been able to fully heat all buildings in real cold weather, for the smoke stack will not carry eased buildings on the campus we have not been able to fully heat all ie buildings in real cold weather, for the smoke stack will not carry y the smoke for the battery of boilers and we have to put part of the K of com IB t— Ion and thus not be able to furnish all the steam w for the and we have to put part of the mmission and led. Again the beating plant should be moved ■ little further down A iting plant should be moved a little further down nil] in order that the return water could flow back to the boilers by t ■ould flow back to the boilers by n w rlty. No* we are compelled to keep one boiler up to high pressure Xov rder to run the pump and pump the return water to the boiler n order to run the pump and pump the return IS 1&lt;4Kislatl " ■• all conn - . a new heating plant moved Just a little further down th. Ing the boilers and cow t-Mel , , Bd we win be to furnish all the heat needed. U of the fund- , [)on for tney are the i little further down the hill r ami unnel. and we will be heat neede a me funds we have not touched upon for they are the iations with the usual amoral inds we t: tl appropriations with the usual amounts. CONDITION OF THE APPROPRIATION FUNDS FOR PERU NOVEMBER 30TH, 1906. CONDITION OF THE APPROPRIATION FUNDS FOR PERU NOVEMBER 30TH, 1906. The report is in detail, carefully itemized, showing to whom the ■enort is in detail, carefully i primed, showing to whom the -iainal vouchers are on file with file in my office. ey has been paid and what for. The original vouchers are on file with Miditor. The duplicates are on file in my office. has been paid and what for. Th I The Roard hoi&gt;e8 to close the biennium without anv defic.enrv in „„ n without any deficency in any lent has compelled very careful igh on the appropriations made. inds, and yet the increased -' in order to carry the scho ment for 190.M904 was 812. The total enrollment for enrollment of 403. The increase in hool — 403 more students at the close n </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 of school last July than at the beginning of the biennium. To properly pro- Tide for this Increased attendance in the way of text-books, equipment. teachers, correspondence, etc., hag required painstaking and careful plan- ning and the most rigid economy possible to live within the appropria- tions. It meant very long hours for the teachers and large classes The increase in floor space since 1903 has been 50 per cent. The in- crease In enrollment since 1903 is nearly 100 per cent, while the increase in the faculty (1903 with 27 teachers; 1906 with 30 teachers) has been only three. In order to meet the increased enrollment and not come to the Legislature with a deflct in the teachers' Salaries fund, we have had to increase the size of the classes, increase the school hours, and the work of all the teachers. Our first classes assemble at 7:30 a. m. and our last classes are dismissed at 4 : 30 p. m. The table found on the following page sets forth in comparison many features of the school at Peru. TABLE SHOWING COMPARISON OF ATTENDANCE AT THE OPENING OF THE PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL SINCE THE YEAR 1903. Gain Over Year Attendance. Previous Year 416 420 4 or 1 491 71 or 15 C - . 655 164 or 33% Annual Enrollment. Total Gain Over Enrollment Previous Year 1903-4 812 82 or ll c 1904-5 982 170 or 20% 1905-6 1,215 233 or 23% or 1,537 (t imate) 322 or 25% (estimate) Annual Enrollment by Bienniums. Average Gain Over Enrollment. Previous Period Biennium beginning 1903 771 Biennium beginning lft05 1,098 or 4 Biennium beginning 1907 1,537 (estimate) 439 or 40% (estimate Membership of Senior Class Gain Ov Year. Membership. Previous Year 1904 45 IMS 57 12 or 26 r.7 &amp;7 IMC 89 31 or 54 ... 145 57 or 64 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Membership of Junior Class. Gain Over Membership. Previous Year. 1MII4 60 66 6 or 10% 102 36 or 54% 145 43 or 42% Increase Faculty. in Gain Over Number. Previous Year. *i 27 28 1 1906 30 9 Number includes Librarians and office force. Other Items Increase in the floor space since 1903 50% Increase in total enrollment since 1903 100% Increase in Junior class since 1904 140% Increase in Senior class since 1904 225% KEARNEY. The Legislature of 1903 appropriated $50,000 for the building in which tc, locate a New Normal. Kearney was chosen as the location. During this biennium the building has been completed and the New Normal (i. The building erected and completed during this biennium is the •i nter wing of what when fully completed will be the main school build- ing. It was completed and formally tendered to the Board for acceptance mber 20, 1905. The architect refused to recommend the acceptance the building and filed with the Board a lengthy written report pointing out eleven defects or failures on the part of the contractors to complete the building according to contract and specifications — claiming, however. that it was possible for the contractors to remedy these defects or to com- plete the building properly. Upon the recommendation of the architect 'oard refused to accept the building and notified the contractors to procted and complete the building In accordance with the contract. April 9, 1906, the architect reported in writing that all defects and in- complete portions mentioned in his report of December 20, 1905 had now completed or rectified except the defects in the marble floor and the val of the alkali stains on the front of the building. The defects in the marble floor were found to have been caused by students stepping on the floor before the cement was thoroughly set and was no fault of the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 i i ! '&gt;n the aikali stains that th°y had tried everything know now such stains and had failed. The architeci rej&gt;orte Hoard that the failure to remove the stains damaged the buildin LTpoa the payment b) the contractors to the State Tieasurer of $50 '11- building on April S linn;, was formally a&lt; aid. The vote of acceptance being unanimous LOCATION. Normal School properties at Kearney are located in the w« Of the city about a mile from the Union Pacific and Burlington pas ,rcund and me dormitory ifur noun as Green Terrace i the land and this building reconstructed ■ iitoiy ].iii .,. donation of Kearney to the State; tht gislature •1 the bolter house and heating plant built with the $15,000 appri irislature ol IMS. During this bieunium the boiler nous ..ling plant ha within the appropriation mad' THE SCHOOL 4»i ent ol and the property manning of the New Xorma faculty we c&gt;ol work is carried on in this one building, except the one depan manual training which uses rooms property fitted up on the prir cipal floor of the boiler house E"he school shows a remarkable growth in its first year, the marticu- The enrollment of the present year, November M, is 548, an increase of 148 over the enrollment of the same date one •8°- Thl rcentage of gain will carry the enrollment this beyond the 1,009 mark. In making the appropriations for the build - and the maintenance of the school the Legislature frequently said an for a school of not U IM the first biennium. The expec - i has been realized, and we enrolled the first year of the biennium n;&gt;rt- than three times the number anticipated. RENTING TEXT BOOKS Elizing the great saving made at Peru to the students by rentin;: their uxt-books, the Hoard in the very begining of the New Kearney inaugurated the same plan, buying the text- books at It- and renting them to tne students. The fees are charge.! wilt with the $50,000 appropr io provide t iii June, 19i»5 with a rammer session, using th&lt; h &gt;hk;\ building ol the city of Keariuy. The regular years wor! PThe buildiiiK was far from beiug completi e school took |K)ssession of the completed portions and niovec around from room to room keeping out of the way of the contractors. Al </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 ch semester). This makes a saving of thousands the students. REQUIREMENTS. ie Board places Kearney and Peru on the same basis in regard Dtrance requirements. The Hoard lives up to the limits of the law ii raise the entranc mits any higher would seriot^ com" today from the western po Mate. i'h&lt; se students have- none as far as their home them. A very careful analysis of the students shows I few that hare nut attained to at least the tenth grade of work quivalent. The ,■ of students that have not mastered all altered them at their home school is very sma rlt SELF BOARDING. of the nt problems in Normal work. It is at Rear i this is a new school with inn w problems to solve. Th uestion is now receiving proper at ■ n from tli ned and will soon be properly equipped, thus af- tin concerned ami l&lt; riliim the student of small means and plenty of energy the one way of ud nt of small mea uty of energy the one way of greatly reducing the uring a good education. greatly reducing the &gt;f secu ing a good education NEEDS OF KEARNEY NEEDS OF KEARNEY For tin- biennium. years ending March 31, 190S and March 31, igoy the or the biennium. years ending M rch loard estimates the following as the expense items to-wit: l'or salary ami wages principal, teachers, engineers, janitors .&lt; Koanl estimates the following as the exj •mployces . 1 Cl KRKNT KXI'I KRKNT XPENSES Printing anil office supp! 'rinting and office f&amp;pplief. f 2,.- Fuel, lights, watt -uel, lights, water .. ".* ■ 5' Postage, telephone, telegraph, freigh Equipment, furniture &amp;c tMtage, telephone, telegraph, freight tec i,_ .S: 1 equipment, furniture &amp;c _ __ _ - iO , Ol Improvement of grounds, Agric mproveineut of grounds. Agricultural experiments, school gar - dens, ftc r 11s. &amp; 'oinmencemeiit and incidental expenses 800.00 tiiniiK'i 800. Addition Ldditional Ixiiler _ Iv Dressing floors and painting wall )ressing floors and painting \vall&gt; 2,,,. hmiestic Science _ 1,, 'raveling expenses. I'rincipal ._ 5« 'wo wings to the main building _ ioo,t.« wings to the main building I The attached report of Principal Thomas shows the overcrowded condition The attached report of Principal T lows the overcrowded condition I the present building. We have even hail to partition the halls in or. 1 - &gt;re of the lemand lor more room for the ever increasing en- sent building. We have evt lad to partition the halls in order ti&gt; iore room for the ever increasing en- ollment </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 \w 1 1 t our Norms] x that tluv fit tin January 7 Honorable State Board of Edi -iilinii ;iiion of t! formal School tt K HISTORICAL. HISTORICAL. \&lt; :. T B.i Education, who irt of about t% - in the western ]&gt;; iKJUt tv 0 for the lime the building ■■&gt;] t(K in an.l At the end of the first month, 350. In D&lt; Xo\ al)out th. :] e attention b al)out their !i- ention All took deli) first yeai the su ■'th of September. The resistratior th of Bepl lose of ih be close of thi )V 10! with 830. Eighteen studei wi Iraining ( liigher c&lt;i ATTENDANCE. ATTENDANCE. of Nt </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 I'ollege and hool based that the enrollment of 1,00 to 1.200 in the second ADVERTISING. * n ropri \V m wl admission to which but we hav, FACULTY. akim mien ENTRANCE REQUIREMENTS. on with the common ource which w hools and niiting to glv ly e &lt;"' f high school work, or wh 'retains EXPENSE TO STUDENTS leh in the i suc-h ■ school. The enrollment for the firsi I with •;:'.'! stu 1 the equii ntrance in: lat we have direct nt is nee led to up -I'hool course Ivaneed </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 ■ in] M I A • tudeiit )f 13.0 idem w) * ( for the ust' of typewrit BOARD BOARD AND ROOM. .ml and room, with fuel and 1 care li w and $ $::.7"&gt; THOROUGHNESS THOR "Thoroug ■ utation Em ;ie quality of training it is iid fully impressed with th Thoroughness" is our motto. V ii:it the ne\ x imitation fo lie quality of training it is able : iiic Our n:&gt; lonal laboratory in which we attempt t ihod. We fully realize the great importance tha rk in the training of the future teachers of N ' working for numbers, but on. thoroughly equ in themselves for instruct in EMPLOYEES. An effort I ep the building in perfect condition. Th iioards, chalk trays, toilets, and floors are carefully cleaned. The is pains- chibits considerable pride in keep g in presentable and sanitary condition. The er x :. his line, and through his knowledge and careful man ment has been able to keep tl heating to the minimum. It of the management of the school to hire worthy students, who m heir way through school, to assist where needed, rather than met- from the men of the community. We way to secure efficieir than w wise could CAPACITY OF THE BUILDING The normal capacity of the building and equipment jr nun ■ At the present time there are over six hundred in actual attend Aside from the model school and laboratories, there 'ire but twelw ut twe class rooms in the building. This makes it necessary fo; ted from room to room during the day, in order t ila ■ our work at eigl &lt; in the mo- ;n t he evening. Our chap </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 i v, : t »ciple« any. During the first year, icating our n n our public schools. The &lt; lance that won] v we w ed within our income. No deficit in any fund will occur, an.l ndance but upon the record of our rinanc R.- submit A.. O. THOMAS, President CONDITION OF THE APPROPRIATION FUNDS AT KEARNEY NOVEMBER 30, 1906. ive the detailed expenditures car ?fully itemized, showing to whom The original vouchers are on hU inds have been paid and what f h the Auditor and the duplicate vc louble our ikIpius, but with all this We pride ourselves nc lehers are properly filed in my </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 m. has greatly inert ased the expenses of the Board !ile with the Auditor will be found the original vouchers properl; itemized and attached thereto will also be found the railroad receipts fo the fare paid. The Auditor's books show a balance in this fund Novembe J A. Hays, labor 121 labor and m.r . 287.88 ber — an iiltneat — has raqolred the greatest of carf ' the hii nnium without a deficit iled hi work the teachers very long hours an&lt;i ■utv laiKe classes and at the same time have not had all the equip ■it to have had. We have gone to the limit of the fund&lt; ■ Plied. The Board have already determined that tlu tunds must carry the different depai ud of the present biennium. ■ will be found itemized of Kearii- EXPENSES OF THE BOARD. I work with 1 1 . irmal, together with the largs of building and the doing away so generally with railroad trans • J Peru, Nebraska FUEL AND LIGHTS. i&gt;rialion for (he biennium beginning April 1, 1905 .$ 8: I Co.. fuel $ : 14 F. SI .mping water ! 2'j F. If. Pettlt, pumping water Coo us &amp; Co., fuel C. B. Hav.-ns &amp; Co., fuel : F. M Pettit, pumping water J. W. Crabtr. ivanced, wood cut- 303.41 13«.O ting John \V ■ il and gasoline lights, etc U. Havens &amp; Co.. fuel C. B. H.i\ fuel Cooper &amp; Cole Bros., supplies &gt;l&gt;er &amp; Cole Bros., supplies Cooper * CoIp Bros . supplies Dec. 23 Phoenix Iron Works, supplies ior 15. W 10.18 80.71 174. 75 9.76 6.65 1.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Phoenix Iron Work toel fuel B. Hav. fuel 412.45 C. B. Hav, fuel. B. Hav. fuel Columbia Ins. Co.. preml 'olumbia Ins. Co., premium •I W ii artv 51 .1. W, Crabtree, cash irie s J. W. Crabtr ; ie supplies Triumph Electric Co., rhe imph EU F. B. BccleatOD Co., sup] Oil Co.. oil am Lumber Co.. brick. B. Eccleston Co., supplies 24.90 oil and gasoline .umber Co.. brick l.i Western Supply Co., supi n Supply Co., supplies Wale's Machine Shop, su Havens &amp; Co., fuel. Wale's Machine Shop, supplies C. B. Havens &amp; Co., fuel 227. ni C. B. Havens &amp; Co., fuel. B. Havens &amp; Co., fuel 332 . 02 C. B. Havens &amp; Co., fuel. C. B. Havens &amp; Co., fuel 309 C. B. Havens &amp; Co., fuel. - &amp; We.iveriin - B. Havens &amp; Co., fuel 114.70 ipplies 174.71) ill, etc E. (',. Conkle, labor ■ mkle. labor 19.60 Phoenix Iron Works, sun Dye &amp; Meek, lumber, lime, etc 112.50 n Supply Co.. supplies 17.24 ndard Oil Co., oil and gasoline luh 10 Otoe Lumber nt indard Oil Co., oil and gasoline 17.* Crane I. B. Dennis &amp; Co., labor 22.00 Mutual Builders, labor and supplies 75.97 .1. A. Hays, carpenter work J. \V. Crabtree, money advanced 94.86 Xebr. City Iron Works, supplies 8.65 I. B. Dennis, carpenter work I. A. Hays, carpenter work 86.25 Star Publishing Co., fuel adv 3.00 Oct. 28 Standard Oil Co., oil 37.42 Triumph Electric Co., ammeter 19.90 Crane &amp; Co., supplies 1 5 . 76 Crane &amp; Co., supplies 256.61 k, brick 7.40 Cieai Western Mfg. Co., supplies 37.50 Korsmeyer Co., supplies 61 . 50 I. W. Crabtree, cash advanced 110.75 Western Supply Co., supplies SB. 13 Balance on hand Dec. II, l!»06 2.072.94 I 8,000.00 } 8,000.00 AGRICULTURE. Appropriation for the biennium beginning April 1, 1905 $ 1500.00 Nov. 26 Bausch A. Laumb Co., supplies $ 663.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 i I FUND S 4 .« t Mutual Builders, fitting laboratory .- MANUAL TRAINING. ion for the biennium beginning April 1 $ COMMENCEMENT AND INCIDENTAL riaiion for the biennium beginning April 1, 1906 $ Co., printing Co., button Jane 10 Con. &gt;., making cuts S. \V inting. 2« J. North &amp; Co., printing Neb. Bag &amp; Paper Co., decorating. Balance on hand Dec SI. 1 !+&lt;»6 t HEATING PLANT. : nation for the biennium beginning April 1, 1! ■ ' N Du'tz Lumber Co., lime and luml&gt;&lt; Howard Burns, new boiler Mutual Builders, setting boiler 1 f si J. V ... 128 J. W. Crab meed . luinlx ■ a hand I&gt; ■"1 James Morton &amp; Sons, tools.. \v. Crabtrae, eub advanced ,v (Juenzel Co., equ I h.inil D' ■ .). D. Bishop £ C&lt; 14 B 28 L. R. Dillon ■ .! . \\ rs J W. Cralilree, cash a&lt;! Jack, ribbon 14 Bee Publishing Co., advertising $ </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Mutual Builders, setting boiler 2d E 200.00 iler 2d E aterial. . C. X. Dietz Lumber Co., material 44.76 Feb. 21 E. G. Conkle, labor 40.95 E. G. Conkle, labor 40.95 F. C. Phillips Co., covering boiler 82.85 o., covering boil 82.85 Apr. 28 Western Supply Co., r boiler 261.00 .1. W. Crabtree, cash advanced 49.00 C. X. Dietz Lumber Co 74.80 rn Supply Co., header for boiler 261.00 I. W. Crabtree, rash advanced 49^00 N. Dietz Lumber Co 74.80 July 1" Western Supply Co., supplies 481.11 i n Supply Co., supplies 481.11 •I. W. Crabtree, money advanced Oct. 11 .1. W. Crabtree, money advanced Balance on hand Dec. 31, 1906 Balance on hand Dec. 31, 1906 &gt; I 2,500.00 $ 2,50 $ 2,500.00 LIBRARY BUILDING. LIBRARY BUILDING Appropriation for the biennium beginning April 1, 1905 1 ■ " K) \ 'D biennium beginning April 1, 190S $32,000.00 May 24 State Journal Co., advertising $ 33.00 May 24 State Journal Co., adverti HH $ July 1 1 Bee Publishing Co., advertising Star Publishing Co.. advertising 5.50 ublishing Co., adverti in Auk. M Star Publishing Co.. adv rtisinj 5.50 Nov. 2:: Shaul £ Assenmacher, cert. No. 1 2,358.05 N nmacht No. 1 2,358.05 Dec. 16 Phillips &amp; Co., cert. No. 1 l,OOo!oO Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, cert No. 2.. 4 635 90 Dec. 16 Phillips &amp; Co., cert. No. 1 2;! Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, cert No. 2 4,635.90 19U6 Apr. 12 Phillips &amp; Co., cert. No. 2 2,527.50 A 52 Korsmeyer Co., supplies 160.49 Korsmeyer Co., supplie: 160.49 Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, cert. Xo. 3 4,326 50 Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, c N rt N. Dieiz Lumber Co., c X. Dietz Lumber Co., cement 137.36 ment M 1 Geo. A. Berlingnof, fees 50.00 June in J. A. Hays, labor 3o!oO E. G. Conkle. labor Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, cert. No. 4 1,500.00 Korsmeyer Co.. supplies 16.50 Jui. Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, c rt No. 4 1,500.00 1H.5H Western Electric Co., supplies 213 80 in Electric Co., sup[ es 213.80 Aus. 20 E. O. Conkle. labor 15.'oo 15.00 Shaul &amp; Assenmacher umacher 3,5o&lt;&gt; 5on.no Oct. 11 State Journal Co., Equipment lV Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, bill for extras 46.10 o. Journal Co., Equipn ?nt 1,1 ul &amp; Assenmacher, bill for extras Shaul &amp; Assenmacher. final cert 3 951 05 Shaul &amp; Assenmacher, final cert 3,951.05 F. C. Phillips Co., final cert 3,772.50 ■ A. Berlinghof, fees 1,378.57 Balance on hand Dec. SI, l!'O6 1,293.18 $32,000.00 $32,0" $32,000.00 FURNITURE AND CASES. FURNITURE AND CASES. Aj:propriation for the biennium beginning April 1, 1905 1905 inning April 1, 1905 $ 800.04 Apr. 21 R. S. Collins, pianos $ 15 00 1 Curtice Co.. rent of pianos 90^00 Xebr. School Supply Co.. globes Hen g chart 6.00 Rudge &amp; ■■ liairs 21 00 Apr. 21 R. S. Collins, pianos $ 15 00 24 Ross P. Curtice Co.. rent of pianos 90^00 Nebr. School Supply Co., globes 30.75 30.75 ' "■■ s"")t-» Jli.it Henry \\ Poor, drawing chart 6 Of 6.00 21 .00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 F s E. 11 rent of ptai - \vi I. W. ( J \V J PUMPING PLANT. $ -:*r PublL im S Mutual Buili :i Burr Mutual Btiilder- Builders. v ■ t s POSTAGE, TELEGRAPH, ETC ■ riation for the biennium t inning April 1, 19 $ 9 I W. ( * July H J. \V I |*osUs J. W. I W. ( phont .! W (r lx&gt;st .1. W. Cr Apr. 28 J. W. Crabtree, post J. \v J. W. Cralv i express J. W ■ l </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 j $ APPARATUS AND LABORATORIES. * &lt;V- * 1.0 PRINTING AND OFFICE SUPPLIES. winning April l $ 2s New Century Print \ 1.7 \. lfi I'litegi'i Nebr. Paper Bag Co.. supplies 8.0 I. D. Bishop &amp; Co., printing 85. • Bishop &amp; Hacker, printing 53 8.00 Harry Poi Cornel] Engraving Co., Buppllea 62.68 45. J. \V. Cr \v Nebr. Paper Bag Co., supplk Harry Porter, supplies 8.00 Bishop &amp; Hacker, printing Journal Co., printing D. Bishop ■ci. I). Carrinetc North &amp; C&lt; Bishop &amp; Hacker, printing Jourri State Jourr J. L. McBrien. printing Klopp &amp; Bartlett, printi Po Nebr. Paper Bag Co., iup| J. North i </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 21 Harry Porter Nebr. Teacher, printing r. Farmer, printing Xebr. Teacher, printing 4", Farmer, printing Nebraska Pai 10.00 Nebraska Paper Ai I Nebraska School Supply Co.. supplies.... 18.50 Nebraska Schoo ipplies IS June 10 State Journal Co.. printing 11.00 June 10 State Journal Co.. printin lag Co., so 12.50 July 11.15 l 8.10 s J. W. Ci 8.00 Aug. 26 Jacob No printing 75.10 li ■' . printing 141.80 141. 8( 11 S. W. Hacker &amp; Co., printing 48.35 Harry Porter, supplies .nee on hand December 31, 1906 5.91 Hurry Porter, supplies Balance on hai] $ 1,600.00 $ U REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS ;iriations for biennium beginning April 1, 1903 $ 5,000.00 riations for biennium beginning April 1, 1903 Apr. 24 Dobbs &amp; Weaverling, hardware $ 36.60 ■ 24 Dol ibs &amp; Weaverling, hardware $ 36.60 V Dietz Lumber Co., lumber V Dietz Lumber Co., lumber Mutual Builders, labor 31.52 Mutual Builders, labor 31 Mutual Builders, labor Id Mutual Builders, labor 10.55 Aug. :!9 J. \V. Crabtr. ivanced 65.13 ■ \V. Crabtree, i need 65 . 13 J. S. Robinson, material 850.00 .!. S. Robinson, material 850.00 Dobbs &amp; Weaverling, hardware 25.10 verling, hardware 25.10 Dobbs &amp; Weaverling. hardware 22.89 A: Weaverling. hardware S!« Mutual Builders, labor and material 97.70 C. N. Dieti Lumber Co., lumber, lime, etc. 80.86 I Meek, brick 107.19 Mutual Builders, labor and material 97.70 tz Lumber Co., lumber, lime, etc. 80.86 Dye &amp; Meek, brick 107.19 Stephen George, plastering 56.00 Dye K Meek, brick 30.21 Dye K Meek, brick 30.21 E. L. Uptegrove, supplies 74.35 E. L. I'ptegrove, supplies J. P. Gillilan, supplies 17.25 J. P. Gillilan, supplies 17.25 J W. Crabtree, cash advanced 199.00 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced 199.00 J. S. Robinson, first estimate 875.00 J. S. Robinson, first estimate 875.00 Mutual Builders, labor 575.00 Mutual Builders, labor 575.00 Feb. 26 E. G. Conkle. labor 9.60 Feb. 26 E. G. Conkle. labor 9.60 J. S. Robinson, plastering 16.50 J. S. Robinson, plastering 16.50 Apr. 28 J. V ivanced 71., 5 J. W. Crabt: advanced 117.63 Apr. 28 J. V -h advanced 71., 5 J. W. Crabtree. cash advanced 117.63 V Dietz Lumber Co., lumber, cement, C. M Dietz Lumber Co., lumber, cement. 278.40 E. L. I'ptegrove, supplies 56.00 Chas. Majors, labor 33.00 Chas. Majors, labor 33.00 O. F. Dubuque, labor 12.00 nkle. labor 57.00 O. F. Dubuque. labor 12.00 nkle. labor 57.00 J. A. Hays, labor 52.70 J. A. Hays, labor n Glass Co glass I'l 17 \V« o. glass M 17 Sunderland .V ■tot!".".!! "I!!!!!! Von J '&gt; 18::. 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 W Crabti 1 . B. (I Conkle. la Oct. 11 Campbell G. a.- I*. Co., loppliei . 161. «S 103 I. A I Lincoln Hardwan 10.90 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, supplies I. W. Crab tree, money advanced 348.63 advanced 348.6; Balance on hand December SI, 19o6 3.53 and Dec b$ 5,000.00 PHYSICAL TRAINING. $ 5,000.00 $ 5,( PHYSICAL TRAINING ion for the biennium beginning April 1, 1905 Appropriation for the biennium beginning April 1, 1905 $ 1 r Apr. 28 E. G. Conkie. labor $ E. G. Conkie. labor $ C F. Beck, cash advanced ; t, cash advanced 125 . 00 Mutal Hr.ildors. lubnr 1 M. Howie, cash advanced... 16.50 M. Howie, cash advanced is ■ A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., equipmenr 1U .1 \V Prflhrrup f^ach aAvartrmA C1 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., equipment I W. Crabtree, cash advanced 51.08 I W. Orabtrce. cash advanced 51.08 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bro.. equipment A. G. SpaldiMK &amp; Bio, equipment A. Q. Si&gt;alding &amp; Bro., supplies 1 A Q. Spalding &amp; Bro.. supplies 4 Balance on hand December 31, 1906 Balance on hand December 31, 1906 45.01 $ MX $ 1.000.00 * 1." LIBRARY FUND, LIBRARY FUND. balance an hand December SI, 1905 Balance an hand Decen Matriculation fees. Dec 1905, to Dec. 31, 1906 3.."," 1906 \ : &gt;r. 28 Western Pub. Co.. book Kenyon News Co., book S 2(1 Century Co., books 105.00 H. H. Ballard, books 33 . 70 Apr. 28 McDevitt-Wilson, books 27.81 .1. \V Crabtree, cash advanced 17.7S Woman's Tribune, subscription 7.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books June 26 Boston Book Co., books 35 . 50 H W. Wilson Co., books 20.00 V C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 48.83 .1 W. Crabtree, cash advanced 12.80 Ringer &amp; Heretead. binding 79.95 If Kenyon News &amp; Sub. Co., periodicals... 5.7S Library Bureau, supplies 4 . 00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 83.73 II State Journal Co., equipment I.OOii.imi Ringer &amp; Hertzberg, binding 99.25 Balance on hand December 31, 1906 4.224. SI </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 i SALARIES. tided balance for biennium, 1903-19( i nation for biennium. 190 roll, facul tfficers and em $70 Lapsed of the II appropna idi 4 a a hand 1 &gt;• DEFICIENCY APPROPRIATION $ 4,019.21 * 4.0 appropriation for the biennium 19 .&lt; nd fuel house umping Lapsed to General Fund » . ..* 2,634.52 34.70 34.81 6.77 495.00 298.52 231.80 283.09 $ .0 Balance on hand December 31, 1905 From room rent, winter term Froni room rent, winter term From room rein, spring term From room rent, spring term ■ in room rent, spring tvrra From room rent, summer term From room rent, fall term .. .$ ...» 79.61 4lT&gt;.9i Brought forward $ MC7.11 .. .1.1, From room rent, winter term From room rent, spring term From room rent, spring term From room rent, summer term From room rent, summer term From room rent, fall term From room rent, fall term From room rent, fall term . . . 85 . 6E 310.3c 25. Of 379. 4f ::: H $ 3,146.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 upholstering C. B. Havens &amp; Co.. hose H. Van Middlesworth. extra help, 2 days. H. Van Mlddlesworth, extra help. 2 days Hardy Furniture Co., counch and pad.. Hardy Furniture Co.. counch and pad... H. Van .Middlesworth, storing Tfi tons ice 44.80 G. K. McMillan, salary fireman, January. 40 . •&gt;•&gt; EL O. Conkle, repairs Preceptress, taking student home \: K. G. Conkle, repairing chairs 2.30 G. U. McMlllen, salary, February U. R. McMillen, salary, March I 8. Robinson, wood 9.00 Robinson, wood 9 C. X. Diets Lumber Co., coal 4.7i .Join: Adams, hauling coal l . 50 .Join: Adanis. hauling coal i V. Byler. room rent refund :'. V. Hyler. room rent refund Carpenter Paper Co., toilet paper C. V Diets Lbr. Co., lumber for repairs.. Kudcce &amp; Guenzel Co., castors H. Van Middlesworth, packing ice 4.75 H. Van Middlesworth, sundry repairs... H. Van Middlesworth, sui E. G. Conkle, repairing roof dormitory.. H. D. ISeck, shoveling coal ■ H. LV Beck, shoveling coa Benj. Bedell, shoveling coal Bedell, shoveling D. J. Young, shoveling coal \V. D. Jack, shoveling coal W. D. Jack, shoveling © iii C. X. Dietz Lun C. X. Dietz Lum. Co.. lumber for repairs. 17. Hi pair A. M. Medly, labor on dormitory 14.10 Mutual Builders, roof paint , Stephen George, plastering dormitory... phen George, plas ig dormitoi' 38.40 Modly Bros., painting, pap toning dormitorj Mrs M. A. Curtis, cleaning dormitoi Hardy Furniture Co., chairs Frank Ivers, labor Frank Iv 1 . 50 A. M. Medley, mason tender A. M. Medley, mason Medley Bros., ealetmining Sadie Hardis, cleaning dormitory Mrs. F. M. Bates, cleaning dormitory..., Mrs. Mary Cole dormitory.... W. P. Clotfelter. painting roof Bennett Co., wall paper 11.31 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. comforters 21 .61) Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., comforters 21 .60 K. G. Conkle, repairs E. G. Conkle, repairs Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., cots, mattresses, etc 140.49 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., cot mattresses etc 140.49 NOT. 21 W. P. Clotfelter, painting 1 W. P. Clotfelter. painting .1 W. Crabt purchasing.... I W. Crahi purchasing Carpenter paper Co., toilet paper... Carpenter paper Co., toilet paper... 9.50 E. L. I'ntegrove, supplies 21'. 65 E. L. Iptegrove, supplie: C. N. Dietz Lum. Co., lumber 5ir&gt; 19 Alfred Jewell, firing for six days 9.00 H. Van Middlesworth. advance for sup Plies g.05 F. M Bates, night watch, Oct. 31 1.00 Feb. in Miller &amp; Paine, rugs and curtains 18.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 i Mar. Jack, slop ja; «ck, pitchers and slop jars U.SO and di.ix i reul refund. . uiatlr Qeo. A. Berilnxhof, ard H. Van Middlesworth. table and i rl4 : i. room rent refund lti [lab] in rent refund ntha Sillik. room rent refund Pratt, room rent refund. . Fund Stella M in rent refund ck, room rent refund llolhrook. room rent refund.. ; O. .1. Milstead. lime for dormitory I W ' ash advanced for po; H. D. Beck, labor on grounds Benj. Bedell, labor on grounds J. S. Robinson, plastering dormitory Miles C'omstock. tending plasterer. . Claret mowing lawn... Frank Medlev. calcimining 4 Smith. paiM-rinu: and painting ■ 1 B. G. Conkle. work on closets 12 Hardy Furniture Co., chairs and rocker H W. Hedell, due for supplies 11.10 Peter Henderson &amp; Co.. lawn mower.... 111. nil 11 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, cornfortors .2 L. S. Wilson, labor on grounds I \V. Bedell, advanced for cleaning dor mitory :!1 ,v Roebuck, wall paper and shad E. L. I'ptegrove, paint and varnish... H. W. Bedell, advanced for lepairs 10 SI Johnson Hardware Co., hardware 2 ■ 9 R. B. Bedell, salary fireman, October S M C. Jack, bowls and pitchers in Carpenter }'. toilet paper 14 Vera Hemming, room rent refund 1 21 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 5.6( Wm. Xeal, shoveling coal . Korsmeyer Co., Ec. base lamp 18.00 Balance on hand December 1st, 1906 897.35 $ ,146.82 $ 3.146.8 LABORATORY FUNDS. Balance on hand December :: : t 4 1. Van Middlesworth. storine v Co., toili Carpfni. 1 Paper Co.. Urfh C. I!. Havna t. Rud^e &amp; Guenzel Co.. pillows and cots.. 145. OC </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 * Laborato igriculture Laboratory fees, botany Laboratory fee«, physh-s Laborai . . . : Laboratory f&lt; ulture Laboratory, fees, physiology Laboratory- fa iphy Laboratory fees, agriculture Laboratory fees, phyaica Laboratory fees, botany and zoology Laboratory fees, embryology Ml rt 9 rVb. 12 14 15 Apr. M .lune 11 16 l'ii July II 24 24 Laboratory fees, botany and zoology Laboratory fees, embryology 1 .aboraton fees, geology Laboratory fees, physical geography Laboratory fees, agriculture Laboratory fees, physiology Laboratory fees, physics Laboratory fees, physiology Laboratory fees, chemistry Laboratory fees, physiology Laboratory fees, physics Laboratory fees, geology Laboratory fees, botany and zoology Laboratory fees, botany and zoology Laboratory fees, geology Laboratory fees, aericulture Laboratory fees, physiology Laboratory fees, physics Laboratory lees, chemistry Laborato hemistry Laborato lotany and zoology Laboratory fees, pi Laborato l*aboratot\ t' </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 agi'irultur -Jiborai embryology ■ iui 7 (I. \V. Cult* r map. f Ar Lomb U4 Tl H II for depart in H. I! f .1 . r. 1 1 E. E. Mui Henry Hell Co. 12 H. B. ; or I.ab ir Lab . . . . ' 1 H. B 1 for Lab. . . H E. W. I Summer S i Co.. lantern glMea -7 Rishop A: Hacker, printing, Lab. I&gt;ept Lab. Ik 10 F. M G 21 Swift | A. 0. Reed, 1. H. I Lab. ribbon. . . . 2&lt;i F. A. I Wa ry Heil Co.. supplies A L. Fullerton. labor apa for Ph laboratorv lies 4 J. I) I J. i ■ &lt;.. printing \Tariin. fuppllei Bio. LaJ A L. Robins Martin, supplies Rio. Lab.. I."..:. 28 Rausch \- I h A F. M Gi So. 79 ■ ames. refund receipt No. 7... 14 11 11 i Chem Julius Gill&gt;er' &amp; l.dinh Co., supplies, liio. Lai W. Adama, labor, green house.... B Laramier, refund on Chem. recei] LomI W W. Adams, lal- houst *b..' !.'!!!."!! </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 Rudge &amp; Halance on hand December 1. 190C $ 1,147.20 % 1,14 MODEL SCHOOL FUND. MODEL SCHOOL FUND. Tuition winter terra $ i • $ fora E. Clark, non-resident pupil Ralph W. Clark, nonresident pupil Dora Borkby, non-resident pupil i uorkby, non-resident pupil 6.00 i;i Waldhams non-resident uunil.. non-rt Adelia Waldhams non-resident pupil Myrtle Pry, no i pupU Leaora I. at pupil Tuition winter term, '114 , .Myrtle Pry, non-resident pupil Tuition spring terra. "06 Lenore Uwm ir pup|] [[[ Tuition spring term, '05 ' Hirky. non-resident pupil Cora E. Clark, non-resident pupil E. Clark, non Ralph R. Clark, nun ' " ' ; Cla Lenore Lawrence, non-resident pupil Law i 1 Tuition spring term. "06 \ Adelia Wadhams. non-resident pnpj ; Tuition spring term. '05 Tuition fall term. '05 Tuition winter term. "06 Tuition winter term. '»', Tuition spring term. "M ......... Tuition spring term, 'M ...... Tuition spring term. '"&lt;! Tuition s| '.'.'.'.'. Tuition spring term, '"f, 4: Tuition fall term. '00 " Tu Tuition fall term. 'nf"&gt; $ Overdraft 1004 $ $ Titus Nursery. Christmas trees N Thomas Cha i., supplies a A. H. Abbot Thomai Ch; i- J. 1). Bishop &amp; Co., li &amp; ( 1 A. H. Abbot II Alii 11.4' Thomas Ch 10 ;:{ Atkinson &amp; Co. matting. \- Public School 1'ii i books Public School Pii Scott Poresman Co., text books Scott Foreman Co.. text bof phard text Vaughn's s 1). Appteton ........ 17 Bilrer Bard Bducattonal Pub All </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 1 Glnn i supplii books iks. . . • •xt bi 1 ( printing. . . Thou Thorn -iip]i]i( Thoiii supplii . x t hi .! bool M A .;i|ilies an Book &lt; .. iiks ipplles Thoi&gt; kTEXT BOOK LIBRA hand Deeembi v TEXT BOOK LIBRARY FUNDS Balance on hand December 31, 1HH4 Rental of b itudenU, \\i Reutal inter term, »nts. spring term, r terra Kental of tKH)ks to studiii Rental of books Rental of books to »tudenl Rental of books ti Sale of books ti Fines for d'iin 1 Rental for school year V.&lt; Aug. 1 Text book rental, summer term Sale to students, summer term, *&lt;&gt;G Text book rental, first semester, fall 06 Sale of text books, first iter, fall 'oti i r. 11 Peter Carey, freight and express $ H. W. Wilson, subscription W. Rardeen. sons books L. Caldwell. books. Art Dept 1^ School Science and Math., subscription. 24 Democrat Printing Co.. catalog cards... M acini 1 hun I 8.45 Silver. Htirdett &amp; Co.. text books 31 H. \V. Bedell, freight and express 6.05 H Anna Jennings, January salary 45. On in Hee Publishing Co.. subscription lyn &amp; Bacon, text books Library Bureau, supplies Henry Holt ; books H. W. Bedell, freight and express 4 "olcs </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 refn N. Foster, refund on book 7 Anna V. Jennings (February) i.i.m -l H. W. Be lell ... ii on Apr. 17 Anna V. Jenuineg. sunn] I -l H. W. Be tell, freii ... n .11: Apr. 17 Anna V. Jenuings, supplies May .' Thomas 1 supplies Democrat Printing n-ds.... c.m t'ni. of Chica C. C. Burchard, texi hooks lft.21 cards Burchard, text hooks l!i Western Pub., subscription ii I'll!)., subs 9 A. C. McClurg ft Co., text book* xt b( 1 11 I) C. Heath &amp; Co., 41.W Ciiin &amp; Co., text books.... 41.52 41. W 4 1 . 52 -1 Macmillian Co.. text books ll.lti 21 Maemillian Co., text books 11 .in 27 J. T. Ake mt in library 1 '7:, T. Ak( June 21 N. K. Griggs, books I). Apple ton ,v is. 411 N. K. G ) 1). A \- ( I" Thos V. Crowell, text books Thos V. ( C. 0. Burchard. text books. C. Burchard. text books Xationa! Ed. Aaao., book reports National Ed. As Atkinson Men Atk xt books Henry I!. g Henry Holt A: &lt; A. V. Jennings, salary I Ma A. V. Jennl ry i .\1 Chicago I'lii Ezar Carey, freight on books... 1 ■&gt;! Ezar Carey, freight on books... 1.21 July t$ Ginn .* Co., text books 1 .'5,1 Honghton Mitflin &amp; Co., text books Hinds. Noble \- Co . text boo &gt;s D. L. Alusseliiian. text books American Boo it books ."i4.l i 4 Macmlllian I Houghton Mifflin &amp; Co., text books :;4 Hinds. Nob D. L. Muiselman, text book Vmerlcan Hook Co., text books Aa|. IS Eire Carey, freight and drayi Woil I'ii 1 ■ -cription 4.O0 Merle Davids, is library If. 8. Joaael, services library 1 ,-,11 M. S. Ju Icea library 1 .(• v • Oct. 9 D. Appleton ft Co., text book Oct 8 D. Appleton ft Co., text books 1-yon ft Healy. text books Macmillian &amp; Co.. text books 79 55 Maemillian &amp; Co., text books 7».M I Silver Burden &amp; Co.. text books 7.56 lurdett &amp; Co., text books Chas. Scrlbner &amp; Co., text books 6.00 Chaa. Scribner &amp; Co., text books Atkinson. Mentzei u books Atkinson. Mentaer &lt;t Co., text books Houghton, Mifflin ft ( »,oks ! 1^' Hooghton, Mifflin A: Co., text h&lt;x)ks 1^ 7,-, 12 Ginn &amp; Co., text books 28^80 Ginn &amp; Co., text books | Henry Holt At Co., text books 28 . 80 Henry Holt &amp; Co., text books 56 80 A. C. MeClurg &amp; Co., text books 1.87 A. ('. HcClnrg &amp; Co., text books 1.87 Hoston Hook Co., text books 1 05 1 Book Co., text books 1 .05 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text books D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text books Gress Pub Co., text books GreRK Pub Co., text books 21.00 Nov. 24 Daily Star, subscription Nov. 24 Daily Star, subscription 6^50 Dec. S E. E. Rulon, books ' ' S. L. Caldwell, text for art department.. 1 70 Dec. 5 E. E. Rulon. book ,1 S. h. Caldwell, text for art department.. 1.70 1906. 1906 Jan. I Hyrne Marcellus. assisting in library i.:?o 1^. isiankenship. assisting in library 2 00 Jno. \V. Forsyth. assisting in library...!! 1. 'I Byrne Marcellus. assisting in library 1.30 L. Iilankenship. assisting in library 2 00 Jno. W. Forsyth. assisting in library. . ... Feb. In Ainsworth &amp; Co., text books Houghton Mifflin Co., text books </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Columbia School of Oratory, text books. . . 41.16 ("has. Scribner &amp; Co., text books 7.50 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text books 27.30 D. L. Mussel man. text books 15.00 Silver Burden Co., text books 18.75 American Book Co., text books 72 . 82 D. Appleton &amp; Co., text books 41.90 26 A. Flanagan, class books 1 .44 Mar. 'i Zaner &amp; Bloser, text books The Macmillian, text books 13.25 ry 14 American Book Co., text books 110. IT 28 Atkinson, Mentzer &amp; Co., text books 22.44 Gregg Pub. Co., text books 11 Ginn &amp; Co., text books 142.78 Houghton Mifflin Co., text books 81 .30 Macmillian Co., text books 66.46 Hinds. Noble &amp; Eldrige. text books DeWolfe &amp; Flske, text books 1.45 iH-nnison Mfg. Co., supplies 2.34 July 19 Irwin Shepard, min. ed. association Am. Academy of Sc, text bookfor debate 1.00 Macmillian Co., text book for debate 1.47 Stiver Uurdett &amp; Co., text book for debate 1.37 D. Appleton &amp; Co., text book for debate. . 3.50 Harper Bros., text book for debate 2.25 9. N. Rhoads, text book for debate 5 . 50 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text book for debate. . . 43.80 Oct. 29 W. L. Mustek Pub. Co., text b'k for debate 15.00 ■ 9 Houghton Mifflin Co, text book for debate 57.37 Atkinson Mentzer. text book for debate. . . 12 .00 McClurg, text book for deate 375.96 Gregg Pub. Co., text book for debate 20 Bee Pub. Co., subscription 4.00 J. H. Rohmeyer, subscription 1.00 American Book Co., text books 62.75 17 Columbia College, text books 14.65 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text books 49.05 26 Hinds &amp; Noble, text books 120.12 Democrat Printing Co., text books 6.35 Henry Holt, text books 35.80 American Book Co., text books 42.65 Ginn &amp; Co., text book 24.72 Houghton Mifflin Co., text books 7.42 Balance on hand December 1, 1906 23. 93* Totals $ 2,751.56 | 2,751.56 TYPEWRITING FUND. June 7 Rent of typewriters for June % 10.00 Sept 24 Rent of typewriters for September 10.00 Sale of books 8 . 75 Oct. 1! Rent of typewriters for October 6.00 Sale of text books 1.25 16 Rent of typewriter for November 18.00 Sale of textbooks 2 . W Dec. 11 Rent of typewriters for December 11.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 Jan . 29 Rent ot tyepwriters for January 13. 00 Sale of text books Feb . 26 Rent of typewriter for February 7 . 50 Sale of textbooks 2 . 50 Mar. 30 Rent of typewriters for March 21. GO Sale of textbooks 2 . M Apr. 16 Rent of typewriters for April 16.25 May 21 Rent of typewriters for May 12.00 June 24 Rent of typewriters for June 20.95 Sale of textbooks 5.00 July Rent of typewriters for July 5.05 Sept. Rent of typewriters for September 80.00 18 Rent of typewriters for October 31 .25 Nov. 18 Rent of typewriters for November 28.25 Sale of charts 4 . 00 Total $ 282. SO Feb. 2 Smith-Premier Co., payment on machines $ 50.00 Mar. 7 Smith-Premier Co., set of lessons 3.00 Apr. 26 Jacob North &amp; Co., printing 75.10 Sept. 18 Smith-Premier Co., book holders 3.95 20 Ezra Carey, express and dray age .50 Anna Lane, refunded fee .35 E. V. Ingerham, repairs on machines 1.00 30 John Ruzicks, refunded fee .45 .Nov. 19 Gregg Pub. Co., shorthand textbooks 23.75 Balance on hand December 1, 1906 124.60 Totals $ 282.50 $ 282.50 ELOCUTION FUND. Bee. 18 Pheobe Shepherd, private lessons. ...: $ 4.50 Flossie Cline, private lessons 2.00 20 Eve Porter, private lessons 2 . 00 Ethel Pearce, private lessons 3 . 50 Floyd Gail, private lessons 2 . 00 Wilma Cline, private lessons 9.00 Maud Boyd, private lessons 2 .00 July 19 Guy Williams, private lessons .50 Byrne Marcellus, private lessons 3.50 Mildred Butler, private lessons 2.50 lone Edgington, private lessons 1 . 00 Rilla Starr, private lessons 1 . 00 Total S 33.50 Feb . 12 Daisy D. Nettleton, supplies $ 2 . 50 Apr. 10 Prof. A. E. Turner, entertainment 17.00 Nov. 19 Columbia College, selections for dept 5.56 Balance on hand December 1, 1906 8.44 Totals $ 33.50 $ 33.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 MUSIC FUND. !!• Kdith Crupenhoft, privmti ..) * private ]&lt; 7 Berth private l&lt; own. pri\ . 11 Beraloe Brown, private U Nellie Hortney, piano rental.. Nellie Hortney, piano rental 4 I May C. Ell&lt; privat Hernice Drown, privaii Iterni' private It ■ hi Kdna Hadley, piano rental Edna Hadley, piano rental Nelll \»'llit- Bengston, music 8. I tennis, prl Mar. I priva 1" Olola li. Harman. privat 1" Ozola li. Harman. private lessons 14 &lt; .Mary El! 14 Cli private lei n Mary Ellenberger, privat Berniee Brown, privati Berniee Brown, prii sons I Josephine Johnson, private 1 4 Josephine Johnson, private lei m Bdaa Mllley, pi ion* ihriel. private lessons Stella Washburn. private lessons Martha Kinj;. privi Mary Elk private lessons iilna Milley. pi i tl Nannie Gabriel, private 15 Stella Wash burn, private Martha King, private Total ... $ * i.; 24 Clayton K. Summy Co . music $ 5 V 45 i Clayton F. Summy Co . music $ 5 45 in Mar i won t Bummj Co.. music l". .July L'o Clayton Music Co., music 38. mi 21 0. C. Hurchaid Ai Co., music Hurchard &amp; Co.. music Mrs. Dennis, tuition refunded 21 Mrs. Dennis, tuition refunded 3.30 Sammy Co., music 12.711 2* (linn &amp; Co.. music 9.21 Ginn &amp; Co.. music 21 Balance on hand December 1. lMiiti 72.55 Balance on hand December 1. lMiiti Totals $ 162.85 $ i a few years acii i he Hoard began receiving reports throu Principal from ;tll thi Associations or Organization*. The Board i financial obligation nor do we in any way control the fun This is all managed by the different committs consisting of stude and different mi the faculty. They all report in complete d« ncipal and he in turn presents the summarized ! The Hoard acts as a sort of Clearing House, thus the stud rthe public know whai dtapoattioa is Bl I present them herewith as a part of this report YOUNG WOMEN'S CHRISTIAN ASSOCIATION 1 Halam f Sale of pennants Tots </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 Y. .\l I F MissW For American eommi For world's w Fi 4 tin t 2111.55 $ 201 MARY JOHNSON, Treasure LECTURE COURSE. 190 Balance (in hand 1 y«&gt;4 $ 27 Feb. 4 Single admission. Adrain Xewens Single admission, ai Apr. 1 Single admission. Dr. (J line . Season tickets summi Single admissions, M. Flowers 18 s Single admissions. .1. F. Hosic Single admissions. Prof. Rowden 11 .50 Single admission, Dr. Fox admission. Dr. Iieattie Oct. 5 Single admission, Dunbar quartette 47. 19ut Single admission. Mrs. Maker tt.M imin Single admission, M Flowers Nov lool year Single admission, Dr. Driver 7.90 1 Feb. 4 Adrain Xewens, :id entertainment $ H. P Whitmore, 4th entertainment 1 V|. Dr. Green, 5th entertainment Jun&lt; M. Flowers, 6th entertainment 100.110 Ezra Carey, express and drayage 1.75 J. F. Hosiac, 7th entertainment E. C. Rowden, 8th entertainment Bishop &amp; Hacker, printing Dr. D. F. Fox, 9th entertainment and drayag 50 Inment • entertainment </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 t 906 t 4 89 . » S % 320.63 % $ 1 i t 4 ■■ r. 2d entertainment irine S \V II ainm Bishop A: Hack printing ■ r. Rrigham h entertainmen Available balance for incidental ATHLETIC ASSOCIATION— 1905^ Foot Ball. EXebi LJnoc L'niv- i Medic gam ..unit'. . n I'aid out ("reijrhton gam Paid out Nebraska I Paid out Lincoln Medic Paid out Iniv. arm Paid out work on At hi Paid o tic field it reception to u Overdraft on foot ball. . ilill Tota Basket Ball. mseh gam Itaki I. l( Dillon, m H W and drayan iirinrin: : Dr. Driver. 1st entertainment '06 B. \V Hack iirintin on, I. W. Crabtr Single ail in i &gt;ta ■ . l"nivt-rsit&gt; Paid out, Tecui . -• I Paid out. S Paid out </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 f. to Syracuse t.st mi, reception to team 6.21 6.21 :n •e on hand credit basket-ball 117.74 117.74 . $ 272.70 $ 272.70 $ ! Baseball. Baseball. i tickets admission, Auhtirn game admi same admission, Crelghton same admission game admission, Shubert game admission me admission. Belli admission, Johnson - $ All A ■ds from trip of team U ut. Auburn game $ 12 . 80 $ 12.80 l&gt; ut, Cotner game 30.80 30.80 ut, Argoes game 8 . 50 g Ightoa same 34.00 34.00 ut, Shubert same 17 lit, \Vesle\ an game ut. Bellevue game 34.75 34 ut, Johnson 14 . 15 14.15 ut, uniforms and supplies 1 }' ut, printing ephoning and p 8 s ut, work on athletic field 21.15 hletic fi 21.15 • ption to team ... e on hand, baseball. 68 $ 420.65 $ ■ Miscellaneous. Miscellaneous e on hand July 1st, 1905. ... 1! $ z-.z Membership tickets. Athletic Associatioc ■rship tickets, Athlt m 3n, Dr. D. Graves admission. Field Day Donation, Dr. D. Gravt Field Da 1 ut, work on field, old bill $ 'aid out. debt of Associatio 1 by Board 1 by Board . . . 11.17 ['aid out, expense to Interroll. .'ball mee 11.17 ut. Field Day expenses 17.4:! ,n, expenses to Intercollegiate i ut, note in bank in full j _ Jt, interest on note !♦ . 06 9.06 tid oi lance Lit. sundry items, dues to League baseball.... . sundry item on hand. nee on hand in athletic fu KEARNEY MAIN BUILDING— House Roll No. 1 Apr amount of appropriation I*. P. 1. 11. Ill- lug $ </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 W K F\j»]. in .1 K Delzell, a locating. I locating. K A. T T. . T. .1 M -v |: '■Using 4 ising \V. K Powlei \V K Fnw \pens&lt; lvertising ing Huh. advertising -ing ! rising Knutzen I So. 1 . . . . . . Knulu 694.64 • II, Est; Knmzen &amp; Isdell, 1 June ■: Knu I So. i. . . . July S Knu 1» A. Dusst-ll &amp; 8 No. 1 No No. 1 II, Esu No So. I A No 4?*; Knutzen &amp; Isdell, Esta. No. Knutzen &amp; Isdell, Esta No Knu Kiiin lell, final A. I) in. final E- A Doaaell &amp; Son. Baal I: rnt'.v Hardware Co., hardware licrlinghof. in full for H ■•.frlintshof. in full for services 1,1 $50 $.". SALARY TEACHERS AND SALARY TEACHERS AND EMPLOYEES Appropriation beginning of biennium. April 1. IMS $4 ion beginning of biennium. April A 0. Thomas, rash advanced, c advanced, cleanin dormitory i C. H. Gregg, cleaning dormitory niuel Tool, fitting rooms 4 21 A. O. Thomas, pay roll summer term ,('. A. O. Thomas, cash advanced Edwin Metcalf, getting buildings ready 4S A. O Thomas, pay roll. September 1,867.5 A O. Thomas, pay roll. October A. O. Thomas, pay roll 122.50 A. O. Thomas, pay roll J" A. O. Thomas, pay roll Geo. Langli engineer .It .00 (•04 1 A. O. Thomas, pay roll Virginia Mercer. 45.00 Arthur Anderson, salary 24 A. O. Thomas, pay roll U|i&gt; 24 A O. Thomas pav roll </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 \ A. O. Th R. B. Al API Geo. A. Berlinghof, fees 358 0( Dec. 11 Knutzen &amp; Isciell, Esta. No. 1 ;, L. \V. Pomerine Co., Esta No 1... -j 1MH6 .Ian. &gt; Knutzen &amp; Isdell, Esta. No. 2 Mar. 21 Knutzen &amp; Isdell, final Esta 1 June 12 L. W. Pomerine Co., final Esta $15,000.00 FUEL AND LIGHTS. FUEL AND LIGHTS. Appropriation for biennium beginning April 1, 1905 1905 Appropriation for biennium beginning April 1, 1905 $ 6,000.00 19(i Nov. 23 F. H. Gilcrest Lumb. Co., fuel $ 116.53 Nov. 23 F. H. Gilcrest Lumb. Co., fuel $ 116.53 A. M. Anderson, firing engine 56.00 T. A. McGinnis, rent of engines 114 ] 00 Dec. 20 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., tools for engine - room and supplies Geo. H. Downing &amp; Son, fuel 1 . F. H. Gilcrest, fuel 4, City Gas Co., electric light ' Geo. Downing &amp; Son, fuel City Gas Co., electric light Geo. Downing &amp; Son, fue 11 1 5 Geo. H. Downing &amp; Son. fuel F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 ( r t ng w; F. H N \V. Eelectrk ric I n 1 I.. W. Pomerine ( i nil HI. ill r coal bi ■ .. plur flttins City W Balance on haii S! i. on $ POSTAGE. TELEGRAPH AND TELEPHONE f C. H. (In 4 19 A. O. Thois n c ill 45 4: 18.65 28 A. O. Thomas, freight and p ir Kearney Phone Co.. phone Balance on hand D«~ 87.46 &gt;v Kuhn Bfrt ■ • C. F oil an.] Keai ■ ry Co., oil City \V N. W md supplit H. Downii r. H. GUci I Mi l&gt;riation for biennium beginning April 1, I9f I A. O. Tl 23 A. O. T postal 20 A. O. T 25 Kearney PI phone. 20 A. O. Thoni &lt;r. Telephi \. O. Thou it ;in ] ; r. Telephone Co., phone &gt;.. phone. . . A. O. Thomas, freight, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 i of appropriation for hienuium beginnimg April 1. 19"5 $ 5,C v A. Edwards, Betting snide $ 11 Swanson, setting trees, etc ill I.uddington. plowing, seeding, etc. 64 W. F. Crossley, hflior and material W. K. rk on grounds Aug. .1. K. Beebe, walks, etc 78! •raniion, labor A. Edwards, setting grade A. Beebe. walks, etc 611.31 K. Ayres, water connections 109 \V. K. Ayrea 395 ii.fio balance on hand December 31, 1906 1.74 $ 5,000. 0( PRINTING AND OFFICE SUPPLIES. A ion for biennium beginning April 1, 1!1O5 $ 1.500.1*. I H A. Wehert. printing H. A. Webert. printing $ 24.1ft Kearney Hub. printing C. H. Gregg, printing H. G Hany Porter, office supplies Smith Premier Co.. typewriter !i"..2T. i Hub. printing 17. M wr i Hub. printing 17 H. A. Webbert, printing j Democrat, printing H. A. Webbert. printing Kearney Democrat, printing ('. H. Gregg, printing and supplies r, printing 15. fw ('. H. Gregg, printing and Nebraska Teacher, printing I'ni. Pub. Co., supplies 7.00 I'ni. Pub. Co., supplies 7.00 New Era Pub. Co.. printing 4.90 New Era Pub. Co.. printing 4.90 29 Omaha Printin- k and Omaha Printing Co., &lt;lesk an.l chair H. A. Webert, printing 41 .Tit H. A. Webert, printing 41.70 fcf. A. Brown, printing Nebraska Teacher, printing Nebraska Teacher, printing 8 Klopp &amp; Bartlet, printing 11.40 Klopp &amp; Bartlet, printing 11.40 Klopp &amp; Bartlet. printing If.. 00 Klopp &amp; Bartlet. printing 1C .1. I.. McBrien. printing I L. McBrien. printing H. E. Webbert, printin H. E. Webbert. printing supplies Klopp &amp; Bartlet. printing Klopp &amp; Bartlet. printing Klopp &amp; Bartlet. rubber stamps 4.50 Kearney Hub. printing 11.25 Kearney Hull, printing IT.Hn H. A. Webbert, printing and suppliei 15 Kearney Hub, printing Hubbell Bros., printing Eugene Brookings, printing Nebraska Teacher, printing ■ 20 A. T. Anderson, supplies H. A. Webbert. printin- H. A. Webbert, printin- 11.3 K. O. Holmes, printing.. 6 $ </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 print ii N ' 81.30 July 6 .... I.M 1 . printing 31.15 H. A \V&lt; 28.85 8 H. A. \\ ;ney Pul). Co.. printing. 13.10 ■ on hand December SI, lwiti 2K7.06 $ 1. ■ t i i EQUIPMENT AND FURNITURE. EQUIPMENT AND FURNITURE. ■ nation for bienoium beginning April 1, 1905 s :ih, carpet and window shades $ - ith, carpet and window shades $ 197.40 14 N. W. Electric Co., electric supplies Rudge &amp; Guenztl Co., furniture 2,399.20 W. Electric Co., electric supplies 130.40 Rudge &amp; Guenztl Co., furniture Omaha printing Co., furniture 42.50 - Mai 14. 0:S Marion Su merit Omaha Sc! .furniture 154.60 furniture 154.60 lurniture 132.00 furniture 132.00 Hi furniture :'■' EUpida Furn. Co., furniture 19 furniture 343.79 Ri: furniture 76 Co.. furniture 7t;7 ply, furniture 56 Dec. ••quipment 19.25 C. H. Stoeltiug Co., equipment y . . I.. Smith, furniture '. . . 264 &amp; Cuenzel Co., equlpmen H. A. Webbert, equipment 32.65 K. C. Holmes, equipment Bausch &amp; IiOmb, equipment F. H. Gilcrest I-br. Co., lumber 13 Thomas Charles Co.. equipment 80.84 W. M. Welch Co., furniture 433.28 T. N Harwell, supplieg 6. \V. K. Avers, equipment 745 Kearney Hub, equipment - - . 4" Feb. 15 Qnutzen &amp; Udell, equipment 1,102.81 Arthur W. Hall, equipment 850.00 Nebr. School Supply, equipment 132.00 School Supply equipment 16.00 &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture 119.10 Prang Education Co., equipment 54.6! Apr. 20 S. A. D. Henline, supplieg 6.80 H. A. Small, supplies ". 16.85 School Supply Co.. supi Rudce &amp; Guenzel Co furniture 11 4" </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 &gt;n hand D • COMMENCEMENT AND INCIDENTALS. \ aiion for the bienniura beginning April 1, 1905 $ S nr C. H. Gregg, livery $ 6.50 A. O. Tli 3.87 A. O. Thorn 3.87 K. O. Holmes, supplies 6.47 K. O. Holm 6.47 Kearney Hardware, supplies 64.95 ncy Har 64.95 F. Bodinson. rubber hose, etc C. F. Bodinson. rubber hose, etc .20 :o ('. F. Boilinsnn, supplies 10.00 10.00 Hubbell Bros., supplies Huhbell Bn David I .u.lilin iing 253.40 Diiviil I Him 40 Hoxie Gi supplies 2.50 60 J. B. Turner. 17.50 17.50 Switx Parnitu 10.21 10.21 Midland i., supplies 10. M Midland C 10. M Eggerss O. Flyna Co., mailing tubes • o., mailing tub New Era Puli. Co., com. printing U C. F. Bodinson Co., incidentals :;.fi0 no A. O. Thomas, spe.iker expenses 75 75 R. 1.. Mapper, opera house R. 1.. N 4o.00 8. A. D. Hcnline, paint, etc A. D. Hi-nline, pain IS A. Hospe &amp; Co.. piano rent, etc IB. 00 A. Hospe &amp; Co., piano rent 15.00 Swltx Furniture Co., supplies Switz Furnitur 4 Rolf Halligan, printing 5.00 Rolf Halligan, printing Midland 10.54 Kearnej Hub. prin 17. mi Thomas Chan supplies 12.66 Prang Educational Co., supplies 11.18 K. O. Holmes, supplies 7.4&lt;i T. N. Hartzell, supplies Omaha Printing Co., supplies .55 Balance on hand December 31, ll'iifi 67.41 Balance on hand December 31, l!nitl $ 800.00 $ 800.00 $ 800.00 $ 800.00 LIBRARY FUND. LIBRARY FUND Matriculations to December 1. lnot :ions to December I, IMC $ 5^1 $ 5,915.00 Nov Dodd. Mead &amp; Co., books $ 113.05 Dodd. Mead «i Co., boc T. X. Hartzell, books. T. N. Hartzell, books. .$ 113.05 T. X. Hartzell, books 515 BIB. 09 T. N. Hartzell, books gu 15 Benj. Sanborn Benj. Sanborn, books 24.30 24.30 Columbia School Oratory, books :;u Columbia School Oratory, books Arthur J. Barnes Co., books , 83 Arthur .1. Barnes Co., books MacMillian Co., books fit!. 44 Slate Journal Co.. book stacks 457.110 Journal Co.. book stacks W. A. Clark, books 10.00 Prang Educational Co., books 20 Prang Educational Co., books D Appleton Co., book! 81.06 Atkinson, Metzner Co books M tiu </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 AUjn &amp; Baron, bo Marshall &amp; Co., books . books Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 109.76 10'.*. 7G Q, MiffliD &lt; 2. SO Hig ... 1.20 Library Bureau, library equipment 178 Library Bureau, library equipment K. O. Holmes, hooks 111. on K. O. Holm 28 Coin ... ;.'::. 40 4" Thos. Y. Crowell, books... 16 School Supply Co., boo nool Supply Co., books 1 4 . 30 nillian mtlllaa G L01.08 Ikx O. Thoni; .... 10.00 T. N. Hartzell, bi&gt;. ... 429.59 T. N. Hartzell, boot Kniilv Horn Ik 13.75 Wni. Johnson Co. boo)- ... D. Apptetoa I .... 4n.t;^ 1.. Smith, li! 2'&gt;.7.~ Little. Brown 2.26 Little. Brown I All 12.70 Alhn &amp; I! ord Bros., boot lord Bros., books A. Flannag.in Co.. books 10 . . A. Flannaean Co., book T. N. Hartzell, bool . . 437.49 T. N. Hartzell. book 437. 4f W. A. Clark, books. . . 20.00 ('lark, book Library Bureau, books ... 11.. 'iO 11. 30 Oxf ... 13.00 • :t, Foresman &amp; Co., books 8.82 Oxford Pn n &amp; Co., books Switz Furniture Co., cqiiipmpiit z Furniture Co., equipment 164.88 164. 8S Balance in fund December SI 194 lie* in fund !&gt;■ ... 2,2(18.89 $ 5.915.00 $ 5,915 DORMITORY FUND DORMITORY FUND. Total receipts from Dormitory to Dec. 1, 1906 $ 1.598 Total receipts from Dormitory to Dec. 1, 1906 $ 1.6M Cleaning, care of halls, toilet rooms, reception room, etc. Cleaning, care of halls, toilet rooms, reception roon paid out as foil. it as follow 8 Edward Metcalf ... 21.80 1.80 3. E. Graham ... C W. Graham Sam S« Cleaning n. Dec. 13 Edward Metcalf Jan. 11 Rachel Ganzans 4.00 Feb. 2 Rachel Gnnzans 6 14 Edward Metcalf 6.84 23 Rachel Ganzans 6 Mar. 29 Rachel Ganzans 6.00 May 4 Rachel Ganzans 10.00 June 2 Mrs. S. L. Armstrong 4 Rachel Ganzans 4 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 John M. Bohannan (studi A. ('. Loshbau Rachel Ganzan: Rachel Gancani Rachel Ganzam A. C. Loshbaugn (student i Rachel G Rachel t, 4.1 Rachel (i li&gt; . 2 Lillian Roadies llace (atodenl I Rimdii-z studen Anna Drury i Undent I Anna Drury (studen Ann;' Drury («tuden Nor. 21 Ann' Dniry (student) LJlj Wallace i student I L'(&gt; Lily Wallace I student Paid Out for Fuel, Lights and Water. Paid Out for Fuel Lights and Water. Nov. 30 Ceo. Langley, fireman J4.0 City Water Co., water &amp; Wingard, Traction engine... Nov. M Geo. Langley, fireman City Water Co., w Patterson &amp; Wlngard, Traction engin 1 N. W. Electric. Co., lights N. W. El 72.49 2 (leo. Langley, fireman 16 N. W. Klectric Co., light* 72.4 N. W. El N. W. D 1 X. W. Elect ri. 1 X. W. Electric Co., light! 27.9 X. W. Electric Co., Ugh K. W. Electric Co., ligh N W. Electric Co., ligh N. W. Electric Co., ligh 1 X. W. Electric Co., lights 1 X. W. Electric Co., lights 1 X. W. Electric Co.. lights 1 City Water Co., water Water Co., w Paid Out for Furniture and Equipment. Paid Out for Furniture and Equipment, 1 Switz Furniture Co., furniture 1 Empire Store Comforts SI. 3 1 17 S. A. D. Henline. supplies Not. 16 Switz Furniture Co ISt.S L. Smith 26. 7i :6 Paid for Repairs and Improvements. Paid for Repairs and Improvements. 10 W. F. Crossley. lal» Oct. 10 W. F. Crossley, labor 24 E. J Thygeson, repairin- ... 14. Oi 14.00 1906 19 D. H. Leddington, 19 D. H. Leddington, - June 12 Peter Henderson, g I 16 E. J. Thygeson, painting June 12 Peter Henderson, gr. in. ort 11.70 July :! A. Troxel, seeding, etc 1 1 . "i Ward Handy, repairing room.. A'ard Handy, repairing room Oct. 1 W. B. Haislet. plastering Oct. 1 H. D. Upton, papering dini ■ ; room IS Sam Tool, roofing vegetabl housi 24 33 F. H. Gilcrest Lamb lumber, etc. . Piano. Dec. 26 Irene Smith 11.4" 1906 Apr. D. H. Baldwin Co July 14 D. C. Traver, moving plan 5.00 Balance on hand Dormit Fund Dec. 1.. 1,161.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 S 1.4 4 S.f s s f- s 4 v S / CASH FUNDS. Received from text book rentals red from book dep&lt;&gt; ■ &lt;1 from ! Received from text book I Received from typewriter rents July 7 Burlington Railroad Co.. Virgin. office help labor 4 Sam W. Tool. 1906 R. P. Laramier labor Jan. 13 Smith Premier Co.. typewrit* Remington Co., typewrite] 17 John Bohannon, 25 Remington Co., typewriter 31 Smith Premier Co., typewrit 3 Wm. Marshall. John Bohannon. (student) labor J. A. Johnson, (student) labor Sam Statum, di Mar. 26 A. C. Lo^ nt) labor Apr. 1 R. E. Allen (student) labor Smithy (student) labor.. Henry Hanley (student) labor Samuel Arnold (student) labor l^emeul Tool (student) labor.. I-emeul Tool (student) labor June 8 Hagger Strong, expense commencement 21 Lemeul Tool, student labor A. Hellreigel, plowing grounds July 3 D. H. Baldwin &amp; Co.. rental piano 18 A. Troxel, labor on grounds 19 Peter Hender, lawn grass seed a&lt; . . l July 19 E. A. Shepherd, labor. nt janitor Aug. 1 Lemeul Tool, student, labor. » Minnie Croston student, labor l *\ oo ■ • • * 1905 June lption Aug. 2 State Tr. ientific permit 11 County Clerk, notary fees Nov. 7 ter. . . 21 V A'. E. All iiien.s 14 John Bohaftnon, labor Otio Moritz (stuilentl labor. F. G. Sn lent I labor Mar. 5 H. E. Coleman, dray; 2 F. T. John&gt; 14 Clyde labor. Bruce C :ahor Wm. Larson (stnednt) labor... </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Aiicp C. Stanley, office I \V Brew D. H. Leddington, unl uling m. in Hill A. Troxt I&gt;lowing tree rows I M i M. R. Sno'i A. J. M F W. S. R i A. Hoi Miss Caldw A. Troxel, i: I.. Ho Roy Tracewell, itndenl labor, assi. janitor Wayne Chapman, stiulem labor, asst. jani W Tin Freil Fisher ("late Hopiii Troxf Ina Pa balance in rash funds I l </seg>
            <seg id="p054"/>
            <seg id="p055"/>
            <seg id="p056">H. M I u M t \1R I.. K i tv h T.J. M C HC.r T. I. M I.i H. M. CI 1.. IK C. H. Cn H. M Ch A. &lt;&gt;. Tin Harrv l'n I.. K. Kill AD !■:. IK I.UllHl ll.nl |i. . l.UtlHT k.i I 'hone Compai II. M. Cliil'S- expense* II. expenses I \V. I. \. o. Tl I.. p. I I'. C. Hunt! C. 11 ' nsen, c II. M. Chtl \ ( i Th&lt;n T. I I.. K T. J. M Henton I I.uther I*. I.inM C. H On M" I.. I'. I.I I. IV Ci c . h . &lt; ; </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>