<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00050.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00050.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Nebraska 1919-1920</title>
               <date value="1920-12-31">1920-12-31</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT of the Adjutant General of the State of Nebraska For 1919-1920 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL REPORT STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 31, 1920. From | The Adjutant General, Nebraska. To: | His Excellency, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. Subject: Biennial Report of 1919 and 1920. 1. In compliance with the requirements of Paragraph 3907, Section 9, Chapter 14, Article 1, Revised Statutes of Nebraska, the following bien - nial report for the calendar years 1919 and 1920 is respectfully submitted: HOME GUAKD Upon assuming the duties of the offiee of Adjutant General, March 4, 1919, it was learned that practically none of the National Guard had re - turned from the World War; that when they did return they would no long - er be available for State duties as a decision of the Judge Advocate Gen - eral, U. S. Army, had been rendered to this effect. No National Guard lad been reorganized after the call of July 15, 1917, but a special session of the Legislature had provided for the organization of Home Guard units and authorized County Commissioners to purchase arms and equip - ment for same. There were approximately 60,000 Home Guards organ - zed within the State, some being equipped and some not, and while the pirit of the Home Guard units was of the very best and the moral effect of such organizations improved conditions within the State, many of these organizations had disbanded on orders issued by the outgoing Governor, tut at the request of Governor Samuel R. McKelvie" the greater portion remained intact until such time as a sufficient number of the National iuard had been reorganized to make it safe for their disbandment. STATE RIFLES Upon information being received from a Committee of Omaha's rep - resentative citizens calling upon the Governor, that conditions were not lie best and that there was unusual activity among the anarchistic ele - men of the United States, it was deemed advisable to immediately organize uch a volunteer force as could be depended upon in case of an emergency nd a State military organization known as the Nebraska State Rifles was organized with one company at Nebraska City, one at Fairbury, one at Clay Center, and one in the western part of the State, at Alliance. These companies were each one hundred men companies and composed of all ex- Crvice men. Federal- equipment was drawn and issued to these organi - tions and it was considered an adequate organization to meet with any </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5 emergency that might arise within the borders of our peace-loving State. These organizations were maintained until a sufficient number of the Na - tional Guard was reorganized to make it safe to relieve them from fur - ther duty. LEGISLATION The State Military Code was amended to conform to the Federal laws which was demanded by the United States Government before Nebraska could participate in appropriations allotted to the respective states for the support and maintenance of the National Guard. Liberal appropriation was made by the Legislature for the support of the National Guard and for the promotion of Rifle Practice, but the ap - propriation for Armory Rental would have been inadequate had it been possible to have perfected an immediate reorganization of the National Guard, which was made impossible by the State Legislature attaching a rider to the appropriation for the National Guard reading, "No part of the foregoing appropriation for the Nebraska National Guard shall be used except for the expenses in conducting the Adjutant General's office, un - til the National Congress has made an appropriation for the support of the National Guard of the United States". This was taken by this office to mean that the Legislature in their wisdom, desired that the State funds be not spent or the reorganization of the National Guard attempted un - til the Federal Government had adopted a military policy and made appropriations for the support thereof, and this was not accomplished until the Act of June 4, 1920, and therefore no concerted effort to re - organize the National Guard was made until after that time. PROPERTY There was but little Quartermaster, Ordnance, Medical and Signal property on hand in the State Arsenal at the time I assumed the du - ties of the office and upon the appointment and approval of a United States Property and Disbursing Officer, I had a physical count made of all property on hand in that the new officer would ba chargeable with only property actually on hand and that the old Property and Disburs - ing Officer would be enabled to settle his account with the War De - partment. A survey has been made of all property considered to be unserviceable and same has been condemned for destruction or to be returned to the War Department. Some antiquated property that was necessary to carry as serviceable has been returned to the Department in that we may draw new and up-to-date equipment u,pon the reorganization of the National Guard. The accountability of the State with the United States Government during the war, so far as this administration is concerned, has been cleared and all property accounts adjusted. The Arsenal has been cleaned out from top to bottom and made ready for new equipment. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL HOUSE ROLL NO. 537 Conforming to House Roll No. 537, an effort was made to obtain from the Federal Government a copy of all records of the Selective Draft, but this was refused by the Adjutant General of the Army who in - formed us that no records would be returned to the States and that the State records would be kept in Washington. An effort was then made to obtain from the respective counties, lists of the Selective Draft nd those who volunteered and an alphabtical list was made, by counties, f most of the counties. These lists were incomplete as they lacked lome addresses and the counties seemed unable to give us the necessary ata to perfect them. About this time we were informed by the Adju - tant General of the Army that photostatic copies of registration and nduction lists would be forwarded from the War Department and upon eceipt of said notice, all effort and expense of obtaining further infor - mation from the respective counties was stopped. Upon receipt of the thotostatic copies and looking over of same, it was discovered that the nformation given in them would be incomplete and that such a record of the ex-service men as the Legislature had in mind could not bs per - fected, and then the united effort was made by the Adjutants General of the respective States to get Congress to pass a law compelling the Adjutant General of the Army to furnish individual records cf men serving from the respective States, which was accomplished and we are now receiving said individual service records which will give to each State an individual record of each soldier, sailor, marine and nurse who participated in the World War. An appropriation of $25,000.00 was made by the last session of the Legislature for the purpose of perfecting the above mentioned records and to furnish to the nearest relative of those making the Supreme Sacrifice a certificate of service with a gold star and to all others a cer - tificate of service without the gold star. These certificates are now on hand, the casual list made up and at this writing we are commencing to n-.ail same out as provided for in the Act. RIFLE RANGE The Rifle Range at Ashland, Nebraska, is much run down and badly in need of repair to place it in condition for range work. Arrangements had been made to have this Rifle Rang put in condition during the spring and summer of 1920, but owing to the fact that a military policy was not adopted by the National Congress until June 4, 1920, detailed information of which did not reach this office until the latter part of July, it was decided to let this work go over until the spring of 1921, and perfect our reorganization before expending the necessary amount of money in fixing up the Rifle Range for camp and range purposes. A Civilian Rifle Team under the leadership of Captain Lincoln Riley of Wisner, Nebraska, was sent to the National Rifle Competition at </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 5 Ep Perry, Ohio, in August 1920, and made a very creditable showing. h interest is being manifested in these Civilian Rifle Teams and a. ber of new teams have been organized during the fall and winter. REORGANIZATION OF THE NATIONAL GUARD As stated before, no concerted effort was made to reorganize the National Guard until after the; latter part of July 1920, when detailed information was received by this office from the War Department as to the military policy adopted by the Federal Government and appro - priations made for the carrying out of said policy. The allotment for Nebraska for the fiscal year ending July 1, 1921, is First regiment of Infantry, one Field Hospital company and one Sig - nal Company (Construction), of which Infantry companies have been or - ganized at Scottsbluff, Omaha, Hartington, Beatrice, Mitchell, Auburn, Falls City, and at this writing a company is ready for its first inspection at Hastings, another one at Omaha, with the organization of other units' in Lincoln, Grand Island, Columbus and Albion well under way. Nebraska's full allotment of National Guard units when the Act of June 4, 1920, is in full force and effect will be: It is anticipated that the allotment for July 1, 1921, will be one regi - ment of 155 mm. Howitzer and some of the auxiliary units. While this 155 mm. Howitzer regiment as such would be of no practical benefit to the State outside of preparing them for a National emergency, arrange - ments have been made whereby they will receive additional equipment from the Federal Governmnt for Infantry organizations and will be drilled as such in addition to their Artillery training, which will make them as valuable to the State, in case of local disorders, as would be an Infantry regiiment. bFull and complete equipment for each organization is furnished by- Federal Government and along this line I might add that the equip - it is of the latest design and model and everything from the skin out DIVISION TROOPS: CORPS TROOPS: 1 Infantry regiment 1 Medical regimental Hdqrs. 1 Sanitary Company 1 Ambulance battalion Hdqrs. 1 Ambulance company (motorized) 1 Hospital company 1 Medical Supply Section 1 Medical Laboratory 1 Veterinary Evacuation company 1 Division Trains (Q.M. C.) 1 Artillery regiment (155 mm Howitzer) 1 Air Service Observation Squad- ron 1 Signal company (construction) ARMY TROOPS: 1 Artillery Ammunition Train 1 Combat Engineer Regiment G. H. Q. RESERVE 1 Typographical battalion 1 Balloon group </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL is furnished the enlisted men. The equipment for each Infantry company costing approximatly $18,000,00., is furnished to the State, free of charge, by the Federal Government. OMAHA RIOT Sunday evening, September 28, 1919, there was a riot in Omaha and the State was called upon for assistance. No National Guard had been reorganized at this time and the Home Guard organizations of Omaha had disbanded. Every effort was made to get United States troops from Fort Crook and Fort Omaha to the scene of the trouble and it was through the efforts of the Governor's representatives that this was done, it being first necessary to take the matter up with the Secretary of War and then the Commanding General of the Central Department which caused much delay before the order for the troops to move was finally received. In the meantime the Home Guard companies of Lincoln, Uni - versity Place, College View, Havelock, and Ashland had been mobilized, a volunteer force of three hundred ex-service men of Lincoln was raised, all available arms collected and a special train was gotten ready and was standing on the track ready to move the aforementioned forces to Omaha when we were informed that the mob had accomplished its pur - pose and was dispersing. The estimated damage to the Douglas County Court House, caused by this riot, was approximately $1,000,000,00 in money and it leaves a blot on the fair name of the city of Omaha and the State of Nebraska, all of which would have been impossible with one battalion of National Guard located in the city and subject to the immediate call of 'the Gov - ernor as was evidenced by the tornado disaster in the city of Omaha, Easter Sunday, March 13, 1913, when with all telephone and telegraph wires down and the whole city in a demoralized condition, the Battalion of National Guard stationed in Omaha at that time was fully mobilized, moved to the scene of the disaster and in complete control of the situa - tion within two hours time. As compared with the above mentioned record of the National Guard at the tornado disaster is the fact that for the riot the first call for as - sistance was received about 6:30 in the evening and both telephone and telegraph were used in an effort to get the Federal troops located at Fort Crook and Fort Omaha, to move out at once but with the wires in per - fect working order and conditions away from the riot perfectly normal, it was after 11 o'clock before the desired order was finally received, thus demonstrating conclusively that we will never be able to depend upon Federal forces in case of local disorders. H. J. PAUL, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 7 General Orders 1919-1920 STATE OP NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 20, 1919. rral Orders, No. 1 1. The resignation of Major Charles W. Ervin, Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby accepted, effective this date. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. E. Clapp, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 20, 1919. General Orders, No. 2 1. Brigadier General H. E. Clapp, Adjutant General, Chief of Staff, is hereby relieved effective this date. 2. Joseph A. Storch is hereby appointed Brigadier General. Chief of Staff, The Adjutant General of Nebraska, effective January 21, 1919. SAMUEL R. McKELVIE, Governor. STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN January 21, 1919. reral Orders, No. 3 1. Ser&amp;eant O. McCullough is hereby relieved as caretaker of the Jstate Arsenal, effective this date. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: J. A. Storch, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 3, 1919. General Orders, No. 4. 1 . The resignation of Joseph A. Storch, Adjutant General, Chief of Staff, is hereby accepted, effective March 3, 1919. 2. Colonel Herbert J. Paul' Infantry, U. S. A., is hereby appointed Brigadier General, Chief of Staff, The Adjutant General, Nebraska, ef - fective March 4, 1919. SAMUEL R. McKELVIE, Governor. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 4, 1919. General Orders, No. 5. 1. Lieutenant Colonel Joseph A. Storch, Inf., U. S. A. is hereby ap - pointed Assistant Adjutant General, Nebraska, with the rank of Major, effective this date, March 4, 1919. SAMUEL R McKELVIE, Governor. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 13, 1919. General Orders, No. 6. 1. The current season of small-arms practice is hereby designated to extend from April 1, 1919, to December 31, 1919. • -■ BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 9 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 30, 1919. General Orders, No. 7. kl. Captain Harry C. Stein is hereby appointed United States Pro - ty and Disbursing Officer in and for the State of Nebraska with the k of Major, effective August 1, 1919. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul. The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: (General Orders No. 7 is the last of the series of 1919.) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 9, 1920. General Orders, No. 1. 1. The current season of small-arms practice is hereby designated to extend from April 1, 1920, to December 31, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT Office of the Adjutant General Chief of Staff Lincoln February 20, 1920. General Orders, No.- 2. kl. The following Nebraska National Guard officers having been norably discharged from the Federal service, are hereby appointed to s Nebraska National Guard Reserve with the rank held on date of dis- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL date charge from the United States Service, and said commissions to from the date of said discharge as follows: Col. P. L. Hall, Jr., F. A., Jan. 9, 1919. Lt. Col. Henning F. Elsasser, Inf., Oct. 17, 1919. Major Joe W. Leedom, F. A., March 11, 1919. Major Otis E. Davis, Inf., July 26, 1919. Major Frank A. Warner, F. A., Jan. 27, 1919. Major R. S. Hart, M. C, May 17, 1919. Major Robert G. Douglas, F. A., Dec. 9, 1918. Major P. H. Bartholomew, M. C, Jan. 28, 1919. Major Eugene T. Harris, Inf., June 30, 1919. Major John F. Spealman, M. C, Aug. 2, 1919. Major Montie E. Lum, Inf., July 11, 1919. Capt. Albert L. Rollin, Inf., Oct. 31, 1919. Capt. Clarence L. Gibson, Inf., Oct. 25, 1919. Capt. Frederick Lanz, Inf., Dec. 23, 1918. Capt. J. B. Miller, Inf., Sept. 9, 1918. Capt. M. S. Moore, Inf., Aug. 9, 1919. Capt. F. E. Crawford, Inf., Oct. 27, 1919 Capt. Jean B. Cain, Inf., Dec. 23, 1918. Capt. Charles W. Hamilton, Jr., Inf., May 9, 1918. Capt. Jay M. Holmes, Inf., March 13, 1919. Capt. R. D. Bryson, M. C, May 23, 1919. Capt. Bernard A. Norsworthy, Inf., May 29, 1919. Capt. Lynn J. Butcher, Inf., Feb. 3, 1919. Capt. P. R. Halligan, Inf., Jan. 12, 1920. 1st Lt. Robert J. Emery, Inf., April 30, 1919. 1st Lt. Wm. F. Bruett, Inf., March 4, 1919. 1st Lt. Carl Gustafson, Inf., Aug. 2, 1919. 1st Lt. Sophus C. Pedersen, Inf., April 9, 1919. 1st Lt. Richard G. Hunter, Inf., Sept. 11, 1919. 1st Lt. Frank J. Major, Jr., Chaplain, Oct. 17, 1919. 2nd Lt. George A. Phipps, Inf., Al*g. 22, 1919. 1st Lt. Verne R. Taylor, Inf., Oct. 20, 1919. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p011">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 11 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 10, 1920. General Orders, No. 3. kl. The resignation of Major Joseph A. Storch, Assistant Adjutant leral of Nebraska, on account of his physical condition, is hereby ac - ted to take effect April 10, 1920. 2. Major Joseph A. Storch having been retired as Brigadier General, I. N. G., and having again entered active service to participate in the World War with the rank of Mapor and during said service was pro - moted to the rank of Lieutenant Colonel, he, the said Joseph A. Storch s hereby restored to his former status, re-commissioned a Brigadier General and as such placed on the retired list. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 1, 1920. rneral Orders, No. 4. 1. Major Harry C. Stein, QMC, is hereby appointed Assistant Ad - jutant General of Nebraska, effective this date, July 1, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 3, 1920. General Orders, No. 5. The following schedule promulgated by Lieutenant Colonel W. A. Me- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Daniel, Inf., Inspector-Instructor for Nebraska, is hereby adopted and will be used by all Infantry organizations for the first six months train - in,? period after Federal recognition. By order of the Governor. H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. SCHEDULE OF ARMORY INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIRST SIX MONTHS 1. In compliance with Par. 486, National Guard Regulations, the fol - owing schedule of armory instruction for the first six months after federal recognition, is submitted in the order of importance of tha sub - ects. The Chronological order in which instruction in the various sub - ects is to be given should be regulated by local commanders, dependent upon weather conditions, facilities for drill, receipt of equipment, number f men present, instructors available and other circumstances: Total _ 36 Hrs. t2. Only the minimum time (36 hours) is included in the schedule, more time is utilized, it should be given to those subjects in which litional instruction is most urgent. bAny military instruction counts as "Drill," but the hour and a half aired, must be exclusive of "Rests". Time for rest and work can be t regulated by the commander giving the signals for simultaneous Subject. ] Hrs. Personal hygiene, first aid, and sanitation (including care of the feet and proper fitting of shoes and clothing) 3 Care and use of arms and equipment iy 2 Lectures on Riot Duty 1% Marching, night exercises and observing, learning and noting routes, and prominent places to be used or guarded in time of emergency 3 Preliminary drills for target practice 3 Assembling and disassembling equipment (including the "Pack", and marching in full equipment) i 6 Physical training 6 Guard duty 1 Close and extended order drill in the school of the soldier, squad, platoon and company : 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 13 resting and resumption of work and keeping record of the time. Daring - rest periods minute instructions should be given group leaders as to exactly what is to be done by each group during the next work period and no time should be lost. Instruction must be carried on energetically. k Recruits, inexperienced N. C. O.'s and specialists should be taught by ecially qualified instructors during such periods as the assembly of whole company is not required as a unit. Better results are obtained by short, "snappy" drills or lectures on different subjects rather than by straining the attention too long on one subject. Lecture meetings should be as informal as is consistent with liscipline, practical work being used instead of theoretical upon every possible occasion. Lectures, conferences and schools should never be teld immediately after a meal. Upon receiving the schedule of instruction the company commander should formulate definite plans for carrying out the schedule in the pro - gressive manner that will accomplish the best possible results. No hours have been set apart for the teaching of discipline, morale, C"litary courtesy and patriotism, as it is taken for granted that they will taught in conjunction with all other instruction. All officers and soldiers should realize that at no time in our history has discipline been so important; therefore discipline of the highest order should be exacted at all times. Leaders must insist that all subordinates do their work properly, but they must set the example themselves. Leaders must know their work. There must be no hesitation. Com - mands must be given correctly and with snap. Superiors must treat all subordinates with courtesy, .give clear and reasonable explanations, and correct mistakes without harshness. Every officer must set a proper example for those junior to him by promptly and cheerfully obeying - orders and regulations. Patriotism is of paramount importance. An absolute and unqualified devotion to the welfare and success of our country is an indispensible pre - requisite that has always constituted the soul of our Army. 3. The following are some of the reasons for attaching special im - portance to the subjects enumerated in the above schedule: (a) Hygience and sanitation: — Although tactical and destructive - superiority are most important in actual combat, yet the preparation for battle begins with the very first instruction of the recruit and without The proper fitting of shoes and clothing is of such extreme importance because of its effect upon the marching and working capacity of the wearers. Ill-fitting shoes and clothing not only incapacitate physically, good health and physique he will never reach the battle field. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL but they lower the morale by causing discouragement, discontent and ill - temper. Tight collars, especially, cause headache, dizziness and other indispositions with consequent mental inefficiency. The actual tryng on and fitting of shoes and clothing must be under the personal supervision of the company commander and he must require the rules laid down in G. O. 26, W. D., Aug. 16, 1912, and other official documents to be observed regardless of individual protests. Left to :heir own discretion, men will almost invariably select shoes and clotti - ng much too tight. bA properly fitting shoe should have at least three-quarters of an inch ant space in front of the great toe and there should be no pressure in the top of the toes; to determine the proper width of shoe grasp the leather over the ball of the foot between the thumb and finger. As the fingers and thumb are brought slowly together over the leather, the shoe should feel snugly filled without apparent tension, while the leather should lie smoothly under the hand. If the leather wrinkles under the grasp of the hand, the shoe is too wide; if the leather seems tense and bulging and the thumb and fingers tend to slip over the leather easily, the shoe is too narrow. Socks should be two sizes larger than the shoes selected. Cotton socks are not allowed for marching, except in individual cases upon the prescription of the surgeon. Shoes are fitted with a 40-lb. weight upon the back and the whole weight of the body thrown upon the foot being fitted. In the fitting of clothing, allowance must be made for free movement at the knees, hips, chest, arms and neck. In trying on the coat an issue flannel shirt should be worn and the double thickness of collar folded between the coat and neck so as to show the shirt above the coat. (b) The best time for teaching the care and preservation of arms and equipment is about the time of their being issued to individuals. Officers and men should be required to receipt for all articles of equipment and clothing issued to them, in order that there will be no question concern - ing responsibility in case of loss or damage. Pistols and revolvers are especially apt to be lost or stolen. They should not be issued to indi - viduals until their use is absolutely required and the number should be ■verified after each drill. Whether in the hands of the organization or individuals they should be kept under lock and key when not in use. In this connection, attention is invited to Pars. 876, 885 and 886, National Guard Regulations; if the arm racks and lockers are not already on hand they should be obtained from the Ordnance Department by requisition. Because of the Government price of small arms being so much less than the commercial price, the paying for an article lost through carelessness </seg>
            <seg id="p015">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 15 Or neglect is not sufficient restitution and an individual should be court - martialed and fined heavily if found guilty in order that the cost to him of an amount much greater than the price of the article may discourage future similar losses. The momentary value of a pistol is not so great as the seriousness of having this destructive deadly weapon in the hands of unknown evil persons. The number of Government weapons so unac - counted for at the present time is appalling. Most rifles turned in to arsenals as unserviceable are found to be worn at the muzzles and having the barrels rusted and pitted inside show - ing improper cleaning and lack of cleaning as having caused the damag - ed condition, whereas, with proper care rifles should become inaccurate only by reason of erosion at the bullet seat, usually after about 4,000 or 5,000 rounds have been fired. Inspection of arms should be made for the purpose of seeing that they are kept well oiled rather than to require the inside of the barrels to be bright and shining. Oil should be removed from the inside of the barrels only when it is to be renewed. There is no necessity for removing the original cosmoline from the inside of the barrel until firing is desired. While firing, cleaning of the inside of the barrel- should be thoroughly done every day under the supervision of competent instructors, the cleaning rod never to be inserted from the muzzle. When the firing is completed the barrels should again be filled with cosmoline, vaseline or other heavy oil and left oiled. Three-in-one and other light oils soon evaporate, leaving the steel exposed to attacks of rust. Web and leather equipment are usually injured by excessive washing and drying in the sun or near a fire, whereas, they should be dried in a cool place in the shade. Ordnance preparations should be obtained on requisition for all cleaning and preserving purposes. (c) Lectures on riot duty should be given at the earliest convenient opportunity as a riot or other emergency may occur unexpectedly. The lectures should be based on W. D. Document 882 and A Treatise on Riot Duty for the National Guard, by Col. Henry Bellow, recently adopted by the War Department and published in May of this year. (d) Marches and night exercises and exercises for the purpose of learning the location of all streets, roads, factories, public buildings, ad - vantageous positions, etc., can easily be combined by practicing the most suitable tactical formations on practice marches made at night, when the necessity for silence, absence of lights, and the difficulty of maintaining contact, communication and direction should be impressed upon every one engaged in the exercises. (e) As the bullet and bayonet are the principal weapons of Infantry, preliminary trainirvg for target practice should be started even before the rifles are received by the company, by conducting sighting drills with the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL sighting bar as prescribed in Par. 16, Small Arms Firing Manual. The secret of successful rifle firing is the proper co-ordination of the breath, eye and muscles in aiming, and the squeezing of the trigger in such a manner that the firer will not know just when the rifle will go off. The soldier's practice must be such as to make proper aiming and trigger squeeze a fixed habit, for only when such is the case will he do it pro - perly under stress of battle. Correct training in rapid loading is im - portant. Gallery practice should begin as soon as the men are far enough advanced. With thorough preliminary drills, men will have the foundation for good markmanship before beginning target practice. (f) Irksome though the making up, carrying and taking apart the full equipment may be, a man cannot be considered as having qualified as a soldier until he can assemble a near pack and carry his full field equipment throughout an average day's march of 15 miles. (,g) With the small amount of time available for physical drill, the correct habits of posture, locomotion and breathing; alertness of mind and body and the lossening of the muscles by setting up exercises should be tried for rather than the development of strength and endurance. The amount, scope and violence of physical drill should be gradually increased for beginners. (h) Although guard duty is of great importance when the occasion for its use arises, only the general principles should be attempted in ar - mory drill, the minute details being reserved for the period of field train - ing or for actual service. (i) Necessity compels military instruction to begin with the school of the soldier, squad, platoon and company (including the manual of arms) in order that groups of men may be converted into military units and that the wishes and commands of the leaders may be executed in unison and without misunderstanding and confusion. Also that there may be a uniformity of training throughout the Army. Except for this purpose and the disciplinary value of teaching men the habit of obedience to orders, both close and extended order are of less importance than the other subjects in the schedule. Most close order drill is for the purpose of teaching discipline rather than for the purpose of teaching men how to get about on the battle field. As it has been found that only thoroughly disciplined troops can carry out a modern attack where every step must be taken in accordance with a careful schedule, the minds and bodies must be trained to habits of precise, un - hesitating obedience to the will of the leader, so that in the stress of battle soldiers will obey without conscious effort, mechanically, auto - matically, as the easiest and most natural line of action. 4. After each drill or exercise the specific work for the next one </seg>
            <seg id="p017">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 17 should be announced, in order that the leaders may have time to prepare themselves, as it is hardly possible to properly conduct a drill or exercise without special forethought and preparation for that particular drill or exercise. An instructor must be prepared to impart his knowledge to his pupils in addition to knowing it himself. 5. The training of Infantry is based on the subjects covered in In - fantry Drill Regulations, Field Service Regulations, Manual for Non - commissioned Officers and Privates, Manual of Physical Training and in other documents issued from time to time by the War Department in accordance with developments in the Art of War. W. A. McDANIEL, STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 7, 1920. General Orders, No. 6. 1. General Orders No. 2, 1920, are hereby rescinded. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 31, 1919. Special Orders, No. 1. 1. The following men are hereby designated as a Civilian Rifle Team from Nebraska to attend the National Matches at Caldwell, New Jersey, commencing August 25, 1919, and will proceed to that range, leaving Nebraska on August 7, 1919, to participate in practice preliminary to the National Matches: Lt. Col. Inf., I. I. J. A. Storch, Captain, Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 REPORT OF'THE ADJUTANT GENERAL » C. L. Burmester, Coach, Omaha, Nebr. C. M. Richards, Quartermaster, Omaha, Nebr. Wayne E. Parker, Farnam, Nebr. Clarence L. Brosch, Farnam, Nebr. Richard H. Walker, Farnam, Nebr. Owen T. Thompson, Farnam, Nebr. Lincoln Riley, Wisner, Nebr. C. H. Hoff, Wisner, Nebr. Otto Frentzel, Wisner, Nebr. Jack Murray, Wisner, Nebr. R. H. Morse, Wisner, Nebr. Martin McGill, Wisner, Nebr. Alfred Jensen, Wisner, Nebr. L. G. Thompson, Wisner, Nebr. Walter H. Rauert, Grand Island, Nebr. E. G. Kroger, Grand Island, Nebr. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 6, 1919. Special Orders, No. 2. 1. That part of Special Orders No. 1, as pertains to C. L. Burmestei is hereby rescinded and Julius M. Festner substituted. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 19 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 13, 1919. Special Orders, No. 3. 1. Major James T. Hollings worth, Ordnance Department, Nebraska National Guard, will proceed from Omaha, Nebraska, to Lincoln, Ne - braska, Monday, December 15, 1919, for the purpose of surveying cer tain Quartermaster, Signal, Ordnance and Medical property and stores as provided under Section 87 of the Act of June 3, 1916, and upon com pletion of said duty will proceed to his home station at Omaha, Nebraska. The travel directed is necessary in the public service. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. Oj«j;1CIAL: (Special Orders No. 3 is the last of the series of 1919.) STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 4, 1920. Special Orders, No. 1. 1. Private John Kilmartin, Staff Corps and Departments, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby appointed Sergeant to rank from this date, March 4, 1920. 2. Sergeant John Kilmartin is hereby ordered to report for recruiting duty at Omaha, Nebraska, this date, March 4, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p020">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 20 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 15, 1920. Special Orders, No. 1. t. Private George L. Hearn, Q. M. Corps, State Staff Corps and De - ments, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby appointed Sergeant to : from this date, April 15, 1920. 4. Sergeant George L. Hearn is hereby ordered to report for recruit - ing duty at Omaha, Nebraska, this date, April 15, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN April 15, 1920. Pal Orders, No. 1. t Private Timon H. Dawson, Q. M. Corps, State Staff Corps and De - lents, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby appointed Sergeant to from this date, April 15, 1920. 6. Sergeant Timon H. Dawson is hereby ordered to report for re - cruiting duty at Omaha, Nebraska, this date, April 15, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN March 9, 1920. Special Orders, No. 2. 1. Captain J. W. McDonnell, Fairbury Company, Nebraska Rifles, i* </seg>
            <seg id="p021">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 21 hereby granted leave of absence for sixty days, with permission to leave the State. 2. Authority is hereby given to transfer property to next in com - mand upon receiving good and sufficient bond for the safe-keeping and security of same. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN February 21, 1920. Special Orders, No. 3. 1. Captain P. R. Halligan, Nebraska National Guard Reserve, is hereby placed on the active list, Nebraska National Guard, and will re - port to the Adjutant General, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 24, 1920, for rscmiting duty. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 10, 1920. Special Orders, No. 4. 1. Philip J. Risch is hereby appointed Captain of Infantry, unas - signed, in the Nebraska National Guard, to date from May 10, 1920, sub - ject to such examinations and requirements as may be prescribed by the War Department. 2. Captain Philip J. Risch, Infantry, unassigned, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby authorized to act as recruiting officer for the Nebraska National Guard, in and for Douglas County, Nebraska. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN May 13, 1920. Special Orders, No. 5. 1. Private Frank C. Shaffer, Q. M. Corps, State Staff Corps and De - partments, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby appointed Sergeant to rank from this date, May 13, 1920. 2. Sergeant Frank C. Shaffer is hereby ordered to report for recruit - ing duty at Omaha, Nebraska, this date, May 13, 1920. 3. Private Bohous G. Sinkule, Q. M. Corps, State Staff Corps and Departments, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby appointed Sergeant to rank from this date, May 13, 1920. 4. Sergeant Bohous G. Sinkule is hereby ordered to report for re - cruiting duty at Omaha, Nebraska, this date, May 13, 1920. 5. Sergeant George L. Hearn, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby relieved from active duty as Recruiting Sergeant at Omaha, Nebraska, effective this date, May 13, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 3, 1920 Special Orders, No. 6. 1. Charles F. Shook is hereby appointed Captain, Medical Corps, Ne - braska National Guard, to rank from May 27, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p023">• REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 23 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN June 28, 1920. Special Orders, No. 6. t2. Private Owen A. Frank, Separate Company No. 1, Nebraska ational Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, June 28, 1920, accept promotion. 3. Owen A. Frank is hereby appointed Captain, Separate Company No. 1, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from June 28, 1920. t4. Private Carl E. Diers, Separate Company No. 1, Nebraska Nation- Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, June 28, 1920, to ac - it promotion. 5. Carl E. Diers is hereby appointed 1st Lieutenant, Separate Com - pany No. 1, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from June 28, 1920. t6. Private Jerome H. Smith, Separate Company No. 1, Nebraska ational Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, June 28, 1920, accept promotion. 7. Jerome H. Smith is hereby appointed 2nd Lieutenant, Separate Company, No. 1, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from June 28, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 2, 1920. Special Orders, No. 7. 1. Mr. E. L. C. Gilmore, Ashland, Nebraska, is hereby appointed caretaker of the Ashland Rifle Range at Ashland, Nebraska, and is em - powered to arrest or effect any person or persons trespassing thereon. 2. The Nebraska City Company, Nebraska Rifles, is hereby honor - ably discharged from State service account of expiration of enlistment. 3. The Nebraska City Company, Nebraska Rifles, leaves the service with a commendable record for service and zeal for duty performed at a </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL time when conditions were such that a military organization was much needed by the State, no other military organization having been per - fected, and to the members of the Nebraska Rifles who voluntarily gave their time and services in this hour of need, the State is deeply indebted. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 5, 1920. Special Orders, No. 7. 4. Captain Charles F. Shook is hereby placed on duty for a period of fifteen days as Medical Officer examining recruits effective this date, July 5, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 16, 1920. Special Orders, No. 8. 1. Private Harry G. Montgomery, Nebraska National Guard, is here by honorably discharged this date, July 16, 1920, to accept promotion. 2. Hairy G. Montgomery is hereby appointed Captain, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from July 16, 1920. 3. Sergeant Timon H. Dawson is hereby relieved from recruiting duty and honorably discharged as of this date to accept promotion. 4. Sergeant Timon H. Dawson is hereby appointed 1st Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from July 16, 1920. 5. Private Frank L. Peterson, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby </seg>
            <seg id="p025">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 25 honorably discharged this date, July 16, 1920, to accept promotion. 6. Frank L. Peterson is heteby appointed 2nd Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from July 16, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 28, 1920. Special Orders, No. 9. 1. The following men are hereby designated as a Civilian Rifle Team from Nebraska to attend the National Rifle Matches at Camp Perry, Ohio, commencing August 1, 1920, to August 28, 1920, inclusive, and will proceed to that range leaving Nebraska so as to arrive at Camp Perry, Ohio, not later than noon August 1, 1920, except as herewith noted: Lincoln Riley, Captain, Wisher, Nebr., entire period. W. H. Plasters, Coach, Stella, Nebr., from noon August 15, 1920. S. Galbraith, Range Officer, Wisner, Nebr., entire period. J. R. Monroe, Quartermaster, Lincoln, Nebr., entire period. E. J. Harvey, Valentine, Nebr., from noon August 15, 1920. A. F. Fuhlrodt, Wisner, Nebr., entire period. E. R. Herman, Wisner, Nebr., entire period L. G. Thompson, Wisner, Nebr., from noon August 15, 1920. M. F. McGill, Wisner, Nebr., from noon August 15, 1920. F. S. Stevenson, Farnam, Nebr., entire period. F. G. Gardner, Farnam, Nebr., entire period, C. M. Sorenson, Elyria, Nebr., from noon August 15, 1920, John Marriner, Lincoln, Nebr., entire period. Dee Stoults, Lincoln, Nebr., entire period. Judson Meier, Wisner, Nebr., entire period. Herbert Lorensen, Wisner, Nebr., entire period. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 29, 1920. Special Orders, No. 9. 2. The following men are hereby designated as a Civilian Rifle Team from Nebraska to attend the National Rifle Matches at Camp Perry, Ohio, commencing August 1, 1920, to August 28, 1920, inclusive, and will pro - ceed to that range leaving Nebraska so as to arrive at Camp Perry, Ohio, not later than noon August 1, 1920, except as herewith noted: Paul Snyder, Wisner, Nebr., entire period. Leonard Kane, Wisner, Nebr., entire period. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN July 30, 1920. Special Orders, No. 9. 3. That part of Special Orders No. 9, as pertains to Herbert Loren - sen, Wisner, Nebraska, is hereby rescinded and Victor Dignan of Wisner, Nebraska, is substituted for the entire period. 4. That part of Special Orders No. 9, Par. 1, as pertains to Lincoln Riley, Captain, Wisner, Nebraska, entire period, is hereby amended. Lincoln Riley is appointed Captain of the Civilian Rifle Team from Ne - braska for 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p027">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 27 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 7, 1920. Special Orders, No. 10. • The Alliance Company, Nebraska Rifles, is hereby honorably dis - rged from State service account of expiration of enlistment. 2. The Alliance Company, Nebraska Rifles, leaves the service with a ommendable record for service and zeal for duty performed at a time when conditions were such that a military organization was much needed &gt;y the State, no other military organization having been perfected, and o the members of the Nebraska Rifles who voluntarily gave their time and services in this hour of need, the State is deeply indebted. 3. The Clay Center Company, Nebraska Rifles, is hereby honorably discharged from State service account of expiration of enlistment. 4. The Clay Center Company, Nebraska Rifles, leaves the service with a commendable record for service and zeal for duty performed at a ime when conditions were such that a military organization was much needed by the State, no other military organization having been perfected, and to the members of the Nebraska Rifles who voluntarily gave their ime and services in this hour of need, the State is deeply indebted. The Fairbury Company, Nebraska Rifles, is hereby honorably dis - rged from State service account of expiration of enlistment. 6. The Fairbury Company, Nebraska Rifles, leaves the service with a commendable record for service and zeal for duty performed at a time when conditions were such that a military organization was much needed ly the State, no other military organization having been perfected, and o the members of the Nebraska Rifles who voluntarily gave their time and services in this hour of need, the State is deeply indebted. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 12, 1920. Special Orders, No. 10. 7. Resignation of Captain Philip J. Risch, Infantry, unassigned, N«- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL braska National Guard, is hereby accepted effective this date, August 12, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN August 14, 1920. Special Orders, No. 11. 1. Sergeants Bohous G. Sinkule and Frank C. Shaffer are hereby re - lieved from duty as Recruiting Sergeants at Omaha, Nebraska, effective this date. 2. Sergeants Bohous G. Sinkule and Frank C. Shaffer are hereby re - duced to grade of Private and transferred to Second Separate Company, Omaha, Nebraska, and will report to the Commanding Officer thereof for assignment and duty. 2%. Sergeant Frank C. Shaffer, Second Separate Company, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby placed on recruiting duty at Omaha, Nebraska, effective this date, August 14, 1920. 3. Private Louis R. Eby, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honor - ably discharged this date, August 14, 1920, to accept promotion. 4. Louis R. Eby is hereby appointed Captain, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from August 14, 1920. 5. Private Robert G. Easley, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, August 14, 1920, to accept promotion. 6. Robert G. Easley is hereby appointed 1st Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from August 14, 1920. 7. Private Rolland W. Heckert, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, August 14, 1920, to accept commission. 8. Rolland W. Heckert is hereby appointed 2nd Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from August 14, 1920. 9. Federal Inspection will be held of Second Separate Company, Nebraska National Guard, Omaha, Nebraska, in the City Auditorium, Tuesday evening, August 17, 1920, at 8 p. m. 10. The Commanding Officer of Second Separate Company, Nebraska National Guard, will assemble his command as set out in Paragraph 1 of this order and hold them subject to the orders of the Federal Inspector. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p029">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 29 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN Sept. 28, 1920 Special Orders, No. 12. 1. Private Robert J. Emery, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, September 28, 1920, to accept commission. 2. Robert J. Emery is hereby appointed Captain, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from September 28, 1920. 3. Private Robert R. Warien, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, September 28, 1920, to accept commission. 4. Robert R. Warren is hereby appointed 1st Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from this date, September 28, 1920. 5. Private Fred H. Stoll, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honor - ably discharged this date, September 28, 1920, to accept commission. 6. Fred H. Stoll is hereby appointed 2nd Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from September 28, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 8, 1920. Special Orders, No. 13. 1. Federal Inspection will be held of Fourth Separate Company, Ne - braska National Guard, Beatrice, Nebraska, in the Armory, Monday evening, October 18, 1920, at 8 p. m. 2. The Commanding Officer of Fourth Separate Company, Nebraska National Guard, will assemble his command as set out in Paragraph 1 of this order and hold them subject to the orders of the Federal Inspector. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p030">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 30 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 14, 1920. Special Orders, No. 14 Resignation of Captain Robert J. Emery, Nebraska National ird, is hereby accepted, effective this date, October 14, 1920. 2. Captain Charles F. Shook, M. C, is hereby directed to proceed from Omaha, Nebraska, to Hartington, Nebraska, so as to arrive Saturday, October 16, 1920, and there conduct physical examination of officers and men of the 3rd Separate Company, Nebraska National Guard. Upon completion of same Captain Charles F. Shook will return to his home station at Omaha, Nebraska. The travel directed is necessary in the public service. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 19, 1920. Special Orders, No. 15. 1. Private Emmett S. Powell, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, October 19, 1920, to accept commission. 2. Emmett S. Powell is hereby appointed Captain, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from October 19, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p031">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 31 1 Special Orders, No. 16. \. Federal Inspection will be held of Third Separate Company, Ne - braska National Guard, Hartington, Nebraska, in the Armory, Friday evening, October 29, 1920, at 8 p. m. 2. The Commanding Officer of Third Separate Company, Nebraska National Guard, will assemble his command as set out in Paragraph 1 of this order and hold them subject to the orders of the Federal Inspector. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN October 29, 1920. Special Orders No. 17. 1. Private Collins Riley, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby ap - pointed Sergeant to rank from this date, October 29, 1920. 2. Sergeant Collins Riley is hereby placed on recruiting duty at Ne - braska City, Nebraska, this date, October 29, 1920. 3. Private Harvey R. Sorensen, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, October 29, 1920, to accept commission. 4. Harvey R. Sorensen is hereby appointed 2nd Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from October 29, 1920. 5. Second Lieutenant Rolland W. Heckert, Infantry, unassigned, Ne - braska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, October 29, 1920, on account of being over the age limit as set out in Paragraph 232, National Guard Regulations, 1919. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 10, 1920* Special Orders, No. 18. 1. Resignation of Captain Harry G. Montgomery, Infantry, unas - signed, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby accepted, effective this date, November 10, 1920. 2. 1st Lieutenant Timon H. Dawson, Infantry, unassigned, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby promoted to the rank of Captain, Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, effective this date, November 10, 1920. 3. 2nd Lieutenant Frank L. Peterson, Infantry, unassigned, Ne - braska National Guard, is hereby promoted to the rank of 1st Lieutenant, Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, effective this date, November 10, 1920. 4. 1st Sergeant Paul J. Auxier, 2nd Separate Company, Infantry, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged, effective this date, November 10, 1920, to accept promotion. 5. Paul J. Auxier is hereby appointed 2nd Lieutenant, Infantry, Ne - braska National Guard, to rank from this date, November 10, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 29, 1920. Special Orders, No. 18%. 1. Sergeant Collins Riley, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby re - lieved from recruiting duty at Nebraska City, Nebraska, effective this date, November 29, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN November 30, 1920. Special Orders, No. 19. 1. Resignation of Captain Charles F. Shook, Medical Corps, Ne - braska National Guard, to accept commission in the Regular Army, is hereby accepted, effective this date, November 30, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR: H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 1, 1920. Special Orders, No. 20. 1. Sergeant William F. Bruett, 2nd Separate Company, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby placed on recruiting duty at Omaha, Nebraska, this date, December 1, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL STATE OF NEBRASKA ADJUTANT GENERAL'S DEPARTMENT LINCOLN December 2, 1920. Special Orders, No. 21. 1. Private Verne R. Taylor, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, December 2, 1920, to accept commission. 2. Verne R. Taylor is hereby appointed Captain. Nebraska National Guard, to rank from this date, December 2, 1920. 3. Private Oscar A. Flau, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honor- </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ably discharged this date, December 2, 1920, to accept commission. 4. Oscar A. Flau is hereby appointed 1st Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from this date, December 2, 1920. 5. Private Dale R. Leeper, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby honorably discharged this date, December 2, 1920, to accept commission. 6. Dale R. Leeper is hereby appointed 2nd Lieutenant, Nebraska National Guard, to rank from this date, December 2, 1920. BY ORDER OF THE GOVERNOR H. J. Paul, The Adjutant General, Nebraska. OFFICIAL: THE NATIONAL DEFENSE ACT APPROVED JUNE 4, 1920, PER - TAINING TO THE NATIONAL GUARD Sec. 58. Composition of the National Guard — The National Guard shall consist of the regularly enlisted militia between the ages of eight - teen and forty-five years organized, armed, and equipped as hereinafter provided, and of commissioned officers between the ages of twenty-one and sixty-four years. Sec. 59. Exemption From Militia Duty — The Vice President of the United States; the officers, judicial and executive, of the Government of the United States and of the several States and Territories; persons in the military or naval service of the United States customhouse clerks; persons employed by the United States in the transmission of the mail; artificers and workmen employed in the armories, arsenals, and navy yards of the United States; pilots; mariners actually employed in the sea service of any citizen or merchant within the United States, shall be ex - empt from militia duty without regard to age, and all persons who be - cause of religious belief shall claim exemption from military service, if the conscientious holding of such belief by such person shall be estab - lished under such regulations as the President shall prescribe, shall be exempted from militia service in a combatant capacity; but no person so exempted shall be exempt from militia service in any capacity that the President shall declare to be noncombatant. Sec. 60. Organization of National Guard Units — Except as otherwise specifically provided herein, the organization of the National Guard, in - cluding the composition of all units thereof, shall be the same as that which is or may hereafter be prescribed for the Regular Army, subject in time of peace to such general exceptions as may be authorized by the Secretary of War. And the President may prescribe the particular unit or units, as to branch or arm cf service, to be maintained in each State, </seg>
            <seg id="p035">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 35 Territory, or the District of Columbia in order to secure a force which when combined, shall form complete higher tactical units. Until July 1, 1921, companies and corresponding units of the Na - tional Guard may be recognized at a minimum enlisted strength of fifty: Provided, That the National Guard of any State, Territory, and the Dis - trict of Columbia may include such detachments or parts of units as may be necessary in order to form complete tactical units when combined with troops of other states. Sec. 61. Maintenance of Other Troops by the States — No State shall maintain troops in time of peace other than as authorized in accordance with the organization prescribed under this Act: Provided, That nothing - contained in this Act shall be construed as limiting the rights of the States and Territories in the use of the National Guard within their re - spective borders in time of peace: Provided further, That nothing con - tained in this Act shall prevent the organization and maintenance of State police or constabulary- Sec 62. Number of the National Guard — The number of enlisted men of the National Guard to be organized under this Act within one year from its passage shall be for each State in the proportion of two hundred such men for each Senator and Representative in Congress from such State, and a number to be determined by the President for each Territory and the District of Columbia, and shall be increased each year thereafter in the proportion of not less than fifty per centum until a total peace strength of not less than eight hundred enlisted men for each Senator and Representative in Congress shall have been reached: Provided, That in States which have but one Representative in Congress such increase shall be at the discretion of the President: Provided further, That this shall not be construed to prevent any State, Territory, or the District of Columbia from organizing the full number of troops required under this section in less time than is specified in this section, or from maintaining, existing organizations if they shall conform to such rules and regulations regarding organization, strength, and armament as the President may prescribe: And provided further, That nothing in this Act shall be con - strued to prevent any State with but one Representative in Congress from organizing one or more regiments of troops, with such auxiliary troops as ;he President may prescribe; such organizations and members of such organizations to receive all the benefits accruing under this Act under the conditions set forth herein: Provided further, That the word Territory as used in this Act and in all laws relating to the land militia and National iuard shall include and apply to Hawaii, Alaska, Porto Rico, and the Canal Zone and the militia of the Canal Zone shall be or - ganized under such rules and regulations, not in conflict with the provisions of this Act, as the President may prescribe. The Secretary of War is hereby authorized to issue from stores now </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL on hand and purchased for the United States Army such articles of clot li - ng and equipment material as may be needed by the National Guard or - ganized under the provisions of the act entitled "An act for making fur - her and more effectual provision for the national defense, and for other purposes," approved June 3, 1916. This issue shall be made without charge against militia appropriations and shall be reimbursed in kind or all Federal property brought into service by State troops; Provided, That the provisions of section 62 of the act * * * shall be considered ful - illed if the first strength mentioned therein be attained by June 30, 1920, and the other increments provided therein be attained by successive ears thereafter: Provided further, That this shall not prevent any State rom compliance with the provisions of section 62: * * *. (Act of July 1, 1919— Bui. 23, 1919, p. 35. Sec. 63. Any corps of Artillery, Cavalry, or Infantry existing in any of the States on the passage of the Act of May eighth, seventeen hun- Ired and ninety-two, which by the laws, customs, or usages of said States las been in continuous existence since the passage of said Act, under ts provisions and under the provisions of section two hundred and thir - y-two and sections sixteen hundred and twenty-five to sixteen hundred and sixty, both ir.cluave, of title sixteen of the Revised Statutes of eigh - teen hundred and seventy-three, and the Act of January twenty-first, nineteen hundred and three, relating to the militia, shall be allowed to re - tain its ancient privileges, subject, nevertheless, to all duties required by law of militia: Provided, That said organizations may be a part of the National Guard and entitled to all the privileges of this Act, and shall conform in all respects to the organization, discipline, and training of the National Guard m time of war: Provided further, That for purposes of training and when on active duty in the service of the United States they may be assigned to higher units, as the President may direct, and shall be subject to the orders of officers under whom they shall be serving. Sec. 64. Assignment of National Guard to Brigades and Divisions. — For the purpose of maintaining appropriate organization and to assist in nstruction and training, the President may assign the National Guard of the several States and Territories and the District of Columbia to di - visions, brigades, and other tactical units, and may detail officers either rom the National Guard or the Regular Army to command such units: Provided, That where complete units are organized within a State, Ter - ritory, or the District of Columbia the commanding officers thereof shall not be displaced under the provisions of this section. Sec. 65. Chiefs of Staff of National Guard Divisions — The President may detail one officer of the Regular Army as chief of staff and one officer of the Regular Army or the National Guard as assistant to the chief of staff of any division of the National Guard in the service of the United States as a National Guard* organization: Provided, That in </seg>
            <seg id="p037">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 37 order to insure the prompt mobilization of the National Guard in time of war or other emergency, the President may, in time of peace, detail an officer of the Regular Army to perform the duties of chief of staff for each fully organized tactical division of the National Guard. Sec. 66. Adjutants General of States, And So Forth.— The adjutants general of the States, Territories, and the District of Columbia and the officers of the National Guard shall make such returns and reports to the Secretary of War, or to such officers as he may designate, at such times and in such form as the Secretary of War, may from time to time pre - scribe: Provided, That the adjutants general of the Territories and of the District of Columbia shall be appointed by the President with such rank and qualifications as he may prescribe, and each adjutant general for a Territory shall be a citizen of the Territory for which he is ap - pointed. Sec 67. Appropriation, Apportionment and Disbursement of Funds For the National Guard. — A sum of money shall hereafter be appropria - ted annually, to be paid out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the support of the National Guard, including the ex - pense of providing arms, ordnance stores, quartermaster stores, and camp equipage, and all other military supplies for issue to the National Guard, and such other expenses pertaining to said guard as are now or may hereafter be authorized by law. The appropriation provided for in this section shall be apportioned among the several States and Territories under just and equitable pro - cedure to be prescribed by the Secretary of War and in direct ratio to the number of enlisted men in active service in the National Guard existing in such States and Territories at the date of apportionment of said appropriation, and to the District of Columbia, under such regula - tions as the President may prescribe: Provided, That the sum so appor - tioned among the several States, Territories, and the District of Columbia shall be available under such rules as may be prescribed by the Secre - tary of War for the actual and necessary expenses incurred by officers and enlisted men of the Regular Army when traveling on duty in con - nection with the National Guard; for the transportation of supplies fur - nished to the National Guard for the permanent equipment thereof; for office rent and necessary office expenses of officers of the Regular Army on duty with the National Guard; for the expenses of the M.litia Bu - reau, including clerical services, now authorized for the Division of Mili - tia Affairs; for expenses of enlisted men of the Regular Army on duty with the National Guard, including quarters, fuel, light, medicines and medical attendance; and such expenses shall constitute a charge against the whole sum annually appropriated for the support of the National Guard, and shall be paid therefrom and not from the allotment duly ap - portioned to any particular State, Territory, or the District of Columbia; </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL for the promotion of rifle practice, including the acquisition, construc - tion, maintenance, and equipment of shooting gaileries and suitable tar - get ranges; for the hiring of horses and draft animals for the use of mounted troops, batteries, and wagons; for forage for the same; and for such other incidental expenses in connection with lawfully author - ized encampments, maneuvers, and field instruction as the Secretary of War may deem necessary, and for such other expenses pertaining to the National Guard as are now or may hereafter be authorizd by law. The governor of each State and Territory and the Commanding Gen - eral of the National Guard of the District of Columbia shall appoint, des - ignate, or detail, subject to the approval of the Secretary of War, the Adjutant General or (act of July 9, 1918 — Bui. 43, 1918, p. 47) an of - ficer of the National Guard of the State, Territory, or District of Colum - bia, who shall be regarded as property and disbursing officer of the United States. He shall receipt and account for all funds and property belonging to the United States in possession of the National Guard of his State, Territory, or District, and shall make such returns and reports concerning the same as may be required by the Secretary of War. The Secretary of War is authorized, on the requisition of the governor of a State or Territory or the commanding general of the National Guard of the District of Columbia, to pay to the property and disbursing officer thereof so much of its allotment out of the annual appropriation for the support of the National Guard as shall, in the judgment of the Sec - retary of War, be necessary for the purposes enumerated therein. He shall render, through the War Department, such accounts of Federal funds intrusted to him for disbursement as may be required by the Treas - ury Department. Before entering upon the performance of his duties as property and disbursing officer he shall be required to give good and sufficient bond to the United States, the amount thereof to be determined by the Secretary of War, for the faithful performance of his duties and for the safe-keeping and proper disposition of the Federal property and funds intrusted to his care. He shall, after having qualified as property and disbursing officer, receive pay for his services at a rate to be fixed by the Secretaary of War, and such compensation shall be a charge against the whole sum annually appropriated for the support of the Na - tional Guard: Provided, That when traveling in the performance of his official duties under orders issued by the proper authorities he shall be reimbursed for his actual necessary traveling expenses, the sum to be made a charge against the allotment of the State, Territory, or District of Columbia: Provided further, That the Secretary of War shall cause an inspection of the accounts and records of the property and disbursing officer to be made by an inspector general of the Army at least once «ach year: And provided further, That the Secretary of War is empow - ered to make all rules and regulations necessary to carry into effect the provisions of this section- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 39 tSec. 68. Location of Units. — The States and Territories shall have right to determine and fix the location of the units and headquarters the National Guard within their respective borders: Provided, That organization of the National Guard, members of which shall be en - ed to and shall have received compensation under the provisions of i Act, shall be disbanded without the consent of the President, nor, hout such consent, shall the commissioned or enlisted strength of any h organization be reduced below the minimum that shall be prescribed therefor by the President. Sec 69. Original enlistments in the National Guard shall be for a period of three years and subsequent enlistments for periods of one year each; Provided, That persons who have served in the Army for not leas than six months, and have been honorably discharged therefrom, may, within two years after the passage of this Act, enlist in the National Guard for a period of one year and reenlist for like periods. Sec. 70. Men enlisting in the National Guard of the several States, Territories, and the District of Columbia, shall sign an enlistment con - tract and subscribe to the following oath of enlistment: "I do hereby acknowledge to have voluntarily enlisted this day of , 19 — , as a soldier in the National Guard of the United States and of the State of , for the period of three (or one) year , under the con - ditions prescribed by law, unless sooner discharged by proper authority- And I do solemnly swear that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the United States of America and to the State of , and that I will serve them honestly and faithfully against all their enemies whomsoever, and that I will obey the orders of the President of the United States and of the governor of the State of , and of the officers appointed over me according to law and the rules and Articles of War." Sec. 71. Stricken out. Sec. 72. DISCHARGE OF ENLISTED MEN FROM THE NATION - AL GUARD. — An enlisted man discharged from service in the National Guard, except when drafted into the military service of the United States under the provisions of section 111 of this Act, shall receive a dis - charge in writing in such form and with such classification as is or shall be prescribed for the Regular Army, and in time of peace discharges may be given prior to the expiration of terms of enlistment under such regu - lations as the President may prescribe. Sec 73. Federal Oath For National Guard Officers.— Commissioned officrs of the National Guard of the several States, Territories, and the District of Columbia now serving under commissions regularly issued shall continue in office, as officers of the National Guard, without the Issuance of new commissions: Provided, That said officers have taken or shall take and subscribe to the following oath of office: "I, , do </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL solemnly swear that I will support and defend the Constitution of the United States and the constitution of the State of , against all enemies, foreign and domestic; that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the same; that I will obey the orders of the President of the United States and of the governor of the State of ; that I make this ob - ligation freely, without any mental reservation of purpose of evasion, and that I will well and faithfully discharge the duties of the office of -in the National Guard of th United States and of the State of upon which I am about to enter, so help me God." Sec. 74. QUALIFICATIONS FOR NATIONAL GUARD OFFI - CERS. — Persons hereafter commissioned as officers of the National Guard shall not be recognized as such under any of the provisions of this Act unless they shall have been selected from the following classes, and shall have taken and subscribed to the oath of office prescribed in the preced - ing section of this Act; officers or enlisted men of the National Guard; officers, active or retired, reserve officers, and former officers of the Army Navy, or Marine Corps, enlisted men and former enlisted men of the .Army, Navy, or Marine Corps who have received an honorable discharge therefrom; graduates of the United States Military and Naval Academ - ies; and graduates of schools, colleges, universities, and officers' training camps, where they have received military instruction under the super - vision of an officer of the Regular Army who certified their fitness for appointment as commissioned officers; and for the technical branches or Staff Corps and departments, such other civilians as may be specially qualified for duty therein. Sec. 75. The provisions of this Act shall not apply to any person hereafter appointed an officer of the National Guard unless he first shall have successfully passed such tests as to his physical, moral, and pro - fessional fitness as the President shall prescribe. The examination to de - termine such qualifications for commission shall be conducted by a board of three commissioned officers appointed by the Secretary of War from the Regular Army or the National Guard, or both. Sec. 76. Filling of Vacancies When Drafted Into Federal Service. — All vacancies occurring in any grade of commissioned officers in any or - ganization in the military service of the United States and composed of persons drafted from the National Guard under the provision of this Act shall be filled by the President, as far as practicable, by the appointment of persons similarly taken from said guard, and in the manner prescribed by law for filling similar vacancies occurring in the volunteer forces. Sec 77. Elimination and Disposition of Officers. — At any time the moral character, capacity, and general fitness for the service of any Na - tional Guard officer may be determined by an efficiency board of three commissioned officers, senior in rank to the officer whose fitness for ser - vice shall be under investigation, and if the findings of such board be </seg>
            <seg id="p041">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 41 unfavorable to such officer and be approved by the official authorized to appoint such an officer, he shall be discharged. Commissions of officers of the National Guard may be vacated upon resignation, absence without leave for three months, upon the recommendation of an efficiency board, or pursuant to sentence of a court-martial. Officers of said guard ren - dered surplus by the disbandment of their organizations shall be placed in the National Guard Reserve. Officers may, upon their own applica - tion, be placed in. the said reserve. Sec. 78. That hereafter, men duly qualified under regulations pre - scribed by the Secretary of War may enlist in the National Guard Reserve for a period of one or three years, under such regulations as the Secre - tary of War shall prescribe, and on so enlisting they shall subcribe to the following enlistment contract and take the oath therein specified: "I do hereby acknowledge to have voluntarily enlisted this day of , 19 — , as a soldier in the National Guard Reserve of the United and of the State of , for a period of one (or three) year , unless sooner discharged by proper authority, and I do solemn - ly swear that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the United States of America and to the State of , and that I will serve them honest - ly and faithfully against all their enemies whomsoever and that I will obey the orders of the President of the United States and the governor of the State of , and of the officers appointed over me according to law and the rules and Articles of War": Provided, That members of said reserve, officers and enlisted men, when engaged in field or coast defense training with the active National Guard, shall receive the same Federal pay and allowances as those occuping like grades on the active list of said guard when likewise engaged: Provided further, That, except as otherwise specifically provided in this Act, no commissioned or enlisted reservist shall receive any pay or allowances out of any appropriation made by Congress for National Guard purposes Sec. 79 stricken out. Sec. 80. Leaves of Absence For Certain Government Employes. — All officers and employes of the United States and of the District of Columbia who shall be members of the National Guard shall be entitled to leave of absence from their respective duties, without loss of pay, time, or efficiency rating, on all days during which they shall be engaged in field or coast-defense training ordered or authorized under the pro - vision of this Act. Sec. 81. MILITIA BUREAU OF THE WAR DEPARTMENT.— The Militia Division of the War Department shall hereafter be known as the Militia Bureau of the War Department. After January 1, 1921, the Chief of the Militia Bureau shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, by selection from lists of present and former National Guard officers, recommended by the Got- </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ernor of the several States and Territories as suitable for such appoint - ment, who hold commissions in the Officers' Reserve Corps, who have had ten or more years' commissioned service in the National Guard, at least five of which has been in the line, and who have attained at least the grade of major. He shall hold office for four years, unless sooner re - moved for cause, and shall have the rank, pay and allowances of a major general of the Regular Army during his tenure of office, but shall not be entitled to retirement or retired pay. While serving as chief, his reserve commission shall continue in force, and shall not be terminated except for cause assigned. Until the chief is appointed, as provided in this section, the President may assign an officer of the Reg - ular Army, not below the grade of colonel, to perform the duties of chief. For duty in the Militia Bureau and for the instruction of the National Guard the President shall assign such number of officers and enlisted men of the Regular Army as he may deem necessary. The Esident may also assign, with their consent, and within the limits of the ropriations previously made for this specific purpose, not exceeding hundred officers of the National Guard, who hold reserve commis - is, to duty with the Regular Army, in addition to those attending service schools and while so assigned they shall receive the same pay and allowances as Regular Army officers of like grades, to be paid out of the whole fund appropriated for the support of the militia. Sec. 82. Armament, Equipment and Uniform of the National Guard. — The National Guard of the United States shall, as far as prac- Ele, be uniformed, armed, and equipped with the same type of uni - s, arms, and equipments as are or shall be provided for the Regular tSec. 83. The Secretary of War is hereby authorized to procure, er such regulations as the President may prescribe, by purchase or -lufacture, within the limits of available appropriations made by Con - gress, and to issue from time to time to the National Guard, upon re - quisition of the governors of the several States and Territories or the commanding general o f the National Guard of the District of Columbia, such number of United States service arms, with all accessories, field - artillery material, engineer, coast artillery, signal, and sanitary material, accouterments, field uniforms, clothing, equipage, publications, and mili - tary stores of all kinds, including public animals, as are necessary to arm, uniform, and equip for field service the National Guard in the sev - eral States, Territories, and the District of Columbia: Provided, That as a condition precedent to the issue of any property as provided for by this Act, the State, Territory, or the District of Columbia desiring such issue shall make adequate provision, to the satisfaction of the Secretary of War, for the protection and care of such property: Provided further, That, whenever it shall be shown to the satisfaction of the Secretary of War that the National Guard of any State, Territory, or the District of </seg>
            <seg id="p043">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 43 Columbia, is properly organized, armed, and equipped for field service, funds allotted to that State, Territory, or District for the support of its- National Guard may be used for the purchase, from the War Department, of any article issued by any of the supply departments of the Army. Sec. 84. Under such regulations as the President may prescribe, whenever a new type of equipment, small arm, or field gun shall have been issued to the National Guard of the several States, Territories, and the District of Columbia, such equipment, small arms, and field guns, includ - ing all accessories, shall be furnished without charging the cost or value thereof or any expense connected therewith against the appropriation pro - vided for the support of the National Guard. Sec. 85. Each State, Territory, and the District of Columbia shall, on the receipt of new property issued to replace obsolete or condemned prior issues, turn in to the War Department or otherwise dispos of, in accordance with the directions of the Secretary of War, all property so - replaced or condemned, and shall not receive any money credit therefor. Sec. 86- Any State, Territory or the District of Columbia may, with the approval of the Secretary of War, purchase for cash from the War De - partment for the use of the National Guard, including the officers there - of, any stores, supplies, material of war, and military publication fur - nished to the Army, in addition to those issued under the provisions or this Act, at the price at which they shall be listed to the Army, with cost of transportation added. The funds received from such sale shall be credited to the appropriation to which they shall belong, shall not be covered into the Treasury, and shall be available until expended to re - place therewith the supplies sold to the States in the manner herein authorized: Provided, That stores, supplies, and material of war so pur - chased by a State, Territory, or the District of Columbia may, in time of actual or threatened war, be requisitioned by the United States for use in the military service thereof,, and when so requisitioned by the United States and delivered credit for the ultimate return of such property in kind shall be allowed to such State, Territory, or the District of Columbia. Sec. 87. Disposition and Replacement of Damaged Property, and So Forth. — All military property issued to the National Guard as herein provided shall remain the property of the United States. Whenever any such property issued to the National Guard in any State or Territory or the District of Columbia shall have been lost, damaged, or destroyed, or become unserviceable or unsuitable by use in service or from any other cause, it shall be examined by a disinterested surveying officer of the Regular Army or the National Guard, detailed by the Secretary of War, and the report of such surveying officer shall be forwarded to the Secretary of War, or to such officer as he shall designate to receive such reports; and if it shall appear to the Secretary of War from the record of survey that the property was lost, damaged, or destroyed through </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL unavoidable causes, he is hereby authorized to redlieve the State or Ter - ritory or the District of Columbia from further accountability therefor, if it shall appear that the loss, damage, or destruction of property was due to carelessness or neglect, or that its loss, damage, or destruction could nave been avoided by the exercise of reasonable care, the money value of such property shall be charged to the accountable State, Territory, or District of Columbia, to be paid from State, Territory, or District Funds, or any funds other than Federal. If the articles so surveyed are 'our.d to be unserviceable or unsuitable, the Secretary of War shall di - rect what disposition, by sale or otherwise, shall be made of them; and if sold, the proceeds of such sale, as well as stoppages against officers and enlisted men, and the net proceeds of collections made from any serson or from any State, Territory, or District to reimburse the Gov - ernment for the loss, damage, or destruction of any property, shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as a credit to said State, Territory, or the District of Columbia, accountable for said property, and as a part of and in addition to that portion of its allotment set aside 'or the purchase of similar supplies, stores, or material of war: Provided further, That if any State, Territory, or the District of Columbia shall neglect or refuse to pay, or to cause to be paid, the money equivalent of any loss, damage, or destruction of property charged against such State, Territory, or the District of Columbia by the Secretary of War after survey by a disinterested officer appointed as hereinbefore piovid - ed, the Secretary of War is hereby authorized to debar such State, Territory, or the District of Columbia from further participation in any and all appropriations for the National Guard until such payment shall have been made. Sec. 88. The net proceeds of the sale of condemned stores issued to the National Guard and not charged to State allotments shall be covered into the Treasury of the United States, as shall also stoppages against officers and enlisted men, and the net proceeds of collections made from any person to reimburse the Government for the loss, damage, or de - struction of said property not charged against the State allotment issued for the use of the National Guard. . . Sec. 89- ANIMALS FOR NATIONAL GUARD.— Funds allotted by the Secretary of War for the support of the National Guard shall be available for the purchase, under such regulations as the Secretary of War may prescribe, of animals conforming to the Regular Arm) stand - ards for the training of the National Guard, said animals to remain the property of the United States and to be used solely for military purposes. The number of animals so issued shall not exceed thirty-two for each battery of Field Artillery or troop of Cavalry, and a proportionate num - ber for other mounted organizations, under such regulations as the Sec - retary of War may prescribe and the Secretary of War is further author- </seg>
            <seg id="p045">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 45 ized to issue in lieu of purchase, for the training of such organizations, condemned Army animals which are no longer fit for service, but which may be suitable for the purposes of instruction, such animals to be sold as now provided by law when said purposes shall have been served. Sec. 90. Funds allotted by the Secretary of War for the support of the National Guard shall be available for the purchase and issue of for - age, bedding, shoeing, and veterinary services, and supplies for the Gov - ernment animals issued to any organization, and for the compensation of competent help for the care of the material, animals, and equipment thereof, under such regulations as the Secretary of War may prescribe: Provided, That the men to be compensated, not to exceed five for each organization shall be duly enlisted therein and shall be detailed by the organization commander, under such regulations as the Secretary of War may prescribe, and shall be paid by the United States disbursing officer in each State, Territory, and the District of Columbia. Sec. 91. Discipline to Conform to that of Regular Army. — The dis - cipline (which includes training) of the National Guard shall conform to the system which is now or may hereafter be prescribed for the Reg - ular Army, and the training shall be carried out by the several States, Territories, and the District of Columbia so as to conform to the provi - sions of this Act. Sec. 92. Training of the National Guard. — Each company, troop, bat - tery, and detachment in the National Guard shall assemble for drill and instruction, including indoor target practice, not less than forty-eight times each year, and shall in addition thereto, participate in encamp - ments, maneuvers, or other exercises, including outdoor target practice, at least fifteen days in training each year, including target practice, un - less such company, troop, battery, or detachment shall have been excused from participation in any part thereof by the Secretary of War: Provided, That credit for an assembly for drill or for indoor target practice shall not be given unless the number of officers and enlisted men present for duty at such assembly shall equal or exceed a minimum to be prescribed by the President, nor unless the period of actual military duty and in - struction participated in by each officer and enlisted, man at each such assembly at which he shall be credited as having been present shall be of at least one and one-half hours' duration and the character of training such as may be prescribed by the Secretary of War. Sec. 93. Inspection of the National Guard. — The Secretary of War shall cause an inspection to be made at least once each year by inspectors general, and if necessary by other officers, of the Regular Army, detailed by him for that purpose, to determine whether the amount and condition of the property in the hands of the National Guard is satisfactory; whether the National Guard is organised as hereinbefore prescribed; </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL whether the officers and enlisted men possess the physical and other qual - ifications prescribed; whether the organization and the officers and enlist - ed men thereof are sufficiently armed, uniformed, equipped, and being trained and instructed for active duty in the field or coast defense, and whether the records are being kept in accordance with the requirements of this Act- The reports of such inspections shall serve as the basis for deciding as to the issue to and retention by the National Guard of the military property provided for by this Act, and for determining what or - ganizations and individuals shall be considered as constituting parts of the National Guard within the meaning of this Act. Sec. 94. Encampments and Maneuvers. — Under such regulations as the President may prescribe the Secretary of War is authorized to pro - vide for the participation of the whole or any part of the National Guard in encampments, maneuvers, or other exercises, including outdoor target practice, for field or coast-defense instruction, either independently or in conjunction with any part of the Regular Army, and there may be set aside from the funds appropriated for that purpose and allotted to any State, Territory, or the District of Columbia, such portion of said funds as may be necessary for the payment, subsistence, transportation, and other proper expenses of such portion of the National Guard of such State, Territory, or the District of Columbia as shall participate in such encampments, maneuvers, or other exercises, including outdoor target practice, for field and coast-defense instruction; and the officers and en - listed men of such National Guard while so engaged shall be entitled to the same pay, subsistence, and transportation as officers and enlisted men of corresponding grades of the Regular Army are or hereafter may be en - titled by law. Sec. 35. When any part of the National Guard participates in en - campments, maneuvers, or other exercises, including outdoor target prac - tice, for field or coast-defense instruction at a United States military post, or reservation, or elsewhere, if in conjunction with troops of the United States, the command of such military post or reservation and of the officers and troops of the United States on duty there or elsewhere shall remain with the commander of the United States troops without regard to the rank of the commanding or other officer of the National Guard temporarily engaged in the encampments, maneuvers, or other ex - ercises. Sec. 96. Use of Regular Army Personnel. — The Secretary of War may detail one or more officers and enlisted men of the Regular Army to attend any encampment, maneuver, or other exercise for field or coast defense instruction of the National Guard, who shall give such instruc - tion and information to the officers and men assembled for such encamp - ment, maneuver, or other exercise as may be directed by the Secretary of War or requested by the governor or by the commanding officer of the </seg>
            <seg id="p047">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 47 National Guard there on duty. Sec. 97. Under such regulations as the President may prescribe the Secretary of War may provide camps for the instruction of officers and enlisted men of the National Guard. Such camps shall be conducted by officers of the Regular Army detailed by the Secretary of War for that purpose, and may be located either within or without the State, Territory, or District of Columbia to which the members of the National Guard des - ignated to attend said camps shall belong. Officers and enlisted men at - tending such camps shall be entitled to pay and transportation, and en - listed men to subsistence in addition, at the same rates as for encamp - ments or maneuvers for field or coast-defense instruction. Sec- 98. When any portion of the National Guard shall participate in encampments, maneuvers, or other exercise, including outdoor target practice, for field or coast-defense instruction, under the provisions of this Act, it may, after being duly mustered, be paid at any time after such muster for the period from the date of leaving the home rendezvous to date of return thereto as determined in advance, both dates inclusive; and such payment, if otherwise correct, shall pass to the credit of the disburs - ing officer making the same. Sec. 99. National Guard Officers and Men at Service Schools, and so Forth. — Under such regulations a&amp; the President may prescribe, the Sec - retary of War may, upon the recommendation of the governor of any State or Territory or the commanding general of the National Guard of the District of Columbia, authorize a limited number of selected officers or enlisted men of the National Guard to attend and pursue a regular course of study at any military service school of the United States, ex - cept the United States Military Academy or to be attached to an organ - ization of the same arm, corps, or department to which such officer or enlisted man shall belong, for routine practical instruction at or near an Armj post during a period of field training or other outdoor exercises; and such officer or enlisted man shall receive, out of any National Guard allotment of funds available for the purpose, the same travel allowances and quarters, or commutation of quarters, and the same pay, allowances, and subsistence to which an officer or enlisted man of the Regular Army would be entitled for attending such school, college, or practical course of instruction under orders from proper military authority, while in actual attendance at such school, college, or practical course of instruction: Provided, That in no case shall the pay and allowances authorized by this section exceed those of a captain. Sec 100. Detail of Officers of Regular Army to Duty With the Na - tional Guard.-— The Secretary of War shall detail officers of the active list of the Army to duty with the National Guard in each State, Territory, or District of Columbia, and officers so detailed may accept commissions </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL in the National Guard, with the permission of the President and termi - nable in his discretion, without vacating their commissions in the Regular fmy or being prejudiced in their relative or lineal standing therein, e Secretary of War may, upon like application, detail one or more en - ted men of the Regular Army with each State, Territory, or District Columbia for duty ir connection with the National Guard. But nothing this section shall bo so construed as to prevent the detail of retired icers as now provided by law. Sec. 101. National Guard, When Subject to Laws Governing Regular Army. — The National Guard when called as such into the service of the United States shall, from the time they are required by the terms of the call to respond thereto, be subject to the laws and regulations governing the Regular Army, so far as such laws and regulations are applicable to officers and enlisted men whose permanent retention in the military ser - vice, either on the active list or on the retired list, is not contemplated by existing Ian. Sec- 102. System of Courts-Martial for National Guard. — .Except in organizations in the service of the United States, courts-martial in the National Guard shall be of three kinds, namely, general courts-martial, special courts-martial, and summary courts-martial. They shall be con - stituted like, and have cognizance of the same subjects, and possess like powers, except as to punishments, as similar courts provided for by the laws and regulations governing the Army of the United States, and the proceedings of courts-martial of the National Guard shall follow the forms and modes of procedure prescribed for said similar courts. Sec. 103. General courts-martial of the National Guard not in the service of the United States may be convened by orders of the President, or of the governors of the respective States and Territories, or by the ommanding general of the National Guard of the Distrct of Columbia, and such courts shall have the power to impose fines not exceeding $200; o sentence to forfeiture of pay and allowances; to a reprimand; to dis - missal or dishonorable discharge from the service; to reduction of non - ommissioned officers to the ranks; or any two or more of such pun - shments may be combined in the sentences imposed by such courts. Sec. 104. In the National Guard, not in the service of the United tates, the commanding officer of each garrison, fort, post, camp, or ther place, brigade, regiment, detached battalion, or other detached com - mand, may appoint special courts-martial for his command; but such &gt;ecial courts-martial may in any case be appointed by superior authority when by the latter deemed desirable. Special courts-martial shall have tower to try any person subject to military law, except a commissioned Ticer, for any crime or offense made punishable by the military laws of te United States and such special courts-martial shall have the same </seg>
            <seg id="p049">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 49 powers of punishment as do general courts-martial, except that fines im - posed by such courts shall not exceed $100. Sec. 105. In the National Guard, not in the service of the United States, the commanding officer of each garrison, fort, post, or other place, regiment or corps, detached battalion, company, or other detach - ment of the National Guard may appoint for such place or command a summary court to consist of one officer, who shall have power to ad - minister oaths and to try the enlisted men of such place or command for breaches of discipline and violations of law governing such organizations; and said court, when satisfied of the guilt of such soldier, may impose fines not exceeding $25 for any single offense; may sentence noncommis - sioned officer to reduction to the ranks; may sentence to forfeiture of pay and allowances. The proceedings of such court shall be informal, and the minutes thereof shall be the same as prescribed for summary courts of the Army of the United States. Sec. 106. All courts-martial of the National Guard, not in the service of the United States, including summary courts, shall have power to sen - tence to confinement in lieu of fines authorized to be imposed: Provided, That such sentences of confinement shall not exceed one day for each dol - lar of fine authorized. Sec- 107. No sentence of dismissal from the service or dishonorable discharge, imposed by a National Guard courts-martial, not in the service of the United States, shall be executed until approved by the governor of the State or Territory concerned, or by the commanding general of the National Guard of the District of Columbia. Sec. 108. In the National Guard, not in the service of the United States, presidents of courts-martial and summary court officers shall have power to issue warrants to arrest accused persons and to bring them before the court for trial whenever such persons shall have disobeyed an order in writing from the convening authority to appear before such court, a copy of the charge or charges having been delivered to the accused with such order, and to issue subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum and to en - force by attachment attendance of witnesses and the production of books and papers, and to sentence for a refusal to be sworn or to answer as pro - vided in actions before civil courts. All processes and sentences of said courts shall be executed by such civil officers as may be prescribed by the laws of the several States and Territories, and in any State where no provision shall have been made for such action, and in the Territories and the District of Columbia, such processes and sentences shall be executed by a United States marshal or his duly appointed deputy, and it shall be the duty of any United States marshal to execute all such processes and sentences and make return thereof to the officer issuing or imposing the same. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Sec. 109 PAY FOR THE NATIONAL GUARD OFFICERS— Captains and lieutenants belonging to organizations of the National Guard shall receive compensation at the rate of one-thirtieth of the monthly base pay of their grades as prescribed for the Regular Army for each regu - ar drill or other period of instruction authorized by the Secretary of V'ar, not exceeding five in any one calendar month, at which they shall ■ave been officially present for the entire required period, and at which t least 50 per centum of the commissioned strength and 60 per centum f the enlisted strength attend and participate for not less than one and ne-half hours. Captains commanding organizations shall receive S240 a ear in addition to the drill pay herein prescribed. Officers above the rade of captain shall receive not more than $500 a year, and officers telow the grade of major, not belonging to organizations, shall receive not more than four-thirtieths of the monthly base pay of their grades or satisfactory performance of their appropriate duties under such regu - ations as the Secretary of War may prescribe. Pay under the provisions f this section shall not accrue to any officer during a period when he hall be lawfully entitled to the same pay as an officer of corresponding grade in the Regular Army: PROVIDED, That section 9 of an Act amending the Act entitled "An Act to authorize the President to increase emporarily the Military Establishment of the United States," approved May 18, 1917, approved August 31, 1918, shall also apply to the purchase of uniforms, accouterments, and equipment for cash by officers of the National Guard and National Guard Reserve, whether in State or Feder - al service, on proper identification and under such rules and regulations as the Secretary of War may prescribe. Sec. 110- PAY FOR NATIONAL GUARD ENLISTED MEN.— Each enlisted man belonging to an organization of the National Guard shall re - ceive compensation at the rate of one-thirtieth of the initial monthly pay of his grade in the Regular Army for each drill ordered for his organiza - ion where he is officially present and in which he participates for not ess than one a nd one-half hours, not exceeding eight in any one calendar month, and not exceeding sixty drills in one year: PROVIDED, That no nlisted man shall receive any pay under the provisions of this section for any montih in which he shall have attended leas than 60 per centum of the rills or other exercises prescribed for his organization: PROVIDED FURTHER, That the proviso contained in section 92 of this Act shall not operate to prevent the payment of enlisted men actually present at any duiy ordered drill or other exercise: AND PROVIDED FURTHER, That periods of any actual military duty equivalent to the drills herein pre - scribed (except those periods of service for which members of the Na - tional Guard may become lawfully entitled to the same pay as officers and enlisted men of the corresponding grades in the Regular Army) may be accepted as service in lieu of such drills when so provided by the Sec - retary of War. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 51 All amounts appropriated for the purpose of this and the last preceding section shall be disbursed and accounted for by the officers and agents of the Quartermaster Corps of the Army and all disbursements under the foregoing provisions of this section shall be made as soon as practicable after the thirty-first day of December and the thirtieth day of June of each year upon pay rolls prepared and authenticated in the manner to be prescribed by the Secretary of War: Provided That stoppages may be made against the compensation payable to any officer or enlisted man hereunder to cover the cost of public property lost or destroyed by and chargeable to such officer or enlisted man. Except as otherwise specifically provided herein no money appropriat - ed under the provisions of this or the last preceding section shall be paid to any person not on the active list nor to any person over sixty-four years of age nor to any person who shall fail to qualify as to fitness for military service under such regulations as the Secretary of War shall prescribe nor to any State Territory or District or officer or enlisted man in the National Guard thereof unless and until such State Territory or District provides by law that staff officers including officers of the Pay, Inspection, Subsistence, and Medical Departments, hereafter appointed shall have had previous military experience and shall hold their positions until they shall have reached the age of sixty-four years, unless retired prior to that time by reason of resignation, disability, or for cause to be determined by a court-martial legally convened for that purpose, and that vacancies among said^ officers shall be filled by appointment from the officers of the militia of such State, Territory, or District: Provided further, That the preceding proviso shall not apply to any State, Terri - tory, or District until sixty days next after the adjournment of the next session of its legislature held after the approval of this Act. Sec. 111. NATIONAL GUARD WHEN DRAFTED INTO FEDER - AL SERVICE. — When Congress shall have authorized the use of the armed land forces of the United States for any purpose requiring the use of troops in excess of those of the Regular Army, the President may, under such regulations, including such physical examination, as he may prescribe, draft into military service of the United States, to serve there - in for the period of the war or emergency, unless sooner discharged, any or all members of the National Guard and of the National Guard Reserve. All persons so drafted shall, from the date of their draft, stand discharg - ed from the militia, and shall be subject to auch laws and regulations for he government of the Army of the United States as may be applicable o members of the Army, whose permanent retention in the military ser - vice is not contemplated by law, and shall be organized into units cor - esponding as far as practicable to those of the Regular Army or shall &gt;e otherwise assigned as the President may direct. The commissioned officers of said organizations shall be appointed from among the mem - bers thereof; officers with rank not above that of colonel to be appointed </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL by the President alone, and all other officers to be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Officers and enlisted men while in the service of th United States under the terms of this section shall have the same pay and allowances as officers and enlisted men of the Regular Army of the same grades and the same prior service. On the termination of the emergency all persons so draft - ed shall be discharged from the Army, shall resume their membership in the militia, and, if the State so provide, shall continue to serve in the National Guard until the dates upon which their enlistments entered into prior to their draft, would have expired if uninterrupted. Sec. 112. Rights to Pensions. — When any officer or enlisted man of the National Guard drafted into the Fervice of the United States in time of war is disabled by reason of wounds or disability received or incurred while in the active service of the United States in time of war, he shall )e entitled to all the benefits of the pension laws existing at the time of his service, and in case such officer or enlisted man dies in the active ser - vice of the United States in time of war or in returning to his place of residence after being mustered out of such service, or at any other time in consequence of wounds or disabilities received in such active service, his widow and children, if any, shall be entitled to all the benefits of such pension laws. Sec 113. Encouragement of Rifle Practice. — The Secretary of War shall annually submit to Congress recommendations and estimates for the establishment and maintenance of indoor and outdoor rifle ranges, under such a comprehensive plan as will ultimately result in providing adequate facilities for rifle practice in all sections of the country. And that all ranges so established and all ranges which may have already been constructed, in whole or in part, with funds provided by Congress shall be open for use by those in any branch of the military or naval service of the United States and by all able-bodied males capable of bearing arms, under reasonable regulations to be prescribed by the con - trolling authorities and approved by the Secretary of War. That the President may detail capable officers and noncommissioned officers of the Regular Army and National Guard to duty at such ranges as in - structors for the purpose of training the citizenry in the use of the mili - tia arm. Where rifle ranges shall have been so established anil in - structors assigned to duty thereat, the Secretary of War shall be au - thorized to provide for the issue of a reasonable number of standard military rifles and such quantities of ammunition as may be available for use in conducting such rifle practice. Sec. 114. Stricken out Sec 115- Physical Examination. — Every officer and enlisted man of the National Guard who shall be called into the service of the United States as such shall be examined as to his physical fitness under such </seg>
            <seg id="p053">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 53 regulations as the President may prescribe without further commission or enlistment: Provided, That immediately preceding the muster out of an officer or enlisted man called into the active service of the United States he shall be physically examined under the rules prescribed by the President of the United States, and the record thereof shall be filed and kept in the War Department. Sec. 116. Noncompliance With Federal Act. — Whenever any State shall, within a limit of time to be fixed by the President, have failed or refused to comply with or enforce any requirement of this Act, or any regulation promulgated thereunder and in aid thereof by the President or the Secretary of War, the National Guard of such State shall be de - barred, wholly or in part, as the President may direct, from receiving from the United States any pecuniary or other aid, benefit, or privilege authorized or provided by this Act or any other law. Sec. 117. Applicable to Land Forces Only. The Provisions of this Act in respect to the militia shall be applicable only to militia organ - ized as a land force .and not to the Naval Militia, which shall consist of fuch part of the militia as may be prescribed by the President for each State, Territory, or District: Provided, That each State, Territory, or District maintaining a Naval Militia as herein prescribed may be credited to the extent of the number thereof in the quota that would otherwise be required by Section sixty-two of this Act. Sec. 118. Necessary Rules and Regulations. — The President shall make all necessary rules and regulations and issue such orders a may be necessary for the thorough organization, discipline, and government of the militia provided for in this Act. Sec. 119- Annual Estimates Required. — The Secretary of War shall cause to be estimated annually the amount necessary for carrying out the provisions of so much of this Act as relates to. the militia, ami no money shall be expended under said provisions except as shall from lime to time be appropriated for carrying them out. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL DISBURSEMENTS ON SPANISH-AMERICAN WAR FUND DURING 1919-1920. Elmer G. Woodruff, Co. B, 3rd Regt Check No. 1 $ 33.64 G- A. Barth and only heir of Wm. Barth, Co. A, 3rd Regt. Check No. 2 14.61 Wm. Small, Co. K, 3rd Regt Check No. 3 9.75 Wm. L. Poor, Co. H, 3rd Regt Check No. 4 31.09 Fred L. Paddleford, Co. C, 3rd Regt Check No. 5 4.80 Otis C. Anthony, Co. B, 3rd Regt Check No. 6 15.70 Joseph B. Wilshire, Co. C, 3rd Regt Check No. 7 21.80 Wm. J. Kendall, Co. E, 2nd Regt Check No. 8 3.20 Frank J. Eaton, Co. M, 3rd Re,gt Check No! 9 35.38 George A. Walker, Co. A, 3rd Regt Check No. 10 14.61 Claude Barnell, Co. A, 2nd Regt Check No. 11 3.20 Total $ 187.78 Certificate of Deposit in Lincoln State Bank $ 1,560.00 Certificates of Deposit in American State Bank 1,560.00 Certificate of Deposit in Continental State Bank 1,560.00 Total $ 4,680.00 Amount of original Spanish-American War Fund $31,196.10 Still due and unpaid to Spanish War Veterans 5,987.05 Cash on hand in checking account 1,702.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 55 SPANISH WAR FUND The following is a list of unpaid claims due soldiers who participated in the service of the Spanish-American War in the First, Second, and Third Nebraska Volunteer Regiments and Troop K, Third Volunteer Cavalry: COMPANY A— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Bye, Joseph G $3.20 Pvt. Kelly, Charles R 3.20 Cpl. Glover, John A 320 Pvt. Keefe, Wm. F 3.20 Pvt. Allen, Roller C 3.20 Pvt. Morgenstern, Henry A. 3.20 Pvt. Buri, George J. 3.20 Pvt. Shively, Bion 3.20 Pvt. Freeman, Charlie O 3.20 Pvt. Gelvin, Robert N 3.20 Pvt. Hensley, Minor N 3.20 Pvt. Kremer, Cochron A. „. 4.00 Pvt. Sommers, Nels J 3.20 Pvt. Turner, Robert W. 3.20 Pvt. Wompler, Elmer B. ... 3.20 COMPANY B— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Doe Pvt. Garinger, Albert $0.80 Pvt. Irwin, Benjamin 4.00 Pvt- Andrews, Chas. J. 4.00 Pvt. Killhom, Perry A. 4.00 Pvt. Black, John 4.00 Pvt. Resseguie, Herbert L 4.00 Pvt. Grainier, Louis I 1.60 COMPANY C— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Doe Pvt. Johnson, Hans $3-20 Pvt. Campbell, Roy G. 3.20 Pt. Brownell, Mike 3.20 Pvt. Dringman, Will F. 3.20 COMPANY D— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name " Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Alley, John S $4.00 Pvt. Hawes, Fred M. 4.00 Pvt. Berger, Harry A- 4.00 Pvt. Kosharek, John 4.00 Pvt. Fitchie, Samuel B. 4.00 Pvt. Bloom, John J 4.0© COMPANY E— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Land, Noah B. $1.60 Pvt. Bays, Wm. .80 Pvt. Amerman, Arba B. 1.60 Pvt. Blackburn, Wm. C 3.20 Pvt. Dunning, Benj. F 3.20 Pvt Duvall, Frank 3.20 Pvt Bliss, Henry 3.20 Pvt. Gilham, Wm. H. 1.60 Pvt. Moffett, Jesse C 3.20 Pvt. Lisko, Jack G $3.20 Pvt Pecinovsky, Joseph W 3.20 Pvt Prokop, Joseph A. 3.20 Pvt. Scott, Sampel G. 3.20 Pvt. Thomas, Harry H. 3-20. </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY F— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Rank Name Amt. Due Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt. Gallagher, Joseph P $3.20 Sgt. Gallagher, Joseph P $3.20 Pvt. Folkner, Horace L. 3.20 Pvt. Folkner, Horace L. 3.20 Cpl. Cpl. Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Sims, Arthur C 3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvin W. 3.20 Pvt. Gilbert, Alvin W. 3.20 Cpl. Hunting, Walter J. 3.20 Cpl. Hunting, Walter J. 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E 3.20 Pvt. Hanson, Chas. E 3.20 Cpl. Cpl. Marsh, Pierce D. 3.20 Marsh, Pierce D. 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua 3.20 Pvt. Hightower, Joshua 3.20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Cpl. Fell, Joseph G 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt. Kesney, John D 3.20 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 320 Pvt. Brown, Lewis 320 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E. 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Dennis E. 3.20 Pvt. Corey, Chas. H. 3.20 Pvt. Corey, Chas. H. 3.20 Pvt. Olson, Alfred 3 20 Pvt. Olson, Alfred 3 20 Pvt. Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Curas, Frederick L 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F. 3.20 Pvt. Porter, Wm. F. 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Davidson, Houston 3.20 Davidson, Houston 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Webb, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D. _. 3.20 Pvt. Dohrman, Henry D. .. 3.20 COMPANY G— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Sgt. Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Burlington, John 3.20 Anderson, Hugh B.___ 80 Deaver, Harvey W. 3.20 Dowis, Johnathan E 3.20 Merryman, John R 3.20 Pvt. Mohler, Chas. E. 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Underwood, Henry C__ 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Guy C 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Wm. P 3.20 COMPANY H— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Rank Name Amt. Due Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Andrews, Ernst H $3.20 Andrews, Ernst H $3.20 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L. 3.20 Pvt. Reed, Chas. L. 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Pvt. Brisbine, Lewis H. $2.40 Brisbine, Lewis H. $2.40 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C- 4.00 Pvt. Renfrow, Peter C- 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, .Eugene M. 4.00 Pvt. Dawson, .Eugene M. 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Robbins, Rees 4.00 Pvt. Hoover, Chauncey J. _. 1.60 Pvt. Hoover, Chauncey J. __ 1.60 Pvt. Smith, George J. 4.00 Pvt. Smith, George J. 4.00 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W. 1-60 Pvt. Hunt, Geo. W. 1-60 Pvt. Sutton, Roy O. 1.60 Pvt. Sutton, Roy O. 1.60 Pvt. Pvt. Downing, Edward S 4.00 Downing, Edward S 4.00 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Seeley, F. Homer 2.40 Pvt. Mansker, James F. 3.20 Mansker, James F. 3.20 Pvt. Thompson, George E 3.20 Pvt. Thompson, George E 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Winagel, Authony J 2.40 Pvt. Mengler, Frank 80 Pvt. Mengler, Frank 80 Pvt. Winagel, Authony J 2.40 Pvt. Pvt. Peterson, Hans C. 4.00 Peterson, Hans C. 4.00 COMPANY I— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Rank Name Amt. Due Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Jeon, John M. 4.00 Pvt. Jeon, John M. 4.00 Cpl. Cpl. Sobotka, Frank $4.00 Sobotka, Frank $4.00 Mus. Hotsell, Leon V. 4.00 Mus. Hotsell, Leon V. 4.00 Pvt. Jones, Oliver J. 4.00 Pvt. Jones, Oliver J. 4.00 Pvt. Lightner, Lewis C- — _ 4.00 Pvt. Pvt. Berndtson, John E. 4.00 Berndtson, John E. 4.00 Pvt. Lightner, Lewis C- — _ 4.00 Pvt McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Pvt Bordwell, Frank J. 4.00 Bordwell, Frank J. 4.00 Pvt McFry, Albert 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Pvt Frazier, Clark W. 4.00 Frazier, Clark W. 4.00 Pvt. Miller, Wm. D 4.00 Pvt. Fricke, Albert W. 400 Pvt. Fricke, Albert W. 400 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 Pvt. Passmore, Lewis D 4.00 Pvt. Gregg, Edwin F. 4.00 Pvt. Gregg, Edwin F. 4.00 COMPANY K— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Delong, Herbert B $320 Pvt. Smith, Robert L $3.20 Pvt. Crittenden, David L. -. 3.20 Pvt. Swanson, August 4.00 Pvt. Fingado, Harry, Jr 4.00 Pvt. Wilson, Chas. F. 320 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 57 Pvt. Schmeider, Wm. G. 320 Pvt. Witsch, Max N. 3 23 COMPANY L— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dae Pvt. Downs, James W $3.20 Pvt. Legg, Marvin O. 3 20 Pvt Green, Fred L 320 Pvt. Taylor, Fred 3.20 Pvt. Humphrey, Mortimer B. 3.20 Pvt. Whitaker, Robert H. .. 3.20 COMPANY M— FIRST REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Spence, Monroe W $3.20 Pvt. Coons, Chas. J 3.20 Cpl. Rucker, Winifred L. ___ 3.20 Pvt. Jack, Cecil B. 3.20 Pvt Coxson, Alvin A. 3.20 Pvt. Kennedy, Phillip S 3.20 FIELD AND STAFF— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae P. M. Brown, Robert S $4.00 Mus. Murnhouse, F. Edd 4.00 COMPANY A— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Dobbins, Myles R. $3.20 Cpl. Cupernell, Ernest H. __ 3.20 Cpl. White, James E. .. 3.20 Art. Devinney, Harry M 3.20 Cpl. Paine, Lewis A. 3.20 Pvt. Blough, Clay C. $3.20 Pvt. Carman, Chas. S 3.20 Pvt. Charles, Alfred W 3.20 Pvt. Marks, Raymond H. 3.20 Pvt. Miller, Ned K 320 Pvt. Mott, Mathew 3.20 Pvt. Coppom, Ole G. 3.20 Pvt. Packwood, Arthur T. ._ 3.20 Pvt. Cornell, George S. 3.20 Pvt. Tuffs, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Dwyer, Patrick 3.20 Pvt. White, Wm. A. 3-20 Pvt. Forman, David A. 3.20 Pvt. Harrold, Harry R. 3.20 Pvt. Walker, Ollie 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Alfred 3.20 Pvt. Kearney, William 3.20 Pvt. Woodruff, Charles 3.20 COMPANY B— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Frink, Alberto D. $3.20 Pvt. Jackson, Wm. 3.20 Cpl- Whitmer, James K. 3.20 Pvt. Minnich, Herbert J 3.20 Wag. Crow, Wallace H. 3.20 Pvt. Robinson, George A. .__ 3 20 Art Grossett, Chas. E. 3.20 Pvt. Smith, Frank 3.20 Pvt Beebe, Chas. E- 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Charley 3.20 Pvt. Williams, Frank 3.20 Pvt. Briggs, Ernest G. Pvt Wilson, Eli A. 3.20 (Died in service) 3.20 Pvt. Cox, Wm. A. 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY C— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. PueRank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Miles, George $3.20 Pvt. Kjellidin, Larsh A. 3.20 Cpl. Spencer, Hiram C. 1.60 Pvt. Burnham, Irwin C. 3.20 Pvt. Christianson, Edw. R— 3.20 Pvt. Church, John H. 160 Pvt. Lee, Ira E. 3.20 Pvt. Leon, Victor C 1.60 Pvt. McLain, Clarence E. 1.60 Pvt. Peterson, Peter 1.60 Pvt. Clark, Wm. B. 3 20 Pvt. Roddy, John H 3.20 Pvt. Hadley, Wm. B. 1.60 Pvt. Shanklin, Sylvester ... 1.60 Pvt. Kime, David 1.60 COMPANY D— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Ant. Due Pvt. Allen, Chas. A $4.00 Pvt. Allen, Chas. A $4.00 Pvt. Churchwell, Meridith L. 4 00 Pvt. Churchwell, Meridith L. 4 00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R. _.. 4.00 Pvt. Anderson, Albert R. _.. 4.00 Pvt French, John C. 3.20 Pvt. French, John C. 3.20 Pvt. Hastings, Bert $4.00 Pvt. Hastings, Bert $4.00 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E. 4.00 Pvt. Mager, Clarence E. 4.00 Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 Pvt. Ludwick, George L 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R- 4.00 Pvt. Pickens, Walter R. 4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T. 4.00 Pvt. Lloyd, Wm. T. 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M... 4.00 Pvt. Semmebroth, Emil M-. 4.00 COMPANY E— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Hank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Andrews, Nick $3.20 Cpl. Andrews, Nick $3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J. 3.20 Pvt. Keen, Robert J. 3.20 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Art. Wiese, Herman 2.40 Pvt. Krajicek, John 3.20 Pvt. Krajicek, John 3.20 Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W- __ 3.20 Pvt. Alexander, Chas. W- __ 3.20 Pvt. Means, James A 3-20 Pvt. Means, James A 3-20 Pvt. Cooper, Clarence 3.20 Pvt. Cooper, Clarence 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Thomas 3.20 Pvt. Dahlem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout, John H. 3.20 Pvt. Dahlem, Henry W 3.20 Pvt. Osterhout, John H. 3.20 Pvt. Drewing, John B 3.20 Pvt. Drewing, John B 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E. 3.20 Pvt. Stroud, Ivan E. 3.20 Pvt. Frame, George W. 3.20 Pvt. Frame, George W. 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Edward J 3.20 Pvt. Vandervort, Samuel M._ 3.20 Pvt. Vandervort, Samuel M._ 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Edward J 3.20 COMPANY F— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt Due Pvt. Boggs, Thomas W. ... $3.20 Pvt. Hall, James H 320 Pvt. Grofton, George 3.20 Pvt. Mitchell, Harry D 4.80 Pvt. Goodwill, Louis M 3.20 Pvt. Wilson, Nelson P. 320 COMPANY G — SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 2nd Lt. Hodgins, Eli $3.20 2nd Lt. Hodgins, Eli $3.20 Pvt. Horn, George L., Jr.,__ 3.20 Pvt. Horn, George L., Jr.,— 3.20 Gpl. Hays, Robert A. 3.20 Gpl. Hays, Robert A. 3.20 Pvt. Hugh, Harry .80 Pvt. Hugh, Harry .80 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Cpl. Morrison, Max 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T. .80 Pvt. Johnson, Martin T. .80 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 320 Cpl. Turcot, Eugene 320 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S .80 Pvt. Lininger, Wilber S .80 Pvt Blenkiron, Harry V. .80 Pvt Blenkiron, Harry V .80 Pvt. McFarland, Samuel F._ -80 Pvt. McFarland, Samuel F._ .80 Pvt. Burnham, Marshall H. Pvt- Burnham, Marshall H., Jr. 3.20 Pvt. Neucomb, Frank S 3.20 Pvt Neucomb, Frank S 3.20 Jr. 3.20 Pvt. Newton, William 3.20 Pvt. Newton, William 3.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 59 Pvt. Deyerall, Ralph HI .80 Pvt. Packard, Hugh M. 3-20 Pvt. Quimby, Lucien E .80 Pvt. Fisher, Leo .80 Pvt. Ritter, David .80 Pvt. Gainey, John H. .8a Pvt. Thompson, Eddie D .80 COMPANY H— SECOND REGIMENT Pvt- Johnston, George H 4.00 Cpl. Borland, John A $4.00 Art. Neill, John W. 4.00 Pvt. Logan, Alvah 4.00 Mus. Ray, Stanley T. 4.00 Pvt. Meitner, Joseph 4.00 Pvt Bowers, Henry H. 4.00 Pvt. Nelson, John 4.00 Pvt. Boyd, Wm. J 4.00 Pvt. Olinger, Joseph 4.00 Pvt. Davis, Harry E. 4.00 Pvt. Perry, Herbert N. 4.00 Pvt. Ditzler, Al 4.00 Pvt. Serensen ,Ole C. 4.00 Pvt. Gillespie, David E. 4.00 Pvt. Tucker, Harry 0 4.00 Pvt. Hershey, Will L. 4.00 Pvt. Whitney, John A 400 COMPANY I— SECOND REGIMENT QM Sgt Rainey, Jacob A $4.00 Pvt. Penland, John W. .80 Cpl. Giblin, John S. 4-00 Pvt. Schooler, John H 4.00 Pvt. Evans, Fletcher 4.00 Pvt. Schuelke, Herman A — 4-00 Pvt. Hamill, Oscar 4.00 Pvt. Thompson, Theodore .- 4.00 Pvt. Walker, Joseph H 4.00 Pvt. Humpal, John J. 4.00 Pvt. Way, Rueben D 4.00 COMPANY K— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Erickson, Francis T $3.20 Pvt. West, Charles 3-20 Cpl. Hill, John T. 3.20 COMPANY L— SECOND REGIMENT Cpl. Jack, Charles H $2.40 Cpl. Kohout, Frank W. 4.00 Pvt. Clarenden, Alvin T 4.00 Pvt. Evans, John 3.20 Pvt. Johnson, John 3.20 Cpl. Sage, John M. 3.20 Cpl. Wellman, Frank P 3.20 Wag. Bauman, John P 4.00 Art. Carter, Charles J 3.20 Pvt. Leonard, Wm. C .80 Pvt. Powell, Joseph A. 3.20 Pvt. Rainey, Wm. N 3.20 Pvt. Abel, Louis 3.20 Pvt. Sloan, John H. 2.40 Pvt. Anderson, Nels J- 3.20 Pvt Smith, George W 1.60 Pvt. Collins, James R 3.20 Pvt- Wilson, Thomas B. 1.60 Pvt Cottrell, Eugene W 3.20 COMPANY M— SECOND REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name . Amt. Due Cpl. Wiggins, Frank E. $5.60 Pvt Payne, Wesley R. 6-40 Wag. Alfreds, Frank H 5.60 Pvt. Schwart, Wm. 5.60 Pvt. Londlodge, Henry W — 5.60 Pvt Steele, Duncan C. 5.60 Pvt- Drake, Henry L .80 Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae Pvt. Jenkins, Frank 4.00 Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL FIELD STAFF AND BAND— THIRD REGIMENT RB Mus Henderson, Roy D $ 9.60 RB Mus Parkhurst, Harry C. 3.20 RB Mus Lyon, Harry C 1-60 RB Mus Wells, Richard L._ 12.00 COMPANY A— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Bank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W..$3255 QM Sgt. Bridenthal, C. W._$3255 Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 Pvt. Lee, Leonard 4.80 Cpl. Ford, John J 5.60 Cpl. Ford, John J 5.60 Pvt. McDonald, Geo. A 4.00 Pvt. Marksbury, Thomas N- 1.60 Pvt. McDonald, Geo. A 4.00 Cpl- Steinbach, George 12.72 Cpl. Steinbach, George 12.72 Cpl. Ross, Matthew __ 1.60 Mas. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. Marksbury, Thomas N- 1.60 Cpl. Ross, Matthew 1.60 Pvt. Michael, Wm. 14.61 Pvt. Michael, Wm. 14.61 Mas. Miller, Wilson N 2.40 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Rader, Joseph 2.40 Mus. Lenker, Chas. 2.40 Mus. Lenker, Chas. 2.40 Pvt. O'Leary, John J. :_ 2.40 Pvt. O'Leary, John J. :_ 2.40 Art. Ball, Wm. A 18.39 Art Ball, Wm. A 18.39 Pvt. Pace, Perle R. 2.40 Pvt. Pace, Perle R. 2.40 Pvt Allen, Thomas 480 Pvt Allen, Thomas 480 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Pvt. Philpott, Tyra A 1.60 Pvt. Avery, John S. 1.60 Pvt. Avery, John S. 1.60 Pvt. Pierce, Frank W. 10.84 Pvt Reynolds, John A 1.60 Pvt. Pierce, Frank W. 10.84 Pvt Bliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt Bliss, Gottle 1.60 Pvt. Reynolds, John A 1.60 Pvt. Collins, John H. 1.60 Pvt. Collins, John H. 1.60 Pvt. Schneider, Wm. 2.40 Pvt. Schneider, Wm. 2.40 Pvt. Gallenbuck, Prank _J._ 1.60 Pvt. Gallenbuck, Frank _J._ 1.60 Pvt. Smith, John J. 1.60 Pvt. Smith, John J. 1.60 Pvt Strough, George W 4.00 Pvt. Gray, Burton E 2.40 Pvt. Gray, Burton E 2.40 Pvt Strough, George W 4.00 Pvt Horahan, Chas 5.60 Pvt Horahan, Chas 5.60 Pvt. Taylor, James J. 240 Pvt. Taylor, James J. 240 Pvt Hinckley, John S. 1.60 Pvt Hinckley, John S. 1.60 Pvt. Trombly, Warden, F A 18.39 Pvt. Trombly, Warden, F A 18.39 Pvt. Hurst, Arthur J. 1.60 Pvt. Hurst, Arthur J- 1.60 Pvt. Wolf, Chas. T. 2.40 Pvt. Wolf, Chas. T. 2.40 Pvt Koontz, Edmund J. ._ 2.40 Pvt Koontz, Edmund J. ._ 2.40 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr._ 2.40 Pvt. Zarbock, Herman, Jr._ 2.40 Pvt Kucera, Frank 17.44 Pvt Kucera, Frank 17.44 COMPANY B— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due QM Sgt Covell, Herbert E._$33.64 QM Sgt Covell, Herbert E-$33.64 Pvt Mungoran, Peter 3.20 Pvt. Mungoran, Peter 3.20 Sgt. Spencer, Chas. L- 33.64 Sgt. Spencer, Chas. L- 33.64 Pvt. McGrew, Frank .80 Pvt. McGrew, Frank .80 Pvt. Kinley, William H 33.64 Sgt. Hawkins, Harry 15.70 Sgt. Hawkins, Harry 15.70 Pvt. Kinley, William H 33.64 Wag. Palmer, James H. 32.69 Wag. Palmer, James H. 32.69 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W 33.64 Pvt. McMillan, Daniel W 33.64 Pvt. O'Shea, Howard 18.53 Pvt. Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt Bowers, Leslie L 3.20 Pvt. O'Shea, Howard 18.53 Pvt. Bradford, George H .80 Pvt. Bradford, George H .80 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H. 33.64 Pvt. Peterson, Paul H. 33.64 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas .80 Pvt. Clancy, Thomas .80 Pvt. Place, John F 21.36 Pvt. Place, John F 21.36 Pvt Custer, Elisha .80 Pvt Custer, Elisha .80 Pvt. Ray, Evert P. 20.42 Pvt. Ray, Evert P. 20.42 Pvt Francisco, John H. .80 Pvt Francisco, John H. .80 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust 33.64 Pvt. Rickenburg, Gust 33.64 Pvt Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt Gasser, Joseph 2.40 Pvt. Roop, Scott D .80 Pvt. Roop, Scott D .80 Pvt Greenlee, William 3.20 Pvt Greenlee, William 3.20 Pvt. Sawyer, Ernest E. 33.64 Pvt Schwartz, Wm. .80 Pvt. Sawyer, Ernest E. 33.64 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Gross, William 3.20 Pvt. Schwartz, Wm. .80 Pvt. Habbick, George W- __ 1.60 Pvt. Habbick, George W- __ 1.60 Pvt. Swanson, Albert N .80 .] Pvt. Swanson, Albert N .80 Pvt Jarvis, Chas. T .80 Pvt Jarvis, Chas. T .80 Pvt. Torrence, LeRoy E 33.64 Pvt. Torrence, LeRoy E 33.64 Pvt Keanes, James N .80 Pvt Keanes, James N .80 Pvt. Ward, William R -80 Pvt. Ward, William R -80 Pvt Line, Jno. M. 17.59 Pvt Line, Jno. M. 17.59 Pvt Whalen, Edwin F. 3.2&amp; Pvt. Whalen, Edwin F. 3.20 Pvt Metts, Edmond M .80 Pvt Metts, Edmond M .80 I </seg>
            <seg id="p061">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 61 COMPANY C— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Rank Name Amt. Due Amt. Due 1st Sgt. White, Thomas R..$27.46 Cpl. Bailey, Frank C 22.74 Cpl. Dillion, Samuel H. 27.46 Pvt. Hileman, Robert E.— 27.46 Pvt. Howell, Harry H. 22.74 Pvt. Keliher, John F 4.80 Cpl. Sydow, Emil 27.46 Pvt. Long, Wilber W. 5.75 Cpl. Miller, William E. 27.46 Pvt. McCall, William J 2.40 Cpl. Burkett, Harry B. 2.40 Pvt. Mitchell, Edward F 2.40 Wag. Clayburg, Elmer 27.46 Pvt. Norton, Ernest H 11.41 Mus. Eberhart, Chas. E 2.40 Pvt. Paul, Henry C. 2.40 Art. Freeman, Nathan W... 27.46 Pvt. Sheil, Daniel J 7.64 Pvt. Breeehwald, Philip __ 2.40 Pvt. Seek, John A. 2.40 Pvt. Costelloe, Michael F— 13.30 Pvt. Stolze, Fred 22.74 Pvt. Strupp, Henry F. 2.40 Pvt. Collins, Bernard P 8.58 Pvt. DeRivieres, Francis L. 4.80 Pvt. Swanson, Oscar 2.40 Pvt. Dobbins, Albert 2.40 Pvt. Taylor, Edward 480 Pvt. Farrell, James 2.40 Pvt. Vernon, George A 12.36 Pvt. Henske, Fred .80 Pvt. Wahlstrom, Albin F... 2.40 Pvt. Hawkins, Elgrin C 8.58 Pvt. Zurubsky, James 7-64 Pvt. Henry, William 2.40 COMPANY D— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Reynolds, Walter D—. $4.80 Pvt. Jansen, Nels P. 23.91 Sgt. Sgt. Dennett, Albert G $29.57 Pvt. Juul, John M. 30.52 Cpl. Abernathy, Fred B 26.74 Pvt. Jones, Lewis C. .80 Cpl. Christensen, Pvt. Kregersen, Henry 22.96 Christian A. 36.18 Pvt. Landsbury, Harry 1.60 Cpl. McDowell, Wm. G 29.57 Pvt. Lundell, Ernest 480 Cpl. Asbough, Albert L 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Chas. M. 8.00 Mus. Howel, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Nelson, Ivan G. 8.00 Pvt. Allwein, John C. 1.60 Pvt. Oelsen, Andrew 36.18 Pvt. Anderson, Edward 4.00 Pvt. Pool, John E- 4S0 Pvt. Pollock, Mak 2.40 Pvt. Anderson, Andrew 3.20 Pvt. Rief, Ralph S 4.80 Pvt. Bandy, John W 1.60 Pvt. Carlson, Albert 29.57 Pvt. Robie, Ernest 4.80 Pvt. Flor, Sigurd 8.80 Pvt. Sutton, Frank E. 6.40 Hamilton, James 3.20 Pvt. Warren, Walter H. _. - 6.40 Pvt. Pvt. Hope, Daniel 4.00 Pvt. Wiederholz, John J 28.63 COMPANY E— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Pvt. Nearly, Chas. A. 28.12 Sgt. Siddell, Bert E. $13.01 Pvt. Anderson, Claude 4.00 Pvt. Pardew, Avery A 20.56 Pvt. Flenniken, Robert B— 13.96 Pvt. Harrison, Chas. A. _._ 13.96 Pvt. Reinbolt, Fred .80 Pvt. Smith, Fred S 22.45 Pvt. Hays, John S 28.12 Pvt. Van Epps, Bert L .80 Pvt. Lewin, Samuel C. .80 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 62 COMPANY F— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Sweet, Clarence A. $36-69 Cpl. Wilburn, Claude A. ._ 36.69 Cpl. Sweet, Clarence A. $36-69 Pvt. Kment, Joe 1.60 Pvt- Kment, Joe 1.60 Cpl. Wilburn, Claude A. ._ 36.69 Pvt. Knott, Fred .80 Pvt. Knott, Fred .80 Art. Becker, Otto 36.69 Art. Becker, Otto 36.69 Pvt Loss, Isaac 1 36.69 Pvt. Loss, Isaac J 36.69 Pvt Baughman, Charles — 2.40 Pvt. Baughman, Charles — 2.40 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Manzel, Charles 36.69 Pvt Brunker, Frank 1.60 Pvt. Brunker, Frank 1.60 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J. 1.60 Pvt. Miller, Thomas J. 1.60 Pvt Elm, William 36.69 Pvt. Elm, William 36.69 Pvt Nicholson, James T.__ 1-60 Pvt. Nicholson, James T.__ 1-60 Pvt. Esplin, Lucius 36.69 Pvt. Esplin, Lucius 36.69 Pvt. Olson, Chris .80 Pvt. Olson, Chris .80 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Gage, Elmer 6.40 Pvt. Olsen, Lars P. 36.69 Pvt. Olsen, Lars P. 36.69 Pvt. Hayes, John C. 8.80 Pvt. Hayes, John C. 8.80 Pvt. Owens, Victor L. .80 Pvt. Owens, Victor L. .80 Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Head, Charles 36.69 Pvt Phillips, George W_._ 1.60 Pvt. Phillips, George W_._ 1.60 Pvt. Hon, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Hon, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Saare, Alfred H. .80 Pvt. Saare, Alfred H. .80 Pvt. Houdek, Charles 1.60 Pvt. Houdek, Charles 1.60 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Sramek, Anton 1.60 Pvt. Hudec, William 3.20 Pvt. Hudec, William 3.20 Pvt Underhill, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Underhill, Charles 36.69 Pvt. Johns, Olvey 0 .80 Pvt. Johns, Olvey 0 .80 Pvt. Whyte, Wm. M -80 Pvt. Whyte, Win. M -80 Pvt Johnson, Wm. L. 36.69 Pvt. Johnson, Wm. L. 36.69 Pvt. Woods, Thomas J. 3.20 Pvt. Woods, Thomas J. 3.20 Pvt Karges, John 36.69 Pvt Karges, John 36.69 COMPANY G— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Rank Name Amt. Due Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt Burnett, Hamilton H._ 29.72 Sgt Burnett, Hamilton H._ 29.72 Pvt. Fuller, Guy W. 1.60 Pvt. Fuller, Guy W. 1.60 Cpl. Larson, Felix G 2972 Cpl. Larson, Felix G 2972 Pvt. Howard, Edward 29.72 Pvt. Howard, Edward 29.72 Cpl. Collins, Wilke S. 29.72 Cpl. Collins, Wilke S. 29.72 Pvt. Jones, Frank 2972 Pvt. Jones, Frank 2972 Pvt. Arnold, Isaac C 21.72 Pvt. Arnold, Isaac C 21.72 Pvt. Knapp, Willie R. 29.72 Pvt. Knapp, Willie R. 29.72 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Pvt. Berg, Axel 1.60 Pvt. Larson, Axel W. 29.72 Pvt. Larson, Axel W. 29.72 Pvt. Brower, Bertie M- 29.72 Brower, Bertie M- 29.72 Pvt. Pvt. Lehman, Albert 29.72 Pvt. Lehman, Albert 29.72 Pvt. Burke, Frank J. 29.72 Pvt. Burke, Frank J. 29.72 Pvt. Lehman, Paul 29.72 Pvt. Lehman, Paul 29.72 Pvt. Burnett, Marcus V 3.20 Pvt. Burnett, Marcus V 3.20 Pvt. Meade, Frank 29.72 Pvt. Meade, Frank 29.72 Pvt. Bowerman, William F- 4.80 Pvt. Bowerman, William F- 4.80 Pvt. Morton, Frank H. 29.72 Pvt. Morton, Frank H. 29.72 Pvt Carter, Wm. H. 29.72 Pvt. Carter, Wm. H. 29.72 Pvt. O'Connor, William 4.00 Pvt. O'Connor, William 4.00 Pvt Conner, Clement T 29.72 Conner, Clement T 29.72 Pvt. Pvt Pickard, Harry M. -- 29.72 Pvt. Pickard, Harry M. -- 29.72 Pvt. Durham, Miller L 29.72 Pvt. Durham, Miller L 29.72 Pvt- Reap, Warren A. 29.72 Pvt- Reap, Warren A. 29.72 Pvt. Ferguson, Isaac .80 Pvt Ferguson, Isaac .80 Pvt. Ryan, William 29.72 Pvt. Ryan, William 29.72 Pvt Forsman, Oscar ■_ 29.72 Pvt. Forsman, Oscar :_ 29.72 COMPANY H— THIRD REGIMENT Bank Bank Name Amt. Due Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt Sgt Lytel, James L. $ 4.80 Lytel, James L. $ 4.80 Pvt Moyer, George E. __. i_ 5.60 Pvt. Moyer, George E. __^_ 5.60 Cpl. Cpl. Barber, LeRoy M. 31.09 Barber, LeRoy M. 31.09 Pvt. Robinson, Edward 3.20 Pvt Robinson, Edward 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Edwards, Wm. A 29.20 Edwards, Wm. A 29.20 Pvt. Robinson, Andrew M._ 3.20 Pvt. Robinson, Andrew M._ 3.20 Pvt. Headwell, Axel 31.09 Pvt. Smith, Edson J. 31.09 Pvt. Headwell, Axel 31.09 Pvt. Smith, Edson J. 31.09 Pvt. Jackman, Wm. N. 6.55 Jackman, Wm. N. 6.55 Pvt. Thomas, James T. 3.20 Pvt. Thomas, James T. 3.20 Pvt. Pvt. Keever, Oscar W 1316 Keever, Oscar W 1316 Pvt. Williams, Edgar T 31.09 Pvt. Williams, Edgar T 31.09 Pvt. Pvt Pvt. Laurine, Edward A 31.09 Laurine, Edward A 31.09 Pvt. Matson, Albert 660 Pvt Matson, Albert 660 Pvt ieichty, John 6.55 Pvt Leichty, John 6.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 63 COMPANY I— THIRD REGIMENT Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Dae Derienger, George —$36.61 Pvt. Lewis, Charles E. 4.80 Sgt. Set. Waterman, Harry D. S. 37.56 Pvt. Marqwadt, Fred W 1.60 Cpl. Porter, James Hall 37.56 Pvt. Masters, Rollie E. 9.24 Cpl. Dickenson, John W.-_ 12.07 Pvt. Miller, Fred S. 9.24 Cpl- Felts, William B. 6.40 Pvt. Morris, Benjamin F.__ 9.24 Cpl. Jensen, Chris M. 4.00 Pvt. Morrow, Edmond 4.00 Cpl. Meyer, Otto $ 4.00 Pvt. Padol, Adam .80 Wag. Brott, Zina H. 22.45 Pvt. Perry, Chas. E. 11.12 Art. Shepardson, Benj. W._ 23.40 Pvt. Phillips, Ellis J 3.20 Pvt. Aitken, George F 37.56 Pvt. Potter, Forrest A 9.24 Pvt. Baird, Francis H 4.80 Pvt- Palmer, Archibald G._ 5.60 Bersley, Wm. G 31.89 Pvt. Ray, Warren Hopkins. 2.40 Pvt. Pvt. Brown, Frank H. 4.00 Pvt. Roberts, James W 9.24 Pvt. Carroll, John W 400 Pvt. Selby, Arthur L 9.24 Pvt. Center, Albert 4.80 Pvt. Starky, Cyrus 37.56 Dinsmore, Claude R 9.24 Pvt. Pvt. Stohe, John G 4-00 Pvt. Dubee, Alexander 3.20 Pvt. Sutton, Chas. O 12.07 Pvt. Fairchild, Homer 1.60 Pvt. Swan, Richard B. 80 Pvt. Guthercole, Fred A_-_ 4.00 Pvt. Unger, Edward W. 4.00 Pvt. Hackler, David D 1.60 Pvt. Vandyke, John T. 6.40 Pvt Hanks, Harry E. 1.60 Pvt. Vandyke, Sherman 6.40 Houston, Homer S. __- 6.40 Pvt. Pvt. Walrath, David A 80 Pvt. Houghs, Chas. L- 4.00 Pvt Warner, Archie A. 1.60 Hutchinson, Albert D._ 1.60 Pvt. Pvt. Warrington. Albert J._ 2.40 Pvt. Jones, Lloyd O 4.00 COMPANY K— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due 1st Sgt. Jacobsen, Carl L $34.29 Pvt. Kruger, Wm. .80 Cpl. Fountain, Francis N 3429 Pvt. Matthews, Stanley ___ 30.52 Cpl. Abbott, Cyrus A 28.63 Pvt. McCaulley, Wm. G 1-60 Pvt. Anderson, Oliver 34.29 Pvt. Meade, Wm. B 3.20 Pvt. Arnold, Otto H .80 Pvt. Mines, James S 1.60 Pvt. Cofield, Chester A 11.64 Pvt. Colford, Charles R 13.52 Pvt. Painter, Wm. C 2.40 Pvt. Porterfield, James R._. 34.29 Pvt. Gray, Lyman 3.20 Pvt. Reardon, Patrick J $ 2.40 Pvt. Gress, Henry C. 14.47 Pvt. Roff. John L 29.57 Pvt. Hare, Howard W. 3429 Pvt. Smith. Albert L. 34.29 Pvt Hanbrock, Edward H._ 34.29 Pvt Hightower, Harry A — 2.40 Pvt Hurford, Frederick L.. 29.57 Pvt Kennedy, George H.__ 7.20 Pvt Snider, Charles 3.20 Pvt Stamp, Samuel 1.60 Pvt. Thompson, James B... 3.20 Pvt. Van Sickle, Cyrus 1.60 Pvt. Kankright, Clinton D._ 27.68 Pvt. Williams, Wm. M- 1.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL COMPANY L— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Cpl. Brown, Cleveland W $ 7.20 Pvt. Kelley, Robert S. 6.40 Cpl. Nicholson, Chas. J 4.00 Pvt. Kritsch, Herman 6.40 Cpl. Lowe, Walter 8.00 Pvt. Kropp, Charles 3.20 Cpl. Taft, Charles C 21.01 Pvt. Laflin, Gilbert B. 8-80 Cpl. Sheets, Frederick L._ _ 20.07 Pvt. Lee, Jestivin E. 1.60 Wag. Stockton, Andrew 32.34 Pvt. Lehmus, Lewis A 21.01 Mus. Woerhide, Charles E. 6.40 Pvt. Mardock, John E. 1.60 Art. Watson, Grant 24.79 Pvt McCall, John 14-40 Pvt. Athos, Andrew G- 27.62 Pvt. McCormick, Benj. D... 8.00 Pvt. Black, Wm. 2.40 Pvt. Miller, August 4.80 Pvt. Bradshaw, Thomas H._ 5.G0 Pvt. Morrison, Edwin 5 60 Pvt. Burns, James £ 3.20 Pvt. Murphy, Simon 3.20 Pvt. Carl, Charles 21.01 Pvt. Murphy, Joseph M. 32 34 Pvt. Croop, Marian E 23.84 Pvt. Nystrom, Charles A... 10.40 Pvt. Chisolm, Ralph O. 5.60 Pvt. Nystrom, Gus E 4.80 Pvt. Dillon, Andrew J 27.62 Pvt. Pendarvis, George H._ 5.60 Pvt. Ferron, Leo P. 3.20 Pvt. Redfield, Cyrus R 480 Pvt. Foster, Louie C. 32.34 Pvt. Rundus, Frank '. 32.34 Pvt. Fowler, Thos. H 27.62 Pvt. Simpson, Wm. R 4 80 Pvt. Fox, Ernest S. 24.79 Pvt. Sherry, John W. 5.60 Pvt. Grove, George W 5.60 Pvt. Swanson, Nels 3234 Pvt. Jensen, Hans 27.62 Pvt. Turner, Carlton B 5.60 Pvt. Jockens, George H. __ 25.73 Pvt. Walker, Chas. 27.62 Pvt. Jones, Joseph B 4.80 Pvt. Werth, Henry 5.60 COMPANY M— THIRD REGIMENT Rank Name Amt. Due Rank Name Amt. Due Sgt- Lord, George E $35.38 Pvt. Foster, Frederick W... 17-44 Cpl. Ayer, Wm. T. S 35.38 Pvt. Foster, John ,E. 4.00 Cpl. Olsen, John C. 35.38 Pvt. Graham, Alonzo 3.20 Cpl. Williams, Richard 12.72 Mus. Porter. Lester E 16-50 Pvt. Griggs, Bert 2.40 Pvt. Heisler, Robert D .80 Pvt. Bennett, Niles 21.22 Pvt. Hensel, Wm. A 2.40 Pvt. Biegler, George 34.44 Pvt. Kleinsmith, Morris 35.38 Pvt. Brewick, Andrew T-_ 3.20 Pvt. Leonard, Harry H 17.44 Pvt. Cantello, John 10.84 Pvt. Maddan, Chas. 35.38 Pvt. Clark, Walter 35.38 Pvt. Maxwell, Joseph E..._ 11.78 Pvt. Car i gaii, Robert J 35.38 Pvt. Ratekin, Jason L. .80 Pvt. Constan, Samuel 2.40 Pvt. Short, James S. 27.83 Pvt. Custard, Marshall 1.60 Pvt. Timmons, Alfred D 3444 Pvt. Drustrup, Nels 3.20 Pvt. Wiesman, Jacob 2.40 TROOP K— THIRD CAVALRY Amt. Due Rank Name Name Amt. Due Cpl. Forrester, Herbert A._$13.60 Pvt. Johnson, John D 13.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 65 Bank Name Amt. Dae Rank Name Amt. Dae Pvt. McLaughlin, Walter __ 2.40 Pvt. Mossbarger, Claude G. 2.40 Pvt. Robinson, Fred 2.40 Pvt. Schutz, Gottlieb 13.60 It is recommended that this list be given a circulation in the news - papers of the State with a view to locating such of these men as possible. MEXICAN BORDER WARRANTS House Roll No. 797, of the Session of 1917, granted to certain en - listed men, the sum of $25.00 each, as reimbursement for clothing sacri - ficed while in the Mexican Border service and under the call of the President, June 18, 1916. Warrants for the following named men are in this Office unclaimed. STATE OF NEBRASKA Adjutant General's Department Office of the Chief of Staff, Lincoln. Name Post Office to which Warrant was Mailed. Robert A. Shaw, Pvt. 1-C1. Co., K, 5th. Otto Sorensen, Co. A, 4th Inf., 46 Wash. Ave., Omaha, Nebraska. Arthur L. Terrel, Co. A, 4th., 4123 St. Mary's Ave., Omaha, Nebr. Willie Schrank, Co. D, 4th., 2623 No. 20th St., Omaha, Nebr. Ollie Weisgerber, Hdqrs. Co., 4th., 805 No. Platte, St., Fremont, Nebr. Victor Moore, Co. B, 4th., Camp Hamilton, Omaha, Nebr. John B. Lowry, Co. B, 5th., Riceville, Tenn. Ecob W. Keyes, Co. C, 4th., Gen. Delivery, Omaha, Nebraska. illiam H. King, Co. A., 4th., 125 Mason St., Decatur, Illinois, seph J. Foley, Co. D, 4th., Edward J. Brown, Co. B, 4th., Camp Hamilton, Omaha, Nebraska. James M. Puett, Co. F, 5th., c|o Adjutant General of Army, Wn. D. C. Jack B. Parker, Co. M, 5th., Grand Island, Nebraska. Thomas Olson, Co. D, 5th., Fred G. Nicholas, Sup. Co. 5th., 220 Swan St., Buffalo, New York. William Meyers, M. G. Co. 5th., Wymore, Nebraska. John U. Mettalfe, Co. A, 4th., U. S. Naval Training Station, Great Lakes, Illinois. Thomas J. Hennessey, Co. H, 5th., Fremont, Nebraska. Bert L. Hubbell, Co. H, 5th., Fremont, Nebraska. John Ellis, Co. F, 4th., Roy E. Donnelly, Co. K, 5th., Golden, Colorado. Alley, Franc Beardsley, Wm. S- Clift, Charles E. Higbee, John N. 2.40 .80 2.40 2.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 av Tj J^ \J J% .J. \ ' V \ f 1 Xa ii A \ T X « r i Xv *l I j Preston Francis Bartlett, Co. B, 4th Inf., Bureau of Navigation. William Waddell, Co. E, 5th., Albey, Iowa. MEMBERS OF AMERICAN EXPEDITIONARY FORCES WHO ENTERED SERVICE FROM STATE OF NEBRASKA AND WERE KILLED IN ACTION OFFICERS Organization at Date of Death Organization at Date of Death Name Rank Time of Death Time of Death Av Sec. Sig Res C July 15-18 Av Sec. Sig Res C July 15-18 Lehr, Manderson 1st Lt. Lehr, Manderson 1st Lt. 117 Aer Sq 117 Aer Sq Philbrick, Fred 1st Lt. Philbrick, Fred 1st Lt. 28th Aer Sq Sept. 18-18 28th Aer Sq Sept. 18-18 132 Inf Mg Co Oct. 11-18 132 Inf. Mg Co Williams, Ross L 1st Lt. Williams. Ross L 1st Lt. Oct. 11-18 Boyle, Junius I 2nd Lt. Boyle, Junius I 2nd Lt. 147 Inf 147 Inf Oct. 11-18 Oct. 11-18 Burke, Walter E 2nd Lt. Burke, Walter E 2nd Lt. Co G 119 Inf Co G 119 Inf Oct. 18-18 Oct. 18-18 Cather, Grosvenor P. Jr. 2nd Lt. Cather, Grosvenor P. Jr. 2nd Lt. Res C attchd to May 29-18 Res C attend to May 29-18 Co A 26 Inf Co A 26 Inf Co B 103 MG Bn June 15-18 Flansburg, Robert H 2nd Lt. Flansburg, Robert H 2nd Lt. Co B 103 MG Bn June 15-18 20 Aer Sq Sept. 26-18 Forbes, Earl 2nd Lt. Forbes, Earl 2nd Lt. 20 Aer Sq Sept. 26-18 Severson, Will C 2nd Lt. Severson, Will C 2nd Lt. MG Co 356 Inf Sept. 23-18 MG Co 356 Inf Sept. 23-18 ENLISTED MEN White: Entered Service With National Guard or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment or Induction. Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Allen, Albert F 1,419,930 Allen, Albert F 1,419,930 Pvt Co E 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Pvt Co E 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Anderson, Albert H 1,420,236 Anderson, Albert H 1,420,236 Pvt Co G 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Co G 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Bender, Albert G 1,417,874 Bender, Albert G 1,417,874 Pvt Co L 102 Inf Oct. 25-18 Pvt Co L 102 Inf Oct. 25-18 Bendowsky, Frank 1,420,240 Bendowsky, Frank 1,420,240 Pvt Co L 59 Inf Aug. 10-18 Pvt Co L 59 Inf Aug. 10-18 Bitting, Arthur 1,417,586 Bitting, Arthur 1,417,586 Pvt Co D 102 Inf Sept. 26-18 Pvt Co D 102 Inf Sept. 26-18 Cpl 7 Engr Co B Oct. 13-18 Cpl 7 Engr Co B Oct. 13-18 Boring, Glen 914,246 Boring, Glen 914,246 Bray, Earl L 1,418,741 Bray, Earl L 1,418,741 Pvt Co C 125 Inf Oct. 5-18 Pvt Co C 125 Inf Oct. 5-18 Brittenham, Floyd E 1,419,974 Brittenham, Floyd E 1,419,974 Pvt Co F 127 Inf Oct. 15-18 Pvt Co F 127 Inf Oct. 15-18 Pvt Co F 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Carlaon, John 1,419,980 Carlson, John 1,419,980 Pvt Co F 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Cerny, Jerry 1,419,981 Cerny, Jerry 1,419,981 Pvt Co K 9th Inf Oct. 3-18 Pvt Co K 9th Inf Oct. 3-18 Croninger, Dewey C 1,419,936 Croninger, Dewey C 1,419,936 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Deeringer, Guy 1,419,654 Deeringer, Guy 1,419,654 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Delaney, George E 1,417,548 Delaney, George E 1,417,548 Pvt 9MGCoB July 17-18 Pvt 9 MG Co B July 17-18 Duckworth, Calvin R 1,418,135 Pvt Co H 23 Inf Nov. 4-18 Duckworth, Calvin R 1,418,135 Pvt Co H 23 Inf Nov. 4-18 Eggert, Thomas M 1,419,711 Eggert, Thomas M 1,419,711 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Erickson, Carl M 1,418,745 Erickson, Carl M 1,418,745 Pvt Id Co D 125 Inf Oct. 9-18 Pvt Id Co D 125 Inf Oct. 9-18 Florom, Marion W 1,420,006 Florom, Marion W 1,420,006 Pvt Co I 59 Inf Aug. 12-18 Pvt Co I 59 Inf Aug. 12-18 Fuller, Albert D 1,419,658 Puller, Albert D 1,419,658 Pvt Co H 127 Inf Aug. 30-18 Pvt Co H 127 Inf Aug. 30-18 Galbraith, Albert 1,419,660 Galbraith, Albert 1,419,660 Pvt Co H 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Co H 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Golden, William L 1,419,952 Golden, WUliam L 1,419,952 Pvt Co H 127 Inf Oct. 7-18 Pvt Co H 127 Inf Oct. 7-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL JUTANT GENERAL «T 67 Rank Organization at Date of Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Grimes, Scott Llewellen 1,447,333 Grimes, Scott Llewellen 1,447,333 Mec Co A 137 Inf Sept. 28-18 Mec Co A 137 Inf Sept. 28-18 Hankins, Dan P 1,420,008 Hankins, Dan P 1,420,008 Pvt Co L 59 Inf Aug. 8-18 Pvt Co L 59 Inf Aug. 8-18 Hanson, Chris 1,417,892 Hanson, Chris 1,417,892 Pvt Icl Co D 102 Inf Sept 26-18 Pvt Icl Co D 102 Inf Sept. 26-18 Hildebrand, William 1,419,667 Hildebrand, William 1,419,667 Pvt Co E 127 Inf Sept. 2-18 Pvt Co E 127 Inf Sept. 2-18 Hilton, Howard E 1,418,093 Hilton, Howard E 1,418,093 Pvt Co A 101 Inf Sept. 12-18 Pvt Co A 101 Inf Sept. 12-18 Hughes, Russell G. Hughes, Russell G. Corp Co L 168 Inf Mch. 17-18 Corp Co L 168 Inf Mch. 17-18 Kerns, Hugh J 101,923 Kerns, Hugh J 101,923 Pvt Co I 168 Inf Oct. 18-18 Pvt Co I 168 Inf Oct. 18-18 Lawson, Floyd 1,418,515 Lawson, Floyd 1,418,515 Pvt Co C 101 Inf Oct. 27-18 Pvt Co C 101 Inf Oct. 27-18 Layton, William A 1,420,026 Layton, William A 1,420,026 Pvt Co E 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Pvt Co E 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Lewis, Milton Oliver 1,461,145 Lewis, Milton Oliver 1,461,145 Pvt Co G 140 Inf Aug. 6-18 Pvt Co G 140 Inf Aug. 6-18 Little, Geo. V 1,417,558 Little, Geo. V 1,417,558 Pvt Co B 102 Inf Sept. 26-18 Pvt Co B 102 Inf Sept. 26-18 McMann, Arthur B 1,417,913 McMann, Arthur B 1,417,913 Corp Co B 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 Corp Co B 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 Mapes, Ray D 1,419,360 Mapes, Ray D 1,419,360 Pvt Co G 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Co G 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Marran, Fred S 1,435,517 Marran, Fred S 1,435,517 Pvt Icl Btry F 70 FA Oct. 8-18 Pvt Icl Btry F 70 FA Oct. 8-18 Martin, Paul R. 1,418,163 Martin, Paul R. 1,418,163 Pvt Co F 58 Inf Oct. 6-18 Pvt Co F 58 Inf Oct. 6-18 Miller, Gale G 1,417357 Miller, Gale G 1,417357 Pvt Ici Co C 102 Inf Oct. 25-18 Pvt Ici Co C 102 Inf Oct. 25-18 Morrissey, James 1,419,737 Morrissey, James 1,419,737 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Nickerson, Howard B 1,419,953 Nickerson, Howard B 1,419,953 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Oct. 12-18 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Oct. 12-18 Norton, Fred W 1,417,859 Norton, Fred W 1,417,859 Corp Co D 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 Corp Co D 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 Oiglevie, Richard 1,419,968 Oglevie, Richard 1,419,968 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Oct. 14-18 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Oct. 14-18 Pvt Co C 102 Inf Oct. 23-18 Pvt Co C 102 Inf Oct. 23-18 Parish, Benj. A 1,418,472 Parish, Benj. A 1,418,472 Petersen, Henry F 1,420,345 Petersen, Henry F 1,420,345 Pvt Co G 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Pvt Co G 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Pizer, Adrian 1,418,129 Pvt Co A 101 Inf Sept. 12-18 Pizer, Adrian 1,418,129 Pvt Co A 101 Inf Sept. 12-18 Poe, Thomas H 1,417,563 Poe, Thomas H 1,417,563 Pvt Id Co F 165 Inf Nov. 1-18 Pvt Id Co F 165 Inf Nov. 1-18 Ripple, Edward C. Jr 101,854 Ripple, Edward C. Jr 101,854 Pvt Id Co K 168 Inf July 29-18 Pvt Id Co K 168 Inf July 29-18 Robinson, Henry 1,417,630 Robinson, Henry 1,417,630 Pvt Co A 102 Inf Sept. 26-18 Pvt Co A 102 Inf Sept. 26-18 Schenck, Oscar G 1,419,372 Schenck, Oscar G 1,419,372 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Oct. 5-18 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Oct. 5-18 Schneider, William 1,416,755 Schneider, William 1,416,755 Pvt Co B 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 Pvt Co B 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 Sesto, Henry 46,228 Sesto, Henry 46,228 Pvt Co B 18 Inf July 18-18 Pvt Co B 18 Inf July 18-18 Shirley, Arthur S 1,416,574 Shirley, Arthur S 1,416,574 Corp Co A 128 Inf Nov. .10-18 Corp Co A 128 Inf Nov. .10-18 Shoemaker, Albert E 1,435,404 Shoemaker, Albert E 1,435,404 Pvt Bty D 119 F A Sept. 29-18 Pvt Bty D 119 F A Sept. 29-18 Sievers, William E. 1,419,929 Rglr Co F 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Sievers, William E. 1,419,929 Bglr Co F 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Stewart, Iver V 1,419,962 Stewart, Iver V 1,419,962 Pvt Id Co A 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Id Co A 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Storm, Bert E 1,417,937 Storm, Bert E 1,417,937 Pvt Co E 59 Inf Aug. 10-18 Pvt Co E 59 Inf Aug. 10-18 Walters, Linas L 1,420,057 Walters, Linas L 1,420,057 Pvt Co E 58 Inf Oct. 4-18 Pvt Co E 58 Inf Oct. 4-18 Wathen, Geo. O 1,417,375 Wathen, Geo. O 1,417,375 Pvt Co C 59 Inf Aug. 10-18 Pvt Co C 59 Inf Aug. 10-18 Welch, James 1,419,695 Welch, James 1,419,695 Pvt Co H 128 Inf Nov. 10-18 Pvt Co H 128 Inf Nov. 10-18 Willadsen, Chris S. F 1,419,163 Willadsen, Chris S. F 1,419,168 Pvt Co G 58 Inf U Pvt Co G 58 Inf U Woodard, Charles H 1,417,579 Woodard, Charles H 1,417,579 Pvt Co A 59 Inf An*. 7-1&amp; Pvt Co A 59 Inf Aug. 7-lfc </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL White: Enlisted in Regular Army or Assigned Thereto Upon Induction. Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Adams, William T 46,517 Sgt Co D 18 Inf July 23-18 Adler, Adam A 61,390 Corp Co 1 23 Inf July 1-18 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No, Time of Death Death Bergstrom, Frank H 45,047 Pvt MG Co 16 Inf July 18-18 Betta, Fred L 511,291 Pvt Co A 314 Engr Nov. 2-18 Bohl, John 559,563 Pvt Co A 58 Inf Aug. 15-18 Bolton, Ervin L 730,783 Pvt Id Hq Co 6 Inf Sept. 12-18 Bottolfson, Bernhard M 45,104 Pvt MG Co 16 Inf Oct. 9-18 Brams, Magnus M. Pvt Co M 18 Inf May 6-18 Copeman, Andrew C 568,276 Corp Co B 58 Inf U Dicksen, Frederick R 561,571 Pvt Co L 59 Inf July 19-18 Dubuque, Bertie L 2,185,644 Pvt San De 356 Inf Nov. 11-18 Farnsworth, Carl 568,333 Pvt Id Co B 4 Engr Aug. 5-18 Finch, John R 51,609 Corp Co K 23 Inf June 6-18 Flood, Frank G 558,062 Sgt MG Co 47 Inf Sept. 27-18 Fountain, Roger Glenn 2,395,292 Pvt Id MG Co 7 Inf July 16-18 Goldner, John H 2,387,304 Corp Co F 61 Inf Nov. 1-18 Grimmeiss, John A 42,257 Pvt Co C 16 Inf Oct. 8-18 HajeTc, Frank Jr 105,463 Pvt Co B 2 MG Bn Oct. 4-18 Haremza, Leo 154,923 Pvt Co A 1st Engr May 8-18 Harmon, Glenn W 50,394 Corp Co E 23 Inf July 18-18 Henson, Richard M 561,576 Sgt Co L 59 Inf Oct. 4-18 Hirz, Henry 2,395,316 5-18 Pvt Co K 7 Inf Oct. Iinhart, Anton 41,738 Pvt Co A 16 Inf May 5-18 Lund, Lawrence N 2,387,827 Corp Co H 61 Inf Oct. 16-18 Maixner, Frederick 2,395,345 Pvt Hq Co 7 Inf Oct. 22-18 Moore, Edward R 732,816 Pvt Id 6 Inf Co F Aug. 11-18 Norton, Fred W 1,417,859 Corp Co D 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 Nunn, Francis 105,650 Pvt Co B 18 Inf July 18-18 O'Leary, Joseph R 914,787 Pvt Id Co D 2 Bn 7 Engr. Oct. 14-18 Poels, Anton 2,196,942 Mec 356 Amb Co 314 Sn Tn Nov. 3-18 ■Quakenbush, Clinton F 43,299 Pvt Co G 16 Inf July 21-18 Reese, Charles H 934,329 Pvt Id Amb Co 21 Rorabaugh, Allen D 50,826 Pvt Co F 23 Inf July 18-18 Rotherham, Arthur J 47,428 Pvt Co G 18 Inf July 18-18 Roy, Martin 130,455 Pvt Id BrtyC15FA Oct. 4-18 Sanders, Albert W 915,604 Pvt Co B 7 Engrs Oct. 13-18 Sanders, Leo J 44,045 Pvt Id Co K 16 Inf July 19-18 Sanders, Sylvester S. 44,047 Pvt Co K 16 Inf July 19-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL FUTANT GENERAL 69 69 Rank Organization at Date of Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Saxton, Lee D 2,399,315 Saxton, Lee D 2,399,315 Pvt Co E 30 Inf June 7-18 Pvt Co E 30 Inf June 7-18 Scanlan, Edmund Geo 1,038,263 Scanlan, Edmund Geo 1,038,263 Corp Brty B 10 F A Oct. 14-18 Corp Brty B 10 F A Oct. 14-18 Spiker, Bernie W 540,770 Spiker, Bernie W 540,770 Corp Co A 7 Inf July 15-18 Corp Co A 7 Inf July 15-18 Stone, Hardin E 131,029 Stone, Hardin E 131,029 Bglr Btry F 15 F A July 19-18 Bglr Btry F 15 F A July 19-18 Wetzel, William W 844,627 Wetzel, William W 844,627 Pvt 314 Sn Tn Nov. 3-18 Pvt 314 Sn Tn Nov. 3-18 Williams, Jay C 573,242 Williams, Jay C 573,242 Pvt Id Co C 58 Inf Oct. 7-18 Pvt Id Co C 58 Inf Oct. 7-18 Wiseman, Chas. F Wiseman, Chas. F.. Pvt Id Co K 16 Inf April 26-18 Pvt Id Co K 16 Inf April 26-18 Wurmbach, Geo. A 41,851 Wurmbach, Geo. A 41,851 Pvt Co B 16 Inf July 20-18 Pvt Co B 16 Inf July 20-18 Young, Geo. W 731,854 Young, Geo. W 731,854 Sgt Co C 6 Inf Sept. 14-18 Sgt Co C 6 Inf Sept. 14-18 White: Inducted Into National Army or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment. Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Adams, Leslie 2,181,948 Adams, Leslie 2,181,948 Corp Co G 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Corp Co G 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 8-18 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 8-18 Akerson, Arthur 2,213,760 Akerson, Arthur 2,213,760 Alexander, Albert B 562,135 Pvt 47 Inf Co I Aug. 7-18 Pvt 47 Inf Co I Aug. 7-18 Alexander, Albert B 562,135 Anders, Warrick A 1,417,284 Anders, Warrick A 1,417,284 Pvt Co A 127 Inf Aug. 5-18 Pvt Co A 127 Inf Aug. 5-18 Anderson, Stanley 2,213,772 Anderson, Stanley 2,213,772 Pvt Id Co A 4 Inf July 15-18 Pvt Id Co A 4 Inf July 15-18 Arps, William 549,305 Arps, William 549,305 Pvt MG Co 38 Inf Oct. 8-18 Pvt MG Co 38 Inf Oct. 8-18 Ashpaugh, Lorin 2,213,778 Ashpaugh, Lorin 2,213,778 Pvt Co D 4 Inf U Pvt Co D 4 Inf U August, Ernest Royal 514,780 August, Ernest Royal 514,780 Pvt Id Co F 7 Inf July 15-18 Pvt Id Co F 7 Inf July 15-18 Backman, Adolph G 2,202,771 Backman, Adolph G 2,202,771 Pvt MG Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Pvt MG Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Baird, Verner A 2,182,074 Pvt Id Co M 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Pvt Id Co M 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Baird, Verner A 2,182,074 Baker, Sterling 572,618 Baker, Sterling 672,618 Corp Co M 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Corp Co M 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Corp Co G 4 Inf Oct. 4-18 Banks, Leonard S 2,213,782 Banks, Leonard S 2,213,782 Corp Co G 4 Inf Oct. 4-18 Barse, Horace C 2,787,812 Barse, Horace C 2,787,812 Pvt Co I 306 Inf Oct. 15-18 Pvt Co I 306 Inf Oct. 15-18 Bartusiak, Andrew E 2,181,753 Bartusiak, Andrew E 2,181,753 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Nov. 10-18 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Nov. 10-18 Bates, Robert H 1,416,897 Bates, Robert H 1,416,897 Pvt Co A 127 Inf July 31-18 Pvt Co A 127 Inf July 31-18 Beachler, Corley C 246,085 Beachler, Corley C 246,085 Pvt Co B 7 Inf Oct. 21-18 Pvt Co B 7 Inf Oct. 21-18 Beam, Guy H. 2,181,365 Beam, Guy H. 2,181,365 Pvt Hq Co 137 Inf Oct. 10-18 Pvt Hq Co 137 Inf Oct. 10-18 Beck, Andrew August 2,213,797 Beck, Andrew August 2,213,797 Pvt Co Do 4 Inf Oct. 12-18 Pvt Co Do 4 Inf Oct. 12-18 Beckner, Howard O 2,213,796 Pvt Co G 4 Inf July 23-18 Beckner, Howard O 2,213,796 Pvt Co G 4 Inf July 23-18 Bennett, Owen 2,845,849 Bennett, Owen 2,845,849 Pvt Co G 355 Inf U Pvt Co G 355 Inf U lionham, Charlie Roy 561,027 lionham, Charlie Roy 561,027 Pvt Id Co K 58 Inf Aug. 5-18 Pvt Id Co K 58 Inf Aug. 5-18 Pvt Co E 4 Inf July 27-18 Bose, Frank 2,213,812 Bose, Frank 2,213,812 Pvt Co E 4 Inf July 27-18 Brandt, Robert H 2,181,848 Brandt, Robert H 2,181,848 Corp Co F 355 Inf U Corp Co F 355 Inf U Brewer, James W 240,815 Brewer, James W 240,815 Pvt Co I 125 Inf July 31-18 Pvt Co I 125 Inf July 31-18 Bright, Louis A 2,181,958 Bright, Louis A 2,181,958 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Brinda, Leo 2,213,825 Brinda, Leo 2,213,825 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Brodine, Edward 2,180,863 Brodine, Edward 2,180,863 Pvt Co D 128 Inf Aug. 3-18 Pvt Co D 128 Inf Aug. 3-18 Brown, Howard Elmer 2,208,392 Brown, Howard Elmer 2,208,392 Corp Co B 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Corp Co B 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Browning, Stephen 2,175,016 Pvt CoA341MgBn Sept. 13-18 Pvt CoA341MgBn Sept. 13-18 Browning, Stephen 2,175,016 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial'No. Name Serial'No. Time of Death Death Butler, Homer J. 2,196,553 Butler, Homer J. 2,196,553 Pvt Id Med De 354 Inf Sept. 10-18 Pvt Id Med De 354 Inf Sept. 10-18 Cain, Henry Earl 2,845,917 Cain, Henry Earl 2,845,917 Pvt Id Co G 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 Pvt Id Co G 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 Carlson, Erik Martin 2,180,508 Carlson, Erik Martin 2,180,508 Pvt Id CoB341MgBn Oct. 21-18 Pvt Id CoB341MgBn Oct. 21-18 Carter, Leora 2,847,952 Carter, Leora 2,847,952 Pvt Co K 320 Inf Sept. 12-18 Pvt Co K 320 Inf Sept. 12-18 Cassel, Gunnar K 1,113,362 Cassel, Gunnar K 1,113,362 Pvt CoC9FSigBn Nov. 10-18 Pvt CoC9FSigBn Nov. 10-18 Capelle, Atlee E 240,911 Capelle, Atlee E 240,911 Pvt Co C 103 Inf July 20-18 Pvt Co C 103 Inf July 20-18 Christenson, Otto H 2,181,964 Christenson, Otto H 2,181,964 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Cone, William A 2,185,611 Cone, William A 2,185,611 Pvt Id Sn Det 356 Inf Nov. 10-18 Pvt Id Sn Det 356 Inf Nov. 10-18 Conley, Leonard 2,181,379 Conley, Leonard 2,181,379 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Oct. 17-18 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Oct. 17-18 Cook, Lester C. 2,213,859 Cook, Lester C. 2,213,859 Corp Co I 4 Inf July 23-18 Corp Co I 4 Inf July 23-18 Cooksley, Frank 240,826 Cooksley, Frank 240,826 Pvt Co E 28 Inf July 19-18 Pvt Co E 28 Inf July 19-18 Cosand, Ni,?el G 2,181,380 Cosand, Nigel G 2,181,380 Corp Co B 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Corp Co B 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Cox, Raymond M. 2,180,340 Cox, Raymond M. 2,180,340 Corp CoA341MGBn Oct. 20-18 Corp CoA341MGBn Oct. 20-18 Crowe, Elmer 2,100,747 Crowe, Elmer 2,100,747 Pvt Co C 39 Inf Aug. 7-18 Pvt Co C 39 Inf Aug. 7-18 Davidson, Earl 2,213,869 Davidson, Earl 2,213,869 Pvt Co E 4 Inf July 24-18 Pvt Co E 4 Inf July 24-18 Evis, Sydney Fred 2,181,514 vis, William Henry 2,847,367 bolt, William 2,213,874 Deck, Ernest Frederick 2,213,875 Dehart, Hugh E 3,953,474 Davis, Sydney Fred 2,181,514 Pvt Co G 137 Inf Sept. 28-18 Pvt Co G 137 Inf Sept. 28-18 Davis, William Henry 2,847,367 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Debolt, William 2,213,874 Pvt Co C 4 Inf Oct. 12-18 Pvt Co C 4 Inf Oct. 12-18 Deck, Ernest Frederick 2,213,875 Pvt Co B 4 Inf July 23-18 Pvt Co B 4 Inf July 23-18 Dehart, Hugh E 3,953,474 Pvt Co F 361 Inf Nov. 1-18 Pvt Co F 361 Inf Nov. 1-18 Delozier, Nealie H 254,179 Delozier, Nealie H 254,179 Pvt Co B 7 Inf U Pvt Co B 7 Inf U Dittmer, Hans H. 2,213,879 Dittmer, Hans H. 2,213,879 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 21-18 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 21-18 Dix, William 1,418,206 Dix, William 1,418,206 Pvt Co F 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Pvt Co F 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 White: Inducted Into National Army or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment. Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Dunken, Guy H 1,419,993 Dunken, Guy H 1,419,993 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Sept. 2-18 Pvt Co G 127 Inf Sept. 2-18 Egle, William 2,182,513 Egle, William 2,182,513 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Aug. 1-18 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Aug. 1-18 Eisele, David W 240,838 Eisele, David W 240,838 Pvt Co A 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Pvt Co A 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Fierstein, Willie 2,213,893 Fierstein, Willie 2,213,893 Pvt Co G 4 Inf Oct. 2-18 Pvt Co G 4 Inf Oct. 2-18 Fischer, Herman H. 1,635,659 Fischer, Herman H. 1,635,659 Pvt Co F 103 Inf Sept. 12-18 Pvt Co F 103 Inf Sept. 12-18 Fogel, Lester G. 2,213,895 Fogel, Lester G. 2,213,895 Pvt Co G 4 Inf Oct. 2-18 Pvt Co G 4 Inf Oct. 2-18 Folda, Albin 2,846,789 Folda, Albin 2,846,189 Corp Co M 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Corp Co M 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Forsman, Fritz C. 240,849 Forsman, Fritz C. 240,849 Pvt Id Co M 125 Inf July 31-18 Pvt Id Co M 125 Inf July 31-18 Foster, Clarence Irven 2,181,147 Foster, Clarence Irven 2,181,147 Pvt Co A 137 Inf Oct. 2-18 Pvt Co A 137 Inf Oct. 2-18 Foster, Sidney Ray 2,213,897 Foster, Sidney Ray 2,213,897 Pvt Co B 4 Inf Oct. 18-18 Pvt Co B 4 Inf Oct. 18-18 Franek, Lewis 2,182,316 Franek, Lewis 2,182,316 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Aug. 1-18 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Aug. 1-18 Garner, William L 3,435,858 Garner, William L 3,435,858 Pvt Co I 362 Inf Nov. 3-18 Pvt Co I 362 Inf Nov. 3-18 Gavelick, Harry 2,213,906 Gavelick, Harry 2,213,906 Pvt Co C 4 Inf July 15-18 Pvt Co C 4 Inf July 15-18 Gernentz, Edward J 3,129,082 Gernentz, Edward J 3,129,082 Pvt Co L 308 Inf Oct. 13-18 Pvt Co L 308 Inf Oct. 13-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 71 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death &lt;Jill, Frederick J. 2,845,634 Pvt 355 Inf Mg Co Oct. 8-18 Gilmer, John E. 2,181,739 Corp Co E 355 Inf Aug. 27-18 Godberson, Herman 2,180,517 Pvt Id CoB341MGBn Nov. 1-18 Gohr, Harry 2,845,759 Pvt Co G 355 Inf Oct. 25-18 Goodwin, Isaac Chester 2,181,401 Pvt Id Co G 137 Inf U Gossett, Horace W 2,213,912 Pvt Co G 4 Inf July 28-18 Graves, Theodore Elmer __2,181,736 Pvt Co D 137 Inf Sept. 27-18 Grainer, Frank 2,202,454 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Grim, Alfred 2,197,007 Wag 356 Amb Co 314 Sn Tn Nov. 7-18 Gruer, Walter J 2,180,755 Pvt CoA341MGBn Sept. 19-18 Haberman, Fred H 3,142,826 Pvt Co D 112 Inf Oct. 1-18 Hablitzel, Jacob Jr 2,213,922 Pvt Co D 4 Inf July 26-18 Hamilton, Joseph A. 2,846,804 Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Hansen, Willard U 2,181,405 Pvt MG Co 138 Inf Sept. 26-18 Harms, Ufkie 1,419,405 Pvt Co I 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Harty, James J. 2,213,936 Pvt Co G 4 Inf July 29-18 Haugh, Richard 2,213,937 Corp Co C 4 Inf June 18-18 Hawes, Will 2,181,070 Pvt Co D 137 Inf Sept. 29-18 Heath, Carl 2,181,986 Corp Co G 355 Inf Nov. 10-18 Heininger, Edwin W 937,580 Pvt 38 Amb Co 6 Sn Tn Sept. 29-18 Herman, William C. 2,201,214 Corp Co C 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Herrold, Carl E 1,418,822 Pvt MG Co 125 Inf Aug. 31-18 Hopeener, Herbert 0 1,419,411 Pvt Co M 127 Inf Sept. 1-18 Hoffman, Ralph 2,196,754 Wag 354 Amb Co 314 Sn Tn Oct. 26-18 Holmes, Oliver W 2,847,904 Pvt Co G 353 Inf 89 Div Sept. 12-18 Holtigrewe, Carl J. 2,213,962 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 27 7 18 Holz, Carl 2,181,933 Sgt Co G 355 Inf Sept. 5-18 Hood, Lewis Leonard 2,213,961 Pvt Co C 4 Inf Oct. 4-18 Hooper, Wilbert G 2,175,754 Pvt Co B 353 Inf Oct. 30-18 Horn, Martin Luther 2,181,529 Pvt Co H 137 Inf Sept. 26-18 Hornkohl, Jos. F. 1,634,071 Pvt Co A 9 MG Bn Oct. 12-18 Houska, James 2,213,963 Pvt Co B 4 Inf July 23-18 Hurlburt, Clarence Orvil __2,847,917 Pvt Co K 355 Inf Sept. 12-18 Imhoff, William B 240371 Pvt MG Co 102 Inf Oct. 29-18 Ivers, Louis Cecil 2,208,446 Pvt Co G 364 Inf Sept. 28-18 Jelinek, Ferdinand 2,182,331 Pvt Co B 137 Inf Sept. 29-18 Jeppson, Hilmer Edward 2,182,197 Pvt CdsC 128 Inf Aug. 1-18 Johnson, Arthur J. 2,181339 Pvt Id Co F 355 Inf Nov. 6-18 Johnson, Chas. Albert^ 2,213,985 Pvt Co G 4 Inf July 29-18 Johnson, Chas. Renwick 2,181,936 Corp Co G 355 Inf Sept. 14-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 72 Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Pvt Co M 112 Inf Nov. 1-1S Johnson, Louis 3,138,105 Johnson, Oakley V 2,297,212 Pvt Co H 355 Inf Nov. 7-18 Bglr Co K 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Johnson, Otto V 2,848,054 Pvt Co C 4 Inf July Johnson, Roy 2,213,984 16-18 Jones, Floyd Elmer 2,846,827 Jordan, John Henry 2,181,985 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Pvt Co A 137 Inf Sept. 20-18 Kallemeyn, Geo. 2,845.969 Pvt Id CoA341MGBn Sept. 19-18 Kappelin, Anders L 1,417,316 Kayton, James Emery 2,214,000 Pvt Co K 59 Inf Oct. 9-18 Corp Co D 4 Inf Oct. 12-18 Pvt Id Co I 125 Inf Aug. Keezer, Charley C. 240,636 31-18 Kenney, Henry G. 1,420,024 Pvt Id Co K 59 Inf Oct. 9-18 Kent, James E. 2,214,004 Corp Co G 4 Inf Oct. 2-18 Kerl, Chester R 1,419,416 Pvt Co D 165 Inf Oct. 15-18 Kinnier, Thomas S. 2,182,063 Corp Co H 355 Inf Sept. 12-18 Kintigh, Roy Clifford 2,378,658 Pvt Co D 2 Engrs July 19-18 Kitto, Silas 2,847,153 Pvt Co G 354 Inf Sept. 24-18 Kline, Roy C 2,208,156 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Koca, Frank B 2,182,527 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Aug. 29-18 Koch, Louie Peter 2,182,202 Pvt Co B 137 Inf Sept. 28-18 Kroff, Carl T.- 2,182,203 Pvt Id Co M 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Korinek, James J 2^14,609 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 12-18 Kregger, William J 2,182,346 Sgt Co L 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Kriewald, Samuel H 2,214,016 Pvt Co F 4 Inf Oct. 18-18 Kruse, Fred 2,180,533 Pvt MG Co 30 Inf July 15-18 Kuehnert, Walter K. A 2,155,340 Pvt Co F 131 Inf Aug. 9-18 Labno, Stanislaw 3,951,405 Pvt CoC347MGBn Oct. 30-18 Lafrenz, Julius H 2,182,278 Corp Co K 355 Inf U Larkowski, Ted 2,181,781 Co C 128 Inf Aug. 1-18 Pvt Larson, Edward H 2,182,034 Co H 355 Inf Sept. 12-18 Sgt Lasher, Arthur E 2,846,735 CoA341MGBn Nov. 1-18 Pvt Laune, Raymond 2,178,985 Co M 354 Inf Nov. 2-18 Corp Lembke, John F 2,214,027 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 6-18 Lewis, Geo. Edward 2,214,031 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 8-1? Lindner, Henry E 2,198,570 CoA341MGBn Nov. 2-18 Pvt Lisenbee, Joseph I 2,181,677 Co A 137 Inf Sept. 28-18 Pvt Lott, Peter M 1,419,423 Co C 128 Inf Aug. 31-18 Pvt Lungwitz, Theobald W 1,419,424 Co C 128 Inf U Pvt McElwain, Harley H 2,182,534 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Sept. 11-18" McGrew, Laverne 2,180,957 Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Nov. 8-18 McJinsey, Geo. M 1,418,216 Co D 101 Inf Oct. 26-18 Pvt i Mack, Arthur C 1,418,523 Co B 101 Inf Sept. 12-18 Pvt Mackeprang, Henry 2,181,884 Co F 355 Inf Nov. 7-18" Corp Marshall, Harold Dayre 2,844,982 Co E 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Pvt Mathers, William F 254,206 15-1&amp; Pvt Co G 355 Inf July </seg>
            <seg id="p073">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 73 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Mathieson, James A 2,214,050 Pvt Pvt Pvt Co C 4 Inf July 15-18 Michelsen, Martin Theo 2,181,785 Co H 137 Inf Sept. 26-18 Miller, Adam 2,214,067 Co C 4 Inf Oct. 10-18 Millet, Jean 572,514 Pvt Id Pvt Co L 59 Inf Oct. 3-18 Mislivek, Frank 2,196,190 Co E 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Moeller, Edward F 1,418,858 Pvt Id Corp Co E 125 Inf Oct. 9-18 Mogensen, Carl C. 2,214,044 Co F 4 Inf July 25-18 Monger, Elic C. 2,181,087 Pvt Co A 137 Inf July 20-18 Moore, Geo. F. 2,214,073 Corp Co G 4 Inf July 29-18 Morgan, Harvey Jones 2,214,077 Pvt Id Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 8-18 Munson, James G 936,459 38 Amb Co 6 Sn Tn Sept. 29-18 Nagel, Paul 246,103 Corp Pvt Co F 28 Inf Sept. 14-18 Nielsen, Laurits 3,335,213 Co F 353 Inf Nov. 5-18 Oliver, Edward C. 558,837 Corp Pvt Co D 47 Inf July 30-18 Palmer, Geo. S 2,847,944 Co K 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 Palmer, Jos. E 2,847,944 Corp Sgt Co E 4 Inf June 16-18 Co E 4 Inf Oct. 15-18 Parry, Robert Owen 2,214,101 Parsons, Chester 2,181,548 Pvt Pvt Pvt Pvt Pvt Pvt Pvt Pvt Mec Co I 137 Inf Sept. 26-18 Payne, James L 2,845,938 Co I 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 Pender, Jasper 2,847,187 Co H 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Petersen, Arvie 1,418,868 Co B 125 Inf Aug. 29-18 Peterson, Nels J 284,669 Co M 353 Inf Oct. 21-18 Peterson, Luther A 2,214,908 Hq Co 4 Inf Sept. 30-18 Peterson, Richard Patrick 2,214,096 Co C 4 Inf Oct. 18-18 Pfeiffer, Martin August 2,214,112 Co D 4 Inf Oct. 11-18 Phelps, Paul C 2,184,002 Co B 356 Inf Oct. 19-18 Post, Gustaf Emil 2,845,878 Pvt Id Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Powell, Charles O 2,846,158 Co E 355 Inf Sept. 17-18 Prendergast, John Leo 2,214,108 Sgt Pvt Co C 4 Inf Oct. 6-18 Quimby, David E 1,418,231 Co A 101 Inf Sept. 14-18 Reed, Glen M 2,181,356 Sgt Pvt Co B 355 Inf Sept. 13-18 Rejda, Anton J 1,419,140 Inf Cam Cody June Repl Dfts Co 7 Sept. 1-18 Rhodes, Roscoe B 2,845,937 Sgt Pvt Pvt Pvt CoA342MGBn Oct. 25-18 Rich, William H 2,195,146 Co B 26 Inf Oct 5-18 Ridlen, Harry Kenneth 2,214,127 Co D 4 Inf Oct. 14-18 Riebling, George F 2,214,130 Co G 4 Inf July 29-18 Riley, Wm. Swearingin 2,212,990 Pvt Id Pvt Co M 353 Inf Sept. 30-18 Robert, John W 2,847,949 Co K 355 Inf Sept. 12-18 Robertson, Lewis H 2,214,133 Corp Pvt Co G 4 Inf July 26-18 Robinson, William H 3,125,696 MG Co 364 Inf Sept. 30-18 Roerick, Gustav 240,745 Pvt Co L 103 Inf June 16-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Roggensees, Earl J 1,420,355 Pvt Co H 58 Inf Oct. 6-18 Pvt CoA341MGBn Sept. 3-18 Co H 355 Inf Sept. 12-18 Rosacker, Chris C 2,180,738 Rosencrantz, Geo. C 2,182,037 Corp Rosmussen, Carl S 2,214,116 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Ross, Raymond L 2,214,124 Pvt Id Co F 4 Inf July 21-18 Roth, Herman 2,195,905 Corp CoB341MGBn Oct. 22-18 Ruzicka, Edward V 1,418,241 Pvt Co D 101 Inf Nov. 11-18 Ryan, Clifford T 2,179,869 Pvt Co E 357 Inf Nov. 11-18 Sanger, Anno ,.3,954,116 Pvt Co L 363 Inf Oct. 31-18 Scharf, Albert 2,209,960 Pvt Id Co B 355 Inf Sept. 12-18 Schellinger, William A 2,846,029 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Sept. 16-18 Schipman, Emil 2,214,149 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 21-18 Schmer, Conrad 2,208,504 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Nov. 3-18 Schneider, Fredrich Wm 2,180,300 Pvt Co B 7 Inf July 15-18 Shallers, Louis A 3,436,224 Pvt Co A 360 Inf Nov. 2-18 Shaner, Elmer W 2,313,162 Pvt Co L 165 Inf July 28-18 Shavlik, Joseph L 2,214,156 Corp Co F 4 Inf July 21-18 Shaw, Stephen R 1,418,179 Pvt Co E 59 Inf Aug. 7-18 Shea, Micheal 2,180,499 Pvt Id CoB341MGBn Nov. 1-18 Shemoski, John 2,180,999 Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Shields, Thomas 0 2,182,067 Corp Co H 355 Inf Nov. 10-18 Shultz, Claire W 2,180,031 Pvt CoD341MGBn Nov. 5-18 Sibbel, Henry 2,847,094 Pvt Co A 355 Inf Nov. 11-18 Skiff, William H 1,418,178 Pvt Co F 59 Inf Sept. 30-18 Skinner, Thomas 1,418,252 Pvt Co E 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Sloggett, Harvey M 2,214,164 Pvt Co F 4 Inf Oct. 14-18 Smaus, Louis J 1,417,932 Pvt Co D 102 Inf Nov. 3-18 Smith, Forrest Roy 2,214,170 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 12-18 Snider, Jesse Max 2,181,319 Pvt Co K 137 Inf Sept. 28-18 Sober, Fred E 1,420,278 Pvt Co B 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Sorg, William 2,846,459 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Stanbarger, Orval E 2,201,144 Pvt Co C 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Steidley, Robert B 2,846,431 Co H 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Pvt Stickley, Harley 2,214,184 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 8-18 Stockwell, Lynn J. 2,847,245 Pvt Co H 355 Inf Nov. 10-18 Stoner, Wallace D. 3,436,437 Pvt Co F 359 Inf Nov. 5-18 Strand, Martin Hartvel 2,846,729 Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Nov. 3-18 Sutherland, Gilbert 2,214,189 Pvt Co G 4 Inf July 29-18 Svec, James 2,182,551 Pvt Co H 137 Inf Sept. 29-18 Tallin, Oscar P. 2,214,196 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 6-18 Thomas, Clyde Orville 2,214,202 Pvt Id Co D 4 Inf Oct. 23-18 Thompson, Chas. Ellsworth 2,214,204 Corp Co D 4 Inf Oct. 4-18 Thomas, Johnie 2,181,568 Pvt Med Det 314 SnTn Oct. 24-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 75 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Tolin, Arvid 3,961,307 Pvt Co A 360 Inf Nov. 2-18 Tomek, Anton Jr. 1,420,368 Tordrap, August 1,419,483 Trobough, Henry Clinton__2,845,827 Pvt Co B 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Pvt Co F 58 Inf Oct. 5-18 Pvt Id MG Co 355 Inf Nov. 11-18 Tucker, Ellis A 2,182,043 Sgt Co H 355 Inf Sept. 12-18 Umland, Elmer V 3,963,423 Pvt Co E 320 Inf Nov. 1-18 Valeche, Vito 1,420,372 Pvt Co G 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Van Dergriend, Nick 1,418,271 Pvt Co E 59 Inf Aug. 12-18 Vitek, Emil 2,214,218 Pvt Co C 4 Inf July 23-18 Vogt, Oscar F 1,418,186 Pvt Id Co C 59 Inf Oct. 6-18 Wallien, Carl Rudolph 2,214,223 Pvt Co C 4 Inf U Pvt 356 Amb Co 314 Wambeam, Floyd 2,196,987 Sn Tn Oct. 27-18 Weibel, William A 1,420,381 Pvt Co F 58 Inf Aug. 6-18 Weiler, Walter 2,256,745 Pvt Id Co F 362 Inf Oct. 30-18 Welch, Lawrence G. 1,420,285 Pvt Id Co F 58 Inf Oct. 6-18 West, Warren Winslo 2,214,229 Pvt Co C 4 Inf July 22-18 Wiemer, Burchard Henry _2,182,426 Pvt Co C 137 Inf July 20-18 Wight, Edward J 3,951,838 Pvt Co A 360 Inf Nov. 2-18 Winter, Henry Jr 1,420,394 Pvt Co G 58 Inf Oct. 6-18 Yates, Homer M 2,202,589 Pvt MG Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Zwickey, Harry J 2,181,328 Sgt Co A 355 Inf Oct. 31-18 Colored: Entered Service with National Guard or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment or Induction. Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Knobe, William E 1,417,851 Corp Co B 102 Inf Oct. 26-18 MEMBER OF AMERICAN EXPEDITIONARY FORCES WHO ENTERED SERVICE FROM STATE OF NEBRASKA AND DIED OF WOUNDS. Officers Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Allyn, Arthur E. Jr. Capt Co D 312 Inf Oct. 24-18 Marsh, Arthur H. Chap 1st Lt 18 Inf Oct. 7-1* Offutt, Jarvis J 1st Lt. 22 Aer Sq attach- ed to 56 Sq Royal Air Force Aug. 11-1S </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Phillips, Clifford F 1st Lt Co H 339 Inf May 10-19 Fryer, Claire P 2nd Lt Co B 342 MG Bn Nov. 1-18 Enlisted Men White: Entered Service with National Guard or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment or Induction. Rank Organization at Date of Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Bower, William 1,419,704 Bower, William 1,419,704 Pvt Co F 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Pvt Co F 127 Inf Oct. 4-18 Carroll, Frank Joseph 2,307,026 Carroll, Frank Joseph 2,307,026 Sgt Co G 127 Inf Oct. 7-18 Sgt Co G 127 Inf Oct. 7-18 Cooper, Albert C. 1,419,707 Cooper, Albert C. 1,419,707 Pvt Inf Camp Cody Pvt Inf Camp Cody June Repl Draft Co 8 Sept. 3-18 June Repl Draft Co 8 Sept. 3-18 Cownie, Brodie G. 102,362 Cownie, Brodie G. 102,362 Pvt Co L 168 Inf July 27-18 Pvt Co L 168 Inf July 27-18 Day, Robert J 1,419,086 Day, Robert J 1,419,086 Pvt Co D 125 Inf Oct. 10-18 Pvt Co D 125 Inf Oct. 10-18 Engler, William 1,418,151 Engler, William 1,418,151 rion, Archie R 1,435,348 Pvt Id Co A 101 Inf U Pvt Id Co A 101 Inf U Irion, Archie R 1,435,348 Pvt Brty B 119 FA U Pvt Brty B 119 FA U Little, William T. 1,530,585 Little, William T. 1,530,585 Pvt Co I 148 Inf Oct. 1-18 Pvt Co I 148 Inf Oct. 1-18 Popa, Frank M. 573,486 Popa, Frank M. 573,486 Pvt Co C 39 Inf Aug. 2-18 Pvt Co C 39 Inf Aug. 2-18 Ralph, Earl 1,419,742 Ralph, Earl 1,419,742 Pvt Co B 128 Inf Sept. 2-18 Pvt Co B 128 Inf Sept. 2-18 Robb, Vernon 1,416,268 Robb, Vernon 1,416,268 Pvt MG Co 125 Inf Aug. 31-18 Pvt MG Co 125 Inf Aug. 31-18 Sadler, Fred I 1,419,958 Sadler, Fred I 1,419,958 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Oct. 5-18 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Oct. 5-18 Saylor, John H. 1,418,242 Saylor, John H. 1,418,242 Pvt Co I 126 Inf Oct. 16-18 Pvt Co I 126 Inf Oct. 16-18 Scribner, Charles E. 1,419,686 Scribner, Charles E. 1,419,686 Pvt Id Co B 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Pvt Id Co B 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Sharp, Edward M. 1,419,891 Sharp, Edward M 1,419,891 Pvt Co G 58 Inf Oct. 4-18 Pvt Co G 58 Inf Oct. 4-18 Smith, Harold V 1,435,176 Smith, Harold V 1,435,176 Pvt Btry D 121 FA Oct. 17-18 Pvt Btry D 121 FA Oct. 17-18 Thober, Fred H 1,417,658 Thober, Fred H 1,417,658 Pvt Co A 102 Inf Nov. 2-18 Pvt Co A 102 Inf Nov. 2-18 Throckmorton, John 1,419,693 Throckmorton, John 1,419,693 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Nov. 12-18 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Nov. 12-18 Welliver, Ira 1,420,058 Welliver, Ira 1,420,058 Pvt Co H 58 Inf Aug. 19-18 Pvt Co H 58 Inf Aug. 19-18 White, John R 2,399,497 White, John R 2,399,497 Corp Co C 30 Inf Nov. 27-18 Corp Co C 30 Inf Nov. 27-18 Wolff, Verne O 1,419,164 Wolff, Verne O 1,419,164 Pvt Co D 125 Inf Aug. 30-18 Pvt Co D 125 Inf Aug. 30-18 Wood, William 1,417,578 Wood, William 1,417,578 Pvt Co A 59 Inf Aug. 4-18 Pvt Co A 59 Inf Aug. 4-18 White: Enlisted in Regular Army or Assigned Thereto Upon Induction Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Beaver, Herbert 126,081 Corp Btry D 6 F A Oct. 5-18 Beyer, William 2,387,505 Pvt Co G 61 Inf Oct. 17-18 Chavet, Albert H 915,223 Corp CoF7Eng2Bn Nov. 5-18 Cullers, Arch 509,599 Pvt Btry E 11 F A Nov. 7-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 77 Rank Organization at Date of Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Davis, Henry H. 1,197,028 Davis, Henry H. 1,197,028 Pvt Co D 15 Mg Bn Oct. 14-18 Pvt Co D 15 Mg Bn Oct. 14-18 Dawson, Elsa 1,042,507 Dawson, Elsa 1,042,507 Sgt Hq Co 18 FA Oct. 9-18 Sgt Hq Co 18 FA Oct. 9-18 Donegan, Noel C. 914,324 Donegan, Noel C. 914,324 Pvt Co B 7 Engrs Oct. 17-18 Pvt Co B 7 Engrs Oct. 17-18 Haubensak, James Harold 753,209 Haubensak, James Harold 753,209 Sgt Id Med Dep Evac Sgt Id Med Dep Evac Hosp 4 Nov. 2-18 Hosp 4 Nov. 2-18 Heyde, Albert D. Heyde, Albert D. Pvt Co L 16 Inf May 8-18 Pvt Co L 16 Inf May 8-18 Houts, John W. 558,299 Houts, John W. 558,299 Pvt Co I 47 Inf Sept. 30-18 Pvt Co I 47 Inf Sept. 30-18 Jarman, Edgar Oliver 2,337,697 Jarman, Edgar Oliver 2,337,697 Pvt MG Co 4 Inf June 28-18 Pvt MG Co 4 Inf June 28-18 McBreen, Charles T 360,672 McBreen, Charles T 360,672 Pvt Co G 110 Inf Sept. 27-18 Pvt Co G 110 Inf Sept. 27-18 Mathers, Charles W 915,391 Mathers, Charles W 915,391 Pvt CoF7Engr2Bn Oct. 21-18 Pvt CoF7Engr2Bn Oct. 21-18 Milliard, Frank B 2,268,612 Milliard, Frank B 2,268,612 Corp Hq Co 346 FA Sept. 20-18 Corp Hq Co 346 FA Sept. 20-18 Nelson, Finn L. 45,067 Nelson, Finn L. 45,067 Pvt Id MG Co 16 Inf July 22-18 Pvt Id MG Co 16 Inf July 22-18 Olsen, Alva F. 43,610 Olsen, Alva F. 43,610 Corp Co I 16 Inf July 31-18 Corp Co I 16 Inf July 31-18 Pvt Co B 1st Brig MG Bn May 2-18 Pvt Co B 1st Brig Ort, John A. 15,556 Ort, John A. 15,556 MG Bn May 2-18 Reed, Irvin O 1,025,719 Reed, Irvin O 1,025,719 Pvt Id Co H 34 Inf Nov. 2-18 Pvt Id Co H 34 Inf Nov. 2-18 Rousey, Paul M. 915,589 Pvt Id 7Engr MedDet Dec. 8-18 Rousey, Paul M. 915,589 Pvt Id 7Engr MedDet Dec. 8-18 Stucky, Arthur 2,395,407 Stucky, Arthur 2,395,407 Pvt Co A 7 Inf July 16-18 Pvt Co A 7 Inf July 16-18 Stukas, Wm. 43,066 Stukas, Wm. 43,066 Pvt Id Co F 16 Inf Oct. 2-18 Pvt Id Co F 16 Inf Oct. 2-18 Taylor, Robert B 564,904 Taylor, Robert B 564,904 Pvt Btry B 17 FA Sept. 11-18 Pvt Btry B 17 FA Sept. 11-18 Thompson, Sam'l Nicholas. 124,211 Thompson, Sam'l Nicholas. 124,211 Pvt CoC5FBnSgC June 17-18 Pvt CoC5FBnSgC June 17-18 Taylor, Verlin W 224,634 Taylor, Verlin W 224,634 Corp Btry C 5 FA Sept. 2-18 Corp Btry C 5 FA Sept. 2-18 White: Inducted into National Army or Assigned thereto upon Induction Alley, Lance 2,181,350 Alley, Lance 2,181,350 Corp Co B 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 Corp Co B 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 Baatz, Herman Frederick ,847,232 Baatz, Herman Frederick ,847,232 Pvt Co G 355 Inf Nov. 3-18 Pvt Co G 355 Inf Nov. 3-18 Babb, James E. 3,310,466 Babb, James E. 3,310,466 Pvt Co K 352 Inf Nov. 6-18 Pvt Co K 352 Inf Nov. 6-18 Beck, Reuben 2,213,801 Beck, Reuben 2,213,801 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 23-18 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 23-18 Benham, Thomas E. 2,845,994 Benham, Thomas E 2,845,994 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Bernert, Joseph 2,213,795 Bernert, Joseph 2,213,795 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 6-18 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 6-18 Bettenhausen, William 2,195,449 Bettenhausen, William 2,195,449 Pvt CoG314AmTn Nov. 7-18 Pvt CoG314AmTn Nov. 7-18 Blatny, Jacob A. 2,213,806 Blatny, Jacob A. 2,213,806 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Boeckner, Henry J 2,314,052 Boeckner, Henry J 2,314,052 Pvt Co C 23 Inf June 28-18 Pvt Co C 23 Inf June 28-18 Bokemper, Anton 2,213,808 Bokemper, Anton 2,213,808 Pvt Co B 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Pvt Co B 4 Inf Oct. 16-18 Bossard, Harry Vern 2,193,795 Bossard, Harry Vern 2,193,795 Pvt CoC314FSgBn Aug. 11-18 Pvt CoC314FSgBn Aug. 11-18 Boudar, Emil 2,175,019 Boudar, Emil 2,175,019 Pvt Co E 355 Inf Oct. 26-18 Pvt Co E 355 Inf Oct. 26-18 Brown, Ralph Albert 2,847,188 Brown, Ralph Albert 2,847,188 Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Chadwick, William O. 2,181,745 Chadwick, William O. 2,181,745 Sgt Co G 30 Inf Sept. 5-18 Sgt Co G 30 Inf Sept. 5-18 Cochran, Thomas M. 2,181,262 Bglr Co A 355 Inf Aug. 14-18 Cochran, Thomas M. 2,181,262 Bglr Co A 355 Inf Aug. 14-18 Colling, Mathias H. 2,213,860 Colling, Mathias H. 2,213,860 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 28-18 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 28-18 Crigler, James W. 4,002,529 Crigler, James W. 4,002,529 Pvt Co E 11 Inf Nov. 5-18 Pvt Co E 11 Inf Nov. 5-18 Crosier, Waldo Henry 2,213,864 Crosier, Waldo Henry 2,213,864 Pvt MG Co 4 Inf Pvt MG Co 4 Inf Dainton, Chester Isaac 2,213,866 Dainton, Chester Isaac 2,213,866 Pvt Co B 4 Inf Oct. 18-18 Pvt Co B 4 Inf Oct. 18-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Debrunner, Francis L. 2,181,266 Pvtlcl Co A 365 Inf Sept. 9-18 Dopp, Benjamin R. 2,847,998 Pvt Co K 355 Inf Sept. 23-18 Fankhauser, Charles F 1,417,599 Pvt Co C 101 Inf Oct. 2-18 Fassmacht, Harry W 240,845 Pvt Co E 103 Inf June 17-18 Fehrs, Peter John 2,182,088 Pvt Co A 128 Inf Aug. 4-18 Fisher, Henry S. 105,271 Pvt Co A 2 MG Bn Aug. 17-18 Fulsos, Neri H. 2,213,898 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 26-18 Garretson, Jesse E. 937,504 Pvt Med Det 58 Inf Aug. 8-18 Gestrine, Frank S. 2,182,378 Pvt Co D 137 Inf July 24-18 Gold, Harvey Edward 2,193,721 Sgt CoC314FSgBn Nov. 16-18 Graham, Samuel N. 658,939 Pvt Co C 59 Inf Oct. 6-18 Hagelin, Paul A. 2,179,380 Corp CoC341MGBn Nov. 2-18 Hansen, Jens 1,419,103 Pvt Co K 59 Inf Oct. 6-18 Harman, John D. 2,180,579 Sgt CoC341MGBn Sept. 24-18 Harmon, James C. 937,629 Pvt Co I 328 Inf Sept. 16-18 Harvey, Isaac J. 2,847,216 Pvt Co H 355 Inf Oct. 6-18 Helzer, Jacob 2,847,980 Pvt Co K 355 Inf U Hennings, Fred D. 2,308,655 Pvt Co G 163 Inf June 3-18 Hurt, Edward 2,213,969 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 29-18 Hurt, Paul George 2,180,923 Pvt Hq Co 355 Inf Aug. 13-18 Johonnsen, John H 2,181,301 Corp Co A 355 Inf Aug. 10-18 Johnson, Segfred 0. 2,213,989 Pvt Co F 4 Inf Oct. 14-18 Kailey, John R 50,784 Pvt Co F 23 Inf July 13-18 Kessler, James P. 937,905 Pvt Med Det 23 Inf Nov. 4-18 Knobel, Roy D. 2,847,866 Pvt Co K 358 Inf Sept. 16-18 Knudson, Olvin H. 2,214,017 Pvt Co K 4 Inf Oct. 4-18 Kolling, William 1,418,835 Corp Co M 125 Inf Oct. 9-18 Krupinsky, Archie 2,181,274 Corp Co A 355 Inf Oct. 1-18 Larson, Ernest G. O. 2,214,022 Pvt Hq Co 4 Inf Oct. 2-18 Lenig, Harvey 1,418,842 Pvt Co G 125 Inf Oct. 12-18 Lewis, Taylor E. 2,200,418 Sgt Co L 355 Inf Sept. 30-18 Lovelady, Grant 2,213,048 Pvt Co K 353 Inf Nov. 5-18 Lovell, Norman E. 2,198,563 Pvt CoD341MGBn Sept. 14-18 Lyons, Irvan B. 1,418,849 Pvt Co M 125 Inf Oct. 10-18 McAuliffe, Clinton 1,418,519 Corp Co K 110 Inf Nov. 10-18 McCracken, Charles 2,181,307 Corp Co M 128 Inf Sept. 24-18 McKin, Elza Clifford 2,847,182 S,?t CoB340MGBn Nov. 5-18 McLain, John B. 2,846,398 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 McVey, Charles Franklin__2,178,708 Pvt CoA341MgBn Oct. 31-18 Mann, Louis H. 2,177,182 Pvt Co E 355 Inf Nov. 7-18 Martin, Charles E. 2,845,832 Bglr Co H 355 Inf Nov. 4-18 Martin, Charlie Marion 2,181,580 Pvt Co,H 137 Inf Oct. 1-18 Matya, Andrew _l,420,031 Pvt Co K 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Melton, Buff E. . . „ ... .2,181,275 Corp Co A 365 Inf Aug. 10-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 79 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Mende, Clarence Amandus 2,180,959 Sgt Hq Co 355 Inf Sept. 13-18 Michie, John 2,181,256 Corp Co A 355 Inf Aug. 16-18 Miefert, Frank M 240,668 Pvt Co C 103 Inf July 22-18 Miller, Peter 2,845,921 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Sept. 14-18 Montello, Mike 2,137,414 Pvt Co C 358 Inf Sept. 12-18 Mrsny, Frank J. 1,417,331 Pvt Co F 165 Inf Oct. 23-18 Nachtman, Frank 2,181,893 Pvt Id Co F 355 Inf Oct. 23-18 Nelson, Adolph J. 1,418,861 Pvt Co H 58 Inf Aug. 5-18 Nissen, Jens Alex Wm. 2,202,517 Corp Co B 355 Inf Nov. 6-18 Norman, Earl P 2,214,256 Pvt Co F 4 Inf July 25-18 Oddo, Tony 2,114,350 Pvt Btry E 18 FA Oct. 28-18 Olsen, Clarence 2,197,168 Pvt Co F 355 Inf Dec. 2-18 Palmer, Harry C. 2,181,422 Sgt Co B 355 Inf Nov. 7-18 Paul, Edward Raymond 2,208,183 Pvt Co A 355 Inf Aug. 10-18 Peck, Frederick L. 2,180,383 Corp CoA341MGBn Nov. 3-18 Piper, Ralph A 2,847,354 Pvt Id Co B 355 Inf Sept. 14-18 Poeppelmier, Reinhard F. 2,214,109 Pvt Co F 4 Inf Aug. 4-18 Pohlman, Albert H. 2,214,110 Pvt Co G 4 Inf Aug. 4-18 Province, Clarence I 2,214,114 Pvt Hq Co 4 Inf Oct. 17-18 Rabes, Jens C. 938,638 Wag Arab Co Hosp Camp 38 6th Sn Tn Sept. 22-18 Racobs, Dan Bryan 2,182,403 Corp Co H 355 Inf Sept. 17-18 Radant, Oscar Albert 2,846,737 Pvt Id Co M 355 Inf Oct. 22-18 Rauscher, Richard 2,202,345 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Sept. 20-18 Reed, Roy C 2,182,142 S,gt Co I 355 Inf Dec 31-18 Rieke, Henry William 2,214,129 Corp Co B 4 Inf Oct. 6-18 Rish, Joseph Clark 2,847,197 Pvt Co H 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Robert, Emil 2,214,134 Pvt Id Co D 4 Inf July 22-18 Roberts, Howard 1,628,229 Pvt Co L 30 Inf Oct. 30-18 Rooney, John P. 2,180,451 Pvt CoC341MGBn Nov. 18-18 Corp Co I 9 Inf Nov. 8-18 Pvt Co I 9 Inf Nov. 7-18 Pvt Id Co F 4 Inf Oct. 25-18 Rose, Thomas M 1,417,348 Ross, Roy C 1,417,349 Rother, Frank E 2,214,123 Schinck, Frank John 2,846,690 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Schneidermiller, John 2,180,668 Pvt Co D 8 Mg Bn Oct. 23-18 Sheehan, John P. 2,198,640 Pvt Co F 314 Eng Nov. 21-18 Simonson, Gaylor T. 1,419,471 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Sept. 1-18 Slezak, Edward 2,208,207 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Nov. 6-18 Smith, Albert 1,419,472 Pvt Co C 128 Inf Aug. 30-18 Pvt Co D 4 Inf Oct. 5-18 Southard, Ernest James 2,214,192 Spicknall, Walter R 1,420,049 Pvt Co F 126 Inf Aug. 30-18 Srutek, John 1,418,577 Pvt Co F 59 Inf Oct. 1-18 Stellges, William Deedrich 2,357,967 Pvt Co C 4 Inf Oct. 2-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Steven, William A. 1,418,256 Pvt Co B 101 Inf Sept. 12-1S Stone, Fred 2,715,952 Pvt Hq Co 314 Inf Oct. 3-18 Stone, Lynn 2347,591 Pvt Co C 355 Inf Nov. 5-18 Stone, Walter A. 2,181,321 Corp Co B 128 Inf Sept. 2-1&amp; Stroh, Henry 2,847,143 Corp CoB341MGBn Dec. 1-18 Stroup, Lee Orval 2,214,188 Corp Co C 4 Inf July 29-18 Taylor, Arthur Clifton 2,195,740 Sgt CoB341MGBn Nov. 25-18 Teigeler, Henry Jr. 2,181,252 Sgt Co A 355 Inf Aug. 11-18 Tousch, Frank 2,181,018 Corp Hq Co 355 Inf Oct. 27-18 Tracy, Victor Andrew 2,845,826 Pvt Id Co G 353 Inf Oct. 23-18 Turnbull, August W. 2,181,245 Sgt Co A 355 Inf Aug. 11-18 Tyler, James M 2,214,210 Pvt Co G 4 Inf Dec. 11-18 Vanskiver, Frank 1,418,888 Pvt Co D 125 Inf Oct. 13-18 Voss, Remmer H. 2,845,948 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Sept. 15-18 Walker, William Harvey —2,181,020 Corp Hq Co 355 Inf Aug. 13-18 Warren, Clarence I 2,182,557 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Nov. 8-18 Weyerts, Tony 2,847,994 Pvt Co K 355 Inf Nov. 14-18 Whidden, William L 1,420,387 Pvt Co D 58 Inf Aug. 14-18 Wilcox, Lemuel R 2,214,237 Pvt Hq Co 4 Inf Oct. 19-18 Wilkinson, Robert 2,181,195 Pvt Co A 137 Inf Oct. 11-18 Williams, Robert Loring— 2,846,720 Pvt Co A 355 Inf Sept. 5-18 Wills, Robert L 2,181,608 Corp Co D 355 Inf Nov. 9-18 Yund, Henry R. 2,847,900 Pvt Co H 355 Inf Oct. 24-18 MEMBERS OF AMERICAN EXPEDITIONARY FORCES WHO ENTERED SERVICE FROM STATE OF NEBRASKA AND DIED OF DISEASE OF OTHER CAUSE OFFICERS Palis, Charles C. Col. .104 FA (Off Div) Mch. 14-19 Fetterman, Albert D. Maj. Sturdevant, Fred F. Capt._. -IGD Feb. 10-19 _127 FA Oct. 10-18 Cadwallader, Charles F. 1st Lt.__. Connell, Robert D. 1st Lt _809 Pion Inf Dec. 3-19 _AS Bin Sec Oct. 24-18 _Hq 186 Inf Brig July 25-18 Harries, Warren G. 1st Lt Huntington, Merle W. 1st Lt. Peterson, William B. 1st Lt. _Serv Pk B 1 Army Feb. 16-19 _Av Dec Sig Res C July 2-18 Sorenson, Soren C. 1st Lt. MP Det 3 Army C June 1-19 Breese, Winfield S. 2nd Lt Det Pst Pilots As Aero Dec. 19-18 Martin, Ralph E. 2nd Lt 9 MG Bn Dec. 18-18 Shillington, Waldo E. 2nd Lt Pilot Air Service Dec. 6-18 ENLISTED MEN White: Entered Service 'with National Guard or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment or Induction Alden, Ormal M 1,438,126 Corp Co F 109 Engr Mch. 22- 1» Clark, Roy F. 1,419,938 Pvt Id Co F 127 Inf Oct. 27-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 81 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Clifton, Jess D._ 1,435,108 Pvt Id Btry C 127 FA Oct. 12-18 Conser, Arthur M 1,419,049 Corp Co D 125 Inf Feb. 21-19 Dowling, William D 1,435,698 Corp Btry C 127 FA Nov. 15-18 Dugan, John P 1,438,215 Pvt Co F 109 Engs Dec. 13-18 Dusenberry, Eldert A. 1,419,089 Pvt Co M 58 Inf Sept. 19-18 Foutch, Glenn W 460,651 Pvt Eng Wash. Bks Sept Repl Draft Co 1 Nov. 11-18 Fraley, Charles A. Sgt Id 166 F Hosp Jan. 4-18 Gandee, Vane W.-l 1,418,456 Pvt Co A 101 Inf Oct. 22-18 Gustus, Vanner A. 1,420,005 Pvt Co L 59 Inf Oct. 5-18 Hare, Warren 1,419,004 Corp Co H 134 Inf Dec. 4-18 Havluy, James A. 140,335 Wag Sp Co 147 FA Jan. 25-19 Jirousek, Matt A. 1,411,258 Sgt CoC126MGBn Sept. 26-18 Johnson, Harry 1,411,298 Pvt Id CoC126MGBn Oct. 6-18 Knowlton, Edward L 1,434,225 Co"p Hq Co 127 FA Oct. 13-18 Kriz, Joseph F. 1,436,771 Pvt Id Hq Co 109 En,g Sept. 25-18 McCarthy, Joseph A 1,434,246 Pvt Hq Co 127 Fa Oct. 14-18 McFate, Ralph W 1,420,033 Corp Co L 59 Inf Nov. 22-18 Madsen, Jasper E 1,418,761 Pvt Id 2nd Cps School Det Sept. 28-18 Meidl, Franke 1,435,821 Pvt Id Sup Co 127 FA Nov. 28-18 Michal, John 1,459,207 Sp Co 140 Inf Mch. 21-18 Wag Michelson, Milton 1,266,424 Sgt 14 Co 3 Mot Mch Reg Sig C Nov. 7-18 Morley, Newman Glen 1,226,424 Sgt 14 Co 3 Mot Mch Reg Sig 6 Nov. 7-18 Parson, Edward W 1,438,259 Pvt Co F 109 Engr Oct. 2-18 Pierson, Arthur H 48,605 Corp Co M 18 Inf June 5-18 Smith, Fred S 1,441,783 109Engr Tn Sept. 27-18 Pvt Smith, Sidney J i 1,417,046 Pvt Inf Camp Cody June Repl Draft Co 4 July 19-18 Solomon, George F 1,434,443 Pvt Sup Co 127 Fa Oct. 13-18 Wells, Claud 1,437,862 Sgt Co E 109 Engr Mch. 12-19 White: Enlisted in Regular Army or Assigned Thereto Upon Induction. Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Abart, Henry H 2,145,232 Sgt Md Dt 339 FA Dec. 6-18 Babonas, Joseph 203,804 Hs Co E 2 Div Am Tn ' Feb. 9-19 Bray, Garnet L. 1,336,551 Ck 875 Aer Sq April 30-19 Cady, Fayette G :— 941,286 Pvt BtyCo388QMC Jan. 16-19 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Capron, Maurice I Capron, Maurice L_ Pvt Btry F G Regt CAC Dec. 9-17 Pvt Btry F G Regt CAC Dec. 9-17 Cates, Edwain L 830,538 Cates, Edwain L 830,538 Pvt Id Btry B 69 CAC Feb. 7-19 Pvt Id Btry B 69 CAC Feb. 7-19 Clark, John B 564,632 Clark, John B 564,632 Pvt Co B 4 Engr April 11-19 Pvt Co B 4 Engr April 11-19 Cullip, Clarence S 21,980 Cullip, Clarence S 21,980 Pvt Id 88AerSqSigC May 15-19 Pvt Id 88AerSqSigC May 15-19 Cunningham, Norman W 728,869 Cunningham, Norman W 728,869 Ck Btry P 75 CAC Oct. 22-18 Ck Btry P 75 CAC Oct. 22-18 Durham, Roy 0 1,081,959 Durham, Roy 0 1,081,959 Pvt BtryC345FA Sept. 25-18 Pvt BtryC345FA Sept. 25-18 Ensley, James H. Ensley, James H.. Pvt Id Co K 23 Inf June 28-18 Pvt Id Co K 23 Inf June 28-18 Gauvreau, Alfred L 14,765 Gauvreau. Alfred L 14,765 Sgt MD Camp Hosp 66 Ward 6 Nov. 12-18 Sgt MD Camp Hosp 66 Ward 6 Nov. 12-18 Geren, Thomas J 1,072,851 Geren, Thomas J 1,072,851 Pvt 660 Aer Sup Sq SigC Feb. 28-19 Pvt 660 Aer Sup Sq SigC Feb. 28-19 Graves, Bert A 153,609 Graves, Bert A 153,609 Pvt CoClstA-ABn Sept. 11-18 Pvt CoClstA-ABn Sept. 11-18 Hicks, Earl R. 501,058 Hicks, Earl R. 501,058 Pvt 260AerServSq Sig C Nov. 11-18 Pvt 260AerServSq Sig C Nov. 11-18 Hotchkiss, John P 2,130,321 Hotchkiss, John P 2,130,321 Sgt Co B Serv Bn 533 Engrs Oct. 18-18 Sgt Co B Serv Bn 533 Engrs Oct. 18-18 Hunt, James H. 1,405,320 Hunt, James H. 1,405,320 Pvt Id Btry E 79 FA Nov. 29-18 Pvt Id Btry E 79 FA Nov. 29-18 Ingraham, Roy E 934,423 Ingraham, Roy E 934,423 Wag 40 Amb Co 6 Wag 40 Amb Co 6 Sn Tn Nov. 24-18 Sn Tn Nov. 24-18 Jensen, Neils P. N. 517,910 Jensen, Neils P. N. 517,910 Pvt Md Dept Evac Hosp No. 17 Dec. 25-18 Pvt Md Dept Evac Hosp No. 17 Dec. 25-18 KilKore, William V Kilgore, William V, Pvt Id Btry D 15 FA Jan. 18-18 Pvt Id Btry D 15 FA Jan. 18-18 Kissane, Jerry J 817,975 Kissane, Jerry J 817,975 Pvt Co B 52 Am Tn Aug. 17-18 Pvt Co B 52 Am Tn Aug. 17-18 Kladek, James 2,397,146. Kladek, James 2,397,146. Sgt 5th Co 4 Mot Mch Reg Sig C Sept. 19-18 Sgt 5th Co 4 Mot Mch Reg Sig C Sept. 19-18 McDonald, Willis E 509,564 McDonald, Willis E 509,564 Pvt Btry C 49 CAC Feb. 15-19 Pvt Btry C 49 CAC Feb. 15-19 Miller, Harry S 253,027 Miller, Harry S 253,027 Ck 107 Aer Sq Nov. 3-18 Ck 107 Aer Sq Nov. 3-18 Nelson, Carl A 563,269 Nelson, Carl A 563,269 Pvt Btry C 17 FA Oct. 16-18 Pvt Btry C 17 FA Oct. 16-18 Peterson, Andrew Else 965,293 Peterson, Andrew Else 965,293 Pvt 831 Aer Repr Pvt 831 Aer Repr Sq Sig C Nov. 26-18 Sq Sig C Nov. 26-18 Peterson, Reuben S 157,392 Peterson, Reuben S 157,392 Pvt Co F 2 Engr Feb. 6-19 Pvt Co F 2 Engr Feb. 6-19 Quisenberry, William M— 129,722 Quisenberry, William M— 129,722 Corp Co A 1 Prov Corp Co A 1 Prov Regt MP Feb. 28-19 Regt MP Feb. 28-19 Robbins, Greeley 30,969 Robbins, Greeley 30,969 Sgt 800 Aer Sq April 26-19 Sgt 800 Aer Sq April 26-19 Rosencrans, Guy W 252,668 Rosencrans, Guy W 252,668 Pvt 153AerSqSgC Oct. 16-18 Pvt 153AerSqSgC Oct. 16-18 Syre, Eric 0. Syre, Eric 0. Pvt 106 Aer Sq Dec. 23-17 Pvt 106 Aer Sq Dec. 23-17 Sutherland, John _. 564,903 Sutherland, John __ 564,903 S,gt Btry B 16 FA April 15-19 S,gt Btry B 16 FA April 15-19 Wilson, Harold Alva 918,551 Wilson, Harold Alva 918,551 Pvt Co A 110 Am Tn April 4-19 Pvt Co A 110 Am Tn April 4-19 Cilson, Harold L 940,499 right, Charles R 500,388 Wilson, Harold L 940,499 Pvt QMC Bkry Co 343 Nov. 23-18 Pvt QMC Bkry Co 343 Nov. 23-18 Wright, Charles R 500,388 Sgt CAC Fort Bar - rancas Sept. Repl Draft Unit 2 Oct. 11-18 Sgt CAC Fort Bar- rancas Sept. Repl Draft Unit 2 Oct. 11-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 83 r White: Inducted into National Army or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment. Rank Organization at Date of Rank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Name Serial No. Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Pvt CoB338MGBn Oct. 17-18 Adams, John L 3,228,671 Adams, John L. 3,228,671 Pvt CoB338MGBn Oct. 17-18 Adolfson, Arthur E 2,196,481 Adolfson, Arthur E 2,196,481 Pvt 355 F Hosp Co 314 Sn Tn Dec. 25-18 Pvt 355 F Hosp Co 314 Sn Tn Dec. 25-18 Alderson, Leonard C 2,180,323 Alderson, Leonard C 2,180,323 Corp CoC341MGBn Feb. 23-19 Corp CoC341MGBn Feb. 23-19 Alford, James Alford, James _. Pvt Co C 7 Bn 20 Pvt Co C 7 Bn 20 Engrs Feb. 27-18 Engrs Feb. 27-18 Amsberry, Ora B 2,181,611 Amsberry, Ora B 2,181,611 Set Co D 355 Inf Sept 22-18 Sgt Co D 355 Inf Sept 22-18 Wag Sup Co 4 Inf Oct. 31-18 Wag Sup Co 4 Inf Oct. 31-18 Anderson, Eddie 2,213,767 Anderson, Eddie 2,213,767 Antram, Clarence Lewis 3,010,620 Antram, Clarence Lewis 3,010,620 Pvt Id Engrs Camp Pvt Id Engrs Camp Forrest Cas Co I Oct. 31-18 Forrest Cas Co I Oct. 31-18 Applebee, Roy Alfred 2,847,249 Applebee, Roy Alfred 2,847,249 Pvt Co H 355 Inf Feb. 15-19 Pvt Co H 355 Inf Feb. 16-19 Augustin, John C 2,846,202 Augustin, John C 2,846,202 Pvt CoC341MGBn Dec. 29-18 Pvt CoC341MGBn Dec. 29-18 Bailey, Erwin M 3,230,261 Bailey, Erwin M 3,230,261 Pvt Btry C 339 FA Oct. 23-18 Pvt Btry C 339 FA Oct. 23-18 Bailey, Walter E. 3,954,704 Bailey, Walter E. 3,954,704 Pvt Hq Co 33 Inf Oct. 6-18 Pvt Hq Co 33 Inf Oct. 6-18 Bauer, Jacob G. 980,275 Bauer, Jacob G. 980,275 Pvt MdDptFtRiley Repl Unit 47 Oct. 2-18 Pvt MdDptFtRiley Repl Unit 47 Oct. 2-18 Pvt Mg Co 355 Inf Oct. 4-11 Pvt Mg Co 355 Inf Oct. 4-1S Behrends, George H. 3,953,456 Behrends, George H. 3,953,456 Beisner, Fred William 2,195,668 Beisner, Fred William 2,195,668 Wag Co D 110 Am Wag Co D 110 Am Tn April 20-19 Tn April 20-19 Belz, Fred P 3,228,627 Belz, Fred P 3,228,627 Pvt Btry E 339 Fa Oct. 27-18 Pvt Btry E 339 Fa Oct. 27-18 Benhart, Edwin Alexander 2,213,798 Benhart, Edwin Alexander 2,213,798 Wag Sup Co 4 Inf Oct. 7-18 Wag Sup Co 4 Inf Oct. 7-18 Bennington, Ralph A 2,181,649 Bennington, Ralph A 2,181,649 Corp Co D 355 Inf Sept. 28-18 Corp Co D 355 Inf Sept. 28-18 Berger, Albert G 3,307,218 Berger, Albert G 3,307,218 Pvt Sup Co 337 FA Oct 21-18 Pvt Sup Co 337 FA Oct 21-18 Bowers, Ardra D 3,913,508 Corp 305 Adv Anml TranwDepQMCNov. 13-18 Bowers, Ardra D 3,913,508 Corp 305 Adv Anml TranwDepQMCNov. 13-18 Brown, Andrew J 2,845,841 Brown, Andrew J 2,845,841 Pvt 353 Amb Co 314 Pvt 353 Amb Co 314 Sn Tn Nov. 20-18 SnTn Nov. 20-18 Buckingham, Earl E 3,228,500 Buckingham, Earl E 3,228,500 Pvt Btry C 338 FA Oct. 11-18 Pvt Btry C 338 FA Oct. 11-18 Burdick, James N. 2,113,833 Burdick, James N. 2,113,833 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 1-18 Pvt Co E 4 Inf Oct. 1-18 Burgenger, Fred 3,228,320 Burgenger, Fred 3,228,320 Pvt 351 Amb Co 313 Pvt 351 Amb Co 313 Sn Tn Oct. 28-18 Sn Tn Oct. 28-18 Burgner, Raymond F 3,961,468 Burgner, Raymond F 3,961,468 Pvt Co I 28 Inf Oct. 19-18 Pvt Co I 28 Inf Oct. 19-18 Burrowes, John B. 1,876,893 Burrowes, John B. 1,876,893 Pvt Id Co C 318 F Sg Pvt Id Co C 318 F Sg Bn Oct. 17-18 Bn Oct. 17-18 Butterfield, Archie W 3,308,379 Butterfield, Archie W 3,308,379 Pvt Co G 350 Inf Oct. 21-18 Pvt Co G 350 Inf Oct. 21-18 Campbell, George W. 936,999 Campbell, George W. .... 936,999 Pvt Id Med Dept Port Riley Repl Draft Det 3 Oct. 11-18 Pvt Id Med Dept Port Riley Repl Draft Det 3 Oct. 11-18 Carder, Paul L. 3,308,279 Carder, Paul L. 3,308,279 Pvt CoB339MGBn Oct. 11-18 Pvt CoB339MGBn Oct. 11-18 •Cattron, Wesley M 3,961,408 Cattron, Wesley M 3,961,408 Pvt Co I 335 Inf Oct. 18-18 Pvt Co I 336 Inf Oct. 18-18 Cerr, Lewis 2,213,844 Cerr, Lewis 2,213,844 Pvt Co C 4 Inf Feb. 1-1» Pvt Co C 4 Inf Feb. 1-1» Chase, Walter 2,194,422 Chase, Walter 2,194,422 Pvt Co E 356 Inf April 16-19 Pvt Co E 356 Inf April 15-19 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Clary, Rolla 3,954,033 Pvt CasCoBTnkC Nov. 7-18 Coffman. Paul 2,845,962 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Sept. 8-18 Conover, Glen Ellis 2,180,509 Pvt CoAlUMGBn Nov. 4-18 Cooper, Robert H— 3,961,414 Pvt CasCoBTnkC Nov. 6-18 Copeland, Clinton A 2,277,368 Pvt MG Co 362 Inf July 23-18 Corleu, August 1,416,653 Ck Co D 102 Inf Jan. 4-18 Creps, Louis W. 3,230,178 Pvt CoC313Engr Oct. 7-18 Crews, Chauncey 3,309,672 Pvt Id Co L 4 Bn 22 Engrs Men 12-19 Crim, James C. 3,228,253 Pvt Btry B 338 FA Oct. 15-18 Crippen, Vincent L 3,228,728 Pvt Btry F 338 PA Oct. 12-18 Czerwonka, Vincent 3,310,332 Pvt CoF56PionInf Sept. 29-18 Dale, True Fred 2,845,864 Pvt Co G 355 Inf Feb. 7-19 Dance, Harold A 3,230,098 Pvt CoA339MGBn Oct. 19-18 Detlefsen, Harry 3,308,883 Pvt Co G 350 Inf Feb. 14-19 Doescher, Edward 2,182,164 Corp Co I 355 Inf Men. 24-19 Eacritt, John A. 3,227,982 Pvt Id Btry C 337 FA Oct. 27-18 Egx, Charles J. 3,961,137 Pvt Co C 335 Inf Oct. 20-18 Ehlers, William 3,955,167 Pvt Sig C Ft Lea- venworth Sept. Repl Draft Co2 Oct. 7-18 Elbert, George 3,230,106 Corp Btry C 339 FA Oct. 31-18 Elder, Guy E 2,114,288 Corp Btry E 335 FA Oct. 30-18 Engle, Walter L. 2,181,392 Pvt Co B 355 Inf Feb. 19-19 Evans, Samuel O 3,228,405 Pvt Btry C 338 FA Nov. 3-18 Fairchild, Fred H 3,961,329 Pvt CoA320MGBn Nov. 22-18 Fanner, John F 240,912 Pvt Co B 7 Inf Oct. 11-18 Fisher, Jesse M 3,230,219 Pvt CoD339MgBn Oct. 9-18 Fix. Willard L 3,953,771 Pvt Co C 333 Inf Oct. 12-18 Foltz, Maxmillion Joseph—2,182,058 Corp Co M 355 Inf Jan. 31-19 Franm, William H 3,951,555 Pvt I Co Ft Lawton Sept Repl Drft Oct. 17-18 Frederick, Harrison B 980,295 Pvt MdDeptFtRiley Repl Unit 47 Oct. 13-18 Garland, Raymond A. 1,416,959 Pvt Co A 162 Inf Aug. 8-18 Gaston, Alfa G 3,229,111 Pvt Co G 352 Inf Oct. 9-18 Gauger, George 2,230,163 Pvt Btry C 339 FA Oct. 20-18 Gilshannon, Thomas A, 3,953,917 Pvt Co H 138 Inf Jan. 22-19 Glantz, Peter 3,953,582 Pvt Co F 334 Inf Oct. 8-18 Goldware, Morris 3,312,539 Corp 344 Butch Co QMC Oct. 18-18 Graves, Julius E. 3,228,543 Pvt Btry E 338 FA Oct. 11-18 Gunn, Leon B 3,280,123 Pvt CoA339MGBn Oct. 20-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 85 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Gyllenstone, Arvid I. 3,811,752 Fvt 10 Co Sept Repl Draft Oct. 4-18 Haase, John 2,213,925 Corp Co D 4 Inf Oct. 31-18 Hagel, Paul W 240,860 Pvt Co D 104 Inf Dec. 21-18 Hand, Robert W. 2,699,340 Hansen, Ernest B 3,953,681 Pvt Co C 113 En^r May 24-19 Pvt Co F 335 Inf Oct. 8-18 Happe, Joseph F. 3,313,520 Pvt CoA339MGBn Oct. 22-18 Harris, Clark W. -3,223,187 Pvt Co F 352 Inf Oct. 5-18 Harris, Dean -1,435,223 Pvt Btry D 127 FA Nov. 24-18 Hays, Merren C._ _2,197,012 Pvt MD 353 Inf Jan. 17-19 Heller, Victor -2,198,049 Pvt CoB341MGBn Feb. 19-19 Hendrickson, Arthur C. -3,961,469 Pvt ici Vet Hosp 17 Jan. 30-19 Hensley, Roy C._ .3,958,822 Corp Co D 4 Inf Oct. 31-18 Hill, Henry A. ._ 856,156 Pvt 318 Engr Engr Tn June 26-18 Hirt, Dave _3,228,453 Pvt 396 Cas CO F A U assgd Oct. 2-18 Holdridge, Ira ¥.__ 1,690,007 Pvt Co C 317 F Sig Bn Oct. 6-18 Horst, Henry G._ 3,310,793 Pvt Co F 313 Am Tn Oct. 20-18 Houael, Harlan B. -3,435,987 -3,308,214 -2,847,318 .3,435,751 .3,953.663 -3,132,845 Pvt MG Co 333 Inf Nov. 25-18 Humphrey, George W. _ Irish, Melvin H Pvt CoF313SupTn Oct. 20-18 Pvt Co C 355 Inf Sept. 19-18 Jackson, Ralph L. _. Jensen, Vilhelm P., Johnson, Carl Pvt Hq Co 362 Inf Oct. 28-18 Pvt Co H 335 Inf Oct. 13-18 Pvt Co L 109 Inf Oct. 1-18 Johnson ,Emil 980,743 Pvt 48UnitFtRiley Kas Repl Draft Oct. 14-18 Johnson, Hjalmer B. __. Johnson, Josef Theodore Johnson, Val -3,308,335 .2,182,198 -2,846,008 _3,952,130 Pvt CoB337MGBn Oct. 26-18 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Feb. 4-19 Pvt CoK342MGBn Oct. 25-18 Jones, Floyd A. Pvt Vet' Hosp 16 Vet C Mch. 20-19 Kaiser, Walter Henry— Keil, Henry -2,213,997 -3,308,228 -2,182,201 .2,181,535 -3,230,030 ..2,182,113 -1,339,271 Wag 4 Inf Sup Co Feb. 24-19 Pvt Co A 109 AM Tn Oct. 8-18 Keiter, Charley Pvt Co B 137 Inf U Kellogg, Francis L Kennedy, William CL_. Kunzman, Jos. Richard. Lange, August W Pvt Co M 355 Inf Jan. 27-19 Pvt Btry C 339 PA Oct. 21-18 Pvt Co B 137 Inf Sept. 25-18 Pvt Id Aug. Av Repl Draft Sept. 28-18 Larson, Edwin Lee, Victor C- .3,228,288 -2,846,791 Pvt Co A 313 Engr Oct. 11-18 Sgt Co H 355 Inf Nov. 9-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No, Time of Death Death Lesehinsky, Armand J 3,228,188 Pvt Btry F 338 FA Oct. 19-18 Lewis, Harry Albert 2,182,116 Pvt Co D 137 Inf June 27-18 Liska, Frank W 3,228,601 Pvt Btry E 338 FA Oct. 10-18 Livingston, William R 3,228,387 Pvt Btry E 338 FA Oct. 11-18 Londberg, Alfred S 3,954,787 Pvt Co G 333 Inf Oct. 22-18 Long, Benjamin H 3,958,798 Pvt Co A 336 Inf Oct. 14-18 McCarthy, Edward J- 2,181,730 Corp Co E 355 Inf Feb. 13-19 McDonald, Hugh E. 3,436,200 Pvt CoC8Prov Vn Ord Dept Oct. 8-18 McEntaffer, Harry M 2,180,040 Pvt CoC341MGBn Dec. 7-18 McFarland, Jess 3,228,390 Pvt FA Unassgd Oct. 4-18 Mclntosh, Dan 2,181,543 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Oct. 9-18 McKeon, Francis J 3,227,988 Corp Btry D 338 PA Oct. 16-18 McKibbon, Everett L 3,999,229 Pvt Inf Camp Gor- don Sept. Repl Draft Co 14 Oct. 7-18 McMillen, Frank J 2,195,704 Set CoA314Sp Tn Sept. 15-18 MsMullen, Orlie C 3,310,926 Pvt CoF313AmTn Oct. 14-18 McNurlin, Walter B 3,310,372 Pvt CoC313AmTn Oct. 15-18 McWilliams, Eugene L Pvt CoC318Engrs May 27-18 Maly, Anton 3,961,132 Pvt Co B 33G Inf Oct. 13-18 Marlin, William P 396,145 Pvt 12SerCoSigC July 15-19 Marshall, John N. 500,260 Sgt Btry B 15 Fa Feb. 25-19 Martens, Hiram F 980,519 Corp Med Dept Ft Oct. 1-18 Riley Repl Unit 47 Martfield, William H. 3,228,481 Pvt Btry E 338 FA Oct. 14-18 Mathias, Oscar L 2,847,916 Pvt Co K 355 Inf Oct. 31-18 Metts, Kurtis J 3,230,055 Pvt Btry C 339 FA Oct. 20-18 Meyers, Harry Edward 2,177,904 Pvt Co E 314 Engr Mch. 11-19 Miller, Glenn 4,071,400 Pvt Co D 4 A-A Mg Bn Feb. 7-19 Miller, Merritt B 3,952,911 Pvt Co C 302 W Tank Bn Tn Nov. 15-18 Mills, Ira 3,953,798 Pvt Co C 336 Inf Oct. 22-18 Moneypenny, Fred R 211,953 Corp Co 3 O R S D June 17-19 Morgan, David R 3,955,176 Pvt 336 Inf Over- Seas Det No. 1 Oct. 21-18 Morrison, Glenn 3,228,984 Pvt Co B 350 Inf Oct. 9-18 Mudra, Vincent 3,955,112 Pvt Co D 364 Inf Oct. 21-18 Nash, Arthur W 2,687,134 Pvt Id 78 Co TC April 18-19 Nekolite, John M 3,308,562 Pvt Co C 352 Inf Oct. 6-18 Nelson, Fred W 8,228,685 Pvt Sup Co 338 FA Oct. 13-18 Nelson, Theodore Moma__8,961,216 Pvt Co D 336 Inf Oct. 19-18 Nicolaisen, Erwin Herbert 2,847,466 Pvt CoM 866 Inf Feb. 6-19 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 87 Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Nordquist, David 1,418,223 Pvt Co A 49 Inf NOV. 15-18 Northrop, Leslie N. 3,312,779 Pvt Sup Co 352 Inf Oct. 12-18 Ott, John H 2,181,169 Wag 355 Inf Sp Co Sept. 11-18 Overfeld, Henry 3,313,198 Pvt F Rem Sq 333 June 9-19 Pallas, Frank 3,951,034 Pvt Rents Requisi- tion &amp; Claims Serv Lst Army Jan. 24-19 Pendergast, Everett R 3,228,472 Pvt Btry P 338 PA Oct. 25-18 Peninger, Ira S- 2,179,707 Pvt Co E 355 Inf Oct. 21-18 Perry, Allie L 185,764 Pvt Co E 16 Engrs Mch. 14-19 Peters, Fred W 3,955,117 Pvt Co K 363 Inf Oct. 29-18 Peterson, Johannes S 3,312,098 Pvt Co L 352 Inf Oct. 15-18 Pfisterer, Emil J 3,436,391 Pvt 4 Co Reinforce- ment Det Ord Dept Oct. 14-18 Philips, Walter T 2,846,067 Pvt Co I 355 Inf Mch. 7-19 Pike, Elvin H. 3,310,880 Pvt CoE313AmTn Oct. 28-18 Porter, Lynn T 3,955,561 Pvt Co K 333 Inf Oct. 20-18 Powell, Nealy H. 980,686 Pvt Co K 118 Engr Nov. 22-18 Prellwitz, Herman 880,871 Pvt MdDeptPtRiley Repl Unit 47 Oct. 10-18 Prokof, Lewis 1,419,403 Pvt Co H 47 Inf Dec. 16-18 Rees, George W 3,230,114 Pvt CoB339MGBn Oct. 12-18 Remington, Claude A. 3,961,382 Pvt CasCoBTnkC Nov. 19-18 Richardson, John R 3,230,091 Pvt Id CoA339MGBn Oct. 13-18 Ridge, Forrest 3,312,913 Pvt Co B 351 Inf Oct. 4-18 Rogers, George F. 3,285,240 Pvt Co D 322 Inf Feb. 5-19 Root, Virgil L 980,558 Pvt MdDeptFtRiley Repl Draft Unit 48 Sept. 28-18 Ross, Elmer 1,418,569 Pvt Co K 106 Inf Dec. 5-18 Royal, Joe P 3,952,664 Pvt Seg Camp Fort Repl Draft Co I Oct. 7-18 Rudge, John M 3,230,079 Pvt Btry C 339 FA Oct 26-18 Sarber, Charles 0 3,228,924 Pvt Co E 350 Inf Oct. 16-18 Sauter, Gage G 938,799 Pvt MdDeptBH30 Oct. 24-18 Schmer, William G 3,229,045 Sgt Co C 355 Inf Oct. 10-18 Schreiber, Harry E 977,368 Sgt 10 Evac Hosp Med Dept Nov. 28-18 Severyn, Joseph F 3,228,371 Pvt Id CoC338MHBn Oct 1-18 Shepard, Claude E- 3,230,248 Pvt Hq Co 339 FA Oct. 7-18 Simpson, Frank H 3,230,171 Pvt Btry c 239 FA Oct. 23-18 Skala, George W 2,180,695 Sgt CoC341MGBn Nov. 1-18 Skow, Walter H, 3,312,786 Pvt 349 Arab Co 313 Sn Tn Oct. 17-18 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Slapnicka, John 3,951,867 Pvt Sig C Ft Lea ven worth Sept. Repl Draft Co 3 Oct. 6-18 398 Cas Co Oct. 2-18 Id Hq Tn 3rd Cps July 20-19 Co E 355 Inf Jan. 11-19 Sparks, George M 3,313,078 Pvt CoC313AmTn Oct. 7-18 Stankiewic, Francisek 3,448,349 Pvt MdDeptBH 81 Sept. 14-18 Stewart, George C 3,230,021 Pvt Btry C 339 FA Oct. 24-18 Stone, Lloyd E 3,230,223 Pvt Btry C 339 FA Oct. 18-18 Streeton, Charley V 3,230,157 Pvt Btry C 339 Pa Oct. 29-18 Sueper, Bernard 1,417,056 Pvt Id Inf Cmp Cody June Repl Draft Co 4 July 17-18 Sullivan, John Lawrence —2,182,490 Pvt Co M 355 Inf Nov. 13-18 Sundquist, Edwin A 3,313,598 Pvt Co E 313 Engr Oct. 8-18 Teleen, Albert L. 3,954,692 Pvt M Trk Co 536 M Sup Tn 426 Oct. 11-18 Pvt Co C 354 Inf Oct. 7-18 Terry, Ira R. 3,229,094 Theilen, John O 1,418,262 Pvt Co M 165 Inf Nov. 2-18 Trofholz, Julius O 3,228,349 Pvt Btry C 361 PA Oct. 7-18 Sgt Walker, Deane.C 3,176,027 Id Mob Hosp 2 Vet C Oct. 21-18 Walther, William 2,182,009 Pvt MG Co 137 Inf Oct. 6-18 Ward, John L 3,958,947 Pvt 79 SnSq84Div April 5-19 Waters, Howard M 3,954,722 Pvt Co M 333 Inf Oct. 29-18 Base Hosp 30 Oct. 22-18 Webb, Chester H 976,765 Pvt Clc Med Dept Fort Wehmer, Henry G 3,445,540 Riley Repl Draft Unit 48 Sept. 26-18 Weiger, Albert M 3,228,089 Pvt Btry E 338 FA Oct. 21-18 Weyerts, Henry G 3,436,261 Pvt Md Det 355 Inf Oct. 9-18 Willey, Rex W 3,313,633 Pvt CoF313Sp Tn Oct. 17-18 Woock, Frank P 3,125,628 Pvt CoD144MgBn Oct. 20-18 Young, Roland D- 1,418,289 Pvt Co E 69 Inf Nov. 20-18 White: Members of Reserve Corps Called Into Active Service. Bank Organization at Date of Time of Death Death Rank Organization at Date of Name Name Serial No. Serial No. Time of Death Death Brainard, William D 2,282,095 Brainard, William D 2,282,095 Sgt Co E 405 Tel Sgt Co E 405 Tel Bn Sig C Meh. 14-19 Wood, Ellsworth C 272,496 Sgt CoA 56 Engrs Aug. 8-18 Eian, Frank B 3,229,073 Pvt It, Edward H 2,314,755 Pvt ndker, Edward H 2,177,344 Pvt </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 Colored; Inducted Into National Army or Assigned Thereto Upon Enlistment. Rank Organization at Date of Name Serial No. Time of Death Death Cisco, George W 4,258,152 Corp Co F 805 Pion Inf Nov. 9-18 Ervin, Ernest J 3,847,052 Pvt Co D 816 Ron Inf Nov. 11-18 Furch, John H. —4,261,259 Corp Co I 806 Pion Inf Jan. 7-19 Libolt, Orin J._ 3,955,187 Pvt Graveyard Det U Apo. 714 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 90 SUMMARY OF CASUALTIES AMONG MEMBERS OF THE AMERI CAN EXPEDITIONARY FORCES DURING THE WORLD WAR FROM THE STATE OF NEBRASKA OFFICERS Killed in Action 7 Died of Wounds , 5 Died of Disease 6 Died of Accident 6 Presumed Dead 1 Total Dead 25 25 Wounded Slightly 17 Wounded Severely __ 13 Wounded — Degree Undetermined _. 6 Total __ __ 36 36 ENLISTED MEN Killed in Action 357 Died of Wounds 177 Died of Disease 244 Died of Accident 15 Drowned 1 Suicide 1 Other Known Causes 7 Cause Undetermined 16 Presumed Dead 12 Total Dead 830 830 Prisoners, Repatriated 20 20 Total Prisoners 20 20 Wounded Slightly 779 Wounded Severely 913 Degree Undetermined 438 Total Wounded 2,130 2,130 Total For Nebraska 3,041 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">J. S. MARINES r rora NEBRASKA WHO LOST THEIR LIVES in the WORLD WAR KA — Killed in actic DW — Died of wounds received in acti&lt; DD— Died of disease doc — Died of other causes AD — Accidental dea </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL U. S. MARINES FROM NEBRASKA WHO LOST THEIR LJVKS IN THE WORLD WAR Death Name Rank Co. Regt. Cause Date Alley, Laurence Elbridge Pvt. 95 6 KA 11-21-18 McClelland Alley, (Father) Whitman, Nebraska. Campbell, Roe Ellsworth Pvt. 20 5 DW 11-19-18 Opal Campbell (Sister) General Delivery Steele City, Nebraska Clark, Clifford Stewart Pvt. 84 6 KA 11-4-18 Jesse G. Clark (Father) Burwell, Nebraska Denlinger, Clinton Elsworth Pvt. 20 5 DW 6-19-18 Til lie Denling-er (Mother) Pierson, Iowa De Veney, John Francis Pvt. 45 5 DW 11-1-18 Mary De Veney (Mother) 130 W. Broadway San Diego, California Fankhauser, Adolph Pvt. Supp 13 DD 9-27-18 Anna Gottier (Mother) Rushville, Nebraska Farley, Fletcher Lawrence Pvt. 51 5 KA 6-27-18 Edward Farley Bancroft, Nebraska Ferguson, Cleasant William Pvt. L 11 DD 2-3-19 Rachael E. Ferguson (Mother) Naponee, Nebraska Flanagan, William Bryan Pvt. 75 6 DW 6-30-18 Nancy Tannehill (Mother) Conseption Junction, Missouri Graham, Alvin Myren Pvt. 73 6 DW 6-20-18 Henry S. Graham (Father) 1130 Cooledge Ave., Wichita, Kansas </seg>
            <seg id="p093">REPORT OP THE ADJUTANT GENERAL 93 Hartt, Paul Mathew Cpl. 18 5 KA 7-21-18 Sanford Hartt (Father) Bloomington, Nebraska Jenkins, Carl Campbell Pvt. 74 6 DD 6-23-18 Herbert L. Jenkins (Father) Box No. 39, Lawson, Missouri Killean, Blair Cpl. Supp 6 AD 5-30-19 Cathrine Killean (Mother) Fairbury, Nebraska Kindig, Lester Harrison Pvt. 17 5 DW 11-2-18 Margaret Kindig (Mother) Paxton, Illinois Lewis, Guy Melvin Pvt M 13 DD 9-29-18 Martha C. Lewis (Mother) Golden, Missouri McCreary, Harry C Pvt. 66 5 KA 11-2-18 Delia L- McCreary (Mother) Ringwood, Oklahoma McLeod, Fred Dodd Cpl. 45 6 KA 6-16-18 Daniel McLeod (Father) Schuyler, Nebraska McVay, Ray Henry Pvt. 79 6 DW 9-16-18 Clair E. McVay (Son) Clearwater, Nebraska Montgomery, Claude Henry Pvt. 16 5 KA 10-5-18 Anna Montgomery (Mother) 1906 S. Wash. St. Sedalia, Missouri Palmer, Merlin Elhner Pvt. 17 5 KA 10-5-18 Judson A. Palmer (Father; Stamford, Nebraska Patchin, Leroy Leslie Pvt. 75 6 KA 7-19-18 Charles A. Patchin (Father) . Hazard, Nebraska Peterson, Swen Harry __ Pvt. 96 6 KA 7-19-18 John Peterson (Father) Craig, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL ■ Ramold, John Pvt. 45 5 KA 6-17-18 Andrew F. Ramold (Father) Nebraska City, Nebraska. R. F. D. No. 3 Schultz, Donald David Pvt. 88 6 DW 10-10-18 Victoria Schultz (Mother) Wisner, Nebraska Stewart, Lester Ehls Sgt 80 6 KA 10-6-18 Anna M. Rogers (Mother) P. O. B. No. 402 Walthill, Nebraska Stuehrk, Ernest Lester Pvt. 9 Sqdrn FMAF DD 10-31-18 John Stuehrk Cedar Bluffs, Nebraska Strand, Clarence Henry Cpl. 75 6 KA 9-14-18 Sophia A- Strand (Mother) Newman Grove, Nebraska Wilson, Roicy Dee Pvt. 49 5 DW 6-17-ia May Wilson (Mother) Randolph, Nebraska </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>