<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00025.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00025.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE FOOD, DRUG AND DAIRY COMMISSION OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE FOOD. DRUG AND DAIRY COMMISSION THE STATE OF NEBRASKA S. L MAINS DEPUTY COMMISSIONER 1910 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA FOOD, DRUG AND DAIRY COMMISSION Ashton C. Shallenberger (Governor) Commissioner Deputy Commissioner Chemist Stenographer n'l Hi t D. L Miimi.x J. E. Yogel.. ml t Dairy Inspector Dairy Inspector Dairy Inspector Charles Pernland 1. \V. ( "arson W. .1. McPheetera D . lir ;. i ns]1LVtor Sir: T have the honor, in to submit herewith my 1&gt; ompliance with the Nebraska nnial report for the biennium S. L. MAINS, Deputy Food, Drug ind Dairy Commissioner. S. 1-. M.i ins. .. K. L Bedfern Bess B. Mark HarriH S. Mjh-.M Lincoln, Neb., Nov. 30, 1910. To His Excellency, ASHTON C. SHALLENBEEGEB, Governor of Nebraska. November 30, 1910 Respectfully </seg>
            <seg id="p003">BIENNIAL REPORT of the Deputy Food, Drug and Dairy Commissioner. The progress made in securing pure food and a con labeling of food products in the past two years is grati- fying. I assumed the duties of the office on January 2o, 1909. In the food, drag and dairy act passed by t he Legislature if 1!mi7 there were parts of sections wherein t lie meaning ,vas not clear. To give us a better hasis on which to enforce the law, we issued a statement on February 11, 190!'. follow-: "In all eases when- there is any question as to the meaning of tin- Nebraska pun- food law and upon the National pure food law is explicit, the Nebraska law will lie inter ted in accordance with the paragraph of the Nebraska National act." The prinei] lend law that was under d ion read as follows: "If I i in package form other than V a ai or measure are not correctly ontents, wt 1 on the outside of tin e." There were those n just quoted wi I who contended that tl tic stated; others anrued that when tlic contents alone were stated; others argued that the contents nm&gt;t be stated in terms &lt;»t' weight or measure. :inn of the Federal law upon this subject roads as Act, an article ri lie mi&gt;l randed: If in package I ted in terms of weight or measure they are noi nlainlv and correctly stated on the outside of t In ncr of the weight or measure clause of the As 1 Nebi iw was not clear and the federal act Wit a law was interpreted in accordance with illicit, tl the Nati( nal law. This ruling allowed food manufacturers retired from the State to place their products on who had iska market. Our State Legislature, being in ses- the Nebi sion, amended the law, making it clear and explicit, as </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 HIENXIAL RKI"MlT follows: "If sold for use in Nebraska and in package form, other than canned corn; if every meh package, as branded and named below, does not have a correct statement clearly printed, on the outside of the main label, of the contents and also of the net weight or measure of the contents ex - clusive of the container, viz: All dairy products, lard, cot - tolene, or any other article used for a substitute for lard, wheat products, oat products and corn products and mix - tures, prepared or unprepared; sugar, syrup and molas tea, coffee and dried fruits." Before this amendment of the food law became effective the following bulletin was issued by this department: BULLETIN NO. 10. Notice to Manufacturers, Wholesale and Retail Grocers: Your attention is called to section 8 of the. food, drug and dairy laws as amended by the last Legislature, which became effective .Inly 2. 1!&gt;&lt;I!&gt;. An article deemed misbranded "If sold for n Nebraska and in package form, other than canned corn, if every such package, as provided and named below, d not bear a correct statement clearly printed, on the outs of the main label, of the contents and also of the net weight or measure of the contents exclusive of the container, viz: All dairy products, lard, eottolene, or any other article c for a substitute for lard, wheat products, oat products and corn products and mixture-, prepared or unprepared; srnrar, svnip and molasses, tea. coffee and dried fruits. Provided, however, that the provision shall not apply to packages put up by the retailer, nor to packages on hand by any retailer at the time of taking effect of this act. In the case of liquids, other than medicines, if the true quan- tity in container thereof is not correctly stated thereon." Package form, definition of: Any filled carton, bottle. bag, box or other container which is for the purpose of selling at -wholesale or retail. The following articles must be branded as to net freight or measure and should bear the minimum net reight: All dairy products, milk (canned), cheese, butter, ce cream, lard, eottolene, ,-ind substitutes, wheat products (raw or cooked), flour, buckwheat flour, crackers, farina, meal and rolled oats, oat breakfast foods, corn products mjicuroni. wh°»1 wtarch, oal pro^'U'ts 'raw or rooked), cwt </seg>
            <seg id="p005">&gt;I&gt; COMMI SIGNER Eraw or cooked), corn flour, corn meal, corn flakes, hominy, oni breakfast foods, corn Btarch. t Mixtures — prepared and unprepared: Any mixture of beat, oats, or corn, or products of same (raw or cooked), incake Boar, sugars, syrups and molasses made from aple, cane. beet, fruit or glu&lt;- Tea, coffee and dried fruit Extracts, liquids, malt, spirituous or vinous liquors or other drinks nui-t bear the r the per centum of alcohol. t weight or measure and also Food Inspectors are dirt the Commission. ted to report all violations to S. L. MAINS, Deputv Commissioner. I am pleased to state that all food manufacturers will - ngly complied with our weight or measure law except one racket- company and the manufacturers of lard and cotto - ene. "We have suits pending in the Supreme Court against hese concerns. The food inspectors were instructed to make an edu - ational campaign and to report all violations to the Com - mission in their daily reports. My reasons for having the nspectors work upon educational linos were that I believed hat a large majority of the business men were honest; that hey desire to obey the law and if they were informed as o the requirements of the law they would insist upon t ; re doing business supplying them with with whom t tods which complied with the law. The reports from the specton prove that my conclusions were correct. It is my belief that the food laws of our State are being rrictly obeyed by food manufacturers and distributors i\&lt; those of any State in the Union, and that this excellent result has been attained by the minimum amount of prose - cutions. LOn June S. 1909. T approved bulletin No. 3, which was sued bv the former Commissioner, and reads as follows: BULLETIN NO. 3 Eggs. The Nebraska pure food law makes it unlawful to =ell Lad eggs and provides a penalty of $10 to $100 for each offer Section 7, part sixth, defines food as adulterated, "if </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BIENNIAL REFORT E consist in whole or in part of a filthy, decomposed or itrid animal or vegetable substance unfit for food," and at means bad en It is unlawful for the farmer to sell bad eggs to the merchant. it i^ unlawful for the merchant to sell them to his &gt;atrons or to eerg dealers. It is a violation of the National aw to ship them from one Stale to another. The law tamed in the interest of honest dealing, and it is not honftst 0 sell had eggs for good money. It is reported that in some rises spoiled eggs have been taken from the incubator and marketed at the grocery store when tho producer thought he buyer was too busy to examine them.. It is the dutv of this department to proseente offenders, whoever thev nay be, no matter whether producer or dealer. The law 1 trying to protect, not only the consumer, who is entitled o get honest food for his money, but the honest producer nnd honest dealer, who is entitled to have his dishonest competitors prosecuted and exposed through publicity. Nebraska hens are producing 90,000,000 dozen eggs nnually. These Nebraska eggs are worth three to five ents per dozen less than the highest market price in Now 'ork, Philadelphia and Baltimore, on account of the low Tade they take in these markets by reason of the dishonest nd careless mixing of bad eggs with the good. Five cents a dozen on 90,000,000 dozen eggs amounts to $4,500,000. Bv reason of this careless and dishonest mixing of bad eggs with good, we lower the '0.000. value of our annual output Dims it pay? The law is trying to force our product up to the highest us as a community to bring standard for our own good. Deputy Commissioner. Lincoln. Neb., .June 8, 1909. The quality of the yield of Nebraska eggs in 1908 wa3 the best that has ever been marketed from this State. The reason for this excellent showing comes from the greater care shown this perishable food produce by all parties en - gaged in this business. Notice is herebv given that bulletin No. 3 issued bv this J. W. J( HIXSOX, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DKIM TY FOOD OMMISSIONER d partment is still in force, and any person found violating ?tion of the pure food law will be vigorously \ i uted S. L. MAINS, c Deputy Commissioner \&gt;st this bulletin in This bulletin has been cc nil State Food Commissi pied in whole and in part by 'tiers and also in Canada. It been used as the ba&gt;i f the agitation which ii 1 t more care be used in handling this important article of food. lopted the sanitary - uri Commission. With tl.is tors score for sanitation all rocery stores, bakeries, hott Is, restaurants, drns st t t t nd manufactories of food These score cards are filed in i ind duplicates are furnished ! he office of the Commission anyone upon request. e of 1909 amended the The Nebraska Lerislattu l iw by approving the bleachii of flour bv nitrogen | le. This amendment wa pproved by the Commi? stigations madt by Dr. AJway of Nebraska iKiii t nd Drs. Weisner and Teller The last of August and t first of September, 1009, National Association of S te Pood and Dairv 1 1 t ntion at Denver, Colorado. cuts held their annual convf i onal fight on the qu&lt; Phis convention was in a fact ! f the use of benzoate of soda od preservative. The wing resolution was suhn tted to the conventi t Resolved, That this iation hereby endorses the ultin report of the referee h&lt; t its lppointed by Secretary of A mi of President Roosevelt upoi ■ oi leu i in food product v r and State Chemist cast ) ( oninnssioi Xel ring t resolution. ( &gt;u &gt;r t t the board v 1 voting for the resolution was t t scientific ability and their of men ot the highest scientinc aiulity ; sional position was so high that they could be nnpn luiMtion v n spit i Your Deputv Commissioner present at the first convention of Western Food Control Officials, which was i conspicuous place.) In October, 1900, this offi. trd which is used by tho Mi- rd the Food and Drug Insp f Columbia laboratory board &lt; re \Y </seg>
            <seg id="p008">BIENNIAL KKI'ORT decision i&gt; made either by the said hoard or the Federal I consider the right to bleach flour by nitrogen peroxide o lie a most vital question, and final decision affects the ■perity of the millers of (Mir State and the Nebraska arniers who raise hard winter wheat. I have strenuously objected to the ruling of the Department of Agriculture on his subject and have spent much time and money gather - nir evidence to refute their contention. la the hot Legislature there were two bills introduced ate hy lion. W. 15. fawning w direct interest to the dairy industry. These bills were approved by the Nebraska Dairymen's Association and your Deputy &lt; onunissioiier. ()?ie n f these bill- proposed amendments to the dairy law as follows: "First— To create an office of r.u assistant, who would have charge of the dairy provisions of the food, drag and dairy law. and to increase the pay of dairy inspectors to four is4.mii) dollars per day. "Second- To amend the testers of milk and cream law -ii that samplers, as well should be required to secure ( 'oimnissioner. a permit issued by the Dairv Third— To amend the 1 iw legalizing the use of a six - m charge, as well as a nine- inch t'-st bottle with nine-gr nch tt-t bottle with an eighte^n-dram charge. To change lie standard of temperature when reading the test from l'ii degrees to 14(1 degrees Fahrenheit (the old standard ras from 130 degrees to 14(1 degrees Fahrenheit) and to ►lace all bottles, glassware and scales nsed in making tests f milk or cream under the supervision of the Food, Drug nd Daily Department." The amendments as originally drawn wen» passed in the Senate by a unanimous vote. They met with a far dif - ferent reception in the House of Representatives. Here the first section of the bill was entirely stricken out when it was considered by the committee of the whole. The third hekl .it Boise, [daho. At tliis convention we presented the ollowing resolution, which was unanimously adopted: ••In the rase of lilt itching &lt;•!' flour, we petition the Fed- •i;il Agricultural Departmeni to Bubmit the same to the vtVr,.,. lx«ud of consulting scientific experts of the Depart- nciit of Agriculture, or a speedy trial in the Federal courts, ind thai we take mi action as State food officials until a </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 f any of said products, and may iile in the office of POOD C MMiS5IOM ,. reading and vot n this bill came on Saturday, when many of the friei the measure were absent, and it failed of t majority. However, it was reconsidered the following onciav. when it had enough friends to carry it to a suc - cessful passaere. cessni The changes in the dairy laws have been very bene- ficial t merit, especially the amendment that re- Cnres a cream operator to secure a permit from the depart- PTlt. Xow when we find nno tmiltv nt &gt;,,.,,, ;,,,,!.,*; *„„*_ we find one guilty of manipulating tests init he is out of the cream business. Be- and fore the passage of this amendment the operator could con- tin introduced by Senator Banning lias since the can law. This law was published in it be&lt; bn ow BULLETIN NO. 5 Senate File No. 262. Act. to provide for the marketing, stamping and andmg of cans, bottles, casks, kegs, barrels, or other re- &lt; the handling and transportation of dairy products, ice cream, milk or cream, and the selection and adoption oi mark or brand; prohibiting any person. orporation from adopting or using any brand conipai rk wh titlark which has been selected, designated or" appro- printed; making it unlawful for any person other than the Eglitlul owner to use any pan, bottle, cask, keg, barrel or her recpi)ta&lt; le marked &lt;&gt;■• b«-:iinl...l ..&lt;. ; ,,,. *.. I. to ;!• lu- rid, mark or stamp; making i lemeanor for any per m or persons to violate any i the act ; pi )\i&lt;ling for a fine of not less \ S than $100 to be imposed upon persons con- (I f a violation thereof; and requiring the enforcement aet by the Food. Drug and Dairy Commissioner. t I Knacted by the Legislature cf the State of Xe Section 1. That all persons, companies and corpora tion iged in the transportation or manufacture of any dairy product or ice cream, or in bottling milk and cream tiry product or ice ere; r &gt;ale and use. mav adi ale and use, may adopt a mark or marks of ownership . . 1 it * tob stamped or marked on any can, bottle, cask, keg. bar- rel or other receptacle used in the handling and transporta- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 HIKXXIAL RKPORT the Secretary &lt;&gt;i' State ■ description of the name or mark m&gt; used by them or either of them, and the use to be made of any i-nrh ran, bottle cask. keg. barrel or other receptacle, and cause the same to be published for two successive we iu a weekly newspaper published and in general circulation in the State of Nebraska. "Section 2. The brand or mark so selected and adopted a&gt; herein provided may consist of a name, design, mark or marks, or same particular color of paint or enamel used upon the can, bottle, cask, keg, barrel or other receptacle, or any part thereof. t "Section '■'&gt;. it shall be unlawful for any person, com - iny or corporation to adopt or use any brand or mark Inch has already been designated, appropriated or ob - ined under the provisions of this act. I Section 4. It shall be unlawful for any person other Kin the rightful owner thereof to use any can, bottle, cask, eg, barrel or other receptacle, marked or branded as erein provided, for any other purpose or for the transpos - ition or handling of any other article or product than esignated or provided for by such branding. "Section ."&gt;. It shall be unlawful for any person other than the rightful owner thereof to deface or remove any such brand, mark or stamp put upon any such can, bottle, cask, keg. barrel or other receptacle as herein provided. ("Section &lt;i. Any person or persons who shall violate ny provisions of this act shall be deemed guilty of a mis - emeanor, and upon conviction thereof before a court hav - ig jurisdiction in such cases, shall be tim-d for each and very &gt;uch offense in a Mini not less than five nor more than ne hundred dollars, and shall stand committed until Be and costs are paid. "Section 7. For the purpose of preventing the nc aid cans, bottles, casks, kegs, barrels, or other receptacles or any purpose other than that herein provided, and to nsure the wholesomeness and high quality of said products and the sanitary condition of the receptacles in which the •■ are transported, it shall be the duty of the Food, Dairy mil Drug Commissioner to enforce the provisions &lt;&gt;!' this act. t" (Emergency.) Whereas, an emergency exists, this act hall take effect and be in force from and after its pa - nd approval." </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSIONER niply with this law any person engaged in the ' • ■ i — dairy, creamery or ice cream business in the State Nebraska must file with the Secretary of State his mark or brand It is unlawful to use any can, bottle, cask, ke«\ barrel or other receptacle thus branded for any purpose other than those stated on file with the Secretary of State. It is unlawful for anv person to any can, bottle, cask, keg, barrel, or receptacle thus branded except he be owner or agent. It is unlawful for any company or their agent to loan any can, bottle, cask, keg, barrel, or receptacle, and dairy inspectors are hereby instructed to report anv violation this act. S. L. MAINS, Deputy Commissioner. While admitting it to be just, it was predicted by many that it would be hard to secure a ready compliance with the enforcement of this ruling. The opposite has been the case. We find as a very general rule the operators have observed this ruling, but where one has violated the law and it has been reported to this department a letter from the Dairy Commissioner explaining the violation and informing the dairyman or farmer that he is subject to prosecution has secured a hasty return of the can to the operator. I find that the farmers and dairymen have no desire for lawsuits. The greatest benefit derived from this law is in the improvement of the quality of the cream brought to receiving stations. The past two years has proven without question that a person will take better care of his own per- sonal property than he will of a borrowed article, especially then the article is a cream can and when it mowed. This law has also induced creamery com- panies to eqnin their stations so cream cans may be cleansed. By these improvements they have added very ruch to the sanitary condition of their cream stations. I venture to state that a greater average of No. 1 butter nnd less of No. 2 butter was manufactured by the cream erics these past two years than during any like preceding period. The greater part of the credit for this excellent result must be given to the can law In June. 1900. this department issued three bulletins on various points of interest to the dairy industry. They are as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 BIENNIAL RKl'OUT BULLETIN NO 6 To .All Cream Patrons: Owing to the fact that a large amount of the cream now being Bojld in Nebraska has been held too long before delivery, and has otherwise not been properly cared for. we are offering the following suggestions for improving the quality and thus increasing the price received by the pro - ducer for his dairy products. !Milk the cow in a clean manner and in clean surround - pfs. Remove the milk as boob as possible from the barn d strain before separating. Separate at once and cool i&gt; fresh cream before mixing with that being held for de - ery. 11' possible, cool to 50 or 55 degree.-; and keep at at temperature until delivered. Stir all cream that is ing collected for delivery at least two or three times per y and do not hold longer than four days in cold weather d three days in warm weather. Separate the cream to -t 4.") per cent or 50 per cent, if possible, and do not allow to run below 30 per cent. Rich cream will keep better an thin cream and you save the skimmed milk. The separator, delivery* cans, and all utensils must be thoroughly cleaned each time they are used. Failure to keep them in a clean and sanitary condition is a violation of *ection 18 of the Pure Food law, which ie;)ds as foil. "It i- hereby made unlawful to use or employ in and about the keeping or handling of any milk, cream or dairy prod- nets to be &gt;-;d as food, anv pail, can, v churn, sen- t^An or other implement which is in an unclean or Diu-ani rv condition. " Cream that is extremely soul on delivery at the re. ing station has ekher been held too long before delivery, or has been handled in unclean receptacles, or both, and as such it i&gt; unlawful. It is to In- hoped the above suggestions will be followed without the necessity of enforcing the laws. S. L. MAINS, Deputy Commissioner. BULLETIN NO. 7 Sampling and Testing Cream. Sampling: The most important part in the testing of cream i curing an accurate sample, for upon this depends the results </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DElTTf FOOD COMMISSION of the test. Owing to its specific gravity, the thin cream «ettles to the bottom &lt;&gt;i* the can, the percentage or fat in - creasing toward the top Tne percentage of fat. age degree of somnPM and temperature also affect the condition of the •ream and usually make more difficult the securing of a •orrect sample. Cream may be mixed by either pouring or Btirring. If it ran.be poured with any degree of riui. this is the better method, providing it is poured until a miform mixture is obtained. Stirring should be done with a vigorous up and down motion, the stirrer being drawn ttom to the exticinc top in order that the differ- iron ent layers of cream may be mixed. Do not stop stirring until the cream will run off the stirrer with a smooth even appearance, or as long as there are any lumps re?naining. The sample must be taken immediately after mixing, as the fat will rapidly rise to the top and a true sample cannot then be obtained. If the sample is allowed to stand 'or ny length of time before testing it should be tightly cov Weighing the Charge: Before weighing the el urge, care must be taken that 1 throughout the sample. To should be heated by partially in water at 100 or 111) del the fat is evenlv distribute submerging the sample jar Fahrenheit and then ponrin oral times until it is quite X from one jar to anothei fluid and a!! lumps dissolved. The charge must then be weighed immediately. The braska law requires either an eighteen gram charge weighed into a nine inch bottle, graduated to at least live- tentlis per cent, or a nine gram charge weighed into a six inch bottle, graduated to at least five-tenths per cent, and also graduated to irive a full reading of the te&gt;t. The ■ample should always be weighed very carefully as the final outcome of the test will depend on the accuracy of the t reigning. No cream should be allowed to get on the ont - ide of the bottle or on the scale pan while the weighing is done. Not quite enough, or a little too much, is m ficient. Adding Acid kTn adding acid the best results are obtained when both e sample and acid are brought to a temperature of 65 orort in order to stop evaporation plisli tliis tlio sample </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 HIKYNIAL REPORT or 70 degrees Fahrenheit. When an eighteen gram charge is weighed from ■ sample that lias been heated, it will be ieoemary to place the bottle containing the charge in cold rater for a few minutes in order to bring it to tins t "n - enitnre. In cold weather it will be necessary to warm tho ci&lt;! slightly in order to bring it to the proper temperature. Hit-ii adding acid, hold the bottle in such a manner that lie acid will run down the side of the nock and not fall iit-ctly into the cream. Mix thoroughly with a gentle ro - iry motion. The mixture should he a chocolate color and it fat column when the test is finished should be a golden el low. Burned or dark colored readings are usually caused by: First — Too much or too strong acid. Lnd— &lt; i c; in. or acid, or both, at too high a te re at time of mixing. Vllowing arid to )':*! i Fourth — Rough mixing of the sample or allowing the imple to stand too long before mixing after the acid has been added. Cloudy or light colored readings are usually caused by: First — Too little or too weak acid tu. Third — Samples not thoroughly mixed before whirling. Rich cream will require a little less acid than thin . and sour cream will require a little less than sweet in. Whirling Samples should bo whirled three times at full speed in ng, the speed depending on tho diameter of the ma- chine First whirl four minutes and fill with wnti?r to the bottom of the neck; whirl two minutes and fill with water until the tat i-o'i'os within the :.": i&lt;1 i';'ii'(| scale nil the nei whirl one minute and place liottles in a tempering vat to bring them to the proper temperature to read. Bain water should lie nsed for tilling, if possible, hut if not Available add a few drops of sulphuric acid to the water before put - ting into the bottle. This will prevent the forming of white </seg>
            <seg id="p015">DEPUTY FIX COMMI88IONE1 15 kbbles on the surface of the fat column. Water for filling ould be ;it about lit* degrees Fahrenheit. Fahrenheit Making the Reading IV read the fat at a temperature between 120 and 140 degrees Fahrenheit as required by law makes the use of a water hath necessary. After the bottles have been run in the tester, they should be placed in water at this tempera- i ture deep enough to allow water level with the top of the tit column. The bottles should remain in this water for ten minutes before reading. The fat column should i be read from the bottom of the column to the bottom of the meniscus and the bottles should be emptied and thoroughly cleansed at the completion of each te-t. Use good hot water together witli soap or washing powder. If the bottles are r cent too high, due to the fat that adheres to the t of the bottle. Accuracy Required in Every Detail Although the Babcock test is very simple, it requires ( "si (are and accuracy at even,- point to get correct re- It-. An accurate sample, careful weighing of the charge, t column are absolutely and a correct readii t isarv and will ' 1 bv the Food, Drug man that samples and Dairv Commission of ever Nebra ka Equipment Die scale is the most d te piece of mechanism con- d with the test. It shoul 1 be -ct level and be kept in a &gt;m time to time for accuracy. nd tcst( v Especial care must be observt 1 in keeping the knives sharp i will break nuickh Anv scale that Is not »t accurate enough to do the work correctly The tester should set lev« 1 and on a solid foundation in order that it may run smoothly. If it shakes it will can remixing of the fat and consequently an inaccurate read Be sure to run the tester at full speed during the entire period of whirling. The following table gives the number of revolutions per minute for the various diameters: so tlio sc;ilo will break quiekh tive to a drop of cream </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BIENXIAI REPCRT Diameter of Machine Revolutions per Minute Use romtaiercially pure sulphuric acid of ;i specific ity of 1.82 to 1.82 and do not leave the container open to the air as the acid will very soon heroine weak and unfit for use. Always use a pair of sharp dividers for measuring the fat column. A thermometer should also be provided. S. L. MAIN'S. Deputy Commissioner. BULLETIN NO. 8 To All Receiving Station Operators: The sanitary conditions and the methods of handling ream in a large number of receiving stations are of such a nature a- to inquire the attention of the Pure Food Com - nission. and thi&lt; may be considered as official notice that vh &gt;rever conditions exist that will render cream or milk nelean or unwholesome, or where a sample of cream or nilk has been taken before it lias been thoroughly stirred, &gt;r where any false or unfair te&gt;-t lias been made, the O] or of such station will be subject to prosecution under the 'me Food law and his permit will be cancelled. Oils, live poultry, or strong flavored merchandise must not he kept where milk or cream is handled. Shipping cans hould be stored in a clean dry place with the lids removed, tad before being filled should he scalded with boiling hot water or live steam and allowed to cool. The stirrer should &gt;e kept in a can of clean water so that it is ready for use at nil times. All testing apparatus must be kept clean and in good order so that accurate tests may be obtained. Facili - ies for providing plenty of hot water should be at hand, ind where such is the ease it is suggested that the patron's cans be washed before returning. An effort should be made to keep sweet and sour cream separate. If mixed the sour cream will spoil the sweet. 12 inches . . 14 inches It! inches . . 18 inche? 20 inches 22 inches . . 24 inches . . 9SO 90S S4S 800 7")0 720 693 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DEPUTT FOOD COMMISSIONER i Cecil ;| H cream us coo] as possible and stir frequently, as he thin cream quickly settles to the bottom, causing an ueveo Kourinp. I nitoi m souring i« essential to good uality; hence the need of frequent stirring. Keep ;ill en the thin ere mi ible and stir frequently, as to the bottom, causing an 1 • ■ 1 Ml need of fre "juent stirring. S. L. MAINS, S. L. MAINS, Deputy Commissioner. Deputy Commissioner. Jn i&gt;sniii«r a permit to sample or test to an operator re always enclose copies of bulletins Nos. 7 and In .June, 1909, we held examinations for cream sam- ilers and testers in the following cities: Omaha. Lincoln, n ng cities: Omaha. Lincoln, i&lt; MeCook, Holdrege, Grand Island. Norfolk, Alliance, North [eCook, Holdrege, Grand Island. Norfolk, Alliance, North Platte, Kairbnry, Central Citv, Columbns and Fremont. I 'latte. Kairbnry, Central City, Columbus and Fremont. I t was able to be present at all of these gatherings except at vas able to be present at all of these gatherings except at Yllianee and North Platte. These two examinations were Vlliance and North Platte. These two examinations were t onducted by I ).;ir\ Inspector Vogel. At each of these conducted by Dairv lnsi&gt;ector Vogel. At each of these ) lectin^s I had tin- pleasure of addressing the operators ings I had the pleasure &lt;&gt;f addressing the operators ii i':t, to explain the law and to try and impress them th the importance of their position. I told them that I is anxious that their patrons should be paid for every und of butter fat they bronghi to them and that I was ually insistent that the creamery they represented -hould •eive every pound they purchased through their agency, 'avored testing at cream stations and gave as my prin - &gt;al reason that it would give greater satisfaction to the tron if he had a chance to see the tot read. Whether . recommendations had any effect 1 am unable to tell, t I know that when I took charge of tin- office there were 18 than eiarht hundred testers in the State who had per - ts from this department, while the total number of per - ts issued by the department from June 30, 1909, to June , 1010, or the first nVeal year, was :!,nnd. and more than per cent were testers. The department has had three dairy inspectors since e l&gt;t of February. 1909, and four since the 1st of June. lese four have been kept busy. They have traveled about .000 miles to inspect the various dairies, cream receiving itioos and creameries. Kach inspector is supplied with ■orrcct set of te^tiiiiT weights, a correct set of test bottles d a McKay sample:-. I require ;i report on each station -ited and blanks are furnished them to report on the llowing points: Date of inspection; name of town: ojier - jr's name: creamerv represented; sampler or tester; present, to explain the law and to try and impress them ! with the importance of their position. I told them that I was anxious that their patrons should be paid for every pound of butter fat they brought to them and that I was t equally insistent that the creamery they represented should ii receive every pound they purchased through their agency. 1 favored testing at cream stations and gave as my prill pal reason that it would irive greater satisfaction to the patron if he had a chance to Bee the tot read. Whether l my recommendations had anv effect 1 am unable to tell. but I know that when I took charge of the office there were in the State who had per ile the total number of per ssued bv the department from June :&gt;0, 1909, to June IX), 1010, or the first fiscal vear, was .'!,00(I, and more than i ;&gt; per cent were testei t were t The department has had three dairv inspectors since the l&gt;t of February. 1909, and four sin.ee the 1st of June. These four pt bu v. They have traveled about I eel tl ies. cream receiving h inspector is supplied with h\ t set of test bottles lied them to report on the i Date of inspection; name of town; ojier - amery represented; sampler or tester; </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 BIENNIAL REPORT average test; price paid for fat; condition of glassware and scales; sanitary condition of cans and utensils; how often cream is shipped; what days; is ■ composite test made of each shipment; docs the creamery report shortage or excess of fat; condition of cream on hand; the operator's report on pounds of cream and pounds of fat; composite pounds of cream and pounds of fat, and a blank space for remarks. These reports, when they arrive at the office, are carefully examined and if any special criticism is made, either good &lt;&gt;r bad, I write a personal letter to the operator telling him the nature of the report and cither compliment him or tell him where he must make improvements. I have used our inspectors on the dumps of the creameries to sample and test the cream that comes from the operator. When an inspector is detailed to a plant lie stays a week cheeking up each day's receipts, lie also secures from the com - pany's books a report on each station for the half of the month preceding his inspection. The facts secured by the inspector are filed on proper blanks and sent to the depart - ment. Then follows more letters. I have written more than than &gt;ix thousand personal letters to operators. I notified them that the data I was gathering would have a bearing on whether they would lie able to secure a per rmit to continue in business after lieve that the dairy industry honesty to his patrons and to their permit expired. I be - demands from an operator tlie creamery he represents. I would state that when i dump lie has instructions to &lt; o the factory, no matter whet n Nebraska or some ndjoinin rom an adjoining State a st iy the inspector is sent to the in inspector takes charge of heck up all cream that comes it i oires from some nine &lt;X State. If the cream comes itement of the facts secured Dairy Commissioner of that Etate. This exchange of information I find to lie very benc rial. II have collected from creameries since January J5, 909, for permits to operate $517.06; from operators for ermits to sample or test. $."&gt;.&lt;;14 ; for oleomargarine per - £4.573.58; from commission merchants, $620, making le total amount of collections $11,324.64. The former bmmissioner's biennial report showed a total collection t $4,487.36. The total increase in fees collected i^ S,837.28. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSIONER In conclusion allow me to recommend for roar eonsid eration some amendments to our present food, drug and dairy laws, and also the other laws which eome directlv ,• .. , "" ' mwa hinni come (IllCCIlV under this department for administration. Thev an follows !• irst. An amendment to the weight or measure clause embrace all food offered foi lollll Second. An increase, of two food and drug inspectors ind a provision allowing six extra dairy inspectors during the months of .June. July and August each veai ind cl torics which produce 100,000 pounds or It r . v ■' "■■'*" I'K-uiiti- m'w.iiuu pdiiiitis or lesa rnird. I.) repeal the tax to operate a creamery or :heese factory, or to make a tax of *: ( on all creameries aid an additional graduated tax on each additional II pounds or fraction thereof. A similar tax should he on each ice cream factory Fourth. An amendment to the paint law. makr heavy penalty for adulteration of linseed oil. Fifth. An amendment to the sanitation law, making it possible to close without where food is served or sold notice any insanitary place t Sixth. A law on stand he creation of an office of St. - res under this department. 1 weight and measure, and sealer of weights and m t Seventh. A repeal of t merchants to file a bond of s ind to pay a tax of $10 per ippears to me that this law h for the benefit of bonding eo ie law requiring commis -.000 with their county judpe year to this department. It ■ »•*-§»«•■ i"i&lt; in. ii - been drawn almost entirely panies. Eighth. Finally, and j propriation for inspectors' This department has been liiennium by lack of funds. st urgent of all. a larger ap - eries and traveling expei Etmpered through this whole i The reports of State &lt; lemist Redfern, of Food and rphv and of Dairy Inspector HON. S. L. MAINS, Deputy Food, Drug and Dairy Commissioner Lincoln, Nebraska Sir: I herewith submit my report as chemist for the Nebraska Food, Drug and Dairy Commission for the bien - uium ending November 30, 1910. Drug Inspector Mrs. MacMi Yogel follow: </seg>
            <seg id="p020">IilEXNIAL HKI'Ol Durinir iliis period 1,389 samples of foods, dm t lints and oils were analyzed in the laboratoi"}' of the ( '&lt; ission. Sonic of these samples v.-ei-e submitted bv deal and individuals, bul the maj&lt; inspectors for the ( 'om n. Of the !•'!] samples of drugs collected, 4'J were illegal from (he fact thai thev were Itelow standard as required in the I nited States pharmacopoeia and Nation; lary, which arc made the standard bv the State law (•nt of the - K 7 samples of ice cream analyzed. Hi ) below the standard of 14 per cent butter fat for plain ice cream and 1l! per cent butter fat for fruit ice cream. Whi this is a large percent of cases these lo'.i samples contained between 1."! and 14 per cent of butter fat. showing that v making an honest effort to comply with the law. Th dition is a marked improvement over that of the preeedini biennium, when the law was new and not genei Eood. There were 1!)7 samples of 1 zed, wliirli included such foods beverages of various kinds ai Many samples of vinegar have been submitted bv farmers who make a few barrels each vear from their mi plus apples, and before the grocer will buy it i that it comply with the law. A great manv samples of bev n analvzed to Bee if they were properly labeled as to alcoholic content. These beverages were mostly temperance \&lt; • called) ind there seems to be a temptation to put more alcohol in them than the label calls for Pops, which are carbonated water, colored an r vored, must show the quantity of saccharine they contain and many -amples have been analyzed to see if the oi ply with the law in this respect Of the samples of linseed oil analyzed the ma.joritv were adultered with petroleum oil. This is one of the n most widely adulterated products on the market today, dv. largely to the advance in price of the pure product Petroleum, being a cheap product, gives the adulterator a wide margin of profit; hence its universal use as a substi tute. As petroleum oils are non-drying, it is evident that a paint mixed with a linseed oil which has been adulterated </seg>
            <seg id="p021">I Y FOOL) COMMISSIONER with such oil- can not |&gt; kIu a coat of wearing qnalii market arc labeled to show All imints being put ii t t of which thc\ a posed, and in ive been found to he ile to make them under man \es|iectfully submitted, Eh nearly correct as it fnctiiring conditions I t K. L. REDFERN, Chemist. HON. S. L. MAINS, Deputy Food, Drug Sir: Herewith find md Dairv Commissioner &lt;l submitted report of my work as for the Nebraska Food, Dairv and I! During that period iected places where fo I 1 ds ive visited L'dl towns and in - iind drugs were manufactured mber of :U&lt;L\ divided as fol or offered for sale to th m lows Groeery st Drug stoic Meat marl 1 ,202 47^ 346 Bakeries, confecti Hotels 593 meries, etc l: ( .»k Salooi o-. ) LThis has necessitati iles of travel. I probably about fifteen hundred tion law. the paint law, tin* coiuinission law varied the duties of an inspector. Under the sanitation law- inspection sometimes had to be followed by orders to al the insanitary conditions, and I am pleased to acknowledge the generally hearty co-operation of County Attorneys in the execution of such orders, in most cases without resort ing to prosecution. V very considerable portion of my duty as inspector was educational, in accordance with instructions from vou. &lt;i information 1&lt;&gt; those inspected concerning the more particularly concerning the proper labeling of package foods. The interest manifested was great and r tail dealers generally expressed themselves anxious to bt informed that they might know how to conform iutelli I&gt;1 HIT ( 'dlllll 1910. imiuni ending November 30, Inspection being required under the food and drag </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 i BIEXXIAL REPORT gently to a law which they considered a wise one and of benefit to them as well at; to the consumer. Comparing conditions of this Wi t - n ti i nm with the pre ceding one, I found them constantly improving, packagt foods better labeled, weights more generally true and tin standard higher. Suggestions made to the retail dealers in regard to smaller violations of the law in the matter of labeling by the manufacturers or jobbers, with a sugges — -, .... .... umiiuiovminB ,1] juuucis, wiui a sugges tion that they notify their jobber that they would cease to cany the product until properly labeled, very soon result e&lt; in the proper compliance on the part of the jobbers, an&lt; probably hundreds of improper labeling* which were no intentional efforts to evade the laws were thus remedies during this and the preceding biennium. I cannot .-ay as much for the betterment of the sanita tion law, which my experience leads me to think should b made the center of future effort. Esjieeially in the case o slaughter houses throughout the State are" the condition deplorable. The law is adequate, but only having been ii effect for a portion of this biennium and because of tlu inadequate force to do the work, much remains to be done In the matter of the handling of eggs and butter by th&lt; retail merchants, the present law is utterly inadequate t&lt; cope with the situation, and they are asking anxiously foi help. Constant surprise was manifested that inspectors visits were so infrequent, the majority seeming to conside it a privilege to receive such visits and the information the&gt; derived from them. When they were told that the law allowed only two food and drag inspectors, who were ;•&gt;: pected to visit every food, drug, liquor and paint establish meiit in the nearly one thousand towns in Nebraska am report conditions, the wonder ceased. The system of card reports on each place inspected met with general approval and a statement of the fact that thereby a complete record of all places inspected was kept on file in the office of the Food Commission in the State House for the benefit of the public was greeted with inter ested commendation. Respectfully submitted, IIAKKIKT S. MacMUBPHY. Food and Drug Inspector. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSIONER Deputy Food, Drug and Dairy Commissioner Sir: Following is a report of ray work as dairy inspector for the biemrium ending November 30, 1910. I have inspected about one thou ted about one thousand cream stations, ted about one thousand cream station Beveral hundred dairies, and have K'Hods of from one to two weeks in ] ■reameries, checking the testing and ii &gt;f the cream as received from the stai Owing to the fact that the dairy i s confined chiefly to the production o: hrongfa t ho medium of the hand sepa uiyers located in each town, who in o the large creameries at the railroad i dairies, and have spent about twenty ind have spent about twenty te to two weeks in length in the various to two weeks in length in the various the testing and inspecting the quality ereameri&lt; ng the testing and inspecting tlu&gt; quality of the ei ceived from the stations. ved from th ( faring to t fact that the dairy industry of this State industry of this Statt t that t is confined chiefly to the pr&lt; to the production of cream on the farm. luction of cream on the farm through the medium of t in of the hand separator, and its sale to and separator, and its sale to buver each town, who in turn ship the cream t turn ship the cream V to the large creameries at t ■lies at the railroad centers, my work has railroad centers, my work has been mainly in connection w &gt;eon mainly in connection with the ini] f the cream and educational as well a neetion with the improvement of quality th the improvement of quality of dutational as well as police work among will as police work among n itiona the operators of the station he operators of the stations. Previous to the time of my app&lt; le stations. Previous to the time of 10 time of my appointment the testing itment the testing i v vas done largely at the central factori&lt; t the central factories, the samples being factories, the samples being aken by the operators at the statioi ators at the station. About this time, station. About this time, iowever, the testing was rapidly bei ng was rapidly being transferred from station, and many times turned over to lly being transferred from the factory to the station, an he factory to the station, and many I many times turned over to inexperienced men. This ma nexperienced men. This made it nee eal of educational work. Many open . This made it necessary to do a great it necessary to do a great deal of educational work. Ma ! work. Many operators seemed to have seemed to have i V O| o idea of what was required with r no idea of what was requin ras required with regard to sanitation. were apparently honest in their belief. with regard to sanitation. They thought, and were ai 'hey thought, and were apparently In lat so longaR the filth did not actually ntlv honest in their belief, filth did nut actually get into the product tually get into the product they were handling, it icy -were handling, it mode no differe :. it made no difference about the condi- bout the condi- tion of t on of their station and surroundings n and surroundings. The bad effect of tation ;iiit The bad effect of n Bch a station was passed along to tl i passed along to the patron, who con- to the patron, who con luded that it was unnecessary to give unnecessary to (rive his cream any extra had become so keen that most operators to give his cream any extra i are. Competition had become s ( &gt; keen are. Competition had beeom n that most operators took cream of poor quality without ; ook cream of poor quality without ; ir quality without a word of criticism, t a word of criticism. One lady complained of my unjustnes&gt; can of cream delivered bv her. the si rne lady complained of my in can of cream delivered bv Ik ed of my unjustness when I condemned justness when I condemned ivered by her. the surface of which was the surface of which was •overed with ;i heavy scum of mold and which, of course. E'iis extremely sour, by Fayiitj nlv ;i week old. while slie hnd was extremelv sour, bv savii the condemned cream w;i&gt; the condemned cream was only a week old. she had been in the habit of keeping been in the habit of keeping her cream until it was two weeks old and selling it in a neighboring town, where it was received without question. Many operators, especially when receiving cream from a man who bad previously been selling to a competitor, would HON. S. L. MAINS, </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 1MKNNIAL REPORT deliberately raise the test in order to make the patron I lieve tin* other man had been cheatii At tlic present time mn T t &lt; ;m everywhere. Operators arc becoming n testing. Scales and other em nt are in lift t us. Manv i In •onipctitors for raising the tcs air competition. Many of the nit a majority were found t ictually making their tests to&lt; ie doing so through eareiessne uade in the process of testing cales. Where the evidence sh ntentionally manipulating tin •uted and on conviction lined a new permit refused him. thus &gt;f testing. ts and thereby creating nn se complaints were baseless We. Of those high many were found to in the sampling or errors 11(1 in the use of t( &gt;wed that the operator was test he was either t id his permit revoked, or a denying him the privilege tin conclusion 1 wish to say ie station operators, and the B made of the courtesy exte ork. Kes; reamerv men, that mention ded bv them to me in my n Dairy Inspector. testing. Scales and other equipment ; ;iik1 there arc 1ml few insanitary sta tions have been built with cement fit effect cannot help 1 tut prove beneficial to the ] the inspection of the dairies I find that, &gt;&lt;&gt; far tli:it it is due the dai pectfullv submitted I. E. VOGEL n&lt;-s is concerned, about 1 per cent arc in had condition m&lt;l only about 1 * &gt; per cent are subject to criticism. Mucli [■ream of poor quality is yet being sold, however, but it is luc to its b*ing held too long on the farm before delivery, and to the fact that proper facilities for keeping il ire not provided, rather than to uncleanliness. Most of the complaints 1 have been called on to in- k'estijrate were made l&gt;v station operators against their e re </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>