<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00007">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0007</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Evolution of a Sanitary Type of Chick Feeder</title>
               <date value="18??">March 1937</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">Bulletin 306 March, 1937 ':¦¦ ¦'!¦¦'¦¦¦' - ['¦¦' '.¦¦.'¦¦¦"'¦ ¦ ¦¦.':".¦ The Evolution of a Sanitary Type of Chick Feeder . L. Van Es and J. F. Olney Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene V.I ¦ . ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ , ¦ - : v-:¦¦¦¦¦:;; ¦^¦¦- ¦:-::: v :V;:::'[ The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln ! W. W. Burr, Director ¦;¦¦.'¦¦' .1 •.".-/¦ .'¦ ¦'¦ ¦' ¦¦ ¦¦' ¦ &#132;.:¦¦.:¦'. ;..".' .• .:. ' - :. ¦.; ¦ ¦;.;-: : .¦¦:': ¦¦¦¦.¦ ' ¦¦: ' :¦¦ : ,-\-:::- ¦¦ : </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">j . ¦:¦!¦."¦- ¦ ;¦¦¦¦• . : ¦¦; v i i ¦ ; ¦¦¦ ' '¦¦"'¦ "¦ ¦ ¦.-'¦¦ ¦" ¦¦ ¦.'¦'¦ \ The Evolution of a Sanitary Type of I ( Chick Feeder ¦.'.¦.¦'¦ l L. VAN ES AND J. F. OLNEY ' In the practice of livestock sanitation no more difficult problem is i encountered than the one pertaining to the prevention of fecal contamina - tion. In the I prophylaxis of a series o£ animal diseases it transcends all others in importance. This is particularly the case in connection with coccidiosis of|young chicks. . . : '¦'.'. :.; : . In a study of the influence of environment on the incidence of certain ; poultry diseases, undertaken by this Station, it was shown that in the I prevention of coccidiosis, ordinary and reasonable sanitary measures are • ¦'. | '¦'... . . ¦ • .'".-'.¦': . ¦ . .;¦ :; Fid. I.—Feeder 3iA. not sufficient. It was found to be imperative that for complete success even the slightest degree of fecal contamination must be eliminated. In the experiments mentioned measures in environmental hygiene, quite successful against other poultry diseases, yielded only indifferent results in connection with coccidiosis of chicks. Hence the possibilities of : fecal contacts were subjected to scrutiny and gradually removed. The last one of these adverse factors was found to be associated with the type of feeder used in the jyards. This type of feeder was successfully designed to prevent the entrance of fecal matter and of the chicks them- </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraski Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 306 \\ ! 33A s In.. 2.—(tuns sfctmn ami tront clc\jtii»n nl Fecdci" J3A. VVAAAAAyyOvJOUYYYxYYi^ Fig. 3.—Feeder 34A. ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p005">.'¦; A Sanitary Type op Chick. Feeder selves, but it proved to have a fatal and more or less unforeseen detect. The top of this outdoor self-feeder was made broad enough to provide shelter against rain for the feeding chicks. This top with its broad, gently sloping parts provided the laslj factor in the spread of coccidiosis to be eliminated. It afforded a roosting place for the chicks, always on the look - out for some elevated situation to find peace and recreation. A certain amount of fecal matter was deposited on the feeder top and coccidial pocysts were found to) be present in this material. It was further found that speculation of these obcysts had been completed and that the chicks,would partake o£ the contaminated feces. When the latter happened to be bloody, the material ap rarently had a marked attraction for the birds. It need not be pointed out, therefore, that the stage was set for the spread of the disease. ¦&gt;.'¦ ¦ . j A j \AAMAAAAAAMAAAAAAAAAAAMMA hlt : ¦-¦ it i 3v..| M •¦; ¦•:¦¦¦ y &lt; : 1 n.\\ //0 ;' 'II :-.1 -'A' I ij ij PR: 1 _&lt;_ II "\ \ _ ¦ ¦ ; \^ . Fig. 1. —Cross section and front elevation of Feeder 34A. As a result of these observa :ions, efforts were made to design and con - struct a feeder in which all hizards of fecal contamination could be set aside. This was done with a considerable degree of success, although in the development of one type of such feeders, certain unforeseen problems were encountered, all of which had at least some sanitary importance. For the purpose of their solution a number of working models were con - structed and tried in the brooder rooms and poultry houses and yards. . It was found that feeder designs based on self-feeder principles should conform to the following specifications: (1) the exclusion of all possibility of the chicks to use the feeder as a roosting place; (2) adequate feeding space and head room; (3) protection against the chicks' entering the feeder; (4) a maximum degree of prevention of feed wastage; (5) a ready passage </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 306 6 of mash from hopper to feeding space; (6) simple and inexpensive con - struction, enabling the poultry grower to make his own feeders; (7) in the case of outdoor feeders, protection against the entrance of precipitation water into hopper or feeding space. In the feeders herein described and illustrated, some of these specifica - tions were fully met, in others only partially so. From a purely sanitary Fir.. s.—Feeder 348. point of view all were satisfactory in the environment in which they were used. At least some of the models made materially contributed to the prophylaxis of coccidiosis, perhaps of all diseases the most difficult one to prevent. In the construction of the working models %-inch and !^-inch lumber was used. With one exception (feeder 35A), simplicity of construction was aimed at. Galvanized sheet iron was used for the protective device </seg>
         <seg id="p007">A Sanitary Type of Chick Feeder on the ridge of the feeder tip and also for some of the hoppers. The feeding space was divided by pieces of No. 9 wire in order to prevent the entrance of the chicks. The length of the feeders varied, ranging between 5 feet, 4 inches, and 8 feet, 2 inches. It seemed desirable not to exceed the maximum length and feeders from 6 to 7 feet in length are probably to be preferred, the number of chicks to be served, of course, being a determining factor. '¦!;' "..-.' ; ''¦:.¦, - -( The feeders for indoor use were made with feeding space on both j sides, and the sides of the top cover, triangular in cross section, were given | such a pitch that they were unsuitable for roosting. .! ;. As far as the behavior differences displayed by the various groups of chicks of identical age and breed made it possible, an attempt was made aVH. '*' |!- f'v^i '¦! I rtitfii I ¦&#132;¦'¦ ¦' ¦ •¦•'' ' ''¦'¦ :::::::: z&gt;, ' . «&lt;*. . v VI ('¦"¦ ¦ °"'r "~ ; &lt; •¦':¦ :.' . \r..,.,.., i. •:• —¦ I ¦— — — ¦ : ¦¦:. i/v^wj ¦¦.;¦ UaAJ ..,...,¦ ¦ '¦'-: . ¦'.¦: . ¦ ! ... ¦.¦""¦ ' Fio. 6.—Cross section and front elevation of Feeder 348. : in the construction of each model to correct defects and errors which came to light when the preceding ones were used. : . -The first model made was feeder 33A (Figs. 1 and 2). It was primarily designed to be operated: during the four-weeks brooding period. In order ¦to prevent the chicks from befouling the top of the feeder, a wire was stretched about one inch aboje the ridge. This '. proved to be a futile attempt. The birds would fly on the wire, press it down, and the more the chicks participated in this activity the less did the wire interfere. The front of the feeder| trough was made with upright sides and although a "4-inch strip was nailed on the inside, the wastage of feed was often quite considerable. The plan of construction furnished other disad - vantages. The distance between the lower edge of the hopper and the feeder floor (% inch) was tod' short. The distance between the two boards </seg>
         <seg id="p008">iNebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 306 composing the hopper was not wide enough at the lower part for a free passage downward of the mash. Although the one-inch width of the individual feeding spaces was adequate, there was not enough inside head room for the feeding chicks after they were two weeks old. Hence, head injuries caused by contact with the external surfaces of the hopper could be observed. This feeder showed certain sanitary advantages, but on the whole it was not satis - factory and could be used only during a limited period. The design of feeder 34A (Figs. 3 and 4) was an improvement over the preceding one. This feeder is larger and provides adequate inside head room. However, for the smallest chicks the width of the individual feeding spaces (1% inches) was a bit too wide. The distance between Fie. 7.—Feeder 34D. hopper and feeder floor and the width of the throat of the hopper was increased to one inch and this was fairly satisfactory, although the mash had to be periodically pushed down. Substituting an inward sloping side of the feed trough for the per - pendicular one helped to reduce wastage, but did not prevent it com - pletely. Recorded wastage by chicks ranged between 6.1 and 8.8 per cent and amounted to 8.6 per cent when the feeder was used for brooder poults. For the purpose of preventing the soiling of the top a strip of gal - vanized iron was made to constitute the ridge of the feeder instead of the wire as previously used. The galvanized iron strip, although, without doubt, by no means a comfortable roosting place, did not prevent the birds from congregating on the top of the feeder. When, however, the </seg>
         <seg id="p009">A Sanitary Type of Chick Feedek. strip was provided with a serrated edge all desire to rest upon it disap - peared. This principle was 'adopted for the indoor feeders subsequently made and proved to be the solution of the problem..: In the construction of feeder 34D (Figs. 7 and 8) an attempt was made to do away with the long throat at the lower part of the hopper, in the hope that by doing so the mash would pass more freely into the feeder trough. This proved to be a delusion. Although this feeder fully met sanitary requirements in feeding practice it proved to be a rather poor utensil. Under certain circumstances the increased head room within tended to promote an excessive wastage of feed. Accurately determined wastage by chicks ranged between 7.4 and 19.0 per cent and was 93 for brooder poults. . T /R FUAAAAA/WMAAA/WWvAAAAMAA/v ;| fetMl . ;^; ¦/ '%kf*t. If : ¦¦¦¦¦'.&lt; ¦-¦¦¦' .| ¦¦'¦¦"'¦ ¦ ¦¦-•.¦¦ ¦ ¦¦- . Fig. B.—Cross section and front elevation of Feeder 34D. '¦¦'.¦¦'¦ I¦ ' i . . ' ¦ ¦ ¦ In feeder 34E (Figs. 9 and 10) the wooden hopper was replaced by one of galvanized metal. This resulted in a more free downward move - ment of the mash, ibut did not obviate the need of occasionally forcing the feed into the trough. On the whole this feeder proved to be quite satisfactory and adequate from a sanitary viewpoint. Recorded wastage observed in the use of this' feeder was 15.8 per cent for chicks and 6.2 for poults. T Feeder 35A (Figs. 11, 12, and 13) was designed to be more elastic than the preceding ones and to meet the requirements of growing chicks. In order to accomplish this, detachable fronts with feeding spaces of dif - ferent width were provided. The design also includes an arrangement by which the distance between the lower part of the metal hopper and the bottom of the feed 'trough may be increased or decreased. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 306 Three adjustable fronts with individual feeding spaces of three-fourths inch, one inch, and 1 % inches respectively were constructed and tried. In practice the front with %-inch spaces proved to be unsatisfactory but with the other two fronts the feeder proved to be adequate for brooder chicks and poults and during a considerable period beyond brooder age. Hence, for practical purposes only two interchangeable fronts need to be provided. It is possible that the design of this model may be somewhat complex for home manufacture. On the other hand, the feeder proved to be quite satisfactory. In regard to wastage of feed and the need for pushing the mash down into the feed trough, it showed no advantage over the pre - ceding model. Recorded wastage by chicks amounted to 8.0 per cent. Fie. 9.—Feeder HE. Only one type oi feeder adapted to the outdoor feeding of chicks older than brooder age was designed. It is designated as feeder 348 (Figs. 5 and 6). It proved to be satisfactory from the first and no further attempts at improvement were made. This feeder is of the simplest construction and so designed as to become part of the yard fence or house wall. Its feeding front is flush with the inside of the fence and hence there is no projecting part upon which chicks can find a roosting place. A steeply sloping board is fastened above the feeder opening so as to keep rain water from entering the trough. The opening on the top of the hopper is situated on the outside of the fence so that the yard need not be entered for the purpose of filling the feeder. This feature also contributes to its sanitary value. This feeder was found to be adequate for chicks of from to 12 weeks o\d and even o\der. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">A Sanitary Type of Chick Feeder , When used by. a chick p filiation of an approximately even size, the wastage was negligible. This design proved to be an important factor in the prevention of coccidiosis 1. A larger feeder similarly designed for the feeding of turkeys from brooder age on to maturity also proved to be eminently adequate. As already stated an attempt was made to construct a type of feeder by which the problem ofl fecal contamination and contacts could be eliminated. This was accomplished in a satisfactory manner. However, aside from this primary objective certain other features of a more indirect hygienic importance presented themselves. A. vV\AAAAMAMtyWA/VW\MA/\A/VW\^ 44 E V ** Tk ..........-yT) ]• ~~~ : ~~~ ' "' ""/ ill ;llr ":; ¦ * Fig. 10.—Cross sc:tion and front elevation of Feeder 34E. An effort was made to meet some of these difficulties in the construc - tion of successive working riodels until feeders, reasonably suitable for the special purpose, could be supplied. In these attempts all the disadvantages associated with otherwise adequate feeders could not, however, be entirely eliminated without wandering too far away from the authorized mvesti - gational project. The principal sanitary problem was solved and rurtner improvements are left to oners who may wish to undertake them. For such a purpose certain observations made in connection with the feeders and their utilization may be worthy]of consideration. More or less wastage was associated vith all the indoor feeders byf which mashi was fed to chicks. Such wastage may not constitute an absolute loss if the spilled feed can be collected and used for other animals such as pigs or fowls in which the transmission of coccidiali parasites is of little or no </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 306 consequence (mature birds ready for dressing). However, on the whole, any considerable waste of feed may prove to be costly and should be pre - vented to the limit of possibility. Feed waste, furthermore, has a very definite sanitary importance. Unless the spiJled feed, by the use of wire panels or some other device, can be made inaccessible to chicks, wastage tends to defeat the very purpose of hygienic feeding. It constitutes a means of fecal contact. As in the case of a water supply, it may be truly said that from a purely sanitary point of view a food supply is never better than the worst to which a chick Fie. 11.—Feeder 35A with removable fronts showing M-inch, 1-inch, anil 1 Vh -inch spaces. population may have access. Hence, any feeder design by which waste can be eliminated would supply one of the most desirable improvements. In connection with the wastage problem it was observed that it may not altogether be a structural one. Although of identical age, size, and breed, the chicks of various populations displayed marked differences in their ingenuity for wasting feed. Among the factors involved in wastage, differences in the size of the birds is perhaps the greatest. When these differences were such that the feeding spaces available to chicks were too narrow for the larger, and yet wide enough to permit ingress of the smaller ones, it became exceedingly difficult to cope with wastage and the subsequent fecal contamination. In </seg>
         <seg id="p013">h Sanitary Type of Chick (Feeder i one population in which there were many small, unthrifty birds owing to . bacillary white diarrhea, all sanitary efforts were'most thoroughly defeated. ; Another observation was likewise instructive. It pertained to a flock .1 of turkeys fed from outdoor feeders of type 348. As long as mash only ";•' was fed, wastage was negligible and did not manifest itself until the mash ; had added to it some whole grain or coarselyj cracked corn. Evidently the poults preferred the latter type of feed and diligently threw out the other. When the jwo kinds of feed were provided in separate feeders, there was ho further wastage. I &lt; V-:-. M\ f i •¦¦—•"-;¦•¦•( ;J] J 7 ¦ uf.: \ \ f / /// B P^VSN ' - : Its. \ " c J;:¦¦ III:^ill\ .I-.-,*-,ii: _A ¦ • irrth ivA"\"XvJ '111 v r \\ y¦• .-;¦; . .-.- j .;,.:..¦ r*. :, ;--- ¦ ; " ¦ Fio; 12.—Feeder 35A: a—cross section showing positions of removable fronts, : - b—elevation, c —adjustment to raise or lower hopper, d—end braces of front, ¦¦: : c—center braces of front, f—cross section of front. ' In the operation of the above feeders, the clogging of the mash in the j, ; hoppers could not be absolutely avoided. It was necessary to push the j ¦.:.; feed down two or three times a day.. The use of metal hoppers brought about some improvepent, but it did not constitute a complete remedy. It i was further observed that the atmospheric humidity exercised an influence. I A high absolute humidity always promoted the clogging, and, no doubt, the addition of cod-liver oil did not improve matters. . ¦'.¦;.'' In the construction of the various models the width of the individual feeding spaces also proved to be something of a problem. Eventually a one-inch space for the smaller chicks and 1% inches in width for those .a week or two older, proved to be satisfactory. It was also observed that </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 306 mj n 1(7 Wmf at c ci Fin. 13.—Removable fronts with !4-inch and 1-inch spaces: a — end braces, b—crnter braces, c —elevation, d—cross section nf front. chicks disliked to thrust their heads into a dark space and therefore an increase in the height of the feeding spaces may be suggested as a further improvement. i The space available between the front of the feeder and the external ii surface of the hopper within also had to be considered. Too little head room produced bruises and abrasions and too much space contributed to wastage by a/lowing too much room for lateral head movements. The arrangement and dimensions of the last constructed modeh, on the whole, proved to be quite adequate. I3M) </seg>
         <seg id="p015"/>
         <seg id="p016"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>