<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00030.00031">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00030.00031</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  THE INHERITANCE OF QUANTITATIVE CHARACTERS IN MAIZE.</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Till I'XIVEKMITY &lt;»l NEBRASKA. BU LLETI N KK THK AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE INHERITANCE OF QUANTITATIVE CHARACTERS IN MAIZL H \ KMER8ON, THB I MUl:-lll M N'BIRAHKA. AMI I \l I rniN !&gt;► Harvard I PI HI ICATKIN VI &lt;il l«T 16, I'll.' LINCOLN, NEBRASKA I S A Hi Oil I AHOKATMIN Hi </seg>
            <seg id="p002">■ AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD. EiU.ES B. ORABI ORABLE THAI. ORABI E WILLIAM I THE STATION OFFICERS '•AI.KS. THE WORKING STAFF K. Alt.w. v\ at • K. J. A R. K. MM, li. 8. A Lawu EKWI \ H. 1UKI: G. R R. A O. V O. A. ■ p. &gt; I'la f\V. lii M. H. Swkvk. A .,; ... OaoaeK K. K. Link, A. M R. 8. Tki Mm ii. A bwix Hni'T. I: I P. B. Bakkf.ii. A M J. A. Rah i in. A I few Aitutam C. B. I.ck. B. S&lt; .. Attittti L. B. Ooom, B. 8c.. Attttta, KSTGATE. A. M.. AlK H. L. Nyf &lt;&gt;K NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p003">TENTS rodnction t theory of iniiltipl' - MtTVrrinjr ;i sinizN- char* couples 8 i mi materials H nheritanoe of — Number of rows per • 28 •h of ears 40 Diameter of earn 54 2 lit of sepds Ith of seed* lit of plant.* Ximrtier of nodt's per stalk 79 Iiiternodc length Niiinhfr of stalks per plan' Total keafftk &lt;if stiilks pw plain 98 I )iiration nf irrowtli 9* Nliinipulatioii of ■in.iiii iiativt- rharacten in ptaat Im-pding. . 11&lt;i 1 18 sum dim i-\ and ytial RonclusktiM l" ;&gt; &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">THE INHERITANCE OF QUANTITATIVE CHARACTERS IN MAEL 1H0KATION OF It. A. KMKKSON AMI K. M. I INTROIHVTION. VVkea Mmxirl'i law of heredity was rediscovered by Con - • l&lt;- Vriea, and vmi Tschcrmak. must biologists were jujrtly iial of tin- |«&gt;ssihilit\ that it mi^ht be general in scope. Tin- earl re that a vile range of breeding facts in both ninial and ilic vegetable kingdom were made orderly and -iiin l&gt;v using i In- Mcndeliau notationf brought about only .in '-haunt- in this attitude A few optimistic minds Mievti i In- similarity &lt;&gt;f the breeding pheaaaMM in animals and in i&gt;lanis indicated thai the MeudeHaa m&lt;M-liaiiism was intimati'lv aMOciatod with tliat fundanifiital ftmetm MMMI to both king \u;il rt'|irodin-t ion. TkOK \\ lio reasoned in this mannet MM|M'&lt;'ti'il a Itinad pHMtml upnation of tht&gt; law of segregation and nhination of unil tacton. The r»Miiainitiir irr*&gt;st t majority in their poaitiea of mpectfal distrust. Tlici-c wwc scvi-ral n-asoiis for this situation. A &lt;;o&lt;&gt;dly por of l In- ifs|ioiisiliilit \ for il rrsts apov di- \ries. who. from uf ilmilitfiil si«;nitii-aiiri'. drew tin- In-oad i-oiii-lusion that :^il cbaracten and speciCc chararters olwy quite ditfen-nt • it heredity. L'apaircd or unisi-xual characters he bettered in hi lain to tin- rank of eperillr dilt'crcnces. These char he thoafht, an- JBcapahit of Mendelian Mgitgatka. iliaracti-i-s he called paired or bisexual qualities, ami he lM-liexeil worthy of only varietal rank. The fallacy in • Ir Vi-ies" reasoning is otwiona, now that ISateson's pre«HMe and Harvard I'niversity, Mussey Institution. Jamaica I'lain. Mass. il lit- inevailinK Mendelian terminology is followed in this paper, but assumed that the writers regard Mendelian formula- as r than a helpful descriptive shorthand convenient for describing dint fa&lt;ts Hypothetical germ cell factors are substituted for somati. i hey are useful in exactly the same manner that hypo - n-al lormulse are useful in describing chemical reactions. To establish coat* in ion that quantitative characters are essentially Mendelian in r inheritance, therefore, it is only necessary to show that the notation lately describes the breeding facts. ■ 1( EXP mm a i ii». Hn— f In nil in i n IT! I Tin </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Pf&gt;t a reversal of de Vries' views. Tor the presence and ji I »—• tion is based on the fact that the hereditary transmission of ;in only be determine when the factor is BMseat in one ie parental gametes and absent from the other. tL ncoad reason for limitin&lt;r the operation of Mendel* law the earlier ■iscoBcept the kaspertaaes of tin- phearaaa - i of &gt; - reason shortly ifaapajeand • In found that |&gt;erfect dominance w;is the exception rather than rule and that cases when- dominance was entirely laekini: • nth found. Tli' concessions That contributed nraea of the Mendelian weep mbliag-Moek to Mendelist, in the eonparati of quantitative variation*. The variations whaaa beharisr in crosses rieMed t&lt;&gt; • sini(ilp fact jii-etai ion were all qaal I n rharaeter. Tln-\ could iwaaonalih l&gt;&lt; l«e tn the pn - of Hoiiietliiiii: in the puai tuber was law with the ninltitudi :iins r-ommon l&lt;&gt; of these differences, it is true were fluctuations due to env which were nun In ritalile.* Imt tl variations were leg \hout tli iMitlieKis was |' which i of facts under the soo| recomliination. Tlie non which thi~ pothesis was then based and the data th. ieen colk sasscqnently are coatparatively few. \et the fact that the ex|&gt;eri I of sevi'ral inde| irrobora ii every detail makes ii plausible to ■■•n \n- established herond the suggest;., ti that th 'ian phenomena really do transmissible character potentialities are transferred hi ivpical sexual reproduction. In othei- words Mendelian phenomem in some way Itound up in and coincident with that preparation of the reproductive cells called maturation and th&lt; nent fusion to form a new organism. This, it is thought is an ad iniRsihle induction from the conspicuous diversity and profusion •It has been shown that if aria &gt;onaea are ever heritable th. phenomenon is so rare that it may be ne*l' tpwli— U i ulturea. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">unl from the fact thai the only indis - putable . DOD-mendeUxiBg eaaracaw are ill that dis - ■i ivns in 1/ iniliilix jiiI/i/mi, where a pathological con - dition affect inn a le;if function is mrrM by the cytoplasm and 1 li 1-1 1 ihe innther. and i "_' i that reported by Baur U . in which vi e aggregates isectorial &gt; 1 1- in F plants anil breed true in re|.i;inre of this point of view depends largely upon whet 1 interpretation of the inheritance of i|uantita Minus has beta reached. The authors, therefore, desire to miltinii a somewhat romplete discussion of the inheritance of gorj of variations. sti|iported by data from experiments that have Iveen gathered inde|tendently. If there be that the eoin-liisions drawn are too broad since the liave beea gathered from ■ single plant species, the authors -wer that e;ich has made corroborative investigations ■pea other s|&gt;ecies whii'li they ex|M-i-t to publish in the near future. The experiment! conducted by one of the writers were begun .it the &lt; onnei-i ii-nt Agricultural Rxpertaeat Station at New n in IMS and removed to the I'ussey Institution of Harvard • ■rsitx at Torest Hills. Massachusetts, in lft&lt;»0. The iii.i In employed in this study consisted principally of crosses of Tom Thumb pep with Black Mexican sweet and of Watson flint with Learning dent. The nuinlter of rows per ear were noted in i| other In- parents of which are listed later in this I'm- help in gatheViag and compiling The data fnun tlies. - e are indebted to H. K. Hayes, plant breeder of the i iiiiiiecticnt Auricultural KxjM-rinieni Station, and to O. K. While and l&gt; I.. l&gt;avis. irraduate students in genetics at liar The iNperimeiils of tile other writer were begun at th ;i Ajii icultuial l'.x|&gt;eriment Station at Lincoln in IMP. • i In- have been continued to the present time. A part o the material studied in 1911 was irrown at the Bussey Institn - liofl at Torest Hills. Massachiisett*. The plants used in this «itiid\ were crawM of Tom Thumb pap with Missouri dent ami t- latter variety with California |M»p. For assistance in con ..n with this work, we acknowledge our indebtedness to R. F. Howard, now assistant horticulturist of the Wisconsin Aft] tural Experiment Station. !o F. ( *. Miles, graduate student in il the 1 niversin of Nelnaska. to K. H. llerniinjrliaiis. student assistant, atnl particularly m I'.. B. Bwiag, who has com imted ni'.«t nt the siatisi -liiiiiv fioni tin 1 data obtained from the Nebraska exix rimetiis </seg>
            <seg id="p008">- THE THEORY uF MLI.IIIN.K FA CHARA' Batesou ami later other writer! have shown thai development af &lt;|iiiilitiiii\&lt;- ckmrmttttm BMJ de|M-ml upon the interaction of M MM pMsetif ' lai are tranaaiitted independently When &lt; • 1 1 • - ni !iii-&gt;c iNscni ini Carton is ahmt fiinn the ivgote the ter does nut develop. Tims color in the sweet pea. nl&gt;. in siiii|Mli':i^i&gt;ns. in primula*, in beans, and in I lie hair nioiiH iininiiils iIih's not develop unli-ss ■ basic factar erallv known ;is ilu- color (actor I -• nt in addition to rh. color deterininei- which li\ nlc af tl oler. When either the eaaar hetw ar ih&lt;- apaeMe Aatnatiner ia :il&gt;s»-nt. ealar ■Icveloji. II two |.«|«i&gt; |.ulilislicl m \'M» and 1!»*i:i. Nilaaoa Khlc ■ •&lt;! thai certain . nlors in wheat ami in oats air determined &gt;\ single factora 'mi l&gt;\ several, the |iri-s&lt;-ncc o| of wliicli a &lt;l«'i •-i-iii i ii&lt;- the i-ohii' In other u. iliho affi i ic i-hanu lot all&lt;'lonior|ilii&lt; to each other. Imt ta their owii Dhle in 1MB showed how such fai theorv iBterftretiaaj ihe iaawritaace •&gt;( tfuentii altlio no experimental Aa mhtuitted tu rapporl A liti le l.i 1 • i aahniitteil a similar ped a HJinilar tlieor\ IKortunatelv this t\ |m- of in &lt; show in;: iloniinaiice. oihei i.-nlt. We « i ir hamriag on tin I- of &lt;|iianiitat ive rhai Nilsson Khle &gt; I ! together manv viirietien ■&gt;! differing: in jrlunie color. The rcsiili* from all Imt one of then* entases \u-re qtrite simple. Prear ace of color dominated abai Where the jwrents differed in one character pair, such as Mncfc H) ami al.Kcn.-e of Mack (hi. Ihe ratio in f was .: : 1 When the |&gt;arents differ«*&lt;l in two alMoi and absence of black (hi. ami &gt;\ nkaJOMC oi . the ma U alack : '■&gt; (traj : 1 whit' m the ciaaaea .ml H;i couhl not Im- tliotin^uisheil. So far ihere were no BBast learned o* Nilsson-Khl. s sexmd paiier, which does not in &gt;l&gt;ment of the quantitative inheritano' thenrv. afti r the first of his own |ia)x&gt;r was written, hut Nllaaon-Ehli full credi&gt; autiful r- - inalitativ. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">be plumed race, however, the F 2 generation was '&lt;■'&lt;» 10 while, clearly ■ ratio of 16 black : I white. Hire red in &gt;«' two fat-tors tat black, each dominant to its i ml rccomhining independently. The i-k rail- may l»e expressed as B l B 1 H.B 2 be while race :is h h \&gt;.h,. The F, generation brings tors to The heteroi nditinn, and ::/./.': 1 /-,''.. I'.tit as the first three i|i|M-aiaine. the i-atio of F 2 is 15 black : 1 texperiotentiBg with wheat. Nilsson Ehle found a di ill Meiidelian rat in. A bfwwi headed wheat croBged with a e headed variety f*TC in F_ 1110 brown headed plants to 94 ■ led plants, a ratio exactly 1.V1. There is hardly a •t ih;ii the brown headed variety had the formula B i B 1 li /&lt;_ tin- white headed varietx the formula l^b^b.b.^. The proof of iiitei-pi-etai ion comes from a more surprising experiment of wine investigator. He ma«le six crosses between a red seeded wheat and a white ■ I variety. The !■', plants were all re&lt;l-seeded : th&gt; il&lt; in rutinn irrrr ahn n ilxit'ilnl. This result . ii liar that selfed seed of all of the 78 F, plants of one own and the progeny of each recorded in the F, it This result was obtained: |ilants pive only red-seeded plants H F plat approximately ;! red : 1 white plants. approximately LS red : 1 white plants. F plant* jjave approximately •!."! red : 1 wkite plants The iniei pretation of this result wm that a trihybrid had been produced hi l&gt; /.' I' I,' I,' A' with r,i each R i in-ill^ ;ihle to produce tlie red color in the seed, but segre - ig «itli its own al&gt;s&lt;-nce ind&lt;'pende!itl.\ of the other factors. The red I" i;ciieiation would have the formula R,r I,' r A' /■ and should h\ rccomltinatioii produce &gt;'&lt;'■'. i-ed : 1 white plants in F . To be sure no white seeded plants were obtained in the 384 in - dixiduals forming the total F generation, but such a result might \|.ecti'i| frei|iientlv in chance nuttings of this type following the Law &gt;i! l&gt;ror. unless more F pnigeny were grown. The real proof of the interpretation come* from the F generation as n.iiiil before. The F generation, theoretically, consists of 63 red* to 1 white The r.:: red plants, tho similar in ap|&gt;earanre. should have tin- different ircntic formulae expected of an ordinary tri- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">&lt; 'ollcitinj; the MM) i»f ! tiixl thiii tin- i. MlllV Ill'ill Illillillllllll 111 -Ili'lllil (fiv« ill I . VV Ill-ll -' liniililiy Hue In inl. K l Ihiivv ini; nils :niil vvliiii-* hi 1 1 1 - S:l, U Unmiiag red* .mil whins in the ratio of 15:1, and ■ throwing n^)^ :ni&lt;l whiiis in tin- ratio of S3 1 From t on** &lt;-mi I'lilriilatf tin- ino^t pnifiiililf nsnlt in tin pxperii • T^ plants vviir f. ■! l&lt;&gt;\\ &lt;■«! la tin- 1" ifffWlti— It Tv|- e\|x I I. .1 - li - 7. ■ - - m. - 11 - 12. ('law n Claw U Omm Cbuw 17 Claw Iv Claw id (Maw M. Claw M ■s iii 1 E /.'///.' // A" ■1 R I /.' •_• R i: i; i i: i; 1 i: R R R i: , I 8 R \ / I / » I 1 /.' /; l: ■1 h ■1 i, I /," K I . /.' /,- 1 /,' L' « •_' R I /,' 1 /.' R i J B I "im| • &lt; 1 1 I V !rll &lt; ill I • li-&lt;| iimIv red n«h i im| iinh lll| II|||V ri 1 1 &lt;nil\ J I \\ 1 1 i i i i&lt;l nnl\ . rid i&gt;\\\\ . iiil iinlv. 15 ri-il : 1 » li'l nil i in I \ . red om\\ . i -cil nali 13 ri-&lt;l I u hi nil nlll.\ . nil ulil\ nil ulilx . 15 nil : I w hi I ml.' i;l nil iii ■iil&gt; . II win i. • iil.\ . itn brwilmc true in nil ing 3 nil : I » Int. . ml 1 whit.- in(t t'M nil 1 «liit&lt; l'.t II 12.7 Ml x 1". M U </seg>
            <seg id="p011">"iilil Im- .1 mosi wonderful coincidence if i lie theorv were The tin- tbeori Atvtloped b\ Hast il'tlo. i. Two factors for the production of ..lor in the eadtaapena i&gt;f mate vctc found. The pre* - tor produced \cllnw seeds identical in appear U .illeloiiiorphic to its own absence in rroMM. \n ear with the scygotio formula ) ) was exactly like u 1 1 is true that tliere m a cnnm is with the zymotic formula 1 , V, V V. were color than those nonioxygona for a single teeter, but lionio/.v^ous for eithi-r single factor were indis ■ le from any cross which produced the con 11 Approximately 1"&gt; yellow*: 1 white in the hen selfed. A total of :&lt;.-.- MfMprtH ! I I NV ei-e yellow and 341 white. This ratio .:ul.\ 15:1, the closest possible ratio bring I therefore astonishing I \ rlase to theo re followed to the P. irfin ration, and | they varied in zvgotic constii ution in accord which has just beea outliiu d. Theoretically of I' ■! Id have the following Rv|mHe formulae I' ffvM in I ) ) ) F, all \ellow all yellow all yellow. l."i yellow : I while, all yellow. .'! yellow : 1 w hite all yellow :! yellow . I white .|i of these rlasws providtnl for l&gt;\ the theory were actually ned. Those ears having the formula r,T,Mh were indis - nhftble from th. having the forniula y^l.Y.Y.,, bat where V ) , and V &gt; were both present in the same y.ygote the -■ • ria were a much darker vellow th.m where either veliow alone W . ! s | . It should l&gt;c noted that Emerson , 1!M1 i has found two yellow '■olors in the endosperm of maize that seem to be unlike in uppuriiw, &lt; &gt;ne is i golden yellow and one a light vellow. It '-silile that further observations will show that the orange vellow is «lue to the cumulative action of two similar or identical ,, - ' J ( 1 1,1 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11- a hitherto unol* factor ii ir tin I'Ik-1 iciion. East an&lt;l Bayei (ltlli rapartod one other caw ni | in rompai'iii o thai form irp wb • pnMiit only in sunlight wen eroMSi. T' jpener ;u mi instead of hcmtif ti-it. a fraieiiiip '"i :iii«I without ill. up in ih«' ratio of 16:1. The ■ further p made on I h producing apimrenth • ■ cha nn l«&gt;inor|thi&lt; I i|i&gt; whi'ii hi i Ik- .i! Ih- !l II ihc -llllW III) - i nt«M-;i«-1 i iili wouM uficii Im- l.ickini; Tli - I I he ilassi«-.i! . | ihIm.i ra«U-ir&gt; in w« ration is MipiMwed lo h;i - in-i^l trinv \ strikiiiL.' rhanirtw in Hn Btak ■ .ir Ihc a llcloiiioiplii. |MJn slmw .i|i|«-ar in ui\c &gt;ii&lt; li | icmiIi One &gt;lnnil&lt;l !•&lt;• careful. ;iIm.iiI if|Kiitili^ hi'liiozv iriiti-s as I. riii \&gt;itlniiil - \liollicr I III | &gt;&lt; &gt;l l;i||| rliiss Of fails nslili^ &lt; • 1 1 lllis tl|, ham»&gt; inav Im- ilhisl lainl I » v tin llial has just 1n-cii ilcsciil.cd. T\\n mai/.i- varieties hntk ' ing true for this peraliar perirarji red thai drretopa mih in a in amount of ligfct. tm FT«ni The K plains \v!i»m, welfed. unexp«*&lt;-ic(ll\ pi\i' one pfaial with ralorinMi pertmrp an the ears oul nf PVet\ sixteen. Now nlir nf lliesi \:ilielies Innl Im-cii j ii-i -\ i&lt; ■ ; i — I \ with a white i nil hud (fivpii the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">■I a sins'*' factor K and ■ •ild when ii met its absence r. Hut since the ■In- two red vark •• the dihybrid ratio in F_,, that, th'i alike in appearance, they were not other. &lt;&gt;ue wi r, and the other I true !&lt;• red within its variety, but when Pi or met me and an F, was produced in both. Tin- resulting neration for thin l\ the same as if a red A',/?,/?..^ had t&gt;eeD d w ii Ii a wlii' .In* iih a ease when mure pairs of factors are iu If imils I I I a. met units &lt;i u n .1, in hybridization. the apparent paradox of two individuals which ■ particular character, giving pure rev I'.ui ihis time the sygote without the chara&lt; ter ii I'.'iti progeny. When one considers the rarit) ■ loni'maiiis or re pure for all factors are in il when three factors «&gt;r more interact, he can hardly avoid ■ ion that hei-e is a jterfectly logical way of accounting .ailed atavism tliat are not explained by i rat-tioi of twi&gt; dominant factors. No definite cases can • .1 out. but it is not uncommon for a florist to have a ippear with regularity tho with extreme rarity for mam iiei- a cross. N'o doubt projter analyses of eon ■ I .iiltm-i-s would elieit simpler explanations of HkM &gt;ui soiiii- of them surely must lie referred to the of phenomena we have just discussed. Tt is quite within — hility lhai some of de \'i-ies" Oenothera mutants originated in fliis maiiner. The roloied sygotes, in i he silunie color of oats and head color n.lor of wheat investigated by Xilsson-Ehle. have been ihe\ wcie exactly alike in apjtearance. This was tlwayi the ease. The eolor produced by additional factors hat iiiimilative. jiarticularly so in the case of ..lined wheat heads. Where the two dominant factors were ut there was wsualh more color developed than where only - in The classes i ould not be distinguished visually. i.iii i he general tendency was cumulative. This fact is nicely rated li\ the F segregates of the maize cross in which yellow sperni Iwharrd as a dih\l&gt;rid. All of the classes having • lilVerent jjametie const ii utions \arv in the intensity of their m rotor. The rdlow becomes lighter in shade in the follow ider: ) ) &gt; ) — ■&lt; \ Tjh *&gt;r r,y,. and These facts (&gt;immi up two new and important phases of Men * ]* 'Mn Ti IU 11" r 1 TjiiM'*' ill* 1 ill?*! i&gt; iiit i m tssi nil i T i «*T lltlVinp IlPw </seg>
            <seg id="p014">11 ins formed under operation of tin- M.-ndelian la*»_ The tter is purely speculative, iicvcrtli. los it in sagyestive. We not know whv two factors should exist Mi. ,tlv cause titicnl i. but emit factor carry 1 Und \\ li e independent nbinatinn in the germ iidicated. If one. take of arjrnmcat onlj i that Mcntlclian factors an » of chromosome ctions (Emerson 1011a i. then the location of any factor "losoiiii- linn ' nionohyhrid ratio ') with a homologous chruMsmne in which I wax absent. ion of the * th chromosomes 1 and I n paired with phrotnosoa ■ if w hicli to the limit of thi i-onHMOii I if in any line of descent ■ I mild Ik-coiii. -ions of the f. ■ new qi. the production of new eh \ second sj.t-.ii that w!i. lers the diffioultv of d - lividnals with all • ininance is li-lian interj.rcf.it ion of the in her therto ' •led. The sirnj&gt;l&lt;- ' this kii plained is the inheritance iM-cnliar physical condition of the starch in ma it and HI). The varieties of maize known as flinty have the end«&gt;- in a hard I i* conditfea Those varieties known as dei -tarch imme&lt;1iatcly surnmndinfr the etnlirvo ;ind th;it it the cap of the in a soft condition so that its jrreat shriakaire while drying - the kernel a dented appearai An eipht-rowe&lt;l yellow flint was crossed with a white dent and jjave in F, an intermediate condition as reirards the ph* nnince of the starch. The selfc. 1 I'tieration pive ears in F, that ran the whole jranint from flint to dent A few were like pure flint ears and ;i few were like pure dent ears, but the preat majority were variously intermediate. Wher followed to the F, generation, however, one ear out of sixteen of the F ears l.red true la the dented condition and one out af ■ ii hi-cd true to the flintv rottdH 'inot describe </seg>
            <seg id="p015">§ particular character (acton here, ar *a.\ such and such ■ - ■•Hi.-iinril ii\ either variety. Hmtc (■ m doubt, how - '. inn thai the presence mm- the abaenc f two factor* of d or other in tin pore condition caused the one dent air n tn Breed iruc. and That the ahaaan (or the - in the pare condition caused the bread 1 trae. Parthenaafe, there is I'-ti'-i- that factorial difference (without doaaiaaaa ■ :illclomof|iliic pairs causes The difference in al appearance of tlie stanh in other maize varieties. IV i is clear thai one may &lt;;ive a valid Men - to the Itehavior of those quantitative eharae i lilcnd in the F, generation. Two adequately 8up ■niitiptiona hum l&gt;e made: first, that dominance is absent 1 1 i&gt;l that two doses ii. &gt;.. the hiunozv irons condition i uf a factor twice the effect of one dose: second, that independent factor* nmnlative in their eparatiea are paired with their absence in * drill. Il.et us assume a case of the so called "Mended" inheritance ■re all fluctuations due to environment are eliminated. A nt 12 inches tall is supposed to be crossed with a plant 2^ II The difference between them is lfi inches. Tf this crence is due io one alleloiiiorphic pair in which dominance iln I" veneration is all intermediate about 20 inches the F generation falls into three classes in which two react - t the urandparental forms and one peaeeaaati the F, form. •in v the per cent arc 12 inches tall, fift.v jmt cent are 20 inches . and twenty five per cent are 28 inches tall. i — \ira in . let us suppose this 1(&gt;-inch difference between the - .i Im' represented liy two allcloniorphic pairs instead of The I generation is ajrain 20 inches tall, but instead of tw i nii ii aea in V . there aiv five classes, viz.. 12. 16. i and 38 inches, and they appear in the ratio 1:4:6:4:1. graadpareatal t.M""s each appear once out of sixteen times Ehe wa.\ this ratio is obtained is hv simple recombination, bnt Miiinance i» al&gt;sent. each time a xiiifrfc -'presence" factor is I. the lieiuht is increased four inches. I I \lili 28 inches ! 2 u,nit I \Rb 21 inches 24 inches » iaRb 20 inches ..(I \.ihh 20 inches. i 2 \&lt;ihh 19 inches .. ( 1 tniHli " i 5 ""Rh 20 inches 16 inches I 1 iiiihli 12 inches. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Mi in this cross, tin- 1" individuals would fall in tin- MM flam as •■&lt;■. but the I" classes would }»■ seven in nunilter and the .lpaicntal sizes would each 1m- recovered onl\ OMi ont nf four limes. I'or four factors there would he nine classes of 'idividnnlH. and tlie jjrandparental trpea would parh onl\ once o\it of 2."iC&gt; times: while with only ei«rht factors, the forms of the fjrandparents would each appear only once out &lt;&gt;f 65.5."' ;ind it would In- ipiite remarkaltle if thev I icd from an oidinat\ cross The entire scheme of this type of inhei-itarx-e ran be expi in niatlieiiiati&lt;al form just Ml Mendolian inheritanii witli full Let u~ Nlendelian i \ 1," or (H 1 Likewise tli' 1 + 1)*" . ha the nnniN insteail ■resenee i Oil till I need when tip t in the ■tpe tlie freqneii li whirl rlaafrc amav form a regular i-nrve called the normal cur • eal ine:ivi. ■ . , : i ;ire similatl' |&gt;l constant deviation from the ;i^ . etr This - ■ is also produced when one plots the Itaftnntions of an\ orjranic channter produce&lt;l b\ the infinite rnmnlnrii conditions. If no non-heriialile fliii'ttiations lapn'naad fen ohaeaff claas to which any partimli •• bt-lonpt saMMld ex]K»ct the following classes in F wlnn pan sti of different sizes di tiering in ti allelomorphic pairs an prossed. The pxtreaMS •sent the jrrandparental tjrpVa in each case, and the inter medial' classes theoretically divide the ditference between the parents into aliipiot parts. It should lie noted, however that this is theory only: in reality the influence of one factor might be t'i-|ilih |&gt;; ilniniiuinre is rompl&lt; expanded binomial. »— 1 (3+ 1 1 » — 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">IT • ., | 1 4 I 4 1 If Lei us now null- ■ few of the practical difficulties iu inter _ breeding results that may follow this method of In t lie theoretical example that we have used for ■ it was assumed that tliei-e were no nun ilile tiiiriiialioiis due to iMiviriiiiineiit. I'nfortunately this ■M in nature. Fluetual ions are everywhere present. ■ ulil obscure the classes to which individuals belong these class differences wen- very large. And since aw usually small, the change of individual form due to ■ • ii 1 1 m-ii 1 ;i 1 cause's makes it impossible to separate U F : p&lt;«pu to the true classes to which each lielongs theoretically the whole trouble. If -flu- table showing the cxp. tn with two pairs of si/.c characters is examined, it is found not all the individuals that belong to a particular size claw the same rrgwtit formula. For this reason one cannot pick ;i certain size and expect them to breed the same. ■ ii-ntialitii-s are likely to l)e different. Furthermore. ing n suits arc undoubtedly complicated In tiion. This correlation need not be gametie. tho such - in all likelihood do occur: they may be merely phvsiological. example, a maize plant might have the gametic possibilities nail plant size and large car size, but it would be foolish to i that a plant capable of only a limited ainonnt of develop 1 • 1 bear M large an ear as if it were, as a whole, capable • development. Thus it must not he expected that M i lilies are always expressed perfectlv in nature. i than it should he expected that theoretical ph\ - in i ions concerning known laws should agree perfectly with ital data The reproductive cells of plants and animals inlecd Im' described as mosaics of inde|K-ndently trans ile factor*, luit a plant or animal certainly can not be lei-ed ■ mosaic of independent unit characters. These &gt;n thai appear to he iaaVpeadeat in heredity act and react upon one another in complex ways during their development. Ehere is ■ means, however, by which it can be determined her segregation does or does not occur in oases of seemingly led inheritance. This is bv comparing the variability* of the * In or* ml the ilat.-i from these experiments it is new ssry T f&gt; n* 1 t nil : 1 1 inr w it n i n* 1 iiiPaniiiK oi wvprm iiininHniaiiiai irrniB uSPfi i •; ir. _'&lt;i li ♦; 1 &lt;u 4 I To r.ti 28 8 I.. 5 l l" i."» ilmi 210 -j:.^ -jki il'ii 4.". ni l = lo-ji </seg>
            <seg id="p018">I. i In* K_.. mikI I! The fiii-i thill .1 hlend in I" il&gt;» blended hsfceritaiM-e obtiiiws. If it iliil i ml future •r«-ii«-r;ui&lt;&gt;ns should breed trme in ilir t\|H Niim-il in F .. If. however, the variahilin &lt;&gt;1 ih&lt;- K gpnei iimih trmiiiT than tluii tit the F generation segregation ;mhI in 'he treatment of statistics. Should any reader be unfamiliar with 11 is hoped that the following abort explanation will ma 1 1 iai ions - 'teeessary to treat them arbitrarily m discontinuous variations example, in one of our studies of heights of maize plants an them into ihri « in* !i &gt; lasses. The names of the classes are etata as* whoe&lt; eludes all the individuals from 57 inches serte is measu which the esMI -arh &lt; lass va ■ ncy with which it occurs and the aun the total nun 1 ally, ih thew d ex|ire«»es the variainlitv ■; h&lt; ' ■ • -i &gt;i. n. \ distribution tr.&gt;m thi&gt; BMM rlass from the in.ai and all to the riuht poattlTe.— squaring them. total number of individuals, and extract ine the square root of i! I a li ie thus obtained hat inches may ters. and only to di nd multn This Kives us a ni&lt; . variability expressed in per i ••( method we have i variability as a single arithmetical term. When terms like the Mean and the Standard Deviation are used also convenient for us to know how much confidence to place In them. Tf we have 100 plants In one frequency distribution and Mt plants in an other, common sense tells us to rely more upon the second di thsn upon the firs' Hut to say just how much &lt; cmti&lt; calculated vali hat is known aa This value is preceded by the plus-or-minus sign -&gt;-. It means that th&gt;rt is an even chance that the true value is found within the limiting values - made by adding to or subtracting from the calculated value the Probabl&gt; Error. For instance, we say that a certain coelllcient of variability is .."52. This means that the chances are even that the true coefficient of variability is within or without the values 6.49 - ami The class of greatest frequency is termed the Mud*. When tn frequency distribution is not symmetrical with respect to the mode it K said to be *****«. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I iBr ..Is true H. Breed true I-V &gt;&gt;l tinclm. \i-l.\ H iuctk*» X-XII • &gt;l ■ XIII XM &gt;» i U-22 inches 1 2r*. |lil U cl..-3 O "" IPI 11 mm n ix "aW '"" J AABhCCDI) i nan 1 '' ' aaltfti'l'fifi 1 I IHHi-rHf) o i i u iti i\t\ i " a ' ' 2 A A Bat t-DD I " "" IABMCOU 2 1 ABHCCDd reed true liBreedlrue M22-2* inches HI) .... rettllru- XM IBtCcDD ■ J.n.he, ! rTTiiiiiim) i&gt;i&gt; i .'&lt;&gt; inches II 1 .4/4' 1 aa BKcctid 1 ..«• - tm*4 inchcsi l iBrecd true </seg>
            <seg id="p020">iltination of a i;iiim-s of Rotiie kind must hav-- taken uliI rliis |mtH variability ' oward mra proof have baca girra l&gt;\ i &lt;«f the invest ji&gt;;iti&lt;iiiB reported ay at least Perhapc brief resume of the results jf i may l&gt;e well t«&gt; illustrate by SMcrete example* just wh.u nori of complexities the ilata e likeh io show if the theory of multiple rfce practical difflcaltiea of proving; this i| in genera] tmaa; let us see in what likeh to preaeal themselves to us in .•■ r I'li-nts. ii a simple case like llial used before, in which the »h1 betweea a 10-ineh plant and ■ 2&lt;&gt;-inch plant ■ he due to four independent, interchangeable, allelo • \aniine the resiiils that are to be exp. F . and I' iieiierations and in bark crosses between an her parent. In ibis example the pre~ - - — .1 to add 2 inches to the height of a of environment on development are assui I El lit &gt; high, has the Ergiitic formula I / 11) in.i the plant I! has the z\gotic formula u.. I \BBCCDD 2i: inches. Since all F, plants K- the zvgotio foi-nmla (m 10 In.) - leBbCcDd, they are all If we apply the formula i I -f-^) 1 for detirmin nc\ distribution of the F the following .rained : in a 14 lti Is _'il S2 M M l B H M 70 56 - &gt;s s I Thus, while the plants of the F, generation are alike, the F - variable. The class of greatest frequency is the i hat of the V generation, but it is really made up of individuals unlike in zygotic constitution and which therefore '.r.-ed \er\ differently in F as is shown in Table 1. I Hue can see clearly what different progenies these various oies will produce. Zygotes selected at random from the ex nes will be more likely to breed comparatively true to their e than will those near tlu- dnss of greatest frequency Thus rhe 71 KTgotK ID to 14 and 22 to 2« inches bigh. 10. or 13." cent, will breed true; lf&gt;. or 21.6 per cent, will produce genies with I'anges of variation of only four inches: anil 48, MJ per ceni. will produce progenies with lanires of eight </seg>
            <seg id="p021">.i!i. will luifil ii-iif : IB, m- M. I ]&gt;• v . |,i..l:' hkIi i-:i ir _ or !'•&gt;.» per eeat, iiiw- pro inrli liiii^cs; tij. in- 3SL2 per pent, l li iw&lt;-i\i n&lt;l Id, or S .T pet cen riif nlil liidiinii • t the popalation toward vhirh .\ • there fbrf erraaeoaa. U \- him $e hiiiiiImt of sizr r.niurs were In -i. iii Hi' mild l« freqf th tl Mi'inl lie nil. Hi I giw rn\ . "I i|ii;ilit; '1 l&gt;\ th^ otliii- L;ri!iil' ■ ■ • re 1'iuwing now in » 1 1. -•■d wilh • ■ ;illcliniiiir|ilii. - &lt;l. i In tin mI liiinm i In ilii. i 11 i |M.|Hil;i|- iinlliiiil mi Mil! \\ likf that • ■ I witli tin' - Ulitimi uf I lie |il ••II the OIK- IiiiimI Iii tllr &gt;i/.r ill the I' an tin- f»tl with the liif^i- |i;it-i'iit. the ilislriliiitinti "ii the him- IuiimI in tlir si/.r uf tin- large parrai ra the nther Tin ffii|iii'iuiis uf the ilasscs U-Twiin dies.' pxtrcmes is found Ir Ing tin' liiiniiiiial -I'Mil uf tin- i;is&lt;- uf iiitcHiiTpiliiiy: the I" iinli\ iilu;ils. InfortniiJitflx oweu merrr inert in praetin a» our hv|^it li.-t ii;il : Tin- first perplexing fartor in pariron iiH-ntal iiifliK'iK-r. Ezteraal roaditiooa inflnenrT the wlmii ■ 1*'\ t'lupiiK'tit uf ImiiIi plantu :iinl Miiimal- I Hit tin" </seg>
            <seg id="p022">tfitilh «vit« helmed with difficulties b\ that tbew i Imm &gt;r«-T i&lt;-:i I sizes are jinxlud uptrnrd and ■ i Om il'»s not know when he !\idii;il s 'in size nhrthiT it even belongs in I'.esides this trouble, the stimulus -i) causes confnaioa. It is - il their |iareiits in size. This enoB is mil one of heredity but one of conditions due to nil- stimulus to development when .1 tn the heirrnz\ 1:011s condition than when it is in the ■ iiclition. Moreover this stimulus is in some &lt;!• ulativc. li Imimm roughly with the iiiiiiiIht of hi ton Por this rfllOl il is ■ force that aids environ t in 1 individual* that theoretically should be in one 11I11 ;i different 1 ' ' tin these are not the only troubles. One is not often- if M two plains i?i which any particular size dilfer lie npreseine.1 \&lt;\ a notation like 1 \ it \m .111,1 \ in iinhesi + AABBCC. A {jreat majority 1 1 -&lt; ■&lt; 1 1 1 « - 1 1 1 1 \ crossed thru insect or other agei&gt; • ninpaiai ivelx la rye number have flower sinictui-' ; .- ■ '1 ■! that lhe\ are always cross fertilized. Iletero ■ ;ilsn favored b\ hisexuality wherever it oecui-s. Many e therefore hybrid complexes from which I rtcieiii kinds can In- isolated liv inbre«*dinjr. Other plants ~i«M-iall\ adapted to aelf-fertiliiatioB may be homo - iic;irlv all their irametii- factoi-s. for self-fertilization - in eliminate heterncTKoaift. I tut such cases arc not common. narih &gt; mm- may pmuM that the two individuals he a ■ ■ iv heteroiyKom for a considerable number of fn&gt; 1 variability which the F, irenenttion lie expected to show over that shown by the F, jreneration. tieration in which the zygotie con 1 ion of each individual is not the same as would be the caw both parents completely homo/.y^ous. A series of F erations rained from different P, individuals, for this reason. ma\ liiite dill'ereiii in their variability. En the other hand, it may sometimes hap]»en that the vatia of the F generation exceeds that of the F. ireneration in a •e unsiis|MMted by the difference in Rize of the pareir l!tl&lt;h predicted that if the theory of multiple interchangeable Rating fai tors pive a time interpretation of the behavior of • 1 1 1 ;i 11 1 ital i\c iharacters in rrflMM woulil be found when t 1 i I till ■■! I iii siy«- would show iicirkcd siye l*ecouiliin*ttions </seg>
            <seg id="p023">111 K . Tin li&gt;r — •■•-!&lt; ■ | &gt;Ij&lt; ii&lt; &gt;i i &gt;• i - /.&lt;•. The size in plant No. 1 la due to the influence of fai-tom " I I /•'/&gt;' '''." the size in plani Xo. - is due to of factors "DDEEFV." Three im« rihaiijieaMi 'i-s in the hontozvgoiiN i-ondition haw produced tin - in eiich case. I'.ut no one of - in plant V" alleloini&gt;r|tliie to :i tUCtOT ill |.l:illt Mo. "_' 1" • t . tore theoretically about the - either (wreni lilitoi-s |ii-csi HI Tile f.-lrt Tll.ll ill oiii de lip of tln-ii I DIOr]' till' ot Ik in the si/e produced lie 4 i-oii&gt;idef;il i llle to h mi the oiIhi- haml. ir.-oniliiinit ion given ;i I 'io\e Mini f.ir ImIow i iieil In fxpnndii In f. VVOIllll ll v\ i 1 !■ :i phllit • I I lilil &lt; , !;■ . ■ i, : i ' ii&lt; inln'1 In both i.-.MI MIIIiiImI' Of Model &lt; • I ; i - I \&lt;&lt;- ■&lt; 'ahan" \ :u studied ,'iikI .'i.l'!i ana" vai •conil n Iieijition «.n- .ilioiit lik. of variability « ,is B.I •howed ■ mii};e of variability so mi ian tin I tion thai it can hardl.i Im - ion of several -ieiif nw eoellirient of rariahilitT • ■ se» of the same kiml .iti r in thin pnper </seg>
            <seg id="p024">I (Juan tit a tin f 9 hmrmeter» 4m Wmizt Si n s I h f • rc -i — f Z — — ri — rt - — r -^ i is s ' o- — » » mn ; __ — - : i = = *- — — — — —— </seg>
            <seg id="p025">u F&gt;\\ sf&lt;riiy;iii&lt;in and irronihination of f;i«-torn of ih»- kind mm KliU- iii 1W8 stated thai be \v.u\ found greater vari;i liilit.\ in Y tli;in in F. in nuiiHTous hciv the pamti differed in &lt;|iiiiinii;iiivc rharartera. l»:it.-i wen- ppaaentedL h&lt;&gt;» onh mi &lt;|iialit;i il'.HOi. in his iinli-|" iro|tot&lt;;il uf tliis method of rrpretiaf the inlii-ritiinic- »f qoantitative character! l&gt;\ ■ ndVlino n&lt;ii;iii&lt;m. sluiwed Imu pertain datn mi the iaheritiiBOP diffii-iiii BHHiben at n "n the ear e&gt;f maiie could Hw a— 1} m il II mui «iiiftici»-ntl\ aamei i. however. In he i-oBriacii tA little later Ki i1910i pa|«er &lt;«n inheritam atitative rtim ippeared. I' 'ion and n - liiiiiit ion i in i h r&lt; ■ ' i IllttI \» /HI. /' '■tilt /(. /«. \ Hqiiiixli Miid .1 riwnd tint Hrflllop - ■■.it ion shorn- in| |&gt;1t-l&lt; rook to tll.ll Of Hi. S. :i ll&lt;»J&gt;. Tl i ' ion « ere an »ho« n U lated lull tin- number ■•( h foi • •in- i&lt;i li »A irons Imiui-i n ■ kMf iiiiiiiiw S| i urttT i-li thicker Flnraed ii;i\i- m similar lirmiK 1 &gt;&gt;f variability I" aver thai shown i»\ f Mran- l.flll!ll I ll:l!IH»trr Cm. Horneii . . . F, hybri.1 . - \i ■ ri,l ; i I ! I IT K 17 n </seg>
            <seg id="p026">&gt;,hnuitit(itin i liunntrrx in Maize 25 K'us riilfjarif*. A large number of crosses between hit — 'i length, breadth, weight, and thickness phi made. and all. showt-&lt;l segregation and recombination in F s . behaved as shown in the following table mid be noted, however, that the F genrrsition was grown in intei i nlmnsc. while the F generation was grown in pen field. Any « -licet that this difference of environment I ha\ •■ nil the variability would probably l&gt;e towards a ariability for tin- grefhowe grow |ilants. i n«'l. Hn- ■ f.'-it^tli Hrvadth ThiekMW m&gt;ii ;ilsd n-|M&gt;i-fed segregation i»ff si/.c of s&lt;-ed and height Ik iii !■' « hrn maize varieties diti'eriiig in those rhari TliiNf n&gt;siilts will not Ih' discussed for the\ are m full later in this paper. For the same reason, thr ■'II .ind I'.ast and Flaves (19111 reyx&gt;rting ■ n of nnmber of rows, height of stalk, siw of car. and ii maize will not lie considered here. Kul I 1 1916) also reported observations on the nundter of hi the maize ear. showing that while an P, population is no nuiahte than the pure su-ains from which it came, the V at ion is much more variable. In 1911 an cMcllehi pa|&lt;cr of Tammes il'.MIi appeared. Miss - made manv mam between rarietk « and betwwa ipi ■h the ftmm I ■!&gt; urn. and studied the inheritance of such charar - iiith and breadth of seed and length ami brendth of the \ riiliivated tlax known as Fgvptian with seeds varying nun. to •&gt;.!• mm. in length was crossed with Limn .■a w hose seeds \ai\ from "2.4 nun. to "2.0 mm. in length -reds nt i he I' generation were interinediate. varving from :t.&lt; mm. to I.J mm The range of variability in the F. generation. '•ii the other hand, ran wrj hirjte. ranging from 2.8 mm. ininiiiniiu 'o 1.7 mm. inaxiiiiiiiii A second rrnai U-tween another ralth &gt;la\ wiih a in i ii i inn in weed length of .'!.."i mm. ami a mav'muin . • 1 1 !_&gt; 1 1 1 of 4.."&gt; nun., wiih l.ininn iiHiiiisiifnliiiiii gave F seed- vary n^ in length from ■".."' mm. to ."...* mm. and f seeds varving in from -.'■'• mm. to 1:1 mm. [n op|M»sition to HmW — Kiving H enmpai "it i\ely uniform F. a cross between the Or &lt;•&lt;■&gt;«/ I'rr rent FltMl I'rr crnl I 1 i. in I :&gt;i I 7 II 1 17 i:i I » 2.3U 1.7 I u&lt; 'i '«i .( 17 I .'I In </seg>
            <seg id="p027">i \;iri;ii&gt;l&lt;- progeuv. ih«&gt; here, too. ;ui intermediate ekandei was niaaifaated. Further, iln- I" wax i&gt;u&lt; little wore rariaMe iliiin the F . Alilm iliis result niiylii i;isiiv Im- exptaiaad i&gt;&gt; garnet i&lt; i m | &gt;u ri t \ &lt;&gt;f the pareata, it warn •&lt;■&gt; iatereatiafi that the progen.v &lt;&gt;f extreme imli\ idnals mm followed to the I ition. • was no doubt, fr the fata obtained in this generatinii tluit \;irii)iis F plants &lt;|n! ha\e ilirfereni «:aiiieiir formulae. \, tin- pMajaaj araa^Med vctr dilfereal \ ■otwewhat similar nttult waa obtained when Rftyptian Max wed with I &gt; Leagta iad breadth &lt;&gt;i ).■ liiil in a rraaa between - r in ii il;i\ ami / ml iis reciprocal. In &gt;-aaea iln- variability '&lt;f V was greater than that »' In Miiaaoa Khle's extended mono(nM|''' "' i'" |() i' was stated ' ■ as inn; of );hinic, lenjith af apike. - • i, hardiness, and resistai e hetag rtwdied. In 1911 that portion of hk .1 the iateraadal linirth of wheat spikes nnd ret - reparted s ,.» ii,. mm had wed to tin- F . i»n. The data -lm« . - 1 . -.- 1 1- 1 \ thai lal diffel n &lt;|i |&gt;. nil ■•! nd&lt; |M-ndeiit fa&lt;ti&gt;i&gt;. allh" JH nut kll - lil\ complete ;ii! il |.arasiti- i-iinnol \*- cleared n|i tt&gt; li'ld woi - for there i&gt; evkl( it genotvpi*' iliffi -: wliicli ,ihii|iIi. I Haves' ilitll'i |ia|«r mi li&gt;liai-.«i |ki* nlrfail\ lieen nielli iiintli&gt; Hi- prenented data ii|M&gt;n niiiulier of |&gt;lant. In . 'Iain and - ' In eacn raap then ta greater \arial&gt;ilitv iii I' than in 1 . and thin different s ilearh ean U- iimjsI 1 « ni »•-; 1 1 1 \ denrrilied h m and iiM'omiiination " \'nn Tachennak &lt; l :»«»ii i s yeai &gt;nnd that aa haaMMMiiin^ aaa eraaaed with a late hlotwoinin^ iiiteimediati W and a xaiialile V Afteiw aiiU • m\\ ii portkM "f the -earlv" and "late and that this behavior eaaiM n&lt;&gt;i be expreiwed by a Rim pie lelinn fnrnmla In a recent paper l!»r_'. ht ■ if his Ii 's on this character complex, and e\ hem with the Mendetian notatkHi - ninz rnu factors. Belliag I 1912 1 hi tweea tw«i bean varieties that diHind in In Knrh i|i </seg>
            <seg id="p028">E characters as time of flowering, size of pod. ami size of there seems to lie no (|iiestion but that factors have segre - and recombined. In the F generation there was invariably variability, and in several rases extremes appeared that ■ ml riie grandparental Tyi&gt;es. The author does not it himself further than to say that segregation has occurred. ta that lie pi- t exactly what should he expecred • &gt;n The multiple factor interpretation. Phiilipa | 1912) has studied the inheritance of body weight in Iran the large French Rouen duck and the small doasestii- mallard. The first named variety is more than double i of the latter. lie concludes that : ''The amplitude of I animals is greater than that of the F, animals. - 'mi extend beyond the nearer limit of the respective &lt; ntal riii •- As a matter of fact, with an F, popula • nix :::; individuals it is remarkable that the variability B" addition to these aspen "riving the results of actual inverti - ■ us. I.jiil; i L911) has imlilishcd a long article showing how isul - 'If i IMS) on ear length of rabbits might have P'lian int&lt;-' :i by using N'ilsson-Ehle's scheme. A» &lt;:ht have raapeeted, Castle had already acknowledged (in .■&lt;-t utt's ■ the |Missibility of such an interpretation, an -incut that was afterwards published i I "astle 1911 ). i &gt;H AND MATERIALS ISEI). thodx employed in making these studies, including the h- plaata. gnardiBg the poUiaatioa. recording the hare been given in detail in |irevious pa|«rs i I'ast ■11 ;iuil I'.meisoii 1911). A brief statement here will ir as possible the different generations uid lepresentatives &lt;if the parent varieties frown together in the same mm Where comp:iri ii Inis fiowi in different years the fact is i ted in the tables nr accompanying text The various lots n|&gt;aied hare ilwayi Ih-cii grown on the most nearl\ rin soil available. In most mm certain plantings line duplicated in different parti of the field, but it has not i'le in earn WH Hiis plan as fully as might he desired ill planting of seed, placing lalx-l-stakes in the field, and ■ linu the position nt llie ditfereiit l&gt;its mi plaBtiaaj plans have •irallv removed the possibility of mistakes in identification In the production of band pollinated seed, liotb staminate and i.isiillaie inlloresi i nees have been protected "itb lii-avv manilla '•' "" I»H" '' &gt;!.-•=' — I '•:.«« »" the silks </seg>
            <seg id="p029">jMiilcn. After polliMtiMi each ear has been rebaayed and :i lalx ii;ii|ic&lt;l t(» it. The &lt;-\(&gt;&lt;-i'itiu'iiiii) error in regard to pollinw is Im|ic\i-&lt;] id ha imi gnats &lt;&gt;n the average thaa ;iIm&gt;hi ».im| per car. wA and Bayea 1911. j I The MMMWltl of hci^hl of plant Weiv made in (lie ti«-l&lt; : ■ instill stalk of eaeh plant waa ektM for mmfwart an&lt;l distance from the aw Caw &lt;&gt;f the grwaad io tin- tap &lt;&gt;f th - n-I determined. The iiiiiiiIkt of nodes \\;is determined b' niiny; tlir lc;i\fh. i-\ic|.i Htf the l&gt;ns»' of tin- «.inlk. arhi i Bpraaaarj to make n m eajwftri esmatiBatioa. Ii is e thai imi all ili&lt;- aaaal in»i noted, i»it aai slight ■ thai sun is nut mi ioi nee all idiniis for tbi - iiln&gt; af an \ &lt;iiic - uhIi liv iiiic |&gt;ii-s&lt;iii. i In i»r wniiUI likcl\ Ik- inailt- m Ii lot. Tht» • ! .11 appi • •.uli natr (lower* mi in o|x-n wa« ta. [ t Ik- rtntf an&lt; ividual imiimImt of tin- plaat. Tin- fi-«ipi«*ii&lt;-.\ ilistriluii ions aixl rlit- conipiltatioiiH Meal com all been checked over -i-. and H-alilf. this BM Imi Ii ilolu- liv a st'iollil HTI §m&gt;! &lt;• hi 1 1 mi PI TO! II li;i III i-oiiii. ll tilt 1 Si Illlil-S. bill . &lt; our belief thai tl • The |ilants of California pop ami of Tom Thunih pop i - makiiij: Ith Hieaaw tin- |il wliii-h the later representatives of t' ■m from aaeal oMaiaed from s«-ii| aValen I'Ih M |&gt;lanls used in iiossin^ anil tliosi froai Which all later I, - sarietv i-anie were fl-om a single open I an exhibitor at the National Con Omaha. Neither of these mrietlea. therefore hail heea pollinated heiare the esBcrtaaeata roi htgua. Tin - us4-&lt;i in tlu-si- encrtaacarta awre in mo- •! fm at least two gpaerattoaa hefare Inmih; I'ronaed. inn in -min there were useil |iari-nt ears obtained from commercial who aaafc a s|«i ialt\ of the trpex faraiahed. In urarral iptive notes below include onh such il 'ii 1 made ns4' of in tlie experimeata reported in ilii- The strain of Tom Thtiinh \w&lt;i in the rraaa " uli Missuiir: i rery dwarf ami verv early jmij&gt; an Tin- plaata tiller .ililv and liave short stalks with few aadtea. The tillei- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">ill adxaini ..| ilif ciii - sliuiits mill smut' da\s liefore tin- pollen is Tin- ran are \i-\\ short and ihhmIIt have ;ilx&gt;ut twelve .ill. smooth, ttii-tv j;rains. ti 'alifornia |mi|i is also h dwarf nun. Inn tin- stalks are eaat - •ral&gt;l\ taller than those of Tom Tlnunli and h:tve nearly twice 1 1 1 ; 1 1 1 \ nodes. The tillers art- more numerous tlian in T niil&gt;. are mosllx of a html tin' same ln-iir lit as I In- main stalk, like il have 01 r lliui-e ears all)) I'llil ill I tassel. 'rili even mtuillrr iliiin rliose i»f Tom Tlininli anil contain niimei-oiis. uuhirU arranged plains. The latter are sharply rice jx&gt;iiited • li ral&gt;l\ smaller than ilie urains of Tom Thnnih. ['alike i Thiimli this varii t\ is \er\ late in l»»eilf[ ;in«l in i-i|M-n 1 11 v: ■ tiri ileni is a karav late ran. It Maaaaaai at abwri the i&lt; lime as &lt; 'alifoinia pofi. Ixit matures sniiirwh;ii later. The tall ami stout ami have few tillers The latter are n slmii ami withonl lassels hi- ears ami. when tall, almost ml in a lassel. Imt frei|iienl l\ lark ears The ears are hi short for ilenl ruin. Imt are lara)e in iliameter ami eontain lermis lows of kernels mosl ■■nmmoalj siMeeli to twent\ grains are of a fairl\ smooth ilent l\|&gt;e ami nieilinm liroail lorn of thai t \ | m • . Tliev are. of eoiirsc. \er\ nnieh lajprt tlian I* of either one of the two |io|i eorn varieties The strain of Tom Thiimli i No. liih useil in misses with Black • .in was similar to ihe strain &lt;lesrril&gt;e&lt;l alxixe in heifilit of d, ii ii in Imt of tillers, earliness. elr.. Inn had slightly smaller ■ Mil »iells. titlark Mexiran sweet i No. ."i 1 1 has meiliiini tall stalks anil l\ iinmeroiis tillers Its ears are loiiir ami almost alwajl i row* of rather br 1. wrinkh&gt;«l grains. »W;ii&gt;oii Hint i No. Si has meiliiini short stalks ami ver\ loii&lt;&gt; « u n Ii eiyht row s of grains as the |&gt;revailin&lt;: type 1 . tl .&lt;-;) in i no • It-n t i No. tii has \er\ tall stalks ami lon^ ears with ii 11* to I'd rows. Hi rows being the modal condition. I* &gt;f Ihe varieties used in the other crosses. oiil\ one rharMeti'i liber of rows is of direct concern to us here. Illinois low tein i No. - i is a dent corn with \'2 to I'M rows and a mode of rows. Illinois hi^h protein (No. Si is a 1l! rowed dent with i n"&gt;- from lit in is rows. Knrlv Craahp i No. 18) is a IS rowed •et corn rxnffian from si« 14 rows. Stnr&lt;:es' Hint 1 No. 11 1 is 'iij;l\ 1"J rowed in t&gt;|&gt;e. only a few ears having other row lanuini; from 8 to HI. Loiijifi'llow tlint 1 No. IS) is an i- il t\pe. raielv e\er having ears with anv other nninl&gt;er of IXHKRITANTK OK M.MBKR UK HOWS I'KK KAK. I he 11 ina\ In- ri-^arileii either as a fusion of four or </seg>
            <seg id="p031">nion joint of t In- nidi's lM-:irin&lt;: two I merisiH rariatioaa or repetition! of ■ radiis bearing two npike The rows an- paired, and m known where I mem •f ;i pair h.is ban abertoal De Vriea lias regarded tin - ihiiiiIm'i- of rows nil i h&lt;- maize . ntinuous rariationa which arv inherited in ■ somewhat temporary manner, lit- eaa peri mm t in which be was : ■ t » I • - &gt;arictv with which h. fr—i an average of abmrt IS rowa per ear to an a\. &lt;if alMHii I'n mi per ear in • onlv to find that tin - .•«l \aric-i\ I to the type of the original \\ i- do not i|ii&lt;-stimi l 1 l&gt;nt the inti'iiMi Kilinn tli;i ive to llicm. Tin- wm-k i»| Eaut, Emerson. l ; i&lt;i Rbnll baa shown conclusively thai the r&lt;'\ersi"ii iii (!«■ \ iliru tli&lt; aJrji aliki * I hilt i ' iiiiImt of ron - hi inait' ap &lt;' inheritai Altlii' there siim- « li\ t | &lt;&lt;&gt;!n|ilf\ sliunld not h to In- cif i in same natui iliat (if other ■ .1 hf i-ontinnoi iitinii"&gt;i - nberited (Inotuatioim. \ laryc n tun her of count! ■aakcr "f rava "I batfe wii&gt; mi ataH mre iwn • lion wliirli is usual! \n car wliiili ;i|ij, til-It 1 tlll-llfn 'H- Jillslll l] I. •In- tna| rJaaa. t»nt the proj will i«- oac &lt;&gt;( (i k tin- a|i|iai-c-m i atral nai \ ' '- earn ' do not have tin s;'im- aliilin iii rcapead to pxti rni «1 mnli Tin 8-rowc-d rondition. which is the last Mhtrartion form in which paara, m;' \ be selected until t!&gt; Itreed* i In a count of the aaawlatkm of an iaolnted maize Beld i jfcllow. an * rowed Hint, had Iki-ii grown for inanv « 4 four rowed h trowed. 2 ten rowed, and 1 twelver. earn were found. Oa the other hand, a I.eamiin.' dent, seli-i-ii . Brl and inltred liv hand for si froin 12 to L'ti rows. Part of tlii^ diffen n eior show ii l»\ ran* «ith a low ■•■her of rowa aad with i 1 1 ; &lt;• 1 1 imimiIh-i' &lt; ■ &lt; rowa 's uiiiloiiliti dlv dm' to correliition hut at </seg>
            <seg id="p032">ijttinitittitir, Ckmrmeten 1m \lni:&lt; •!! h ran \ ;i r\ ii&gt; any SM of eight spikes will show | (fleeter fluctuation than one wliicli ran vary only in an\ one For iliis riMsnn ii is likely that strains with a »\ ill never show t In- low variability seen in &lt;U a low nnntber of row*. f- deration the probable amount of tnetnating ation -i.n:: point* arc presented in the tahles • nr\ distributions of the number of rows per in ihe varioim '&lt; slmw the results from three different irmm dirk No. - rawed white flint, was crossed with other In Table 3 the male parent was No. &lt;&gt;. the well kiumn • lent. In ihe particular strain from whirli this male I iUim. the modal condition ithat is. the rlaai af -ixteen. Four P. families were £rown. f»nh one was markedly more variable than the V on The modal condition of P,(12) was intermediat. the two jiareiits. In three of the F. families, the modal lif»n was ten: iii the remaining family it was twelve. In I the male parent, a white dent, was also typically I we] I* 1 The F and K. (BHwratioM were comparable to tfcaae While tin- I' neialion was miieh more variable iiinn. m&gt; KTeni contideiice ean l)e plaeed in the K !&lt;i the me:i»er nninlwrs of the F, &lt;rener:il ion .". sh.i\\&gt; ■ peiuliar result. Here No. I was the male vliile the female parent was ■ 12 rowed Hint whiih is low in variability. Roth the F, and F. generations i M\ twelve rowed. I data form the basis for several speculations. In two lie typical condition of the hybrid was intermediate. ihi&gt; last .toss the TJ rowed condition apj&gt;ears to be domi - i Is this due to the fad that the 12 rowed parent was tht - hit-'.' Is if due to the fact that the maternal individual was lllj If rOWgd? Is it due to there bring few differences reen the parents h\ which couiplications thru correlation lit at-ise. for I'oth are llints? It seems probahle that the last HUftffPttioM are likely to )«■ at the basis of the phenomenon, there is no wa\ i»f deciding: from the evidence at hand. Eible •; merely shows thai this same TJ rowed varieM when ■d with another varicM which is tyjiically twelve rawed i no greater varial&gt;ilit\ than one of the parents. Table 7 prea the data from a cross between nn 8-rowed ind r \er\ variable 12,-rowed dent. The denrriptioB of the mention was not taken ;it the time, as the cross was made u-i!\ to sirnh n not her i|nentiAn. The omission is partially </seg>
            <seg id="p033">The interesting part of the retard is decidedly the F, families, for they arose fr&lt;un thaaa ■ k having a different nuinhfr of - rowed mother &lt;i;iM' proayni with a few more Ifl • I ear* Hmb fc-rowed ears. Imt ■ can aee what ■ nudem \ ■ ward Hi. 8-rewed condition. Ii voaM probably he er ;i typical s rowed rare in ih&lt;- next federation &lt;»n the ether hand, tlit- |n-oi;i!i\ of the 14-rowed mother ilj with tlit- modal coaditJop at II rows The unmix -r of c.i ding this i-omlit ion is nnfficienf to lead "in • lieve tliiit ;i ia&lt;&lt;- like the No § pamil would he at - the one like the No. 15 parent. Bni this coaM ma we lN'lie\c. In detecting pan having tin- Mint eonditiofl Thtie is cartaial -&gt;vi tt i tuvreUitioa hetwaai the deal tion .(lid ;i lii^h iiiiimImt &lt;&gt;f rows, for all of the e;irs with ■ high ihhiiIm ■!• &lt;■ ■ r. I This deaf with an 8 i • ■ .".i i Blaci Mexican i - the Black ! ■ hile the pn _ :.i 1 1 :. aad N iiIm'i tlin 1 1n ■ \ both differ in othi i fltarai ti rw I Table* !». l§. Bad 1 ! lar to i idnalt inil&gt; ;ind in wen t of the \:i|ioiis i;;innti. |iossilii I il h &gt; within what mij;lil tx - sidel-ed siniil. 'i|ll|i:i l"it i\el \ |.ni- - t, 1 »n t \&lt;&gt;. M. sin. i it produce* individuals h Iti rows. !n;iv he expected to have \ Table !• lists the data from the ctom km»« ■iniiition is rtry rariahh •■ placed |M&gt;pnl:ition of onlv 33 eat*. TI from a LS-rnwvd ear. and •how tlint it had within it poaaibilitiea different fnmi ilms.- of ml i tin -!\."w i ii. the other two earn thai prodareri In faet. iho iai l(W-3x54l 1 produced no dai._ ean with /&lt;•** than TJ rows, ear i fffl-.'tx.Tl i -fi |.n.din&lt;': bter lais with aiara th;m ll' rows. \d further pM ■eceanary to show th:it one of the pamtal plant* is for certain of the fartorn i for the prodwiioa of 1 1 ei- than ei&lt;rht in asaaher. The I" individu;ils. in athai words, were different in gametir constitution. Kven the tiimilv &gt; ••" !!\."i t i 1 eontaiiie«l n&lt;li\ diialf hetero w hill low ill .1 :l|i|i.;lini|. • </seg>
            <seg id="p034">I • t ■ &lt; i ii t ■ 1 1 \ of i lit- four ears from it th;ii were followed into _■ m-ration. Tin- progeny of ciir { t'i(l-:!x."4 i 1-1 KO. .1 If, -howed :i inoilal condition "f li rows, with mh !i;i\ i n&lt;j both l x and l''i rows. None hail less tlum 12 rows. Imt undoubtedly m u accidental rireuMtsaea neeraw the wed rhiss oeCVNi 1"&gt; times. In ■ pcrfwt sample of the population. ! one would expert ta find individuals with HI and - \t the MM time the modal condition of Family ru unquestionably sixteen rows, while that of the 'amilies was twelve, fourteen, and twelve. This riking when ossnparci with the F, families .ind I fiO-3x54 ) fi-3, where the moihil conditions are - .n-tivelv. I'ive F families of the .toss tin r.x."» I Table 10 1 were grmwm. again different in character. Famih (60-5x54) (I iharartcristicalh twelve rowed, while faniih (t§-SxB4&gt;-ll chaiMiteristieallv 8 and 111 rowed. I 'nfortunatelv otilv I ■ &gt;wed ear from family (M-5x54)2 was carried to the M ion and its progf J tended to form an S rowed t\|ve t reinai-kalile for its tendemv to form a non varialde familv. m faaailv 80-5x54)-ll. Five ears were &lt;;rown ami ai-h there was a notable tendency toward an s rowed strain. • lay l&gt;e doubted very seriounlv whether s«'leetion toward .i type in all of these families would l»e MU-eessful. Sin - one in one or two instances, far &lt;ranietic ponnibili h; rowed race max still exist in some of the faniili' nild not Ih- likelv in every family. On the other hand. fraternities raised from ears 1 60-5x54 1 12-1 EH and Ji:s are very high in variability and show that thev i ■■• ilii p« of \ ielditifr races averairin;: from If to "_'n r&gt;4. Table 11. a race characteristicall\ 8 rwwed iiristicallv 12 rowed were olitained in t! tion. * In Talile 12 are presented data derived frwn a cross of Tom 1 ' Missouri dent. I'ew iccoids are availaM' I' .ind 1' families powi in 1911. No V genera - grow* in IMl and the records of F, ears produced in accideiitly destroyed. There are entered in the talile. under The designation of F, generation, such records !■!• obtainable from the ears kept as samples. Tho both t varieties were frowa in 1911, no record was olitained of i he ears of Missouri dent since this variety failed to mature in - idiusetts. « &gt;w i ii ji to pool- germination only a few plants ■ in Thumb pop were grown in 1911 and these, bmmk nf the unfavoralile wi-ather in early summer, while they were develop- </seg>
            <seg id="p035">M ing, anil |MrlM|M alwi bec-anae "I |»t«*vhmm aeilag. [Mud ears. Tin- entries in tar table under the d«*&lt;i|pintioii of Tliuinli |»i|i ami .it Missouri tlt-nl. like those at T lit- I tion. were obtained trmm - « as had '■li dat;i as .lie available indicate a l_' rowed l\ |k- I Thumb \k&lt;\&gt;- The ran. .liiaifd for Missouri aoggeetK thai the ataefc ■ •' liiar rarieti used may h beterotygous for aniiihrt of rows. » trndciK v to | The tliii-i- I' fan 510 i ind l r_'T and 1 1 :&gt; grumm in MawuK'IniM'iis in 1911. '»liai different in the mean iiuiiiInt of iln-ir r*Wl and in ih. variation. behavior tin- i Ik- tailors 1-oin ■■ in dttiTi in tl "iid tin ranges of tbj bt said to show i ! Tin- Imsi i \ nil ii. ■ id iiuiiiIm r of iou&gt; i^ lir more f u 1 1 \ later, in ih&lt; i i, the differ) ■ideratiiH) bn*e • ioiiiIm ion &lt;&gt;1 l hi' |ia in F, famili' i rain . \«i 5H&gt;. &gt;» in turn, of i ■■ otlier 1" |H even whiit other - iM-ed. in addition to the twn . fin«ll\ in these I famili&lt; theae K fain i related aacrilialiU- mii\ &lt;■ F, lots, linn mi pe, 1 1 C, lik» Tom Thuinli |io|. .d ryjM-. and t» of a 1'n rowed type, pan i&lt; ularl.\ 111 11 and 1141. will hap* also 14 rowed and 18-rowed i\|'i- lilt. 1134, 1138 That a i\|m' with iin&gt;r&lt; iha'i 'Jo rnws miulir lie isolated N i ' 9 VI I itf f t I t r i I i i M i \ I \ t I ! \ ' * 1 1 1 I' ' </seg>
            <seg id="p036">■ -c- lor number nf nn pn - in U it M Is -•&lt;&gt; -*•-' -'t I' s Mi I' Is i. :il :&gt;l Is I I s 1:1 :;t. 53 in I 12 !J ts 3&gt; '.i 1 I in 7 S3 IS 2 I ID K t.". SI 1 I 12 I X mi is i 2 i I 1 1 (fin in a ilixi i iiuii inn of ii ii iii hi' nf pom per ear in iliiss 'i.r.'l. I' N I' Hi I s I II) I is 111 I t ilisl i Hull inn nf ii li in In i nf inns fur e4ir III Rows ( laaaai fur iiuiiiImt of ro»&gt; pm ear m in a m m is aa n m (.,n of tin.. i- a I I :ls7 7 1 Him I* s .'so ] ] I 12 II _t. .' Uv.-.i-h I 12 III :fs kit _•:; H 'tint/tun itf ii ii i/i h&gt;, nf mtrx /, Row&gt; I niimlxT ot row &gt; |ht ear ..I in- s 111 |J H |6 IH M 1 i u m a j&lt;) i 1 i ■ j&lt;i i - / Ir.'i I. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">v in 12 No II Him I' 1 1 1 N || . ". Hint I" s Mi 1' 1 I 1' II No i:.\l«» I | 1 in II I :, I 12 -.'-HI 1 II 1 s 1 1 ., 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Ill \hti:&lt; distribution of Huiiibrr nf rotes per M ( 'lasses lor iiiiiiiImt of rows par ear i-~&lt;- for iiiiiiiImt of n 111 1-' 11 1 1 . 18 M I 1 12 1 13 11 1 1 1' I 38 -' 1 I in 8 in 1-' -' 1 18 I 1 .' 7 » 1 t I 1 i ia ". ii a I -1-1 \- I 12 1 ■ B M) -It 1 Hi I.'. Hi J."&gt; ti 1 1 16 -' 111 IB L'l 10 I 13 3 :«i !ki 48 1J Kit -i i u -' :«&gt; (hi hi "&gt;4-.vi I ia 1(1 S3 H H) 1 l"i 4 7 U I 1 1 S i'J 7- i -') I 10 _':: M Ii r distribution &lt;&lt;/ mwmhor of rMN /" K 10 U 1 1 16 M 12 Is r 1-' :; .11 I' KM J.I 7 I 13 1 I It I \1 B 22 Hi I 12 I :; Iti I Id 1.1 s; I 8 -ti S8 ."-i I 10 ill is :,» I 10 32 '.:&gt; U 1 s 5 ■_&gt;() _&gt;; I 12 33 l.Vs I 12 1 :;n MB I s Very irrcuul:ir. i I in M s ■ &gt; 1 1 1 1 _&gt;li I 8 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">- III 1 _' II I' II I I p I I I I I III - l-10\&gt; I ' N III 12 II l&gt;. I" I.' 1 IS II I 1 I' II »4 I HI I lit *\ t - </seg>
            <seg id="p040">&lt;9 -"- r -L" ?, -••••••-••••a-ai &gt;■ -5 _ 2 2£2££5S22222£225 - i z — i-Tirt — — — •" 2'£ 'Z.'— L - ; * 5 - = *Z*?rS«£*22 j x_ =&lt; i-s.i -* — _ </seg>
            <seg id="p041">I n r* rC I I J\ C r* ' ' r I - f^ -\ ( j | \ \ 'ft* r* j\ i v l.enutli of tilt- fin- of inaizi- Is |M-rli;ii "| a ,|i.i complex for inheritance stn&lt;l found in tin- &gt;|.c. u It ■ ' jillolcd Ii\ Ik' I ;i degl illtliu siiiiic effect m;i\ Im- traced. Like other si/.e i|i;ir.-i length •&gt;' intimately cuimectei) in development and in luutt W~fll • * urv., / »« it /4 &lt;t » 4 uikiiuiUM 7 S f f II li II 14 IS IS IT IB II 20 II n &gt;« j« a rr t&gt; im to 'i a iii T\f. 1. Sice of ears of Tom Thumb pop and Bla&lt; k Mexican swe. • rowl, the F, generation of the cross I row i, and the F ; itineration of natural size. litv witli otlier romplexea, yet it is n&lt;&gt;i &gt;.i uiarkedl; \ternal conditiuns as the hei^lit of plant. This slat. &lt; however, must In- i-oiisidered &gt; somewhai tentative Lenfth of „, ji ( 7 t r '* r » /• a« 21 •• »k» 4 II 14 I J it is o r 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">41 ■ lid if ilusc conditions arc suitable for normal unavoidable changes in ■efcesrsiofieaJ conditions i- development to any great extent. The • iiiur thru physiological correlation. Number and therefore total muster of seeds, is in - d with car length. Size of seed and possibly ilic seed may also have mm effect, tlio just k \\c lit not prepared to say. Size of plant is lated with length of ear. KIlow imicli of these correlations is gametir in the _- i unknown. It is apparently pi ho this physiological correlation is imposed ion. In other words, a plant which is Kit is gameticalU small have differ - r ilcvclopnient oven when the BMM genes rting car development are present. Kxprwwed _ i i tvgote iiall — ear length I \Hli&lt; - than jtygote &lt; short — ear length I IBBCC). K- 13. 14. and 15 give the data &lt;m lengths of car fst the Bfl-5x54&gt;, and («rt-8x54». These, it will be .iic three crosses made l&gt;ctw&lt;&gt;en individual plani \o. tliii ;mil Hlack Mexican sweet 'No. r &gt;4 \ . the data on the F generations were taken onlv It can lie stated definitely that the i [her two families was no &lt;;reater. out not the i variability was no greater. It U iitroduci'd. therefore, in comparing tl&gt; g of tl - r,n:;x.-,4i and (M-8xM) with Hk 5x54). From what is known of the is thoaghi that the error is veil small. 1 1 families were grown from selfcd ion. If 12.48 Tl! per cent represents the liility of the F ireneration i Table IS), then the ; generation is much grealei, namelv. 67 |nm- cent. «;:: |mt cent, and lftJM M per ■ lively. Perhaps it is wronjx to compare the variability of the total population in F with that of F,. for the F wed to the F generation may have had different iiametic ulae. The Bgnres 22.30 .71 per cent are simply given for what the\ are worth. There is no way of disregarding the fact that one F family, (60-3x54) 1. had a greater range of variability than !' by fire Individuals were obtained, therefore, thai ' t ly like typical individuals of both of the parental </seg>
            <seg id="p043">&gt; oah '_".' individuals, i In ic is h raufie of variability from ui &lt;■• 111 ' i-iii. There is bo quei then l&gt;n i thai iht- pMgraies «f diff&lt; levia iMlitv of ear length, M &gt;he*M Im- etpectel if segre ti nf multiple t - The most interesting ii' ililliii tins in mean lenjrth "I ear shown !i\ the I" The mean leiijrih &lt;&gt;f the l cm. TIm'.v i-iH-. r HKiii t lei n rht'V sIhhiIiI Im - si/i- il o«1 • vor hie to On the other hand 15 i-iii. '! t\ parent ixmt u\- IMlll;l|i - as lonu us they wmM \»- with if ilu-\ rere tj : wrinklcl ■k llexican. At ii;ist the • 'row it, rwiw in var tram jut « ii. Itnt If oli elfiriciit is i-onsiil, BThc nine I ! wnallesi ~ Hi. Hi it. Ii is nnfortnnate that n&lt; tremel\ short ears ami Imt oi ■1mm M not Im- ii-jjanh 'Xperinu n the ear is liagge&lt;l f. inable to tell whether it will be larp or small. &lt;•&gt; irs were wlfod in t! generation and of these alwint 117." matured, but iimonjr them found but one normal ear of 7 &lt;m. ami bur one ear of 18 en. Mne destroyed the short ear. anil ri-ioui- -s 0 cin. and It Oil I 111.- li\. h.irllt Ol I. Ill 111. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">II ttion of a cross between pop and Black Mexican MF— I M natural sue. UNI 11*1" .niaii\»- ears ti an F generation of a cross betwefn Tom Thnnib pop and l: natural size. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">&gt;&lt;h Bulletin \&lt;&gt;. i ml. pop bi arura ars of an F Alteration of a Th'tnib pa natnra </seg>
            <seg id="p046">, ars of ai ation of a cross between Tom Tnmiili ih&gt;i&gt; and Black Mexican sweet— 2-9 natural sl«e. W • "~i~ ars of an it ion of a crow between Tom </seg>
            <seg id="p047">i.; +•**&gt;) I. Represents Thumb i&gt;o|i am. natural sit ■^^•^ r^ </seg>
            <seg id="p048">47 ,at an W generation of a cross between Tom Mexican ' natural </seg>
            <seg id="p049">I 'he av&lt; In- progenv of .mi- t;u~,\~.i rj-ji H ii. l»»ii _ nT These fain i«lv with the family prodm-i-d I. | i' \s luiij;. for tliis ; ic cxti-eim ' &gt; .mil ilif Ii mi variabilit per pent The total mi' ttcient ol I - s. I In from ■ ■ i ■oted ■ ire froiii ;i si in; Ii- I" Mir. differed do U-ri-ith w ;i&gt; ;i lii ;i little I'M i familii - Jith loiijrer thai th&lt; ht fMiiiilics. probable tli. ic pairni I &gt;■ l&gt;&lt; i this material. T:ililc 17 iiulndfs nil a\ nihililc data in regard in • from the miss of California pop with Missouri ilent. F fa 1 md "&gt;(C&gt; w«rc yrown under fairlv faroraMe weather raawJ tionn in ttli. while all tlie tHhu famil . nditieM ot ntraM drowth prevailing .i l.im-oln. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">It IMietM that th.-.v suffered more seriously „■ .in weather than «li.l the California pop plants. M«nj planta pro.ln.e.l no ear* and a considerable produced were little better than -nubbin*. p« 8.W5 and 8S7. were apfMreatl.! much Itw .1 b\ ihr unfavorable weather than anv of the doubtless, in part at least accomta for the verajted unite as lout: as the ears of the ,rent. The mean ear len-rths of the F, families Dterniediate between the means of the pa nation in the F, families was not exi i.-nt of variation. ,.f the f families. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">: - | m 4. j 2 &lt; 6- I </seg>
            <seg id="p052">£.=?Kt8;Si5 - '- — — --. '■ --£LT ■ — — = r &gt;-■ : „__ -™ ri =3z~"" *~ *F * X rf' ' J I I ■ i : - — — -»-■ ?&lt; ™" -* — « 5 3 | ■ ! j I i B-I — — ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p053">I ■~" e - ~ -J c I s^ &gt; I % I i - _ ~ _ Z « 11 = -- — — • </seg>
            <seg id="p054">53 o* -T-.l - -■;i. -i — — t ,g "^ i~ a K ! - :-'"rr-,. •*■ a ~ - - I = ■*] ■-.-■-- - i »^5i?-2S25 — 22 E : : I : r r. r r r x x ~x £ / f </seg>
            <seg id="p055">INIiKHI I ANCK OF 1 I 'IAMKIKR Or EAK5&gt; Diameter of Mr is directly i-orrelated with Dumber of r&lt;&gt;«^ and with aeed site and probably also, negatively, with length .&gt;' ear. In general, cars show less tlu&gt; mat ion in diameter than th. .1.. in len«th. Table is exhil i.itii obtained from the n-oss • ■• I ■ Itrii \* ftrowu in 1911, the f«&gt; - diameter of :&gt; little lillineten mean dhuu I nearly i'2 millii it A inilliiiK rlii' mid-parental \;ilu. nans ltkil\ thni this null iBetcaw orer tin ■idyn - iIih tn the ii i.m\ iii&lt;; hetei ho mean iliii i hf I' *gfi *&gt;nl over 37 laillisietera. or nlmoi utf. Tin- I' fan nxli'i- the iintri- favoi na of 1910. nauirall\ had ■ frreater ear dteawten Hun tin 1" fainiliea nf 1911. Tin- raagn of irai ation &lt;&gt;( th \ii-mli-&lt;l i • 1 1 1 \ lie mean pop to a littli- Im'Iow tin- niiiin i iiri ili-Tit. Whil. number of indi\ iduals u) nn out I i;nnil\ » than a nM(i( ninn |M»K8ilili i-oiiiiij|i:itii&gt;lis of luiir faitorv. h is |iinltai&gt;l&lt;-. Imwi'M-i. tka Bar t he ii ii in I »«' i (if mi of tlif parents ilii' i two nd. since diai other ear duuraoten it umild ao&lt; l» • 111* to UK M:.:ii\ ■■ iei in BoatetkiBf I ndividvabi trow Id bav&lt; even ffaance '•! &gt;&lt;&gt;■ plant (■■etit-allv like t lu- two pa real i\|» •Iiiiii'iii^ din meter of Mrs. In tl 'ti&lt;l - tlir .:"_' I &gt;!nnilil pro* ir diameter facton ;unl shonlil. ilun-forf. pradhM i &gt;l:i ntK HMCC astretHC than an\ plants of I Thin ap]iarontl\ is exaotl.v what aappened in &lt;Toa« of Missouri ilt-ut with Tom Thumb pom. the data for whirl, are presented in TaMc l!i. Several nf tlie F families eontaim-fl individuals witli cars of smaller iliameter than anv F. ear. In fart the mean iliameter at \n. I1S2 was praotiralh ii|iial to the '11nnit*TPr OT I lit* SlllJi ! IPHT »*fl m ni T &lt; it MPfl 2TOWT1 Tn^ HLIW </seg>
            <seg id="p056">■ •in which il (••line. Whether tvpes with still siiuiIIit Mfl liittil by sch-i'tiou from family 1132 remains to he seen. Man\ ot the F. families of il - were distinctly differ ruin • &gt;t It • : diameter. Theic wen six laniilies. for of which were larger than the largest l!tt! Tin ■ r i • ■;&gt; ii diameter ruried from ni'arlv oi </seg>
            <seg id="p057"/>
            <seg id="p058">equenvi: liameter of *'arn •&lt;• I hnmb pop and Missouri dent. It f L *1U 1 .17. .14 -•-■ »-MKI .41 H4.:fl -M (7 _~i .'.' (7.74 :«l II. VI -»l 4H.IW .21 I.'.:i4 .21 I »2.1rt -'1 4.1.IW ..'I l.i. lv -'I ti n -"• t " 7ti -"' ilfc^^^^M« Inr 1 1 ian^t^r rW inn 1 4 1 - I I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">57 ■ &gt;K WEIGHT OF SEEDS. Tlic behavior &lt;&gt;t seed weight in the tf-SxM), Mini itiiiv x .-,j, ||, ;n | K . considered together. The de - ■ I data are slmwn in TaMea Sf, 21. and :.':.'. In making the - wtuty, it \v;is necessary to use a scheme by - _ar\ or wrinkled seeds of the Black Mexican parent. I. and of certain reo ites from the cross, could la. 'I'll is end was accomplished by hav ■ li\ families growing near the wrinkled families. - which had 1mm nine stardix thru xenia were usually ned in sntlicient numbers to make data upon 2") seeds pos- Ati insufficient numlier of hybrid starchy seeds, however. i lie meaner data in certain families. It must be ratood that this method of weighing is correct in theory. - i of the seed is governed by the development of the trp and sinc-e this is nnaffected by the jtollen from a starchy ■ pericarp ia merely Hied oui with starch by the laai si irehiaeai in the i*, endosperm. III! (IJHCaasiBg these results, the weight of 2S secils i* Taken the unit niiantity. When the mean weight of any particular ted, therefore, this is what is meant. I Tom Thunili No. M haa an extremely small seed. The mean 2.7 n:: graaM. The mean weight of the Black Mexi - : 1 grains. Imt this is probalily too high. These data n from plants raised from commercial seed, which was mixed condition. The last three |&gt;ositive classes should &gt;babh rded for this reason. The ears upon which they ■i- borne showed plainlv that they had come from hybrid seed. • nt evident l\ beiag some large dent variety. ill iminhers in the freqneBCT distrilmtions of both psirents •idit.i in the Black Mexican undoubtedly make the co - riability 1 t .44 M per east and 14. ."it !MJ per too high; Imt. even leavint' this fact out of deration, the ten K. families gndra show increase&lt;l varia - t&lt;ilit&gt; over that of the 1' generation in every case. The range of ibility in each &lt;-ase orerlapa that of the grandparents. The .li\ iduals do not leach the extremes of either parent. ' one leaves out of account the three higher classes of the i.m rent, for the reason given above, the extreme size of the Mexicaa is generally obtained. This may be a question - proeednrc, hat, as a matter of fact, the individuals used as tale parents of the crosses were only average in this char- Tin- F families often gave segregates with seeds as small e smallest Tom Thumb needs. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">■ /■'&lt; f ,1,1 h Iliilli tin v (tft&amp;c.Vl i ti 1 i :.VS. mikI Min.-, x :,4 ■ 1L'JI&gt; »,tn "7. ;m«l »•; .111 mp 1 iih«iis Is not appNaeft tli»- ■■■ "f the Tom Thnmli 1 &lt;-Jo«p1_\. vet tin- SfpSMMM of tht- ImmIUn « li"|. lik&lt;- tin- Tom Tliumli. Fnrrhcrmorf ih&lt;- great iliil'&lt;Tt'ini- in n which »&lt;• might of prodi « like the original |&gt;nri&gt;ntn 1 little mor* • Tin- fami </seg>
            <seg id="p061">'-/f#f//ff^ f »l f I f ' * Flf»Tf/lf*/JC fr§ . II ff *^C 59 ** T . _ / — : =" a -i - _ - t _ — - *i— — — — r^ — 7&lt; — I -5 — H* J|* I * -^n^jc </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Reteanh liullrtiti 3t = T - - -■ ■ I -c .•c ■e 2-= = | - ( _ f- .- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">61 BREADTH OF SEEDS. In mm «&gt;i tl. California pap with Missouri dent and &lt;&gt;f tli&lt;- latter with Tom Tlnunl&gt; pap, the breadth of twenty - ■tc kernels from an Mtf of each plant was determined. Tables S.\ ami L't eOBtain these daia. Of the varieties of corn known to ■Jiformia pop lias by far the smallest seeds. As grown in 1910 and 1911 (Table 23), the sfwagc breadth of twenty-five ki-i-nels of iliis variety was only about S."&gt; iiiillimetcrs. while the dth of twenty ti \ t- Missouri dent kernels averaged about 216 niillimeiers. The I' -.ids were distinctly intermediate in size. In l'.tm the difference between the largest twenty the seeds of California pop and ihe smallest rtaM &lt;&gt;f I' was M inillinietera and then- was die same difference between the largest class of ■ I l In- smallest of Missouri deiil. Iii l!ll 1 the F, families had - ilian in lilt. The variation in the F, ily greater than in the F, lots. The range riatioa, howerer, was not surti«'ieni in all the V 2 families in i- completely to dose the gap between even the inner ex - tremes of the parents. The greater variation in F. was doubtless due to a segregatioa of size factors, and tv|«es like the parents would probably have appeared had a raficieni another of F, plants heea grow*. How many W t plants it would Ih- necessary • &gt;n in order to have an even chance for the appearance of forms like the parent! cannot l&gt;e told. More than enough were grown to realise this result if the parents differed by only four - nfluencing breadth of kernels. Obviously the difference 'hem must lie considerably mare than four factors. If tlifv differ b\ the factors, over three times as many plants as w ti would nave bees I ; if by six factors, nearly thirteen time* as many: if by seven factor*, over fifty times as many, and if by eighi factors, over two hundred times as many. ■ put of the question to prow in ordinary pedigree cultures : 1 1 1 \ such nnaaber of individuals as would l&gt;c accessary ta regain tin' original t.\|&gt;es of s 1 tiae in F, if tne parents differ k man,\ as seven or eight factors. Bat, by selecting F jilants with the smallcM mmiIs and continuimr the selection in F, and I mary, it should be possible to pajaia the parent types in a few geaoratiosjs without gioalag. excessively lar«e aasnbai an\ generation. The I' families of the cross of Missouri dent with Tom Thumb pop i Table 241 illustrate the possibility of accomplishing this isolation gradaalh without growing extremely mr§i nunibers. True the ]iai-ents of this cross did not differ so jrreatly in seed iii-i dent and California pop and all the inter- </seg>
            <seg id="p064">the F families taken together contained a few individual* with seeds smaller than The mean ami size of Tom Thumb pop and also a few with seeds larger than the mean seed siee of Missouri dent. But none of the more than 300 F 2 plants had seed as small a* the smallest of Tom Thumb j&gt;op or as large as the largest of Missouri dent, and neither one sf tin- three F, families alone lapped appreciably even the inner extremes of both parent varit iilnnts represented in Table 24 sad a fe\&gt; \ ith seeds met ■ssll ax the mean seed size of Tom Thumb jx&gt;p but none with seeds larger than the smallest seed -size ebus of Missouri dent. From this ■—iM ■»»*■ *~\ OT.VU "P I #« ' l«l«f III 'I ■ "*^' Ml I | llf^Ill. 1 I UllJ IIIIB '*IJ' frateruitv. tkj sta hwiasM in the table were gr - imly came from I F i&gt;lants. so that F s ftuniHea and Ilin w. , e lv smalls,., not the HI. ThVir mean - than i! f their F parents and their smallest I te the equal of the snin seeded Tom Thumb pop plant* The rather pronounced vari: shown bv thew 1 i&gt;ossible that a si with see.! Thumb pop n he established br fun I </seg>
            <seg id="p065">a c i ! t £ - o.*.hCC££ftCeCfiC ;re = ____ a 52i£22»2222£2 L_ il </seg>
            <seg id="p066">i i .'I 1 ".4 I.M I 141.08 1.17 0 ■ a i.i)7 c - ■Mi 1.49 I «2 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">63 * I nh' ' ii'itK &gt; ••! tfHmntitmtir*. 1*hmrmct€r* in CkmrmcU r* in - - - " t -_,.,.- I £ i • j ?l - ■- - T - . r — T- — • " "I r-r — ■" — ?i ~i _ I -.---,;-,..,.,,- -s 2 4 — — / *B^ II - ; "*" — M99 T- Wt '- K "' — .»§ |2sg»«ggag5 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">Table* 25, i'&lt;;. Mini i'7 roataia the data &lt;m the height* of the alaata in the tkiw croaaea §9-3x54. 60-5x54. Mini 60-8x54 TImiiiiI» pap emaaai with Black Mexican sweet. \&gt; Btated hi differ only in th&lt;' fart that npantt ia41»idaaki tin- |«.-m-ntv In ■ uuaa fcillliaed speciei like naiae, haan mijrht i. r i x&lt;i ■■ •■■iai raaaha mm ix-tween did iiciiial i Tin- crosses haTiag In-en made originally for the i'iujmiw of itadying other characters, the height ..c \ii tin ;nul af the I' geaecatioa were bo&lt; recorded It is kaowa thai the extreme individual! of So. 60 wen 4» in. Ins aad tliiit il" hials of the F _■ Mt-.'tx.VI « Mm inn- i&gt; coinparat aaff in sii|i|iiisim^ thai ) m &gt;r li populations exhibited ' ;i|.|.i&lt;i:i&lt;iiin^ thai "t ;i iioini;il eanre. GraatiBfE 'Mis aaaumpt till- liioit;ll &lt; I:ISS(- U illi'ln - iiiclp fivelv. Th&lt; i difference, i In-ti. uf i • ■»-ii i lie • ' the two pan .■itncc uf is , n i h, plus extrpBie uf th&lt; it and tin- ii ajeaemt iuii ». n tin- two pai modal riaaa woald be ahawl SS in«-he« In r&lt; ilit "in 7fl iinlu-s In other word* HIM' 111' i to In' ii-i;.i|'i|(h| • liu .cM'tli.-iciil r&gt;l tinted, r Thill' :iri- ;i nilllltx ivered bj ■ nimple iaapertion ol Tahk . ■ ii ami in en . 1 1 • tliosi' of ilir parents I 1 ri'il. I' fainilii s i |" paj . ahow ililliTi'in averaipp tn-i^his Hnd il bilin. SiiiIi ri'siilts \\&lt;fc obtained. The progeni n\ abort F in&lt;li\ iiluals were, in yeral. short, and the diotribui clitliTi-nt in their rariabilitj. The iin«], ,,f the danj ix.ili ."• ."! was ::7 imlns. while the mode of the dauj 17 was 58 imlii's Thr parental npis wen ruv.-i'i'il in the 1" yi-ni ratiun. l&gt;ut there is good reawaa fraai the aaaearaaee af the P dinrribntioaa to believe thin mold '» by farther aeieetioa. The I' diatribotioa in craaa 60-5x54 (Table hhkIi mon- varialil&lt;- than the I' ilistrilmi inn Oah oae familv from this i tuss was followed to the ' sit ion. however, sn no pjtrison iK'twet-n |&gt;ro«j«Mii«'s of lar^r ami of muall |&gt;lantn ran I.. - niaili' </seg>
            <seg id="p069">IH i;o«. x .-,j ,Table 27) one finds the same in ed variability in 1' over that shown by the F, generation. [plants wen- followed to the F s generation. One wai a -hint plain II inches Ugh; the other was a tall ph. The raaga of tlie first fraternity was from ".." inches with the mode about 40 inches. It is rpe than the original Tom Thumb. Part of doe in the vi&lt;;or of heterozygosis, but certainly ni is not reproduced. The other distribution, the tall stalk, is remarkable for its extreme variability. from 37 inches to itl inches with the mode at t t;i Tin- modes of the two families differ therefore imething like :_'! inches One can scarcely doubt the poasi - rei-overiaj; a very iall strain from this hitrhly variable ■ nil illlleil selertion. table 28 shows i lie results from a cross lietween a small .. and a larire dent. No. •&gt;. The mean of the first varien - ml tin mean of the second variety 101 inches. The variability of the F geaerattoa is about the - K i rent. The roeflcienta of variability of the - bit siv r iiiticantl\ greater. One has aajjj range of variation t&lt;&gt; see this. Individn i &lt;\ with the complete range from the smallest individual* variety to &lt; lit- largest individuals of the tar|| T% .., Imicnt of variability of F 55, while i ire 15.75 «8, 13 ipectivelj. r&gt; -an If reported for this cross, became th. rimeni \\;&gt;s of necessity moved ■orthward il not mature. Tabl tains the data secured from a cross of Tom ni dent, very short and rather tall strains was made in the irreenhous" in the nd i In F, treiieration grvwi the following sum - Mo. 170. The two parent plants growl in the greenhouse m open pollinated eara and no aeifed seed was obtained her plant. There was grown, however, along with the - in 1909, i( presentatives of the two parents 14f&gt;. dent, and 151. Tom Thumb pop from The same o|&gt;en-po] . &gt;l c:iis from which the two greenhouse plants used in the own. The plants of all three of these families were ■Hired, but the data were recorded in six-inch classes and lore can not lie presented in a table in which one-decimeter -id. The extreme fluctuations of the families are. mi-, show n in i lie table b\ means of arrows. F is plainlv mediate between the parent! but somewhat nearer the large ihan the small parent. •• </seg>
            <seg id="p070"/>
            <seg id="p071">n n lliKht of plants of th»- F. generation of Tom Thumb Rourl dent, as grown in 1910 l'.tlu ilit- parent rarietiea umi a small huihImt of F, plants I «cir mini in growv fur iutii|iarisoii with the F., jf—aH— No. "&gt;&lt;in. 1 In- I' generation, is from tke hum OHMd bu that pro - dvoed No I To. No. 508 from the name ear as No. liil. and N'u. "?(».■{ li the MM &lt;ar M \o. I Hi. Ajrain the F, generation was 'iitii-iiK-i! i.-i i«- between the parents in neigM of stalks with ■ • •oni|iai.iii\fl\ small i-aum- of variation. The ¥ t generation fmnih 510, i-oiitaint-il BOMe plant! quite as small as the smallest ■ &gt;f Tow Tlminli pop anil sunn- as large as the average of the Missouri ilfiit. with all yiadat ions between. Siiife no selfed -&lt;-&lt;h1 was obtained trim Iln- two original plants used in the cross iiii'.i In- known in h&lt; « far tin lii'terozvgons for sise #&lt;-it </seg>
            <seg id="p072">|Mitenti;ilitics is indicated I ».\ ih&lt; difference !«■! oar fr:ii' ;'&gt;"&gt;7. and 358, whic |rm i&lt;l i»f ililliriiit imlix 'iiliiiil |&gt;l;mt* Hi' Vt&gt; 146. In mi the parent stocks, two I' families mid - The I slmw i il g i ■ linn lli. in i iilh liv tlii' i-.iiil ml l&lt;\ i n. Mm tin imlivi.! Fl^ 14 oonri dent at ih &lt;iniii- »n Mn.ill as i ■ and f. hit^'i' ;i&gt; them &lt;if the lw|p parent, v of ih. r ■ ■xliiliitcd Mic raBfV of variation Rhown b\ th&lt; I Mm as iipi-asin-i'd liv th *um*&gt; nf tin-in iii-a!l\ M vatialili- M.aMii-.'.l In Ml uulanl. lm\\ ■1 tin-in were em I- - Mi Mian fix- paifii ~. Imt « licili. r am nf i h.-i , '| ,, ■MWt &lt;if 1)11 1 &lt; In itlli </seg>
            <seg id="p073">■Mi. of the K families. 114!t. from plant of the previous year, however, aeaalai the . I»'ii t par , in height. This fait is proltalth not .I in ;m\ ni'w coinbinattOB of height factor* not • tall parent variety hat rather to the fart that the M ssouri ditii families un&gt;\vn in 1911 had haca tt ling. \ns. lll'M. 11J8, ;m&lt;l 114S. the latter duplicate*, were from aelfed ean «&gt;f N&lt;&gt;. :&gt;r«:!. wUca m fed car of Nu. 1 16. A* x 5 /o 3i yj. '? V 3 s. I hi K RPntratton of Tom Thumb |Ki|. • nrawm la 1911. The variation in height within ;m.\ lol at the parent varieties .iml within the F general imi would neiessarilv 1m- influenced hv I in the size facton of the parent storks, the varia - Dg with an incrra wiag aaaaacr of hetaraajyaw size The s;u niidiiioti iiiijrln also reaaH in noticeable &lt;lif intweiMi 1' families imuwii fiuni ditfei-ent V , eM well aa between different nelfed straiaa of the aareat rarie \niinmi ni til' tori, " rrpUiin the fitmi vaHatiaa a nun inn I profffMtf, in" ilx i)i&lt;&gt;itottn&lt;t&lt;l &lt;l i ff r n'nees be- </seg>
            <seg id="p074">7- I 10. which, of ...in— aim- In. ill a sinjjli- I |&gt;lalll. Mini ill is phi 111 (loin llii- union i.l .! single tjaiiirlc fi-i.ii: nf ibf itarmta. WIhiIk-i all the other gametes proateeeal -■ inn |i;ii«'iii |iliinis wire liki the two ci&gt;iic&lt;-rn«'&lt;i in thic - iic whether thej were of fvwaJ different xu-is can oliviuiiMlv mi Viiriiit: &lt;&gt;ii I In l«li:i \ i«i| of the oae I" [ilant. I In- sin^lt - niilv. mid tin- HHveml I" funiiliea ii i|W tk»». ben &gt; .■!' mii'Ii. hail mi c&lt;&gt;nne&lt; III f r ! n "s y? T* Z7? ibST 235 1/b 6 /6 3 9 /? // •.i of |.lai Thin «llli lllis line (it |i|((j;( li!( &gt; In iiiIki- nordtt. llic |mi^~ • veil (tniiuliic. tmri iliai the parent plants may mat have Im li(tiii(&gt;7.\^oiis iii all size factor* can in m w«j lc&gt;«s«'ii tke iinjwr ' of the principal roaclaMom to be drawn from tliis and sim . . - MO ( xcii/h I mill I In I'll I ■•' / mi-nix irith nxjHt I h, si:, in, i,,rx jnxl &lt;ix truly nx it ,1m x uith ■&lt;rx fm ntlni rhiit a, tt rx. Ill, i, i» nix,, a,, getting anmmd Hi, /ilnui t /' size ■ iling </seg>
            <seg id="p075">itteatioB to the fact that the inherent differences hetween the aternitiea weir exaggerated smnew hut l&gt;\ ■ }»«-&lt;- 1 1 1 i ; 1 1- coin - iiiniitinn of ui;iilicr I'OBhditiona with character! of tin- planta other Mi. h happens thai Toai Thanh pop is not &lt;&gt;nl\ Iml also i-xtlM -iin-1 \ ear!\ and that Missouri «1«&gt;ii I is very -lioun later i s»-e T;il&gt;le 39 i . ■» a&gt; (lues si/c. Whether thn gettctir corn'la &gt;r not. it happened ihat the akori 1' tamilics rm also Mini the tall families lair. Thr weather of earlv mmmer &lt;\\t&gt; F families of Tom Thumb Mi - &gt;n in ll'll Noli' iliftVri-ni &gt;• In variability. u In n i In iarl\ familiis »in- ftevektpiap rapMI? was \cv\ uti will while th&lt; ucallirr laic in siiiiniiii- when Hi- tamillt's well- making their niosi i-apid growth was favorable. The earh fninilie* were, therefore, shoi-ti'i- and ih&lt;- late I'aniilit's taller than 1 1 1 &lt; ■ \ would have heea had the ion ditkHH hen more aaifora ihruoin tin- wrmmam. This effei-t of t in- weather i&gt; readily seen by Bntian the various F fraterniiies ami the b he I" plant* from which i li«-\ were sirowii. In raae nf each F fainilv Ae iiw class i&lt;&gt; which the K. lmrent plant Ulon,.,l i&gt; imlMa.cl I. l.lackfacd fibres in the F arr«T. The </seg>
            <seg id="p076">lalli-r than iln- b\ plains frinn which th&lt;-\ w.tc derive M the magr "f variation M tin- V |ilam&gt; lthwii in 1911 lh|\ iii-r&lt;asc&lt;l liv lli&lt;- \\ t • : 1 1 1 n • i ■ cOBditionH llic Mrli |ilanl&lt; j • st and one oi th- riMl s of 7 Missouri dent as Mi- y il.ml'i less hflvinK bwi - n&lt;l th&lt;- late plan - than lli«',v hihiM ulk. l!ut it miisi ;i - iim'IiiIm r«'&lt;l that tin- saint* mil </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Er ( i; 1 1 ■ comparison of heights of tin Missouri dent familii ■&lt; I in 11*11 witli the heights of the IMC plants from whirh loet "i show the saint' effect noticed in case of the - Inn this is inosi likely due to the repeated l: of the parent stocks. 1 1 • 1 \ in the study of this cross it was foreseen that the groat ■ in earliness hetweea tlie parents mijrht introduce the ■ onipliiatioli discussed aliove. and an endeavor was therefore in overcome tlie difficulty in later crosses by using as 'is \arietien that, while differing much in size, had practi raljj the same S4';is4)n of growth. The varieties chosen were • 1 1 1- i dent, the same one used as tall parent in the cross ■ 1\ described, and California Kice |&gt;op. The latter is only He taller than Tom Thumb ]&gt;op and. while it ripens some what earlier than Missouri dent, its time of blossoming and con - duration &lt;&gt;f growth are not appreciably different Missouri dent. California pop also differs much from Tom Thumb in the number of nodes per stalk. In this reapari it is rimitar to Missouri dent. The difference in height bttween Thumb poji nnd Missouri dent is largely a difference in MiimU-r of intcrnodcs. while tlie difference between California iinl Missouri dent is largely one of internode length. • » :!1 to :tl. i The one cross, therefore, supplements the other n this study of the inheritance of height of stalks, since I i&gt; apparent l\ merelv a product of number of nodes and node length. In Table :t(l are brought together the available data derived roes between Missouri dent and California |&gt;op. As in i he preceding table, tlie progenies grown in the same garden the _ ..iiped together. Of the lots grown in 191n • in selfed seed of ;i single plant of Missouri dent, #M and re lioin selfed seed of i wo plants of California pop. ami Sm ind •"'•." ,ire from crosses of the parent plants of 49rt ami MM the parent plant of :!•"&lt;•"{. In this case, therefore, tli ration is fallj co— pa fa Me with the parent generations grown - imc rear. la 1911. two families. 8S3 and S.",8. were grown i.ri -sent Missouri dent. Thev were from selfed seed of two plants of .■!.-&gt;:!. Likewise two lots. B34 and US, grown from selfed ■eH of two plants of 4!t!». represent California pop. N'os. S3fi and v:7 i-onsisted of F plants from the remnants of the same Mom which had lieen grown the previous year Noa, MB and 5M9 rcs|M-ctivel\. Nos. gB», fQA. s:?l. s:fj. s:?9. and M« were F, _■ nies from selfed seed of six different F, plants. The !■' lots of both years were almost as tall as the tall </seg>
            <seg id="p078">u 111 behavior is undoubted!.! dm- to th«' fait thai in the one - iimiiiImt of imkIo was tlir important consideration while in t In- other ii was iiitrriHxli- li-n^tli and to the farther fact that F plants in gcarral have ■■ iatermediate another af iateraaAai but iiiciiinili- leujrili greater than that &lt;&gt;f the tall pawat That tlit- talliK'ss of the I' phmts of the (*roM ■ i' i roiisidiiat ion was not &lt;lm- to dominance of |&lt;in&lt;; over short iatprnndn i • ■ 1 1 rather to the incfi-ax-il i uBipaaTiag hetnv i In the fart that tin- mcnii it &lt;&gt;f tin- F - 1'i-act iia ll\ the 1 1 1 • « 1 -paivnta 1 it part ial h&lt; Hired in P and alsn li&lt; the fait that i hi' F \ i it- nut vo pro iioiwi'i ilh sk would have been nteniodk ■ ■ between tl il F Mihalilv din' to th&lt; - planl&gt;. \o mil | 1 nti'f i-M D thi i f the \' fa in i \\a&gt; p till' ol! • if lli* </seg>
            <seg id="p079">75 ki I nh* &gt; ittinr&gt; of Ifiuintittt «M« i/#r&lt; r tin SgSi" 5 *■" - 5"S»1 ■ i_- | ■J " R| 5 : i 28 c* y: y: — - — JE Blflh J I ~ — — i - I- — r-. — — z. ~ £: ~~ — -3 «i?i'-r- 3 SgSi" 5 *■" ;_-.•-■--&gt;-■- - 5*211 •3*2 ;i _^ 1 = m Jr ■ &lt; BXSR Mte»" r " - ,£ I 1 - £ — ?.". I ---- </seg>
            <seg id="p080">; t -= « ■ r — r- / : " -:: / </seg>
            <seg id="p081">77 S222E225 -.-.= — — — n ?t — — — .£*' ' '—Z^HZ-'r z-zlz. ~ ~"r'"lj'"l'l"_:i. _- -_ ---;-.- " - — — I ! ■ 1 r-.-»ir. i * , s r« wuio.a.a.a.a.a.iSa.a.a.a.a: g - </seg>
            <seg id="p082">7- _ ». 32SS2888-----2-i -r: li = !*2 = = 2 X^ = r I s &gt;■ . I ~ ; E i -= I — — I I </seg>
            <seg id="p083">THE INHERITANCE OK NI'MBER OF NODES PER STALK. i! 11 case of rlit- eroaaes of Missouri dent with Tom Thumb pop — ui'i dent with California pop. discussed under the he inheritance of bright of plant, the nodes of the main li plant were counted ;it the time the stalks were ismi-il. The lt-siilis of these counts are presented in Tables 31 '■'&lt;-. Since the relationship of the various families was given one detail in tin- discussion of height, it will not Ik- necessary " repeal ii here. In cas.- of Missouri ilent crossed by Tom Thumb, where the number of node* is very unlike in the parent varieties, the F, iiiimU is «ere distinctly intermediate between the parents and i -l.\ bridged the «;ap lietween them. The three F, families I'd much greater variation than the parents and the F, ration. Thej overlapped both parents but did not contain duals with so many nodes as the largest nuniber found in ill parent nor individuals with so few nodes as the least numb red in the short parent. The total ranjie of varia exhibited b.\ the F fraternities was greater by three nodes thai of the I' fraternities, lint possibly would not have iad aa equal iniiiilier of I" plants Ix-en ;t»wii. In Bgk? I' family was the variation so };reat as in the F. lots uid iii some families it was no greater than in OMB of the parents. While the parent types were not completely recovered in tl ihe difference between the several F.,'s was notable. For hi the torgf &lt; number of nodes recorded in families 1191 I"..'! (TaMe .'!1 i was thirteen, while the smallest number ! in families 1144. 1147. and 1140 was fifteen. I 'alifornia pop. th&lt;&gt; very short, is unlike Tom Thumb pop in it has nearly as many nudes as Missouri dent. In the cross wo varieties i Table ."'.2 1 . F, was intermediate between parents. With the parents so nearly alike, it would seen individuals like the extremes of lioth parents should have •red in F. even with smaller numbers than were grown. r families run mined plants with as many nodes as the snanher shown by any Missouri dent plant, but no F, l\ contained ■ plant with so few nodes as some of the plants alifornia pop. In this connection it should be noted that 1'oinia pop produces numerous tillers while Missouri dent ines very few. It seems possible that the small nuniber of a in &lt; 'alifornia pop may in some way be associated with the ■ nnmher of tillers. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">; ■ ! \t " •r — i 1 ! — - - II 5 5 I £: H; £; - = = = * " - ~ ~ -■ ?■ -• r • - - " " </seg>
            <seg id="p085">81 II r - — ~ c — 7 r. r- r. r. 3D r. r; r; " r-. r. a n * r. 3 ?J I — - I " - I- — tr.~ — I- — ro-Jfja *. •....^^^^^^^^^ — — 3| '" ~ - '~: — &lt;-.V~- J ■ - ■- e«« i- — — i -» c —. ■&gt;! ?i .s — &lt; ■ .£•*&lt; — "• •&lt; i- f = - — , — — — — — - Z —'— — — 2.1.^ 1 - I 3 Z I iiji I r i 9 — — — ri ■c — .- — / = ?&gt; — fi '' *' : ~ : U 2 Z ?, - "' t — '" — I' ?! I- — — f — /-«[,- = - -i - n ri ~i?i- I / — s - i : t - — c - 1 — — - — — — — ri ri m r- = — — — . ,»__ — _ _ -i </seg>
            <seg id="p086">« 1 -N H tKI I AN( r. ' It" I 1 fe»rv^(M)Ki I . K. .\ ( » I i i IFi-oih die data given for height &lt;if stalks and number &lt;&gt;f uodea tlie crosses «if Tom Thinnli j»op with WlMMiri dent and of th&lt; ter with &lt;"alifoinia |h&gt;|». tin- average internode length per plani » determined. Tables :'.:'. and .",4 contain them calculated data I While in 1909 the height and niiinlter of nodes VCR detenu inert each individual plant, only the frequencies of the various ;lit and node number eaaaaaa were recorded It is impost refoi-e. to show (W| the range of internode length for thl wn that vciir. Fi i the mean htighta and the mean nuinU - lot*, however, an approximation of the mean rnixli- li-iii.'tli ■■&lt;] TbeM a|i|ifoximatf iimmi - ii Table •"!•■&gt;. The feature of thea hat the iiii'.iii internod4' length of tlie P, t tin intfiiiodi- Ii own in 1 In l!*' 1 arly gnnimei riillhili BOp I .1 \er\ •! - when tin- I • and I' plants ia|iidl\ . ii i the internnde I ral famil ■■■ eiinsi-l. i ■ . . -v !•&lt; ihat of Misuouii dent Tin- mean mode lei . 'hat of V d'llil' .if the deireaseil lag partial homo the in ter node lenjrtl dent. Th&lt; 1 ion in F . Vo. "il 11 lew hat i pd in roniKitioii with the raag Th. greatest intiTinxIc length in I mil the shortest thirtv milliiiietei - an ill. iiemis found amoiiir the aarcata. This inn tnav iloubtless Ih- airoiintcd for in pan. thfl 'i-rtainh not entireh by the fart that more individuals arere iaclnded in F than ii .ill the other lots together. I ribte that thi weather conditions that tended to ituriase the internod« 'Ii of the earl\ Tom Tlmmh |m&gt;|i and to decrease that of the -■ &gt;nri dent, and therelix to restrict the combined rang* 'if variation of the parents, could have had the opposite effwt • m the F. NHfja, Then- was. ms a matter of fact, in this par ticuliir F.. family. No. lit, a correlation between cat-lines* and internode length of about M. In other words, ther.- wan tontf tendenr.v at leaot for the parly plants to have loag internodes </seg>
            <seg id="p087">ii »i';ii her. ftceetamtiag the growth of the early plants and re - larding that of the late ones. If. however, this correlation were geaetii . or even inereh physiological, so that, without respect to seasonal weather . iianges. the early plants tended to have r internodes than the late plants, then the weather actually • \perienced in I9M would have tended to make the long inter 'MMle* longer and the short ones shorter, thus tending to extend the range &lt;»f variation of F, while lessening that of the parents. I tut it is difficult to se&lt;- how there can l&gt;e any physiological cor illation MlM earliness and long internodes. And it is even difficult to U-lieve in gcnetu- correlation between eurlinexx i iid lnn&lt;i inti i fnili x when it is remembered that in rase of the iits the '■«//// one has the short fr internodes. On the whole. therefore, it s.'&lt;-ms very probable that the production of inter &lt;&gt;«{&lt;■ lengths in F. tioih almve the upper and below the lower • ■\t miies of the parents was due in part at least to new combine - of internode- length factors. If the above is the correct explanation of the very long ami • r\ short internode tyjK's that appeared in F 2 family No .'•Hi. it should be possible to isolate strains from it that have oiiger or shorter internodes than do the parent varieties. The rion of F plants to be tested by F, progenies wan based upon heighi of stalk and upon earliness rather than upon inter length, and it happened that no F.. plant with extremely short or extremely long internodes was chosen. The F a fani - pwi in 1!H1 are arrauge&lt;l in Table X\ in order of th« - nteriKMle length of the F. plants of which they are the progenies ;is indicated by black -faced figures in the F. arrays. The exact i-exerse in seasonal weather conditions between 1910. when in Vehraska the early summer was favorable for growth and the summer unfavorable, and 1911. when in Massachusetts the -arlv summer was unfavorable and the late summer very favor .idle, made it impossible to determine from a single season's -tudy of the F 3 families whether types more extreme than thf i&gt;arvnts could be isolated. By reference to Table :&lt;3 and to I'.iMe :?!». which latter contains the data for earliness of these same .unities, it will be noted that, with the marked exception of No. 11.17. there was a strong tendency for the early F, families to ii;i\«- much shorter internodes and the late families much longer internodes than the F. plants of which they were the progenies Id short the early F 2 plants had longer and their F 3 progenies shorter internodes while the late F, plants had shorter and their f progenies longer internodes than would have been the case had the weather been more Marty uniform thrnout the two </seg>
            <seg id="p088">ii» earlincM. ■hnrtcr iataflMdbia than their pmay itwi of This is doabtleaa due to the fart thai the pwcal atacka ha&lt;l been Ballad until 11n-\ had lost niucli of the vijior acajoiraa 1 thru their former het. s condition. i'hc 1" families «ii phi m not readih hroughi into line with behavior of the I' families of the s 4ince the.i liMcrin! F phml ;-. froii! the F f'aiuih of 1916 1911, ami since iticse different plant* 1 1 1 ; i \ lia\&lt;- ha&lt;l different inii rnodc Icnjrth iaheritaaeea in tin- more or less betel parent stocks, it is not hat their h length should differ from the F iil\ of tlie pn Tin :i with California |«&gt;p (Table 31 aitfc somewhat longer inti-rnodes than m the had. lint tl I no! mi iii&lt;at as ii of the cross dent and Tom Tliumli. In HMO tin •i internode length of lhaari s mm. gwtat than that nf MiHtuiuri dent. Ml mm. fjreater than that of California pop, and iliciefore "_'l mn i than the average of the interaode lis nf the parents Similarly, in 11*11 the F families had internixles in;iii&gt; 8 i! ban Missouri ilcnr. Bearlv S8 mm. i ;t it Californin pop, and ahoat 23 nun. longer than the; i the p.r That the loop iateraoi not due to dominance nf loag o\er short internodea bui p io increased viffar a4 growth due • i tin ( 1 1:1 1 tin- internode lengths of the 1' familiei (tron'n in I'.U! onl\ alxiui 18 mm. greater than those of California pop. alxiul |J nun leys than those "' Nlissonri dent and iImi milx alMint .'! mm. greater than tin average internode lengths o( the parents. Further, if dominan eoaceraed. the I" ft* • ineiic\ (tistiilnit ions would be noticcahh skewed While no F. fainilv had ipiite the combined NMfp nl extreme of the pare own in 1911 reached l&gt;\ tlnei- I" lots and the upper extreme In two. The ition in F was consideraldv yreater than in F . The therefore, evidence of wprejiation of internode lengths in I this from, as well as in the cross af Missouri dent and Tom Thumb: and here, nioveover. the weather must have atFeded all generations practically alike atone then all hail alM&gt;ut the same ii of growth. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">I . . '_ .... r — «2 --: /i..---iri«N*Si HM9 - ,- J _ — -, _ -i P 5="2*' r 5-=-S8S2r«*» r "2 .« -- , ;:; — -m.-;j,» : /-j.-.-.: Z~'Z^~ : --"■'-• - \\ I _ - r. r. r. « „.„„„_-„„_ | I 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">t | - ; r. / &gt; I v z. — r ■ ~ J i .; r i^ ! s i -i — I — f Z. I - I - J - "I "&amp; - b a- C - B — "^~ — i - 4 — . — - - ■ -r c f. ri r-. i» -i ?i ~i ■- — — — i- - / •- t- ri — . ■•: — — — i - — ?r -2 _ - ?i i i - r - - — .-' ri c ' c •" - — — — - — - -*. *i 7tz ~\ -z r. •- — z I - — -■-- ■ 1 I </seg>
            <seg id="p091">NMKRIiANi r. Hr \ I MBKK Or S I A Lj/vS I Kn "LA.N 1 . 'in i di-iil. like must largo dent varieties, tillers very liulc. - a rule only uiie tall stalk, or at most two stalks with occasional short tillers. Tom Tliuinb |H&gt;p and California &gt;n The other haiul. produce numerous tillers. Tom Thumb • isiialh lias one or two principal stalks with several shortet rs that end in ears instead of tassels. In the California pop of the numerous tillers have both tassels and ears. In diim tin- data furnished by crosses of these dent and pop hi attempt was made to distinguish stalks from tillers. the distinction in very many rases was neeessarih i i^ di-eiiicd l&gt;esi to count every branch from near .round as a stalk without regard to its relative length or H ace of a tassel or an ear. Lumping everything in tli i — - not always bring out the real difference between differ For instance. No. 1148 is shown in Table rtl&gt; to contained two |ilants with four stalks each, whereas, as a • r of fact, there was only one plant in the whole lot that had Kan\ cal stalks. The almost universal condition in family, ;is Am in figure M, was one tall stalk without an.\ with one or two very short ones. In family 11-Hi. on I otter hand, four or the almost equally tall stalks with ver.\ -liott tiller was the prevailing condition. In many cases. ever, all gradations occurred from tall stalks with ears and M stalks with tassel but no ear. equally tall stalks end - in an ear instead of in a tassel, etc.. to very short branches i neither tassel nor ear. In tl I it w;&lt;s obviously im .il»|i- in irroiip the various sorts of branches into two definite The I' of the cross of Missouri dent and California pop. Table intermediate lictween the parents in number of stalks plant both in 1918 and 1911. The range of variation in foinia pop was greater than in some of the F ; families. It lite probable that the stock of this varietv used was hetero lln I' families exhibited more variation than the F nit only one of them covered the entire range of the nts as iii-owii the same year. The cross of Missouri dent with Tom Thumb. Table 36. pro - ■ I W '• that were intermediate tietween the parents and F,'s »ith a ran^e slight l\ jrreater than that of the parents combined. That this pa) variation in F was due to segregation of factors for maker of stalks per plant is shown by the F, families grown n lftil. These are arranged in the table according to their mean minders of stalks. Of course, not all of the Fj's were like the f plants from which the\ came The modal clasa of family 1142 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">■ was thtw stalk!* .iinl the mean number of its stalks a littk mil a half. Kvidentlx its one stalked V paicat was a iniim&gt; i ii t i»f a two stalked or three-stalked t&gt;pe. Similarly faniilv 114*1 had n modal value of tiv&lt;- stalks and a mean of about four and a quarter, while its F, parent had only three stalks, and 1149 had a mean of on I \ alMiiit two stalks, tlio its I' parent had four Kamih ll.'.'.t. whose I' parent also had four stalks, had a mean "f Mart) foiir and a &lt;|iiarter stalks. The four stalks of th&lt; nt of 1 Hit. howewr. eaaaMei afl one main stalk and three Fie- It. Three F, families of Tom Tbumli pop &gt; Missouri dent st marked differences in number of til !■ -mber 19. 1911. rathe I short sii'kcrs. while all the four si:ilk» &gt;il the parent of ll.'.'.t were tall. That this difference. iln&gt; p&gt;N .MiihVant • aniiot In' relied upon is shown 1&gt;\ the 1:nt that families 1 132 ami 1140. the F parents of whi.li. like that of I I 111. had onl.v aaf stalk and three sin-kers. had four stalks an their i la I U'tween thriN- an&lt;l four stalks as their means. The most significant fact established 1&gt;\ thes,. \' families as a whole is that fvom the apffTVgStP* ,,&lt; |" u, ic prodn&lt;vd t\pes with various ii ii ii 1 1 :ilks ranpinn ne p.irent t\]M- to the </seg>
            <seg id="p093">■ inliliitin r/,. V«N ■ / iiiilifs of Tom Thumb pop X to show the number </seg>
            <seg id="p094">varieties, t h«- frw|«eacj diatribatioM foe r.Mm and 1910 an haps more useful tllilli those of 1911. While the 1M11 stocks of \;irii-iies were doubtless more nearly hoinozvpous than tht - ■ of previon- ■ hey prolciMv did not |M&gt;ssess jusf tht ilHe&lt;l li\ the Iwn gCTM cellH whose utlion resulted &lt; iiiilly in the 191] I" families, Approaching homoiyguxia of M filelors reli(lere&lt;l the 1911 p.irent I leM vigorous than they were in pnviw and tin lessened the IcimIcii. \ to tiller, somewhat U poor or &lt;i . am to do Tl '•« tillem iMndiic'Ml iiv the 1911 - •&gt;f Tom Tliuinli. No. ir_'t;. «^i^ due iu par! perfcapa to H ii |&gt;iirt to the rerj •aJararaUp weather conditiona while ii ■ lev eloping, .mil tloulitless in | &gt;;| I f with roenparativeli !•■« vi ;1 |ks. \\ llether ill|\ of I he I .ill the (acton thai have to &lt;l" vita Banter of -i;ilk^ caaa* deiermiued wiilioiii further us |tmhahli xonie of them, like 1 1 4 ~* for ii thai had ;i nniall raa| iiiou will lie found to h ill\ true, while will |ielli;i|is lie (Missililc pal fy|&gt;eB.* \inonjr the F fauiiliem of T Thamb Black H in nun plant •iimilies (u-areeh e\er tillered, while one family 1 illers |m-i- pljuit. • W h i I « will b aa waa BUgsntcd aa thmi stalk ma&gt; would. ho» ■ attaaa Only furt Ii akow huv aow nnii I </seg>
            <seg id="p095">91 i « , ,- — ~i — ti "i" sS2SS|58l5a?Sp^ 2r,ii-?3^?S7.22 J| X *• -— ? - _ ■"-£'" '"'"'- r £ ?i - ?i?i- — 5 i ™* " *i r"i -i S " ,-i i — — - — -i • ~ 7=?^^£US^~i-^^5= = r,€- : i :^6-€'£'i'i = i.'i'i g^gS-ssgggSSS^^ --&gt;■-■ -x-,-zz*?,V, •= </seg>
            <seg id="p096">M 1 S I i j • | « I '_■_-_-_■_ ._ I ■c She z- — z. — — - — — ZZ- — _ - s 5 - </seg>
            <seg id="p097">I In I -ml itiitiri (Inn il&lt; li is in i!ui:i 1M1K: \l. I.KNCTII OF STALKS PER PLANT For i lie studies of height i&gt;f plants, onlv the main stalk &lt;»f Ii plant was measured Mini fur the studies of number i&gt;I -:alk» |&gt;I;iii Ik. whether tall cir short, was counted. I diit a given a vi r\ &lt;:imii1 Mm nf iln- tstal nut of stalk produced. While ii certainly wmiM have Ik-cii liiirinini- the dry weight of each plant, thai euaM in- ill ii H-. I »i hi lii less a fair nut inn nf the ;i iih unit of rabstnnee rmilil he obtained from ■ knowledge of the total length • Ibniii-ii-i- nf sialks per plant, hut M determinations iameter* were Bade. The only nMMareBtenti of total length \mii- made in Ml. Tin- ilata arc give* in TnbV . aiVui-ils a iiinipaiisiiii of Missouri dent, California pop. r and 1" (ppnerationn of a mm of thenr yarietie*. WTiile ! iiiiint laniilirs r&gt;f the saim- parent of hyhrM ■»■&lt; ration i*d considerably from one another, thi-ro vcie also fairl.i well i :.-in-i's hetweeii the iliffi'i-i'nt genenitkMn. Tne ihart - .(I California pep, Nns s::4 ami MS, uwinir to its large ninn .Iks per plant, had a greater total lonjrth of stalk ihiin iliil the iniiili lallrr Missunri dent. Von. s:;:. am - •! vigor ut tin- I' iicneration. Soa. s'iti and s::^ d in a total length of sialk ronsidcrahlv greater than iliai of pan-Hi Vme nf the F. families had an average total length 'k ii|iial in I' nor iliil any of them nnn-h neeed the &lt; 'alifn pareal in (his raapect. Sunn' of tin 1 F_ famibes, howi i range "f rariation the pombiBed range of the parents Whether a iy|M' In- linsr tme to a total stalk lenirth ■i- ilian that of either pa rent roaM he isotated 1&gt;* si-li tr the 1 i 'an Im- tolil only by farther breeding. H milar data for the (Tons nf Missouri dent and Tom Thumb woted in Table 38. So F gmeratton of this jiiiuii if 1!&gt;H. hut tin- parent and F. jjcncr-atioiis will i ni!|iai ismi with tin- various F families. Tin- unfavorable m -~« » 1 1 ami prerions inbrwdinp i-ombined to niaki- tin- total k nf Ton Thumb pap. No. llSt, unusually small. • mix about one-fifth thai nf Missouri dent. Nos. 1129. llSft. Mil'! Tin- average total length of stalks of tin- F families, 1 127 and 1 128. ii|iialrd or exceeded somewhat that of the Missouri dent parent. Tin- range of variation in F was considerably ter than in the parents. In sunn- of the F families tin - uf variation was even urea ter than in F.. while in othi Ittle if any tr?-&lt; -:i t«*i- tbaa in the parent \arii-ties. The • total length of sialk of the F families varied from ahont midway i»t«ic" tin- parent* '" "omewhat wer I wire that of the larger </seg>
            <seg id="p098">ui i('oui|MUC \o V 1133 and 114." « itli IJ44 tad 1 l»i&gt; While ■&gt;( miirsc tin' Missouri ili-nt stock in 1§11 • 1 1 « t n&lt;&gt;! ;•!-&lt; m] ■■•■•- ;iv i.ill wl;i!ks M ii doubtless woillil have dmir if it li.i.l Imimi |ni'\ iouslv sclfi-d. it is qaitc unlikely thai aa.i |M»|lin;itioii within the nrigimml ttoeb vwiM him raaaHH in ■ like 1;iinily 114f,. Tin- .toss of ■ tall. fpw-stalk.'&lt;l nu with ,i short. im:iii\ -l.ilkr.l sort hfl* Wlllted in iln- i.io.Iu.i i ill in.'iiiv sl:ilki'&lt;l type mm ili- unlike .i I li&lt; r ;&gt;;iivni r'ntill Iiiii/Hi (,j ■ I ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p099">95 1 t / — - _i, ■- — Z. — — Z. — Z.-. i - I- I - " £' T r r £L;_ . umummuuuim | - f ,- - •"■■ </seg>
            <seg id="p100">\\liil&lt;- tin- linn- repaired for a can pl;i n t i&lt;&lt; reach ;i &lt;li ti xiagc in its development. mk*Ii m Moai i-harnrtcr. it li. ma a marked ialu of |&gt;l;ints or plaat (t.-iriK. It luis itccn po : ihix |i.i|&gt;ir Iniw I I.I (llilUtK il llli Ml HIM I HIM taonable to expeel n ; relation nd daratiui - 1 i" uuike iImmi- |pii!i«i]p.i! (fron th ;llks. lie - date ;iiiil 'hr plant iii_ lilv tllr | • ■ plant i«i peach tin Ii|«iks.. n&lt; I tin- time Elo iiiuli fill! iiiiiliiritv. Tin- ill\ not rut nt ili«- latter. 1 1 tin- Ml .( 1! </seg>
            <seg id="p101">'liiii ant] ilic \i'i-\ small cared California | H&gt; |' blossom er. l&gt;n i the hitter ri|K*ns sonic days ahead of the i in. ;i very earh eon niav have its later stages : relatively In ihe heat of midsummer, while a very late t\ 1 1 1 : i ,\ have its ripening stage relatively prolonged b\ the weather of autumn. In 1!»l(i the dale of ripening of each plant of the crows under de ratios Tom Thmiih Missouri dent was deiennined as - practicable, while the dates of blossoming were noted ■nl\ such |ilanis as were hand-pollinated. The various lots ruined carefully mi the same day each week and all - deemed ripe were noted. Since in 1911 this corn was i ii. Massachusetts, it was foreseen that the later families ! licit possibly ripen, and. therefore, blossoming dates alone rcccirded. The time of the exposure of the tirst anthers nf - i mi the main stalk was chosen as the date of blossom In ih) case of proiandrous plants, which constituted the •■I ilnisi growa, this was ihe only date recorded, but for the protOgynoM families the date of exposure of the tirst silks aim noted. Tl utire lot of plants was examined each day .iml those just beginning tO blossom were fagged. Tile avail data are jfrooped together in Table .'!!•. Since in 1010 the - of ripening were taken weekly while the dates of bloMom - !&lt;■ arranged in three-day classes. onl\ the range of varia of the IMA families is shown in the table. Since the owing date* of hand-pollinated plants onl\ were recorded in 1910, the ranges of variation indicated in the table are not Mttrilj the complete ranges of blossoming dates. A la rue ■ i in of the plants, however, blossomed within the dates n in the table. The class headings indicate the nunilter - cini planting to blossoming or ri|&gt;ening. In I'M &lt; i. Tom Thumb pop i family 606) was in blossom tin to 7n days from planting time, while Missouri dent i .'{."&gt;:! &gt; was Moauoming 83 to !d days after planting. The F, plants (ft§) distinctly iniermediate. with a blossoming time of ~'.l to 83 days from planting. Some of the F plants (51#) were nearly lie earliest Tom Thumb nap plants, while others ihiiost as late ,is the latest Missouri dent. The F 3 blossom xtended aver a parted of thirty days. 62 to 92 days after planting. The lMfl families held the same relative order in ripening as in flowering. The parent varieties were farther apart in ripening than in blossoming. Missouri dent having ripened in 141 to 151 days and Tom Thumb j&gt;op in 91 to 98 or while Missouri dent was still in flower. The F, plants somewhat later than half wax lietween the parents, with </seg>
            <seg id="p102">N I" 14&lt;» days from |il;mtinjr. A^ n Massiuhiisol ts in 1911. Turn Tlmiiili pop &lt; 1 1 12 1 *&gt; ■ bad an Brer loniing d mi ii:it&lt;- towwil of about &lt;&gt;4 d.iys f nun |il,iiniii&lt;:. in- ]if;nlii;ill\ tin - in Vclinisk : before, dint &lt;lli'!i. 1130. Ill*', oa the other hand, was aheart littn-n daye later ili.-m tin- ptwkxw war, its rtag date haviag, beta •bovt IM days from plant The inniparativHy iimiI wi;irli&lt;M- nf midsummer ami later was doul - di in while ilu In ii htaaa rhomb pop into Ion brant. |&gt;laBti w ii in 1911. Tin 1127 I li&gt; ' . ilni i uiitiiiniiif; fewer indiridnal* the I Eaaiih of ISlfl iie^'erthelean showed .i Homewbat nf \.iri;ii inn rible th.ii thi - which iii.hIi- MisMiiiii dent later than in 1910 ami forced Ton Thiiiuli ]»t\&gt; into %tm ■ 1918 tended b i.nil the I - jiuw n in l'.H I . w miw climatic infl - th* pai howtw i mi I" fami i&gt;-&lt;l i&lt;&gt; I souri dent did. The -i tImi imt the \&lt;i in the table \&gt;\ h •! h |k- ii It w;is eX|M'ilcd i In i MMW of I Im illllliiSI if lint &lt; 1 1 1 i 1 « ■ ;is late :is \ll«s' had an bloaaoaril |tl:mtiii&lt;;. while the average dart- of flon lliMouri din i fami I \ waa nearly 1.'! it - probable aaaa &lt;&gt;f tin- pla I91d were plus rariatea ai &lt;&gt;nlv Medina late trpea, for rafjcaiaa, aa&lt;»ilhalia&lt;liag the cooter weather ol tli&gt; l:tt»- Kunmicr of 1911, wer 1910. This was partirulai I Hfi. 114S, and 1 1 Hi. The jiart-nt af tamih 1145, fnr i— taaif bloMuiiiinl alwuit ss ( |a\s after planting, white imt a single plant of 1145 was (piite so late as that, ami tin- average &lt; 1 ;i t *- of lower iiiff for tin- familv was onl\ I little oxer ":! days. Fainilits 1149 and 1131 and the lattcrs daplieate 1147. aa the ather hand, were fmin F, plants that MaaaaaMd in 1i»1" ahaa&lt; W days after planting:, and their BfWMHJi dati* of bkMMmminf! in 1911 was al dara from piantini: </seg>
            <seg id="p103">families and now of the F "s had mi id the Miamnri deal plants of 1!MI is w hiti i! &gt;'&lt;l thai tlic original ■iii.nixrs nf rciiniii. iii;il strains whi&lt;*h tollinated and whea it is lentiag tin- two parent varieties were lie plaatfl used M parents of the i varieties were beterosjgoua for Hi r various other characters is indi&lt; in- of tin- lots "i-own in 1911 m roaaiderabh Km other. It is |..issilili&gt; that tin- sinjrh- gaasete from .[••ni. rtliirli by union with a gamete from Tom Thumb unity 310 and to all the F families, la few lorn; i ontinned growth that wen rents of tin- lots used later to represent Missouri Jit further 1m- sappostd that the I'.tin represent* lent were farced into abnormally earty bli ■ I try weather of that suiiiiner. It would then still r» - i \|']aincil why the weather of ltli in Nebraska ■ I make Missouri deni |ilants unusuallv earl\ and at the many of the later F. ptaatl to In- nnusiialh Mil before. Or perhaps ii will he as m-ie«aary p whj the weather of 1911 in M;issai-liusetts &lt;!&lt;■' Missouri dent and at the same time has' of the later F families. Rn this loiiiiei'tioti it should not be forgotten that ton I . ire, |&gt;artieularlv if associated with extreme drvneaa, d the development of plants not adapted to such eon bile hasteaiag the akvclosaseal of other sm-ts of plants. l.i nut know that diverse surfs of corn actually respond in '\a\s to unusual conditions, bat the possibility is a Is it possible that an early corn like Tom Than idapted to growth in the North, may develop &lt;|iiite i Icratc temperatures as at higher ones. /'. c. the optimum temperature for it is low. while a late variety, which illy In- matured in the South. nia\ be ijreatly retarded in ■ I'mint 1 1 \ anrthiaf short of high temperature* '.' And -^ . I&lt;1«- also that this issumed adaptation to growth at ivliat low t&lt;-m|K'ratuies might be inhei-ited independently of \on for eailiinss. so thai I" segregates mi«rht qaite ciifferentty in parliaesa in ditferent seasons? The n Id not lie .1 without referriag back to the ilx r&gt;f height of plant of these wtnie lots of corn i Table we meet the gnggestire farts, prat, that the 1911 Missouri familie* wen i tall as the I *H «» ptesjti from which Inn! inmh longer to complete their </seg>
            <seg id="p104">ami. *«&lt;&lt;.«./. ill. i! ii-iiiiin nf iIm- 191 1 F families taller t Icm their I'Mn f pareata, Hm i I i &lt; ■ \ reqaired less time niplete their growth. It would Mem Thar sometime*, at least, the conditions that hasten develofMMpI arc favorable to a luge i growth while ilii- conditions that pralaag growth undulv unfavorable in HI f Ml height growth. Since the nil ainl her iiMditionw l«&gt; •'hica the Miaaowi dent an&lt;l I' plaits subjected in I'M 'i wiie practical h the mum* for- Ixith lot* .iikI since the same was line tor i lie Missouri dent and I lies in l'.lll. 1 1 ■&lt; - Inarkedh different liehav ior of llie two luts iii the fi - «;is dne oli\ioiisl\ to an inhereiu difference 'Wo lots lit |&gt;l;i It I &gt; a ilitVereliee in the W a \ thev ll«le&lt;l In like env iroliniellls Whether I li is ililletvnee lna\ U'eii as i matter of different optimum t»'lll|Miatliref&gt; DM 1 the two lilts. Or whelher the more neaflv iiilli •josis ill .f the other lots inav !. I t is i thai Missouri dent in;n have hail shorter stalks in 1911 than in 1910. nutwit r i-onditionH latter si ason. Umm ater in 1911 ih.m i I the The l'.tll I Ii.mI ki iilks than their I'M 1 ' r i«Hl( in 1 * • I 1 . 1 1 eertainlv i oiihl inn o) In' I tut « I. llie holler ItHlditiollH nl 1910. unless iw them is Io\m r I linn fur v I\ 'hili- there are. then, numerous il I ;ilanal ion • -;i n In i:lil out in this siu.h o| ih&lt; iuherilan&lt; &gt;ih. they shouhl noi be perwitted in i4i * lhal a iross ol . •I \ |iriMlineil an F i;iim r;i ! ii &gt;i ■ inli |iarenls in eariiw .' ner.M imiv with from lhe earl\ |.areni t«. or nearlv to. tin Ieiierations with diverse seasons »l hlotuMMiiin^. I'rom Talile I em be wem thai the laiesi I family ItlimMomed on itn I little OVCV three weeks laler than iIm Iv and that the earliest three I" lamiliis rere all Inn out of ■r beffare the latest three begMn I'losscmin^. The iraprex slim i iliit'eieiiee in earliiiess made 1 • v the plains in the fielil even more vivid than thai made I . \ i In tgnrea in lhe table |iho'o^r.i|ili ri |iroilin ed in this |ia|&gt;er &gt; lii'iin '*l | i^ims &gt; alioll of the ililVerem-i's as ll|e\ :l | .| h-;i I ■ i| in the ' Tin re is one olher leal llie ol III </seg>
            <seg id="p105">ii ill &gt;n&lt;:h protOjiynous as seeu from Table 39. i In- freo,uein\ (lisiril)iition of (lavs to tirst exposure of • pf |»i-oio&lt;;\ nous families is show n iii italics ini aw rhe freqaMMM &lt;listril»uiions for days to first &lt;&gt;f pollen for die same families. Of Tom Thumb pop ilv I rjti i . the plains showed their silks from one to eijfht F families of Tom Thumb ■ Missouri dent as they ap - -it in ihr li.-M Julj L'ti 1911. Note differenre in earlineM. i arlier ami mi the average four ila\s earlier than the lirxi ~he«lilin^ of pollen. The Missouri ilent used was evidenth nwyumM for ihis condition, sim-e one 1011 lot i family 1129) l'ioiaii&lt;liipiis t Ii i in mi t while ilie other lot i family 11M and li:|ilic:ite 11l&gt;i was proton nous tliiiiout. all but thrw pla&gt;ii^ "t i|u Limit having hail tlieir silks liisl &lt;\pose&lt;l from one !■&gt; six ilavs and on Hie arc I age just three da\s before any </seg>
            <seg id="p106">Minil\ ."111 i wen- "l&gt; - orda were mkmIi- "(' tluit fnmih 1 L32) raatained * M thii fa mi I plants amtj twelve proi CM the l;i ■ to M tl ili.ui iIh- pollen II M-ll (ll \ ■ &lt;»f ll tin- tin .1111] in ll' ■M know n In iiv | In .1!- hearii i - .in iml mli! |il:n- ■ proto icter :iinl make tin- st;m IVn :ittfin|ii baa Imi-ii iiuiiIi OfJM} mt |irul;inili\ .is ill I'm ilu\ ik mere H listilhiic ■ Bd siiiiniiiiit*- tl" |H-nii&lt;miiiit! physiolofncal of the t\\- ■ roiw klerable ntrnge i - Hiw .ill ajradaiini - iv « ith slight pmtendn or pi .mliil loiiilit inn. It is mIsii lil,il\ iIiiii ill. n Ixnvciii Ihr li: ml thai </seg>
            <seg id="p107">Hint • 1H II 71 T \IU I .!!• / hi I'liintili /»&lt;//&gt; 1 "l:t-n -t-iifi r? i r 77 mi , ■ 77 II I ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p108">it an\ ver\ early with an.\ very late variei Ixitli df which m protandroiis. iniisi result always in F, ptaat -i rough protogynow than anv now known and also his more deeidedh protandrow ihnn any known. S1ONS. . as stated in the introtluction, is to e inheritance of quantitative ekndai iml t&lt;&gt; preseni data bearing upon this subject secured from ex - - with maize. The results of these experiments, given in earlier in this pu|&gt;er. are here summarized. I The inheritance of number of rows jter ear has ban studied different crosses. The parent varieties were of S rowed owed. lC-rowcd, and l'm rowed tyjtes. In nearly every rase F! i iatermediate bttwata the parents, tho in case of one cross of 8 rowed variety with an apparently 12 rowed variety, the latter m ned to be dominant. In most eases the F, genera - - had a wider range of variation than F,. a range that ■ led Uith parent types. Differences l&gt;etween the F, families re belie red to have been due to hetcrozygosis of ■ i her of the parent varieties. Where F, families were 'i. the pareni types were recovered in every ease and inter re als.i seen. In one ease a series of ¥ lots roaa, showed modal conditions of 1J, 14. lti. 18, ■ nit I'll rows. Inheritance of length of ears was studied in three crosses of ties. In each ease the ear length of one parent two and one-half times that of the other parent. OM of Tom Thumb with Black Mexican, the F, ear length diate l»etween the parental ear lengths. In 1 1- i dent with California pop. on the other hand. _ ■neration had ears practically as long as those of the d parent, luit here the extreme length of the F, ears was doubtless in part due to heterozygosis. for the means of the F, - uere distinctly intermediate Itetween the parental means. In every case the P fraternities were more variable than the F, In most cases tlie F ,'s completely bridged the gap between the parents and in one case the F. range of variation was from practically the shortest ears of the short eared parent to beyond the longest ears of the long-eared parent. The short-eared parent !ias not as yet lv*en recovered in any F- lot and in only a few milieu has the ear length been equal to that of the lonjf I parent. In case of eaeh cross, however the ears of some </seg>
            <seg id="p109">104 ENui- was this difference in size I h&gt;- &lt; &gt; 1 1 1 &gt; feature d Hint: the kwhI F families. Tin- \arialiilitv of ■ e V m gimfai iliiin that df tin- aamti or of I' , while other I n|ualed in variability tli&lt;- !•' peiM*r»ttion. tl nlicrit.iiKc nf diameter of cars was invititigated in two H in nf F, mt intermediate in diameter between «• af tlu- parents. Inn somewhat nearer the larfw-eared than small eared y alien. The K. raaajM &lt;&gt;f \ ;i i-i;lt inn little more i tilled tin- gap Im-iwim-u tin- parent races The parent e not .1 in I' . Inn the several P ini* wrii- \.i 1. The sinal .if the I red I' families :er than tin- lai lie smallest eared family. I determined iinlx fur ilu- . r ■ Mill Itlai k \|e\iiali. The seeds taken t" re|iresent tin •r variety wen* |nnlialil\ t&lt;*&lt; '\\iiii: tn |ireviuiis mil rains. If allowance is made for this, the I" seed weigh) a little Iwlow ii -.il weight and the rang) iition of the I I o\erla|i|M-d tin range* "t the u t — Tho distinct tTp d weight were isolated tier |iareni i \ ; f.-i mil v . how . ed weigh! mvr!&gt; equal •■ thai of Black Mexiran t \ariiiliilit \ m indicated h&lt; I to elialile till' iw&gt;l)ltiotl of the 1 1:1 rill I type* •lion. ■Breadth "I Beedi vaa noted in tin ifoinia pop and with Tom Thnmli In waa distinctly intermediate between the Tin- variability of the 1' i"t- »;i&gt; not noti&lt; than that of the parents T 1 leration. on the showed a markedly greater varialiilitx tlian F i»r iIh I n one cross i lie roinliinnl rjui^e of rar lier was not sufficient to overlay) even the inner e\ the parents. Inn in tt ther cross, while the I' rai ■ r. the parents differed It - &gt; that pr all the classes from In-Iow the mean of the sm.ill seeded pan I altove the mean of the la r«re seeded parent were &lt; &gt;. &lt; -n i &gt; iniliy iilnals Two of tile 1' lots of the latter cross, im-owii sma II settled V \ui\\\ iduals. hail seeds practically of the small sei-ded parent. Since the total nuinlier i plain iffhtl.V " v&lt; "'' :&gt;&gt; ' MI in eaeli hoiiL'ht nii dent and Tom Tlmnilt pop prohahlf differed I ■ \ not over five factors and Missouri dent ami &lt; 'alifnrnia pop liy arrhaf many as six factors influencing lireadth of snl« Four different crosses xvere cMiplovi-d in the studies of tin inheritance of height of plants. A peraliarit&gt; of these .nwnpn </seg>
            <seg id="p110">i.hiiutiitatir, Vhmructera in Vmige 106 i in three &lt; &gt; t them the F. plants were almost M tall as the lall : mi in the fourth we considerably taller than the iiu'iin of the two parents. That this increase in height of F, ■ nuil |i.-i rt'iitii I height is in no case ascribable to i' &lt;it la lines* over shortness, but is due rather to in - ompanyiBg beterosygosis, is indicated by the the mean height of the F, plants is about the height! of the parents and is also shown g in the F. frequency distributions. I of the F fraternities overlapped in height the their parents. Most of them had a ratiL tin ':ui height of one parent to the mean height of parent anil in &lt;me cross the F., range was from the i lie short parent to the plus extreme of the i The F families were very diverse in height and in I » r families were as tall as the tall parent and - quiti -~'i abort as the short |&gt;areut. tho the tatter was ly in a few cases. In ease of some of the inability was sufficient to make it probable - like the parents could be isolated in the next gcattl Moreover, certain F families witli heights variously inter 'lie parents had variabilities small enough to nf their breeding true to these brig In », the height of plants w number of nodes and internode length i lie I' families were strictly intermediate In parent varieties imd the mean numlM-r of nodes in I • all\ thi ; n F . both of which facts ind her of nodes is not appreciably affecied by hctero/.ygosiii. all ilie other iptantitative characters studietl. thi* F gem ra ■ I a wide range of variation and the several F, reTJ diffen-nt mean niiiiiU'rs of nodes, including ■ liing those of the jiarents and also various inter- A -mdv of internode lengths explains the excess in height - '\cr the average of the parent heights. Tho number of nodes in F is apparentlv alwavs distinctly intermediate be - tween i he parent nuniliers. the internode length is so greatly increased by heterrorrjprtnin that F plants are often nearly as tall as the tall parent, and always taller than the average of the i heights the former when the tall and short parents differ little and the latter when they differ much in number of nodes. In the two crosses in which internode length was calculated, the F plants Icid internodes longer than those of the long-internode parent In Tom Thumb Missouri dent, in fact, the latter 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">106 that of the other parent \arietv aai of the !' general of the F, families of tliis rr«M had a Mage of \ a rial ion i from considerably below the minus otHM of iln- short intirimd&gt; parent I nrli almve the plus lltllt of the long i n i &gt; : parent ami rim innaidi uhlj akove the plus ntitM of I' eme range in F is thought to !»«■ &amp;m to aew romWnatk) tin- intcruodc I &lt; - ii ll 1 1 1 factors of the two parmts. in two croaM'B. one parent of which prodaoed numerous • tin- other few tiller*. I' was intermediate in number o! stalks [thint. In Imtli mMMi I" m n- variable than !•' ami m CTOM* the I rani; DM one to eight stalks, wh'l. I In- largest iiiiiiiIm'I' i in tin- parent \ ; t i - -«-• I nios! fi-f.'l\ \ni..iiu ill. I' t lu&gt; :i few were |&gt;r i&gt;|m-s ami a I m had a somewhat I i iiiiiiiIm-I' ot stalks ihan the lillii-in- parent ami a it ic in .is tn - iiilitx of isol.it ii&gt;_ tion a i \ |m- with a still larger number of stalks Ob aiiounl of i hi (ait that in one cross the tall parent a few sialkeil type ami the shuti |&gt;aretit a mam sta Ikeil tTpe, Tin i »o |iar»'iit \ ariet ie&gt;. i|id not differ (treat 1,1 in total length of stalks |M-r plant. (Nrtag to ihe mici nucli.i n nnniher of stalks in I In the tailings of I" slalks in this iioss tin- total leliifth was niiiih greater than that of either parent in fail a ii|iial to the eiiniliiiieil &gt;talk lenyllis of tin- parentf). I total length &lt;&gt;f stalks of ' liilitv was lonsiileraltlv greater. In Mother ihe pan-ills differed nnirli more in total leiiirth • Is of il i-ration are availalile. lint the m «talk leny:ih in I' iwhieh was ilmilii than in I ■Maewhat than that of either pan-ni. OwinjJ ;q lack of eorrelation either ph.v sioli&gt;&lt;;ieal or L'en. ti iiiii Im-t- of stalks and height of plnnt. some of the I I this I 1 row had a mean total length of stalk twii it at the loiitr Ktalkul parent and one V familv had ;i mean k paaaw Ihan the pins extreme of thai parent This Rival stalk ■ li is tlionnlii to he due in the main to a mmbinatioa of th« • rn inrtneni in^ total stalk length, some of which come from one parent and si from the other. In earliiu-Ks 1"\ plants were intermediate between their parents. The F™ generation more than tilled in the gap hatwvca the pan-nts in all cases where exact reiords were made and in one pane had a range from below the mean of the early parent to aUtve the mean of the late parent. Yer\ distinct t \ pes wen obtained in 1* some of which were nracticallv as carlv in flower </seg>
            <seg id="p112">. I.,,, none ..f which mn frite » late as nt. In general tin- siinu- relative order ww maintained in ripening ;is in lowering. BaagMj tin- number of from planting to towering was &lt;&gt;" per enrt af tin- number of r !•• mi planting to ripening. Tin- relative taagtka af tlu- two • l&lt;-| &gt;&lt;-Ii&lt; I sol new hat H|mi|i the season ilt which 'In- iv|m' in qaeatioa nature*. In llien. it max lie s;ii&lt;l that the results means' in is witli maize were what might well be expected if i-nces were "hie to numerous factors inherited O'-ndelian manner. It is qaite likely, as pointed out itedh in ilie detailed discussion af results, that aaBStk ijticins (1,-iur hetweea Barton for distinct quantitative char i in &gt;e and the phyaioloftieal con-elations so frafaeatl.i i make the results more diflieult of interpretation, but do imi ilmiw them out of the realm of Mendelian phenomena. I'lusinlojiieal &lt;(.irelation is a phemniienon of development, not ■ if inheritance, and. as such, has less interest for students of _:eiiet irs than for experimental niorpholoirists. Kven in practical plain Itreediui:. ■ nn-elations af this sort are of im|M)rtance mainlv • in arrouDi of the physiological or morphological limits that the\ M'i tu ihr perleci de\ elopment of jiarticular oonihinations of ■haraclers. I»4;i! genetic i-orrelations in the sense of gametic associations. ,ii-.- not .1 1 1 1 ;i^&lt; in is I ic to the Meudeliaii doctrine. True, the funda i i nial principle of Mendelism is segregation of separate factors ..nd ii might therefore. l&gt;e held wiih soiii"' degree of p]ausibilit\ uaimtii roapHnft of factors is nonMi-ndelian. I'ut where 'he .iss.ii iati-d faiiors segregate regularlv from other factors r other groapa of factors, thev can cortainlv l&gt;e said to Mendelize tln'\ mereh Meudalize together. Such correlations an these have ilisiiuct importance in genetics. Numerous apparent correlations, genetic as well as plivsio - al. have lieen encountere&lt;l in these ex)&gt;criments and manv nf them have 1m en Bated imiilentallv in the detailed discussions of resu'ts. \\Y ha\i' reason to believe, for instance, that length nt ear is direct l\ correlated with height of plant and inversely • irrelated \\ i 1 1 • amaber of rows per ear. Number of rows seems :ilso to 1m- related in some way to the diameter of the endo- Mperin. since in some prosat'B aeftregatm with a large number of inws have dent grains while those with few rows have flinty grains. It is apparent also that, while height of plant and tiuinlwr of stalks per plant may not lie directly related, number i.f stalks and diameter of stalks are negatively correlated. Onr • Is indicate that then- is little if any correlation, either </seg>
            <seg id="p113">108 ihmIc length. Tin -&lt;&gt; little of im physiological correlation Imiwi-cii duration &lt;&gt;! prowl ■ ami ininilier of mules, bat ;i|ip:ir eflth ■ (!i&lt;tii i relation between these two charm In 1911. which from previous --« • Hi n v were &gt;p ■ hint: :i eoadition &lt;&gt;' ho ami h show ■ 'relation t&gt;. ■amber th. while I" families. fur hull', ii and tor deration of of iiiiiiiIi ii iniiiht have ■ IWth of the . smiiiuer. by in - futiiro. ITIie in ten . rirruiiit' . of tm e without h.n itiniiv ii ph\ - toffri iniiMiKsililc ti- tell in ;i |i;irt ienhir i ;is&lt;- « Ii imi fiictops iirc rooftled in inheritance or whether &lt;&gt;r i»lnv8 a |'sirt in the fcrtlopwrnt of wh.-it ire rr(piriV iiiet i-liiii In thi' liitii iin):i tally «inr of the |ih\siolo'j;\ of develop than of ,tie*. &lt;'ert;iin &lt;|uantit;uivr- prtatkMM in maize ilhistmtc thr infln of a single faetor in the ile\i-lo|iinent of two or more ohnr - mil M the inrtncmi' of wwral f the dcvelop - nieni of a sinjile character. It is ohvion* that any factor that nffWis sav intertiode length will also have an influence upon </seg>
            <seg id="p114">Tin I i'Ic i itiinrf nf ijiniiilit'iliri I liiiruihi.i in \lui;t' 1&lt;)9 K and therefor*, in addition, upon stalk weight mil even upon to _ i of plant. Likewise miv factor - liiriic iim mi. \ with an effect ujm&gt;ii aniount of • ■r tin- diameter of stalk, size of mlhbIii of u ill all Im' iiinifi-iii-d in flu- development of the one char ■ !.il weight of |&gt;lant. If one argue thai total in pie character, he must also admit that neither italk, which of come is determined by the number the mieiiiiMle length, and must not forget thai evm he length of one interoode is the protect of the number and In' cells contained in it. Tho total weight can thus d nt&lt;&gt; numerous sub-characters, it is none the letw a • i-.-H lei ' of tin- plant or t\|K- in question. It wat shown earlier in this paper that the multiple factor nisfaiiorv and simple interpretation ■II i »r the results secured from these maize expert tients lint also ot the results from ex(&gt;erimciits |&gt;reviousl\ re urted for oilier plants and for animals. We are familiar with thesis not baaed upon the Mendellan principle of ngrc ii .iih! reconil&gt;iiiai ; on of factors which furnishes a plausible nation of main of the fads re-rardinj: the inheritance of liiaiu itat i\ c iliarai -ters. W« arc aware of the MfJBJHrtkM .■ 1912) thai a hgtctogtacaas distrilmtion of growth in lucii ore* in the cells of an organism would result in iiiliM in its pro«;env. that this heterogeneity of the proto would lie iiici-eased bv crossing, and that, therefore, the h would bt increased in generations Ix'.vond F,. Tliis tit cannot, however. l&gt;e said to interjiret satisfactorily ■ /.c inheritance, until it is shown, for instance, how .nit ol a size intermediate hetweea the parent var ■ ■ :in F progen\ nf great rariabilitv while another of the same intermediate size yields an V prof nore variable than the parent! or the F generation. In ither words, ii must tirst be sbowi how some F. plants pi i&gt; have the si/i .,( I" plants and at the same time have the ohiparativeh hoiiiogenc'on* disirihutiou of growtk inducing Bah tain -es rharacterintir nf the parent races while other F. plants re like F plants in both size and heterogeneity of these 8UD - t.mccs. And even if inci-cascd protoplasmic heterogeneity of ienernl growth- inducitr.: mihutanoes &lt;an l»e made to account for he increased varialti'ii \ ordinaril\ observed in V ,. it is still not juite dear just how such a condition can bring alMiut an F ■ange of variation a«a\ lieyond the aster extremes of the laretits in resjiect to cine size character, while the range of ariation of some other size character of the same F individuals iicclv enongh to bridge the nap httwcm the inner exti </seg>
            <seg id="p115">110 BREEDING I Tin* i &gt;i-i u«-i i •-! I iim' of hybridisation in plant breeding urv m coiiiliiiiiiiions n! ihr rhUMtcn present in i h&lt; s t&lt;&gt; roiiiliiiir in Hue nee ffce desirable characters of tlu - ■ent mm ;m&lt;l to rliminati- ih&lt;- iin&lt;li-siralili- characters. In hb a idiidition iajtermediate bttweea tin- parentl with rv it t&lt;&gt; ■ ii -rtain rharai tir BUM U- ileiiired. of valtw for lirin^iii^: oat characters that were latent in fln - inis. i Int. siiiif snih |ius&gt;iliil ii iis : t it- uMiallv onforeaeen, thin aekktm the main oliji Tin incrcai lipiil '" i in' in plant lirei from the pn Tin- iih-i IkhI simple - well km All that is — — f In- hoim W Inn tliis ban i» • to |»ro|i I I ll Illl II|M)II « li:l! fai'tlll ■ l|l!iil&gt; t lit- ■■iimltiiia i Itine in one variety i»f ray ■ Tin and ;i ■■&lt;■ auriilcK fioni 1 1n- ba«e i»f tl •ill in iiilun lliis ii. h of tin xweet i ui ii i • inilil l«' ilisii^aTili'il or ai'tern v\ i tv linn ihe i w ri inirance thai ahMrt m uoiilil he DHiiiocvfmi* for l«»ili &lt; &gt;r Im-i i . i ulv Nfjarj grains need be planted, \\iili I iliai iill the pi-ol'iiiv will Im' - law «ill have erect, noo-anricnlati Tin- procedare rkn dealinE with i diaVm in mi « a v fioni thai mil limil fai-iois arc conccrnril. more individuals must he frown in ilsr the I" ami |ierhaps pven the I", (fewration mm iimI far the aV 1 aired rnniiiinaiioii \&gt; ;i nutter of fart the nioic aiaiple qwilitati rareh ever no ■ liamlli'il in actual | • t " : i &gt; 1 1 • iiiil 1 1 \ the example </seg>
            <seg id="p116">'iot usually w ;i ii t merely tn combine on*- desirable character iiti \ariet\ with one other eqwillj draiiaMe charact. 'v. Ih' |MTha|ps lias a variety that for certain VMM 1 1 lint it larks conspicuously sunn' inic or two very ible character* iliai he sees in mm other vnriet.v. He p his variety as it is but transfer liodilv to it the iiararitT from the other variety. Very likely this aeeond .diode in numerous respects As I matt' \arieiies. insteatl of dirt'erin;: l&gt;\ merely tliis one ikiii character, netnalh differ in very many characters. Mi:, therefore, the imich desired character to the 1 1 variety, one is a|&gt;t ta lose some of the highly I ■ liaiacii is of the latter, unless wr\ Hrgc liiimlx'rs are in F or selection practiced for two or three more genera- I nly difference in manipttlation between i|iiantitative litative characters is. the*, one of decree. And in breeding even this distinct ion is of little imjM)rtance. :, ill\ e\er\ cross Itetween ciiniinereial varieties must \ 1 11 ■ I in )•■ both qnalitHtive and ipiaiititative rhari jji iiiiniber of factors by which distinct commercial of crofi plants are differentiated is almost utapjferinjf. n illiisiration an extremely sini|&gt;le case We will smji. i- thai it i^ desired to prodnee a ltetter silage corn than that rijeil 1 1 \ the tall few --stalked dent varieties of the West and ill in i&lt;\ Ktalked lint vai-ieties of the Northeast hint a iv ;ie ill coin cnmliininfr the tallness of one variety with kid condition of the other. For sake of simplicity. iNinl difference* in season of ripening and various - uhich. as a matter of fact, could not ordinar\[y ■ I in acinal practice. We will assume that the - ins differ by ti\e Mendelian factors inftnencinjr i and li\ live factors RffertiBg imiiiiImt of stalks per 1 ■ .1. Ii uf these factors is indi'i&gt;cndent of the others lieiitaiicc assumptions which, tho the\ may not represent rateh the actual facts, are at least not unreasonable and rate •erre for purpose of illustration. From a crow i»f ihesc varieties, an F of onl\ altnut 1JMW plants, or say one - tenth acre, would be required to irivc an even chance of recovering .1 mam stalked typ* like the one pavent or a tall stalked tjwt I thir parent. Per hap* three or four Ham tlint many should lie to Ue at all sure of recoveriii}: the parent Rut with this number of individual* there could he no thai anv of the very tall plants would also have very many </seg>
            <seg id="p117">112 ■ iiMinw'ittiiMiiHi" tinjiil)&lt;*nt i in other word* over one hundred huts. would Im- re ■juired fc»r U even eliame of fret I in;: the desired eoiuhiiiat ion of character*, aai at least two ar thVK times thai numlx r should • &gt;wn to make sun- of results Now. while |Wiha|w breeding on sueh ■ Kale is no) iin|K&gt;Hsililt'. it is rertainlv out of the •antion under ordinary londitions. What method then mn Im - used in sueh pp the ]&gt;r&lt;i|»osed results impossible of ;i&lt; -i o|ii|i|islllll&lt;Ilt " Inder th&lt; the method of back &lt;-roM - »itli oiu- |i II 1 1 . i a n not h* used, for, while rin*: ihf ultimate rwover the nian\ stalked parent . it wi&gt;iil&lt;l at the same time make impomihlp the nrmn aM stalked IV |M- of I lie other li.Uellt The onlv niethoi) in siieli liiHt* is i. 1 1_\ K pi - practi&lt; omliine mosi nearl\ the desired comliina Of height and iiuimIm-i- oi Hid from selfrd wed of I I' |'i rom wlii'li in turn forth nous In- made and »■■ "ii fi her of plant* im! M rmim ; H ■ tiiii«'. It iii.h not Im- out of place here i. show more d&lt; • he element of I -in. . ,ni In in mdvinjf a &lt; [ &gt;i&lt; &gt;1 • Ii-im In of simplieitx. let iis now assume that the |&gt;ai niil\ four fartors for heighi and !■• in all. thus ii-&lt;|ui&gt; chanee of freltiiii; the lioiwd P trim -talks. l!\ rpferrtBK lia&lt; k to Table 1 at .i lilanee what U-ha\ ior «ill result l&gt;oth in F and m I' follow ■ loss i he jMireiitx of which differ in ft mi f:»« - torx /' I If the elass headings are read as aVrii ill r*pi well arlual heights of &gt;hotl atxl tall ram |il;!iil&gt; Ku or will then Im- assumed to add two d&lt; to tin- initial I of 1" deeimelels. If now we .all th. '. /»' and sii|i|iok&lt;- eaih to add one &gt;ialk to an inn ditioti. the same table will serve to illusirate the iuheritan iiiiiiiIm-i- of stalks per i&lt;lant where the pamita Iked and 9-Htalked res|.eet i\( l\ . Vow from the rrOM of a 1 Stalked. ■ i ter type with a !• stalked. 1" -«!••• -imeier type, we v.i from 1 that, out of 'J.'iti I itidix iiluals. one shoiilil have the formula I I /&gt;'/{' (I &gt;l &gt; and also lhat one should have the formula I' \'li'lf( -c'h'h' In other words, there ■fconld be o,, 4 •!■ ♦ t* i 1 • 1 1 t «»i»1 ■ 1 hid ■» i ' 1 i 1 L I tl« t I • t tl •►** 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">ked plain would noi be M decimeters tall, unless about -i. 'ail &lt;&gt;f •_'."&gt;•&gt;. were grown. To be sure of ked |ilant. lei us pw f&lt;»ur times the number sited in Table 1. or approximately l^ttf F. plants. Since • nt nf all the 1' plants nc from Hi to 20 decimeters ire iliat tin- one it-stalked plant will be from IK ■ lall if taller so mui-h the better. T^et us sup I.-, imeteis tail like the P, |ilauts. &lt; Mi wlfing tliis one !t stalked. 1 &gt; &lt;ltyiniet« i- |ilant. what will be We 'an Im' sure that the progeny will all be of ked type. Table 1 shows that out of the 70 IS decimeter ■up III i will breed true. IS (grOTf) XI I will have roan 1 4 to _"_' decimeters, and 16 (group XV) will have _ i on, in to l'i; decimeters. If then the 9 stalked F, lielonged in group XV for height, we would have an even Bee oi getting one it-stalked. 26-deciraeter plant by growing _'."pt. I' individuals and would lie fairly sure of "retting it by ■mo |' plants. In short, we would accomplish with i I' :uid 1' plants what we would have had only an even troniplmhing with 85.MN V t plants or what would reqaired perhapa 250.000 F, jilants to make its accomplish t fairl\ sure. If. however, as is much more likely, the ilked. I s decimeter !•' plant l&gt;elon«red in group XI in height. geny, while breeding t i-ii»- to the !t stalked condition. . I 1 1 . — &lt; fl-oiu 14 to •_'•_' decimeters. Since all the duals of grovp XI are heterozygous in onl\ two factors, an '&lt;&gt; plants would afford an even chance and M — make fairlv sure of &lt;jeiting one 9 stalked. 2"J-decinieter Bill : ■ all the F. individuals of group XT lack ■ t i he four height factors, tin- one 22-decimeter F plant Im- honinsvyova for three factor* and lack the fourth, like plants o) yi-oup IV. and will, therefore, breed true to this i There will then l&gt;e no pomiMlitT of producing a 20-deci .l;redl\ any more than from an F, 18-de«*i - plani bekM|(ing to |troap III. which would of course breed to thai height. Crossing between different F types must '■• reported to. We have naaamed that a Mstalked. 2Hdecimeter plant has iK-en pri'duced as desciilM-d alnive b\ selection from 1.000 F : and "mi 1" plants. From the same 1.00(1 F plants a 2li decimeter. ked plant could also have been selected and would of oiirse have bred true to the -•&gt; decimeter height. It would \&gt;\\ also have bied true lo the ."stalked condition i if be- n &lt;r lo "t'oiip III for number of stalks), or possiblv would </seg>
            <seg id="p119">114 l&gt; XV tar siiilk iiiiihIhti. in wliiili eaae the desired '-'•• ■talked type wmm M have heea wcared in I". Min 1 1 •« ' cluinrc is greater, M us nppaae that the It aecia i&gt;l;:ni iMitmjrril to 14 oaf) XI (&gt;&gt;v Damheff "f st;ilks Then !i\ growing 50 F plum* from it, «&gt;• iroald lie fairh tiiin nf p;« • 1 1 i 1 1 1: ;ir li-iisr ooe 28-decimeter, 7st;ilked plant a would breed trae in 1m &gt;i Ii Im-i^Iu and number i»f si.-iiks. Tin i iihvitnish his hiiniozv uiiii&gt; 26-dwiun i c ii I plant, &lt;&gt;r :m\ nt ny. with tin- 9-stalked jil.mi obtained froni r h«- other »plertMH with :tn\ nf The t w • &gt; F plant* wo«M «ar&lt; 1 ii- fitl-llllllil sili'i l;i|- !n I !■■ 1 1 1 i't; ill i i inn run \ • \ 11 ikiiii *l n lk.nl . I'l Hi: CC'D'D'. 1 1 ■ plant*, l :iii'l • •ii I % in tin F plai nfce inoic Mill i j - -&lt; « I ■•■ I'htni ih IhMIIII I III II LM'UU II I .INI plant! I"" I' - Ii « Ii;ii » i|&gt;s 1 1 : 1 \ • • i-i'&lt;|iiir&lt;-il .1 1 1 ii a I it wuilld h;i\. crowd the 9-stalked. &lt; il'H I • - 1- i ul uf li;i&gt; III till SJIIIIC \\ .! \ I tinii of • 1 1 1 .- 1 ■ 1 1 ii.ii I II i.lllv , IIIW1I ill I i iii anv i ii&lt; I i \ idnal. !'•&gt; titl&gt; illiiKt rated. In the detailed ;ni mini »f our &lt; • \ | •&lt; i been |iointed out thai illi n 1' (row F Ihis ( ii.it roatained no individn mi us the parents. Far Instance, in nertain plant! had aeeda ijnite like tho«r of i ■ ■ pareni nixen were pecori i- ■■ &gt;\ IV rhapa the nio»1 snikin. in mil- c\|m-immi ins i&gt;. thai i &gt;• While in -is tin parent height* wen • -« I in I" . in othef • rosse* the • 1 1 • ■ —. t rxtreme I' ln-i^liis laHunl mwh nf reaching tbe i - ii! i In |., n hi i r I I' phi </seg>
            <seg id="p120">very near the ininus estraae of iln- snmll .IT. lii actual practice. &gt;&gt;t' ronrae. one must we larger numbers w paragraphs hack, to 1»' snlti&lt;-i»-nt ; - &lt; tin | &gt;t ion. it w;is shown that L,0M I* ami IjtM ■mmi in all would Im- as likely t&lt;&gt; fire the desired b abool •J.'iii.immi I' plants, while following another as that I.immi F . inu F ., and ."&gt;&lt;• 1", )»lants l.lSfl in all would In- required to MtM the same result. one heae tw&lt; can were that the F plants differed not in size lint merely in zymotic formulae. however, there is m way of distiagaiakiig n eral I' plants all hekmgiag to the mum hul haxinj: iliffereni ivgotic formulae, as mam V indi - - have to In- grows from the F plant that is n onlv i«o factms as from the one that is Inttr ii lour faitois. Fiirihri-niori- .iml ivcii moi thin ii i annot In- known whether two plants of the i:il|\ In-Ioiiu: in tlie same size class. Not onh max f in the same size elass have differi-nt RTgotk iilae. Inn those i hat belong in wry different classes may be • I together and made to appear to heiof; in the same i:il)lc couditioiM surroiindin« one and tin - niidi!ions rormnndinn asother, or than not only i-Ihm Imii having identical zy&lt;;otic form - iilat-|\ he made to ap|N-ar in different i nf i-oiifiisioii of this sort arising ilnii "LM)i&gt;h at si^lil iN'twcrn genetic variations ■Hoiiiueiid in our pxperim for Hhisiraiion. Of a!! the F families I'.ililc ::ti i . \h. 11 If, had the laiirisi nnmlN-r of stalks - mean In-iii^ l.l'l sialks. Imt its I" parent had only than the mean of the F . family (51©1 to which 'ainih 1111). on the other hand, had a mean 2.04 notwithstanding that its 1' pai-ent stalks above tie I. mean. Oae of these I' plants Men toici (I Ih-Iow and the other al&gt;ove its true class. In jilani ■ Tulile i'!ti. family 114f exreeded family lilt! by J..I7 deeimeters. their respective mean heights being 2.". 14 and _'■_'. 77 ileeimetcrs. tho the F parents of 1140 belonged to the ■im! was fthonl four decimeters taller than the ireni of 1146. If one had heel selecting a single 1' jdanf for both ■' Us. the I': 1 , decimeter. I stalked i of Mi .l&lt; m in ]&lt; : — have I n chosen in prefrreaet .. 111*1 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">116 of 114(5 w - decimeters — a linost tvie it. Evideath in actual jd-in-tic-f one must select ;i iiimmImm- of pWiraii stund ■ t:»ir chance of gettiag ;m F, type to hN I There is very little dinittt tliiii tli&lt;- striking recall* ■et-ared in tin- well known lelertioa erperimeati with corn carried mn Ml Kxperimcnt St;iti&lt;m iSmirli 1MB) :ire to he ex l&gt;l:iiii&lt;il nil the s.ii:h- linsis aa that aied in this dtHCUMion tn - aov types ean bi ' h\ the proper nap of inuri! aumben ■ &gt;f plants in I r later 1 mis tvjx&gt;s th;it coulil :n.i U' n peril nambeni lmuwii. If oil jiiicI protein contest in can are iaheritoi in the sniiie way tli;it other qoantitative character* are, we shouM not i tintl rerj I* "il or protein conteal in iin\ KMi ar - (|1 ben ;ii Rindoni fnrni ;i lot of opea |»&gt;I •elected |&gt;i:iin&gt;. bm aica are mlntmi eertaiah thei are kimun tu Im- fin- uiIhi- id ;m inlernii nut Iiii' ft tn ■ ii i the mere ;i&lt;t of i haa |ii-iif(inn&lt;1l\ i liai iil mid protein &lt;*h;\i urn mil- in rail iato v that mntai rred repeatedly ilnrinp tin ruing that tl&gt; nun ti BBMller hi'i'jlii chai iinit;itiiiii in . uriiil u|i|M&gt;rtiiiii]v . Between th&lt; »hort-st:ilke&lt;i trpe in F f' I th&lt; - •ion nf ;i li'\\ or liiirli &lt;&gt;il t&gt;"pe trntn aa opi earn ffi} hetertwyattiin i ipparentl^ m ■ I (fiUVri'ini- A WimiI slnmli! Im&gt; s;iiil of the prau fliniiiy liara greater or leaa than the p pie i&gt;f this Front urn- awa exp ii i\]«' with ;i idtiil IciiL'tli nf *t;i!k* more th;in twice that &lt;&gt;f tht ■ r parent wi* sccomplidhefl Im tiiiiinj; the niitm Rtalked rooditioii of one pareal with the mil ■talked rondition &lt;&gt;f the ather aavcat. Visibly different \&lt; mnhined ta foria ;i Be* character oomidex The |.!'&gt;ilin linn of :i type «itli iateraodea niinh loader thaa thoa the iiiiiTiits (Table :!;! diaTera frnai the ahave mih in thai the Barest t\|«s were apparently rerj aiaiilar aad it nrmM imt he hmm thai the timilar internode ! the two varietiea '■nt factor* thai run 1 . hined into ■ new I . i i i I'll "1*1 " MM |'H \ It \ ( |, -j T </seg>
            <seg id="p122">Ei h the avowed object &lt;&gt;f securing conibinn ilikc the continuations responsible for the par i i In i&lt;lc;i is wi-ll worth keeping in min&lt;l. tin- o do with the development of the liave .ill ImhIi smtol out and tagged 11 proceed in their undcrtak iliaii at (resent. be said that a breeder dealing -icnild ptoeaeel just as hi- would if !i &lt;|iialitativi characters as eotor where the ■ it in numerous characters. The prin - ■■■&lt;ii tin- iwn rases are that ipiantitative !.. differ in more factor* than qualitative iiinmrntal influences cause more confusion, lie slants as his facilities rIIow. ■ iiMt numerous promising individuals. ml grow their progenies on as large a scale Bll ' \ of these I' lota are of the desired tv|K» he opnjrate them and discard the others, or if not - il smile of them and continue his selection -m;: mirs. Or if no K. family shows \&gt;\ its ndcnc\ to produce ultimately a type thniili! Im- liad lo intercfossin^ lnt lots OT Itetwcell their I' 1&lt;. with the hope i we Bight almost that il ty|Ms. tho the\ are similar in appearance. different sets i»f t:"tins to insure the mii in c). - When dealiBg uirli plants like I.: .ir in m h more vigorous when iiianx characters are iler will tind it necessar\ to practice n ditlereiit isolated tjpta or to |&gt;rovide for He should not. therefore, l&gt;e content with the le strain of fhe desired type WIJ ;i single tv|w Inn should isolate two or more such tv|ies. Iwith of prh in oil conieiit. liitl which differ l»y enough minor nxntitntive or i|iialitative. to insure a vigorous de - 'elupmeiii on crossing them or on ultowlag them to interorosB naiiii-allv when |l««l in mixtiii These methods appl\ jnsi as well to improvement by selection from the complex hybrid mixtures, which, becruise of some out standing fealnres. have been assigned varietal names, as the\ do to the isolation of ty|ies from the similar, tho perhaps somewhat complex, hvbrid mixtures resulting from tin* crossing of two named varieties. The dilleience at most is onlv a matter </seg>
            <seg id="p123">118 |HiIlili;l|cil plants will, if he |&gt;ersists long •■IKMiyli. BUi in | &gt;■-&lt; m] ii«-i 11^ ;i i\|m- with easagfe tartan far nil production hi rank ;i» ;i lii^h nil type and with th«-&gt;.' Facton nfldentl.t to insure comparative COM \hile .it tile HUH - time a sufficient tm n 1 1 M-r- of factor* for other miauf character* mparativeh rigUfOWM strain. lim i\illi the sanu- Milt of si-lc.tidii ral practically honu&gt;7.\ nous hi^h-nil Ht rains could al »urH\ lia\c Im^'ii |n mlnt-ed in nnn-li li-ss tiint- And thesi- sirain&gt; .1 donbtk ■ ■ i&lt;-nil\ unlike in tarton for minoi re aliiimlain vijfor of pfrowtB on croMiing tin n While a few \iai- !&gt;&lt;• an important icmsidiiatini; « lui-e ili. in Im- determined at si^'ht 01 In men in breeding work requiring 1 eliemi' \\ i 11 1 1 h &gt; t 1 .1 1 1 1 thai tin- ii&lt; Mill tlll'l i!e u. W. 1:.. n M Studies of inlieiilaiM PIK^ie I in»t..n. I'uli. 114: 1 7N llei-iditv in relation to evolution and anin j \-w York. A|i|il.ton. pp. 1 IM till. The inconstane\ of unit H » \ Sal 4* ins. K. M. The dixtinetiou lietween developnienl and lniidit\ inter Nat. 43: 17::isi. ifto-t. A Meiidclian interpretation of variation thai it apparent^ .-oiitiiiiioiis. Amer. N'at. 44: 65-82. 1910. The &lt;ienot\|M liv|Kithesis an&lt;) hvnridization. Amer. \ai 46:KWn74. Itll. i: M.. and II \m:s. II. K Inheritanee in Maiae. Hul 167 1 141 PI. 25. Itll. Ic.hn .{linn ill rh&lt; \U-.\u&gt;. Ann. R|t( 1'l.n-hl.i \ L - - 1911 *2 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">IiiIm' inl shapes in plants. A preliminary note Aiiht. \ai 44: T-'.M 7 M&gt;. 1910. Uiteni culms in com. Aim. Kpi. Anici- |{n-&lt;'dt»rn" .\mm 6 1911. 'ii'iniii iiii-i-i'laiioii Mud Bpnriom allelouiorphiam in inaizr. \iin. Itpi. Nebnwkai Aiii- Exp. Sta. 24: tin &lt;M). 1911a. Tin- hilKMiiaiicc of tin 1 lignlc .mil auricles of corn lr Ann. Kpi. \eln-iiska A-r. Rrp. Sta ■: 81-88. MS. II. K. irreliition ami inlu-i-itam r in V untimiii tiihuiuui. liul. 171:::-4.-,. PI. •". VM-2 lit \i:i I !\p. Sia l»if Krlilichkriisvrilialiiiissr del- Olii-t'iiliiiiuc dfi- Kanintlifii naili ( 'asilc mill das I'rnltlcin dw iatermediftm \*«"i***rt»n n^ iiikI r.ildiinii kniisiaiiii r Kasiardrasscn. Zciisilir f. in diiktivi- Alisiaimiiiin^s mid \fi-i'i-lMiiijp&lt;l«'hn' 4 : 1 "_':?. Itti. Vole sur rhrbridiition sans froif ■!!■&lt; mi fuMK lixbiida &gt;n. Mfiii. Bee. dis Sii. plivs. el nat. d&lt;" !»i«rdt:iu\ 4: \' '- S.-ii, . 1S!U SON KlII.E, II. mt von krcuzimjien Imm Ha!Vr und Wrizni Ki.ian. Nutisi-r lMt:357-2M. U Krcii/.iiii^siiiitci-siirliiiiii;* 1 !! an Safer mid WMWB. Lnnds I liiMi-siii'ts Ai-sskrifi. n. s. wer. -. \&gt;&gt;\. ."&gt;. no. "J. pp. 1 li'"-' IMW. l\icii/.iin&gt;;smi!('i-siiclimii:iii an Uafcr und \Veiz»'n II. T.iinds I iii\ii&gt;iii'ts Afsokrift. n. s. we. "_'. vul. 7 M ♦&gt;. pp. 1 H 1!»11 ll&gt;. .lull \ i '. Size iiiln-i-iiaih , in diK'ks. •lour. Kxp. Zool. 12:36'.' 1 !•!■_'. i I . li II 1 1\ liridi/.al iuii iikiIhhIs in ruin hnetfBff. Ainrr. IiI-immIits Mag. 1:98- in". 11*10. ■II. I. ul IK ||. Ti'ii j;inriat iuiis .&gt;! . urn Inii-dini; Mill. Illinois Agr. Exp. </seg>
            <seg id="p125">120 t1ukmi.-nn&lt;I v.im. t .-ii.l. r M.rkiii;i!. 1 all. Versu.hf pej.-h 19 52 - </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>