<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00047.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00047.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Biennial Report Board of Education Nebraska State Normal Schools</title>
               <date value="1921-01-21">1921-01-21</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT Board of Education Nebraska State Normal O f f rf^fe I £^% ocnoois To His Excellency SAMUEL R. McKELVIE Governor Compiled by H. E. Reische, Secretary LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, JANUARY 1, 1921. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">L/irxEA^ 1 v*Jr\ I Board of Education Nebraska State Normal Schools MEMBERS APPOINTED Dan Morris, Kearney Term expires 19J4 H. E. Reische, Chadron Term expires 1925 Frank Pilger, Pierce Term expires 1921 W. S. Heitzman. Osceola Term expires 1921 T. J. Majors. Peru Term expires 1323 MEMBERS EX-OFFICIO D. B. (Jropsey, State Treasurer Lincoln John M. Matzen. State Superintendent Lfncotn OFFICERS OF THE BOARD Dan Munis, President Frank Pilgi-r, Vice-President H. E. Reische, Secretary D. B. Cropsey, Treasurer STANDING COMMITTEES riting: Cropsey, Heitzman, Pilger Executive: Morris, Majors, Reische, Pilger Instruction : Majors, Reische, Heitzman Rules : Matzen. Majors, Cropsey SCHOOLS IN OPERATION KEARNEY, opened in ign? </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL His Excellency, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor of Nebraska. Sir :Complying with the law governing the Board of Education haviag control of the Nebraska State Normal Schools, we herewith transmit to you the biennial report and statement of expenditures made by this Board from December i, 1918, to December 1, 1920. All original vouchers are on file with the auditor of public accounts and duplicates are on file in the office of the Board of Education. Respectfully submitted, H. E. REISCHE. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 CREDITS The Auditor of Public Accounts has certified credits to the Normal School Fund as follows : 1918, includes all collections and unexpended balances $ 94.571-";? 1919, 1 mill levy .$ 567,645.41 1920, 1 mill levy 778,000.00 for biennium $1,345,645.41 appropriated 93% 1,251,450.23 $1,346,021.06 ESTIMATES The several budgets giving in detail all contemplated expenditures have been submitted through the Finance Department of the State. Total amount required by each school is as follows : Public Improvements 24,000.00 $1,447,899.00 Chadron $ 334,616.00 Kearney „... _ _ 367,288.00 Peru _ 373,500.00 Wayne _ 367,095.00 Board _ _ 5.40000 Total $1,447,890.00 CLASSIFICATION Salaries and Wages $ 961,286.00 Expense 55,229.00 Supplies 160,084.00 Material, Parts and Repairs for Upkeep 80,050.00 Fixed Charges, State Aid and Contributions 3,250.00 Lands and Buildings 120,500.00 Equipment 42,600.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">BIENNIAL REPORT 5 FINANCIAL STATEMENT NORMAL SCHOOL GENERAL FUND The statement includes expenditures by the Board of Education for all purposes, other than maintenance of the four normal schools. during the biennial period from December 1st, 1918, to December 1st, 1920, inclusive. Each school accounts for the fund assigned it for maintenance, a statement of which occurs under the proper heading of the institution. Total expenditures for two years....! $130,686.42 CLASSIFICATION Expense account Board members $ 1,149.03 Salary of Secretary 800.00 Printing, advertising, office expense, etc 1,362.73 New buildings, repairs, paving, etc 127,374.66 $130,686.42 $130,686.42 ITEMS 1919 Jan. 13 F. E. Mulhollen, east wing Chadron $ 1,500.00 Frank Pilger, Board expense 15.14 Dan Morris, Board expense 43-34 H. E. Reische, salary 100.00 Chadron Journal, Biennial report 292.10 H. E. Reische, Board expense 49.66 T. J. Majors, Board expense - 13.92 J. C. Stitt, Architect. Chadron east wing 159.02 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense 10.43 Mar. 10 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense 10.08 H. E. Reische, Board expense and salary 190.03 Dan Morris, Board expense 30.12 T. J. Majors. Board expense - 1376 Chas. Haas, repairs Peru Training School 963-75 Apr. 25 H. E. Reische, Board expense 45-48 T. J. Majors, Board expense 14-04 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense „ 10.04 Frank Pilger, Board expense 18.60 Dan Morris, Board expense 11.90 June 18 T. J. Majors, Board expense 22.62 H. E. Reische, Board expense 35-42 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Frank Pilger, Board expense -24-44 H. E. Reische, salary .'. 100.00 J. C. Stitt, Architect, Chadron 30.00 F. H. Bolte, house and lot, Kearney campus .2.300.00 Walter Knutzen, repairing roof, Kearney : 177.69 Aug. 6 H. E. Reische, Board expense 41.48 J. C. Stitt, Architect, Chadron gymnasium 2.176.94 T. J. Majors, Board expense 13-9*) Oct. 6 J. H. Miller, grading Wayne campus 2,280.00 Fritz Denkfnger, grading Wayne campus i.39-ft&gt; B. S. Fleming, grading Wayne campus 345.60 F. L. Hughes, grading Wayne campus "... 71.10 B. W. Davis, grading Wayne campus _ 52.00 J. L. Coon, grading Wayne campus 250.80 U. S. Conn, acct. grading Wayne campus 93-55 H. E. Reische, salary 100.00 WorM Pub. Co.. advertising 8.25 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense 10.05 H. E. Reische, Hoard expense, stamps, etc 46.48 Frank Pilger, Board expense 19.10 T. J. Majors, Board expense 10.92 Dan Morris, Board expense 29.12 J. C. Stitt, Architect. Chadron gym 65.02 Ernest Rokahr, estimate, Chadron gym 4&gt;335-OO Jan. 5 C. J. Burke, repairs, Kearney 100.00 W. H. Johns-Manville Co., pipe covering, Wayne 5,32250 U. S. Conn, Wayne, money advanced 186.75 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 42.50 T. J. Majors, Board expense 1398 Frank Pilger, Board expense 18.86 H. E. Reische, Board expense 41.48 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense 10.04 Dan Morris, Board expense 12.12 H. E. Reische, salary 100.00 J. C. Stitt, Architect. Chadron gym 170.85 W. A. Danley. office supplies 4.00 Chadron Journal, printing ,17-75 Ernest Rokahr, estimate Chadron gym 1 1. 390.00 Feb. 16 J. C. Stitt, Architect, Chadron gym 79.05 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense 10.04 H. E. Reische, Board expense 46.51 T. J. Majors, Board expense _ 16.82 Ernest Rokahr, estimate Chadron gym 5,270.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">BIENNIAL REPORT Apr. 12 Frank Pilgcr, Hoard expense 19.60 H. E. Reische, Board expense 44.48 T. J. Majors, Board expense 10.82 H. E. Reische, salary 100.00 Dan Morris, Board expense 12.50 Middle- West School Review, adv 1 10.25 The. McGraw Co., light plant, Wayne 1,580.44 June 21 Frank Pilger, Board expense '. 8.95 John M. Matzen, Board expense 10.88 T. J. Majors, Board expense 24.80 H. E. Reische. Board expense 36.02 The Nebraska Teacher, adv.. . 40.00 A. Schael Co.. corner stone Chadron gym 2oo.&lt;xj H. M. Plummer, estimate Chadron gym 2.975.00 J. C. Stitt. Architect, Chadron gym 44983 H. W. Johns-Manvillc Co.. supplies. Wayne 892.50 H. E. Reische. salary 100.00 E. Rokahr. estimate Chadron gym 17,680.00 E. Rokahr. extra Chadron gym 194.70 Aug. 2 Middle West School Review, adv J 21 00 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense....! 10.04 Frank: Pilfer. Board expense uj.20 H. E s Reische, Board expense 45-93 T. J. Majors. Board expense 7.82 Peter J. Lavigue, Peru, truck 1.475.00 City of Kearney 464.00 Roberts Construction Co., Pern, paving. . 2.3&lt;&gt;4.(H&gt; H. M. Plummer. estimate Chadron gym 425.ix&gt; J. C. Stitt. Architect. Chadron gym 264.38 •V The Mc(iraw Co.. light plant, Wayne S./'Xt/M City of Wayne, account paving 8,000.00 Ernest Rokahr, estimate Chadron gym 10.200.00 Oct. 11 Ernest Rokahr. estimate Chadron gym 21.335.00 H. M. Plummer, estimate Chadron gym 1,089.00 1,989.00 J. C. Stitt. Architect, Chadron gym 419.86 Claflin Printing Co.. printing, Wayne 80.00 C. W. Roberts Construction Co., paving, Peru 6,152.67 H. E. Reische, salary ioo.oo Nebraska Teacher, advertising schools 38-4&lt;&gt; World-Herald, advertising for schools 88.20 World-Herald, advertising for schools 171.60 Middle West School Review, adv 10.50 Tucker-Shean, supplies 3.20 The Star Pub. Co., advertising for schools 122.48 Omaha Daily News, advertising for schools 25200 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Frank Pilger, Board expense 19.32 T. J. Majors, Board expense 10.82 H. E. Reische, Board expense, stamps, supplies Si. 17 Dan Morris, Board expense 14.66 W. S. Heitzman, Board expense 7.04 W. J. Neal, Kearney 986.76 Manuel Scoonover Co., Kearney 374-O0 State Journal Co., advertising for schools 115.50 Roberts Con. Co., paving, Peru 5,673.3ft- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 9 CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Chadron, Nebraska, December I, 1920. To Th* Honorable Board of Education of the State Normal Schools : Gentlemen : 1 hereby submit a report of the condition of the Chadron State Normal School for the past biennium and some suggested improve - ments for the next biennium. NEW BUILDINGS The new gymnasium will be completed about February 1. This building would be a credit to any school in the state, and we now will be able to emphasize the physical phase of education, as well as the mental. The west wing of the main building should be extended the fifty feet in accordance with the original plan, which will enable us to enlarge our commercial department, provide an art and biology de - partment, and to house the library in a fire-proof building. We should have a dormitory large enough to accommodate all the girls who attend from out of town. This would also enable us to turn the present dormitory over to the boys. It is imperative that the young people who come here receive careful supervision, and this is possible only when they are housed in a dormitory, with someone in direct charge of them. Since the erection of the gymnasium, it will be necessary to enlarge the power house. It is now equipped with only two boilers, and two more at least should be added, which will give us a reserve of one in case any become incapacitated. By enlarging this building, provision will also be made for a larger supply of coal. NEW DEPARTMENTS In order to put our school on a par with the other normals of the state, it will be necessary the next biennium to provide for an art and a biology department. These have been neglected in the past, because of lack of space, but it is my desire to place more stress on this work in the future than we have in the past. Chadron, Nebraska ROBERT I. ELLIOTT, Pre.ident </seg>
            <seg id="p010">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 10 ATTENDANCE Our attendance has been gradually increasing, although during the war it was not so noticeable. We hope to do more advertising in the future, and attract the young people in this section, who have not heretofore seen the importance of an education, and the advantages of a state normal. CAMPUS A landscape gardener has been employed and at the present time s plotting the campus. According to his statement this is one of the - reatest opportunities for campus development with which he has ome in contact. He is to plot the entire campus, and to attend to he planting of the trees and shrubbery himself this spring. I trust othing will interfere to retard this work, as I feel it if one of the most important single things to be done. ATHLETICS AND SCHOOL PAPER For i hi- past two years we have been developing an excellent foot - ball team, and this year it was even better than last. We hope to make this a permanent feature in the school. During the war athletics of any kind was practically impossible. tThis year, the school inaugurated a publication, issued weekly, is is appreciated by both the student body and the alumni, and going to add materially to the interest in the school. ASSEMBLY ROOM As soon as the west wing of the main building is completed it is loped an assembly room can be made of the present library. This will enable us to supervise all students below the junior and senior years, and is necessary in order that the young folks may make the greatest advancement. ENROLLMENT The enrollment for the school year 1918-19 was 599, counting none twice and including the model high school. Counting student twice who registered for consecutive semesters, the enrollment wa 752, including the model high school. For the school year 1919-20 the enrollment was 640 counting none twice and including the mode high school. Counting students twice who registered for consecu live semesters, the enrollment was 898 including the model hig! school </seg>
            <seg id="p011">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 11 It will be noticed that there was a material increase the second year, and indications point to a still larger enrollment the coming biennium. Respectfully submitted, ROBERT T. ELLIOTT President CHADRON Financial Report for Biennium, Beginning December 1, 1918, and Ending December 1, 1920. SUMMARY OF MAINTENANCE FUND SUMMARY OF MAINTENANCE FUND Balance in fund December i. kjiK S 10.573.86 Balance in fund December l. 10.18 Balance in Rural School fund 12,046.00 Balance in Rural School fund Deficit allowed by Board 4,964.87 Deficit allowed by Board Appropriation April, 1919 175,000.00 $208,584.73 iqi8 Dec. u December payroll $ 4,032.20 1919 Jan. 22 J. H. White &amp; Co.. hardware 24.10 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 663.02 Vestal Chemical Co.. fixtures and towels 25.00 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. D. S. material 19.25 E. H. Sheldon &amp; 'Co., tcrrils 26.85 Schwabc Bros., repair work 5.35 E. H. Sargent Co., Lab. supplies 2.51 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, dishes 7.20 Remington Typewrite Co., straps 1.50 W. R. Pettycrew, labor 27.30 R. B. Perrine, use of team 90.00 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 64.57 Charles Olson, coal hauling 8.81 J. C. Neff, tuning pianos 12.00 Nebr. Sch. Supply House, chairs, etc 456.72 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 65.53 Morison Lumber Co., lumber 131.15 Intermountain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 176.95 Roberts Bros, drayage 197.85 Freeport Gas Mach. Co., air mixers 34-54 Water Com. Fahnestock, water rent 50.00 Distilled Water Ice Co., ice 1.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies .87 Chadron Telephone Co., service 29-95 Chadron Journal, printing and cards 52.35 Chadron Garage, drives 4.00 Chadron Drug Co., drugs 28.90 Chadron Chronicle, advertising 4JOO Beacon Press, letter heads 53-OO Amer. Multigraph Co., copy holder 5.54 Harry Porter, supplies 15.74 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 1,052.21 Jan. 27 January, 1919, payroll 4,196.57 Feb. 18 February, 1919, payroll 4.269.15 Mar. 12 Chadron Garage, drives 3.50 Chadron Journal, blanks and receipts.... 8.00 Chadron Laundry, D. S. laundry 3.60 R. I. Elliott, cash advanced 1,358.17 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 21.53 Chas. Christensen, labor, bolts .75 W. A. Danley, mailing tubes ; receipt bks 8.80 Dawes Co. Farm Bureau, advertising.... 24.00 Dennison Mfg. Co., Mill, supplies 2.60 A. B. Dick &amp; Co., mimeograph 200.00 Eberbach &amp; Son, slides 3.40 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 18.27 Garden City, Ed. Co., M. S. supplies 15.41 Garlock Packing Co., packing, washers 15-55 George Brothers, paper 6.90 Gillam-Moorman Co., supplies...^. 12.15 Harbison Mfg. Co., barn equipment 41.88 Intermountain Ry.. Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 145.93 H. F. Maika, drugs 1.20 E. E. Morey, D. S. silverware 13.00 Morison Lumber Company, lumber 6.50 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 45-02 Neb. Sch. Sup. House, mats, paper, etc. 49-26 Jacob North &amp; Co., bulletins, envelopes 177-45 C. M. Parker Pub. Co., M. S. leaflets.... 1.84 W. W. Parsons, hardware 109.63 R. B. Perrine, use of team 67-50 Harry Porter, pads and guides 3.10 Prang Co., M. S. supplies 11.80 P. P. Proudfit, lumber 532.30 Remington Type. Co., typewriters 54000 Roberts Bros., drayage 64.00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, furniture and linen.... 432.23 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 13 Schwieger Lumber Co., M. T. lumber 9:30 If. E. Smith &amp; Co., D. S. material 5.55 Sullivan Hat Shop. Mill, dept. material 7.50 Carl D. Town, lead, oil, turpentine 7.60 Underwood Typewriter Co., ink 2.50 Vestal Chem. Co., fixtures 24.00 Western Electric Co., supplies: 42.16 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 9.30 S. L. Allen &amp; Co., drill 11.10 Amer. Electric Heater Co., plugs 6.37 Chadron Chronicle, receipt books 4150 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 565.66 Chadron Furniture Co., supplies 4.20 Huse Pub. Co.. record sheets 50.16 Mar. 24 March, lgiy, payroll 4,160.75 Apr. 5 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 346.18 April, 1919. payroll 4,649.75 May 6 F. Fahnestock, water commissioner 57-30 C. H. Stoelting &amp; Co., lab. materials 349-8o A. B. Dick Co., stencils and ink 75-15 Chas. Christensen, iron 2.70 Thomas Charles Co., yarn 3.41 Chadron Journal Co., printing.. 17.00 Chadron Laundry, D. S. laundry 5.05 Chadron Furn. Co., sockets and rings 251.50 Chadron Garage Co., drive 3.00 Chadron Drug Co.. drugs 3.00 Burroughs Add. Mach. Co., machine 300.00 B. A. Brewster, envelopes 60.00 Thos. Betts, drayage 181.62 Beghtol Co., millinery material .75 Bausch &amp; Lomb Co., microscopes 177-75 Art Metal Const. Co., vault door and fix. 777.50 Amer. Mult. Co., repairs .63 Advance Pump Co., cylinders 12.47 J. S. O'Hare, labor 213.00 Yawman &amp; Erbe Co., filing case 185.75 Wyoming Nebr. Tel. Co., service 32.26 Edna E. Work, fringe... 4.75 Woodruff Printing Co., bulletins 147-50 J. H. White &amp; Co.. hardware 252.72 Vestal Chemical Co.. paper towels 1950 Underwood &amp; Underwood, views, scopes 208.50 Carl D. T° wn . paint 2.30 C. G. Tidd, repair and labor 56.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">&gt;4 W. T. Stockdale, typewriter 90.00 J. C. Stitt, specifications 40.00 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., B. B. supplies... 21.35 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., millinery material.... 1.70 Albert Sechrist Mfg. Co., furnishings.... 69.25 Reitz &amp; Crites, lumber 3.20 Remington Type Co., cylinder 3.00 F. A. Rausch &amp; Co., nails and mole- skin, M. T 26.75 Harry Porter, office supplies 73-35 Albert Pick &amp; Co., bread sliccr, boiler 479-25 J. S. O'Hare, vault labor and material.... 1,650.00 J. S. O'Hare, labor and material 500.00 Nebr. Sch. Supply House, paper 24.40 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 37-8s Morison Lumber Co., lumber and glass 124.65 Ralph Meyers, supplies and labor 68.50 H. D. Mead, surveying 40.50 Intermountain Ry.. Lt. &amp; Pr. Co 255.12 Imp. Pub. Co., Stereoscopic Anatomy .... 15.00 Hili-Standard Co., playground apparatus 246.00 Hickok Pro. Co., oil - 86.40 Harbison Mfg. Co., barn material 19.70 Golden Rule, Sewing Dept. material 1.39 Gillam- Moorman Co., furniture 174.16 George Bros., letter heads 8.25 W. S. Gillam, sockets and thermometer 3.30 A. Flanagan Co., undercharge 9.45 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 191-49 James Mfg. Co., barn equipment 240.55 Harry Plummer, repairs and labor 291.03 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 312.20 May 24 May, 1919, payroll 4.504-95 June 23 R.I. Elliott, cash advanced 968.14 Chadron Battery Service, recharging 4.00 Chadron Chronicle, printing, cards, etc. 43.87 Thos. Betts, drayage .-. 90.00 Baker Bros., landscape view 65.05 Harry Porter, blotters 2.00 R. E. Yarndley, cash advanced for music 52.45 Skinner Irrigation Co., sprinkler 31.00 Wyo. &amp; Xebr. Tel. Co., service 3I-I4 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 208.28 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 147-00 W . Al . W t?ICn iVl Iff, QiplOTllaS 95*75 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 15 E. H. Thompson, labor and material 105.50 J. C. Summers Lumber Co., lumber 181.20 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., rihbon 3.20 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 331.66 Omaha Sch. Sup. House, paper, chalk.... 92.86 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 7.50 Moore-Shenkberg Co., sugar for D. S 10.35 James Mfg. Co., anchors 1.21 Intermountain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 82.84 Huerfano Agency Co., coal 192.51 R. E. Holch, expenses 14-39 Evelyn Good, drive 15.00 J. A. Munkres, I). S. groceries 54-24 Chas. Emery, repairing vacuum cleaner 33-96 G. E. Goodhand, tar kettle 30.00 Gillam-Moorman Co., window shades 3.00 \V. S. Gillam, mower and pail 9I-I5 Garlock Packing Co.. packing 7.08 Eugene Dietzgeti, arrows and paper 4.57 Chadron Furniture Co., cotton and rods 23.25 VV. A. Danley. clips and paper 5.00 H. R. Condrey, D. S. supplies 23.88 Chadron Journal, printing 80.06 Chadron Garage Co., service U-75 Chadron Drug Co.. drugs 1.00 Harry M. Plummer, supplies 273.38 June _7 June. 1919, payroll. 4.994-55 June 28 Garden C'ty Ed. Co., \l. S. supplies 39.66 July 21 July, 1919, payroll 4.795-95 Aug. 15 Chadron Garage Co., drives 11.50 C. E. Chamberlain, clover seed 8.40 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 29.24 1 \xr \ r&gt; u: i: I l.~ ~-o o . W. A. Boyer, binding books 238.84 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 20.07 Chas. Christensen, supplies and labor.... 10.50 Central Scientific Co., Dom. Sci. supplies 5.70 Compton Drug Co., drugs 3.75 Distilled Ice Water Co., D. S. ice 12.55 Cudahy Pckg. Co., soap polish 9.00 F. B. Fahnestock, water commis. rent.... 80.45 Hammond &amp; Stephens, diplomas, inserts '7.74 lntermountain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 58.48 N T . C. Leary Co., letter heads 20.65 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 64.05 J. C. Neff, tuning pianos 12.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION KS Omaha Hd. Wd. Lbr., Co., M. T. lbr 115.10 H. M. Orschel Co., Asphalt felt 469.05 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 99.27 W. R. Pettycrew, cash advanced 627.65 Albert Pick &amp; Co., stools and matting.... 38.25 P. P. Proudfit, lumber 441.20 Reitz &amp; Crites, tile and lumber 88-59 Schmoller &amp; Mueller, piano 1,000.00 Schwabe Bros., welding 2.60 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. oilcloth 2.40 Standard Supply Co., cheesecloth 6.50 Skinner Irrigation Co., sprinklers 45-00 W. T. Stockdale, extension work 70.35 J. C. Summers Lumber Co., lumber 116.40 Carl D. Town, paint 1.10 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 161.66 Woodruff Printing Co., diplomas 15.00 Wyo. &amp; Nebr. Tel. Co., service 25.44 R. E. Yarndley, cash advanced 13.17 R. I. Elliott, cash advanced 821.65 Aug. 28 August, 1919, payroll 1,538.50 Sep. 24 September, 1919, payroll 5,322.05 Oct.- 8 Wyo. &amp; Neb. Tel. Co., service 32.20 Lew H. Wright, cane seed 9.00 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 348.45 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 22.20 G. E. Taylor, drayage 25.00 Carl D. Town, paint 14.05 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 61.50 State Journal Co., notices 9.50 D. Snydcr, plastering 16.00 Geo. C. Snow, printing and advertising 89.65 Schmoller &amp; Mueller Co., piano cover.... 10.00 Leora A. Rustin, cash advanced 1.50 Prang Co., M. S. supplies 3.92 P. P. Proudfit, lumber 32.60 Omaha School Supply Co., clock 108.00 W. W. Parsons, hardware 63.82 J. S. OHare, labor 25.00 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, chalk, desks, etc. 285.15 G. H. Mathews, repair work 283.50 W. G. Moreland, labor '. 82.77 H. F. Maika. paint, oil, etc 49-6o J:ickson Piano Co.. piano 228.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 17 Intermountain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 75.57 R. E. Holch, expenses 2.35 F. Fahnestock, water rent 96.80 James English, use of car 5.00 J. S. Dickerson, repair work :.... 50.00 Eugene Dietzgen, tracing cloth, paper.... 14-84 Creamer Pkg. Co., powder 4.96 W. A. Danley, office supplies 9.85 Win. Christensen, hauling 8.50 Chas. Christensen, repair work 10.00 Chadron Chronicle, printing 16.00 Chadron Laundry, D. S. laundry 15.60 Oliver Brown Printing Co., bulletins 399-14 Beghtol Co., supplies for sewing dept 3.75 Robt. I. Elliott, cash advanced 540.17 Oct. 25 October, 1919, payroll 5.55570 Nov. 25 November, 1919, payroll 5,526.40 Dec. 12 December, 1919, payroll 5,482.05 1920 Jan. 8 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 2,208.11 Gillam-Moorman Co., rep. work, shades 24.19 Gus Hackler, hauling coal H-55 Hickok Producing Co., oil 86.40 Chadron Journal, tickets, cards, ptg 56.55 Intermountain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 275.04 Kalamazoo Parchment Co., D. S. paper 6.26 Keuffel &amp; Esser Co., tracing cloth 15.66 Lincoln Fine Arts Shop, pictures 229.95 Miller Brothers, labor 8.00 Molzer Violin, repair bass viol 54.13 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 8498 W. S. Gillam, hardare 39.85 Natrona County Tribune, advertising.... 1.26 National Ed. Association, programs 2.00 Omaha Hardwood Lbr. Co., M. T. lumber 527.75 Nebraska Telephone Co., service 59-70 Northwestern Stamp Wks., brass plates 13.15 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 272.88 Albert Pick &amp; Co., cheesecloth and mops 19.69 Harry M. Plummer, labor and supplies 2,949.33 P. P. Proudfit Lumber Co., lumber 46.95 Reitz &amp; Crites, lime, shingles.... 80.55 Remington Typewriter Co., paper 2.84 Rutledge &amp; Taylor Coal Co., coal 450.00 Schwabe Bros., chain and welding. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">«8 V"^ *-* V/* L *' 1^ v v. rV k 1V/.N llarloek Packing Co., rings and valves... 16.25 Scott-Marriott Co., shoes and repairing 4.25 M. E. Smith &amp;• Co.. sewing material 19.86 Standard Elect. Sup. Co., supplies 162.68 J. C Summers Lumber Co., lumber 86.00 Carl I). Town, lead, oil and brushes 2.90 Western Electric Co., fuses 76.75 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 32.50 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 810.30 L. R. Willis Sanitary Co., liquid soap.... 20.00 Edna E. Work, cash advanced 2.60 American Lead Pencil Co., pencils 2.55 Art Metal Const. Co., guides, divisions 19.70 Baker Bros. Eng. Co., six halftones 78.50 Beghtol Co., D. S. supplies 5.90 Thos. Betts, drayage 399-95 Carpenter Paper Co., stationery 11.00 Cbadron Drug Co., drugs, thermometers 11.40 Chadron Chronicle, tickets, sta'y, etc 34-5O Chadron Frn. Co., casters, switches, etc. 26.15 Chadron Garage Co.. drives 16.00 Thos. Charles Co.. M. S. supplies 26.25 Burroughs Add. Mach. Co., paper 3.50 Clarke Chemical Co.. polish 1950 Chas. Christensen, repair work 10.40 Creamery Pkg. Mfg. Co., cleaner 9.92 Comptou Drug Co., drugs 7.45 Distilled Water Ice Co., D. S. ice 7.90 Elect. Sup. &amp; Const. Co., wiring and sup. 154.60 W. D. Field, piano tuning 10.00 Carl Fischer, music 28.35 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 30.34 Frankel Ribbon &amp; Carbon Co., paper.... 3.50 Garden City Ed. Co., M. S. supplies 68.47 L. J. Baker, labor 31-45 Alliance Times, advertising 3.35 Jan. _&gt;3 January, 1020, payroll 5,472.6o Feb. .23 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., sewing dept. supplies 5.54 J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 25.80 C. A. Wickman, sewing dept. supplies. ... 16.50 Edna E. Work, cash advanced _ 6.9O \V. A. Putts. 1). S. laundry 5.15 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 131.27 Hv.se Pub. Co.. record sheets 73.25 Garden City Ed. Co.. reed and inkweels 6.66 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 19 A. Flanagan Co., hooks „ 2.90 Atkinson, Mentzer Co., M. S. supplies.... 5.08 Beckley-Cardy Co., M. S. supplies 1.10 L. J. Baker, labor 18.90 Chadron Chronicle, tickets, bills, etc.... 24.00 Chadron Telephone Co., service 27.20 Chadron Garage Co., service .75 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 24-39 Mrs. Regina Cockrell, lamps 2.75 Daltnn Adding Machine Co.. ribbon 1.00 \V. A Dan ley, M. S. supplies 2.55 Distilled Water let- Co., D. S. ice 2.40 Douglas Enterprise, advertising 6.00 Durand Steel Locker Co., lockers 75-6o J. L. Hammett Co., Educ. games 1.66 James H. Hill, labor 39-90 Hot Springs Star, advertising 6u}O Intermomitain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 125.47 H. F. Maika, drugs 2.40 Nebraska Schol Supply House, supplies 57-35 Office Squipment &amp; Sup. Co., folders 49-65 Pettycrew &amp; Bengson, labor, material . . 19-45 Harry M. Plummer. labor and supplies 159.38 George E. Potter, labor 29.16 Remington Type. Co., type, cylinder, etc. 3.80 Randall Bros., D. S. groceries 3.20 Schwabe Bros., welding 1.90 E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co., cabinet 105.00 Western Electric Co., renewals 1.72 R. I. Elliott, cash advanced 1,089.82 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 595-2O Mar. i February, 1920, payroll..! 6,970.50 Mar. 23 March. 1920. payroll 6.919.92 Apr. icj University Pub. Co., class records 21.00 U. S. Blue Print Paper Co.. drawing ink .3.00 Whitebreast Coal Co.. coal 985.05 J. H. White &amp; Co.. hardware 79-70 Guy Taylor, drayage 2.00 Peerless Elect. Co., screws and brushes 9.24 Harry M. Plummer, plumbing materials 135.16 Proudfit Lumber Co., lumber 16.60 Reitz &amp; Crites Lumber Co., lumber 20.75 Remington Typewriter Co.. machines 211. 10 Rudgc &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture, etc 130.47 Rntledare &amp; Taylor Coal Co., coal 174.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Schwabe Bros., welding _ 2.25 C. H. Stoelting, chemical supplies 605.68 Kennedy &amp; Parsons, bottles and tester 22.19 H. F. Maika, wax 3.00 E. E. Morey, repairing clock 1.00 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 116.07 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, supplies and map 151.74 National Refining Co., oil '5-19 Omaha Printing Co., record book 29.46 W. S. Gillam, hardware 4.65 Hemingway &amp; Evans, D. S. meat 1.90 Intermountain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 427.39 Iroquis Publishing Co., maps 4.59 F. Fahnestock, water com. rent 76.35 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 289.47 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 59-63 George Bros., stationery 42.55 Distilled Water Ice Co., D. S. ice ...! 2.40 Eugene Dietzgen, M. T. supplies 12.82 Chas. Christensen, irons, rake, etc 5.50 Compton Drug Co., medicines, etc 20.60 W. A. Danley, pennants 1.55 Chadron Journal, cut _ 5.50 Chadron Telephone Co., service 63.55 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 6.35 Chadron Furniture Co., furniture 96.00 Chadron Garage Co., car service 3.25 Thos. Betts, drayage 487.08 Central Scientific Co., Lab. supplies 25.06 Chadron Chronicle, advertising, cards.... 84.35 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 1.564.77 Apr. 27 April, 1920, payroll _ _ 7,689.22 May 27 May, 1920, payroll 7.35O.42 June 23 June, 1920, payroll 7.047-07 July 1 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 960.14 Chadron Journal, programs, cards, etc. 354.87 R E. Yarndley, cash advanced 5.82 L. R. Willis, pipe clean 3.25 Harry M. Plummer, labor and materials 204.90 Kalamazoo Veg. Parch. Co., D. S. paper 6.00 K. B. Printing Co ., paper 1.46 H. H. Lembke, supplies 20.01 Meek Lumber Co.. M. T. lumber 96.53 E. E. Morey, clock and repairing 1700 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 21 M. H. Stuart, Treas. fee 10.00 Office Equip. &amp; Sup. Co., pamphlets no.oo W. \V. Parsons Hardware Co., harwarde 201.18 Albert Pick &amp; Co., cheesecloth 6.50 Nichols &amp; Walsh, D. S. groceries 11.00 Randall Bros., D. S. groceries 5.15 Prang Co., M. S. supplies 27.54 G. E. Rokahr, hauling 2.00 E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co., drawing tables.... 312.00 Sullivan Hat Shop, mat'l for sew. dept. 16.06 J. C. Summers Lumber Co., lumber 1325 Carl D. Town, oil, paint, etc 95-8s Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 140.00 J. H. Hill, plastering 32.15 F. E. French, repairing 4.00 Hemingford Ledger, advertising 2.60 George Bros., stationery 9.65 Garden City Ed. Co., reed, etc 21.32 Educational Bureau, assembly books 87.50 Wm. Chaulk, grading athletic field 3,250.00 Thomas Charles Co., penholders 1.36 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 23.82 R. S. Fleming, labor 128.00 Bausch &amp; Lomb Opt'l Co., microscopes 267.75 Thomas Betts. drayage 58.35 Carpenter Paper Co., paper 4.15 Atkinson-Mentzer Co., M. S. supplies.... 4.11 Art Metal Construction Co., file guides 2.35 Armstrong Clothing Co., supplies 20.00 American Disinfecting Co., soap, etc 192.00 July 26 July. 1920, payroll 6,969.37 Aug. 3 Harry M. Plummer, labor and materials 272.15 P. P. Proudfit, lumber 35-10 Rutledge &amp; Taylor Coal Co., coal 152.25 Schmoller &amp; Meuller Co., piano 1,025.00 Remington Typewriter Co., carbon 3.75 Ernest Rokahr, labor '. 26.50 Schwabe Bros., repair work, etc 3.85 Steinway &amp; Sons, frt., repairing piano 316.41 N. W. Thomas, D. S. ice 10.75 Chaulk &amp; Birdsall, hauling dirt 500.00 Thomas Charles Co., M. S. supplies 59.33 H. F. Maika, shellac, wax, etc 5.30 Hammond &amp; Stephens, engrossing 2.30 F. Fahnestock, water com. rent M5-3O </seg>
            <seg id="p022">J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 26.62 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 645.58 E. C. Byerly, D. S. supplies 12.80 Chadron Chronicle, adv., tickets, etc 58.80 Chadron Drug Co., drugs 2.20 W. A. Danley, supplies 16.60 Chadron Garage Co., drives 4.00 Chadron Laundry, D. S. laundry 19.00 Hill-Standard Co.. swing 20.00 Hickok Producing Co.. gas 80.08 Chadron Furniture Co., supplies 64.10 Graves Studio, pictures 8.55 Garlock Packing Co., gaskets 22.06 The Electric Shop, supplies 17-95 Eugene Deitzen, supplies 20.78 Omaha Sch. Sup. House, paper, shades.... 87.52 N'ebr. Sch. Sup. Co., office supplies 89.18 Nichols &amp; Walsh. D. S. supplies 8.40 J. A. Munkres, D. S. groceries 119.1ft Jas. H. Matthews, stamp 1.60 Midland Chem. Co., paper towels 47-50 J. C. Summers Lumber Co.," lumber 9335 Kewanee Mfg. Co., storage case n3-5&lt;&gt; \V. T. Stockdale, cash adv. for ext. work 45-85 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., sew. dept. material 34.83 Molzer Violin School, repair viol bows 3.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., service 68.30 Omaha Hardwood Lbr. Co., M. T. lbr. 275.83 United Chem. Co., brushes, paper, etc. 184.55 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 82.50 Mrs. E. P. Wilson, D. S. milk 4.00 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. diplomas and engrossing 12966 Vestal Chemical Co., powder 12.50 Tucker &amp; Shean, office supplies 180.53 Purity Ice Cream Factory, D. S. supplies 6.75 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 36.86 Ormesher Bros., D. S. meats 17.95 Intermountain Ry., Lt. &amp; Pr. Co., service 567.56 Compton Drug Co., drugs 3.10 Aug. 25 August, 1920, payroll _ 1,658.02 Oct. 15 September, 1920, payroll 7.953 47 Robert I. Elliott, cash advanced 3,586.42 Parsons Hardware Co., hardware 137-32 R. C. Siekert, materials and labor 823.69 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL ■3 J. H. White &amp; Co.. hardware 4«./&lt;&gt; L'nderwod Typewriter Co., stencils 3.00 K. E. Yamdley, cash advanced for music 4.46 Edna E. Work, cash advanced 0.80 VV. S. (iillam, supplies 4-2-45 K. S. Fleming, Frisno 33-oo F. Fahnestock, water rent 106.90 VV. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. diplomas engrossed son Tucker &amp; Shean, supplies £3° West. Sup. Co., tank. regs. wrenches... 117.98 United States Supply Co.. supplies 1.279.30 Rowe. Peterson &amp; Co.. M. S. books 5.72 Carl D. Town, paint _ 49.55 Fred Medart Mfg. Co., S. pool fittings 110.00 Lincoln Fine Arts Shop, framing 9.00 Remington Typewriter Co.. carbon 3.75 Randall Bros., D. S. materials (&gt;.jo Nebr. Sch. Sup. Co. paper a-nd desks 67000 Rut ledge. Taylor Coal Co.. coal 1.072.54 Nebraska Telephone Co., service 63.20 W. &lt; 1. Moreland, labor 95.85 A. N. Palmer Co.. M. S. supplies 1.31 Intermountain Ry.. Lt. tV Pr. Co., service -5470 Kewanee Roiler Co.. grates 438.75 Distilled Water Ice Co.. D. S. ice 3.00 flu- McGraw Co., electrical supplies 59.67 Electric Shop, cord 3.20 Grd. Rapids Fibre Cord Co.. wire stakes 18.41 Hemingway Bros.. D. S. meats 8.75 Compton Drug Co.. drugs 20.50 VV. A. Danley. mailing tubes, erasers. ... 1(1.20 Crawford Courier, advertising i.8o Chadron Chronicle, eiiv.s. progs., etc.. 48.15 Thos. Betts, drayage 661.48 Durand Steel Locker Co., locker keys.... 37-91 Oliver Brown Printing Co.. bulletins 135-OO A. H. Abbott &amp; Co., supplies 35-37 B. B. Brooks, supplies 400 J. VV. Boyd, labor 62.00 Baker Bros. Engraving Co., halftones. ... 8.83 J. T. Baker Chem. Co, chemicals 136.91 American Elect. Co., labor and supplies 609.75 Chadron Journal, printing, etc 75-7O Chadron Garage Co., drives 7.75 Chadron Furn. Co. bed, spgs.. mattress 59-75 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 24 Central Scientific Co., lab. supplies 428.83 Jesse Keeney, iron 14.40 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lbr. Co., coal 693.23 Oct. 29 October, 1920, payroll 7,981.67 Nov. 29 November, 1920, payroll 7,869.22 Balance in fund December 1, 1920 4,087.27 $208,584.73 $208,584.73 INSTITUTION CASH Balance in fund December 1, 1918 $ 5,899.64 1919 Jan. 8 Sent State Treasurer 1.957-73 Jan. 22 Yawman &amp; Erbe Co., book $ 1.00 22 R. E. Yarndley, mus. collections 237.00 Ed. J. Walt, music and postage 30 12 Alyse Swedberg, collections 248.25 Silver. Burdette Co., books 7.78 H. M. Rowe Co., B. K. sets 62.31 R. A. Peterson, collections 78.00 Macmillan Co., books 15.36 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 2.03 Gregg Pub. Co., books 28.60 Carl Fischer, music 17-53 G. A. Crancer, music .". 3.13 American Book Co., books 4.10 State Journal, certificates 20.00 Feb. 10 Sent State Treasurer 1.289.35 Mar. 3 Sent State Treasurer 523.93 Mar. u R E. Yarndley. collections 380.00 Alyse Sweedberg, collections 341.00 G. E. Stechert, book 1.63 R. A. Peterson, collections 201.00 Omaha Hardwood Lbr. Co., M. T. lbr 08.20 Macmillan Co., books 18.54 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. books 1.77 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 50.08 Gregg Pub Co., books 8.85 Ginn &amp; Co., books _ 70.92 Carl Fischer, music 12.41 G. A. Crancer, music _ 4.55 D. Apleton &amp; Co., dictionary 2.77 American Book Co., books 19.91 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 28.O8 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Apr. s Sent State Treasurer 568.55 535-90 May s Sent State Treasurer May 7 Vivien Bard, collections 62.00 College Book Store, tests 2.99 Samuel Freeh, books 22.11 Ginn &amp; Co., books 6.30 Hinds, Hayden &amp; Eldredge, books 2.91 Macmillan Co., books I4-4O R. A. Peterson, collections 91.00 Silver, Burdett Co., books 3.08 Alyse Swedberg, collections 85.00 Sewal Townsend, collections 10.50 Wards Nat. Science 65.50 R. E. Yarndley, collections 186.00 June 30 Sent State Treasurer _ 1 ,082.07 June 23 Henry Holt Co.. books 4.65 A. N. Palmer, penmanship books 9.66 R. E. Yarndley, collections 283.00 Edw. J. Walt, music 16.62 S. E. Townsend, collections 2.00 Alyse Swedberg, collections 107.00 R. A. Peterson, collections 59-00 Houghton-Mifflin Co., books 23.50 Gregg Pub. Co., books 24.06 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 8.28 American Book Co., blanks 4.32 Vivien Bard, collections 79.00 Carl Fischer, orchestra music 1.68 Carl Fischer, orchestra music 3.68 Vivien Bard, collections 225.00 Aug. 5 Sent State Treasurer 1.502.4/ Aug. IS Vivien Bard, colections 241.00 G. A. Crancer, music 10.19 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 9.19 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., cabinets 18.78 R. A. Peterson, collections 37-0O Prang Co., books 19.20 H. M. Rowe Co. B. K. sets ;.. 78.81 Alyse Swedberg, collections 5.00 R. E. Yarndley. collections 159.00 Oct. 1 Sent State Treasurer «. 557-23 Oct. 8 American Book Co., textbooks 19.70 Vivien Bard, collections 411.00 Vivien Bard, collections 74-OO Century Co., textbooks 51.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Carl Fischer, music to be sold 24.00 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 46.71 Houghton-Mifflin Co.. books 5-97 Longmans, Green &amp; Co.. book 1. 16 Macmillan Co., books 82.29 David McKay, book 2.42 R. A. Peterson, collections 109.00 G. Schirmer, music to be sold 17.24 Fred A. Stokes Co.. book 2.49 University Pub. Co., textbooks 34-52 R. E. Yarndley. collections 335-00 Wards Xat. Science, i model of brain... 120.00 Nov. 5 Sent State Treasurer 327-15 Dec. 6 Sent State Treasurer 736.45 1920 .Ian. 9 R. E. Yarndley, collections 295.00 Geo. Wahr, textbook 2.76 University Pub. Co., manual .71 Underwood &amp; Underwood, views 93-2&lt;&gt; Silver. Burdett &amp; Co.. books 3-66 G. E. Stechert &amp; Co.. books 5.44 Scott. Foresman &amp; Co.. books --32 Chas. Scribner's Sons, books 0.29 G. Schirmer, music to be sold student... 60.68 H. M. Rowe Co., bookkeeping sets 4462 Pranjj Co., books 6.75 R. A. Peterson, collections 100.00 Chas. E. Merrill, books 6.48 Macmillan Co., textbooks 28.06 Houghton-Mifflin Co., books 6.16 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 9.77 Gregg Pub. Co.. textbooks , 48.12 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 49.20 American Book Co.. books H-99 Vivien Bard, collections 327.00 Century Co., books 1.20 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 37-H Duffield &amp; Co., book .94 Funk &amp; Wajrnalls, dictionary 16.13 Feb. 5 Sent State Treasurer 2,176.73 Feb. 18 Vivien Bard, collections 520.00 Henry Holt &amp; Co , textbooks 16.48 Houghton-Mifflin Co., books 15.06 Macmillan Co., books 29.32 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 26.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL ■27 K. A. Peterson, collections 212.00 R. E. Yarndley. collections 473-00 H. If. Roe Co., bookkeeping sets 58.45 A. N. Palmer, books • 4.53 Mar. 1 Sent State Treasurer 903-55 fr)i.58 Apr. 2 Sent State Treasurer Apr. 17 Ginn &amp; Co.. textbooks 33.69 Macmillan Co., books I5-3O Henry Holt &amp; Co.. books 6.92 Carl Fischer, music to be sold 24.21 Educ. Pub. Co., textbooks 10.67 Century Co., textbooks 7.00 Vivien Bard, collections _ 295.00 American Book Co.. textbooks 53-74 Allyri &amp; Bacon, books 6.28 R. E. Yarndley, cash advanced for music 63.24 R. E. Yarndley, collections 375-00 (i. Schirmer, music to be sold 58.64 Silver Burdette &amp; Co.. books 8.32 Cbas. Scribner's Sons, books 13.91 Rand WcNally Co., map 12.50 Pran.Lj Co.. books 20.54 R. A. Peterson, music collections 203.00 May .1 Sent State Treasurer 684.65 2.864.95 July 7 Sent State Treasurer July 1 \llyn &amp; Bacon Co., books 13 44 American Book Co., books and sets 54-88 Vivien Bard, collections .' 325.00 Vivien Bard, collections 377-00 H. \V. Gray Co., textbooks 6.52 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 25.57 Macmillan Company, books 41.72 Houghton-Mifflin Co., textbooks 69.93 R. A. Peterson, collections 290.00 (1. Chirmer, music to be sold 11.88 R. E. Yarndley, collections 132.00 R. E. Yarndley, collections 452.00 Aug. 5 Sent State Treasurer 9O5.59 Aug. 3 R. E. Yarndley, collections 126.00 Vivien Bard, collections 38.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 20.16 Henry Holt &amp; Co , books 31.17 Longman's Green &amp; Co., books '9-4i R. A. Peterson, collections 78.00 H. M. Rowe Co.. textbooks 22.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 28 Macmillan Co., books 50.65 Carl Fischer, music to be sold 27.05 Oct. 13 American Book Co., textbooks 17.72 University Pub. Co., books 42.49 R. E. Varndley, collections 315.00 Chas. E. Merrill, books 8.19 R. A. Peterson, collections 209.00 G. Schirmer, music to be sold 12.71 Silver, Burdett Co., textbooks 8.87 Vivien Bard, collections 618.00 Vivien Bard, collections 151.00 Educational Pub. Co., books ;... 5.63 Carl Fischer, music 13.09 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 66.84 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 17-55 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 34-28 Houghton-Mifflin Co., books 37-44 J. B. Lippincott Co., books 52.28 Macmillan Co., textbooks 32.85 So. West News Co., budgets to be sold.... 4.94 Nov. 3 Sent to State Treasurer 2,364.80 $12,000.48 Balance in fund December 1, 1920 13,671.84 $26,572.32 $26,572.32 LIBRARY FUND Balance in fund December 1, 1918 $ 1,007.70 1919 Jan. 8 Sent State Treasurer 575-O&lt;&gt; Jan. 22 Alliance Times, subscription 6.00 A. C. McClursr &amp; Co., library books 10711 Bruce Pub. Co., magazine 2.00 Herman Goldberger, magazines 161.95 Library Bureau, book ; 6.07 Manual Arts Press, subscription 1.50 National Ed. Ass'n, proceed and dues.... 58.00 World-Herald, subscription 5.50 Feb. 10 Sent State Treasurer 95-Oo Mar. 3 Sent State Treasurer 30.00 Mar. 12 H. W. Wilson Co., magazines 52.80 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding mag. 81.83 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books _ 123.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 29 Library Bureau, library supplies 8.48 H. R. Humting Co., encyclopedia 22.50 Alliance Herald, subscription 1.50 Middle West School Review, adv 10.50 Apr. 5 Sent State Treasurer 15.00 10.00 May 5 Sent State Treasurer May 10 H. W. Wilson Co., subscription * 15.95 Bee Publishing Co.. subscription 5.50 Art Metal Constr. Co., lib. shelving 40675 A. L. A. Pub. Board, book list 1.50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 96.82 June 23 Sent State Treasurer 500 Warner Library, books 87.00 Waldorf Binder, binding books 3.90 State Journal, subscription 6.00 A. C. McClurg, books 137-34 H. W. Wilson Co., magazine 1.00 Aug. 5 Sent State Treasurer 530.00 Aug. 15 Custer County Chief, subscription 2.00 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co., year book 6.30 Doubleday, Page &amp; Co., books 2.70 W. A. Hixenbaugh &amp; Co., books 27.00 Kearney Daily Hub, subscription 4.00 Librarian of Congress, cards 15.04 Waldorf Bindery Co., magazines 1.75 Oct. 1 Sent State Treasurer 490.00 Oct. 8 Library Bureau, library cabinets 108.25 Nov. 5 Sent State Treasurer 60.00 30.00 Dec. 6 Sent State Treasurer 1920 Jan. 8 H. W. Wilson Co., volume 51.50 Mitchell Index, subscription 3.20 Lusk Herald, subscription and adv~ 7.10 Librarian of Congress, cards 30.22 H. R. Huntting Co., books 6.51 Farmers Exchange, subscription 1.50 Casper Daily Tribune, subscription 6.00 Burr Printing Co., subscription 2.00 Bruce Pub. Co., subscription 2.00 Warwick &amp; York, books 56.25 A. C. McClurg, library books 293.28 Feb. 5 Sent State Treasurer 90.00 Feb. 18 Library Bureau, library supplies 11.43 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 150.30 Star Journal, subscription 1.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Waldorf Bindery Co., binding mag 97-97 World-Herald Co., subscription 6.50 Western Nebraska Observer, sub 4.00 Democrat Printing Co., cards, etc 6.47 Sidney Telegraph, subscription 2.70 Mar. 1 Sent State Treasurer 10.00 15-00 Apr. 2 Sent State Treasurer i Apr. 17 Florence Chandler, books 7.00 Herman Goldberger, periodicals 183.80 Librarian of Congress, cards 20.39 Morril! Mail, subscription 2.00 Williams &amp; Wilkins, bot. abstracts 12.10 H. W. Wilson Co., catalogues 1.60 A. L, A. Pub. Board, book list 1.50 Luke M. Bates, subscription 2.00 July 7 Sent State Treasurer 72500 July y Bee Publishing Co., subscription 9.00 Burr Printing Co., subscription 2.50 Goring Courier, subscription 2.00 Hooker County Tribune, subscription.... 1.50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 251.1 1 Aug. 5 Sent State Treasurer Aug. .? Chamber of Commerce, Nations Bus 5.00 Arthur H. Clark Co., books 33.14 H. R. Huntting Co., books 18.72 Kearney Daily Hub, subscription 5.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 52.98 G. P. Putnam's Sons, books 21.20 Oct. 13 Rapid City Daily Journal, subscription 6.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 122.12 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co., year book 8.10 Library Bureau, tables 392.13 H. R. Huntting Co., books 1.92 Caster County Chief, subscription 2.00 Nov. 3 Sent State Treasurer... 38o.(xj $3,484-5;? Balance in fund December 1, 1920 608.17 $4,092.70 $ 4,002.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 31 KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Kearney, Nebraska Kearney, Nebraska, December 1, 1920. The State Board of Education of Normal Schools The Nebraska State Normal School at Kearney has attempted during the past two years to meet the demands made upon it by the State of Nebraska. In some cases, notably when those demands were for trained teachers, the institution has been absolutely unable to comply. Kor three years past the enrollment has steadily declined. There are so many contributing causes at this condition that it is not possible to enter into its discussion here, as nothing in the way of conduct of the school can be charged with the falling off. At present tin- tendency is for the enrollment to increase, as will be observed by the report appended concerning ENROLLMENT Enrollment, 1918-19 4&amp;J Enrollment. 1918-19, correspondence students.. Enrollment, Summer Term. 1910 7^ 85 • i.4«" Enrollment, 1919-20 4-^4 Enrollment, correspondence students 122 Enrollment. Study Center students 40 Enrollment. Summer Term, 1920 1,087 1 .67.? Enrollment. 19-io, to December 1 370 Enrollment. Correspondence students 129 Enrollment. Study Center students 173 681 GEORGE E. MARTIN, President Gentlemen : </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Number of Elementary Certificates granted since Dec. i, 1918 12 Number of Junior Certificates granted since Dec. 1, 1918 60 Number of Diplomas granted since Dec. 1, 1918 166 Number of A. B. Degrees granted since Dec. 1. 1918 29 Number of Advanced Rural Certificates granted since Dec. 1, 1918 10 Number of Elementary Rural Certfs. granted since Dec. 1, 1918 41 3i8 EXTENSION WORK There has been an earnest effort on the part of this institution o carry its services to the people through two important channels. )ne of these is through correspondence work, where the student does lot come in direct contact with the Institution but acquires his train - ng, so far as possible, through the means of themes written for omment and correction and in following the outlines of courses of eading. The other means is that of study centers. Wherever ten people will select some subject or subjects they wish to study, the nstitution has sent an instructor who takes charge of the class on r riday evenings or Saturdays, and attempts to carry the atmosphere of the normal school to the local center. The first named means. as will be observed from the increase above, has shown a steady ncrease. Ere long a special faculty will have to be appointed for uch work. The last named means has been especially popular dur - ng the fall months just passed. Twenty-five such centers are now in operation in the towns and villages surrounding Kearney. LIBRARY For the successful carrying on of the work outlined above, as well as that of the regular school activities, numerous additions and mprovements have been made in the library here, in the way of books and decorations of the walls. The number of volumes at present is 23,972. This, it will be noted, is an increase of 7,883 volumes since he last biennial report. GYMNASIUM The work in the splendidly equipped gymnasium, erected in 1916. has been enhanced by the addition to the faculty of a physical di - rector for men and one for women. Each of these teachers regularly is carrying work in physical training for the students of the institu - tion. Much good is resulting therefrom. During the present year a </seg>
            <seg id="p033">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 33 School Nurse has been added, whose services are of practical value to those carrying on the work just mentioned. It is the intention to make her work largely preventive, rather than curative, in her min - istrations to students. AFFILIATED RURAL SCHOOLS The work of the Rural School Department has been considerably broadened by the affiliation of several rural schools in the immed - iate vicinity. At present, affiliation has been effected between this institution and the Victor School, District No. 88, the Glenwood School. District No. 14, the Riverdale School, District No. 15, and the Collins School. Kearney City District. The head of the ruarl school department in the institution exercises supervisory powers over the schools named above, and the students of his department do practice teaching in them. The result is of benefit to the normal school and 10 the affiliated district. PERMANENT IMPROVEMENTS At the beginning of this biennium the State was in possession of an experimental farm of eighteen acres situated three miles south - west of the main building of this institution. In 1919 it became ap - parent that the land lying adjacent to the campus on the west and north would be purchased by home builders and a number of dwell - ings be placed quite near the normal school campus. Since the land was for sale, it seemed wise to the Normal School Board of Educa - tion to secure this land and add it to the campus. A trade was ef - fected by means of which the eighteen acre experimental farm was transferred to the hitherto owner of the land adjacent to the campus. and the latter became the property of the State and is now a perma - nent asset of the State Normal School at Kearney. This extended the campus about thirty-one acres and gives the campus an area of approximately fifty acres at the present time. It would be greatly wise if the State could see fit to purchase additional land to the east of the present plant to the extent of about one block. This would give room for an administration building, which is one of the things that will be needful within a comparatively few years. The advance in price of building property makes it evi - dent that such a thing should be consummated at the earliest pos - sible moment. OTHER NEEDS OF THE SCHOOL The need for a Training School Building in this institution is so obvious and has been mentioned in so many previous reports that </seg>
            <seg id="p034">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 34 it is not wise to enlarge upon it here. It will suffice la my that the need is no less urgent than hitherto. The most imminent need is that of suitable dormitory facilities to house the students. This need became a crying one during the past year. During the Summer Term of 1920 it was well-night impossible to accommodate alt students. A commodious, modern building, capable of caring for at feast two hundred students, should be erected during the next bienniutn. FINANCIAL STATEMENT Maintenance: Amount in fund December I, 1018 $ 8,Jof&gt;.8R Appropriation for Agricultural and Rural School purposes. r2,soono Additional appropriation January %, joio ao»ooo.oo $40,700.88 Expenditures: 1018 Dec. 14 Pay roll $ 6,413.30 iokj t_&gt;i George S. Dick. Pres.. reimbursement. ... 592.16 City of Kearney Water Wks., con. pipes 1,024.57 W. C. Van Andel &amp; Son. office expense 7.00 Radge &amp; Gaeiizel Co.. furniture 28.5" Harry Porter, office supplies 57-5° Harry Porter, office supplies 57-5° Tablet &amp; Ticket Co.. dept. supplies 7-12 Tablet ft Ticket Co.. dept. supplies 7.12 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co.. gen. supplies 31.78 T. F. Crawford, repairs 15-4° T. F. Crawford, repairs 15-4° W. F. Crossley, Collins Farm House est. 1,215.15 W. F. Crossley, Collins Farm House est. 1,215.15 George S. Dickk, Pres., traveling exp 17.60 George S. Dickk, Pres., traveling exp 17.60 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat. Co., gen. sup. 128.80 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat. Co., gen. sup. 128.80 Kearney Hdw. Co.. general supplies 100.55 Kearney Hdw. Co.. general supplies 100.55 Central Power Co.. light 195-8" Central Power Co.. light 195-86 City of Kearney Water Works 48.50 H. A. Webbert. printing and office sup. 30.10 The Willard F. Bailey Co., printing 166.86 The Willard F. Bailey Co., printing 166.86 Manuel-Scoonover Co.. furniture 6.25 Manuel-Scoonover Co.. furniture 6.25 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co.. fuel 426.32 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co.. fuel 426.32 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co.. lumber 10.15 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co.. lumber 10.15 Barrett Adding Machine Co., equipment 66.00 The Nebraska Teacher, office (adv.) 7-5" Midland Chemical Co.. janitor supplies 18.00 American Disinfecting Co., janitor sup. 167.83 L". S. Sanitary Products Go., janitor sup. 89.25 George Brothers, printing 100.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 35 Thomas Charles Co., dcpt. supplies 33-75 University Pub. Co., dept. supplies 7.00 Jan. 22 January pay roll 6,433.40 Mar. 3 February pay roll 6,86970 Mar. 12 Gco. S. Dick, Pres., reimbursement 635.44 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 76.00 W. R. Macauley, repairs 32.10 Central Power Co., light 108.78 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co., fuel 2,311.72 Beckley-Cardy Co., office supplies 8.03 H. A. Webbert, printing and office sup. 36.35 City of Kearney Water Works 34-25 United Chemical Co., janitor supplies. .. 12.50 American Disinfecting Co., janitor sup. 131.75 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 23.36 Klopp-Bartlett Co., office supplies 44.82 Bradner-Smith Co., office supplies 12.00 American Prtg. Co., printing Bulletins 155.00 The Korsmeyer Co., electric fixtures... 118.35 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co., janitor supplies 24.00 Yarnall-Waring Co., repairs, heat plant 13.00 Oliver Ditson Co., dept. supplies 2.13 A. T. Lockhead, office supplies 5.35 American Geographical Soc, dept. sup. 12.00 Middle-West School Review, advertising 10.50 Mar. J4 Pay roll 6,89400 May (1 Geo. E. Martin. Pres., trav. expenses... 38.60 S. A. Courtis, dept. supplies 27.05 Midland Chemical Co., janitor supplies 90.75 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., general sup 32.25 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co., dept. sup 39-74 Oliver F. Brown Prtg. Co., printing 126.60 E. A. Eck, repairs '. 12.55 The Jeffrey Mfg. Co., equip., heat, plant 730.00 A merican Multigraph Sales Co., repairs 26.05 Vonnecut Hdw. Co., repairs 2.46 Library Bureau, office supplies 66.87 Bradner-Smith Co., office supplies 21.00 The A. H. Andrews Co.. dept. supplies 23.70 Beckley-Cardy Co.. office supplies 8.88 Theo. B. Robertson Prod. Co., Jan. sup. 210.77 Zion lust. &amp; Ind.. office supplies 6.94 Win. M. Lewis &amp; Son, dept. supplies.... 9.00 Meek Lumber Co., dept. supplies 140.00 The McGraw Co.. lights 122.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION The Nebr. Sch. Sup. House., dept. sup. 1026 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising. 7.50 Columbia University, dept. supplies 1.79 Remington Typewriter Co., equipment.... 494-35 City of Kearney Water Works 26.60 Kearney Hdw. Co., general supplies 4.00 Katheryn Laughlin, Co. Supt., off. exp. 15.00 H. A. Webbert, printing and office sup. 12.35 T. F. Crawford, repairs 3.75 Gaston Music Co., dept. supplies 44-25 Kaufman &amp; Wernert, dept. supplies 27.61 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co., fuel 1476.14 Central Power Co., lights 86.42 W. F. Downing, janitor supplies 21.52 W. F. Crossley, Collins Farm House est. 1,296.14 Charles A. Hazlett, equipment 432.65 L. B. Sipple, traveling expenses 150.55 Geo. E. Martin, traveling expenses 122.87 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 290.62 569.93 $41,276.81 $41,276.81 Appropriation available March 19, 1919 .$240,000.00 1919 May 2 April pay roll _ _$ 6,604.65 May 24 May Pay roll 6,673.60 June 20 June pay roll 8,053.95 June 23 T. H. Bolte, office expense 48.00 F. C. Scott &amp; Son, furniture 24.35 A. C. Killian Clothing Co., dept. sup. 104.52 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 7.50 J. S. Elliott, traveling expenses 56.06 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., equip., gen. exp. 243.42 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co., fuel 1,708.90 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co., dept. sup 54-69 Oliver Brown Printing Co., printing 14-03 Kearney Hdw. Co., general supplies 82.66 Central Power Co., light 160.53 City of Kearney Water Works 42.10 H. A. Webbert, printing and office sup. 72.75 Kearney Daily Hub, prtg. and off. sup. 185.36 Monarch Note Book Co., dept. supplies 1.83 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., traveling exp 13.37 Pittsburgh Plate Glass Co., repairs 207.69 The Jeffrey Mfg. Co., equip., heat plant 89.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 37 Chas. A. Hazlett. equipment 6.00 W. J. Neal, repairs 347-25 Singer Sewing Machine Co., equipment 29.52 Middle-West School Review, adv 10.50 Midland Chemical Co., janitor supplies 171.00 Yawman &amp; Erbe Mfg. Co., furniture.... 125.10 American Disinfecting Co., janitor sup. 76.00 C. C. Birchard Co., dept. supplies 11.26 Intern'l Harvester Co., dept. supplies.... 10.23 Oliver Ditson Co., dept. supplies 50.67 Carpenter Paper Co., janitor supplies... 35-8o Nebr. School Sup. House, dept. supplies 28.35 U. S. Blue Print Co., dept. supplies 5.44 Souders Dept. Store., dept. supplies 142.30 Central Power Co., equipment 249.00 Hillyard Chemical Co., janitor supplies 12.50 Albert Pick Co., furniture 16975 The Globe-Wernicke Co., furniture 168.75 Educational Music Bureau, dept. sup..... 24000 Cocker Mfg. Co., repairs 25.65 O. C. Keckley Co., equipment 85.00 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 1,033.45 Henline-Armitage Drug Co., dept. sup. 6.50 July Ji July pay roll 8,233.70 Ausr. 14 The N. C. Leary Co., printing 1600 Munson Supply Co., office supplies 3.50 U. S. Sanitary Products Co., Jan. sup 14900 The Korsmeyer Co., repairs 1.88 Leedy Mfg. Co., dept. supplies 11.55 Nebr. School Supply House, furniture .... 140.50 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 66.67 "J. A. Stryker, pictures for advertising 40.00 H. A. Webbert, printing and office sup. 94-55 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., gen. sup 32.00 Kearney Floral Co., imp. of grounds 80.00 Kearney Hdw. Co., general supplies 34-27 W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co., fuel and lumber 20760 City of Kearney Water Works 66.00 Central Power Co., light 156.78 The Antelope, annual allowance 100.00 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., traveling exp 70.43 Manucl-Scoonover Co., furn., dept. sup. 20.60 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 68644 Aug. 28 August pay roll Ii755-oo Sept. 24 September pay roll _ 7.939-65 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">* STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Oct. 9 F. H. Gilcrest Lbr. Co.. lbr. and cement 21.35' Central Power Co., light 180.01 The Eclipse Paint &amp; Mfg. Co., repairs 104.00 City of Kearney Water Works 22.45 Geo. E. Martin, Pres.. traveling exp 101.54 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat. Co., general supplies and repairs 464.10 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co.. gen. sup 54-6i W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co.. lbr and fuel 334-5O The A H. Andrews Co.. furniture 720.00 Kearney Hdu. Co.. gen. sup. and repairs 5-J.u H. A. Webbert. printing and office sup. 49.25 Oliver F. Brown Ptg. Co., ptg. and sup. 58.67 Western Stamp &amp; Stencil Co., off. sup. 3.10 Cudahy Pkg. Co.. janitor supplies 9.00 The Gardner Gov. Co., rep. heat, plant 2.39 The Independent Co.. advertising 5.60 Lcedy Mfg. Co.. dept. supplies 3.48 Beckley-Cardy Co., office supplies 4500 American Disinfectant Co., Jan. sup 64.00 U. S. Sanitary Products Co., jan. sup 15.00 H. Channon Co., equipment 141-24 American Multigraph Sales Co., repairs 3.09 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., printing 50.00 Kaufman &amp; Wernert, dept. supplies 20.28 Crane &amp; McGlenen, printing 5.00 Geo. E. Martin, Pres.. reimbursement.... 883.93 Will J. Scoutt, land 11,000.00 Oct. 25 October pay roll 8,077.80 Nov. 26 November pay roll 8,214.25 Dec. 18 December pay roll '. 8,021.10 1020 Jan. 8 W. F. Downing, janitor supplies 41-85 Lambert's Bakery, dept. supplies 8.10 Midland Chemical Co., janitor supplies 312.50 Manuel-Scoonover Co., dept. supplies 58.00 Central Power Co., light 200.07 City of Kearney Water Works 52.70 S. A. Courtis, dept. supplies 7.95 Kearney Plumbing &amp; Heating Co., gen- eral supplies and repairs 171-85 Allan J. Coleman, repairs 7.58 The Tablet &amp; Ticket Co., dept. supplies 227 John A. Miller, office expense 10.00 Ravenna Creamery Co.. dept. supplies.... 8.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 39 Kearney Daily Hub., ptg. and off. sup 570.38 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co., dept. sup 107.44 Midway Motor Co.. repairs 4.50 Tollefsen Motor Co.. repairs 19.70 S. E. Webster, repairs .2.75 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., gen. sup., rep. 43.65 ■Oliver Brown Ptg. Co.. office supplies 28.50 \V. R. Macauley. repairs 21.00 Kanzler Electric Co., repairs 5.00 H. A. Webbert, printing and office sup. 54-00 Kearney Foundry &amp; Much. Co.. repairs 2.2. Gildner Bros., repairs 3.00 Dan Quinton. repairs 20.05 L. Schwarz Hdw. Co., equipment 18.00 W. F. Crossley, repairs 300.41 Amer. Wood Work. Mach. Co., dept. sup 11. 10 Kaufman &amp; Wernert. Dept. supplies 44. 1S Bidwell iS: McClure. imp. repairs 83.20 W. L Stickel Lbr. Co.. fuel and lumber 2.864.90 The A. Schoehriui Cn.. dept. supplies..- 43.4; Vawman &amp; Erbe Co.. dept supplies 24.25 Xelir. School Snp. 'House, dept. supplies 25.19 World Book Co:, dept. supplies 25.00 I eachers Col., Columbia, dept. supplies 2.80 Atkinson, Mentzer Co., dept. supplies... 2.23 State Normal School, Emporia Kans .51.20 Leslie B. Sipple, equipment 800.00 The A. H. Andrews Co.. dept. supplies 2.(1,5 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 7.50 Polk County Democrat, advertising 4.00 World Publishing Co.. advertising 28.00 The Bee Publishing Co., advertising 25.811 Publisher of Railway Guide, office exp. 2.50 The McGraw Co.. repairs 14.00 Rubon Wood Finishing Co.. janitor sup. 13.95 Western Boiler Compound Co., repairs 45.75 The Garlock Packing Co., repairs 5.55 Pann. Oil Consumer's Co., repairs -5-75 Anchor Packing Co., repairs 22.48 Medart Mfg. Co.. equipment 8.75 Geo. E. Martin, Pres.. traveling exp 00.06 J. J. Tawzer, repairs 37.50 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement... 461.74 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 68.55 Jan. 2b January pay roll 8.196.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Feb. 18 City National Bank, abstract 36.00 L. Schwarz Hdw. Co., dept. supplies.... 500 Kearney Hdw. Co., general supplies 56.23 Manuel-Scoonover Co., dept. supplies.... 137-75 Central Power Co., light 12283 Tollefsen Motor Co., repairs 04.08 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat. Co., rep., sup. 139.75 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., gen. rep., sup. 74-57 Kearney Daily Hub, ptg. and off. sup. 417.75 Dwight Merryman, improvement rep 47-04 C. V. Krebs, dept. supplies _ _ 147.14 Singer Sewing Machine Co., equipment 39-36 Dan Quinton, repairs 39-8i E. A. Eck, repairs 751-68 Geo. E. Martin, traveling expense „ 47-17 W. L. Sticke! Lbr. Co., fuel and lbr 2,598.68 City of Kearney Water Works 30.80 Ravenna Creamery, dept. supplies 7.50 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co., office sup. 5.10 L. R. Willis San. Pro. Co., janitor sup. 10.00 Kearney Floral Co., dept. supplies 5.25 Oliver F. Brown Ptg. Co., ptg and sup. 50.63 Kearney Foundry &amp; Machine Co., rep. 49.80 University Publishing Co., dept. supplies 13-45 Xebr. Sch. Sup. House, window shades 246.81 Theo. Presser Co., dept. supplies 10.22 Wrought Iron Range Co., repairs 9.00 Burroughs Adding Machine, equipment 206.25 J. J. Tawzer, improvement repairs 118.50 Manhattan Oil Co. of Nebr., Jan. sup. 14.00 H. A. Webbcrt, printing and office sup. 71.00 The Empire Store, office expense 3.00 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 447.65 Feb. 28 February pay roll 9.955-45 Mar. 28 March pay roll 9,881.35 Apr. 19 Central Power Co., light 222.99 Amer. Wood Work. Mach. Co., dept. sup. 27.91 Kearney Daily Hub, ptg. and sup 143-05 Tollefsen Motor Co., repairs 24.22 Geo. E. Martin, Pres.. traveling exp 135.92 Kearney Plumb. &amp; Heat. Co., rep., sup. 236.70 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., lumber 6746 A. C. Killians Clo. Co., dept. supplies.... 354.62 Ravenna Creamery Co., dept. supplies.... 6.00 H. A. Webbert, printing and supplies.... 45.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 41 Manuel-Scoonover Co., furniture 305.60 Oliver F. Brown Ptg. Co., off. sup 44-50 A. G. Spaulding &amp; Bros., dept. supplies... 10.73 City of Kearney Water Works 47-45 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co.. dept. sup 8.65 The N. C. Leary Co., printing 72.00 Schmelzer Arms Co., dept. supplies 57-55 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 71.10 Thos. D. Wood, dept. supplies 16.60 The University Prints, dept. supplies... 4.65 Stephen Blackhurst, dept. supplies 4.50 West. Boiler Com. Co., repairs, heat. pit. 40.95 The Garlock Pkg. Co., repairs, heat, pit. 17.15 The McGraw Co., lights 49-39 State N'ormal School, Emporia, Kans.. dept. supplies 15-70 Monarch Note Books Co.. dept. supplies 5.00 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, dept. supplies 10.00 Willis Music Co., dept. supplies 25.71 W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co.. fuel and lbr 2,821.51 Apr. 28 April pay roll 9.959-30 May 3 Geo. E. Martin. Pres.. reimbursement,... 1,048.14 May 24 May pay roll 10,009.75 June 23 June pay roll 11,931.90 July 1 F. C. Scott &amp; Son, furniture 47-75 Kearney Plumbing &amp; Heating Co., gen- eral repairs and supplies 136.55 Oliver F. Brown Prtg. Co., printing -10.53 R. \Y. Powell, traveling expenses...: 50.42 W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co.. fuel and lbr 2,036.58 Geo. E. Martin, Pres.. reimbursement... 982.90 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co., dept. sup 13.00 Carl Fischer, dept. supplies 94-28 A, C. Killian Clothing Co., dept. sup 3.75 Kearney Hdw. Co., gen. repairs and sup. n-35 Manuel-Scoonover Co.. dept. supplies.... 10.95 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., traveling exp 24.34 Kearney' Daily Hub, printing Bulletins 542.13 City of Kearney Water Works 38.60 Central Power Co., light 159.63 Nebraska Cash Grocery Co., dept. sup. 6.30 Ravenna Creamery Co., dept. supplies.... 28.12 H. A. Webbert, printing and office sup. 112.40 Crandall Pkg. Co., repairs, heating plant 3.54 Bureau of Edu. Meas., dept. supplies... 68.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION * Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 180.73 Amer. Wood Work. Mach. Co.. dept. sup. 10.02 Nebr. School Supply House, dept. sup. 36.96 Univ. of Chicago Book Store, dept. sup. 8.38 World Book Co.. dept. supplies 84.47 D. J. Schofield. janitor supplies 6.75 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co.. dept. supplies 10.50 Independent Pub. Co., advertising 8.40 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., gen. rep., sup. 129.50 July 24 July pay roll 13,042.10 Aug. 3 Kearney Plumbing &amp; Heating Co., gen- eral supplies and repairs _.. 145.95 W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co.. lbr. for repairs 167.25 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co.. lbr. for rep. 22.50 J. 1. Holcomb Mfg. Co., janitor supplies 26.64 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 32.85 Bee Pub. Co., printing 13-44 City of Kearney Water Works 23.50 Central Power Co., light 57-92 Ravenna Creamery, dept. supplies 8.25 Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co., dept. supplies 20.35 Cit-o. E. Martin. Pres., traveling exp 102.19 Oliver F. Brown Ptg. Co.. ptg. and sup. 359.50 Kearney Daily Hub,, ptg. and sup 342.95 Dennison Mfg. Co.. dept. supplies 4^9 Souders Dept. Store, janitor supplies.... 3/.00 The Anderson Studio, off. exp., adv 10.50 Kaufman &amp; Wernert. dept. supplies 59.64 A. Flanagan Co., dept. supplies 11.50 Crane &amp; McGlenen, printing 5.00 Bureau of Publications. T. C. dept. sup. 2.09 Sam Fox Pub. Co., dept. supplies 10.15 Pittsburgh Plate Glass Co.. repairs 63.49 A. G. Spalding- &amp; Bros., dept. supplies.... 409 W. F. Downing, dept. supplies 40.75 tico. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement... 56729 Aug. 23 August pay roll 2,784.15 Sept. 27 September pay roll 10,811.70 Oct. 15 West Disinfecting Co.. janitor supplies 397-25 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement... 921.52 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 92.53 Omaha Daily News, printing 19.95 The Anchor Pkg. Co., rep., heat, plant 2.62 Russell Sage Foundation, dept. sup 1800 Carl Fischer, dept. supplies 2.83 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 43 Reading Hdw. Co., repairs 2.46 VV. L. Stickel Lbr. Co., fuel and lbr 1,322.90 Halm &amp; Lackey, dept. supplies 3.74 Omaha Printing Co., equipment 29872 H. A. Webbert, printing and supplies... 123.10 L. R. Willis San. Prod. Co., Jan. sup.... 59-00 University of Illinois, dept. supplies The Bock Duplicator Co., equipment Rubon Wood Fin. Prod. Co., Jan. sup 21.40 52.00 11.00 Centra] Power Co., light 20096 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co.. gen. sup., rep. Western Brick &amp; Supply Co., repairs.... The Kearney Daily Hub, ptg. and sup. Chamberlain W'ther Strip Co., imp, rep. 88.64 2.50 908.26 3473 Nellie D. Gibbons, equipment 300.00 Cudahy Pkg. Co.. janitor suppTie 6.60 Eagle Ink Co., dept. supplies 2.50 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, furn. and sup Eclipse Paint &amp; Glass Co., rep, heat pit. 43976 361.90 Samuel Lewis, janitor supplies 7.00 The Jeffrey Mfg. Co.. equip., heat. pit. 132.08 L. Sonnoborn &amp; Son. janitor supplies.. 23-43 L. Schwarz Hdw. Co.. equipment 384.80 Kearney Floral Co., imp. of grounds.. 99.60 ToUefsen Motor Co.. repairs 303.14 Mattie Funnan, dept. services 110.00 Oliver F. Brown Ptg. Co., ptg. and sup. 118.00 Kearney Hdw. Co.. gen. rep. and sup. 6375 City of Kearney Water Works 73-6o Kearney News &amp; Sta. Co., dept. sup (jeo. E. Martin, Pres., traveling exp.... 7372 35-85 Oct. 27 October pay roll 11,091.00 Nov. 24 November pay roll 11,439.70 228,439.04 Dec. 1 Balance : $ 11.560.96 INSTITUTION CASH 1/ Amount in fund December 1, 1918 $ 8,824.30 1918 Dec. &lt;j Deposited with State Treasurer. Rec. No. 144604 873.59 1919 Jan 8 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 145512 2,032.16 Feb. 7 Deposited with State Treasurer. Rec. No. 146299 2.405.88 Mar. 6 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 147085 650.17 Apr. 7 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 147923 335-26 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 44 May 8 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 149145... June 20 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 150562.. July 9 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 151 114.. 545-68 91783 1.79304 1,024.42 251.10 Aug. 18 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 152197... Sept. 8 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 162866.. Oct. 30 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 154557. 1,004-95 470.38 Nov. 19 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 155336.. Dec. 4 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 155933.. 29O.45 1920 Jan. 5 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. N*o. 157174.. 281.22 1,014.25 Feb. 9 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 158239.. Mar. 11 Deposited with State Treasurer. Rec. No. 159341.. 698.16 646.50 427-53 754-52 Apr. 7 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 160371.. May 8 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 161516.. June 3 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 162383.. July 16 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 163879.. 2,573-36 1.654.36 1,912.13 Sept. 20 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 166692.. Nov. 17 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec. No. 168966. $31,381.24 Expenditures: ,9.8 Dec. 14 M. Worlock. voice instruction $ 79-63 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 70.00 1919 Jan. 2\ L. E. Knott Apparatus Co., lab 3505 Maxro-Ross Co.. typewriter 168.00 Geo. E. Dick, reimbursement 2,083.33 (irefffi Pub. Co., textbook 11.02 J. D. Hawthorne, dormitory I.50 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 26.89 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 52.45 Central Power Co., dormitory light 1 13.18 Dan Quinton, dormitory repairs 8.25 Williams, Browne &amp; Earle, textbook 1335 G. Schirmer. music 58-44 The John Church Co.. music 23.12 McKinley Pub. Co., textbook 10.08 The Century Co., textbook 11.52 The Macmillan Co., textbook 2.83 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 33-io Scott. Foresman &amp; Co.. textbook 421 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbook 8.14 Silver. Burdette &amp; Co.. textbook 6.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 45 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbook n.64 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook 12.00 American Book Co., textbook 12.00 A. C McClurg &amp; Co., textbook 17.77 Bausch &amp; Lonib Optical Co., lab 42.26 H. A. Small, dormitory repair work 25.10 Robinson-Miller Co., laboratory 14.05 Jan. 24 M. Worlock, voice instruction 73-50 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 81.38 Mar. 3 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 144.38 M. Worlock, voice instruction 119.88 Mar. 12 George S. Dick, Pres., reimbursement 69571 Nebr. Cash Grocery, laboratory 13.42 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook....: 92.00 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 35-53 Central Power Co., dormitory light 5779 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 31.15 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 44.16 The John Church Co., music 5.17 University Pub. Co., textbook 26.69 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbook 39-6o Univ. of Chicago Press, textbook 14.16 American Book Co., textbook 14.02 The Century Co., textbook 10.80 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbook 8.17 The Macmillan Co.. textbook 12.69 Chas. Scribner's Sons, textbook 61.97 Johnson &amp; Johnson, dormitory supplies 9.00 Mar. 25 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 123.38 May 7 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 132.13 Newson &amp; Co., textbook 3.75 J. B. Lippincott &amp; Co., textbook 18.00 Silver Burdett &amp; Co., textbook 4.06 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbook 43-2O The Macmillan Co., textbook 8.26 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook 6.30 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook 31.29 Vocational Supply Co., textbooic 81.10 Central Power Co., dormitory light 4170 Nebr. Cash Grocery, laboratory 4.48 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 20.70 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 7.20 University Pub. Co., textbook 9.14 The Gregg Publishing Co., textbook 13.64 American Book Co.. textbook 2279 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION May 24 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 131.25 M. Worlock, voice instruction 24.00 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 182.88 E. C. Tillotson, piano instruction 28.00 M. Worlock, voice instruction 35-87 Central Power Co., dormitory light 64.82 Kearney Steam Laundry, laboratory 24.90 City of Kearney water works, dorm 36.40 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 7.58 W. F. Shoemaker, dormitory repairs 119.20 Manuel-Scoonover Co., dorm, furniture 40.55 Row, Peterson Co., textbook 2.87 A. Flanagan Co., textbook 18.19 Babson Institute, laboratory 5.63 Charles Scribner's Sons, textbook 3.81 Univ. Publishing Co., textbook 5.25 G. Schirmer, music 103.40 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 76.44 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 54-57 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 182.88 E. C. Tillotson, piano instruction 51-63 Grace E. Steadmon, voice instruction.... 53-38 M. Worlock, voice instruction _ 105.50 Aug. 13 Charles Scribner's Sons, textbook 72.00 J. B. Lippincott, textbook 9.00 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 42-48 AHyn &amp; Bacon, textbook 21.42 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 120.96 Silver, Burdette &amp; Co., textbook 37.35 The Gregg Pub. Co., textbook 108.14 American Book Co., textbook 1536 World Book Co., textbook 28.86 University Pub. Co., textbook 2.44 Burroughs Adding Mach. Co., typew 300.00 Kansas State Normal School, textbook 13.20 University of Wisconsin, textbook 2.50 J. D. Saunders. laboratory 53-98 Nebr. Cash Grocery, laboratory...- 8.53 Kearney Plbg. &amp; Ht. Co., dorm, repairs 165.72 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 96.30 Central Power Co., dormitory light 64.82 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, laboratory 28.35 Gastou Music Co., music 123.40 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement... 341.90 Webb Pub. Co.. textbook 2.59 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 47 Charles E. Merrill Co.. textbook 9.14 Auk. 38 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 71-75 M. Worlock, voice instruction '. 62.13 Sept 24 Mrs. H. J. Hull 35.88 Oct. g Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 20.40 F. C. Scott &amp; Son, dormotory furniture 6.60 W. F. Crossley, dormitory repairs 884.74 City Water Dept., dormitory 22.35 Manuel-Scoonover Co., dorm, furniture 35-95 I'lu- Marine Biological Lab 70.21 Yawman &amp; Erbe Mfg. Co., typw. dept. 36.55 Kearney Artificial Ice Plant, laboratory 14.05 McKinley Pub. Co.. textbook 23.52 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement. 81.42 L'nderwood Typew. Co.. typcw. dept 223.03 Oct. 25 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 176.75 Florence Drake, piano instruction 14.00 -Nov. .«&gt; Mrs. H. J. Hull 205.63 Florence Drake 15.75 Dec. iS Mrs. H. ]. Hall 9^i 3 Florence Drake 17.50 1920 Jan. &lt;j The Macmillan Co.. textbook 1 ne .uacmiuan Co.. textbook 30.00 The F. VV. Faxon Co.. textbook 16.20 American Book Co.. textbook 21.87 The H. M. Rowe Co.. textbook 26.21 Bretano's textbook 23.48 Gaston Music Co.. music 30.95 Frankel Carbon &amp; Ribbon Coa.. typew. 36.00 L'nderwood Typrewriter Co 1.8s Central Power Co.. dormitory light 115.27 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 31.90 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 34.94 G. P. Putman's Sons, textbook Normal Cash Grocery, laboratory. 5-03 3-9» Remington Typewriter Co 140.60 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory •93-35 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co.. laboratory 1.67 Conrad Slide &amp; Projection Co., lab 61.60 The Will Corporation, laboratory 29.26 University Pub. Co.. textbook 23.58 D. C Heath &amp; Co., textbook 54-17 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook Scott, Foresman &amp; Co.. textbook 6.18 Houarhton Mifflin Co.. textbook 8.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">4* Silver, Burdette Co., textbook 40.04 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 12.48 Charles Scribner's Sons, textbook 6.33 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbook 21.73 The Century Co., textbook 16.94 Longsman, Green &amp; Co., textbook 25.31 Benj. H. Sanborn &amp; Co., textbook 4.29 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook -'4448 A. L. Burt Co., textbook 6.00 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 48.23 Jan. 26 H. J. Hull (Mrs.), piano instruction 11725 Feb. 18 McKinley Pub. Co.. textbook 15.00 Current Events, textbook 3.00 Gregg Pub. Co., textbook 28.50 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook 2903 J. B. Lippincott Co., textbook 58.00 L. E. Knott Apparatus Co., laboratory.... 42.44 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. laboratory 239.94 Remington Typewriter Co 3.50 Globe-Wernicke Co.. typewriting 315.00 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 25.05 Central Power Co.. light 74-79 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 42.39 Nebr. Cash Grocery. laboratory 8.68 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 22.99 U. S. Retail Store, dormitory 427.00 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbook 35-43 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 10.06 Feb. 27 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 147.00 Florence Drake 19.25 Mar. 25 Mrs. H. J. Hull 112.00 Florence Drake 12.25 Apr. 19 Charles Scribner's Sons, textbook 20.20 Central Power Co., dormitory light..-. 80.57 Nebr. Cash Grocery, laboratory 9.80 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 55.84 Gaston Music Co., music 7995 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., textbook 3.85 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 38.20 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory 80.15 L. E. Knott Apparatus Co., laboratory.... 3.43 Ben.. H. Sanborn Co.. textbook 3.22 G. P. Putnam's Sons, textbook 7.70 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 43-62 The Gregg Pub. Co., textbook 16.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 49 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook 10.28 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook 4.04 Richard G. Badger, textbook 18.00 The John Church Co.. music 34-58 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbook 27.45 Robinson &amp; Miller, laboratory 23.95 G. Schirmer, music 6.17 Apr. 28 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 147.88 Florence Drake 11.38 May 3 Geo. E. Martin. Pres., reimbursement... 64.83 May 25 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 140.00 Jui.e 23 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 68.25 Margaret Black, piano instruction 38.50 J. Horace Smithey. voice instruction 44.63 July 2 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement... 42.06 Oliver Ditson Co., music : 18.11 Central Scientific Co., laboratory 20.20 Vocational Supply Co.. laboratory 72.00 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbook 24.40 Silver Burdette &amp; Co., textbook 15.80 The Macmillan Co., textbook 17.03 Scott, Foresman Co., textbook 12.00 D. Appleton Co., textbook 5.07 McKinley Pub. Co.. textbook 22.50 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbook 38.97 Frankel Carbon &amp; Ribbon Co., typew 30.00 Longsman, Green &amp; Co., textbook 8.81 Little, Browne &amp; Co., textbook 24.00 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook 71-57 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook 20.16 Charles Scribner's Sons, textbook 3.43 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 51.60 Kanzler-Themanson Lbr. Co., lab 71.15 Central Power Co., dormitory light 61.86 Gaston Music Co., piano rental 45.50 H. A. Small, dormitory 10.10 Kearney Tea &amp; Coffee House, lab 62,69 July 24 E. C. Tillotson, piano instruction 84.88 Margaret Black, piano instruction 84.88 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 220.50 J. Horace Smithey, voice instruction.... 265.15 Aug. 3 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 26.85 Central Power Co., dormitory light 27.72 Manuel-Scoonovcr Co., dorm, furniture 35-5O Geo. H. Troxel Co., dorm, furniture 171.05 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 125.56 American Book Co., textbook 404.13 J. B. Lippincott Co., textbook 24.00 C. J. Mosher Co., typewriters 530.00 Underwood Typewriter Co 3.00 Vocational Supply Co., laboratory 41.60 The John Church Co., music 5.58 5.58 The Century Co.. textbook 14.85 Remington Typewriter Co _ 140.00 D. Appleton Co., textbook 28.32 Charles E. Merrill Co., textbook 20.38 Rowe. Peterson &amp;• Co., textbook 12.49 The F. W. Faxon Co., textbook 57-50 Albert Pick Co.. dormitory 585.00 Kearney Flour Mills, laboratory 7.50 The Gregg Pub. Co., textbook 28.11 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbook 40.00 The Macmillan Co.. textbook 30.00 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbook 18.29 Sept. J7 Mrs. H. J. Hall, piano instruction 50.31 rt 13 Goo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement... 1,291.77 Marine Biological Laboratory 81.44 Mcliuosh Stereopticon Co.. laboratory 33-34 City of Kearney Water Works, dorm 46.90 Central Power Co., dormitory light 57-98 Grand Island Typewriter Exc 10.00 The Ravenna Creamery Co., laboratory 10.89 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook 16.62 University Pub. Co., textbook 35-12 American Book Co., textbook 637.83 The Macmillan Co., textbook I3-5O Gaston Music Co.. piano rental 75-3O G. Schirmer, music 42.91 Remington Typewriter Co 335-75 Oct. 26 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 253.32 Elonore Kurth. voice instruction 69.56 Anita Householder, piano instruction.... 7.00 Nov. &gt;4 Mrs. H. J. Hull, piano instruction 246.75 Elonore Kurth. voice instruction 78.75 Anita Householder, piano instruction... 17.50 21,643.84 Dec. ! Balance $ 0.737.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 51 LIBRARY Amount in fund December I, 1918. 1918 ..$ 6,760.05 Dec. 9 Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec No. 144604 190.00 1919 Jan. 8 Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Rec Rec. Rec. Rec Rec. Rec. Rec. Rec. Rec. Rec. Rec. No. 145512. No. 146299. No. 147085. No. 147923 No. 149145 No. 150562. No. 151 1 14. No. 152197. No. 154557 No. 155336. No. 155933 15.00 Feb. 7 110.00 Mar. 6 50.00 Apr. 7 10.00 May 8 10.00 June 20 120.00 July 9 2,100.00 Aug. 18 25.00 Oct. 30 685.00 30.00 Nov. 19 Dec. 4 Deposited with State Treasurer 40.no 1920 Jan. 5 Deposited with State Treasurer Rec. Rec, Rec. Rec Rec Rec Rec. Rec Rec No. 157174 No. 158239. No. I5934I No. 1 60371.. No. 161516. No. 162383 No. 163879 No. 166692 No. 168966 20.00 160.00 Feb. 9 Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Deposited with State Treasurer, Mar. 1 1 30.00 25.00 Apr. 7 May 8 10.00 June 3 85.00 July 16 2,965.00 Sept. 20 25.00 Nov. 17 885.00 $«4J55-O5 Expenditures 1919 Ian. 21 A. C. licCterg &amp; Co.. books The H. W. Wilson Co., books. \V. A. Huccnbaugh. books Army &amp; Navy Journal ', .$ 49009 24.00 6.80 6.00 The U. S. Infantry Association Geo. S. Dick, Pres., reimbursement Nebraska State Historical Society.... A. C. McClurg &amp; Co 3-50 13.21 Mar. i_» 2.00 144.72 Bureau of Publications 11-53 J. M. Hansen-Bennett Mag. Agcy. I. H. Jensen, books 326.00 2.70 Alexander Hamilton Institute The H. W. Wilson Co., books Geo. S. Dirk. Pres.. reimbursement 33-6o 44-50 Q.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 52 May 7 The Lougsman, Green Co., books 1.35 York Blank Book Co., printing 101.99 Waldorf Bindery Co 4.90 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 18.77 June 23 Ward Bros., books 18.30 Art Institute of Chicago, pamphlets 4.06 A. L. A. Publishing Board 1.11 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 1.00 The H. R. Huntting Co., books 1 19.37 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 526.87 The Kearney Daily Hub, printing 11.55 Nemaha County Republican, book 1.75 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 40.47 Aug. 15 The H. R. Huntting Co., books 3.34 The Nat'l Geog. Soc, books 13.00 Teachers College, Columbia Univ _ 1.80 Library Bureau, furniture 18174 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 276.48 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 4774 Alma L. Healey, books 3.10 E. A. Miller, picture frames 39-15 Oliver F. Brown Printing Co 6.50 Oct. 9 Bureau of National Lit 77-50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 11.35 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 31.22 1920 Jan. 8 Boyer Bros., books 160.23 Albert S. Huesser, book 1.50 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 27.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., books 75-90 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 7.85 Oliver F. Brown Printing Co 10.00 Feb. 18 Geo. E. Martin, Pres.. reimbursement 1+65 Bee Publishing Co 2.25 H. W. Wilson Co., books 47.85 J. M. Hansen-Bennett Mag. Agcy 386.05 Mississippi Valley Historical Soc 4.00 H. P. Whitmore, pictures 204.00 Gaylord Bros., supplies I3- J 5 World Pub. Co., subscription :. 6.50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 369.79 Apr. 17 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 315-74 Art Metal Const. Co.. furniture 585.00 National Geographic Society 2.75 The H. W. Wilson Co.. books 1600 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 53 Harry P. Whitmore, picture 23.75 Nebr. State Historical Society 2.00 Waldorf Bindery Co 65.98 Apr. 21 Oliver F. Brown Printing Co 7.50 May 3 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 12.44 July 2 Daniel H. Newhall, books „. 13.25 Wheeler Pub. Co., books 34-20 McGraw-Hill Book Co 4.25 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 293.83 Geo. F. Cram Co., book 9.00 The Arthur H. Clark Co., books 8.94 The Daily News Pub. Co 2.50 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 4.54 Aug. 3 The Mentor Co., books 58.00 McGraw-Hill Co 4.25 The American Educational Soc, books 98.10 Student Volunteer Movement 2.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books .. .. 384.17 Bee Publishing Co., subscription 8.00 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 3.39 Eames-Luckett Corporation, books 12.00 Oct. 13 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 8.40 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 4.00 Geo. E. Martin, Pres., reimbursement.... 12.75 L. C. Smith Bros., typewriter 95-6o 6,088.19 Balance December I, 1920 $ 8,266.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Peru, Nebraska E. L. ROUSE, President Peru, Nebraska, December 2, 1920. To the Nebraska State Board of Education : Gentlemen : I am pleased to submit herewith the biennial report of the fern State Normal School. This report includes a detailed statement of the receipts and expenditures for the biennium up to December 1, 1920. I am taking the liberty of submitting an estimate of the funds needed for this institution for the next biennium. There is set forth a brief outline of the essential needs of the institution. If they arc to do their part in meeting the present emergency in education it seems to me the slogan for the State Normal Schools should be, "A trained teacher for each boy and girl in Nebraska." You will find a detailed statement of the attendance by years. This smaller attendance is common to all Normal Schools of tin- United States. There is need for a vigorous campaign to awaken the public to the startling shortage of trained teachers and to enlis' their interest in recruiting students for the Normal Schools. BUILDINGS AND MATERIAL EQUIPMENT Improvements During This Biennium Mt. Vernon Hall, the girls' dormitory, has been greatly improved. The building has been replastered throughout, new floors laid, walls inted, and woodwork revarnished. The bathrooms have been fitted with the most up-to-date equipment, including shower baths. The dining room and kitchen in connection with the dormitory have been completely remodeled. We have taken over the boarding department and are conducting it as a state institution. It is proving highly satisfactory. We have constructed during the biennium a coal storage building. This re-enforced concrete structure was built by our own force at a very limited expense, when the annual saving it insures is considered. It permits us to store during the summer time 1500 tons of coal. We have just completed the paving of a 24-foot road across the </seg>
            <seg id="p055">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 55 campus with a spur to the coal storage plant. This was done at ;i cost of $20,000. One needs only to see the improvement to know thai it was money well invested. Needs for tbe Coining Biennium The most imperative need of the institution is a new Science building. Tbe old frame structure which we have been compelled to use for this important department is entirely inadequate. A new modern fireproof building should be constructed at once. It would probably cost $125,000. The old Normal Hall, which has stood since the organization of the school, is practically useless in its present condition. The south wing should be wrecked. There should be an appropriation to re - model and make modern in every way the north wing. It could then he used for the Music Department, Estimated cost $35,000. There seems to be no reasonable way to correct the poor accous - lics of our Auditorium. I suggest that the Auditorium be converted into a gymnasium and that the present basement gymnasium be remodeled so as to provide a swimming pobl and adequate locke 1 rooms. Estimated cost $25,000. PROFESSIONAL ATTAINMENTS During the biennium the school has employed a trained nurse as a regular faculty member. We have rented a suite of rooms which is known as the school infirmary. Each year every pupil in the train - ing school is given a thorough physical examination, and recom - mendations are made to parents. The health of all students is care - fully considered. We are certain that this department keeps our student body much more efficient and is saving hundreds of dollars each year for the student body. During the biennium we have greatly increased our extension woi k through study centers and correspondence courses. For the school year 1919-20 we enrolled 142 students in study centers and 42 in correspondence courses. The advantages of a Field Director are very apparent. From practically every community he visited, he brought recruits. The in - creased enrollment of men is due largely to his work. By keeping in direct touch with the work of our graduates, he is able to bring back many valuable suggestions for not only the training school but the various departments. There has been a steady increase in the enrollment for the Senior College work. During the biennium more than one hundred students have been enrolled in this department. We have granted 23 A. B. Degrees this biennium. It seems to me the time has come when the Normal Schools should be recognized as Teachers' Col- </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 leges. This recognition is given the Normal Schools of Iowa, Colo- rado, Missouri, and many other states. NEEDS FOR THE COMING BIENNIUM The following estimates represent the minimum needs for the biennium beginning April I, 1921 : 1. Salaries and Wages : Administration, salaries of president and office force $ 40,282 Faculty 183,342 Assistants 7.300 Employees 26,576 2. Administrative expenses, including postage, telegraph and telephone, freight, express, drayage, water, printing, ad - vertising 15,000 3. Supplies, office supplies, fuel, educational supplies 35,000 4. Material : Buildings and grounds, machinery, power plants, trucks 8,500 r Lands and Buildings, original construction, additions and improvements 200,000 t Equipment, office furniture, fixtures, and equipment, labo - ratory, books, magazines, and maps 7,500 Total maintenance $523,500 ENROLLMENT Regular Summer Regular Summer Year School Year School 1918-19 1919 1919-20 1920 Collegiate students in resident attendance 263 416 221 535 Secondary students in resident attendance 186 121 95 147 Correspondence students 36 37 42 Study center students . 142 Total 485 574 500 682 Training school, kindergarten to tenth grade, inclusive 181 109 176 82 Affiliated rural school 37 42 Grand Total 703 683 718 764 t^tion of the Appropriations Funds of the Peru State Normal School, Peru, Nebraska, December 1, 1920. MAINTENANCE FUND </seg>
            <seg id="p057">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 57 Dec. 14 E. L. Rouse, Prin., December salaries....$ 6,644.84 Transferred 12.sm.tx 1919 Jan. 6 Sinclair Refining Co., oil 54-00 Standard Electric Time Co., clock rep. 8.06 Standard Oil Co., oil and gas 13.65 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., supplies 83.44 Stacy Vance, 63 hours work 21.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal.... 591.07 Nebr. Material Co., power house sup 10.00 Richard Overholt, 112 horus work 33.60 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 262.29 E. L. Rouse, traveling expense 19-95 Laurance Rouse. 54 hours work 16.20 R. E. Shaver, 89 hours work 26.70 H. M. Mackprang, general supplies 4140 W. W. Mardis, general supplies 26.00 Murray Iron, Works Co.. repairs 32.00 Nebraska City Iron Works, bar casting 10.78 H. U. Landolt, D. S. supplies 90.14 H. W. Lawrence, hauling 7.00 H. W. Lawrence, 398 hours work 145.60 N". C. Leary Printing Co., printing 4405 S. W. Hacker, printing and supplies.... "93-35 H. Hallenbeck, supplies 54.60 C. G. Kingsolver, water rent 318.44 E. E. Good, Agt., infirmary rent 45-OO T. F. Gockley, 367 hours work 133.00 Mrs. L. L. Fuller, repair bass viol 10.00 Carl Flau, 63 hours work 18.00 Fisher Bros., general supplies 64.03 D Donovan &amp; Son, supplies 29.85 W. N. Delzell, S. A. T. C. trips 35.18 Crane Co., powerhouse supplies 99.28 Earl Coulter, hauling coal 68.50 Cincinnati Regalia Co., flags 29.06 Thomas Charles Co.. Tr. Sch. supplies.... 70.81 W. W. Barnes, general supplies 41-55 Roy F. Boyer, 112 hours work 33-6o Meek Lumber Co., lumber... 838.76 The Garland Co., one barrel protex 75.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Jan. 22 January payroll .-. 6,731.00 Feb. 21 February payroll 7,117.30 Mar. 10 American Book Co., Tr. Sch. books 6.71 American Elec. Heater Co., M. T. rep 3.55 W. W. Barnes, supplies 47-65 G. L. Barnett, infirmary rent 105.00 H. C. Bates, brooms 10.00 Burgess-Granden Co., sup., brascolites 327.40 Bruce Publishing Co., supplies 7.50 E. P. Carey, livery trips 20.25 H. Channon Co., M. T. supplies 232.25 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 13.50 J. C. Chatelain, supplies, clocks 18.00 Central Scientific Co., chemical sup 71.56 Cornell-Searl Co., repairs 13.60 C. F. Farley, work powerhouse 11.70 Fisher Bros., supplies for departments 00.32 Ginn &amp; Co., Training School supplies.... 26.82 T. F. Gockley, work powerhouse 18.55 American Printing Co., letter heads 105.00 S. W. Hacker, printing 305.80 Hillyard Chemical Co., toilet paper 100.00 H. H. Humphreys, running engine 6.60 King Foundry Co., globes 21-34 H. U. Landolt, department supplies 04.19 H. W. Lawrence, work powerhouse 86.05 W. W. Mardis, supplies 15.35 Marshall Field &amp; Co., Stewart machine 4.30 Yock Michel, hauling coal 404.05 Middlewest School Review, advertising 10.50 Milwaukee Dustless Brush Co., Jan. sup. 47-77 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, supplies 29.32 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Jacob North &amp; Co., envelopes 95-°o North Western Sch. Sup. Co., desks 23.75 A. J. Nystrom &amp; Co., one map 11.75 Oliver Machinery Co., supplies 15.00 Harry Porter, paper 27.20 The Perolin Co. of America, met. treat. 55.00 Louis W. Roettger, jan. for infirmary 45-00 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 144-50 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 1,49521 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 229.31 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., filing cabinet 2332 Scott Foresman &amp; Co., Tr. Sch. supplies 6.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 59 Sinclair Refining Co., cup grease 10.92 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., p. h. sup. 50.40 Underwood &amp; Underwood, sup. Fr. dept 27-55 Standard Oil Co., oil 82.89 LeMoyne Vance, hauling coal 18.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal.... 2,192.52 The Van Evern Co., book covers 68.00 E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co., keys 7.80 H. M. Mackprang, supplies 53-95 Transferred from General Fund 6,533.19 Mar. 19 March payroll , 6,891.50 Apr. 25 Vouchers dated March 31, 1919: Laurance T. Rouse, B. M. Normalites.... 100.00 The H. W. Wilson Co., subscriptions.... 21.08 E. L. Rouse, cash advanced, supplies.... 251.17 Irving G. Banghart Co., supplies 1576 L. R. Adams, hauling 16.12 Elmer Allgood, work and hauling 87.25 H. Channon Co., supplies 83.05 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 13-94 Cornell-Searl Co., covers and frames.... 455-52 Eugene Dietzgen Co., supplies 86.83 Mrs. H. M. Dressier, milk and cream 13-19 A. Flangan Co., map and chart 9.44 Katherine Foster, salary 50.00 S. W. Hacker, printing 2847 M. Alice Hanthorn. traveling expense 8.85 Arthur Hayes, hauling and work 82.87 Imperial Brush Co., brushes 45-20 The Library Bureau, furniture 103.35 H. M. Mackprang. supplies 27.10 The Macmillan Co., books 24.76 Manual Arts Press, books 15.00 McKinley Publishing Co., books 16.25 M. C. Medley, Water Com, water rent 283.17 Meek Lumber Co., material and cement 1,032.77 Nebraska Material Co., bars 1,300.00 Omaha Hardwood Lbr. Co.. M. T. mtrl. 77.60 F. A. Rauch &amp; Co., M. T. material 38.96 Remington Typewriter Co., repairs 7.35 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 36.13 John E. Scheetz, work 12.00 G. Shirmer, Inc., music 10.85 Sinclair Refining Co., oil 43-O0 V. A. Sink, work 21. 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Standard Oil Co., oil and gas 45-10 Underwood Typewriter Co., machines.... 105.00 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., repairs.... 18.00 Austin Vanderford, hauling 15.20 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., biology supplies 12.30 Western Electric Co., repairs _ 23.25 Williams, Browne &amp; Earle Co., slides.... 10.43 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal.... 1,963.94 Julius Wey, hauling 43 33 F. W. Setzer, hauling "5-25 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 2,356.09 D. Appleton &amp; Co., books 21.86 Nebraska Material Co., supplies , 30.00 Betty Lauman, Bus. Man. Peruvians.... 200.00 Chas. Haas, work on new building 303.19 John W. Hannaford, work 51.00 T. F. Gockley, work 37.20 Guy E. Gamble, hauling 49-55 C. F. Farley, work 36.00 G. L. Barnett, infirmary rent 30.00 W. W. Barnes, supplies 12.30 J. C. Bare, work 15.00 J. W. Able, work and hauling 85.12 Frank Majors, work 21.00 H. U. Landolt, supplies '. 21.18 Ellis Wilson, work 72.60 Redfern &amp; Ellenberger. D. S. supplies.... 1207 Mamie R. Mutz, study centers 21.63 Eldie Cameron, work 25.05 T. R. Raines, work 18.00 Balance May 31. 1919 39-59 $48,571-66 $48,571.66 MAINTENANCE Biennium beginning April 1, 1919. Appropriation biennium beginning April I, 1919. .$250,000.00 April payroll $ 7,060.70 May payroll 6,911.10 June payroll 7,707.16 June 23 F. C. Jean, traveling expenses 15.24 I. A. Hull, work at dorm 44-50 Kingsley. work powerhouse 136-95 Hugh House, pr. house and dorm work 132.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 61 Arthur Hayes, work powerhouse 48.30 A. Hospe Co., pianos and tuning 742.00 John Hannafoid, work powerhouse.... 51.30 S. W. Hacker, supplies 124.65 Mrs. T. F. Gockley, board, Mr. Davis.... 52.90 T. F. Gockley, work dormitory 192.00 Fisher Bros., general supplies 22.98 Farmers Lumber Co., flooring 814.18 Cedric Farley, work powerhouse 11.40 Will Dowd, work powerhouse 71.10 Eugene Dietzen Co., files 39-52 Chas. H. Ditson Co., music 12.18 Gaylord Chase, work powerhouse 32.70 Harold Brown, work powerhouse 15.00 Mrs. Maude Cowell, steno and b'kk'p. 7500 W. M. Davis, plastering 291.25 H. Channon Co., M. T. supplies 44.02 J. C. Bare, work dormitory 57-00 Eldie Cameron, work dormitory 105.45 Bausch &amp; Lomb Opt. Co., biology sup. 23.82 VV. W. Barnes, general supplies 59-8o Ellis Wilson, p'rhouse and dorm work 121.95 E. P. Carey, livery trips 27.75 Herman Walters, work dormitory 45-OO Stacy Vance, work powerhouse 1650 LaMoyne Vance, work powerhouse 6.25 Roy E. Shaver, work powerhouse 12.00 Sunderland Bros. Co., plaster, bars 146.10 Warren Stephenson, work powerhouse 20.70 Standard Oil Co., kerosene 11.69 F. W. Setzer, hauling to dorm 43-58 Isaac Robirds, Jr., work powerhouse.... 25.50 T. R. Raines, work at dormitory 160.60 Loyd V. Prante, work powerhouse 37-20 Plant World, rest'd'dizing atmometers 15.60 Richard Overholt, work dormitory 46.50 Perolin Co. of Amer., metal treatment 65.50 W. L. Neal, work powerhouse 30.00 Ralph Miller, work dormitory 27.00 U. C. Meyer, contract work dorm 86.00 Geo. Meyer, plastering 288.75 Meek Lumber Co, lumber 84.75 Geo. A. Medsker, base ball supplies 8.00 H. M. Mackprang, general supplies 74—4 Carl Mackprang. work powerhouse 32.70 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">6. STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION William Little, work powerhouse 18.00 Carl Lehrman, work dormitory 18.00 H. U. Landolt, D. S. supplies „. 71.51 Korsmeyer Co., repairs 9.95 W. N. Delzell, traveling expenses 6640 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 428:04 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 38.36 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., supplies 10.59 E. L. Rouse, cash advanced 260.69 Elmer Allgood, hauling for powerhouse 22.80 July 16 July payroll 7,198.30 Aug... 15 L. K. Willis San. Prod. Co., dressing.... 65.00 West Disenfecting Co., pipe Klenzo... 9.00 Herman Walters, work dormitory 7.50 Stacy Vance, work powerhouse 121.85 LaMoyne Vance, work powerhouse 43-75 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., supplies 47-79 Warren Stephenson. work powerhouse 43-20 Standard Oil Co.. gasoline and oil 23.28 Sinclair Refining Co., oil 64.00 Laurancc Rouse, work dormitory 12.75 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 97-36 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 221.58 N^ R. Rogers, chain 5.00 Redfern &amp; Ellenberger, D. S. supplies 12.37 Tom Rains, work dormitory 1 18.75 Andrew Rader, work powerhouse 76.25 Plant Study Co., botanical supplies 6.94 Richard H. Overholt, work dormitory 90.75 Donald If. Overholt, work dormitory.... 17.50 E. J. Newman, printing 27-75 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, dept. supplies 37.64 Middlcwest School Review, 6 mo. adv. 15-75 U. C. Mayer, work dormitory 296.84 Meek Lumber Co., lumber 988.97 M. C. Medlry, water rent 175-92 Frank Majors, use of wagon 20.00 H. M. Mackprang, supplies 53.75 Carl Mackprang, work powerhouse 1 17-42 E. Lyle Laughlin, work powerhouse 54.75 Joseph Krepela, work powerhouse 41-70 J. A. Hays, traveling expenses 13.41 S. W. Hacker, printing 6.00 Otis Gregg, work dormitory 43-5O The drafanola Shop, records 7.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 63 T. F. Cocklcy, work dormitory 171.00 Harry E. Gockley, work dormitory 12.00 Fisher Bros., departmental supplies 259.1 1 Elmer Docal, gasoline engine 105.00 D. Donovan &amp; Son, departmental sup. 10.50 Mark Delzell, work dormitory 17.50 Crane Co., repairs and supplies 21.57 Cornell-Searl Co., supplies 133.06 Gaylord Chase, work powerhouse 111.70 H. Channon Co., M. T. supplies 9.48 Central Scientific Co., supplies 38.82 Harold Brown, work powerhouse 83.75 W. W. Barnes, departmental supplies.... 17-95 Auburn Auto Co., truck complete 4,708.00 Elmer Allgood, hauling at powerhouse 18.00 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 114.81 Sept. 4 August payroll 1,911.30 Sept. 22 September payroll 71639.96 Oct. 8 State Journal Co., advertising 12.00 Irl W. Wright, shades for dormitory.... 184.50 Elmer E. Wilson, work powerhouse 21.00 Julius Wey, campus improvement 27.00 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., biology supplies 20.23 Whitebreast Coal &amp;• Lbr. Co., coal 473-86 Stacy Vance, work powerhouse 75-25 Wm. E. Thomas, work powerhouse 11.70 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., supplies 8.49 Sunderland Bros. Co., m'ble, tile work 2,562.05 Star Publishing Co.. advertising 12.60 Standard Oil Co., kerosene 23.26 Mrs. L. Sharrar, board and room 15.75 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 15.10 E. L. Rouse, Prin., dept. supplies 82.00 Tom Rains, work dormitory 35-O0 Andrew Rader, work powerhouse 47-25 R. H. Overholt, work dorm, and pr. hse. 103.25 Burgess-Nash Co., toweling 66.50 John Able, campus improvement 57-00 Ralph Allen, campus improvement 91.00 W. W. Barnes, departmental supplies 28.60 Bausch &amp; Lomb Opt. Co., lab. supplies 13.88 W. Buettgenbach. work campus 3I-I5 Harold Brown, work powerhouse 23.80 Cornell Photo Supply Co., print, slides 14.00 Claflin Printing Co., printing 58.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Gaylord Chase, work powerhouse 95-25 Crane Co., supplies , 133-37 Cornell-Searl Co., dorm supplies 9 2 6-93 W. M. Davis, plastering dorm 71-25 Geo. Daugherty, work powerhouse 33 60 S. W. Hacker, printing 189.50 Hillyard Chemical Co., janitor supplies 117.00 Herbert Hallenbeck, dep. and repairs.... 6.32 Ctis Gregg, work dormitory 63.00 T. F. Gockley, work dormitory i4'-75 H. E. Gockley, work dormitory 24.50 Fisher Bros., general supplies 150.75 Mark Delzell. work dormitory 84.00 Carl Mackprang, work powerhouse....... 80.50 Industrial Chem. Sup. Co., janitor sup. 7.50 H. U. Landolt, general supplies 60.90 H. M. Mackprang, general supplies 46.76 Lincoln Tent &amp; Awning Co., curtains 950 H. M. Mackprang, water rent 196.09 W. W. Mardis, dept. supplies 17.20 Meek Lbr. Co., M. T. and powerhouse 415-64 U. C. Meyer, contract work dorm 160.05 Yock Michel, hauling coal, work 97-8i Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, exam, paper 75-00 Nelson Hanne Ptg. Co., biology sup 5.37 Donald M. Overholt, work dormitory.... 103.25 E. J. Newman, printing 10.65 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 75-6o W. N. Delzell, field exp. and fair 109.36 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 194-87 VV. G. Speer, traveling expenses 21.99 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 514-17 Oct. 22 October payroll 8,013.05 Nov. 20 November payroll 7,922.20 Dec. 12 December payroll 7,900.35 1920 Jan. 5 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 1,970.06 Irl W. Wright, general supplies 35-95 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., basketball 18.20 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal.... 876.60 Sinclair Refining Co., oil 80.50 Stacy Vance, work 58.80 Tucker Shean Co., carbon paper 20.00 Standard Oil Co., oil and gasoline 31-43 University Pub. Co., general supplies.... 30.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 65 Sun. Much. &amp; Sop. Co.. coal barrows 26.00 Sumlcrlarid Kros. Co.. marble and tile 17.56 YV. (I. Specr. traveling K. L. Rouse. I'rin.. gen-e E. L Rouse, I'rin.. work K. I.. Roust, traveling expenses 11.35 ;il supplies 897.82 xpenses 68.56 car coal . .. 27.^6 sketball. 60.05 Biulue &amp; (iinn/el Co., c Mrs. Anna Rogers, oil F. A. Rauch &amp; Co., M. Kami McXallv &amp; Co., 1 8.80 invas stove s.oo T. material... - 34-O5 24 (XI ivanced.. 233.3; ! stands 1 1 ~.i« ■ 1'atil Monroe, slides Meek Lumber Co.. ti Meek Lumber Co., ci coal 754.35 1 1 I'i Mi issner I.. 228.00 Lloyd .1. Hay-, w 177.80 S. W. Hacker, supplu I . 1- . 1 iockle\ . \\ 6rt 45 -50 Fisl ul.all 322.90 Federal j s 10.36 us Carl Da I. P. CI; Churchill &amp; Gt 1 and instruction 157.00 .1. \V. Able, haulinji Schmelzer Arms C \i. L, Rouse, Priii.. casl Allan Pick &amp; Co.. toil I'rann Co.. training school art.. . 211.20 I Ik' Plant Study Co., botany supplies 11.56 •V ). Xv.stroni \" Co.. maps. FrYli. geog. 10.64 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, supplies 103.50 27-50 Meek Lumber Co., r&lt;&gt;:il . 1,600.37 H. M. Mackprang, locks for dorm... 412.29 H. U. Lartdolt, training school supplies 14.10 The Korsmeyer Co., general supplies... 160.39 L. E. Knott Apparatus Co., P. S. sup 11.20 J. \Y. Jenkins Sons Mus. Co., orchestra 3427 H. Hallenbeck f&gt;9 45 71.67 Chas. 11. Ditson Q Devoe &amp; Reynolds, W. N. Delzell. trav I. yon &amp; Healy, mus </seg>
            <seg id="p066">STATE HOARD OF EDUCATION W. VV. Barnes, general supplies 23.82 Auburn Automobile Co., war tax truck 73.20 Ralph Allen, work 14.00 M. (. Medley, water rent 319.82 Jan. 23 January payroll 7,768.75 Feb. 18 Raymond Huffer. Xormalites 100.00 J. W. Jenkins Sons Mus. Co., band rep. 12.64 The Korsmeyer Co., powerhouse sup. ... 197.87 H. I". Landolt, D. S. supplies 4418 H. W. Lawrence, hauling one car coal 28.88 The \. C. Leary Co.. emb. letterheads 23.25 H. M. Mackprang, genera] supplies 30.85 Corwin Medley, powerhouse work 49-70 Mirk Lumber Co.. lumber and coal. 1,072.61 Hillvard Cliem. Co., janitor supplies 125.OO C. W. N\al, hauling one car coal 27.23 \. O. W-Imid Mfg. Co., depreciation rep. 86.03 Memaha County Herald, payroll sheet&gt; 12.00 Pt-rnliii Co. of Amer.. boiler treatment 80.00 Tin Pilgrim Press, chapel hymnals 120.01) E. I.. Rouse. 1'rin.. advertising 7290 Schmei.zer Anns Co., basketball 17.34 E. I.. Rouse, prill., dept. supplies 136 54 F. W. Setzer. hauling one car coal 32.25 \Y. G. Spier, traveling expenses i/.fx&gt; Standard Oil Co., oil 83.25 Sunderland Bros. Co., coal and one rod 703.07 Sund. Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., dept. repairs... 74.45 The Surety Guard Co.. M. T. material 39-OO Wards Nat. Sci. Kstab., zoology sup 82.35 Whin-breast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. coal 1,356.24 \V. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. dip's, gen. sup. 113.12 West Disenfecting Co.. janitor sup 31.20 E. I.. Rovtse, Prin.. cash advanced 2,519.71 Henry He.il C hem. Co., biology sup 8.05 Lloyd J. Hays, work at powerhouse 22.40 H. Hallenbeck, gas 72.51 S. W. Hacker, printing and papers 98.52 S. W. Hacker, catalogs and stationery 947.50 Fisher Bros., department supplies 74-51 Crane Co.. depreciation repairs 81.7^) Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 52.77 Lloyd Bertwell, hauling one car coal.... 19.09 W. W. Barnes, department supplies .... 23.77 Irving &lt;i. Kanghart Co., art material... 9.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 67 Fer Pel) Mar. 21 Apr. K) A \; May i(j lime Ralph Alien, work at powerhouse. 43-4O W. N. Delzcll, traveling expenses 50.05 \y. G. Speer. traveling expenses 14.31 14-31 E. L. Rouse. Priii.. cash advanced 459-o8 E. L. Rouse. Priii.. cash advanced 459-O8 E. L. Rouse. Prin.. dept:. sup. and ser\ . 105.93 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 128.44 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 128.44 F. A. Ranch &amp; Co., M. T. supplies 32.24 F. A. Ranch &amp; Co., M. T. supplies 32.24 Geo. I'm Peck DrygQod Co.. M. T. sup. 26.00 Xeniaha County Herald. pamphlets 50.00 \ehr. Sch. Sup. House, dept. supplies 163.33 R. D. Moritz, instruction 140.00 Milwaukee Dustless B'sh Co.. brushes j7.cn&gt; Martin (Irate Co., repairs \ 159.00 H. M. Mackprang. general supplies 47.57 Lockhart -Hodge Co., saw guard 25.00 H. U. Landolt, D. S. supplies 114.05 The Korsmeyer Co.. lamps 28.63 The Korsmeyer Co., lamps 28.63 Imperial Brush Co.. mops... 1350 I3-5O J. M. Howie, trip to Fremont 14.0*) J. M. Howie, trip to Fremont 14.06 Lloyd J. Hays, work., 18.55 Lloyd J. Hays. work.. 18.55 Hillyard Chemical Co.. pine-o-cide 3o.&lt;x&gt; S \V. Hacker, printing 53-SO S \V. Hacker, printing 53.50 H. Hallenbeck, supplies 36.43 H. Hallenbeck, supplies 36.43 Crane iS: Co.. powerhouse supplies 199.48 Crane &amp; Co.. powerhouse supplies 199.48 Fisher l!ros.. general supplies 42.91 Fisher Bros., general supplies 42.91 Arthur K. Burley. drums and traps 59.00 Arthur K. Burley. drums and traps 59.00 Cliford Allen, work Cliford Allen, work 49.00 49.00 W. W. Barnes, department supplies 23.90 23.90 Tims. Charles Co:, office and dept. sup. 148. si \|iril payroll : 9,940.81 May payroll 9,912.31 Jnne payroll 10.691.4.? E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 54-24 H. J. Cottle, bus. man. Peruvian 200.00 Stacy Vance, work at powerhouse 68.60 February payroll March payroll ..._ \V. X. Delzell, traveling expenses 9,589-7' 0,681.46 95-37 Central. Scientific Co., dept. supplies 47.21 L. R. Willis San. Prod. Co.. soap 10.00 Wallick Elec. Works, powerhouse rep. Sund. Mach. it Sup. Co.. dept. repair^ I73-63 58.92 C. H. Stoelting Co., lab. supplies 26.15 Standard Oil Co.. oil.' 47-23 Sinclair Refining Co.. oil 23-75 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 1 July i Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal... 1,074.82 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal... 348-10 John A. Salzer Seed House, plants 10.75 Walter K. Schmidt Co.. stain for ML T. 8.76 Sunderland Bros. Co., one piece marble 9.70 E. L. Rouse, Priii.. cash advanced 577-86 Sand, Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., powerhouse. ... 37.01 L. R. Willis San. Prod. Co.. Jan. sup 185.75 Elmer Wilson, work and truck repairs 82.45 Meek Lumber Co., supplies 233.80 Miller &amp; Paine, D. S. supplies 8.65 Mil. Dustless Brush Co.. floor brushes 30.00 Nat. Child Welfare Ass'n. panels 36.00 E. J. Newman, fillings and pictures 16.44 A. J. Ny strom &amp; Co., geography maps 22.50 The A. N. Palmer Co., dept. supplies... 15.87 Patterson &amp; Stephenson, gen. supplies 7.50 Harry Patterson, auto and ice 40.38 T. B. Patterson, for grass seed 16.60 The Puritan il &amp; Paint Co. oil and paint 71.98 E. L. Rouse. Prin., cash advanced 929.80 E. L. Rouse. Prin.. services rendered... 582.46 The Anglers Co., zoology supplies 12.30 W. W. Barnes, supplies 16.63 Charles Boellsturff, campus improve 49-4O Calebaugh Self Lub. Carb. Co., brushes 17.04 Burgess-Nash Co., dry goods 69.70 J. P. Clark, powerhouse supplies 10.55 Peter Cooper's Glue Factory, glue 18.50 Crane Co.. pipe 13-73 Cudaby Packing Co., lab. supplies 10.00 Carl Davis, work at powerhouse 136.68 Denoyer-Geppert Co., map for Tr. Sch. 6.38 Elmer Dovcl, tile : 56.00 Fisher Bros., dept. supplies 62.30 S. W. Hacker, printing 145-5" H. Halk-nbeck, general supplies 6.55 J. A. Hays, expense on trips 23.2 Hillyard Chemical Co., janitor supplies -4365 Ideal Com. Dresser Co., powerhouse .21 The Korsmeyer Co., supplies 20.3c H. U. Landolt. D. S. supplies 74-42 H. M. Mackprang, general supplies... 94.ig The McGraw Co., electric goods.. 320.0c Frod Medart Mfg. Co., gym supplies... 17-04 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 69 W. N. Delzell, traveling expenses 82.67 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 96.36 July 23 July payroll 10740.91 Aug. 3 Fillmore Music House, music, Holch.... 9.05 Fisher Bros., general supplies 548.35 F. J. Gilbert, equipment for dorm 682.49 Thomas Charles Co., general supplies.. 42.23 Walter Buettgenbach, work 58.30 Chas. \V. Boellstorff, work on gorunds 54-40 J. A. Beattie, books 24.00 W. W. Barnes, general supplies 29-50 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, gen. supplies.... 75-66 Miller &amp; Paine, supplies D. S 17.56 Meek Lumber Co., supplies 32.75 H. M. Mackprang, water rent 253.16 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies.... 40.62 S. W. Hacker, printing 40.45 E. J. Newman, filling certificates I3-I4 H. M. Mackprang, supplies : 58.50 H. U. Landolt, D. S. supplies 74-52 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 149-42 Standard il Co., oil 59-37 Sund. Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., powerhouse.... 1,214.21 Elmer E. Wilson, work 187.25 E. L. Rouse, Prin., supplies 746.14 Auk. -3 August payroll — 2,171.41 Sept. 20 September payroll 9,576.66 Oct 14 Mark Delzell, work _ 77.40 W. N. Delzell, traveling expenses 21.31 E. A. Coe, work 93.00 Thomas Charles Co., Tr. Sch. supplies 35.62 Burgess-Nash Co., supplies 18.77 W. W. Barnes, supplies 10.90 Chas. Boellstorff, work 58.60 The McGraw Co., lamps 28.33 Win. Swartzwelder, work 24.30 Sund. Mach. &amp; Sup. Co., powerhouse.... 72.55 State Journal Co., grade transfers 42.50 Standard Oil Co.. oil and gasoline 79-98 Singer Sewing Mach. Co., D. S. sup 91.20 John Shellhorn, work 29.60 The Schmelzer Co., football supplies.... 212.00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., library table 54-OO E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 1,583.09 E. L. Rouse, Prin., services and sup 642.87 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash advanced 144-77 Walter Wilson, work 79.20 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal.... 1,310.25 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., nat. study glass 16.75 Truck and Tractor Corp., truck tires 266.68 S. W. Hacker, printing 36.75 Loy J. Hacker, work 82.80 Fisher Bros., supplies 539-72 E. L. Rouse, traveling expenses 9i-'3 The Prang Co., Tr. Sch. art supplies.... 23.15 Perkins Huffman Co., furniture 92.70 J. W. Paul, state fair expenses 71.85 Richard H. Overholt, work 1 1 1. 15 Neniaha County Herald, printing 90.00 Nat. Ass'n Audubon Soc, field glasses 90.00 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, sup. Tr. Sch 35-99 Meek Lumber Co., general supplies 277.19 Wm. Fulton Davenport, work 18.40 Crane Co., powerhouse supplies 20.31 C. B. Liver &amp; Co., dorm furnishings... 622.90 H. U. Landolt 76.65 H. W. Johns Manville Co., powerhouse 64.76 Leo. E. Jewell, work 60.75 J. W. Jenkins Sons Mus. Co., band sup. 4427 J. M. Howie, state fair expenses 43-O2 J. A. Hays, traveling expenses 30.32 H. Hallenbeck, supplies 35-69 Eclipse Paint &amp; Mfg. Co., armorcote.... 175.00 J. Lawrence Eason. exp. trip to Peru.... 14.86 Elmer Dovel, tile . 58.75 Chas. H. Ditson Co., music, Dr. House 6.86 H. M. Mackprang, water rent 219.36 Oct. 22 October payroll 10,11982 Nov. 22 November payroll io.3S2.73 Balance December 1, 1920. 23,458.32 $250,000.00 $250,000.00 INSTITUTION CASH Balance reported December I, 1918 $ 5,922.40 1919 Walter Johnson, carrying mail. Dec $ 3.00 Jan. 3 Sent State Treasurer 630.98 Bausch &amp; Lomb Opt. Co., biology sup 15.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 71 (jeo. YV. Brown, study center 15.00 Central Scientific Co.. agric. supplies... 15-74 The Century Co., war aims books 94-4O Chas. H. Ditson Co., music supplies 5.74 Ginn &amp; Co., books 54-72 The Mactnillan Co., books 38.80 McKinley Publishing Co.. books 32.50 Tin' Missouri Book Co., books 37-2O Mamie R. Mutz. expenses 14-50 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, maps 16.50 Omaha Hardwood Lbr. Co. lbr. M. T 52.26 The Prang Co.. art supplies 5.90 Mrs. E. R. Priel, accompanists 7.00 Mrs. E. R. Priel. S/jA'/r tuition 60.00 Remington Typewriter Co.. rental 12.60 LeRoy Carlson, 871,2% tuition 35-O0 Wards Nat. Sci. Estab.. P. S. apparatus 90.00 University Publishing Co.. books 12.71 Underwood Typewriter Co.. rental 15.90 Rita Thomas. 87' '/'• tuition 45-00 Chas. Scribners Sons, books 19.20 E. I-. Rouse. Prin.. supplies 7-2.4" E. 1.. Rouse. Prin.. supplies 208.32 Rudge \ Guenzel Co.. supplies 50.50 Clarence Ward, carry dorm mail. Jan. 3.00 E. 1.. Rouse, i'rin.. Feb. salaries 215.00 Mar. is Si-nt State Treasurer 4'»-4, Mar 10 Current Events, current event Doubleday Page &amp; Co.. books 19.20 S. W. Hacker, printing 100.95 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 45.84 Lyon &amp; Healy, music 5.37 Mamie K. Mutz. study center work i+5&lt;&gt; Maxro-Ross Co., typewriter ribbons 45-oo Remington Typewriter Co., rental 6.50 Undei wood Typewriter Co., rental 18.00 Royal Typewriter Co., repairing 9.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, book? 18.00 The Van Evern Co., book covers 118.00 Western Biol. Sup. Co., supplies 9.10 E. L. Rouse, Prin.. March salaries 133 00 \\\r. 25 Vock Michel, hauling coal 346.90 Sunderland Bros. Co., sup. and mat 90969 S. H. Avey &amp; Co., piano rental 156.00 H. U. Landolt. D. S. supplies 109.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 72 E. L. Rouse, Prin., May salaries 79.85 Apr. jo E. L. Rouse, Prin., April salaries 178.00 May 15 Sent State Treasurer - 1,304.20 June 23 E. L. Rouse, Prin.. cash adv. supplies.... 61.23 IRedfern &amp; Ellenberger, D. S. supplies.... 16.31 Mamie R. Mutz, study center 7.44 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 19.20 Ginn &amp; Co., books 43-55 Central Scientific Co., Physics Lab 96.07 Atkinson Mentzger Co., books.. 40.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 62.40 E. L. Rouse. Prin., June salaries 567.00 July 17 E. L. Rouse, Prin., July salaries 249.68 Aug. 4 Sent State Treasurer 3.984.79 Aug. 15 H. U. Landolt, D. S. supplies 73.39 A. X. Palmer Co., supplies 9.60 Periolat Bros., M. T. supplies 50.50 E. L. Rouse. Prin.. cash adv. supplies.... 84.53 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., books 12.62 Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., books _ _ 28.80 Chas. Scribner's Sons, books 8.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 8.00 Dr. T. D. Wood, chairman, lab. supplies 6.50 Bruce Publishing Co., books 14.63 Col. College of Expression, books 10.01 Cudahy Pkg. Co., psychology supplies 15.75 Ginn &amp; Co., books 42.48 D. Van Nostrand Co.. books 8.40 Waldorf Bindery Co.. binding 89.00 S. H. Avey &amp; Co., 5 months piano rental 130.00 Sept. 4 E. I.. Rouse. Princ, August salary 25.19 Sept. 22 E. L. Rouse, Prin, September salaries 122.00 Oct. 9 J. M. Howie, traveling expenses 49-96 Keuffel &amp; Esser Co., M. T 40.91 Houghton Miftlin Co., books 70.42 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. hooks 11570 F. M. Gregg, books 17.25 Columbia Sell. Sup. Co., physics sup 9.00 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 51.75 Charles HoeJlstorff. work 26.25 Ally &amp; Bacon, books 36.OO American Book Co., books 62.40 H. l\ l.andolt. D. S. supplies 12.42 Lippincott Publishing Co.. books 11.52 Little Brown &amp; Co., books 8.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 73 The Macmillan Co., books 39.86 The Manual Arts Press, books 6.00 Oliver Mach. Co., M. T. supplies 5.40 Perkins Huffman Co., furniture H4.30 The Prang Co.. art material 5.60 F. A. Rauch &amp; Co., M. T. supplies 15.78 Redfern &amp; Ellenberger, D. S. supplies 13.52 E. L. Rouse, Prin., cash adv. dept. sup. 167.03 Royal Typewriter Co., rep. on typw 8.00 Charles Scribners Sons, books 8.41 University of Chicago Press, books 13-65 D. Van Nostrand Co.. books 13-44 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., P. S. supplies.. 54-32 Albert Pick &amp; Co., dormitory furniture .2,156.00 Oct. 22 E. L. Rouse, Prin., October salaries 168.33 Nov. jo E. L. Rouse, Prin., November salaries.... 180.00 Dec. 11 Sent State Treasurer 461.7s Dec. 31 E. L. Rouse. Priu.. December salaries.. 106.00 1920 Jan. 5 Geo. W. Brown, study center work 31.52 American Book Co., books 5.71 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 8.00 Giiin &amp; Co., books = 86-73 Gregg Publishing Co.. books i4- 2 3 Alice M. Burley, study center 26.70 N. Maud Carpenter, study center 15.36 Rose B. Clark, study center 10.00 A. Crago. extension work 14.77 Current Events, papers 10.50 Curry School of Expression, books 7.65 W. L. Davenport. D. S. milk 7.23 Henry Disston &amp; Sons, M. T 13.27 Mattie C. Ellis, study center 42.35 P. C. Hayden, music 6.65 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 6.48 Houghton Miff lin Co., books.! 12.80 H. C. House, study center 5.00 H. U. Landolt, D. S. supplies 59-38 Longmans Green &amp; Co., books 44-85 The Macmillan Co., books 19.26 Oliver Mach. Co., M. T. supplies 8.94 Redfern &amp; Ellenberger, D. S. supplies.... 17.58 E. L. Rouse, Prin., sale prop, charges 106.75 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., P. S. supplies 41.17 Jan. _'3 E. L. Rouse, Prin., January salaries 121.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 74 Feb. 18 Alice M. Burley. study center 20.69 X. Maud Carpenter, study center 58.84 S. H. Avey &amp; Co.. piano rental 156.00 Ginn &amp; Co., books 13.61 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 8.01 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 102.45 H. C. House, study center 5.00 F. M. Gregg, books 11.50 The Macmillan Co.. books 30.21 Red fern &amp; Ellenberger, D. S. supplies.... 11.35 E. L. Rouse, Prin., dept. supplies 63.53 Royal Typewriter Co., typewriters 261.50 The John C. Winston Co., books U-75 J. B. Shouse. study center 10.57 H. U. Landolt, D. S. supplies 16.03 Mattie C. Ellis, study center 19.05 Geo. W. Brown, study center work 6.17 American Book Co.. books 56.70 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 18.41 Feb. 27 H. L. Rouse. Prin.. February salaries 363.00 Mar. 3 Sent State Treasurer ■Q'5-97 Mar. 22 E L. Rouse. Prin.. March salaries jj8.&lt;x&gt; Apr. 6 Sent State Treasurer 1.088.53 rr. 19 Redfern &amp; Ellenberger. D. S. ... &lt;&gt;3.52 University Publishing Co.. cards 12.47 A. J. Stoddard, study centers &lt;jo.oo L. C. Smith &amp; Bros. Type. Co.. repairs 27.50 Chas. Scribners Sons, books 12.80 Royal Typewriter Co.. new machine 60.25 Remington Typewriter Co.. ribbons 12.50 A. J. Xystrom and Co., map 6.75 Meek Lumber Co., M. T. lumber 12.20 Claude Medley, water rent 167.92 The Macmillan Co., books 9.41 Lussky White &amp; C'lidge Inc., M. T. sup. 6.26 Lincoln Tent &amp; Awning Co., curtains.... 22.30 Lincoln Fine Arts Shop, painting 50.00 Kansas State Normal School, tests 10.63 J. W. Jenkins Sons Music Co.. repairs 67.46 F. C. Jean, money adv., w'k garden plot 36.99 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 583 H. C. House, study centers 10.00 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 21.94 General Electric Co., M. T. supplies 7.03 Mattie C. Ellis, study center 25.38 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 75 Gregg Publishing Co.. books 4.51 Cutler-Hammer Mfg. Co., M. T. repairs 67.40 J. L. Elliott, milk and cream ,. 1445 Central Scientific Co., lab. supplies 82.19 X. Maud Carpenter, study centers 44-47 Apr. 27 E. L. Rouse. Prin., April salaries 173.00 May 18 E. L. Rouse. Prin., May salaries 189.50 June 30 E. L. Rouse. Prin., June salaries 835.00 June 21 Redfern &amp; Ellcnberger, groceries 1 16.55 VVm. Volker &amp; Co., M. T. supplies 19.89 D. Van Nostrand Co., books 21.77 The Van Evern Co., book covers 96.00 Underwood Typew. Co., repairs, paper 6.00 Royal Typewriter Co., repair machine 7.00 E. L. Rouse, Prin., books and din. rm. 97992 Western Biological Sup. Co., lab. sup. 5.45 G. W. Brown, extension work 10.13 N. Maud Carpenter, study center 979 Eugene Dietzgen Co., M. T. supplies 16.03 J. X. Dillon, three dressers 42.00 Enterprise Plan. Mill Co., screens 350.00 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 76.80 H. C. House, one study center 5.00 J. M. Howie, traveling expenses 26.35 C. B. Liver &amp; Co.. dorm dining room... 54-35 Lussky White &amp; Coolidge Inc.. M. T 15.08 H. M. Mackprang. dining room 890 The Macmillan Co.. books 38.99 W. W. Mardis, supplies 25.93 F. A. Rauch &amp; Co., M. T. material 7.12 July 31 E. L. Rouse. Prin.. July salaries 665.00 Aug. 2 E. L. Rouse, Prin.. supplies 4,728.61 J. N. Dillon, dormitory supplies 5.65 Central Scientific Co., lab. supplies 132.98 Gregg Publishing Co.. books 18.24 Ginn &amp; Co., books 5.21 S. H. Avey &amp; Co., piano rental 130.00 American Book Co.. books 10.85 Harry Patterson, supplies 121.20 W. W. Mardis, dormitory fruit 25.20 The Macmillan Co.. books 165.13 J. B. Lippincott Pub. Co 14-06 Houghton Mifflin Co.. books 20.46 Perry Holt &amp; Co.. books 7382 Wbitebreast Coal X- Lumber Co., coal... 469.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p076">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 76 Southwestern Pub. Co., b'kkeeping bks. 263.04 University of Chicago Press, books 73-94 Silver Burdett &amp; Co., books 3.19 Scott Foresman &amp; Co., books 20.78 Royal Typewriter Co., new Royal No. 10 75.25 Remington Typcw. Co., 5 new machines 350.00 Redfern &amp; Ellenberger, supplies 25.58 Aug. i) Sent State Treasurer 8,764.50 Aug. J3 E. L, Rouse, Prin., August salaries 195.88 Sept. 20 EL L Rouse. Prin.. September salaries.... 335.00 Oct. 13 Miller Lock Co.. locker keys 5.14 Omaha Crockery Co., dorm dining rm. 19.12 Fisher Bros., dorm supplies 36.13 Economy Fuse &amp; Mfg. Co., M. T 10.84 J. N. Dillon, dorm supplies 57-5O A. Crago, study center work 42.58 Cleveland &amp; Son Stores, curtain rods.... 13.85 The Century Co., books 61.93 Byrne &amp; Hammer D. G. Co., dry goods 156.61 Atkinson Mentzer Co., books 27.36 D. Appleton &amp; Co., books 60.45 American Rook Co., books 80.11 \V. W. Mardis. inf. supplies 20.35 Manual Arts Press, books 20.58 Manning Abrasive Co., M. T. supplies.... 13-34 The Macmillan Co., books 84.33 H. M. Mackprang, supplies 43-50 H. M. Mackprang, dorm supplies 57-00 Lussky White &amp; Coolidge Inc., M. T 10.98 H. U. Landolt. supplies 9.84 Electro Importing Co., P. S. supplies.... 30.68 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 26-99 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 147.57 Gregg Publishing Co., books 10.80 D. Van Xostrand Co.. books 6.72 Silver Burdett &amp; Co., books 6.37 Chas. Scribners Sons, hooks 8.43 Scott Foresman &amp; Co., books 9.87 The Paul Schminke Co., dorm. din. rm. 6.25 Rutledge &amp; Taylor Coal Co.. carof coal 124.00 Royal Typewriter Co., new machine 32.00 Row Peterson &amp; Co.. books 8.42 Redfern &amp; Ellenbergcr. supplies 39-06 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 37-56 Oct &gt;i E I. Rouse Prin.. suoolies 144.QI </seg>
            <seg id="p077">PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 77 H. L. Rouse. 1'rin., October salaries.. Nov. 22 E. L. Rouse, l'rin.. November salaries LIBRARY Receipts: Balance reported November 30. 1918 1919 Jan. 3 Sent Stall- Treasurer. Matriculation Library fines Mar. o Sent State Treasurer, Matriculation Library fines Library fines Aug. 4 Sent State Treasurer. Matriculation Dec. 11 Sent State Treasurer. Matriculation 1920 Mar. 3 Sent State Treasurer. Matriculation Apr. (1 Sent State Treasurer, Matriculation Inly 8 Sent State Treasurer. Matriculation Disbursements. 1919 Jan. ii Democrat Printing I jrinting $ 15.65 1, magazines 1970 supplies 17.43 two books 5.40 -y. pottery 15.75 inscriptions. ... ... 11.00 subscription 5.50 Vp \ag. 15 Dodd. Mead &amp; Co.. lnc 4&lt; Waldorf Bindery (. nding 11 E. 1.. Rouse. Prin.. cash adv Ul Balance November 30, 1920 May 15 Sent St;it&lt;- Treasurer. Matriculation Waldorf Bind. Co., hind, b'ks and mags. 17&amp;23 E. I.. Rouse, cash adv. library supplies 32.00 A. C McClurg &amp; Co., books 152.U The Mentor Association, magazines 1970 Mar. to Gaylord Bros., library supplies I/-43 Longmans Green &amp; ( \lr&lt;. A. W. Montgome The Omaha Bee, two subscriptions...... u.oc Omaha World-Herald, subscription 5.5c E. L. House, Prin., cash adv. magazines 10.6; H. \V. Wilson Co.. U. S. Catalog sup. 24.01 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding 82.5; E. L. Rouse, Prin.. cash adv. magazines? 17.4!" C. McClurg.&amp; Co.. book </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 3 Baker &amp; Taylor Co., books 627.56 Get g Democrat Printing Co., pamphlet cases 7.15 Gayloril Bros., supplies 7.37 A. C. McClarg &amp; Co.. books 380.20 Waldorf Bindery Co.. binding 165.00 1920 Jan 8 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 08.00 Library Bureau, supplies 245.25 Moore-Cottrell Sub. Ages., magazines ... 356.25 H. W. Wilson Co.. yearly books 87.30 E. I.. Rouse. Priii., supplies 31.50 Peb. iS Democrat Printing Co.. pamphlet cases 6.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 76.80 Apr. 17 E. I.. Rouse, I'rin., supplies rg.iX June 21 Library Bnreau, cards 15.62 The H. W. Wilson Co.. back magazines 6.47 E. L. Rouse. Prin., magazines -4-54 Gaylord Bros., binders 24.07 Aug. 3 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books | 344.40 Oct. 14 Dodd Mead &amp; Co., year book 6.75 H. W. Wilson Co.. magazines 44-7« Balance November 30. 1920 2,399.19 S 5.754-35 $ 5.754 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 79 I WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOO Wayne. Nebraska, December i. iq:s&gt; To tin Sum- Board of Education of Normal Schools i I am pleased to submit herewith the- biennial report of the State Mormal School. This includes a detailed report of the expenditures during the past two years and suggestions as to the needs of the school for the ensuing biennrum. FACULTY This institution is very fortunate in haying a strong faculty. For the most part the same professors are at the heads of depart - ments as were placed in charm' more than ten years ago when the school was organized. They have grown with the institution. Their fine spirit of co-operation in all the general activities of the school has contributed materially to the wellbeing of the institution. When members of our alumni association visit the institution and find their old instructors in their accustomed places it tends to center interests in the institution which could not obtain under any other condition. PERMANENT IMPROVEMENTS Daring the past two years no building has been attempted. Quite an amount of grading, however, has been done on the enlarged campus and the excavating for an artificial lake has been practically completed. This lake when cemented and filled will make an at - tractive feature in the landscape scheme of the campus. But little has been done in the way of laying out permanent drives for tin reason that it has been impossible to secure material for their con - struction. An electric light plant lias been installed and from now on tin - institution will be able to produce its own current at a fraction of :he cost heretofore paid. The generators an- driven by steam tur - bines: the exhaust from the turbines is all used in heating the water Wayne, Nebraska U. S. CONN, President Gentlemen </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 in the general hot water system. So there is no loss of steam and apparently no increase in the amount of coal consumed. During the past year the street leading from the business part 01" town to the Xnrinal lias been paved. This is a much needed im - provement and is of much advantage to the school. The paving ex - ends entirely along the west side of the campus and one block along he south side. The expense to the State for this imprvement will be about $12,000. NEEDED IMPROVEMENTS k During the ensuing btennram some additional grading should In ne. The athletic field should be completed and permanent drives ould be laid out and paved. DORMITORY The most urgent need of the institution is a modern dormitory n view of the fad that those who teach school, for the most part, ome from homes of moderate means, their expenses must be re- Inced tq the minimum in order to enable them to secure the neces - ary preparation for teaching. Experience has shown that dormitory ccommodations of the most approved kind can be provided at an xpense of not to exceed one dollar per week for each student, whilr accommodations of a similar kind in private homes cost from two o three dollars. Such a difference is very marked in the total yearly expense of the student. In view of the fact that those who attend the State Normal School are preparing to teach and in this way will reimburse ihe commonwealth for the money expended, it seems &lt;.• \ i dent that the state may make no better use of some of its funds Em to build modern housing facilities for those who are preparing teach its youth. When viewed from the standpoint of discipline, alth of students, progress in the work, and social well being, to say nothing of the reduced expense, the dormitory is very desirable. A building should l&gt;e erected ;it the earliest possible date which will provide for the comfortable housing of from two hundred to twi hundred fiftj young women. The housing- facilities which are now provided hj 1I1, school together with all available housing facilities &lt;&gt;f tin- town are i:c\ni to the utmost during certain parts of the ;t year and unlen&gt; more adequate quarters nrr provided the growth rhe school will b« bronchi to ;\ standstill. Such a dormitory as wil inert th&lt; needs of iln school will cost from $150,000 to $200,000. Othi general improvements of tin grounds which should not longer be .1 such as drives, grading, ornamentation, landscaping and im- provement of athletic field, will cost at least $40,000. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 81 GENERAL EXPENSES It will be noted that the general expenses of the institution for maintenance- have gradually increased during the last biennium. This increased expense, however, is only in keeping with increased ex - penses in all other lines. One or two specific instances may suffice to explain this necessary outlay of public funds. Five years ago the coal delivered at the heating plant cost $4.85 a ton ; the same coal now delivered costs $10.60 a ton. The night fireman five years ago was employed at $45.00 a month ; he now receives $105 a month. Other items of expense, while possibly not increased in the same ratio, are very much more than formerly. ELEMENTARY RURAL DEPARTMENT The elementary rural department is performing an important service. It covers the two years immediately following the com - pletion of the eighth grade. For the most part those who take this work are mature students who have completed the work of the country school. These young people understand rural conditions and have no difficulty in organizing the work of the rural school. County superintendents who have our elementary rural students teaching for them are enthusiastic about the work which is being done. No claim is made that such teachers are professional. The attempt in the two years is to give some definite notion about or - ganization and management and a good knowledge of the subjects to be taught in a country school. Before the elementary rural course was established a majority of the mature students from rural districts, remained in school an average of one semester; now all of those who complete the work are enrolled at least two years. I feel that it will be a long time under present conditions before we can expect rural teachers to have the same scholastic attainments as those who teach in the graded school. Social, financial and general living conditions are not such in the country as to be an inducement to the graduates from the advanced course to choose country schools rather than graded schools. The elementary rural course which seeks to give two yta^s of intensive training is the most valuable thing which state normal schools are doing in the solution of the rural school problem. ATTENDANCE RECORD The annual enrollment for the school has increased in ten years from 539 to 1062 and the number of graduates from the advanced course from three to 79. The number receiving professional life cer- </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION tificates during the year 1919 was 51 ; in 1920 it was 69. In 1930. twenty-nine received the elementary rural certificate. Respectfully submitted. U. S. CONN. MAINTENANCE FUND State Normal School at Wayne Apportionment of fractional mill levy for 1917-19 $150,000.00 Transferred from General Fund. April. tqu) 8436.51 Si 58.436. 5 1 Expenditures reported to December 1, i&lt;)i8 S126.351.57 Kjl8 l)ec. id Payroll for December ■. 5,465.01 1911; Jan. .1.3 Cariiart Lumber . Company,, hdw. sup. . J3-49 Thomas Charles Co., ,Tr. Sch. supplies 101.05 ■U. S. Conn, .traveling expense; 25.19 U. S,. Conn, casji adv., work and sup. 209.99 U. S. Conn, cash adv. exp. and frt 513.41 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 24.87 Crane Company, plumbing supplies... .. 553-25 Keillor's Pharmacy, supplies 54-35 A. Flanagan Co., equipment 102.42 11. S. Fleming, labor 389.21 Frank Gaertner, furniture 82.00 General F.lectric Co., M. T. equipment iiS-33 Gordon-Van Tyne Co., storm sash 4"-4' Hawkeye Compound Co., boiler comp. 15.62 W. H. Hoguewood, drayage 47.45 I. 1. Holcomb Mfg. Co., jau. sup 58.30 J. T. House, study center work 45-«&gt; Hunt and Schuetz, equipment 32.20 (Continental Kompound Co., jan. sup 12.98 E. E. Lackey. Treasurer, Goldenrod. 100.00 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies .. 108.54 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies .... 178.46 E. E. Mahaffey, plastering 71.10 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, supplies 54-02 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 The Nebr. Tel. Co., rent and messages 24.17 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint, sup. 284.38 Harry Porter, office supplies 108.90 Rand McNally Co.. suspension globe... 23.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p083">WAYNE STATE. NORMtAL SCHOOL 83 Robert's Drug Co., supplies 23.10 Standard Oil Co., gasoline _ 16,09 City of Wayne, light and water power .518,70 Whit.ebrcast Ccal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 356.40 Feb. ') Payroll for January 5,020.00 Feb. J4 Payroll for February 5,216.25 Mar 10 J. J. Ahern, janitor supplies 22a) American Printing Co.. envelopes 32.00 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 17.20 L". S. Conn, cash advanced _ 36.34 LJ..S. Conn, traveling expenses '.82.27 U. S. Conn, cash adv. c-xp. and frt 831.09 Educational Music Bureau, song books 15.60 B. .S.. Fleming, hauling coal 127.35 General Electrical Co.. electricaj sup. 37-95 J. T. House, extension work,. 40.00 Huse . Publishing Co., advertising 11.76 Industrial Chem. Sup. Co.. toilet paper 45-O0 Janes' Hook Store, art supplies. 20.5,1 (Continental Kompomul Co., jan. sup...., 12.98 The McGraw Co., electrical -equipment 84.27 Uiddlewest School Review, advertising 10.50 Middlevvest School Review, advertising 10.50 • ■-.. .;, . N'ebr. Tel. Co., rental and messages 23.0)) Omaha School Supply House, supplies 20.2(1 Standard Oil Co , oil and gasoline 16.53 Steam Boiler Equipment Co.. cement . 32.00 City of Wayne, light and water power 591.00 The Wayne Herald, printing 23.60 Western Electric Co., supplies 756.37 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 731.63 Prang Company, permodello 6.00 Mar j; Payroll for March 5,215.00 Apr. 25 American Geographical Society, maps 1200 Raker Bros. Engraving Co., halftones. 19.19 O. R. Bowen, Treasurer, annuals 200.00 Carpenter Paper Co., t'let paper, towels 82.00 C. A. Chase &amp; Co., lumber, cement, sand 42.65 Claflin Printing Co.. printing bulletins 326.86 L'. S. Conn, traveling expenses 27.22 U. S. Conn, express, freight, telegrams 34.32 U. S. Conn, cash advanced... 189.92 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 30.58 S. X. Cross, expenses for field work... 82.13 Frank fiacrtrer. furniture 61.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 Gasoline Supply Co., gasoline 100.58 General Electric Co., equipment ISS-79 Gregg Publishing Co., books 71443 International Electric Co., glue heater 12.00 Jackson Piano Co., pianos 400.00 Kewaunee Mfg. Co., motor 45-59 Marsaline Lewis, services as pianist.... 12.00 The McGraw Co., electric equipment.... 15.36 Paul Mines, clock 6.00 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, equipment 87.50 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 Nebr. Tel. Co., rental and messages.... 13 91 A. N. Palmer Co., penmanship methods 0.60 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., gym equipment 24.00 The Taylor-Holden Co., drawing paper 24.24 Warwick &amp; York, educational graphs.. 12.00 City of Wayne, light and water power 220.14 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., lab. sup 233.29 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass 93-34 Harry P. Whitmore, art supplies 36.00 The Yale &amp; Towne Mfg. Co., hinges... 19.98 Yawman &amp; Erbe Mfg. Co., cabinet file 91.70 $15843651 $158436.51 Apportionment for maintenance, biennium 1919-21.. $108,000.00 1919 May 3 Payroll for April $ 5.440.00 May 27 Payroll for May 5,440.00 June 18 J. J. Ahern, janitor supplies 9.55 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 46.25 Carpenter Paper Co., toilet paper 51.00 U. S. Conn, traveling expense 1922 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for freight 49-53 U. S. Conn, cash advanced for sundries 521.12 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 56.15 H. B. Craven, hardware 405.85 S. X. Cross, field work expense 9396 Fritz Denkinger, labor 50.25 Farwell, Oztuun, Kirk &amp; Co., paint, sup. 70.39 B. S. Fleming, labor 167.60 Gasoline Supply Co.. gasoline 47-59 E. D. Hammond, spruce trees 30.00 J. T. House, extension work 40.00 The McGraw Co., lamps 189.07 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 85 Magic City Ptg. Co., office supplies 8.25 Lowry D. Monson, assit. in instructing 15.00 The Nebraska Democrat, Tr. Sch. sup. 12.55 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 A. C. Norton, painting 232.80 Sunderland Machinery Co., repairs 7.00 Welch Mfg. Co., P. S. supplies 48.03 West. Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass, paint 74.83 June 27 Payroll for June 5,786.30 July 24 Payroll for July 5.792-50 Aug. 6 Baker Bros. Eng. Co., halftones 24.80 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lumber, sand, etc 1,393.20 U. S. Conn, traveling exp., frt., express 156.44 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for sundries 343-7O C. M. Craven, photographic views 31.00 H. B. Craven, hardware 161.30 Fritz Denkingcr, labor 118.85 B. S. Fleming, labor 195.20 Gasoline Supply Co., gasoline 25.76 W. Ray Hickman, asst. in instructing 20.00 Husc Pub. Co., advertising 35-70 Industrial Chem. Sup. Co., toilet paper 60.00 Jones Book-Music Store, supplies 17-59 James Knapp. surveying on campus 25.00 N. C. Leary &amp; Co., stationery 173.25 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies.... 121.98 J. H. Miller, grading 3.109.37 Nebr. Tel. Co., rental and tolls 62.76 Harry Porter, ink 6.00 The A. Schnenhut Co.. kin'garten blks. 6225 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., athletic equip. 23.25 Superior School Supply Co., desks 187.50 The John Van Range Co., repairs 18.69 City of Wayne, light serv., water power 580.06 The Wayne Herald, supplies 4795 Wset. Glass &amp; Paint Co.. glass, paint 227.06 Aug. -'8 Payroll for August 1,520.00 Sept. 29 Payroll for September 6,466.50 Oct 6 Adams &amp; Nelson Co., tool grinder 75-00 Baker Bros. Eng. Co., zinc etchings.... 866 Carhart Lumber Co., hardware 22.25 Claflin Ptg. Co., printing catalogs 317.20 U. S. Conn, cash adv. frt., express 420.20 U S. Conn, cash adv. for sundries 118.36 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 19-73 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 86 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for sundries 103.00 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 158.72 A. Flanagan Co., dept. supplies. 369.44 B. S. Fleming, hauling coal 89.65 Hammond Printing Co., advertising 24.50 Hawkeye Compound Co., boiler comp. 21.67 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co., Jan. sup 99-54 Huse Publishing Co., advertising 25-20 Keystone Driller Co., repairs 9.12 Kontinental Kompound Co., Jan. sup 21.15 J. G. W. Lewis, extension work..- 43-94 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies.... 36.02 The McGraw Co., repairs 62.13 Nebraska Material Co., fire brick.... 27.14 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, sup. and equip. 119.82 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, supplies 17.02 A. C. Norton, painting i74-6o Omaha School Sup. Co., supplies 18.16 Standard Oil Co., gasoline and oil 43-13 Standard Paint &amp; Lead Works, cement 30.00 A. V. Teed, extension work 22.00 Transcontinental Oil Co., gasoline 50.29 The John Van Range Co., repairs 11.75 City of Wayne, light and water 3326 The Wayne Herald, Tr. Sch. supplies.... 19.15 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 306.03 Thomas E. Wilson Co., athletic supplies 334-30 Dec. 2 Payroll for November 6,536.00 Dec. 19 Payroll for December 6,449.00 1920 Jan. 5 J. J. Ahem, janitor supplies 26.08 American Radiator Co., repairs 22.53 Baker Bros. Eng. Co., halftones 30.60 Mabel Brinker, reading English papers 36.00 Carhart Lumber Co., hardware 23.18 Caxton School Sup. Co., office supplies 23.38 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 10.27 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lumber, sand, etc. 950.80 Chicago Mill work Sup. Co., storm sash 2,001.25 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 32.77 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for misc. items 782.24 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for frt., exp., tel. 1,044.68 J. L. Coon, work on grounds 228.80 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 1,285.55 S. X. Cross, field work expense 9744 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Fritz Denkinger, work on grounds _. 68.00 Educational Music Bureau, dept. sup 15-42 L. A. Fanske, laboratory supplies 5.50 Harwell, Ozmun. Kork &amp; Co., lanterns 10.80 Farwell, Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., M. T. sup. 308.45 Freeport Gas Machine Co., tank 39-60 Frost Manufacturing Co., repairs 15.00 Haakinson &amp; Beaty Co., repairs 25.62 H. H. Hahn, institute expense 22.50 C S. Hammond &amp; Co., maps 48.00 Huse Publishing Co., advertising 20.16 C T. Inghani, X-ray machine 56.00 Jones Rook-Music Store, dept. supplies 99-O4 W. A. Jones Fdry &amp; Mach. Co., pulleys 17.28 N. C. Leary Co., stationery 108.46 \V. N. -ong Co., typewriters 280.00 W. N. Long Co., typewriters 350.00 Lyon &amp; Healy, music Dept. equip 87.14 J. C. Mines, equipment 7.50 National Wood Works, lumber 363.00 Nebr. Tel. Co., rental and toll 3270 Wbr. Tel. Co., rental and toll 33.55 A. C. Norton, painting 98.70 R. M. Powers, exp. State vs. Hunter... 17.80 Rand McNally &amp; Co., maps... 123.50 L. M. Rogers, labor 126.40 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., office furniture 24.80 A. C. Serfling, exp. to athletic conf 1622 Sioux City Crockery Co.. equipment.... 18.50 Standard Oil Co., oil 15.59 Superior School Supply Co., desks 187.50 Tucker-Shean, mimeograph supplies.... 6.00 Ward's Nat. Sci. Estab., supplies 87.98 City of Wayne. light and water 261.00 West. Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass, stain 101.36 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 777-7^ Thos. E. Wilson &amp; Co.. athletic equip. 90.80 Jan. 24 Payroll for January 6,545.00 Feb. 16 J. J. Ahern, janitor supplies 26.83 Bauttch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., equipment 10.22 O. R. Bowen, Goldenrods 100.00 Mabel Drinker, reading English papers 24.00 II. S. Conn, traveling expenses 34-84 U. S. Conn, cash adv., misc. items 332.68 U. S. Conn, cash adv., frt. and tel 2,099.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION J. P. Cooke Co., rubber stamps 5.48 J. L. Coon, labor 20.40 Crane Co., hardware and plumb, sup. 225.12 H. B. Craven, hardware 176.75 Fred Denkinger, labor 83.60 Educational Music Bureau, T. S. sup. 2393 B. S. Fleming, hauling coal 659.25 C. W. Hiscox, repairs 6.60 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co., Jan. supplies.... 29.80 N. C. Leary Co., letter heads 5.90 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies.... 140.71 Metropolitan Supply Co., diplomas 63.00 National Supply Co., coal 470.17 Nebr. Tel. Co., rental and tolls 40.85 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., floor paint 7.41 Edwin Puls, orchestra equipment 20.00 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriters 285.38 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriters 420.00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., office furniture 22.00 Terminal Ptg. Co., printing pamphlets 118.50 Transcontinental Oil Co., gasoline, oil 124.56 City of Wayne, light and water 241.28 City of Wayne, coal 371-72 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 658.57 Mar. 1 Payroll for February 7,951-67 Mar. 26 Payroll for March 7,956.67 J. J. Ahern, janitor supplies 8.99 Arcus Ticket Co., printing 63 50 Mildred Bacon, work in office 30.70 C. C. Birchard &amp; Co., chapel song bks. 39-14 Mabel Brinker, reading English papers 24.00 I. H. Britell, piano 160.00 Buroughs Add. Mach. Co., add. mach. 219.37 Carhart Lumber Co., hardware 39-78 U. S. Conn, cash adv, misc. items 1 15.49 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 125.39 U. S. Conn, cash adv., frt., exp., tel 1,111.59 S. X. Cross, field work expense 54-00 B. S. Fleming, hauling coal 30.50 Frceport Gas Mach. Co., equipment.... 15-94 Frank Gaertner. piano and rental 195.50 {Continental Kompound Co., jan. sup 25.00 X. C. Leary Co., letter heads 16.00 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies.... 115.10 Maxro-Ross Co.. office supplies 9.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 89 National Supply Co., coal 73-48 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, exam, paper.... 74-5O Nebr. Tel. Co., rental and tolls 33-85 Nemaha County Republican, ptg. bull. 336.00 A. C. Serfling, exp. to athletic conf 14.56 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 1,042.42 Fred Medart Mfg. Co., equipment 282.10 Apr. 37 Payroll for April 8,291.67 May 24 Payroll for May 8,309.17 June 23 Payroll for June . .'. 8,641.67 June 21 West. Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass, stain.... 12.62 J. J. Ahern, janitor supplies 73-86 Mabel Brinker, reading English papers 24.00 Myron Brown, work on grounds 50340 Carhart Lumber Co., hardware supplies 17.02 Carpenter Paper Co., toilet paper 4140 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., sand, cement, lbr 1,147.69 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies.... 185.67 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses _ 14301 U. S. Conn, cash adv., frt., exp., tel 225.27 U. S. Conn, cash adv., misc. items 284.93 Crane Company, plumbing supplies.... 624 11 H. B. Craven, hardware supplies 182.85 Crescent Machine Co., equipment 18.20 S. X. Cross, field work expense '47-4° Fred Denkinger, work on grounds 124.00 Devoe &amp; Raynolds Co., dept. supplies 20.95 Luther O. Draper Shade Co., shades.... 1389 Electro-Magnetic Tool Co., tools _ 56.80 Harwell, Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., hdw. sup. 119.00 General Electric Co., repairs 30.00 J. 1. Holcomb Mfg. Co., steel mat 700 Irving-Pitt Mfg. Co., office supplies 10.20 Rexfo-il L. Holmes, Educ. Conf. rep't 10.30 Jones Book-Music Store, dept. supplies 49-92 Jones Book-Music Store, piano 200.00 Kay &amp; Bichel, steel scraper 1400 Mrs. J'. G. W. Lewis, typing 18.60 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies.... 41-47 Marshall Brothers, nursery stock 21.50 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, dept. sup 377-91 The Prang Co., dept. supplies 69.86 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, book case 40.00 Standard Oil Co.. oil 14.44 Transcontinental Oil Co., kerosene 12.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Transcontinental Oil Co., gasoline........ 123.03 United States Supply Co., hardware.... .. 40.33 Waldcraft Co., department supplies 8.50 Wayne Herald, office sup. and adv 239.15 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., supplies 186.15 World-Herald, advertising 6.37 O. R. Bowen, Treasurer, school annuals 200.00 July 22 Payroll for July 8,791.67 Aug. 2 J. J. Ahern, janitor supplies 12.60 American Seating Co., hardware 36.00 O. R. Bowen, Treas., adv. in Goldenrod 50.00 Myron Brown, work on grounds 262.10 N. A. Bruce, work on grounds 129.60 Burroughs Add. Mach. Co.. paper 5.25 Central Garage, gas and oil 1430 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 109.63 U. S. Conn, cash adv., misc. items 212.61 U. S. Conn, cash adv., frt. and tel 1,099.62 DeForest Tel. Co., dept. supplies 92.74 Fred Denkinger, work on grounds 117.20 W. S. Dickey Clay Mfg. Co., tile 429.50 Eclipse Paint &amp; Mfg. Co., paint 239.80 Farwell, Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., chairs... 108.00 W. A. Hiscox, hardware 58.40 Iowa Army &amp; Navy Sup. Co., tent 45-00 Ivar C. Jensen, auto hire 9.00 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies... 230.36 Mrs. A. W. Montgomery, art equip 37-8o Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, desks 162.90 Nebr. Tel. Co., rental and tolls 59.35 A. C. Norton, painting 129.20 Omaha Sch. Sup. Co., dept. supplies.... 137-40 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint, glass 172.30 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., waste baskets.... 63.00 V. A. Senter, tent 15.00 Sioux City Crockery Co., equipment 52.80 Transcontinental Oil Co., oil, gasoline 32.59 Union Coal Co., coal 426.47 Vestal Chemical Co., soap 30.00 City of Wayne, light and water 691.62 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 359-37 B. W. Wright, truck 1,500.00 Sept. 1 Payroll for August -.. 1,946.67 Sept. 28 Payroll for September 8,631.67 Oct. 11 Aalfs-Harper Co.. paint _ 165.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 91 J. J. Ahem, janitor supplies - 47-00 Myron Brown, work on grounds 585.45 N. A. Bruce, work on grounds 190.80 C A. Chacc &amp; Co., lumber, sand, gravel 1,039.95 Thomas Charles Co., dept. supplies 31-92 Claflin Printing Co., catalogs 382.80 U. S. Conn, cash adv., misc. items 383.92 U. S. Conn, cash adv., frt., tel 1,054.27 Coryell &amp; Brock, supplies for truck 140.00 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 372-05 H. (ft. Craven, hdw. and plub. supplies 244.95 S. X. Cross, field work expense 135-30 DeForest Radio Tel. Co., repairs 13.00 Fred Denkinger, work on grounds 199-70 J. A. Fay &amp; Egan Co.. M. T. equip 22.04 Hammond Printing Co.. advertising.... 20.16 Hawkcye Compound Co., boiler comp. 27.56 Joesting &amp; Schilling Co., dorm, equip. 1,210.25 Grace Johnson, office assistant 90.00 Robert H. Jones, surveying 51-40 C. B. Liver &amp; Co., dining hall equip 210.15 The McGraw Co., electrical supplies 169.54 National Supply Co., clastite 78.00 Xcbr. Sch. Sup. House, seats 128.47 Nfebr. Tel. Co., rental and tolls 37.25 N\ O. Nelson Mfg. Co., repairs 16.93 Norfolk Daily News, advertising 44.80 Omaha Printing Co., mimeograph 172.50 Perry Owens, carpenter work 97-75 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint, glass 100.60 L M. Rodgers, work on grounds 5100 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., trays 219.00 Sioux City Iron Co., steel 4.62 Sioux City Journal, advertising 71.68 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 17.40 The Tribune Co., advertising 60.48 The Wayne Herald, supplies and adv. 62.75 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 152.04 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 620.00 Oct. 26 Payroll for October 8,640.67 Nov. io U. S. Conn, cash adv. for freight 1,850.70 Nov. 26 Payroll for November 8,625.67 Balance November 30. 1920 5,840.58 $198,000.00 $198,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 92 INSTITUTION CASH FUND Receipts: Balance December I, 1918 $ 4.193-05 Total cash receipts for biennium 25,848.69 $30^41.74 Disbursements : 1918 Dec. 16 Payroll for December $ 65.00 1919 Jan. 13 U. S. Conn, refund to students 413.21 Frank Gaertner, furniture 292.60 Mrs. Mary Myers, services as nurse 50.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 26.65 J. J. Ahem, supplies for D. S 71-56 Edwin Puls, laboratory assistant 100.00 National Wood Works, M. T. supplies 105.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 72.00 American Book Co., textbooks 67.50 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 154.86 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbooks 92.45 Houghton. Mifflin &amp; Co.. textbooks 240.75 Charles E. Merrill Co.. textbooks 35.57 W. B. Saunders Co., textbooks 32.84 C C. Birchard &amp; Co., music books 30.54 Hackelman Music Co., music 6.25 J. W. York &amp; Sons, orchestra equp 12.51 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lumber, cement, etc. 503.00 Ellis Pub. Co., bookkeeping sets 54 56 Farwell, Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., supplies... 21.40 Joesting &amp; Schilling Co., supplies 43-93 Jresting &amp; Schilling Co., supplies 191.71 E. E. Lackey, Trcas., reimbursement 75-O0 The Orcutt Co., supplies 42.10 John Van Range Co., repairs on range 16.15 Feb. (&gt; Payroll for January 65.00 Feb. 24 Payroll for February 65.00 Mar. 10 U. S. Conn, refunds to students 191. 16 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 9.00 J. C. "Nuss, brooms and paint 9.06 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 38.12 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, bookkeeping sets.... 8.76 Benj. H. Sanborn &amp; Co., textbooks 6.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 93 Scott Foresman &amp; Co., textbooks 7.68 Webb Publishing Co., textbooks 5.00 American Book Co., textbooksk 38.61 National Wood Works, lumber 87.50 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., stain 26.70 J. J. Ahern, D. S. supplies 2754 The Willis Music Co., music 6.08 Mar. 25 Payroll for March 65.00 Apr. 25 U. S. Conn, refund to students 57-6i J. J. Ahern. D. S. supplies 12.98 Frank Gaertncr, pianos 500.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 4.95 City of Wayne, light and water power.... 134.92 C. A. Chace &amp;• Co., shingles 94-50 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 74-40 D. Appleton &amp; Co., textbooks 14.26 Doubleday Page &amp; Co., textbooks 70.26 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 7.92 University of Chicago Press, textbooks 33-79 O. H. Venner, textbooks 36.00 National Wood Works, lumber 30.00 The H. H. Rowc Co.. bookkeeping sets 4.43 May 7 Payroll for April 80.00 28 Payroll for May 80.00 June 18 U. S. Conn, refund to students 72.99 Jones Book-Music Store, supplies 186.60 A. C. Norton, painting in dormitories.... 91.80 J. C. Nuss, dormitory supplies 20.75 American Book Co., textbooks 26.02 (jinn &amp; Co., textbooks 8.66 Metropolitan Textbook Co., textbooks.... 101.25 The H. M. Rowe Co., textbooks 40.50 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbooks 38.40 J. J. Ahern, D. S. supplies 16.27 The Lufkin Rule Co., D. S. equipment.... 6.23 National Wood Works. M. T. supplies 110.00 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriters 127.40 Modern Farm Utilities Co., equipment 156.30 Swanson-Nolan Theater Equip. Co 483.35 S. R. Theobald &amp; Co., S.A.T.C. hos. sup. 17.75 Payroll for June 85.00 &gt;■ ■/ July 24 Payroll for July 85.00 6 L'. S. Conn, refunds to students 112.69 Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental 18.09 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., floor wax... 17.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">STATE BOARD OF. EDUCATION - Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint • •■71-95 Farwell, Oztnun, Kirk &amp; Co., supplies.... 105.00 D. Appleton &amp; Co., textbooks - . 25.05 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks... .-..- : 33-95 Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks....: 22.77 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks 8.69 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 32.42 Manual Arts Co., textbooks 6.00 The Charles E. Merrill Co.. textbooks 18.34 G. P: Putnam's Sons, textbooks 24.00 . VVorW Book Co., textbooks....... :.:. 38.40 J. J. Ahern, D. S. supplies ::: ■ 42.64 Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., textbooks 6.92 Ward's Nat. Sci. Estab., supplies 20.15 Thfr Prang Co.. art supplies :...'.... 18.30 C.' : Ai- Chace &amp; Co.. M. T. supplies 39.65 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriter 70.00 Underwood Typewriter C'OV typewriter 35-OO I .yon", ft Healy, miisic '. i 31.60 Joesting &amp; Schilling Co.. equipment... ■ 163.53 A. C Norton, painting. : : 238.81) Aug. 28 Payroll for August ..'...' :: 70.06 Sept. jg Pa'yrbll for September 80.00 Oct. (1 U. S.'Conn, refunds to students.......... 85.19 J. C. Nuss, supplies for dormitories.:: 4335 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks..... 21.00 Knox Business Book Co., textbooks 22.50 The Macmillan Co., textbooks... 41.40 Orr &amp; Orr, D. S. supplies 9.79 Felbcr's Pharmacy, drugs for S.A.T.C. 5.35 Wayne Drug Co., dormitory supplies. .. 5.65 W. M. Welch. Mfg. Co., lab. supplies... 69.36 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., M. T. sup. 31.37 Crane Co., plumbing supplies 7.39 Russell &amp; Erwiii Mfg. Co., locks 44-20 Oct. 27 Payroll for October 80.00 1910 Dec. 2 Payroll for November 80.00 it) Payroll for December 85.00 19211 Jan. 5 U. S. Conn, refund to students 47-48 R. B. Judson &amp; Co., rug for dorm 17.50 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 10.50 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 10.50 J. C. Nuss. dormitory supplies 37.51 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 95 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks.... 18.00 American Book Co., textbooks : 40.09 P. Blakiston's Sons &amp; Co., textbooks.... 6.45 Gtnn &amp; Co., textbooks 3140 Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks 30.04 Hall &amp; McCrcary. textbooks '.... 9.18 Riiox Business Book Co., textbooks 5.32 Lyon &amp; Carnahan, textbooks 46.08 The Macmillan Co., textbooks : 22.57 The Manual Arts Press, textbooks 27.49 Park Publishing Co., textbooks ■ 11.81 Silver. Burdettc &amp; Co., textbooks 29.45 Win. H. Anderson, ice for D. S. dept.:. .:' '• fs.oo Orr &amp; Orr, D. S. supplies... ::..'.*.v.L:.. 29.17 Duuiffer Condenser Co.. lab. equip. 29.00 I.evf'fs 1 "' Institute, art dept. supplies:..'...... ''16:37 Victor Electric Corporation, lab. equip. •• 46.60 FaVw'ell. Oztnun, Kirk &amp; Co., M. T. equip' 73.38 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., lab. equip; "4 34 The Taylor-Holden Co., "M. T. supplies. .. 13.13 Kee Lox Mfg. Co.. supplies '. 30.25 Royat Typewriter Co., typewriters 261.24 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Bins. Co., band bks 6.56 Jones' Book- Music Store, piano 275.00 J. A. Parks Co.. music 5.87 Willis Music Co., music 44-6i B. S. Fleming, hauling coal 410.00 National Supply Co., coal 338.56 Ian. -'4 Payroll for January 85.00 Feb. i&lt;&gt; L". S. Conn, refunds to students 6.86 Louise Feyereisen. services nursing 104.50 The McGraw Co., dormitory supplies.. 46.40 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 10.50 A. C. Xorton. painting 106.80 U. S. Army Retail Store, dorm equip. 568.62 American Book Co.. textbooks 29.04 D. Appleton &amp; Co., textbooks 28.36 P. Blakiston's Sons &amp; Co.. textbooks.... 10.36 Hall &amp; McCreary. textbooks 9.98 Macmillan Co.. textbooks 86.38 Charles E. Merrill Co.. textbooks 6.06 Scott. Foresman Co., textbooks 35-52 Orr &amp; Orr. D. S. supplies 16.25 Central Scientific Co.. lab. supplies 40.91 John \ "an Range Co.. repairs 22.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Wayne Drug Co., lab. supplies 11.35 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 42653 Mar. 1 Payroll for February 110.00 25 Payroll for March 110.00 Apr. 12 U. S. Conn, refunds to students 53-23 Frank Gaertner, dormitory equipment 225.15 Joesting &amp; Schilling Co., equipment 378.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., rental 16.30 Ray D. Norton, hauling coal 15910 J. C. Nuss, dormitory equipment 21.50 City of Wayne, light and water 282.92 American Book Co., textbooks 26.77 Atkinson, Mentzer, &amp; Co., textbooks 8.64 Thomas Y. Crowell Co., textbooks 50.00 Macmillan Co., textbooks 51.25 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 40.81 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., textbooks 22.95 Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., textbooks 11. 14 Silver, Burdette &amp; Co., textbooks _. 5.84 University of Chicago Press, textbooks 37.31 University of Illinois, textbooks 12,53 University Publishing Co., textbooks.... 49.65 West. Pub. &amp; Eng. Co., textbooks 36.00 Willis Music Co., textbooks 8.10 B. F. Wood Music Co., textbooks 11.40 Carpenter Paper Co., D. S. equip 7.89 Orr &amp; Orr Co., D. S. supplies 34.01 Wayne Stor. Bat. Co., lab. equipment 6.00 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., supplies.... 86.00 Remington Typewriter Co., supplies.... 7.00 Educational Music Bureau, music 18.00 Carl Fischer, music 6.87 Lyon &amp; Healy, music 53-62 National Wood Works, lumber 645.80 Apr. 27 Payroll for April 110.00 May 25 Payroll for May 110.00 June 23 Payroll for June 100.00 21 U. S. Conn, refunds and misc. items 73-i6 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., dormitory supplies.... 776.56 Farwell, Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., dorm. sup. 82.21 Frank Gaertner, dorm. sup. and equip. 383.10 Joesting &amp; Schilling Co., repairs 30.80 A. C. Norton, painting 322.15 Perry Owens, carpenter work 82.00 Wayne Drug Co.. nurse's supplies 25.85 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 97 July 22 \u Sept. I r.s Oct. 11 Central Scientific Co.. lab. supplies National Wood Works. M. T. supplies. ... 167.50 L nderwood Typewriter Co.. repair.. 18.50 Orr &amp; Orr Co.. I). S. supplies 8.70 Central Scientific Co., lab. supplies 5.70 Joesting &amp; Schilling Co.. Payroll tor August Payroll for September L. S. Conn, refunds to sti Farwell. Ozmun, Kiik &amp; I Thomas Kilpatrick Co.. &lt; Xai'l Wood Renovating C Nebraska Telephone Co., I IO.OO .'. lire exting. 80.00 rental 14. (hi 14.00 central actentmc Co.. lab. supplies 116.94 Taylor-Holden Co., laboratory supplies 49.16 W. M. Welch, Mfy. Co.. lab. supplies.... 24.20 !). H. equip 323.00 go.&lt;x&gt; tudents 56.00 Co., dorm. sup. 4' p -.?5 dortn. supplies m'j.-'N Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 94-o&gt; 49-02 Houghton, Mifflin Co., textbooks 13-7* Manual Arts Press, textbooks 55.» School Art&gt; Magazine, textbooks University Publishing Co.. textbooks.. io.j; Orr &amp; Orr Co., D. S. supplies .^6.6; Willis Music Co.. music 10.80 Abel Const. Co., dirt to fill campus 86.75 Xathan Bruce, work on grounds II2.O0 George B. Carpenter &amp; Co.. equipment Sioux City Crockery Co.. !). H. equip Payroll for July L. S. Conn, refunds to students 22.70 10. (jo I oo.(j( &gt; IOI.I2 Anderson Furniture Co., dorm, equip 72.0O Mrs. A. \i Bruce, service as nurse 99.OO C. A. Chace &amp; Co.. lumber. H. B. Craven, hardware.. 474-/O 181.95 Ferry Owens, carpenter work 195-So Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental Philleo &amp; Harrington Ubr. Co.. Ibr 24.40 460.00 Richard 1!. Badger, textbooks X-75 Ginn &amp; Co.. textbooks 162.09 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. textbooks Hough tan, Mifflin Co.. textbooks 6.09 42.03 Macinillan Co.. textbooks 59-7.? Nebraska Democrat, textbooks 92.50 A. X. Palmer Co.. textbooks 8.00 Scott. Foresman &amp; Co.. textbooks _&gt;8.So Charles Scribners' Sons, textbooks 16.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 Carl Sund, painting 439-45 American Book Co., textbooks 37.26 Houghton, Mifflin Co., textbooks 14.18 E. E. Lackey, scales 5.60 Little, Brown &amp; Co., textbooks 20.16 Rand, McNally Co., textbooks „ 75-00 The Ronald Press Co., textbooks 36.00 Silver, Burdette &amp; Co.. textbooks 152.46 Orr &amp; Orr Co.. D. S. supplies 11.20 A. D. Patten, music 7.35 Felber's Pharmacy, nurse's supplies 20.20 Dr. G. J. Hess, insp. sma'pox pat'ns 10.00 Wayne Drug Co., nurse's supplies 22.65 26 Payroll for October 110.00 Nov. 26 Payroll for November 110.00 Balance November 30. 1920 8,297.10 $30,041.74 $30,041.74 LIBRARY FUND Balance November 30. 1918 $ 5,712.05 1918 Dec. 31 Matriculation fees for December 590.00 1919 Jan. 31 Matriculation fees for January 205.00 Mar. 31 Matriculation fees for March 15.00 Apr. 30 Matriculation fees for April 500 Jan. 13 D. Appleton &amp; Co., reference books $ 8.70 The Century Co., reference books 5.73 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for books 17.58 Harper &amp; Bros., reference books 26.67 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books.... 19.75 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books.... 37.02 Macmillan Co., reference books 19.98 Moore-Cottrell Sub. Arcs., periodicals 244.05 Charles Scribner's Sons. ref. books 6.80 Underwood &amp; Underwood, views 16.83 Waldorf Bindery Co.. binding magazines 99-io Mar. 10 U. S. Conn, cash advanced 39.50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., ref. books 66.53 H. W. Wilson &amp; Co., catalog sup'ment 24.00 Apr. 25 Brentano's, reference books 39-12 The Century Co.. reference books '. 7.32 Arthur H. Clark &amp; Co.. ref. books 9.1x1 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 99 U. S. Conn, cash advanced 4407 Dodd. Mead &amp; Co., reference books 6.48 John Lane Co.. reference books 4.58 Longmans, (ireen &amp; Co., ref. books 5.40 A. C. McClur^ &amp; Co., ref. books 8.23 The Macmillan Co., reference books... 7.55 Charles Scribners' Sons, ref. books 8.31 Waldorf Bindery Co., bdg. periodicals .... 5.01 Harry P. Whitmore, pictures, framing 317-75 June 30 Matriculation fees for June 1 .240 00 940.00 Sept. 30 Matriculation fees for September Oct. 31 Matriculation fees for October 40.00 40.00 Nov. 30 Matriculation fees for November June 18 L*. S. Conn, cash adv. for ref. books 12.20 Houghton, Mifflin Co., reference books 24.61 The Macmillan Co., reference books... 15.17 Webb Publishing Co., reference books 59-75 Aug. 6 L*. S. Conn, cash adv. for ref. books.k... 7.45 Little. Rrown &amp; Co.. reference books... Q.08 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., ref. books 63.29 Waldorf Bindery Co., brig, periodicals 34-90 Oct. 6 Houghton Mifflin Co.. reference books 11.43 Library Bureau, library supplies 16.06 A. C. McClurg- &amp; Co.. ref. books 77.08 Moorc-Cottrell Sub. Arcs., periodicals 232.00 The School Arts Magazine, ref. books... 9.18 Harry P. Whitmore. picture .. 22.50 Dec. 31 Matriculation fees for December 135.00 1920 Jan. 31 Matriculation fees for January 345'"' Feb. ..2Q Matriculation fees for February 30.00 Mar. 31 Matriculation fees for March !O.(K) Apr. 30 Matriculation fees for April !O.O0 May 31 Matriculation fees for May m.oo Jan. 5 Boyer Brothers, rebinding books 78.40 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for ref. books 24.72 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co.. reference books 6.30 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 66.78 Review of Reviews Co.. reference books 16.20 Underwood &amp; Underwood, ster. views. ... 7308 Waldorf Bindery Co.. bdg. periodicals 44.65 Feb. 16 I'. S. Conn, cash adv. for ref. books 45-02 A. C. McClurg Co.. reference books 46.75 Manual Arts Press, reference books i8.8y Hairy 1' Whituiorr. pictures 158.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 Apr. 12 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for ref. books.... 21.81 C. W. Bardeen. reference books 6.45 A. C. McClnrg &amp; Co., reference books.... 386.43 Waldorf Bindery Co., bdg. periodicals... 9.73 H. W. Wilson Co., reference books 7303 June 30 Matriculation fees for June July 31 Matriculation fees for July Sept. 30 Matriculation fees for September Oct. 31 Matriculation fees for October Nov. 30 Matriculation fees for November June 21 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for ref. books 10.22 Library Bureau, cards 31.29 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books 78.32 Matthews Book Store, reference books 6.42 Aug. 2 U. S. Conn, cash adv. for periodicals ... 10.00 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co.. year book 8.10 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books.... 4336 School Arts Magazine, reference books 27.50 World Book Co., reference books 5.19 Oct. 11 U. S. Conn, cash advanced 11.39 A. C. McClurg: &amp; Co.. reference books.... 8327 Moore-Cottrell Sub. Ages., periodicals.... 288.95 Waldorf Bindery Co.. bd.a;. periodicals.... 49-35 Balance November 30, 1920 8,500.14 $ 9.153.50 $ 9.153-50 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>