<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Twenty-fourth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Twenty-fourth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">306 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA RESIDENT OFFICERS J. D. Case Superintendent H. A. Neweli Assistant Superintendent and Physician (Pathologist) R. H. Spraui.ing Staff Physician Alma Chapman Staff Physician J. R. Helms Steward Margaret Helms Matron Chloe A. Ogg Bookkeeper NON-RESIDENT Fredekk k A. Stuff Chaplain </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 307 NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To his Excellency, Honorable Keith Xetille, Governor, and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Commit missionera of State Institutions. Henry Gerdes, Silas I. Holcomb, (turf Eugene 0. Mayfield, U( nth mi n : Since the beginning of the period covering the bien - niuni. beginning December 1, 191G, and ending November 30, 1918. there have been three superintendents in charge, namely: Dr. B. F. Williams, until January 1, 1918. Dr. L. B. Pilsbury, former first assistant physician, who was ap - pointed superintendent to succeed Dr. Williams and served until September 15, 1918, when he resigned to enter the Medical Reserve Corps of the army. Dr. J. D. Case was appointed superintendent September It;. 1918. During my superintendency, conditions have been unusual and at times serious, owing to the depletion in the ranks of the nurses and attendants, caused by the demands of the war. Added to this we have to cope with an epidemic of Spanish in - fluenza, which was a problem during the past summer and fall, causing much sickness among the employees, and add - ing a greater burden to the hospital physicians' duties. We are proud to state that forty of our employees have entered the service, eight in the Red Cross service as nurses and the remainder in various departments of the army and navy. Of this number three have given their lives for the cause. The Nebraska Hospital for the Insane at Lincoln came into existence in the year 1870. Since that time there has been a steady increase in the demands on the institution. The receiving district assigned to this institution com - prises the following fourteen counties in the southeast por - tion of the state: Cass, Douglas, Dodge, Gage, Johnson, Lancaster, Nemaha, Otoe, Pawnee, Richardson, Sarpy, Saun - ders. Saline and Seward. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">308 THIRD BJKXNIAL REPORT OF The following reports and statistical tables comprise the twenty-fourth biennial report of the Nebraska Hospital for the Insane at Lincoln. This report embraces the period beginning December 1, 1916, and ending November 30, 1918. The population of this hospital on the first day of December, 1916, was 731 patients, 318 male and 413 female. There were admitted 233 male and 231 female patients dur - ing this biennial period. We have discharged from the hos - pital ninety male and 124 female patients. One hundred and five male and ninety female patients have died. There were in the hospital on the 30th day of November, 1918, 350 male and 436 female, or a total of 786 patients. The monthly average population of the hospital has been 759, and there has been a total of 1,195 patients under treatment during the biennial period. ACCOMPLISHMENTS During the biennial period special attention has been given to the development of the industrial department. An effort has been made to provide every patient with some occupation, such as needle work, basket making, rug weav - ing, and such household duties as are applicable to the various patients. Patients are made more contented and in many instances improve mentally by reason of having certain duties to perform. We regard industrial pursuits as very essential. The training school has made reasonable progress. Many of our nurses have gone forth into general work, some into army service, still others are completing their courses of instruction with our affiliated training school, the Cook County Hospital. AMUSEMENTS AND LIBRARY Various forms of amusements have been furnished for the benefit of our patients. Under the supervision of at - tendants those patients who wish to read are brought to the library, where they choose their own books for reading, and the librarian devotes a part of the library period read- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 309 ing to the patients. The institution is furnished with twen - ty-seven of the best periodicals which are circulated in such a manner that they come into the hands of all who desire them. There are about 900 books of fiction, history, law, poems, encyclopedias, etc., in our library. Each Tuesday evening a motion picture show, which is greatly enjoyed by the patients, is given in the amuse - ment hall. Our Friday evening dance is always looked for - ward to by the inmates. KEMGIOl'S SERVICES Religious services are held each Sunday morning at 9:30. The institution choir, made up of persons connected with the institution, supplies the music. Dr. Frederick A. Stuff, our chaplain, conducts the services and we consider this hour of chapel most profitable. MEDICAL TREATMENT When a patient enters this institution a prompt diag - nosis is made of the case in order Liat a proper prognosis and treatment may be given. As an aid to diagnosis, seri - ological examinations are made and thus is being accom - plished to simplify our treatment. Epileptic patients are receiving great relief under proper institutional treatment, but much is to be learned by the medical profession regard - ing the cause and treatment of this disease. Excellent re - sults are being obtained from the hydrotherapy treatments and this institution is well equipped with the proper ap - paratus for this work. DIPSOMANIA A remarkable feature to be noted in the hospital records during the biennium, and possibly two years previous, is the gradual reduction in number of patients committed to be treated for drug and liquor habits. This undoubtedly is due to the laws governing the use of narcotics. One hundred ninety-eight patients were treated in 1915, 150 in 1916, seventy in 1917 and fifty in 1918. At this rate </seg>
            <seg id="p006">310 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF of decrease the admittance of a patient of this type will only be an occasional incident. DENTISTRY Many patients of the hospital come to us with tooth con - ditions very bad. Some develop tooth troubles while here. Bacteriological research has revealed that many physical difficulties are caused from tooth infections. The institu - tion has at its disposal a visiting dentist upon call. PLANS FOR THE FUTURE There is now under way a hospital building for men designed to accommodate 180 patients. This building will be ready for use before another year and will partly relieve the crowded condition existing now. The present hospital kitchen is small and rather poorly equipped. We hope to have a new one, bringing with it a new bakery and cold storage plant. A good-sized still which could furnish distilled water for making ice is also very much desired. The present boiler equipment is growing old and should be enlarged. Among other needs should be mentioned a new dairy barn. The dairy herd is poorly housed at present and there is no proper milk handling room. An ornamental iron fence in front replacing the barbed wire, and well distributed lights would add much to the campus. CONCLUSION I wish to thank the governor of Nebraska, and your honorable Board for the support given me during my period of superintendency, and to express my appreciation of the earnest efforts put forth by our staff and co-workers in the institution. Respectfully, J. D. Case, Super in ten den t. Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 311 MATRON'S REPORT I)c&lt;fiiib«T 1916 !&gt;.-( 1, 1918 Sewing R i Mini Apron S69 Awnings Bed Pads in 731 Broom Covers 34 u Burial Ror Caps .... 18 Chemi 174 Comforters lv Curtains, pair Drawers .. . 177 Dres Dresses 600 La u nil rv Bags 128 Mending, pieces 4,072 Night Gowns 470 Night Shirts 154 Petticoats 590 Pillow Cases 876 Rest Jackets 244 Rubber Covers 81 Sanitary Napkins 1.442 Sheets 2,531 Shirts 498 Stand Covers 164 Strong Suits 39 Table Covers 498 Table Napkins 102 Towels 3,000 Towels, dish 1,708 Surgical Binders 12 Surgical Leggins 12 Sofa Pillows 109 Canned Goods Seventy-five glasses jelly one barrel tomato pickles. gallons grape butter. seven </seg>
            <seg id="p008">312 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE PATIENTS' TRUST FUND December 1, 1916. to December 1, J918 Note— These are the personal funds of the patients held in trust by the Institution for these atients and received and expended for their sole individual benefit. " "&lt;""«" "&gt;r mese Approximate average number of accounts December 1, 1916, to December 1 1918 was thp hundred eighty-nine. ' n PERIOD Dehi Credit* Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1916. $1386.93 December. 1916 January. 1917 Fehruarv. 1917 March. 1917 $ 347 33.1.99 Ml 143.36 205.73 159.05 261.90 April, 1917 May, 1917 June, 1917 July. 1917 August. 191 215.31 M.8.65 900.5. M04.66 MM :!36.50 193.11 145.44 1K2.9H September, 191 October, 1917 November, 191 (195.29 154.45 M42 Total for year $4287.52 $ 4615.89 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1917, $1715.30. Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1917, $1715.30, December, 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 March. 1918.. 186.26 194.62 HI 272.93 129.29 250.07 123.62 291.81 April, 1918 May, 1918 June, 1918 July, 1918. August. 1918 61.29 M6.65 434.91 MM! 584.00 :I2!).(I9 486.49 262.81 291.45 268.15 September, 1918 October, 1918 November, 1918 181.43 401.68 170.51 217.70 181.64 50S.33 Total for year $2926.04 * 4327.53 Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, $3116.79. Grand total for two years $7213.56 &lt; 8943.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 313 RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1 916, to D. ember 1, 191 AMOUNT RECE VED Total KN HAL SOUR Dec. 1. 1916 Dec. 1. 1917 Dec. 1. 1916 r. 1, 1917 Dec. 1, 1918 , Dec. 1, 1918 1). 1, 1918 Dec. 1, 1 126.75 $ 166.17 , $ 292.92 room 29.63 ! 29.63 Corn, green 2947.01 , 1525.27 4472.28 Dipsomaniac charge EKKS 26.50 23.70 Fence S.4I '.'.'... I 3-41 Freight !93 376.81 1065.74 Hides and tallow Live stock . 10398.78 15326.84 8936.49 24198.70 33135.19 Maintenance Mea'.s 225.50 38.14 | 89.09 Miscellaneous Motors 1697.37 62.78 Potato 21~.h5 629.94 Rags and bom Rentals 525.00 65.76 Scrap iron Telegrams Telephone 10.81 19.49 6.90 218.80 616.59 Uniform materials Wool 174.42 174.42 J M 1 M.M S 20 37WK Total </seg>
            <seg id="p010">SI l THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS. FURNITURE, EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE- MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE Novembe ullivatH Acre- mate t- 178 28480.00 $124 11* ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING AM) IMPROVEMENT Bui Id inn praeni Improvnnfli tiri Total O.Ofl $ 3000.00 IIMKI.IKI 000.00 1 DUlKllll^. .OUUU.l Employes building . 12000.1; 1010.00 600.00 3000.00 7000.00 3500.00 7500.00 1000.00 2100.00 13610.00 H .nil n.VMIO.oii A ' building 35000.00 46000.00 Kilrhen building 4000.00 7100.00 Bake she 50.00 600.00 150.00 MOO .00 15.00 40000.00 1650.00 Laundry building 15000.00 24150.00 Engine room 8000.00 48015.00 .-moo.iMi 3175.00 Paint sh&lt; 50.00 50.00 215.00 600.00 Orchard cottage 300.00 515.00 Farm cottage ! 1400.00 192.00 125.00 1717.00 old storage 2500.00 KMjM Morgue . ... 1400.00 50.00 537.00 1W7.00 Poultry house 200.00 400.00 Pump house 100.00 250.00 Tool house | 75.00 115.00 Brick barn 6000.00 6000.00 Farm office 2000.00 2075.00 Slaughter house 2500.00 2600.00 Frame implement shed ' 300.00 3500.00 WeM farm office 1 300.00 4(1.1X1 :14O.o» Went (arm barn and shed. 500.00 500.00 Band stand . . 75.00 75.00 Summer houae ] 25.00 25.00 frame poultry house* ■ 1600.00 2400.00 2 poultry houses I 200.00 200.00 duck hou»e 100.00 100.00 1 calf barn 100.00 400.00 Cow hospital barn :{«hi.oo 300.00 Pig housed iT ) 70.00 70.00 cattle sheds 1200.00 1200.00 1 sheep barn 200.00 200.00 Ground improvements 595.00 10050.00 $ 14850.00 17787.00 1124802.00 : $ 14850.00 25495.00 Total If 695245.00 * S 862684.00 Arm I'ncultivmted Totml Esti •d ( impus Waxte age Value Amusement IrtiildinR $ 75000 "B" buililinsc 70000 Mmin l.uiltinu 3CXMKK) H0970.OO 82950.00 32X000.00 86000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">315 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS * "a «* a 2 H? I * Ills : i I H "5 "5 S:'i ?i l- iiw i !!2 * ■3 ■a I -SS : " 1 I $1 i ! s « 5 5 5 5 P II i ! ? t 1 U : : 2 &amp; I s I fe-a ? 5 p _; •a 2 •3 ? 0 O £ £ S a •a o ! 5 i i i I : I z o M z 7. Z 1 I! •5 i I! i u Si §5 ii i § ?!? I 1 ?.££ s M ? 3 Pa i 3 &gt;&lt;k I B 5 ' :: $ P = 2 I 8 11 I« -r = ?! S .-4 i! s=_- ■■■ s ] Mi ■ 1 'a i. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Sll THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF sms s ■ X M C: &gt;r x iff 1 Vr * El 21 1 \i U*i ii i ii5 i ii ii ii*ia 51 5 ? N S"S* a i ri 5^ K a. - Z 81., 31 2 'r 5- * -• °l -a- 1 i ,i ii^i ii i iii i Jjj ii ji^ii * i.: 3 s — Kl 1 S |1 |PJI|llbKli9j h".« *'-r iij;.i a a c Z ; I lilSt-'ijili ?. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">J17 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS ;; -ii I 1 * ei in — -: n w '? ss I! O B is z e: I X ae Mr ?J RJ Mid M * N ce-i n « — a 3 2 SSx!^ N te tlf ■OOx X C 3 lull risli ii = s i« zsi H9 — 06 o Ji S_ s" I S , * . . _ ■ ; -^— ■;.-:": • T j ' j % </seg>
            <seg id="p014">318 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 2 t«a is «* ' Ijglg82«ai58" = -:■ Li ■3 g,S8§ E i. l m"i\2 «is;s«eo^eel» tr 8 i- 3 ■■ x — »O 2 U- tn S I ■ I |isss§2?sagg* ; I 1 C ** u. I JS I? ?SS : 8E 8 : £ -a s 1 &gt; I i I l&gt; B T i N .« T h F \ouxxxxxoei$$i L jj i ill jjssisjjjjs ll j* £ J|g8g8=8a»8" 1 i* f JJS: Si I Niiiim i i « 1 ? jiff 1 8 MSUI- g </seg>
            <seg id="p015">319 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS *~ £ -■ * a ; ill J11J11;:UI;;1;M ; I i * 2 5ig'.o2SSSS S£S : -a -Sj&gt;\ : g &lt; j. ju I ' _^ - IS |S « B : 5SS5S3S SS : B j a l&gt;i* S t i ••" *!Eii-!iiIIIi d££ t SON • ? S|b;;-b 1 h I 1 1 I ? i. 1 I ill ! Uii^ii! i I ■pill*! :S !3S2S88 J K : : ;S J g z = Sil § ilUIS Si! 3 5ii : 1*1* - "! ' i 3 © © © © © © «* © «O © © ' © *S ' % its c « © t© es © t- 'xoex | oo £ , 5 . S i"R3-o«n ©toe .|» ; lj pJJ : : : j^ 3 I ssssssi i£3 ■ ■ £ I IS : S«S2§SS 5S N 1 1 ■ 3C I a ! §gg§§sSS§»SSS§S§§ | ?. = &gt; I » * gJM ; i,|i|illlfillliJiiJ!!i| | S I «s w " |_ _ „ 1 S555S0 5-»55 n on S 3 OiAOOOX OOCKOOC •- Q &lt;O — t - i </seg>
            <seg id="p016">320 i. THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF ! rl s : ;J I I !*■ ||i*]; 2 1"! g MXIS I ■ 5 Gil ! JJ-I ! ■ I 'i » 1*1 x « I * ! j? [* . seo 8 3 -5-S : 5 « nisrrj Pi I ;;:| : ! i i s I f : : : : t u ' e I = I 1 Z|| \\\ I til ii| - I K5 5 S I iii Q &lt; U x s u 4 si" - s O I ~| (I ,, , TT~ * a -mill Hi 2 = 2 ? I30MM — . — M : : : : -ri S.I £ 8 1 B - : : : : : : •: J MN i I °l : ■ ■ ■ Tie ! :| ° i fl s ,2 yw a yij || ■ ■ : : •&gt; K t E 5 ? 2 '-- fi SI 5 5 j il ■? ii s e ? Jj, ; ill ii' I tij &lt;^c ttl|«-|" "I ijliii&amp;Hrj 1 ! ■s Z : I £ H </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 321 iiSg?§lS |iSiS5!S = 3 tj • I SI SS 1 1 s - ■-- TO O*J 3 ! .^x z- . rt ST. ?J ■«■— ' oo •* i •» IS z *31! I !S£ t E *- V, s i." 3 Z" M a". : « i &gt; • f si h— 1 ! 5 i j B-TTrtr z ? S 5 51 ik i : • -/. ! ■ i &gt;. I E2 ' "* L!!_; js iz I "5 PI^Mi! .! h llilllliW * - S2 ' 5 H^iii i 3 51 * £ liil Etr z" 2«. S5SSS 5 I 0. q - 51 | I sgsss 3 | g -' i| i ■ i e • • • ■ I ■ ' &lt;\ 1! i &gt;lt §l illi \\ l J il^r a - • 1 U— a £ r xi-tftxir 1 ~, &gt;x' roc Si *t 3 ' ss 5- I ■ 5 1 iJs ! is i -S &lt; «»-«s! ■ i x . X I ; " ,_ ! . ! 85SB8S I 8 J^ £ — I I : -c U V ' csjnjic I J9 \ i g S nirsa-M 1 6 s iiiiiirri :-:l S ; ,151: i|S \ &gt; 'I L 1 A ~ 17, !|iiS8|ri \W\ iTSlpIS illi &gt;ii s ''IE ! !'l&gt;sg: &gt;■■■« a" a iil^lij-w-atl ~\ a || , S88888 8 s Iliu iSiiii I § still III!;;! i f J 31 liFri"" »e — r- — ©j i M . ISS888I3 |° I"!*!.! . it88M3|&amp; Sal 3 1 r;d'ricc»«eOrt p I *|t tJ a Z 555 5 &gt; = •9 5 S i 00 j|» 1 a« I N 1 Z liilL M i Wll»JTn *|linri|l WlliiTn « a P s SS g SIS is a ?i % : 2 S* :::: : li 52 1 SI I a a is I I si i a s ■a ' s : ■ ■ -3 1 iJiiti hi diiiH IM Iliilll^ </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 71 S*Srf«2 f x it if ■3 fr- : 3 s» M&lt;e m &gt;^ z X _= * s a V. as s 5 i! ji . sjg.SS : 8 :{= f SI 111 -»-::-:: » . |§:;3:;l3 ! - ||j ■iliSii "1 life nil* *l : J iriiii i - 8 _§i ; &gt; !« — jg i KP I i pi I i — — i i» • •" • i g i &amp; | | |p life f I " ' I s IS = I IS* I " : : , ■ . 2$ -S .!g li " ' ' "- Q l *r •£ .- : : : tl I ill IS I?. PliilTiilj a 2 . ■•_ . 88g.S§§l£ Hl| «| -11! 1 I 1 S |l|S|"-« !: g | ,. !SS8£8 . S gsS&gt; &gt;!?+T++ : J " L2 i» *, ||H::::H lflj ■= i "« I !«■ • • ■ ■ ig i ■is I II ;|i »«p : j n MllHl 1 1 P IP : : i : : I 2z ii B S _■ c a 3 I r c ;gsg§gsj§ *2 i I iisHl i I w lautis </seg>
            <seg id="p019">323 I I THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS MOVEMENT OF POPULATION TABLE I For Year For Year ending Total •..i» Nov. 30. Nov. M, (or 1917 191(1 Biennium 1OVEMEN um M F. T. j M. F. T M F. T. F. T T ,1. F. T !^J18 413 731 843 lln Ttil :UX 11:1 "31 B3 63 126i 95 73 168 158 136 294 -:«i ■resent al begir kdmitled: 36 294 78 137 1 For 33 39 72 26 39 65 59 78 137 Readmitted 1 1 11 Transferred from Returned from parole, grante.i 5 5 10 5 5 10 K.I 4 t _4_ __4 4 menl of period 1 520 Mil M.I .VI" WM Sir. 6*21177 6 S 11 6 8 14 12 16 28 -,:|cl K:i21177 Total undi &gt;i»chan[ed Restored 23 85 58 26 23 49 49 58 107 :).&gt; 5» 26 2:1 19 49 58 107 Improved I'nimpruve Not insane 11 18 29 16 14 30 27 32 59 h'.l 2 X X . . 2 Transferred u Died 39 41 80 66 49 115- 105 »0 195 }9 41 80 66 49 115' 105 90 195 | 81 102 IH 111 HI 20* IN 196 391 196 391 1X3 114 94 208 'otal removed 313 418 761 350 436 786 350 486 786 Ml 41X 761 350 436 786 350 436 786 leriod Remaining at close of Average number treat Absent on parole at c! 33:1 116 749 348 423 771 681 8391520 7. 7 1 11.1 SS3 116 749 348 423 771 681 8391520 Ml 1 . . 1 if I m 1 J this or similar institution! in Nebraska o r diichanjeJ without returning to Hospital . Nebraska o r who h nitar in-*'itati Includes patient elsewhere LO.*pita! • escaped and lat tcape at close of Includes patient also patients absent &lt; i paroled or in parole or 6 .f tar. II -AGE OF THOSE ADMITTED OSE ADMITTED For Ye«r For Year , ending ending Total Nov. 30, I Nov. 30, , for 1917 1918 , Biennium I M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. I i 1... 1 TABLE For Year For Year ending ending Nov. 30, . Nov. 30, Total f.pr AGE 1H1 Biennium !i M. F. T. M. F. T M. F. T. 1 ... 1 1 Under 1 4 2 6 3 3 « 7 5 12 16 and under 20 20 and under 25 25 and under 30 30 and under 35 35 and under iO 0 and under 45 4b and under 5&lt;&gt; ■»i and under 55 7 6 13 12 7 191 18 13 32 9 7 16 15 13 2S 1 24 20 44 7 12 1»| 14 17 31| 21 29 50 13 21 34 11 13 24. 24 34 58 10 IS 28 11 17 28 21 30 51 10 13 23, 5 11 161 15 24 39 8 7 15 10 9 19) 18 16 84 7 7 14 10 3 13] 17 10 27 and under 60 527 3 4 7 8 6 14 K0 and under 65 65 and under 70 Over 70 5 2 7 9 6 15| 14 8 22 11 10 21! 16 9 25 27 1» 4« 2 2 2 X Unknown 97 102 199 121 112 233| 218 214 432 Totals </seg>
            <seg id="p020">324 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OK TABLE 111— CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Yemr ending ending Nov. SO, Nov. 30. Totml CIVIL STATIS 1*17 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T F. T. 24 S3 47 24 71 86 Is 134 mule Marrie.1 Widowed Divorced S'pmrated I nknown 42 55 »7 44 56 100 86 111 197 10 18 28 15 20 U 19 38 63 4 3 7 9 8 17 18 11 24 112 4 1 Si 4 Totml 102 I'M 121 11 !:)_■ TABLE IV EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Ye»r For Year ending ending Total Totml EDUCATION Nov. SO, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium ■ mi M. F. T. II. F. T. M. F. T «. F. T. i M. F. T. M. F. T. 14 11 25' 1 6 13 21 17 38 Frim:u\ 14 11 25 7 6 13 21 17 38 High school 62 67 129 82 91 173 144 15* 302 67 129 82 91 173 144 158 302 6 14 20 10 10 20 16 24 40 6 14 20 10 10 20 IB 24 40 College or uni None . . . ■it 5 5 10 3 :t 8 5 13 111 :l IS 7 3 JO 6 3 » 13 6 It 3 10 6 3 in L'nknc .1 2 5 13 2 15 16 4 20 .1 2 5 13 2 15 16 4 9 6 4 20 97 102 199 121 112 23.'! 218 214 132 Tot mis 102 199&lt; 121 112 2:11 218 214 432 TABLE V -NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED &gt;SE ADMITTED For Y«ar For Year ending ending Total For Year For Year ending ending Nov. 30, Nov. 30, NATIVITY Nor. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 I!- .mum 1917 1918 Bie-inium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. I. t. T. I M. F. T. M. F. T. MahMfca 29 29 58 :13 22 65 62 61 123 29 29 58 H 22 65 K2 SI 123 U. S. other thmn N Total native born Austria •brmakm 39 51 901 51 49 100| 'III 100 190 39 51 901 51 49 100| 'III 100 190 68 80 148 84 81 165 152 161 313 68 80 148 84 81 165 152 161 313 5 3 8| 3 3 » 3 11 3 81 3 3 » 3 11 Belgium Bohemim Canada Denmark England Finland (Jermany Gracee 1 1 1 1 I.... 1 | 1 . 1 4 15 5 3 8 9 4 IS 416 638 94 13 2 2 4 2 2 4 2 2 4| 2 2 4 2 3 5 2 3 5 5 6 2 1 3 7 1 8 I... 1 1 . 1 I... 1 1 1 7 9 16 7 7 14 14 16 30 7 9 161 7 7 14 14 16 30 1 1 1 ... . 1 2 . . . 1 1 1 1 . 1 2 . . . 2 Hungaria Holland IreUnd .. 1 1 2 1 1 2 112 11 1 1 .... 1 1 1 1 .... 1 1 11 4 3 7 4 4 8 11437 448 IUly 112 1 1 2 13 1 1 t\ 1 1 2 1 3 Poland 1 I .... 1 1 1 I .... 1 1 Rumania Ruaaia 1 1 .... 1 1 2 2 1 1 1 I 2 t 112 3 3 6 4 4 8 1 1 2: 3 3 6 4 4 8 1 2 I .... 4 4 1 6 7 Sweden Total foreign born Unknown 28 21 49 30 28 58 58 49 107 112 7 3 10 8 4 12 Totals 97 102 1991 121 112 233 218 214 482 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">325 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLS VI OCCUPATIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Yew ; For Year ending endinj. Total Nov. 30, Nov. SO, for UPAT ION Biennium 1917 l»l| A. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T Agent 1 . . 1 Bank teller Barber 1 1 1 .... 1 3 1 4 4 1 Bookkeeper Bricklayer. Bute her :l 3 ».... 3 1 1 .... 1 1 I . .. 1 I . 1 Baker 1 1 1 1 I.... 1 Blacksmith Carpenter Clerk I «.... 6 3 3 6 1 1 4 4 8 1 1 1 1 ... 1 Coal miner Cook 1 1 . . 1 1 J 1 Druggist Electrician i! i i.... i Engineer, locom Farmer v&lt; 51 51 1 1 1 . . 1 Fireman Gardner 1 I.... I 83 . ... 64 «4 . ... 147 147 Housewife La borer 23 23: 24 2 26, 47 2 49 :i 3 1... 1 «.... 4 Machinist Mason Merchant Miner . 3 3 1 1 1 ... 1 ».... a 1. . 1 1 1 Musician Peddler 1 1 1 1 1 I.... 1 Pharmacist Plum ber 1... 1 1 1 1 1 4 1 5 Printer 2 . 2 Real estate 1... 1 1 1 1 1 5 1 6 1 1 1 1 3 3 Railroad employe Salesman 3 3 2 2 Stenographer Student 1 1 1 1 ■' 6 2 8 1 . . .. 1 1... 1 Shipping clerk 2 4 6 1 .... 1 3 S 2 7 9 1 1 Teamster Tailoreas Veterinary None 1 1 1 1 1 1 11 10 21 1 1 29 21 50 22 26 48 18 11 29 20 26 46 Unknown Totals 102 199 121 112 233 218 214 432 o&lt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p022">rHIRI) BIENNIAL REPORT OF r ABLE VII COUNTIES OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM lf( k'i Ul Mi hi. li M. F. T. M. F. T i :i 13 li V 1 :i ked U 1 1 10 18 14 II 16 II I 11 11 .1. 4 13 16 IK 32 15 20 1 1 Th Wi u. 3 a 1 1 1 I 3 a i 112 233 218 214 432; 350 436 THt 19 16 11 12 8 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE VIII FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE ADMITTED D'BEASE 7. Hrain Tumor n Tumi 'hosis: 1 4 Senile Psyohows: 1. Simple deterioration . . . 2. I Mirious and confused state 3. Depressed and agitated stat 4. Paranoid states 7 14 21 IS IS 28' 22 27 49 VI rious and confused ressed and agitated i 3 3 3 3 \ 11 3 4 7| 3 5 8 3 3 2 13 5 16 ■i &gt; 5. Paresis: 1 . Orebral form 2. Tabetic form 19 6 25' 23 7 30 42 IS 55 19 6 25' 23 7 30 42 IS 55 TTl 1 1 4 2 6 5 2 7 fi. Dementia Pra*cox Group: 1. I'ndifTerentiated 2. Hebephrenic :t. K:tt atonic 4. Paranoid "). Allied to dementia prsecox I). ix Grout: differentiated l&gt;ephrenic 1. . 1 i 1 ... 1 1 .... 1 6 11 17 13 5 3 8! 4 1 6 11 17 13 g 21 19 19 38 19 19 38 5 3 8! 4 5 9&gt; 9 8 17 8 17 iranoid 5 10 15 6 10 16 11 20 31 10 1« 11 20 31 1. ... 1 | 1. ... 1 ■ntia prsecox 1 7. Manic Depn^ssive Group: 1 . Manic states 2. Depressed states 3. Mixed states 4. Allied states Manic Depressive Group 15 15 6 19 25 6 34 40 Manif 6 34 40 1 &gt;epres«ed state 3 13 16 4 20 24 7 33 40 13 16! 4 20 24| 7 33 40 M tied stai I .... 1 ! 1... 1 I ... 1 2.... 2 1 2. ... 2 Aiiied Ptat 8. Involution Melancholia Involution Melancholia Other tlnuressed states. 112 1 1 2 13 :i 9. Other d«- pressed states 1 . Simple depression 2. Symtomatic depression 3. (^differentiated depression ::::::::::::::::::::::|:::::::::::: 8 3 li 5 3 8 IS 6 19 mple depression Svmt.»matic depression 3. Tndifferentiated depression 10. Paranoid states 10. Paranoid states 11. Kpileptic states: 1 . Kxcited 2. Depressed :i. Deteriorated 4. No mental change 1 li 6 4 10; 7 4 11 I 3 1 4! » 1 4 2 6 8; 3 2 5 5 8 13 3. ... 3| 3.... 3 :i 12. P«ychoneuroses: 1. Hysterical type 2. Psych asthenie type :t. Neurasthenic type Hysterical type Psyehaathenic typ* Neurasthenic type IS. Psychopathic Personalities: IS. Psychopathic Personalit 14. Developmental Defects: H. Developmental Defects: 1. Idiocy 2. Imbecility 3. Constitutional inferiority. 1. Idiocy 9 4 13 4 6 id 13 10 23 Imbecility 2 2 3 1 4 5 1 6 15. Unclassified 15. Unclassified 16. Not insane 11 3 1 4; 3 2 5 1 .... 1 I 1 1 11 3 1 4i 3 2 5 16. Not insane 1 ' I ' l 97 102 199J 121 112 233 1 218 214 432 97 102 199 121 112 233 1 218 214 432 For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 80, Nov. SO, for Huntington'w chorea Posi paralytic psycho: </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE IX NUMBER OF ATTACKS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XI HEREDITARY INFLUENCE IN DISORDER OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year ending e.,&lt;l,n,; Total ATTACK Nov. SO. Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. j M. r. T. , M. r. T. FirM M 62 115 »5 74 169 178 IM 314 SwjmI 5 27 32 12 28 40 17 &amp;S 72. Third 9 9 9 5 14 it II 23 Fourth 3 4 7 2 2 .1 6 9 Fifth . 1 1 1 1 Sixth . 1 1 1 1 Seventh 1. ... 1 ' 1 1 Kighth 1 1 11 112 1 nknuwn 4... 4 4 1 5; K 1 9 Totals 97 102 1 Hi* 121 112 2:M 2!x 214 43* TABLE X PREVIOUS DURATION OF DISEASE IN THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Total IMKATION Nov. 30, Nov. 30. (or 1917 1918 Biennium ' M. F. T. j If. F. T. M. F. T. Less than 1 year ' 28 38 66 SI 3« NT 7S ." ' IM 1 year 13 18 M 14 12 2li 27 .11 57 2 yean 6 6 12 11 9 20 17 15 32 From 2 to 5 years 11 13 24 12 12 24 23 25 48 From .") lo 1(1 yearn 1 12 9 21 10 19 2S. 22 2S SO From 1(1 to 1 5 yean ! 4 7 11 6 6 10 7 17 From IS to 20 years ! 3 1 4 3 2 5 ti 3 9 From 20 lo 25 yean j 6 3 9 2 3 5 X B 14 Over 25 yearn 8 5 13 1 1 » 6 14 l'na.s&lt;-ertained 6 2 8 12 18 30 IS IM M Totals 97 102 19S 121 lit 233 218 214 432 ii.« 1*1 HEREDITARY INFLUENCE For Year •MfaH Nov. 30. 1917 For Year endimr Total Nov. 30. for 1918 Iiiennium I M. F. T. " M. F. T. M. F. T. Hereditary taint denied Father or mother insane Grandfather or grandmother insane Aunts, uncles or cousins insane Brother or sister insane I'nknown 76 80 166 5 9 14 3 1 4i 5 4 91 3 11 14, 8 2 lOi 69 68 137 145 148 293 15 9 24 20 18 38 12 3 4 3 7 6 9 15 11 13 24 9 19 28 12 30 42 ' 28 11 39 36 13 49 Totals 100 107 207 128 118 246 228 225 453 ■ol </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 329 'I TABLE XII -~ORM OF DISIAS2 OF THOSE DISCHARCXD AS RECDVERED TABLE XIII DURATION OF RESIDENCE IN HOSPITAL OF THOSE RECOVERED TABLE XIV -NUMBER OF ATTACKS OF THOSE RECOVERED DISEASE For Yew RMiiBf Nov. 30, 1917 For Year ending Nov. 30. 1918 Total for Bie.inium M. F. T. M 1. F. T. M. F. T. Acute alcoholic psychosis Dementia preeox. . . Manic depressive insanity Allied to manic depressive insanity Infective exhaustive psychosis. . . 1 1 2 2 I 3 7 10 1. ... l| | 1. . . 11. 1 1 3 3 S 1 1 2 2 ! 5 t 6 12 1." 2 S 1 1 Totals 6 » 1 5 S 8 1 II , 12 17 M DURATION For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Y«r ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Biennium ess lhan two months to 4 month* to 9 months &gt; to 12 months t to IK months • to 2:1 months. years and over M. F. T. M !. F. T. M. F. T. 2 2 1 3 3 1 1 1 '..'. 1 4 1 li 1 2 1 1 : 3 2 2 1 1 » 1 2 1 3 3 6 4 4 5 5 10 1 2 3 2 1 3 1 1 2 1 1 Totals 6 9 1 6 8 1 II 12 17 29 ATTACK For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Yemr ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Biennium Firm Second Third Fourth Sixth Eighth M. F. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T. 3 3 2 2 3 ......... 1 6 j 3 4 7 2 2 4 1 1 2 a 7 is 4 4 8 1 4 5 11 1 . 1 1 » Totals 6 9 1 IS |. 6 8 14 !2 17 29 U </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XV AGES AT ADMISSION OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XVI CAUSE OF DEATH AGE For Year endinj Nov. 30, 1917 ForYiv NoV'sO, 1918 Total for Riennium M. F. T. I M. F. T. ; M. F. T. Inder IS 15 and under 20 . ill mnd under J&gt; :lu and under M Hi and under 10 . . . 40 and under !5. . 45 and under 50 . . 50 and under l»&gt; . BO and under 70 . 70 and over . : I... 1 1 2 ;i 1 1 1 3 4 2 3 5 1 . 1 _^.___: 3 3 1 1 2 1 1 2 2 4 1 2 3 1 1 1 3 2 S 1 1 3 5 3 5 1 I :, ■-» - 8 I 1 TotmU j 6 9 15, 6 8 14 12 17 i a CAUSE OF DEATH For Year ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Year i-i-itng Total Nov. ». for 1H1X Biennium M. F. T. j M. F. T. M. F. T. Apoplexy Arterio-ecleroais Alcoholism Angina Pf-etoris Broncho-pneumonia Carcinoma: 1 . Intestines 2. Stomach 3. Uterus Cerebro spinal syphilis Dementia pra?cox Endocarditis chronic Erysipelas Epilepsy psychosis Exhaustion of insanity Influenza Nephritis Paratyphoid Paresis Pellagra Pneumonia Senility Sepsis Suicide... . Tuberculosis pulmonary Tuberculosis meningitis Totals 5 6 11 ::::::: ...":■::...•! i i \. 2 3 51 ::: :::::...!...5 ::■:■:::■:::: it ::.." ? '{I ....... ■ ■- b - - 9 i.... i '.'.'.'.'.'.'. : ii is 1 1 2 39 41 80 »tS 8 8 16 2 . 2 5 S 1 1 1... 1 1 I 1 .. .. 1 2 3 5 I 1 ... 1 1 II 11 2 2 6 17 112 112 6 4 10 8 7 IS » 1 4 3 1 4 4.... 4 7 .... 7 ».... S «.... S 112 13 4 | 21 9 30 33 11 44 I .... 6 6 .... 7 7 5 1 6 5 1 6 11 12 23 15 17 32 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 Ui 11 3 23 26 1 1 2 i 66 49 115 105 90 195 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 331 TABLE XVII -PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN HOSPITAL OF THOSE WHO DIED For Year I For Year ending ending Total Nov. SO, Nov. 31), for AGE 1917 1918 Riennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Under 15 15 and under 20 20 and under 25 25 and under 30 30 and under 35 35 and under 40 40 and under 45 45 and under 50 50 and under 60 60 and under 70 70 and over 1.... 1 I.... 1 1.... 2 213 347 55 10 2 3 5 6 6 11 7 9 16 8 3 &lt; 11 4 161 14 7 21 15 6 6 6 12 7 11 18 326 347 6 6 12 8 4 12 11 11 22 19 16 34 7 9 16 11 4 16 18 13 31 12 14 26 16 10 25 27 24 51 39 41 80 66 49 115! 105 90 195 Totals I I I Less than 1 month . From 1 to 6 months From 6 to 12 months From 1 to 2 years From 2 to 5 years From 5 to 10 years - From 10 to 20 yean From 20 to 30 years From 30 to 40 years Totals PERIOD For Year For Year -ndinij endinf Total Nov. SO. Nov. 30, (or 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 53 8 9 5 14 14 822 8 6 14 12 8 20 20 14 34 3 1 4 10 6 16 13 7 tO 9 S 18 5 5 111 14 14 28 6 9 IS 15 11 26 21 20 41 4 37 9 4 13 13 7 20 3 7 10 4 9 13 7 16 23 2 2 2 1 3 2 S « 1 1 2 1 1 2 .... 39 41 80 66 49 115 105 90 195 I _l I TA BL1 .E 3 [VIII- -A Z£ AT DEATH </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XIX ALLEGED CAUSES OF PSYCHOSIS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XX— AVERAGE NUMBER OF PATIENTS EMPLOYED Average Number Employed CAUSE ForYemr ending Nov. 30. 1917 For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1918 Biennium If. F. T. M F. T. M. F. T. Alcohol Worry Disease Senility Heredity Arterio-seleroMs Dissipation Grief Menopause " Sexual perversion Menstrual disorders ...... Family trouble Over work . Pregnancy Constitutional itensitiveness Trauma Religion Epilepsy Love affair Masturbation Syphilis Over study . v . Drugs . . Sun stroke. . Imbecile Constitutional inferiority Operation Goitre Emotional shock 7 4 11 4 5 9 2 &amp; 7 6 6 12 3 6 9 . . S S' 4 4 9 9 11 2 2 3 2 5 6 6 2 4 6 7 2 9 2 2 2 1 1 '.!' ".'. '.'. '. IT T 14 1 1 7 71 14 4 18 9 7 16 13 12 25 2 4 6 4 9 13 13 ' 10 23 19 16 35 8 10 18 11 16 27 3 3 1 II 1 14 5 18 9 9 9 1 1 ( 1 1 2 . ... 4 4 6 6 2 2 3 4 7 2 2 5 5 11 11 2 4 6 5 1 6 12 .'! 15 2 2 6 4 10 8 5 13 1 12 2 3 2 5 6 2 8 19 10 29 36 17 53 1 11 1 1 1 1 1 112 112 13 4 13 4 3 3 3 3 11 11 15 6 15 6 Totals ' 60 6* 129 I SI 76 157; 141 145 286 Not given fnknown 8 12 20 29 21 50 11 10 II 19 it 41 29 26 55 58 47 105 ~ — , Average Per Cent In Ward Outside Ward Aggregate Population Employed ii. F. t7 M. F. T. ' M. F. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T During year ending Nov. 30, 1917 140 160 300 101 114 215J241 274 575.141 418 762 70.5 65.5 67 During year ending Nov. 30, 1918 120 134 254:108 73 18122s 207 435351 424 775 64.9 48.8 56 \verage for biennium 1180 147 277J104.5 9.5 198 234.5 240.5 5051347.5 421763.5 67.5 57.161. I : i </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE XXI— RATIO OF EMPLOYEES TO PATIENTS TABLE I MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year For Ye«r ; ending ending Total For Year For Year MOVEMENT MOVEMENT Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium 1917 1918 Biennium ; M. F. T. ' M. F. T. M. F. T. 18 2 20 1 1 18 2 20 M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T Present a' beginning of period Admitted: Present a&gt; beginning of period 18 2 20 1 1 18 2 20 Admitted: For first time Readmitted Returned from parol? granted before commence - ment of period Returned from escape made before commencement of period . Total unier treatment | 45 8 53 29 U 45 74 24 98 For first time Readmitted . . 45 8 53 29 16 45 74 21 98 16 1 17 5 5 21 1 22 16 1 17 5 5 21 1 22 1 1 Returned (rom parol? granted before comme ■niv nce- ment of period Returned from escape made before commencement of period . MOt 82 11 93 35 16 51 116 27 143 3 ».... S Total under treat/nen •Discharged: 82 11 931 35 16 51 116 27 143 * Discharged: Recovered Improved Unimproved Died Insane Escaped, not yet returned or discharged. . Recovered Improved 13 5 1 I:! ."» IS 8 S 11 20 8 29 11 20 8 29 i 49 4 53 15 5 2&lt;i 64 9 73 49 4 53; 15 5 201 64 9 73 12 1 13 5 2 7 17 3 20 Unimproved Died 12 1 13 5 2 7 17 3 20 17 3 20 2 1 3 .....'....'.'. 2 13 Insane 1 3 1 2 1 3 Escaped, not yet returned or discharged Total removed . . 5 5 6 6 12 11 6 17 6 12 11 6 17 Total removed 81 11 92 34 16 50 114 27 142 81 11 92! 34 16 50 114 27 142 1 lj 1 1 1 1 10 2 12 2.5 .58 2.08' 6.25 1.29 7.54 Remaining at end of period Remaining at end of period Average number treated . 1 1 1 1 1 . . . 1 Av9rage number treated . ♦Includes patients paroled or escaped and Ian 10 2 12 2.5 .58 2.08 6.25 1.29 7.54 ♦Includes patients paroled or escaped and also patients absent on parole or escape at close Later discharged without returning to hospital* of year. Later discharged without returning to hospital* also patients absent on parole or escape at close of y TABLE II— AGE OF Tl AGE of year. THOSE ADMITTED For Yemr i For Year I ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 1 1 2 '.'.'.'. ' i " 'i 1 3 4 TABLE II ACE OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year I For Year AGE 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. i II. F. T Under 15 Under 15 15 and under 20 20 and under 25 25 and under 30 30 and under 35 35 and under 40 40 and under 45 45 and under 50 50 and under 55 55 and under 60 60 and under 65 65 and under 70 Over 70 15 and under 20 112 2 2 13 4 S14 426 73 10 20 and under 25 3 14 4 2 6 7 3 10 7 2 9 4 3 7 11 5 16 H 1 :i 7 11 5 16 25 and under 30 30 and under 35 9 »\ 10 5 15 19 5 24 13 3 161 5 2 7 18 5 23 9 9 10 5 15 19 6 24 35 and under 40 IS 3 16) 5 2 7 18 5 23 7 2 9| 2 2 9 2 11 91 2 2 9 2 11 40 and under 45 45 and under 50 9 9 3 1 4 12 1 13 9 9 3 14 12 1 13 50 and under 55 2. 2 ».... S 5 5 ».... Si •.... 6 55 and under 60 6 6 112 7 18 6 6| 1 1 2! 7 1 8 4.... 4 1... 1 5.... 6 60 and under 65 4 .. . 4 1 .. . . 1 5. ... 6 €5 and under 70 Over 70 .... ■■■ — ■ t ■■ -••■ •■ - Unknown Totals 1 . ... 1 1... 1 Unknown Totals 61 9 70 34 16 SO 95 25 120 61 9 70 34 16 50, 95 25 120 Male j *— »» Total Number of physicians, including superintendent Ratio of physicians to patients Number of day nurses and ward attendants. ... Ratio of same to patients Number of night nurses and ward attendants . . Ratio of same to patients Total dav and nigh: nurse*) and ward attendants Ratio of same to patients Total officers and employees Ratio of same to patients 3 18 ■ 4" 22 42 1 38 16 54 59 4 1 to 192.125 56 1 to l:l.7 20 1 to S8.4 76 1 to 10.11 101 1 to 7.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 334 TABLE IV^EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE V— NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED CIVIL STATUS For Year For Year endin, endinr Nov. 30, Nov. SO, 1917 1918 M. F. T. M. F. T. Total for Piennium m r. t. Single Married Widowed Divorced Separated . . . 23 ... 2SI 10 2 12 25 5 30 21 9 30 8 1 91 2 1 3 4 3 7 . . 2 2 I..." 1 1 * 3 3:1 2 35 46 14 60 10 2 12 4 5 9 2 2 4 Totals 61 9 70 34 16 SO 95 25 120 For Year For Vw ending endinc Total EDUCATION NovTsO. Nov. SO, for 1917 1918 Bienniura M. F. T. U. F. T. M. F. T ' '" " ' — — —— — Primary 2 2 4 I.... 1 3 2 5 ■ommon school 49 S 54 26 11 37, 75 IS 91 •ligh school 4 2 6 4 S 7 8 5 IS College or university 4 4 1 1 2 5 1 6 Slone 1.... 2 1 1 2 3 1 4 Jnknown I.... 1 1 1 ToUta (1 9 70 S4 IS 50' 95 25 120 l 1 i NATIVITY Nebraaka L'. S. other than Nebraska rotal native bom Canada Denmark Germany Ireland Norway Scotland Sweden For Year For Year endinf ending Total Nov. SO, Nov. SO, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. ! M. F. T. . . 25 4 29 16 4 20 41 8 49 26 5 SI 14 12 26 40 17 57 . 61 9 60 30 16 46' 81 25 106 I.... 1 1 ... 1 1.... 1, 1... 1 t... 2 1 .... 1' I.... S ».... t 3.... S l.... i ! i.... i S ... t i 3.... » . 10 10 S. ... Si 13 IS 1... I 1.... 1 . . 61 9 70 14 It W 95 26 lt» Total foreign born Unknown Totali </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 335 TABLE VI OCCUPATIONS OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year .endin. For Year ,-nding Nov. :)U, Total Nov. 30. for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T M. F. T. | M. T. T. Accountant A|«it. 2 .... X 1... 1 1 1 S .... t 1 1 1.... 1 1 1 Art r.-^ Barber 1 1 1 1 1 Billposter Butcher Carpenter Clerk 1 1 1 &gt; ■I 2 4 Contractor Cooper 1 1 1 1 1 :! 1 1 I Cook 2 1 I.... 2 1 S Dairyman Dentist 1 I 1 1 Electrician Drujnjist 1 1 1 1 :i 3 1 1 4 . 4 Engineer, civil Farmer 1 1 1 1 12 12 1*. . It Housekeeper Insurance 5 5 12 12 1 1 I.... 1 Laborer 14 14 4 11 21 4 IS Machinist Mason 1 1 1 1 1 ... 1 1 ».... 3 MUSICS!, Nurse 1 I.... 1 1 3 1 3 1 1 1 1 X Painter Peddler Plumber » ... t 2 2 1 2 . 2 1 I.... 1 Railroad employee Reporter 1 1 I.... 1 I... 1 1 3 Salesman ■ I 5 &amp; Saloon-keeper Stockman 1 1 1 ■1 2 Tailor 1 1 1 1 1 1 Taxi driver Teamster Waiter 1 1 3 3 1 s ... s 1 1 1 I.... t No occupation Unknown 2 2 4 ■2 2 4 1 1 5 2 6 2 8 Totals 61 9 70 34 16 SOI 94 26 120 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VII -COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For Yemr For Year All ending ending Total Remaining Nov. 30, , Nov. :», for Nov. 3D, COUNTY Nov. SO, Adams Antelope Buffalo Clay Cumintc Dakota Dodge Douglas Frontier Furnas Hall Holt Kearney Lancaster Merriek . Nance Nemaha Otoe Pawnee Phelps Pierce Platte Red Willow Richardson Sarpy Scotts Bluff Seward Sheridan Thurston Washington Total 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T Alcohol habit Drug habit 51 1 52! 8 2 10 59 3 62 10 8 18 26 II 40 36 22 58 Total. 61 9 70, 31 16 50 95 25 120 TABLE IX TIMES PATIENTS HAVE BEEN COMMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Tctal Nov. 30, Nov. 30, : for COMMITMENTS 1917 1918 Biennium Once Twice Thrice Four times Totals 61 9 70 34 16 SO; 95 25 120 M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 47 8 55 26 14 40 73 22 95 11 1 12 8 2 10 19 3 22 ■ .... * 2 2 1... 1 I.... 1 1917 1918 j- Biennium . I ■ 1918 8 I M. F. T. i M. F. T. | M. F. T. ! ML F. ' T. 1.... ij 1.... 1~ I.... li 1... 1 ... 1 1. 1 1 1 1 2 2 2 1 1 3 :l 1 . 1 1 . 1 1 1 .... 1 1 r ... 2 2... 2 17 8 25 23 12 35 40 20 60 2 ... 2 . . 2 2 1 1 2! 1 1 2 2 1 3 2 1 :&gt; 1 1 1.. 1 1 ... 1 ...... 1 1 8.... 8 4 1 5 12 1 II 1.... 1 1... I 2 t ... 2 ... * 2 2 I... 1 I... 1 I . . 1 1 . 1 ... 1.... 2 2 2 *.... X t... 2 «.... * 2 ... 2 3 . . 3 1 ... I 4 . . 4 . r 1 1 1 1 s . s ».. . 3 I... 1 1 . 1 r i . . i i i, . i .. . i i . i . r i. ... l i i . S 3 1 1 4 4 I I. ... 1 1. 1 1 1 ill 61 9 70 34 16 50 95 25 IM 1 TABLE VIII -CAUSES FOR ADMISSION OF THOSE ADMITTED For Year For Year radini ending CAUSE Nov. 30. Nov. 30. Tot«l for </seg>
            <seg id="p033">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE X -AGES WHEN HABIT BEGAN TABLE XI -CHARACTER OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED AGE For Y.-ar ending Nov. 30, 1917 For Year I ending Total Nov. 30, (or 1918 Biennium I Under 15 15 and under 20 20 and under 25 . . 25 and under 30 30 and under 40 . 40 and under 50 ... Over 50 yearn Unknown M. F. T. M. F. T. M F. T. .■I 2 5| 9.... 9! 1U 2 12, K 1 9 20 3 2S !l 1 10 _!l J: 61 9 70 2 . 2! 6 2 7 3 3 6 12 3 15 12 6 18 22 8 30 6 3 9 14 4 18 8 4 12 28 7 35 2 2 11 1 12 I... 1 I.... 2 '■ ' i 34 16 50l 96 25 120 Total* RACE For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium j M. F. T. I M. F. T. I M. F. T. Father: 1. Normal 2. Diseased Apoplexy TulH*rruloMs Nephritis Heart trouble Cancer Paralysis 3. Defective — Feeble-minded Insane Kpileptic \. Neurotic 5. Intemperate — Liquor Drug 6. Delinquent — 7. Not reported . - I I 8 S 11 8 3 II ».... 2! 2.... 2 1... 1 I.... 1 3. 31 3 2 5 6 2 8 2 2 3 1 4 5 1 6 2 2 2. 2 2 2 2 1 3 4 1 &amp; 1. ... 1 1 ... 1 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'." 1 i 2.'..'.'"t "a.'.'.'.'"i 15 3 18 1 ... 1 16 3 19 1 1 .... 1 1 33 6 39 14 8 22 47 14 SI Totals : _^_^__ 61 9 70 1 34 16 50 95 25 120 Mother: J. Normal 2. Diseased — Tuberculosis Cancer Apoplexy Heart trouble Paralysis Nephritis 3. Defective- Feeble-minded Insane Epileptic 4. Neurotic 5. Intemperate — Liquor Drug 6. Delinquent — 7. Not reported. Totals 13 6 19 13 6 19 1. ... lj 2 . . 2 I.... S 6. ... 6' «... . • 1 ... . 1| 1 1 2 2 1 S I.... 1 2 1 S 3 1 4 I 3 2 1 3 6 1 6 1 1 1 1 1.... 1 I.... 1 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'. '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. .'.'.'." i" i !"""i""i 44 9 13 13 6 19 67 IS 72 61 9 70 34 16 50 96 26 120 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">338 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XII DECREE OF USE OF INTOXICANTS BY THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XIII— DURATION OF TREATMENT OF PATIENTS DISCHARGED Average Residence in Weeks RESULTS Apparently cured Improved a M Unimproved Died 11.6 l».l Average residence of all discharged TABLE XIV— SUMMARY OF RESULTS OF THOSE DISCHARGED DEGREE OF ISE Constant Periodic Mot specified For Yemr For Year endinc ending Nov. SO, Nov. 30. 1917 1918 M. F. T. M. F. T. 44 9 53 26 13 39 17... 17 g 2 10 1 1 Totml for Miennium M. F. T. 70 22 92 25 2 27 1 1 Totals 61 • 70 34 16 50 95 26 120 Apparently cured Improved Unimproved RESULTS Number 28 7S 23 124 Per Cent 22.58 58.87 18.55 100.00 Tot»l» I </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>