<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00029.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00029.00004</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIRE PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK FOR USE IN THE PUBLIC SCHOOLS OF NEBRASKA</title>
               <date value="1911">1911</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FIRE PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK FOR USE IN THE PUBLIC SCHOOLS OF NEBRASKA By C. A. RANDALL Chief Depu'y Fire Commissions for Nebraska t- </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CHE8TER H. ALDRICH, Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">PROCLAMATION BY THE GOVERNOR The people of the United States are rapidly awakening to the appalling loss of property and life from fire. Eis a fact that a large per cent of the fires in this country ? from preventable causes, and is usually the result of lessness or neglect in handling this very useful servant lankind. i authorities of different states have recognized the ne - of the reduction of fire waste, and to that end procla - b have been issued by executives of cities and states forth the necessity of some concerted action to focus attention on this subject and setting apart days to be as "Fire Days." Other states, through their legislatures, have enacted laws providing for the observance of Fire Day. and have also created the office of Fire Marshal for the purpose of carry - ing on a campaign of education, and reduction of fire waste. Eie state of Nebraska is in the vanguard, in so far as lation is concerned, along this line. The last session of legislature very wisely provided that the first Friday in ?mber be designated as State Fire Day. This law recognizes the fact that one of the most terrible things in connection with fire waste in this country is the loss of life that has many times occurred as a result of fires breaking out in schools. The school children of Nebraska should be an object of special solicitude, and nothing should be left undone to re - duce to a minimum the danger from disaster by fire break - ing out in school buildings. Parents and teachers should unite in assisting state offi - cials in seeing that the law enacted by the legislature if </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 observed in a way that will make a lasting impression on the minds of the children. E r or the purpose of assisting and calling special attention this subject I do hereby proclaim that, in accordance with the first Friday in November shall be designated and known as "Fire Day," and I hereby request all teachers in the public, private, and parochial schools of the state to ap - propriately observe the day. I In testimony whereof. I hereunto set my hand and cause to affixed the great seal of the state, this 24th day of Au - st. 1911. By the Governor: [seal.] Chester H. Aldrhii. rnor of Xcbraska. Addison Wait, Secretary of State. Note. — Teacher, please read to pupils. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">C. A. RANDALL, </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">PREFACE The State Fire Commission Law was enacted by the legis - lature of 1909 for the purpose of reducing fire losses, by systematic inspection of the buildings and premises in the various towns of the state, and the investigation of fires where property has been destroyed or damaged; also, for the purpose of gaining information and statistics of the number of fires, the cause, and the amount of loss both to the owner and the insurance companies doing business in the state; also, for the purpose of ferreting out the origin of suspicious fires and the prosecution of persons guilty of the crime of amra. Ehis law has been enacted in over half of the states in the on and is materially reducing the loss by fire in the es where it is in operation, and doubtless the law will be cted by every state in the Union as soon as its effective - * is brought to their attention. Phe people of the country can be brought to realise the ous and unnecessary loss that the nation suffers every every day, and every hour, they would look aghast at the figures and be frightened as the knowledge of it dawned upon them. The stupendous fire waste suffered in this coun try each year has been justly termed our National Folly. The annual per capita fire waste in the United States is esti - mated at |2.51, and in Europe only 33 cents. In France there is a law, dating from the time of Napoleon, which provides that if a fire starts in your house or property and damages the property of your neighbor, you are liable to the owner thereof. If a law similar to this were passed in this country, there is no doubt but that fire losses would be materially reduced ; as over half of the fires that occur could be avoided </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 FIRE PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. t proper care were exercised in the handling of explosives 1 not permitting rubbish and other inflammable material accumulate in and about buildings. This is an age of progress and I know of no better field for advancement than in the education of the present genera tion along the lines of Fire Prevention, and there is no sub - ject that can be made more interesting and profitable and that will have a more lasting effect and will be the means of saving the lives and property of the people than the study of Explosives, Dangerous and Careless Practices, and How to Prevent Disaster by Fire. It will not be possible to cover every phase of the subject in this one publication, but we hope to inaugurate in some small degree a system that will t prove conditions and in a measure fulfil the intention of I law under which this book is published. C. A. Randall., Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner. Note. — Teacher, please read to pupils. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">MISS MAMIE MULDOON, </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013">To School Boards and Teachers of Nebraska: I At the thirty-second session of the legislature of Nebraska law was enacted establishing a "Fire Day," and provisions ere made for its observance. In compliance with this law the Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner has arranged this book of instruction on the subject of "Fire Dangers." The loss of life and property has been so great the past few years that many states have made laws regulating the use of inflammable substances which tend to lessen the dis - asters caused by flre. Nebraska has awakened to the fact that to reach the highest efficiency in any undertaking the children of the state must be aroused to see the need of the movement contemplated. The law requires that thirty minutes be devoted to the sub - ject of fire dangers each month. The plan of this text-book is such that every school may be teaching a similar subject at the same time, thus making a uniform crusade against "Fire Dangers." The "State Fire Day" as fixed by law is the first Friday in November, and there shall be appropriate exercises for the day on the subject. Fire drills are recommended as a part of the special day program. We suggest that the program be arranged to arouse an interest in the law and in its enforcement. Each teacher should select appropriate songs and recitations suitable for the day. Have compositions written on some of the fire dangers. Teachers should have pupils clip from papers all notices about fires and classify them according to the different lee- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 tares in the text-book. A repor' hould be made on Hie clip pings for the information of pupils and paints. We trust school boards, teachers, parents, and pupils will so interest themselves in the study of "Fire Dangers" and in the "Special Fire Day" program that excellent reports may be made on the results of the combined efforts to lesson fire Jas. E. Delzell, Deputy 8tate Superintendent of Public Inxt ruction. Xotb. — Teacher, please read to pupils. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">JA8. E. DELZELL, Deputy State Superintendent of Public Instruction. </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">Sbction 1. (Fire commission — Commissioner — Deputies.) There is hereby created a fire commission for the state of Nebraska, with headquarters at the Capital, which shall have general charge of the inspection of buildings and premises, and the investigation of all fires occurring in this state by which property has been destroyed or damaged. The affairs of said commission shall be conducted by a fire commissioner and snch subordinates as are provided for by this act. The governor is hereby made the fire commissioner. Within thirty days after this act becomes a law and every two years there after, between the 15th day of January and the 15th day of February, he shall appoint two deputies who shall hold office for a term of two years and until their successors are appointed and qualified, who may be removed by the gover - nor at any time. One of said deputies shall be designated as the chief deputy fire commissioner. He shall reside in the city of Lincoln and shall under the direction of the fire com - missioner, devote his entire time to the affairs of said office. The other deputy shall be designated as assistant deputy fire commissioner. Raid chief and assistant deputies shall each give a bond to the state of Nebraska in the penal sum of 15.000.00 for the faithful performance of the duties of his office. In addition to the deputies herein provided for. the State Fire Commissioner may appoint any person as in - spector who may be known to him to be competent and skilled in the inspection of buildings and their contents. R person shall have all the powers of other deputies to and inspect buildings, including their contents and incies under section five thereof and it shall be the of such inspectors to report to the Fire Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 riU PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. any faulty or dangerous conditions found. Such deputy in - spectors to be duly commissioned to serve without compensa - tion. Sec. 2. (Fvrea — Investigations — Record*.) The state fire commissioner and the chief of the flre department of every city or village in which a fire department is established, and the mayor of every incorporated village or town in which no fire department exists, shall investigate the cause, origin and circumstances of every fire occurring in such city or village. and the sheriff may be required by the fire commissioner to investigate the cause, origin and circumstances of every tire occurring in his county without the limits of any organised city or village therein, by which property has been destroyed or damaged, and shall especially make investigation as to whether such fire was the result of carelessness or design. Such investigation shall be begun within two days, not in eluding the Sunday, after the occurrence of such flre, and the fire commissioner or his deputy shall have the right to supervise and direct such investigation whenever he deems it expedient or necessary. The officer making investigation of fires occurring in cities, villages, towns or counties shall forthwith notify said fire commissioner, and shall within one week of the occurrence of the flre, furnish to the said fire commissioner a written statement of all the facts relating to the cause and origin of the fire, and such other information as may be called for by the blanks provided by said fire com - missioner. The state fire commissioner shall keep in his office a record of all fires which may be determined by the investi - gations provided by this act; such record shall at all times be open to the public inspection. Sac. 3. (Further investigation.) The state fire commissioner shall, when in his opinion further investigation is necessary, take or cause to be taken testimony, on oath, of all persons supposed to be cognisant of any facts or to have means of knowledge in relation to the matter as to which an examina- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">PUBLIC SCHOOLS OP NEBRA8KA. 19 to be reduced to writing; and if he shall be of the opinion that there is evidence sufficient to charge any person with the crime of arson, he shall cause such person to be arrested and charged with such offense, and shall furnish to the proper prosecuting attorney all such evidence, together with the names of witnesses and all the information obtained by him, including a copy of all pertinent and material testimony taken in the case, no action taken by such Fire Commissioner shall affect the right of any policy holder in respect to his B reason of any fire so investigated, nor shall the result such investigation, or the fact that an ' investigation luested or made, be given in evidence upon the trial civil action upon such policy. El. ( Witnesses — Evidence. ) The state fire commissioner deputies shall each have power, in any county in the ' Nebraska, to summon and compel the attendance of es before them, or either of them, to testify in relation matter which is by the provisions of this act the sub - ject of inquiry and investigation, and may require the pro - duction of any book, paper, document deemed pertinent thereto by them or either of them; such witnesses should be allowed such fees as are now allowed by the district courts of this state. Said state fire commissioner and his deputies are each hereby authorised and empowered to administer oaths and affirmations to any person appearing as witness before them; ;ind false swearing in any matter or proceeding aforesaid shall be deemed perjury, and shall be punished as such. Any witness who refuses to be sworn, or who refuses to testify or who disobeys any lawful order of said state fire commissioner or his deputy, or who fails or refuses to pro - duce any book, paper or document touching any matter under examination or who is guilty of any contemptuous conduct, after being summoned by them or either of them, to appear before them, or either of them, to give testimony in relation K matter or subject under investigation as aforesaid, summarily punished by said fire commissioner or his </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 KIRK PREVENTION TEXTBOOK. deputy as for contempt, by a fine in a Bum not exceeding one hundred dollars, or be committed to the county jail until such time as said person may be willing to comply with an order made by said state fire commissioner or deputy state fire commissioner as provided in this act. Said state fire commissioner and his subordinates, or either of them, shall have authority at all times of the day and night, in the per - formance of the duties imposed by the provisions of this act, to enter upon and examine any building or premises where any fire has occurred, and other buildings and premises ad - joining or near the same. All investigations held by, or under the direction of said state fire commissioner may, in his dis cretion, be private and persons other than those required to be present by the provisions of this act, may be excluded from the place where such investigation is held, and witnesses may be kept separate and apart from each other, and not allowed to communicate with each other until they have been examined. Pdc. 5. {Dangerous building*.) Any building, or other cture, which for want of proper repair, or by reason of age and dilapidated condition, or for any cause, is especially liable to fire, and which is so situated as to endanger other buildings or property; and any combustible or explosive ma - terial, or inflamable conditions placed, kept, or existing in or upon any building or premises which is dangerous to the safety of said building or premises, and the same is so situ ated as to endanger other buildings or property, is hereby deemed and declared to be a nuisance; and any owner or oc - cupant of such building or premises who shall cause, continue or maintain any such nuisances shall be guilty of a misde - meanor and, on conviction thereof, shall be fined in any sum not exceeding the sum of 1500.00 and the court shall order said nuisance to be abated. The state fire commissioner and his subordinates, upon complaint of any person having an interest in any building or property adjacent, and without any complaint, shall have the </seg>
            <seg id="p021">PUBLIC SCHOOLS Of NEBRASKA. 21 right at all reasonable hours for the purpose of examination to enter into and upon all buildings and premises within their jurisdiction. Whenever any of said officers, shall find any building, or other structure or any material placed, kept or maintained in or upon any building or premises, consti - tutes a nuisance within the meaning of this section, he shall order said nuisance to be abated, and such order shall be forthwith complied with by the owner or occupant of said building or premises. Provided, however, that if the said owner or occupant shall deem himself aggrieved by such order, he may, within twenty-four hours, appeal to the state fire commissioner, and the cause of the complaint shall be at once investigated by direction of the latter, and unless by his authority said order is revoked, the same shall remain in force and be forthwith complied with by said owner or oc - cupant. If any such owner or occupant shall fail to comply with said order, he shall be prosecuted for maintaining a nuisance, and said nuisance shall 'be abated. 8ec. 6. (Officer$, misfeasance.) Any officer referred to in section two herein, who neglects to comply with any of the requirements of this act shall be punished by a fine of not less than twenty-five dollars, nor more than two hundred dollars. S. 7. (Salaries — Expenses, how paid — Insurance oom - r.) The chief deputy state fire commissioner shall re - an annual salary of $2,000.00 and each assistant deputy fire commissioner $1,500.00, payable monthly, and their ac - tual and necessary traveling expenses while engaged in the duties of their office. Said fire commissioner shall employ clerks and assistants and incur such other expense as may be necessary in the performance [of the duties] of his office, not to exceed, including salaries, such sum as may be paid into the state treasury in the manner hereinafter provided. For the purpose of maintaining the department of the state fire commissioner, and paying the expenses incident thereto, every </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 FIRE PREVENTION TEXTBOOK. the stock or mutual plans, doing business in the state of Nebraska, shall pay to the state treasurer in the month of January, annually in addition to the taxes now required by law to be paid by such companies, three-eighths of one per cent on the gross fire premium receipts after deducting can - cellations and re-insurances of such companies on all busi - ness done in Nebraska the year next preceding, as shown by their annual statements, under oath to the state auditor, the first annual payment to be made within thirty days after this act goes into effect and each and every annual payment there - after to be made on or before the first day of January of each succeeding year. No certificate shall be issued by the audi - tor to or on behalf of any such company, authorizing it to do or continue business in this state while any such percentage or tax remains due and unpaid. The state treasurer shall hold the money so received into the treasury as a special fund for the maintenance of the said office of state fire commissioner, and the expenses incident - thereto. The state fire commie sioner shall keep on file in his office an itemized statement of all expenses incurred by his department, and shall approve all vouchers issued therefor before the same are submitted tthe auditor of state for payment, which said vouchers shall allowed and paid in the same manner as other claims linst the state. Skc. 8. ( Deputies, duties; readiness to serve.) The deputies of the state fire commissioner shall not engage in any other business, and shall at all times be ready for such duties as are required by this act. Sac. 9. (Annual report.) The fire commissioner shall sub - mit annually, as nearly as consistent with full and accurate preparation, and not later than the 15th day of January, a detailed report of his official action. 8»c. 10. (Compensation — Chief, mayors, sheriff.) There shall be paid to the chiefs of fire departments, and to mayors of incorporated villages, Who do not receive compensation for their services as such chiefs and mayors, and to count v </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 PUBLIC SCHOOLS OF NEBRASKA. sheriffs who are by this act required to report Urea to the state fire commissioner, the sum of one dollar and fifty cents for each fire so reported to the satisfaction of the state fire commissioner, and in addition thereto, mileage at the rate of ten cents per mile for each mile actually and necessarily traveled to the place of fire. Said allowance shall be paid at the close of each fiscal year, out of any funds appropriated for the use of the office of the said state fire commissioner. Approved April 3, 1909. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATE FIRE DAY LAW Potion 1. That for the purpose of creating a public tenti :, and in order that the people of this state shall have d to their attention the great damage caused, both to and property, by fire, there is hereby set apart and es - tablished the first Friday in November which shall be des - ignated and known as "State Fire Day." This day shall be red by the public, private and parochial schools of the with exercises appropriate to the subject and the day. E: 2. That for the purpose of instruction in fire dangers, n methods of fire prevention, it shall be the duty of the Deputy Fire Commissioner and of the State Superin tendent of Public Instruction to prepare a book conveniently arranged in chapters, or lessons, such chapters or lessons tr be in number sufficient to provide a different chapter or lesson for each month of the maximum school year. The ex - pense for publishing the books of instruction, or other litera - ture on the subject of fire dangers, shall be paid out of the special fund for the maintenance of the fire commissioner's office, and said books of instruction shall be distributed by the state superintendent of public instruction, in quantities sufficient to provide a copy for each teacher. And every teacher or instructor in every public, private or parochial school shall devote not less than thirty minutes in each school month, to instruction of pupils in the subject of fire dangers, and in the methods of fire prevention. Sbc. 3. It shall be the duty of the members of school boards, school directors, trustees, or other body of persons having control of the schools of any city, village or district. to cause a copy of this act to be printed in the manual or handbook prepared for the guidance of teachers, where such manual is in use or may hereafter come in use. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Kmpliance with the law, which you will find printed in this book, we are herewith submitting short lectures ects to be taken up by you with your students. As the lectures, of necessity, had to be abbreviated, it will be necessary for you to make some previous study and prepara - tion, in order to successfully present them to your pupils. EiVe have prepared a pledge that we are very anxious to re you place on the blackboard, and have the children copy with pen and ink and take it home so their parents will ome interested. EiVe also request you to loan this book to the clergymen your school district, and request them to prepare and de - ?r a sermon on some Sunday in October on the subjects in general, and also to deliver a sermon on the December sub - ject in December, and the May subject in May. The clergy men of this state are the conservators of moral and spiritnal life of a community, and will certainly assist their people to conserve their property by advising them to take precau tionary measures to protect and preserve their lives and E first Friday in November has been designated by law ite Fire Day. It will devolve upon you to make these ses as interesting as possible. You can prepare a pro - gram that will be very interesting and profitable, by hiving several of the children write compositions on the subjects we have taken up in the book. Appropriate pongs should be sung, and a general discussion by the children of the causes and dangers of fires, and the great loss of life and property from fire, etc. Be sure and invite the fathers and mothers of your pupils to attend the Fire Dav exercises; we want them to be- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 riSX PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. come interested. At least once each month have a flre drill : ■ee how quickly yon can march the children out in order. We trust that yon will catch the spirit and enter into this work with great interest, and the inculcating of knowledge and habits into the minds of the children under your tutor - ship will have a lasting effect, and will be a means of spread - ing a knowledge, not only to the present, but future genera - tions, that will conserve and protect life and property, and yon will have the satisfaction of having had an important part in this great work which is being installed in the schools of several of the states of the Union. Very truly. C. A. Randall. Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">TO THE CHILDREN OF NEBRASKA E duties of my office require me to use every means pos - to reduce loss of life and property by fire. This is a state and I need more deputies. I want every boy and girl in the state to copy the following pledge, sign it, and take it home and have their father and mother sign it and tit up in a conspicuous place, and have it read occa - ly and keep posted on the requirements that constitute deputy of this department, and I am certain that with assistance the loss of life and property by fire will be y reduced. C. A. Randall, Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner. PLEDGE I will not permit rubbish, greasy rags, paper, and useless waste to accumulate in and around buildings. I will see that the supply of matches is kept in metal boxes throughout the house, out of the reach of children. I will not permit children under ten years of age to use matches. I will see that all lamps and lamp burners are kept clean and that all foul oil and sediment is cleaned out often, that wicks are changed often, and all lamps filled by daylight. I will see that all kerosene oil is kept in a closed metal can in a safe place. I will not permit gasoline to be kept in the house. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 ■11 not permit gasoline to be kept in anything but an it metal can, painted red. I will not allow anyone to fill a gasoline stove when it is lit, or by artificial light. I will never allow anyone to wash clothes or other articles in gasoline in a house. If they are washed out of doors, I will not permit them in the house until the gasoline has en - tirely evaporated. I will have the chimneys, stovepipes and stoves inspected often to see that there is no danger of fire, and will never permit a stove to be set up without a metal protection being placed on the floor under the stove. I will see that all ashes are placed in a metal tightly closed receptacle and will not permit them to be thrown in alleys, or on the street, or piled up against buildings or fences. I will not permit cotton or other flimsy decorations to be used on or around Christmas trees. Ell not celebrate the Fourth of July by shooting Toy , Fire-Crackers, Roman Candles, Skyrockets, and other 3us explosives. Erill inform all of my friends of the dangers from fire, will do all in my power to prevent the loss of life and srty by fire. (Sign here) Child, Father, Mother, </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Since the foundation of the world fire has been considered the greatest agency for the comfort and use of mankind of any of the great forces. Fire is the agency that furnishes artificial light; it also furnishes the heat for the preparation of food and for the heating of the homes of the people of the entire world. There is no country where it is not necessary for cooking and lighting, and but very few climates where it is not necessary for heating. It is not strange that an ele - ment in such general use by all classes of people becomes, when carelessly handled, a dangerous element, and that great damage to property and loss of life result from it. Daring the past few years inventive genius in the manu - facture of explosives has largely increased the dangers from fire. Owing to this fact there has been a greatly increased number of disastrous fires and greater loss of life. Before the advent of kerosene oil, gasoline, acetylene, and other dangerous oils and minerals used for lighting and heat - ing purposes, the danger to life and property by fire was very small, as the light used was the tallow candle or animal grease with a cotton wick in a dish, and the only fuel used was wood or coal. Of late years, since the advent of kerosene, gasoline, naphtha, and calcium carbide, which are used for illumina - ting, heating, cooking, and power, the dangers have been greatly increased and the loss of life and property have reached such appalling figures that it has become necessary to forcibly impress the people with the great responsibility that rests upon each citizen in the handling of these dangerous fire agencies. During the past five years the average annual fire loss in the United States was over 1200.000,000; there was |500 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 rttt PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. worth of property destroyed every minute of the day and night. A very large part of these fires was caused either through ignorance or carelessness and could have been avoided if proper care and judgment had been exercised. Nora.— Teachers will please read the above aloud to pupils. SEPTEMBER LESSON LECTURE. MATCHES. R match is a very useful but dangerous article. It is the of nearly every fire that occurs, whether by legitimate by carelessness. Every year hundreds of thousands of dollars worth of property is destroyed and hundreds of lives are lost through the careless use of the match. Our forefathers had no matches. When they desired to start a fire they used a flint stone and a piece of rough steel and held some tow close to the flint so that the sparks made by striking the flint with the steel would ignite the tow. By blowing upon it they would fan it into a flame and in that tiy start a fire. It was no uncommon thing for neighbors to rrow fire of each other, and when a fire was well started it was covered with ashes at night in order to preserve it from day to day. r!"he first matches were invented in 1827 and were very crude, ice that time a great many improvements have been made the match. The matches in use today will produce a blaze much more readily than the old style, and owing to that fact they have become much more dangerous, as it takes less fric - tion to explode them. A great many of the matches manu - factured now will explode if they are stepped upon or if they come in contact with the least amount of friction. Owing to this fact great care should be exercised that matches are not carelessly thrown upon the floor or left where children can obtain them, or where rats and mice can bite them. Very often people are burned by stepping on matches and their clothing </seg>
            <seg id="p031">PUBLIC 8CHOOL8 OF NEBRASKA. 31 ing of people who carried them in their pocket. The slight friction of the matches rubbing together was sufficient to ignite them, set the clothing on flre and severely bnrn the per - son carrying them. Matches should always be kept in metal boxes. Children, nnder no circumstances, shonld be permitted to use matches ; especially little girls, because their clothing is of such an inflammable nature that the flame from a match may set flre to it and bnrn or disfigure them for life, if it does not kill them outright. Never light a match in a closet or attic where clothes are kept. The head of the match may (It off and set the clothing on flre. erreat manv flres that occur, where thousands of dollnrn ■ of property is destroyed, are caused by children plavine matches. Rome children amuse themselves bv starting bonfires in rubbish and brnsh. the flre sets beyond their con - trol, spreads and destroys houses, barns and other buildings, and sometimes the lives of the children themselves. OCTOBER LESSON LECTURE. CHIMNBT8 AND FTTTES. One of the principal causes of the destruction of the home by flre is the defective fine. There is ordinarily too little nt tention paid to construction of the chimney or flues especially in private houses. Chimneys are usually constructed of brick and mortar and are only four inches thick. They are exposed to the elements above the roof and the action of the rain and wind upon the mortar causes it to crumble and wash out from between the brick, leaving a space that permits of smoke and t coming out. As the smoke is hot it dries the roof boards shingles so that they are liable to catch flre. The annual property loss caused by defective chimneys in the United States is over 140.000,000. This is an age of im - provement along the line of architecture and in the construe- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 FIRE PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. be as profitably exercised as in the construction of the chim - neys. Where it is possible to do so chimneys shonld be bnilt from the basement up through the building to a point at leant four feet above the highest point of the same. The founda - tion should be of brick or stone, laid in cement mortar; there should be a clean-out hole in the base of the chimney so that all Boot and sediment can be removed. The chimney should he so constructed that no woodwork is connected to it. so that if the chimney shonld settle it will not be supported by the woodwork and cause an opening in the chimney between the brick. There should be a fire-clay or terracotta lining in the chimney, so that in case the action of the wind on the house causes the house to vibrate and break the mortar joints of the chimney the lining will prevent any fire or smoke passing through between the bricks. The fire-clay lining is the better lining for chimneys as it costs less and will stand more heat than terra -cotta. KA11 joints and cracks around the lining should be slushed th good cement or fire-clay mortar, so that the chimney will be solid from the ground to the top. There should be a stone or cement cap placed on the top of the chimney of at least one inch larger sise than the chimney, so that the rain will not run down the side of the chimney and wash out the mortar. Thimney thimbles should be placed as far from the ceiling and the woodwork of the house as is possible and great care should be taken in placing them firmly in the chimney. Fire - clay mortar should be used in fastening them in their place. Ehere it is not possible to extend the chimney into the ment. it shonld at least go below the floor line of the ad story and rest upon a substantial platform placed in the center of the partition, so that the weight of the chimney will rest directly upon the studding. No chimney should be placed upon a side bracket, as the weight of the chimney will cause it to lean out into the room and open the seams, thus permitting the smoke and heat to escape and set the building </seg>
            <seg id="p033">l-l BL.K I» IIIHII.M &gt;&gt;f &gt;EUIUB&amp;A. 33 floor or ceiling, if there is a possible way of avoiding it, and there are very few cases when a house is constructed but what Lean be so arranged. When it cannot be avoided, a large tal ventilator should be used. Every chimney should be thoroughly cleaned out at least twice a year to prevent the accumulated soot from catching fire and throwing the sparks out onto the dry roof and setting the house on fire. One of the great aggravations is a chimney that does not have sufficient draft, causing the stove to smoke and poison - ous gases to be emitted through the house. If a chimney is built with a large flue and straight and to extend at least three or four feet above the highest point of the house, and then is cleaned out occasionally, there will be sufficient draft to carry off all smoke and gases, and there will be no incon - venience and trouble from this source. Every chimney should be carefully inspected at least twice a year, and no chimney should pass through an attic where there is no access to it for the purpose of inspection. Do not forget the old adage that "An ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure," and that a little time spent in in - specting the chimney may prevent the destruction of your home and possibly the loss of life. NOVEMBER LES8ON LECTURE. 8T0VK8 AND 8T0VEPIPB8. There is no economy in the purchase and use of a cheap and poorly constructed stove or heating apparatus. Especially is this true of the cook stove, which is used almost continu ously every day in the year. A well constructed stove or heating apparatus is less liable to cause a fire that will destroy the home, if it is properly installed, is much more economical in the amount of fuel used to produce the heat necessary for warming the house or for </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 FIEK PREVENTION TEXTBOOK. cooking, and will outlast the cheap and poorly constructed article. Thousands of dollars worth of property is destroyed every year by "overheated stoves." One of the principal reasons for overheating is the purchasing of too small a store for the work, and it becomes necessary in order to obtain the re - quisite amount of heat to open all drafts and fill the stove completely with fuel. If a larger stove were used the lire would not have to be forced, the stove would not be over - heated, this danger would be averted, and there would be a great saving of fuel. i Every stove should have a stove board covered with metal, an asbestos metal-covered sheet placed under it so that the floor underneath the stove will not be overheated and take fire. A great many fires are caused and a large amount of property is destroyed each year by neglecting this simple precaution. Stovepipes should fit tightly upon the stove, should be curely fastened together and wired substantially, and a tight - fitting metal collar should be placed upon the pipe next to the chimney. One of the reasons why stoves do not draw better sometimes is because the pipe-joints are open and the draft of the stove is affected. If all stovepipe joints are airtight and the chimney of sufficient size, the draft of the stove will be perfect, which is necessary for good serve. At frequent intervals stovepipes should be examined carefully, as the steam from fuel and the sulphur and salt fumes from coal have a deteriorating effect upon the metal in the pipes and will cause them to rust on the inside. When they become thin or perforated they are very dangerous, and a great amount of fire loss is caused by stovepipes that should have been dis - carded and replaced by new. Great care should be taken to see that the wall paper does not come in contact with the stovepipe. When there is a </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 tused and securely fastened in its place, but this stop aid never be papered over unless there is asbestos pnt p it before the wall paper is put on. DECEMBER LESSON LECTURE. CHBI8TMAS. Pe all look forward with great expectancy and pleasure he Christmas-time. To the young it means happiness by receiving and giving of presents on the holiday they en - joy from their school and other duties, and the feasting upon good things provided by their parents and friends. To the older people it is a reminder of the birth of the Savior of mankind who came upon earth to bring peace and good will and whose life has been and always will be an inspiration for better living. Nothing should occur upon Christmas eve or at any of the exercises being held in commemoration of the day to mar the happiness and pleasure attending it. Christmas tree exercises are very common in this country and they are in a great many instances very dangerously ar - ranged. In order to represent snow, which is typical of the Christmas-time, the tree is sometimes surrounded by cotton, and ornamented with cotton, inflammable ornaments and tinsel to represent snow and frost. The presents for the children are hung upon the tree, a large number of little candles are fastened to the branches and lighted in order to give the tree a bright and pleasing effect. A spark of flre from one of these little candles might ignite the cotton upon or under the tree and canse a con - flagration that would destroy the building and canse a great Christmas-trees are all right and the children ought to be given an opportunity to enjoy them, but cotton or other in - flammable material should never be placed on or aronnd a Christmas-tree. A Christmas-tree without a Santa Clans, to the average </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 child, does not fulfil its mission and it is a common practice for someone to impersonate the character. Usually a gray fur coat, a long cotton wig and beard are used, and Santa Claus is the one that takes the presents from the tree and hands them to the children. His fur coat and cotton trimmings, long beard and wig are placed in close proximity to the lighted candles, and not only Santa Plans, but the children who usually congregate around him in the expectancy of re - ceiving gifts are in a most dangerous position. All this danger can be averted if asbestos wool is used to produce the snow effect and Santa Claus can use it for his beard and wig. Where electricity can be obtained small electric bulbs can be attached to the branches of the tree to produce the light. Where there is no chance to use electricity, reflectors should be placed upon lamps so arranged as to throw the light upon the tree. Candles should never be used. The tree can be deco - rated with several different kinds of ornamentation that are not inflammable or dangerous. The effect will be as pleasing tthe children and will not jeopardise their lives nor cause ir parents unnecessary worry and anguish. Ens all vie one with the other to make Christmas a Christmas without any scars or blemishes by reason less practices that ought to be discontinued. JANUARY LESSON LECTURE. RUBBISH AND ASHES. R ("cumulation of rubbish in and around buildings is ngeron*. Rubbish becomes dry and is easily ignited park from a chimney or by children playing with i. It is of no account, and should not be permitted to accumulate. It is very little trouble to destroy each day's accumulation of old papers, rags, etc., and if every one will follow this practice fires from this source will cease. Oreasy rags and waste, as well as other combustible materials, when allowed to accumulate in piles in buildings, closets, and </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 alleys, will become decomposed and heated and cause soon taneons combustion which destroys property. If it is not convenient to burn the rubbish each day, a metal receptacle with cover should be provided and all paper, rags, and other worthless trash should be put into it, carted away occasionally and burned where there will be no danger of destroying other property. Ashes thrown out in streets, alleys and back yards, or put in open or wooden receptacles, are dangerous from a fire standpoint and are a nuisance. Hardly a day passes but what we read of disastrous fires from ashes. Of course, the person throwing them out thinks there is no fire left in them. L perhaps there is just enough to come to life when fanned he wind and set everything around on fire. There is another good reason why ashes should not be thrown out where the wind can blow and scatter them. We all like to breathe pure air. but air filled with ashes is by no means pure and the dust fills our eyes and lungs and injures onr sight and health, and also fills our clothes with dust that is verv hard to clean off. L Ashes should be put in a metal can with a tight cover and iptied where they will not injure health or property. FEBRUARY LESSON LECTURE. KEROSENE. Kerosene is the refined product of mineral oil known as petroleum. The oil is pumped from the ground through deep-bored wells and is usually found in coal-producing dis - tricts. The oil as it comes from the ground looks like tar or molasses. The raw product is put through the process of re - fining and from it is derived kerosene, gasoline and naphtha, and several other products which are lubricants and not inflammable oil. ■ improved process used in refining the kerosene oil has it much lem inflammable, as the dangerous gases are </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 riU PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. extracted and form the gasoline and naphtha product. Kero- sene oil is used for illuminating purposes principally, but there are several makes of kerosene stoves, both for heating and cooking. The principal danger from kerosene oil is in permitting the oil to become old and stale in the lamp and to attain a large amount of impurities by reason of the lighter oil being taken up by the flame and leaving the heavier and more dangerous part of the oil in the lamp. This will also cause a bad odor from the lamp when it is burning. All this sediment should be emptied frequently so that this accumu - lation of impure and dangerous oil will be destroyed. The burners should be thoroughly washed and cleaned in soap - suds, so that the little air flue leading into the lamp at the side of the wick will always be open to allow the gases that accumulate to escape. Plamp turned down low should never be left burning, is a common practice where people desire to have a lim - amount of light, and is very dangerous. It is liable to cause a lamp to explode by reason of the draft of the lamp not being sufficient to draw off the accumulating gases from the oil through the little tube that is open by the side of the wick. As the gas is not consumed, it is thrown out into the room and poisons the air and is not only dangerous but is very unhealthy. Where a small amount of light is desired a small lamp should be used and permitted to burn to its full - est capacity. A lamp should never be filled when lit, or by artificial light, other than electric, nor should a lamp be ex - tinguished by blowing down a chimney, as a strong draft of breath might cause the blaee to follow the wick down into the oil and gas below the burner and cause an explosion. Cen you want to extinguish the lamp, turn it down slowly il it goes out. The kerosene-oil stove used for heating and cooking works on the same principle as the lamp and should be treated in the same manner, as the stove and the lamp both use burners and wicks of the same construction, but the volume of oil used </seg>
            <seg id="p039">PUBLIC SCHOOLS OF NEBRASKA. 39 in the stove is so much greater that the accumulation of heavy oil in the receptacle should be changed more frequently and the wicks should never be allowed to become foul from the accumulation of soot and greasy substance that may have boiled over when cooking on the stove. Always keep lamp and oil stove burners clean and never allow a wick to become soaked with foul oil or sediment It is a common practice to start fires in stoves by pourir^ kerosene oil on kindling and cobs after they are placed in the stove. This is very dangerous. There are thousands of dol - lars worth of property destroyed and hundreds of lives lost every year by this practice. If you desire to use kerosene to start a fire, put your kindling wood or cobs in a metal re - ceptacle, pour the kerosene onto the kindling or cobs out of Era and then put it in the stove with your wood or coal there will be no danger of an explosion from this source, ve your can outside away from the stove. kDo not throw water on flames which start from kerosene i, as this tends to spread the blaze. Smother the flames th a carpet, quilt or heavy clothing. MARCH LESSON LECTURE. GASOLINE AND NAPHTHA. Gasoline and naphtha are derived from the refining of petroleum oil. They are used for the manufacture of gas for illuminating, cooking, and power purposes, and also for cleaning clothes. They are very dangerous fluids and are the means of destroying more property and lives than any other of the explosives now in use. Ethe United States every year over three thousand homes arned and about $3,000,000 in other property destroyed, nearly 5,000 persons are badly scarred and at least lose their lives, as the result of the careless use and ing of gasoline. A gasoline stove makes work easv for the cook, but it is </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 riRK PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. dangerous to have in your home unless every precaution is taken in the handling of the gasoline and the managing of the stove. A gasoline stove should never be filled when lit or by artificial light, as the vapor of the gasoline will reach the blase and an explosion will follow. The tank on a gasoline stove should never be filled completely full, as when the gaso - line warms it expands and the pressure on the tank might open the seams. Never keep a gasoline can in the kitchen; in fact, it should never be kept anywhere in the house There should be a place provided for it on the outside, away from fire and artificial light. Gtausoline should be kept in tightly closed cans, and, under the laws of this state, no one is permitted to keep it in anything that is not painted a vermilion red. Gasoline vapor takes up 130 times as much space as the gasoline from which it comes. This vapor in the air forms a deadly explosive gas which will take fire from a blase or flame and explode. It is from this vapor that automobiles and gasoline engines get their power. Gasoline is the cheapest fuel for running small engines and automobiles that can be procured and when handled care- Pj out in the open they are not as dangerous as the gaso - stoves or lamps, as they are usually handled by expe - ced persons. The only fire danger from them is in having gasoline about. One of the most dangerous uses of gasoline is the cleaning of clothes. Every week there are from fifteen to twenty per - sons burned to death by the use of gasoline in this manner, and thousands of dollars worth of property destroyed. Gaso - line should be used for cleaning out of doors only, and away from all buildings. Bline should never be thrown into a sink, cess-pool or but should be carried away and emptied out on soft in the open air. During the past winter in Lincoln in one of the clothes cleaning establishments the clothes were washed in gasoline </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 PUBLIC SCHOOLS OP NEBRASKA. the clothes were hung over &amp; steyni radiator id the store to dry. The warm air from the radiator and the gas from the clothes formed such a volume of gas that when the proprietor struck a match to light a gas stove an explosion took place, which did |S,000 in damage and nearly cost three lives. Windows were broken across a 100-foot street and the build - ing was completely wrecked. The most dangerous way of lighting is by gasoline. There is no such thing made as a safe gasoline lamp. Some may be safer than others, but gasoline or gasoline gas is just as dan - gerous when coming from a well-made receptacle as from a poor one. If the receptacle holding the gasoline and the carbureter are on the outside, away from the building, the danger of an explosion is somewhat reduced. If there is any other way possible in which to obtain light, the gasoline sys - tem should not be used except in a large city plant where the "Dry Air System" can be employed. APRIL LESSON LECTURE. CALCIUM CARBIDE AND ACETYLENE GAS. Calcium carbide is a product manufactured from quick lime and coke, ground and baked together in an electric arc furnace at a heat of about 6,000 degrees Fahrenheit. After it is cooled it is crushed and screened and packed in metal cans of various sizes to be used for the manufacturing of calcium and acety - lene light. The flame from acetylene makes a bright and colorless light, and the flame gives off less heat and less poison than any other illuminating gas. Acetylene gas is more dangerous than gasoline gas, as ■ flame is needed to explode gasoline vapor, while a soldering iron, or other red hot metal, a pipe or glowing coal will ex - plode acetylene gas. Calcium carbide in itself will not cause an explosion, but when it comes in contact with water the gas is generated and the gas when ignited by artificial light will cause an explosion. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Ecetylene gas has such a decidedly offensive smell that its r will give notice of its presence, and an artificial light lid never be used in a room, basement or building where odor of acetylene gaB can be detected. The volume of gas that passes through the holes in the burner is so small that there is no danger from an explosion when the gas is ignited, as the holes in the burner are so fine that there is not enough of the gas to cause an explosion and it is entirely consumed by the flame as fast as it escapes through the holes. 1 would advise that an acetylene machine should not be placed in the cellar or basement underneath a house, for the reason that when the machine is being flushed and cleaned it emits an offensive, filthy odor which passes all through the house, and in case of a leak in the machine the gas will fill the basement and pass through the house and come in contact with the fire or artificial light and is liable to cause a disastrous explosion. During the last few months in this state several pMph have been killed and a number of buildings wrecked by people hunting leaks in acetylene machines and pipes or the escaping gas coming in contact with artificial light. The safest way to install an acetylene gas machine is to place it away from the house or building in Rich the gas is to be used, in an underground cave where the ter will not freeze in the machine. In case there is a leak in the machine or pipes they should be repaired by daylight, and no artificial light should ever be used near the machine or pipes. The cave should be so constructed that sufficient natural light will be furnished to fill, clean and repair the machine, and should be sufficiently provided with ventilators to curry off all escaping gas. cans of carbide used for filling the generator should al i\ u be kept in a dry place away from the house and should be kept sealed, both air and water tight. If air comes in con - tact with the carbide, it will air-slack and become worthless; and if water comes in contact with it, it will generate a gas in the cans which will explode if it comes in contact with arti - ficial light </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 MAY LESSON LECTURE. INDEPENDENCE DAY. The Fourth of July is looked forward to by both young and old as a day in which to celebrate the birth of the great - est nation in the world. Patriotism on that day is usually aroused to the highest pitch and there seem to be as main different ways of showing one's appreciation of the freedom and liberty that we enjoy as there have l&gt;een ways and means devised of showing it. The most common way to arouse enthusiasm among the young boys and girls seems to be the use of the firecracker, the torpedo, the toy pistol, ronian candle, sky rocket, and other ways of making a loud noise or bright light. Usually the boys and girls in whose hands these deadly articles are placed have no idea of the danger that attends them and it is not until after the deadly work has been accomplished that they fully realize they have been playing with death and destruction. On July Fourth. 1910, there were 2,923 per sons injured in the United States, and of this number 131 died ; 67 deaths were due to tetanus or lock-jaw and 19 were caused outright by firearms. 11 by explosion of powder bombs or torpedoes, 6 by cannon or similar contrivances; there woe 72 cases of lock-jaw; 40 people lost their sight; 2fi lost arms, legs or hands; 141 lost fingers, while 26, mostly little girls, were burned to death by fire from fireworks. This is a startling showing, but it has been materially reduced since 1903. when there were nearly double the number injured and four times as many lives lost. The reduction in injuries an&lt;' fatalities has been brought about largely by the education of the fathers and mothers and children, and also by the deal - ers in these deadly explosives discontinuing the sale of them. I recently saw a picture and underneath it was inscribed "The Day After the Fourth." Reclining upon a couch waa a little boy about ten years old: a bandage was over his eyes: </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 KIRK PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. bin mother was kneeling beside the couch ; her prostrate body was thrown across the body of her boy; she was crying bitterly, while the father and the doctor stood by gazing ujKin the little sufferer with a look upon their faces that depit-ted despair. Only the day before this little boy started out to celebrate Independence Day, just as you boys and girls will start out on the coming Fourth of July. He had spent the money that wag given him to celebrate Independence Day for dangerous explosives; he had touched them off and his eyes paid the penalty. During all of his after life he must grope his way in darkness; the beauties of nature were closed to him forever. This is a sad but true picture, and yi t is only one of hundreds of cases that occur each year as Independence Day conies around. Children, read over the description of this picture, com - mit it to memory and impart it to others and then use your influence to see that every effort is put forth to avoid an occurrence of this kind. We should all be happy and joyous, and show our appreciation of the privileges and liberty that we enjoy by reason of the efforts put forth by our forefathers in fighting for and obtaining their independence, which has been preserved and handed down to us by the patriotism and loyalty of the citizens of this Republic, but let us so observe the day that it will forcibly remind us that we must do our share in the preserving and upholding of the dignity and freedom of American institutions and show our intelligence by observing Independence Day in a Safe and Sane manner. .TINE LESSON LECTURE. FIRE INSURANCE. Fire insurance is a voluntary tax paid through different agencies, or companies, for the purpose of distributing over the entire community the great financial loss and distress canted by the destruction of property by fire, thereby avoid - ing vuin and disaster to individuals. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 I'l BI.Ii" SCHOOL* OF NEBRA8KA. Fire insurance does not and cannot replace the destroyed property. Every fire, no matter whether large or small, takes from the wealth of the country just so much capital. The fact that the burned building or property, valued at $10,000. is fully insured does not alter the circumstances and the com - munity is flO.000 poorer than before the fire. The owner, who first suffered the loss on account of the fire, can take the money received from the insurance company and replace the property, but a large number of people, through their contri - bution to the fund that paid the loss, are out their propor - tionate share of the money. So on through the years, those who avail themselves of th'e protection of fire insurance con - tinue contributing to those who lose by fire. C losses by fires are not made good by insurance, or. to it better, are not distributed by insurance. As the tax by which the money is raised is voluntary, in order for a Pn to participate in the benefits it is necessary to con - to help to pay the losses of others. Such a contract is I a policy of insurance, and the peculiar province of a contract is shown by the following accepted definition : A fire insurance policy is a contract to indemnify the holder thereof for actual destruction, by a certain immediate cause, namely, fire, of value appertaining to certain specific prop - erty owned by him. Analyzing the definition it will be found that insurance is for actual loss sustained. This is so that no profit may romp to an individual at the expense of the community through the destruction of property. A policy is limited in its terms to a certain amount, and the holder cannot recover to ex - ceed that sum under any circumstances; but if the value of the property destroyed does not equal the limit of the policy, the person holding a policy can recover only for the valu* destroyed by the fire. Kn our definition embraces the matter of value and the worth in money, or what is known as market No account is taken of the sentimental or the personal </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 FIRK PREVENTION TEXT-BOOK. value of the property to the assured. The property insured may be an article such as a piece of furniture with which the owner would not part for hundreds of dollars, but which has a market value or exchange value of only one dollar. As the community is making good to the individual only the loss to th&lt;- community, actual value is the basis of the indemnity. Pen. too, insurance reimburses only for value at the time e fire, whether that value be more or less than the orig - cost of the property destroyed. Ethe definition, "immediate result of fire" means that the ance would pay not only for property actually con - 1 by fire, but also for loss or 'damage to remaining prop - cauaed by fire, smoke, and water or other process of r&gt;licy of insurance does not follow the property insured, a personal contract and insures the holder, not the property. This means that no person who does not have an interest in the property or does not own it can be paid for its destruction by fire from the insurance funds. The prop - erty to be insured must be specified in the contract; that is, the description must set forth every article insured or be written in terms broad enough to include the property, or everything intended to be insured. R insurance arrangement is also affected for a definite of time, called the term. This is also stated definitely policy, and is a material part of the agreement. The location of the property is another important fact, having a decisive effect upon the insurance. All contracts, to be binding, must have a consideration. In the case of insurance this consideration is called the pre - mium and the rate of premium or the amount charged varies necessarily with different localities and on different kinds of property, for some sections are obviously more liable to fire than others and certain kinds of property are much more subject to destruction by fire than other kinds. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 extremely technical and involved contract. When, however, the great number of contingencies against which it ranst provide are taken into consideration this is found not to be the case. That a general understanding may be possible, most states have adopted what is known as a "Standard Policy": provisions and wording of all policies of insnr - made identical, no matter what company issue* the </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>