<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00025">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Systems for Farm Homes</title>
               <date value="1930-05">1930-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 245 May, 1930 Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Systems for Farm Homes IVAN D. WOOD AND E. B. LEWIS. . Department of Agricultural Engineering THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. B'Jim. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Introduction — The need of adequate water supply — The choice of a water supply system — Other factors — Water requirements 3 Description op Various Water Supply Systems ;.... 5 Pitcher spout pump at kitchen sink ; 5 Force pump at kitchen sink..: 8 ■ Force pump and range boiler 8 The hot water system , t 8 Wash room warm water supply 10 Special connection to range boiler ; 10 Variety of hot water storage tank circulation connections „... 12 Attic tank and force pump 13 Deep tank at well ....; IB Elevated tank and tower .' ; 16 The underground masonry reservoir ..._ 18 Protecting well water from contamination 21 Windmill replaced or supplemented by a motor and ordinary pump jack 21 Automatic electric water supply system — well near the house 23 The hydropneumatic tank 25 Complete automatic electrically operated pneumatic tank system — well remote from the house .'. 26 Complete automatic electrically operated pneumatic tank system installed in pit and having fresh water attachments 28 Arrangement for piping hard and soft water to modern plumbing 30 Installation of air chambers and pressure regulating switches 31 Air traps 32 Electricity as Power for Farm Systems... 32 Reliability of electric service .'. 33 Convenience of electric service .-. , 33 Cost of installation of electrically driven systems. 33 Cost of operation when electricity furnishes the power.. 33 Amounts of water used in the home 33 Hints about purchasing a water system... 34 Hints on installation / 35 Hints on wiring to motors 35 Commercial Water Softeners 35 Sewage Disposal Systems 37 A safe farm sewage system 37 Kitchen sink and disposal tile . 39 Septic tank with tile disposal system 40 Water-tight Concrete 41 Hints on Construction 42 Questionnaires 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Water Supply and Sewage Disposal Systems for Farm Homes IVAN D. WOOD AND E. B. LEWIS 1 When the well "goes dry" or when the windmill or pump ™S Wn&gt; every * on , e m th e household immediately ap - preciates the value of plenty of water. In other words, "You never miss the water until the well runs dry". Fortunately «ht^ St ,i S K Ctl ° n £- 0f thi f, st 2 te ' plent y of P ure wat &lt;* may be obtained by sinking wells of moderate depth, yet surprisingly StV^ 1 ™ h01 ?,? 8 %* K SUPplied With running water P /n the and tank! V * are equipped with hydrants THE NEED OF ADEQUATE WATER SUPPLY According to the 1929 assessors' reports, compiled by pre - cincte, only 21,854 farm homes in Nebraska have waterpfped to the kitehen and only 15,672 farm homes have bath facil - ities, yet there are approximately 127,000 farms in the state ■ Many examples could be given of the amount of work done, w^T f SeS by the i^use^fe. carrying water from wells i?,ffi? * a J vari o" s -distances from the kitchen door. It is sufficient to say that many families pump more than 75 tons ?L™ ifn" per i^5 a ? d carry ifc t0 the house from wells located irom 50 to 100 feet away. It is the purpose of this bulletin to present a number of water supply and sewage disposal systems which have been used in Nebraska and surrounding states and which add greatly to the comfort and convenience of the farm home. THE CHOICE OF A WATER SUPPLY SYSTEM No doubt the members of every rural household desire the best of home conveniences but often finances do not permit a 3^* JfS ojrtfcy-K w then necessary to seek the best system available for a limited expenditure. 1. The water supply systems shown in Figures 1, 3, and 9 are well adapted to the following: a. The renter who cannot afford to spend much money improving a place belonging to some one else. b. ine landlord who does not care to put expensive im - provements on a farm which he is renting to others c. The young farmer just starting in business for him - self on his own place. 2&lt; T vi e fa J" m ow " er in moderate circumstances would prob - ably choose the water supply system shown in Figure 3 and later add to it as shown in Figure 4. Or he might well choose the system shown in Figure 9. v£&amp;g*Sl£&amp;£ '£ £rpl^. J i\ 1 £'3SeSjr&amp;i3 t 3 e a 'a « ln *i </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 245 will decrease the maximum vertical distance thru which the pump can lift the water. If one-inch pipe is used, this de - crease! in lift will be approximately one foot for every 100 feet of horizontal pipe. • . FORCE PUMP AT KITCHEN SINK (Figure S) Thei system shown in Figure 3 does not differ from that shown in Figure 1, except that a force pump is used instead of a pitcher spout pump. In all other ways the arrangement is the same. The advantage of the force pump is that later a range boiler may be used and, when properly connected to a water back in the range, will permit both hot and cold water to be pumped at the sink. The force pump may be of the bracket type which bolts to the wall with wood screws or it may be the kind which fastens to a wooden shelf after the manner of the pitcher spout pump. At some later time it may be desirable to include the equip - ment shown in Figure 4. FORCE PUMP AND RANGE BOILER (Figure 4) Figure 4 shows a range boiler and water back attached to the force pump shown in Figure 3. By closing the valve at A and opening the one at B, cold water is pumped to the sink from the cistern or well. It is also possible to pump cold water to the range boiler by closing the valve at B and opening the one at A. When the boiler is full and a fire is started in the range, circulation of water takes place thru the water back on the stove to the boiler. The hot water, being lighter, rises to the top of the range boiler. When hot water is then desired at the sink, it is only necessary to close valve B, open valve A, and pump. The cold water entering the boiler thru pipe C forces hot water out thru pipe D, to the sink. By placing an additional valve at E above the sink in the hot water line it is possible to force the hot water to a bath tub, situated in another room, thru the pipe F. This pipe must be raised slightly higher than pipe D, however, since water will more frequently be wanted at the sink. The valve at E should be closed only while pumping water to the bath tub. THE HOT WATER SYSTEM The 40-gallon range boiler is the correct size for the aver - age farm family. The water back should be of the proper size for the boiler. It will be noticed that no valves of any kind are put in pipe D, Figure 4. This pipe is left open so that there is always a chance for the steam from the boiler to escape; otherwise an explosion might result. </seg>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms The range water back, kerosene heater, and house furnace SVo^Kgure 7 ** hot - water "*»■»&gt; *«* as" shown tankwitMtte^inJXor"^ bSCk COimeCti ° n tO a Storage ™iS c?™? 1011 . hot-wafer storage tank or range boiler may be placed horizontally against the ceiling as shown in G. Pine (a) supplies cold water at the bottom of tank, and pipe (b) ?n^&amp; 3 Wa p- f r ° m f he h J 0ttest part of the t* 1 * t° pfumb - mg fixtures. Pipes (c) and (d) are circulating pipes only Supporting strap-iron bands are shown at (e). ATTIC TANK AND FORCE PUto? (Fi BO re 8) The water supply problem of the household may often be solved by the use of a tank placed in the attic or even in some unused room on the second floor. Figure 8 shows how the connections may be made when using a horizontal double - acting pump in the basement to force water from a cistern to the attic tank. An ordinary galvanized-iron stock tank is used for storage, inese tanks may be obtained in various sizes and shapes but tte oblong type with rounded ends is to be preferred, since it may be set directly over a partition. : This lessens the load on ™»«,f 0 ho ? no f Pi?*** over a partition, additional joists must be used under it to take the weight from the ceiling Eh f VS? 6 ,f eet l0 "?' 2 f eet wide,. and 2 feet deep will hold about 150 gallons, which should ordinarily be a two days' supply. Very little trouble is experienced from freezing if water is pumped at least twice a day in cold weather The warmer water from a well or cistern keeps the temperature m the tank above the point where solid freezing takes place except in the coldest weather. Trouble due to condensation n +1 fT e ? ted i. y Placing a galvanized iron pan and drain under the tank. The use of a tight cover is recommended. The overflow pipe should be 2 inches in diameter and may be carried out under the eaves or returned to the basement beside the supply pipe. Regular tank connections may be purchased for attaching the 1-inch supply and 2-inch over - flow pipes to the attic tank. . When complete bath room ™f. as ™. e . n as kitchen sink are used with this system, a 250-gallon attic tank should be purchased if a two days' sup - ply is desired. Various modifications of the system are in use. For in - stance it may be desirable to pump water to the tank from a force pump at the windmill. The overflow can then be carried down thru the partitions and out to the stock tanks. It is desirable to have this overflow pipe I*/* to 2 inches in diameter. </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017"/>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 245 3. The 1- or H/i-inch pipe connections from well to tank and to all places where water is to be delivered. This pipe must be well protected where it passes up thru the tower to the tank, or freezing will result. This may be accomplished by placing it in a box 12 inches .square packed with dry sawdust or mineral wool. A shut-off valve at B provides a way to save the supply if a leak is detected anywhere in the system, or it may be closed for making repairs. 4. A three-way force pump at the well. The under-ground connections are made in a pump pit of concrete. This pit is made 4 feet square and 6 V1&gt; feet deep and should be tightly covered with a concrete slab. 5. A stop and waste cock in the supply pipe where it enters the basement. By closing this, all the pipes in the house can be drained to prevent freezing. When this cock is shut, the range boiler pressure is relieved thru the pipe J, which goes to the attic and then out under the eaves. Unless the tower is made higher than shown, the bath room must be on the lower floor of the house. A height of 8 feet to the bottom of the stave tank is usual for fixtures on the lower floor. This height should be increased to 14 feet when the bath room is on the second floor. THE UNDERGROUND MASONRY RESERVOIR 1 (Figure 11) One of the most satisfactory gravity systems obtainable consists of an underground reservoir, placed on high ground, with proper pipe connections to a force pump and to points where water is to be delivered. It has the following ad - vantages : 1. The work of building the reservoir may be done by the owner. 2. The water is fairly cool in warm weather. 3. No trouble is experienced from freezing. 4. The cost of upkeep is low. The disadvantages are: 1. Limited number of farms where it may be used. 2. Leaks are not easily detected. 3. Long pipe lines often necessary between reservoir and buildings. The main features of the system shown in Figure 11 are the same as those of the system shown in Figure 10 with the ex - ception of the storage reservoir. Any one of a variety of masonry reservoirs may be used, for instance : 1 Those interested in installing: this system should obtain the following: blueprints from the Extension Service, Agricultural College, Lincoln, Nebraska: No. 10.873-16 Plans for underground concrete reservoir „....-. 10 cents No. 10.873- 8 Plans for concrete pump pit and hydrant connections ..10 cents </seg>
            <seg id="p021"/>
            <seg id="p022"/>
            <seg id="p023">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms ings. A standard gate valve is placed at C in the reservoir to control the supply when repairs are needed. At G is a stop and waste cock which will allow the house plumbing to be drained. This is the same type as described in Figure 10. PROTECTING WELL WATER FROM CONTAMINATION (Figure 12) Much of Nebraska's water supply comes from deep tubular wells and the danger of contamination is slight. There are, however, some communities where the shallow bored, dug, or driven well is still in use. In such cases it is imperative to protect the top of the well against the entrance of flood water and the drippings from the pump. Protection against flood water may be obtained by raising the well platform above the general level of the ground. Stiff clay should then be tamped around the curbing as shown at B in Figure 12. After this, the surface of the ground should be raised around the well by grading. Protection against dripping can well be provided by ar - ranging a sanitary sleeve in the well curbing as shown at A. The cylinder C should be placed in the water. Not more than 6 to 10 feet of suction pipe should be necessary below the cylinder. Where sand is near the end of the suction pipe, an enlarged pipe, as D, (to cut down the velocity of the in - coming water) and the screen E will lessen the amount of sand drawn thru the cylinder leathers. WINDMILL REPLACED OR SUPPLEMENTED BY A MOTOR AND ORDINARY PUMP JACK (Figure IS) When the farm is supplied with electricity from any source and the windmill becomes worn and in need of repair, or trees and buildings begin to shut out too much wind, a small motor is often belted to a pump jack to furnish the needed supply of water. It has the following advantages: 1. Fresh water is not dependent on the moods of the wind. 2. Rate and time of pumping are under control. 3. The cost of the motor is usually less than that of a new mill. 4. The upkeep cost of motor and jack is low. The disadvantages are: 1. The gears in the ordinary pump jack, usually built for a gas engine, are not in correct ratio to give the desired pumping speed when a motor, which has a much higher speed and is equipped with a smaller pulley, is the source of power. 2. More oiled bearings, etc., are exposed to weather and dust. 3. Possibility of no current because of breakdown in power source. </seg>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms this kind is shown with the dotted lines and the indicated 3 - way and 4-way switches at B, C, and D. When this switch control is used it is possible for anyone in the house to start the motor by throwing switch D. This switch should not be within reaching or touching distance of any plumbing fixture It is also possible for someone else to start the motor by throwing switch C at the pump or switch B at the stock tank Either 32-, 110-, or 220-yolt direct current, or 110- or 220 - volt alternating current circuits are permissible for this con - venience, provided the switches when open always disconnect the ungrounded wires. Usually the 220-volt circuit is not grounded when the 110-220-volt 3-wire system from power lines is used. Hence the 220-volt power line circuit should not be used thru switches as indicated at B, C, or D When P 10 * 01 " 8 , °L */2 5- P- or larger are required, the 220-volt service is the better if proper switches and fuses are installed. Line K. is from the distributing panel or switch. Attention should be called to the low pressure relief valve a Z Si } -P\P e F at stock tank were much lower th an the faucet at the kitchen sink, it would be impossible to draw any water at the sink if water were allowed to flow freely atF Bv placing this relief valve G in the line to the tank, enough re - sistance to water flow can be set up to allow some water to be drawn at the sink. This is a special convenience when a meal is being prepared and the teams from the field want fresh water at the same time. AUTOMATIC ELECTRIC WATER SUPPLY SYSTEM— WELL NEAR THE HOUSE (Figure 14) If the well, either shallow or deep, is close enough to the house, a well pit may be connected to the basement. In the case of a cistern the pump and motor may be placed on the basement floor. The advantages are : 1. The equipment is easily accessible. 2. Warmth from the basement has some advantages in winter. 3. More room to work than is found in many small pump 4. Short runs of pipe to house. 5. Additions and changes take minimum labor and expense 6. The system is completely automatic. 7. Any type pump head or system can be used. 8. A broken belt or other trouble may be noticed soon The disadvantages are : 1. Many well men are not equipped to make a well so close to the house. ! 2. Noise of pump and motor operation may be disturbing. </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">Water and Sewage Systems fob Farms 3. An elevated cover to prevent filthy wash leaking into the well. 4. The addition of pneumatic pressure tank. In installations of water systems for which pits are neces - sary, it is much more convenient when men are working on the pump connections to have the well to one side or towards one corner rather than in the center of the pump pit. This type of installation is as good for the shallow as for the deep well pump, and with a slight change in suction con - nections, pumping from the cistern can also be done to jrood advantage. K Pipe A as indicated is shown to represent discharge pipe from any type of pump head. The motor and pump may be belted or direct connected and relative positions changed to fit local conditions. At B is indicated a thermal cutout in - stallation. While the thermal cutout is not necessary to the working of any electrically operated water system, it is an in - expensive protection against burning out the motor if for any reason continuous excessive current passes thru it The line fuses do not prevent motor burn-outs in many cases CC indicate prevention of surface wash from entering the pit or well. THE HYDROPNEUMATIC TANK The small tanks used in the present-day water systems are called pneumatic water tanks or hydropneumatic (water-air) tanks. Air occupies the upper portion of these tanks and causes increased pressure on the water when more air or more water is pumped into the tank. The air must be main - tained in some manner. Some of this air is absorbed by the water and must be replaced at intervals to prevent water logging. // an automatic water system becomes water logged the pressure regulating switch cuts in and starts the motor each time a faucet is opened. A sufficient quantity of air must be trapped at all times to produce the pressure necessary for a steady flow of water. The pressure regulating switch usually is set to start the motor when the pressure falls to 25 pounds and to stop the motor when the pressure builds up to 50. All these pressure regulating switches are adjustable Often a range from 29 to 40 pounds is very satisfactory When the best service is obtained, about the upper third of the tank is occupied by air alone and only from one-fourth to one-third of the water in the tank can be drawn when the regulator works between the limits indicated. Except in special cases tanks of 40 to 75 gallons capacity are large enough when used in automatic systems. This does not pro - vide a large storage capacity but is enough to prevent the </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment • Station Bulletin 245 motor from starting every time a small amount of water is drawn. The distinct advantage of the small tank is recog - nized when fresh, cool water* is desired at all times. I ■ ■ COMPLETE AUTOMATIC ELECTRICALLY OPERATED PNEUMATIC TANK I SYSTEM— WELL REMOTE FROM THE HOUSE (Fiirure 15) On many farmsteads the well is located some distance from the house. In these cases convenience, permanence, and de - pendability must be emphasized. The system pictured in Figure 15 brings out many features of the complete pump head and the installation recommended by the authors. The advantages of such a system are: , 1. Dependable water service at any place desired on the farmstead at a satisfactory pressure. 2. Very little care is necessary. 3. Water under pressure at all times makes possible in the country home any of the modern plumbing found in the city home. 4. Automatic switches and running water save steps that are required when there is only manual control or but one faucet from which all water is carried. 5. Sanitary conditions are better because of good tight platform and covers at the well pit. 6. Very little stale water will accumulate in the tank or pipes. The disadvantages are: 1. More care needed in installation. 2. Relation of air pressure to water distribution must be understood. 3. Absolute dependence on one source of power — electricity. 4. Higher first cost than that of simpler systems. 5. When the 40 to 80 gallon pressure tank is used, short - ages of stored water may occur when both the house and barnyard require large amounts at the same time. \The main features to be emphasized in Figure 15 are: 1. The complete unit in motor and pump head, including frost set-length installed above ground for easy accessi - bility (this should have a good removable cover built to keep out dust and snow). 2. A good reinforced concrete platform having raised flanges at both pump and manhole. 3. The pit should be 6V2 to 7 feet deep and at least 5 feet in diameter if round, or 5x6 feet if rectangular, to allow two men to work in the pit. This pit should be of masonry construction with drainage from the floor allowed thru lower part of pit wall. (Drainage out the lower part of the side walls seems better than a posthole </seg>
            <seg id="p029">27 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 245 sump near the well — there is less chance of this water getting back to the well.) 4. For the pneumatic system an air pumping cylinder is desirable; an air chamber E near the pump serves as a cushion and prevents water hammer in the pipe system and allows the pressure-regulating switch to work nor - mally and not open and close at each stroke of the pump. 5. The relief valve D prevents excessive pressure; the check valve prevents water running back into the well from the pipes and storage tanks. 6. Any pipe lines may be taken off on the under side of the service, pipe for hydrants as at F or in some cases at H and the cutoff and gate valves become necessary when changes or repairs are wanted. 7. The pressure regulator is placed on the discharge line from the pump. This can be adjusted to start and stop the motor at the desired pressures. 8. A cutout switch with proper fuses is installed in a con - venient place to cut off current while working in the pit or on the pump. 9. Near the motor a protective thermal cutout should also be used. These thermal cutouts prevent motors from becoming too hot if something goes wrong. 10. At A is the entrance switch and meter — panel box at K. This installation is being replaced in many districts by placing meter and switch on a pole in the farm yard. B and C represent conduits to house and appliance circuits. At G is a convenient place to install pneumatic tank in the absence of a good cool basement. This in - stallation has many points in its favor. THE COMPLETE AUTOMATIC ELECTRICALLY OPERATED PNEUMATIC TANK SYSTEM — INSTALLED IN PIT AND HAVING' THE FRESH WATER ATTACHMENTS (Figure 16) In many districts in Nebraska soil conditions are such that a well pit can be kept comparatively dry. Under these con - ditions the installation of the motor and pump head in the pit is good practice. Many times even when a small storage tank only is used, a fresh water outlet brings water direct from the well without wasting stored water that may be warm. The advantages of the system as shown : 1. The installation is usually free of the dust that causes much of the wear when pump head and motor are more i exposed. 2. The frost set-length is no longer necessary. 3. At a small extra expense the added benefit of fresh drink - jing water is provided. </seg>
            <seg id="p031"/>
            <seg id="p032"/>
            <seg id="p033">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms 1. It is possible to have either hard or soft water or both at any plumbing fixture in the house. 2. When soft water is on hand it may be used in the range boiler, thus preventing much of the scale deposited when hard water is used. 3. Pipes are so arranged that well water can be distributed in the soft water pipes if the soft water supply fails. The disadvantages are: 1. More piping and pipe fittings. 2. Necessity of drilling extra faucet outlets in sinks or of buying special sinks. 3. The scheme is not practical where a dependable pressure system can not be used. The main features are : 1. The gate valves A and B are used as by-passes to control the distribution. 2. The use of soft water where wanted. 3. The use of well water to flush-box or other places where soft water would be wasted. 4. The adaptability to use if a commercial water softener is installed. 5. A commercial water softener may replace the soft water storage tank of Figure 17 and connections may be made directly from well water system. 6. When valve A is opened, soft water flows to range boiler; then warm water flows back to kitchen sink lavatory, bath, etc. thru pipe C. 7. Cold soft water or cold well water can also be pined where convenient. 8. If the supply of soft water is exhausted, closing A and opening valve B will allow well water to flow thru the range boiler and, as warm water, supply the fixtures. a &amp; c o Figure 18. — Air chambers and pressure regulating switches. INSTALLATION OF AIR CHAMBERS AND PRESSURE REGULATING SWITCHES (Figure 18) Some kind, size, or type of air chamber should be placed near each pump. The pressure regulating switch should be installed near an air chamber. While the exact location of </seg>
            <seg id="p034"/>
            <seg id="p035">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms RELIABILITY OF ELECTRIC SERVICE It is very seldom that scarcity of water results from break - downs in electric service. Power lines are supervised care - • ] y «&gt; P re vent. any let-down in service and the small indi - vidual light plants are sturdy and usually can be depended upon to furnish electricity for pumping. CONVENIENCE OF ELECTRIC SERVICE Most industries have recognized the convenience of pressing the button to start operations. Motors take very little atten - tion, give steady speed performance and especially the small sizes can be started or stopped as easily by women and chil - dren as by the men of the family. COST OF INSTALLATION OF ELECTRICALLY DRIVEN WATER PUMP SYSTEMS Water systems and complete plumbing costs vary in much the same way as automobile costs. The more convenient elaborate systems cost more money than the simpler systems However, the first cost of a system to supply water when and where needed would have to be very elaborate indeed to cost as much as the cheapest new car on the market. COST OF OPERATION WHEN ELECTRICITY FURNISHES THE POWER _Since the project on rural electrification was started in 1926, accurate costs of operation, amounts of water used in the house, and data on depths of wells from which the water was pumped have been kept. On one farm the well is 65 feet deep The maximum pressure in the pneumatic tank is set at 48 pounds. The electrically operated water system has required 1 kilowatt hour of electrical energy for every 400 gallons of water. The farmer pays 5 cents per kilowatt hour for elec - tricity for the pump operation. At this rate the power cost is 12% cents per 1,000 gallons pumped. On another farm a well is 35 feet deep, maximum pressure in tank is 50 pounds, and 670 gallons of water per kilowatt hour are pumped At 5 cents per kilowatt hour this cost is about 7.4 cents per 1 000 gallons pumped. One system pumping into open tanks about 500 feet from a well 70 feet deep is pumping 900 gallons per kilowatt hour. A shallow well system pumping from a cistern and against a maximum of 50 pounds pressure in a pneumatic tank is pumping 940 gallons per kilowatt hour of electrical energy used. At 5 cents per kilowatt hour the power for this pumping is costing less than 6 cents per 1,000 gallons. AMOUNTS OF WATER USED IN THE HOME On all of these systems water meters as well as electric meters have been used and read once each month. Where modern toilet, bath, and kitchen plumbing are installed the family of six is using slightly more than 100 gallons per day. This is an average from nearly three years' observation. </seg>
            <seg id="p036"/>
            <seg id="p037">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms HINTS ON INSTALLATION Get a good careful mechanic to install the pump, piping and plumbing. See that tests are made for leaks, perform - ance, etc., before settlement is made. Do not expect good motor performance and long pumping service if the working and oiled parts are neglected or allowed to be exposed to sand, scaling walls, dust, grit, or other foreign substances. Care should be taken that stuffing boxes, differential cylinders, and bearings are not too tight. Before attempting to start the pump-system motor, be sure the data on the name plate of the motor correspond with the data of the circuit to which the motor is to be attached. Usually very good instructions for installation and opera - tion accompany each water system. These should be followed carefully. HINTS ON WIRING TO MOTORS (Pieure 20) In Figure 20, A shows how wires may be connected at the motor for 220- volt alternating current, B is for 110-volt alternating, C is a hookup for any of the direct-current cir - cuits, D is motor hookup thru a protective thermal cutout and a 2-pole pressure regulating switch. This is the safe hookup for a 220-volt ungrounded circuit. E shows the thermal cut - out and a single pole pressure switch for the circuit in which one side of the line is grounded. This hookup can be used for 32-volt direct or 110-volt, either alternating or direct circuits. The drawings in Figure 20 are not placed there to show definitely how any motor is to be .hooked to service line. Always consult the wiring " diagram that accompanies each motor. Then know you are right before throwing a switch to start the motor. COMMERCIAL WATER SOFTENERS (FiBUre 21) There is considerable interest at the present time in com - mercial types of water softeners which soften the entire household supply. These can be used only where some kind of pressure water system is available, however, from either a pressure tank, automatic electric pump, or gravity tank mounted on a tower or on a hill. These softeners are manufactured in small units for house - hold use. They somewhat resemble a range boiler in appear - ance and are connected to the water line where it enters the house. After softening a certain number of gallons of water, depending on conditions, the softener is easily reconditioned for further service. It is desirable to arrange the piping so that the water used in the toilets and at the cocks (where water is drawn for watering the lawn) does not pass thru the </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms softener where it encounters the layers of gravel and sand which support the zeolite. Here some filtering action takes place which removes silt and fine sand. It then passes up thru the zeolite granules where the magnesia and lime are taken out by chemical action. It then passes out thru the pipe A as soft water which can be piped to any part of the house. Other softeners are sold in which the hard water enters at the top and passes downward thru the zeolite to be softened. Advantages are claimed for both types. After a time the zeolite will absorb no "more lime or mag - nesia and the supply of water will be found to be coming thru as hard as it was on entering. It is now time to recon - dition the zeolite by backwashing and the addition of common salt. First, the direction of flow thru the softener is reversed by closing valves B and E and opening valve C (Figure 21) The hard water now enters the top of the softener and passes down thru the zeolite and the gravel, washing out any silt or other foreign material which may have accumulated The dram valve at F is opened so that this dirty water can run to the sewer. After 10 minutes or so of washing, the water is shut off and the charging door at the top of the softener is opened and a quantity of fine salt is spread over the top of the zeolite. The charging door is replaced and a slow flow of water turned on thru valve C. This carries the salt solution down thru the zeolite and removes the lime and magnesia which it has collected and washes it out thru the drain valve at F. When a salty taste is no longer present in the drain water, the softener is reconditioned and ready for use again. SEWAGE DISPOSAL SYSTEMS A SAFE FARM SEWAGE SYSTEM The sanitary disposal of sewage, including all of the wastes from the kitchen sink and the bathroom, can be accomplished safely and at reasonable cost by means of a concrete septic tank and a carefully laid-out absorption field. Such systems have been in use on farms for more than forty years and have proved their value as safe, sanitary methods of sewage dis - posal. The septic tank is a water-tight receptacle having a capacity sufficient for at least 24 hours' sewage detention, or 50 gallons capacity for each person served. The tank acts as a settling chamber where the solids in the sewage are decomposed and changed to liquids or gases. As the sewage enters the tank, the solids sink to the bottom, where they are decomposed by anaerobic bacteria which live without air. The greases rise to the top and form an air-tight blanket over the sewage, which aids the bacteria in their work. The liquid flowing from the tank, while almost clear, is not </seg>
            <seg id="p040"/>
            <seg id="p041">Water and Sewage Systems for Farms should be laid in a^ed of gravel as shown in Figure 23 the i™ £ wS* ? °- Ve . red th tar paper t0 P revent soil from work! ,£ f£ the JO11 2 ts - T £ e success of system depends largely installatfon 86 * sufficient number of «le and their cariful As a rule the septic tank is located 40 or 50 feet from the TWoSS i?" i?t down -stream side opposite from the well. The tank should be placed only deep enough in the ground to allow for the proper depth of the absorption system. The «lw£° n " eCtm^ he i} 1O - U ? e J md tank should be a 4 - in &lt;* sanitary sewer pipe, with all joints cemented and laid with a slope of 8 inches in one hundred feet. The sewage must enter the tank slowly, as undue agitation retards the action within the This system if properly installed will require little or no. attention for five or six years, when the tank should be cleaned 0U K , e slud^ e whlch collects at the bottom of the tank must not be allowed to come up to the bottom of the baffle boards - likewise the scum on top must not be allowed to occupy too much space. Regular inspections to determine the amount of sludge and scum are advisable. KITCHEN SINK AND DISPOSAL TILE- (Fieure 22) The main features of this simple system are: 1. The kitchen sink, which should be firmly set to the wall with the top of the rim or apron about 36 inches from the floor. 2. The trap at B provided with a clean-out plug. The trap is necessary since it prevents foul gases from entering the house from the sewer. 3. The clean-out plug in the basement which permits re - moval of any material clogged in the pipe. 4. A 5-foot length of cast-iron soil pipe shown at H, con - necting the sink drain and the sewer tile. i t ri ng of 4 " inch sew er tile with cemented joints to lead the sewage at least 50 feet from the house before it enters the gravel-filled trench where it soaks away into the ground. This vitrified sewer tile should have a fall c 2f.A rom /s to &amp; mch P er foot (C, Figure 22). f?rJ f eet £ f ordinar y 4-inch drain tile laid in a gravel - oof d %^ c \ wt t a fal1 of % inch P er foot (D. Figure 7u 4.-i s &lt; f®° ch 1S du S approximately 2 feet deep and the tile are laid not more than 18 inches below the sur - face. No trouble will be experienced from freezing. At j the end of the ordinary drain tile is a rock-filled sump - just a hole filled with rock and covered over with dirt. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 245 In extremely sandy soils it will not be necessary to do more than lay the tile in a trench and cover them up. The gravel and the rock-filled sump/will not be necessary. SEPTIC TANK WITH TILE DISPOSAL SYSTEM 1 (Figure 23) The main features of this system are: 1. Complete plumbing in the house as shown in Figure 23. This includes fixtures for the bath room, kitchen sink, cellar drain, laundry tubs, etc. At A, Figure 23, is shown the cast-iron soil pipe which extends from roof out under the foundation of the house a distance of 4 or 5 feet to where it joins the sewer tile. At D is shown the galvanized iron vent pipe, 1V% inches in diameter. Recessed, cast-iron fittings are used on this pipe. 2. From 30 to 50 feet of 4-inch sewer tile with cemented joints shown at G laid from the house to the septic tank. This pipe should have a fall of from % to *4 inch per foot and should be laid to a uniform grade. 3. A water-tight concrete septic tank consisting of two chambers, the first one of which is 3 feet wide, from 5 to 7 feet deep, and 5 feet long. The second one is 3 feet wide, from 3 to 4 feet deep, and 4 feet long. The walls of the tank are 6 inches thick while the covers are made of 10 concrete slabs 4 inches thick which may be re - moved for cleaning the tank. 4. From 300 to 500 feet of ordinary 4-inch drain tile laid to a grade of 6 inches per 100 feet, in a gravel-filled trench about 18 inches deep. After the tile and gravel are placed in the trench a layer of tight clay is tamped over the gravel to keep the fine soil particles from wash - ing down into the gravel and filling the spaces. The raw sewage from the house enters the first chamber of the tank thru the pipe 6. After it has been in the tank for a certain period, bacterial action takes place which liquefies a part of the sewage, turns part of it into gases, and reduces some of it to a sludge which settles to the bottom of the tank. This sludge must be cleaned from the tank once in five or six years. The effluent which leaves the tank is usually a colorless, thin liquid which soaks away into the soil surrounding the drain tile. This colorless liquid is not free from germs, how - ever; therefore the strings of drain tile should not be located near the well or other sources of water supply. 'Persons interested in installing complete plumbing fixtures in the house and a septic tank for disposal should procure the following material from the Extension Service. Agricultural College, Lincoln, Nebraska: No. 10.812-2 Disposal Chamber Septic Tank _ 20 cents Extension Circular 703. United States Department of Agriculture, Farmers Bulletin 1227. United States Department of Agriculture, Farmers Bulletin 1426. </seg>
            <seg id="p043"/>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 245 To secure dense water-tight concrete it is necessary that not more than 5V&amp; gallons of water be used in mixing each sack of cement. In case the sand-gravel is wet instead of moist the amount of mixing water should be reduced to 4 or 4Vfc gallons with each sack of cement. Enough sand-gravel aggregate must be added to the cement paste to bring the mixture to a jelly-like stiffness. This sand - gravel must be well graded and clean. The mixture must contain just a few more sand particles than are required to fill in the spaces between grayel particles. It is next to im - possible to produce a water-tight concrete with a coarse or under-sanded aggregate. To produce a water-tight concrete the curing process must be guarded carefully. Time is required to build up a dense structure that is impervious to water; hence in building tanks, cisterns, or any water-tight concrete it should never be per - mitted to dry out rapidly, but should be kept moist for at least a period of two weeks and longer. if possible. HINTS ON CONSTRUCTION 1. Underground water pipes in Nebraska should be laid 4 to 414 feet deep. Use only galvanized wrought iron pipe. . ! 2. Carry water pipes to second story thru inside partition. Put fixtures on inside walls if possible. 3. Keep sewer and water pipes away from wall or windows in basement where freezing may take place. 4. Use pipe compound on joints when screwing water pipes together. 5. Arrange all water piping with slight slope so that it may be drained if necessary and air traps may be avoided. 6. To lessen the expense of plumbing, pian the bath room above or near the kitchen. 7. Remember that the water in the range boiler and water back expands when heated and an explosion is likely to result when pipes are frozen or when piping is not prop - erly installed. Write to the Extension Service, Agricultural College, for more definite instructions before installing the complicated water supply and sewage disposal systems. [ism] </seg>
            <seg id="p045">QUESTIONNAIRE I Information Regarding Water System Persons wishing to inquire further regarding water supply systems j may fill in the following blank and mail it directly to the Extension Service, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska! 1. What is the source of your water supply? 2. (a) If well, state: Type [ Depth Lowest level of water Whether well ever goes dry (b) If spring or stream, state gallons per minute 3. Which is higher, source or buildings? ...... How many feet fall between them? 4. Distance between source and buildings 6. For what service is the water required — house, barns, lawns, gardens, etc.? If for stock, what kind and how many? Horses Cows Pigs... Sheep 6. How many persons will use the service? „ 7. Do you require both hard and soft water service? : ~ 8. What is your estimate of the gallons of water required per day? a X 9. Is the pumping to be done 'by hand, windmill, gasoline engine, 0 £• electric motor, or hydraulic ram? g If electric motor, give the following information: (a) Direct current?.... If so, what voltage? (b) Alternating current? Cycles Phase Voltage . Note: If in doubt about these, ask the company that supplies your electric current. ■10. What system do you propose to use? '. 11. Describe your present pumping machinery, if any, and we will advise you whether it can be. used, in connection with your pro - posed system or not 12. Make a sketch showing relative positions of source of water supply and pumping machinery, tank, etc., marking in the distances vertical and horizontal. Name - Address •- -•-.■ </seg>
            <seg id="p046">QUESTIONNAIRE II Information Regarding Sewage Disposal System Persons wishing to inquire further regarding the installation of sewage disposal systems should fill in the following blank and mail it directly to the Extension Service, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska. 1. Number of persons in the household where septic tank will be used 2. Is house located on level ground or does it slope from the house in any direction? Give details I■■ ' . 3. Is house now equipped with plumbing fixtures? 4. Does sewer leave from bottom of basement or near ground surface? 5. Is a basement drain necessary? 6. Nature of the soil where disposal field must be constructed. State whether sandy or heavy clay 7. Type of septic tank preferred — Metal - .Concrete Vitrified materials ( Name '■ Address •. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>