<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Twenty-fourth Biennial Report OF THE Warden OF THE State Penitentiary To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium ending November 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">i .: &gt;&gt; as &lt; F z H E ■ V. ■ o as | _ as a a </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE OF NEBRASKA Twenty-fourth Biennial Report OF THE Warden OK THE State Penitentiary LINCOLN, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Beard of Commissioners of State Institutions Fur the Biennium ending November 30, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">354 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATE PENITENTIARY Lincoln, Nebraska To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Commis - sioners of State Institutions, Howard Kennedy, Henry Gerdes and Silas A. Holcomb: Gentlemen: tl respectfully submit to you my report for the biennial od beginning November 30, 1914, and ending November 1916. I During this period the State prison has made rapid igress along the lines pertaining to reform methods. He - rn in penal institutions signifies progress. Under our new orms we have made it possible to work a number of our 's at other State institutions, — nothing to hold them but ir honor. This progressive reform has made it possible work from fifty to eighty men on our farm and rented d, and for farmers close to the prison. It has created in minds of those men a sense of honor which is lasting, th few exceptions, the boys have caught the spirit of pro - sss. To every order of new rules that we have put into jet the men have willingly responded. All seem to realize it the new regulations are along the lines of real advance - nt. Discipline under our new reforms was never better, ports for infractions of rules are very few. The men real - that on their conduct depends the continuance of the vileges extended to them in the way of recreation and amusements, — such as Sunday privilege in the yard ; two baseball games a week during the ball season. — after their day's work has been done; movin&lt;r picture show each week, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 355 during the winter season; and the privilege of attending night school five nights a week. One of the most important accomplishments during this period is the fact that we have been successful in creating in the boys a sense of self respect and neatness of their per - son. Each man has been provided with a neat blue suit of clothes, made by our prison tailor, also, a neat light shirt and tie, for Sunday wear. This has had a very marked effect on the men. With this change the men present a neat ap - pearance, and, on Sunday, we see no more sullen and de - pressed countenances, but rather a spirit of contentment. The policy of our administration to recognize and re - ward good prison conduct by recommending only such pris - oners for parole, at the expiration of minimum sentences, has demonstrated that there can be justice in prison adminis - tration, which leaves the inmate hopeful that from his own efforts he may better his present unfortunate condition, though he may be in prison. In this connection the success - ful working of the indeterminate sentence law has had a close connection with discipline and efficient work. EDUCATION The evening school continues in a most satisfactory con - dition. The enrollment and average attendance has increased to such an extent that it is difficult to find room for the classes. The law contemplates holding nine months school each year, but, owing to the transient nature of the student body entering and leaving at all times on the indeterminate sentence of from one to a number of years and parolable in ten months, it was found that, having but nine months school each year, many could not attend more than six months. To avoid this difficulty and to give to all the full benefit of the school as well as the extra good time allowed, — three days for each month's attendance, it was thought best to continue throughout the year. In all about 400 men have registered, the enrolh .ent at times reaching as high as 150, with an average attendance of 125. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">356 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF When it is considered that one-third of the prison popu - lation, because of the nature and time of their regular work can not attend, the number that do is somewhat remarkable. Another gratifying feature is the excellent deportment. There are no formal rules to be observed. It is an honor institu - tion. There have been but six cases of discipline during the biennium. The lively and sustained interest shows clearly that most of the men really desire to take advantage of the op - portunity offered. The original course of study prevails, i.e., all the com - mon branches, with special emphasis given to the most essen - tial. Special attention is given to the illiterate and those with little education. The aim is to have all able to read, write, spell, and to use the fundamental operations in num - bers. The commercial course is popular, attracting many of the better educated. We have a class in Spanish numbering about twenty, a number of whom plan on going to South and Central America at the expiration of their terms here. Last year the policy of having all inmate teachers was adopted. There are many men received who have necessary qualifications as teachers and it was thought advisable to give them these positions of honor and trust. The plan is proving very sat- RELIGIOUS WORK (Regular services have been conducted each Sunday dur - this period by our chaplain, personally, or under his di - tion. Assistance has been given in the music by Mr. J. E. ix and Miss Rose Scott. Special musical talent has been ured for nearly every service during the two years. Sun - r school has been conducted each Sunday under the super - ion of Mr. J. E. Cordnar assisted by an able corps of chers. The Volunteer Prison League held meetings al - st every week. This organization reached a membership two hundred and twenty-five and was a medium of ex - ;ssion for those of a literary turn of mind as well as for •se who were religiously inclined. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 357 Each Sunday afternoon the chaplain does personal work among the men while they are resting in their cells. At least once a week the chaplain visits the shops to give a word of cheer to the men while they are engaged in their regular tasks. The moral condition of the prison is on a high plane. The inmates show a deep appreciation of the religious work done. Close and interested attention is given at the chapel services and in the Sunday School. The attendance at the Sunday School is voluntary. About one hundred and twenty - five avail themselves of this privilege each Sunday. Father Moran, our voluntary Roman catholic chaplain, conducts services regularly every two weeks for those who are of the Roman Catholic faith. Under his direction a Holy Name Society was organized and proved to be a great benefit to its members and its influence was felt throughout the whole institution. Chaplain Johnson's and Father Moran's work has been very satisfactory and they deserve a great deal of credit for the interest they have taken in these unfortunate men. HEALTH OF INMATES I am pleased to note that, since the Harrison Act pro - hibited the indiscriminate sale of narcotic drugs, only four men have been admitted to this institution addicted to the use, in any degree, of habit forming drugs. During the biennium five of our inmates have died from causes as follows: Cancer of colon 1 Obstruction of bowels .' 1 Septic pneumonia 1 Rupture of pulmonary vein 1 Separative peritonitis 1 Twelve inmates have been adjudged insane by the legal board of insanity. Of this number seven have been trans - ferred to hospitals for insane and five are awaiting order of transfer or are awaiting room for acceptance at the hospitals for insane. There are others who should really be </seg>
            <seg id="p007">358 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF in an institution other than a penal one. In the past few years there have been a number brought here from different counties of the State who should have been sent to hospitals for the insane or an institution for the feeble-minded. I would heartily recommend that a building at some institution be erected for the care of the criminally insane. We are not equipped here to take care of such patients and it is unfair to require the superintendents of the hospitals for the insane to care for this class of patients unless a good safe place is furnished them to hold insane prisoners, because if these should escape and murder someone or commit other depra - dations the superintendent would be held responsible. I also recommend the erection of a small building within the walled enclosure to hold the insane here until transferred. At the present time we have no place for them except the hospital where we have sick patients who at times should not be annoyed by the insane. Of course, it is impossible to keep these in the cell house as they would disturb all the inmates therein at night. During the two years, 148 patients have received hos - pital treatment and of this number forty-eight have been operated on in major operations. Out of the entire number admitted this biennium sixteen were partially disabled for task duty and nineteen were totally disabled for physical work. The general health of the inmates has been for the two years past and is now better than could be expected. IMPROVEMENTS MADE In the east cell house we have built over the tier of cells a roomy and well-ventilated auditorium. This space had not been utilized for any purpose. We put a cement top on the cell house; placed a steel railing around it, constructed a good stage, with scenery painted by some of the inmates, and two dressing rooms. The body of the auditorium has a seating capacity of about eight hundred. We also use this for our chapel services and for our moving picture shows. This was a much needed improvement as our old chapel was </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 359 too small for religious services or entertainments of any kind. The old chapel is now used as a display room for the furniture manufactured here. During this period the visiting public voluntarily con - tributed sufficient money to purchase a moving picture ma - chine, which is very much appreciated by the men. The au - ditorium was built with but little expense to the State, as the inmates did all of the work. Another valuable improvement was the tearing down of the old stone barn which was inside the walls and a rendez - vous for rats and which made our inclosure very unsanitary. The old barn was close to the cell house and even made the cell house unsanitary. Tearing this down and hauling the stone outside of the wall and removing the old green house gave us space for a good baseball diamond and recreation ground. Another needed improvement was the building of a large vegetable cellar in the hill south of the prison. This cellar is twenty-four by seventy-five feet. The stone from the old barn was used for the walls of this cellar. This work was all done by the inmates. The old cellar under the shop building was so damp and unsanitary that it was impossible to keep vegetables or fruit for any length of time. Our furniture shops have been remodeled, an elevator installed, and many changes made in the building which make it a very comfortable factory building. We erected a stucco building which is used as a factory office, picture gallery and record room. This work has all been done by the inmates with small expense to the State. We have erected a good hay barn where we can store our hay which was, heretofore, stacked outside. This barn was constructed at little expense, as a great deal of the lumber was taken from old buildings, that were torn down. The old store room south of the wall was bought from the Lee Broom and Duster Co. for two hun - dred dollars, remodelled and the main part converted into a good ice house. The two small store rooms are used for ma - chine sheds and make ample room for all our machinery. The fences on the prison farm were in bad repair, most of these have been rebuilt and are now in good condition. We have </seg>
            <seg id="p009">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 360 Eilished a chicken ranch on the hill south of the prison e we have put up some good buildings and expect to chickens enough to furnish eggs for our institution. t Since tearing down the old barn inside the walls, we have ired and converted an old barn on the outside into a good e barn. Where the gutters had rusted out and the water was ruining the foundations, we have had installed on the shop buildings new gutters, downspouts, and sewer attachments to carry off the water. The open sewer around the foot of the walls was in bad condition and it was necessary for us to wall up the sides and put in a cement bottom to prevent the water from cutting under the walls. This was a great improvement and a badly needed one and required a great deal of work. It was necessary for us to put a new roof on the ad - ministration building. SANITARY CONDITIONS The sanitary conditions of the prison are very good. Since the building of the new water plant about three years ago, we have an abundance of water for flushing purposes. The cell houses have all been painted and kept in a clean and sanitary condition. Our dining room and kitchen are kept clean and the food is well cooked. POWER PLANT During the past two years the entire plant with the ex - ception of some equipment has been renewed. There have been installed three water tube boilers of the Murray type. Each boiler is 250 horse power. These boilers are equipped with automatic valves of the Lagonda type with S. C. water regulators and high and low water alarm. The boilers are equipped with Jones stokers which have been in service for seven years. These stokers are doing good work but, of course, require considerable repair. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">X. &lt; z a E z a. Ed i B life "--1 H 11 1} r i. t Ed PQ Eb Q Z Q Ed Ed </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 361 There have also been installed two 125 K. W. units, con- sisting of two automatic Uniflow Engines of Skinner make. One 200 K. W. machine of the same type is now on the road and will be installed as soon as it arrives. One 750 H. P. feed water heater of the Warren Webster type is another addition to the new plant. This is equipped with a Warnell Waring Meter which enables the operator to weigh the water as it enters the boilers. A Fairbanks scale has been placed in the boiler room to weigh all coal used. With this new equipment the operator can tell the exact amount of evapor - ation per pound of coal used and thus keep a check on what is being done with the coal. There has also been installed one feed water pump 51/2x81/2x10. This pump is of the simplex type and is use&lt; in feeding the water to the boilers. The steam heating system in the tunnels and the east and west cell houses has been practically made anew. In the tunnel, six inch pipe has been replaced by ten inch. In place of the old heating coils in the cell houses, new radiators have been installed. Anothe great improvement in the heating system has been the in- stallation of the receiving tank for returns. In connection with our new engines, there has been erec- ted a new Westinghouse switchboard equipped with auto - matic circuit breakers, an automatic voltage regulator, and all the modern equipments a switchboard can have. There is also a condensing equipment in connection with the engines which enables the plant to run condensing in the summer time when steam heat is not needed. The building over the engine room has been entirely remodeled. We have in connection with the new plant, seven motors, as follows These motors are used to communicate power to shops, ice plant, water pumps, and laundry. There is also installed Fairbanks Morse 40 H. P. Fairbanks Morse _ .20 H. P. Westin^house 50 H. P. Westinghouse _ 14 H. P. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">362 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF in the boiler room one hot water service tank which fur - nishes hot water to the entire institution. !We have two water plants in connection with the insti - on. One is located in the yard and the other a half mile th of the institution on State property. The pumping it in the yard is not much good. We can get only about y gallons per minute and the water is very hard. The »r plant, on which we depend almost entirely for our er supply, furnishes a hundred gallons per minute. I ild suggest that another well, which has been started, be »hed and a new pump purchased for the plant north of the itution. The old pump frequently needs repairs and its acity is insufficient. The electric wiring in the cell houses is in bad condition and I suggest that this wire be placed in conduit. The motors are nearly all too large for the load we have for them, thus making a very poor power factor and putting excess load on the generator. I would suggest that these be sold and motors more adapted to our purpose be purchased. I With this new plant, we are now furnishing power to Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, Orthopedic Hospital, ernor's Mansion, Capitol Building and Grounds, and Ne - jka Home for Dependent Children. A good power line has 1 constructed to transmit current to these places. This be a means of bringing good returns to this institution at the same time effect a large saving to the other insti - ons. The Board of Commissioners of State Institutions aid see that we receive a reasonable compensaion for the rent thus furnished. RECOMMENDATIONS I would respectfully recommend the purchase of more farm land. I only need to refer you to our tables on pro - ductions and earnings from farming, stock raising and gard - ening, to convince you that this has been a profitable line of work to follow at this institution. The purchasing of more land will further develop an open air industry and will enable us to enlarge upon our trusty and honor systems and also </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 363 give many of the inmates practical training in general farm - ing. Our farming has been very productive of results — by being profitable to the State and in rebuilding men. I trust that prison farming may continue to expand until a large proportion of the prison population is engaged in this work as a self supporting community. I would, therefore, recom - mend at this time that at least a half or three quarters of a section of land be added to our prison farm. Owing to our increased population, which now numbers over four hundred men, with but three hundred cells our cell houses are too crowded. One man only should really occupy the small cell room. During the summer months this condition was relieved by permitting our farm boys and other trusties to sleep in the barn and other places outside, but as winter comes on it is necessary to put them all in the cell houses. In view of these conditions, I recommend an outside dormitory for all trusties who work outside of the walls. This dormitory building should be made as much homelike as possible, with kitchen and dining room in con - nection. Some employee of the institution and his wife should be in charge to exercise a parental influence over these boys who by their conduct merit working on the outside. This building should be so constructed as to permit adding thereto at any time, if the dormitory plan outside should prove a success, which I am confident it will. A small canning factory should be established here for the purpose of canning tomatoes, beans, corn, apples and other fruits and vegetables. This would in time, make a great saving to the State. Canning could be done for other State institutions instead of buying such products at retail prices. CONTRACT WORK From thirty to forty men are working for the Lee Broom and Duster Company. The remainder of the men are on State work, manufacturing furniture, farming, stock raising, construction work, and other work which is necessary around the institution. I recommend that the State take over the manufacturing of brooms in connection with the furniture </seg>
            <seg id="p014">364 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Eness. This would give us an opportunity to work more at this industry and keep all our men employed at State k, thus doing away entirely with contract labor. ROAD WORK Fifty of our boys were put to work on Holdrege Street building about three quarters of a mile of paved street. This work was, indeed, very beneficial to our boys. It was also profitable for the State. The men worked on this road for about three months and during that time but one be - trayed the confidence placed in him. This was a man who had but a few months to serve. Much credit is due Governor Morehead, under whose supervision this work was carried on. He visited our camp almost every week, took a personal inter - est in the work, and encouraged the men in every way pos - sible. We fully appreciate the assistance he gave us in the new undertaking. He came personally to the prison and assisted us in the selection of the first fifty men we put to work and as - sisted us in every way possible while the work was in pro - gress. His presence at camp and on the work at different times made the men feel that he was taking an interest in them and the work they were doing. I sincerely hope that this Legislature will give us some good wholesome legislation for permanent road building in Nebraska. The past experi - ment justifies our contention that the boys from the peniten - tiary can be trusted to build permanent roads. The quality of work done on Holdrege street speaks for itself. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 365 ESTIMATED APPROPRIATIONS The following is the biennial estimate of the appropria - tions required for the State Penitentiary for the period be- ginning April 1st 1917, and ending March 31, 1919: Salaries Warden Deputy ... Steward Physician Chaplain Matron . $5000.00 2760.00 ... 2400.00 2400.00 1200.00 1200.00 2000.00 Clerk Total $16960.00 Wages Captain Guards Engineer 1 @ $100.00 1 9 110.00 $2400.00 2640.00 1800.00 1800.00 1680.00 1680.00 2880.00 2640.00 27600.00 Night Engineer Yard Master .... 1 @ 75.00 1 0 75.00 Farm Superintendent Clerk 1 © 70.00 1 « 70.00 2 @ 60.00 Guards Guards Guards 2 @ 55.00 23 © 50.00 Total. School Principal 1 @ $50.00 for 10 mo. 1 @ 10.00 for 10 mo. 9 © 3.00 for 10 mo. Head Teacher comm.. Teachers ..for 10 mo. Supplies Total. Paroles and Discharges Five hundred men © $10.00. Total. Oftce aid CoBtmgeat AH office supplies and postage </seg>
            <seg id="p016">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 366 Fid Steam coal 13000 tons @ 53.50 $45500.00 Range coal 250 tons @ 6.00 1500.00 Blacksmith coal 12 tons @ 8.50 102.00 Total. $47102.00 General Repair* Ker room., ine room $1210.00 100.00 220.00 100.00 rps, shafting: and belting - plant Cell houses 25.00 Water supply (engineer's estimate) Plumbing 100.00 1000.00 200.00 300.00 5000.00 Stove repairs. Farm implement repairs. Repairs to buildings and grounds Total $ 8255.00 Other Maintenance Other maintenance $110631.00 New Equipment for Farm Potato planter, two row. Potato digger _ Corn hinder Three cultivators Grain drill Hay rake Two wagon trucks for hay racks Two farm wagons complete Dump cart Ensilage cutter Two hay sweeps Total For L&amp;tmdrT Eouipincnt $ 6000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 367 New Buildings and Land Our old stone laundry building is dangerous. It should be torn down and a new building erected for laundry purposes, the estimated cost of which is $12000.00 For the erection of an outside Dormitory building for all trusties working on farm, stock-raising and gardening. Building to house an average of 50 men 10000.00 For building to hold insane inmates temporarily until they can be transferred to hospitals for the insane 500.00 For slaughter house 200.00 For 120 acres of land on which the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions has an option 20100.00 Total $42800.00 Grand Total $288188.00 REPORT OF THE HANDCRAFT FURNITURE COMPANY Herewith is submitted the financial statement of the in- dustrial department of the State Penitentiary, known com- mercially as the Handcraft Furniture Company. The state- ment shows condition of this department up to and includ- ing November 30, 1916. The above department was opened under State owner- ship on May 25, 1915, employing during the first month of operation 52 inmates of the institution, working under the supervision of four department foremen, a manager and a book-keeper. The number of inmates employed in this department has increased monthly until at this time there are employed 132 men in this industry. At the time of engaging in the manufacture of this line of furniture it was necessary to perfect organization, obtain a correct itemized cost report showing factory cost of each piece manufactured, compile and complete a suitable catalog showing the line, and organize a selling force to place the </seg>
            <seg id="p018">368 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF goods on the market, thereby consuming considerable time during the first three months of operation of the industry. kThe sale of the line of furniture in various states has made through the manager, commission salesmen, and ers. No salaried salesmen have at any time been em - ed in the selling of the output. The product is sold principally in the mid-western and southern states, comprising the states of Nebraska, Iowa, Illinois, Wisconsin, Minnesota, North Dakota, South Dakota, Montana, Wyoming, Colorado, Kansas, Missouri, Oklahoma and Texas. During the period of operation the total sales have ag - gregated the sum of $61,517.00. tThe present parole system, combined with the present , of payment of the inmates, has brought the quality of line up to a high standard and an increasing demand for same has resulted. During the period of operation of the Handcraft Furni - ture Co. under State ownership, the sum of $5,659.68 has been paid the inmates through the warden, for the benefit of the men and their dependents, — the wage paid varying from ten cents to twenty-five cents per day according to efficiency shown, each inmate being required to serve a 30 day apprenticeship. Manufacturing conditions have been very difficult dur - ing the past 12 months of operation from the fact that there have been many and constant advances in the cost of all raw materials entering into our manufacture. Advances in sell - ing price have necessarily had to attach to the entire line. tin view of our present list of customers and new accounts ng constantly added, we anticipate a larger volume of liness will develop during the coming year. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I _ w^ - ■ 1 (»"i 5 1 D a L a: S SB u C a </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 369 •5 |terc«&gt;nt dedti*^ed from equipiuent. account depreciation. tTheae Bgures total of inventories. t*i&gt;40.()0 added to total inventory of supplies, and included herein, account of finishing, wrapping, and shipping hardwood furniture from supplies of the Reed and Fiber department. *5 per cent deducted from equipment account depreciation. tThese figures total of inventories. 1*64000 deducted from the tot.il inventory of supplies account, flnlahl ig. wrapping and shipping from supplies of the Reed and Fiber department. Reed and Fiber Department Dr. &lt;r. Lo*4 ami (jaiu Ketource* Liabilities L'apital Macfc * Bills lti-.eivnl.le Commission lii.-ic.unt Kquipuienr Kxpciisf KllHT^'fln\ &lt; ;ish Finished Murk Illt*Tt'St Lost aud iraln... Office supplies Supplies State Peniten- tiary deposit Cash fund over- drawn Act-'ts receivable Acc'ts l'ayal&gt;le.... $ .'fj.dliocj; ■Mi :«•.■.• i 13.08J.35 L'OU.OO 36,«73.!I3 38.6N m !•.' ' 42.4-T.7J 4«,8O2.5« .-.L'.4&lt;»&gt;.7i; MHM UMJi .&lt; 383.4!) ; I $X&gt;.000.« 890.00 *8487« mum ttl7,.-iaB.77 4«y8O3.M S32.4O8.7l 9,2S4.ft4 l.i IMS »12-J,5«&gt;.35 ♦li-.'.jsy.jr. 110,071.74 * IMMfl $S5,4!I8.1J lain .. $10,071.74 ♦10,071.7' $10,071.74 »aO,(ffl.74 $U6fift4.8O «96.5&lt;H. lepartment I&gt;r. o. Lou and Gain Keoources Liabilitiea Capital stock t DlfM'OUIlt Equipment KXIH'IIS** Finished gto&lt;-t... OnVe Equipment.. Loss and Gain...... Supplies State Peniten- tiary deposits... Gash fund, over- drawn Acc'ta Receivable A«'t» Payable... 2,200.32 1.47t;.ir.&gt; 121.75 «ui 2.817.11 1.916.S8 1.130.29 « 3.0U0.00 « 3.16 2,«23.31 4,066.51 115.50 V.HS.11 46.11 I | 2.155.S5 tr&gt;18.»&lt; 1-J1.75 tXto.U 1.916.88 1.130.29 « 3.0OX0U 4.UN5.51 11SJW * »..&lt;C7.48 $ »X!7.4s % 944.32 f 6.2M.79 f 7.201.01 Lou . * M4.22 I 1H4.22 S 944.22 $ 044.22 * 7.201.01 * 7.201.01 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">370 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF Library The prison library is under the State Library Commission and we receive frequent visits from Miss Nellie Williams, who has general supervision of the libraries in State institutions. There are 3200 carefully classified volumes on the shelves and a complete catalogue is given each inmate with the priv - ileges of selecting his reading. One of the inmates acts as librarian under the supervision of the chaplain. The present assistant has been in this position ten months and his records show that 28765 volumes have been read in that time, making an average of 1191 per month. Magazines subscribed for during biennium 30 Magazine circulation per month 681 Total magazine circulation for biennium _ 16344 Number of books purchased 450 Catalogues printed _ 500 The character of the reading may be seen by the report for October, 1916: Philosophy 27 Fine Arts IB Religion 8 Literature 34 Sociology 33 Travel 73 Science 18 Biography 84 Useful Arts 21 Fiction _ 859 kit is the purpose to have works read that are of a high •acter and to keep out such reading as would not be fting. CONCLUSION tin conclusion, I wish to thank his Excellency, the Gov - or, and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions their co-operation and assistance rendered me during this iod. I wish to express my appreciation to the superin - dent of the prison school, who has labored earnestly in the icational work, and to my worthy deputy I wish to ex - d my sincere thanks for his faithful work and assistance. Chaplain Johnson, Father Moran and all of those who re assisted them in the moral uplift of the inmates of the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 371 institution, I desire to extend my sincere appreciation. To all of my co-workers, I extend my sincere thanks for their assistance and their loyal attention to their duties. Respectfully submitted, W. T. Fenton, Warden. Lincoln, Nebraska, November SO, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">372 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATEMENT OF EARNINGS, EXCLUSIVE OF THE FARM AND GARDEN Labor Contract Labor: Lee Broom and Duster Co $18951.61 Handcraft Furniture Co. (former firm) 3143.13 Other state institutions 3209.60 Public road work _ 4960.67 Miscellaneous employers 4420.34 Total $34684.35 Institution Enterprises Inmate store, (cigar stand) $ 1725.55 Postal card stand 503.53 Barber shop 180.00 Green house 33.00 $ 2442.08 * Total earnings $37126.43 rt of the total earnings there was paid to in - mates as follows: Overtime and wages $ 8092.39 Inmate store keeper, percentage of profits 378.85 Postal stand keeper and photographer, per - centage 251.75 Barber 55.00 $ 8777.99 Net earnings to state $28348.44 * This item does not include wages to the amount of $5659.68 paid to inmates by the new state industry, the Handcraft Furniture Company. Labor and Service Credits New Manufacturing Industry, (Handcraft Fur - niture Co.) 32580 days @ 60c, (contract price) $19548.00 6486 days @ 30c, (apprentice price) 1945.80 $21493.80 Electricity Furnished: Orthopedic Hospital, 12240 K. W. H. @ 3c $ 367.20 Nebraska Hospital for the Insane, Lincoln, 108270 K. W. H. @ 3c _ 3248.10 State House. 65270 K. W. H. @ 3c _ 1958.10 $ 5573.40 Total credit items $27067.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 373 TABLE OF ACREAGE Our farm cousists of 2tW acres. Of this, 15) acres are taken up with buildings, yard, and railroad. Tbe following table* show the land rented and the crop* VI ■IK k: I'OBT I ANIMAL | i I I I I ■ i s 13 1 ■ 1 HorseH •» Mules 3 Cults 1 Cowk, (milk) 18 Heifers _ 11 Calve* _ _ 10 Bulls .... 1 Pisrs. fall 108 Pijcs. sprinjr- _ Sows nnd old hogx 101 Boars 1 Chickens _ 75 Guilders 3 1 M 12 16 ISO aw 184O~ 2 _ 2 10 $1200.00 , 8 3 8 1200.00 _. Horse . 8 3 21 2100.00 18 _ .. 7 386.00 _. _ 3 28 575.00 1 1 1 10000 143 76 « 196.00 210 154 1925.00 3 B 34 1020.00 1 __ 2 50.00 360 986 580 477.00 3 1.50 Total $9227.00 »ro&lt; sreon. 1IU Acres Rent Crop Quantity Value 40 18 10 1*% IS * 80.00 108.00 Half share 140.00 75.00 Oats Corn Corn Alfalfa Hay TOO bushels 10S0 bushels 000 bushels 30 tons 18 tons t 304.00 M8.00 300.00 300.00 180.00 $1792.00 ♦883.00 i : 1»1« 40 ■ 40 38 • 80.00 140.00 Half share Half (bare 300.00 378.00 140.00 i 1434.00 OaU Alfalfa Corn Corn .Alfalfa . Corn Wbeat* Hay 838 bushels 28 tons 380 bushels 900 bushels 26 tons H73 bushels 873 bushels 48 tons 319.00 I 260.00 342.00 45a 00 2S0.00 •■77.96 taimso $ 1434.00 •Stsndin when rented. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">374 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF FABJf FKODICT8 OF INSTITUTION DIKING THE BIKNNICM Item Metiure Quantity | Valve Annies _ Bushels 85 t 32.50 Alfalfa _ Ton* 227 2270.00 Beeta ___ I Bushels 950 406.00 Beans, green _ _ Bushels 120 96.00 Carrots ...... _ Bushels 290 158.25 Celery Crates 10 60.00 Cabbage - Ton* 25 234.0ft Cantaloupe* Number 326 32.50 Corn Bushels SI61 S025.90 Cucumber* — Bushels 463 461.75 DU1 Bushels 3 S.00 Ensilage Tons 265 2130.00 Fodder „ Ton** 43 2M (10 Hay. prairie .. Tons 63 630.00 Timothy hay Tons 10 140.00 Lettuce Bushels 620 408.00 MUlett Tons 5 35.00 Onions, green j Bushels 680 544.00 Onions, mature i Bushels 600 598.75 Oats Bushels 1600 70A.8O Oyster plant Bushels 4 4.00 Parsnips Bushels 40 20.00 Perns __ __ Bushels 120 96.00 Potatoes Bushels 7200 5X00.00 Pumpkins i Number 675 36.00 Radishes Bushels 390 228.00 Rntabaa-aa ' Diisbels 90 46.00 Rplnnaeh Bushels 126 75.00 Sweet corn Dosens 3150 315.00 Squash _ | Number 168 33.60 Straw Tons 140 280.00 Tomatoes, ripe Bushels 1085 542.50 Tomatoes, green... _ Bushels 146 43^30 Tnrnlpt 1 Bushels 540 289.00 Wheat _ Bushels 1464 1576.31 Total i $24600.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 375 INCOME FROM ANIMALS, POULTRY AND MISCELLANEOUS Item Measure Quantity Value Beef,, slaughtered Pork, slaughtered. Hogs, sold _ Hides, sold - Poultry, slaughtered Ganders, sold- _ Pounds Pounds... Number Number Pounds Number 9277 ! 59990 140 30 $ 871.13 6231.61 2200.70 206.48 960 3 14800 134.40 150.00 1926.00 Milk, consumed. Butter, consumed Eggs, consumed Mules, sold. Kindling _ Cinders Junk Bones Empty barrels Gallons Pounds Dozens Number 341 250 3 102.06 57.50 340.00 12.75 82.50 476.25 "" 43.55 25.65 ..._ Total I $ 12712.08 VEGETABLES CANNEI I, PICKLED AND PRESERVED DURING THE BIENN1UM Variety Measure Put Up Value On Hand Value Piccalilli Sauer kraut Tomato preserves Tomatoes, canned Tomato pickles Pumpkin butter Pickles, dill Gallons Gallons Gallons Gallons Gallons Gallons Barrels 200 $ 60.00 ... 2720 410.40 . 734 213.13 725 217.50 75 22.50 135 40.50 65 715.00 $ 290 87.00 495 148.50 75 22.50 130 40.20 47 517.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">376 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF FARM PRODUCTS SOLD DURING THE BIENNIUM lu-m Measure Quantity Value Beets, bunched Beets, bulk 10 $ 88.05 Bushels Bushels Baskets Pounds Baskets Bushels Bushels Pounds Bushels Bushels Number Bushel . Bushels Bushels 10 4.00 8 7.91 Cabba ;i . 2880 14.35 Cucumbers 10 6.10 Carrots, bunched 6 3.25 10 4.20 Onions, matured Onions, bunched . Potatoes 1254 21.95 10 12.03 500 240.00 1 .25 Tomatoes Turnips . V4 .35 20 9.30 1218-% 1350.73 FARM PRODUCTS ON HAND AT C OSE OF BIENNIUM Item Measure Quantity Value Llfalfa — ar= Tons _ Bushels Bushels _ Crates _ Bushels Tons ..._ Tons Bushels Bushels Bushels Number Bushels Number _ Tons Bushels Bushels Bushels 110 150 40 4 1600 60 $ 1100.00 90.00 24.00 24.00 1360.00 480.00 lay, prairie )nions, mature 30 2 300 560 100 20 25 40 170 60 86 300.00 2.00 150.00 907.50 5.00 10.00 5.00 8.00 85.00 90.00 127.00 _. Vheat, in bin. Vheat, sowed Total .. ; * 4757.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">as I I a at ■ I] I L^ Ji - c s m ' ■ 1 r. M </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 377 SUMMARY Value of farm products on hand. % 4757.50 Value of vegetables canned, pickled, etc., on hand. 815.20 Value of institution stock on hand. _ 9227.00 Total..._ _ _.._ _ $14799.70 TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year For Year ending endiug Total MOVEMENT Nov. 30. Not. 30, fo' 1915 1918 Bienniuui M. F. T. ! M. r. T. M F. T. On hand beginning of period 800 o 365 I 340 5 » Admitted: For first time* 196 — 19« 254 2 23« 450 3 453 Iff -admitted _ 27 27 i 41 .... 41 6N 68 Retnrned parole or furlough. 26 _... 26 19 _— 19 4S 45 Returned escaped _ i 3 3 3 3 Total recovered. 240 249 | 317 2 319 '928 s 934 Keleaaed : Escaped ! 3 S | 7 7 | 10 1O Discharged at expiration of sentence.... 21 21 ■ 17 17 38 38 Died _ 4 — 4 ! 3 — 3 7 7 21 21 17 17 38 M Pardoned — - I 1 1 1 1 Order of i-nurt 4 4 2 ..... 2 6 • Transferred S — 31 7 — 7 10 10 Executions 1 1 1 1 Paroled, furlougtaed, or deported dur ing period 225 5 230 233 1 M «S 6 «Vt Total released 280 5 265 271 1 272 531 6 837 Remaining at end of period. i ..396 2 387 Av«*r;iirt* population _..— .... 375 — 37T •Including those who have been previously incarcerated in this or other prisons. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">378 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE II. AGE OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For Ve»r ending ending Total Nov. 30, Not. 30, lor AGE i or 1915 1916 Bleiiuiuni M. F. T. It F. T. M F. T. I and under 18 and under 21 and under 26 and under 30 and under 35. and under 40 and under 46 and under 50. and under 55 and under 60. and under 65 and under 70 and over 1 13 3 4 — 4 2« 26 44 _... 44 70 70 54 54 ffi 63 117 117 Vi 49 70 _.. 70 119 11!» 27 27 , 45 1 4« 73 1 74 24 1 25 32 1 x: :&lt;* 16 l«i 11 11 t » 12 n 21 -J1 » — 9 7 7 16 1« » S 7 7 16 lrt • « 3 3 9 — 9 • « 3 3 9 — 9 1 — 14 4 5 I 1 1 1 1 Unknown 1 1 Totals.. 223 1 224 295 2 297 518 3 521 TABLE III. RACE OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For V#or ending ending Total Nov. 30, Not. 30, for BACE for 1915 1918 Biennlum M. F. T. | M. F. T. M. F. T White _. 204 1 206 ! 262 2 2«4 46H :S 4*' Negro _ 18 18 30 30 4S 4S Indian 1 1 3 :; 4 4 Totals 223 1 224 , 296 2 297 r.18 :t .V.'l TABLE IV. EDUCATION OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For Y«ar ending ending Total Not. 30. Not. 'JO. for EDUCATION f,,r 1915 1916 j Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. K. T None - 10 — 10 13 ...... 13 23 23 Primary 38 .._.. 38 47 47 K5 __ . 8B Common iichool — 151 1 152 192 1 193 34S 2 345 Hijrh school. 18 — 18 37 13856 1M College or university — I 6 — 6 6 « 12 12 Totals 22S 1 224 296 2 297 . 51S 3 521 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 379 TABU V. CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For Yea- endine ending Total Nor. 30, Not. 30, for NATIVITT for 1915 1918 Blennium M. F. T. j If. F. T. I M F. T United States : Alabama _ _ 1 1 1 i Arkansas 1 1 1 1 ■ California 2 2 1 « 6 8 8 Colorado _ 1 18 R fi • Connecticut _ _ l _.... i i i Florida _ j 1 1 ._ i i Georgia I 1 1 1 ; _ _ i __ i Illinoia _ 18 — 18 24 24 42 42 Indiana _ _ _ 2 2 C » 8 8 Iowa 17 1 18 27 27 44 1 45 Kansas 11 11 18 18 29 20 Kentucky 7 7 • 6 13 13 Louisiana 2 2 4 4 Q 6 2 2 4 — 4 6 • Maryland 3 S 1 14 4 Michigan 2 — 2l 3 _ S 5 5 Massachusetts 1 1 4 4 S 5 Minnesota. 1 1 4 4 6 S Missouri 20 20 31 _.... 31 51 _.. 51 Mississippi _. _ 2 1 I | 1 3 Montana 1 — 11 l Nebraska 38 — 38 58 58 M M New Hampshire 1 1 1 1 Neir Jersey 2 ■ New York rt • ! 8 8 14 14 Ohio 15 15 9 9 24 24 Oklahoma 1 — 12 — 2 3 3 Oregon 1 — 1 1 — 1 2 ? Pennsylvania _ - 10 — 10 10 — 10 20 20 South Dakota _ I 1 — ill 12 .._.. 2 Tennessee • — • i 5 — 6 11 11 Texas -.-. • — • 4 — 4 10 10 B 5 5 5 10 10 Vh-Binla ' » — 5 ! B — 5 , 10 10 West Virginia 2 — 2 1 1 3 S Wisconsin I 1 1 4 _ 4 5 5 2 Wisconsin Washington — ■ — — — : 1 — 1 1 1 Total native born — 184 1 186 259 1 280 443 2 445 For Year ending Not. 30, 1915 For Year ending Not. 30, 1916 Total (or Blennlum CIVIL STATUS M. F. T. M r. T. M. F. T. Single . If* Married ' 4S _ Widowed _ _ 7 DlTorwd 10 1 l-Ki 1MB 1 lsn'rsi 1 36! .... 4S 81 81 12B ia — TIM 1 11 17 1 11 -.... 10 1 11 11 21 21 Total! "J22S 1 224 295 2 297 51S .i 5 1 224 M 2 297 .-.lv .i ■ TABLE VI. NATIVITY OF THO8E COMMITTKD </seg>
            <seg id="p032">380 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI. NATIVITY OF THOME COMMITTED— (Caatlaurd) For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for \.\T1\ II V for 1915 1916 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T oth«T ctiiimri' Argentine „ - .. 1 1 1 1 » 4 1 Australia 1 1 1 tustria - 1 ohetuia _.— _ G 1 4 1 1 I Itrazil 1 3 i anada i; f, Denmark I : lit- hi ml France .. 1 1 1 1 4 _.... 4 H 1 ..._ 1 1 (•••rumii.r 1 1 S 1 « • 1 '.i &lt;;reece | 1 ] Holland Hungary „ __..__..„ 1 I !-• - i H 1 1 &lt; I — ''• 1 1 1 Italy _ _ 4 Mexico tt 1 1 hrni I-oland 1 1 1 1 'tou mania Raw* ... 1 1 1 SbimIoii ;&lt; Scotland 1 1 1 1 1 1 Syria ...- _ 1 1 1 « 1 1 I nknonn 1 Total foreign horn. Totals L&gt;^3 1 224 SB -,1&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p033">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 381 I tlll.l. VII. PHYSICAL AMI MKNTAL CONDITION OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Total CONDITION AT COMMITMKXT Nov. 30, Not. SOl for 1915 1916 lii.-nniuiu M. F. T. M. F. T. JI. F. T. General health : Sound — - — ... !neral health : Sound 170 175 201 I 208 376 2 S78 IT.". ■ 173 201 208 376 2 378 2 102 Diseased -Ht 1 50 101 1 102 150 2 102 Diseased 1 50 101 1 102 150 Montal st:it.' Sane eiital stnte: Sane 208 206 280 L&gt; J91 4!»5 2 487 2M 2lW 23H 2 Ml 4'.K&gt; 2 487 Feeble-minded _ 7 _.. 7 13 13 20 2P Feeble-tuiuded Insane 13 _ IS 11&gt; 20 Insane - - 11 1 1? 1 1 12 1 13 11 1 1? 1 1 12 1 13 Dise.Tt.eil : General d General Utcmaw: Syphilis -.. ■ _... 8 64 64 72 72 Syphilis '■4 64 72 1 1 n i S |ilM';l-rs of 1 1) [&gt;laea»M "&lt; th» mart* »jsipm 1 l 1 l 1 i. Diseases of the circulatory system... 1 2 '-' 2 circulatory svsn-ui l»U»;ises of tlit' respiratory system— 2 2 2 2 I 4 - of tli&lt;- "liue^live - J '1 2 4 4 v. ( Diseases of the ttenito-nrinary sys - tem » » 8 8 17 17 Diseases of th&lt; 'Uito-nrinar.v sy '.• 9 8 8 17 IT tern Astlimn 3 3 1 1 4 4 3 1 1 4 4 Hernin 8 8 13 — 13 21 — 11 s Defects, injuries, amputations: v rm 2 2 2 Z Hand •"&gt; 5 ■ __ j 10 10 2 .-, 5 io 10 Leg | 2 _ 2 2 ■_&gt; Foot 1 1 I I 3 _.... 3 3 Blind I Oue eye Bon 1 1 1 12 I I'onf: One ear 1 ..... 1 1 — 1 it. i Epileptiii 3 3 3 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">382 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VIII. PKEV1OI S OCCUPATION OF THOHF. ADMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Total Xov. 30, Not. 30, for OCCUPATION for 1915 1916 Blennium M. F. T. M. F. T.l M. F. T. Appraisal engineer ! 1 1 1 1 Artist 1 1 1 « 10 1 Barber j 4 4 10 BeU hop 1 11 1 2 2 Butcher S 3 8 • 9 9 Ball player j 2 2 2 2 .. ■■ Bookkeeper 2 — 2 0 — 5 7 7 Blacksmith 2 2 1 IS 3 Blnrksnilths helper j _ _ __ j 3 3 , S _.. S Butler — ! 1 __ 1 1 1 Brick layer .1 1 1 1 Cook 9 9 13 13 J 22 22 Clerl 4 4 7 7 11 11 Cleaner and prener 1 1 1 1 Carpenter 5 — 5 8 8 13 IS 1 II 1 __.. l Carpenter 5 — 5 Cow boy _. 2 2 Cow boy ■2 Cement worker i 2 2 Chauffeur I 5 5 4 ...... 4 9 9 Cooper —_-_—_-_-__— ~~~~~—~ — 1 1 1 1 Cabinet "■**—• I 2 2 2 Copper miner 1 1 ! 1 1 Kruif elerfc. . .... 1 1 _ I 1 1 * »-«»™- — — ---- — — - — * Donor - 1 I 1 1 DUh washer 1 1 ! 1 1 Dancing teaclier 1 1 - 1 1 Draymen _ _ 1 1 | 1 1 Engineer 3 _... 3 3 — S 8 ...... « Electrician 3 3 4 4 7 Electrician's helper _ 3 3 3 _... 3 I 1 1 57 88 _... 88 4 8 8 ■ I 2 " 1 1 1 Gardner 1 — 12 — 2 3 ...... 3 Grsin jn«»rpfrnnt_ ., ,. ..■■■■ , , . ., , j l ...... 1 j X — 1 Housework — 1 1 I 2 2 3 3 Horseman _ _ - 1 1 j 1 1 Horse trader _ 1 1 1 1 3 '.'J 1 Lanndryman - 1 _.. 1 1 1 1 2 . 2 Lather - 1 1 ' 1 1 Miner _ 1 1 j 1 1 Machinist 2 2 8 — 8 10 ...... 10 Machinist's helper 2 2 4 — 4 8 — 8 Musician 2 — 2 1 — 13 — 3 Morle man 1 1 . 1 1 Marble cutter 1 — 1 1 1 Merchant 1 1 1 1 MaMtnr operator 1 1 1 1 taker'! helper (oiler maker 'oal miner 2 a 2 ~3 2 5 5 2 1 1 1 1 3 2 7 3 _. 1 t ..... 7 3 1 Egg handler Farmer Flrrman Florist .... 57 _ 4 _. 2 .._ j Gu fitter arnpss maker •borer . 51 51 3 48 1 ..... 48 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 383 TABLE VIII. PKEV1OI M OCCUPATION OF THO8E ADMITTED — I ( oarladed &gt; For Year For Year ending ending Total OCCUPATION Nov. 30. Xov. 30, for 1915 1916 Bienniiim If. F. T. M. F. I. M. F. T Movie operator | _ _ [ 1 1 1 1 Miller 1 11 1 Nine 1 I 1 1 Porter • • 8 8 ! 17 17 Painter 7 7 5 5 12 i_ Plasterer 2 _ 2 Puuip man_ _ i . 2 2 2 2 . I * Plumber _ 1 1 2 2 3 3 Paper hanger 1 1 3 3 ] 4 4 Printer S S 2 __ 2 1 5 ...... S Policeman 1 1 1 1 2 2 Powderman _ „ 1 1 '' 1 1 Railroader _ _ 4 4 4 4 k x Ranchman __ I | 3 3 _.... 3 • __. • Rug maker __.... 1 1 1 1 Real estate 1 1 1 1 Stenographer 1 1 ! 1 1 Stone mason. Sailor 1 1 1 1 Salesman 5 S 5 3 1(1 .... 10 Show man 1 1 5 5 *l • Shoemaker _ 3 3 4 4 Stone cutter 1 1 1 1 Stock buyer ? - - 1 1 1 1 .... 1 Stock man _ _ __ 1 til — 2 * — * Structural Iron worker- Steam Otter I _ 1 -.-. 11. 1 Switchman __ a 2ii — i a s Trapper _ _ 1 — 1 1 1 Teamster _ 4 4 12 _.... 12 Id M Telegrapher - 1 — 1 ' — ' Teacher 1 1 1 1 2 * 1 1 Teacher Telephone man 1 — 1 1 — 1 _ 1 Tailor 4 4 2 2 « _.... • 1 1 1 11 I rmbrella repairer _ _ 1 1 1 - 1 1 Walter 4 4 S _.. • j 10 1* Wireless operator 1 — 1 — - i 1 1 Totals. 221 2 223 286 2 297 518 3 521 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">384 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE IX. KKl.H.IOl S PREFERENCE Of THOME COMMITTED For Year For Ysar ending ending Total Not, 30, Not. 30, for RELIGION for Catholic j » 1 54 «B 1 «6 llx 2 120 E ew _ I __"._.. _ _ 8 S 2 2 5 __.. S __ __ 2 2 S 3 5 _.. 5 Grrr-k _ I 2 I 8 SB— 5 Not reported 27 27 84 _._. 54 81 «1 reported 27 27 M _._. 54 81 «1 Totals 1223 1 224 (3K&gt; 2 297 518 3 521 Totals 223 1 224 !(*f. 2 297 [518 3 521 TABU X. NCMBEB OF CONVICTIONS OF THOSE COMMITTED TABLE X. NCMBEB OF CONVICTIONS OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For i'eur For Year For i'eur ending ending Totil ending ending Total Nov. 30, Not. 30, for CONVICTION Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for for 1915 1916 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. ' M. F. T. fiitt _ _ M0 190 255 2 257 445 2 447 26 26 S2 ._. 32 57 57 Third 4 16 7 7 11 1 11 Fourth 1 1 ._ - 1 1 1 1 Industrial school - - — I I — 3 3 3 3 3 Totals 22S 1 224 295 1 -".ft 51S 3 521 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">£ a i F p E a i I i I I as I ? 1 | si Z H | ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p038">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 385 TABLE XI. COISTV FBUM WHICH (OMIIITI Kit For Year ' For Y-.-ur ending pndlng Tout Not, 30, Nov. 30, for 1915 l-.ilt; Blenniuin COUNTY M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 4 4 &gt;; • 1 1 I 1 I l l l i 1 13 3 4 4 Hoi Bntle .; 6 j M 14 30 M I 3 3 x s Bojd - - - 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 I .". I 1 1 1 1 I 4 .: « 10 in Cl«r _ _ 1 1 .1 j 4 4 - I 3 3 I 13 4 16 Colfll 1 1 1 1 Pin-venue i 4 » !) 13 13 I) -i ■i 1 1 1 1 :i I H, H | Be 5 _ 5 17 17 ™ a r*uH i :::zi::: ::::::....:::.... 1 1 :: 1 .. 1 lioufflaa ... - » 1 90 75 1 7« *■ 1 Vft 1 1 1 1 ! i i i i 1 1 1 1 4 4 I 5 » • I « 6 7 _... 7 IS 13 S .-i 1 ... 1 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">386 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XI. COUNTY FROM WHICH COMMITTED — &lt;( onlinurtl) For Year For Year ending ending Total Not, 30, Not. 30, for COUNTY for 1915 1916 Blennlom M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Hitchcock _ _ _ i _.... ! i i Hamilton ■' Keariu'y 0 Keya P&amp;ha - „ 1 11. l Keith 1 .... 1 4 ..... 4 .-, 5 Klmhall _ 1 1 1 11'.. 2 Lancaster ..., 17 17 35 35 52 5'J Lincoln !• •&gt; 7 7 10 _ 16 Lonp _ 1 1 1 1 Madison 1 1 1 11' 2 Merrill 1 13 .*[ 4 4 Nance 1 _ 1 1 1 2 2 ■2 NuckollB _ 1 1 2 ...... 1' ;i 3 Otoe 1 1 7 7 X 8 Perkin* 1 1 1 1 Platte 1 1 1 1 Pbelpt , _ •_• 2 3 S :, 5 Richardson _.. 3 S 6 6 9 .... 9 Red Willow 2 3 2 _.. 2 4 4 Rock 3 3 3 S Sarpr . 2 2 3 3 5 5 Scott* Bluff _ _ 4 4 2 _ 6 • Seward 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 .1 4 6 • 1 1 1 2 2 4 4 1 11 1 5 Kl 10 Valley _ - 1 1 1 1 Webster __ — _ _ 2 2 ■• 2 Washington 2 2 1 1 3 3 Wayne - 1 1 1 1 TotaU- 223 1 224 296 2 SW 518 3 521 1 ... 1 ... 2 ... r. ... 1 . 1 2 2 5 x 2 .... 4 .... 1 2 .... 1 __ 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 387 TABLI XII. ( KINK FOB WHICH COMMITTED For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Not. 30, for CRIME for 1915 1916 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T Abbetlng felony _ 1 1 I 1 1 Assault to wound 1 1 1 1 Assault to injure _ 4 4 Assault to rob _ 1 1 1 1 2 ...... t Assault to kill Assault to rape - :( 3 7 7 10 10 Arson 1 1 1 1 Attempted arson 1 1 11 Auto stealing 2 2 2 2 4 4 Burglary _ 38 38 ai 20 56 SS Breaking and entering _ 38 38 :» :w 77 . 77 Bigamy _ _ 2 2 2 2 4 4 Blackmail _ — .. 1 1 1 1 »'nT*-tiiir &lt;-nm*ealed weapons - 5 5 7 7 l'J 12 Cattle stealing 7 7 3 3 10 HI 7 Embezzlement _ 1 1 2 2 3 1 Forgery 30 30 50 M 80 80 Furnishing cocaine to prisoners 1 1 1 1 Grand larceny ...._ - 23 23 42 42 C5 *i Humbling 1 1 1 1 -' I Hot stealing 1 1 1 1 Highway robbery _ 16 16 36 26 • 43 I Incest - - 1 1 1 1 Intent to defraud by forgery — 1 1 1 -.-. 1 Larceny as bailee _ _ I I I — t Ckwrk "No Funds" 1 1 4 1 5 5 1 • I &lt;'lM»ck "No Funds" Lerreny from person « 1 7 12 — 12 18 1 M 3 6 1 7 11 1 12 Manslaughter - 5 5 6 1 7 11 1 11 Murder 12 12 11 11 23 — 2» Murder Obtaining money under f«lw smtasma— 2 2 4 — 4 6 — ( Poultry stealing 1 1 1 ' Rape 3 3 9 9 12 U Receiving sinlen property 1 1 1 — 1 Sodomy Shooting to wound _ 1 1 1 1 Shooting to kill. 7 I Stabbing to wound 1 1 4 4 5 S 1 .... 1 Selling mortgaged property 1 1 1 — 1 Statutory nun- I 2 4 4 6 ...... • Statutory rape Wife desertion 1 1 3 3 * * Totals 223 1224295 2 297 518 3521 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 388 TABLE XIII. TBKM OF KENTKXCK OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For Year ending endiUK Total TERM Xov, 30, Nov. 30, for TERM 1915 1916 Blennium M. F. T. M. F. T. j M. F. T, M. F. T. M. F. T. 11. F. T Death 2 2 1 1 3 3 Death 2 __. 2 1 1 ' 3 3 Utt „ „ 7 7 9 ft 1 ig 19 Uft „_ __-_„_____ _ .. 7 7 9 .„.. % 1$ 18 V yean 1 l 3 3 4 4 10 rear* 1 1 3 ...... 3 ! 4 4 15 jean - ' 2 ._.. 2 1 . 1 1 3 3 15 jean - 2 ._.. 2 1 . 1 3 S 12 jeara _ 1 _... 1 l 1 10 years — 4 4 4 4 10 years — 4 4 4 4 7 jaars "!..... 2 .!.... 2 2 __ 2 7 you. I 2 2 , 2 2 ■• « jr«-»riL.._ _ 1 .._.. 1 1 1 •) jvarn... 1 .._.. 1 _ 1 1 8 yMrt. 8 &amp; 'I 2 5 B 8 yttrt. 3 3 2 2 5 S 4 years... - 1 _.. 1 1 ..... 1 2 . 2 5 8 4 years-. 1 1 1 1 2 2 5 jean , 1 12 2 3 3 yean ,1 12 2 • 3 3 2 yean - 8 8 6 • 2 jean - 8 8 8 • 1 year 4 4 » 1 10 IS 1 14 1 jaar 4 4 » 1 10 13 1 14 • month! to 10 jeara. 1 — 14 4 5 5 « month! to 10 years. II — 14 4 5 5 •a am to 90 d»T» _ _ - 1 1 ' 1 1 00 days to 90 days — - 1 1 ■ - 1 1 12 montlii to 15 mouths S 3 10 10 13 IS 13 mootbi to ISmouthi S 3 10 10 IS 13 12 month* to 13 months. _ ! 2 2 1 1 12 month* to 13 months... 12 months to 18 months 1 18 6 12 month* to 18 month* 1 ..._. 1 8 8 7 7 1 to 2 jean _ ! 4 4 8 8 12 12 1 to 2 yean - ! 4 4 8 8 12 12 1 to 3 jean . - 7 7 20 30 27 27 1 to 3 years 7 ..... T 30 20 ; 27 ..... 27 1 to 4 jemnJ j 4 4 7 7 11 ll 1 to 5 years.- _ -. 1 11 _ 11 17 17 28 28 to 7 years.... — 32 1 33 49 49 81 1 8B 1 t» 8 yean 1 1 1 1 1 10 10 year»_ - j »2 96 59 1 W|1J1 1 152 1 to 20 yean _.... - 28 — 26 S7 37 82 82 » to 15 years i 5 5 7 ..... 7 1 12 12 J to 4 yean - 2 2 2 2 1 to 8 yearn - - 1 1 j 1 1 2 _ 2 12 2 to 15 years- - — 14 14 23 231 37 _.... »7 2 _ 2 2.. 2 Totals. \-Sa 1 -JM 205 2 297 518 3 521 TABU XIV. DURATION OF IMPRISONMENT OF THOSE DISCHARGED, PAROLED OK ESCAPED IHRINli BlENMId For Year For Year ending ending Total Not. 30, Not. SO, 1 for DURATION OF IMPRISONMENT 1915 1916 Biennlum M. F. T. M F. T. I M. F. T. Less than 6 months. 12 1 IS M 16 28 1 29 6 months to 12 months _ 152 2 184 j 1«S _ 188 1 320 2 322 12 months to 18 months. I ■ 1 86 38 — 38 1 TS 1 74 18 months to 2 years 7 — 7 1 8 8 ' 16 15 2 ye." to » yean. - _ » _ • » » 48 48 S years to 5 years 17 — 17 8 8 25 2B 5 years to 10 yeaW. - — 6 — 6 6 — 61 12 12 17 17 8 8 1 25 2B Totals I 260 4 284 1 264 264 j 624 4 528 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">B 1 - 3 » - c = &lt; 1 - z, mm ■ 1 &gt; « I 2* 1! 15 I | I </seg>
            <seg id="p043">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 389 TABLE XVII. Al.E AT DEATH AGE AT DEATH For Ye«r ending Not. 30, 1915 For Y#»r ending Not. SO, 1816 Tot«l for Blcnnium M K. T.lM. r. T. II. r. T. ■J4 yran — 25 rear* _ _ - . _ - . I » ynn HZ _ -'-'.'..._ 44 ytmn - _ -A 1 1 1 — 1 __.. 1 1 1 1 . 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 1 I 1 Tot«l» J sr 3 ... 2 _ ■ 3 .. TABLE XV. &lt; II \K\t I KK OF IIKKMK.t. OF THOSE COMMITTED For Year For Year ending Not. 30, 1915 ending ending Total PARENTAGE Not. 30, Not. 30, for PARENTAGK 1915 1916 Biennlum 1918 Bienuium I m, V. t7~u. i\ t. I m. v. t? ■» Both parent! deml Both pareoti deml fl9 ...... 6» 85 I * i.^ 1 15.1 86 1 88 l.VI 1 l.V. Father dead _ _ 50 1 51 72 72 122 1 123 Motiier dead 38 38 40 1 41 W 1 TO Motiier dead » 38 Both parents llTlug « « 97 »T I iaa 1*.' Both parents llvlug « 88 vt »t I iaa i'i- Unknown _ 1 1 1 1 1 2 2 Unknown — 1 1 1 1 12 2 TOUU W 1 2M| »6 2 OH 1 518 3 621 Total* | 221 1 234 286 2 207 1 518 S 821 TABU! XVI. CAIHK OF DEATH TABLE XVI. CAIHK OF I)K\I II For Year For Y&lt;-nr endliiK vndiug Total eudln* ending Total caisk iik mm x,.v. :«&gt;. Nov. 30, for for 1915 l'.tli; ' Biennlum l'.tlii ' Biennluui M. F. T. ~lf! i\ tT| M. -F. T. Cancer of the eolou- _ j 1 1 l l Obstruction of ttae bowela ' 1 1 1 1 Septic pneumonia i ii i l ltupture of artery 1 1 1 1 — i»t_ &lt;■ , , , Peritonitis _ 1 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">390 SECOND BIENNIAL REPORT OF 1 KBI.K XVIII. STATISTIC* OF PAROLED, I I K I &lt;&gt;l &lt; . II Kli AND BEMANDKD PBISONKKS On parole, furlougb and remand, November 30, 1014. _ „ — 184 Re-paroled. re-fnrlon»rlie«l ! re-remanded - _.. _ 20 raroled and furloagbed „ 451 *»."w Discharged on parole, furlough and remand 329 Returned from parole, furlough and remand : For default 40 Without fault _ In other prisons... *Eacaped while on parole, furlough and remand „ _ Ml 4435 Tfrtal on parole, furlouirh and remand, November 3*», 1916. 100 •This number Includes 28 escaped during the preceding biennium but not accounted for. TABLE XIX. DIM IPLINAEV KKI'UKI FOB HIKWII M For Year For Tear endltiK ending Total Nov. 30, Not. 30, for DISCIPLINARY MKASIRE for 1915 1916 Blenniiim M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. Number of prisoners reported for bad conduct 161 161 294 294 4W 4.V&gt; Number of reports for bad conduct 147 147 232 232 37!&gt; :t7!i Number of times reprimanded ami ex- cused 47 47 1O7 Mf l.-&gt;4 154 Number of Sunday privileges taken. _.. 71 71 S4 :« lft"&gt; .... M E amber of other privileges taken umber of prisoner! committed to sol - itary confinement once umber of prisoners committed to sol- Number of other privileges taken.. 51 _.-. SI I.Vi 135 1S8 _ Mi 51 _._. 51 I.Vi 135 1S6 . IM Number of prisoners committed to sol- itary confinement once-. 3ft _... 3!» 30 SO «fl &lt;» 3* _... 39 30 30 ».!&gt; Number of prisoners committed to sol- itary confinement twice 10 10 7 7 17 17 t umber of prisoners committed to sol - itary confinement thrice 6 6 1 1 7 Number of prisoners committed to sol- itary confinement four times - 1 1 1 1 Number of prisoners committed to sol- itary confinement more than 4 times—. 3 3 1 1 4 4 Xnmber of prUoners deadlocked in cell 20 20 52 .".•.' M M Total number of days In solitary con - finement 101} 101} 110} 110} 22-Jj r.'-'j Total number of days good time lost 4O 40 45 45 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>