<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BULLETIN No. 87. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  A TEST OF CALF RATIONS.  METHODS OF CONTROLLING CONTAMINATION OF MILK DURING MILKING.</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">HI LLETIN 05 THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION A TEST OF CALF RATIONS. By A. I.. Haecker. METHODS OF CONTROLLING CONTAMINATION MILK DURING MILKING. C. W. Melick. ■ 1 1 O A C f A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD JOHN L. TEETERS, P&gt; ncoln BUSH A C. arney CARL J. R .Aha WH. G. WHIT THE STATION OFFICERS RURNETT, WH. W. MARSHALL THE WORKING STAFF SSmtth, B. Sc., Animal Husbandman 'BTKRS, D. V. M., Animal .ES E. BKSSHY, Ph. D., BoL S. A very, I'll. D., Chemist A. L. Habckrb, B. Sc. A., Dairy // La wren CK Brvnt.r, B. Sc, Entomci Erwin H. Bardovr I'h. D., Geologist R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer G. D. Swkzey, M. A., Meteorologist J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Associate Animal i W. P. Snydkr, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation North Platte S. W. Feslis, Farm Foreman </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A TEST OF CALF RATIONS. BY A. L. HAECKER INTRODUCTION. ■neral use of hand separators by - r ate, the interest iu calf rear - l.v increased. iy no means a small one, as some twenty - are now being used throughout uli hand separator represents a farm where '■d on skim-milk. To use this valuable by - 10 the best advantage is a problem worthy of much ml investigation. ring of 1899 the Department of Dairy Hus - nilurting experiments in calf rearing by ir.itor skim-milk and light rations of grain. it was published in Bulletin No. 68 of this '■alt with a comparison of calves reared by with t* !;in&lt;; their dams. The hand-fed calves skim-milk, ground flaxseed being used to re- g butter fat. This test resulted in a fine lot i very low cost, but it also brought out more data were needed in the way of i' used with skim-milk. THE EXPERIMENT. THE FOOD THAT WERE COMPARED In the fall of 1901 an experiment was planned to test some rations rich in fat to replace the absent butter fat in skim - milk. Owing to complaints from feeders that flaxseed-ineal was often difficult to obtain, it was thought advisable to use BULL. 87, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XVII, ART. III. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 ommercial oil-meal for being a product ire in almost any part of the country. The two by-producta of factories ueal being one and corn oil Tip from the corn jjenu and re* il in appearance but h. orn fla\ the oi! ii itains al ■ Oiln* Alfalfa Ii &lt; 'ieri &lt; !on Shelled ■ For convenience the eah group including eiglr ration, -ly two years were required to complete the test owing ie necessity of securing a number of calves nearly ■ age and the convenience in feeding one group at a time. LCk calf in all groups was \ it birtli and all'' ■ick its dam for two or three days or until it was in a ng condition and tl milk fit for use. The caJf then taken fron her and fed whole milk for v 6 ■* ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p005">o riie i milk for the first two we feed, while th&lt; ! two n skim-milk, six or seven pounds •ond j&gt;eriod the calf received eight 0111 then on U'n pounds were given. _ found and the calf generally b old. The rat.;. iie calf would eat up clejui. Hay c-d at all times and the animals and water. GROUP I. the calf was changed to skim-milk - added to the milk and stirred in. ■ I in small rations, starting with a teaspoon - iiil the fifth period, when the animal capful at a feed. The linseed - in the milk for the first three months, after with the corn and oats and fed after the .7 as a j If tH Si Bw.lingof calf. Miring Pounds. 68 90 310 217 250. 221 223 '.'43 220 •:» </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 7 6th period 5G0 10. C 1.4 Total... 210 2828 I 38.00 68. 0q 188 68.i ■ GKOl P IL The germ oil-meal lot, or (Imup II, was fed about the &amp; in every way as Group I, corn-germ oil-meal being used stead of linseed-meaL The eight i f firing to the n irious feeds wen Rat. «cb. mtlk m '- Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. I lrt period 210 140 3d period 4th period 3 00; 16.0 5th per. I 0 18.00( 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Srx animal- of Group II. Group II was fed skim -milk with C 'RN-GEKM OIL-MEAL. e calf "White" may be used for reference of this Group. • / white, a calft kite, a ca, V ,rou. £2% I o« Pas- ture, days. Cost for period. wt at end of period. Gam ii wt. C&lt;Xt Of t lb. of gain. -eh. m«I. — -=j Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. Lbs. 85 120 170 205 Lbs. 31 35 r O 35 1st period 245 GO °d period 448 3.00 4.00 4.00 31 pe- 448 6 8.00 4th period 8.00 12 00 1*2.00 5th period 560 10.00 12.00 12.00 6th period &amp;O 10.00 14.00 14.00 TtoUl 262* 37.501 50.0o| 50.00 14 28 28 H«T. 60 100 * 2.55 .98 1.27 1.35 1.36J 1.58 235 290 30 55 9.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 in r ht t feed. 1 t a thre GROUP III. The corn-oil lot, or Group III, was given coi of the oil-meals of the other Groups. The ration of sents this Group. Some difficulty was exjKTieuced in using this was first attempted to produce a milk having about Mat fat, by simply pouring in the oil and stirrinj ith the milk. This could not lie done, as the much lighter than the milk and would not mix by t agitation. A Ion barrel churn w used to emulsif hurniiiL ;l, and a churning from four I ag but would hi enough to last whi It was found n- instead of three as th x the lower por cent it Gtaoup III — Eigh: BtmduicofcK.r W t*-K Nam. of ski* J\unds ss 65 45 MO 320 Holstein grade 85 r- nfrnn grade 69 ssr. HoUteinFriesian. 115 3H0 Holstein grade 94 314 SS Angus grivl* no eraey . . 45 74.5 I </seg>
            <seg id="p009">4 y « "ip Grout III. GltOtTP ITT WAS FED SKIM-MILK )IL. WITH : n Group III. Wt at „., ,„ i en.l of °*i" to i ture. reriod period WT ' (tain. /A |JO| 40. (d 119 Lbs. \ Lbs t 2.49 i * .V&gt;4 7 1.42 110 . 1.77 14 1.80 180 35 ■ 2 00 28 1.97 265 43 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 d-mea i REMARKS AND CONCLUSIONS. Milts obtained in tli it not on butter fat in skim-milk for &lt;;&gt;lt i hers &lt;&gt;&lt;1 results ;ls I may In- food i oil in id requii !i work were :' tli* </seg>
            <seg id="p011">METHODS OF CONTROLLING CONTAMINATION OF MILK DURING MILKING. ' KKK AND a W. MKLJCK. ibject of public interest, and of all our ft more easily contaminated. Nebraska of grading cram bj the acid added interest in preventing the product miniating bad flavors. oation takes place largely during the pi rial I v when tlu ire kept in the barn. liought best to start with investigations and iiH«st troublesome source of infection, speriment was to test a number of advo - ling milk contamination. To do this. cted from the University dairy herd, all u in sv eight, and time of lactation, so as to is much ile, variation among individual ani- ere rated before each milking in the follow r:&gt;lcr of cow No. 1, Diana, was sponged with water, udder &lt;&gt;: Annie, was sjnmged with a five per of carbolic acid. The udder of cow llat- i rubbed with vaseline. The udder of cow N lot treated, but the dust merely brushed off with milkers hand as in the usual way. 1 both in the barn and out-of doors. to compare cement and wood - with and without bedding. Exposures were also made in the barn, both when the cows were present and when they fmine the condition of the air. In all, two hundred plates were exposed, developed, and ex - amined for bacteria with the microscope. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 lioli The exposures wire madu on sterile \- cast - extn ri &lt;1 made case, iu which the barn. Fio. 4.— Method of exposing p Fig. 4 illustrates the method of niakii milker simply going through the in f mi extracting any milk, to avoid danger of spla drops on tbe plate. The Rgar medium covering the bottom of th( was made in the following wa\ &lt;U the dishes </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 it a temperature of 3 . rams of agar was added to grams salt, five grains beef ex- ed water. This mixture was F. for three consecutive minatiog from spores which the plates were allowed to re sity bacteriological laboratory for twenty - rature of 7&lt;i- i\. after which they incubator and developed for twenty four This was to give the different Bpecii •rable temperature varied a chance to de- were thus treated, the colonies were nd the predominating specie* deter- lensed tables made by averaging one mder the methods named : ■jposurcs made in barn h of the treatments. Colonies er udders treated with 5 per cent 344 r udders treated wnth vaseline. . . . 346 " water ... 483 nut treated (see fig. 5) x 20500 II. — Shcncinq s between cement and board h and tcithout bedding, cows present and absent. Colonies tea exposed on cement floor, cowg present, bedding present 120 Dishes exposed on board floor, cowb present, bedding present 272 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Controlling C. a I fishes * presi Inildinj: iilis. ! IMsIh bedding . ' Tib. 5— Shows a plate exposed one half mi&gt;tte cn COW'S UDDER TREATED BY HER haitd. Each op the i.itti e spots represents a col ONT OP SOUS EJXD OF BICTUU. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 KMAKKrf four ' unent, in Table I .-(I with the five per cent solu- 38 "iitamination than by any The vaseline treatment was about the while tin- sponging with water glit TR EXPOSED ONE-HALF MINCTE tJNDER BATED WITH N OF CAR - IMAL \T FLOOR WHEN vi. It w: . :-:d this plate ib NT OVBR PLATE SHOWN IN FIG. 5. untreated udders are in striking contrast to those 1. Many of the petri dishes were so covered as to ren- _' impossible, but the average of those counted nty thousand In the comparison of cement and board floore (Table II) til be seen that cement flours showed less than half the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">jr, rwere taken in i of limply tell the condition of tl When as might be The open air mil k i t suits than tIt - tion being even bettej than the tr While in d less, (be quality of the mill quality was injured by The records obtained i r desired comparw average, for in al nnii tllO ct'lJilr* U I'll L . 1 1 i i III! </seg>
            <seg id="p017">i f i IT ii the foregoing ex{&gt;eriinent that tilk contamination daring milk- niitl's llank anil udder ; improvement can be made on the gallon, which is The only objections to this method •r and the bother of mixing. - - about the same as the carbolic acid and •ventive for chapped or sore teats. It is ■tided for cows with short teats which uilked by the stripping method. This treatment when tin- cows have dirty iiddi itinent is to be recommended for genera - cheaper and does the work well. This method can be used on any farm no inconvenience and the results obi. sate for the extra time required. not only easier to keep clean, but are jrowth and developmen bedding in winter, in summer kept in the barn only during milking • I with to the bettermei in clean yards or pasture jjives bet than in clean barns, even under the best of con- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">AVAILABLE BULLETINS. The following bulletins of the Station may be had on request: No. 25, DeUsseling Corn. No. 27, Experiments In the Culture of i No. 29, Cost of Farm Crops. No. JO, The Influence of Changes of Food and Temperature on th.- Quan tity and Quality of the Milk of Dairy Cows No. 32, Wheat and Some of Its Prodi. No. 33. Meteorological Obser No. 38, Nebraska and the B r Industry Report of Dr. Max Hollrung Translated from "Zen Verelns fuer No. 40, A Preliminar No. 44, Experiments No. 46, The Rainfall of !&gt; No. 48, Windbreaks. No. 49, Suggestions for i No. 60, Notes on Pruning. No. 61, Observations on the I :2, Cornstalk Disease. No. 53, A Preliminary Repor .4, The Effect of Ce Crop. No. 65, Ornamental No. 66, Methods of No. 58. Annual Forar No. 60, Experiments in No. 70, Locusts or Gra? No. 71, Sheep Feeding Experiments !n menL) No. 72, The Adaptation and Improven No. 73, Experiments In the Culture of the Sugar H&lt; • No. 76, Experiments with Dairy Herd. No! 77, Poisoning of Cattle by Common Sorghum and No. 78, Macaroni Wheats. No 79. Experiments In Orchard Culture No. 80, Experiments in Mulching Garden Vegeta No. 81, Experiments In the Culture of the S No. 82, Kherson Oats. No. 83, CooperatiTe Variety Tests of Corn li No. 84, Pasture, Meadow, and Forage Crops. No. 85. Feeding Experiments with Cattle No. 86. Destroying Prairie Dogs. Press Bulletin No. 19, The Hessian Fly Press Bulletin No. 20. Fattening Pi:- Alfalfa and a Grain Ration Address AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>