<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00006">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00006</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>Report of Sixth Annual Meeting of the Nebraska Conference of Charities and Corrections For 1902.</title>
			            <date value="1902">1902</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-16</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-13</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-07</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p003">I 


NEBRASKA 

State Board 

OF 

Charities and Corrections. 

GOVERNOR E. P. SAVAGE, - - Chairman. 

Wii. K. FOWLER, .... State Sup't. 

G. D. FOLLMER, - - - Land Commissioner. 

JOHN DAVIS, - Clerk 

Advisory Secretaries. 

A. W. CLARK, Omaha 

J. W. SEABROOK, ... University Place 

JOSEPH RUESING, - - - West Point 

Mrs. E. C. JOHNSTON, .... Lincoln 

For information address John Davis, State House, Room 8 

Lincoln, Nebraska. 

—3— </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
5 

OFFICKRS OF 

State Conference 

OF 

Charities and Corrections 

FOR THE YEAR 19O2. 

President - - - A. W. CLARK - Omaha, 

Vice President - MRS. A. M. EDWARDS - Fremont 

Secretary 

JOHN DAVIS 

Lincoln, 

Enrolling Secretary, MRS. J. E. ARMSTRONG, Beatrice 

Treasurer 

C. E. PREVEY 

Lincoln 

K( Chancellor E. Benjamin Andrews. 
ecotive Committee ¦{ Governor E. P. Savage, 
f Dr. J. V. Bejjhtol. </seg>


            <seg id="p007">
NAME AND LOCATION OF 

State Institutions 

AND SUPERINTENDENTS IN CHARGE. 

NEBRASKA HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE— LINCOLN 

Dr. J. L. Greene. 

INSANE ASYLUM AT NORFOLK 

Dr. F. F. Teai 

ASYLUM FOR THE INCURABLE INSANE— HASTINGS 

Dr. W. B. Kern 

NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME— GRAND 

ISLAND 

Colonel A. V. Cole. 

SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME— MILFORD 

Colonel Charles Penx 

HOME FOR THE FRIENDLESS— LINCOLN 

Sarah B. Sohus 

STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL— KEARNEY 

Dr. J. V. Beghtol 

GIRLS' INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL-GENEVA 

H. M. Clark. 

NEBRASKA INDUSTRIAL HOME— MILFORD 

Margaret Kealy. 

STATE PENITENTIARY— LINCOLN 

E. D. Davis. 

NEBRASKA INSTITUTION FOR FEEBLE-MINDED YOUTH 

BEATRICE 

Dr. A. Johnson. 

INSTITUTE FOR THE DEAF AND DUMB— OMAHA 

R. E. Stewart. 

INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND— NEBRASKA CITY 

J. F. Morey. </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
HISTORY 

OF 

rBRASKA CONFERENCE OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 


EA brief history of the Nebraska Conference of Charities and 
rections leading to the passage of a law creating a State Board of 
.rities and Corrections. 

tRev. A. W. Clark of Omaha was the first one at work enlisting 
ng others Governor Silas A. Holcomb and Chancellor McLane of 
State University. 

kThe first Conference was held in the University Chapel, Febry 
10th, 1897. Among other speakers— H. H. Hart, General Secret 
of the National Conference addressed the meeting. 

meeting resulted in the formation of a permanent organ iza, 
with the following officers: 

President, Governor Silas A. Holcomb. 
Vice President, Prof. J. A. Gillispie. 
Secretarv, Rev. A. W. Clark. 
Recording Secretary, Mrs. Burwell Spurlock. 
Treasurer, J. P. Hebard. 

Mrs. E. H. Leavett. 

Executive Committee J Chancellor G. E. McLane. 

] Silas A. Holcomb. 
[A. W. Clark. 

t Since this first meeting there have been held five meetings, 
h except the last two being held in the University Chapel. The 
in 1901 was held in Omaha and the last on February 1902 la 
trice. 

kMr. Clark has been the Secretary of the Society since its organon 
until the last meeting when John Davis, Secretarv of the Slate 
¦d of Charities and Corrections was elected. 

I At the third annual meeting held in February 1899, as a result 
addresses and discussions, a bill was formulated and presented to 
: legislature seeking to create a State Board of Charities and Correc- 

At this meeting Chancellor McLane was elected President 
and Rev. L. P. Ludden, Treasurer. 

tA change in the Chancellorship of the State University, brought 
¦ midst Dr. E. Benjamin Andrews. He has given to the work a 
inspiration. Has entered into all its plans with hearty enthus- 

-9— </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
10 

iasm and with his experience in similar work has been able to do much 
more good than another having the same desire but less ability could 
have done. 

The conference has from time to time been very fortunate in 
securing speakers. The General Secretary H. H. Hart being with us 
the second time in 1901. </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
MINUTES 

OK 

rTH ANNUAL MEETING OF NEBRASKA CONFERENCE 
OF CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 

The sixth annual meeting of the State Conference of Charities 
and Corrections was held at Beatrice, February, 6th and 7th, 1902. 
The opening session was held in the Methodist Church in the afternoon, 
beginning at 2 o'clock. Chancellor E. B. Andrews of the State 
University President of the Conference, called the meeting to order 
and introduced Mayor Norcross of Beatrice, who delivered a splendid 
address of welcome. In this address, he discussed the nature and 
importance of charity work and emphasized the necessity of training 
children to be self-supporting in order to prevent an increase in the 
number of delinquents and dependents. He also mentioned some of the 
work now being carried on in the vicinity of Beatrice. 

Rev. W. H. Kearns, pastor of the Presbyterian Church of Beatrice, 
was then introduced and delivered an address of welcome as the 
representative of the ministerial organization ot the city. Mr. Kearns 
gave a historical review of charity, showing that the spirit of Christianity 
was the main spring of action and that Christ was the author and 
founder of all movements in charitable work. 

These earnest addresses of welcome were responded to by 
Chancellor E. B. Andrews. (See address page 16) 

"The Administration of County Charities" was the subject of 
an excellent paper presented by Hon. Geo. A. Murphy of Beatrice. He 
advocated that county charities should be administered directly in 
accordance with principals of justice. He believed that where relatives 
were able to pay part or all the expenses of keeping that this should be 
required. Attention was called to the fact that Nebraska laws made 
wise and liberal provision for county asylums. The laws of other 
states were compared with the laws of Nebraska. 

"Jails and Lockups" was the subject of a splendid address 
presented by Mr. Hoagland, Chief of Police of Lincoln. He emphasiied 
that public sentiment must be educated in regard to proper management 
of jails. 

tHe regretted that the condition of American jails was most unsfactory. 
Managers of these jails generally do the best they can but 
buildings are so constructed that the proper classification in most 
;s is impossible. Often the innocent are locked up awaiting trial, and 

—11— </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
associated with vile criminals. It often happens that in some cases 
that witnesses are thus locked up in order to hold them until the day of 
trial. A vigorous discussion followed which was engaged in by quite a 
number who thoroughly sympathized with the sentiments expressed by 
Chief Hoagland. 

Thursday evening the session was held in the Methodist 
Church when the exercises were opened by music by part of the choir 
and prayer was offered by Rev. J. \V. Merrill, Pastor of the Baptist 
Church. After another piece of music by the choir, the address of the 
evening was given by the President of the Conference, Chancellor E. B. 
Andrews, who spoke on the subject of the "Future of Charities and Corrections." 
Reference was made to the creation of the State Board of 
Charities by the recent legislature. This marks a new era in the progress 
of charity and reform measures in the state. In looking at the 
future, several things present themselves to us which must be accomplished. 


1. — Dissemination of interest in charity work among all the 
people throughout the state. 

2. — To rationalize charity. 

3. — To rationalize the whole business of correctional work. 

4. — To reform our charitable and penal institution laws. 

5. — To bring about conditions which shall tend to diminish 
poverty and crime throughout the state. After discussing exhaustively 
these important points, the Chancellor asked the question 
— "What is likely to be the outcome in the far future as to our work for 
charity and correction? In answer to this question, he ventured to 

1. — That all true work for morality and religion is always profoundly 
efficient. He believed that social and economic changes will 
certainly take place whi;h in the future will greatly lessen crime, 
though he was inclined to believe that for some years past crime had 
been upon the increase in the United States. 

2.— That a better standard of life is coming and that this will 
elp to solve the problems before us. The standard of life as held by 
'hinamen in San Francisco who live in rat holes was compared with 
he standard of life as held by our best citizens. The standard of life 
which was expressed in charitable and correctional institutions some 
ears ago was compared with the standard of the present. This 
nspires hope for the future. There will come a time when no able 
bodied poor will be idle. All will be willing to work and there will be 
work for all. 

t After the appointment of the nominating committee, consisting 
Chief Hoagland, Mr. Murphy and Mrs. A. Johnson, the meeting 
journed, the choir leading in the singing of "America." 

The Conference met Friday morning at the Institution for 

Feeble-Minded Youth. In the absence of the President and Vice Presi- 

—12— </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
13 

dent, the meeting was called to order by the Secretary, and Chief Hoagand 
of Lincoln was elected President pro tern. The first upon the program 
was a song by Miss Francis Atwater, after which an address of 
welcome was delivered by Dr. A. Johnson, the superintendent of the 
nstitution. This was an able paper discussing the problems involved 
n the care of feeble-minded youth and in it a most cordial welcome 
was extended to all the delegates and visitors. 

This was followed by a paper presented by John T. Mallalieu, 
Superintendent of the Industrial School for Boys at Kearney, on the 
ubject, "The Aims, Methods and General Features of Juvenile Trainng." 
He emphasized that the aims now are really reformatory. The 
old custom of half starving the inmates of such institutions has been 
lone away with. As to the methods employed, he emphasized that they 
were modern and that they involved moral training as well as intellectual 
and aesthetic training. He also emphasized the great importance 
of physical development as the means of reformation. The proposiion 
was layed down that reform schools do reform and the history of 
many cases was given to show that in Nebraska this has been true. 
le believed that 70 to 80 per cent of the inmates at Kearney and 
Geneva had been greatly helped. This was followed by an earnest 
iscussion entered into by Superintendent Clark of the Industrial 
School for Girls at Geneva, Rev. J. W. Seabrook, former Superintenent 
at Geneva and by others. 

Prof. Bolton of the State University at Lincoln then discussed 
the following subject, "The Classification of State Wards." The 
arly idea of insane, feeble-minded and criminals, and others, was that 
ley were possessed of evil spirits or devils. On this account they 
were horribly treated, were shut up in dark places of confinement and 
erribly neglected and abused with the idea that the sooner they were 
out of existence the better it would be for society. The beginning of 
le last century marks the beginning of improvement in the conditions, 
ue largely to the efforts of Pinal and Esquirol. Professor Bolton 
rgued that all persons who are drawn into jail even for a short 
&gt;eriod of time ought to be made to work, not as a punishment but as 
reformatory measure. The universal conception prevailing throughout 
America is that such work would be a punishment. This is a false 
conception. He showed the necessity of securing data as to the history of 
amilies that furnish delinquents and dependents in our state and 
bowed the necessity of careful study in order to draw the lines beween 
a feeble-minded and a criminal and also emphasized the diffiulties 
in such study. His excellent address which was greatly apireciateU 
by all was followed by an earnest discussion at the close of 
which the following resolution was presented and adopted. 

k Resolved: — That we are in favor of the establishment of a 
oratory in the Department of the Interior at Washington, for the 
lection and study of psychological sociology and abnormal data. </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
14 

Eially as found in institutions for the criminal, pauper and dee 
classes and in hospitals and also as may be observed in schools 
other institutions and also among- tramps and other classes outof 
all institutions. 

An invitation presented by the superintendent of the institution 
for all the delegates and visitors to file to the dining room was accepted 
and the meeting adjourned to convene in the chapel at 2 o'clock. 
The afternoon session was opened in the chapel of the institution by 
Supt. A. Johnson, when the following program was rendered by inmates 
of the institution. 

These exercises upon the part of the children were greatly enoyed 
by delegates and visitors and to many it was a revelation beause 
they had not believed it possible for such high degree of training 
be realized in such an institution. At the close of the exercises, adournment 
was taken to the rooms below when the regular program of 
he Conference was taken up. A paper by Dr. C. G. Sprague of 
maha on "The Care of the Feeble-Minded" was presented. This 
&gt;aper seemed to be in opposition to the school system conducted in this 
nstitution and other institutions for the care of the feeble-minded. He 
believed that the teaching of reading and other school branches was of 
cry little or no value. He emphasized the importance of industrial 
raining and farm work. The paper was followed by a sharp discusion 
and all present seemed to be opposed to the sentiments expressed 
n the paper and to be thoroughly in sympathy with the school work 
now in vogue. A very practical paper and discussion on the subject 
was presented by Mrs. Armstrong who is in charge of the school de 
artment of the institution. She emphasized the great value of kinder 
arten training and showed that the school training in the various de 
artments was absolutely necessary in order to successful manua 
raining and industrial training and efficient work on the farm. 

bThe closing paper of the afternoon session was on the subject of 
nsanitary Marriages" by Dr. Powell, Superintendent of the Instiion 
for Feeble-Minded Youth at Glenwood, Iowa. He believed that 

fG - - - Happy School Day» - - Chorus Class, 
iitation - - Welcome - - - - G. P. 
hem - - Sing Unto the Lord - - Glee Club. 
The Lord's Praver 

Calisthenic Drill and Motion Song, Primary Class. 

Recitation - Our Little Boy Blue - - Bessie S. 

Recitation - Ambitions - - Five Children. 

Emb Bell Drill - ... Fourth Grade, 
.dad - Sing Me a Song of the South - W. H. H. R. 
:itation - - At the Circus - - - - C. W. 
.o and Chorus - Anchored - - Glee Club </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 

ton the rights of the state to restrict marriages. Many cases in 
a were cited to show the necessity for such restriction. He did not 
eve that legislators were prepared to determine at present what the 
s should be regulating and restricting marriages but believed that 
missioners should be appointed by every legislature to thoroughly 
¦stigate and decide upon what measures would be for the best interof 
society. The Conference then adjourned that delegates and viss 
might inspect the institution and grounds. 

[The closing session of the Conference was held in the evening 
the Methodist Church. After the opening exercises of music and 
lyer, Mrs. Geo. A. Tilden of Omaha, presented a paper on "Juven- 
Courts" which was followed by a brief discussion. The next on the 
igram was a paper on the subject of "Scientific Charity as Applied 
Smaller Cities and Towns" by Prof. C. E. Prevey of Lincoln. 

The closing address of the evening was by Dr. J. L. Greene on 
"The Causes of the Rapid Increase of Insanity in Recent Modern 
Times." The election of officers of the Conference for the following 
year resulted as follows: President, A. W. Clark, Omaha; Vice President, 
Mrs. A. M. Edwards, Fremont; Secretary, John Davis, Lincoln; 
Enrolling Secretary, Mrs. J. E. Armstrong, Beatrice; Treasurer, 
C. E. Prevey, Lincoln. 

The attendence was the best in the history of the Conference 
and the interest manifested was greater than it had ever been before. 
A vote of thanks was given to Dr. Johnson, Superintendent of the 
Institution for Feeble-Minded Youth and to others associated with 
him on the local committee of entertainment. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
16 

THE FUTURE &lt; OP CHARITIES AND CORRECTIONS. 

ring Address by the (President, Chancellor E. t B. 
Andrews of the University of Nebraska. 

HE state and all citizens interested in the welfare of the defective 
classes are to be congratulated on the establishment 
of a State Board of Charities and Corrections. This conference, 
being the first that has gathered since the new 
law was passed, marks an epoch in the history of charity 
and correction work in Nebraska. 

The immediate business of charities and correction 
in this state is important. Until now the public and the Goternor 
had no trustworthy or responsible advisors touching 
the important matters which this conference and the new 
board are endeavoring to work out. If there were abuses, 
and such are always occurring even in the best ordered 

tates, there was no means of ascertaining them, and there was no 
&gt;roper agency for correcting such abuses as might in one way or another 
become known. No method offered itself for effecting reforms 
hat were known to be necessary or for assisting with light and guidance 
well-meaning functionaries conscious of their ignorance or inexterience. 
The existence of a regular organization for this and similar 
urposes is therefore a fact worthy of public notice. We gather at 
his time in part to celebrate the new order. 

The work which is immediately before us may be summed up 
as follows: 

1. To disseminate and intensify interest in charity and correction, 
aims and methods. 

2. To rationalize charity, seeing to it that only those receive 
harity who deserve it and will be benefited by it, that the public is 
not duped by pretending and vagrant applicants sturdy and able to 
work, seeing to it that there is as little as possible overlapping in 
harities, several agencies contributing to an end where one wouk 
uffice and that, on the other hand, no deserving poor or needy persons 
are overlooked. 

3. To rationalize penalty, taking the idea of retribution or 
vengeance entirely out of it. 

T 
I </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
17 

to the above advanced ideas. 

15. So far as we can to give such a healthful bent and trend 
the economic system and to man's whole moral and civic life that 
¦er will tend to poverty and crime than now do. 

tit is not my purpose this evening to exhibit these elements of 
pressing task, but rather to look futher into the future. I raise the 
stion whether the need for charity and correction is likely to 
permanent. Many seem to think not. They so intensely believe in 
progressive amelioration of society that they expect all need of 
irity and all such thing's as prison discipline to pass away. Many 
ak as if this consummation would probably occur within com•atively 
few years. How far is such expectation justified? 

Great amelioration both in charities and in correction may be 
looked for. Were it otherwise one might be excused for despair. 
There is every reason for large hope. Take it first in the matter of correction. 
We must not be discouraged by the increase of crime in the 
United States at present. Whatever the causes of this increase, there 
is good ground for believing that a reverse tendency will set in before 

This conviction is based, first, on the growth of moral ideas 
and restraints of the usual order. 

t Second, the better economic conditions, it being well estabd 
that much crime and much vagabondage is due to poverty and 
of work whether permanent or temporary. 

Third, to the rise through education of man's standard of living, 
s latter is the great source of hope. 

It is an error, however, to imagine that improvements from 
these sources will realize the anarchist's dream, according to which all 
coercive government, hence of course all civil discipline, like fines and 
imprisonment, will utterly pass away. The necessity for a coercive 
power somewhere in society is a permanent one. The necessity for 
coercion does not arise wholly from man's wickedness, which, we hope, 
will largely, if not wholly, pass away, but in great part also from 
man's finiteness. Some of the worst dead locks ever occurring arise 
among men of the most perfect honesty and integrity. They fight each 
other hard because each is sure that he is right. So far as can be seen 
society will always need to reserve the right to insist with force, if 
necessary that such people go about their business. 

Is it not the same with reference to charities? The identical 
considerations touched above support the expectation that charity to the 
able-bodied poor may wholly pass away. Work will offer itself for all 
who are able to work, and every one able to work will wish to work. 
Sturdy beggars will disappear as also frauds and thievery. 

1 There is also reason to anticipate vast diminution in the number 
defectives. The deaf, the blind and mute and deformed, the feeble - </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
Ei on the one hand and to the maladministration of industry on the 
When these causes pass away the painful results enumerated 
(jo with them. 

tBut alas there is one source of defective population which must 
ver remain. It is accident and illness springing therefrom. Let 
morals of society improve ever so much, so long as men live in a 
Id like this, bodies may be crushed by falling rocks or trees, peostruck 
by lightning, systems invaded by deadly bacteria, and 
mings through railway accident and many other such misfortunes 
r occur. 

It is obvious, therefore, first, that boards and conferences like 
ours will forever be needed and will forever have more or less work to 
do. It is clear from our review, secondly, that our work is hopeful as 
for an indefinite time at any rate more and more victory will attend it, 
less and less remaining undone of what ought to be done. 

—18— </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
19 

ADDRESS OF WELCOME. 

rfor. A. Johnson, Superintendent of Nebraska In~ 
stitution for Feeble-Minded, (Beatrice. 

T IS with a great deal of pleasure that I, on behalf of the 
management of this institution, bid you all a hearty welcome 
and hope that the words of the well known hymn 

"This is the Place We Long Have Sought" may fitly apply 
to all here. When the advisory board visited this institution 
some time ago and we talked over the plans of holding 
this meeting in the city of Beatrice and at least one session 
at this institution, I was heartily in sympathy with the 
plan for I believed that much good would come to the institution 
by reason of you visiting with us, seeing our work 
and thus becoming better acquainted with our methods of 
taking care of and instructing our unfortunate children, for 

my limited experience in this work has taught me and the 

t&gt;ple that have visited our institution and those that I have talked to 
regard toiit, have demonstrated to me that our work is comparatively 
:le known even to those living in our own city and immediate vicinity. 

Not only did I believe this but I also believed that all of you 
ho are with us today would be benefited by your visit to our instituon. 
You will here see the different types of individuals; the physical 
as well as mental defects of our children will be brought to your attenon 
and I am quite sure that alter you have seen all of this, your symathy 
will be with us, that you will always remember our work as 
wing done not only for what financial benefits may be derived 
rom it but as the work done for the welfare of suffering humanity and 
te uplifting and enlightening ot those weak in mind and body but still 
uman beings and perhaps in the sight of God Almighty, more thought 
than many with a strong mind and body. When we stop to consider 
le fact that most of our unfortunate children have inherited this condion 
from their father or mother or perhaps both, they are to be all the 
more pitied for they are in no ways responsible for this condition themselves. 


may be that the heads of all of our state institutions consider 
or her institution as the most important but be this as it may, it </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
20 

Painly seems to me that there can be no institution of greater impore 
than this one. Ours is not an institution for mad people but a 
&gt;ol where feeble-minded boys and girls might be kindly dealt with 
carefully and skillfully taught and trained. 

To Christain charity, every stricken one is a creditor to whom 
he has a debt to pay, the debt of service. One of the saints of the 
ncient church once being taunted with the poverty of his community 
reduced the cripple, the sick, and suffering of that church and said: 
These are our treasures." I am afraid the church in our day does not 
so consider the sick, or feeble-minded and her epileptics, and still had 
not been for the fact that some broad-minded people of our own state 
ad worked up an interest for these unfortunate ones that we have here, 
his institution would not have been established. 

Have you, my friends, any idea of how many of our fellow creares 
are suffering from that terrible disease, epilepsy? It is difficult 
get at reliable statistics, for epilepsy is one of the sorrowful afflicons 
of mankind which both the sufferer and their friends endeavor to 
de. After carefully looking through the statistics at hand I have 
rrived at the conclusion that l&gt;i to 2 per thousand is probably within 
e mark. Iu reading through the reports from the various feebleinded 
institutions of our country, I find that from 20 to 25 per cent of 
11 the inmates are epileptics and amongst our own children I find that 
ully 20 per cent are epileptics. This fearful affliction is not a new 
lsease. It was known to the ancients and was probably as frequent 
len as now. We learn from the new testament and other sources that 
s terrors abounded in the time of our Lord. Now, the question arises 
hat is to be done with all of these unfortunates? Many of them while 
large are shunned by their own family. They are hidden away. 
n the poorer classes of society where they ought to gain a livelihood, 
ho will employ them? The work shop, the office are closed to them, 
le church even, once they have had a seisure there, tells them not to 
eturn again. He is condemned to starvation, mental, moral, spiritual. 
oone will have him anywhere. In reading over the literature on thi« 
ubject, I came across a case so striking that I will ask your permison 
to quote it in full: "I am a cripple, 25 years of age and since my 
urteenth year have suffered from epileptic fits. The first overtook me 
ust after I had been apprenticed. I was dismissed from the work shop 
nd though I tried and tried again anxious to learn a trade, no master 
ould keep me. I tried work at home but it was almost impossible 
because of the constant attacks. My parents are very poor and never 
could pay any one to look after me. They are both at work which 
akes them from home daily. Thus, I have been in constant danger of 
fe and limb with the .result of several severe accidents. I have 
earned to do a little fret work and was rising from that occuation 
one day to sweep away the cuttings. There was a healed stove 
the kitchen and on it a kettle of boiling water. I ought not to have </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
gone so near for I bad a fit, fell unconscious and lay on the stove, the 
boiling water pouring over me. In this state, terribly burnt, I warn 
picked up some time after and taken to the infirmary. Thirteen months 
I lay there, my right arm having been amputated and I came away a 
cripple. The parish has allowed me half a crown a week. I am not 
therefore starving but what I need more than bread, is a friend to 
watch over me. And I pray you earnestly, receive me in your home." 
So far the quotation. 

It seems to me that this one unfortunate being has told us what 
to do with our epileptics, namely receive them into our home, into this 
our institution for it is a home to all of our children that are here. 
Here they are tenderly cared for, watched over and receive the very 
best of medical treatment that is known to our noble profession. 

All of our children appreciate what is being done for them, and 
re truly thankful for this good home. It goes to one's heart to hear 
lem sing their favorite songs. When the Lord shall relieve the bound 
nes we shall be like them that dream. Then our mouths shall be filled 
with laughter and our tongues with singing, for the Lord hath done 
great things for which we are glad. Since I have been at the head of 
lis institution, just one year, we have had Sunday afternoon service 
t 3:30 p. m. The members of the Beatrice Ministerial Union have 
indly taken turns in coming out and talking to our children and this 
without any pay and I now before this meeting do most heartily thank 
hem for the many pleasant and encouraging things they have told us. 
Many of them, yes, I may say all ministers have been highly pleased 
with the way our children behaved and especially have they been pleased 
with their singing and I believe that even the ministers have been beneited 
by being with us for in my estimation there is nothing that will so 
ouch the tender cords of one's heart as to hear our children sing their 
avorite songs. 

I am glad this institution has as many friends as it has but we 
need a great many more, and as our work becomes known, I am sure 
our friends will increase for it is evident that much is owing to our 
riends for the success of the movements, for the ameliorating the condiion 
of the feeble-minded. But long before the friends took up this quesion, 
the immortal John Bunyan had put out all of his strength to bring 
before them the picture of the feeble-minded in his own day. He was 
ery happy in his title. There was not only little faith and faint heart 
but there was also Mr. Feeble-minded who described himself as a 
sickly man as you see and because Death did usually once a day knock 
at my door, I thought I could never be well at home. I am a man of no 
strength at all of body nor yet of mind but would if I could, though I 
can but crawl, spend my life in the pilgrim's way. When the Master 
called him, he sent for his friends and said: "Since I have nothing to 
bequeath to any to what purpose should I make a will as for my feeble 
mind, that I will leave behind for that I shall have no need of in the 

—21— </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
22 

place whithei I go. nor is it worth bestowing upon the poorest pilgrim. 
Wherefore when I am gone I desire that you, my valient, would bury it 
in the dung hill." His last words were, "Hold out faith and patience," 
and so he went over to the other side. In this immortal description, we 
might see a record of the work that we are seeking to accomplish. 
Our aim is to care for their body, their minds and their souls. Their 
bodies are developed, their minds are to be enlightened and their moral 
faculties quickened. Those of you that help our institution are helping 
to carry the feeble-minded up the hill of difficulty and to so train them 
that through the faithful spirit of God's grace, when they come to the 
river and hear the call, it will not be a call as though they were 
unworthy but would be a call from the Master Himself. 

Ladies and gentlemen, again I bid you all a hearty welcome. </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
23 

GENERAL FEATURES OF REEORMATORY WORK. 

'By John T. Mallalieu, Superintendent Industrial 

HE rapid and wonderful development in the material 
resources of our country, in the arts, sciences and literature, 
has scarcely been more marvelous than the advancement 
made in behalf of unfortunate humanity or the growth 
of public sentiment in connection therewith. Until within 
recent years this work was confined principally to individual 
benevolence rather than organized assistance. Voluntary 
organizations succeeded individual efforts and there 
are many noble examples 01 men and women who sacrificed 
their time and means in order that this charitable and corrective 
work might be promoted through these societies in 
communities, municipalities and states. Under these volun- 

tary associations the work grew and spread in spite of selfish opposition 
and keen discouragements. The great problem of advancing and 
promoting the welfare of the defective, delinquent and dependent 
classes could not be solved alone by voluntary organizations; hence 
statutory provisions have been made in many states for the maintenance 
of state organizations and in accordance with the provisions thereof 
we have had the satisfaction of seeing the work pushed forward 
with vigorous success. Through the agency of these voluntary and 
state organizations, representatives of societies and institutions have 
been brought together at stated periods and a wonderful impetus has 
thus been given to each and tvery department of charitable and corrective 
work. The institutions have been strengthened; men and women 
have formed broader conceptions of their responsibilities; public sentiment 
has been educated to a higher degree concerning its obi igations to 
humanity, public officials and legislative bodies have felt the power of 
these organizations because they have been characterized by honesty 
of purpose and a determined energy to make known their objects and 
desires in no uncertain language. The platform of the associated 
charities is broad and comprehensive; its mission is humane, noble, 
unending and universal; it is here that all sects, creeds, nationalities 
and parties can meet upon an equality and part in mutual friendship. 

School for (Boys, Kearney. </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 

¦migrant, the tramp, the feeble-minded and the infirm — all are objects 
of their most serious consideration, earnest study and practical philanthropy. 
These men and women inspired by a noble, lofty and Godlike 
purpose are devoting their time and talents— for what? That the 
pathway of fallen humanity may be made cheerful ; that the institutions 
for the insane and feeble-minded may be made more comfortable and 
that the patients may have the very best of attention; that the jail system 
may be freed from the contaminating influences and impure association 
that has characterized its past history; that the penitentiaries 
may be better arranged and the physical and sanitary condition of the 
convicts may be improved; that the reformatories may be more practical 
and better fit boys for usefulness when they return to active life; 
that all the subdivisions of this great charitable, reformatory and penal 
work may be elevated and improved. 

While admiring the progress made and the great good accomplished 
through the instrumentality of all the other ennobling agencies. 
I am impelled on this occasion to give some idea of the general features 
of the training of juvenile delinquents. We look with just pride upon 
the grand and practical unfolding of our systems. We revert to the 
days of the old "workus" and prison methods of dealing with boys and 
girls, and view with awe the little "Oliver Twists" writhing and suffering 
in their loathsome dungeons; and from this scene we turn to the 
industrial schools of the present day and behold a contrast as great as 
that between the darkest night and the brightest noonday. During all 
these years the amelioration of the condition of these youthful outcasts 
and criminals has been pushed forward with amazing rapidity. 
Changes and improvements for their benefit have been going on at a 
constantly increasing ratio. From the English "Workus" have been 
evolved, through successive stages, the modern industrial schools of our 
country with their many conveniences for comfort and the advantages 
for improving the individual. In place of rickety, dingy buildings in 
some obscure quarters, where boys and girls were stored, for the purpose 
of getting them out of public view instead of ameliorating their 
condition, the modern schools are characterized for the architectural 
beauty of their buildings, convenience of arrangements, sightly and 
healthy locations, environed by verdant lawns, and adorned with 
flowers, shrubbery and trees. Large playgrounds greet the eye of the 
new arrival and the happy voices of the children at play cheer him and 
give him to realize that he is entering a home and not a prison. The 
tattered garments which seemed simply to cover the person in the 
earlier institutions rather than protect him from cold, have given place 
to neat-fitting, warm and attractive uniforms. The beds of straw on 
the rough, hard floor in an obscure corner, have been replaced with 
tidy cots, warm bedding and good mattresses. Instead of one small 
porringer of gruel repeated each meal, day after day, and one onion </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
25 

¦2S 

the parochial board visited the "Workus" on holiday occasions, at 
which time two and a quarter ounces of bread were given as a luxury,) 
instead of this weal gruel diet, the tables of the modern reformatories 
are supplied with such wholesome food as characterizes a good country 
home. The parsimonious and heartless overseer who believed that a 
tth could subsist on the "smallest possible portion of the weakest 
sible food," and demonstrated his theory at a mortality rate of eight 
out of every ten cases, has been relegated to obscurity and the practical 
humanitarian believing in bread, beef and beans as moralizing as well 
as vitalizing agencies, has taken his place. Our modern reformatories 
are not places of incarceration. They are homes of strict discipline, 
physical development, educational advancement, moral culture and 
industrial training. We do not eliminate punishment, but use it as a 
means to an end. We believe in the "beefsteak and boquet" system — 
the one as instrumental in developing the physical nature, and the other 
as inculcating principles and practices of refinement; but at the same 
time we believe that these youths must obey, kindly if they will, forcibly 
if necessary. 

The aim of our institutions then is to develop noble manhood 
and womanhood and to prepare boys and girls to go out into the world, 
take their places in society and make an honest living. The work of 
an institution is broad and varied. Its aim is high and grand. As a 
parent, it is expected to take the youth and train him. Where the 
parent has failed, the institution must begin to rebuild. It is not the 
little child, laughing and playing in its crib that is placed under the 
fostering care of the school, but the neglected youth, the vagrant, the 
incorrigible, the prostitute and the criminal. As a teacher, it must 
give its pupils a fair education. As a ministering agent, it must provide 
for his moral and religious training. As a true statesman, it 
must teach them loyalty to the state and its laws, and instruct them in 
the science of good government. As a master mechanic, it must teach 
them ch practical trades as will insure them a good livelihood. As a 
disciplinarian, it must embody all the elements of the fireside, the 
school, society and the church, and not only mould character, but 
remould many phases of it. 

While our aim is so exalted, the material upon which we have 
to work is often of a discouragingly inferior quality. The assertion so 
frequently made that the worst boys are the smartest is an eroneous one. 
It reflects unjustly on good home training. It places a premium on vice 
and a discount on virtue. Boys are smart in the line in which they 
have been trained. If this training has been of a street-Arab nature 
they are cute in the depraved slang, repartee and trickery of the street. 
When they are required to take up the substantial lines of study or work 
you will find as a general rule, they are slow to learn and dull to comprehend. 
The absence of an even and symmetrical development is plain- </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 

constant practice to undo the work of the street and place them on the 
right track. The doors of an institution swing inward to receive the 
degenerate representatives of all classes of society. Our schools are 
recruited from the homes of luxury, where indulgence has been mistaken 
for kindness and the boy, failing to have his increasing desires 
gratified, resorts to larceny in order to replenish his purse; from the 
great army of adventurous juveniles whose minds have been poisoned 
by the trash literature of the cheap novelist; from the haunts of misery, 
where criminal tendencies, following the laws of heredity, have been 
transmitted from sire to son until the penal nature of the former has 
left its impress through thephysical and moral degeneracy of the latter; 
from the homes of the inebriate, where intoxicating drinks have broken 
up family ties, extinguished filial affections, and domestic happiness 
has given place to starvation and crime; from the vile dens of iniquity 
which infest our social system and which are sapping the manhood and 
womanhood of so many of our youths of the present day. 

Many youths committed to an institution are consummate lawreakers 
and iconoclasts. The beautiful images devised around the 
ireside have fallen a prey to their destructive habits. The laws of 
home, of the school and of society as well as those of the state, have 
been set at defiance by them. Such an incongruous mass of disturbing 
nd undisciplined elements tails to our lot for correction. To teach 
iem loyalty and that the laws are made for the common good of mancind 
and therefore should be respected, is one of our imperative duties. 
o bring them to realize that although the past may have its dark pages 
lied with man}- shortcomings, yet the future may be one of usefulness, 
our mission. When penitence for the past, ambition for the future, 
ove for home, faithfulness to duty, regard for law and morality, are 
uccessfully instilled into their minds, then is the goal of an institution 
ealized. Such is the aim of our work, and such is its responsibility. 

METHODS. 

The methods by which our aims are accomplished can only be 
t forth in a general way. Institutions, like men, have a specific 
ndividuality. In the detail workings, each has its peculiarities in 
inging about certain results. It is only the general feature, 
&gt;plicable to all, that I take time to consider. An institution must 
eate and foster an interest in its pupils; engender a spirit of noble 
emulation; develop the faculties of mind, heart, phisique, and reconruct 
a tarnished character into one of honesty, nobility and worth. 
'he development of the moral, physical, educational and industrial 
acuities must go hand in hand. The completed pupil is the result of 
icse united agencies. Each faculty is an essential element of true 
anhood the same as each limb or part of the body is necessary to dis&gt;lay 
a perfect physical man. </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
27 

I The moral training is the cement which unites the characterding 
into one grand and solid structure. It should permeate e»ery 
irtment and be instilled into every duty. Living examples of its 
it influence should be embodied in everyone employed in an institu- 
Honesty, faithfulness and loyalty to its highest interests on their 
: may be more potent elements in this moral development than lecs 
and sermons. Deception in the use of means as well as materials 
disloyalty to those in authority may do more harm than can be 
gined. What if a boy should take one of us for a model! Would 
daily actions justify him in making such a selection? Assuming to 
rhat we are not and pretending to do what we do not, may cause 
to lose faith in us and confidence in humanity. Consistency is the 
:ht jewel which should be worn on every breast and engraved on 
y heart. A noble example is the shining star in the reformatory 
lem. Its effulgence may lighten many a blighted soul to honor and 
&gt;ectability. Every duty should exemplify morality. 

The playgrounds and sports are features that must not be 
overlooked or underestimated. Physical development can to a certain 
degree be accomplished through the agency of the working departments, 
but its full fruition comes through the physical exercises and 
mental relaxations which the playground affords. The interested 
teacher will superintendent these and impress his individuality upon 
them. In fact, he should be the moving spirit, the life and soul of the 
playground. This not only begets an interest, but makes the boys 
more contented and cheerful. Among such a restless, surging, active 
crowd amusements are almost as necessary as food itself. If the 
hours of recreation be crowded with sports and plays, the countenance 
will reflect the jo\ fulness of the heart during the hours set apart for 
labor and study. The football is the concomitant of the spade; the baseball 
and bat, of the rake and hoe. No one must expect a boy to work 
merrily and freely if deprived of all means of physical enjoyment. 
The hours of play should be as specific as the hours of work, and 
proper instruments should be provided in each case. A reform school 
boy should be induced to study faithfully, work diligently and play 
enthusiastically. 

LAn institution must provide proper means for giving each inte 
a fair education. The training of these youths, whose future 

uccess will be measured more by physical labor than intellectual 
ulture, should be practical and should embody a knowledge of those 
&gt;usiness forms and principals which are required in the ordinary 
ocations of life. As many committed to a school possess very meager 
or no education, the principal work of a schoolroom should be directed 
n instructing those who have thus been unfortunate in the ordinary 
branches — reading, writing, spelling and arithmetic. This must be 
done, and if the institution neglects this it becomes a usurper and 
wrongdoer. More should be done in the educational line if it can be 
</seg>

            <seg id="p028">s 

28 

municipality act the part of the wise, benevolent and discreet guardian 
and a day will come when the wards will return the favor with grateful 
hearts and willing- hands. A few wander from the path they are 
taught tn tread, the same as members of any family, for a school is 
nothing more than a large family; but the great majority will appreciate 
and profit by this training. 

One of the most important functions of an institution is the 
ndustrial training or the teaching of practical trades. Whether sup»rted 
by the state, church or municipality it is the duty of this corporate 
guardian to provide avenues and facilities for this purpose. A 
outh is taken from his home by the superior majesty of the law or the 
ctates of parental authority. He is partly secluded within the grasp 
an institution for several years, probably the most important in his 
ife. If he is too young to learn a trade he should be placed in an adanced 
kindergarten or manual training department. His mind should 
&gt;e trained in some line of industry, and as his age increases his opporunities 
should be extended. The industrial departments should be esablished 
and regulated with reference to the ability of the boy, and 
so in reference to the trades in vogue in the state. They should be such 
as would insure occupation for the inmates when paroled. It would be 
lly to have a department that could not be properly utilized by the 
K&gt;y after he leaves, but tailoring, shoe making (hand work) painting, 
arpentry, cabinet making, printing-, wood turning, blacksmithing and 
uch practical trades would be appropriate. These should be thorughly 
taught. Such trades, backed up by fair education; environed 
&gt;y a good moral training; set off by a well developed, clean, healthy 
lysique, are the grand designs and methods of reformatory instituons. 
These can all be accomplished by earnest work and proper 
acilities. 

With the qualifications resulting from these various methods, 
a boy is prepared to face the world with its exacting dealings and 
stern requirements. But the interest and watchfuluess of the institutions 
should not cease when these conditions are fulfilled. They 
should follow the boy into active life the same as a kind parent does 
his son when he leaves the parental fireside to struggle for himself. 
He needs a friend to assist him in securing a place, to look after him 
in his new and strange home and also to counsel and protect him. The 
institution must be that friend. 

RESULTS. 

Whatever may be the adverse criticism of those of a pessimistic 
or fault-finding disposition, the fact is patent that reform schools do 
reform. And what is still more encouraging, the results of the work 
become more fruitful each year. As our insitutions become better 
equipped the officers and employes gain more experience, the principle* </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
29 

beral policy is pursued by the controlling boards, the work becomes 
more efficient and the percentage of those who go out and do well is 
rrespondingly increased. Our mission is a just one and the results 
are noble and enduring notwithstanding the assertion of those indiridals 
who are generally on the wrong side of every question. It is a 
comparatively easy thing to tear down a building. Any person possessed 
of an ordinary supply of muscle can accomplish this task. It 
lowever, requires the genius of an architect and the skill of the expernced 
mechanic to properly erect a symmetrical and durable structure. 
Some persons imagine that with broad assertions they can discredit the 
ork of the reform school system. Our institutions are characteruilders 
and when their mission is properly carried out by judicious 
chool training and subsequent guardianship the results become of a 
permanent nature. It is very easy for a fault-finder to affirm that our 
laroled pupils are not what they should be. One case of an adverse 
ature is sufficient for him to unjustly judge all cases. If one boy 
rays from the path of right after his institutional career is ended you 
ill often find it a subject of local gossip and probably newspaper 
notoriety. The "I-told-you-so's" will put on a wise expression and 
roll the news as a sweet morsel under their tongue, yet there may be 
several paroled pupils in the same community, living quiet, indusious, 
manly lives. The newsmonger however, can't see them. He is 
oo busy proclaiming the demerits of the strayed one and casting reftecons 
upon the schools. In his mental make-up the exception becomes 
he rule. 

Would a reasonable man judge a whole family by the improper 
acts of an erring son? Would he judge our charitable organizations 
by some of its members who may be ostentatious charity 
workers? Would he condemn all the dicisions of a judge because 
some of his cases were overruled by a higher court? Would he 
etract from the merits of a physician because an occasional patient 
ies and say that all the patients become victims? Would he accuse all 
msiness men of dishonesty because he has found that some are not 
honest? I think no reasonable man would form such an opinion. 
Thy then pass condemnation upon our work because a small per cent 
f those paroled, whose past was vicious, go back to their old ways; 
&gt;erhaps led into old associations by lack of proper environments. 


I There is a limit to all things and reform is not an exception. 
le constant depraved training of many committed to our care, from 
rliest infancy and probably through a period of a dozen years, has 
disarranged their mental faculties that only a similar term of opsite 
training can change. Yet it is expected that a few month's deition 
is sufficient to revolutionize the individual. This reminds me 
an experience I had several years ago with a parent whose boy had </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
been in the School about fifteen months the father was very anxious to 
get him home. The Board finally directed the Superintendent to parcle 
him regardless of his standing. When the boy had been home 
a few weeks, his father wrote and expressed himself as well pleased 
with the boy's training at the School. A few months afterwards he 
addressed another letter to the maragf rrent in the following language 
"My boy has been home about six months, but he is not doing well. I 
can't manage him. I must return him and at the same time I want to 
give you a few pointers how your institution should be run in order to 
reform boys." I may have been impertinent in my reply, but I 
couldn't resist the temptation to answer him as follows: "You had 
your boy under your care for fifteen years. He came into your family 
a pure, innocent babe and remained under your training until he became 
incorrigible and guilty of petty misdemeanors. Through your 
failure to train him properly, he was sent here and we had only about 
fifteen months in which to undo fifteen years. When he returned to 
you, you acknowledged that there had been a marked change in him for 
the better. You have made another failure in managing him and now 
want to cover up your shortcomings by proceeding to dictate a policy for 
those who have given the management of this class of children years cf 
earnest study and careful consideration. Before you display your 
wonderful wisdom in giving pointers how two or three hunderd boys 
should be managed suppose you demonstrate your ability to manage one. " 
The reformatory that receives into its custody the dregs of society with 
a small sprinkling of a better element, is expected to mould every case 
into perfect symmetry — mentally, morally and physically. I believe 
that the work of any reformatory will show that not less than seTenty-fi ye 
per cent of the inmates develop into good men and wcinen and useful 
citizens. Such a record is one of which any superintendent should be 
proud and whether the public gives him credit or not, he has the higher 
reward in the inner satisfaction of knowing that he has done much 
good in the interest of humanity and is not fostering a "nursery of 

If we could only accomplish the results that some people deand 
by thoroughly reforming every case, what a miracle would be 
rought. The penological problem would soon be solved. The earth 
ould shortly become a terrestrial paradise. Ministers, charitable 
nd reformatory managers would te cut of a job. Penitentiaries and 
ails would only exist as relics of a past demoralized age. But the 
anagersof reformatories are simply mortal and can only accomplish 
esults on a human scale. They cannot eradicate entirely hereditary 
riminal traits that have been transmitted generation after generation 
ny more than a physician can effectively cure hereditary scrofula, 
'hey may benefit it, but they cannot permanently cure. We cannot 
tut sound brains where diseased ones already occupy the cranial 

—30— </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
¦pace. We can only work patiently to improve them. We can develop, 
but we cannot create. We can keep these unfortunate-born youths on 
the right track while they are under our control, but cannot insure the 
future, unless they can have the best of environments after their institutional 
life has been ended. 

Then we have to succeed in spite of legislative drawbacks. 
Means are asked of these important bodies to establish branches that 
will be instrumental in preparing the pupil for citizenship. A plan is 
outlined and placed before the proper committees aud the figures appal 
hem. They throw up their hands at the apparent ridiculousness of the 
proposition and look upon it as the embodiment of cheek and extravagance. 
Without proper facilities for teaching trades, without funds to 
&gt;roperly man and adequately compensate a competent corps of instructors 
ajid foremen, often without genuine encouragement from sources 
where most should be given, an institution is expected to accomplish 
wonderful things. And it does notwithstanding these discouraging 
eatures and the seventy- five or eighty per cent of benefited boys te»-ifies 
to this fact. If it turns out five inmates who do well and fails on the 
sixth, you will hear a cry go up from modern Sodom, as its denizens 
ook at the unfortunate sixth, "that is the work of your reform school." 
f one graduate out of twenty (and this is a large allowance) finds 
lis way to the penitentiary, public opinion does not stop to consider the 
nineteen who stay on the outside, but holds up the twentieth to public 
scorn as a sample of institutional work. 

I often wonder if these fault-finding people ever stop to consider 
hat the Savior of mankind in selecting his apostles, found eventually 
hat among the chosen few were the betrayer, the doubter and the 
enyer; that when nearly all the remainder were confronted with the 
ision and reality of Gethsemane they trembled for fear they might be 
dentificd as followers of the lowly but divine Nazarene. 

"But," says another news-monger, "the most hardened crimnals 
in the prisons are graduates of reformatories." Well, what of 
t? You do not expect that the boys who graduate with a determination 
o live proper lives are going to hunt a job behind the prison walls, do 
ou? We have among our number some mean boys from the Sabbath 
School. It does not follow that the Sabbath School has made these 
scholars bad. Our public and private schools contribute a share to the 
efonnatory population. Does this signify that the public and private 
schools are places for educating the most hardened juvenile crimials? 
ecause a youthful criminal oamm from a family it does not follow 
lat the whole family are tr.imed criminals. The discipline of the 
ome. the school and the church has not made them criminals. They 
lave become such notwithstanding such discipline. Nor has the trainng 
of the reform school made ;.iese candidates for the penitentiaries 
ardened criminals. Their institutional experience has only served as 
few month's respite between tiie prior criminal schools of the streets 

-31— </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
32 

mature scale. Instead of the implication or insinuation that the "hardened 
criminal" was made so while in a reform school, the fact is that 
the only period of his life, from the hour he left the cradle until the 
prison doors closed upon him, during which he was restrained from 
disobedient or criminal acts, was the few months he spent in a reform 
school. As workers we must expect such insinuations and criticisms, 
aod notwithstanding this discouraging feature must look at. the bright 
side. The clouds of unjust criticism at times may dim our institutional 
horizon, but above the leaden gray there is a silver lining, and as we 
look upon that beautiful band we know the sun shines beyond. 

Our work is one of an unceasing nature. Our pupils are 
ur first consideration and if we are true to their interests it matters 
not what the world may say. We must so manage our pupils as to 
ain and maintain their confidence and respect. If we would govern 
em rightly we must set an exanple of proper self-government. If we 
ould have them read good and wholesome literature, instead of demoralizing 
trash, we must advise them of what is good and wholesome, 
f we would correct bad habits in others' we must be sure that these 
ad habits are not a part of our own make-up. In the language of one 
the wits of the country: "If we would train up children in the way 
wy should go, it is a good idea to shirmish around a little in that diection 
ourselves." 

The development of our reformatory institutions has not been 
the mushroom order. The great success that has characterized some 
the most important has been attained by long and constant work. 
'he problem has been thought out and wrought out. Great and lastng 
results are accomplished only in this manner. One may theorize to 
&gt;is heart's content; he may form beautiful ideals of what he wishes to 
ccomplish; he may stand on the threshold of apparent success and look 
own the mosaic paved hall-ways to the goal of his ambition; he may 
ead in the faces of those committed to his care the bright hopes of the 
uture, but, after all, his cherished dreams may disappear when he 
wakens from his entrancing reveries to face and combat with the 
ustere reality of actual experience. Many a beautiful idol will be 
lattered by the rough hands of experience. It may require an iron 
nerve and a steadfast determination to accomplish the desired and conemplated 
results. Amidst all such discouraging surroundings, hope 
till remains, and he who has heart in the work, and is willing to take 
counsel from the experience of others, will ultimately see the glorious 
riumph of his labors. 

There is no position in life that has not its trials, vexations, 
discouragements and disappointments. These dark phases of official 
life are, in facr, necessary for strengthening official character. They 
are the monitors that serve to admonish us of our duties. Carelessness 
is often the result of continuous success. We become puffed up with </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
I own vanity and imagine that our acts are perfect. It needs the disline 
of adverse circumstances to bring us to a realization of our imfect 
natures. The prudent man will profit by each reversal and 
le out of the slough of despond better prepared for the next encounter, 
ere are times when the embers burn very low on the official hearth; 
en the heart seems to sink beneath the heavy burden; when our best 
&gt;rts to benefit mankind seem fruitless; when those whom we strive 10 
nestly to train and elevate, seem oblivious of our labors and most 
nest endeavors; when everything' appears to go wrong. But with a 
n and steadfast determination, the practice of well directed energy, 
exercise of hope that knows no discomfiture and an inalterable 
iance in the ultimate success of our vocation, we surmount these disragements 
and press on towards the goal of a noble ambition — to lift 
the fallen and care for the unfortunate. 

In all our instructions it should be borne in mind that the displine 
of youth will be the foundation upon which manhood is built. 
mistake on the part of a teacher, through rashness or premature 
tion, may blight the entire life of his pupil. The pupil must be 
ught to cultivate the habit of self-control. He must learn to do right 
because it is honorable and manly, and not simply because it pays. 
e must teach him to be industrious, for it is only by hard labor that 
ic palm is obtained. Confidence gained is a long stride in a boy's 
areer, but confidence maintained is a golden link that binds thai souls 
men. He must be taught that temptation and trials are to be 
countered and overcome. These are some of the agencies necessary 
or the development of true manhood. 

tin conclusion I quote from a favorite author: "If I would reap 
rte&amp;y and hospitality and kindness and love, I must plant them, for 
i the sum of all arrogance to assume that I have a right to reap them 
hout sowing them. Blessings on the man (or woman) who sows the 
Is of a happy nature and a noble character broadcast wherever his 
wander — who has a smile alike for j&gt;y and sorrow, a tender word 
ays for a child, a compassionate utterance for suffering, courtesy 
friends and strangers, encouragement for the despairing, an open 
rt for all — love for all — good words for all." </seg>


            <seg id="p034">
34 

PRESS COMMENT. 

Dr. J. L. Greene, Superintendent of the Hospital for the Insane 
t Lincoln, delivered an address upon "The Causes of the Rapid 
ncrcase of Insanity in Recent Modern Times," which was regarded by 
1 as one of the best of the meeting. As an introduction to the subject 
le speaker quoted the following from Hack Luke, the most famous specalist 
in nervous diseases of modern times: "Man must be viewed as a 
ompound of nerve, vessel, life, mind. He must not be isolated in 
egard to any one function. He must be studied as a symmetrical 
hole one design, one ultimate law within all parts of which he is comtosed. 
Their connection and inter-dependence must be clearly seen 
nderstood and most important of all acted upon." 

What are the causes, real or apparent, of this increase of mental 
derangement and general nervous disorder? Are men changing in 
their physical constitution with a growing tendency to develop organic 
and functional disease of the nervous system, particularly in the socalled 
civilized world? I would answer in brief, that we may find 
sufficient cause if we examine. 

First— The religious and moral condition of the people. 

Second — Their education and occupation. 
Third — The accumulation of bad inheritance. 

Fourth — The modern cultivation of the disease and the meager 
means used to suppress it. 

f Among the ancients the same rules prevailed regarding the 
filiation that toil ay would be found upon a good stock farm managed 
th intelligence. The modern stock raiser finds no profit in rearing 
nd, lame, feeble or vicious animals and such are disposed of at once 
prevent further breeding of the same kind, and thus the cumulative 
ce of physical degeneration is wiped out. The ancient law of 'life</seg> 

            <seg id="p035">
es; the law which subjected the new born babe to an official inpection 
did away with the deformed and feeble during infancy. Not 
ly were parents and the state relieved of a useless burden, but 
tailmcnt of future woes. The lepers were sent to the desert to die 
nd every unclean disease that could be inherited was abolished by 
e law of Moses. In China and Japan thieves were put to death as 
ere also liars and forgers. Not only the perpetrator was killed but 
lis whole family was destroyed. A radical cure of the disease and a 
&gt;revention of further propagation. When the feeble were not destroyed 
&gt;y law of the tribe or nation, the very character of external conditions 
life soon did its work in making selection of a survival of the fittest. 

We can thus see that the anti-Christian civilizations were 
reed from that element of hereditary tendency to nervous disease which 
a prominent feature of our own time. Indeed the most important of 
sanity is heredity. Upon this point the speaker dwelt at considerble 
length and quoted many statistics of a startling character. He 
rther said: "In addition to the fast mode of life involved by our 
modern American civilization comes the loosening of the chains and 
tters of religious belief with no substitute in an anchor of morality, 
te passions of men no longer controlled by either are freely indulged 
the sacrifice of their physical well-being. It is true that while 
arriage may be as frequent, yet maternity is not. Sterility in man is 
cry common, the result of his own vices and the wife who is not a 
mother, or but an imperfect one, is so because she is the victim of an 
nnatural system of education, occupation and servility to fashion. 
"he children who crowd our public schools today, the girls in particuar, 
are deficient in physical strength and endurance and more deficnt 
in their ability to control their whims and desires. Large num&gt;ers 
of our children, young men and young women, are deficient in 
ght and hearing, deficient in bone and muscle, living examples of 
ccumulated evils physical and moral." 

tA paper read by Mrs. George Tilden of Omaha on "Juvenile 
urts," followed and was of an interesting character. The purpose of 
s paper was to show the necessity of the establishment of courts for 
al of juvenile offenders, looking toward their reformation and cortion 
rather than to their punishment for the thoughtless infractions 
laws or the commission of misdemeanors. She read from the very 

—35— </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
36 

Itllent law of Illionis on this subject, and showed by statistics that 
;nile incorrigibility has been very greatly lessened by this humane 
and urged that a similar law be enacted in Nebraska. The comsory 
eductional law of this state was (food in its way, but it did not 
ch the evil. Children should under no circumstances be taken to 
s and there placed in contact with adult criminals. A place of 
ention should be provided for them and kind and humane officals 
:n charge of these houses of detention. In Omaha during the past 
r 247 juveniles had been arrested and lodged in jail for minor 
.demeanors, and in almost every instance the child was irrepary 
injured, mentally and morally, by its contact with the jail and 
adult inmates. 

Professor^C. E. Prevey of .Lincoln read an interesting paper 
the subject of "Scientific Charities as Applied to Smaller Cities 
nd Towns." He held that there should be a harmonious union or 
ntralization of charities especially in the smaller cities. The popuation 
of Nebraska was somewhat over a million. But 175,000 of this 
reat population was concentrated in the two large cities of the state, 
he vast remainder was to be found in the smaller towns and cities 
and in the rural districts. The question of scientific charity was 
erefore just as essential in these smaller towns, cities and rural cornunities 
as in the larger cities. . The centralization of the charities In 
maha and Lincoln had been found most beneficial and most intelgently 
bestowed. In Lincoln the plan was to have cards displayed 
conspicuous establishments about the city, the owners of which were 
members of the central organization, these cards directing the appliants 
for charity to the central office where their needs could be proply 
looked after should they prove themselves worthy. It was found 
many instances that the best charity was to give employment to the 
pplicants. A wood yard had been provided and the men applicants 
ere given the opportunity to earn something, instead of being put to 
e humiliation of absloute beggary. Professional beggars and 
amps not being disposed to work soon disappear and today there were 
ewer tramps in Lincoln than in any city of its size in the west. In 
le case of women, they too were given employment in an industrial 
room where clothing donated for the poor could be repaired and re-made 
nd then distributed to the needy. Considerable of this clothing was 
ft over, and was sold for a nominal turn through the rummage sales </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
37 

nd"a considerable fund realized thereby, that was available for emerencies 
andlto meet pressing needs. By this system of the centralizaon 
of charities the need of the transient or tramp moving families 
could also be looked after itellig-ently, if these people were in absolute 
need of assistance, or sought means to transport them further on their 
ay. By a system of general charities throughout the state it could be 
scertained whether these people had relatives or friends at the point 
which they plead to be assisted. Many of this class of tramp fames 
are veritable nomads. They have no habitation but their wagons 
and are constantly on the move from one community to another, subsist - 
ng the meanwhile upon what they can beg or obtain by questionable 
means. The smaller cities and towns and rural communities suffer 
more from the appeals of this class than do the larger cities. Prof. 
•revey believed that the harmonious union of the different charities of 
ic small towns would prove a solution of the charity question, especally-if 
carried out on the lines as applied in Lincoln. </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
t 

T 

—38- </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
39 

The La.w Creating State Board of Charities 
and Corrections. 

Section 1. The Governor of the state, the Commissioner of 
•ublic Lands and Buildings, and the State Superintendent of Public Intruction 
shall constitute the State Board of Charities and Corrections 
n and for the State of Nebraska. None of the members of said Board 
nd none of the four Advisory Secretaries hereinafter provided for shall 
eceive any compensation for their services but they or any of them may 
&gt;e reimbursed for their actual expenses incurred in the discharge o! 
leir official duties under this act. The Governor shall be the Chair 
.an of said Board, and the said Board shall appoint four persons as 
Advisory Secretaries to co-operate with and assist said Board in carry 
ng out the provisions of this act, not more than two of whom shal 
&gt;elong to the same political party. Two of the persons so appoints 
Advisory Secretaries shall hold their office for the term of two years 
nd two for the term of four years, to be determined by lot in the firs 
nstancc, and after the expiration of two years every appointment shal 
be for the period of four years. Appointments to fill vacancies causei 
y death, resignation or removal from the state of appointees shall be 
made for the residue of the unexpired term or terms in the same 
manner as the original appointments. 

Section 2. The said State Board of Charities and Correcons 
shall make such rules and orders for the regulation of their own 
iroceedings as they may deem necessary, not inconsistent with the 
aws of the state. It shall be their duty to inquire into the whole sys 
em of public charities and the methods of and practices in the correc 
ional institutions in the state and counties to ascertain the condition 
hereof from time to time by inspection or otherwise, especially o 
&gt;risons, jails, infirmaries, public hospitals, asylums, reformatories 
and industrial schools: and the officers iu charge of all such instituions 
and any officers for the distribution of public outdoor relief shall 
at all times furnish to said Board upon its request such information and </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
40 

completeness, in statistics, the said Board may prescribe such forms of 
port and registration as it may deem essential. The plans for all 
w jail building's, lockups, infirmaries or reformatories, shall, before 
le adoption of the same by the state, county, or municipal authorities, 
le submitted to the said Board for examination and approval. The 
Jovernor may, at any time, in his discretion, order a special investiation 
to be made by the said Board or by a committee of its members, 
advisory secretaries, into the management of any state and county 
&gt;enal, reformatory, or charitable institution in the state, and the said 
Board, or its said committee, in making such investigation shall have 
x&gt;wer to send for persons and papers and to administer oaths and afirmations. 
A report of such investigations, with such portion of the 
stimony taken as may be necessary, shall be made to the Governor, 
be submitted bv him with his message to the Legislature. All 
nvestigations undertaken by said Board or any committee by it created 
mil be directed wholly toward the betterment of methods pertaining to 
he health, punishment, education, and reformation of the inmates of 
le various institutions described in this act and the procuring of 
egislation to that end. The said Board shall have authority to appoint 
Chief Clerk, to define his duties and fix his compensation. Said 
oard shall also have authority to employ special clerks and stenogaphers 
in conducting special investigations under this act. 

Section 3. The said Board of Charities and Corrections shall 
make a full report of its proceeding biennially to the Governor, 
embodying such recommendations as to said Board may seem advisable 
or necessary, together with a detailed statement of all expenses 
incurred by it in discharge of its duties. 

Section 4. Whenever the Governor shall deem it advisable or 
xpedient to obtain information in respect to the condition and practical 
orkings of like institutions in other states, he may authorize and 
esignate any member or committee of members or advisory secretaries 
f said Board or the Chief Clerk thereof, to visit such institutions in 
Deration in other states, who shall personally inspect the said instituons 
and report to said Board. 

b Section 5. No member of said Board nor its Chief Clerk nor 
of its advisory secretaries shall be either directly or indirectly 
rested in any contract for building, repairing, or furnishing, or fur- </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
nishinff 

act; nor 

ment of 

Board 

and the 

supplies to any of the institutions in this state described in this 
shall the officers in charge of or connected with the manageany 
such institution be eligible to appointment under said 

as advisory secretary or Chief Clerk. 

Section 6. All acts and parts of acts in conflict herewith be 
same are hereby repealed. 

Approved April 1, 1901. In force July 1, 1901. </seg>


            <seg id="p042">
42 

t-La.ws of the Stale Board of Charities and Corrections 
of the St*.it of Nebraska. 

(Adopted Octobek 15, 1901.) 

I.— OFFICERS. 

The officers of this Board shall be a chairman, (the Governor 
ex-ofticio), a vice-chairman, and a chief clerk. 

LThe vice-chairman shall be elected at the annual meeting and 
1 act in the absence of the chairman. 

t The chief clerk shall hold office during the pleasure of the 
rd. He shall receive such salary as the board may determine from 
; to time, besides his necessary traveling expenses. His duties 
11 be: 

LI. To be present at all meetings of the board and keep a 
rd of the same. 

2. To conduct the correspondence of the board. 

3. To devise and execute a proper system of statistics for the 
institutions, subject to the inspection of the board. 

4. To study diligently the whole subject of charities and corrections, 
with reference to the present and future interests of the state. 

5. To prepare the bennial report to the Governor, subject to the 
approval of the board. 

To refer to the various committees of the Board in advance, 
h business as is to come before the board at its next meeting. 

7. To perform such other duties as the board or chairman may 


II.— MEETINGS. 

The regular meetings shall occur on the 3rd Tuesdays of January, 
April, July and October, in each year; provided, that the chair 
man of the board may postpone any quarterly meeting, at his discre 
turn not exceeding four weeks. </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
43 

I The July meeting- is hereby designated the annual meeting, 
ecial meetings may be held at the call of the chairman; or on the 
itten request of any two members, or at the call of the chief clerk. 

tAt special meetings no final action shall be taken on any subnot 
specified in the call for said meeting unless all the members be 
ent. 

Meetings shall be held in the office of the board unless other- 

wise ordered. 

III.— ORDER OF BUSINESS 

1. Reading minutes of preceding meeting. 
2. Report of chief clerk. 

3. Reports of committees. 
4. Communications. 

5. Unfinished business of last meeting 
6. Miscellaneous business. 

IV.— COMMITTEES. 

EAt the annual meeting, or ns soon thereafter, as possible the 
ird shall appoint the following standing committees; to be composed 
two members each: On Charitable institutions. Correctional instituns. 
Plans for construction and Accounts, which committees shall 
•ve until their successors are appointed. These committees shall rert 
at the regular meetings of the board. 

V.— VISITING PUBLIC INSTITUTIONS 

I The charitable, penal and reformatory institutions, supported 
the state, shall be visited, at least quarterly, by the chief clerk and 
least annually by each member of the board. 

I County jails, hospitals and poorhouses shall be visited annual 
by the chief clerk, or some member of the board, if possible. 

City jails and lockups shall be visited as often as practical. 

VI.— FINANCES. 

I All accounts for expenses of the board, except the salary of the 
ief clerk, shall be certified by the chairman of the auditing comttee 
and an itemized record made thereof. 

VII.— AMENDMENTS. 

These by-laws may be amended by a vote of four members at 
any regular meeting. </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
Report of the Work of Chief Clerk and State Board of 

Charities a.nd Corrections 

I Immediately after the appointment to the office of Chief Clerk 
the State Board of Charities and Corrections we went under the apintment 
of the Governor to attend the National Conference of Chares 
and Corrections, held in the City of Washington, D. C. The inmation 
and instruction received there has been of great' service in 
e organization of the work. 

On the first day of July 1901 we were assigned to room 8 in the 
State House which has since been headquarters for the Board. 

tOur first work was getting in communication with County 
rks, Sherriffs, and Superintendents of Poor Farms, in all counties 
the state. 

LWe also commenced at once our duties as inspector of institu 
s both state and county. 

As far as we have inspected everything seems to be in as 
good condition as could be expected in the state institutions. 

I The Penitentiary is greatly in need of the extra room which 
11 be furnished by the new building if it is ever completed. 

tThe addition to the Lincoln Asylum adds greatly to the comt 
and convenience of the inmates as well as those whose duty it is 
care for them. 

The Home for the Friendless has undergone much needed reairs 
in the way of new floor and new roof. The need for a place to 
are for crippled children who are capable of receiving an education 
¦hich will make them self-supporting has had careful consideration 
y the Board and an order from the Board of Public Lands and 
luildings for the home to receive such children as the Board recommend 
has been one of the many important things done. 

After the fire at Norfolk which occurred on the 23rd day of 
ptember 1901, which destroyed all of the main building of the Insane 

—44— </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
Hospital the temporary place was found unsuitable for the care of the 
inmates during the winter months and they were removed upon the recommendation 
of the Board of Charities and Corrections, to Lincoln 
and Hastings. 

The Board with the exception of Father Ruesing, visited the 
Institutute for Feeble-Minded Youth at Beatrice and found it very 
ably managed by Dr. Johnson. The school, with Mrs. Asmstrong as 
principal, is doing a wonderful work. The industrial work done by 
the pupMs would do credit to any that might be done by pupil- of normal 
mind. 

b'Our visit to the Industrial Home at Mil ford under the manage 
of Mrs. A. M. Edwards was quite a revelation. So much more is 
iplished, than we supposed possible. 

have not time or space to give an account of each visit to the 
e institutions, though such a report could not fail to be interesting. 

I should like however to mention the visit to the institution conducted 
by our worthy Advisory Secretary, A. W. Clark, of Omaha. 
Although his work does not come under the supervision of the Board, I 
must say he is doing a good work and one that could be done in no 
other way. Placing homeless children in homes where they will be 
under the watchful care of foster parents. 

tl have visited twenty City Lockups, City Jails and Poor 
s. Have found them with few exceptions, in about as bad a conas 
it is possible for such places to be. 

Considerable time has been spent preparing reports for the 
office use and blank reports for the State and County Institutions. 

Of the 90 counties in the state we have had reports from only 67. 
In most cases the information gained has been very meager. We are 
not discouraged however for much of the work of the Chief Clerk must 
necessarily be for the first years at least, to arouse an interest in the 
work and lead the people of the state to see what a great work can be 
accomplished when all labor together for the sam: end; namely the uplifting 
of the dependent, delinquent and deficient classes. 

tFrom estimates made from reports it is found that about one 
f of the counties of the state have Poor Farms, and that these farms 
e about 800 inmates. Besides those who are at the Poor Farms 
re are about 400 that are receiving continuous aid from the counties. </seg>


            <seg id="p046">
46 

tmany more are receiving partial aid. The whole cost of keeping 
&gt;e paupers exceeds $50,000. 

Reports from sheriffs and jailers show 884 prisoners in county 
jails. City jails have 276 making a total of 1160. No estimate could 
be made of the cost of keeping these prisoners as there is in most cases 
no separate account kept for this expense. 

I In our state institutions we have at the present time 1400 insane 
Including 76 out on parole. 

We have 545 dependents besides 417 on furlough. 

The defectives number 483 and 52 on parole. The Industrial 
Schools have 180 inmates, 27 on parole. 

The penitentiary has at the present time 282 convicts. Four ot 
these are women. 

In November the Chief Clerk, in company with some of the 
other charity workers of the state, attended the National Prison Conference 
at Kansas City, Mo. A number of promient workers of the 
Nation were present and great enthusiasm was aroused by their stirring 
addresses. 

K Visited the Kansas Penitentiary and also the National Prison 
Ft. Leavenworth. 

The work is already growing on us. 

We are working in harmony with charitable societies and 
private institutions. 

I The coming session of the Legislature will be presented with 
carefully prepared bill on Juvenile Courts, also one on sanitary 
images and another on the care of adult feeble-minded and epilep- 

Lln fact we are looking for much needed legislation along the 
of advanced Charities and Corrections. </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
CONTENTS 


State Board 3 

Officers of State Conference 

State Institutions 

History of (Nebraska Conference 9-10 

Minutes of Sixth Annual Meeting 11-15 

Opening Address, Chancellor Andrews 16-18 

Address of Welcome, Dr. A . Johnson 19-22 

Address, Reformatory Work, John T. Mallalieu 23-33 

Press Comment 34-37 

Law Creating Board of Charities ,38-41 

By-Laws Board of Charities 42-43 

44-46 

Report of Work. 

47— </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>