<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR OF 1905</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">MK I I </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nkbrabka 1 )airymen i h Association Hik THK Vkak of l»&gt;or&gt; I'KKI'AKKll IfS' C. IIASSK'I'T. SlOCKKTAKN « Dairymin " Amwmmatiii!* </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">1 </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">TABLE Of CONTENTS. n - ■ - *t -:• </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">• Vuuntr. I - DIRECTORS </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010"/>
            <seg id="p011"/>
            <seg id="p012">9 LIST OF MEMBERS. New t • ■ Lincoln. ( tililn .(lit. I...I. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">10 \\\ H. ljau. K. \\ I i trown ■ Burk« </seg>
            <seg id="p014">11 \ t miaiiu, Superior, Albion. ( liapman, , ork, Nobr. - . Lincoln, lUniu't, Wv . Lincoln. Havelock, Sebr .Clarkson. t 'lark- Sebr Dakota Funk. i . Lincoln. Lincoli Madison, . . I 'a v i K.-&lt;l (loud. i . Omaha. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">12 I . K IMulinho </seg>
            <seg id="p016">13 Lincoli Ruskii - ( slant! i slaml i. oniaha . Himil Illilllbolt Ilii veliK - k. Fairtii-hl. Lincoln. Lincoln, L'Nt St Omaha. '. airmont, tflleviif. . lin;li-.. 'aim' . WiWon f'hil -. Itavmi Hern . Phillips, Tekamah. Kimball. Nordon. Normal. 'rirarci </seg>
            <seg id="p017">14 H. h John S T. .T. Sclwr^er. - ! - H . H ■ Thor: 11 J. H. Thoi (J. H. Til.:. Tornquisi Boaldrk. W'artvn. . . l.h Witt.. ■ Sheldon - ). M. N </seg>
            <seg id="p018">15 t hnuliii. Nebr. IVt^rsburj;. Nehr. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">\EBRA8KA TWfNTY FIRST AWLAL MEETIMG OF THE DAIRYMFVS ASSOCIATION • </seg>
            <seg id="p020">17 \ unlx-i (if will r Farm of package and |i . rrv.n kxhimit ::.iwi </seg>
            <seg id="p021">18 rninimun, n proporti&lt; (I abo\ inum. All butter exhibit - &lt;&gt;. charges prepaid, not laU-r than.Ianuar v Kith 1 ■ will !»• ! </seg>
            <seg id="p022">19 PROCEEDINGS OF THE TWENTY FIRST ANNUAL MEETING OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. called t ■rder. and said: First of all ung men coming to _rlad to welcome them. It augur* ■ ii Ik- out of the way ai. man .unjf men cominn forward to tak- .■• , - ■ iddress bj the President. I hop for 1 have not prepared it. PRESIDENTS AUDI: I tor our Anm w, to tnjo\ the social ■ ■ f th. -ku. &gt;een a pn for them uniform]; pood. has no just can- ■ latters intimatelv conr. to call vour particular attei. B.airv wort in our work. » : liraska with her more than - t. Hut what of the quality? While we have made ■• in pounds of butt tTereil a decrease in prle • f this'/ T and I 1) eel thoroughly discussed, and i found or I, I trust the members of th ■rill all be found in the front rank to apply the remedy. is and ut&gt; ilv increasing. (Hirout- r than &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p023">20 ■till all " .Ian. _ . T. L. II .1. B. T </seg>
            <seg id="p024">21 - • ■■ 1.71' l."«i L80 - . •■ ..,:, - i :t" - -. .- ■ .. I I.W </seg>
            <seg id="p025">(). 1' M. H . Min tid fiv W. A. R </seg>
            <seg id="p026">'I with yum j . but tn t for y f work of th l)ut for the futun all tilnt UT .i in 1901, which in cuilture in the public- school*, the principle &gt;\ tfx , ill 111.. ! much more fullj tha industry o •i is not organized and i- , I'lition. ;i •vern in il &gt;t in the busii ds. I! it i-&gt; im- the number ol ■ tiin. why is it di .'lu.ixki (laii-\iiii-n - jnininjj the i" 1 • hu'li I had in mi - tx-ing made in that </seg>
            <seg id="p027">24 r for i Not H ■ I nf our \x w • ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p028"/>
           
            <seg id="p029">\ ar and l'nit. &lt;ml\ a it I fa nil hail a a i atv. mstruc ant consideration. Si tin- lower . all our people old and j lation. utopn short of II ajjrieu &lt;&gt;f ap would ha. undid person that t&gt;&gt; lass u Hon. .1. U Me follow •.■lit of our people u </seg>
            <seg id="p030">■ </seg>
            <seg id="p031">IHE \ECESSITY FOR IMPROVIVG HAND SEPARATOR CREAM. \ . Pci illustrul 'hi-v wan: anil \&gt; ■ &gt;f our |" ii which the peop r 11 • liil::i ani iKl he raw material which, th rails Africa ai The . r thai - and -1 th - from the ility of (hi ha v insr the un&gt; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p032">28 I ( a f qualii upwat*' ■»-: Klavoi- . »wi]l note that flavor, wh </seg>
            <seg id="p033">29 - - THK MAMKAi Tl'RKR thai ma - mi the i. t - i tlif hai iblic in tli' -anil-, of &gt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p034">30 . - ■ I ■ "f all kit. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">31 ■ . ■ ". They aiv mrillii the} «i!l §■ ' . </seg>
            <seg id="p036">32 ' </seg>
            <seg id="p037">■ . A. In fi if t! ■ ■cidit) i - </seg>
            <seg id="p038">&lt; \ ■ ■ I ha vi </seg>
            <seg id="p039">35 No. . r wif \&gt; fa mat Hi all a c.f a -!. V(l &gt;h a cat for li - t i&gt; not : im, what iinf man would call In nt: mi. It a tna" An. I « ihiwi Mr. &lt; ha 1 tiiii that these ~ln&gt;u •low a certa </seg>
            <seg id="p040">. How. ' whirl ■ umber on ■ lo for you. The n </seg>
            <seg id="p041">37 ad he may :ies in |iii: i ■ niiin who was I think tl, ni-.li c- am, and on the othei whai fai but ii will ell t-n t i« ) n two wt n. I will ailiiii&lt; you h;i'! .mil it nil Hid it nil i into t hi ~ II product will produci opln whether we ran p ■ I this plai whether we ran e pro 1 one I don't know ihis business, ami I ■I for all cases alike. 1 t hit, ee, when you li they mal. nadred tal There may lie a good many one 1 don business, and I dike. I think we when you I As for ir nc they mai hundred tu will »\ here may &gt; many (lard, but that is the nilejtli. al from it. Tl ihei uit weis;li but that is the nil- ( from it. The a f the' hat weitil will simpl\ i- r &lt;t pay for tht i and </seg>
            <seg id="p042">I ■ tha " l.;ii Now » milk on tl row I .mi tha </seg>
            <seg id="p043">\ I in. and r ( - 1 &gt;o 1 1 n 1 1 . ! milk th;&gt; not wai If \v will ! on who et ;i!l he I ii Why? 1! ir skinimi 1 nutrilion. If you let ii </seg>
            <seg id="p044">f-OllH • - ■ perature of It has now thai i ati Yon oimtii ihii :. of things. That troul h thi •• s with U member, tli </seg>
            <seg id="p045"/>
           
            <seg id="p046">41 ,11 tend to produce a r ilian I • Bui I « Knave it in a clos. n. If cream i ;ii. why ii is up to Lh&lt; ■ They ■ it. They hail about HI here. Shi 1 • : _ ibl dl r. We - the milk and . but "Where did all that She went to tbi did all thai din come from?" We said it came to under they did not have an&gt; iraior. T Ue m hit : stood back as sort of a ; hai lady, with all th&lt; ip, that that dirt came out &lt;■: \ iuht here loniKht. and we will ilk in th- g, and 1 will wash that separator myself. clean, and :1k. 1 have | </seg>
            <seg id="p047">42 • . </seg>
            <seg id="p048">43 ■ i il with. I ; as a ViHTl I - he? Tl.- ■ i thai pli - ■ .'.ill." V. ■ii in this In ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">44 luch hard &lt; and tell him </seg>
            <seg id="p050">I uynus ho; I ■ . </seg>
            <seg id="p051">I I . </seg>
            <seg id="p052">r. ah ti i . • • </seg>
            <seg id="p053">48 with wondcrfu: I 1j&gt; • - P • </seg>
            <seg id="p054">a prodiii not know • m. We ■ 1 • wliirh i milk 81 home. \V. r bills. ■ - : ■ ill do, and I will I ■ !;ivor iini! •ifflcult I can not say how it </seg>
            <seg id="p055">50 ■ ■ ' , ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p056">51 1 K- • I had . </seg>
            <seg id="p057">52 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">53 from thai If you :!.(l&lt;Mt of - nil) then they will lx&gt; tilled in tin -:i~ which aiv handling »;in.\li(id\ that will mil what I hi ook it in i '. How arr you yoiti: :i man ould like to ask you on&lt; any whole milk plant - : 1 1 y '! ,. or iff i - man. a Hair) ma: hbor who lives on tl ■ v man. and I ■ ill. Now. tin man com i, and tu\ neijrhbor'i on the opjx ■ and dumps my cream i ! in who has ney invt-stcil in thi ■ i more n i inV (^tion of my friend wa - taking up Prof. Haeelo ■ ing should \m' don in any 18 •rraru*. Youi for </seg>
            <seg id="p059">54 ! I will ' . . - </seg>
            <seg id="p060">55 I n. But I ' whii-h a . - , ■i»t Wf luld fair! aintr for " </seg>
            <seg id="p061">56 f ■ ' »\Vhir tion with </seg>
            <seg id="p062"/>
          
            <seg id="p063">• What \ ou wai - now. Tomorrow ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p064">58 STATE FARM. STOCK JIDCING PAVILLIOV JAINlLARY 18. 1906. 9.30 A. M Kt a w« That w ' one tautrl. ilturv • &gt;int in the pi from the ini|x-rial by ttit KKtnpire. Thi </seg>
            <seg id="p065">59 in by • (. Gibbon. . I). Still-.. n. A. L. H.i- :nk. .1. K. ■ 1 to the offices named f&lt; lining Ap in- following report: ;ni(lit the account - it we have examined said ai- t\Ve will take up our program where we left oil paper on STABLE VENTILATION. H RKVNi Minn rural features, but rather stable ventilation a&gt; In order that there may be no po Pinn • ;ind that I may be more certain tha: not be harmful rather than helpful, li - of supposed ventilation: rack vide varia - "f writers on ible hygiene: lack differ - of opinii ninjr the amount of air needed, and very little ■ I on any actual demonstration or otli knowledge. The whole subject is in a very unsettled and un - ■aditioii. . .: may go into stables and find some of the inlets are lettii . ■ .i-ivi-t. ami that the expenditun - idustry of the - hairman. \! H. I £&lt;■&gt; n&lt; • ;. of Minnesota: </seg>
            <seg id="p066">60 &lt; a ■ i »ir per hour. found in I aumont found in two a\ •h rrporl DO informal]' i, the </seg>
            <seg id="p067">61 Air tak' :i I i* M ■ ■ rhaps I n. K.m Lncrea rarying i»m • the formation of I id then union of this with the ('&lt;&gt;■• foi n In Ei 1 ititr. T tount of Cl &gt;i that would -lall in sri - - Kin mind tha' inutll unventila - anil the OOj, vratcr. anil other I lain point, l&gt;u' - not hold room. IS Fori. AIK flAKMKCL? B, human and i . i - i _• re many classical exam concerning the bad effect of foul air. irically. but possibly the explai. \n authority Us us that il »r uhi'ii sick aniraa 'hat are dark and Ulj - in Stall -. described :. ..« </seg>
            <seg id="p068">62 • B </seg>
            <seg id="p069">63 I to an uni' computing i urine into tix tent 01 the oh . </seg>
            <seg id="p070">64 I; U'lnix-rature, &gt;li&gt;ji -. The averapv |hm v im-rvasexl. There »a&lt; a I hoth animal- &gt;ther. ■&lt;! ati ,1 |Miint ■■ led ir w &gt; all ■ nard - In our t-x)&gt;erimental work « tlie air was yrailvi in Stall 2. which wwtd in perfaot comfort. H&gt; would -■!■■ &gt;!i la/il.v: : to make (rue -rain^ at the rate of o </seg>
            <seg id="p071">65 ii that hi - practical imm indie Jim) &lt;&gt;n his I tinuous period we have ■ be stall during .at incurr situation except a trifling amount _. and around the c i perinwat in full, »ul liar intoxication when I ally foul air (foul air wh. ■ - taken out. tr Hook of thi Bl, and in Dr. Atwa meter." we tind on page* L'lti and 217 hi this question and closely corroborating usly had with cattle. Apparently .icidently in the e - to call for extension ai nth of the ventilal Kair for ti - lt wa&gt; rapid h contaminated. The ra- K accumulate until il •lavintr about .03 percent. The suhject wa ■ t in progress. This irai ffect. So far as could t* § absolutely normal condition for the indivi. i. mentall;. t. or lacking in appetite. It connection that the air in the respiration • ; &gt;\ chemical means. -late in which all the natural . « ithout pain or disea- Ba.s: "That condition of the Performance of their normal func- It ' inarv -IONS. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">66 . . ■ germs which could ; of tilt* »»t*-i(^ -• ■&lt; ' fi * 1 1 - work w » !*• ■ "i tTi'ft* ' w ' ' ■ i ■! t ] sciv ( )i •■■- </seg>
            <seg id="p073">67 ■ rul I would I; ! I am ■ ■ con- :rd of hint; only We then h inch a half and ;&gt;ound rn part of the st: lilnce where there wa? ireful ry durinir the I to that work, ;on. r that i with dai in 1 fart that a would al- nnins I am I </seg>
            <seg id="p074">68 you have here. Our im n from dairy "i.ooo. I find that at the pn m I 6(9,000 cows and that t] than $10.0OO,&lt;M ■■ ; that in fat on '1 had reached I ■ sola was in n fat a ■ of butter fat per (&lt;i» of bu Be of I &gt; 110 i 000 an I your has t is made in ti Is of but'&gt; ow means $1,3 mough extra care ti I ill not ask the Nebraska fai r, Guernsey or any other kind of a particular cow. hut will &gt;k him to put that cow ion, give her a little better care, lit tip l . | than he has doing heretofore, and by th. can earn ore. A great problem rests with the farmer who owns the cow and than ■ ou have is a d </seg>
            <seg id="p075">69 iportanlth ; v thing brought to ■raska with ■id from Minn- m of a re- K.in anyth the influ or who it ■ m^ on which ■ fm the look nut n pur- for a m: : v fortun. irork in Minnesota, our own Prof. Mr. H. C. Young, of I-incoln. on. ids." hOW TO IMPROVE OLR DAIRY HERDS. Kiiiil Kello How to improve our dairy ti i 1 will only have time to call your attention to ■ bould end' II know. ;old many ;ilf of the herd. So it Roes without savins we ran procure. If you ha of your herd, don't riflce him hull of merit. Get a good indi - i'le. but not only this rich milking strain and that rand dam both h; Is. and when you find bay him at any price within your means. I of your herd, commence we - md the 1 o do ii is to use the scales, and milk sheet and scales riyht in tbe and 1 !iat you will know exactly what each vou find a cow that is not paying her way and whole lot of trouble, Rliull and much of cows, you can im; 1 attention to the raising of the h and mid have especial attention from the beginning of tie from the bunch, r milk all tog&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p076">70 ami ;• 8nd out that you will have trouble on your km of Uu ;hem warm milk. h from (he cow ami separator— Iiile In Oli i an up-to-dat. , and saw t! ■:!..:..:-•: to ag so No matter how . Ibutt. Kr an&lt;i »od feed. . • goodly suppl improving out I her w;i ty of M will I dair&gt; • easy enough to know how is to put in the way I will surely m don't for&gt;.-. also milking regularly has eal to do wl raisint the standard of our dairy hi Mr Elijah F : who hear PULLING TITS. I have been one good farmer for more I raise some wheat, some cori; lU; I fat some hog and I watch that farming baatMM And find him comii . B pulling - </seg>
            <seg id="p077">71 • whole year round; hen been poor, y lose a more. e bully times, you bet. round be dry, or ground B-.'l just a raising fits, ■ ullm tits. am, pleasant dream, bank he not it in his mitts, •n puttin tits. Chief of Dairy Division, United BD of Nebraska, if it is only for a few Ik with you of your work, which ins lo continue •r from ht or ten blbited at this convention, 1 find plenty of rea - • n who produced the milk that went Into r of the poods showed that something But on. 'lie lot would score Western Ex- There I dairy 1; I that I tra of the cream; if th - i;ilit &gt;-, they think they have lid let the from their men that they cannot expect to I that makes such butter as &gt; I undoubtedly the best goods that There is no excuse for i) of thin that the farmers were not sufficiently what the result of such practices as are now in vogue ral market conditions of the country show the •n the last few years a general it-ry butter. This is not because the r now as formerly, from iflc knowledge in the manutacture of butter. &gt;r tret tins; the quality of milk hould to manufacture into butter. To be sure the it fault in many things, and one of the most "!ari p heir willingness to take any I am glad to know that the KM. H. W&lt; ■ • </seg>
            <seg id="p078">72 'ion and o put in force the shading o f cream he payment for it on 1 man should w&lt; for not hi:, .ind, will lity, and his prod if you as NVI&gt;raska ■ Kit I I uth. JUST COW *«: -I health. I » range 18, according to it. w To a man who dot's no - boon. a lop chain, hut she wil! la one-fourth short horn and I will also throw in a double-bai in which ?ws with her In for a week or two and returns with a ta leg*. Her name is K&lt; ■- Irrinp a few points in the description of this particular cow, old well described the kind of cow found in too many of the of our state. They are just cows, pure and simple, with no for existing except that they are here and have an owner who ious and kind h. ,oard bill year after You as i age man about his cows -what they can do, how </seg>
            <seg id="p079"/>
           
            <seg id="p080">73 I or will ii' Will 11(1 il ami pro thai is thi lid opinion. ! milk and on of liecf. :ul Id ■ u when found with an\ !. owned by I i.sfied with the irovement in their i : i &gt; t h called the dual purpose ic influence in their vicinity, and into the hei </seg>
            <seg id="p081">74 Th - iht Kit-* no fill ea the dual pui I will (| . "Thf laFt t» year. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">75 Quantity of prod '•ssary I ins, »nd not i a race your -tai&gt;lc- ittte, th* milk. BI won! In ■ that it i- 110 think that i*&gt;rh.i m - mt than someone nearer ! -tied herds or well ■open to the ■ live *tnrk In not a professional exhibit., p a herd and he can at .ml if hi ■ Me amou: n "How to 1 11 1 lividual winnini;. ■ n'leman who read a • I i Hnir\ in like manner carried off a individual pn '1 nienn for ti ad th«' p tor Holstein &gt; premiums on cattle than was &lt;ka State Fair, and to Mr. i 1 would like to include in n ir. J. K. Honeywell. He ha&gt; on from its beRinning. H- - liat can be found Li and. Bi ■ ■ - an m </seg>
            <seg id="p083">76 ilk that " mrt often better ca- !own roat 1 ■ haa i n wh </seg>
            <seg id="p084">77 nearest to it he wilt give a hat the winner may choose. El up a herd wi;hout very much money. Fri' &gt; a valuable prize, and that wil. ■ ittle. IHt COW A«D BITTER JUDGING CONTEST. row and but which took place at the B ■•■.. January IX, under the auspice-, of the Nebl Delation, was unique in character and arrangement and icator and a stimulator of in I Ten cows each of the two dairy brt 1 officially by the Association as regards utter producers, during Hfetime in the State • ■ry cow being kept from the first Einio the dairy, this record was compiled with accu * judging of these rows, ten points were made the basis of n in ■ each cow placed by the contestant on his ' record placed Jier in comparison to the other nine em toward the total score, and as many points »• i cow as the contestant placed her p iy from the correct placing. rait paid $1 to become a member of the Association and ;tnd the prizes offered were as follows: To in both breeds, a $15 gold watch; to the one on Holsteina, a $50 Holstein heifer by Henry (' Omaha; to the one making the highest score on Jerseys, a Ben by H. ('. Young and J. K. Honeywell, Lincoln, N m each brteil and divided pro rata amongst those • r over. The result was that of all those who : th{&gt; con "red 75 per cent or over. In J&lt;- In the money. In 'red in the money. rif Tekamah made the highest average score in jud &lt;i was awarded the gold watch offere I Allison of York, .lohn Korberger of Lincoln and Arthur J. Peter - if Phillipp each n M in judging Holsteins and • rmine the ownership of the registered Holstein calf \ i. The result favored Arthur J. Peterson. ■ - John J. Schacht of Cook and A. Wayne Wilson of points and in drawing lots to determine the -hip of the registered Jersey calf valued at MO, A. \\ is the lucky man. In t) packages of commercial b </seg>
            <seg id="p085">78 were purchased in the Chicago market of grades known as "ex ••first," and "secondB." These packages were first scored official Eer expert, and a contestant was required to make an averagt &gt;f the three package* of i cial score. ■judging the butter, perfect in quality or flavor, counts 45 ] 25 points, color 15 points, salting 10 points, package and pa* itB, total 100 points. K contest was in charge of Prof. T. L. Haecker, instructor in dair&gt; dry at the Minnesota Agricultural College, and who, in advance contest, explained fully in regard to what is required in the com I market as to flavor, grain, color, salt, package and packing. K package to be scored was placed on a table and each contestant trier of the butter and recorded his judgment on a score card for such purpose. ■ thiB contest 166 took pa I of the number made an : ; of 93 points or more, and received some portion of the J75 oi emiums. The highest a\ re was made by Val Kuska. Ohiowa. student at tbe School of A Mr. Kuska's pro rata share of it Below we give a list of those w: :t&gt;w Judging com- - ■ •nar. I.u« ■■ Jim Waldo i hnstrn«on I. - 7S .ndict. Bennet. Wf F J :»pm»n. NVI.r Earl DsTiaaon. Havenns. Netir p m Doom. h.. J K Drspela. Owksou N.-l ■ - .'umjd. Beaver Crossinu N &lt; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p086">79 :■ T^ 7:. -J -I " ■ . 78 ■ 78 80 II - *( &gt; •y' -, • keby Nebr - M - Ml « ■ • ■ &gt; n re : 80 nev». Nebr ■ • • 4 * ■ ■&gt;) . ■ :• r (•!• " "4 n </seg>
            <seg id="p087">80 I. J I Arthur J Peterson Phillip* I. Y. Reed. Omab*. Nrt.r M A. JainetiRee*. Frinmwe. N J K Rubens Nonual Sebr J A I.- I ler Ranom. Fairtleld ■dear Id 1 1 1. n irk I 11 Ui&lt;-&lt;- i ; mud Island N&gt;i H H Sniriwr. Axbtoi; Hermitn Su-in M. Henr&gt; - John I a w Uamp—m Tbctx: Wn - rtionwir. 1 Tbon. Tfn-r Van Aetoraen ( cd.ir Km - A Wajne ■ FYmI A Warm JUltf' W.Midhndi-. «mrpti V»u -.. ndw»l jrratifv ii w -inn- in th»' pro rata pr&gt; I &lt;&gt;f Airriculture at this time. BUTTER JUDGING CONTEST. ■ &lt;&gt;f conu-stants who - to a pro rata share in the premium money ofl. Names Add trleu I I J Arrostronir i &gt;nl iWD. VtnxB Hlair I^xinirton . Iteekmao. lirand Island M </seg>
            <seg id="p088">81 M ■ « H Omaha. 18S9 So. SSth \ I •■ ■ *t • i M Knuth ■ ' C E. Lu Juniatu .85-Hii .88.00 ..mm ..mm M.84 .86.00 88.M Hennet IT7 .(» . 88.00 88.5* 94.M 88. &gt;l lbk.it.. .85. OB .83.00 Oakland . 8&amp;.18 irg .8&amp;.50 95.13 P»wa*a 88.M HancToft. 88. t« Omaha .8B.W .86.11 8D.OB IVkanmh York. fl«.lW MM WI.IK niWll 8B.M Otaiowa Miili iran fniver- 8H.0H 84.M Cedar Blurts 94.33 95.00 94.H 9&amp;06 l.inc.lii 94.ai 84.m Shelby .88.31 .94.11 . '..int UJ ft ■ ■ ...M.a </seg>
            <seg id="p089">82 MiUard . s H H Smelser. Ashton Superior H K Stau&amp;er. South Oa»b» • berirer Darr B. R SlouSer Jr D. I- Sbedd. Columbus. Jobo SntMidon. I wager i m. alia KradisU P K TriMon W. LI iMdro 1 Tbo*. TtaumiMen. = . Ksndn.; Kted \\ Ed. V F. J. M- Keiutsaw M He &lt;; j v H.J.Ms Broken »..» J. H ' RaytuoDd A J N'elsoD. P A S r. e. i Tekamab r K Pratt. i t. J. r Nordon P. K Peterson. Herman Pedret. Kimball Urar Rot brook A J. RcM. Primrose. J. A. Reedy. Linoo.n liladst.me . </seg>
            <seg id="p090">83 . 83.00 KM . , W.«8 I I THE DAIRY EXHIBIT 1 twenty-nine entries of creamery and dairy the dairy building. In addition the dair; tastefully arranged exhibit of dairy pro rse. but which could not c&lt; was judged by Mr. E. 1). Webster, el lartment of Agriculture, at Washington. The rain, color, salt, package and pack- it off in flavor. Ti as follows: CREAMERY BT'TTKR. - ."re. 8».S0 •M ■ •*&gt; m&lt; . ■ &lt;i i ■ I 87 U0 H in SX'.lH) DAIRY HITTER. Socire. 88.00 91. SO - » 9O.M&gt; 91.00 PRINT Bl'TTKR. Hrst premium Baeoad premium Kavem. Third premium Fourth premium &lt; (RNAMENTAL Bl'TTKR. -?mium </seg>
            <seg id="p091">84 THE DAIRY SEPARATOR PROBLEM EMacnsaed from the Standpoint of the Man Who Milks - and Runs the Machine to Produce Cream. By A. I.. HAECKEK. Of the Nebraska Experin, Esing the hand separator problem I wish to treat it mainly it's standpoint, and by producer I mean the man who i: ws and run "am. In introducing th and u ishout the country: for we find a marked developmei. while in oth&lt; iction of the hand was for several years a gi hi ion of machine em and midii Th» - large home dai - of this new tioo for creaming milk, and ! considered a luxur&gt; more than a necessity. In a brought about and a ■ ichine wi throughout not only the eustrrn s' t&gt;ntral an I. The farmers that carried on i up the ha Sig the !• of Xeliiaska . b. Th - or we find d countr: eparator w:i Iked of a' ying on western daii} Starting wit: .: 1900, t. 1 ally taken up among farmers in parts of Iowa, Kansas ihls yeai be famous growth of tbi of dairying in • d change was brought about in th. .f dair&gt;inj; tL all this great plains region. The rapid spread of the ha: aska. Kansas. Iowa and South Dakota can ability to I he respective regions, and not th&lt; of creameries. In faci. the creameries at the beginn hand separator system and encouraged it only after thi - atnau the farmers and the chance for greatly . To the western farmer it made dairying ]&gt;ossible, by making cream a marketable product that could be sold at the nearest railn This growth was very marked du </seg>
            <seg id="p092">85 &gt;t care was od employed was as hin and outside at within tl cream buyers wu hem to report i town or post- This, however, was ■ who shipped ■ or. STATISTICAL DAIKY MAP. n accumalatlng all the om the I rt a map m of the nia&lt; •ibuted thi n in the range and sand Ii is quite sin-; of hand separator dairying, espe- For ex;-. •rs, which four n&lt; I machine, wn in the state and 1 to the ■ SOME OF THE ADVANTAGES. ;ttor from the milk pro - '*&gt; well known to discuss at length, but I iniiK&gt;rtant items to the farmer. Pnse of hauling w pri Not &lt;mlv di lire less space '■k. it is not neces - niich lighter it tlPARATOl &gt;ie to ascer- </seg>
            <seg id="p093">86 E rapidly and at less cost. This. I bell ■ n with the li; c on hat a man and team on the farm or ;i j of ' for this I M MILK 1 morn i n l DOB - l&gt;e flu Klderfni . crwM ow in a safe v. cream. 71 itlon wag brou d in collt'Otinii and payn necessarily h^d to lie a man who knew li The produce! a good article. In </seg>
            <seg id="p094">87 '-ring good •n the In 1 quality ol &gt;m poor c heir butter was fa rada cream and BE CRAPEP. o not cai and should ii building up the best ii but what and the pro. -hould who market cream for 1 on the farm by t: will be if the proper opport i making qua farmer in the Mississippi \ irator The hah i stay, at ind do doiilit will be mot- in the fa ■re can d&lt; ihe quality. of the i I. In this inn both th. buyer have a part to i Kfor after this rl le for its iing will be a for wheii pocket book is wll requln when wi that nine-tenths ol not dairymen in the ;t doing some dairying along .in and paying for grade to furnish a good article. Pi producer will make some attempt to turn or one that will demand a good price. The fifth man i to produce a good cream or will compel him to produce a second grade cream. 1 toond in man rs who are perfectly willing to r&gt; Id not do except where K opportunity to &lt;■■ of the hand separator. Th&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p095">88 ream is M e small c: this dif?i' who Id • IK ill i it at ■ operation i clean: - of wash in. will ■ rooms or building (1 work aeeea This may 1 i 'ainly shoulil I m which GROWTH IX DAIRY IXnVSTRY growth in </seg>
            <seg id="p096">89 the Pacific coast. I and has dipped down into the . 1 1 1 &gt; products in ret I by whole-milk system dai he introduction of imptove.: nils of farmers millions of dollars which hU- for them to accumulate had it n&lt;&gt; §han., nd their influence should They should insist, where tti - taking pur|K&gt;ses, that it be graded accoidir, E.| for butter (:i&lt; by accurate methods. They should n interest in all th. ,s thai ai &gt; &gt; 10 place thi^ advantage The) ithould jjive care '■ ins;. Th many opportun D can oaly be carried on a the part of all ro work in harmony. This is possible the riglr me it is well worth thi ins and grading there is a fair field for &lt;■&lt; E hipped in large quant Itiea from towns one man i itid ship all the product. This would do awaj llf d&lt; ii buyers often found in a small town and • illed n an at bet er pay ami housed in a buildit n the cream. THE FARMER'S COW. ■raska Shorthorn breeder! in iheii tiK. January It. by H. C. Wallace of I)es Moinest til Ml should be, us many different kinds o! of farmers. The farmer who m ■ on a small farm, who has high i near ity. who has a family of boys and girla to hei run a factory which turns out a no tn 10 sell the lible amount of fertilit or what In doe* sell this kind of a i dairy cow He wants a highly organized ma which will t. lains an and convert them into of high quality. With him cream ami butter are the finished i the skim milk are byproducts, to be hand ■ much as |K&gt;ssible out of them, but not to be ike much of his time and thought. He has no tin with sieci calvi • 11s them young for what they will Thf fanner, on the other hand and b&gt; him I mean Ike .'Han — who has great difficulty in </seg>
            <seg id="p097">90 • I iK farm help, who has cheap land and k who fan hack, has little use for tl him la feed her if he had her. li iken down and the milk taken away from iheni. Hi thai will give enough milk for her calf but no more \h.n »'il! take Ht milk until th. .aid when it in he. Hi« land h;is ailvam ad mom causi $6n to $ ■ lifficnli 1" and fed. » •anno, afford to K' chan&lt; i If. The small ihm hunches for from %l$ ind conditions. I will i han thin to keep a c&lt; ir. Thi r lore, is to continii heir keep in BlUh .rom. I' would le unreasonable ' the highest excellence in d iines, but it is entire)* of practical men has demonst;iied. that the right kind of a cow ot this sort will of the </seg>
            <seg id="p098">91 nly in con w of this kind has been so is bow ! • o fill ml breeds. Durham: she may be a will be found to I &lt;■ Shorthorn, usually a grade. There are good Shorthorn lireed origin;* »kept cows for milk as we f cow that the farmer in the corn belt v. Buie of the It cows of the early da liken and their bull calves proved to be - i r known. Even in recent ) illy competed with all Bnglisb shows. e unfortunate for the breed thai S' ntion to the milking qualities of the 8 probably true that three-fourths of the dairy cowa of 1 think it is also true of Iowa, carry a b .irthorn blood Notwithstanding this, very few of the pun In dairy liius and the number of wi kept careful I ui be counted almost on the four two hands. Some of the experiment stations which i all the cows milked have reported on Shorthorn the most accurate infounation. The Iowa 3 1 1 ton for example, i record! of a Burntx Shorthorn cows, cows which have descended from S 5 His. milk. I3.i lbs. butter. months record, lli'i Ihs. milk. r&gt; f. . 7 lbs. butter. fng the last lactation period very high, and the cow was nitiK for the International Show and was fed heavier than \o chii iile for labor in 'arm for ». 1 quoti .-(I by this si at ion College Moore — Shorthorn, Calved. October 19. 1891. ■ Besdnnini.' Beginning Bi of s of milk. : 7 Ml MM. 2 41" 474.:: M $67 $l(tt $91 24.91 27 ;. 4" l" </seg>
            <seg id="p099">92 Exposition ;ii Cfcieai inter in nine months as a two-year-old &lt;is months as a tkn ear was $7" refit exr' $24 Thli nt a ne profn Bat t he Omaha I Ik I which luntii'l OIKi. to claim nut Ihi'll &lt;il |.M|iH !;iir\ lin« - nd of infi ii|M'n The U| - olll to find a Shorthorn lull fi he HaiiKfled with lh&lt; for I wo i the caM i&lt; tbrovsl know how niitny ihiys in tl •uiirh mi 1 worth. In wan </seg>
            <seg id="p100">93 ng out thi I are not profi Elf be will do this in. More and more Shorthorns. It will not do for the hi mi much bother or i ■ i tile to »h' ■ cows that will milk ten mom I milk a herd of tows one year when ear when lieef 1- p to milk. Tha! kind of practice will ratal Excellence at th. rid from breeding. The h. heir first calf, and they must i t.i dairy ration, and nm i with ■ :n to the troub n They prefer to fall back on the hat the Sh&lt;&gt;' 'hey can set along for a numl» iiitiK when general claims will n. n, I it i he Shot' horn is to retain its inner: Ks must do their part and ]&gt;• nilkiaf .mi; and &lt;■ HOLSTEIIM FRIESI/WS I t - </seg>
            <seg id="p101">94 JERSEYS A f RIENDl Y MILKING CONTEST iliciv «a - tin ll&lt;' I: the oowi lie both the property of U t contort wm» nadwr the wipervinion of P w of tln&gt;c t»o ifinarkalilt cows ■ -!. Prof, llaevh </seg>
            <seg id="p102">95 Milk. Uutt.i 1.21 pound* •• official j • ■ mi hat Karen produced more milk ai :.t handicapped ;i&gt; ~lu If. Whili E Nebraska row pr«M mitill tiki Nebraska i-owtt. Where i- the man «li •II. dllll |P KATY Of RBf V No. 68099. il 1 1 1 i — . cuv. and herewith i- a rvcii .1 fin- thii • - . i!."3 um It 17 - ] hi mi- RK&lt; OBD. ■ i*ember SO, I!m4 \ 13, l!"Hi. IS.* u.u 17 &gt; IS. 94 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">96 LIST OF CREAMERIES AND CHEESE FACTORIES [•KAI.I/.KD CKKAMKKIKS. ■ i ►'ninixwi Creamer '.r^lrfi Island CMWB •'&lt;&gt; tioMea Rod I ■ nim Creauen MeUlmmtt Cnamcry ■ ■ ■ Linus CreMiK Nelirh Oreaii Plrpe Creiroen • -n riruiirn i . • Kpr Cfeam«r&gt; • CHEESE FACTORIES IflH M B&gt; Cbaaaa Vteelur} V K Kftimif&gt;-i eCbetwnelon J M Wiidhsbrr • Ifcitim-iiroir CraHKn &lt; " '- H tvT Mix hi PfcaaaMiChMa* VteMan .1 H ITMki &lt; bf« Factor* K \\ </seg>
            <seg id="p104">COV. CR or HAND SEPARATORS NUMfi m - epurotjrj pufttlora 5tfc n.lJS Kfmtha 4o7 7.015 18C jcolti Bi^n 7!S rnite^ Cows mi lea covs Adamt Jl* V* 7 **° Lhiycnm Z. ».57i Ani.iop, g74 I,ui3 Clou Banner ta» B8e9 ♦ 5  - fllo.nc ".i *♦} Jo Cuminq Dooni kU &gt;aBi9 520 Custer fVwtKcllj 572 8.3 2* 500 jf~aru SBf n JB2 I5L Shenaur, lilt ■ihermar, 5b8 tJO OtOf blk I 5 3« 250 rtfof ney f\i«fh v.t Kryo Fthu 10 Him be 1 1 %c UE5 'Vbt Ulo '»*l 50 »vrt «t3U lie Oi'xun 3bt Ctu &lt;M&gt;a7 DouoIoj 3*1 ''i 1 Odor 715 'IJBS7 3o&lt;- Oi/nSy 9tl i-tk. 1*10 Chelt fui ]jk7l Fllmurr 5 b» Luqon 57fc t-uw-p 57* Ji2 iJO ■«32 IC 3 so^. '57k iE.ISO 580 c« »bC 31L/ Tt' *3 1 •n ,ki,o C*H*ntj No &amp;ooutt MoMilcH Ho liana ISann.r CoUa» S8e9 Blame ".i *♦} Jo Comma Dooni kU I(*I9 520 Custer Oo&gt; Ruttr ip78 5 it? Oakuta '2fc&lt; Brown i.ZU 2&gt;M l&gt;0 Oawsuo 1687 auttoio se; n,«ie •**" o«uci »vrt ti3« 2.KO Oi'xun 43c ibt P&amp;wnrs +37 130 'ihermar, 5b8 P«i-Kins 8»5 3.8*7 c?: 5.ou* IjOV Phelps 5b4 F.JJi JO0 jluntun +3! P.erce 5 k6 oOO Thcyer J72 iOIOT Platle b6» +bO Tnumus TtO i^i 432 1.0M i*0 Tnursiun 39i H»d r. ■ 5J9C 500 fohy 518 55y: i** 0 R lt n(.rJS. 54» |OP37 oU «e.»h.r&gt;C)Ton 3SE Ruth 3.886 i30 «aynt -t + l 6^»' «" 37W u.BJt ISO Wrbiler 51» Bo 5arp«, ».5T2 BO Whxlfr 581 YorK •&gt;&amp;* °!'fl 5 JO ♦c Ucncc^fffr StB SO.793 1*30 Lincoln 1570 6,057 +80 ric Pht'jon ,ba; v»- ' «»^ _. , BOX _^- r-^ X&amp;r^.-" __ •*M"" r I c m (C I 1 &gt;%-"t\ ~ '■'.-'' : H a • w 1 I ~=^^ -^ .•■-.••■ • .: \ "4y-~^ &gt;a^*-*~ T; I I %k c«nt,. .100) I \_ c^^%£S^ :^^^^'"/. 4~-^r^ P"' !^£Eg^ Stlljjfc separator. W.Z87.15O • . ' J^fi- *r r -^I^tJ^a^l^fe 'SSI'TGf"" &gt;"'. ' X7' ■ i •: • J 1 -MAPISOf L -c* • •f £ .. f • • ia * m *9® g£4^ -•^ .^ ., "Vt* 1 \.' (L • • i '2 =3 * _ ■ es * 1* — j "-1 i'- "^... ■" m *—**■- • r^ •• .'.•t • i( .■■» . •*, w^ '.,• •^ S : C #j| GENERAL ST/MijiiCJ (Ccn»*. llucj No tarcr, -.R cpxj • iT,»6,89? KuMvr u! hana s»porato»j "^o C»( »»lx» u» hur&gt;d stp&amp;nators » 1Z87.75O ft, unJ , C'»a-"«r, Bw'fer rota . - »-t,t79 B ■\ ' • / * ""j^^ &amp; .»^.— &gt;v7 • • '." • :^5 ad [^ £8? L I » E • • 3*5 E£ - •joi &amp;?g 1 .*" •• • IIEM/.&gt; I 1 ■•-} &amp;—*■"* On map each du*«O &lt;- ■ * rtprftinh r«n n**od Wpi-' * tmrr&gt;*.r*xan locality •y] • • • z* 1 'A ti * K, r .«— -■ * " • • •* TABL SHOWING </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>