<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Message of Keith Neville Governor of Nebraska to the Thirty-Seventh Session Nebraska Legislature 1919</title>
               <date value="1919">1919</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">MESSAGE OF KEITH NEVILLE GOVERNOR OF NEBRASKA TO THE THIRTY-SEVENTH SESSION NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1919 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">To the Members of the Thirty-seventh Session of the Legislature of Nebraska: GENTLEMEN : It is with the deepest sense of gratification and pride that I discharge my constitutional obligation and advise you of the events transpiring since I assumed office two years ago. The great war which for more than four years has threatened the security and freedom of the world, is at an end. Justice has prevailed. American valor, ingenuity and push has turned the scales and our victorious fighting boys are already homeward bound. More than 51,000 of the finest of our young manhood was Nebraska's contribution to the Nation's war effort. No sturdier soldiers ever fought to aid humanity. Their deeds will be in - delibly inscribed upon the pages of the world's history. In their iibsenee over there, the homes fires have been brightly burning. Nebraska has excelled all of her sister States in the purchase of war savings stamps. In general Red Cross work also, no State has equalled Nebraska. In subscriptions for Liberty Bonds and in donations for war work activities, we have more than filled our quotas. Yes, we may well feel proud, for Nebraska has an - swered every call, has fulfilled every obligation. The war has been fought and won, but it has levied a heavy toll. Before the hearths and firesides in many homes, there is a vacant chair. The grief of those who gave sons to the cause of humanity is keen, but they will take consolation from the fact that their sacrifice was not made in vain. Nebraska's heroic dead must not be forgotten. A monument should be erected on the State Capitol grounds, facing the battle-fields of France and having inscribed thereon the names of all Nebraskans who gave their lives that peace might reign supreme throughout the Universe. While we honor our dead, we will not forget the living. The federal government is already laying plans to establish the re - turned soldiers and sailors upon farms secured by the purchase of suitable tracts and thru the reclamation of waste lands. It is </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE also more than probable that the scope of the farm loau Ian - will be extended so that it will virtually fulfill the functions of the building and loan associations now operating in the cities and towns. By so doing, many of these men can readily be supplied with farms, paying for them thru installments cover - ing a long period of time. I am quite sure that this Legislature will do everything possible to cooperate with the federal gov - ernment in carrying out this program. You gentlemen are inducted into office at the close of the war period. It is for you to solve the problems of reconstruction and to finish the work begun in the past. National Guard Under a recent ruling of the Judge Advocate General of the United States Army, all men who have entered the federal service thru National Guard organizations will be automatically dis - charged from state service when they receive their discharge from the United States Army. This ruling will leave the several States without National Guard organizations and until the fed - eral government announces a definite plan to accomplish the se - curity of the Nation, it will be unwise for the State to attempt to reorganize its National Guard. In all probability a definite program cannot be promulgated before the adjournment of this Legislature and I would, therefore, recommend that no effort be made to organize or maintain state troops during the next two years at least. Prohibition. Nebraska has completed the first and most important period of its career as a dry state. In all communities where a whole - hearted and conscientious effort has been made to suppress boot - legging, the present prohibitory laws have been found adequate. During the period from May 1st, 1917, when prohibition became effective, until November 1st, 1918, there were 5,145 prosecu - tions for violations of the liquor laws and fines have been as - sessed aggregating $142,366.55. There will continue to be vio- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1919 5 lations of the law as long as alcoholic liquors are manufactured and sold in the Nation. With few exceptions, county officials have cooperated wholeheartedly with the executive office in the enforcement of prohibition. By virtue of a federal enactment, prohibition will shortly become effective throughout the Nation. As a result, enforcement in Nebraska will be much easier and less expensive in the future than it has been in the past. Never - theless, it would be unwise to cause the Governor to become en - tirely dependent upon local authorities for enforcement of the liquor laws. The present plan of maintaining a limited number of state agents should be continued. Ratification of the Federal Amendment. I take pleasure in presenting for your consideration, the fed - eral prohibitory amendment. The people of Nebraska have now had an opportunity to pass upon this important question in the selection of members of the Legislature, and I have no doubt but that you will faithfully represent the will of your constituents with reference to it. Prohibition is no longer an experiment in Nebraska. The abolition of the saloon has, without doubt, proven a great benefit to the people of the State. Ratification is the logical and proper action on the part of Nebraska, and I recommend that the federal prohibitory amendment be ratified. Americanization. One of the most important problems demanding your con - sideration is that of Americanization. It affects not only our citizens of foreign birth, but their children and their children's children. Whether the future generations in many communi - ties of Nebraska will be American in language, thoaght and ideals, the action of this Legislature will determine. In deal - ing with this problem, the prejudices engendered by the great conflict from which we have so recently emerged victorious should be forgotten. It affects not only those born under, or whose ancestors bore allegiance to the flag of the Nations with which we have so lately been at war, but also those from coun- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE tries whose sons have fought and died even as our boys have fought and died, that the world might be freed from the domination of men who have no regard for the inherent rights of mankind. Consideration should be given to the fact that many of our people of foreign birth, because of age and other disabilities, can never master our language. Under no circum - stances should people of this class be denied religions instruc - tion in a language they can understand. Under no circumstance should the worship of God be regulated by statute. The key to the problem of Americanization lies in the schools. If our language is used in the teaching of all secular branches in the lower elementary grades of public, private and parochial schools throughout the State, and if intelligent and persistent effort is made to inculcate the ideals and traditions of our conn - try into the hearts of our foreign born residents as well as those who may take up their abode among us in the future, the prob - lem of Americanization will, in the natural course of events. automatically solve itself. I, therefore, recommend legislation prohibiting the use in the teaching of all secular branches in the lower elementary grades of the public, private and parochial schools in Nebraska, of any foreign language, and requiring a curriculum in standard the equivalent of that taught in the public schools of the State. The Constitutional Convention. I felicitate the people of Nebraska because of the fact that they have declared in favor of a constitutional convention. The new constitution will, without doubt, provide a more economic and efficient method of handling the State's business than thru the multitude of Boards had under the present sys - tem. The Board system is not only expensive and inefficient, but in addition divides authority and responsibility. It is, at present, impossible to handle the State's affairs in the efficient manner that would be demanded by any business man in the conduct of his private transactions, and the thing most needed </seg>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1919 7 is a centralized responsibility for the discharge of the trust assumed by men who are elected by the people to serve as public officers. Divided authority and responsibility breeds waste and inefficiency, conditions too often incident to the expenditure of the funds raised in taxes from the people of the State. The new constitution will, without doubt, grant equal suffrage to all without regard to sex, and to confer upon women the right of franchise will be a merited recognition of their efforts and sacrifices in assisting the government to successfully prosecute the war. It should also provide practical methods and remove existent b;irs to the development of the State's water power and mineral resources and thereby eliminate one of our greatest sources of economic waste. The terms of state officials should be for four years instead of two, and the Legislature should meet after the men elected to state offices have had an opportunity to familiarize themselves with the needs of the State. State's Potash Resources. There are approximately eighteen potash lakes upon state lands in western Nebraska, sufficiently adjacent to each other to be pumped from a central plant. Two of them, known as the Briggs Lakes, are immensely rich in mineral deposit and are worth literally millions of dollars to the people of the State. Strenuous efforts have been made by the great potash cor - porations operating in Nebraska to secure control of these two valuable lakes which constitute the cream of the State's potash possessions. Such control would eliminate the possibility of a competing plant being constructed, the balance of the lakes not being sufficiently rich in potash to warrant the erection of a plant. Then, too, with the prospect of an additional plant eliminated, the corporations now operating could reasonably ex - pect to secure leases to the balance of the State's lakes at their own price, because the only outlet for the development of the </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE lakes retained by the State would be thru the plants already in existence. The successful conclusion of the war put an end to the neces - sity for immediate development of the State's potash lakes as an emergency war measure and by the same token, the days when potash plants costing $400,000 can be erected and paid for out of the earnings of the first hundred days of their operation, have gone, never to return. In providing for the development of tin- State's potash resources there should be but one consideration, viz: the best interests of the people of the State and their posterity. Nebraska is primarily an agricultural State. When our farmers are prosperous, the State as a whole will be pros - perous. The rich potash resources of the State should be con - served for use upon the farms of Nebraska. Under no circum - stances should they, now that the war is over, be bartered for paltry bonuses and royalties. I recommend that the State's potash resources be conserved until a State plant can be erected to develop same and to manu - facture fertilizer to be sold to the farmers of Nebraska at the actual cost of production. Federal Aid Eoads. Every message to the Legislature in recent years has em - bodied a recommendation for better roads, but the first intelli - gent step towards a permanent, well kept system of roads in Nebraska was taken by the Legislature in 1917, when they accepted federal aid and provided State aid for the purpose of constructing roads throughout the State. Under the Federal Good Roads Act passed by Congress in 1916, $1,600,694.97 was made available for expenditure in Ne - braska during the years 1917-1921, inclusive. This appropria - tion was to be expended under the supervision of the Office of Public Roads, U. S. Department of Agriculture, and the State Board of Irrigation, Highways and Drainage. It was condi - tional upon a like sum being provided by the State. The Ne- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1919 9 hraska Legislature in 1917 appropriated $640,000 and authorized the State Board of Irrigation, Highways and Drainage to proceed with the work of constructing highways in Nebraska. In co - operation with county officials, a state and federal aid road system has been designated, totaling approximately 5,000 miles ar.d connecting all county seats in the State. With the excep - tion of Keith, Keya Paha and Thurston, all counties have filed application for state ar.d federal funds, pledging the county to maintain the roads after sr.me are constructed. Under the super - vision of the State Engineer, 1,600 miles of road have been sur - veyed and plans, specifications and estimates for 1,100 miles have been prepared. Contracts have been awarded in Otoe, Nemaha. Richardson. Xuckolls, Clay, Adams, Kearney, Lincoln and Lancaster Counties for 215 miles of road to cost approxi - mately $500,000. With the exception of o\-&gt; miles of brick road in Lancaster County and 2 miles of gravel surface road in Hall County, the roads are all of earth construction. Road projects have been submitted to the Department of Agriculture to the number of 24, of which 21 have already, or will shortly, be approved. There is no reason why Nebraska should not have a well kept system of highways throughout the State and the work already commenced should be vigorously prosecuted until sr.rli a system is an established fact. Vocational Education, One of the weaknesses of our High School system has been the training of young people along the so-called cultural lines and the omission of practical lines. As a consequence, boys and girls have not been able to see the important relation be - tween their studies and the work they will perform in the world after their school years have passed. Vocational educa - tion fits the young people to make a living. The federal congress in 1917 passed the Smith-Hughes Act making funds available to the several States for the encourage - ment of vocational education. The 1917 session of our Legis - lature appropriated $21,000 to enable the State to qualify for </seg>
            <seg id="p010">GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE 10 federal aid in this work. Only $6,742.30 of this appropriation has been expended because of the fact that the war made it im - possible for the schools to secure competent teachers and for thta reason they could not meet the government requirements for state and federal aid. The total federal fund for the period beginning January 1st, 1919. and ending December 31st, 1921, is approximately $73,186. An appropriation of $55,000 by this Legislature will be necessary to enable the State to meet the federal requirements and to carry on this most important work during the next two years. During the past bieanium, agri - culture has been taught under the supervision of this Depart - ment in the High Schools at Bbir, Franklin, Hastings, Kimba'.l and Seottsbluff and in the Bratton-Uuion consolidated district, Nchawka consolidated district and Union-Center consolidated district schools. Home Economies has been taught in the Hooker County High School and the Alvo consolidated district school. Trades and Industries have been taught in the Omaha Commercial High School. Teachers who can qualify under the Smith-Hughes Act to instruct in agriculture, home economics and trades and industries are being trained at the University of Nebraska. War training classes in radio buzzer work have been maintained in the evenings at the University of Nebraska, Chadron State Normal, Kearney State Normal, Peru State Normal, Wayne State Normal, Doane College and the Omaha Y. M. C. A. Vocational education is of the greatest importance to Nebraska and it will be given a new impetus with the return of our fighting boys from over there. Many of them answered the call of their country before they completed their education and every effort should be made to fit them for their work in life in the years that are to come. Taxation of Banks, I deem it advisable to direct the attention of the Legislature to a ease now pending in the Courts affecting the assessment of banking associations for purposes of taxation. The First National Bank of Aurora appealed to the courts </seg>
            <seg id="p011">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 1919 11 from a decision of the State Board of Equalization and Assess - ment and the Hamilton County Commissioners, refusing to per - mit the deduction of government securities from the taxable Kssets of the institution, contending that such denial was, in effect, a taxation of the government non-taxable securities. The binl; claimed a lawful deduction of $95,473.77 from the amount of the capital stoek, being the par value of government bonds owned by the bank on April 1st. This deduction, if allowed, won'd reduce the valne of the Bank's taxable assets to $28."&gt;. The State Board of Equalization and Assessment has never, fvr a moment, contended that the State could tax government securi - ties. The attitude of the Board was, however, without doubt, misrepresented to the federal government and the United States Attorney for the District of Nebraska was directed to inter - vene as a friend of the Court for the purpose of protecting the government's interests. In order that your Honorable Body may be informed as to the attitude of the federal government, I quote from a letter written by the Assistant Attorney General of the United States on October 29, 1918: "The matter (alluding the Hamilton County Bank case) was referred to this Department by the Secretary of the Treasury with a statement that the papers seemed to indicate a direct tax on Liberty Bonds owned by national bands, but that it was possible that the tax whs in fact laid under section 6343 of the Revised Statutes of Nebraska npon the stock of national banking associations. Nevertheless, it was stated that the State of Ne - braska made a direct c'aim that "War Stamps, certificates of indebtedness, and Government bends are subject to a tax of 7.68 mills for State purposes." The Secretary therefore re - (inested this Department to instruct the United States Attorney to intervene in the suit as an amicus curiae merely that the Gov - ernment's interests therein might be set forth. The matter was called to the United States Attorney's attention in this light, and the statement was repeated to him that possibly the tax was being levied upon the stock of national banking associations, but the papers did not make this clear. His attention was called to the decision of the Supreme Court of the United States in Home Savings Bank v. Des Moines. 205 U. S. 503. and Farmers Bank v. Minnesota, 232 U. S. 516, and he was instructed to present the case to the court in the light of these authorities." </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE The United States Attorney, following the instructions of the Department, filed a petition of intervention as follows: "Comes now the said Thomas S. Allen, United States Attorney for the District of Nebraska, being thereto duly authorized by the Attorney General of the United States, and leave of this Honorable Court thereto being first had and obtained, respect - fully submits to the consideration of the Court in the above entitled cause. (a) That the government of the United States is directly and indirectly interested in the event of the above entitled cause. (b) That in the view of the Treasury Department and the Department of Justice of the United States, the United States has an interest in the outcome of this cause, and makes and submits the claim that the federal securities mentioned and de - scribed in the pleadings of this cause are not, either directly or indirectly, subject to state or local taxation. (c) That a denial of the right of said bank to deduct from the aggregate of the value of its assets for the purpose of taxa - tion the amount and value of said federal securities, amounts in effect to a taxation of its securities. (d) That the appeal of said bank in this cause should be sus - tained and said bank permitted to deduct the amount and value of said federal securities actually and in good faith held by it from the aggregate value of its assets for the purpose of taxation. THOMAS S. ALLEX j United States Attorney ror the District of Nebraska." The right of a state to tax the value of the shares of a bank - ing institution and the inability of a state to tax government securities, are not debatable questions. The only question in - volved in this suit is whether the refusal to permit the deduction of the value of government securities from the amount of the capital stock of the bank, is, in effect, a taxing of such securi - ties. The District Court of Hamilton County held that such denial was, in effect, a taxation of the securities and found in favor of the bank. . The revenue law of Nebraska, under which banking institu- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE 13 tinns are taxed, has been upheld by the Supreme Court of the State in the case of State v. Fleming, 70th Nebraska, "&gt;:*7, and alluding to the last clause of the Revenue law, being Sec - tion 6343, which reads: "Such association, bank or company shall pay the taxes assessed upon its stock and shall have a lien thereon for the same." The Court says: "This clearly con - templates an assessment not upon the capital stock of the bank itself, but upon the value of the shares held by the stockholders and against the stockholders. This is the only method in whicli revenue may be derived from National Banks. It is the only procedure authorized by the laws of the National Government." In a recent decision of the Supreme Court in the case of the Nemaha County Bank v. the County Board of Equalization and Assessment, the Court declared the following doctrine: "In assessing shares of stock for taxation, everything that enters into value must be included unless it has been separately as - sessed. ' ' The State Board of Equalization and Assessment is advised that under the Nebraska law which taxes the value of shares and not the assets of the institution, banks can no more deduct government securities from the amount of their capital stock for purposes of assessment than they could legally deduct real estate mortgages which are also not subject to taxation. Na - tional banks have never attempted to deduct government bonds used to guarantee circulation and there is no reason why Lib - erty Bonds should not be as acceptable to the government for the purpose of guaranteeing the circulation of banks as any other government security. The ownership of bonds used to guarantee the circulation of banks remains in the bank. Not to exceed a half dozen banks in Nebraska have made any effort to deduct government securities from their capital stock for pur - poses of assessment and it is improbable that any bank would contend that the value of its capital stock was impaired by the ownership of government bonds. If the decision of the District Court is sustained, any bank might possess a sufficient amount </seg>
            <seg id="p014">GOVERNOR'S MESSAGE 14 of bonds on April 1st to exempt it from paying any taxes what - ever and could dispose of the bonds the following day. An early ruling by the Supreme Court upon this question which is of such vital importance to the taxpayers of Nebraska, is most desirable and should the decision of the lower Court be upheld, it is the instant duty of this Legislature to make it im - possible for unscrupulous banking associations to evade legiti - mate taxation. State Hail Insurance It is especially gratifying to be able to announce to the Leg - islature that state hail insurance in Nebraska has proven a suc - cess in the first year of its operation. There were 6,014 policy - holders, of which number 760 sustained losses. The total prem - iums collected by the State amouated to $154,259.95, and the total losses were $125,286.63. The expense of administration amounted to $5,828.68 leaving a balance in the Treasury, after all losses and expenses had been paid, of $23,144.65. No other State, so far as I am able to learn, has ever paid 100% of the losses sustained by its policyholders. The state hail insurance should be well advertised before the next season, and ii° the number of policyholders can be considerably increased and well distributed throughout the State, there is no reason why 100% of losses cannot be paid year after year. Supreme Court Commission. The Supreme Court of Nebraska is now well abreast of its work and there is no further necessity for a Supreme Court Commission. Civil War Veterans' Reunion and Peace Jubilee. The 35th Session of the Legislature appropriated $20,000 to enable veterans of the Civil War to attend a reunion and peace jubilee held in October, 1917, at Vicksburg, Mississippi. J. S. Hoagland of North Platte, W. H. Stewart of Geneva, and W. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE 191* 15 Gifford of Lincoln were appointed a commission to supervise the expenditure of the appropriation. The Commission ap - pointed J. H. Pre8son, Secretary. The reunion was attended by 512 veterans from Nebraska and the expenses of the pilgrimage totaled $19,847.60. In agreement with the provisions of the constitution, I here - with append a list of all moneys collected thru the Executive Office and a list of all pardons and commutations issued under my hand. Conclusion. In conclusion I desire to express my appreciation of the cor - dial manner in which the members of the 35th Session of the Legislature of Nebraska, without regard to party, cooperated with the Chief Executive for the good of the state. I trust that you gentlemen will be actuated by the same desire for cordial cooperation with the honorable and distinguished gentleman the people of Nebraska have elected as my successor. KEITH NEVILLE, Governor of Nebraska. ADDENDA Moneys Collected by Executive Department. In keeping with Article 5, Section 7, of the Constitution, re- quiring a statement of moneys received and paid out by the Governor, I submit the following: For license to Druggists and other dealers to use and sell ethyl alcohol $1.43.00 For licenses to conduct Storage Warehouses 26.00 For extradition fees 87.00 For Commissioner of Deeds 25.00 The foregoing amounts have been paid into the State Treasury for which proper vouchers are on file in the Governor '■ office. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 GOVERNORS MESSAGE Reprieves, Commutations and Pardons. John Evans, No. 5763. Crime, safe blowing. Sentence, 28 years, Aug. 21, 1911. Commuted July 3, 1917, to 8 years. Bert Pickrell, No. 6061. Crime, murder 2nd degree. Sentence, 25 years, March 8, 1913. Commuted July 16, 1917, to 6 years. Calvin Wain, No. 4652. Crime, murder. Sentence, life, June 4. 1906. Commuted Nov. 6, 1917, to 16 years 5 months. John Ryan, No. 6973. Crime, forgery. Sentence, 1 to 20 years, Nov. 24, 1916. Pardoned Dec. 24, 1917. Max Ploehn, No. 4450. Crime, murder. Sentence, life, July 5, 1905. Pardoned Jan. 9, 1918. Lemuel G. Goldsberry, No. 6767. Crime, statutory rape. Sen - tence, 3 to 20 years, March 2, 1916. Commuted Feb. 25, 1918, to 2 years 8 months. Wm. Craig, No. 4508. Crime, murder 2nd degree. Sentence, life, Nov. 21, 1905. Commuted Feb. 9, 1918, to 12 years i months. Alson B. Cole, No. 7298. Crime, murder. Sentence, April 1, 1918. Sentence, death. Reprieved July 2, 1918, until Jan. 17, 1919, in order to serve as witness in case of another engaged in same crime. George B. Weed, No. 5802. Crime, murder 2nd degree. Sen - tence, life, Oct. 16, 1911. Commuted Dee. 14, 1918, to 10 years, 3 months, 21 days. Alma H. Weed, No. 5803. Crime, murder 2nd degree. Sen - tence, life, Oct. 16, 1911. Commuted, Dec. 14, 1918, to 10 years, 3 months, 21 days. Harry Heath, No. 5804. Crime, murder 2nd degree. Sentence, life, Oct. 16, 1911. Commuted Dec. 14, 1918, to 10 years, 3 months, 21 days. Joe Lewis, No. 6396. Crime, murder. Sentence, life, Sept. 9, 1914. Commuted Dec. 14, 1918, to 6 years. Louis Keezer, No. 5564. Crime, murder. Sentence, life, Dee. 5, 1910. Commuted Dec. 23, 1918, to 12 years. Isadore Sitzman, No. 5565. Crime, murder. Sentence, life, Dec. 5, 1910. Commuted Dec. 23, 1918, to 12 years. In all of the above named cases, my action has been based on the unanimous request in most cases, and a majority in all, of the State Board of Pardons, and upon the recommendation of the Trial Judge, and of those engaged in the prosecution. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>