<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes</title>
               <date value="1922-06">1922-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Hulli-tin 180 June, 1922 Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes O. RANKIN THE READING MATTER ARRIVES M ne-tenths of the farm homes studied were reached by mail delivery. AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF THE UNI VERSITY OF NEBRASKA AND UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY BY LINES especially need amusement at home. Page 3. inspiration, and information to use Farmers and town people get very .iniilar reading matter. Pages 4-6. iame things, but owners get a little Owners and tenants read about the more. Pages 6 and 7. Part-owners get still more periodicals of most kinds. Page 10, Figure 2. Page 11. rding matter in Nebraska farm homes should and largely dot 1. Conserve past progress. Page 7. 2. Aid future progress. Page 8. 3. Aid in farm marketing. Page 8. 4. Furnish rural mental recreation. Pages 8 and 9. 5. Develop a liberal healthy class consciousness. Pain •&gt; '. Periodicals reach almost all Nebraska farms studied. Page 10 Farm papers and newspapers furnish most of the r Pages 10-12. Women's magazines reach between a fourth a i Page 12. Family or general magazines reach a sixth of the homes. F Children's magazines reach less than one horr studied. Page 13. Reading matter varies a little with local needs. Pages 14 Books from libraries enter about one home in every twenty. Figun Each farm home must supply many of its own needs. Pag Book loans the library's main service to farm homes. Pa Book and magazine clubs help, but libraries are needed. Pa State commission traveling libraries are cht t unsupplied. Pages 22-24. County library systems render the promptest and the rv Page 24. Library extension may foster book wagons, rtory telling, an coir munity meetings. Page 24. Library stations make books accessible to the people. Page 24 Nebraska libraries are cordial toward country patronage. Page 26 Bibliography. Pages 27 and 28. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes J. O. RANKIN 1 Reading matter is important. — "Tell me what you read and 1 will tell you what you are." Judged by this standard, how does the Nebraska farm tenant compare with his neighbor who owns the farm he operates or with his cousin who lives in townt How well is his household supplied with the printed page's news, The fanner is even more dependent upon the printing press an the town dweller. It is harder for him to keep in touch FIG. 1.— WHERE THE FACTS CAME FROM dicate areas in which the reading matter of 1338 farm home* was studied. ibout one dot shows where reading matter of 18b town homes was studied. witli the world or to obtain his information or instruction or avr his •rood times by attending the school, the church, the tdge, the leeture. the hall game, the fair, the theater, or the mov- 1 Based mainly upon the results of a survey conducted in cooperation with Drs. C. J. Galpin and L. C. Gray of the Office of Farm Management and Farm Economics of the United States Department of Agriculture in 1920-1921. The manuscript was submitted to that Office and the drafting done by it from data and rough copy supplied by the author. Some portions are based in part upon a survey made in cooperation with the Interchurch World-Movement during the preceding winter. Acknowledgments are also due to mem - bers of the teaching staff of the Department of Rural Economics of the University of Nebraska and officers and members of the Nebraska Public Library Association and of the Nebraska Public Library Commission for suggestions and criticisms ; to one or two Held men in each area ; and to Messrs. S. C. Baasett and L. A. Wight for a vary com - plete statement of the periodical literature entering the town and country community of Gibbon, Nebraska. ntcrtiiiiiiiifiit. instruction, and inspiration* </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 4 ing picture. When these have done their best for him there is still much time that must be used at home — more time than in case of most other people of similar economic and financial in - dependence. Bain, snow, mud, and the nature of his work keep him more constantly at home. His spare time comes most largely when it is least convenient to other activity away from home. go raiting or to eagage in any Be is more in need of enjoyment and teaching that io not take him away where lie can not Ml and hear what is happening to his livestock or other property His wife and children likewise depend more upon the home an&lt;; what they can use there than do the women and children of thf TOWN AND COUNTRY COMPARED Country and small town reading much alike. N farmers seem to realize the valin pretty well supplied with farm of the printed page and and news reading matt indicated by a study of that which reaches about 1,500 in the State. The reading matter of the village or ran home was studied for comparison with that on the farn one of the eleven Nebraska areas in which the 1.."&gt;(H) farms were located. The community center of this region was ai w eastern Nebraska town of less than l.(XX) population, rather typical except that it is located near enough sill have a small part of its country weekly circiilati&lt; that of a local daily. It had a little lew than L'(M) and supplied about 3(M) farm homes with periods matter. Town and country homes appeared about equally v \ supplied with daily newspapers but the countn more weekly and not quite so many month I"- household. There were almost exactly as many subscriptions to daily papers as there were homes. This was true in country and town alike. The character of the daily paper taken was a little differ ent, however. A fifth of the country daily papers were liv stock market reports and another fifth were subscriptions to a </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Readim; Matter ix Nebraska Farm Homes 5 paper published in a near-by small city which supplied the town with more than a quarter of its daily paper subscriptions. If we omit the livestock market papers, we thus find that the aver - age town household was a little better supplied with daily newg than the farm home of this region. Every four weeks the average village home received daily, weekly, and monthly periodicals to the total number of 43.5 issues as conipared with 4-'5 per open country home — about one daily. -.') weekly, and three monthly periodicals per town home ne daily, three weekly, and three monthly periodicals per country home. Each month the village dwellers received only M trade or professional journals, which are in some ways the town equivalent of the farm newspaper and farm magazine. The farm m a jjraziin* and farm newspaper went into even the homes in twice as great numbers as did the trade and pro- :il journals The American Legion Weekly happened to go exclusively country homes and the Stars and Stripes exclusively into the town homes. Nearly twice as many religious weeklies and more tlian five times as many religious monthly periodicals went into the town homes as into the open country homes, in spite of the fact that the latter are about one and one-half times as numerous, but the vast majority of both country and town homes were without any religious periodicals whatever. Similarly, fraternal publications went more largely to the town homes if we omit the 158 subscriptions to the Nebraska Grange Journal, all of which were from country homes. Only seven of the nearly 500 homes of the community received any children's publications. These seven were all open country homes. Women's and house - hold publications, however, reached the community to the extent of 414 subscriptions, of which the open country homes had 238 and the town homes had 176, so country and town had each about its proportionate share. Local weekly newspapers reached the town to the extent of 124H subscriptions, or a little more than enough for one for each household. The country took them to the extent </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska IIiXPEriment otation 1&gt;i i.i.ktin lbO of 269 subscriptions, or less than one per household, but 40 of the open country homes received the daily paper published in a neighboring small city, so there were almost exactly enough sub - scriptions to local daily and weekly newspapers to supply each open country home with one, if two or more of the seven local papers circulated in this territory did not enter the same house - hold leaving some without any. The few foreign language publications went entirely into the country homes, while the somewhat greater number of family publications intended for reading by the entire household went largely to the town homes. This makes it very easy to see why the great demand that farm people make upon libraries is for fiction. They are well supplied with news and agricultural peri odicals and can pal all the agricultural experiment station an.l other bulletins they want thru the farm bureau, or otherwise, but in many eases have little or no other reading matter. ' OWNER, TENANT, AND HIRED MAN Tenants need more but get leas. -The Nebraska teaai tually gets less periodical reading matter than the owner c owner, altho it seems reasonable to believe that he Med He may be working even more hours per day to climb th. cultural ladder" from his past condition el farm hand t t mortgaged land owner and finally debt free owner. He is inger and even more in need of the better methods to he learned m the printed experience of others. In Nebraska the tenant is a little farther from town, school. and some other activities than is the owner-operator. He moves oftener and is sometimes not quite so well established as a mem - ber of club, church, lodge, or other group and is less able to afford the expense ; but he and his household are often younger and more in need of recreation and growth. Nebraska tenants do not differ as much from owners as do those of many other t Later pacei of this bulletin include no data from this arem in which both town and IT reading matter wu studied. They are in Keneral harmony with the data of this but were completed before the Gibbon data beeame available. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes 7 stat atei is si ther and t tit I iiiir pert' test s, but such differences as do exist are in the directions indi - 1. Many of the differences are so slight as to be negligible, io\vn hv studies of over eleven hundred Nebraska farms, but ■ is &lt;i difference of several years in average ages of owners tenants. l'lie Nebraska tenant, who is perhaps a little better edu - 1 than the owner, may be able to make a fuller and better ding matter and may need more of it. He grew up a ■ when schools may have been a little better, he may ue to school longer than the older man who has already I the ownership of a farm; but. as we shall see more ly later, he is not getting quite so much of the product printing pres: Hired men. — Less than a sixth of the hired men took news- Hi and far fewer took magazines or farm papers of their •rot books from libraries. They appeared to rely almost on their employers' reading matter. In the Milligan hired man took any periodical of his own and this was v true in the southwestern Nebraska areas and in M eastern Nebraska areas. Most of the hired men's us reported were in the Xehawka and Filley areas, w in the Stromsburg and Walthill areas. Owner and tenant get about the same. — Among owners, part- ints, with little variation, the same general ppeared. Newspapers and farm magazines furnished great mass of their periodical reading matter with family, religious, fraternal, miscellaneous, and juvenile periodicals following and ranking in frequency in the order PRESS FUNCTIONS Services rendered. — The periodicals found in farm homes are orming a fivefiold service for Nebraska agriculture. (1) The tried and true farm methods that have met the of past experience are being kept before those who should </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 \rHRARK 4 FTPFfiTUFVT StaTIOV Rfl I PTT\ 1 RO practice them now and the mistakes of the past emphasized just enough to prevent their repetition. (2) Progress is aided by the spread of knowledge of the current experience of other localities and other countries and of new facts constantly Mag discovered by agricultural experiment stations, home economics departments of colleges of agriculture, and numerous other agencies working for similar purposes. (3) The periodical press and certain free bulletins distrib uted monthly, weekly. &lt;&gt;r even daily to those espeeially interested who request them bring market and financial reports that help to answer the questions. "When, where, and bow shall we market our products.' What crops shall we grow.' Shall we market them as grain and hay or as meat and as milk, cream, butter, or cheese? Shall we sell directly from the threshing maehin chard, or field, or shall we store until iome future time whei product will be more useful to the aMMMf and w higher prices .' What are the oar praapeetsi What able future prices for instance of coal, grocer other things we must buy for use on the Kami Ho take advantage of the conditions of supply and den of letting others have all the advantage of this 1 (4) Recreation and pleasure are import*] every member of -the farm household obtain from reading. Relaxation i f sake of having a good time but al All work and no play makes poor workera not only of the pi verbial Jack but of his father, mother, brothers, ai Properly selected reading matter will greatly inrmaat physical and the mental pleasures of farm life and will the social and community life. It is just at this point that the reading matter of Nebraska farm homes appears to fall furthest short of its possibilities. Tlu Nebraska farm dweller can get many of the benefits of visiting other people in our own country and abroad without the expense of travel. We can profit from the best of art and learn what the world is doing, know the thoughts of the best minds, and </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Reading Maiter in Nebraska Farm Homes 9 strange people ami scenes, without leaving our homes. Thru the printed page the children may voyage to fairyland in imagination and all can i:&lt;un more pleasure from the fairyland of nature about them and make the press aid in maintaining health without so much expense for doctors visits. Homemade fun is often much better than purchased fun and less likely to leave had after effects. It is better to play in a ball 0MM Of any other game than to sit and watch without fretting the benefit of the exercise, the training and team work, or any of the other good effects of participating. It is much better for the country community to secure its own well-selected plays and present them for itself, even if crudely, than to depend upon the commercialized amusements which can be purchased at much a performance by going away from home. (o) A healthy class consciousness without bitterness toward my other class but with great respect for the business of farming appreciation of advantages and possible improvements of ry life is aided rather than hindered by most of the peri- odical* found in the homes in the areas covered in this survey. A good librarian in each Nebraska farm county in charge of a uity library lending properly selected books as traveling or x libraries to the stores or churches or perhaps best of all to mtrv of the county would accomplish wonders in •tion. Such a librarian must understand the country Wf may best understand and most fully enjoy lea when it is expressed in the terms of the life which Much that is best in our art and literature is expressed country life, country people, farm livestock, and farm crops. Some most excellent novels have their plots laid in our own section, and the farm papers are beginning to publish such stories serially. Some of our best pictures, such as The Auxins. The Song of the Lark, and Rosa Bonheur's famous animal pictures, present country scenes or subjects and can best be understood and appreciated by the people who best under - stand and appreciate the original in actual life. Of course, the mental diet of the open country should not be so exclusively of </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 10 this character as to result in a narrow provincialism or elaa sciousness but only enough to give a proper self-understan and self-respect. Such a well-developed, lmt not overdevelc self-respect on the part of all classes combined with a pr understanding of each class liy all the others would reduce &lt; mi din;: ped. [&gt;|)ff lass friction and strife to the minimum. BP. IOC 9C OIHEHS 90 sc PABT-OIHERS ■ : 1 RUITS TO 60 ■sc 50 II W 3C X m * ■ ■lit o !■ — mmn ■ H 21 CHILERES'S LIBRiHT fOKEI'S MA5AZISES BOOKS USiZISES 3EFERA NEWSPAPERS riHH UZAZlttS PAPER: FIG. 2.— PUBLICATIONS RECEIVED IN FARM HUM Newspapers and farm papers furnish th? and children's publications are must n*tfl«'&lt;-i PERIODICALS RECEIVED Periodicals in every home. — Practically every boi received periodical reading matt ir. Lists of the papers and magazines taken were obtained in :i!l cases out of every 40, leaving nly 2.6 per cent or 1 out of every 40 to he regarded as (1) receiving no periodicals or (2) failing to report any of those received. These failures to report were highest in the sandhills nd southwestern Nebraska areas, not in the areas peopled by the oreign-born or by those of immediate foreign descent. In fact in </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes 11 M other area were periodicals more universally reported thau in hat about Stromshiirir. when- the Swedish element predomi- I'art-ow ners reported more universally than either owners .. in s|)ite of tin 1 fai-t that a disproportionately high per - f the part -owners are in the newer regions in which &gt;wners and tenants most frequently failed to report receiving matter Newspapers. Newspapers reach practically every home ied. Tlie &lt;rivat bulk of those found were (1) country week- i dailies published ill Omaha. Lincoln, or Kansas City, published in smaller cities which happened to be near ) the areas studied seemed to some extent to displace both weekly and the daily from a larger but more distant city, subscription* were to dailies published in cities farther ) Kansas City. \ much smaller circulation was enjoyed in those areas by lation news and farm papers as are published in con - th some dailies. Only about one out of every eight ied received two dailies; and one out of every sixty ree. In no case did four or more dailies reach the hut at least one was received in each of nearly three - lie homes. It has been sufTfrested that this fraction •rher than it was in normal pre-war times and that it is now inin&lt;r toward its former status, but this study has not been xtended to cover that point. Farm papers. Farm papers reached more than three out of very four homes studied. In number of issues per week or per month they were excelled by newspapers but were far ahead of all other kinds of periodicals. Nearly half the homes received two. three, or even six farm papers apiece. The farm papers reported were much more widely scattered than the newspapers, but the vast majority of them were pub - lished in Nebraska or adjoining states. The principal exceptions were livestock papers devoted to the livestock irfdustry in general or to the interests of particular breeds. Of 1,529 subscriptions </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 to farm papers reported, 862 or 56.3 per cent were to papers published in Nebraska, 201 in Iowa, 135 in Kansas, 64 in Missouri, and 51 in Pennsylvania. The others were very widely scattered, representing special livestock breeds or other interests and in some instances perhaps the state of former residence of the sub - scriber or a state in which he had some particular interest or from which chance subscriptions an- scut to him. Women's magazines. — Next to the child and youth the house - wife and especially the tenant's wife is generally least well pro - vided with periodicals published mainly to aid her to enjoy farm life and make a better farm home. It' children's magazines and books are not plentiful in the areas studied, women's magazines and family magazines are only less rare. While this is true of the magazines devoted mainly to the needs of women, childr and the family as a whole, it is also true that these needs supplied in part at least by the daily and weekly newspap and the farm papers that are generally present in the hoim- Perhaps it would be mueli truer to say that all members of I given tenant or owner household are equally supplied with iding matter. All have aeeess to every printed page that enters • home. Each may. then, select from each publication those s from which he gets the most enjoyment or benefit. However is may be, it seems fair to say that the great bulk of the reading itter found on Nebraska farms in this survey comes in publi - tions whose main purpose is Is take ears of the news and the liar side of life and deals secondarily if at all with home-build - ? and the things that make life more worth while in the country, my of the periodicals taken are of course paying a great deal attention to making farm life more worth living as well as enabling the farmer to feed and clothe the world more effec- Only sixteen different women's magazines were reported, with a total of 304 subscriptions received, in the 1,034 homes studied individually. Enough homes received more than one woman's magazine, however, so that nearly three homes out of every four were left entirely unsupplied. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes 13 I Family magazines. — Family magazines found in 1,034 farm mifs totaled 149 subscriptions to 32 different family magazines, )ut 16 of these magazines had 133 of the subscriptions and the ither 16 had only DM subscription apiece. These family or household magazines reached only about one MM out of every five studied. They reached a little higher WMlUtl &lt;&gt;f part-owners" than of owners' or tenants' homes but fferenee was not great. Juvenile. — Perhaps the most startling fact revealed by this uly is the almost total absence of periodicals intended primarily he younger members of the household. Only four children's ieations with only 31 subscriptions in all reached the 1,034 ouicn. — less than one home out of every thirty-three. Sunday ehool papers doubtless received by many who reported Sunday ehool attendance would of course swell this showing, and a certain f juvenile matter may be gleaned from news and farm ii and from school books and books in the home; but it is ul whether all of these combined can satisfactorily replace the juvenile periodical, which seems to be reaching only four per eent of Nebraska farm owners' homes and about half that portion of tenant homes. Miscellaneous periodicals. — Less than a hundred subscrip - tions were reported which were not classifiable under any of the groups already dismissed. They are probably indicative of kinds of publications which (1) have a greater circulation elsewhere in the State or ( 2 | were purposely or inadvertently omitted from lists given to enumerators. They include about twenty-five sub - scriptions to religious papers, a few to fraternal journals, and three to a musician's journal. The remainder are almost all foreign-language papers — Bohemian, German, and Swedish. A later inquiry covering 61 of the homes of the Milligan area showed Bohemian papers entering 35 of the 61. The re - ligious papers had in most cases only one subscription apiece. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 THE AREAS tMost of the individual areas studied show some special tures in addition to the general situation already stated. Per - &gt;s the changes from east to west and from south to north may t be suggested by beginning with the southeasternmost area area E working west and north, altho such influences are o ured by such local conditions as the pnMlM of the for&lt; this area appear to depend distinctly more upon weekly and daily newspapers than those of most areas and less than usual upon farm papers, as an unusually high percentage failed in this Ei to report the taking of any farm papers whatever. No public ary is within easy reach, but a few who had children in the solidated school reported borrowing books from that source. THE EASTERN NEBRASKA AREAS The Nehawka area in Cass County. — Three principal peculiar- ities or deviations were ubaeived in the area about Nehawka. (1) Part-owners made I better thawing than either tenants or owners on most points. "_' No library books whatever were reported as secured by any of the households visited \,\r there was reported a distinct tendency to supply this lack of library patronage in pari by exchanging hooks with neighbors. Every owner and more than nine-tenths of the tenants took farm papers, seven out of every ei?ht took daily newspapers, and doubtless a very high percentage :&lt;&gt;ok weekly newspapers. but women's, children's, and family magazine! were taken by only about the usual percentages. I The Filley area in Gage County. I e Pilley area lies elve miles east of Beatrice in one of the older, better developed regions of the State near a small country town. It is outside the immediate influence of the city of Beatrice in most particulars except that the daily papers taken are mainly those published in that city. A few Lincoln and Omaha papers are taken and a few livestock market dailies were reported. The farmers in </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes 15 I The Milligan area in Fillmore County. — A special study was Bohemian farm homes of the Milligan area. Not I home received less than two publications, and all but three r or inntv apiece, the average being 6.3. The monthly wiis most frequent with M6 subscriptions or nearly If per household. This included monthly farm uilv. women "s, and household magazines, and a few paper*. The receipt of only :{i3 dailies might seem jck of news supply, but 51 of the 60 received \\ spiipers and much news wu doubtless supplied by the is Hohcmiiiii papers taken. These Bohemian papers in- !(i weeklies, fi bimonthlies, and 4 dailies. Aside from foreign laagaag* papers and magazines taken were miscellaneous in eharaeter. The better ones und and the nondescript periodicals were extremely The Geneva area in Fillmore County. — Of the 107 farms ied in the area about Geneva, not one was without newspapers nd. Every tenant and all but one of the owners took rs. while two owners out of every five and one tenant ry six pot books out of the library. The Stromsburg area in Polk County. — The people of the Strniiishurj.' area arc mainly of immediate Swedish descent; yet only one foreign language paper was reported, but unusually high percentages took women's and children's periodicals and obtained library books. Not far from half of all homes received women's periodicals. Newspapers were taken by more than nine-tenths and farm papers by nineteen out of every twenty owners and nine-tenths of all operators, owners being distinctly in advance Source &lt;&gt;j run], '/hi/ matter: (lenem area All ho»«« Number Percent Owwn Teaanto Number | Per cent Number ; Per cent •»ry 107 10? IN 106 99.1 28 26.4 41 M 41 10* M IN 40 !&gt;-.* M 100 17 41.4 11 1«.« </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 16 of tenants on this point. Nearly all of the owners took more than one farm paper apiece, so did every tenant and many of the part-owners. Part-owners were in this area markedly below both owners and tenants in all reading matter particulars except that they excelled tenants in the matter of farm papers. Owners and tenants were about equal in the use of library facilities, with owners slightly in the lead. The Clay Center-Fairfield area in Clay County. — The (lay Center-Fairfit'ld area seems &lt;|iiite representative of the State so far as the data fathered indicate exeept that it seems to rely to a little more than the usual degree upon the paper for reading matter and to a less degree upon library books, altho there is a good public library building with facilities to meet all de - mands in each of the towns of the area. The Walthill area in Thurston County. — The pccKMc of ar Indian reservation prevented much of the land of the Walthill area from being brought under cultivation as early as that in adjacent northeastern Nebraska regions. The fact that much, of the land is still owned by the Indians results in the presence of extremely large percentages of cash tenancy and of part-owner operatorship. These tenure pecularities do not seem to have made any marked difference in the relative emphasis placed upon the different kinds of periodicals, altho there was an un - usually high percentage reporting subscriptions to weekly news - papers and only a single subscription to any child's magazine. A sandhill area. — The Logan County area lies in the vicinity £ Gandy and Stapleton in the southern portion of the sandhill region, which occupies about a quarter of Nebraska "s land area. iltho sparsely settled, this area makes a showing in many ways ery much like that of others of the State in reading matter ound. It differed mainly in (1) the entire absence of children's magazines and of any books secured from any library source whatever, (2) an unusually high percentage of homes receiving amily magazines, and (3) an unusually large proportion of religious and fraternal periodicals, altho these constituted little </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes 17 more than a negligible percentage even in this county. All classes of periodicals were low both in number of homes entered and in number of subscriptions per home. THE SOUTHWESTERN NEBRASKA AREAS 01 the two arciis studied in the southwestern part of the e neither lies in the estreat western portion. One is near Sf Cutbridgc in Furnas County in the southernmost tier just far enough west to be distinctly in the southwest quarter of the State. The other is near Grant in Perkins County. The Cambridge area mainly in Furnas County. — Alt ho the area i-entering about Cambridge lies mainly in Furnas County, it extends across the boundary into Red Willow and Frontier It is divided by the Republican River, which makes &lt; ■odenteijr rough and tends to adapt it to the production excellent lireatoek, particularly cattle and hogs. It naturally lows that the livestock papers more liberally intermingle with ■ farm magazines than in the other areas studied and that the daily newspapers come almost exclusively from the livestock centers in and out of Nebraska, even aside from the livestock market dailies. The periodical literature of this area seems to consist almost entirely of newspapers and farm papers. Only five homes reported receiving family magazines, one home a wo - man's magazine, and not a single one reported receiving any children's magazines or other publication for the younger mem - bers of the household or any library books whatever from any source. The Grant area in Perkins County.— The westernmost area studied lies in the vicinity of Grant in Perkins County. It has a much higher proportion of part-owners and lower proportion of owners and tenants than most of the areas farther east. Be - cause of the absence of rural free delivery or for other reasons, there is a much lower reliance upon daily newspapers and a far greater reliance upon local and other weekly newspapers for the ii&lt; ws than in any other area studied. About the usual proportion </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 18 tiok family magazines but an unusually high percentage took omen's magazines, particularly among the tenants, as compared with the tenants of other areas, altho they were exceeded by the part-owners of this area, two-fifths of whom took women' magazines. OTHER READING MATTER HOME OWNED Non-periodical reading matter. Tun other town ing matter were (1 I boaki owned in the homes studied farm bulletins obtainable from the College of Agriculture or tin county agent. Both differ from the periodicals already in that they are seeured onlv on special order or requi Nebraska, altlm in tome states 1 ulletins are sent eith or at irregular intervals to r&lt;"_ r however, farm bulletin* go only liar nailing lists. In X to those who have take) interest and trouble in writ in hi it v «it' Nebraska Ag periment Station and most tl states are mailed without eha the supply is exhausted. The free bulletins of the United States Depart culture that are of greatest value in Nebraska by county agents and at the College of Agrienl Nebraska. From either of these soiin Ml the asking. Lists of the free bullet ins are distribut wish to make their own selections instead of allowin or the county agent to select for them LIBRARIES AND READING CIRCLES Some means of improvement. — We have now seen what read ing matter the Nebraska tenant farmer has. and how h &gt;m- pares with owners and part-owners. In what ways is this situa- tion likely to change in the future? Is the situation growing better or worse? What agencies and forces are at work in Xe- braska material delivered regular] special request is the newspaper ;i All the bulletins of the University </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes 19 !&gt;ra \ r it 1 Cm w&lt; throw any light upon our probable future de - nt by noting what has already happened in other portions country I ka !'" it has passed further ami further from pioneer conditions, ding public lias doubtless found more time and more A far raadng natter of all kinds. The changes have been rily brought about by the individual homes or little groupa ! banded together into reading circles, magazine clubs, s. and cooperative libraries. Better education has helped the demand for reading matter. perative reading circles and clubs increase the in - ii reading and reduce the cost of books and peri - seeured. If there are six homes united in the circle each an get the most of the benefit of six new books rice of one if they agree to purchase one apiece and then reading circles or study clubs may be purely for partly or wholly for profit and educational growth. results are sure to follow in one proportion or another. matters with one partial exception have been best \ te instead of public agencies in the country ne exception is the book, which may be more supplied by the public library than by the private nies. Of course each home should have its u books, but few homes own all the books they could lily, or have the ability to make as wise a selection brarian should. e public library can not accomplish the same economy a/.ines that it can of books, for country readers, and the newspaper is still further out of possibility of public library ilation to country people. The town people can to a con- rable extent economize in this way. They can come into the library to read periodical literature, but country people must do all or nearly all their reading of periodicals at home. Libraries and library extension. — To country people, then, public libraries mean more books. A glance at Figure 3 will show that more than three-fifths of all the people of Nebraska are with- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 Et access to public library facilities, and that as things are now ganized those parts of the State which have the fewest people towns have also tin- lowest percentage of the people living in territory served by libraries, is located, is the only county of the people have access t&lt;&gt; Douglas County, in which Omaha in which ninety per cent or limn - library facilities, and Lancaster County comes next with between seventy and eighty per cent its people in territory entitled to library facilities. more appreciation and profit. They read less fur timc-k.illin« or mere entertainment, and more for information and inspiration Their close and familiar contact with nature and the simple fundamental things of life gives them greater power of inter - pretation for the great literature of nature and life than city- Pi; j | | | | | | | I | FIG. 3. NEBRASKA'S I'NI.IBRARIED POPULATION Lcm than two-fifths have access to public library facilities. The sparser the popu- lation the greater its dependence on home-owned reading mattrr. This dearth &lt;&gt;f lil&gt;r;iry taeilitK* exists in ipite of tin- gre»1 need stated by our nation;)! Commissioner of Kilucat ion whei he said: "If time permitted I would like to say a lew word' in emphasis of the importance oi proridiBg booka for pe&gt;pl&lt; living in the open eountry and rillagea under rural eonditions For many reasons these people have nior.- time for reading Thai city people, and will read the l&gt;fst Itooks. of the best type, wit! </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Rkadinc; Matter ix Nebraska Farm Homes 21 bred people are likely to have, and their time for reading comes in larger sections and with less interruption. I have been a country hoy myself and have lived in the backwoods, three mill's t'niin the crossroads store and the blacksmith shop. I know the long rainy Sundays, the long succession of rainy days during the wet spells of the crop-growing season, the long snowy days of winter, and the long winter evenings with nowhere to t haii a dozen miles away, and the shut-in feeling. Under a Club Room o Office Co. *gem £ Miscellaneous FIG. 4. WHERE THE TRAVELING LIBRARIES WENT Each symbol shows where the Nebraska Public Library Commission sent a travel - library during the two years ended November 30. 1920. A large share went into 'ssible to farmers 1&lt; than in the city, where one must hold the attention against a H Meeting the need. — Probably the library need is not perfectly met anywhere, but Nebraska laws have already made possible at least a start along the lines that have been found most successful in other states. These lines include (1) a state library commission, i 2 1 public libraries. :! school libraries, (4) library extension activities thru book wairons or trueks, (5) reading circles, and (•) the use of the library building as a community center. The libraries may operate independently or as county 1 Claxton. P. P.. Libraries for Rural Communities. Papers and Proceeding's of the Thirty-sixth Annual Meeting of the American Library Association. May 25-29. 1914. 150. ■■tanrra ■ kaok becomes a close companion, closer d tempting dntractiom.' </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 22 systems which have the general advantages of the consolidated school largely without its disadvantages. Library Commissions. — The traveling libraries circulated in boxes by the library commissions of many states furnish the cheapest means of meeting the farmer's need for good books. They should be used in addition to, but not instead of. a local library system. They are cheaper because the box of fifty or sixty books not only serves all people of one community but FIG. 5. TRAVELING LIBRARY LOAN Each dot indicates one box of from 40 to 60 be two yean ended November 30. 1920. after being returned to the commission for repa Ut a (rain to serve community after community. This may be done by only one central library staff and at the very lowest possible cost per book per person. Figure 5 shows where these travi-lin&lt;: libraries went in N'e - raska during 1919-19:20. Not all of these were placed primarily, r even largely, at the disposal of farmers, but Figure 4 will sug - est fairly definitely which were so placed. The Nebraska Public .library Commission at Lincoln loans its traveling libraries so ar as they are available to "any library, community, local or - anization, either incorporated or unincorporated, or any body f citizens or tax-payers organized for library purposes . . . upon complying with the rules prescribed by this commission." The provisions of the commission's form used in applying for </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Reading Matter in Nebraska Farm Homes 23 traveling libraries require the signature of a number of resident taxpayers of the community which desires to borrow. The group agrees to provide a suitable place for the traveling library and to loan tlie books without charge to any one in the community who obeys tin' tixed rules and who pays promptly for all loss or dMMft to the books or cases except those resulting from ordinary use. The form of application used calls also for the name of the person in charge of whom tlie traveling library is placed, the FIG. «. POSSIBLE LIBRARY STATIONS IN RURAL SCHOOLS the map would have looked had each Nebraska country school received loan library just once during the two years. Compare Figure 5. statement of the place in which it will be put at the disposal of the public, and the hours during which it will be open. Each traveling library is made up of about forty volumes, selected with special reference to the needs of the readers. It is loaned for three months with the privilege of extending the time. Special study clubs may secure books selected to meet their needs, and individuals may borrow from 1 to 12 or 15 books apiece, the length of the loan depending upon the circumstances. The commission as far as possible promotes and assists by counsel and encouragement the formation of libraries where none exist. It may send members or officers at its expense to aid in organiz - ing new libraries or improving those already established. State library commissions can furnish the most highly trained supervision, ability, and advice, and make library loans more eco- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 180 24 nomically than any other agency, but there are certain things they can not do as well as local libraries or library systems. They cannot be as well acquainted with the needs of the people of particular counties or townships. They cannot respond as Emptly to the requests of the er borrowers. They are pe ■itory without other library local farmers, county agents, or rmanently needed (1) to serve facilities and (2) to supplement the books already in local libraries l&gt;y sending them traveling libraries. FIG. 7. TAX-SUPPORTED PUBLIC I.IBRAR1E Some of them have branches but many of them d&lt; but m Other library extension.- While the fully develi&gt;| library system is probably better mid mon- efficient under favor - able circumstances than any other means of gating books to farmers, there are many valuable services t&lt;&gt; lie performed on ■ smaller scale. Book wagons are soniet inies run to the farmer's door. Library buildings so far as their accoinmodat ions permit may be used as community center buildings. Story-telling for the benefit of the children may be a valuable adjunct even in the smaller communities. kThe library station in the country school or elsewhere is )bably the most practical library extension plan under most braska conditions. A brief account of the operation of a </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Reading Matter a Nebraska Farm Homes 25 leriea of such ■tationa from a distinctly "rurban" library w- if that there was a need for a largrer collection as well type of books in our rural schools both for teachers V riment by placing small libraries pupils, we decided to expi which were outside our township 'ols, six of \s we could not spare from our own shelves the ■amber of books required for this work, we borrowed a hundred FIG. 8.- A TOWNSHIP LIBRARY AT SHELTON Public Library was built, supported, and patronized by town and Le on a tax basis. It supplies reading matter to many outside the pports it. s from the Nebraska Public Library Commission, to we added sixty from our own shelves. We then divided Hues into sets of 20 volumes each and sent them to The work of preparation was done by the librarian. Cards •oiitaininsr authors and titles were tiled alphabetically and sent &gt;ut with the books. This simplified the record work so that our rural teachers, who have always helpers, could care for the char;. been our most loyal and efficient in? and circulation. ■ Vow. Mrs. B. A., former librarian, neither rural nor urban but "rurban" since iied by town and country cooperating. Shelton public library. This library is it was established, maintained, and patron- n </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bii.letin 1K0 26 t" Books were loaned to schools for three months, then re - ed and exchanged. In this way we kept these books in tant circulation and from time to time added others from shelves, also loaning periodicals for short periods. k"Thru th&lt;- county agent and the College of Agriculture we red lists of recommended hooks on agricultural subjects ie we purchased and loaned with tin- several collections. b'^Ve found that while our rural readers read and appreci - these books to some considerable extent, the great demand for recreational reading. Now while this plan must necessarily fall far short of what might be accomplished thru a {Treat improvement over existing and unqualified approval of th boards, teachers, pupils, and a it an interesting and very niu it not only furnished books to Bounty library system, it wa&gt; conditions and bad the supp • County Superintendent, aefa lult patrons and we consid •h worth while experiment. read durint the winter mo t people who were ten or twelve miles from the lit ds were almost impassable but -rave them a gene in our library work and proved to us concilia given a reasonable opportunity our farmers are library patrons. I "Our books were returned in good eondit destroyed. On the whole, while perhaps no found it much more satisfactory in every post or any other method that had beei v What Nebraska librarians say.— Forty-six Nel i&gt;7 county superintendents of public instruction, an people filled and returned quest ionnaires from which it appears that the general public in Nebraska communities is rarely served by school or church libraries. Hooks from outside the home seem to be obtained, if at all, from public or semipublic libraries rang - ing from the well-equipped public library down to the cooperative reading circle which has brought together a little collection of books to serve its purpose. I Fourteen libraries, or 18.4 per cent of the number replying this point, were apparently built entirely by taxation and 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Keadin&lt; AIattkk ix Nebkahka Farm Homes &lt;&gt;r •")."). -2 per cent in part by taxation and in part by donation. N'early two out of three are sustained by taxation, altho 9.6 per nt mob to be supported by women's clubs or otherwise than hru public taxes tax and other support usually seem to come largely from the towns but in some cases from people of the ntire township or other unit including the open country tax - layiT. In 57 or about two-thirds of the replies to this question was stilted that linoks were loaned without charge to fanners; lile iii 1&gt; cases a charge of $1 was made, usually covering the uscliold rather than $1 per person. Even under these eral conditions a large share of the dwellers in the open mm within reach of these libraries appears not yet to have ■n reached by them. Some libraries, however, appear to be i more a-r^rressive policy of undertaking to render all in the territory regardless of past contribution. with the expectation that the resulting goodwill may e(|iiate future support from all who have enjoyed the the library here was any difference between owners and tenants in e of library facilities the librarians rarely seemed aware ho six said that owners patronized the library more than its. Few or none report the use of schools, stores, churches, rinlioiises as library stations, altho a considerable percentage Nebraska Public Library Commission's traveling libraries iitn such locations. BIBLIOGRAPHY Antrim, Saida Brumback and Antrim, Ernest Irving. The County Library. The Pioneer Press, Van Wert, O. 297 p. 42 ill. 1 map. County Library Number, Sierra Educational News, Vol. 17, No. 6, June, 1921. Contains numerous good but short articles of which the following are part: Bacon, Virginia Cleaver. The County Library on Main Street. 308. Crocheron, B. H. The County Library and the Farmer. 292. Gillis, Mabel R. Legislation Needed to Establish County Free Libraries. 291. Huntingdon, Stella. How County Libraries Cooperate with Schools. 301. Milam, Carl H. The Nation's Need. 287. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nkuhaska ExrouiiEin' Station IUi.i.k.iin I s 28 1 Provines, Cornelia Douglas. How the County Library is Cooperat - ing with All Agencies in Making Rural Life More Attractive. 303 Curtis, Henry S. Play and Recreation for the Open Country. G &amp; Co., N. Y. Cubberley, Ellwood P. The Rural Library. In Rural Life and Edu tion. 239-242. Houston Mifflin Co., N. Y. 146-149. Dudgeon, M. S., The Rural Book Hunger. Rural Manhood, VI: 3( September, 1915. Reprinted in Phelan. John. Readings in Rural Socic ogy. 394. Dyer, Walter A. The Spread of County Libraries, World's Work 609-613. September, 1915. Reprinted in" Sims, N. L. The Rural ( munity. 265-274. Eddy, Harriet G. California Co nty Free Libraries. Journal ii.nal Education A: sociation. 10 Proceedings and Addresses of the N'a 1026-1029. Ferguson, Milton J. Thi' CftUfOI Educational News, 15: 317-:J19. Jur a Library System. Th&lt; 6, 1919. Fiske, George Walter. The Oppor v of the Village I The Challenge of the Country. As 'n Press. T24 East 28 256-257. Foght, H. W. The Library and Ru ■al Communities. In T Rural School, Macmillan Co., N. Y. 1912. 254-281. Hamilton, Wm. J. County Library Work in In&lt; Journal, 45: 343-347. April. 1920 Hamilton, Wm. J. Summary of Existing ( Library Journal, 45: 780-788. Oct. 1. 192( McCardle, Sarah E. The County Library Servic4 Small Town. The Sierra Educational News, 15: :!22-:;2'f. Jur Magill, H. N. W. The Rural Library in P 43: 84-86. January-, 1918. Morgan, Joy E. County Librari* K nal, 45: 497. June. 1920. Preston, Josephine C. Thi- Com y tional Education Association, 1914. 796-79 Ranck, Samuel H. Rural Library E I missioners, Michigan Libraries, December, 1912. Rice, O. S. Rural School Libraries: Their N National Education Association. 1913 Utley, George B. The Rural Trave ■ 10- I 486-487. Walker, N. G. How to Establish a County Library. Am. City ( T Co. ed.), 14:125-6. February, 1916. Wilson, L. R. The County Library An Agency to Promote Genera Reading. American City, 20:340-342. 1919. Unsigned. Socrates on Wheels: Indiana, The Orange Judd Farmer 68:62-63. February, 1920. [5M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>