<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00079.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>MESSAGE OF R. L. Cochran GOVERNOR Delivered to the Fiftieth (Special) Session of the Legislature of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1935-10-28">1935-10-28</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">MESSAGE ..OF.. R. L. Cochran GOVERNOR Delivered to the Fiftieth (Special) Session of the Legislature of Nebraska October 28, 1935 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">1 Message of R. L. Cochran Governor of Nebraska DELIVERED TO THE FIFTIETH (SPECIAL) SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA October 28, 1935 To the Members of the Fiftieth Session of the Legislature of Nebraska m Extraordinary Session: Ladies and Gentlemen: While a number of matters have been brought to your attention m this extraordinary session, it would not have been necessary were it not for the need of legislation providing for old age assistance and related security legislation. When you were m regular session, the Congress had not passed the National Security Act. Your adjourn - ment took place on May 25th. The National Security Act was passed and approved August 14th. Obviously you should not have remained m session for a longer period for the purpose of awaiting action by Congress on this important measure. It is the intention of this call to limit the means of raising revenue to carry out the purposes of old age assistance and related activities to those decided upon at the regular session. On all corrective legis - lation set forth m this call, when and if appropriations are required, m considering necessary taxes to be levied for that purpose, the legis - lature should confine itself to the existing forms of taxation. Our state laws contemplate that the counties shall be responsible for those m need of public relief. In a broad sense, security legislation is relief. The Security Bill passed by Congress provides for the follow - ing: Old Age Pensions Blind Pensions Unemployment Compensation Aid to Dependent Children Maternal and Child Health Service Services for Crippled Children Child Welfare Services Vocational Rehabilitation Public Health Work Unemployment and Home Relief The main feature of this law has to do with old age assistance and activity. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">If the counties at this particular time were financially able to maet this obligation and to match the provisions of the Naional Se - curity Act and if the existence of a state agency was not required under the provisions of the National Security Act, I would say that this session would not have been called. With the information that was available when you were in regular session, you did the very best possible. You took a course designed to meet the provisions of an Act not yet passed by Congress which the court disapproved. The Supreme Court also ruled that this was an excessive grant of authority to a state agency in that it gave the State Assistance Committee authority to extend relief to counties in proportion to needs. You are to be congratulated upon the efforts you made to avoid the necessity of a special session. As to my previous recommendations to you on this subject, 1 again recommend the enactment of a law which will meet the pro - visions of the National Security Act. Full knowledge of this Act is now available. It was not then available. I have asked the At - torney General to draft a bill. He is in Washington at this time con - ferring with federal authorities as to the adequacy of this bill from the standpoint of meeting the provisions of the National Securiy Act, while at the same time keeping in mind (in the the framing of this bill) the objections raised by the Supreme Court. Let us refresh our minds on the provisions of the National Se - curity Act as to old age assistance. This act provides for old age pensions starting in 1942 by a contributory method which contemplates the building up of a fund to make possible these old age annuities or pensions. Congress, however, provided that in the meantime old age assistance would be granted to those dependent upon- the public for support with a maximum limitation of $15.00 per month and with a further limitation that these payments shall go only to those de - pendent on the public for support. As in the case of any public activity, there is in this case two main factors to be considered; first, the method of financing; second, the method of administration. At to the method of financing, you have already decided. You appropriated $300,000.00 of beer taxes. You provided for an additional one cent gas tax dating from March 1st, 1935 to July 1st, 1936. You appropriated $700,000.00 in additional funds to be derived from beer and liquor taxes. $1,100,000.00 have been collected from the one cent gas tax for which you provided. It will be necessary that this be appropriated by your honorable body for the purpose which you originally intended. Your wishes also in the regular session should be made effective by 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">a re-enactment of the one cent gas tax to be operative from the date of your action to July 1st, 1936. To follow such a course will mean to avoid confusion. To follow such a course will be to avoid incon - sistencies and should result likewise in a brief session. So much for methods of financing. As to administration, let us have the greatest amount of local control possible. Local self government is democratic government. I have always believed that our constituted board of commissioners and supervisors should handle matters of a purely local character, such as I here present, with as little outside interference as possible. We must have a state agency in order to comply with the require - ments of the National Security Act. There must be a constituted body to whom appeals may be taken. There are many related activ - ities in the National Security program as enumerated above. I will not burden you with a repetition of these. Most of them are self explanatory. Some are provided for in existing laws. I do wish to call your attention, however, to one activity that is entirely new — that of unemployment insurance. Whether or not our people are ready, the facts are that the National Congress has made provision for an excise tax on employers. The facts are if we do not pass legislation, the estimated loss to the state during the year 1936 will amount to one hundred times as much as the maximum cost of this present session. To be more explicit, to delay this legislation until the next regular session would mean an estimated minimum loss of over two million dollars to the state with a possibility that this would reach to double this amount. A large sum will be collected from Nebraska whether we enact this legislation or not. Legislatures are meeting and will meet the county over to take advantage of this taxation to be imposed within their states. It is our obvious duty to give serious consideration to the end that we not lose rev - enue running into millions of dollars which will be collected from our people under the terms of the National Security Act. In your wisdom you passed a law, during the regular session of this year, providing for pensions for the blind. Our existing laws provide and have provided for many , years for mothers' pensions. Crippled children have received the benefits of public aid as well as that of charitable organizations for many years. Aid to dependent children, maternal and child health service, vocational rehabilitation, public health work, child welfare services, unemployment and home 1 relief, and public health work are all subjects which demand our humanitarian interest in complying with the National Security Act. This is true, as we can well see, especially because by taking this course we will be merely taking advantage of federal monies already provided for by national legislation. We have recognized these ac - tivities for many years as a public obligation. We have met these 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">obligations with a direct tax in the support of such institutions as the State Orthopedic Hospital. We have met these obligations in the past with a public tax in the support of such insitutions as the Home for Dependent Children. Mothers' pensions have come from a direct tax for many years. Let us 1 hope that the organizations which have been so active and so generous in the past will continue their efforts in the support of these activities to the end the public expense might be correspondingly reduced. It is my hope, and I. know it is yours, to have a full public under - standing on the part of our people on all public questions and par - ticularly those where taxation is involved. The federal security plan contemplates the building up of funds for old age pensions and an - nuities by contributions of the individuals themselves to become effective in 1942. This is not new. The large railroad systems of the country have had this in effect for years. It is a plan that has been in effect for our postal employees and those holding federal positions generally under. civil service. It is to be hoped that a system of old age pensions generally can be built up along sound economic lines. This cannot be done im - mediately. It can be accomplished and it is hoped will be accomplished over a period of years. In the meantime, we should cooperate with our national government in bridging the gap and granting some as - sistance until the plan now set up by the federal government be - comes operative. Next of importance to the taxpayers of the state is a measure which was enacted in the regular session known as House Roll No. 78. As in the case of tne Security Act passed by you, our Supreme Court has rendered your Act invalid. Your original action in passing House Roll 78 together with strong public demand convinced me that you should have the opportunity to correct this measure, if possible from a technical viewpoint. During a long legislative session, such as you had for almost five months, it is not strange that some corrections as to the admin - istration of some measures might be necessary. Our State Tax Com - missioner, our Attorney General and many County Treasurers of the state have advised me that this is true of House Roll No. 70 and House Roll No. 90. Slight changes in these laws will insure the car - rying out of your original intention. In the regular session of the legislature you provided for an avia - tion commission and a real estate board. I am advised by the State Treasurer, the State Auditor and the Attorney General that your will in regard to these measures, as expressed in the regular session. 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">cannot become effective without a small amount of additional legis - lation. Fortunately, this will not mean any additional taxes. In the case of the real estate board, as provided by you, it will be sustained by fees paid by the members of that particular business activity. The same is true in the case of the aviation commission. The funds de-' rived in the case of each of these activities, provided by you, cannot be expended without being appropriated. The National Congress provided for an appropriation for the elimination of railroad grade crossings. It so happens that some of these most needed are in locations within municipalites where the question of damages becomes an important factor and where pro - visions for financing these damages are not covered by existing stat - utes. I have included this item in the call at the request of many of those municipalities as a means not only to accomplish needed improvements but also because of the need for relieving unemploy - ment. I have included in my call three measures requested by the city of Omaha and Douglas County. All of these measures were requested by. officials and citizens of Omaha and Douglas County in order to make a more intelligent use of federal public works money. Ordin - arily, I am not in favor of granting additional powers to city councils and commissioners and to county boards in the expenditure of funds. This, however, appears to be an emergency and a marked instance where, if not allowed, enormous sums of federal money will be lost to Omaha, Douglas County and our people. Included in the construction program of the national government and in the appropriations made available to our state is that of con - struction of armories to provide needed facilities for our National Guard as well as also to provide employment along beneficial lines at this particular time. My attention was called by city attorneys to the fact that there is no existing law providing for donating or con - demning ground within municipalities for this purpose. I have in - cluded this item at the request of those municipalities and recom - mend it for your favorable consideration. Many years ago it was the practice in legislative sessions to pro - vide an emergency fund for crisis and emergencies necessitating the use of the National Guard. This practice was discontinued. During the past summer, after you had adjourned your labors in regular session, the worst disaster in the history of the state occurred in the Republican River Valley. An emergency arose in the city of Omaha where the constituted authorities admitted their inability to maintain law and order and found themselves helpless in facing this emergency. They appealed to the state for help. Another situation necessitating 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">the use of the National Guard arose m western Nebraska. Taken m the order given, the cost of meeting these emergencies was as fol - lows: Republic River Valley flood $4,848.38 Omaha Strike Irrigation difficulties m western Nebraska $3,639/69 It was necessary to use a part of the appropriation made by you to meet these emergencies. It is now recommended an appropriation be made to replace this amount to carry out the -state's moral obligation to maintain law and order. In the regular session you appropriated the sum of $20,000.00 for the investigation and audit of all the business transactions and activities of the department of banking, including its activities as receiver and liquidating agent of failed or insolvent banks, since January Ist, 1930. Provisions of this bill were that a report of this investigation by the State Auditor shall be made at the next regular session of the legislature. The State Auditor advises me his report is practically completed. It is my belief you should have the results of this report as early as possible and, m view of the fact you are meeting m extra ordinary session, I recommend an amendment to House Roll No. 392 to provide for this report being made to you m special session. It is my belief we should have one receiver for all failed banks, such receiver to be the superintendent of the state banking depart - ment. The administrative receiverships, as provided m the 49th session of the Nebraska legislature, have been transferred from the old super - intendent of the banking department to the new superintendent of the banking department. It is my belief that judicial receiverships should likewise be transferred and an account made to the state bank - ing department. By having a report made on the investigation and audit of these receiverships at this time, I have m mind that there should be no reason for continuation of the duplication which now exists. The public generally of Nebraska will appreciate your early and expeditious attention to these matters. 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE 7 LOAN AGENCIES Section 45-113, Compiled Statutes of Nebraska for 1929, provides for the licensing of loan agents or agencies, and is designed to regulate the loaning of money in small quantities upon chattel securities. The bond to be given by the company is in the sum of $2,000.00, to be renewed and filed annually on March 1st. The companies now operating, their place of business, and the amount of money loaned, follow: Acme Loan Company 105 North 16th Street • Omaha, Nebraska American Loan Plan 219 City National Bank, $119 603.77 Omaha, Nebraska American Securities Co. 212 No. Wheeler 17,607.40 1 Grand Island, Nebr. Apex Commercial Corporation 6204 Maple Street 11,935.18 Omaha, Nebraska The Auto Loan &amp; Finance Co 1554 O. Street, 25,297.68 Lincoln, Nebraska Capital Credit Co 856 Stuart Bldg 53,556.00 Lincoln, Nebraska Central Credit Corporation 2044 Harney St 19,419.70 Omaha, Nebraska Central Finance Corporation 417 Norfolk Avenues 59,929.51 Norfolk, Nebraska Century Finance Corporation Mezzanine Flsor, Federal Securities Building Lincoln, Nebraska Central Finance Corporation Columbus t Central Finance Co T 1328 P. Street 3,188.91 Lincoln, Nebraska Citizens Mutual Loan Co 504^ Court Street.... 9,231.63 Beatrice,^ Nebraska City Investment Company 509 E. Street 9,293.71 Fairbury, Nebraska City Loan Company 314 Richards Block * Lincoln, Nebraska C. &amp; G. Finance Co 211 No. Locust St 8,314.16 Grand Island, Nebr. Credit Bureau of Alliance Box 1368, 298.43 Alliance, Nebraska Commercial Security Company Grand Island, Nebr._ 7,354.69 Darling Finance Company 324 North Pine St., *1 Grand Island, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE Home Finance Co . 322 First National Bank, ... 2,327.90 Lincoln, Nebraska H. W. Davison No. 9 West 17th St 15 374.02 Scottsbluff, Nebraska Elkhorn Valley Finance Company 101 I.O.O.F. Bldg 33,308.56 Fremont, Nebraska Federated Finance Co 1503 O. Street 68,310.18 Lincoln, Nebraska Fidelity Finance Co._ 211 Arcade Building. 4.406.54 Beatrice, Nebraska General Financial Service Kearney, Nebraska __ 16,651.85 General Securities Company 4805% South 24th St. f Omaha, Nebraska General Securities Co.... 1803 Dodge Street... 90,780.17 Omaha, Nebraska Grand Island Finance Company. 212 North Locust St._ 55,448.15 Grand Island, Nebr. Great Western Finance Corp 226-230 Union State Bank Bldg 57,782.39 Omaha, Nebraska Hastings Investment Company Hastings, Nebraska.- 17, 563.15 Helpful Credit Plan 120 Farnam Buildinp: • Omaha, Nebraska Household Finance Corporation 308 Barker Bldg 243,624.66 Omaha, Nebraska Household Loan Co. Beatrice, Nebraska _■_ 23,672.64 F. R. Hussong Finance Company 502 Federal Securities Bldir. _ 14,629.17 Lincoln, Nebraska J. B. Carey 123 No. Denver Ave., * Hastings, Nebraska Kearney Loan &amp; Finance Company.. Kearney, Nebraska _. 27,670.60 Lincoln Finance Co 403 Kresge Building,. 38,013.75 Lincoln, Nebraska Loan Service Corporation, 460 Omaha National Bank Bldg 22,256.72 Omaha, Nebraska W. A. McCain, ScottsblufT, Nebraska 15,588.20 McCook Finance Company 107 West B. Street,___S17,755.42 McCook, Nebraska Mack Investment Company Scottsbluff, Nebraska 77,505.52 Mercantile Credit Co 125 East 5th Street,. _ 21,319.20 Fremont, Nebraska Merchants Investment 819 First National Bank Bldg 142,002.78 York, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p011">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE .':•••! I . Meridian Finance Corp McCloud Hotel Bldg._ 27,406.65 York, Nebraska Miller Finance Company 114 East 13th St.. 9,188.78 Crete, Nebraska Motors Finance 1524 O. Street 24,342.26 Lincoln, Nebraska Nebraska Finance Company 205 Masonic Bldg 17,130.88 Grand Island, Nebr. Nebraska Securities Company Scottsbluff, Nebraska 97,289.96 North Platte Loan and Finance Co 111 East 5th St 46,316.96 - North Platte, Nebr. Peoples Loan Company 236-238 Keeline Bldp. 53,759.28 Omaha, Nebraska Personal Finance Company 206 So. 13th Street,.. 95,231.18 of Lincoln, Lincoln, Nebraska Personal Finance Company 204 South 17th Street, 146.433.8S of Omaha Omaha, Nebraska Personal Loan &amp; Finance Co Ogallala, Nebraska.. 3,846.67 Personal Loan &amp; Investment Company.-Alliance, Nebraska * Personal Loan Service, Inc 510 Federal Securities Bids:.. 21,691.36 Lincoln, Nebraska Platte Valley Finance Co 511*2 Dewey St 14 523.83 North Platte, Nebr. Provident Loan Society of Omaha 432 Securities Bldg 206,515.57 Omaha, Nebraska Reliance Finance Co 4719 So. 24th St..' 23,507.26 Omaha, Nebraska Saunders County Finance Company, Inc Wahoo, Nebraska 7,337.13 Securities Investment Corp 216 Insurance Bldir... 335,860.00 Omaha, Nebraska Securities Investment Corp 103 North 4th Street t Norfolk, Nebraska Securities Investment Corp 1640 O. Street, t Lincoln, Nebraska Standard Finance Company 603 Redick Tower... 18,108.41 Omaha, Nebraska Standard Finance Company 111 No. Hastings Ave. 13,127.97 Hastings, Nebraska State Loan Company of York 626^4 Lincoln Avenue * York, Nebraska State Securities Company 124 South 12th St 580,469.15 Lincoln, Nebraska Lewis H. Stover 231 N. Lincoln Ave 590.04 Hastings, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p012">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE Globe Finance Company, 223 South 13th St . 70.574.91 Lincoln, Nebraska Underwriters Acceptance Corp 1119 First National Bank Bldg 55,230.47 Omaha, Nebraska United Finance Co 117 No. 14th Street,.- 8,832.86 Lincoln, Nebraska United Finance Corp 2420^ 13th Street,... 27,160.02 Columbus, Nebraska United Financial Service Grand Island, Nebr. t United Financial Service Fairbury, Nebraska t United Financial Service North Platte, Nebr. f United Financial Service Hastings, Nebraska t United Financial Service Omaha, Nebraska 232,599.91 United Loan Company 323-24 Securities Bld K . ..1 39 355.25 Omaha, Nebraska Citizens Finance Co., 938 First National * Bank Bldg. Omaha, Nebraska United Securities Company 601-2-3-4 Farnam Of Omaha Bldg. .. 22,794.84 Omaha, Nebraska Prairie Loan Company 1320 First National Bank Bldp 39,856.60 Omaha, Nebraska The First National Bank of Omaha. .l__16th &amp; Farnam St 204,216.71 Omaha, Nebraska Allied Securities of Norfolk 119 So. 4th St 2,163.1:5 Norfolk, Nebraska Omaha Wimsett System Co 200 So. 19th St 339,606.01 Omaha, Nebraska Packers National Bank. . 24th &amp; O. Street, * Omaha, Nebraska Secuiities Investment Corp.. Kipp Building t Hastings, Nebraska Nebraska Finance Corp. . Nebraska City, Nebr. * Industrial Finance Company 620 World Herald BldR. 54,455.40 Omaha, Nebraska The Western Investment Company 11 East 17th St. * Scottsbluff, Nebraska Grace Mayer Company 1102 City National * Bank Omaha, Nebraska American Finance Company Kearney, Nebrrska * </seg>
            <seg id="p013">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SECRETARY OF STATE Clarence C. Worden Ogallala Nebraska • Volentine Auto Company McCook, Nebraska * Securities Investment Corp Hastings, Nebraska t Securities Investment Corp 216 Insurance Bldg. t Omaha, Nebraska Securities Investment Corp -103 No. 4th St. t Norfolk, Nebrasku Securities Investment Corp 1640 O. Street t Lincoln, Nebraska Employees Financial Service, 740 First National • Bank Bldg. Omaha, Nebraska The Triangle Finance Wayne, Nebraska * Fremont Securities Company 104 East Sixth Street • Fremont, Nebraska Fremont State Company 132 East Fifth Street * Fremont, Nebraska State Finance Co 323 Securities Bldg. • Omaha, Nebraska Nebraska Finance Co. of Omaha 301 Union State Bank • Building Omaha, Nebraska Companies which have been licensed the required length of time have been examined annually, as provided by law, and reports of examination are on file in this office. Respectfully submitted, HARRY R. SWANSON, SECRETARY OF STATE. '■■'■■' • New licenses. No reports. t Reports consolidated in Main Office report. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>