<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00048.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00048.00006</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Administration of the Workmen's Compensation Act of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1921">1921</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 ~»s&gt; '-'■■: Administration OF THE WORKMEN'S COMPENSATION ACT of Nebraska By ERNEST GLENN CALLEN Me Cook, Nebraska A THESIS Presented to the Faculty of The Graduate College in the University of Nebraska in Partial Fulfillment of Requirements for the Degree of Master of Art Department of Political Science mm Lincoln, Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002">• </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 CHAPTER I Passage of The Nebraska Law Modern inventions and discoveries have resulted in a complete re - organization of the economic life of the world, the result being termed the industrial stage. The industrial stage has substituted the factory for the home or small shop, the machine for the hand tool, the impersonal corporation for the personal master, and the simple relation of master and servant has changed to the complex relation of employer and em - ployee. Accompanying the industrial stage has been a tremendous in - crease in the number of persons killed and injured because of their em - ployment. This more complex relationship between employer and em - ployee along with the increased number of industrial accidents, has necessitated a change in the method of caring for the injured workman and his dependents. Workmen's compensation laws defined as "enact - ment which embody the principle that the workman is entitled to com - pensation for injuries received in the course of his employment," 1 is the method which has been developed to meet this need. Or it may be said that workmen's compensation laws are based on the principle that the injuries and human waste of any industry are a legitimate part of the cost of production; so, the consumer and not the injured workman should bear this cost. Of course society through charity has been taking care of the industrial cripple, but this method is satisfactory neither to the injured workman nor to society. With workmen's compensation in effect the employer pays the workman for the injury and the cost is passed on to the ultimate consumer in the form of an increased price. Thus the workman Is not the object of charity but is receiving payment for what he has contributed to production. Workmen's compensation legislation is- of recent development. At the beginning of the industrial stage, the relationship between employer and employee was governed by the common law. The liability of the em - ployer for industrial accidents was included in this relationship. Under the common law, however, the only way an injured workman could secure compensation for his injury, was through a damage suit against his em - ployer. This damage suit must be based on the negligence of the employer. That is, before an injured workman could secure payment for his injury, he must prove in court that Ms employer was actually at fault. It Is true that the common law did lay certain duties upon the em - ployer, breach of which was considered negligence or fault on his part. 1 Boyd, J. H., Workmen'! Compensation, p. 206 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 "These duties were: (1) to employ suitable fellow-servants; (2) to estab - lish and promulgate proper rules; (3) to provide a safe place to work; (4) to furnish safe appliances; (5) to warn youthful and inexperienced servants of the dangers 1 of the employment." 1 In theory both the em - ployer and the employee were equal before the law, but the equality stopped there. As stated above, the injured workman must, to establish his case, prove that the employer had been negligent or at fault. In many cases this negligence could not be proven, as many injuries resulted without human fault. In an investigation in Germany in 1887 it was shown that "out of every 100 serious accidents 43 are such as no care on the part of the employer could have prevented."' In addition to the difficulty of the employee in proving the negligence of the employer, the employer was further protected by certain defenses which developed in the common law.' These defenses are known as the contributory negligence rule, the fellow servant rule, and the doctrine of the assumption of risk. tThe contributory negligence rule briefly is that if the party injured I by his own negligence contributed to the circumstances which caused injury, he cannot secure damages from his employer even though his ployer may also have been negligent and at fault. The fellow servant rule is that when a workman enters the employ of another, he takes upon himself the ordinary risk due to the negligent acts of his fellow employees. To meet modern conditions this has been modified to the extent that when the fellow servant is clothed with the power of the employer, the employer is liable for the injury caused by the action of the fellow servant. Any advantage which might be gained by such modification is, how - ever, more than offset by the use of the doctrine of the assumption of risk as a defense, of which the fellow servant rule is a part. The under - lying principle in the doctrine of the assumption of risk is that after the employer has done everything he is bound to do, for the purpose of securing safety for the worker, the employee is assumed to have accepted such risk as may be incident to the employment. Or the doctrine may be stated thus: "Whenever a man enters another's employ he does so with his eyes open, and with a knowledge of the risks incident to it including those due to negligence of fellow servants, and those he contracts to take,' e. g., a minor or sailor, whose occupations of their very nature are dangerous.'" It is evident that the employee was at a distinct disad - vantage for it was comparatively easy for the employer to prove that the employee by his own act had contributed to the accident, that the injury was caused by the act of a fellow employee, or that the employee had 'Van Doern, D. H, Workmen's Comp&lt;nution, p. 8. • II Columbia Law Review, p. 40, N. 9. material on the defense* i&gt; taken from Rhodes, J. E., Workmen's Compensa - , Chapter I, and Van Doern, D. H , Workmen's Compensation, Chapter I. • Dawbarn, C. T. C , Employer's Liability and Workmen's Compensation, p </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 assumed the risk of such accident. If any one of these defenses could be established, the employer was not liable for damages. It is evident that in many cases the injured workman could secure nothing for the injury even though he was not at fault. In addition to the difficulty of establishing the case the workman encountered other difficulties. These specific inadequacies, of the common law system to meet the needs of the modern industrial stage, may be summarized under four general heads ; the uncertainty as to the basis of a claim for damage, the delay incident to the enforcement of a claim in the courts, the un - certainty as to the amount of damages which may be awarded, and the difficulty incident to the collection of a judgment after one has been secured.' The common law system Is both unsound in theory and unjust in practice. In a few cases the injured workman was able by exciting the sympathy of the jury to secure large verdicts, but this was the exception, not the rule. It has been estimated that the common law remedy fur - nished compensation in not more than twelve per cent of the cases of injuries; and even in these few cases the amount paid averaged scarcely .one-fifth of what is deemed adequate. 7 These defects in the common law system led to the enactment of compensation legislation.' The distinction between the two systems is that under workmen's compensation the injured worker is entitled to re - ceive compensation for his injury, regardless of the negligence of the employer. As the question of .the negligence of the employer is not an issue, there is no place for the common law defenses. The principle in workmen's compensation is that all workmen are entitled to compensa - tion for all injuries caused by accident "arising out of and in the course of employment."* While this 1 is the principle the practice is not so all in - clusive. No state has a law which includes all the employees in the state. More than this, most compensation laws make it optional with the employer as to whether he will be governed by the provisions of the law. Not only has workmen's compensation legislation been fairly success - ful in eradicating the evils of the common law system, but it has also re - sulted in other indirect benefits. The most important of these benefits are: * Rhodes, J. E., Workmen's Compensation, p. 13. 1 Boyd, J. H , Workmen's Compensation, p. 54. ■ "It has become a matter of usage to apply the term 'Employers' Liability' to the common law system and the term 'Workmen's Compensation' to the compensation system, but strictly speaking this is an inaccuraey and should be corrected in the beginning, for both the common law system and its statutory successor, the compensation system, are parts of the general legal system of employers' liability, and for the sake of legal aoeu - rary the use of the term 'Employers' Liability' should be discontinued when referring to a part of the system and should be used only in its general and proper meaning." (Rhodes, Workmen's Compensation, p. S.) * This is the phrase used in the English law and in moat state laws, including Ne - braska. Its significance will be discussed in Chapter III. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 t(l) Workmen's compensation has given the employer an incentive seriously consider accident prevention, for by preventing accidents he y be saved the cost of compensation; and (2) Workmen's compensation creates a better spirit between the em - ployer and the employee. The bringing of a damage suit by an employee against his employer generally meant the termination of the employment relations. But under the compensation the workman may receive his compensation without affecting his employment. The United States has been behind the European countries in enact - ing workmen's compensation laws." Before the principle of workmen's compensation was adopted in the United States a few states modified or removed the common law defenses in damage suits brought by injured employees. Such laws were known &amp;e Employers' Liability Acts. Two reasons may be given for the delay in passing compensation legislation in the United States: (1) The constitutionality of such acts was in doubt; and (2) each state was afraid to take the first step in the movement for fear of placing the employers of the state under a disad - vantage in competing with employers in states not having compensa- The first compensation law in the United States was passed in Mary - land in 1902. It was soon declared unconstitutional in an inferior court, from which no appeal was made." Laws were passed in Montana" in 1909 and in New York in 1910. Both laws were declared unconstitutional soon after their enactment. The reason these laws failed to stand the test of constitutionality was that they compelled the employer to be bound by them. This waa held to be depriving the employer of property without due process of law." All early compensation laws of the compulsory type were declared unconstitutional primarily because they were compulsory. To overcome this difficulty another type of law was devised, whereby the employer and the employee accepted the provisions 1 of the act, only after mutual agreement. However, this type of law was rendered nugatory and in - effective through the failure of employers and employees to make agree - ments to accept the law. 1 ' tit thus appears that the compulsory laws were unconstitutional while elective laws were ineffective. To meet the situation a law was de - d, which gave the employer the choice of accepting the act or operat - under the liability law, but to encourage the employer to elect com- " Rhodes, J. E., Workmen's Compensation, Chapter III. 11 Ibid. p. 89-90. "The Montana law applied only to miners. k u Montana law was declared unconstitutional in Cunningham v. Northwestern Im- Mnent Co.. 44 Mont., 180, 110 Pac. 554, and the New York Act in Ives v. South »k&gt; Railroad Co., 201 N. T. 271, 94 N. E. 481. ■ Rhodes, J. E., Workmen's Compensation, p. 100-6 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 pensation the old common law defenses of fellow servants' fault, con - tributory negligence, and assumption of risk are greatly modified or ab - rogated. When an employee refuses to be bound by the acts, his em - ployer, if under law, is permitted to use the three common law defenses in any suit brought by such employee. The so-called elective principle as one writer has said is clearly intended "to force the employers to take advantage of" the compensation laws." The elective principle was first applied in New Jersey in 1911 and is sometimes referred to as the New Jersey plan." In 1914 New York, after amending her constitution, enacted a compulsory law which was permitted to stand. Other states' followed the lead of New Jersey and New York, and during the ten years 1911 to 1920 compensation laws have been enacted in forty-two states, in addition to Alaska, Hawaii, and Porto Rico." The history of workmen's compensation in Nebraska began in the 1911 session of the legislature, when the first bill was introduced. The bill was unusually liberal for that stage of development in workmen's compensation. It was complete in that it provided a commission to ad - minister the law." While this bill never had the slightest chance of be - coming a law, it did arouse enough interest in the subject of workmen's compensation to secure the passage of a resolution providing for a com - mission to investigate the problem and the needs for such a law in Nebraska." A commission of seven members was appointed which made a report to the legislature in 1913. 10 During the summer of 1912, and before the commission made a re - port, the Democrats, in their State Convention at Grand Island, pledged the enactment of a workmen's compensation law if they controlled the legislature.* 1 The Democrats had a chance to make good their pledge for they controlled the house while the republicans controlled the senate. However, as will be shown later, it was through the efforts of the senate " Lowell, J. A., Ifus. Law Quarterly, Vol. 1, p. 49. "Rhodes. J. E., Workmen'! Compensation, p. 118-21 ■' Bulletin of United State* Bureau of Labor Statistics, No. 275, p. 14. The Mis - souri law was rejected in a referendum in 1920. (Monthly Labor Review, Jan. 1921, p. 170-171.) '•Session 1911, H. R. 536, introduced by I. D. Evans. " The labor committee never reported the bill but in its place they reported a sub - stitute to provide for the appointment of a commission. The resolution authorising the commission was passed independently of the report of the labor committee on H. R. 536. (House Journal 1911, p. 814.) ■* The members of the commission were : C. D. Traphagen, Lincoln ; Victor Rom water, Omaha; A. C. Weitiel, Omaha; F. I. Elliek, Omaha; I. D. Evans, Kenesaw ; F. M. Coffey, Lincoln, and A. L. Weatherly, Lincoln. A. E. Sheldon, as Director of the Legislative Reference Bureau, acted as secretary for the commission. » State Democratic Platform adopted July 30, 1912. Copy in Nebraska Legislative Reference Bureau. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Ethe compensation law was enacted." The enactment of a compensa - law was recommended by both the retiring 11 atid the incoming" gov - rs In their addresses to the legislature of 1913. The first report of the commission was published a short time before the legislature convened." It contained a list of the accidental deaths which had occurred in the state during the first ten months of 1912. The personal injury cases tried during the same period were also listed. No designation was made as to the cases which would probably come under a compensation law. No information was given concerning the number of industrial accidents occurring in the state and no conclusion was drawn as to the needs of a compensation law for Nebraska. The first report also contained two bills', one representing the ma - jority and one the minority views of the commission. Both bills were far more liberal than the legislation finally enacted and each created a com - mission to administer the law. In a final report another majority bill was •ubmitted much like the first bill except that in the new bill the schedule of payments were reduced fifteen per cent." Several bills 1 dealing with workmen's compensation were introduced in both houses of the legislature. Some merely modified or removed the common law defenses while others went so far as to establish a state in - tiice fund." Each house referred its compensation bills' to its Judiciary mittee. As workmen's compensation was a Democratic campaign pledge an understanding was reached whereby the Democratic house was to work oat the details of the compensation law while the senate was to give its attention to the insurance code." The house Judiciary committee per - mitted Interested parties to appear before it to present their views. Special consideration was given to the suggestions of the Commission which had made the investigation." The bill reported by the judiciary " In the 1813 wuion of the legislature there were 55 Democrats and 45 R&lt;vu1 beams in the honae and 15 Democrat* and 18 Republican* in the senate. " Senate Journal, 1913, p. 77. "Ibid, p. 87. k" The preliminary report of the Nebraska Employers' Liability and Workmen's pensation Commission published as Legislative Reference Bureau Bul'etin No. 2, :r date of December 20, 1912, was the first report of the commission. k" Final report of the Nebraska Employers' Liability and Workmen's Compensation mission. The four members who made this report were the members reporting the irity bill in the first report. " The bin* introduced in the 1913 session dealing with workmen's compensation - may be classified roughly as follows: Employers' Liability, that is those which modified the defenses H. R. 28, 49, 236 and S. F. 37. General Compensation H R. 193, 199, 200, 206, 549, 642. and 8. F. 1, 112, 140, and 247. The bill providing the state in turanre fund was H. R. 193. ■ Statement by Senator John Cordeal. " Statement by Mr. F. L. Bollen, chairman house judiciary committee, session 1913 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 committee was the one which most nearly met the approval of the com - mission." The compensation bill came up for discussion in the committee of the whole rather late in the session." From the first the bill met with a great deal of opposition. Members opposing the bill were those who represented the personal injury attorneys, the farmers and other small employers, and those who did not understand the proposed law." By a combination of these forces the bill was* defeated, many Democrats vot - ing against it." With the defeat of this bill there seemed little chance of securing a compensation law in 1913. A little later, however, the Demo - cratic house, realizing that it had failed to carry out a platform pledge and that there was a demand for a compensation law, expressed a desire to have another compensation bill reported for consideration. This 1 the Judiciary committee would not do." Friends of compensation now turned to the senate to induce it to pass a compensation law and put the matter up to the house again. The senate Judiciary committee was willing and a sub-committee" was set at work to draft a compensation measure." The sub-committee permitted interested parties and especially members of the commission to appear before it and present suggestions. The bill submitted by the committee passed the senate with a few amendments' and with little opposition." The fact that the compensation law was a Democratic platform pledge but had been turned down by the Democratic house, was strongly brought out in the senate debates." The house began the consideration of the bill the same day it came from the senate." The bill as passed by the senate was to apply to a large number of occupations' and employments; no exception was made for the employer ■" Session 1913, H. R. 549, introduced by Mr. F. L. Bollen at request of rommissioi: 11 It was msde a special order for March 19. It was taken up again on March 26. On this day the morning, afternoon and evening sessions were given over to s discus - sion of the bill. "Nebraska State Journal. March 20. 1913, and March 27, 1913. Statement hy Mr. F. L. Bollen. "The vote to indefinitely postpone H. R. 549 was 46 for and 43 against. (House Journal 1913, p. 912.) Of those voting for indefinite postponement 28 were Democrats and 18 were Republicans. •* Statement of Mr. F. L. Bollen, Chairman house judiciary committee, 1913 " The sub-committee was msd; up of 3 republican members of the judiciary com - mittee who had not introduced a compensation bill. The committee was Senators Cordeal. Hoasty and Saunders. (Statement of Senator John Cordeal in an interview.) "Session 1913, S. F. No. 1 was taken as a basis but the sub-committee made many amendments to it. 17 Passed on third reading by a vote of 21 to 5 on April 7. (Senate Journal J913. p. 838.) " Nebraska State Journal, April 8, 1913. ■House Journal, 1913, p. 1176. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 employing only a few men. Certain classes of farm labor "Were included in the list of enumerated occupations. To secure the support of the farmers and small employers," an amendment was passed substituting a short section exempting employers employing less than five persons and employers of farm laborers, for the long section naming the occupations covered by the act." With this change the house passed the senate bill." bThe conference committee accepted the bill as amended by the house, report of the conference committee was accepted by both houses" on 1 16 and was signed by the governor the same day." The opponents of the law made a final effort to keep it from becom - ing effective by invoking the referendum against it." But the voters of the state sustained the law in the election of 1914 by a vote of 92,513 for and 85,777 against it." The law thus enacted provided for a compensation benefit of 50% of the wages paid at the time of injury but not to exceed ten dollars a week.' 7 No commission was created to administer the law, this being left wholly to the courts. No change was made until 1917 when the legislature increased the per cent of wages payable as compensation to 66% per cent. The maximum weekly payment was Increased to twelve dollars a week." The ommlssioner of labor was made compensation commissioner and was given extensive powers in administering the law and conducting hear - ngs." The law was made to apply to employers, employing one or more persons, but continued to exempt employers of farm laborers." In 1919 he chief change in the law was to increase the maximum weekly pay - ments to fifteen dollars'." The time limit during which medical aid was Nebraska State Journal, April 8, 1913; also Mr F. L. Bollen, maker of the dment. in an interview cave this at his reason for making it. " Houae Journal 1913, p. 1323 UThe bill paaaed the houae 70 to 18 on the third reading, April 15. (House 1. p. 1836.) k**The vote on the conference committed report in the senate was 23 for with the not voting. (Senate Journal 1913, p. 1003.) In the houae no roll call was taken ise Journal 1913, p. 1170.) "Senate Journal 1913, p. 1083. "Those favoring the law claimed the referendum had been invoked by the personal injury attorneys of the state. (Referendum Bulletin 1914. pp. 3 8.) Senator Cordial in an interview stated this to be the general opinion throughout the state. " Abstract of votes. Election of 1914. Office of secretary of state • Eer. St. 1913. See. 3««2. « Sea*. L. 1917, Ch. 85, Sec. 8 • Ibid, See*. 25 to 29. "Ibid, Sec. 1 " Sess. L. 1919, Ch. 91, Sec. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 to be furnished was removed but the amount of medical aid, as before, was not to exceed two hundred dollars." The law as now in force applies to all industries, where one or more persons are employed, except domestic service, agriculture and inter - state commerce." Persons in these exempted classes may come under the act by voluntary agreement between the employers and the em - ployees." On April 1, 1921, only thirty-three employers were operating under the law through such agreements." The Nebraska law is elective and denies the three common law de - fenses, of fellow servant fault, assumption of risk, and contributory negli - gence, to employers electing not to come under the act. 1 * On April 1, 1921, there were only thirty-four employers electing not to come under the law." All persons employed by the state or any governmental agency created by it are entitled to compensation unless they are elected or ap - pointed for a definite term." In private employments, not excluded from the act, all persons including aliens and minors," are entitled to com - pensation except casual" employees and home workers." Injuries compensated under the Nebraska act are those caused by accident arising out of and in the course of employment," unless the acci - dent was caused by the wilful negligence of the injured." Persons 1 suffer - ing from occupational diseases are denied compensation." No compensa - tion is paid for the first seven days after the injury unless the disability continues for more than six weeks in which case compensation is paid for the full time lost." The employer is required to furnish medical and hospital service as long as the disability shall continue," subject to the approval of the compensation commissioner. For total disability the injured worker receives 66% per cent of his wages for three hundred weeks and 45 per cent of the wages at the time of injury for the remainder of his life. During the first three hundred "Ibid, Sec. 1. "fan. L. 1017. Ch. 85. Sec. 1. "Ibid, Sab. (3). ■* Record* in the commissioner'! office at the Capitol. R«v. St. 1913, Sees. 3643, 8644, 3645. " Records in the commissioner'! office st the Capitol. "As imended in 1021 by 8. P. S, See. 1. "Ibid -Ibid •&gt; Ibid "Rev. St. 1013, Sees. 3650 and 3861 "' Ibid, See. 3668. « As amended in 1921 by S. F. No. 3, See. 1 "Ibid. "Ibid. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 weeks the maximum allowed is fifteen dollars a week and the minimum six dollars a week unless the wages were less than six dollars a week when the compensation is to equal the full amount of the wages." The law provides' two methods of compensating permanent and par - tial disabilities. The first group is specifically stated in the law and for each disability definite provision for compensation is made, e. g., for the loss of an arm 66% per cent of the daily wages for a period of two hundred twenty-five weeks, or tor the loser of the index finger 66% per cent of the wages for thirty-five weeks. The second group consists of partial disabilities not definitely named in the law. These are compen - sated by the payment of 66% per cent of the loss in earning capacity. In no case, however, is the payment to exceed fifteen dollars per week nor be less than six dollars a week except when the wages were less than six dollars a week, when the full amount of wages is paid." If an accident causes the death of an employee, leaving one or more persona wholly dependent upon him for support, the employer must pay he dependents compensation equal to 66% per cent of the wages earned T the deceased, subject to the fifteen dollar a week maximum and the x dollar a week minimum. Compensation is to be paid during de - pendency but not for a longer period than three hundred fifty weeks." only partial dependents survive the compensation they are entitled to to equal 66% per cent of the part of the wages of the deceased con - ibuted by him toward their support.™ Death benefits may be paid to non-resident aliens if they are, widows, children, or parents of the deceased, but not to non-resident aliens who are brothers, sisters, or widowers 1 of the deceased." Compensation to children ceases' when they reach the age of eighteen years unless their earning capacity is in some way impaired. 71 When the injury causes the death of the employee the employer must pay a reasonable burial expense not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars whether any dependents survive the deceased or not." In Nebraska as in most other states the entire payment of compensa - tion is made by the employer. The employer is also held liable for in - juries 1 caused by the negligence of a third party, but is subrogated to the right of the employee for suit against the third party." An employer under the act must insure his liability for compensation in an authorized -Ibid. -Ibid. "Ibid. "Ibid. "Ibid "Ibid ■ Sea. L. 1819, Ch. 81, B*c. 8, Sub. "«H. St. 1813, Sw. 86S9. &lt;»). </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 insurance company, or furnish proof of his financial ability to make the payments which might be required of him." Insurance policies must in - sure directly to the benefit of the beneficiaries and be enforcible in an action by them.™ Aside from requiring the employer to insure his liability, the act con - tains the following provisions for the further protection of the workmen: (1) The employee cannot waive his right for compensation; 77 (2)the amount of compensation the injured worker is entitled to receive is not affected by payment from other sources, on account of the injury; 71 (3) compensation is given the same preference over the assets of the employer as unpaid wages for labor; 7 * and (4) the amount received as compensation is not assignable nor can it be attached nor guarnisheed. M All disputed compensation claims must be submitted to the com - pensation commissioner for settlement. Appeals from the commissioner may be taken within limited time to the courts. The courts are also limited as to the time in which they may render their decisions." The foregoing is a brief discussion of the essential features of the Nebraska law. Points of the law which have attracted special attention will be discussed in detail below. "A* intruded in 1921 l.y S. F. 2, S |M "Sesi. L. 1917, Ch. 85, Sec. 22. " Rev. St. 1913. Ser. 3672. "Ibid, 8ec. 3671. &lt;* Ibid, Sec. 3692. "Ibid, Ser. 3691. " At amended in 1921 S F. No. 2, ■b </seg>
            <seg id="p014"/>
            <seg id="p015">15 CHAFfER II Powers and Duties of the Commissioner A serious detect in the common law system, which the compensation system attempts to eliminate, is the litigation which was necessary in order to enforce common law rights by legal process. Compensation legislation attempts to overcome this defect by providing a special system of administration for compensation law. Two methods of special admin - istration have been tried. The first method leaves the administration of the compensation law in the hands of the courts, but requires that com - pensation cases be decided with as little delay as possible, and be freed from legal technicalities 1 .' The second method is to establish a special commission to administer the law. Most states now have the commission system.' Nebraska adopted it in 1917.' The principle of providing special administrative machinery for special laws has* become popular. Commission administration is especially prac - tical for laws requiring more detailed attention than can be given by the authorities intrusted with the general administration of the laws; and for laws requiring, for their proper administration, certain technical qualifi - cations which are not generally possessed by the regular executive au - thorities. The commissions are considered part of the administrative machinery of the state and are given both executive and Judicial functions. Of course the Judicial powers of such commissions do not exist outside the organization of the courts, but are only preliminary tribunals from which appeals to the courts may be made. The chief judicial functions of a compensation commission is to make awards in disputed cases. Among the administrative functions of such commission is the power to prescribe blanks for the various re - ports, to supervise insurance companies, to grant permission to certain employers to carry their own insurance, and to keep a record of all elec - tions to come under the law. A report of all accidents and the compensa - tion paid for all injuries is- sent to the commission. The commission may thus judge as to whether the settlement was made according to law, and if it is not, may require a legal settlement. This supervision over the accidents reported combines the judicial and administrative functions of the commission. 1 Rhode*. J. E., Workmen's Compensation, p. 181. 'On January 1, 1920, 34 states had a compensation commission while 11 state* provide no machinery except the courts. (Bulletin United States Bureau of Labor Statistics 275, p. 114.) •Seas. L. 1917, Ch. 85, Sees. 25 27. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 The power to administer the law may be vested in a board of from hree to five members, or in a single commissioner as in Nebraska, ebraska, as many other states, consolidate the administration of the compensation law and the various labor laws in a state department of abor.' The tendency has been to increase the powers given the com - pensation commissions. This increase in powers has aided greatly in the Ilcient administration of the compensation laws.* The points considered under the general administration of the Nebraska law, are: (1) The organization of the administrative machin - ery; (2) the general administrative functions of the commissioner; and (3) procedure and methods in making awards. Organization of the Administrative Machinery The Nebraska law was administrated by the courts until 1917 when a compensation division was established in the bureau of labor." For con - stitutional reasons the governor was made chief compensation commis - sioner of labor was made chief deputy commissioner. 7 The commis - sioner of labor was appointed by the governor and served for a term of two years.' By the civil administrative code, enacted in 1919, the bureau of labor was superseded by the department of labor. The head of the department is now the secretary of labor who is also compensation com - missioner.' A description of the department of labor will be given in order that the administrative machinery of the compensation law may be understood. The department of labor is one of the six administrative departments created by the code." The head of the department is appointed by the governor with the advice and consent of the senate for a term of two years, and receives an annual salary of five thousand dollars. The gover - nor is empowered to appoint all the clerks, deputies, and assistants In the department and to fix their salaries at the time of making the ap - pointments, but is to confer with the secretary in making the appoint- • Bulletin of the United States Bureau of Labor Statistics, No. 275, p. 114 * John Mitchell, while a member of the New York compensation commission, said be - far* the City chub of Philadelphia: "In every American state the laws are successful just in proportion to the power that is placed in the hands of the administrative board." (American Labor Legislative Review, Vol. V., p. 16, March 1915.) * Section 28 of Art. V of the former constitution of the state provided that : "No other executive state officers shall be continued or created and the duties now devolving •pom saVsn not provided for by this constitution shall be performed by the officers here - im created." To get around this the governor was made chief of the new bureaus and appointed the deputies who managed the ottee. ' Sew. L. 1917. Oh. 85, Sec. 26, • Rev 8t. IBIS, Sees 3551 3554 The deputy labor commissioner received a salary of $1500 a year. • Seas L. 1919. Oh. 190, Title IT, Art. 1, Sec. 1, Sub » Btm. L. 1919, Oh. 190, Title I. Art. 1, Sec. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 ments." The power to remove both the secretary and the assistants Is vested In the governor." The secretary of labor gives the greater part of his time and attention to the administration of the compensation law. He has the assistance of the chief of the division of compensation, and a bookkeeper who keeps a complete accident and compensation record. The investigator and the stenographer also do a great deal of work in con* action with the compensation law. In fact all members of the de - partment are used in compensation work the greater part of the time. No attempt is made to set aside certain persons or periods of time for the different work of the department." The main office of the commis - sioner is located in the Capitol at Lincoln. A branch office" of the de - partment is maintained at Omaha. This is important us- a large number of accidents occur in Omaha." General Administrative Functions of the Commissioner When the division of compensation was established in 1917, the com - missioner was given extensive powers in administering the law. Most important of these is the power to conduct hearings and make awards. Aside from this power the commissioner is to make rules: and regulations, to prescribe blanks and forms, and to approve the policies upon which compensation insurance may be carried. The commissioner must approve all requests of employers to carry their own insurance before an em - ployer is permitted to do so. Notices of election not to come under the law or to come under it by voluntary agreement are died with the com - missioner. All accidents and payments of compensation are also re - ported to the commissioner. The commissioner is also in a position to do constructive work in preventing accidents. Both as compensation commissioner and as secretary of labor the commissioner is given authority to make rules and regulations not in - consistent with the law, for the government of the department." The rules promulgated by the compensation commissioner follow: Every accident which causes loss of work, or where medical or surg - ical services are rendered, must be reported to the commission on blanks 11 Ibid, Sees. 4, 5, 7, and 8. 11 The general provisions of the code say, "The governor shall have power to dis - continue the servici 1 of any such secretary or employee when in his judgment the same is no longer necessary." (Title 1, Art. I, Sec. 5.) ■ Interviews with department members and observations at office of commissioner at capitol. " The department hcuds are given power, with the approval of the governor, to es - tablish and maintain branch offices through the state. (Seas. L. 1919, Ch. 190, Title 1, Art. 1, Sec. 12.) "In 1917-18 of the 73 cases hoard 56 were Omaha cases. (Sixteenth Biennial Re - port. Compensation and Labor, p. 44-60.) In 1919-20 of the 244 ca?e* heard by the commissioner 170 were Omaha cases. There were over 2000 accidents in the six pack - ing plants in 1919-20. (Seventeenth Biennial Report. Compensation and Labor, p 11.) "Seas. L. 1919, Ch. 190, Title 1, Art. I, See. 11, and Session 1921 S. F. No. 2. See. 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 furnished by it, within ten days from the date thereof. The amount ex - pended for such medical or surgical services must be shown on the t2. Periodical Compensation Receipts or Statements must be filed th the Commission at least once each month. Likewise copy of ex - nditures for medical or hospital services in every accident reported, 1st be filed monthly. 3. Every employer must keep conspicuously posted in the workroom beard, furnished by the Commission, informing the employee as to hi; ;hts and benefits under this law. LI Where an accident occurs during the first half of the day or night, n that day or night shall be counted as one of the seven calendar days for which no compensation is allowed. This rule shall not apply where the injured employee receives wages of $2.50 or more as earnings for the day upon which the accident occurred. tS. Where wages are paid weekly on the basis of 5' 2 or 6 days' work istituting a week, compensation shall be computed on the basis of a -day week; where a seven day week is worked, compensation shall be nputed on that basis. 6. Compensation in cases where disability is apparent shall be paid as and when due; in cases of fatal accidents', the burial benefit of $150.00 must be tendered to the dependents within forty-eight hours after the death of the injured employee unless this be shown to be physically im - possible. k7. In cases where there is any permanent disability, a copy of the •sician's report, setting forth the nature and extent of such disability, st accompany the final releaee and receipt for compensation. t8. Generally speaking, the policy of the Commission is to discourage p-sum settlements; in the event such a settlement is mutually agreed n, the commissioner will approve same only when the strict letter of law is complied with. 9. It shall be the duty of every insurance company, authorized and licensed to practice the business of workmen's compensation insurance in this state, to furnish the commission with an accurate and correct list of the names and addresses of the employers insured by said company; this list thall be corrected and revised on or before the 10th day of each month, and is exclusively for the information of the Commission. 10. Any employer to whom permission has been granted to pay direct the compensation in the amount and manner and when due, who tails, neglects or refuses to comply with the provisions of the Nebraska Workmen's Compensation Law regarding the payments of compensation, shall be deemed guilty of violating the provisions of said law, and his permit shall be revoked by the Compensation Commissioner." bThe law gives the commissioner complete authority to prescribe all is and blanks for compensation records and reports." The most im - ant blanks are: 1. First Report of Accident 2. Periodical Statement 3. Final Riport and Settlement Receipt 11 Pamphlet ropy of the l»w tuned by the commiuioner, p. 46-47 &gt;• Sen. L. 1917, Ch. 85, See. 29, Sab. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 4. Financial Statement of Employers desiring to carry their own in - surance. 5. Petition for a Hearing Before the Compensation Commissioner." The facts called for by these blanks enable the compensation oommis- Bioner to secure all the information needed to keep in touch with all cases in which compensation is being paid. Recently the commissioner prepared a medical fee schedule to be used as a basis 1 by the department to adjust claims for professional serv - ices to the injured workers who come under the compensation law. The assistance of the department of public welfare and fifty physicians of the state were secured in preparing the schedule." It is not enough that accidents be compensated after they occur. Measures must be taken to prevent their occurrence. Accident preven - tion is best accomplished when the agency charged with the work is closely allied with the agency administering the compensation law. The arrangement in Nebraska secures the co-operation of these agencies, as the department of labor has charge of both the compensation law and the accident prevention work. The secretary of labor is required to secure and publish information relative to the prevention of accidents. 1 ' As compensation commissioner he receives much valuable data concern - ing the accidents which occur in the state. More than this the secretary of labor is given general supervision over the enforcement of the safety and health provisions of the labor laws." and receives 1 reports of all acci - dents, from all employers operating plants in which machinery is used." Again, may it not be said with reason that employers can well give con - sideration to the accident prevention suggestion? of a secretary of labor as he is also their compensation judge. Insurance companies are active in accident prevention work. Em - ployers are rewarded for taking their advice by being allowed a reduction in premium. Violations of the safety and health act were formerly voluntarily reported to the department by the insurance investigators. In 1921 a law was passed requiring such reporting by the insurance com - panies." In order that the employer may always be able to pay the awards, the law requires each employer to carry insurance with a company licensed to write compensation insurance in the state, and on a policy approved by the compensation commissioner, unless permitted by the " A specimen of these blanks will be found in appendix. " Seventeenth Biennial Report, Labor and Compensation, p. 8 » Sew. L. 1919, Ch. 190, Title IV, Art. I. Sec. 1, Sub. 8. » Ibid, Art. IV, Sect. 1-4. "Ibid, Art. IV, Sec. 17. ••Session 1921. H. R. 801, Sec. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 commissioner to carry hit own insurance." Bach policy contains a rider stating that the company is insuring the total liability of the employer under the Nebraska workmen's compensation law." On April 1, 1921, there were twenty-seven companies writing compensation insurance in the state. With the exception of one nationwide mutual the insurance companies doing business in the state were all stock companies." The permission of the compensation commissioner must be secured by all employers who wish to carry their own liability without insur - ing it. Before permission is given the commissioner must have satis - factory proof of the employer's financial ability to pay directly any com - pensation which might be assessed him. The commissioner makes his determination from a report of the business, which report includes a financial statement. These reports are submitted to the commissioner on blanks furnished by him to the applicant for self-insurance." At any time the commissioner may require an employer, carrying his own liability, to take out compensation insurance. In order that the commissioner might secure up-to-date information oncerning the financial condition of all employers carrying their own lability, during the unusual business conditions existing at the close of &gt;20, he required all such employers to submit new applications by the rat of 1921. Upon these applications forty-three employers were per - mitted to carry their own liability and three other applications were pending on April 1, 1921." Several applications were rejected by the ommiasloner. The law permits the commissioner to require deposits of cceptable security from employers carrying their own liability." As yet o deposits have been required. The' Insurance provisions of the law give the commissioner power enough to see to it that all employees under the law are properly pro - tected. It is generally believed that when the employe does not get the compensation to which he is entitled, it is because of his lack of knowl - edge of the law and the lack of co-operation between employer and em - ployee in securing it, rather than because of any defect in the law or the " Sees. L. 1017, Ch. 85, Sen. 21, 22. The insurance eommiuioner iune* the Unue to all insurance companies in the stats. k" The compensation commissioner has on file a specimen copy of sll policies approved the rider attached. The provisions of an approved policy and a copy of the rider be found in the appendix. " From specimen policies on file in office of commissioner, April 1, 1921 " See form in appendix. " Records in commissioner' • office, Lincoln, Nebraska t m Commissioner Kennedy so stated before the Nebraska Manufacturers' Association Omaha on December S, 1920. Chief of the compensation division, L. L. Dunn, re - is ifnorance of the law and lack of co-operation between the employer and the em - res the greatest problem of compensation administration * Boston 1921, 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Making Awards The Nebraska law has been in operation (or a little more than six years. The amount of compensation, including medical benefits 1 , paid during this period has increased from $51,167.57 in 1915 to $540,213.08 in 1920, w more than tenfold. However the number of accidents has not in - creased in proportion to the Increase in compensation which has been awarded. The number of accidents reported in 1915 was 4,082 while the num - ber of 1920 was 13,676, or three times the number reported in 1915. Tbe larger amounts of compensation being paid at present are due to the in - creased per cent of wages which are paid as compensation, the higher weekly maximum allowed, the shorter waiting period, and the larger number of cases closed because of commission administration. The fol - lowing table shows the changes in the law and their effect upon the com - pensation paid. STATEMENT OF ACOIDENTS REPORTED AND COMPENSATION PAID UNDER THE NEBRASKA LAW Year 1915 1916* 1917 1918 1 1919 1920' No. Accidents 4,082 10,822 13,293 | 7,066 11 273 13,676 Cases Closed I 2,222 | 5,411 13,298 6.463 8,791 9,729 Compensation $24,923 j $76,143 $101,204 |$102,540 {$255,313 $402, 7S0 Medical Aid 26,243 I 50,814 I 51,827 39,231 90,162 137,432 Total $51,166 |$116,958 |$153,031 |$141.771 !$345,475 !$540,212 1 Seventeenth Biennial Report. Labor and Compensation Commission, p. 10 ■The waiting period in 1915 and 1916 was fourteen days. The compensation was fifty per rent of tbe wages subject to a maximum of ten dollars a week. ■ In 1917 the waiting period iti reduced to seven days and the compensation was raised to 66% per cent of the wages with a twelve dollar maximum per week. 4 The 1919 legislature increased the maximum to fifteen dollars a week To secure compensation the workman must serve notice of injury upon the employer within six months and make claim for compensation within one year." Both notice and claim are required and neither takes the place of the other." When the injury results in mental incapacity, the limits are six months and one year after the removal of such inca - pacity.' 4 Notice of injury six months after the culmination of an injury, which at first seemed trivial, but which later developed graver symptoms 1 , -Seas. L. 1917. Ch. 86, Sees. 11 and 14. » Good t. City of Omaha, 103 Neb. 864. « Seas. L. 1917. Ch. 86, Sees. 11 and 14. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 complies with the law." Failure to make claim for compensation often keeps an injured workman from receiving compensation to which he would otherwise have been entitled." The commissioner tries to inform all injured workmen of their rights to compensation." If possible the employer and employee are to settle "all matters of compensation between themselves." Only disputed cases are taken to he commissioner for settlements, but all Injuries are reported to him nd all settlements approved by him before they become binding." By means of reports the commissioner secures all the data concerning the njury and the payments of compensation." A complete record of all the acts is kept so that the commissioner knows at all times the status of all cases in which compensation is being paid." The final receipt and release Utement is sent to the commisisoner when signed by the injured worker, his report is checked to determine whether or not the compensation as awarded according to the provisions of the law. If the settlement was Incorrect the case is continued until all requirements have been met nd approval given by the commissioner. The fact that both the employer and the employee agree to the settle - ment does not make it final unless it is according to law." Further com - pensation may be had after a release is signed if the Injury later causes a further disability," or if it can be proved that the signature of the em - ployee was secured through fraud or misrepresentation." Practically all cases are settled directly between the employer and the employee and come before the commissioner only for his approval." " Johnson t. Union Stock Yard* Co., BO Neb. 328. "Thru cam in March, 1821, in which compensation was denied because of failure to saake claim are found in Docket 4. Claim 4, Claim 22 and Claim 59 — 1920-21. Each eoammiasioner has used a different system of recording the cases presented to him. This brine the case, the date of the biennium in which the rasa was beard will be given with Ik* Docket and Claim number. k" Through newspaper clipping* the commissioner learns of practically all the injuries occur in the state not reported according to law. To each injured workman as s is seat a copy of the law and a letter from the department offering ita aid in ing tke rights of the injured man. For a copy of the letter tee appendix. "8e»s. L. 1917, Ch. 85. Sec. 12 k" The commissioner requires three different reports concerning the injury. In the 1 in which they are required they are: "First Report of Injury," Form C1-20H, iodirsl Statement of Payment," Form CS-Slf, and "Final Report and Settlement ipt." Form C4-5M. See appendix. I" A ledger record is kept of all injuries. On an individual ledger page is recorded payments for injuries extending over a long period of time. « Perry v. Huffman, 179 N. W. 501 « Docket 2, Claim 52—1919-20. - Swan v. Lincoln Terminal Co., 103 Neb. 88. "The commissioner may attempt to settle disputes by an informal hearing. In 1917-18 tk* commissioner estimate* he settled some 800 cases through informal hearings. (Sixteenth Biennial Report, Compensation and Labor, p. 44.) During 1919-20 the number of such hearings was about 350. (Estimate Investigator Jchn Tan— in an lmurvww,/ </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 This being the case the importance of careful checking and examination of settlements at the commissioner's office is apparent. When an agreement between the parties cannot be secured a formal hearing is held. To secure a formal hearing either party may file with the commissioner a petition which sets forfti the facts and points at issue. 4 * The assistance of an attorney is not necessary in making out the petitions.** In many cases the injured person presents his claim be - fore the commissioner without employing an attorney." The power of the commissioner in hearing cases and receiving in - formation is practically as complete as that conferred upon the courts. The commissioner is not hampered by any technical methods in pro - cedure, for the commissioner is permitted to "adopt reasonable and proper rules to govern procedure, which procedure shall be as summary and simple as reasonably may be."** Furthermore, the commissioner "shall not be bound by the usual common law or statutory rules or by any technical or formal rules of procedure, other than as herein provided, but may make the investigation in such manner as, in his judgment, is best calculated to ascertain the substantial rights of the parties and to carry out the spirit of"** the compensation law. Formal procedure never blocks the progress of a case before the commissioner. Appeals from the commission may be taken to the district court "which shall have authority to hear and determine the cause as in equity and enter final judgment therein, determining all questions of law and fact." The petition to appeal from the award of the commissioner must be filed with the district court within seven days after the award of the commissioner is given. The district court shall then hear the case with - out delay." If the case is to be appealed from the district court, the notice of appeal must be made within thirty days after the judgment is given. Compensation cases before the supreme court must be advanced so as to come up for argument within sixty days after the notice of appeal was filed. The supreme court must submit its opinion within thirty days after the case was argued." Thus the appeal of a case to the district court cannot delay the settlement for more than four months. Another provi- &lt;* Session 1921, 8. F. No. 2, See. 1. ** If requested by the injured person the commissioner or his assistants will draw up the pttition for him. (Statement by chief of compensation division, L. L. Dunn.) A blank form of the petition will be found in appendix. "Seas. It, 1917, Ch. 85, Sec. 29, Sub. ((). Personal observation of cases being tried before the commissioner. "Seas. L. 1917, Ch. 85, Sec. 29, Sub. (a). •Ibid, Sub. (b). M Seas. L. 1919, Ob. 91, See. 5. ■ Session 1921, 8. F. 2, See. 1. "Ibid. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 sion, which helps the worker when an appeal is made, provides that the award of the commissioner be binding until the court has rendered final Judgment. " Certainly the Nebraska law makes possible a rapid settle - ment of compensation cases, an essential element of a good compensa- tln the cases which have required the services of the commissioner the courts' in their settlement, several important interpretations of the r have been made which will be considered in the next chapter. "The law nji: "Every order and award of the compensation rommiuioner shall br binding u|x&gt;n each party at interest unless notice of intention to appeal to the district court bat been filed with the compensation commissioner within seven days following the date of rendition of the order or award: Provided, that the order and award shall be binding and final, notwithstanding notue of intention to appeal has been fllod within the time limit, until the appeal has been perfected and service had upon the opposite party or paitiea." (Seaa. L 1917, Ch. 85, Ser. 29, Sob. (().) </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 CHAPTER III Construction and Interpretation of the Law It possible all matters pertaining to the settlement (or an injury, are to be agreed upon between the employer and the employee. If such is not possible the commissioner hears the case and makes an award. The method of bringing disputes' before the commissioner and appealing them to the courts has been described in Chapter II. The number of disputes brought before the commissioner and the courts has been very small. 1 But these cases In dispute have brought out several important constructions and interpretations which deserve consideration. Disputes arise chiefly over such questions as these: Does the law apply to a certain employer and employee? Is the damage and injury caused by an accident? Did it arise out of and in the course of employ - ment? Did the wilful negligence of the employee rause the injury? What is the nature and extent of the injury? Shall a lump sum settle - ment be made? And is the injured worker entitled to "Waiting time penalty" money? Arising out of these various questions, the two that have attracted most attention and deserve the greatest consideration are the application of the law to the employees of the state, and unfair methods of lump sum settlements. The first of these will be discussed under the coverage of the law, and the latter under lump sum settlements. The important constructions and interpretations as determined in the dis - puted cases will be presented in this chapter. Coverage of the Law The only questions raised In Nebraska regarding the provisions for election to be bound by the law, have been in connection with the em - ployers who have failed to take out insurance and who failed to elect not to be bound by the schedule. The law provides that such an employer shall be assumed to have elected not to come under the law, but "shall be required to respond" to damage suits brought by his employees. In such suits he shall be denied the common law defenses.' Elsewhere the law provides that unless the employer definitely elects not to come under the law, it shall be assumed that he has elected to come under it.' The 1 The commissioner began hearing disputes in July, 1917, and from that time to January 1, 1921, the commissioners have heard 313 cute*. (Seventeenth Biennial Re - port, Compensation and Labor, p. 8.) The supreme court has rendered derisions in about fifty compensation rases. ' Session 1921, 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1 •Seas. L. 1917, Ch. 85, Sec. 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 commissioner permits the injured employee of such an employer to choose, after the injury, between suing his employer, or attempting to secure compensation according to law.' The legislature of 1921 made the commissioner's interpretation the letter of the law.' The Nebraska law applies to the state and the governmental agencies created by it and to all employers not specifically excluded. The general classes excluded are employers of farm laborers, domestic servants, and employees of railroads engaged in interstate commerce.' According to the definition of the term "employee," persons doing work away from the regular place of employment at their homes and "casual" workers, are denied the benefits of the law. 7 The question has been raised as to the rights of farm laborers injured while not directly employed at farm work. If their employer follows arming as his chief occupation, such employees have no right to com - pensation.' Injured thresbermen are entitled to compensation only when he owner of the machine is working for pecuniary gain.' Compensation of course denied railroad employees even though their work is- always performed within the state." No dispute has as yet arisen as to who are considered domestic servants. The term "casual" as defined by law "shall be construed to mean 'occasional'; coming at certain times without regularity, in distinction from stated or regular." 11 A workman who unloaded coal for various coal yards but who was specifically hired by each yard to unload each car at a price per ton fixed at the time of hiring, was held to be a casual." While the law definitely states 1 that employees of the state are en - titled to compensation," they have recently lost this right, because the "gain or profit" phrase" has been held to apply to state employees. In an early case this question was at issue, but was not settled because com - pensation was denied on other grounds." While the matter was an open question compensation was paid to employees of counties" and cities" as • Docket 2. Claim 17 — 1019-20. • Session 1921, 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1 •Beat. L. 1917, Ch. 85, See. 1. I Session 1921. 8. F No. 3, Sec. 1. • Docket 8, CUim 85 — 1919 SO. •Docket 8, CUim 10 — 1919-20; also opinion of eommiuioner, April 19, 1920 "Docket 1. CUim 4 — 1917-18. ■ Session 1921. S. F. No. 2. Sec. 1. "Bridcer t. Lincoln Fuel and Feed Co., 179 N. W. 1020. ■ Seat. L. 1917, Ch. 85, Sec. 1. and ReT. St. 1913, Sec. 3655 "Sen. L. 1917. Ch. 85, Sec. 4, Sub. 3. Good t. City of Omaha, 102 Neb. 654-7. Compensation was denied because claim not been made within six months after the injury. M Docket 1, CUim 51 — 1919-20, and Doekrt 3, CUim 84, 1919-20. ■ Docket 1, CUim 58 — 1919-20, and Docket 8, CUim 150, 1919-20 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 well as employees of the state." Thus the present attitude is a distinct reversal of the former policy. This new doctrine was laid down in a case involving the rights of a Lincoln school Janitor to compensation and the same day the doctrine was applied to three policemen." The benefits of the law were thus denied to practically all state employees for very few are engaged in activities conducted for gain or profit. The few governmental agencies from which a revenue is derived are considered as being conducted for profit." The legislature of 1921 removed the phrase "employment for gain or profit" so that governmental employees are again covered by the law." State employees or employees of a governmental agency created by the state are not entitled to compensation if they are elected or appointed for a regular term." "Regular" was once construed to "have been used by the legislature in the popular sense of 'conformable to law,' " but later this construction was overruled and "regular term" is now taken to mean a term which expired at a definite time." Few state employees should be excluded from the law by this meaning of "regular term." The application of the law to sub-contractors, independent contract - ors, negligent third parties, and those extra-territorially employed may also be considered a subdivision of the coverage of the law. The law sets forth- .so clearly the relation of a contractor to a sub-contractor that no litigation has arisen. The owner or contractor may require the contractor or sub-contractor to carry insurance on the men working for him. But if the injured worker cannot secure compensation from a contractor or sub-contractor, because of his failure to insure, the owner or contractor is still liable." However, as a sub-contractor or an independent con - tractor is not an employee he is not entitled to compensation." Another feature pertaining to the coverage of compensation laws is the question of the extraterritoriality, that is, the application of the law "Docket 3, Claim 9 — 1919-20, and Docket 3, CUim 89, 1919-20. '• On December 23, 1920, the Nebraska supreme court handed down four decisions involving the question of state employed being engaged for profit or gain. In Ray v. School District of Lincoln, 181 N. W. 140, the phrase was held to apply to the state and its governmental agencies, and that a school janitor was not engaged for profit or gain. In Mccomber t. City of North Platte and Rogers v. same, 181 N. W. 145, and Rooney r. City of Omaha, 181 N. W. 143, policemen were held not to be employed for profit and therefore did not come under the act. " Ray t. School District of Lincoln, 181 N. W. 140 11 Session 1921, S. F. No. 2, Sec. 1 n Session 1921, S. T. No. 2, Sec. 1 " In Rooney v. City of Omaha, 177 X. W. 166-7, the first opinion was stated. The present attitude was handed down in a rehearing of the same ease, 181 N. W. 143-44. ■ Rev. St. 1913, Sec. 3657. =• Barrett v. Selden-Breck Construction Co., 174 N. W. 866. Also Docket 3, Claim 90 — 1919-20. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 to employees injured outside the state. On this point the Nebraska law s silent. Nor has 1 the question been settled by a judicial decision. How - ver a tendency was indicated when compensation was awarded the de - pendent of a worker, who was killed on the holdings of the Carter Lake Club. These holdings are on the Nebraska side of the Missouri river ear Omaha but on land included within the state of Iowa. Compensation was paid, not because the land was on the Nebraska side of the river, but because, in this case the place of employment was definitely stated in the insurance policy. 1 " Evidently if the place of employment is specified tthe policy, the insurance company will be held liable although the ce of employment is outside the state. Workmen hired outside the state and injured in Nebraska do not come under the law." When an injury is caused by the negligence of a third party the em - ployer directly brings suit against the third party in order that he may recover the compensation he is required to pay. However the employer is not limited, in making the suit, to the amount he is required to pay, but may if possible secure more, all of which goes to the injured em - ployee, except costs." If the employee, but not the employer, wishes to bring suit against a negligent third party he may do so. But the amount secured in the suit is to be deducted from the amount due the employee as Empensation." The employee is entitled to secure a larger amount than his mpensation would have been, in which case the employer is required to y nothing." An injured workman and a liable third party cannot make settlement without the consent of the employer." The Nebraska law rtainly gives the employee all possible advantage in dealing with gligent third parties. Yet it is equally fair to the employer for not only es it give him the right of suit when the third party was wholly to ime. but also when his "negligence concurred with the negligence of » third party."" Accidents and Injuries The terms "accident" and "injury" are both defined in the law. An ccident must be an "unexpected or unforeseen event happening suddenly and violently, with or without human fault, and producing at the time bjective symptoms of an injury." The term "Injury" "shall mean only violence to the physical structure of the body and such diseases as aturally results therefrom.'"* The term "objective symptoms-" has been » Venuto t. Carter Lake Club, 178 N. W. 760 " Docket 3, Claim 92, 1919-20. "Her. St. 1913, Sec. 3659 »Thoma» t. Otu Elevator Company, 103 Nab. 401-6 " Docket 3, Claim 136 — 1919-20. •&gt; Hugh Murphy Construction Co. v. Seeok. 177 N. W. 747-8 "Otii Elevator Co. t. Miller * Paine, 240 Fed. 375-9. Diacnucd in Bureau of Labor 8tatiitiea, Bulletin 243, p. 84. "Se««ion 1921, S. F. No. 2. See. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 broadly construed, it being held "that symptoms of pain, and anguish, such as weakness, pallor, faintness, sickness, nausea, expressions of pains clearly involuntary, or any other symptoms indicating a deleterious change in the bodily condition may constitute objective symptoms as re - quired by the statute."" One type of injuries which presents puzzling problems to the ad - ministrators of the law are those which arise from natural cause as sun stroke, heat stroke, and freezing. It is generally held that if the employ - ment has increased the effectiveness of the natural forces the person is entitled to compensation. But compensation is not granted if the injury was just as likely to have happened to anyone not so employed. The Nebraska courts have accepted this attitude and have clearly expressed it when they awarded compensation to a widow whose husband had died as a result of a heat stroke. The court said, "It is our view that com - pensation is a charge against the industry because the industry in itself is responsible for'the injury." Heat stroke is an accident because "an accident is an event which proceeded from an unknown cause or is an unusual effect of a known cause and therefore not expected."* 9 Persons suffering injuries due to freezing and frostbite are entitled to compensa - tion under the Nebraska law." Questions are sometimes raised as to whether poisoning, asphyxia - tion, etc., are injuries caused by accident. In Nebraska compensation has been paid for injury caused by axphyxiation," over-exertion," and poison - ing from sal soda." Infection following an injury is considered as part of the injury." A laborer received compensation for his disability caused by Infection in a boil which developed under a callous on his hand." Com - pensation is paid for strains and hernias if it can be shown that they were caused by some specific accidents." A difficult problem is raised when the prior existing condition of the worker appears to modify the normal consequence of an accident. That is, to what extent should the employer be held liable when the increased seriousness of an injury was caused by the previous condition of the in - jured? In such cases the general rule Is that "the employer takes his em - ployee subject to the physical condition he is in at the time he enters the "Manning t. Pomerene, 101 Neb. 127 30. "Younf t. Western Furniture Co., 101 Neb. 806-701. Other heat stroke caaea are Kanseheit t. Garrett Laundry Co., 101 Neb. 702, and Docket 2, Claim 42 — 1919-20. "Docket 1, Claim 4 — 1919 20, and Docket 3, Claim 35 — 1919-20. " Docket 3. Claim 31 — 1919-20. ■ Docket 1, Claim 28—1919-20. » Docket 1, Claim 45 — 1919-20. ■ Docket 1, Claim 20 — 1919-20. " Docket 2, Claim 36 — 1919-20. Manning v. Pomerrnc, 101 Neb. 127-9, and Docket 2, Claim 50 — 1919-20 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 employment;"" and, even though the injury were in reality only the aggravation of existing conditions, compensation must be paid as if the injury actually caused the disability of a person otherwise able to con - rue his employment. The construction of the Nebraska courts conforms this general rule. In a case in which the employer claimed the death his employee was due to the aged and weakened condition of the em - ployee, the court said, "A stronger man might have lived, but it is enough that the injury brought about the man's death."" However compensation need not be paid when the condition is the development of natural causes Cnot the result of a specific accident." Quite possibly there is a ten - cy to attribute a condition due to natural causes to an accident. Occupational diseases are not subject to compensation, both because they are definitely excluded" and because they are not caused by accident." Arising out of and in the Course of Employment The injury not only must have been caused by an accident, but must also "arise out of and in the course of employment."" Note the two parts of the phrase which requires not only that the accident be in the course of employment but also that it arise out of it. The question as to whether the accident arises out of the employment, gives rise to the greatest amount of litigation. To be within the meaning of the phrase the accident must occur at the regular place of employment and during working The question has sometimes been raised as to whether accident! hich occur on the way to and from work, arise out of and in the course f employment. It is held that such accidents do in cases where the em - oyer furnished the transportation," and where the employee was per - orming a service in the interest of his employer." Compensation was warded the dependents of a man who was killed while posting a letter or his employer." A clerk who was injured while going after a lunch uring working hours, with the consent of the employer, received com - pensation." extent to which compenstalon would be paid, to persons doing k other than that for which they were specifically hired, has never " Decision industrial accident commission of California, Vol. 2, p. 525, quoted in Bureau of Labor Statistics. Bulletin 20S. M Young t. Western Furniture ft Manufacturing Co., 101 Neb. 090 " Docket 3, Claim 158. «• Seasion 1921, 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1. " Blair w. Omaha Iec ft Cold Storage Co., 102 Neb. 18 ■ Rer. St. 1913. Sec. S650. " Seasion 1921. 8. F. No. 2. See. 1. "Docket S, Claim 1 — 1919-20; alto opinion of commissioner October 28, 1920 ■ roster t. Thompson Hotel Co., 102 Neb. 585. 11 Farmers Grain * Supply Co. of Minden ». Blanchard, 178 N. W. 257 " Docket S, Claim M — 1919-20. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 been fully determined. However, any employee injured while advancing the Interest of his employer, although not directly acting under orders, would no doubt be regarded as having received his injury from and in the course of his employment." If the injury is caused by the wilful inten - tion of a fellow workman or outsider the Injury is held to arise out of the employment only when the cause of the attack was the result of the em - ployment." The supreme court has recently reversed itself on the question as to whether all injuries received while playing aris« out of the employment. The first opinion of the court was that an employer was not required to pay compensation to an employee injured by the playful assaults of a fellow workman, although the injured worker himself took no part in the frolic." But at present the court holds that the injured employee who did not engage in the horseplay which caused his injury, is entitled to compensation. In rendering this decision the court took into cnsidera - tion that such play is likely to occur where a number of men are em - ployed, hence It is one of the risks of employment, and consequently arises out of it." An injury does not arise out of the employment if the injured employee has stopped his work to take part in the frolic. M Gen - erally speaking, the phrase, "arising out of and in the course of employ - ment," has been liberally construed in Nebraska. Wilful Negligence If an employee is injured because of his wilful negligence, neither he nor his dependents are entitled to compensation. 1 * Wilful negligence in - cludes a deliberate act, reckless indifference to safety, or intoxication.** In a recent decision the supreme court said reckless indifference to safety "implies a rash and careless spirit, not necessarily amounting to wanton - ness, but approximating it in a degree, a willingness to take a chance.'" 1 Another point, favoring the dependents of a worker who has been killed, is that accident is assumed until suicide is proved." Medical Benefits Originally the law provided that the employer should provide medical aid for twenty-one days after the accident, which in amount need not •• Morris * Co. v. dishing, 103 Neb. 481. "Cauil t. American Smelting ft Refining Co., 178 N. W. 639. "Pierre v. BoyerVan Kuran Lumber ft Coal Co., 99 Neb. 321 " Soeha v. Cudahy Packing Co., 181 N. W. 706. "Docket 3. Claim 22, and Fcda v. Cudahy Packing Co., 102 Neb. 110. » Rev. St. 1913, Sec. 3668. "Farmer! Orain Supply Co. of Ifinden v. Bianchard, 178 N W. HI « Ibid, 258. ■ Seuion 1921, 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 exceed two hundred dollars." Even though the Injury did not reach its most serious development within the twenty-one days no aid could be secured after the twenty-first day." In 1917 the time limit, during which medical aid was required, was removed in cases requiring dismember - ment or a major surgical operation." In 1919 the time limit was removed for all cases" and in 1921 the limit on the amount was removed. 87 So now the employer is required to furnish "reasonable" medical aid without limit as to time or amount. No limit through interpretations has as yet been placed on the term "reasonable." The employer is to designate the physician to be employed, except in cases of dismemberment or major surgical operations, and is not re - sponsible for medical expenses otherwise contracted." Employing physicians, not designated by the employer, is costing the injured work - er* of the state a large amount. This is especially true among the foreign Nature and Extent of Injury To determine the nature and extent of the injuries the employer may require the employee to submit to an examination. Refusal fo submit to the examination is a bar to compensation. 7 ' The request for an examina - tion must be reasonable. 71 It may Include an X-ray examination if such is deemed necessary. It was held unreasonable, however, to require the in - jured employee to submit to the injection of "coloragal" into the kidney to make it opaque. 11 In many cases a physician is called upon to determine the nature and extent of the injury so that the proper schedule may be applied. 71 Injuries may be classified as partial or total in character, and perma - nent or temporary in extent. For injuries permanent and total the worker receives 66% per cent of his wages, not to exceed fifteen dollars a week for 300 weeks; then 45 per cent of his wages, but not to exceed $12 per week for the remainder of his life. If the injury is total in character but only temporary in extent the worker receives 66% per cent of his wages "Her. St. ISIS. See. 3061 L* 4 Simon t. Cathroe Co., 101 Neb. 211, and Epslen v. Hanrock-Epsten Co., 101 442. "Bra*. L. 1921 or 1919, 8m. 1 ;Ha&lt;liI T. Morris Co.. 103 Neb. 84, and Docket 2 Claim 8 — 1919-20. * MtntmWe nth Biennial Report, Labor and Compenaation, p. 127 "Her. St. 1913, See. 3875. " United States Fidelity * Guarantee Co. T. Wickline, 103 Neb. 38. "United Stain Fidelity * Oanrantee Co. t. Wirkline, 173 N. W. 889. "Docket 1, Claims 18, 19, 80, 39, and Docket 2, Claims 12, 27 and 30 — 1919 20 ■ Sen. L. 1917, Ch. 85. Sec. 7. •8m. L. 1817, Ch. 01, See. 1. - Smuob 1821, 8. F. No. 2, 8m. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 during the period of disability. 7 ' Temporary disability is not necessarily ended if the injured employee works a few days at other than his regular employment, even though the wages thus received are higher than his usual wage.™ There are two general methods of compensating injuries for partial disability: (1) payment of 66% per cent of the wages for the loss in earning power, and (2) payment of 66% per cent of the wages for a specified number of weeks when the injury is one definitely enumerated. If the injury is in the schedule of enumerated injuries the compensation must be according to such schedule and not otherwise. That is, while the loss of one leg may render the injured man totally disabled he is en - titled only to compensation equal to 66% per cent of his wages for two hundred fifteen weeks, and no more. 7 ' Loss of function of a member is equivalent to the loss of the member. Partial loss of function of any member enumerated is to be compensated by an amount equal to the re - lationship that the partial loss bears to the amount which would have been received for the loss of the member. When the injury results In the amputation of a member sometime after the accident the injured worker receives total disability compensation until the time of amputation and in addition to this the full amount allowed for the loss of the member. 77 Lump Sum Settlements While periodical payments, in accordance with the method of pay - ment of wages to the employes, is the required method by which com - pensation is to be paid, 7 the law permits a settlement by one lump sum."' Agreement of both parties' is the first requisite to a lump sum settle - ment." An insurance company is bound to make the payment in the lump sum agreed upon between the employer and the employee, even though the insurance company was not consulted in making the settle- 74 Seuion 1921, S. F. No. 2, Sec. 1 '•Hanley v. I'nion Stock Y»rd« Co., 100 Neb. 232. "Session 1921, S. F. No. 2, Sec. 1, and Hull v. United States Fidelity A Guarantee Co., 102 Neb. 246. ** The law was not clear on the question as to whether the injured worker was to hare total disability compensation in addition to the amount paid for the loss of the member. The commissioner held that the workmen were entitled to the full amount of the loss of the member after it had been amputated. (Docket 3, Claim 60 — 1919-20; Docket 4. Claim 3 — 1921-22.) A test case of the principle was made of Docket 4, Claim 3 (Holler v. Cudahy Pack. Co. in Douglas Co. Dis. Ct.) which upheld the interpreta - tion of the commissioner. A group of insurance adjusters agreed not to appeal the i-aae. In 1921 the law was clarified and now reads, "For disability rc«ulting from permanent injury of the following clasaes, the compensation shall be in addition to the amount paid for temporary disability." (Seuion 1921, 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1.) '•Session 1921, S. 7. No. 2, Sec. 1. "Meyers v. Armour, 103 Neb. 407-9, and Bailey v. United Statn Fidelity and Guarantee Co., 99 Neb. 109. "Seu. L. 1919, Ch. 91. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 ment." In all cases the approval of the commissioner is required, and in cases of death or permanent disability the approval of the district court must also be secured." The weakness in the Nebraska compensation law in the past has been connected with lump sum settlements in cases of death and perma - nent disability. The particular evil was that settlements were permitted In which the workman received much less compensation than entitled to under the schedule. However, the present commissioner has corrected this 1 abuse so that lump sum settlements are no longer a means of de - priving the worker of the total amount due him. A brief discussion of he method of settlement for less than scheduled compensation as it previously existed, and the correction of this abuse, may well be taken up at this point. Lump sum settlements for less than provided for in the schedule in - volve only cases of death and permanent disability. These are the only cases requiring the approval of the district court. Settlements for death were probably most inadequate in the first years under the law," while recently permanent disability settlements have been the most unjust. Taking the loss of a leg as an example, the method practiced was some - what as follows: For the loss of a leg the workman is entitled to 66% per cent of his wages, not to exceed fifteen dollars' a week, for two hun - dred fifteen weeks." If the worker had been earning more than twenty - two dollars and fifty cents a week he would receive in all $3,225.00. If an attempt were made to settle the case for less than 13,225.00, weekly pay - ment would probably be made for a few weeks and then discontinued. Before resuming payment an offer of a lump sum would be made, which with the amount already paid, would be less than the total of 13,225.00. To make the illustration clearer, let it be assumed that the amount paid in weekly installments has been $500 and that $1200 more is offered as a lump sum to settle the case. The injured worker would be in a position to choose between $1200 in a lump sum or $2,725 to be paid in weekly in - stallments over a period of three years. The temptation to accept the " Bailey v. United SUtes Fidelity and Guarantee Co., 99 Neb. 109 " Seaaioo, 1921, 8. F. No. 2, See. 1 k" The following table it compiled from bulletin 32 of the Nebraska Bureou of Labor Industrial Statistics, p. 20, and from the Fifteenth Biennial Report of the Nebraaka au of Labor and Industrial Statistics, p. 183. tonly one case were the dependent* paid an amount equal to or in excess of the imam provided by law. M Bill OB 1021, 8. F. No. 2. See. 1 Year ToUl Cum I Total Medical I Ann.. B.,«i&gt;. by »&gt;Md. P.yment M imi«« | Xui.a. 1915 S 18 $127.00 1,722.31 • 1,041.46 $2,050 $3,800 1,221.31 2,050 3.800 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 lump sum would be great to an injured worker needing money and having had difficulty in securing the weekly installments of compensa - tion. When such a settlement was accepted the district court generally approved the settlement regarding it as fair to both parties since each had agreed to it. In this way many cases were settled for less than scheduled compensation." A method for commuting the amount of lump sums was incorporated into the law in 1917." As indicated above this method was not followed in all cases. The supreme court did not hold the district courts to the letter of the law. In one case the court said: "The question appears to be whether the parties and the trial judge must with mathematical pre - cision, first proportion the loss, then commute the number of weeks and then the present value of the total amount, or whether they will be per - mitted to agree upon a lump sum in settlement without carrying out the commutation in detail." Quoting further the decision reads, "although the use of the word 'commute' may make the argument at least plausable, we do not think the statute intends to impose this necessity upon the parties. Settlements are usually arrived at by compromise." 87 That was just the trouble, the lump sum settlements were regarded as compro - mises. Ability on the part of some insurance adjusters to negotiate and the urgent needs of the injured worker were the controlling elements in the settlement, rather than the compensation provided by law. When the present administration learned of this it took a firm stand against the practice and refused to approve settlements for a single cent less than the law provided." Finally, in the Perry case," the old practice was overruled and the commissioner's policy approved by the supreme court. As this case is the most important event of the past two years in compensation administration, a brief history will be given. "John E. Perry was injured on June 20, 1918, while employed by the Huffman Automobile Company. 1 " The accident was reported to the com - missioner and compensation paid for twelve weeks. Payments were then "Docket 1, Claim 7 — 191718, Docket 1, Claim 24 — 1917-18, Dockrt 1, Claim 49 — 1917-18, are case* for less than settlement where hearings were held. Undoubtedly there are many others which did not give rise to a hearing and therefore are not recorded. M The provision of the law is "that where commutation is agreed upon or ordered by the -court, the lump sum to be paid shall be fixed at an amount which will equal the total sum of the probable future payments, capitalized at their present value upon the basis of interest calculated at five per centum per annum with annual rests." Session 1921, 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1. In an early case the same method with simple interest was held a correct method. Bailey v. U. S. Fidelity and Guarantee Co., 99 Neb. 109. This of coarse was before the amendment of 1917. " Perry v. Huffman, 175 N. W. 1021. It wa» in a rehearing of this case that the old principle was overruled and the present principle laid down. (179 N. W. 501.) "Docket 1, Claims 11, 40, 48, 58 — 1919-20. " Perry's injury consisted of two broken bones in his left ankle, which resulted in a "permanent partial loss" of the use of the foot within the meaning of the statute (Sew. L. 1917, Ch. 85, Sec. 7.) " Seventeenth Bienniel Report, Labor and Compensation, p. 69. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 denied for nine months by the insurance company. Then a petition was filed before the compensation commissioner for a hearing. Before a hear - ing was had Perry's attorney and the insurance company's adjuster agreed to settle the case for five hundred dollars. Perry accepted the settlement, but when the final receipt was filed with the compensation department approval was denied. The compensation department then went before the district Judge who had approved the settlement and asked that It be set aside In order to allow the compensation commissioner to determine the disability as provided by law. But the district court refused to do so and the matter went to the supreme court. Here in the first Perry case the supreme court upheld the old idea of lump sum settlements being compromises.* 1 But the commissioner was not satisfied and finally secured a rehearing of the case. In the latter case the court handed down a decision which sustained very point maintained by the compensation commissioner. On the commutation of lump sums the court said, "In entering into an agree - ment under the workmen's compensation act to discharge the employer rom all liability for a permanent disability of the employee upon pay - ment of a lump sum in lieu of periodical payments, the parties are not t liberty to make a settlement at variance with statutory terms; and ascertainment of the amounts of a compensation payable periodically nder the law is a prerequisite to a contract for commutation." Note the contrast between this and the early attitude taken by the court. Further- Cre the court said, "Without accurate knowledge of the nature and i extent of the injury the compensation to which the plaintiff is en - titled is unknown and compensation based on the injury is a material factor in the approval of an agreement for commutation. The probable uture payments capitalized at their present value upon the basis' of nterest calculated at five per centum per annum with annual rests, is he statutory method of determining the lump sum payable in lieu of periodical payments. (Laws 1917, Ch. 86, Sec. 16.) There is no other tandard for commutation. Any method reducing the compensation thus scertained is unauthorized as a basis for the approval of a settlement."* 1 his case only Involved permanent disability but the commutation of a ump sum for a death benefit must be commutated by the same method." kBoth the supreme court and the compensation commissioner have out mselves on record as being opposed to lump sum settlements as a eral rule." And as the commissioner now has the power to approve M Perry t. Huffman, 175 N. W. 1031. » Perry T. Huffman, 179 N. W. 501-2 "Session 1921, S. F. No. 2, See. 1, says in part: "Lump-Sum Payment. The amount! of compensation payable periodically under the law by agreenunt of the parties with the approval of the compensation commissioner, may be commuted to one or more lump-sum payments, except compensation due for death and permanent disability, which may be commuted only upon the order of the district court." M Rules of compensation commissioner, pamphlet copy of compensation law. p. 47, 8. Perry t. Huffman, 179 N. W. 501. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 all lump sum settlements before they become binding, be may see to it that the rights of the injured worker are not infringed upon. The Perry case will serve as sufficient warning for those few who are inclined to deprive the injured worker of his Just compensation. Waiting Time Penalty The only penalty under the compensation law Is the requirement that the amount of compensation be increased fifty per cent on all delinquent payments after thirty days' notice has been given of injury." The maxi mum fifteen dollars a week applies only to the payment of regular com - pensation; so a payment which includes the penalty is not limited to this amount."* The law makes no provision to prevent the penalty from be - coming effective when a disputed point is unsettled at the end of the thirty days. But the supreme court has held that the penalty does not apply during the time a reasonable dispute is pending." The penalty is operative in all cases in which the compensation clearly due is not all paid, although the whole amount of the claim may be disputed." Conclusion The interpretation of the Nebraska law has been in keeping with the underlying principle involved in workmen's compensation legislation generally, which is that industrial accidents are a part of the cost of production and should be charged against the industry. The law has been so construed that the great percentage of injuries caused by em - ployment are compensated. The method now required in making lump sum settlements is of distinct advantage to the permanently disabled worker. It is unfortunate that the state employees were denied the benefit of the act for a short time, but in 1921 an amendment was added bringing them again under the act." •8ei». L. 1919, Ch. 91, Sec. 4 "United States Fidelity and Guarantee Co. v. Wickline. 170 N. W. 193 •' t'pdike (train Co. t. Swinion, 178 N. W. 618, and Oiborn t Omaha Structural Steol Co.. 179 N. W. 1020. " Abel Construction Co. v. Goodman, 181 N. W. 706. "Sowion 1921. 8. F. No. 2, Sec. 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p038"/>
            <seg id="p039">39 CHAPTER IV Rehabilitation, Occupational Diseases, and State Fund Insurance Social insurance is a broad subject and includes insurance against occupational disease, against old age and invalidity, and against unem - ployment as well as insurance against industrial accidents. While it is not the purpose of this chapter to consider any of the above named phases of social insurance, attention will be given to such subjects as are distinct outgrowths of workmen's compensation, and to phases of com - pensation legislation not existing in Nebraska but used in other states. The subjects to be discussed are: (1) Rehabilitation of industrial cripples; (2) occupational diseases; and (3) state insurance funds. The last two named have been connected with workmen's compensation since its beginning but which are assuming increasing attention. Rehabilita - tion is a distinct outgrowth of workmen's compensation of recent de - velopment. Rehabilitation "The most important recent legislative development of workmen's compensation legislation is in extending the benefits of compensation acts to include vocational education and rehabilitation of men disabled in industry.'" While a few states' independently take up this work, the federal government recently passed an act to co-operate with the states In providing vocational rehabilitation for industrial cripples. The first state act was that of Massachusetts passed in 1918. The Federal Indus - trial Rehabilitation Act* was approved June 2, 1920. Under this act, as under the act of federal aid for vocational education and the federal act for the rehabilitation of soldiers and sailors, the federal government does not propose to undertake the organization and immediate direction of vocational rehabilitation in the states, but does agree to make substan - tial financial contributions to carry on the work. "It undertakes to pay over to the states annually certain sums of money, and to co-operate in fostering vocational rehabilitation. The grants of federal moneys are conditional and the acceptance of these grants imposes upon the states ■ French. I. Will., The Trend of Workmen's Compensation, Monthly Labor Review. Vol. XI, p. 875, November 1920. * States with iuch acts are California, New York, Massachusetts. Illinois, Pennsyl - vania, New Jersey, Minnesota and Oregon. ■United States Public Laws, 66 Congress, Session II. Ch. 219 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 specific obligations to expend the moneys paid over to them in accord - ance with the provisions of the act.'" The money granted by the federal overnment is not large, being only $750,000 for the fiscal year ending une 30, 1921, and $1,000,000 annually thereafter for a period of two years. Payment to the various states is to be made in the proportion which the opulation of each state bears to the total population of the United Utes. No state is to receive less than five thousand dollars for any ear.' The allotment to Nebraska for the year ending June 30. 1921, is 1,757. 19.' As in other acts providing federal aid for the state, the states are required to match federal money with state money, dollar for dollar.' he object of the Federal Industrial Rehabilitation Act is "the conserva - on of the economic efficiency of the whole citizenry economically fit."* he benefits of the act are in no respect limited to the injured employees ntitled to compensation under the law of any state.' Rehabilitation work is to be accomplished through the co-operation of the state and federal governments. This co-operation of the state with the federal government is based upon four fundamental ideas:" "First, that vocational rehabilitation for persons disabled in industry or other - wise being essential to the national welfare, it is a function of the na - tional government to encourage the states to undertake this new and needed form of service; second, that federal funds are necessary in order to equalize the burden of carrying on the work among the states; third, that since the federal government is vitally interested in the success of Industrial rehabilitation it should participate in this work; and, fourth, that by creating such a relationship between the national and state governments proper standards of efficiency in vocational rehabilitation can best be set up." No new governmental machinery is created by the act, its admin - rtion being placed in the hands of boards which already exist. For federal government, the Federal Board for Vocational Education Industrial RehmbiliUtion — A Statement of Policies to be Observed in the- Admin - lion of the Industrial Rehabilitation Act, Bulletin ST. Series 1. p. 7. ■ United Bute* Public Lawi, 66 Congress, Seaaion II, Ch. 219 Industrial Rehabilitation — A Statement of Polieiea to be Observed in the Admin tion of the Industrial Rehabilitation Art, Bulletin 57, Series 1, p. 47. 1 United States Public Laws, 60 Congress, Seaaion II, Ch. 219, Ser. 1 * Industrial Rehabilitation — Methods of Organization, Misc. 240, Series No. 2, p. 1 * "The Federal Board for Vocational Education considers the sections and clauses re ferrinf to beneficiaries of the act to mean that the states will offer vocational rehabilita- Uoa to all persons of employable are. who by reason of a physical defect or infirmity, whether congenital or acquired by. accident, injury, or disease, appear to be or may be expected to be totally or partially incapacitated for remunerative employment in industry or in any legitimate occupation, and who may be reasonably expected to be fit to engage in a remunerative occupation after receiving a vocational rehabilitation course." (In - dustrial Rehabilitation — A Statement of Policies to be Observed in the Administration of the Induatral Rehabilitation Act, Bulletin 57, Series No. 1, p. 15.) " Industrial Rehabilitation — A Statement of Policies to be Observed in the Admin istration of the Industrial Rehabilitation Act, Bulletin 57, Series No. 1, p. 7. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 is to bave general supervision of the work. In the states the work is in charge of the state board for vocational education, but the state board must work in co-operation with the state agency which administers the workmen's compensation. While the Federal Board for Vocational Edu - cation Is required to approve the plan of the state boards and to see to it that the general provisions of the law are carried out; and that the federal money is used as required by law; the state board works out the details of the administration of the law within the state. The agree - ment for the co-operation of the federal and state boards is made be - tween the Federal Board and each state board separately, thus enabling each state to provide a system which will meet its particular needs." The agreements are made for only one year at a time." "To secure the co-operation of the states the act provides that the state shall, through its legislative authority, accept the provisions of the federal act and empower and direct the state board for vocational educa - tion created in the state through the state's acceptance of the Federal Vocational Education Act, to co-operate with the Federal Board." "The legislature of the state must also require a plan of co-operation between the state workmen's compensation board, or other similar board, and the state board for vocational education, such plan to be effective when approved by the governor of the state. In addition to this the state must provide for the supervision and support of the courses of vocational rehabilitation and appoint its state treasurer as custodian for federal funds received for the purpose of providing courses of rehabilitation."" In states where the legislature did not meet before December 31, 1920, the governor was permitted to temporarily accept the provisions of the act." Industrial rehabilitation and workmen's compensation are both a part of social legislation. "In a very real sense, industrial rehabilitation may be said to be a supplement to and an outgrowth of the workmen's compensation laws."" Since such relationship exists between the two phases of the work it is essential that the state board of vocational edu - cation work in connection with the administrative authorities of the com - pensation law. To secure this the federal law requires that an agree - ment be drawn up between the compensation commissioner and the state board of vocational education." While the chief part of the work will be carried out between the compensation agency and the rehabilitation serv - ice, there are other agencies and organizations which can furnish informa - tion of advantage to the state board of vocational education. In most 11 Industrial Rehabilitation — A Statement of Policiea to be Observed in the Admin - istration of the Industrial Rehabilitation Act, Bulletin 57, Series No. 1. p. 16. ■ Ibid, p. 17. "Ibid, p. 18. 14 Governor MeKelvie accepted the provisions of the act October 18, 1920. &gt;• Industrial Rehabilitation — Methods of Organization, Miac. 240, Series No. 2, p. 2 ■ Ibid, pp. 11-17. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 states injuries to railroad employees are reported to the State Railway Commission rather than the compensation commission. Red Cross societies, labor organizations, organized charities and even insurance com - panies are generally in a position to report accidents, which have not been reported by the compensation department. The state board will do well to secure the co-operation of these agencies. The extent and nature of the courses of instruction and training to t offered is a big subject. It has not been worked out in all its details is 1 it essential that it should be before rehabilitation work is under - taken. A guiding principle laid down is that the rehabilitation work is essentially a matter of dealing with individuals and not with groups. 11 The importance of studying the individual and his needs is further brought out by the federal board's recognization of the following state - ments regarding costs: 1. "The ratio of the amount expended for ad - ministration and supervision of the case work will be large in comparison with the amounts expended for tuition," and 2, "The number of cases that can be assigned to any one year to one agent has an upper limit which can be exceeded only at the expense of efficiency."" Realizing that the work is largely individual the nature of the work divides itself into two distinct fields. The first is to determine the eligi - bility of the disabled man for vocational rehabilitation. The second is the work of rehabilitation proper. In determining the eligibility of a per - son for vocational rehabilitation the points to be considered are: em - ployability; physical disability; incapacity for remunerative occupation, and feasibility of vocational rehabilitation both from a vocational stand - point and from a physical standpoint." L Vocational rehabilitation proper is usually considered as consisting the three phases of advisement, training and placement. Vocational advisement includes an intensive study of the disabled persons, and of the various factors which affect his future welfare." Before specific vocational training begins the disabled person must have a specific Job or occupation in view. While a certain amount of general education may be given in order that the individual may have a foundation to permit vocational education, the vocational education is 1 Always the end. "Under no consideration shall any rehabilitation case be regarded as first a school case and then a placement training case. Disabled men often discover their vocational training needs to better advantage on the Job than in a school." Preparation must be a "Job preparation."* "In securing the necessary training it is 1 believed that the experience of the federal board in the rehabilitation of soldiers. &gt;' Ibid. p. 10. '• Ibid, p. Cl. ■ Ibid, pp. 20-22. ■ Ibid, pp. 30-81. M Ibid, p. 35. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 sailors, and marines demonstrates tbe wisdom of utilizing the existing educational institutions — public and private — in so far as possible when training of an institutional nature is given."" These existing institutions are to be developed when inadequate, rather than create new ones. In some few cases special tutors will need to be employed. In rare instances correspondence courses may offer a feasible method of instruction. "The problem is so largely an individual one that it cannot be solved through the formation of general classes."" The federal funds or state money to match them is to be used for instruction and tuition and not for maintenance. The payment of com - pensation is relied upon to meet this need. However it may be necessary to amend some compensation law so that compensation will be paid during the period of retraining." The period of training should be considered to extend to the time when the impaired worker is able to receive wages equal to the worker in the field for which he has been retrained. The state board is to have charge of the placement work, but may work through public employment agencies, employment managers, associations, labor unions, and other organizations of this type. If necessary more than one placement may be attempted." As the basis of all rehabilitation work is the individual, the type of person in administrative positions is of vital importance. This is essential not only that the work may be properly directed but also that the confidence of the injured person may be inspired to under - take the work. All requirements for accepting the provisions have been complied with by Nebraska." The legislature of 1921 appropriated $25,000 as the state's share of the money for the next two years." The directors of the state board plans to confine the work, for the first at least, to persons in - jured in employment and to cases in which the injured is receiving compensation or other means of maintenance." Up to April 15, 1921, no rehabilitation work had been undertaken although some cases were pending. Occupational Diseases Of the forty-two states having workmen's compensation laws only six provide compensation for occupational diseases. The laws of four » Ibid, p. 37. » Ibid, p. 38. ■ Ibid, p. 83. " Ibid, p. 40. "The governor on October 18. 1920, temporarily accepted the act. The contract between the compensation department and the director of vocational education was drawn up and approved November 27, 1920. The state plans have been accepted by the federal board. " Seasion 1921, H. R. 232. " Interview with C. A. Fulmer, Director of Vocational Education for Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">t Btates Include occupational diseases among the disabilities for which com - pensation is to be paid. In Massachusetts and North Dakota occupational diseases are compensated through Interpretation. In other states the ex - clusion has been brought about (1) by limiting the scope of the law to injuries by "accident," (2) by adverse rulings of the courts and commis - sions, and (3) by express provisions in the compensation acts them - selves." IThe reasons given for the exclusion of occupational diseases are lack information as to their prevalence, and the large payments that prob - y would be required." Since the enactment of the early laws, investi - ions and experience have brought out two facts concerning occupa - nal diseases. These are: (1) That a large proportion of so-called occu - ional disease cases have already been covered by the laws, "Such les as lead poisoning and anthrax have, in many jurisdictions, been ssifled as accidents and compensated under the terms of workmen's npensation laws provided they occurred under certain conditions 1 ,"" 1 (2) that the maximum cost of occupational diseases, if included in rkmen's compensation acts, would not be greater than two per cent the aggregate cost of industrial accidents." There is no good reason why the man disabled by disease contracted because of his employment is not entitled to compensation equally as well as the man disabled by an industrial accident. No serious attempt has ever been made to secure compensation for occupational diseases in Nebraska." State Fund Insurance kin practically every state the employers are required to carry insur - i to cover their liability under the law. Some states have established state fund which is an insurance organization operated by state ials on the mutual plan. tThe state fund may be either competitive or monopolistic." lAt sent exclusive or monopolistic state funds insurance exists in seven tes while nine others have a state fund but permit private; insurance apanies to do business in the state." It is estimated that in 1919 the " Bulletin of the Bureau of Labor Statistics, No. 275, p. 51 Hookstadt, Carl, Co»t of Occupational Disease* under Workmen's Compensation in the United States. Monthly Labor Review, Vol. XII, p. 402, February 1921. Ibid. Quoted from proceedings of the casualty actuarial and statistical society of ■ica 1918-20, Vol. 6, p. 380. •Ibid "Ib the 1921 Session a bill (8. F. S24) was introduced providing compensation for its— us, but the bill received little consideration at Blanehard, Ralph H, Liability and Compensation Insurance, Chapter XIV and Chapter XV. Hookstadt, Carl, Comparison of Compensation Insurance as to Coat, Service and ritjr. Monthly Labor Review, Vol. XI, p. 1255, December 1820. ♦4 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 stock companies wrote approximately $91,000,000 in premiums in compen - sation insurance. The mutual companies wrote $27,000,000 and the state funds wrote $33,000,000. The percentages for each is sixty for the stock companies, eighteen for the mutuals and twenty-two for the state funds, taking them as a whole. The amount of business written by the com - petitive state fund varies from four per cent In Michigan to about forty - nine per cent in Montana, the average being about thirteen per cent of the insurance business done in the competitive states." The advisability of state fund insurance is a much debated question. Blanchard summarizes the arguments as follows: ARGUMENTS FOR STATE FUND INSURANCE. "1. The premium rates, which are often lower than those of other carriers, may be lowered still further by the payment of dividends, since the funds are operated on the mutual plan. Where the state pays ex - penses of administration or contributes a subsidy the employer may be benefited by the consequent reduction in the amount of his own contri - butions. "2. In those states which provide that insurance in the state fund shall relieve the employer of all liability for payments to his injured workmen, for the payment of assessments to the fund, or for both, he is given absolute security in return for his premium. "3. The state fund, managed in all cases by public officials, and usually by the same body which administers the compensation law, may be operated to carry out the fundamental purposes of compensation legis - lation, conserving impartially the interests of the employer, of the em - ployee, and of the general public. "4. A monopolistic state fund, by the concentration of the entire compensation insurance business of the state, promotes uniformity in the treatment of employers and employees and eliminates the waste due to competitive expenses and duplication of equipment and organization. "5. A competitive state fund may, through its rates and service, act as a regulatory ageney, compelling private companies to adhere to fair rates and practices. "6. The state fund is as carefully regulated as private companies in some states and might be so regulated in all. "7. Such criticism of the state funds as is tenable is directed, not at the principle, but at the methods which have been followed in apply - ing it. State fund insurance, since it is a new venture in the United States, must pass through a period of development and experimentation, the cost of which is fully justified by the possible future service to be ex - pected from this plan of insurance." ARGUMENTS AGAINST STATE FUND INSURANCE "1. The management of the funds is vested In appointive state offi - cials, and politics plays too large a part in their selection. Insufficient salaries, political considerations, and insecure tenure of office all tend to produce inefficiency which is a characteristic of state-managed insti - tutions. " Ibid. pp. 1258-57. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 i t"2. Neither the policyholders nor anyone financially interested in success of the funds have any direct control over their management. "3. In the event of insolvency as a result of inefficient management or of rates fixed by the legislature the employer will be obliged to make further contributions or, where he is relieved of all liability, the em - ployee will lose a portion of his compensation. If the deficit is made up from the state treasury it will involve a higher tax rate. There is also some question as to whether a statute relieving the employer of all liability on the payment of a stated premium would be held constitutional by the courts. "4. The payment of expenses by the state gives the fund an unfair advantage In competition with private companies which must meet all expenses from premium receipts. "5. The state fund is not in a position to reject poor risks and is forced to accept many which private companies are unwilling to carry. "6. The practice of fixing rates by legislative enactment, which ob - tains in some states, is unscientific and impractical, involving unfairness tthe distribution of compensation cost and endangering the solvency of &gt; fund. "7. The state should confine Itself to regulation and should not at - tempt to enter business enterprises which can be conducted by individual initiative."" The United States Bureau of Labor Statistics has recently completed n investigation of the relative merits of different types of insurance under workmen's 1 compensation. The investigation covered twenty-one tates and two Canadian provinces. States with exclusive state funds, with competitive state funds and with no state funds were studied. The olnts upon which Information was particularly sought were cost, security nd service. Under service were considered promptness of payments, dequacy and liberality of payments and accident prevention work. The ummary conclusions as given by Carl Hookstadt follow: "The cost of compensation insurance to employers under different in - urance systems may be indicated by their expense ratios. The average xpense ratio of stock companies is approximately 37 V4 per cent; of utual companies, about 20 per cent; of competitive state funds, about 2V4 per cent; and of exclusive state funds, from 5 to 7Vfe per cent. Under n exclusive state fund, therefore, the cost to employers would be 30 per ent less than under stock Insurance and 12% per cent less than under utual insurance. The total saving to insured employers of the United ates, If all were Insured in exclusive state funds, would be over 30,000,000 annually. This figure is obtained by applying the differences ►etween the expense ratios of the exclusive state fund and stock and utual companies to their respective annual premiums., "Service. — As regards service comparisons are difficult because of the great variations among different insurance systems. As to promptness of payments there is little to choose among the different types of insurance carriers. Some of the state funds have the best record while some have the poorest. The same thing may be said with respect to stock and mutual companies. However, a comparison of the best managed state fund with one of the best managed private companies shows that the best state fund is more prompt in its payments than the best private ■ BUnehsrd, R»lph H., Liability and Compensation In«ur»nce, pp. 191-198 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 company. Another significant fact developed by the investigation is that self-insured employers, whom one would expect to pay promptly, are no more prompt in this respect than either state funds or private carriers. As regards liberality of payment most of the state funds are more liberal in this respect than either stock or mutual companies. As regards acci - dent prevention some of the private companies are doing excellent safety work whereas few of the state funds have done any effective safety work. "Security.— Thus far no injured workman has lost one cent of com - pensation because of the insolvency of state insurance funds, nor has any large mutual company become insolvent. On the other hand, there have been several disastrous failures of private stock companies during the last three or four years. These failures have resulted in hundreds of thousands of dollars in unpaid claims."** It is 1 significant to note that no state has established a state insur - ance fund which was not provided for in the original compensation act, nor has any state abolished such a fund after its establishment." The important thing to be considered in determining the best type of insur - ance is the result to the workmen. The laws are not for the benefit of the employer, the state or the insurance companies, but for the workmen. The type of insurance which is best for the workmen is the best type of compensation insurance. ** Hookstadt, Carl. Comparison In.urance Systems as to Cost, Service, and Security Monthly Labor Review, Vol. XI, pp. 1255-76, December 1920. *&gt; Bulletin of the United 8taU&gt;» Bureau of Labor Statistics No. 275, p. 9. </seg>
            <seg id="p048"/>
            <seg id="p049">49 CHAPTER V Summary and Conclusion The first general workmen's compensation law to stand the test of constitutionality and become operative in the United States was the New Jersey law, passed in 1911. Other states followed the lead of New Jersey, and during the ten years, 1911-1920, compensation laws were enacted in forty-two states in addition to Alaska, Hawaii and Porto Rico. Recently the compensation laws have been made more liberal by shortening the period during which no compensation was paid and by requiring the ex - penditure of larger amounts of money for medical aid. However, the scope of the laws and the partial disability schedules have undergone relatively little change since the initial enactments of the laws. Formerly the laws were elective but recently compulsory laws have been enacted in several states. After a bitter fight a compensation law was enacted in Nebraska by the legislature of 1913. The law did not become effective, however, until it had been sustained by the voters through the referendum in the elec - tion of 1914. The Nebraska law at the present time ranks among the best compensation laws in the United States. The law has been made more liberal from time to time by increasing the compensation scale, by raising the weekly maximum, by shortening the waiting period and by requiring that unlimited medical aid be furnished the injured worker. The administration of the law was made more efficient in 1917 when the commissioner of labor was made compensation commissioner. The powers of the commissioner are sufficient to enable him to secure Justice for the injured workers. The effectiveness of the Nebraska law has not been reduced through interpretations or constructions. The part of many compensation laws which limits compensation benefits is the phrase requiring that accidents arise out of the employment as well as occur in the course of it. In Nebraska the construction of this phrase has been very liberal. During December, 1920, the Supreme Court held the "gain or profit" clause to apply to the state and governmental agencies created by it, thus depriv - ing public employees of the benefits of the compensation law. But the legislature struck out the "gain or profit" clause, so public employees are again covered by the act. Of unusual significance to the worker suffering a partial permanent injury is the decision in the Perry case. By this decision a lump settle - ment cannot be made for less than the compensation schedule provides. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Lump sum settlements are no longer compromises as they formerly were, but are commuted in strict conformity with the law. In the same de - cision the court held that the compensation commissioner as well as the district court must approve the lump sum settlement before it is binding. The commissioner is now in a position to secure the rights of the injured worker. One of the most important outgrowths of workmen's compensation is the movement for the rehabilitation of persons disabled in industry and their return to remunerative occupations. The United States is taking the lead in the work and the states are making plans to co-operate with the United States in carrying out the work. All necessary agreements and appropriations for doing rehabilitation work have been made in t While most states now provide compensation for industrial accidents, r states provide compensation for diseases caused by the occupation the worker. In all fairness to the worker, occupational diseases should compensated for as well as industrial accidents. tSome states provide for the creation of a compensation insurance d managed by the officials of the state, known as the state insurance id. There appears to be little real need for such measures, as no te. not adopting a state fund when its compensation law was enacted, has found it necessary to adopt it. However, it has apparently worked well in states having it, for in no state has it been abolished. Although Nebraska has a good compensation law, liberally con - structed and efficiently administered, one further stop is necessary be - fore all the workmen of the state secure the benefits of compensation. It is that the workmen of the state be informed as to their rights under the compensation law. In many cases it will be necessary to inform the workers of the existence of the law. Perhaps 1 it is too much to expect the workers of the state to fully understand the law, but at least they should know of its existence and know how to proceed in case they are injured. No doubt it will be a difficult task to give the workers of the state the needed information on the compensation law. Yet, unless this Is accomplished the expenses of medical aid and wages lost, which should be treated like all other expenses of production, must be borne by the injured workers themselves. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">APPENDIX </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 RIDER ATTACHED TO ALL COMPENSATION INSURANCE POLICIES *% Pp For attachment to Policy No. PR. «3"I l\ The obligations of Paragraph One .(a) of the Policy to QOA which this endorsement is attached include such Workmen'* J^JJ Compensation Laws as are herein cited and described and none other: r Chapter 198. Laws of 1913, incorporated in Chapter 35, Article VIII, Revised Statutes, 1913, as amended by Chapter 85, Laws of 1917, and Chapter 91, Laws of 1919, State of Nebraska, and all laws amendatory thereof which may be or become effective while this Policy is in force. The Employer, upon the acceptance of this Policy, agrees that at the effective date hereof, he is bound by the above cited Workmen's Compensation Law in full compliance with Section 103 of Paragraph 3653 thereof and will not reject, the obligations of the act by notice or otherwise as therein pro - vided during the Policy Period. This Employer, upon the acceptance of this Policy, agrees that the remuneration of all employees of any contractor or sub-contractor, or of any other real or alleged direct em - ployer, who undertakes for this Employer any part of the business operations covered by this Policy under the condi - tions set forth in Section 107 of paragraph 3657 of such Workmen's Compensation Law, shall be included in the re - turn of remuneration upon which premium is computed, and such remuneration, so reported, shall, in all respects, be gov - erned by the same terms, conditions and requirements of the Policy as the remuneration of the direct employees of this Employer. The requirements of this paragraph shall not apply if this Employer is not liable under said section or is exempted from such liability through compliance with its terms. Globe Indemnity Company, Hartford Accident and Indemnity Company, London Guarantee and Accident Company, Ltd., Maryland Casualty Company, The Ocean Accident and Guarantee Corporation, Ltd., The Standard Accident Insurance Company, United States Casualty Company, United States Fidelity and Guaranty Company. Countersigned by. Registrar </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 L. ETT c. n T U T M c U NIN • CJ n M c» D Letter sent to injured worker by Commissioner when information is secured through Press Clipping Service: Dear Sir: We gee by the papers that you recently sustained an injury in the course of your employment. For your information we are enclosing copy of the Nebraska Work - men's Compensation Law. together with "Accident Card." Written claim for this compensation must be filed with your em - ployer within six months 1 from the date of the accident, according to the law. If your case has not been properly taken care of, write us all of the particulars, and we shall be very glad to take the matter up for you. Yours very truly, DEPARTMENT OF LABOR. F. A. Kennedy, Secretary, Labor and Compensation Commissioner. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 FIRST REPORT OF ACCIDENT FIRST REPORT OF ACCID EEL.^_ ** £51421 (Ta ka IW wtta ni«|Hlllill OlMMllllll. liaeslm, Bakraaki, witbil to (U71 irtSScc{i£JtfftflMiP|MMli, .t lau &gt;M ka I ■»■!■« wkjn ■ liin) lliillllll is rao.uir.ii) •*•»&gt;» m». 1 ■Ktfktm i«n (OMM» Hi M 4 Miilil «r J4 «. 1 Mt • I I IJ 1 i&gt;l| . ■ ■ - ■ ■'— T M.OO «.. Up .«M ptc ~t . ill Final Report— Disability One Week or Less ■»!■ J^M«» All QmiiMmi Filly, OUMT^a r,y t^M t M^fc T t ltuXX. ftfM «t IMNv J^ s^b ■• •— «7 •■ •&gt; «kM* k • ■■■— ••* mm ri|iw u «• kat x bi mwr u4 Mix . \ «*»&gt; iv iT Cf H»p«tr«r ••. — .«■ If! !■&gt; !•-£! Mb w i»i«j k|u.lMM u _ U. ■» M k »w.T_I_Sat .thlM !■ — l«ft «r«. owl f moral of » 1&amp; Xmm aad Iimr «€ lajarfn l» «HM| W|«» »i M. WW. w» k|M MX. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 PERIODICAL STATEMENT OF COMPENSATION BEING PAID PERIODICAL ST&gt; Nebraska Workmen's Compensate froai Jo*, lat to 30th laolualTa ion CvRtmiuio^ \%i\ Ma Ovar as EajrtaVftyftnod ot Tistl (To Be Filed « UaM Moathly Wbara Compaoaauoo ia Paja MAIM Of IMftOVI &gt;n» f * 7 nami tar iMriovu L. A. I111UM Patar J. Coat.r Trick Jackaoa In I. Lm Sail PttarijQ ■Ilk* Iraleiarak 1. f. Oaaatock Cha.a. C. Rork ■ra. 0111a Coafort I. r. 3t.ph.niD3 'r»iu laeoraoll Jo. Lgbob. J. K. Iwr ■ - Kvbr.OM * :i«etrlo Co. Thoayioa Hot«l Coo|»qj dwha let A CoU Stormy !•• &amp; L»non City of P. lit City A. Irlitooa .:.C.?«t«rt lll.l Co. Hpf e Brotkva «. P. Crcialay Uneoln l.'T«rtiala£ Co. City &gt;t Red Cloud Orchard L '«1Ui«1q BloaM 3ioen Co. Ail ma Hu bar t • a a me. l» lr i*j it 19 «o».l» 14 Sec. II 13 9aa.ll 14 Juaalt 15 Jaa.20 it auiuo S2 iprlltO 17 Uj 20 24 a*j 20 It lu«.» It S.pt.20 ■ N " 40.00 40.00 46.16 ♦8,00 4J.0O 48.00 48.00 60.00 60.00 33.30 60.00 58.44 6, .00 15.00 46. 04 (rartlal 60.00 60.00 75.00 60.00 Lay « Juka 1 Uaj 31 la, 1» liar a La? 10 km; 30 Jama 3 ■ar 30 taj . 6tb Lay 31 aajr 27 Jaaa 1 Kaj 27 Juaa 3 oap.ntatl I Juoa 1 Ma, II ka, 21 liajr 14 Jona 21 Juaa 2* Juna 27 tmt 15 Juaa 25 Jan. 6 AM 26 Jus* 30 Joaa 26 Juaa 29 Juaa 27 Juna 30 Jaaa 2* Jun. I Jaaa 30 ■I Jaaa 29 Juaa 15 Jaaa 24 Jaaa 10 -•or*. Xr^atronc C. L. King trtinjr l»jrlor John (mil Cornbalt iua*»»r Go. Qibaoa Uotor 4 Tr*otor Caottml 3rld£« - Coaat PI •ld-H»vBi 1 toa-Snl th Papar roa^aoy Pmok CarttU S Oat. 20 4 1ST. 10 II Ioy.20 i Urck 0 fllliaa -UMk* 9 Ifrll 11 106.00 iprll 9 ■ • ■ ■ * ■ U IKjr 21 23 tar 21 77 l#»U.l 9 J«M21 14 JuwZl 21 Ool.tO •0.00 105. JO Ta.00 106.00 46.00 16.00 68.30 Laj t* Hay U -a, 23 La/ 13 Jaaa * Jaaa 21 Jaaa » Jaa. 14 Joa. 30 Jttaa 26 Joaa 30 Jou 21 Job. 27 Juaa :«lp&lt; i -. I. XlllbolUa John Poach Toajt lMbutl ■. o. j.fmw ». 1. later •a. m«. Ulll.r t n&gt;loa, lac. mti laaaaa I. U»lciaon i Co.,I«c.t Paopl.'. lea • Col4 Stfr Tllla«a of 3tarUo( I. J. Wchajr |4«.ao Lrtlal coa LnMtio.1 I. lalTaraoa ■ • t.0)l»'§ lo« I Col« ■to.aca Jo. *• • • 31 ll«.20 * • 15.00 •orkaa 30.00 IH itb U Juaa 11 Jaaa 4 Jun. lOtk Juaa 24 u I tMnar twtif. .fc» aw mhwn to ha m* .-- «™&lt;i t* M w a* i-ypuiku yf4 *SSfor&amp;^^ </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 FINAL REPORT AND SETTLEMENT RECEIPT r«aO4-tM FINAL REPORT AND SETTLEMENT fjf£§iK?|^ a.t.tM.MU. Ci.iiinl.1 CwmmMm Lteaala. M&gt;. likl. m •»» .cwr aul JUa&amp;aW M21 Dm •/ fi^tvW Emplopr JBAJC13 maa*n* ... JEJ^IFJatMtUHKIMWl Nmmt of Emflottr OUA.UA. COUBIBY COIttAJlI ™ MITK Da m* sii&gt; Ifcia K*e«a&lt; ulna jmm imttwl to EW NiaMi «4 ClB &lt;n aaj Qm Ik. Cm* FINAL RECEIPT RECEIVED OF »•" "' C0UK22Y Ci.UB BAM* OP WTTimBMT AMOUNT PAII nw w b|KT Juiy 12ib if 21 »«*»&gt; «*u « r»ni.ii« . . . i lb.00 t IT. &gt;0 i— «, »«. *«ly 15th ,,21 w — T "^~» ™ «»—««»— W«rtu Tnaponrr hnlil PImMMH _.. nm ■«, m Jul/ 2Blh it &gt;il ta - x H t. July .mini i,2l ' •■— - — '"— ■"-*'-••»• r . u mm ... Jul? Wlh in q, Bl T^,, |M , '""„',„ ,,-h, bS.OO IIIW af DtaMlltr 2 Wata 1 Dwi TWL th* TOTAL mm of SKTEHIEEI DOLH.BS AJJD fiO/l 00 - - , DOLLARS ($ IX.fiQ &gt; m 1*11 KttUmnU and mtitfmrtum of mil rlmrmt for rtmtpnmtitm tmdtr Ike girotutou of the NEBRASKA WOKKMESS COMPENSATION ACT &lt;m trrounl of mjuria nuUined fc» me &lt;u &lt; rtnM of «■ arridnl &lt;m orokmmt Urn.. 12%h of Juljf &lt;!■» •/ J» a . wkiU ra (k€ «mpto» of Q.IAHJk COaUIHY CLUB OTXUU UOOkTRY COB 2*J^)U^/iiM?J^M/ 5- yJ^~^rf*J yy±u*aUm* , /.M^rT i«-&lt; "« i»~-^k» '-.-&gt;■.!) iciin &lt;c«./») mini ICn </seg>
            <seg id="p057">~&lt; PETITION FOR A HEARING KFME TIE CeWEHSATION CONMISSIONEK OF TIE STATE OF NEBRASKA Frank Ulaakl »• Uorrle A Company, COMES NOW Frank Ulaelcl , 60? .Morth 17th i/a^ , 0»a|A, mi nianHalj pnmu I* iW Ci^imum (~ iia ' tW hk»|: Vbr».k.. TWt o. tW 6ti&gt; day of September , . 19 20 . wu. .. d» oapfey oi Horrl 8 oonmr d» aWw aamd plaiatil iomJ p«Mil immrim UM| oal of aad la tW cowm of laaphyin V *" «kov« aurJ Jilnlni. ■• a laborer / &gt;•••■•« ud uw •&lt; &gt;m R«n boat «plla ter under juU of »econd finger of HMMk MO) right hand, which become infected, leaving the finger partly etiff . Hm At pkMif Mir nmW) XM IUmk«&gt; ■&gt;■■■ tnHily) ...T.M. __..T*d&gt; ...1.9. -Partial? Ye&gt; Ertim.teddvr.no.&gt; A.«i«f» urrunp .1 tua. ol i.|ury. $...36.90 per waek F«alirir had kaowUdat of la^r •« S.tlX. &lt;k T .( Eeptocter. 19 20. Beaten, Mom* 6 Conpemy's doctor A— aat. it ur, .1 catnawliaa pud to da*. $ IftJaf pe, Mak far. . 1 1/3 -~kv TW tcaerd aatan of dw qiilioa ia rtajali » u lilnri: (a) TVr defeadaat dxM. aaUkty for ca^eauboa O) TV plaiatif aad ililaarlaat duaarM ai to itx aaioul of eoapcaialioa payable (c) TW pUiatif aad *ltad..r dHafraa at to IW daraliaa of [ia&gt;e fot wtuck caaapcauboa u payabk. OHlill I — ou., of r.f....h.. daiaMd 1 15.00 p., «,, („, 14 2/3 wkl WVCREFORE. TW alaiataf prayi aSal aa awaid W aade kjr dw Caaapaannoa tnataac nek raWc •■ tW iiimiiaii aajt W taulbd to aadtr lae pn i«m of tW Wntaiii'. rii.nnrigi Law of tW Suit of Nebr..k.. Omi u. PlM*.». "•**., «W..?.?tt dar .f J»»iarr. ,,21. ' » PlaSTbi iUW.&lt;}Q3 Hprth 17th 6tr#et. 0 M h« J . Hebr. STATE OF (CBRASKA : .....FrjBk. UlMkl. C-« W »9Wgl.M W«* am dJr ~»ra. apoa «.■» d&gt;p*M&gt; aad -r&gt; dW tW aMttonaat o«« ia tW fonaaut peliboa .re In. S^Werdtod i. |M. dm. Wf M M »W 3«th .W J«»W, 19^1 1 1 Notary P«Mc My r, ..,„„. •*« n •w.ln.t. .«W tAiMMMb 1923 . I »o™ lie limill Illllln aM aat na&gt; Mr u. MMM •hill ►« tM »lu lat C ■ I ■ Cm air.) IMoat IM •&gt; ad»W &gt;M Iwuw l&gt; MM rUUCK ••• WKiri U Hat « UUII </seg>
            <seg id="p058"/>
            <seg id="p059">59 BIBLIOGRAPHY GENERAL WORKS BOOKS Blanchard, Ralph H., Liability and Compensation Insurance, D. Apple - ton and Company, 1917. Bullock, Edna A., Compiled Debaters Handbook Series Compulsory Insurance. 1912, Wilson &amp; Company. Commons, John R. and Andrews. John B., Principles of Labor Legis - lation, Chapter VIII, Harper and Brothers, 1920. Rhodes, J. E., Workmen's Compensation, McMillan, 1917. Rubinow, I. M..' Social Insurance, Chapters I-XII, 1913, H. Holt * Company. Van Doern, D. H., Workmen's Compensation and Insurance, Moffat 1918. MAGAZINES AND PERIODICALS Beyer, David S., Accident Prevention, Annals of the American Acad - emy of Political and Social Science, Vol. 70, 238-243, March 1917. Fisher, W. C, America's Experience with Workmen's Compensation, American Economic Review, Vol. X, 18-47, March 1920. Meeker, Royal, Lacks in Workmen's Compensation, American Labor Legislative Review. Vol. 37-46, March 1919. Mitchell, John, Operation of the New York Compensation Law, American Labor Legislative Review, Vol. 5, 16-19, March 1915. Monthly Labor Review, Vol. IX, No. 1 to Vol. XII, No. 4, Division of Workmen's Compensation. Rhodes, James E., Compensation Administration and Adjstment, Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Vol. 70, 273-296. March 1917. Ryan, Harwood E., Methods of Insuring Workmen's Compensation, Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, Vol. 70, 244-254, March 1917. Vocational Summary, Vol. Ill, Nos. 4-12, Rehabilitation of Persons Disabled in Industry or Otherwise and their Return to Remune - rative Occupations. PAMPHLETS AND BULLETINS Federal Board for Vocational Education, Bulletin 57, Industrial Re - habilitation — A Statement of Policies to be Observed in the Admin - istration of the Industrial Rehabilitation, Oct. 1920. Bulletin 64, Industrial Rehabilitation — General Admin- istration and Case Procedure, 1921. Hoffman. Frederick L , Facts and Fallacies of Compulsory Health In- surance, 1917. More Facts and Fallacies of Compulsory Health Insur- ance, 1920. Insurance Federation of Minnesota, Brief addressed to Workmen's Compensation Commission of the Minnesota House of Representa - tives on "State Fund" Insurance, 1919. Lott, Edson S., Which will be Best for the Workmen? </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Minnesota Plans for the Administration of the Federal Act Providing for the Rehabilitation of Persons Disabled in Industry. United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics, Bulletin No. 203, Workmen's Compensation Laws of the United States and Foreign Countries, 1917. . Bulletin No. 240, Comparison of Workmen's Compensa- tion Laws of the United States up to December 31, 1917. Bulletin No. 243, Workmen's Compensation Legisla- tion of the United States and Foreign Countries, 1917 and 1918. , Bulletin No. 275, Comparison of Workmen's Compensa- tion Laws of the United States and Canada up to January 1, 1920. Industrial Rehabilitation as Conducted in Minnesota, Vocational Rehabilitation for Persons Disabled in Industry or Otherwise. NEW8PAPERS THE NEBASKA STATE JOURNAL Files January 1, 1913, to May 1, 1913 Files January 1, 1920, to May 1, 1921 PUBLIC DOCUMENTS LEGISLATIVE Bills of the 1911 Session of the Nebraska Legislature, H. R. 386, H. R. 536. Bills of the 1913 Session of the Nebraska Legislature, H. R. 28, H. R. 49, H. R. 193, H. R. 199, H. R. 200, H. R. 236, H. R. 266, H. R. 549, H. R. 551, H. R. 642, H. R. 653, S. F. 1, S. F. 37, S. F. 112, S. F. 140, S. F. 274. Bills of the 1921 Session of the Nebraska Legislature, H. R. 232, H. R. 301, H. R. 516, H. R. 567, S. F. 2, S. F. 237, S. F. 324. Journal, House of Representatives 1911, 1913. Journal, Senate, 1913. Nebraska Referendum Bulletin 1914. Manuscript Records in the Office of the Secretary of labor. Through this work the Secretary of Labor has been referred to as the Compensa - tion Commissioner. REHABILITATION Explanation of H. R. 232, Session 1921 Nebraska State Plans for the administration of the Federal Act Pro- viding for Persons Disabled in Industry or Otherwise. Plan for Co-operation between the Nebraska State Board for Voca- tional Education and the State Department of Labor. STATUTES Revised Statutes 1913, Chapter 35, Article I, Article VIII. Session Laws 1913, Chapter 198. Session Laws 1913, Chapter 124. Session Laws 1917, Chapter 85. Session Laws 1919. Chapter 21. Session Laws 1921, Chapter 190, Article I and Article IV. Session of 1921, S. F. No. 2, and H. R. 301 as passed. United States Public Laws, 66th Congress, Session II, Chapter 219. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 REPORTS Nebraska Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics, Bulletin No. 18, Labor Organization, May 1910. Bulletin, No. 25, Industrial Survey, November 1912. Bulletin, No. 32, Report upon the Operation of tbe Nebraska Workmen's Compensation Law for the year ending November 30, 1915. Fifteenth Biennial Report, 1915-1916, December 30, 1916. Sixteenth Biennial Report, 1917-1918, December 1, 1918. Nebraska Department of Labor, Seventeenth Biennial Report, 1919-1920, December 31, 1920. Nebraska Employers' Liability and Workmen's Compensation Commis - sion, Preliminary Report, Legislative Reference Bureau, Bulletin No. 2, December 20, 1912. , Final Report. TABLE OF CASES Abel Construction Company y. Goodman, 181 N. W. 713. American Smelting and Refining Co. v. Cassil, 178 N. W. 639 Anderson v. Kiene, 174 N. W. 301, 103 Neb. 773. Bailey v. United States Fidelity and Guaranty Co., 155 N. W. 237. Barrett v. Selden-Breck Construction Co., 174 N. W. 866. Beideck v. Acme Amusement Co., 166 N. W. 193. 102 Neb. 128. Blair v. Omaha Ice and Cold Storage Co., 165 N. W. 893, 102 Neb. 16. Bridger v. Lincoln Feed and Fuel Co., 179 N. W. 1020. Coster v. Thompson Hotel Co., 168 N. W. 191, 102 Neb. 585. Epsten v. Hancock-Epsten Co., 163 N. W. 767, 101 Neb. 442. Farmers Grain and Supply Co. of Minden v. Blanchard, 178 N. W. 257. Feda v. Cudahy Packing Co., 166 N. W. 190. 102 Neb. 110. Globe Indemnity Co. v. Larson, 173 N. W. 597, 103 Neb. 673. Good v. City of Omaha, 168 N. W. 639, 102 Neb. 654. Hanley v. Union Stock Yards Co.. 158 N. W. 939, 100 Neb. 232. Hugh Murphy Construction Co. v. Seeck, 177 N. W. 747. Hull v. United States Fidelity and Guaranty Company, 166 N. W. 628, 102 Neb. 246. Johnston v. Union Stock Yards Co.. 156 N. W. 511. 99 Neb. 328. Kanscheit v. Garrett Laundry Co., 164 N. W. 708, 101 Neb. 702. Manning v. Pamerene. 162 N. W. 492, 101 Neb. 127. Miller v. Morris and Co., 162 N. W. 417, 101 Neb. 169. Morris and Co. v. Cushing, 172 N. W. 601, 103 Neb. 481. Mucha v. Morris and Co., 179 N. W. 500. Muncaster v. Graham Ice Cream Co., 172 N. W. 52. 103 Neb. 379. Myers v. Armour ft Co., 172 N. W. 45, 103 Neb. 407. Osborn v. Omaha Structural Steel Co., 179 N. W. J022 Otis Elevator Co. v. .Miller ft Paine, 240 Fed. 376. Parson v. Murphy, 163 N. W. 847, 101 Neb. 542. Perry v. Huffman, 175 N. W. 1021. Perry v. Huffman, 175 N. W. 501. Pierce v. Van Kuran Lumber and Coal Co., 156 N. W. 509, 99 Neb. 321. Radii v. Morris and Co., 170 N. W. 363, 103 Neb. 84. Rooney v. City of Omaha, 177 N. W. 166. Simon v. Cathroe Co.. 162 N. W. 633. 101 Neb. 211. Socha v. Cudahy Packing Co., 181 N. W. 706. Stoica v. Swift and Co., 160 N. W. 964, 100 Neb. 434. Swan v. Lincoln Terminal Co., 170 N. W. 497. 103 Neb. 36. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Thomas v. Otis Elevator Co., 172 N. W, 63, 103 Neb. 401 Updike Grain Co. r. Swanson, 174 N. W. 862. Updike Grain Co. v. Swanson, 178 N. W. 618 United States Fidelity and Guaranty Co. v. Wickllne, 170 N. W. 193, 103 Neb. 86. United States Fidelity and Guaranty Co. v. Wickline, 173 N. W. 689, 103 Neb. 681. Venlto t. Carter Lake Club, 178 N. W. 760. Young v. Western Furniture and Manufacturing Co., 164 N. W. 712, 101 Neb. 696. Information was also secured through interviews with public officials and members of the 1913 session of the legislature. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>