<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  THE BUD-ROT OF CARNATIONS.  A MITE ACCOMPANYING THE BUD-ROT OF CARNATIONS.</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">1 A ersity ok Nebraska Ml'LUKTIN THh AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION NEBRASKA XX, Artri.k IV THE BUD-ROT OF CARNATIONS. P. I). 1IKAI.K MITE ACCOMPANYING THE BUD-ROT OF CARNATIONS. ROHKRT II. WOLCOTT 4T1OM OCTOIIKK 15, lSKli no Jam ary 10. liXiM. LINCOLN. N!-:BRASKA U. S A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGCPtTS or THf UNtvFUS \VM. G. WHITMOKE, \ FREDERICK H. ABBOTT, A VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls C i HAS B. ANDERSON, ( &lt;;Ki iRGE OH PLAND, I THE STATION OFFICERS I. BURNETT, I DALES, M.I'n. W. MARSHAI THE WORKING STAFF B. Smith, B . Peti k-. I Frederick D. Hi F. |. Al WAY. I'll. I I. HAECKI k, BSi A . /'.; Brumes, I I. Montgomery, kk J. Phillips, M.F., l\ in H. B arbour, Ph.D., :. i HAiKiKN. A.M., Hig i. Emerson, B.Sc., //.&lt;// . 1'. S, lirig* ,. LOVELAND IN K.KYSKK, A.M 1 J. H. Gain, M.D iaie n A 1 . Magoamz, Jr., a.]'. L. B. Sn kdkvani. A M a A. Hartzell, MA.. . / El. Little, li.S&lt; ant in /&gt;, tin Nelson, M.S., Assistant in hi . Dknny, A.B., Assistant in J; '. Perin, Farm SuperinUni€ui ie \V. 1'. SMVDEK, M.S., Sup.-riiit </seg>
            <seg id="p003">na th THE BUD ROT OF CARNATIONS. IX V. I). !IKAM». NTUOIH (TWIN. 1- past few vcars a troublesome and destractivc mat ions has been prevalent in a number of the tea of the slate. The disease affeetl the buds in ages of maturity ami produces a rottiag of the |x&gt;t - iliei- (lower parts, at least the parts enclosed bj the iterfering with the normal oix'iiiuj: of Um flower, has therefore been termed the "bad-rot" of the HISTORICAL. mi of carnations was first reported in 11)0.") 1&gt;\ Dr. from specimen* received from a greenhouse at Re* Nebraska. He attributed the trouble entirely to a mite instantly present in the affected bad*. The mite iesi i-ibed as belonging to a new and hitherto un- ecies and possibly a new genus. At this time the n of the trouble was not inspected. Later in the the same trouble was reported to the writer and Ration was begnn. The first examination showed and in addition the rotting jn-tals were found to Im. 1 nyeeliiim of a fungus. An examination of \ illi: buds led to the belief that the mites were OOlj and that the fungus was the primary factor in cans- seasc. Fumrium spores were found upon the rot- o bibliography at &lt;&gt;n&lt;l of in::, am:. i.\i\ station mi NEW. VOL. xx, akt. iv. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 i i \ this fungus.- It was found later tlmi iln- trouble wa a different fungus, and that the Fimariiim was a t ion which developed during the transit of the specii The bud-rot has Iteen found in greenhouses in Lincoln nice and Omaha, Nebraska, and is known to oecu •tate of New York. The fungus which is iln trouble has been described by Peck 3 and he has exam cultures and reports as follow "1 consider the specimens referable to tipt thophtium Pk. They show the rharacters nicely. 1 &lt; &gt;n .Ian. 29th of the present year a letter was rec Professor 11. E. Hodgkiss, Geneva, \. Y.. asking ination in regard to the bud-rol which was report luaska. He stated that the aecompanvin itive had been sent to him. Tl was deterniined 1p\ Proft ('. S mntkophilum Peck. About April ;&gt;o the request of Professor Hod lillds atl'ecled with tile disease nil to him by the writer for comparison w ith the New \ incus. Not until August i^lst w that tlie Nebraska and New York The carnation is attacked bv a considera - which atl'ect the roots or si few are known to affect the buds or flowers due in the majority of cases to fungi, I insignificant put. The following ai that have heen described : have been studied by Stewart' and Sturgis, 3 due to a / riitnt and to the sterile fungus Rhizottonia. What is pro! ably the same I'lisiuiimt disease has been studied by !• croix" ami the causal organism determined as / I I 1 1 !_1 iK'lillS i I 1 1 &lt; 1 II WilS Slll&gt;lMIS4*t| I 1 1 ■ I I I 1 1( * llOlIIIM* "&lt;l 1. Tiil Stk.m Kots. — Two (lilVci-cnt ty] </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 w \ i ril I I I inn I. n ion Spot of &lt; \u / ■mllii ]&gt; i ii&lt; 1 Euro] Ey white or central ai \ikinsuir under (In- name of "carnation A true bacterial spol disease of th&lt; ibed by \Voo&lt;ls. s while the disease for to be caused by the punctures &lt;&gt;f apt lias been named "sri^nionos. Three (litlVrent writers have des&lt; ribed iniiilioiis affecting si ems and leaves: Hal lisease to !»■ due to Colletotfichum ilinnthi. uted the anthrai nose which lie described to ihiiilln. The anthrai-nose which Cooke" de - rrinir in England was attributed to Gloeotpo- Ii is quite probable that the causal orgaaJssa in all three cases, luit if can hardly he cos&gt; in the light of present information. Ring. — This disease of carnations has been immon name has been derived from the fa«t produces its fruiting hrphae in coacentrii- (inter of infection. While the disci foliage and stems it has been reported as nd Inids. Relbv" meniions the same funens itimt il!erk.i Ponke) as the en 11 s of carnations, which produces un n calyces and pedicels as well as upon has recorded a case in which the dia the flowers. Many buds did not open at all nd flowers that did open showed brown dry als due lo the growth of tlie fungus and the he spores nations. — This (lisease which is due lo &gt;'/ /&lt; in. is known to occur in both this country The spots are circular or oblong with a iwn center, bordered by a dark purple band, shows black specks or pyenidia tilled with Arthur iintl l'.nll&lt;\ '■' ns "bacteriosin" Km oiis writers (Berkeley," Smith.'" Atkin- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 i i tt n I fun IT I s i fairv h is pi ie tronltl nhv has i ■pores. N&lt;&gt; mention is made by any writers who liav this fungus of its occurrence on parts other than It stems, altho it is probable that it may be found i parts, at least the calyx. i Carnation Lkak Mom&gt;.— This carnation tro described bj Hoisted** and attributed t&lt;&gt; a ■ oaporium. No specific name was assigned tn tli fungus caused a spotting of the foliage ami i the entire leaves or entire top of the plant wen •This disease is known ountrv. 2 - 1 According I U.TKRNARIA DlSI'ASK. - hoth in Europe and in this leaves, stem and calvx. Later the leaf turns hro completely killed, while the affected spots show Si-hroet.1 .attacks carnations at the green parts producing th&lt; this disease did not appear in the United St it is now very generally distributed. It is pr ■less extent in nearly all greenh&lt; ). Smut. — Carnation smut i / Fckl. I is not known to ( in s other hosts. 2 air of the greenhouse are kept t&lt; \ described the same trouhle, Inn neither writer ref&lt; jius to a definite species of liotryi Iu the fore«;oin&lt;x list it may he noted that the 01 fungus diseases affecting the flowers are due to th fungus and the unnamed species of Botryti*, whi ahly llotrytix vulgnrit. In addition to these t known as "petrified buds," which is apparently a leal trouhle. was reported by Kennedy.-- Arthur th&lt;» trouhlo first shown :is yellow, sliurhtlv rwoUi Kdcr due to the accumulation of [It Rrsr. — This &lt;lis. Hi. BOTKYTIS Pi ska si-:. — According i&lt;&gt; Atkins* tion flowers and buds in;iy suffer tr&lt; This trouble is prevalent </seg>
            <seg id="p007">/ 7 \ III t 1 condition of carnation (lowers iu which dherent. No auinial or fuugus pmiitai Mociated with this trouble. \ MlTU.Us carnation* produces effect* which show ex - racter depending upon the extent ami ■ Lliou. I he most striking external symptom is he affected buds to expand iuio perfect flowers. i benches in which the bud-rot is prevalent generally nsiderable number of flowen that w ill uever opeii Sometimes the affected flowers deviate only otii the normal (PL IV, figs. -3 aud 24). rTowew split calyx may resemble these superficially iu of the petals. Iu buds iu which the infection is * begins at au earlier date, the petals becdaw ih expanded and the buds die without ever devel - p perfect (lowers i 1»1. 1\", tigs. 21, 2S, 28). It such are not picked off, the projecting portions of r and turn brown and the calyx soon dies ; iU&lt;&gt;. w n coloration. In a few cases the lmd&lt; are • I at a very early stage, for the calyx does l,\ to allow any projection of the ]&gt;etals. bttl md dries up (PL 1\", tig. J7 ). mis show upon closer examination that all \ be flower parts included within the calyx are af- rot which has caused a brown coloration and a he tissues. Jn sonic cases the spaces It. petals show a whitish hyplial growth plainly evident to the bile in other cases no hyphae can be detected without a microscopic examination. When affected buds are broken pen, oblong watery-looking objects. 1 12 inch or loss in gth, are found buried in the soft mass of rotting petals Of lying between them. These objects are the distended abdo- •us of minute female mites, which have been fouud at uit accompaniments of the fungus. In the earlier - </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 i II IN Voi t l lie flrn w itl fe rot in natural infectious the mitts may be qi inconspicuous, but iu veil-developed cai are so evident that they could uoi be easily o\ ETIOUX.l. The bud-rot here described has been proved bey*, tiou to be due to a specific organism, ISpoiutriiliii jjliiluitt l'cck, which is oiie of the fungi lmpirf&lt;: following technical description of this fungus is Peck 3 1'rom apeciuieuM observed iu ihe state of New IHyphae creeping, interwoven, branched, contiii ringly septate, variable iu thickness, .OOUOS .000 i in diameter, hyaliue, loruiiug a loose collony i res globose or broadly ovate, .OOUHJ .0003 ol g, borue at the lips of short brauchlels which an rowed towards the apex ami pointed. "l'arasitic ou the lilameiits and \ discoloring them, destroying their i flowers. Jtayside, (jueeus Co. &lt; \\ contributed by F. C. SsUwari. Since the completion of the n and its submission to the pub! tiou, a staleiueut has beeu rect tie Experiment Station at Geneva. Sew \ bud-rot fungus. The following is taken I wart's letter: "1 am confident tl have studied is identical with tl • fuugus was described by Peek ti ,um Uttthopkilum. The specimen wed the same fungus." Krofessor Stewart's statement bearing up ed to this species should also lie noted: Eotwithstanding the presence of the septate sp&lt; i opinion that the fungus should lie placed in I ttrickum. Except for the occasional septate B] lical Sporotrichum. Moreover, it is identical </seg>
            <seg id="p009">/ 9 in 1-iln-d hv L'«-ck a few yean ago from it liini i N. V. Slate Mus. Kul., 67 • ii.iiiic of the carnation fanguM !&gt;&lt;•• &gt; constantly associated with the fungus a Dew ami hitherto undeecribed ■peck's, nite is given by Ur. [{ II. Wolcott at bulletin the fungus ami the mite in the pro- rouble lias been determined by cultures ami »n i-inii the past two years the fnngutJ h:is •aiedly from all'erie.l ImkIs. In the great it was possible to ohtaiti pure culture* l&gt;\ the allectetl IhiiIs with sterile instruments. portions of the rotting petals ami planting In a few rases cultures were contaminated saprophviir fungi. Inn the various isolations mially alone, to eil her the S This fait being true, the •"inhirlnnii or the mite ur aether. i's of the fuiiirus. For the •re obtained from a house ml-rot was entirelv absent. The inocnla nto lariie. well-developed hmls !,v makinv he calyx with a sterile lame ami passin; •s charged with the inoculum thru the in - rior of the bwl. Of the total number of s per cent were successful. The greateiM in - typical development of tin disease was oh - inoculation of young hods, that is, in lnids till to show the tip* of the petals at file time When partially expanded hmls were used. 1 II In n genus as wan nr thst supposed. frit-hum &lt;-\isir&lt;! in Hie rotting | M -t;il •mini- definitely w IkiIk-i- the fungnu .il ihuin-i i Ik- i-.»i. ;i lnri»e nunilier i&gt;f inncuhi- sinu pure cnltin on (iiriiiitioiis w </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 i i i ition &lt;li&lt;- inoculation failed or resulted in only an im ■l fi-il inn . su Iliiiiiii to i-ot tin' sianieus ami the eh petals to a Blighl extent. Six to etghi ilays wer for i lie- fungus to become well established in the y&lt; ami this will explain the failure of the infection tially open buds are inoculated, since they unfold fungus lias had time to proiluee a general in feet io In determining the result "f the infection, jjenei uce and microscopic examination were no( i-.-lied many cases it is true that the fungus was olearh the naked e\e. hut when in &gt;t visible its presence «*o he demonstrated b m v microscopic examinai pan of the artificial infections, the fungus u&lt; tares. Such an isolation culture is slunvn ii re 29, in which six neparate inociibitionH were Bli developed wilhoi nociilat iona were at except what were due directly to Hie ii from the failure of these inoculatioi in quite a secondary part in t probable that the mite acts as this is the only planftible c-\phi perfectly closed buds. The voting YOUTHS and could easily migrate from one flower to atio female produces a large Dumber of yo«in«i ones i parent that only a limited number of Hi reael flowers, otherwise the trouble would 1»- more scvc-T'e mites find in the rotting petals a very mitable sulis for their development and apparently intensify the t Experiments to prove definitely the part of the mites riers of the disease have been planned and will he rarri hut results will not he obtnined in time for this puhli Eoorntricluiin atithophiliim produces snores vor Hy on nil kinds of culture media. Peck's des s lint one kind of spoi-e. hut two kinds of spore* fungus, lmt no injuri </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Tk Bud-Rot of tarnations. 11 1 I h n linn i t a 1 : microconidia,* which are nearly globular or 1 macroconidia, which are elongated and i septate. xonidia are produced in much greater ubuii - he uuurocouidia, and always make their appear - i the cultures. The spore- bearing branches are somewhat clustered and each conidiophore is ca - jriuiug au indefinite number of spores. The couidia ted from the ends of the branches, but with the rowtb they may appear in some cases to be Lit - the fact that the liypha lias grown out beyond 1). This manner of growth frequently gist - of spores (PL I, tig. 1). The microconidia are nilar, or slightly pointed at the proximal end, al - e-celled aud vary from Tt.o to 8 microns in diam- y germinate at once in water or culture media ami o a much-branched septate mycelium (PL 111, tig. ome cases in crowded cultures I lie Inphae may g w couidia at their tips without any branching or on uioconidia are produced less abundantly than the idia, but both may occur in tin* same hanging drop mycelium. One or more spore-bearing branches from the Mime cell of the central axis and tli •*.■ a tendency to extend parallel to the central axis ry acute angle with it. while in the production it' lateral branches are more inclined to ics. alt ho this is nut always the case. In nyphae anl spores are completely tilled a a niitely granular protoplasm, but vaciioles mm ap - tliese become prominent in the course of several The conidia are formed in essentially the same way microconidia, but they always become septate. The all may be formed while the wpott is still con* terms niicroconidia and macroconidia are used for convenience ate the two kinds. iteral branches t L'i. Ill, tig. 18). </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 with thf hvplia, or its formation may be delayed until aftei the spores have been completely separated. The sin. stages in the formation oi' the spores as well as the vaciiola tioii of the hyphae are shown in figure! 7 to It, Plate 11. Tin macroconidia are generally two-celled, but someiiiiics three celled (rare;, elliptical or slightly more pointed at the prox imal ends, and vary in size from 4.5 to o&gt; microns \ 10 i&lt; 17.5 microns. No other spun forms have been found on ain Eure media, but it may be m ;ates of hyphat; were t'ornu 1 plates. These aggregate* of sderotia or resting bod ntioued that minute pin 1 in old cultures upon were presumably of r I * &lt; uuuwm on n TUBE MKDI te HporotrichutH grows we media and with bin litth upon all ill variation in soon rises above tin- surface in the torn in w I'lium. After the first day or tw tinged with pink, and by the time the cult in the color has assumed a deeper hue and n madder color. The growth on plain agai pigment production is entirely lackii faint coloration. &lt; &gt;n potato in growth is very vigorous, dense, an All of the regular culture media employe*! and had i he reaction 1(1 of Pull \ observed, but no distinct zonal ion occurred in i|,, grown in the light i PI. VI i. PREDISPOSING CAISl E bud-rot of carnations is a disease that is not lik.lv to troublesome in greenhouses that are kept in prime con for plant growth. It is rather a disease of neglected I poll glucose agar 11 prodiu on gtacoae agar, but tli&lt;- pigment productioi tarding effed &lt;&gt;f light apon the growth of i in </seg>
            <seg id="p013">i &lt; Hud Rot of Carnation*. 16 1 hi list as certain human diww uc fraauenJ in rrouudiiigs, so the bud rut is a disease that at- liations and become* troublesome when the plants ted to unfavorable conditions. Only sporadic I t lia\c ever been observed ill the l&gt;est houses, where methods and greenhouse hygiene were r ie lirst and perbapti the most importuut factor iullueuc - ihe development and spread of the disease is the water n. In all of the houses where the bud-rot has been ■in tlie air and soil have beeu kept too damp. Over- 1, which keeps the soil Maturated with water and sup - ii in lit ii 1 moisture bj evaporation, affords favorable us for the development and spread of the di» fad has been demons! rated by culture experiments in greenhouse and is completely corroborated by the exain - on of conditions in houses where bud-rot has been valent. uldition to the water factor, mention should \m made unhygienic practices that often prevail in poorly cared oases. The accumulation of debris in the form of lea\ •■•*. mings and other plant remains, rotting benches, and de - iu organic remains in general, afford favorable coadi- for molds of various kinds, and I his is especially true -i ilium which is only a facultative parasite. &gt;/ i varieties of carnations appear to be entirely exempt the bud-rot. Sporadic cases have been observed on all lies grown in the houses where the trouble was preva- \ (The LmtC8on has suffered more than any other variety must be considered especially susceptible. The only r variety which has been ai all seriously affected is the ■n Louise. Benches of these two varieties growing side ide often have double the number of Lawsons affected. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 I i \ i I \ 1 1'ltOUNOS The bod-rot don not serioiulj atfccf the plant i;us i.s confined entirely to the buds, it has never been growing on other pans. The Injury is due, then the fact that affected buds produce deformed Bowei tirely fail to develop. Flower* which upon superficial iuatiou appear only slightly malformed arc badh within the calyx and soon wither and dk\ This fact ha especially noted in the discussion of the symptom*. buds have remained without infection until the call opened Sufficiently tO expose the tips Of the petals, sill infection will cause but sliyhi injury, as the fungus have time to develop before the llower has expan&lt; houses where the trouble is severe 1 lie buds I.ecoill when quite young, probably when not more thi inch lony. When infection took place at th many of the buds rotted before thev had tin they did open at all produced very impel flowers. The actual loss from the disea badly affected plants. In one small house tl the Law son variety if it is introduced into a house, by pureu UCk. The Iliosl successful growers of &lt;■ to fear from this disease, as conditions in the well-regi houses are unfavorable for the spread of the disease. tlio the disease is present it wil! not become genera] if i precautions are observed. In order to t--si this by dire periinent. Law son carnations were obtained from a where the disease was especially prevalent and then : for a time under conditions as favorable for the disc; fniction of one \h'v rent to twcnn ported ;l loss of fl.50 to |2.00 ]kt (li 1V l'ltOI'llYI.A.MS \M&gt; II The lnul-1-ui (Jin cjisilv be proven </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 ! 1 1 overwatenng and allowing the accumu- rotting buds and other debris. After the lahlislicd the watering was made less fre •ss amount of water was employed, while the irroundinps w.ic kept free from decaying or- ns. All affected buds were removed as soon as d at once dcst roved. By pursuing this method as,- was entirely stamped out. The treatment recom - was followed in one large commercial house with lisfattoi-v results. ork which has beea carried out up to the present Is to the conclusion that the disease can lie prevented icated if the following measures are carefully heeded: actice clean culture with the destruction of all refuse gfat offer a temporary lodging place for either fungi Keep the moisture down to the minimum necessary for ealthy growth of the plants. Pick off all affected buds as soon as they appear and »y by burning. Do not under any conditions throw down on the benches. The benches should be gone over isi every other day until the disease is thorolv under nta are due to the following in carrying out ned in this bulletin: To Mr. II. \Y. Rarre for lures and inoculations and assistance in mak- drnwin .\fr. A. W. Sampson for some of the work ltures of the fungus; and to Prof. ('. H. Peek for the atinn of the fungus. Wolcott: Science. X. S.. II: :!S&lt;I. 1M6. Heald: Science, N. 8., tit: (ii'O. inoc. Ann. Bep. Xebr. Exp. Sta.. W: "». F.-b., 1900. Peck: Bull. Xew York State Museum, /"" 28. 1900. I.ITKRATl RK f'lTKI) </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 The littil-liot &lt;// Carnal 4. Stewart: Hot. (lax., '? : U'.t. ls'.i'.t. ."&gt;. Storgia: Ann. Hep. Conn. Exp. Si;i.. i/; 175. 189 (. Delacroix: Conipt. Rend., 1,11: 961 963. 1900 7. Atkinson: American Florist. v 727. 1893. S. Woods: Science. N. S., (8:537 538. 1903. !». Arthur and Bolley: Bull. Purd. Univ. Ajjr. i 59; 1 38. 1896. 10. Woods: American Florist, Hi: JI90. I'.MH 11. Halsted: American florist, S: 733. 1X93 \-. Atkinson: American Florist, S: S23. 189 13. Cooke: Hardener's Chronicle, 3 Scr.. .{/: 193 l'.M n 14. Berkeley: Gardener's Chronicle, 1870:38 15. Smith, W. O.: (Jardener's Chroniclf, X: 244. 1' 1&lt;». Aikinsun: American Florirt, S: 7i'&lt;; "27. !*!&gt;.:. 16. Atkinson: American Florist, S\- , jr. ,_'7. l^'.c: 17. S.-ll.y: Hull. Ohio Agr. Exp. Hta., /.'/: l ( i\ 1900 18. Sorauer: Zeituehr. f. Pflanscnkr., v -2sr, 288 i lit. Atkinson: Ameru-an Klorirt, s : 721. 1M»."». lit. Atkinson: American Florist. S: .L'l. 189 I'll. Haisted: Ameruan Florist, 8: 731. l^'.t::. JO. Halsted : American Flori s'i SI. Sonmci-: Zeitm-h. f. Pflanxenkr., 8: -s:\ ii'tu. |v 21. Sorauer: Zeits. h. f. I'tlany.eiikr. N: i'v.i 22. Halsicd: American Florist. S: 7:!:'.. 18U3. 1'2. Halsted: American Florist. i l':{. Boraner: Zritachr. f. PHanxcnkr., &lt;S; 291. I- Clinton: Ann. lf&lt;-|&lt;. Conn. Agr. Kxp. Si.-i.. |\*i :i\-2 313. Orton: Yearbook U. s. h pi. Agr., 1905: fill. .'.■{. Soi-aner: Zeitschr. f. I'tlanzenkt Clinton: Ann. IJi|&lt;. Conn. Agi ill' ::i Orton: Yearbook U. S. 1&gt; |.t. Ajjr., 1905: «1 III 24. Arllim-: Hot. Oar., Hi: 321. 1891. U. Arthur: I'.ot. (lay... /(;.• ::i'l. is'.i 25. Clinton: North American Flora, T.i'l 1906. Proc. Boston Sue. Nat. Mist. ..;/.• :;77. 1904. 25. Clinton: North American Flora Mil Proc. Boston Soc. Nat. Hist.. .;/.- to L't;. Atkinson: American Florist, S: 728. ls'.t.:. .'•&gt;. Atkinson: American Florist s. is'.t ■27. S.'lhv: Ball. Ohio Agr. Kxp. 8ta., 121: 22. 1900 .'7. Selhy: Bull. Ohio Agr. Kxp. Sta., 121: 22. 1900 SB. Kennedy: Ann. Rep. Rhode talnnri Agr. l!\i&gt;. i 209. 1896. R. Kenncflv: Ann. Bep. Rhode Island Ajjr. Exp. S -it. Arthur: American (lard.. /?; 14."). Is'.h 90. Puller: Joan. Am. Pnh. [Tealth Assoc., ."/• 381 . -&gt; &gt;1. Smith. E. F. : Bacteria in Relation to riant l» </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 i PI .AN \TI&lt; i.\ i &gt;1 1'I.A'l i ■\ ] ■ Plate* I. !I. and 111 s I. II, and III PLATE I. IM.ATF I 1 6 - ' i» the formation of the microconidi;, n the formation of the microconidia. All mm hanging drop cultural in glncoae agar. in RlllCOSI PLATE II. ATE II F • -Hypha showii ni&lt;iia, drawn at t:M )in banging drop culture in glncoi F . — The same bypha draw* at 11:45 AM. None of the spores have hypha ilrawn ;it 1 : i:, P.M. - &gt;he spores have liawii at 11:45 AM. Nona of the spore-, have 9 i drawn :it 1:46 I'M - | the spores hav septate and hare reached normal form and F 10. Hypha beariag conidiophorea and macrocoaidia .lrawn at triac conidiophorei and nMkcroconidJa, drawn at M. Glucose agar nankins drop. tme eonidlopbi mi ivm. ndi(ip!ioris bearins miiroomidia, drawn at 4::n I'M innn F bearinK niirroconidia, drawn at 4:30 P.M. iron agmr hanging drop. Line : onidiopl.or.'s druwu the next morning at 8:00 lrnwn the n.\t mornins at 8:00 +. Coaidiophorea liearini? micux midia. ilrawn at !:«• I'M from agar hanging drop. ui (onidKiphores draws the next moinins at S:&lt;mi o'dock. ophorei draws the next Moralas at 1:00 o'clock 1'I.ATE III 1'I.ATE III tup ol mac 'I'lirimidia sit owing variation in form size -ind wing variation in form, size ami ii. in nl mil roiimidia midia 8. Spons thai have germinated and are already prodm-in ■ ininai d an I arc all' ad y prodacllll ildia (sp. i. Taken from a crowded culture. Taken From a cr wiled cult ill F 19. 20.- Various the germlnatioa of spores aad 19. 20, n th im'natioD of snores and PLATE IV. LATE IV 21, 22. 23. — Open Lawaoa cainations affected l&gt;y badrfOt I : within the calyx completely rotted. .vsnn carnations affet-ted by bud-rot Fl calyx completely rotted F 4. A normal Lawaon carnation. al I.awson carnation Figs. 25. 26. ' ,!,„ p ,, ta i s haV( . , urned ?5 - 26 - Old&lt; of hud-rot: in ■«. M the petals have turned nil shrivelled. hud of Lawaoa carnation that has kem killed treat plate (glacose agar) of Sp,rotn,hnm mad.' ip. form F I. ml of I.Mwson carnation ihat h killed I. ATE v Fig. 28 ur) of .S/&gt; iro/i i, hum made j n fora are. Direct from bod. Fig. 29. (lliii. plate of Sfioroirirk 9 - (;il: Phite of Sporolrickmm. Six separate laocvta- Iiarate inixula- ide direct Horn artiflciallv infected hud. PLATE \I Fig. 30. Clue. plate of Spot otiuh urn. 4 days old: inenhated at lark chamber ■ Fig. 31.— Similar to tig 30 but exposed to lii?ht </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">II' I 1 % &amp; »J %V\ Ik N &gt; AU; J A » m f\ ri: VI g T ' w 8 9 m / J b o^ s </seg>
            <seg id="p021">1'I.ATK 111 15 t </seg>
            <seg id="p022">c-J t^v i*r *&gt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
            <seg id="p024"/>
            <seg id="p025">\ ii I MITE ACCOMPANYING THE BUD ROT OF CARNA- TIONS. IV KOISKKT II. \VOI.&lt; Oil December, l'JUi, there were received from a llorist at Nebraska, specimens of bad* and blossoms of car - iiug tiic appearance described by Dr. Heald i wing tin- presence of the carnation bud-rot. Ou sep - g the discolored, soft, and matted petals, there wCTC red bcif and there small white object! appearing •ladders full of lluiil, varying in size from t li • o be barely visible to the eye to others nearly a i of an inch iu length. When placed under the aUcro - object! were seen to be tilled with eggs floating lear tluiil, and on closer examination tin re tu de - one end of them the fore part ot the IkmIv of the which the sac formed a part, appearing as a little in- end of the sac. Further examination amoved the of other mites in which the body was not distended these referred to, and Bach showed the characteristic nites belonging to the family Taraomemidai and to l'i iliiiiloiih s. The mites have since been reported Lincoln and from Omaha. les belonging to this genus can be recognized by that the body is soft and elongated, with a distinct in i or ''head"), and divided into two port ions horax" and ■•abdomen"), the posterior of which shows of segmentation. The legs are in two groups, the an- w two pairs being situated toward the anterior end of body and the posterior two pairs distant from them and ■ the posterior end. The mouth parts are formed for Anatomy, The University of Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">A Mit&lt; A&lt;romi&gt;anyi&gt;i() the Bud-Roi of Cam 26 racking, the palpi are small, and the mandibles Btylet-like. There are in the females two club-shaped organs of oncer - tain use, situated between the two anterior pain of legs, and near each of these a spiracle opening into an air chamber, neither of these two structures being present in the male. The legs are live-segmented and the second and third pain each bear at the tip two claws am! a sucking disk; tin- ante rior leg has but a single (law and no sucking disk and on the last pair of legs of the male there is also but one (law and no disk. These mites show marked sexual dimorphism. They are ovoviviparous, the young passing through all the pea in development within the swollen body of the femaJ parent. Thej live as parasites on the bodies of in* as in the case of the mite under consideration, suck th from plants. Aside from the interesting biological relationship ex between the mites ;tnd the bud-rot fungus which tin pnreatly distribute and the growth of which in the plat uishes ideal conditions for the development of the mil E&gt; themselves show a number of remarkabli omena, of which perhaps the most remark I of development. The female, after fertilize hibit a swelling of the posterior end of the b tying the development of tin ad wit hit sac-like, distended body, the eggs and young and voung the whole cycle of development and final! from the parent fully mature male and feu Et generation. These pair and the cycle of development is in repeated. In the parent may be seen at the same time 3 and young in all stages of development. I trucker. " in a lograph on Pediculoide* centricotu$ (Newport), hat bed the male of that species as wandering over the body rullotin scientific u6 dc la Franc** t*t d* 1 hi xvm-xxi. 1901. xxxv </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Fie gravid female, awaiting the birth of the females of the generation. During this time he lives parasitically on older female, ami on the birth of the younger females all is parasites until fertilization has been effected, when ind the younger females leave the parent to be tan independent existence. The young are produced at rvals. a few at a time. The following is a description of the mite under consider Eo.N-fiRAVii) Fkmai.k.— .Measures 2'M&gt; to 240 microns in th, with an average maximum breadth of about 70 mi - is and a height of about 4a. Body thus elongated in form th sides neatly parallel, narrowed anteriorly toward the pitnlum and but slightly narrower posteriorly, the poste - ii- end being truncate with rounded lateral angles. The entral surface, from end to end of the body, is straight or lightly concave, and the dorsal Moderately convex. The body is made up of a capitulum, about 21 microns ong, and a body proper, the latter being again divided into wo portions by a transverse constriction about 47 microns roin the base of the capitulum and just behind the second Traces of further segmentation are seen far- r candad, especially at one level just in front of the third r of legs. It bears on the dorsal surface a iiuiiiImt of slen- i- slightly curved hairs, varying in length and arranged in Irs, the two of each pair being placed toward either lateral [in. Half way between the base of the capitulum and piracies and opposite the randal margin of leg I is one pair 12 microns long; opposite the cephalic margin of leg II and just in front of the spiracles another 120 microns long; and about half way between these two pairs a third 20 mi - i-rons in length: all of these bain are directed cephalad as well as dorsad. About 2~t microns behind the transverse con - striction is a third pair, opposite the cephalic margin of leg IV a fourth, and about half way from this to the caudal end of the body a tifth. each of these pairs being about 20 mi- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 'J i !•(' SI I i ii in. i Vent 1 le el i i &gt;n Uetw n i i ions long: these liiiii-s ;ill point nearly Ktraigui doi about ll ( microns from the i-audai end &lt;&gt;f i!n- l.od\ in front of the genital opening is ;i pair of inon curved hairs directed caudad, rather stontei aad i-"i mil rons iii length, while between them short ones only Id microns long. On the caud a pair about li! microns long. Finally, on tin face of the body are a few short pairs placed on each about s to 10 microns in length The spiracles are on the dorsal surf are ncai margin about r&gt;i! microns from the anterior end and opposite the second |&gt;air of legs. They an E about .") microns long an&lt; laterad of each spiracle i ler stalk about 7 mieronf broader towards the tip, 11 mil poi The rapitulum is pyrifomi in dorsal surface being strongly eon and projecting beyond the ventr hood for the month parts liene opening of which is directed vi st\ let-like, short, and do not |&gt; El in the preserved KpecimeiiH. I ect beyond the hood a shori distj ess a terminal segment of tin- foi I; the two anterior pain of epimera are nni two posterior. In the case of the former ih&lt; enl. and the cando-medial angles of the first dnced backward between the second. The posterior epimei are less heavilv chitinizi-d and the line of junction betwee them less evident: they are somewhat larger th nor ones. Tin- anterior three pain of legs are about &lt; •■ | m Measuring from tin- proximal margin of the l&gt;; The epimera of each pair of legs m </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 &lt; i it a htlv nvoh i linn ."U to 56 microns; leg 1\' is longer ii each segment •? — roonting from the — is the shortest. They arc provided various lengths, most numerous on the distal ihvavs one very long hair, and KreraJ is. more or less curved, and a few witli ver\ 1 io 111 tin- basal segment is elongated n at righi angles to the axis of the body, teg ! outer than the rest and has a short spine on the irgin of segment •"&gt; and a elavate spine on the same f segment 4. near the distal end; on the fiU'—nt f segmeni - is an extremely long hair, the tip of eaehes to even with the tip of the leg or even sonic - vond. (Mi segmeni 1 is another long one. the length is not so extreme; segment ."&gt;, seen from the dorsal apers to the tip, hot when seen from the sid&gt; equal width to the very end. the claw lK-inir articn- the disto-tlexor angle. Le^s II to IV show a gradual [ion of the distal segment from near the base to a yond the middle, where the segment becomes very while beyond this is a small bulb-like enlarirein.iit ip of which are the claws and the stalked sucking lal opening is on the caudal surface of the body dorsal than the ventral margin. Female. — In tin- gravid female the size of the bodj until it may become even eight times the original ne specimen measured was 1.9 mm. long, 1.2 nun. ind 1.1 mm. high. The body at first is more ovoiilal, it becomes greatly distended it becomes ellipsoidal. flattened on the ventral surface. This diston s that portion of the body lying eandad of the trans - nisiriction. tin- dorsal and caudal surfaces being « ar - rther and farther dorsad and eaudad, leaving the two ixis of tin- extended l«*ij to ilic l&gt;a&gt;&lt;- &lt;&gt;( ili&lt; iis. They bear a general resemblanci </seg>
            <seg id="p030">i 11 1 1 it* 1 ml. I i i r 1 far 3U A Mite Accompanying the Bud-Rot 0/ posterior pairs of limbs nearly iu normal relation ers, but carrying the genital opening clear to the end of the swollen, sac-like body. Malk. — The body of the male is shorter, broader, ai higher than that of ilie female, varying in length from IK to 100 microns, in breadth from 80 !&lt;&gt; !M» micron height from ."&gt;() to ••&lt;&gt; microns, li is broadest about tli tand tapers from this point in both direction here seem to be two transverse constriction lying just ccphalad of the third pair of epimera two-thirds the length of the body from the cephali hairs upon the body are much fewer in number, th a short distance in front of the transverse constri long ones, one toward either lateral margin, an them and nearer the median line two other sh while behind the constriction are three pair long, tlie second of moderate length, and th The capituluiii is similar in size and structure to tl female and thus somewhat larg length. There are minor differences in tin while, aside from the characters refern show the following characters distingnishi II and III are proportionately longer, l.'g I ~&gt;4 microns, II and III about (V2 microns, and I\ microns in an individual of average size. ! stout, with the basal segments especially thi&lt; 1 tal segment is small, tapers rapidly and bean claw. Leg IV is little stouter than IT nnd ITT. hu S is thick and not contracted until at the tip. ami number of variously modified sensorv hair The genital area is crowded into the -marie between tl pair of epimera, the medial borders of which diverge caudad is at the same level ns the epimera, and projects beyond 'I caudal extremity &lt;ftf the body, which lies on a le\ </seg>
            <seg id="p031">i •ciiuciis bare been available in the prep - 'iption, I'm the material was ptuam led oliol. forinol, corrosive sublimate. Car pitroniirii , and Koenike'a solution. PLATE VII Ma^nifi Drawn surface, i460. Came n ly distcndf.l with eggs and younR. Seen from PLATE VI is k» belong to a speck* hitherto umlr- appropriatelj be designated Prdicuioide$ Xri.AN \TION OF PI.ATKS with ca-'.i [ m en preserved in alcoholic ill surface. k460. Camera, surfai Outline iblimaip. are borne on the posterior margin of </seg>
            <seg id="p032">• </seg>
            <seg id="p033"/>
        
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>