<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  OATS.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN NO. 113. The University of Nebraska. BILJ L^L^Enri N OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXII, Article III. OATS. Variety Tests. Rate of Sowing. Cultivation. By E. G. Montgomery. Distributed February 15, 1910. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. HONORABLE CHAKLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls Citv. HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERV, Ph. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. WM.W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk. THE WORKING STAFF. E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. J. Alway, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. H. R. Smith, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. A. L. Haeckkr, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Bkdner, B. Sc, Entomology. E. G. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. Frank J. Phillips, M. F., Forestry. Erwin H. B arbour, Ph. D., Geology. ER. Chatburn, A. M., Highway Engineering. A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulture. ■ P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineering. Loveland, B. Sc, LL. B., Meteorology. . PUGSLEY, B. Sc, Soil Agronomy. rP. Snydeb, M. S. , Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Platte &gt;S Venus W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Herbert Coons, A. B., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. S. Trumbull, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. P. B. Barker, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). P\.. Kiesselbach, B. Sc, A. B., Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). 3. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. H. Swenk, A. M., Assistant in Entomology. R. F. Howard, B. Sc, in Agr., Assistant in Horticulture. W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Assistant in Soils and Crops, North Platte. Ebwin Hopt, B. Sc, Assistant in Crops and Horticulture, North Platte. S. W. Perin, Farm Superintendent. •Miss Louise M. Allen, A. M., Scientific Assistant, Seed Testing. * Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. („, ....NT. or thi MMam.) </seg>
            <seg id="p003">INTRODUCTION. ! There is no more serious question confronting the Nebraska armer today than the oat problem. During the past few years, farmers generally believe they have lost money on the crop. It is necessary to grow some spring grain crop, and while many are looking for a substitute, such as barley, speltz, and spring wheat, yet none of these crops takes the place of oats in a satisfactory manner. While soil fertility must receive immediate attention, still our yields would be decidedly increased thru the use of vari - eties best adapted to the region, with good preparation of the seed-bed, drilling with a disk drill, and cultivation when the season is dry. VARIETY TESTS OF OATS L Table I gives a summary of results with 12 varieties tested ! 1902. Note.— Since not all varieties were tested for the full 7 years, the only way a comparison could be made between the varieties was to compare all with a standard variety like Kherson, for the years in which they were grown. The Kherson oat was always ranked as 100. For example, Canada Red was grown 4 years. 1903-1906. During those years it yielded 91 per cent, as much as Kherson. On this basis if Kherson yielded 55.3 bushels for 7 years, Canada Red would be calculated as yielding 50.3 bushels. Some 20 varieties have been tested, but only 12 of them have &gt;een grown four or more years. A study of the data shows a marked advantage in favor of early varieties. This is more clearly shown by Table II, where the varieties are arranged according to date of ripening. By E. (i Montgomery*. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 806l-i06l ISnj )Q30 add -a v ?t--* •UJ©C0t-'N© • ■ • -u : : : : I I I *. t 50 . 50 . us a CO-* 35©C»00N --*O — cSO"H05i-ieai-ii-ciMus^ig-&gt;] (U I I I I I I I I I I ] 1 f fc^M 1 1^* r^^ i^* r^* t^" f™** t^* i^^ a *^ WCN • U5 US 00 © ■&gt;* IO • • • i.hcq 'OnMnnn • • • 00 5^t» "t^OSIOQOOS© • • T3!2 :££££££ : : ■ Si : ■ • ■ i—{ isSSSSiSSSsS i : : 4 ■ • : '• 00 • © r- cccortOHOaoM ■ . • &gt; O HrirHNNNrtWOO • • • L OB I I 1 1 I • I I I • • • !-* r- r- r- r- r- r- i— r- 1— - • • 8O6l-tO6t ■ 3SBJ3AV Si « »4j K •S oo i^c^Nna I ' . I ■ S T i T i i i i i i i r i r^* t^^ £ t^* t^ t*^ t^* t^* t ™ i. ™ t^" t^™ io .rH us oo oo oo — co — « ta oo S I I I I I I ! I I I ' I ,— , t^ i- t— i- t— r- r— t- cd t- t^ t- s I S?©-^OrHlOC5©C300i— 'r—Oi u ©3305t-t-I-OOOSOSC-CD r m HHHMMrtrtTj* -—COM p HrtnNN«MMt-HNN A I I I I I I I I I I I I i I s* a&gt; a. •a -s | naOCD Ort C- -X * ■ * »5 ■* o" Tt&lt;-*oseoco-* • • • 0-1 05 in » eg — i ai oo r- oo • • • • I B^s-JiMioeonffl moo; ■•0 -r— — — r-r-7 —X &gt;, r OT l I • I 1 I I i I • • • O ?&gt;-H«CCO ■CDt-!O!Dt-t- • • "S t- OHDOO O tC»O-- . 5 OlMIMi-iMM-HMlfl— i-H • • l_! ! S I I i. I TT I ■' 43 n oooei-t-sof es ■ S 0 &lt; 3 5 J.1 1 f 1 11 1 ' 111 l_&lt; * h eosteeeooses 05 jj-^-^t-OONXlCCOOMC^t- o einn«HHn«3-&lt;H • • O5 I I I I I I I I I I • - i-i »!D!DOt-r-»J-S3 i-c "S oo oo oo cc r- 1- oo io oo oo t- 1- ■* os i-i co oo us oo us ao ■* ■o«h OS i I I I I I I I I I t— I ;OCOCOC05O5OCO;©OX&gt;COC0 eo jj©«o-*io«o ■ : • : ©«us os moot-NHia • • • -cooim ■* e&lt;5 m m in M — m ■* mcM'N 3b I I I I I i I i i I i i rH :cc050cccosoto:C50:r;r-.r i rH oo I- © SO • '• • 1 3 S3 8 .::::::::: • • &gt;&gt; • • • t. :::::: :^ : : :&amp; :::::: :| :: : 1 : : : :|J '« : : .5 j ! i ! i i ii 1 1 !l ;■ ; :»«• : | j.-je • ■ • a . is . . . „ : : :■§ a o ."no : .' "-.'S • : * ;■§!£ SJ^gjI §2 til I </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Types of oats. Nos. 1 to 5 inclusive represent early varieties; Nos. 6 to 12 inclusive, late varieties. 1, Burt. 2, Sixty Day. 3, Kherson. 4, Canada Red. 5, Texas Red. 6, Lincoln. 7, Swedish Select. 8, Uni - versity No. 6. 9, White Queen. 10, American Banner. 11, Prize Cluster. 12, Mold's Black Beauty. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Types op Oats. — The early and late varieties also represent two types of oats differing in other ways than time of ripening. The early varieties are either yellow or reddish in color, and have rather small sized grains, while the late varieties are all, with one exception, of the light colored varieties commonly known as white oats. The late varieties also average taller. Farmers have generally preferred the larger grained late varieties, probably on account of the nice appearance of the grain and also in order to bring their harvest time after wheat harvest, and also after corn is laid by. K)ecasionally we have a season when late white oats will re - a heavy yield of good quality, but ordinarily, we may de - on much better results from early varieties of the Kherson xas Red type. V'he Burt oat was secured from Mr. M. A. Carleton of the Department of Agriculture four years ago. While it has giv- Table II. — Varieties of 01 ipening. arranged according to date of Early oats Date ripe, 1904-1908 Yield per acre Number of years jrrown Height, 1907-1908 ofgraTn Burt Sixty Day Kherson Canada Red July 6 July 9 July 10 July 14 July 15 Bushels 59.7 52.5 55.3 50.3 52 0 4 5 7 4 7 Inches 39 "46" ■" 40 " Average July 11 53.9 40 Late oats Lincoln Oats Swedish Select University No. 0 White Queen American Banner Improved Prize Cluster. . . Mold's New Black Beauty July 19 July 19 July 20 July 20 July 21 July 21 July 22 44.2 5 42 Whitish 39.2 6 44 Whitish 43.7 5 44 Whitish 42.6 4 Whitish 41.4 6 46 Whitish 38.1 4 Whitish 32.6 5 43 Black ii\ I A A 44.2 39.2 43.7 42.6 41.4 38.1 32.6 5 6 5 4 6 4 5 42 44 44 "ie" ■■43'" Average . . July 20 I 40.1 I I 44 I 40.1 44 I'aking the earlies varieties, we find of ripening, and five v£ irieties compared with the latest an ave rage difference of nine days in [ bushels difference in yield per ibout 1&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 en a high average yield, it has also lodged and rusted badly under favorable conditions. In view of this it cannot be recommended above Kherson until after a thoro test in the state. RATE OF SOWING OATS. The average amount of seed oats sown per acre among Ne- braska farmers is about 10 pecks, but the amount sown by indi- viduals varies considerably, the extreme being from about six pecks to fourteen pecks per acre. An experiment was started in 1903 with the object of noting the effect of various rates of plant- ing on yield of grain. Data have been secured each year with the exception of 1904 when the plats were so badly injured by a Krm that accurate yields could not be secured. Table III. — Rate of planting Kherson oats, 1903. Rate of I Total seeding- yield Net return Method of planting per acre I per acre Pecks I BiitheU Bushels Drilled 6 62.5 ! 61 Drilled 8 65.7 63 Drilled 10 58.4 55.9 Drilled 12 61.7 Drilled IK 64 2 Drilled I 8 65.7 63 « Table IV. — Rate of planting Kherson oats, 1905. m.u.0, * P i.», lnB ESS £»* 32" ,£«. ! SS. l*racre Per acre Pecks Indus Bushels Bushels Drilled 6 June 29 33 86.3 I 83.8 Drilled 8 June 28 35 88.1 M.] Drilled 10 June 28 34 83 ' 81.2 Drilled 12 June ! 34 83.4 »0.4 Drilled 16 June 28 34 80.9 ; ;6. y Broadcast 6 July 7 30 72.2 70.7 78.1 76.1 Broadcast 8 | July 7 ; 32 Broadcast 10 July 7 ' 33 81.9 ! 81.2 Broadcast 12 July 7 30 Broadcast '. '. '.'. . .' . . '. '. '. '. '. '. '. '. I 16 I July 7 32 81.4 i 71 4 The broadcast oats gave best yield seeded- at the rate of ten pecks per acre, and the drilled oats at eight pecks. The broadcast oats ripened nine days later and straw did not average quite so tall. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">drouth, the rains coining late. This caused the quite uniform. ripening to be Kherson oats for four years. Table V. — Rote of pla ting Kheraon ow I, 1906. Method of planting Rate of seeding per acre Date of ripening Height of straw Yield per acre Per acre Drilled '..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'...'.'.'.'.'. Drilled Broadcast Pecks Inches Drilled 6 July 9 31 Drilled 8 July 9 30 Drilled 10 July 9 29 Drilled 12 July 9 27 Drilled 16 July 9 27 Broadcast 6 July 9 29 8 July 9 28 10 July 9 26 12 July 9 26 16 July 9 26 Pecks 6 8 10 12 16 6 8 10 12 16 Bushels 63.7 67.1 66.5 66.2 64.1 61.5 62.8 63.7 62.5 61.2 The drilled and broadcast oats matured ai the sac ie time. while in 1905 the broadcast oats were nine di tys later, ever, all of the oats in 1906 were retarded in gr&lt; iwth by i lsprins Hrrmtli th* rains onmino Into TViio panoprl tVi i TMrkAnin o tn h&lt; ABLE ting eraon oats, Method of planting Rate of seeding per acre Date of ripening Height Yield J?** of straw per acre = = -= -^= Peeks 6 8 10 12 16 July 15 July 15 July 15 July 15 July 15 Inchti Bushels Bushels 31 49.1 48.3 31 53 4 51.4 31 50.7 48.2 31 54 2 51.2 31 54 5 50.5 Table VII. — Summa 'or rate tlantin unth drill Method of planting ! Rate of seeding I per acre Net return per acre 1903 1905 1906 1907 Average Peck* Drilled ..'..".'.'. '.'.'.'.'.'. '.'..'. '.'.'.'. 10 Bu. 61 63.7 55.9 58 7 64 2 Bu. 83.8 86.1 81.2 80.4 76.9 Bu. 63.7 67.1 66.5 66.2 64.1 Bu. 48 3 51 4 48.2 51.2 50.5 I Average yield 61.7 I 81.7 I 65.5 49 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Table VIII. — Summary for rate of planting with Kherson oats, broadcast, two years. Rate of Xet return per acre seeding- Average per acre 1905 190ti Method of planting b Eight pecks of seed per acre has uniformly given best re - where the oats were drilled, and ten pecks per acre where were broadcasted. E'he number of pecks of oats which should be sown per acre y particular variety will depend on the size of grains, and the stooling qualities. The following table will illustrate on between size of grain and the rate of sowing necessary ier to secure the same stand of plants. Table IX. — Relation between size of grain and volume in three varieties of oats. In order to note the effect of rate of planting on the stooling of oats, a place was selected in each plat where the stand was uniform and normal, and all plants within a measured area were examined, with the following results: ♦ Broadcast Broadcast Broadcast Broadcast Broadcast Pecks 6 8 10 12 16 Bu. 70 7 76.1 79.4 78.2 77.4 Bu. 60.0 60.8 61.2 59.5 57.2 Average yield 76.4 59.7 Variety Number of grains Hecks per acre to secure in one pound same number of plants Kherson Dun Oats New Rel iance 22176 12128 9232 8 pecks 14 pecks 19 pecks </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Table X.— - Stooling of Kherson oats, 1907. following results. Counts were made in duplicate plats. Both series are given. when 8 pecks or more per acre was used. Practically- no tillers developed when 12 or 16 pecks was used. (Similar results have been obtained with corn plants. See Ne - braska Experiment Station Bulletin 91, page 19.) It is worth noting that, whatever the rate of seeding, there was a strong tendency for the thin seedings to tiller enough to bring the stand up to normal. The normal stand seems to be about 1,700, - 000 stems per acre. Results at the Kansas Station 1 show that there is a marked difference in the tillering habits of different varieties of oats, the ■Kan. Bui. 144, p. 173. 1 Num- Area ex-: ber of amined plants on area Total num- ber of stems Num- ber of tillers Number of tillers per plant Number Total Y i I of plants number per of stems acre per acre I Sq. feet 28.44 28.44 28.44 28 44 28.44 28.44 28.44 105 328 613 784 843 1042 1376 643 918 1075 1075 1165 1210 1462 518 590 462 291 322 168 85 5.12 1.80 .75 .37 38 .15 .06 160,797 984,686 34.7 492,299 1,405,825 41.4 938,748 I,64«.2o5 49.8 1,200,617 1,646,255 51.8 1,290,970 1,784,081 50.0 1,595,718 1,852.994 53.4 2,107,206 2,238,906 44.3 In 1908, counts were made in three rates of seeding, with LK . — j itOOi ing o, xraon oats, 5? Area ex- amined Num- ber of plants on area Total number of stems Num- ber of tillers Number Number Yield of tillers of plants-^- per per plant per acre acre I kq. reel 32 32 32 32 32 32 229 218 428 487 1180 1228 1048 1038 1235 1310 1762 1593 819 820 807 823 582 365 3.57 3.76 1.89 1.69 .49 .30 311,726 1,426,590 37.0 296,752 1,412,977 38.5 582,615 1,681,144 50.0 662.929 1,783,237 46.5 1,606,275 2,398,52- 1,671,615 2, 168. 47 1 Fhe oat plants tillered abundantly when sown very thin, ucing over five tillers per plant in 1907 when two pecks of per acre was used. The number of tillers decreased rapidly when l the rate of planting was increased, very few developing </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 common variation being from about 10 tillers for 100 plants to about 150 tillers for 100 plants. The rate of seeding is affected not only by size of grain but also by the amount of tillering. CULTIVATION OK OATS. 1 value of cultivation for hoed crops has so long been ognized that no one knows when the advantage was first dis - covered, and it is altogether reasonable to suppose that had the cultivation of small grain a corresponding advantage the dis - covery would have been made early. However, the fact that the cultivation of small grain is certain to yield less striking results than the cultivation of hoed crops does not prevent it from pay - ing returns to the farmer. Nebraska farming has so prospered that land is as valuable as the time of horses and men. In other words, it may be as profitable to add three or four bushels to the average yield per acre by careful cultivation as to buy more land for the growing of extra grain. "What painstaking culture can do for small grain on Nebraska farms, the Station during the last eight years has been attempting to determine. Planting Oats in Wide Rows. — In 1898 and 1899, oats were drilled in one-tenth acre plats at distances of twenty-four inches, eighteen inches, twelve inches, and six inches between the drill rows. One of the two plats devoted to drills six inches apart was left uncultivated. For the cultivation of the others the harrow wag used until the grain became too high. Then a small-shoveled cultivator was substituted. Table XII gives the data and results : lData on cultivation of oats are condensed from Bulletin 104, technical bulletin, which was not distributed generally. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 tivation may be considered here the standard plan of growing oats. The standard plan yielded 22.5 per cent larger than the 18-inch, and 8 per cent larger than the 12-inch plan. However, the advantage of once cultivating a plat drilled six inches apart is 17 per cent. The conclusion from the experiment is that in a year of normal or slightly more than normal rainfall, one culti - vation given a field seeded in the standard way is advantageous ; but that the advantage secured by cultivation does not warrant the placing of drills farther apart than six inches for the purpose of facilitating cultivation. In 1899 the results of oats cultivation were as follows : ABL eu, ■vation on oats in Fista nee part of drills Seed Number of culti- vations Yield K per acre Method giving larger yield per acre S Inches 24 6 Qts. 16 64 3 21.1 Ordinary method without cultiva- 0 25.8 tion, 22.5 per cent larger. 3 0 Bushels 21.1 25.8 5 18 6 21 64 3 21 2 Ordinary method without cultiva- 0 25.8 tion, 21.7 per cent larger. 3 0 21 2 25.8 : 12 6 32 64 3 24.0 Ordinary method without cultiva- 0 25.8 tion, 8 per cent larger. I 0 24.0 25.8 : 6 6 64 64 1 30.2 Ordinary method with one cultiva- 0 25.8 tion, 7 per cent larger. 1 0 30.2 25.8 Precipitation: Ev&lt; mal inly distributed; fall 1897, 2.46 inches above nor- 1; spring (January- July) 1898, 1.90 Inches above mal. nor The method c if seeding in drills six inches apart without cul- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Table XIII. — Effect of cultivation on oats in 1899. The standard method of growing yielded, in 1899, 26.6 per cent better than the 24-inch 4-cultivations plan, and 6.3 per cent better than the 18-inch 4-cultivations plan. In that year, however, the 12-inch triple cultivation method gave 23.1 per cent larger results than the standard, and one cultivation increased the yield of a standard drilled plat 13.6 per cent. I The difference in the results obtained on the two years with b 12 inches apart may be accounted for in the difference in ipitation of the years. The growing season of 1898 was more normally moist ; that of 1899 was more than normally dry. I The conclusions drawn from Table XIII are that one culti - &gt;n in a dry season is a decided advantage to a standard ed acreage, and that under very dry conditions a further ad - age is secured by lessening the number of drills by one-half cultivating three times. Cultivation op Oats with Standard Methods of Sowing. — The experiment of drilling oats in wide rows, 12 inches or more apart, was dropped in 1900, but cultivation has been continued since on plats sown by standard methods. By standard methods is meant in drill rows 6 to 8 inches apart or broadcast, and at the rate of 10 pecks per acre. The cultivation usually consisted of W Distance Seed Number V ioi&lt;i apart of per ofculti- **?£- drills acre vations P* 5 ™ 0 ™ Method giving larger yield S Inches Qts. 24 20 6 80 18 27 6 80 4 0 4 3 Buxhels 23.4 29.7 28.0 2H.7 Ordinary method without cultiva- I tion, 26.6 per cent larger yield. s Ordinary method without cultiva- tion, 6.2 per cent larger yield. B 12 40 6 80 6 80 6 80 3 0 1 0 36.5 29.7 33 8 29.7 12 inch drilling with cultivation, 23.6 per cent larger yield. 3 Ordinary method with one cultiva- tion, 13 per cent larger y ield. Precipitation: Fall. 1898. .03 Inch b 3.40 inches below n slow normal; January-July. 1899 irmal; June, 3.92 Inches a*x&gt;v« normal. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 have found the weeder much the better under all conditions. "We do not attempt to cultivate when the soil is wet, but only when dry and in condition to pulverize. The following table shows average results of cultivation on oats for seven years: P?able XIV. — Summary showing effect of cultivation upon of drilled oats for seven years. Treatment j 1898 1899 I 1900 1902 1903 I 1905 1906 Average The experiment was not conducted in 1901. In 1904 the plats were sown, but owing to wet weather and high winds they were blown down so badly that they could not be harvested. An average increase of 4.8 bushels was given by cultivation. The cultivation generally consisted of two or three harrowings, a few days apart, with a common smoothing harrow or weeder, about three to five weeks after sowing. The weeder is much better than the harrow, principally because it does not carry coarse trash, like cornstalks, and is not as severe on the young plants. Kr four years, drilling and broadcasting with and without tion have been compared. The results are given in the fol - table: Bu. Bu. Bu. iultivated 30.2 33.8 29.0 rot cultivated 25.8 29.7 24.7 Hfference in favor of cultivation Bu. Bu. Bu. Bu. 43.5 62.4 102.1 59.2 39.3 67.1 80.0 59. 9 M : : .. i Table XV.— Su; \ata, with and without mar ulti\ ■y vat comparing an tion, for a peri d and broadcast of four years. Method of planting Treatment 1900 1903 1906 Av. Method giving larger yield Drilled . . . Drilled . . . Broadcast Broadcast' Cultivated .... Not cultivated Cultivated Not cultivated Bu. 29.0 24.7 36.0 31.7 Bu. 62.4 67.1 59.0 63.4 Bu 102.1 80.0 75 6 81.0 Bu. Bu. 59.2 63.2 59.9 57.9 57.0 56.9 59.0 58.8 59.2 63.2 57.0 56.9 59.9 57.9 59. 0 1 58.8 Cultivation, 5.3 bu. larger, or 9.1% Without cultivation, 1.9 bu. larger, or 3.3% Drilled . . . Broadcast Cultivated Cultivated .... 29.0 36.0 62.4 59.0 102.1 75 6 Drilling, 6.3 bu. larger, or 11% Drilled . . . Broadcast Not cultivated Not cultivated 24.7 31.7 67.1 K3.4 80.0 81 0 Broadcasting, .9 bu larger, or 1.5% ' </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Where broadcasting and drilling were compared without cultivation, the broadcasting gave slightly better results. When cultivation was practised, the drilled oats were increased in yield 5.3 bushels per acre, while the broadcast oats were decreased 1.9 bushels per acre. In cultivating the oats sown broadcast, the harrow destroys some plants, while with the drilled oats very few plants are destroyed. In our experiments we have used the same amount of seed per acre in both cases, but the loss due to cultivation in oats sown broadcast might be offset by heavier seeding. However, experience leads us to believe that where cultivation is to be practised the grain should be drilled. Pt will be noted that in this experiment the broadcast oats yielded as well as the drilled. This is contrary to experi - on the farms, but In this case is due to the great care used in sowing the broadcast plats. In order to make a test of the effect of cultivation on broadcast and drilled oats, every pre - caution was used to insure as good and perfect a stand on the broadcast plats as on the drilled plats. This required a perfect preparation of the soil, an even distribution of the seed, and careful, uniform covering. Under ordinary conditions, however, better results will be secured with drilling than broadcasting. CONCLUSIONS. One point brought out clearly by the seven seasons of ex - periments with oats is that the same treatment does not insure the same results each year. In years of much more than normal rainfall, positive damage is done by cultivating either oats or wheat. When there is sufficient moisture to mature a heavy crop of grain, it is certainly unwise to destroy plants with harrow or pulverizer. On the other hand, when precipitation before seeding has been meager and dry weather follows, cultivation of grain results well. Early varieties of oats have given an average of 14 bushels per acre greater yield during the past five or six years than late varieties. The early varieties used have been rather small grained and </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Eight pecks per acre has given the best results with drilled oats and ten pecks per acre when the oats was sown broadcast. Cultivation of drilled oats has given an increased yield of 4.8 bushels per acre, while cultivation of broadcast oats has given decreased yield. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>