<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1903</title>
               <date value="1903">1903</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">v. s </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1903 Prepared by S. C. BASSETT Secretary Nebraska Dairymen's Association FREMONT, NKBR. PRIHTBD BT THI HAMMOND PRJWTIBG OO. </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">iraska Dairymen's Association, ktary's Office, Gibbon, Nebraska, February 1, 1904. \ Kxeellency, John H. Mickey, Governor of Nebraska: : In compliance with the law in this case made and provided, I hereby transmit the annual report of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association for the year 1903. Respectfully yours, S. C. BASSETT, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">TABLE OF CONTEN List of Members I Program . . . 14 Cream Testing Conte- Cow Judging Contest . &gt; Remarks 16 President's Address. • • 17 Secretary's Report- 18 Report of Auditing Committee Address — By 8. C. Bassett to Care for the Dairy Cow— By L. D. Still* Discussion . How to Feed the Dairy Cow — By H. C. Glissman 36 IL Some Things 1 Have Ivearned — By J. A. Harris .61 ssion . .65 Selection of the Dairy ( Sow Discussion Address— By W. A. Henry --83 lesion &gt; • • • . 90 Appointment of ( 'ommittees its of Committee 96 List of Creameries • 102 Table of Cows in Content .... 103 </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">OFFICERS— 1903-1904. President C. A. Clark, Ravenna Vice-president J. A. Harris, Shickley Secretary and Treasurer . . S. C. Bassett, Gibbon DIRECTORS. J. K. Honeywell J. C. Merrill A. L. Haecker L. D. Stillson Henry C. Glissman </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">LIST OF MEMBERS. HONORARY LIFE MEM I J. H. Monrad Winnetka, 111. C. L. Gabrilson ... w Hampton, Iowa W. D. Hoard Foit Atkinson, A. C. Tupper Oaage, Iowa Lumbard I &gt;maha, Nebr. LIFE MEMBERS. Elijah Allen D. P. Ash burn !). P. Ashburn ... .ibbon, Nebr. J. Dixon Avery Cor. Clark arid Water sts., Chicago, 111., k '&lt; ibbon, v Bassett • ibbon, ? K, Wilcox cS: Srreeter Baumer Bayley N'ebr. N'ebr. ( '•. W. Bemis . . . H. Binghain &amp; Co 'niaha, x v Bolin. . . I &gt;maha, I . Carpenter U, Buffalo, ~ . . Fort Dodge, North Clark I. N. Davis Milford, Mass. J. H. Davis J. B. Din- Dn.rv i ibbon, v Frank T. Emerson 422 South Fifth St., Omaha, : </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 Germantown Cooperative Creamery Assn., Germantown. Henry C. Glissman Station B, Omaha, Charles Finch Omaha, T. i . Fisher Gibbon, Nebr H. F. Flint Gibbon, Fulnier Gibbon, I R. \V. Furnas Brownville, H. C. Glissman Station B, Omaha, E. W. ( uinther Albion, J. W. Harrell Gibbon, Chr. Hansen 17 Dearborn st., Ofadcsg Hainer Aurora, 8 Ileimrod Omaha, E. F. Howe Omaha, S. W. Hoyt 3-5 Han \ York, N. V W. EL [jams Omaha, P. E. Her Omaha, : H. B. Kellev Inez, Thomas Kirk Gibbon, hbaum Omaha, F. W. Iz-sseiitin. Omaha, Magenau Fremont, I Merrill Sutton, t[ Meyer .. Miller nk E - &lt; &gt;maha, &lt; &gt;n:aha, Omaha, W. T. Mount &lt; )niaha. . M. H. Noble Gibbon, Keefe Omaha, ' \ Pundt &lt; hnali:i. ■11 ,V- Rid.lell Omaha, J. H. Rush ton Fairmont, ( )maha, ... </seg>
            <seg id="p012">OF MEMBERS 11 George H. Silvernail Gibbon, v J. G. Southwick Benn. Chr. Specht Omaha, I J. T. Stanhope Dubuque, Iowa B. R. Stouffer South Omaha, ? Otto Stuben . . Omaha, v William Sutton . .Table Rock, Nebr. Julius Treitschke Omalia, v Troxell &amp; Williams Omaha, ! D. H. Wheeler Omaha, J I). H. Wheeler, Jr • Omaha, : .. Whitmore Nebr. Whitney &amp; Co man &amp; Co Omaha, . v H. H. Wing.... Ed Whittig C. E. Woodruff Grand Island, v Furgason Beaver Crossing, v Haskell &amp; Bosworth B&lt; F. H. Vaughan Wyo. J.J.King Charles W. Stevenson AL MEMBERS. J. K. Honeywell Lincoln, x L. D. Stillson York, ? F. C. Stillson C. A. Clark Prof. A. L. Haecker State University, Lincoln, .' C. E. Laverack .... I^eighton, care of Beatrice Creamer}' Co., Lincoln, . Snively. .care of Beatrice Creamery Co., Lincoln, A. ML Prie&gt;t . . .care of Beatrice Creamery Co., Lincoln, x Morris Friend, care of Beatrice Creamery Co., Lincoln, x J. Holmes . . . .care of Beatrice Creamer incoln, Lincoln, I </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Max Buschow Blue Hill, Nebr W. H. Clarkson 704 N. 16th, Omaha, Nebr Art Gentzler • -care of Beatrice Creamery Co., Lincoln, Nebr B. E. Bowersox Bladen, Nebr. W. A. Doubt Havelock, Nebr. J. A, Harris , Shickley, Nebr. G. C. Noble Crete, Nebr. M. W. Lang. .Department of Agriculture, Washington, D. C. N. E. Wescott . Des Moines, Iowa, H. C. Haverly ♦« Hastings, Nebr. C. H. Hinman . . 3i ate Farm, Lincoln, Nebr. W. Dodds Columbus, Nebr. Fred Kohler . • Deweese, Nebr. J. M. Brown 11. F. D. No. 1, Scribner, Nebr. R. L. Tolles Laurel, Nebr. John Gibb Staplehurst, Nebr. Blodgett Beatrice, Nebr. Lamb Tecumseh, Nebr. O. R. Myers Lincoln, t M. A. De Peel Cleanvater, Nebr. H W. Ehlere Clieney, Nebr. J. N. Ash burn Gibbon, Nebr. E. L. Franklin Eustis, Nebr. Wilson Honey Creek, Iowa R. L. McDonald Sutton, Nebr Wheaton 308 N. 22nd., Omaha, Nebr. G. D. Calkins, .care of Beatrice Creamery Co., Lincoln, Nebr. J. F. Schlappi Lincoln, Nebr. Mclntosh • Alda, Nebr. J. B. Hughes Cozad, Nebr. C. W. Tolles. • • Laurel, Nebr. Mrs. C. De Peel Clearwater, Nebr. S. Pierce Woodlawn, Nebr. Mrs. S. Pierce Woodlawn, Nebr. E. C. Leigh Beatrice, Nebr. F. M. Hoxie. . . . .1232 R st., Lincoln, Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 A. J. Olson • ■ Wahoo, Nebr. J. B. Varnev • Bennett, Nebr. D. N. Syford • Lincoln, Nebr. John Balster •■ Chalco, Nebr. M. M. Sterns Humbolt, xNebr. Life Members . • • • 87 Annual Members • • 53 Total '40 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">NINETEENTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE BRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. HELD AT DAIRY BUILDING, UNIVERSITY FARM, LINCOLN, JAKUABY 20-21, 1904. PROGRAM. WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 20, I Ba. M. — Address of President J. K. Honeywell, rt of Secretary and Treasure: intment of Committees. Bto Care for the Dairy Cow . . . L. D. Stillson, York, Nebr. to Feed the Dairy Cow, Henry C. Glissman, Omaha, Nebr. p. ii. — Some Things I Have Learned •I. A. Harris, Shickley, Nebr. • mg ;i Dairy Cow Prof. 0. Erf, Kansas Agricultural College THURSDAY, JANUARY 21. a. m. — Report of Committees. Election of Officers. Cream Testing Con f p. M. — Judging Dairy Cows Contest. niversity Farm; Their Records . . Prof. A. L. Haecker, State University </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 PROGRAM CREAM TEST I EST. RULES AND REGULATIONS. Prof. A. I,. Haeckk intendent, Lincoln. number of points, 100; Minimum number of point - The pro rata premium will be divided among the ante scoring above the stated minimum (95 points) in pro - portion to the points scored above the minimum, pro 1 no contestant shall receive, of the pro rata fund, to e Only members of the Association who are residents of the state can compete. Instructors in cream testing, including I by creamery companies to instruct employes, not allowed to compete. Hand separator cream will be Babcock method, samples to be taken with a pipett contestant permitted to use his own method as to taking sample, reducing same with water, temperature, et t will have the use of laboratory in dairy building including all apparatus necessary to make the test. Tlu \ ill be at the state farm on Thursday, January 21. mencing at 11:00 a. m. In order that facilities for all may be furnished, persons desiring to compete must notit tary on or before January 10, 1 COW JUDGING CON'! HEGULAI I gold watch suitably engraved, value, % 1 Bto members of the Association who are residents of the te. In case of tie for first prize it will be drawn bj The pro rata premium will be divided am* 75 points out of a possible 100 points in | Pro Rata Premium, .$75.00. Pro Rata premium. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">' 16 number of points scored above 75, provided, that of the pro rata fund no contestant shall receive i nn of 115.00. Bie butter fat production of the cows to be judged, for the two years, is a matter of record, and the judging will ist in placing tli- in numerical order according to • relative value as producers of butter fat. The judging will be done on Thursday, January 21, at p. m. in the live stock pavilion on the state farm. iber of the Association is invited to take part in this i REMARKS. Any person m me a member of tli i— ition. bership 00. There will be no exhibit of dairy produ B sessions will be held in the dairy building at the - A free lunch at noon, will be provided for those in at- r facilities between I state farm. (quarters of tin iation will be at Lindell Hotel. programs or other information in regard to tl)p i r y&gt; Gibbi </seg>
            <seg id="p018">PRESIDENT'S ADDRES yn assuming the duties of president of the Nebraska men's Association, I do so with a full sense of the duties esponsibilities attending it, and I fully realize that I o nothing without your earnest and cordial cooperation upport. I congratulate you all upon the prosperous year just closed, and upon the increased interest taken in the dairy and creamery industry. Many creameries and dairymen doing business in this state have increased their productions and profits by a large per cent, over former years. Parties owning cattle ranches in the grazing districts of the state, have found a source of income from their cows never thought of or realized before. The young men of the state, by experience on the farm, and education under the influence of our State Uni - versity, are becoming interested in the dairy and creamery business to such an extent that Nebraska is bound to be a dairy state of national reputation. We have the soil and the climate. We can raise alfalfa and clover, corn, oats, and barley. The dairymen of the state can be entirely independ - ent as to the feed of their herds. Alfalfa hay and ground corn and cob make a cheap and well balanced ration, leaving the miller to ship his bran to other less fortunate localities, where they are compelled by existing conditions to purchase the protein necessary in the feed of their cows. The people engaged in the dairy business should be encouraged and edu - cated by numerous institutes, and by frequent local meetings of those interested, in discussing the feeds and the care of cows, and the various and successful ways of the different people engaged in the production of milk and butter. "Push the man behind the cow;" teach him how to buy the best 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 that he may learn to breed better. Have him aim high that he may receive six thousand pounds of milk and three hun- dred pounds of butter, or more, per year, from each cow in his herd. Have him work, plan and push his business, and while he may not become a Rockefeller, he has enriched his land, increased it in value, has a happy home, rests under his own "vine and fig tree" and is the most independent man in our free and independent country. The President: The next in order on our program is the report of the secretary and treasurer, Mr. S. C. Bassett. SECRETARY'S REPORT. To the officers and members of the Nebraska Dairymen's 'ciation : I herewith transmit the following report as Treasurer of this Association for the year ending Dec. 31, 1903. S. C. BASSETT, Treasurer RECEIPTS. Jan 1. To cash on hand $ 25 28 Jan. 23. To cash membership fees 38 00 State appropriation 361 00 May 23. State appropriation 225 00 Apr. 3. State appropriation 261 93 Sept. 30. State appropriation 125 00 Sept. 30. State appropriation 27 00 Dec. 31. By deficiency 60 Total ..$1,06381 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 EXPENDITURES. Tan. 22. By paid W. D. Collyer, judge of butter exhibit $ 35 00 Jan. 22. By paid A. S. Enyeart, expenses to de- liver address i 4=; Jan. 22. By paid T. L. Haecker, expenses to de- liver address 29 60 Jan. 22. By paid Mrs. F. R. Lott, expenses to deliver address Jan. 22. By paid A. J. Glover, expenses to de- liver address 9 65 Jan. 22. By paid E. Sudendorf, sweepstakes medal 15 00 Jan. 22. By paid J. W. Uhl, services in charge of exhibit 10 00 Jan. 22. By paid A. L. Haecker, telegrams .... 1 00 Jan. 22. By paid B. R. Stouffer, expenses attend- ing directors meeting 1 65 Jan. 22. By paid Samuel Hall, supplies 1 10 Jan. 27. By paid Whitehead &amp; Hoag Co., badges 16 00 Jan. 27. By paid F. D. Reed, programs, entry blanks and envelopes 11 Jan. 27. By paid J. C. Merrill, expenses attend- ing directors meetings, June 10, Oct. 8 and Jan. 23. .. . 15 65 Jan. 27. By paid Lindell hotel, entertainment of guests at annual meeting 17 75 Jan. 27. By paid J. E. Ferris, services as sten- ographer 4^ Jan. 2"j. By paid Ravenna Creamery Co., pre mium 12 40 Jan. 27. By paid R. K. Emily, premium 13 90 Jan. 27. By paid Beatrice Creamery Co., pre- mium 14 40 Jan. 27. By paid Malcolm Creamery, premium 12 90 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 NEBRASKA DAIRYJI \TIOX Jan. 27. Jan. 27. Jan. 27. By paid Schuyler Creamery, premium. . By paid Herbert Craven, premium .... By paid Adams Centre Creamery I5 9O 13 4O Jan. 27. an. 27. Jan. 27. Jan. 27. Jan. 27. Jan. 27. Jan. 27. Jan. 9. Jan. ,6. Jan. 19. %, I: May. 16. June 6. May 16. May 16. premium 16 90 By paid August Leader, premium .... By paid J. K. Honeywell, premium . . . By paid Thos. Uhlang, premium .... By paid H. C. Glissman, premium .... By paid J. S. Temple, premium By paid Mrs. F. R. Lott, premium .... By paid A. F. Hartwell, premium .... By paid J. N. Ashburn, expenses to de- liver address ! 11 40 By paid Pacific Express Company, ex- press 4S By paid Pacific Express Company, ex- press *5 By paid telegram, W. D. Collyer By paid U. S. Express Company, ex- " press 7° By paid Benton &amp; Benton, printing . . 375 By paid Benton &amp; Benton, packing and shipping reports By paid S. C. Bassett, salary as secretary from July i, 1902, to March 1, 1903. By paid E. S. Harte, agent, freight on reports By paid Benton &amp; Benton, printing re- ports F. D. Reed, stationery and printing . . . :: 225 00 261 93 475 By salary as secretary from March 1, 1903, to April 1, 1903 By paid W. A. Rodgers, P. M., postage stamps By paid S. C. Bassett, salary as secre- tary from April 1, 1903, to Sept. 1, :: I9O3 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">21 NINETEENTH IIoN Sept. 30. W. A. Rodgers, P. M., postage from \pril i. 1903, to Sept. 1, 1903 27 00 Total $1,063 81 It was moved and carried that the report with the accom- panying vouchers be referred to a committee of three to report later on during the meeting. The president appointed as such committee Messrs. H C. Glissman of Omaha, F. C. Stillson of York, and J. C. Merrill of Sutton. Later the Auditing committee submitted the following report which was accepted and adopted. REPORT OF AUDITING COMMITTEE. To the Nebraska Dairxmoi's Association : We, the undersigned, to whom was referred the repor; of the Treasurer, find the same to be correct, and the items of expenditure proper in carrying on the work of the Associa- Hexry C. Glissman. Fred C. Stillson, J. C. Merrill, Committee. ADDRESS BY S. C. BASSETT. Mr. President and members of the Nebraska Da men's Association : — It has been customary for the Secretary Kake a report and I should have written it perhaps, but I make it verbally and let the stenographer take what I to say. Statistics in regard to any industry in this state, as you all know, are largely guess-work. I will not say the merest guess-work. We have certain foundations to start with, but in the end. we have to do some guessing. Of course, we have as a basis the government census, which is taken once in ten years, but there is considerable guess-work even in census re- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 turns. There are a great many farmers who, when the cen - sus enumerator comes to one of their houses and asks him as to the income from the farm, asks him perhaps how much butter his cows have produced, is at a loss to tell him just how much it amounts to. He has kept no record of it at all. He guesses at it. Of course if he has sold to the creamery so many pounds of cream or so many pounds of butter fat, that is a different item. But as to how much has been used on the farm, he guesses at that. If he is asked how many eggs he lias sold during the year, he might tell how many have been sold, but not one in a hundred can tell how many have been produced. And so it is in regard to all statistics pertaining to products of the farm. To secure from month to month, information as to the farm products, the U. S. Department of Agriculture has as its reporters, persons in every county and in fact at most townships in each state. There are a great number of these reporters in this state and each year at the beginning of the year each reporter is asked to make an estimate as to how many milch cows there are in his locality as compared with 1902, we will say. If he thinks there has been an in - crease, of say ten per cent perhaps, or five per cent- 1 — whatever in his judgment the increase has been, he so states. Or if a decrease, he so reports. Now you will note that if you should make an estimate for your locality, you must to some extent guess at it. You could not go around and count ex - and so there is a great deal of guess-work with it. Still the census returns and the reports based upon these returns are the most accurate information we have. ■ &gt;w just what increase in the dairy industry, the past year there has been in this state, we can not say definitely, but there are certain things that indicate in regard to it. If we take the United States census returns for the year 1880, they I that we had an average of 2. 1 milch cows to the square mile in this state. In 1890 the government census gave us an average of 6.6 mulch cows per square mile, and the latest </seg>
            <seg id="p024">23 MS! returns I have seen from the U. S. Department of Agricul - ture in regard to the number of mile! \ the state would give us an average of 8.5 milch mre mik does not mean there are necessarily that many more cows in the state, but you understand that in the xapid development of the dairy industry in the last few years a great many cows are being milked and can be termed milch cows that before that time were what we termed stock cattle, and are now enumerated under the head of milch cows, and we would have perhaps a less number under the head of "other cattle." The number of milch cows in the stan en in the ical returns of the Department of Agriculture on January 1, 1904, is 649,839, an average of 8.5 per square mile, and their value is given as Si 7,240,229. In the ! census returns for 1900, we find that the value of the dairy products average to the cow,— to be exact I think any of you will concede that is a very conservative ite, that a cow produces $16.60 worth of dairy products in a vear. We will however take that as a basis, and on that basis the value of our dairy products from this number of cows for the year 1903 would be $10,789,327. Now while this is somewhat of guess-work, these figures yet plainly indi - cate the growth of the dairy industry in the state. The manager of a prominent creamery in this state, one of the largest, informs me that the legitimate increase of their business would be 70 per cent for the year 1903 as with the previous year. Much of this rapid increase is due to the use of hanc separators in this state. I do not know whether we exceec in number, in this state, those used in Kansas, but in this section, Nebraska and Kansas, hand separators are much more largely used than in any other locality in the Unite&lt; 6 The I Department of Agriculture has il agent to investigate the condition in Nebraska rd to the hand separ &lt;tem and that gentle </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 NEBRASKA DAIRY V \TIOX man has prepared his report within the last few days. We had requested his attendance at this meeting, but the Secre - tary of Agriculture wrote that it was impossible to spare him at this time. In the use of hand separators, while we greatly increase the profit* to the individual dairyman, because he saves a great deal of what he heretofore wasted, we are liable to produce not so good a quality of cream and consequently not so good a quality of butter. This has occasioned a great deal of concern among creamery men. those who manufac - ture butter, because, of course, upon the quality of the cream purchased depends th*e quality of the butter manufactured. Now I take this position that a creamery company must have a certain amount of profit out of the business to pay the expenses of the business, and a profit to those engaged in it. That portion must come out of the gross receipts. No matter what they receive for the butter produced, they must have about the same profit out of the business, and their expenses are the same, whether their butter brings the high - est price in the market or the lowest. I think this is a fair proposition that when the company has received a sufficient amount from the sales of butter, to pay the expenses of manu - facturing, maintaining the plant and the profits of the busi - ness, that any additional profit inures largely to the men from whom they purchased the cream or butter fat. Con - sequently the better the quality of the butter fat that the dairy - man sells to the creamery company, the better the quality of the butter which they can manufacture, the higher the price they will receive and the better price they can afford to pay the dairyman for cream. tit is too often the case that the dairyman thinks "Well n't cut much of a figure in this business anyway and so 11 just simply unload onto those people the most I can be done with it:" and perhaps it doesn't cut much of a e, the little that he sells them, but it is the littles that : the much, and a small amount of inferior cream placed </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            
            <seg id="p027">25 NISETKKNTII ANN &lt;TIOX with some that is superior makes it all inferior. And while there might be perhaps a dozen dairymen that bring in their cream to the central receiving place to be shipped, and it is all good except one — the whole is injured thereby, so that it is necessary that every one take pains in that respect; that one furnish the best and when he is doing that, he is not only helping himself but he is helping all the rest of the patrons to receive a better price for their cream. So I think you want to take this broad-minded view of it, that if you can increase the value of the product, you are increasing the price that you will receive for it. Competition is all right, and is "the life of business," but sometimes even competition works an injury. I know of an instance up in our locality — there are three places where they buy cream, and some cream was brought in one day that one agent refused to receive. It was worthless for butter purposes. He could not afford to buy it and he told the man so. The boy it home and the father came in and said, "You must take this cream. You have got to take it." He said, "I will not take it. It is of no value to my people. I could not ship it and I don't see why we should pay you money for something that is of no use." The man took it over to another agent who bought it and paid him for it. That second agent al committed a crime. He not only injured his own company, but he indirectly injured those who produce cream t That man should have been taught that that cream had no value and that he should bring better cream if he expected it to be received. I am urging that point because it is of great importance to all dairymen. There is another point I wish to mention, because we have a great many young men with us here today and I am greatly pleased to see them. If I were going to take my choice, I was going to say, I would rather have the young men in our dairy convention than the old men, because the young men are beginners in this bus id they can be interested </seg>
            <seg id="p028">26 KF.BH in new and improved methods, but the older men generally i a rut and dislike to chai The young men can easily become the nucleus of better methods in the business in their locality. The fact that you have come down here to I igate these matters and to study, will lead the people in your locality to think that you know more about it. You ought to know more about it. Whatever you may say will have more influence and you can be a great help in the development of this industry. You can do this work much better than older persons. And so I mention this matter to you. There is as much of value to a state in getting a good reputation as there is to an individual. I suppose that it is a fact that to-day Minnesota butter is more highly prized by many people largely on account of the reputation which that state has secured in this respect. There are a great many peo - ple buying butter that do not know good butter when they buy it. That is, they can not distinguish in regard to the fine points between the higher grades of butter and some not so good. But if they knew that a certain creamery or a certain locality or a certain state has the reputation for market - ing a desirable grade of butter, they would prefer that grade. This is natural. You and I would do the same thing. If a certain brand of butter is popular and we wish to buy, we 1 prefer that brand. We would take pleasure in saying to people, we use that brand, whatever it was. There is a great deal in popularity — there is a great deal in acquiring a good reputation and when we help our own state acquire a good reputation for good butter, we are helping ourselves. tNow let me give you just a little comparison as to the rtance of the dairy industry in this state. From the census ns, that of 1900, we learn that of animals sold, the value $49,022,404; Corn, $51,251,213; Wheat, $11,877,347: $ XI '333.393; Hay and forage, $11,230,901 ; Dairy ucts (milk, butter and cheese), $8,595,408. That a basis of about 512,544 cows in this state, whereas, </seg>
            <seg id="p029">27 we have at this date, 649,839; Poultry and Eggs, $7,567,046; Animals slaughtered on the farm, $4,508,457; Potatoes, $1,734,666. Now the value of animal products sold was in round numbers, $70,227,060 and 13 per cent of that amount was dairy products. It ble if we make this business profitable, and if we look after the details of this business it will be profitable, that instead of being 13 per cent of the value of our animal products in a year, it will be 20 per cent or 25 per cent, and this is one of the purposes of this meeting, to collect these thoughts and present them and thus distribute them throughout the state. I do not know as I have anything further to say at this time. Mr. President, ■plause) The President: The next paper on our program at this time is entitled "How to Care for the Dairy Cow," b; L. D. Stillson of York, who will now address you. Mr. Stillson : Mr. President and Gentlemen, may I tell you a story first? I want to tell this story to emphasize one thing Mr. Bassett has said in regard to the cleanliness and the work of the dairyman in preparing cream and taking it to the creamery. Now in China there is no compulsory education. Ev - thing is absolutely free for a child, but if the child does not want to go to school he is taken up before the town council and whipped ; and then if he does not want to go to school his father is taken up before the town council and whipped ; and then if the boy does not want to go to school all the neigh - bors are taken up and whipped by the town council. Now what has that got to do with you Nebraska Dairymen? I want to say to you just this: that if there is a man in your community that is producing a dirty article in the dairy business you are all whipped. It is just as much to your interest to see what your neighbor is doing in this </seg>
            <seg id="p030">28 NEBRASKA DAIRY\ \TION ft as it is in China for the people to know that the other boy is going to school. If he does not go to school whipped. And if your neighbors don't produce a good article you are all whipped through the pocket book. Mr. Bassett, in fixing up the program here, has seen fit to put me on for a paper. Now he knew very well that if he had to let me get up and talk I would do just like we used to when he and I went out on institute work together. We used to hold the watch on each other and if we were talking too long, we would step on each other's toes or pull each other's coat tail. So he did not want to pull my coat tail for fear it would embarrass me and therefore he asked me to write a paper. That is very hard for me to do because I can hardly read my own writing when it gets cold. If I make a bad effort to read what I have written, please excuse me. My style is in answering questions more than in the line of an address or a paper. However, I will read, or at least try to read the paper which I have written and then answer your questions afterwards, if I can. I have gotten old enough so that I am not ashamed to say I can not do a thing if I can not. HOW TO CARE FOR THE DAIRY COW. Bv L. D. Stillson. Dairying, or the system of making money from the milk and cream of the cow, is based upon her maternity. Man, by appropriating the milk of the cow, designed by nature for the preservation and growth of the calf, is using to his advan - tage the motherhood of the cow, and to make her yield greater quantities of milk richer in cream is his greatest aim. In so doing, by breeding and feeding, he is making her more or less -«i artificial creature. ■ Successful dairying upon the proper recognition of this and so caring for the cow as to make her produce the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">29 greatest amount of human food at the least possible cost, and still keep our machine (the cow) in the best possible condi - tion, should be the aim of every true dairyman. The cow has a different system of converting her food into human food than her big brother, the beef steer. The steer converts his food into fat and places it in layers just under the skin, and between the fibers of his body, storing jt up to be used as fuel if need be, or to be sold as beef when his carcass goes to market. The dairy cow will eat heartily of the food we give her, not to create fat to store upon her own body, but to secrete milk for the maintenance of the calf. Food given her at night will be digested and be converted into milk ready for the youngster's breakfast. By her pro - cess of assimilation, she converts our cheap forage into a highly nutritious human food cheaper than the beef steer. The condition of the dairy cow is such by her system being so relaxed by the annual production of a calf, and furth - er by the daily drain upon her for milk, that she must be cared for as to best withstand the changes of weather, espec - ially in winter. To be most profitable and to yield whole - some milk she must be comfortably housed in a well lighted and well ventilated building where the temperature never falls to freezing. Here she should be as well taken care of as possible for on her comfort depends in a large measure the owner's profit. Her stall should be kept clean and well bedded so as to keep our cow clean. She should have plenty of fresh water and never ice cold, or she will take some of her butter fat to heat it with. We must recollect that our cow is an artificial creature which takes our rough feeds and transforms them into a palatable finished product, so that we must see that she has plenty of raw material with which to do our work. She must be fed and watered regutorly so that she will not waste time and energy worrying when her next feed will come. She should always be treated with kindness. The </seg>
            <seg id="p032">30 NEBRASKA 1&gt;\IR\ VTION dairyman should never curry the cow with the pitch fork nor pound the milk out of her with a milk stool. When - ever the attendant is in a swearing mood he is not a fit com - panion for the dairy cow and he should at once "go back and sit down" until he is in a better humor. He should never swear in the cow stable any more than in the kitchen in the presence of his wife. There are nlany men who still follow the old time custom of having all their cows fresh in the spring. In our own work we find that we can secure at least iooo pounds more milk per cow per year by having them fresh in September or October. We can then carry a good flow of milk through the winter and into the spring with its green feed giving a very even flow nine or ten months, then a much needed rest just when the hot weather, flies and short pastures cut the milk flow most. As to feeds and how to feed, each should study a little for himself. If we are after the greatest flow of milk, irre - spective of cost, we would say wet or steam all dry forage and grind all grains. It is a matter of doubt to us as to whether it pays to grind the grain for a healthy active cow, although the flow may not be quite so large. The cow has a good sized dinner basket and we prefer to only feed twice each day, leaving her free to rest and re - chew her food already given. She soon learns when to expect her food and is content until near that time. As to her care before calving, her food should be some - what reduced in quantity and of a cooling, laxative nature. Roots, silage, alfalfa hay and shredded corn fodder are excellent for roughage, while oats, bran or a little oil meal are good concentrates. After calving only tepid water should be given for at least a couple of days. Keep her in a dry, warm box stall and see that she gets no sudden chill for .several days. YY hf^Tl ttif* flA 1 T*VTT1?1T1 mSIS COtltf* t"O t"f"l^ f^YTtf^tiQP C\T tf^OWC </seg>
            <seg id="p033">31 stables, land, utensils, etc., for dairy work, he must keep one principle well in mind : That about 60 pei cent of all the feed the cow can eat goes to her maintenance and that he must make his profit on the balance of what she eats. With this in mind he can very readily see that he must be liberal with his feed if he would make the most from his in - vestment. He should watch his feeding very carefully and know of a certainty that he is feeding all that his cow will stand. By carefully weighing his milk at every milking, then by accurately measuring or weighing his feed, he can increase his feed just so long as there is a corresponding increase in milk, but watch closely the danger point of over feeding and drop off a little. He will soon surprise himself with results. One-half the Nebraska cows are star boarders. Some from natural tendencies, others from want of proper care and feed. An old saying is, "A good dairyman always has good cows." In this there is a great deal of truth for it indicates good care, good feeding and careful selection. ■ Many of us call ourselves dairymen when in fact we ve not yet left the kindergarten style. Because we own some cows and milk twice each day, look wise and let our wives take a little butter to the store to trade for tea, coffee and tobacco, we are not dairymen. "This world do move," and the dairyman must move with the rest. He must keep step to the music and be wi'ling Ie a learner. He should mark progress on his stable door, out of the rut and study well his care of the cow aiid surroundings. Learn what to feed and how to grow her at the cheapest price possible. Balance her ration with ns, salt with common sense and season with kindness. Then and not till then will he be on the best road to success. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">32 \ DAIRY V ITION DISCUSSION. Mr. Depeel: I would like to ask what would be your preference about handling cows in the stable. Would it be by stanchions, with a trough behind them in order to keep them clean, or how do you manage? Mr. Stillson : Our stalls are all stanchions, with • a trough behind and well bedded. Mr. Depeel : Do you think you need bran and oil meal where you have all the alfaPfa the cow can eat? (Mr. Stillson : No. In our work, we have discarded entirely, but since we have been raising alfalfa, we find peated weighing we can produce milk just as well with a. We have substituted alfalfa for bran entirely in our Mr. Haskell: Do you feed any corn in that connec tion? KMr. Stillson : Yes, we are feeding some corn and stalks. Mr. Depeel: Just one other question in regard to the stanchions : Is it a detriment to the cow to keep her in a. stanchion over night, or would she do better if she was tied with a rope so she could have more freedom? I Mr. Stillson : It might be and I would not say it Id not be, but we are practicing that method and have : that for a good many years. Forty years of my life ve spent in the cow work and that has been our system &gt;st invariably. We used to use a chain with a post ding up by the manger and a chain around the neck, we discarded that because it took too much room and i in Nebraska we want to look after carefully. But our i never did any better in that condition than with the :hion, that is, we never could discover any difference. ■Mr. Depeel: Then by keeping them close in the hion it keeps them from working backwards and for - s and keeps them cleaner. </seg>
            <seg id="p035"/>
           
            <seg id="p036">33 Mr. Stii. The chain would work just as well in that respect, but if you have cows with horns they will be hooking the next ones to them unless you have a good deal of room and very wide stalls. The chain will keep them as clean as the stanchion because if the drop is deep enough and back of them they will not step back or Mr. Depeel : Now in regard to feeding : We are grinding corn and cob and feeding that with alfalfa hay. Would you think anything else would be necessary in order to get a better flow of milk? Mr. Stillson: What is your roughage: Mr. Depeel: Alfalfa hay. Mr. Stillson : Entirelv Mr. Depeel: Yes. Mr. Stillson: I would as soon have say two-thirds alfalfa and one-third shredded corn fodder as all alfalfa hay. Alfalfa hay itself and the corn you are feeding is a very heavy protein ration and I should think you could make a better ration by substituting something else for a part of that heavy feed. Mr. Depeel: How would sorghum hay do? Mr. Stillson : Sorghum hay I am sure I cannot tell you about, because I have never fed it very much. We have fed it some, but only as a late summer feed, or something like that, or as a cured feed for the winter. There are a great many theories and when you ask me to give my opinion, I don't care to talk theory at all. I would rather tell you what we are doing. But we have not made a success so far with sorghum as a cow feed, that is, not to any great extent. Mr. Dodge: You spoke about a silo: Is it necessary to silo when you have alfalfa or clover? ■ Mr. Stillson : The silo is the cheapest place you can corn fodder and make a good feed out of it, but with your alfalfa you are getting a very heavy feed of protein, the same t </seg>
            <seg id="p037">34 • DAIRY* \TICX as this gentleman here. You are getting too much of it rather and the cow is wasting a part of the protein in order to get another of the ingredients of feed to do the proper work. In the northwest part of this state that same question came up, that is in Scotts Bluff county. A lady said, "I have always had the best success when I have allowed the cows to eat all the corn fodder they want and then feed them all the alfalfa hay they would eat." She said invariably they had enough good results to let the old cow eat between the corn fodder and alfalfa ; that they brought better results than when they were confined on alfalfa alone. I think you will find that true of alfalfa, that it has too much protein for the best results from the cows, because it is too fattening. RMr. A. S. Hitchcock: In regard to the care of the and neatness: About a year and a half ago I had oc - on to visit Holland for another purpose than studying dairy cows, and I was greatly impressed by the way they cared for the dairy cows in that country. I entered Holland in the fall of the year and, as you know, Holland is qne of the greatest dairy countries of Europe, chiefly on account of its very excellent pasturage that they are able to produce there. The first thing that attracted my attention beside the excellent pastures, was that all the cows were covered with coats, that is with pieces of canvas or very thick cloth tied over their backs and fastened about them. I was told that was to keep them from chilling. Now when they take so much care as that to cover each cow carefully to prevent their chilling during the day, they are taking considerable care of t Again the dairy stables are as neat as it is possible to : them. They are just as neat as our dairies are here in country. You will go into one of those cattle stables e the cows stay during the night and everything is per - y clean. There is no odor of any kind. It is often likely the barn is at one end of the house. It will be one build- </seg>
            <seg id="p038">35 X1SKTKKN Til ing — the living portion is in one end and the barn in the other end. And just another point I noticed, while you were speak - ing about keeping the cows in stalls : The fact is there they have a provision for keeping the tail clean. There is a rope or cord that hangs from the roof or ceiling of the stable and when the cow is brought into the stall there is a loop in the rope that is tied around the end of the tail. While the cow is standing up she is able to use the tail in the normal way. but when she lies down the rope is of the right length so that it keeps the tail up from the floor and in that way there is no way of getting the tail dirty. Mr. D. P. Ashburn : There is one idea that Mr. Hitchcock brings out that cannot be too strongly impressed upon every person who is milking a cow ; that is the blanket to prevent a sudden chill. That a day like to-day, if any man will experiment by taking samples of his milk to-night, if he lets his cow run out through the day, and then taking a sample to-night, he will find he has lost butter fat from the chill that the cow has received during such a day in this cold winter. These Hollanders understand this exactly. PThe matter of cleanliness, too, is something that should attended to a great deal more than it is; and here is an - £r point in regard to the hand separators and that is, the 1 separators ought to make the best butter to be made, use, if a man is careful of his cream after il is separated, he takes the cream from the milk before it is tainted from the dirt that gets into the milk from the milking. Still there is that question of cleanliness after the cream has been separ - ated that is a factor in making good butter and it should be so handled that it is made from clean cream soon after having it separated from the milk, right after milking and before it is tainted from the dirt that gets into the milk during the milking process. The President: We will now listen to a paper by </seg>
            <seg id="p039">36 Henry C. Glissman, of Omaha, on the subject, "How to Feed the Dairy Cow." Mr. Glissman : It is with no little embarassment that I appear before you to-day, because it seems to me that older heads should have filled the place on the program, but never - theless, in what I have written here, I have expressed merely a few personal opinions, and to say the least they will be open to criticism. In the assignment of our topics, Mr. Still - son and I were put pretty close together and I think therefore either in my paper I have encroached upon his subject or he has on mine; so I think you will find a great deal of repeti - tion in my paper of what Mr. Stillson has said. HOW TO FEED THE DAIRY COW. After having incurred the expense necessary to operate a dairy, in the purchase of lands, buildings and cows, comes the question, how shall the dairy cows be fed to yield a profit - able amount of milk. I The profit of the dairy depends, in the greatest measure, the best use of the materials consumed in the business, no one formula could be given that would be applicable guide for feeding a herd of cows, coming fresh at all » of the year, and kept according to the locality, under rent conditions. In fact, I believe that feeding by rule •t so much in vogue to-day as it was a few years ago, i nearly everybody who gave the feeding of the dairy a second thought, was rather blindly following the I standards. Those standards no doubt served a good purpose. They set the higher class of dairymen to thinking and experiment - ing. Yet I deem that the proper feeding of dairy cows is yet very far from being an exact science and probably will never become such, largely because of the individuality of each cow. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">37 NINETEENTH AXXl'AI The cow is very often compared to the steam boiler, which I hold as a very good comparison, inasmuch as both are of no great benefit to man, unless given his personal at - tention and care. With a steam boiler, it is known that a careful, intelli - gent and attentive fireman will get much more and better service from a given amount of fuel than an indifferent and inattentive one can get, although he may use fifty per cent more fuel. It might be perhaps more correct to say "waste" instead of "use" in this instance. If such differences occur with an insensate, man-made, iron apparatus, what may not be expected from the delicately sensitive and intelligent and warm-blooded dairy cow? To yield the greatest possible profit she must have kind and sym - pathetic care and attention, must be fed with reason and judgment on feeds graduated in quality and quantity accord - ing to her health and condition and the quantity and quality of the work expected of her. The knowledge of properly feeding a dairy cow can only be acquired by long continued and exact experiments and through the knowledge of the chemical analysis of the feed stuffs used. And it is only to be regretted that this knowledge is beyond the ability of the average dairyman to gather for himself. To investigate, experiment and report on these matters is the work of the chemist and the various experimental stations of this and other countries, who are able through scientific knowledge, combined with practical experience, to comprehend the exact value and bearing of such knowledge to the dairy industry. In fact, science with practice must be our motto,' and the basis upon which we must work to be able to reap the fullest profits out of our business, or in plainer words, we as dairymen and feeders of dairy cows, must use all the common sense at our disposal, combined with all the experience of others within our reach. I repeat : We as dairymen and feeders of dairy cows, must </seg>
            <seg id="p041">38 NKBBASKA [&gt;\IH\\ VTION use all the common sense at our disposal, combined with all the experience within our reach. In the feeding of dairy cows, there is perhaps no sub - ject that so often comes up for discussion as "the influence eed on the amount of butter fat in milk." This subject is not of recent origin, however, and has been thoroughly tested by the ablest authorities of our various experiment station's and individual dairy experts. The sum of their conclusions seeming to be that the fat content of milk cannot be raised by feed, at least not to any marked degree. Yet I believe that by long continued feeding of scant and unbal - anced rations, the fat contents of milk can be materially lowered. If a change is then made from a deficient to a normal or liberal ration, the fat contents of milk can again l&gt;e raised to the limit determined by the inherent qualities of the individual cow. So the dairyman, who wishes to im - prove the quality of his milk must look to the quality of the individual cow, rather than to the kind of feed she consumes. Within the breed or breeds, he must select those animals testing high in butter fat, and after securing such animals, he can reach the desired quantity of fat by supplying his cows with rations ample in quantity, rich in digestible com - ponents and altogether palatable and wholesome. Certain articles when eaten by cows give noxious odors or flavors to milk that are easily detected. Among the most common are onions, leeks, cabbage, turnips, green rye and sometimes rape. While I do not consider the above feeds, without perhaps the exception of green rye, very desirable cow feed, there may be times when some of these feeds can be fed at a profit and I will say that almost invariably they can be fed without pro - ducing any off flavors in the milk produced by having feeds of this variety consumed at least five hours before the next milking. Feeding directly after the morning milking is per - haps the best rule. Grass also has a marked effect on the flavor of butter produced in the spring, when the cows are </seg>
            <seg id="p042">39 rioN R changed from dry feed to pasture. This flavor is very jraily detected, but soon becomes unnoticed, but whether isappears or becomes unnoticed because of the familiarity brought about by daily use is an open question. The frequency of feeding dairy o in my mind, an unsettled question and will perhaps lemain so until the members of the human family agree on the nurnber of meals they require per day and the character of each. But judging from the digestive apparatus of the cow, I consider it un - necessary to feed many times a day. Two feeds of grain and hay, one in the morning and one in the evening, with I roughness to pick over during midday, has been my ce and generally satisfactory. At the morning and ig feed, the grain ration precedes the hay ration. The on of whether or not to feed while milking is an un - i one and one that I am not able to discuss as we at have never fed our cows while milking them. As to reparation of the ration for the dairy cow, I believe in eparing the feed that it can be readily masticated and ted. »\11 grains should be ground when fed and roots should liced, for I consider a cow giving a large flow of milk, rd worked animal and that all that can be done to ease task will be appreciated and well paid for in the amount of milk produced. I do not believe in feeding the grain ra - tions of cows wet or in a sloppy condition, for as a rule Er dry feed to that in a wet or sloppy condition. By ng dry feed the mangers are also kept in a more whole - condition and less work is incurred, which in most :s is no small item. Wherever cows are fed for milk or butter production, liberal feeding will pay, for we should not forget that about sixty per cent of all a cow eats is required to sustain her body and only after this amount is provided, can there be any re - turns to us in the way of milk. After the point of liberal </seg>
            <seg id="p043">40 NEBRASKA DAIRW ITION feeding has been reached, we must study the individuality of our cows. Some cows can profitably utilize more feed than others, and should be supplied with all the feed necessary to work their producing capacity to its limit or nearl This study of individuality in our cows is never ending and must be followed as long as we have cows under our care, for upon the respondence of the feeder to the individual needs of the cow the profit of the dairy in a large measure depends, or I might say individuality in both feeder and cow are requisite to profitable dairying. E Before closing my paper on this subject, let us together up the more important factors tending to the feeding dairy cow for profit. They are first, kind and sympa - c care and treatment; second, liberal but judicious feed - third, the constant' study of the individual cow; and last lot least, an energetic, attentive and observant feeder, who .11, an unselfish love for the dairy cow. DISCUSSION. ■ Mr. Stillson : Do you advocate only feeding twice a while the cow is confined in the barn? Mr. Glissman : That is of grain rations, I would feed onfy twice a day as I stated in my paper. She might have the liberty to pick over roughness in the middle of the day. If she is confined altogether a liberal feed of hay during the day is all right. Mr. Stillson : You would then give three feeds a day? Mr. Glissman : Three feeds, two of grain and one of Mr. Depeel : I want to know if you have ever fed close enough or have observed close enough to know whether it would pay to grind the feed ; for instance, if you had to pay </seg>
            <seg id="p044">41 NINETEENTH ANN five cents a bushel to grind the grain and the time it took for the farmer to take the grain to the mill to have it ground, and then pay five cents a bushel for the grinding, would it pay in the increased amount of milk that you would get? Mr. Gi .! I have never given the item of ground feed any thought, that is, of having it ground, because I have always ground our own feed and being in the eastern part of the state where the dairy business is carried on more extensively than in the west, we have found it paid to do so. Question* : What kind of feed do you grind ? Mr. Glissman: Corn. Corn forms the basis of the grain ration. Question : Corn and cob ? Mr. Glissman: Corn and cob might be all right, but I would prefer the corn, if bran is fed in connection with it. Where no bran is fed with it, as I understand it is in the ern part of the state. I think corn and cob meal would be a ben - efit. Corn would !&gt;e concentrative but we overcome this trouble by using bran in the eastern part of the state. Alfalfa with us is not grown very successfully, not until recent years. Depef.l: Don't you think conditions chang&lt; deal, for instance, if a farmer has hogs following o there will not be that amount of loss that there othe- would ? Mr. Glissman: Yes, I think locality would alter that to a great extent. Prof. Hixmax: You spoke of feeding during mak- ing or after milking, and I understood you to say you fed rr hay first and then grain. Mr. Glissman : No, grain. Mr. Depeel: Is sweet corn better than early dent for fodder? Mr. Glissman: Well. I don't know. With us, we did, several years ago, use sweet corn, but we found that the </seg>
            <seg id="p045">42 NEBRASKA DAIRY \ • E3n field corn gave us a greater amount of feed, but not of as good a quality, the quantity more than made the lack of quality. B Question : You think then by planting early dent, I d receive more returns? Mr. Glissman : Yes, sweet corn has naturally a smaller stalk and smaller ear and you don't get as many tons of rough - and a good deal more corn off of an acre of dent corn. I think the chemical analysis will show sweet corn is richer in feeding quality, but not enough to overcome the amount of gain by planting the field corn. Question : In grinding the cob, do you think the cob has any nutrition in it? E\1r. Glissmax : Xo, I would feed it only as feed, that lighten the feed on the stomach of the cow. I don't ier that the cob has any nutrition whatever. Mr. Clark: I would like to ask the gentleman if he is going to make corn the basis of his grain ration, if he does not think it would be economical to ensilage, cutting the corn and putting it in a silo and feeding silage instead of husking the corn and grinding it? Any man who is as extensive a dairy man as Mr. Glissman is. I think is behind the times a good many years, if he has not a silo. ■Mr. Glissman : I will admit that I am behind the ; then and I don't know a thing about ensilage, because I never had a silo. Question : It would not cost much to get up to the times and have a silo and if you once have one and find the benefits of it, you will never go back to feeding dry corn in the winter. IMr. Glissman : I will have to back off on this int. I am young and have not had the reins in my own s long enough to get onto all these things. Mr. Ashburn : The Secretary of this Association </seg>
            <seg id="p046">43 had a silo for several years and has quit it. Why did he quit it? Mr. Stillson : Because it did not pay. He'll be here however and tell you himself about it. Mr. Clark : I will say that in the old dairy states of the Union, silos are growing continuously. I think in this state they are quitting them, because it takes more labor. Labor on a farm is cheap and should not work against a silo. Prof. Hinmax: I hesitate somewhat to speak before men of your age, because of my own age, but I have had eight years of constant experience with two silos and know something of the care and feeding of silage. My home is in Central New York and while Mr. Ashburn is correct in saying the silo adds no feeding value to the corn, at the same time, the statement is misleading, because the corn loses from 23 to 25 per cent in curing and corn in the silo, count - ing the loss of the top of the silo when it is not covered. — and it is worth while to cover it, — loses no more than an av - erage of from 10 per cent to 13 per cent. These are figures taken from experiment station work. A Voice : You are speaking of New York conditions. You must remember that the loss here in the curing of corn in Nebraska is not as great as in New York. fPROF. Hixman: Yes. that might be, but the lo aska will not van- much from the loss in Iowa or Kan- The average I give you, of about 25 per cent, includes these states ; so that although the silo does not add anything to that it does conserve that amount to that extent. I will say that in traveling over the states of New York and Vermont in institute work I find that there is quite a difference of opinion in those states. We will take the Moulton Bros, of Vermont, who took the Grand Sweep- Es at the World's Fair for their butter ; they get from 50 I cents a pound for their butter in the city of Boston, are looked upon as the high men in the state of Ver- </seg>
            <seg id="p047">44 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S \TIOX mont. Those men have both silage and dry fodder and they feed about an equal amount of each. tMR. Stillson: Will you please tell us in what man - ;r you would handle the corn to obtain as much benefit om it as from the silo? A Voice: That would depend entirely upon your con - dition. If you have plenty of labor so that it is not difficult — nobody has plenty of labor — well then I would say our or - dinary way is equal to the silo. Mr. Stili-so.v : What is vour way ? I Prof. Hixman : fhe average way is for a man to his corn and husk it. We shred a great deal of ours, rut our corn with the binder and shred it, and then we I and feed it. Mr. Stillson : What per cent of loss do you get ? Prof. Hinman : Well, I cannot tell you the, exact fig - ures, I had them before me. but I can not carry them in my mind. We are considering just one side of a ration, when we are talking about corn. If we had no other feed than the corn itself, we might desire the succulence of it, and leave out the digestibility. One must have something to balance that ration anyway and I think alfalfa is the cheapest. I do are to enter into a discussion of the silo and to illus - trate the point whether we are going to get an increase out of the ensilage or not, on account of its succulent nature. We are going to find that out. The first half of this winter we have fed no silage ; we have had 25 tons of pretty well cured silage over in the new barn. Now when we go over there we are not going to start in on the silage; we will leave the cows in there a week or two and feed them as in the old barn and feed them dry feed so they will not shrink on account of the change. Then we are going to start in and feed silage. We have a herd there of about twenty-five cows in all stages of lactation and I believe we are going to get some information out of this. About four years ago I tried </seg>
            <seg id="p048">45 a little test and it was done for the purpose of determining the difference between sugar beets and mangolds an&gt; the test we carried on, we found the silage just a little bit bet - ter. It was so small 1 in amount that we determined the dif - ference to be between feeding silage and beets was small enough not to mention. But this is true; we know that not only from numerous tests but also from the number of prac - tical workers that the feeding of green succulent feed in the winter months is a very profitable thing and that it increases the quality of milk and acts as a cooling feed and assists in digestion. I believe that the silo is a coming feature in the Xow of course there are lots of men who have quit the silo. Where ever one fails it is held up as an awful ex - ample, but let me tell you that the silo has been coming West as emigration has been coming West. There is such a thing as not having to have a silo. There is such a thing as leav - ing thousands of good corn-stalks standing in the field There is such a thing as wasting lots of fodder, because we do not have to glean it. but we will have to do that and will find it economical to do it. I belice the silo is an economi - cal adjunct, not only to the dairyman, but to the feeders; that is coming, though it may not be here now. §Prof. Haecker: There are a lot of men in the West are very independent. There are a class of men we particularly in the short grass country where they say we do not have to grow any crop ; we do not have to put" up hay. I went up there last year and found that country cov - ered with ice and snow about two feet deep. We held a meeting that evening and the men came into the hall from all over the country there and wanted to hear all they could about the dairy business. The first time I went up there I got a cool reception when I tried to talk cows. They said they had to milk them on horseback and that was the only way they wanted to milk them. Now they have changed, their minds and they want to know the best way to milk </seg>
            <seg id="p049">46 them and they want to know very badly. Cattle were dying all over that country. Right here I desire to say that as far as leaving corn-stalks stand, that is something they can do but there is a time coming when they can not afford it. A Voice: Is not that time right here now? Prof. Haecker: Yes, I think so, to the first-class farmer. Mr. Clark : One remark I wish to make. The Pro - has illustrated the point very nicely indeed. A man coming here from the East is surprised in going through this country, to find the amount of corn fodder that is wast - ed here. If we are going into the dairy business, let us use the feed we have. Now to-day there is enough corn fodder going to waste in Nebraska alone to almost keep double the number of milk cows we are keeping, if properly cared for. There is no question about it. Because it is easier and you have lots of corn, and you want to let it go to waste and not use it, that does not signify good farming or good dairy - ing. Now a farmer has enough corn fodder going to waste to keep double the number of cows he does. That is a proposition we have to face in this country. We can raise a little bit of grain this year and make a big profit on it, but we have got to keep on increasing. tMR. Schlappi : The silo has been pretty well aired The difference between dry corn fodder and silage 'rofessor has explained very thoroughly. While he says is not had very great experience, he believes in the ex - nce of others. The chemist tells us there is a certain int of nutrient in corn. We all know that by putting in a silo that it does not add anything, but the cow is iest judge whether it does or does not put it in the form Rshe might appear to like it, is a different thing. I have as much experience in feeding silage and corn fodder aps as anyone present. The experiment was carried on very carefully. I refer to the Pan-American Exposition and </seg>
            <seg id="p050">47 NINETEENTH ANNUA1 IIoN the feeding of cattle in that dairy test. I bought all the corn for those cattle. We fed corn green. We ran it through a cutting box. We fed each cow just so much and no more, that is, I mean it was all weighed for them. When the time came we had a silo filled with corn and at the same time for about five days the overflow of that corn that we could not put into that silo we fed just the same as we did before. But as soon as we opened the silo, although the fermentation was not as complete as it is here at the state farm, yet we found that as soon as we began to feed the silage, though we did not feed any more in weight, we found an increased flow of milk at once, and that increase I think was something like five per cent over that from the corn — the same identical corn which was put into the silo. Now, we will admit that we cannot add anything by putting it into the silo, but there is a feature that does make it appear that there is something added. Now, what is it gentlemen? It is the better digestibility of the corn. The animal has to labor less to digest that predigested food than it would the raw material. That is about all I want to say in regard to the difference in the silage and corn food and the difference in the silage and the difference in the stalks as they stand out in the weather — there is no com - parison. The nutritive value of the stalks that stand out in the field is so small that it can hardly be considered. You may run your cattle out in the stalks, they may fill themselves up on those stalks, and you might just as well, in my opinion, feed them so much sawdust and expect to get nutriment and results out of it as to get it out of those stalks. The dreaded corn-stalk disease, I believe is nothing more or less than a starvation disease. Mr. Ashburn: I would like to say one word, gentle - men, in regard to ensilage. The first silo I ever saw built within 500 feet of where we are sitting at this time, </seg>
            <seg id="p051">48 XKBBA8KA DAIRY3 \ IloN ■that has been discarded. Now if the silo was such a good % to discard, what was the trouble? IProf. Haecker: The trouble was that the old silo built in the barn here, and was an experiment in its traction, and the consequence was they never could get [ silage. It was not a silo, really, it was a high bin. it was such a failure that it had to be given up. Mr. Depeel: I would like to ask in regard to shred - ed fodder; how do you protect that? Mr. Stillson : We put it in a good barn. Mr. Depeel: Will it not spoil? Mr. Stillson : No, not if properly handled Mr. Depeel: What is the proper way of handling it? Mr. Stillson : If shredded too early in the season be - fore it is thoroughly cured and it is stamped down, wherever you have a foot track, it will spoil, but if you put it in with w-stacker, it will not spoil or mould. The feed must be thoroughly cured. Don't wait until this time in the year to do your shredding, because it gets too badly weather-beat - en on the outside, and there is too much waste to it. Mr. Ashburn: I want to say this: who said the silo was a terrible thing? Who said anything against the silo? I have not. I say a silo is all right, and silage is all right, led it does not cost more than it is worth. I realize it and believe it is aM right to have it if you can afford it, but I cannot afford it. It is going to cost too much to get that little benefit that there is in it. I believe it is a good thing, but I want to say this : I don't think it is a fair definition of this question to compare silage with stalks out in the field. You are not going to waste a great deal between good silage and proper corn fodder. You don't need to put it in the barn to keep it. You don't have to come way out West to do it either. Go to Hebron and see the men stack - ing that shredded fodder down there and feeding it to the cattle and getting the best results. Because we don't be- </seg>
            <seg id="p052"/>
          
            <seg id="p053">49 SINETKCNTH \N&gt; in just the same things some other fellow believes in we need not have it compared with the most wasteful con - dition. It is not a fair distinction in this case. I believe the time will come, and believe Prof. Haecker has hit the nail on the head when he says that "when we come to more intense farming we will come to the silo." Now. take the average farmer throughout this state, the average man who milks cows throughout this state — what does he do? Does he make that a specialty? He does not. Nineteen-twen - tieths of the milk that comes from over the state comes from the beef type of cattle, and the large share of the work that they are after is the beef sule of ii .if that feed is not quite so succulent those am that feed and that will balance up the dairy side of this question. They should feed alfalfa and other foods that are rich in protein, and they can do it without the expense of the silo. I don't think we have come to the time in this state where we want the silo, that is, in the western or middle part of In regard to the increased milk that is coining from the ranges in this state, I think it is a God-send to this coun - try that we have low beef, with all due respect and kind re - gard for the cattlemen of this state. There is a very large interest that is going to waste in this state. An old neigh - bor of mine knowing something of my dairy work, came to me the other day and talked over the situation as to how he could milk ioo cows on the range and select them out of 500, that is, he wanted a start. He said, "The time has come when we have got to milk, and I am not the only one. There are hundreds of us in the same fix. "And I want to say to you that the low price of beef is going to redound to the lasting benefit of these cattlemen themselves. Dr. Thomas: In Nebraska it is a question of saving the fodder. Last year we raised in Nebraska 213,000,000 bushels of corn. Prof. Haecker tells us that the fodder is </seg>
            <seg id="p054">50 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN \TION worth from one-third to one-half the value of the corn. What is the corn worth? That corn, if it is worth but 25 cents a bushel, is worth how many millions of dollars? About $53, - 000,000. He says the corn fodder is worth from one-half to one-third; it would depend upon the time it is cut. If the corn is nearly ripe when you cut it, we have the forage and the grain. If we cut it to save that forage when our corn is in its best condition, your fodder then is worth one - third. If, as is done here in Nebraska, our corn is nipped by frost, at the time the frost hits it, it is worth a$ much as your corn, but if you let it stand there you have lost one - half your crop. SNow, let us go back to figures again — figures will not Suppose we take out one-third of the value of that crop orn in the fodder, if it is only one-third, that makes it th half the value of the corn. Now, take it this year, corn is worth 25 cents, that would be $26,000,000 wast - and that is the smallest crop that Nebraska has produced 3ur years. Now, we lose cattle on the stalks that we allow to stand. The stalks standing in the field, as this gentleman says, are of no more value than sawdust. It is wood! And the people know that when they turn their cattle out in those stalks, that is, many of our best men do. They might as well turn them loose on a wood pile. It is a very hazardous experiment. I received a letter a little while ago from the western part of the state, way out in Hayes county where some of you would think they did not raise corn. The gentleman said to me in the letter, "I have about 80 acres of corn-stalks, 50 head of cattle and 20 head of horses. I would like to tthem out in those stalks." He said, "My neighbor on south has turned his in and has lost half a dozen head; neighbor on the north has done the same thing, and I would like to have an expert sent out here to investigate </seg>
            <seg id="p055">51 the matter." He said, "If necessary, I will board the man free of cost and furnish him a horse, but," he said, "I want an indemnity for all losses." Here is the point: The question comes over and over again. What is this corn-stalk - disease? I have repeatedly brought that question up in arti - cles. It is indigestion, or, in other words, gastro interic ver- Prof. Hinman: If you will allow me, I want to make two or three points in connection with the silo. I have been in this state three years and I have heard from all over the state, "What are we going to do with soft corn?" We have got to feed it. This year to feed it is not profitable. I am told. If you have a silo, there is no question about being able to feed soft corn. You have a way to handle it. Then I want to speak of shredding corn; if you are going to shred your corn you have to have a machine and you have to have power. You will have to be handling it all the time. I will ask the gentlemen who are acquainted with the silo, if in their opinion, it really costs more labor to han - dle corn by the silo method than it does by the shredding method? If any one thinks it does, I would like to have him tell me about it. If the labor feature is taken away, we have reduced this question to the silo, because you have to have a shredder anyway. The silo will cost you less than two dollars a ton the first year and the silo will last for several Now the silo has gone out of use in some of the East - ern states, that is silos have gone out. I said I had eight years experience with a silo. That same silo is not in use now; not because silos are not good things, but because they were not properly built. We had a double-walled silo and had a dead wall between, but no ventilation to our silos and it rotted out, but it lasted about nine years. If the silo had been properly built, it would be in use to-day and that is the reason, in my opinion, that a good many of them have </seg>
            <seg id="p056">52 gone into disuse in the Eastern states. There was a time and I can remember it, when they said, "You cannot keep silage in anything but a stone silo." Then we tried mak - ing holes in the ground and using them, and then a wood - en silo. Now we have a stave silo. It is a building like a tank and it should last indefinitely. It can be bought of the manufacturer, who will guarantee his product and put up a silo holding one hundred and fifty tons, for less than $300.00. Now that is the cost of a silo, for one that will last ten years. That is thirty dollars a year for a silo that will hold one hundred and fifty tons. All experiment sta - tions, in silo feeding, have found that on an average you will increase the milk production ten per cent. If you increase the milk you increase the butter fat production, because if the cow is on full feed she is giving just as much butter fat on twenty pounds of milk as on ten pounds. If your cow is giving three hundred pounds of butter fat a year, I have cows here that are doing it and they are not fed any better than any other farmer in the state can feed, and I know of dairies in my own state that have that average for a number of years, — over three hundred pounds to the cow. Now an increase of ten per cent on that would be an increase of thirty pounds of butter fat. How much is that butter worth? It is worth about twenty cents per pound, I do not lcnow as it is worth just exactly that — then what is your thirty pounds worth? It will be worth about six dollars. I sub - mit to you gentlemen that six dollars of saving on the feed - ing from the silo will more than make up for the cost of the silo, or the cost of handling and the machinery and in - terest on your money and everything of that sort. Then I claim, and I think it can be borne out by the experience of the gentlemen present who know about silos, that the cost of the silo is a bugbear and has no existence in fact when com - pared with results. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">MNFTKENTH \W flOS 53 Mr. Ashburn: You say there is an increase of ten per cent? Prof. Hinman: Yes Mr. Ashburn : An increase of ten per cent over what kind of feed? Prof. Hinman : Over the same stalks handled in th« best manner of drying the stalks. Mr. Ashburn : We admit that, but suppose you don't have to feed these stalks to your cows and you have some other good feed that will take the place of that; what is your silo worth then, and what will be yotrr increase? Can you feed silage and make an increase over corn and alfalfa? Prof. Hinman : I believe you can, yes. I believe that twenty pounds of silage and twenty of alfalfa and corn will make you a ration that will give you better results than you can possibly get by feeding your alfalfa and your dry corn. I believe that is true. Mr. Ashburn : Well, I will say I cannot do it with my cows. Prof. Hinman : Without discussing the handling of corn there are other feeds that will doubtless give you as good results as from a silo. With corn handled in a better method than is handled ordinarily in Nebraska, you will get at least ten per cent increase. Now there is another point I wish to make and that is that the silo is not exclusively a dairyman's aid, that is, there is no animal on earth that will not eat silage. Hens Reat it, and it is a good thing for them ; hogs will eat ut it is not a good thing for fattening them, but a good thing for brood sows; your horse will eat it, Krially brood mares; your stock cattle will eat it, and a good thing for them. It puts them in a good thrifty ition so that when you put them on your grain for fat - g, they will make good gains. It can be used for other </seg>
            <seg id="p058">54 NEBRASKA DAIBYMEN'S ASSOCIATION things, and so I said it is not exclusively for a dairyman's use, but with the dairyman, you will find it most acceptable. Prof. O. Erf: I regret to interrupt this discussion, but I think I can give you a few data in regard to the cost of corn silage and corn fodder, or corn put up in shocks I will say, several years ago at the Illinois experiment sta - tion we carried on some tests in regard to the relative cost of corn fodder with the ears in the fodder. We found that from the time the corn is grown until it is put in the silo that corn cost forty-nine cents a ton. You can add your grinding to your fodder and you have your exact cost, com - pared with corn silage. I want to emphasize or corrobo rate the statement Prof. Haecker has made and also these gentlemen here in regard to the statement as to buildim; I think the key-note to the whole situation is in the building of a good silo. It was my good fortune in the year 1887 to attend the first silo convention that was ever held in Cleve - land, Ohio. I think the enthusiasm was so aroused that every member that attended that convention went home and built a silo. About three or four years afterwards I found all of those silos converted into ice houses. I wanted to know what the difficulty was. "Oh," they said, "corn silage was no good at all. Why, the butter men in Cleveland would not even take our butter." That was the statement. I know there was not a man in that community that would dream of building another silo, but times have changed, and to-day you go back and you will find most all those dairymen have silos. What was the trouble? The trouble was that they did not know how to build a silo. You must build a good silo in order to have good silage, to make a comparison whatever in the feeding value with corn fodder. They did not know how to handle the situation. They put in silage away along in August. You know silage put in at the best time, should be dry and corn should be as dry as you possibly can get it. I prefer putting it in </seg>
            <seg id="p059">NINKTKKXTII ANN 1 ION 55 very nearly dry and then watering it. Put the hose up in the silo and let the water run through. That turns out to be the best silage, l)ecause the sugar does not ferment as rapidly as in the corn silage. It makes a sweeter silage. For that same reason sorghum cannot be silaged, because it contains too much sugar, it turns the sugar into an acid and forms an acid condition. Mr. Nixon: I want to thank you for permission to call from these gentlemen the discussions that we have had. I know it was necessary that I should be very careful, be - cause I am twelve hundred miles from home and I have had a little experience and I know a little something about the silo. I would not like to go away from here and permit any impressions to get out that are erroneous, because I not"re there is an inquiry here upon the part of young men and farmers that shows that they are inclined to build silos, or at least they are considering the question. If you would not put your corn into a silo, what would you do with it : how would you handle it in order to get an equal return that you can get from, a silo ? You have seen that that question has not been answered very definitely. I want to have that question answered by my neighbors, because I am a Nebraska man as well as a New York man. I have silos in Nebraska and I have built two silos that would ho'd one hunderd and fifty tons each for $150, instead of $300 as was stated. It might be the question of building a silo and opening up a large field. I built two silos for $300 for the two; not $300 apiece, but $300 for the two and I also built one silo in this state for $500; it will hold from one hundred and fifty to two hundred tons. It is thirty-five feet deep and it is twenty-five feet around it. That is the most expensive silo that can be built and I might say the best. But the question of building silos is one that will take more time here than I care to consume and I would not want to open up any more discussion in regard to that. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">56 NEBRASKA DAIRT.M vMOX POf course you have lands here that are fast approaching value $100 an acre. You are in the corn belt. Now my Kds, all of us have been discussing the production of corn the best use to make of that corn. I don't see any other to get as good a return from the entire crop of the com thnn through the silo. T have five different dairies and Bve tried all methods that :rience. I have heard of, and that is mv Mr. Ashburn: What do you keep besides dairy cows? RMr. Nixon : Well we ipal business — it is the cows. raise dairy cows. That is our milking of cows and raising Mr. Ashburn: Do you have other stock? Mr. Nixon : No, not extensively. Mr. Ashburn: Then your condition is not like that of the average Nebraska man. If you put all your corn into silage, what do you have? !Mr. Nixon : First I want to answer a question of my g friend here, who spoke a little while ago of putting into the silo. If you are producing eighty acres of corn our farm, which a great many do, and it will perhaps ige ten or fifteen tons to the acre, and you build a [red and fifty ton silo and you are going to put up a 1 portion of that corn into the silo, and now what are going to do with the rest? These are suggestions only, i not trying to answer them, simply suggest them. Now if my friend can tell me of any better way that I can use my corn, than I can through the silo, I will adopt his plan. Also, in connection with the silo, I would fatten steers as I have done before in this state, but not at a great profit. The question is, on these high priced lands if we continue to produce, how can we get a fair return from them ? We cannot continue the business of keeping these lands and letting them go to waste, that is, of letting the stalks go to </seg>
            <seg id="p061">NINETEENTH \\N i (ON 57 Avaste. We must utilize them. Now how can we do it? If we put a corn harvester in and cut it when it is green, corn is not quite as marketable and it is a little difficult tr get it into the market in good shape. Mr. Ashbvrn: When your corn is ready to go into the silo, is it not readv to cut and shock? Answer: That depends a good deal. I have a great deal of respect for scientific investigation. The prof made a remark in which I do not entirely agree with him. The experiences of different fanners vary so much that it is hard to answer the question. The time thnt would suit me best to put the corn into the silo is just as it is entering the roasting r just as it is passing out of the roasting stage and beginning to harden. I don't want it soft and slushy. In New York state this year the trouble is not to get the com into the silo, but to grow the corn and get it into the silo. This year we waited until almost the first of October to get it into the svlo in order to give it a chance to grow. We had a backward season and when we put it in, we found the juice was running out of the corn to that ex - icnt that the silage is poor, as to what it ought to be. Xow we ought to have the corn hard and not to have stn excessive amount of juice. If it is too wet, it will not "keep properly in the silo. So to hit just the right condition of the corn as to whether it should be put in dry or whether — some will cut it and let it dry a week before putting it in : others wiTl cut it during a rain storm and put it in the silo when it is wet; others will throw water over it in order to give it more juice, etc. Now all of these matters are mat - ters of experiment, matters of result, which every man gets as compared with another. Science tells us a great many things, but we have to experiment and sometimes an experi - ment does a great deal of good and sometimes we are in a fog and do not know what to say. Of course there are so many different conditions. The seasons vary so much that </seg>
            <seg id="p062">58 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN ITIoK I: can be no iron-clad rule. A man must use good corn - sense in the matter of putting up silage as in any other of the work, but the more experience he has had, the : difficult he will find it to do these things every year do it properly. KMr. Ashburn : Probably the average man through - his state raises sixty acres of corn. How is he going it it in a sik&gt;? He can not do it. Then what is he to ith the balance? xswer : That is what I am here to-day to learn. That is why I asked you the question how you would use this corn if you don't have a silo. I cannot say to-day for the life of me. While I know the large value of corn is in the stalk you cannot get it, if you leave it in the field and let the cattle run into the stalks. I ask the same ques - tion, how will you use that? How will you utilize the bal - ance of the stalks? I cannot answer it. I am interested in your state and in the dairy business and I would like to learn a great many things I do not know. Prof. O. Erf : I ought to have made my statement a little clearer in regard to putting up corn sitage. I did not mean to say that corn should be absolutely dry, I Nke corn silage when the lower leaves are dry, that is, the corn in such a state that the lower leaves are dried up, the top of the husks on the ear of the com beginning to dry. In other words, it is just a little different stage from what these gentlemen told you. Now if you put up silage in this state without adding water, you are not going to have good corn silage, because there is a little mould that gets into it and makes it very unpalatable and sometimes makes it poison - ous ; but if you add water and thoroughly saturate it so that fermentation can set in in due time and kill the bacterial life, thereby preserving it, you will have good sweet corn silage. Bear this thing in mind, that you must add water. If you level up your silage, the tendency is in settling, that it will </seg>
            <seg id="p063">59 settle away from the walls toward the center; thereby you do not get the proper pressure against the silo and you lose a great deal; while if you keep the center high, so high that you can thoroughly mix the leaves in with the corn, then the pressure of the silage is out toward the silo walls. Mr. Ashburn : Now if you should fill in your silo with a blower, or, I don't care how you do it, If the center is high, does it not make it additionally that it not settle away from the wall? Answer : It will settle away. It will settle down toward the outside, but by having the center high it has a tendencv to settle down toward the outside. Mr. Ashburn: Then you would make it higher on the sides than in the center? Answer: Xo sir, higher in the center. I would al - ways have the corn silage at least three feet higher in the center than on the outside, because the tendency is then to squeeze it outward. If you have the center low and the out- Kiigh, it settles toward the center and spoils. This was ughly experimented with in Ohio a few years ago. I :d on the experiment myself. The idea was how to I ad the silage to get the best results. At that time we a long sack that ran from the carrier down to where silage was piled and we carried this sack around in the and the corn would fall down where ever we wanted it. result was, we had about a foot of waste on the outside, kept the silage level and kept the outside high. We had it a foot of space where it had settled away from the wall and it had spoiled all the way down to within six feet of the bottom. On the other hand when we let the sik&gt; fill itself, did not have anybody in it at all. we had fine silage in that silo; but we had corn on the outside and leaves in the center, which was an undesirable thing; so a happy medium of the two is the proper thing to do. You cannot </seg>
            <seg id="p064">60 NEBRASKA DAIRYM \TION tramp silage as well as you can let it setrKe of its own ac- Mr. Ashburn: My idea has been to tramp the silage next to the wall and let the center take care of itself. [Answer: That is my idea, to tighten it on the sides, lieve the shredder is the solution of what should be : with the balance of the corn that does not go into the I find by tracing it further that we have about one - ■ur corn taken care of in the silo, but no provision been made for the rest of it. The man who raises 60 5 of corn can take care of five, eight or ten acres of it le silo, but the balance of it is out in the cold. What is oing to do with that? It seems to me that the average ought to look out for his five-sixths rather than his one - or one-sixth. Mr. Ashburn : You would have to keep more steers or plant less corn. Prof. O. Erf : Yes, and more alfalfa. If you have to look out for five-sixths of it by some sort of machinery, it seems to me you are investing in too much machinery when there is such a little gain between the question of en - silage and the question of the shredded article and alfalfa with it. Prof. Hinman: One of the leading brands of cut - ters manufactured also has shredder knives that are placed on the knife head, and they cost very little, so you don't have to have a cutter and shredder both. AFTERNOON SESSION. The President: We will now listen to a paper en - titled "Some Things I Have Learned," by Mr. J. A. Harris of Shickley, Nebraska. Mr. Harris: I think they could have made a great </seg>
            <seg id="p065">61 deal better selection than I am for this subject. I am not an old dairyman. I have just started recently, but I think I have learned a great deal. There is one thing I have learned and that is that I did not know near as much about the dairy business when I started, as I thought I did and I deal yet to learn. SOME THINGS I HAVE LEARNED. First. That the dairy business can not lie learned in one day. one month, or one year, even if one &lt;1 all he can about the business. Reading about the dairy, and running the dairy are two different thin There are things we must practice, before we will learn them. Milk - e of the things: we become expert only by practice. One who can start and milk a steady gait, will have better results than the one that milks fast, then slow, then again. We must learn to milk a steady gait and as f l&gt;ossible for us. to keep it up till the cow is milked dry. Feeding is another thing we must experience before we can feed successfully. What each cow wants and the quan - -he wants, we must learn by actual practice. t Second. It is almost impossible to buy a number one cow : she is seldom, if ever, for sale and if she is for a friend or neighbor will get her. We can not tell the i of a dairy cow until we have milked her through one d of lactation and used the scales and tester in deter - ig the quantity and quality of her milk. She may have a perfect shaped body and udder, and yet be defective in some way. She may have the self-milking habit, a kicker, a breachy cow, or hold her milk and not let it come down as she should, or some other habit that would make her an unprofitable cow. The safest way is to raise the dairy herd" </seg>
            <seg id="p066">62 NEBRASKA I'AIin \TIOX by careful selection of dam and sire, and using only the very best milk strain to be had. t Third. I have learned that a cow will fail to yield nvner a profit on an empty stomach and the shady side barb wire fence for shelter. She must be satisfied with feed and shelter for twenty-four hours a 'day, seven a week and fifty-two weeks in a year, in order to be table. Comfort means profit with a cow. If she is ied she will not need an iron yoke or a crotch of a nwood limb to keep her from going through the fence. I Fourth. I have learned that keeping a record of each ; milk, of both quantity and quality, will promote bet - are and feeding, also promote better cows. The time ces to do this amounts to but very little and will detect obbers in the herd. t Fifth. I have learned in the past season that my cows ing in the pasture would fall off gradually for four or weeks, then after a good show they would go back to former yield per day. If I had supplied them with during that time, my profit would have been much ter. I Sixth. That it pays to get a good milk breed. They generally of a kinder disposition and when you feed a y cow, she will show it in the milk part and not in lay - on of flesh; with the half breed it is just the reverse. I Seventh. That it pays better to run a dairy without g. The cows are quieter. A dog that will nip their will cause kicky cows. The moment one touches the &gt; leg while milking, she will kick, thinking the dog is her. I used to think it was impossible to get along &gt;ut a dog to drive the cows with, but since we have been jut one the cows are so much quieter and the cows do &gt;ffer to kick. I have no fault to find with a dog for other Eighth. That it pays to keep the cows clean and also </seg>
            <seg id="p067">63 NINKTKKNTH . I [&lt; &gt;X the stable by having a floor of some kind and a gutter about six or eight inches deep and sixteen or eighteen inches wide behind the cows, it is then an easy matter to keep the cow and stable clean. The barn should be cleaned both morning and night ; also the heifer calf that is kept in a clean and drj place till she becomes a cow will not lie in filth if she can help it; also if a heifer calf is provided with clean water and not allowed to drink out of a mud puddle, it will l&gt;e hard to get her to drink filthy water. I have three Jersey cows and one heifer that were kept and raised in a pasture that had only a mud puddle for them to drink out of and after I got them they would drink out of a mud puddle before they would drink out of a tank, when none of the other cows would do this. Ninth. By feeding the cows after milking, the milk will not have any disagreeable odor from the feed we may give them. In my part of the country we are bothered very much with wild onions or garlic in the pasture, and for a few weeks in the spring we could hardly use either milk or butter, but when we take the cows out from the pasture three to four hours before milking, the smell of onions could not be detected in the milk or butter. Tenth. That sugar beets and sugar beet tops make very good feed but must be fed carefully or they will cause the milk to have a peculiar odor. Should not be fed heavy if cows are kept in the barn all the time on account of the strong odor they cause. Tops make much better feed if cured, but if fed very heavy it will take a long time to churn the cream. t Eleventh. I have learned that a calf given alfalfa hay xmi as it will eat it, wdll make a better calf than on any r roughness I ever fed. I have raised as good calves ;eparated skimmed milk, oil cake and alfalfa hay as can aised running with the cow. Oil cake and alfalfa hay cheaper than butter fat. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">64 v 1&gt;AIHY \ \ll&lt;&gt;\ E Twelfth. I have learned that it will take years to [ up a very good dairy herd and that we must be very ul in breeding and purchasing our herd. My plan in ing out would be to purchase good heifers just a little ■e they become fresh. By careful selection and care one mild up a good herd in a few years. Thirteenth. T have learned a great deal in the past year, no doubt have learned only what others in the dairy business have learned years ago, and I expect to learn a great deal more if I stay at the business. I intend to stay at it too. I find that it requires an attention every day, we have no days off: we do not have to wait till the end of the year for harvest : it comes every day : it is a very good teacher to teach one to tend strictly to business. When we work by the month or day and we lay off a day, one's pay stops too; we would lay off a great many days if we could lay off and draw pay too. In the dairy business if we neglect our work for one day, we do not only suffer loss for that day but for to come. I find it is a very good business for one that has a family growing up and can teach them to be industri - ous and helpful, but I have learned that I cannot tell the boys to go and do this or that, but when I am with the boys and say come and lets do this or that thing, we can accom - plish something and my wife and I expect to have a day off once in a while by and by and know that the work will not be neglected. It is an occupation that is healthy because you have the pure article for food; pure milk, pure butter and good veal and plenty of exercise, will make the doctor wish he had a few cows to milk. kit beats all the* drug establishments in the world f.or h; neither do we need drugs to keep the pure article t; we draw it fresh every twelve hours. What do you better? Mr. Stillson: I would rather leave the subject of sugar beet tops to Prof. Haecker. </seg>
            <seg id="p069"/>
           
            <seg id="p070">65 MNKTKKNTII I Prof. Haecker : This is a question I do not like to er at this time, because I do not know. I have heard ame complaint. There are several causes we lay to the ulties in churning. Of course we know there are a many different kinds of fat in butter fat. Certain fats iroduced, hard fats and soft fats. It may be that sugar beet is one of the feeds that produced a very hard fat. Hard &gt; difficult to churn. It does not' unite well. It may be in some way it affects the nature of the milk or the but - it globules themselves, but it does pot seem hardly pos - or it may be hat it does not. In the fall I get letters not only from people who feed sugar beet tops, but those who do not. It may be that they do not ripen their cream when it gets cold and their cream gets cold and they try to churn it cold. It may be that they do not have a thermometer and do not go according to rules in ripening the cream and churning it. It may be some of those things that is the cause. Perhaps Prof. Erf has some data on that. I know I have not. i D ROF. Erf: I do not think it is the universal com - . There are a few cases in which sugar beet tops been referred to as causing this condition, but it is not rsal. and the simplest reason that I can give, or can ute to hard churning, is that the sanitary feature has eeen taken care of. Sugar beet tops contain consider - ree sugar, which is apt to turn into carbon the cream and the swelling of the cream produces a period of churning. That is the only reason I can give. Mr. Stillson : What do you mean — increases the amount of butter fat? Prof. Erf: No. It inflates it with air. Mr. Stillsox: Why I asked this question was be - cause in the vicinity of Norfolk, I go there to the Farmers' Institute year after year and that same question comes up. I have never had a chance to ask a person wh6 could an- 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">66 \ DAIRW \riON" swer it, and that question has been raised in the neighbor - hood of sugar beet factories, where sugar beets are raised and I have never found any person who could give a reason Prof. Eef: I think if you will warm your cream and churn it in a reasonable temperature, say about 58 or 60, you will have ■• difficulty. Prof. Haecker : The time that you generally feed sugar beets is just before the time they go onto dry feed. Now the fact of the matter is, I have more complaint from people who do not feed sugar beets- than those who do and I have believed that it is as much that as anything else, that is, poor ripening of the cream, thin cream, cold ripening, cold temperature and churning in "advanced stages of lacta - tion and hard fat. Mr. Harris : Our experience has been this : We use a thermometer and when we feed sugar beet tops, it takes us from two to three hours to churn the cream and immedi - ately after we take the cows off the sugar beet tops, we can churn that same cream in from half an hour to an hour sooner and at the same temperature of cream as before. So there must be something in the sugar beet tops that causes Prof. Haecker: Was not your cream inflated, more or less? Mr. Harris: Perhaps it was. As soon as we quit feeding the tops, it stopped the trouble. KMr. Dodge: I have had some experience along this line and I laid it to the fact that too much of the tops fed at one time. I found when I would feed something to excess that it pretty near produced the same effect, came to the conclusion that we fed too much at the time. Prof. Lane: I was out to the college this fall and the professor was making an experiment on this very thing, </seg>
            <seg id="p072">67 NINETEENTH that is, the use of sugar beet tops as a feed for milk cows. I do not know when his report will be out, but he was mak - ing an experiment along that line. Prof. Clark of the State Agricultural College of Logan, Utah, was the party making the experiment. Mr. Brown (of Scotts Bluff) : We generally do not feed sugar beet tops, but I think we discovered the difficulty. In the fall of the year there is no trouble to keep the cream nicely and we let it keep cool until about twenty-four hours before churning. We found by keeping the cream in a E" rate temperature, say in a room from 65 to 70 de - , that it would ripen and we had no difficulty whatever, llowing it to remain cold for two or three days or forty - hours, we always had that difficulty in the fall of the Prof. Erf: I think you will find that is the universal complaint when you churn in the fall. The principal reason is this : the later part of the lactation period of the cow pro - duces a small fat globule in the milk. Now the smaller the fat globule, the slower it will rise, and the same inducement as in feeding dry feeds makes it still smaller; consequently, it makes it still slower to rise and you get very thin cream. You will also skim it thin and in churning thin cream, you will find you will have to raise your temperature in order to have it come at the same time. If you do not raise your tem - perature, you will churn for hours. So there you have the whole situation. It is the small fat globules and cold churn - ing and invariably at that time of the year you churn in a cold temperature, and you churn in a cold room. Mrs. Depeel: When I was only a girl there was no ttution for us to attend to learn anything of this nature. :n it came to the fall of the year, we had trouble that with our butter and we always put a little bit of salt - r in. Now can any of you tell us what effect that had t? It always brought the butter. In churning a batch </seg>
            <seg id="p073">68 En five to eight pounds, we would put a piece in of the size of a white bean and it always brought the but why I do not know. Prof. Erf: I am at a loss to explain that, unless it increased the specific gravity. Perhaps you put some warm water with it? BMrs. Depeel: Only a tablespoon full, not enough to t it. A Voice: I used to put in a hot horse shoe and the butter used to come for that Prof. Erf: Down in Pennsylvania we tried a little experiment There are quite a number of spiritualists there and I remember of one case where a man had a great deal of difficulty in churning cream; on one of these occa - sions a spiritualist came along and told him that the trouble was due to the spirits and he would have to kill the spirits in the cream before he could churn it into butter. He said that was an easy matter to do. He asked him to get a hot iron, which he did, and he doused it into the cream and he said, "Now do you hear those spirits sizzling in there? Now," he says, "that is not sufficient. We will have to try it over again." After he had tried it three or four times, the butter came and the man to whom this was demon - strated, said it was almost impossible to convert him to the idea that it was not due to the spirits. A Voice: How was the butter after they had warmed the spirits? Prof. Erf: I do not know. The President: We will now listen to an address by Prof. O. Erf of the Kansas Agricultural College, on the subject of "Selecting a Dairy Cow." Before reading his paper Prof. Erf spoke extemporan eously as follows: ■ Prof. Erf: It happened to be my privilege sometime to attend several of the eastern dairymen meetings, and </seg>
            <seg id="p074">69 NINETEENTH ANNIAI I frequently heard such remarks : "This is the way they do over in Nebraska and Kansas." It made me feel as though the whole world was looking toward these two states that are really the peers, I might say, in the dairy business. They are looking towards Nebraska and Kansas for the ad - vancement and for the modern methods of dairying. It pleases me greatly to know of this situation. The hand separator system has, no doubt, brought about this condi - tion. There were some states a few years ago which were opposed to and there probably are still some that object to the hand separator system. There are some states, and I know it is a fact, that the butter of certain manufacturers scores higher than that of Kanasas or Nebraska; but upon investi - gating the situation I find that in Kansas, and I think this is no doubt true in Nebraska, that the average score is 30 per cent above that of any other state. These two states are putting out a more uniform product, and when the United States wants butter it comes out here to these sunny cKmes, Kansas and Nebraska, to get a uniform quality? Now, while the methods of manufacturing have been pro - gressing the production side has been developing, but not at the rate that the manufacturing side has. We wonder why the cow, or the product of the cow, which is the foundation of the manufacturing business, has not developed more rapidly. It is simply because we have too many unprofitable cows. We do not know, or we do not understand the dairy business from the producing side. I cannot help but think that we are in the same situation as the little Jew who 'swallowed a five dollar gold piece, and all the doctors couM pump out of him with a stomach pump was $3.65. We are putting $5.00 worth of goods into too many of our cows, and only getting about $3.65 out of them. In the modern relation of the dairy fanner to the dairy cow we cannot help but think he has neg - lected his side of it. He is neglecting the bookkeeping fea - ture of it. He does not know what he is doing; that is the </seg>
            <seg id="p075">N EBRASK A Da En five to eight pounds, we would put a piece in of the size of a white bean and it always brought the but why I do not know. bPROF. Erf: I am at a loss to explain that, unless it ased the specific gravity. Perhaps you put some warm r with it? Mrs. Depeel: Only a tablespoon full, not enough to affect it. LA Voice: I used to put in a hot horse shoe and the tter used to come for that. Prof. Erf: Down in Pennsylvania we tried a little experiment There are quite a number of spiritualists there and I remember of one case where a man had a great deal of difficulty in churning cream; on one of these occa - sions a spiritualist came along and told him that the trouble was due to the spirits and he would have to kill the spirits in the cream before he could churn it into butter. He said that was an easy matter to do. He asked him to get a hot iron, which he did, and he doused it into the cream and he said, "Now do you hear those spirits sizzling in there? Now," he says, "that is not sufficient. We will have to try it over again." After he had tried it three or four times, the butter came and the man to whom this was demon - strated, said it was almost impossible to convert him to the idea that it was not due to the spirits. A Voice: How was the butter after they had warmed the spirits? Prof. Erf: I do not know. The President: We will now listen to an address by Prof. O. Erf of the Kansas Agricultural College, on the subject of "Selecting a Dairy Cow." K Before reading his paper Prof. Erf spoke extemporan - ly as follows: Prof. Erf: It happened to be my privilege sometime ago to attend several of the eastern dairymen meetings, and </seg>
            <seg id="p076">TEESTH ANN I frequently heard such remarks: "This is the way they do over in Nebraska and Kansas." It made me feel as though the whole world was looking toward these two states that are really the peers, I might say, in the dairy business. They are looking towards Nebraska and Kansas for the ad - vancement and for the modern methods of dairying. It pleases me greatly to know of this situation. The hand separator system has, no doubt, brought about this condi - tion. There were some states a few years ago which were opposed to and there probably are stilJ some that object to the hand separator system. There are some states, and I know it is a fact, that the butter of certain manufacturers scores higher than that of Kanasas or Nebraska; but upon investi - gating the situation I find that in Kansas, and I think this is no doubt true in Nebraska, that the average score is 30 per cent jbove that of any other state. These two states are putting out a more uniform product, and when the United States wants butter it comes out here to these sunny dimes, Kansas and Nebraska, to get a uniform quality? Now, while the methods of manufacturing have been pro - gressing the production side has been developing, but not at the rate that the manufacturing side has. We wonder why the cow, or the product of the cow, which is the foundation of the manufacturing business, has not developed more rapidly. It is simply because we have too many unprofitable cows. We do not know, or we do not understand the dairy business from the producing side. I cannot help but think that we are in the same situation as the little Jew who 'swallowed a five dollar gold piece, and all the doctors couM pump out of him with a stomach pump was $3.65. We are putting $5.00 worth of goods into too many of our cows, and only getting about $3.65 out of them. In the modern relation of the dairy Er to the dairy cow we cannot help but think he has neg - his side of it. He is neglecting the bookkeeping fea - &gt;f it. He does not know what he is doing; that is the </seg>
            <seg id="p077">70 XEBP VTION rHe does not know how much his cows are worth to He does not know how much they produce, nor how profit they are making for him. You know there was a girl in Boston who came out here ! believe it happened down here in Kansas. She had never ; on a farm before. Of course, she believed everything was said about shorthorns, silage and things of that kind, had not seen a cow milked before. She did not know milk originated. One day she went out to the piggery she saw there what was a daily occurence to the fanner, little pigs were nursing the big one ; she had not seen this re. She came tearing into the house and said, "Auntie, e out quick ! the little pigs are eating the big one." Now is exactly the situation with the dairy farmer. He does know the situation or the profit. SELECTION OF THE DAIRY COW. No problem in recent years concerning the dairy busi - ness has attracted the attention of dairymen and investiga - tors more than the relation of the proper type and formation of the dairy cows for the economical production of dairy pro- tA cow may be considered a machine for the purpose of srting coarse or rough feed into a refined product called Different cows have different capacities for developing from the same amount of food, just as some steam rs have "the power to generate more steam per pound of than other boilers. kit may be said in general, that all cows utilize the feed ti they eat for one or two purposes, provided the animal good healthy condition. The first is for the production lilk; the second for the increase in live weight. Cows h, through hereditary tendencies and environment, have loped a capacity for transforming a large quantity of </seg>
            <seg id="p078">71 NINETEENTH riOS feed into milk, instead of utilizing the same for an increase in live weight, are known as dairy cows. Other cows, from influences of the same character acting in the opposite direc - tion, have a capacity for transforming their feed fergely into flesh and fat on their bodies, and the milk produced by such cows is of minor importance and is used entirely for the nour - ishment of their calves; these cows are known as beef cows. Between these two classes we find a large number of cows which combine the characteristics of the dairy cow, in so far as giving a legitimate quantity of milk is concerned, with those of the beef cow which produces calves which are profit - able for the feeder for the production of beef. Such cows are generally spoken of as dual purpose cows. For these wideJy different purposes dairy cows have shown a conformation widely differing from that of the beef The conformation and external appearance of a beef cow is a fairly safe rule and guide from which to judge her merits for her particular purpose, but it is not as easy a task to judge the capacity of a dairy cow for producing milk and butter fat economically from her external appearance and conformation. It is plainly evident that success in dairying then depends upon the productive capacity of the individual, rather than upon the herd or breed, inasmuch as there are such variations in different cows of the same breed in regard to the amount and composition of the milk they produce. The merits of a dairy cow can be estimated by accurate record of the number of pounds of milk she has given, and by testing the butter fat with the Babcock test, but this alone will not completely express all the qualities that is possible for the dairy cow to possess. y"he question as to how long the cow has the power to ue this flow of milk, during the period of lactation and year to year, and whether she has a strong constitution, commonly indicates the power of producing an off- </seg>
            <seg id="p079">72 NEB I. spring equal to or better than herself, are points of excellence to be desired in the ideal dairy cow. These factors — aside from the regular yield of milk or the actual pounds of butter fat — must depend upon the good judgment of the dairyman to select his animal by external conformation. SThe type of a good dairy cow depends upon anatomical physiological principles. Such expressions, as "the dairy must be wedge shaped." "she must have large nostrils." je mouth," "thin neck and large paunch on a compura - y Nght frame work," "broad between the thighs, with a i udder and large milk veins and wells," are, strictly king, a means to an end. I The first and all important point in selecting a cow. is note the size of the udder; whether it is large, uniformly ped, with teats placed* at their proper distance; to note ether the udder is flabby and not fleshy, which is particu - ly apparent immediately after milking. According to the •s of correlation, a cow that is a large milker must neces - ily develop a large udder, and if free from fleshiness, the ; of the udder is one of the truest indications of efficiency an animal. The development of a large, udder necessarily in' a large blood supply, the blood being the intermediate t tory step from the raw material of the blood to the final transformation into milk which takes plnce in the udder. A large blood supply necessarily means a large circulator} tern, a large heart with large arteries and veins ; hence, the size and tortuous appearance of the milk vein which runs from the udder toward the anterior portion of the body is a good sign for the dairy cow. However, all good dairy cows do not have large tortuous veins, for the reason that a second vein leading from the udder up through the abdomen may be large and receive the greater portion of the blood that comes from the udder. A large and well developed circulatory sys - tem necessitates a large respiratory apparatus to purify the </seg>
            <seg id="p080">73 noN K utilized in the system. Not only that, but the heart, is the pump that circulates the blood, must be supplied ample energy, stimulated by a well-developed nervous i to keep up its function. The blood is made from the food that the cow consumes ; hence, in order to keep an ample and steady supply of blood there is necessary a large and efficient digestive apparatus. These are the important factors which are closely connected for the production of milk, and the accessories, such as tVc large nostrils which necessarily must admit a good supply of air to the respiratory system, a large mouth with a good mas - ticating apparatus to supply the digestive organs, bright eyes, wide forehead indicating a strong nervous center, and large openings in the spinal column to admit a number of large nervous cords which lead to the digestive organs and udder are all features that are necessary for economic production of According to the theory of evolution we find that the udder is nothing more than a modified mass of sweat glands. We find that in the classes of animate known as Orny - thorycus the milk gland consists merely of milk tubes opening close at the surface of the skin. The secretion liberated from these glands is licked off by the young and supplies the food for their nourishment. In the Marsupial class of animals these glands have sumed a more compact form and a number of ducts emptv into each other before they open at the skin. Each follicle of which there are ten to twenty in number, empties through a separate duct into a slight protuberance on the surface. This protuberance is known as a rudimentary teat. It is noticed in tracing up the scale of life we find that a gradual development in this particular gland from the lower types of animal to animals of a higher type is increasingly pronounced until the greatest development is reached in the dairv cow. Since this condition is a fact, it indicates that </seg>
            <seg id="p081">74 there should be a somewhat parallel development with the sweat glands and the udder. Large sweat glands which exude a liberal supply of secretion of a yellowish fatty nature are found to be another strong indication of the real merits of the dairy cow. While it is generally advisable to have a cow of good size, it has, however, been found that size does not enter in as a factor of profitableness. Cows with strong nervous sys - tems, and quite active, are probably the most efficient pro - ducers of milk if they are well cared for and kept in a com - fortable condition. A cow of this nature reduces her flow of milk when ill-treated more quickly than she responds to good treatment with an increased flow. A cow with a strong nervous constitution, phfegmatic temperament, not excitable, although not as efficient a milk producer, is probably the best cow for the average dairy. Discomfort or ill-treatment apparently do not affect the milk supply as much in a phleg - matic temperament as in a nervous animal. The saying that "A dairy cow for the dairyman and a dual purpose cow for the dual purpose man," is not inappropriate. I While these are all facts which tend strongly toward ating the proper type of a dairy cow. it is not saying a dairyman should alone rely upon conformation, for the ock test, and the scafles with the milk pail are accurate ods of determining the profit or loss of any particular al. We have the assurance of every successful dairyman they are most essential even for the man with but one For by this method only can dairying be put on a sys - tic and profitable basis. (Prof. Erf: It has been demonstrated in DeMerk that igorously massaging the udder of the cow as does the calf, you can develop a greater milking tendency. Now I : wish to lay too much stress on this. That has been the ■t and there is no doubt but what there is some truth </seg>
            <seg id="p082">NINETEENTH 75 A Voice : If a cow had the exterior apparatus as seen, would not she be likely to have the interior apparatus? Answer: Yes, she would be likely to. Question : Well, more likely than another cow ? Answer: Yes; the interior apparatus conforms to a great extent with the exterior but not always, but it would be a good strong indication. Question : Would that massaging process have any - thing to do with the interior part of the cow? Answer: That merely excites that part of the system and brings the blood supply to that point, and consequently develops that part of the body. Now, a blacksmith has a tre - mendously large arm because he exercises vigorously and de - velops a large arm. The modern facial expression, which applies more especially to women is the effort to wipe out the wrinkles, the massaging of the face, brings a large quantity of blood to that portion of the body, and consequently, gets rid of the wrinkles and develops that part of the features. A Voice: It is the development of the internal portion of a cow, as well as the external portion, that is done by massaging? Answer: No, it does not develop the internal part You have to develop the internal part by breeding and feeding. k Question : The feeding of a calf would help develop e internal part of the calf? Answer : Yes. Mr. Dodge : I understand you would recommend a cow that gives a quantity of milk. Now, might not a cow that does not give quite as much milk produce as much butter fat as the one that gives a larger quantity ? Answer : Yes, a cow might give less milk but test higher, and consequently you might get the same amount of butter fat from that cow as one that gives more milk but tests JO i\ Ci • </seg>
            <seg id="p083">76 IProf. Erf: No; feed does not increase the per cent; creases the quantity of milk and increases the amount of ;r fat in proportion only. KProf. Hinman : In judging in the show rings at our would you use more of the general score cards than are used, that is, they now go according to the cards put out ie various breeding associations to a certain extent? Prof. Erf: I do not know of a show ring that uses a score card. I Prof. Hinman : Should all the breeds be judged on same standard, or should you make a difference in a dard according to the breed? IProf. Erf: I judge an animal from one stand-point, if you are speaking of a dual purpose cow. I should judge •om another stand-point. The digestive apparatus is the Drtant point. A cow must have that before she can pro - ! milk. Prof. Hinman: The same rule applies to all breeds? Prof. Erf: Yes I Mr. Stillson : In feeding our cows, when I find a cow i a heavy flow of milk we feed heavier. Now is the butter affected by feeding as the flow of milk is affected by feed- Prof. Erf: You mean to inquire then whether you in - crease your butter fat, or per centage of butter fat in the milk by feeding? tMR. Stillson : No ; my idea by the question was this ; : a heavy milker requires heavy feeding. Now would a ner producer in butter fat require the same amount of ling, or more? That is, does the feed influence the butter in the same shape, or does the amount of butter fat influ - ence the amount of feed required ? That is to say, a cow that is producing a large amount of butter fat — does that cow need more feed than a cow producing a large milk flow ? </seg>
            <seg id="p084">77 Krof. Erf: Do you mean that a cow should be fed ntly. ■Mr. Stillson: No, not differently, but more in tity. EProf. Erf: You cannot feed butter fat into a cow. that in mind. If you feed for butter fat, why you neces - f must feed for milk, because the butter fat is in relation e other solids, more or less. EMr. Stillson : Perhaps I cannot make myself under - i but is the feed required for a heavy producer of butter he same as it is for the one that produces less, or does it an influence, the feeding quality in proportion to the v flow of milk? I Prof. Erf : I think I understand your point. 1 to ask if a cow that produces a large quantity of butter hould be fed differently than a cow producing a large titv of milk? I Mr. Stillson : No ; but do you have to feed in order oduce a larger flow of cream? A heavy milker has to ;d heavier in order to produce a heavy flow of milk. , she may give a less amount of milk and more butter Does that cow need to be fed with a heavier feed than e was one of the lighter milkers and a less producer of I Mr. Ashburx: I think I understand Mr. Stillson's , and I wish to say this : I do not think a heavy flow of means anything. I do not think you necessarily have ed heavy for a heavy flow of milk. It depends a great whether a heavy flow of milk is solid or water. Now, ave five elements in milk, four solids and one fluid, and fluid is water. We do not have to feed heavy to get r into milk. The solids must come out of the foods ; the r can come out of any old tank. Now, the point is, understand, and the question is as it occurs to my mind, it depends upon whether it is a rich milk or a poor milk. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">78 Now, the difference between rich milk and poor milk is, that poor milk has more water in relation to the solids, and the rich milk has less water in proportion to the solids, and we have to feed for the solids. If a cow is giving a copious amount of the solids whether there is a large amount of water with it or not, we must feed the heavier to produce the solids. We will not have to feed heavier in order to get a larger flow Mr. Stillson: Where will you get the milk? Mr. Ashburn : If we have three per cent butter fat, we have the other solids in proportion. Mr. Stillson : That is good logic, but it is not always practical. »Prof. Erf : When a cow gives a large flow of milk she -ally requires a good feed. Mr. Stillson : What does she do with the solids that do not go into the milk? Answer: She does not- generally digest it. Mr. Stillson: She is a waster then? Answer: Yes sir. Mr. Stillson : Then when you are telling about the large amount of milk a certain cow gives and holding a cer - tain cow up to us as an example, are we to understand that she may have been a very profitable cow, or a very unprofit - able cow, because she may have consumed a very large amount and not have put the nutrition into her product? In other words, she may have been a waster? Prof. Erf : What I mean by a profitable cow is a cow that will give you more value in butter products than the feed you put into her. She may give you little or she may give you much. K Question : Can you not take the ordinary cow and by oving the feed increase the flow of milk, and also the tity of butter fat? That is, if you re-arrange your feed ; to give her a balanced ration, in other words? </seg>
            <seg id="p086">NINI TION 79 Answer: Yes sir. S Question : Then that answers the gentleman's ques- By increasing the quantity of digestive feed you in - ;e the quantity of milk and butter fat. Suppose we have cows : One gives 40 pounds of fat, and the other 20 pounds. Professor: I would rather have a cow that gives the higher per cent of butter fat, that is, if all other things were equal. Question : If you were in the general hog business I do not think you would. Answer : I can put water into skim milk. Remember that whenever you have a high percentage of butter fat you have a high per cent of solids; and all you have to do is to put water in and you will get the same thing as poor milk. You don't have to milk water out of a cow. 1 Question : I understood you to answer me a while ago the cow that gives a large amount of poor milk wduld heavier eater in proportion to the amount of butter fat rave, than if she gave a very small amount of rich milk. K Answer: I don't think I said that, at least I did not 1 to say that. Question : What is the ratio or per cent of butter fat to the feed? Answer: Anywhere from 2.7 to 4.2. The relation is very uniform. As the butter fat increases the solids are in - creased, but still there is no rule for that. Question : Now, how is it when it is below 3 per cent? Answer : Generally the butter fat runs down while the solids run up. Question : For instance, in certain breeds of cows you have a low per cent of fat and a large per cent of other </seg>
            <seg id="p087">80 Answer : Yes. R Question : Now, I would like to ask you a question ilation to the charts : Were the cows producing those : amounts of butter fat all fed the same amount of and in the same proportion? kr : Xo : those tests were made in various places and on different kinds of feed. Some were made in London at the royal show, some at the Chicago Fair ten years ago, and some at the Pan American exposition at Buffalo; in fact, they were made at various places. Euestion : You have not determined the amount of that these cows have consumed to produce this t of butter fat? I Answer: No, I cannot do that for the reason that is a fluctuation in the market price of butter and feed, pends upon where you are. Question : Is there any such thing as increasing the per tentage of butter fat by feeding, that is, I mean the per cemage? Answer : No. Question : There is no such thing B Answer : When the cow has once reached her ca - y, you cannot feed fat to a cow. L Question : Could you not make a little flurry, just l short time? Answer: Yes, by a large amount of food, but she will come back within two or three days to the original quantity. P Question : In placing cows in their rank and order herd can you depend on one year's record? k Answer : No, you cannot because some cows make a omenal record in one year, while the next year they ically do nothing. To illustrate that, take the Zeider it the Illinois Experiment Station : Two years ago she : a record of 86 pounds of milk one day and tested 3.5, </seg>
            <seg id="p088"/>
           
            <seg id="p089">81 and she gave 21,000 and some odd pound !k which tested on an average of 3.4. Next year she made 128 pounds of butter fat the whole year. Question: Now, as a rule, is not that an except and as a rule don't cows run in a pretty fair even trend? kvswER: Yes, as a rule. There are c 1 all ese rules. I just mereh ! to bring out I that ch things do happen. L Question* : This cow was under high pressure that ? nswer : Yes sir, and she was a 2-year old, too, when she made that record. She has already produced over 400 pounds of fat this year and has been milked little over five months, showing she is coming back to her normal state. Oustion : In judging cows by external appearance and upon which you lay a good deal of str - you consider the most important, large abdominal develop - ments or large udder? Answer: I say large udder. Of course, internally, she must have abdominal development, because othe no cow can develop a large udder — I do not mean fleshy udder. There are some cows that have large udder - they are not fleshy — there is no cow that can devel udder unless she has a good large efficient digestive appa - ratus. Bear that in mind : that is in direct relation to the size of the udder. She must have a large respiratory appa - ratus, and a large udder cannot be developed without these requisites. * » Question : It does not necessarily follow that because ,v has a fleshy udder she cannot give a large amount of ? ■ Answer: There are some exceptions. But take a with a fleshy udder that gives a large quantity of milk, always has a large abdomen, but as a rule a cow with a 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">82 large fleshy udder is not a good milker; however, as I said, there are exceptions. H. C. Young: The largest milker I have in my herd has a large fleshy udder and she gives about five gallons a Prof. Erf : Is the udder really fleshy ; that is the point? Mr. Young: Yes: you would think after she had been milked that she had not been milked. Prof. Erf: Is the udder as distended as it originally was ? Mr. Young: No, but it shows the shape and all. Prof. Erf: What I mean is, is it a loose flabby udder? Mr. Young: No. Prof. Erf: An udder might be just as much dis - tended after milking as before; that is a fleshy udder, and the udder can retain its shape and not be fleshy. Mr. Young: Can you tell us about the secretion of milk? Prof. Erf: The secretion of milk is a problem that has not been worked out in detail. It is a complicated pro - cess. Perhaps I can better explain it by explaining it on the board. (The professor here explained on the board.) A Voice: When I stepped in here this morning I heard one man say that there was an over-abundance of pro - tein in alfalfa hay. Remember protein has the power of be* ing converted into fat and carbo-hydrates, but carbo - hydrates do not have the power of being converted into pro - tein. Remember that. Mr. DePeel : In milking, would it not be well to give the cow's bag quite a vigorous rubbing before milking? Answer : Yes. Mr. DePeel: Your subject is "The Selection of the Dairy Cow." I suppose you mean selecting from your neighbor's herd when you are buying cows? </seg>
            <seg id="p091">83 NINETEENTH Answer: Yes sir. EAr. DePeel: I suppose if you should select from own herd you would take the Babcock test, or some test of a like nature? S Answer: That would be the natural way. Some have a very weak nature, and their offspring would e very desirable. If it was for the purpose of retaining individual cow, the Babcock test is probably the best KIr. DePeel: In selecting from your neighbor's herd vs, if the appearance of two cows were equal in milk - hich one would you select, the one in a fat condition or e a little below the normal condition in flesh? Answer: It would depend on her vigorous appear - ance, that is, whether the cow that was fat had a bright eye and a vigorous constitution. You can tell by the way the cow moves. I can hardly describe that. But you go out here and you will see one cow spirited and another cow lagging along slowly. The one that has a phlegmatic temperament probably will put on fat, while the other one is a dairy cow. I would rather have the latter, provided other things were ■Question : Then you think that the cow that is good sh will stir up more butter fat than the other? Answer: Yes, she will produce more butter fat Question: In what form is that energy stored up in the other cow? ■Answer: Well, you can call it latent energy; that is, isual name for it. RThe President : We have with us today Prof. W. A. ry, of the Wisconsin Agricultural College, who will now ess you. Prof. Henry: Ladies and Gentlemen: It is a great pleasure to be with you to-day. Dairymen have mutual interests. They are a live set of people wherever you find </seg>
            <seg id="p092">84 NEBRASKA DAIRYV them. I have visited them in the old world, and 1 have ted them in many parts of the new world, and they are all alike wherever you go, just as a new dairy cow produces a certain type wherever you find her and has certain quali - ties that recommend her and appeal to you at once. They fall into a certain classification, I don't care whether he is a Dutch dairyman, a Danish Dairyman, a German dairyman, a French dairyman, or one in Wisconsin, or one in Ne - braska; they are a good deal alike, about the same breed of pups everywhere. There are reasons for this, the same as for the conformation or type in the dairy cow. The dairy - ii has got to be a hard worker. He works constantly, vv that has its good effect. It even has a good effect on mn who is in a state prison. The fact that he has got to something continuously all the while helps him. It mal etter man of him. The dairyman works contimtov [ while he frets and chafes at it, it is to his ad The banker has to work steadily; the merchant has to work steadily, and that is the reason they are good safe busi: men as a class. Xow you go into a community where a man works six months in a year and loafs around the store for the other six months, chews tobacco, talks politics and le. his corn-stalks in the field, that community is not a very good community to live in. They are not of a very particularly high degree of citizens in most directions, or in fact, any. i go into a country though where there are dairymen who have to work all the year round — they complain a great deal about it — but you will find a good bank account, good roads and good vehicles. You will find their buildings I'nted ; you will find the farmer's house tolerably well fur - hed; you will find, best of 'all, his children are coming on splendid representatives of the best class of American »ple, because they are brought up to work. They are &gt;ught up to frugality. They are brought up to persistent industry of the right kind. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">85 NINETEENTH Now the highest class of people in the world, agricul - turally are those that deal with animals, wherever you find them. Of course, the fruit raisers and bee raisers, and our horticultural friends generally, they are of a high type of fanners. Brt the corn growers, wherever you find them, in California or in our own state, they are not of the higher type of people — they are land robbers. They have many of the characteristics of robbers, as a people, and their children show it. Now I don't believe the dairy industry is going to assume enormous proportions in this state for some time, but to you as individuals that does not matter much. If more people are living in town in a certain community, and can make a living there, the few people who remain in the country ought to do better bcause their neighbors have gone to town. The fewer people in an industry of any kind the better for them because they follow it wisely and well. Don't fear of the dairy business going to pieces and don't worry. The cow is by all odds the most economical food pro - ducer that we have. Let me tell you that Laws &amp; Gilbert in their work in England brought that out nicely. The steer gains about two pounds a day in weight when you are feiding him a large amount of corn. Now quite a large per cent of that two pounds is water. In other words, the steer will put on about ten pounds of fat in a week and a little bit of lean meat, and that represents the week's work. The cow will give you seven or eight pounds of fat in a week, about ten pounds of sugar and give about eight or nine pounds of cheese, part of the milk, as well as some other pro- So taking it as a whole, the cow is at least twice as economical as a steer. You can see the evidence of this, if you want to look at it carefully, by studying the densely popu - lated parts of the world. Go to China and India. You don't find the people there eating meat. They cannot afford it. The same thing in Germany. Only the rich can eat meat, except pork. Where people become less dense, they will tat </seg>
            <seg id="p094">86 \ DAIRY v \TION meat, that is, beef. Otherwise, they will keep a cow bcause it is more economical. The first animal to disappear in a te&lt;e\y populated country is the steer, I mean, aside from ts of burden, for the reason that he is the most extrava - gant and most useless of animals. The next animal to go I would depend upon several things, but the dairy cow would longer than the steer because she is so much more eco - ical. And so you will find in Europe where people live : together they keep cows where they cannot afford to steers. They will work the oxen as in parts of France Germany, then after they have had a long period of &lt;. from them, they will fatten them. But in Nebraska steer and sheep 'are going to be your principal animals, ther this from looking at your soil and the great areas ind that you have. So you dairy people are going to be a comparatively small community, but that need not discour - age you in the least. There must be thousands and tens of thousands in the dairy business, at least. To-night I will Ba little to you in regard to the dairy industry abroad. I tell you something of the Danes and Hollanders, but I not refer to them here. II will tell you a little of our Wisconsin work. I have in my work there for twenty-three years. I remember Prof. Haecker, I will always remember him as a boy t cows. His father was a man always with cows, and is in Minnesota with cows, and the young man here is fol - lg in the same line. In Wisconsin the dairy industry is large and must continue so because of the hardships we had to go through there as a people. We have some that is rich as some of your Nebraska lands. A pretty part of our state is not near so fertile as yours. Our farms are small and many of the people are foreigners who K there without anything — 40 acres, 80, 120 acres, up to acres are the usual sizes of the farms. Our people are il and thrifty. Our bank accounts which were nothing </seg>
            <seg id="p095">87 NINETEENTH ITION years ago are swelling all the time. The town I am in of 20,000 people has over $7,000,000 on deposit, and it mostly came from dairies. Take Jefferson county — they turn out about $2,000,000 worth of products in that one county a year ; and money is very abundant in that county. Take the county south of us; they make over a million dollars worth of Swiss cheese in that county a year, and yet that county was avoided by settlers in the early days because the land was rough and poor. They left that county open to settlers and it was settled by people who were hired to leave their own country. People in Switzerland became so dense that they could not all live there and they said "Let's pay our neighbors to leave our country," and they did so; and some of you may have been one of them. (A Voice: I am one of them.) Some other people came out West here, and their neighbors felt that they had better go, too, (laughter) not because they were bad people, but because the community could not sup - port" all of them and they came into Wisconsin and took up that particularly poor land because they could get that land cheap. To-day that is the richest part of the state. There is more money there per capita than any other part of the state of Wisconsin. They have a great many silos. There has been an address over there in the stock judging rooms regarding silos. I am wondering when the silo will become common in Nebraska. A good many do not need it. Don't think of a silo any different than a horse or wagon or a plow on your farm. Some of you need more plows on your farm. S of you need a cow. Some of you need more horses, but of you don't. Now if you don't cut up all your corn, if you don't take care of your corn fodder in good shape, if farm is not very heavily stocked, you don't need a silo. It is only an instrument to an end. If you have not got wagons enough to take care of your crop, if you suffer for something to haul your material in, you need another wagon. If you cannot plow your corn properly because you have not </seg>
            <seg id="p096">88 NEBRASKA' DAI RYV \TION horses, you need another horse. If you have got your farm running in "bang up" order and use all your corn fodder and you are getting short of roughage for the number of cows you have, you had better buy more land, or you had better put up a silo. Sometimes you had better put up a silo than to buy more land. I have had a silo on a Wisconsin farm for 23 years and use it every year. A great many of our farmers are still building silos. They use them for a time and then give them up. They are just like the man who went out and bought a wagon and did not need it. or bought a horse and d it: he found no use for it. So some of our people thought a silo would make them good dairy - men. They did not need a silo; they needed more cows. what will the silo do? Your 1 th a silo will eat up all your corn-stalks. If you want your cattle I iur stalks, put them in a silo. 'Corn-stalks, tassels, butts ything. Rememfber no nply a giant • think a corn-stalk is not palatable or digestible. It is . The best part is in the ear, but there is still g« amount in the stalk. It is a large coarse grass. We farmers in our state who have used the silos from ten to fifteen years. I have found farmers in Iowa who have used the silo for thirteen years who have been raisi horn cattle. We use the silo where nt to keep all the we can on a given acreage. Then articular kind rn for a silo. We found at one time that a chea] a good thing because it took but little money. Xow we build We use the silage as a succulent feed. It tty hard to keep a cow five or six months in the year on drv feed. That would be like feeding them sugar beets and mangels if we could get them, but we could not always them. I know that mangels would be to my cows as - are to me and my children. Xow you can raise a ton and put it in the silo for just about half of what </seg>
            <seg id="p097">89 NINI - IIOX you can these big beets; that is, it will cost you about half. So if you thjnk of growing beets, or are now growing beets, you may just as well grow silage and save half of your labor. Now silage by careful experiment made in two or three places in Canada will go as far as beets, and in Canada for fattening cattle it went further. Silage will go as far as mangel wurtzel beets, weight for weight, and cost half as much to produce. So there you have the figures on them. The American people will never become growers of root crops except growing beets for the sugar factor}', and farm - ers will not do.it in ed. There is no reason to do it, because you can raise a crop of silage with half as much labor and get the same amount of nutrition. Now we grow from six to eight and ten tons to the acre; that is in - cluding the ears. We run it through the feed cutter and put it in these wood and stone silos. That silage in the win - ter is brought out and fed to the cows from twenty to forty pounds a day. With that is fed sometimes dry stalks, but generally clover or timothy and clover mixed but very few of you are in condition to use the silo. A great many ought not to have a silo; you need more cows to eat up the roughage you have, and you had better scrape along in the condition you are until you get into the silo stage. The silo stage is the advanced stage of dairying. Some of you have got there probably, but the most of you have not got there as yel. It is only a means to an end. It will not make a poor dairyman a good dairyman. It will not make a man who has corn-stalks wasting in the fields better ; it will not help him a particle, but when he has gotten beyond that stage of shiftlessness he will desire a silo. Now another thing: In this state you are quite winter wheat growers. Some of you could cut the corn-stalks out and run them in! and put in a. crop of winter wheat. I do not see why you could not put winter wheat on that ground. Xow think that over. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">90 §Mr. Ashburx : We are putting our winter wheat in the corn-stalks and raising good winter wheat in way. Prof. Henry: You will come to the time when you cannot afford to waste as much feed as you are doing now. All it costs is the mere gathering of the corn-stalks. Mr. Ashburn : What is your mode of dairying in our state; is it cheese-making or butter-making largely? Prof. Henry: Well , we make a great deal of cheese and a great deal of butter. There are parts of the state right south of Madison where it is nearly all cheese, and in the upper part more butter, and still farther north more cheese. We have about 1,800 cheese factories and about 1,200 creameries in the state. ■ Mr. Ashburn : Some years ago we were advocating a silo to dig a hole in the ground ; in this country we not bothered with anv water. Prof. Henry : I know your conditions to a certain extent. If a farmer wants to try silage that is a very good way to start, just dig one of those holes in the ground. The only difficulty is to get the silage out : it is easy to put it in. Let me tell you how the silo started. It you will come with me to the north of France near the Belgian line you will find the foreigners there growing great quantities of sugar beets, and there was practically the origin of the silo — where the silo started. They will haul a load of beets to the beet factory and they are in a hurry, and they will go home and bring a lot of pulp; and they have a hole that they have scraped with a scraper near their farm, so they will drop that beet pulp in and go right on and get a load of beets and go back to the factory. You will find these holes in the ground and the beet pulp rotted a short ways down, but under that it is all right, and they take that and feed it to their stock. LNow if they can do that with that beet pulp you can do ith vour corn-stalk^. The largfc in the wnr' </seg>
            <seg id="p099">91 NINETEENTH [ION in Indian Territory. There the stock raiser built a large stockade. He grows sorghum there because it is too dry to grow corn. He has feed cutters that are run by threshing machine engines. He has Indians working for him. He runs his stuff through the machine and runs it into the silo and after it is full he tears it down and puts up another one a short distance away and he fills that. Mr. Ashburn: Does not the outside of it spoil? I Prof. Henry : Yes, the outside of it will spoil. I have at your beet factories here and in California, and I have the pulp rot two or three feet and there would be fine pulp inside of that. PMr. Ashburn : How about clover, or the first cutting lfalfa in the silo? Prof. Henry: I have never but once succeeded in making good clover silage. We have tried it ten or fifteen years, and nearly always failed. Corn is best, clover next. I have heard of alfalfa being put in. I would prefer to stack green alfalfa and see if I did not get a lot of good material inside of the stack. • UMr. Ashburn : Would not spontaneous combustion i? Prof. Henry: It might, but you would not lose much anyway. Prof. Erf: We have a silo of alfalfa hay at our sta - tion, and it is very good. We made it from the first cutting of the alfalfa, and I think our cows have done better on it than anything else we have had. Prof. Henry: If it comes out when in a mouldy con - dition, is it good cow feed? Prof. Erf: Well, a little mould will not hurt. I like cheese with mould all through it. A Voice: I raise some alfalfa out in Polk county. I got the first crop about the ioth of June, and I let it lay that day and the next morning, whether it rains on it or not, </seg>
            <seg id="p100">92 I rake it. When the water is out of it I put it in the barn, and what does not go into the barn I put into stacks, and if it does get a little mouldy there is no hay that will shed the mould as alfalfa. As quick as you raise it, it drops out, it appears, and the stock eat it just as well as where it is not mouldy at all. L Question : You would not get the white mould : it ild turn brown, would not it? \er : It first gets white and then turns brown. Question : Did you ever try putting corn in a silo without cutting it? kr : Yes, you can do that. We had a farmer in our state once, one of the most successful dairymen we ever In feeding the different feeds to liis cattle, he would ke some of the droppings from his cow and it in order to determine what had passed through them. He would study it very carefully in order to learn how to feed ; and he came to the conclusion that he did not want to cut his and put it in the silo whole. The only trouble about it is in getting it out. They pack it in there so tight that it is difficult to get it out of the silo, but aside from that it is a good way to fill a silo: that is, to not cut the fodder. It is a question of ease of getting it out and in. : In putting it in in that way. would it be !1 to tramp it in tight? xswer : Always get it tight. Get it close and solid ; that is the point. Keep the air out. P Question: Now do you think that would hold good ling a silo with good silage, to tramp it? Prof. Henry : Yes, we tramp it. We keep one man tramping all the time; we found it was a great advantage. Grow good corn. Always have your corn denting when you put it in a silo. ■ Now, about this dairy business : In this country you find your land running down in fertility. The dairy </seg>
            <seg id="p101">NINETEENTH 93 farmer here is going to continue producing enormous crops on his land if he feeds wisely ; and your solution here is going to be alfalfa. With alfalfa and dairying and a rotation of your farms where you follow dairying is going to keep it in value, while those who persist in growing corn, are going to run down. Now land runs down as people or animals do. You seen men working up to a certain time and then break. He may have consumption. He may do a pret* le day he cannot do as much, and from that time he runs down rapidly. That is the way with land. I can take you to places where they have worn out the land, call it. but the farmers by one means or another keep up the fairly well, and then the land goes out very sudd I Now in the Red river country where they t wheat crops the land is going the same way. In ka where you are following dairying, dairy fan going to be all right. You have not too high uk - value of your good land. This is an empire of great th through this region and you are to be congratulated 1 living in this region. I was pleased to-day in coming through to notice 1 Eiska is improving in regard to buildings. I think higher class of agricultural people than Iowa. Take n parts there, they are not as careful with their dairy and dairy buildings as you are here. There are i isconsin and some parts of New York where they are not keeping up their general appurtenances as you are here in Nebraska. If you can keep on in this way you are going to make this state famous all over by reason of the thrift and wisdom of the people. You have a gold mine here, but do not work it for all it is worth. In Wisconsin our state is growing richer, the soil is growing richer : I will tell how </seg>
            <seg id="p102">94 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION kota wheat fields and putting it on our land. We are feeding bran and hauling the manure out into the fields, and each year the land is growing richer, while our less fortunate Ihbors there are sending their wheat to Minnesota to be md and are losing by it. I know where at three oad stations they unloaded 400 car loads of bran in one We are manufacturers. We turn bran into butter cheese. In dairying you gather up a little money each It is like money at interest. When you sit down and : a cow at night you say, "If I feed bossy well and treat kindly. I will have a little more milk to-morrow morning, a little more milk is a little more money." I know of a boy who put $200 at interest and he began to figure out how much interest a day he was going to get. is only a few cents, but he was just as proud as he could be that he was having an income of three or four cents : that he hnd sorrething working for him besides his two hands. Now the cow is working for you just the same. That is what makes you good citizens, because you are" Efhtful, kindly and provident. The people in a dairy dis - are always a wise, conservative and safe people. When government gets in danger you are there. When hard strikes us you are safe. Now the state of Nebraska can afford to help this association as a state. You can af - !1 to push dairying at your agricultural school. You can ird to push it as a state, because in the time of trouble have got a safe, conservative and wise people that will y you over its adversities and trials as the people of the will not. The country has to save the city and nation its conservatism and frugality, and by the children they raise who go into all the walks of life. So the state of Nebraska can give this agricultural col - lege all the money it needs to push dairying. They can afford to push the fanners' institutes. They can afford to publish its reports just as much as it can afford to pay three </seg>
            <seg id="p103">95 or four million dollars for a grand war ship. That money is spent to save the country in time of need and nobody ob - jects to it. And what would that amount of money do in the dairy business. We had better build some war ship course, but along with that let us build up a wise, thoughful and conservative, honest and law-abiding, thrifty people that can conserve the richness of the soil. Question : How far can land be run down and be restored again by clover or alfalfa? Can it be run d so that you cannot get the clover or alfalfa to grow or do well? Prof. Henry : Well, I will tell you : you would have to answer that question for each locality. I have bet land in Georgia and Virginia that I think you and I would lay down before we would try to restore it. But our farms in Indiana, Illinois, Wisconsin, or out here, are not out. It is just like you and I would be if we started to run to town. Before we got there we would be tired out and would have to rest a little while and then we would be just as good as before. The land throughout this country worn out, but down in Virginia and Georgia, God help the people, it is pretty nearly gone! Mr. Ashburn : Now, one of the live questions we are up against is, what relation or how much of a necessity is a silo to be with us, considering our alfalfa? Should we put in a silo just as quick as if we had not any? Prof. Henry: No. Five or six years ago we put in a week studying alfalfa in your state, and I saw some very strange things. You don't need silos nearly so badly with your alfalfa and I would go slow with a silo until I had got my alfalfa proposition and fodder proposition well balanced up; because, that .alfalfa is a thing to study with the most of you before you study the silo. Alfalfa is one of the burning questions with you in Nebraska, but when you have got it, </seg>
            <seg id="p104">96 NEBRASKA DAIRY) then with your corn and corn fodder you have got all the elements of success for splendid economical dairying. R Question : In stacking alfalfa hay would you rather ck it pretty nearly green or get nearly dry? Prof. Henry: I have studied alfalfa in France and California and spent a week here several years ago at it, but I am not well enough posted to advise you. If you start in and take some alfalfa and let the hot sun shine on it and work it around with a tedder, you can knock off fifty per cent of your crop. Mr. DePeel: The proper way to handle alfalfa, I think, is to let it get wilted and then put it into small bunches, let it cure a day or two and then draw it in. The following committees were appointed : On Secretary-Treasurer's report — Henr\ F. C Stillson, J. C. Merrill. Resolutions — A. L. Haecker, D. P. Ashburn, J. F. ippi. On Nominations — B. R. Stouffer, L. D. Stillson, T- S. Clark. On motion Association adjourned till to-morrow morn - ing at 9:30 o'clock. MORNING SESSION, JANUARY 21 Called to order by President J. K. Honeywell. First in order was the report of the committees. REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON NOMINATIONS. »Mr. President : Your committee on nominations de - to make the following report: For President, C. A. Clark, Ravenna. For Vice President, J. A. Harris, Shickley. For Secretary-Treasurer, S. C. Bassett, Gibbon. </seg>
            <seg id="p105"/>
          
            <seg id="p106">97 DIRECTORS. J. K. Honeywell J. C. Merrill, L. D. Stillson, Prof. A. L. Haecker, Henry C. Glissman. IOn motion, the report of the committee was accepted adopted and the persons named in said report declared ;d to the various offices mentioned for the ensuing year. Mr. President: Your Committee on Resolutions re - spectfully submit the following: (Be It Resolved, That our thanks are due to Secretary sericulture, Hon. James Wilson, and Hon. Major Alvord heir kindness in having present at our Annual Meeting M. W. Lang, representing the Department of Agri- K Resolved, That our thanks are hereby extended to the bers of the late legislature for the liberal appropriation ! for the building of a Dairy Barn at the State Experi- Station. K Resolved, That the Association indorse the present plan olding the annual meetings of the several associations organized Agriculture at the University Farm. J. F. Schlappi, Committee. The matter of the form of contest to be used in the cream judging contest was discussed to some extent. It was finally moved by Mr. Merrill that the contestants be required to confine themselves to the pipette system and not by weight, which motion prevailed. fr. Stillson moved that a committee of eight be ap - pointed by the president to be present while the contest was (Signed) L. Haecker, </seg>
            <seg id="p107">98 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION being made. The motion carried and was adopted. The lent appointed the following committee: ■ Mr. L. D. Stillson, R. L. DePeel, Mr. R. S. McDonald, J. F. Schlappi. J. D. Harris, J. C. Merrill, Fred Kohler, Mr. F. A. Leighton. CONTEST IN CREAM TESTING. In order to obtain some reliable data in the different methods of cream testing, and at the same time, to encour - age careful, accurate work by operators and parties inter - ested, it was thought advisable by the Association to conduct a cream testing contest. I The plan of the contest was to select a number of com - :ial cream samples and test them for acidity and then the Babcock test by both weighed sample and using pipette. A sample of the same cream was also sent to :hemist where a gravimetric analysis was run. This con - was opened to all members of the Association living in the state but professionals were barred. The follow - persons entered the contest : H. W. Ehlers, Cheney, Nebr. R. L. Tolles, Laurel, Nebr. J. M. Brown, Scribner, Nebr. J. X. Ashhurn, Gibbon, Nebr. H. C. Glissmann, Omaha, Nebr. W. A. Doubt, Havelock, Nebr. H. S. Wilson, Lincoln, Nebr. Max Buschow, Bluehill, Nebr. The following table will show the per cents found by the committee, chemist and those entering: </seg>
            <seg id="p108"/>
            
            <seg id="p109">99 Ing was calculated as follows: Taking ioo as a perfect :, each .5 of a per cent above or below would cut off point and each 1.00 per cent would cut off two points 1 the contestants score. Thus, if the contestant reported 42 per cent butter fat when it should be 40, his score would be q5 points. The contestants were furnished the i.?e of the Dairy School Laboratory and provided with all necessary ware and machines for making the test. I The work was done in the presence of an expert who rintended the laboratory and the Association members i allowed to watch the work if thev desired. iln referring to the table it will be noticed that cream j by using 18 grams by weight corresponded el the chemical gravimetric analyses, while the te samples ran about one per cent lower. The coi came nearer the weighed sample than to either the te or per cents found by the gravimetric method. Kit is safe to say that by weighed samples more accurate can be done and more to be relied upon than volumetric to. IThe cream may vary in specific gravity caused by large nail percentage of butter fat, and also by high and low •MMITTEE CONTESTANTS 1 1 By weight 18 G. Per Cent fat Pipette 18 CC. Chemical GraTlmetric Score Name — A »H 33 5 M. 34 84 I 4« S IS: 5 100 SA M «T M SS H. W. Khlera W. A Doubt Ashbarn R. L. T - Wilson « 37% 46.50 46. 46 m C »H 34.50 3S.10 M.a D P 41. S7.30 38 !S0 28.511 41 .84 2».W "n'.e" • jj-- as.M ».■ 1 .. S« M Th« : pro rat i premium, $75.00, was divide 1 among the ontesta nts who scored above 95 points. Th&lt; : bas </seg>
            <seg id="p110">100 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION E:y so that a measured sample would be more likely to than one taken by weight. However, it was decided le Association to base the contest on the i8cc pipette le because throughout the country cream is largely 1 by this method. kAs to whether or not the butter can be recovered suffi - ly to warrant the exact per cent of fat is a question, fat, however, should be stated in correct terms and if mtter cannot be recovered then the butter fat should be for accordingly. The Association is greatly indebted to Dr. Samuel v, chemist at the Experiment Station, and Miss Corr, ant chemist, for their kindness in making the gravi - metric analyses. Also to Prof. A. L. Haecker and his ants for use of the Station Laboratory in conducting the contest. In the matter of the contestant, Buschow, the result as announced by Mr. Buschow was ten per cent less than that found by the committee. The committee in charge are of the opinion that an error was made, possibly in the readmg of the per cent of fat, but as the sample tested had been des - troyed there was no means of determining. </seg>
            <seg id="p111"/>
          
            <seg id="p112">.TEENTH 101 COW JUDGING CONT One of the most interesting sessions of the annual that devoted to the judging of dair\ The condii of contest and premiums offered to cont. may be found in the program of the annual meeting in this report. The cows to be judged consisted of ten head, used for experimental pur - poses at the State farm, whose milk yield and butter product he past two years was a matter of record, but known only to I'rof. A. L. Haecker of the department of dairy husbandly. The cows were placed in the stock-judging pavilion, « being given a number for the purpose of identification, and over each cow was placed a placard giving her age, breeding, period of lactation and when bred. Each contestant was given a blank card in form as follows: Where a contestant placed one of tli a in her proper posi - tion as regards to her value as a dairy cow, he was entitlt a credit of ten points, but if, as for instance, the I among the numl)er, which should be placed number one, was placed number five, she was considered as placed four p out of her proper position and the contestant would be enti to a score of ten minus four, which is six points. There were forty-four entries in this contest, of which twe three scored more than the seventy-five points which w entitle them to a portion of the prize money offered. For the prize, a gold watch, valued at $15.&lt;x&gt;, Messrs. 11 Ifclntosh and B. R. Stouffer were tied, each having a eighty-four points. They drew cuts, and Mr. Mclntosh se&lt; the watch and Mr. Stouffer participated in the distributi' the pro rata fund. The following are the names of the contestants who so e than the seventy-five points: A. L Wood, Omaha, 78; Wendel Brinton, Lincoln, ilopt, Cambridge, 7 k, Lincoln, 7b'; U Mclntosh, Alda, 8-4; B. B. StoulT. ; i Omaha, t how, Blue Hill, 78; J. N. Ashburn, Gibbon, 78 </seg>
            <seg id="p113">102 Tolles, Laurel, 82; It If. Stem, Bumboldt, 80; J. B. Varney, 78; H. W. Ehlers, Cheney, 76; C. W. Tulles, Laurel, I. F. Schlappi, Lincoln, 80; Henry C. (llissman, Omaha, Lincoln, 80; J. M. Brown, Scribnei . Wheaton, Omaha, 78; I). N. Syford, Lincoln, 82: M 78; W. A. Doubt, Havelock, 80; H. S. &gt;n, Lincoln, It is interesting to note that of the twenty-thr - ore, two correctly placed cow No. 1; four correctly 2; one correctly placed cow No. 3; one rectly placed cow No. 4; two correctly placed cow No. 5; two ectly placed cow No. 0; one correctly pi. BCtly placed cow No. 8; five correctly placed cow N while fifteen correctly placed cow No. 10. KAMI OF UKIAMIHT MANA(,IK OB 8BC- HSTAKY IIUTTEB-HAKKK POST-omcB te is Centre la Beatrice Carleton Elkhorn Valley Fontanelle Germantown Golden Rod Hygela Hampton ** J ■ ■ ■ mi Henderson Lyons Malcolm Martinsburg Nebraska and Iowa Rlverton Ravenna Ravenna Ravenna Sutton Avoca Cheese Factory E. Hansen K W. MeGinnla Geo. E Haskell O. W. Llcbty T. S. Pexton I E. Cahoon Geo. Petre F. E. Pratt Chas. Harding J J.Oox J Cox W. H. Lyon John Weltzel Chas. Hurley J. J. King T. N. Moore •••• J.S. Clark J. S.Clark J.S Clark J. C. Merrill Ernest Samzellus . . . R. A. Carpenter Wm. Bechter J. H. Rushton T. E. Qarlty J C. MoKendry P. E. Fisher J. A Holmes J. S. Bunts T. S. Pexton R. O. Cahoon Otto Schmidt C. E. White G. E. Parker Frank A met C C. Carroll R. A. McHal. John Weltzel Joe Bom bar P. F. Hanna O. Muckel K. L. Stacy F.N. Henry A. J. Wise . J. C. McDonald Ernest Samzellus . . . A H. C»Rwell Herbert Craven Arcber Amelia Lincoln Carlelon Nehlth Ponlanelie German town Fremont Omaha Hampton Henderson Malcolm Martinsburg Omaha Rtverton Ravenna Loup City Ord Sutton Schuvler Grand Island Pierce Fairmont Avon </seg>
            <seg id="p114"/>
            <seg id="p115"/>
          
            <seg id="p116">Table showing the cows and their recoi I in the cow judging contest at the annual meeting of the Nebraska Dairy- men's Association: name or cow Last Calf 1901 Lbs. Butter- fat 1903 Lbs. Butter- tat Are. Milk Ave. Butter- fat Q Breed Born Lbs. Milk Lbs Milk Bessie Me- Klnley .. Holstein . Feb. W. 1885... Aug at, 19U3 .. 8.518.90' tU 37 1802 10,978.401 378.1 1903 9,748.16 B4.M Mabel Shorthorn Jersey Cross... Sept. 5, 1884.... Mar. 7, 1903 ... 7,5(2.00| 316.V7 1M1 7,458.90| 3-7 Mi 7.500.40 B1.5I Ruth 3d... Cora Jersey Grade... Jersey Grade ... Jersey Grade . .. Marl, 1888... Nov. t. 1884.... Oct. S, 1894. Not. 10, 1X99 ... Dec. 19. 1896... Nov. 10, 1886... April 18. 1903 ... Oct. 7, 1901.... Oct.lt, 1901.... Dec 7, 1902... Nov. 4, 1903... Oct 14, 1808.... 7,481.20 7.319.0M .•.-." Ml. 10 6.526.30 7,044.90 Ml. a -J 7,008.» 7,181.95 -J 315.49 3 4 Hattie 8.S28.60 309.17 6.108.80 298.34 8.499.15 303.75 5 Karen .... Holstein . 6.543.80 230.23 9.380.50 320.64 7,»M.1» 273 461 « Belle Jersey Jersey Grade ... Jersey Shorth'n Grade... S,aM.TO 209 94 5.551 80 3a as 4..S90.S H 7 Diana t . . . 5.434.101 2W54 3.861.40 S11.2I 4,847.761 ■■!!.• -7 I Annie Deo. 87, 1X96... S .X 1 :. Auk. », 1903... May 4, 19UI. .. 8.U4 8OJ 230 S6 7,-wo.;oj H8.8W «,»47.7J -J » Snowflake Jersey 2.3-JS.»0 ; 1J8.48 3.047.15' 173.37 MM m, 149.9l| 10 </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>