<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Influence of Various Soil Factors Upon Potato Scab caused by Actinomyces scabies</title>
               <date value="18??">August 1937</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001"/>
         <seg id="p002">¦¦.-¦. ¦.¦,'¦:- ¦ ¦¦•¦..'¦ ; '¦¦ ;^ '•¦' . ¦' .' : :" J COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA j AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION ! . . RESEARCH BULLETIN 93 | The Influence of Various Soil Factors Upon Potato Scab caused by Actinomyces scabies : '": .' ¦. :¦;¦'•¦¦ ¦¦ R W.Goss '; '\ ' \ ; ' . ;¦ ' ••',.¦¦. !¦ . . . Department of Plant Pathology . ¦ ': '¦¦- , I"' ¦;¦' .. ¦ i: ¦¦'¦'¦'!. . • !-"...:'-' ! ; - ¦ ¦ - - :. ... ¦':""'¦¦-..-"¦; ' '¦' " ¦ ' j | '.'( ' ' ¦ ' ¦•¦.¦'¦¦ -.'•.'¦.'¦¦. : - -¦ ' ' } i.-,K . , .'¦'.:'•; . :- . ¦ ;i; :•:¦'¦ . /..'¦ ¦..;¦/:¦. j '.;. ¦•' : i ; .'.;'¦ - ¦¦¦¦'¦¦.'¦ •¦¦:.¦¦'" '.:..•¦.•'¦¦':'"¦'¦. \ ¦' '. ' . "i j -^: - - ¦ ' ¦. . ¦'¦ ,: :¦:¦' . ¦ .¦ ;..'¦; : : !;. ¦ ]¦. \ '¦¦ ¦'" '-¦ ¦•:.. : ; ¦'.'¦¦ ¦¦.'¦.•¦. - '--:'¦ ¦ ¦¦'.-¦:':'-¦¦: : ¦¦' ,¦''- ': ¦; '1 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA ,1 \%. AUGUST, 1937 ¦ V. I .''.'¦ ¦ ¦ . '. ¦¦¦ ¦'¦""¦. ' ¦¦¦ -.'¦'. i . . ¦; 1 i;. " ¦ ¦ ' ¦¦...-;;. ¦ .-¦ ; -¦¦¦...¦ .: . (¦ \ . ¦ ¦ ¦ . j ; ) -f ' ' ¦ ' ':.¦¦'¦¦'. ¦ ' ' ' . • ' ! " ' ¦ : ' ¦ ' J '¦' ". , , .:¦-'..... '¦&#132;-.'. -'. .' " •',-¦'' ' ¦- ' ¦-. ¦ \ ¦ ' _* </seg>
         <seg id="p003">CONTENTS Introduction . 3 Experimental Methods 4 Influence of Soil Microflora and Other Factors 8 V.rTect of the Temperature of the Soil Preceding Tuber Formation 13 The Relation of Soil Moisture to the Disease 15 Effect of Soil Aeration . 33 Discussion .. 3.J . Literature Cited _ 30 / SUMMARY I The effect of soil moisture, temperature, and aeration, and of the soil microflora .is influenced by these factors, upon the occurrence of potato scab was studied under partially controlled conditions in the greenhouse. The influence of these factors upon the development of .-/. scabies in the soil preceding the infection period was emphasized ; in these experiments. ; 2. The severity of scab was found to be correlated with the amount of inoculum in ' lllL- SOll. J. The amount or inoculum was in turn found to be affected by 4 thc degree of '. ci'injjetifion of other soil microorganisms. ' •t. Soil sterilization before inoculation resulted in the most severe scab. This effect .; owld Ik- greatl) reduced by the addition of filtrates of unstcrilizcd soil or of organic matter in the form of manure and by delaying inoculation until soil saprophytes had .;: become established in the soil. ¦¦ "&gt;. .-/. fruroix added to tlie soil in amounts approximately equal to that of A. scabies }' ilul nut reduce the severity of scab, as reported in the literature. " (1. .Sterilized soils inoculated with A. scabies and incubated at temperatures below 22° ¦&gt; ('. did not gnc rise to as much scab as^those incubated at temperatures from 22° to 30°. . j (All were held at a temperature of 22° during the infection period.) Unstcrilizcd soils |j diil not show this effect of temperature upon the development of the pathogene. I '. The eflcct of soil moisture was variable. In the majority of the experiments the .¦'.. I must scab occurred in the dry soils, but the occurrence in a number of experiments of i. sescrc deep scab in soils held at or near the saturation point did not indicate an ¦j - ctrcciivc control ul the disease by high moisture, as reported in several publications. X. The results of one experiment on soil types, while not conclusive, indicated that jl caution should be used in comparing the effects of soil moisture in different types of soil. :jj ''. The largest amounts of scab occurred in soils that had been held at medium or '§ high moisture contents for some months previous to planting. While results were not jj always consistent, there was no indication that high soil moisture had a depressing effect '3 .n the development of ./. scabies in the soil, as determined by subsequent infection. '. ;j 111. Counts of Actinomyccs in soil dilution plates and on soil slides did not check I ivit/i each other, nor did cither show any consistent relationship to soil moisture or to % stab. In general the percentage of Actinomyccs was greatest in the drier soils, but the | numbers were sometimes greater with high moisture, in contrast with the reported in- "S 1 l-ibition by high soil moistures. : ¦ 11. A lack of soil aeration during the period preceding tuber formation had a^ greater effect than during the period of infection. In both cases scab was decreased. .! ¦ 12. The type of scab appeared to be determined by the host reaction, the environ - ment, and the virulence of the culture. Common, deep, and raised scab often occurred ': on the same tuber in sterilized soil inoculated with a single pure culture of A. scabies. ' Superficial or russet scab occurred only in the unstcrilized soils and may have been ' due to another strain or species of Actinomyccs. **}. 13. The development of an experimental technique which will permit the study of ji; the pathogene in the soil immediately surrounding the susceptible plant tissues, as con- )! tiasted with the present gross methods, is essential for the determination of the effect H ' ot many of these soil factors upon the disease. ,': ;.: '¦'{'• I </seg>
         <seg id="p004">The Influence of Various Soil Factors Upon Potato Scab caused by Actinomyces scabies i '."'. R. W. GOSS - Scab, caused by Actinomyces scabies (Thaxt.) Gliss., is a potato disease 01 major importance in western Nebraska. Seed treatments are effective in controlling seed-borne scab, but it has been shown that even when healthy or treated seed potatoes are used the disease may be very severe because of infection from the soil (7). Crop rotation will reduce the in - cidence of the disease, but the fact that potato scab may cause serious loss in soils never before planted to potatoes (7, 10) indicates that there are numerous factors other than the time interval between potato crops which affect the occurrence of the disease. A study of many of these factors has been undertaken in the field, greenhouse, and laboratory and the present publication deals with some of the results obtained under partially controll - ed conditions in the greenhouse. , ;¦¦¦ High temperature, low moisture, alkalinity, abundant aeration, and the addition of barnyard manure are generally accepted, in the extensive litera - ture on' potato scab, as favoring the occurrence of the disease. On the basis of/the published evidence, it should be possible to correlate the occurrence of the disease jn the field with one or more of these factors. Unfortunately, however, the author has often found it difficult if not impossible to do this in many instances, as illustrated by the following examples. During the; past six years careful records have been made of the amount of scab occurring in all of the irrigated rotation plots at the Scotts Bluff Substation and of the unirrigated plots at the Box Butte Experiment Farm in western Nebraska. In addition, the inspection records o£ some 10,000 acres of potatoes being grown for certification have been examined each year. During this period there was one year, 1934, when extremely high temperatures and low rainfall prevailed. According to the literature this should have favored scab, but it was in this year that the least scab occurred.- It was evident that further investigation of these factors was needed for a complete understanding of their influence oh the disease. It has been a common observation of many potato growers in western Nebraska that potato scab is always severe following heavy, packing rains when the field cannot be cultivated subsequently. Scab is also common in flooded areas at the lower ends of irrigated fields and in poorly drained portions of dry-land fields. This is the reverse of what one might expect from the work of Sanford (16) and Dippenaar (4) on soil; moisture and Sanford's work (17) on the necessity-of abundant aeration for the best development of the organism. . ';.¦ As regards the use of barnyard manure, the potato plots at the two sub - stations previously mentioned, offer a striking contrast. The application of manure preceding potatoes has always resulted in a great increase oi scab </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Nebraska Agrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 in the irrigated Scotts Bluff rotation plots, while at the Box Buttc farm, under dry-land conditions, no increase has been noted with similar applica - tions and in many years the amount of scab has been materially less than in the unmanured plots. No data are presented in this publication dealing with soil reaction. While all of the older publications point to the favorable effect of an alka - line soil on the disease it has recently been shown by several authors (5, 7, 18, 19) that highly alkaline soils may result in less scab than neutral or slightly acid soils. Jt is evident from the above statements that further investigations arc needed on the effects of environmental factors. There is a great lack of data on the effect of these factors on the organism in the soil, as most of the experimental evidence relates to pure cultures or is limited to the period of infection. It is impractical to change soil conditions greatly during the growth of the plant, with the one exception of soil moisture, but it is possible to modify the soil environment by rotations and cultural practices pieccding the planting of potatoes. It was therefore considered desirable to place the emphasis in the following experiments upon conditions existing previous to infection, as this phase of the problem was in the greatest need of investigation. EXPERIMENTAL METHODS The experiments were conducted in a greenhouse held (at a tempera - ture ol 21)° to 21° C. In the first experiments (Tables 1 and 2) it was found that infected tubers occasionally were produced in the uninoculated controls grown in sterilized soil. This was eliminated in the later experi - ments by the use of individual saucers for each pot, careful watering, and the cleaning of floors and benches with water instead of by sweeping. In many experiments unsterilized soil was used and a small amount of slight stall usually occurred in these uninoculated soils. Unless otherwise specified, the following methods were used in all the experiments. Soil.—The soil used was made up of three parts of bluegrass sod, one part sand, and one purl stable manure. The bluegrass sod and manure were composted for a year or more. This compost was then run through a modi - fied ensilage cutter before being placed in the soil bins. This treatment re - sulted in a fine, well mixed soil that did not require screening. Just before using, the compost was thoroughly mixed with river sand. Enough soil was prepared each fall to provide for all the experiments conducted during the winter. The soil thus prepared had a moisture-holding capacity of about 42 per cent as determined by the use of 25 cm. soil tubes. When sterilized soil was required, the soil and containers were placed in a large steam sterilizer at 25 pounds pressure for 2/2 t0,3 hours. Seed tubers.—The experiments were conducted witl^ potatoes of the Bliss Triumph variety. Scab-free tubers were selected and!treated with hot formaldehyde (1 to 120) for three minutes at 52° C, after which they were covered for one hour. When dry the tubers were cut into seed pieces weighing 40 grams each, which were held at a high humidity at room temperature for 24 hours to facilitate healing and were then treated with </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab ethylene chlorhydrin to break dormacy by dipping in a 3 per cent solution and placing in a dosed container over night.'They were then planted in sterilized sand. As soon as the sprouts and roots were well started, they were transplanted to the containers being used in the experiment and us - ually the soil was inoculated at this time. : . '. Containers.—The plants were grown in seven-inch clay pots with in - dividual saucers, except in some o£ the soil-moisture or aeration experiments when earthenware crocks or galvanized iron cans holding about 10 kilos of soil were used. Wlien crocks or cans were used, the desired soil moisture was maintained by supplying water at the surface, which was covered with a half-inch layer of gravel, and also through glass tubes leading to an in - verted two-inch clay pot filled with coarse gravel and placed in the center of the container. The amount of water needed was determined by frequent weighings. In some of the soil-moisture experiments the plants were grown in benches with the soil about eight inches deep instead of individual plant containers. Usually 24 plants were grown in each bench compartment, which was 30 square feet in size. This method had the advantage of pro - viding a greater amount of soil per plant, and there was less variation in the soil moisture within each set of 25 plants than with clay pots or crocks, even with the daily weighings in the latter case. Methods of recording scab.—Three types ot scab will be referred to in this paper: common, i.e. definite, ruptured, corky lesions; pit or deep, i.e. lesions of about the same size as common scab but extending into the tuber about one-fourth inch and usually with the margins of such pits slightly raised; superficial or russet scab, i. c. diffuse, indefinite, brownish areas on the surface of the tuber. All these types of scab are pictured in Plate 1. In nil of the experiments the tubers produced were usually of a size fairly cbmparable with potatoes grown in the field. While it is often con - tended that the number of infections per tuber is the best method of recording scab, it was found to be too time-consuming. It also has the dis - advantage of failing to differentiate between very small, inconspicuous scab spots and larger spots or deep scab pits. If the size and type of scab pustules are dependent to any extent upon tuber development, which is in turn in - fluenced by soil environment, then the size and type of lesions become just as significant and as reliable an index as the number of infections per tuber. In field experiments and in the practical interpretation of the results of greenhouse tests we must consider the number or weight of tubers Jinfected and proportion of surface infected. This was determined both on a weight and on a number basis. As the results were practically the same on each basis, usually only the number basis is used in the tables. ' ( Dilution plates for quantitative determination of soil microorganisms.— Cultures were usually made from a composite of three to five soil samples. A 20-gram portion of each composite sample was added to 200' cc. of sterile tap water in a 500 cc. Erlenmeyer flask and shaken for five minutes. Dilutions were made to the desired concentration, one cc. of which was added to each petri dish. Seven petri-dish cultures of Waksman's albumen </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Nebraska Agrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin* 93 .'.".. C D Plate I ,j A. Russt-l i.r sujxTtui.il &gt;c.ih (tn a Bliss Triumph potato &gt;;ro\vn in unstcrilizcd soil 'j (sec Table 2). ' ', h OiiniiKin st.ih .m j Dins Triumph /mtato jjnmn in soil inocu/alci/ ivith ./. scabies '¦ \-2.i. C. Dtcp scab on a Bliss Triumph potato crown in soil inoculated with A. scabies N-23. I). Ciimimin scab nn .1 potato xr"» m in uninnculatcl sanil cultures flooded with &#132; nutrient solutmns several times daily. The proliferated Icnticels show the effects o£ J liillll moisture winch failed to inhibit the development of scab (courtesy of H. O. '' Werner), i 1 agar 1 were used tor each determination of bacteria and Actinomyces, and -I an equal number of Jensen's asparaginate agar- were used for the determin- :]¦ ation of fungi. Counts of fungi were made after two to three days and of ¦) bacteria and Actinomyces after 10 to 14 days. Soil moisture determinations jji were made from other portions of each sample and all data presented in !| the tables are on a dry-weight basis. ¦*' 1 1.0 cm. Jtxlrow. 0.5 B m. K-HPO,. (1.2 cm. MbSO,. intt Fc;(SO,),. 0.25 gm. cg s albumen ij! MnprndcrJ in 5-10 cc. of water and neutralized to phcnolnhthalcin with N/W XaOH 1 1)00 cc water- ¦'¦'' pH 6.5. ' s'l - '2o 0 cm. dejtroie. 2.0 gm. aiparafin, 1.0 jm. KH.PO,. 0.5 c m. MgSO,, 0.5 cm VaCI 01 cm S FKI,. 10 gm. JCJf. 1,00(1 cc. ».,ter; pH 3.8-4.0. S ;| i </seg>
         <seg id="p008">. ¦ • . . '¦¦.!¦¦"•' '$¦ ¦¦'-'¦•¦ ¦ ¦ I "S3 : .'•'/. Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab 3 :, \'' ¦ "¦¦ ..-' ¦ ¦ ./"¦ ¦ ¦¦' -'¦¦¦ ¦" ¦ '.'¦"•. ¦¦¦¦¦' | Soil slide cultures. —In addition to the quantitative determinations of ,'| If. microorganisms by dilution plates, an attempt was made to check the re-' fa .'; suits by use of Cholodny's slide technique (2). Clean glass slides were sjjj &gt;.: placed in the soil at a depth of 3 to 6 inches in a vertical position and in 'j{t % firm contact with the soil. These were left from 7 to 10 days and then y f;' fixed and stained by Conn's method (3) with rose bengal and examined ;,| I' under an oil immersion lens. About 200 fields on each of two or more | S3; slides were examined in each test. 'i Inoculum.—Cultures were prepared by inoculating the surface of potato ,' ? ;i'v- dextrose agar in petri dishes with one cc. of a water suspension of the i organism obtained from agar slants. This iamount just covered the surface .j i: or the agar without undesirable excess water. After about two weeks' f| , growth thY surface of the petri-dish cultures was flooded with sterile water ;j i. and the surface growth scraped and washed off, after which the suspension ;| J was filtered through fine muslin. The total inoculum for an entire expen- 1 'ii ment was made up in one container and 200 cc. of this per plant was used ,; :j: , to inoculate the soil. I -V ; ' The concentration of the inoculum was determined by the following i ' preliminary test, the results of which are presented in Table 1. Sterilized ,;' soil was inoculated, at the time tubers started to develop, with 240 cc. of -:\ • inoculum per pot in five different concentrations. The undiluted inoculum &#132;'' ; of A. scabies N-23 contained thtee petrwlish cultures to each 240 cc. o£ | water, which was the amount of inoculum used in each pot of Set 1. For ~£ '';'.' each of the next four sets, 0.1, 0.01, 0.001, and 0.0001 dilutions of this ;ij : . inoculum were used; and an additional set was left uninoculated as a con- •; L:¦'¦.'.• trol. Each set contained 18 plants, except the control, which had only 10. --i Table I.—lnfluence of the amount of inoculum upon the production ; J of scab.' ¦¦ &gt;.-.' : ¦ ¦ . Clancs of tubcn, determined by percentage '.:p :•¦ i Sc.Vo. Amount of inoculum: of lurfacc scabby i;| fe'.j . 0 | 0-1 | 2-25 | IS-75 | 75-100 :.| ', .J- Ko. P. a. P.ct. c.a. P.m. P. Ci. -j .¦'"; 1 . Undlluicd&gt; 76 9 12 50 26 3 'A ' ( 2 1-10 dilmion 72 14 S7 46 3 0 '= &#132;j 3 . 1-100 dilution... 63- '33 52 Mi 0 0 ¦« ', i 1 1-1,000 dilution... ;... 64 56 41 3 0 0 . i Si. 5 1-10.000 dilution..... 73' .78 ' 22 0 0/0 -g, t'.\\ 6 Ch«lc 38 92 8 0 0 0 ;! ;r ¦ "Tlie undiluted inoculum was at the rate if three, petri-diih cultures, m weeki old, !n 240 cc. V; "::'H of water per plant. . -¦. - . . &gt; . . j r; The data presented in Table 1 show that the percentage of tubers in- ¦;; i: '"•; ' fected and the scabby area per tuber were both directly correlated with . . -; the concentration of the inoculum. In addition, pit scab'occurred only in i ; Sets. 1 and 2, which had the greatest concentrations. ;, '¦•'¦'; It is evident that the amount and severity of scab in this test was !j&gt; r.: -; directly dependent upon the amount of A. scabies in the soil, and that 'y .•&gt;..• good results could be secured in sterilized soil by the use of one to three ?&gt; ;/*,., petri-dish cultures per plant. Accordingly, in all of the following experi - §J- ''.. . : . '- .. ¦¦;¦¦; -¦¦ ¦[[ ¦'. '¦ .¦ ¦¦¦¦ ¦''¦'¦ ,¦¦¦.:¦¦ ¦¦ :j ¦ . '.¦¦ ;| i|f; ; ¦ ¦..-.¦ :'¦¦- ¦•' &gt; :;i? %:¦¦¦¦ ¦¦¦ .'¦¦'¦:¦¦'¦¦¦:'¦.':-' y ¦¦¦:¦ . ..- I </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 ments the inoculum was used at the rate of one and one-half petri-dish cul - tures in 200 cc. of water for each plant. The inoculum was thus of only approximately the same strength in different experiments and with different cultures of Actinomyces, but it was uniform for the individual plants in each experiment. The inoculum pre - pared in this way will be referred to in this paper as a spore suspension, although this term is not strictly correct. In all experiments, unless otherwise noted, the inoculum was pre - pared from cultures of //. scabies N-23. This strain was isolated from lesions of the pit scab type on Bliss Triumph potatoes produced in western Nebraska in 1928. INFLUENCE OF SOIL MICROFLORA AND OTHER FACTORS In many of the experiments reported in the literature, the soil has been sterilized before inoculation. It is obvious that sterilization changes the physical and chemical nature and upsets the biologic equilibrium of the soil. The effect of any one limiting factor may thus be greatly modified and results obtained in this way are not necessarily a true index of what would occur under field conditions. This has been recognized by a few workers who conducted their tests with unsterilized soils. Many of the experiments reported in this bulletin were conducted with unsterilized soil and were duplicated with sterilized soil for comparison with published data of a similar nature. Preliminary studies were made of the effect of soil sterilization and to throw some light on the question whether any differences in the occurrence of scab were due to chemical or physical changes in the soil; or to the lack of competing organisms. This was tested by adding to sterilized soil an ex - tract of unsterilized soil, filtered through muslin. At the same time the effect of the time of inoculation was determined by adding 1 the inoculum cither at the time of planting or at the beginning of tuber formation. 3 The data regarding the effect of these treatments are presented in) Table 2. Among the different soils with similar inoculations, scabj infection was greatest in the sterilized soil of Set 1, where it was very severe, while Set 2, to which a nonsterile filtrate was added, produced only slightly more scab than the unsterilized Set 3. These results offer presumptive evidence that the greater amount of scab developing in the sterilized soil was due to a lack of competing soil microorganisms. This was further indicated by the fact that while there were no significant differences in Sets 2 and 3 due to time of inoculation, there was less severe scab in the sterilized Set 1 with the late inoculation made at the time of tuber formation (1 B), possibly because of the competi - tion of many organisms that had become established in the soil after sterili - zation and before the inoculum was added. 1 In tin! and in man)- of the following experiments and in Ihc tabulated data, tilt beginning of tuber formation or "time of tuber set" hai been used in an arbitrary manner to divide the growth period of the plant into two seneral phases. It was determined by examining the itoloni of a number of pbntj in each set and whenever tuber initiation was evidenced the time was considered as that of "tuber let," although it ii recognized that tubers were initialed on many plant! after Ihts time and on a few plants before this time. </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab Table 2.— Effect of soil sterilization and time of inoculation upon scab development and upon the numbers of bacteria and Actinomyccs. Stt J . . ¦ Number Weight Number Clawc. of tuber., determined by Inoculation o f o f of percentage of surface scabbyl "' pbnu tubejs luben p \ 0 . 2 | 2 . 2S |15.75|75.|qq| Russet No. Gtami No. P.«. P.rt. P.tl. P.rt. P.«. P.rt. . ; STERILIZED SOIL 1A Ar planting 18 3,165 88 0 0 10 24 66 0 IB At tuber formation. 20 3,895 97 0 7 30 36 27 0 IC Uninoculaied ...... 10 ; .... 35 66 14 17 )3 0 0 STERILIZED SOIL PLUS FILTRATE OF UNSTERILIZED SOIL 1 2A At planting... 20 4,270 67 0 15 43 21 3 18 2B At tuber formation. 18 3,860 68 0 13 48 25 2 12 2C .Uninoculalcd 10 2.330 43 0 7 5 0 0 88 .•'¦-.-. UNSTERILIZED SOIL 3A At planting........ 20 3,880 61 0 26 44 '15 0 15 3B At tuber formation. 19 3,590 56 0 14 34 JO 0 32 3C Uninoculated ...... 10 1,960 32 0 6 X 0 0 78 ¦ . ,„ ; . ¦. ¦ ' Time of sampling ' Bacteria Actinomyccs - S" : Inoculation per cram per gram ™,5 f . . No. r.. (dry weight) (dry weight) «enl'«- moeuU - . . ¦ tion tion . Million! P.el Millhni P.rt. Dm Difi STERILIZED SOIL 1A At planting 176.6 76 55.7 24 82 78 in At tuber formation.: 250.8 91 25.2 9 82 35 IC . UiTinoculited 292.8 97 8.5 3 »2 .. STERILIZED SOIL PLUS FILTRATE OF UNSTERILIZED SOIL 1 2A At planting .... .. ... .. .. 2B At tuber formation .... " ... - ... ¦ .. '.. .. 2C Uninoculated ..;........... 80.2 90 9.1 10 82 . UNSTERILIZED SOIL 3A At planting .... .. ... 3li At tuber formation.... '.... .. ... .. .. .. 3C Uninoculated 353 78 9.7 22 ... ..' 1 Percentages baseil on number of tubers. . '¦¦¦ 3 Filtrate obtained from about 1 pound of soil by adding water and allowing it to aland overnight and then filtering through muslin. 300 cc. of filtrate was added to each plant. 3 Avciage numbers of three dates of sampling. . ; ¦ Russet or superficial scab developed only in the unsterilized soil or when a nonsterile filtrate was added, and in these soils it was most common in the uninoculated checks. It may well be that this type of scab was caused by a different species of Actinomyces that was present in the original soil. The other types of scab varied from common scab to deep pits. There was a small amount of slight infection in the uninoculated controls. The numbers of Actinomyces in the soil, as determined by the dilution plate method, checked very well with.the incidence of scab in the various sets, as shown in Table 2. The largest number of Actinomyces 82 days after sterilization occurred in Set IA, which had been inoculated for the longest period of time and in which the inoculum had apparently become well established before the soil became infested with competing organisms. The later inoculation in Set IB had the next highest number of Actinomyces and the least number occurred in Set IC, which was not inoculated. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 The amount of scab produced, as recorded in Table 2, appeared to be directly correlated with the totaj number rather than with the percentage of Actinomyces. A comparison of the uninoculated sets shows that the number of Actinomyces was least in the uninoculated controls. The effect of sterili- [ zation on the uninoculated soils was very noticeable in the high numbers of bacteria in Set IC, while the addition of the nonsterile filtrate in Set 2C ! resulted in a much lower number. Ordinarily the numbers of bacteria in - ciease rapidly in a sterilized soil but eventually decrease to the approximate number present before sterilization. In Set 2C the soil was immediately treated with a filtrate of unsterilized soil and the maximum number of organisms had probably occurred previous to the time of sampling. This process was much slower in IC, which depended upon chance contamina - tion. ; Table 3.— The effect of the competition of soil microoganisms upon the ¦ occurrence of scab in inoculated soils. j Number Number eh"" °f '"&gt;"«. determine,) b; i 1 toiimcni of Mul o j o j percentage of surface scabby ' plan» tubers , Q | Q. 2 | 2-25 | 25-100 :Vo. So. P.et. P.cu P.ci. P.ct. MlßinZin Mill.. IXOCI I.ATF.D WITH A. tcaUn I No treatment . 58 2-19 2 6 34 58 . ! : I ilu.ur i.f iin.rrriluol Mil 34 176 » 17 27 48 3 l-ilirjte nf Mrnli/nl manure 40 205 7 8 36 49 &lt; MiTili/cil manure 20 102 ]2 13 49 27 i I titrate &#132;( nnucriiuni m.u.ure 30 2B 20 22 34 24 i. r n .ienli/e.l manure .... 20 7fl 54 I" 13 6 I'riiiollunn »i' VI 1«) 1 4 35 CO f lj.r,r,.i .10 ICO 9 9 3S « 9 Acimnmvc 11 I .jf»f&gt;|&gt;*w&gt;.') 20 "13 7 7 4R 39 10 Mulurc "( ircjlmcnl. „( 7. 1. 'I 19 94 2 2 52 » SIF.RII.IZFII SOIL. NOT INOCULATED 11 No irunnrni ... 20 85 100 0 0 0 LSMIKII.IZMI Mill.. IMAXI. VIED WITH A. ."•¦«« 12 No .ifjim.ni 50 211 17 25 39 19 * All ircjlmcnu «ere m.nlc at ihf lime of inocublion. All inoculations were made at the rate of 200 cc. nf inoculum per not. equal to I/i pctri-diju cultures. Saprophytic organisms were added at the same me The filirjies were obtaincil by soaking 4 parts of soil or manure in 6 parts o£ water over ni^ht. filtering through cheesecloth, and adding 200 cc. per pot. The manure in Sets A and 6 was added at the rate or 200 gr.iim per pot. Additional tests were made botK of the effect of the addition of sterilized -.' and nonsterilized organic matter and of the filtrates of the same to sterilized inoculated soil. Three types of organisms isolated from the unsterilized soil were cultivated and added to^the soil in amounts approximately equal to that of A. scabies in an effort to determine whether either of these particular groups were effective competitors of the scab organisms in the soil. These tests were made during different years in the greenhouse but as the results were of the same general nature they have been compiled into one composite table (Table I). As in the previous experiment, there was much less scab in the un - sterilized soil (Set 12) than in the sterilized soil (Set 1) similarly inoculated, </seg>
         <seg id="p012">; Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab 1 the difference probably being due to the lack of competition of microorgan - '.¦ isms in the sterilized soil.. The addition of a filtrate from unsterilized soil (Set 2) did not have as great an effect as in the preceding experiment, al - : though there was a decrease in the severity of scab that is not clearly :.:, indicated.in Table 3. Only, one-third of the severe scab in Set 2 was of the /'}.¦¦ very severe type, as contrasted with Set lin which one-half of that listed in the table as severe was of this very severe type (more than three-fourths of •f . the surface of the tuber scabby). The addition of a filtrate of sterilized f-. ¦' ¦ manure (Set 3) had very little effect, but the addition of organic matter in , the form of sterilized manure (Set 4) decreased the disease considerably. li This decrease could not have been due to organisms added, nor to organic acids or other substances also present in the filtrate added to Set 3, which : did not reduce scab. Possibly this added organic matter so changed the soil |:; Table 4.— Effect of competition of A. praecox with A. scabies upon scab. „ „.„ Total child of tuber, determined by percentage }X; Treatment ""of T °f "*« «*» &gt;:; ¦ . . phnu num b er 0 | 0-2 1 Z-.25 1 25-75 \ 75-100 X ~"~ iio, Graml P.ct. P,el. Pet. P.cl. P.cl. ' OV WEIGHT BASIS Check 15 750 100.0 0 0 0 0 ; 7,«0T 3W 15 1,210 100.0 0 0 0 .0 tSw N-23.::: :: .: »¦. 3im 25.1 39.3. 18.9 i« 2.5 ; A. ™Ole, +A. i££t .....30 3.375 26.7. 35.6 16.3 19.3 2.2 | ','"¦ ON NUMBER BASIS . j ¦ • Check .'.:.' 15 46 100.0 0 0 0 0 i P' A ,'m°: ........ 30 93 24.7 43.0 18.3 10.8 3.2 j; A.-icaia + Al.piiaox.. .30 105 28.6 -11.0 16.2 12.4 -1.9 texture that. it acted indirectly upon the development of scab through changes in aeration and moisture-holding capacity of the soil. It is more probatte, however, that this additional favorable substratum resulted in a H more rapid increase in the number of microorganisms resulting from | chance contamination following sterilization and that the number of i Actinomyces were inhibited by these competing organisms. This is further ':i borne out by the fact that the filtrate from unsterilized manure (Set 5), . j containing many microorganisms, decreased the amount of scab more than j the sterilized organic material in Set 4 and the addition of unsterilized »; manure in Set 6 containing both the microorganisms and the favorable 1 organic substratum resulted in less scab than any other treatment under ;j greenhouse conditions. [:¦ &#132;"'"¦ y:. . . .: t The addition of cultures of saprophytic forms of Penicillium, bacteria, Sj and Actinomyces, and mixtures of all three in amounts equal to that of the t inoculum, failed to have any appreciable effect upon the occurrence of if; scab. ¦¦--:,: -;- ¦'. . &amp;¦ The tests with/^./»/v7&lt;?co^Millardand i ßurr 4 were made in 1935-36 ?¦¦} under conditions where the amount of scab produced by A. scabies was not ft as great as in the previous tests and the results are presented in Table 4. .v\. 1 »Culture obtained through the courtesy of Dr. S. Wakiman. . . </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Nebraska Acrl. Exper.ment Station- Research Bullet.* 93 These results fail to reveal any antibiotic or inhibitory action o£ A. praecox on A. scab.es, as judged by the amount of scab produced on tubers Zh appioxmutcly equal amounts of the two organisms added to sterilized Jo f This is not ,„ agreement with results of Millard and Burr (15) fert£ nTS g ef Pe"'m MtS Were made with a soil of high fertilrty and the results would not be strictly applicable to field soils Similar experiments therefore were planned with unsLilized fieldfffi rom the upper 6to 8 inches of potato fields in western NebSa S soils were most y very fine, sandy loams.or silt loams in "he Rosebud ser.es the pH of which varied from 6.8 to 8.1. The tests were made dur TaVef SU"eSSIVe WmterS 3nd thC reSultS arC a" brOU Bht together in Some of the results presented in Table 5 are difficult to interpret in Ze Pd r;r Th tHr °btf Cd " **!«**V experiments Sm" posted soil. The only s.gn.ficant reduct.on in scab as compared with the Table x-The effect of various treatments of field soils upon the occurrence of scab in the greenhouse. l a , , Number c| a"« of tubcrj, determined N« Vl" ""'mtnl of by pcrccnugc of surface scabby . luben q j —g~5 —j—^~rz —. 1 N.. ,-c.,, m ,n, Sj- '•"• '"•"• I-"- I S£?*L ¦::.:.:.:: S U i II g f SvSi*si--»-- ! ] | « -J l^L^^l '¦"¦¦"—«"" --^ n H 2i g S m°'; -* •¦ s-™ -' -l" t^ii/Ts sxsSdSXr pot 'about six weeks controls (Set 1) occurred in Sets 3 and 4 with the addition of manure. The It if dfffir l^ Bam Hmatte!, Wu aS S'milar tO the reSultS Presented in T=&gt;We 4re u,el "k Why the Ste"lized ™nUre in Set 4 resulted m less scab than the unsteriiized manure in Set 3, or why the £7 ° a fihrat? ot manure ' either alone (Set 5) or with sand (Set 6) L.led to decrease the amount of infection. In fact the percentage of in fcction was even h.gher in the latter two sets than with untreated^,! (Set tuber! in T" "" * S'gnificant hoWCVcr- as the numbai of tubers ln these two sets were rather small. These field soils weK much lower in organic matter than the composted soils o£ the previous experi - k's effecVth' dltl°n °{ °rgT mS " a filtrate -ouH probably have o^m of a ffe h" 1! PreV&gt;OUS tCSu V l' additi°n °f Breen man«fe &gt;" torm ot alfalfa had no appreciable effect upon the amount of scab In addition to the test reported in Table 5, three lot, of field soil were 2t7m S bef°re PJ anting as follows: 0) fr°^&gt; (2) a«- irlin </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato .Scab EFFECT OF TEMPERATURE OF THE SOIL PRECEDING TUBER 1 FORMATION j Many of the experiments reported in the literature on the effect of soil temperature upon the development of scab, have been based upon soil held at a constant temperature throughout the experiment. The effect of steriliz - ing the soil and the effect of soil temperature upon the pathogene in the soil before tuberization usually have not been considered. The following experiment was designed to throw some light upon these two poi its. The soil was divided into two parts, one part being sterilized; and both portions were then inoculated with A. scabies N-23, applied to the soil as Table 6. — The effect of the soil temperature preceding tuber formation upon the development of scab at 22"' C. 1 So -" vt 1 Classes of tubers, determined by percentage of surface scabby temperature ¦ Number ¦ ¦ U_ _ ' preceding * of . tuber tubers 0 0-2 2-25 25-75 75-100 formation ' ' '. •"'¦'-¦¦ peg.C. Number P.ct. ; P.ct. P.ct. P.cl. P.el. SOIL STERILIZE!) BEFORE INOCULATION 6 . , 13 ' .:' 0\ . ¦'¦:»','¦¦ 38 31 23 ' • . ' 10 .-.-¦¦ 11 0 '0 8 42 50 H 16 0 0 ;.. 0 31 69 18 8 0 0 0 37 63 22 . ': ¦ .10 0 0 0 0 100 26 11 0 0 0 0 100 30 10 0 0 0 10 90 ¦•;.'.¦ SOIL NOT STERILIZED BEFORE INOCULATION 6 13 0 15 31 31 23 10 8 0 0 0 75 25 14 11 0 .0 46 46 9 18 8 0 0 13 63 25 22 11 0 9 9 73 9 26 I. 12 0 ;.»!. .8 33 50 30 10 ' 0 , ¦; 0 10 60 30 'Soils at 6° and 10° C. were held it .those tempciatutei tot 70 days. All others were held at lie jpecificd tempcrJlurei for 89 dayj tefbre tramferr/ng to 22° C. for lubcrizau'on, 33 days afltt planting. it was being thoroughly mixed before potting. The moisture content of the soil at the time it was inoculated was brought up to about 20 per cent moisture dry weight, which was equal to 50 per cent of the moisture - holding capacity, and it was held at that point by daily watering based on weight. :-..-' .'.¦:_¦ ¦¦'.-, . - .... .¦¦ ; . ¦'' ¦ ... i ¦• '.¦ : The experiment was divided into seven sets of eight plants each, four in sterilized and four in unsterilized soil. These sets were placed in soil - temperature tanks held at the following temperatures: 6°, 10°; 14°, 18°, 22°, 26°, and 30° C. After inoculation the soils were held at these tempera - tures for 55 days before the seed pieces, previously sprouted in sterile sand, were transplanted. The plants at 6° and 10° C. developed so slowly that they were trans - ferred to a temperature of 22° C. 15 days after the seed pieces were trans - planted, while all. the other sets were transferred 19 days later, when tuber </seg>
         <seg id="p015">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 development was just starting at the optimum temperature. Thus the sets ar 6 and 10 were held at those temperatures for a total o£ 70 days and the other sets were held at the desired temperatures for 89 days before they were all placed at the same room temperature of 22° C. The effect of the soil temperature preceding tuber formation upon the envelopment of scab is shown in Table 6. No healthy tubers were produced in this experiment. The greatest amount ot scab occurred with soil sterilized betore inoculation and held at 22° and 26° for 89 days. Slightly Jess scab occurred in sterilized soil held at 30° and smaller amounts with the lower temperatures, particularly at 6° and 10°. In the soil that was not sterilized there were no consistent differences in the amount of scab in soils held at the different temperatures. Table '.—Bacteria and Actinomyces per gram of soil (dry weight) in sterilized soil, held at various temperatures, after inoculation with . Ictmomyces scabies. .5,,,| 21 '|J" ¦*''" ""*"¦¦"'"" » .l.m Jlicr inucubliun 89 days af.cr inoculation ¦ ""c **«'" | .VHwimno njcierij wiinomyccj Jlxrcria Actinomycci '"¦" ' ¦"'""'" "'""'"¦ ''¦' •&gt;'&lt;"&lt;•&gt;«&gt; Minn, /¦.,/. .!/,///„„ ilittiln , J^~ &#132;',', ', "' :!' ":¦* "¦• 0.2 171.8 H. 3 7.7 ,| ,'; '"' sl" H-i 27.9 89.9 75.2 1)6.5 •« ' ' ' *8" •"'¦« -&lt;5.6 59.0 87(1 59 6 v" ,;;, ;,'.' "¦* 1J"" '¦'¦" n.C 100.9 80.G UA _±_J^_J± z;, Mi "¦ «•* in % ihuJ 7X""n«' 'f,.r,L!"'l JZ 2 ° C' 7" 'bVI J"" in"cuUliun- »' W &gt;lw Wo&gt;c. Ac Soil samples were collected from the sterilized soils 21, 54, and 89 days after inoculation and the number of bacteria and Actinomyces were deter - rnmed by J.lution plate cultures (Table 7). The number and percentage of Actinomyces could be correlated with the amount of scab produced in the sterilized soil as shown in Table 6. Fewer Actinomyces occurred in the soils held at 6 and 10° C. than at the higher temperatures and these , "mV olls that had the leclst scab- At the hi Rhe« temperatures, 26 and 30 , the greatest total number of bacteria and Actinomyces was reached within 21 days, while the highest number at 22° was reached at the next sampling and at the lower temperatures at the third sampling. The n UmD c r and percentage of Actinomyces remained relatively constant at 26 C. The percentage of Actinomyces did not change greatly at 22° although the number increased at each sampling. At 10° and H° both the number and percentage tended to increase with increased time intervals up to the 89-day period. The great increase in both bacteria and Actinomy - ces at the third sampling was undoubtedly due to the fact that these soils were changed to 22° C. 19 days before the final sampling. fn the soils that were not sterilized before inoculation the average numbers of bacteria and Actinomyces were much less than with the steri- </seg>
         <seg id="p016">. Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab ... - i ¦ . . . lized soils, averaging 5, 11, and 15 million, respectively, on the three suc - cessive dates of sampling without any consistent differences in the total number of Actinomyces as a result of exposure to the different temperatures for different periods of time. There was, however, a decrease in the percent - age of Actinomyces at the lower temperatures, being 18 per cent at 6° and 21 per cent at 10° C, while at the other temperatures the percentages were between 24 and 29. There was no increase in the percentages with succes - ive sampling as in the sterilized soil. It is'clear that the results obtained following sterilization are not necessarily an indication of what would occur under field conditions. The effects of soil temperatures in the sterilized soil as presented here do, how - ever, explain the differences in the magnitude of the effect of soil tempera - tures when held constant throughout die life of the plant, as in the results presented by Dippenaar (4), who, working with unsterilized soil, did not find as great temperature effects as Jones, McKinney, and Fellows (9), who worked with sterilized soil. The greater infection in sterilized soil may be partially due to the man - ner of growth of Actinomyces. In this experiment two counts of Actinomy - ces colonies were made, one at the end of 4 to 5 days, the other after 10 to 14 days. McLennan (13) has shown that counts taken in this way with fungi can be used to differentiate spores and mycelium. While no work of this nature has been reported with Actinomyces, it is interesting to note that if they behave similarly to the fungi we may assume that the colonies appearing at the first reading are mycelial fragments and those at the second reading are both spores and mycelium. On this basis counts made on these soils indicate that when the cultures were made 54 days after inoculation, 84 per cent of the colonies in sterilized soil and 66 per cent in the nonsterilized soil were from mycelium. There is a great need for investigations dealing with the effect of environmental factors on the morphological development of soil-inhabiting pathogenes of this type before.the effect of the various factors can be correctly interpreted. " The single experiment here reported indicates that temperature may have an effect on the scab-producing power of the soil but that.the effect ( is very slight in unsterilized as compared with sterilized soils and more ex - tensive experiments than were here possible are heeded before definite con - clusions can be drawn. .-.'..- ! ¦•.:¦.'. •....¦" THE RELATION OF SOIL MOISTURE TO THE DISEASE j , Sanford (16, 17) and Martin (12) concluded from, their experimental evidence that high soil moisture is a limiting factor in the development of | potato scab. Sanford (17) also concluded, from his study of soil moisture in relation to the critical period for infection, that high soil moisture during the early stages of tuber development would prevent scab even though the soil became dry later in the season. Dippenaar (4) not only agrees regarding soil moisture as a limiting factor but further concludes that even after the tubers have become infected they will recover and slough' off the diseased tissue when the moisture </seg>
         <seg id="p017">Nebraska Agrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 content is raised, if they are stili actively growing. He does not agree with Word (16) that the influence of soil moisture is largely limited to the early stages of tuber development, although he does consider that the maximum influence is exerted during the first four weeks after the tubers are set. Dippenaar's conclusions are largely based upon an experiment in which the soil moisture content was changed at intervals beginning 30 days after emergence, and he assumes on the basis of Fellows' work (6) that all o! the tubers of an individual plant are set at about the same time It has been shown, however, by Werner (20) and others, that plants in a highly vegetative state may differentiate tubers over a considerable period of time and that the time, duration, and extent of tuber setting can be altered con - siderably by environmental factors. In contrast with the above, some of the older papers on this disease report an increased amount of scab with increased moisture. Beckwith (1) found that when scabby seed was irrigated there was 57 per cent oi scab, as contrasted with 32 per cent for the unirrigated. On manured soils he found an even greater difference. 71 and 30 per cent respectively. It has been previously mentioned that field observations in western Nebraska have revealed that potato scab is usually more severe in years of high rain - tall and of little importance in drouth years. In 1935 the certification records showed an average of 11.2 per cent of scab culls in potatoes from over 300 fields in western Nebraska when the effective rainfall 5 for the period of tuber development, August and September, was 4.43 inches. In contrast with this only 1.4 per cent of scab of a similar degree of severity was present in 1934, when the effective rainfall for the same period was only 1./ inches. These results conform with the general experience of farmers in lhat area over a period of years. It is also a matter of record that stall is just as great a problem under irrigation as in the dry-land areas. In a preliminary test conducted at the Scotts Bluff Substation it was found that withholding the las! irrigation (August 17) did not affect the amount ot scab as compared with those receiving an additional irrigation. The author has seen severely scabbed potatoes produced in sand cultures where the tubers were only one to two inches above the water level and in others where ihe sand was flooded with nutrient solution several times a clay. The moisture content was high enough to cause proliferation of the lenticels on these scabby potatoes (Plate 1). The above statements have dealt primarily with the disease, but there remains the question of just how the soil moisture exerts its influence. Dip - penaar (4), employing the Cholodny slide technique, came to the con - clusion that high soil moisture favored the development of bacteria which were antagonistic to the scab organism and that spore germination and growth of .-/. scabies were inhibited under these conditions. Sanford (17), using the dilution plate method, decided that the development of the causal organism in the soil is retarded by either very low or high moisture con - tents, although he found the disease in maximum amounts in very dry soil. Supplementary but indirect evidence of the effect of soil moisture may be 1 Effective rainfall ij here considered at 0.25 inch or more in 48 hourj. </seg>
         <seg id="p018">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab ¦ . " ¦ . . i found in the numerous statements in soil bacteriological literature to the effect that the Actinomycetes in general are favored, in comparison with the ; bacteria, by low soil moistures. • ' On the other hand^ Lutman, Livingston, and Schmidt (11), using the dilution plate method of studying bacteria and Actinomyces in relation to i the soil moisture of field soils during different seasons of the year, came to ¦ a different conclusion. They found that the Actinomyces counts roughly paralleled those of the total number of organisms, which were highest in winter with high soil moistures and lowest in summer with low soil moistures. They did not find any evidence of antagonism between bacteria and Actinomyces. The author (7) found by plating out samples of some 100 field soils, varying in moisture content from 8 to 32 per cent, that the percentage of Actinomyces was highest in the medium moisture group and lowest in either the extremely dry or wet soils, although the total number of organisms was highest in the high moisture samples. One phase of the soil moisture problem that has received relatively little attention is that-of the effect of different types of soils. It is possible that what might be considered low rainfall in one section of the country would be a hjgh rainfall in another section, as regards both actual precipitation and moisture-holding capacity of the soil. Inasmuch as the soil microorganisms live primarily in the colloidal film surrounding the soil particles, it is evident that in experiments with controlled water supply the lower the colloidal content of the soil the smaller will be the amount of water neces - sary for microbiological activities. Excess moisture in a soil would be ex - pected to inhibit the growth of aerobic organisms. It was therefore thought possible that the amount of water present in proportion to the water-holding capacity of the soil might have a greater influence on the disease than the actual water present on a dry-weight basis. . There have been practically no studies dealing with the effect of soil moisture and other factors upon the development of the pathogene in the soil preceding the infection period. In most of the studies constant soil moistures have been employed or the moisture content has been varied, as in Dippenaar's work (4), during the period of tuber development. The emphasis throughout has been placed upon the conditions essential for infection. Because of the many contradictory statements in the literature and the author's inability to correlate the occurrence of scab in the field with much of the published data, it was felt that other factors must be involved and that further vrark was needed before an adequate explanation of the relation of soil moisture to ,the disease could be found. The following experiments were planned to determine three points: first, the effect of soil '•' moisture during the period of infection;, second, the influence of soil moist - ure preceding the period of tuber formation upon the development of the causal organism and as a result the scab-producing power of the soil; and third, the effect of soil moisture in different types of soils varying in their moisture-holding capacity. : ; Soil Moisture Experiment I.—-The first preliminary experiment employ - ed the soils. previously used in the soil temperature'experiments. These </seg>
         <seg id="p019">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 were originally in two sets, sterilized and unsterilized, and the soils of each set were thoroughly mixed and then divided into high and low moisture sets, one being held near the minimum for growth and the other above the optimum. The plants were grown in seven-inch clay pots and the relative moisture contents were maintained approximately without weighing. Table B.— The effect of soil sterilization and moisture content upon scab jolowing inoculation with A. scabies (Soil Moisture Experiment 1). . L Classes of tubers determined by percent- Sr , I Numbrr Wci s hl aRC of surfa£c Ka|lby I j Jxnl Irejtmcnl of of j j j ¦ ; '"I-"' &amp;*«• 0 I 0-2 I 2-25 ) 25-75 | "5-100 ,Vn. Grjmi P.cl. V.lt. P.cl. Pel. P.cl. I Mcnlucl-h.ch m»i&gt;.ure . . . 33 1.460 1 4 35 34 26 ! Mtrilimi—Vw mimiim: .41 WO 0 0 3 0 97 i No. .itrili/cl-liiKh m,,i..ufc . 36 1.795 3 12 84 I 0 1 N,,. Mtrillleil-liiw mmslurr W 1.111 « 0 21 15 64 It is evident from Table 8 that low soil moisture greatly favored the development of scab. Even with the high soil moisture severe scab occurred in the soil that had previously been sterilized. The effect of soil moisture, however, was greater than that of sterilization. Soil Moisture Experiment 2.—ln this experiment the plants were grown in three-gallon earthenware jars and moisture requirements were deter - mined by frequent weighings. Sterilized and unsterilized soils were used, and each was divided into moisture sets of 20 plants each held at 30, 50, and 70 per cent of the moisture-hoWing capacity, which was 58.7 per cent dry weight as determined by the use of one-centimeter cups. The soil was inoculated with ./. scabies N-23 at the rate of two petri-dish cultures per plant at the time the sprouted seed pieces were transplanted. The plants grown in the sterilized soil, which were larger and more vigorous than those in unsterilized soil, developed an abnormal condition about rive weeks after the start of the experiment. Many ot the plants were wilting and a number started to develop small tubers at the surface of the ground, similar to those often found in the field as a result of the death of the underground stem due to Rhitzoctonia or other causes. Later examina - tion showed that the underground stems of these plants were severely infected with .1. scabies. This infection sometimes involved all tissues of the stem and resulted in a soft rot. Infection of the roots, par - ticularly at the base, was also noted. Cultures made from such stems and roots as well as microscopic examination of sections always re - vealed the presence of Actinomyces. This wilting, caused by stem and root infection, occurred only in the sterilized soils and was more severe at the low moisture contents where six plants wilted as compared with four at the medium moisture and three at the high moisture content. At the close of the experiment it was found that 60 per cent of the stems were infected in the unsterilized soil but that infection was not severe enough to cause wilt, while 91 per cent of infection had occurred in the sterilized soil. </seg>
         <seg id="p020">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab It was evident from these results that the inoculum applied was probably excessive and that the Jack of competition, particularly in the sterilized soils, allowed the pathogene to develop profusely and cause a severe infection of stems and roots. While no reports are available of such severe attacks in the field, it is evident that the organisms can produce a stem rot under some . conditions at least. Later findings have shown that Actinomyces are more commonly present in stem and root lesions and in root hairs of potato plants in the field than has previously been reported. L. R, Jones, McKin-^, ney, and Fellows (9) report similar infection but of a less severe type in their soil-temperature experiments and A. Powell Jones (8) describes infection of roots and etiolated shoots in his histological study of the dis - ease. ¦¦.'....' ¦'-, ' •.'-.¦'. . . ¦ Table %—The effect of soil moisture upon scab development (Soil Moisture ¦¦'..'" Experiment 2). son ~ , r «- «£?JgB.» T . V hoUllng capacity tubers 0 ) 0-2 ( 2-25 | 25-75 | 75-100 f«- No. P.cl. P.ct. P.cl. P.cl. p.ci. STERILIZED SOIL 30 &lt;3\ ¦ »-..•' I 16 .13 54 SO •-• . 80 5 ¦ ¦ 5 14 31 « ¦'. 70. 102 2 ¦¦¦..- .14 23 36 25 UNSTERILIZED SOIL 30 ¦;'¦ 47 : 2 25. 32 26 15 50 . ¦ . f,9 ¦•¦...« - U 26 12 4 70 . KB 29 26 28 H 3 Analysis of the lovv-moiiture sen on (he basis of soil surrounding each individual tuber! Tubers in dry 50i1....... 28 ' : 25 32 32 11. 0 One-halt of tuber in dry soil.. 34 0 18 35 35 12 Tubers in wet soil 48 .' 0 -4 8 10 77 1 See discussion of data. • ' . l Scab was much more severe in the sterilized than in the unsterilized soils and it was likewise more severe with low moisture (Table ?). The effect of soil moisture was partially obscured by the severity of infection in all the sets with sterilized soil. ' . ' iA more detailed examination o£ the tubers in the low-moisture sets re - vealed an unexpected condition. The soil in these was very dry at the start and the small amount of water added at each weighing did not become equally distributed through the soil. As a result the soil immediately sur - rounding the inverted clay pot to which the water was added had a much higher moisture content than that in the rest of the container. It was noted that the tubers tended to form at this point and many tubers there - fore were formed in such a position that part of the tuber was in contact with the moist soil and the rest of the tuber surrounded by dry soil. By careful examination of the position of each tuber at digging, it was found that scab had developed only" on that portion of the tuber in contact with the moist soil. In Table 9 is recorded the amount of scab in relation to the position of the tuber as regards soil moisture. Both the sterilized and un- </seg>
         <seg id="p021">z Table 10. — The effect of the soil moisture (in relation to the moisture-holding capacity) and of previous sterilization £ upon the occurrence- oj stub and the numbers oj biicterni, .tetinomyecs, and fungi (Sod Moisture Experiment 3). &gt; Ratio water Cl.im.c-. ..I tubes. deicrniine.l Mi,,,.or_ mi.m. l*r cram of uil (dry wrifht) ' &gt; Wjter to in.iiX-ic by prrtriil.n:c r.l -uri.i.c . . . s (dry holdinc Tube _s,.ibl,,^ 71 .1..n .iflrt inm-ul-tinn 95 .lays jflcr iiwculaiinn j&gt;" welKht) niucur „ I v , | :" 25 | .«; 75 | 75 111" ; lli.trru | A.lin.nnuc. | runiil li.i.lcrij | Auini.myccs | TunßJ £ i.nMi-cisr sun. si imi i/i n ?5 XI. g ¦&gt;(, l» ill IT U II II «"ii (rf,2 I7JII J3» 184.11 61.0 3W1.7 i 9.0 g ir. &gt; ii » :&lt; m. :i n iikmi w.3 «.» 7.7 M.4 r*3 «.ci 33.7 c Ht.J 7S tl 1 -'1 2: 1^ .'S- "1 W1..1 In 117 K.I 'Id. I i.4 .&lt;« • .. S , . ' t*l nnllii-il S'HI. I'll s s\Mi Nil KM.I/ID _| 11. I .'l. .': -'&lt; .7 IK .7 2Jl.ii 66. -t Ilill HI, 2 c5f,.(l 49.5 261.0 50 5 15.2 45 25 -I s 2S J2 2H 111.(1 95.4 5.3 4.6 55.0 87.8 8.1 12.2 _P 31.9 75 26 4 4 If 12 12 54.1 17.4 1.4 2.6 K3.9 98.2 1.5 1.8 &gt; HIM Vi Ml 15 In Sll 5 II- ll.tl 6K.li fi.s 30. X 191.7 (1.7 2H.3 66.6 14.0 33.0 184.0 0.4 «,,' 45 14 21 7 57 H (1 20.5 6»..l u.i 31.2 163.(1 (1.5 24.0 6K.0 11.1 31.4 209.0 0.6 50 6(1.2 75 27 0 56 41 4 0 22.8 71.0 9.1 28.4 235.0 0.7 27.5 68.8 12.2 30.5 273.0 0.7 jri rciMI'O.ST SOU. II.US S.\Nl&gt; NOT STI.KILI7.FI&gt; &gt; 11. 1 26 19 (1 32 6« (I (I 15.4 62.6 9.1 36.9 110.0 0.5 20.3 69.2 8.9 30.3 HB.O 0.5 o 19.2 45 12 0 25 58 17 I) 16.0 65.0 ».5 34.3 181.0 0.7 15.2 67.4 7.2 32.0 M 7.0 0.6 X 31.9 75 4.! 5 16 5.3 19 7= S2.G 76.7 9.7 22.9 173.0 0.4 29.8 79.4 7.5 20.1 166.0 0.4 a 1 liv the sterilized soils the presence of r:ip'ul-Krowin« colonies of Mticors made it inipossihlc to mnkc accurate, counts of the number of fungi. Tlic percent- p :iho are therefore based only on the number of bacteria aiiil Atiinomyces in the sterilized soits. r - A considerable amount of the severe scab in tln-sc sets was of the deep or pitted type, while the common type of scab predominated in all other sets. £j 20 </seg>
         <seg id="p022">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab sterilized soils behaved similarly in this respect and are therefore grouped together in the table. It is clear from the results that when all the tubers were grouped together the low moisture content resulted in the most scab but the individual tubers in these sets became infected only when in contact with moist soil. The author has repeatedly made similar observa - tions in trie field. In dry soils scab infections are often found on the under side of the tuber where the soil moisture is slightly higher than that in contact with the upper part. v " . Soil Moisture Experiment 3.—This experiment was started for the pur - pose of comparing the effect of the actual moisture content on a dry-weight basis with the percentage of the moisture-holding capacity. A rich com - posted soil was used which had a moisture-holding capacity of 80.4 per cent as determined by one-centimeter cups. Sand was added to half of this soil ; ... at the rate of one part to two parts of soil by volume and the moisture - holding capacity of this mixture was found to be 42.6 per cent. Each of these soils was divided into three sets at 26, 45, and 75 per cent of their ; respective moisture-holding capacities. A comparison of the first two columns in Table 10 will show that with these percentages the lowest - moisture set with composted soil contained practically the same amount : of water on a dry-weight basis as the medium- moisture set in. the soil plus sand. Likewise, the medium set in the compost soil was only slightly higher than the high-moisture set in the soil plus sand. The two; soils were again divided into sterilized and unsterilized por - tions and were inoculated, as in previous experiments, with A. scabies. The plants were grown in four-gallon earthenware jars and the moisture , requirements were determined by frequent weighings, the water being add - ed both to the surface and to a subsurface reservoir. ¦"..' Most of the scab was of the common type. The only deep scab occurred ;'.¦¦¦ in the high-moisture sets of the sterile compost and the unsterilized compost plus sand. The sterilized sets with both soils produced more : severe scab than the unsterilized (Table 10). The effect of soil moisture on scab was variable. In the sterilized compost soil and the unsterilized ¦¦. compost plus sand the severity of scab increased greatly with increased soil ; moistures and the most scab occurred in each instance with the higher per - ¦ centage of the moisture-holding capacity. This would indicate that the percentage of moisture-holding capacity rather than the actual water present |¦' is the more important factor. This conclusion, however, will not hold for the sterilized compost plus sand and the unsterilized compost soil, where , there was but little difference in the amount of scab with different soil ! moistures, or where the medium moisture content was slightly more favor - able for scab. • : At two periods, approximately 71 days and 95 days after inoculation, I soil samples were obtained from each set, each sample being a composite of ¦). three borings of the soil for the full depth of the crocks. ¦ The results of the dilution plate counts of bacteria, Actinomyces, and ; fungi show certain definite trends even though samples were only plated twice during the experiment. It is evident from Table 10 that sterilization </seg>
         <seg id="p023">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 greatly increased the numbers of bacteria, which were still very high 95 days after the stan of the experiment. In these sterilized soils there was also a great increase in the numbers of both bacteria and Actinomyces with decreasing moisture contents, the percentage of the moisture-holding capa - city being of greater importance than the actual water present. With the higher soil moisture there was also a very marked increase in the percent - age of bacteria, with a corresponding decrease in the percentage of Actino - myces. The sharp drop in the percentage of Actinomyces in the medium - and high-moisture sets as compared with the low was particularly pro - nounced in the sterilized compost plus sand. It was impossible to make accurate counts of the fungi in the sterilized soils because of the abundance ol Mucors in the samples, colonies of which rapidly spread over the plates. Jn the unsterilized sets there was a much smaller number of bacteria, the highest counts being only about half as much as the lowest counts in the sterilized sets. The numbers of Actinomyces were greater in the un - sterilized soils at the medium and high soil moistures and lower with a low soil moisture as compared with the sterilized soils, although the percentages were about the same at the low moisture contents. There was very little effect of soil moisture on the numbers of micro - organisms in the unsterilized soils. The percentages, however, followed the same trend as in the sterilized soils, with an increase in the percentage of bacteria and a decrease in the percentage of Actinomyces with the higher soil moistures. The effect on the percentage of fungi was variable. The ef - fect of soil moistures as regards both numbers and percentages was much less marked in these unsterilized sets as compared with the very marked differences occumng in the sterilized soils. There was no apparent correlation between either the number or per - centage of Actinomyces and the occurrence of scab. In the two. sets where the amount ot scab increased with increasing moisture contents, there was a corresponding decrease in both numbers and percentages of Actinomyces. Soil Moisture Experiments 4, 5, and 6.—The influence of the soil moist - ure content during the period preceding tuber formation, as contrasted with that during the period of tuber development when infection would occur, was studied by experiments in the greenhouse during three successive years. During the first two years the plants were grown in seven-inch clay pots. In 1930-31 (Experiment -1) each set contained 10 plants, while the following year 20 plants were used for each set. In 1932-33 (Experiment 6) the plants were grown in compartments (78x58 inches) of a greenhouse bench in eight inches of soil, with 24 plants in each compartment. In all of these tests the soil moisture content was held approximately at the desired point by careful watering so that the low-moisture sets were kept slightly above the wilting point, the medium sets were at about optimum moisture content, and the high sets were kept saturated. While there was naturally considerable variation in soil moisture in an experiment ot this type, the three groups covered such a wide range that there was but little danger of overlapping and the plant growth and weight of tubers produced always indicated the great differences. While experiments of this </seg>
         <seg id="p024">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab ¦ Table 11.— The effect of soil moisture preceding and during the period of tuber formation upon the development of scab. ~ Soil moisture ¦ Clasjes of tubers, determined by per- Set Number - ¦¦' centace of lurface lobby • ' No. Before I After of ! j i ~T~ tuber set | tuber set tubers 0 | 0-2 | 2-25 | 25-100 ... No. Pxt. P.el. P.rt. p.n. EXPERIMENT ' 4, 1930-31 (IN CLAY POTS) SOIL INOCULATED AT PLANTING I! • . Lo»r . 30 ¦ 13 . 10 .- 17 60 I I' Medium Medium 34 12 .' '¦ ¦ 9 30 50 f H/sh 35 6 20 51 23 ¦ ¦ .' ¦¦' 1 &#132; &#132; L°K 2' 15 7: 37 41 5 Medium Medium 29 24 2» . 38 10 :;-¦ 6 High 37 •: 46 -.19 27 ,8 EXPERIMENT 5, 1931-32 (IN CLAY VOTS) SOIL INOCULATED AT PLANTING • 1A Low Low 70 . 3 1 6 90 ',¦¦-.'¦ IB Medium Medium 89 1 9 19 71 ; 'c H'Bh Hi B h 107 42 13 22 23 2A f Low 70 1 3 21 74 211 Medium ' { Medium 94 2 4 25 69 |; 2c I Hish . 103 9 11 22 58 i . SOIL INOCULATED AT TUBER SET , 3\ Low Urn. 54 28 . 26 ¦¦ 26 '" 20 ; 3D .Veilium MnHum 79 65 • 24 II 0 ', 3C Hi s h High 101 86 8 . fi 0 SOIL NOT INOCULATED ' -. 4A Low Low 24 54 29 17 0 41) Medium Medium 41 76 17 '7 0 4C Hish High . , 47 . 87 11 2 0 EXPERIMENT 6, 1932-33 (IN BENCHES) SOIL INOCULATED AT PLANTING 1 Low 41 42 22 24 12 - 2 Low Medium 56 39 II 43 7 3 •• I High 107 . : 49 : 24 26 1 4 t Lou- -II 29 17 4» 5 i .5 Medium Medium 56 36 11 50 4 ¦ ¦ .;&lt;¦-. High 119 .29 23 44 4 &gt;....;• " Low. 69 46 16 32 i 5 i ..'¦¦¦¦!.. Hi s h Medium 75 . "' &#132; 21 25 50 3 9. . ¦ ¦¦¦ High 121 43 . ' 26 . 26 6 -.'. .. SOIL NOT INOCULATED ; ' 10 Low Low 32 • 87 13 ' ' 0 0 i ¦ II Medium Medium 59 -95 2 3 0 : . 12 Hish .".. High . : 136 91 7- 2 0 :. ¦ l Tile soil was sterilized before planting. In all other sets' the soil was unslcrilizcd. ¦ ¦ type are in some ways not as accurate as those in which the water require - ments are determined by weighing, they do have the advantage of more uniform distribution of water through the soil. There was also the advant - age of a much greater quantity of soil per plant in the bench experiments ¦;'¦;¦..¦ (Experiment 6, Table 11) and all plants in each set were in one compart - r :¦-¦ ment, thus eliminating the individual pot variation occurring in the other .; '-"tests. :¦:'.¦.;,., '.. ¦¦„..¦¦ - '..!" ¦ . '.', ; ":.. '-\--_ - .'¦... ¦•'¦ •¦'¦'- The greatest source of error was in changing the moisture contents at the time of tuber formation. Those in which the moisture content was in - creased could be changed immediately, but when a lower moisture con - tent was desired it took considerable time for the soil to dry out and the j plants required more water to keep them from wilting. As a result the </seg>
         <seg id="p025">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 low moisture contents following previous medium or high moisture were never as low as those started at a low moisture. The results presented in Table 11 show that the disease was much worse with low than with high moisture contents. This was more evident in the first two years' experiments in clay pots than in the open bench experiments of 1932-33. Scab was also more severe in sterilized than in unsterilized soil (Experiment 4, Table 11) but trie effect of soil moisture was similar. The influence of the soil moisture content preceding the period of tuber formation was evident in Experiment 5, 1931-32. In sets IB and 28, which were held at about optimum moisture content throughout the life of the plant, the percentages of scab, particularly of the severe type, were almost identical. Set 2A, in which the moisture content was lowered dur - ing tuber development, did not have as much severe scab as IA, where it had been low during the entire experiment. Likewise 2C produced more scab than IC, showing the more favorable effect of a medium moisture content as compared with high moisture on the development of the patho - gene in the soil preceding the infection period. In the same experiment there was an even greater decrease in scab with constant high soil moist - ures when the inoculum was not added until the period of tuber develop - ment (Set 3), than when the soil was inoculated at the start of the experi - ment. The uninoculated checks (Set 4) showed the presence of the patho - gene in the soil used in this experiment, and the effect of soil moisture was the same as in the inoculated sets. The inconsistency of soil moisture experiments was evident in Experi - ment rt, 1932-33, where there was very little effect of soil moisture either preceding tuber formation or during the entire experiment. There were some slight differences in the number of severely infected tubers, but if all infected tubers are considered the differences are either negligible or in - consistent. In this experiment the drying-out process when the moisture content was lowered took longer than in the clay pots and might have in - fluenced the results, but this would not apply to Sets 1, 2, and 3, where the moisture content was low preceding tuber formation. It is not clear why these results were so different from those of the previous year. The amount of inoculum per cubic foot of soil was less than in the previous tests but this should not have affected the influence of soil moisture, which was so evident in the uninoculated soil of Experiment 5. In Experiment 2 it was noted that stem infection occurred in the inocu - lated soils that had previously been sterilized and was most severe in the drier soils. This stem infection was again evident in Experiment 5 (Table 12). In contrast with the previous observations, both the number of infected stems and the severity of infection were greatest with the highest soil moist - ure contents and when the soil had been inoculated at the beginning of the experiment. The least stem infection occurred in the drier, uninoculated soils. In Experiment 6 soil samples taken at the close of the experiment failed to reveal any significant differences that could be correlated with the occur- </seg>
         <seg id="p026">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab Table YL.—Jhe effect of soil moisture upon the injection of stems with A. ' - ¦ scabies {Experiment 5, 1931-32)} '. S£t Soil moisture Number i Severity of stem infection No. ' Before I After of ¦ I ~j j 1 . tuber set T tuber set '.'"¦" None ) Slight | Medium | Severe Ka. P.ci. P.ct. P.ct. p,a. SOIL INOCULATED AT PLANTING M Low Low ' 26 58 27 8 I IB Medium ¦ Medium 25 36 . 32 16 16 1C High Hijn 27 22 4 22 52 2K f Low . 32 « 22 22 12 2B Medium A Medium 35 29 29 26 17 2C L High 35 6 6 34 54 ... SOIL INOCULATED AT TUBER SET ' 3A Low Low . 30 73 13 13 ' 0 . 3B Medium Medium 34 100 0 0 0 . 3C High High . ,29 66 17 ¦ 7 10 • SOIL NOT INOCULATED • 4A Low Low 15 .100 0 0 0 ; 4B Medium Medium 17 100 0 0 0 4C High High | 10 90 10 '-. , 0 0 ¦ . 'See Table 11, Experiment 5, for data on tuber infection. '-. ¦ ' . ' &gt; ¦ ' -¦ - ¦ I rence o£ scab with regard to either the number or percentages of bacteria, fungi, and Actinomyces as" determined by dilution plate cultures. Three series of samples were taken from each of the low, medium, and i high moisture soils of Experiment 6at monthly intervals, starting three 1 weeks after inoculation. These likewise failed to reveal any significant ; differences that could be correlated with the occurrence of scab. There was ; an increase in the percentage of Actinomyces with increasing moisture ! contents in both the inoculated and uninoculated soils (Table 13). This ;;¦'¦ result is just the opposite of what might be expected on the basis of the ! published data of Dippenaar (4) and other workers. ; In addition to the usual soil samples for the dilution plates, a set of samples was obtained from the soil in close contact with the potato tubers. i The tubers were carefully removed from the soil, all the loosely adhering Table 13;— The effect o] soil moisture upon the numbers of bacteria, Actin - :- qmyces, and fungi in inoculated and uninoculated soil, x ' ¦¦ „ &#132;."¦- _ , . Pcrcenuge of organisms in each group | Per cent soil rnois- Total number — 2-^ 1 b y \ - . ture (dry weight) of organisms . Bacteria ] Actinomyces I ¦ Fungi .! ¦¦¦-.' . Percent '.. Millions Percent ' Percent Percent • INOCULATED SOIL L0w..... 16.6 12.1 79.9 18.8 1.3 i Medium 21.1 9.5 79.2 19.3 1.6 p. High 28.7 10.4 76.4 21.9 1.7 I ¦.'¦;¦ .¦¦ - . . UNINOCULATED SOIL \ . 1 Low 16.1 U. 4 82.7 15.9 13 ; Medium 23.6 13.1 81.6. 17.4 1.1 j High 30.3 . 13.4 78.7 19.7 1.5 ¦The data presented are the averages of three leriei of samples taken at Intervals of one month, i the first sample being taken three weeks after inoculation. All data arc on the dry-weight basis, 'j For data on tcab see Table 11, Experiment 6, 1932-33. . . ' . </seg>
         <seg id="p027">Nebraska Agrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 soil was detached by shaking, and the tubers were then immersed in a measured amount of sterile water and the soil removed by vigorous shaking. Estimated dilutions were made from this suspension after the tuber was ¦ removed and plates were then poured. The exact dilution was calculated Liter by evaporating the unused portion of the suspension to dryness and determining the dry weight of soil in the original suspension. This method . •¦: has been used repeatedly by the author in field studies with roots and under- ''. ¦ ground plant parts and always reveals a much higher number of micro- s organisms than do the usual soil samples. In the present test the total number of bacteria and Actinomyces in the low-moisture series was 294 • i million, with only 0.7 per cent Actinomyces. In the medium-moisture set i it was 90 million, with 0.8 per cent Actinomyces, while in the high-moist- I urc set it was 102 million and 1.9 per cent. The total count was 10 to 20 ' times as great as in the usual soil sample (Table 13), because of the great ; increase in bacteria rather than Actinomyces, which were no more numer - ous and the percentages of which were of course greatly reduced. The per - centage of Actinomyces. however, was increased with an increase in the soil moisture content. ¦'; The results obtained by direct microscopic examinations of slides buried j for two weeks in the soils likewise failed to aid in the interpretation of the j experimental data previously presented. The data given in Table 14 do not check with the results of the dilution plates. Actinomyces in the form of • \ both hyphae and spores were much more numerous in the dry soils. This corresponds to the results obtained by Dippenaar (4). &lt;! In the preceding experiments there was some indication of an effect of .. J the soil moisture content during the period preceding tuber formation upon ;; Tabu H.- -Effect of soil moisture upon the development of Actinomyces, ; bacteria, and jungi in soil inoculated with A. scabies. ¦ j - scii mmMurc Actimtniycej During Spirjls jnd Bacteria Fungi i ''""""" r.pt'urc '"I'"" ""h?pto"' ¦'»'"' . j M.IPKS PLACED IN Still. IT..V WEEKS AFTER INOCULATION 1 &#132; i r i^ rz -*-+ ' ~ +^r+ ++ ¦ &gt;¦ » cJ ,» m vwmn, ;+ + --' r XX IX ¦ ' ¦ ¦¦ :.. j -\\ERV(.F nY IHRU- SKIS OF SI.IIIF.S I'LACF.I) IS TUB SOIL H. 16. AND IS WF.FKS AFTER &gt; IMXLLUION—SOIL MOISTURES CHANGED AFTER H WEF.K!i :¦ 1^ ~* 7 *T V ~- ' \ Li ( w Mclium * j. i Uw High ++ - * ++ __^____ '¦; | ¦ ~ i Mciiium !.'&gt;«' ** ** **" ¦ ¦ i Mcilium Mnlium * * * * +t ¦ _ ! Mciiium lli ß h - * * +_J_ ' } "&gt;iirt u.w + + '-- -v + * \ High Mnlium * + + ** *T+ tt 1+ '{ High High - + -J_ ' i 1 Duplicjic were u\cil an.! jproximately 200 ficl.U were examined on each sliilc. 1 Symbols jrt: —. ncgjliie, t [race; t+, few; * * i-, common; + ++&#132; aliunilanl. I' ] i • i i i ij </seg>
         <seg id="p028">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab the incidence of scab. It was thought possible that if this period was ex - tended over some months before planting, the differences resulting from the various treatments might be more clear cut. Accordingly, Experiment 7 was planned, which was essentially a continuation of Experiment 6 (1932-33, Table 11). No additional inoculum was added to the soil during the 1933-34 tests. Immediately after harvest of the tubers of Experiment 6 in April, 1933, all the soils were brought to optimum moisture content and held at that point for about two months. On June 15 the new treatments were started and these were not changed until November 25. One week later all sets were planted with healthy seed pieces previously sprouted in sterile sand. The complete history of the soils for the two-year period and the amount of scab in 1934 are shown in Table 15. Table 15.—The effect of. soil moisture and other treatments before planting upon development of scab and upon the soil microflora (Soil Moisture Experiment 7.) . :'¦'• ¦ '. I Set Number' Item : ; ; I" ¦¦ . . I 1 - 1- -2 - 1 -3 - I -i -- | 5 | 6 | 7 | 8 | 9 i . "'¦'¦: Moiuutc content and hiuory of the soil (l^=low, M=Medium, H=High) . Hinting, Nov. IS, 1932 ¦ ¦¦' ': ' ¦ ' to.tubcrscl 3 L L L M M M H H H Tuber-Jet to harvest, . •-..-.. - .- . Apt. 8, 1933 L : M H H M L H , M L April 8 io June 15, 1933. M M MM M M M M M June 15 10 planting, ¦ I ¦ : ¦ Nov. 30. 1933........ Airdry' Air dry* H . H , M Sand' Manure" Barley" Naph - ¦ ¦ ' '¦ ' - thalcnt? After planting, 1W3 : 34 * L M M H M H M M M ¦ '.; Number of tubcri 25 34 85 109 63 11 . 60 61 41 ]'¦¦ Weight of tubers (g.)!.'.. 1,250 3,000 8,600 ; 10,600 3,600 2,450 3,800 3,450 2,550 Classes of tubcri determined by percentage of area scabby: 1 0 0.r;.) ..;.. 100.0 100.0 4.7 52 3 92.1 95.1 95.0 82.0 85.4 0-2 (/..«.)... 0.0 0.0 36.5 38.5 7.9 2.4 3J 18.0 12.2 2-25 (p.a.)...; 0.0 0.0 55.3 8.3 . 0.0 2.4 1.7 0.0 2.4 :'¦ 25-100 (p.«.). 0.0 0.0 3.5 0.9 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0- 0.0 Microorganisms per gram o£ soil (dry weight) . • Total (n;/7/«iiw&gt; ..... 6.2 4.6 10J 13.2 3.6 1.9" 5.8 A3. 4.9 Actilu&gt;mycei(miHioiii). 3.2 1.2 2.4 1.8: 0.6 0.5 0.9 1.1 '1.2 Actinomyce* (p.a.).. 51.6 26.2 23.1 13.6 17.9 26.6 IS.B 26.7 23.8 Dactcria (p.rf.) 45.1 69.6 76.0 85.6 79.4 . 70.0 82.9 71.0 72.6 Fungi (/&gt;.«.).. 3.2 4.3 0.9 0.7 2.8 3.4 1.4 2.3 3.6 : ¦ "' s Each let consisted of 25 plants. . . ¦ . 3 All soils were held at a medium moisture: content for one month after inoculation October 15, : 1932. . ,¦ ¦¦-";¦¦. ". '¦¦¦'¦ ';".'¦ :. "Sets 6 to 9 were held at •medium moisture content during this period. Sand and wtW-roUtd : stable manure were added at the rate.of 1 part to 2of soil by volume. The barley was grown dur-. ; ing the summer and turned under about a month before planting. Naphthalene. was added at the . ; rate of 1 pound to 21 cubic feet of toil. . " ¦¦¦ .'¦'¦'. ". - .',- - - - *At the time of sampling for dilution plates the soil moisture in Set 1 was at 53 per cent of • moisture-holding capacity; the medium-moisture .Sets 2, 3, 5, and 7 varied from 67 to 73 per cent; } 2nd the high-moisture Set ¦} was 90 per cent! of the moisture-holding capacity. Self 6', 8, and 9 . . varied from low to medium moisture. j ' '.:.--'-: i The plants in Set 4 with high moisture grew the most rapidly and pro - v duced the largest crop; those in Set 3 where the moisture content was I dropped from high to medium at planting time gave nearly as large a 1 yield. This was partly due to the fact that during the first few weeks of i ¦. - ' ¦ ¦¦¦ ¦¦-.; ,';¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p029">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 the experiment this soil was still above the moisture content of the other sets that had been previously kept at a medium moisture content. Set 1, with a minimum moisture content, produced the smallest crop. Manure as applied in Set 7 gave only a slightly increased yield over the untreated Set 5. The results as regards scab infection were very clear cut but did not check with many of the previous experiments. A large amount o£ scab occurred only in Sets 3 and 4. These were the same two sets that had the largest crop. The scab in these two sets was also of a more severe type with some deep scab, while the other sets were mostly common scab. The dry soil of Set 1 and the medium moisture soil of Set 2 which had previously been air dry were entirely free from scab. There was a great difference in lioth scab and tuber development in Set 2, previously dry, and Set 3, pre - viously at high moisture content, although both sets were held at a medium moisture content during tuber formation. The addition of manure in Set 7 resulted in slightly less scab than in the untreated Set 5, although the dif - ference was hardly great enough to be significant. Neither the turning under ot barley nor the addition of naphthalene reduced scab; in fact there was slightly more in these sets than in any of the others except Sets 3 and 4. Soil samples were plated out from all sets during the period of tuber formation, but neither the number nor the percentage of Actinomyces could lie correlated with the amount of scab (Table 15). The highest number and percentage (51.6 per cent) of Actinomyces occurred in the dry soil of Set 1, which had no scab. The lowest percentage (13.6) of Actinomy - ces occurred in the high-moisture soil of Set 4, which had next to the largest amount ot scab. Set 3, with the largest amount of scab, had next to the highest number of Actinomyces and a percentage about the same as the other sets that had very little scab. The addition of manure to Set 7 did not increase the number or percentage of Actinomyces. Neither the turning under of barley nor the addition of naphthalene or sand had any great effect upon the percentage of Actinomyces, all of which were slightly higher than the untreated soil in Set 5, although there was a marked reduction in the total number of organisms with the addition of sand. Slides were placed in the soils of Sets 1, 3, 4, and 5 about five weeks after planting and left for ten days. An examination of these showed abundant hyphae of Actinomyces in Sets 3 and 5, with only a slight amount in the low-moisture Set 1 and the high-moisture Set. 4. Spirals were present only in Set 5, while free spores were abundant in Sets 1 and 5 with only a few present in Sets 3 and 4. The results obtained in this experiment, which was a continuation of the previous year's test without the addition of new inoculum, might have been greatly influenced by the preceding soil treatments. It is possible that the air-drying of the soil in Sets 1 and 2, where the soil moisture was as low as 3.7 per cent for four months before planting, resulted in partial steriliza - tion which greatly reduced the numbers of the scab organism, although the number and percentage of all Actinomyces were very high in Set 1 (Table 15). Certainly the data do not indicate that A. scabies is favored by such dry conditions or that it is inhibited by high soil moistures such as occurred </seg>
         <seg id="p030">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab in Sets 3 and 4 before planting and in Set 4 during the growth o£ the plants. These results are very different from those reported by (4) and Sanford (16,17). Likewise, the data for the manured sod in Set 7 do not bear out the oft-repeated assertion that the appl.cat.on of manure eliminate the possibility of any variation in the amounts.of inoculum at the start of the test, such as occurred m Exper^ntj^other f «r /Fxoenment 8) was started in the winter of 1934-35. This experiment s£HS?ta &amp;¦« benches as the preceding ovf""**™ fbout the same moisture as during the preceding 40 daytand Aebgh- T.bli 16. I. took one ™* » Jrj «* !*»"» !•'» d=tad pom. and 24 nd pon,«» «™ 4M planted m -* "ff^J (November 13), alter having been sprouted ,n mnlized sand. 11k Of* - £ess agSj*ffis?JSJSS2««* bo* </seg>
         <seg id="p031">Table 16.— The influence of sail moisture preceding and during the growth of rhe plant upon the development of potato &gt; scab (Soil Moisture Experiment 8). £* pijininc I [.i...v.,, c i (i | (&gt;: I ::s | is mo o | 02 | 225 | 25 mo jo 1 Air dry 1.,,, v ,75 Jl I l*i (.11.11 411.11 (] II Si. 2 Jf, H n II ? - Atr dry 1.1 Medium 21.1 '.'J U. 711 «*S.7 4.3 n (1 c,| (i y 0 0 () y 3 ir Jr &gt; Ills'" H.&lt; !-'«. I..mm Ui.li f. 4 II (I &lt;11.4 It 0 1) -i 4 Medium 1.,,, v ir.il .'S 4711 Ni.li 411.11 II II 51.1 aO7) 0 0 if 5 Medium 34.2 Mnliuin 25.11 47 1.25" '«.» 4.2 [1 I) 96 0 4 0 II I) &gt; 6 Medium High .14. 1 is S.ifti «i.4 17.6 0 0 75.4 24.6 DO 3 7 Hjch l.mv M 1.5 11 1,310 41.5 ill !.K Til 2(ui 71.» 5X 2J ~ Z « Hill I 42.1 Mnlium 24.0 HI .1,4411 ill 4II.» 4.'l 1.2 55.X 3«.0 4.&lt; i 0.6 S3 9 Hisl" Hisl" JW 1»7 5.6)11 91.6 6.5 0.9 11.1 90.6 7.5 0.5 1.4 M 1 &amp;cli Xt cunsiiicil .il 24 plimi. jj 3 Si.il was Inocublcd lmie 1 nn.l luld :il a medium im.isliirc comcnl until Ji.lv 1" nm\ ilicn clvii K cil ami belli at the ilesired moisture content! until October g 13. wlien they were clianucil to [lie mmiturr culiient&lt; ctriircil after platilini;. Hxpcriniciit planted Kovcmlicr 13. " g C r 2 30 </seg>
         <seg id="p032">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab ;. pared with the comparable sets held at the same moisture contents dur - ing growth o£ the plant. This was not true of Set 9, which was held at a high moisture content throughout the experiment. It can also be concluded from the data that low soil moistures during the growth of the plant (Sets 1, 4, and 7) favored the development of scab. There is no apparent explanation for the greater percentage of scab in Set 6 at a high moisture content than in the medium-moisture Set 5 of the same series. : ¦¦ . . ' ¦ . .-,¦... The counts of Actindmyces, bacteria, and fungi were made by the dilu - tion plate method three times during the experiment, the first about one month after inoculation, the second just before the soil moistures were changed (October 13) and the last at the end of the experiment. The re - sults are presented in Table 17. . . The percentage of Actinomyces one month after inoculation and after one month at a medium moisture content averaged about 28 per cent and was fairly uniform in the different compartments. The second sampling (October 13), made about three months after the soil moistures had been changed, revealed some marked differences in the three groups. There was a great decrease in the total number of organisms in the low-moisture sets (1,2, and 3) due to the fact that these soils were allowed to become air dry. The effect of desiccation was greatest on the bacterial flora, while the percentages of Actinomyces and fungi were greater than at any other time during the experiment. The higher soil ¦ moisture in the medium sets (4, 5, and 6) resulted in a greater total number of organisms and a lower percentage of Actinomyces and fungi. Raising the moisture content still higher failed to have any further depressing effect on the percentage of Actinomyces, although the total number of organ - isms doubled. The samples taken at the dose of the experiment (February 15) showed a considerable-increase in the total numbers of organisms at all moisture contents, probably due to the effect of the root system of the potato plants. Unfortunately the data for Sets 1 and 4, in which the greatest amount of scab occurred in their relative series, are not available. There was an increase in the numbers of both Actinomyces and bacteria in Sets 7, 8, and ?, which had previously been held at high moist - ure contents. It is significant that these were the same three sets in which the greatest amount of scab occurred in comparison with the respective moisture contents in the other series. It is likewise noticeable that the two sets having the lowest number of Actinomyces, Sets 2 and 5, likewise had the least scab and Set 6 with a greater number had a larger amount of scab. It is possible that if data were available for the two low-moisture sets (1 and 3) a more refinite correlation could be made. An examination of the soil microflora was attempted by the Cholodny technique at intervals throughout the experiment. Slides placed in the soils during the first month after inoculation and left for two weeks show - ed an abundance of Actinomyces on all slides. Long strands of mycelium, as well as many mycelial fragments, chains, free spores, and a few spirals were observed. Slides buried for two weeks during the period before plant - -- .' .'¦¦' --¦" '' .",'¦ ' "¦¦' ¦:'; : . (•. ' ' . ¦ '¦ ¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p033">Nebraska Agrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 =I - " •| xi . 2 £a a« k i - f ~ 5 &gt;¦ I s « s s s s I -I 4 ,„ ,„.. M, T rr S ; 5c _ &gt; r — ° : - a II b ? 5 - i ¦= I - I £S =~~ .2^ | ~ ?.?,r, ' i?.s •- = = ---•«¦&lt; ; bfl^A £. ' - V&gt; — £ - c co t S» , Si . ' "*3KT=.~ ~ r I i ! i «. i X III! ll'ilzt-: ¦,:,:! 235:^5 ! "s- Os- Cs *- § ill,: *.* -« S w = S «,| - jj_« "*" j f i:i c = =|a * " Ei -^—¦ "'""I! "SI I §M§ </seg>
         <seg id="p034">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab ing, about three months after the soil moitures were changed, showed a great decrease in the numbers of Actinomyces in the soils held at .low moistures, but this may have been due to the fact that this technique is not very satisfactory with dry soils owing to the poor contact between the slide, and the soil. The greatest number of Actinomyces were found in the soils held at a medium moisture content, and only traces were found in the soils at the high moisture content. The slides buried about two months after planting (two months after the second change in the soil moisture content) failed to reveal any significant differences and rfiere was no correlation be - tween either the numbers or the type of growth of Actinomyces as revealed on these slides and the numbers of Actinomyces as determined by the dilu - tion plate method or the amount of scab on potato tubers. The only conclusion to be drawn from this experiment is that while low soil moistures during the growing season favored the production of scab, high moistures preceding planting likewise increased scab in this experiment, provided favorable conditions for infection existed during the period of tuber development. ; ¦ THE EFFECT OF SOIL AERATION UPON POTATO SCAB Sanford (17) found that A, scabies in pure culture required an abundant supply of oxygen for all phases of its life cycle and he therefore suggested that lack of sufficient oxygen might bo a limiting factor in the soil and "help to explain why scab is not so prevalent in wet soils as in drier ones". On the basis of observational evidence in western Nebraska, this theory was inadequate to explain the common occurrence of severe attacks of scab following hpavy packing rains and in the low portions of irrigated fields, particularly when the fields could not be subsequently cultivated. A few simple tests were therefore planned to obtain some experimental evidence on the effect of lack of aeration of the soil upon the development of scab. Since these tests were made, Dippenaar (4) has published the results of his experiments, in which he tested the effect of different degrees of forced aeration in soils of different moisture contents. His results did not show any increased amount of scab in,the aerated as compared with the unaerated controls. . In the following tests instead of forcing air through the soil it was con - sidered that normal cultivation of the surface soil was sufficient for the development of severe scab and that a decrease in aeration would test the possibility of insufficient oxygen acting as a limiting factor. It was also considered that the effect of aeration on the infection phenomena might be different from the effect upon the growth of the organism in the soil preceding tuber formation. An attempt was made to simulate the condi - tions occurring in the field after a heavy packing rain and subsequent hardening of the surface soil by covering the soil with an inch layer of ciosely packed, wet clay in contrast with ji frequent cultivation of the surface soil. : •',;„ . , The plants were grown in an unstenhzed mixture of composted sou and sand in four-gallon glazed earthenware jjars. The soil was inoculated </seg>
         <seg id="p035">Nebraska Agrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 one week after planting with n suspension of A. scabies N-23. One series of 10 plants was covered with clay as soon as the sprouts emerged and left that way until maturity. Another series was covered the same way but the clay was removed at the time the tubers started to set and cultivated there - after. A third and fourth series of 10 plants each were treated conversely to the first two, one being cultivated throughout the experiment and the other cultivated until time of tuber set and then covered with clay. From 90 to 100 per cent of the tubers in each series were scabby, most of the scab being of the common type with little pit scab present. The amount of infection was slightly greater in the series that was cultivated throughout the experiment, but there were no significant differences be - tween the other three series. It was noted in this experiment that the tubers on the plants that were covered with clay during tuber formation had all formed at the surface of the soil with the upper side in contact with the clay. In every instance the scab lesions on such tubers occurred on the lower side in contact with the soil, while the upper portion was always healthy. The above experiment was repeated with a similar number of plants grown and inoculated in the same way except that the soil was sealed by pouring over it a one-half-inch layer oi paraffin as soon as the sprouts had emerged, and the soil was kept at an optimum moisture content by weigh - ing and adding water through a tube to a three-inch clay pot reservoir in the center of the soil mass. The results of the experiment are given in Table 18, It is evident from the data that a lack of aeration inhibited the develop - ment of scab. It is also obvious from a comparison of Sets 3 and 4 that a lack of aeration was of much greater importance during the period preced - ing tuber formation than later in the growth of the plants. Apparently the effect of the treatment was upon the organism rather than upon the host and a lack of aeration did not affect the vegetative development of the organism. It is possible of course that some small tubers had formed and become infected in Set 4 before the soil was sealed. However, developing tubers are susceptible during their entire growth period, so that the com - paratively low percentage of infection in Set 3 must be explained on the basis of lack of inoculum due to the preceding lack of aeration. Further experiments on this point combined with a study of the organ - ism in the soil by dilution plates and slides are needed for an exact under - standing of the effect of aeration on the organism in the soil. DISCUSSION It has long been considered that environmental factors, particularly those of the soil environment, are of major importance in determining the severity of potato scab. The literature of the subject is replete with observa - tions of the effects of these factors, although accurate experimental work is not so abundant. Many contradictory statements have resulted from the observational evidence and while most of the experimental evidence is in fair agreement, it is often difficult, if not impossible, to correlate the </seg>
         <seg id="p036">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab occurrence of the disease in the field with published experimental findings obtained under controlled conditions. Temperature, moisture, and to a less extent aeration fluctuate greatly during the growing season in compari - son with the other more stable factors, such as reaction, soil type, and organic matter. It is quite probable that these fluctuating factors are the cause of the many contradictory observations and for this reason they were selected for investigation in the present study. It is obvious that these factors may exert their influence in two ways, either by their effect upon the pathogene and its host at the time o£ infection or by their effect upon A. scabies in the soil previous to infection. This latter phase of the problem has received very little attention in previous -* investigations, and the experiments in the present paper were therefore designed in an attempt to throw some light on this question. Effect of competing organisms—lt has been shown (Table 1) that the severity of scab is directly dependent upon the amount of inoculum in the soil. It can be concluded that the amount of inoculum will be conditioned by the direct action of the environmental factors or indirectly by their influence on the soil microflora, which may be either beneficial or antagon - istic to the pathogene. ;¦ ; The increased infection resulting from soil sterilization and subsequent inoculation is apparently due to the lack of competition of soil micro - organisms rather than to changes in the physical or chemical structure of the soil. The addition to such soils of a filtrate from unsterilized soil tends to counteract this effect, and the effect of sterilization is greatly reduced if the inoculum is not added until after saprophytic organisms have become established in the soil. Tests of the antagonistic effect of A. praecox as reported by Millard and Taylor (15) failed to substantiate their report of its potency in reducing tVie amount of scab. No evidence was obtained as . to whether the effect of the soil microflora upon A. scabies was due to specific organisms, related groups of organisms, or simply to numbers of competing organisms. . Soil temperature.—lf the soil microflora exerts such a pronounced effect upon A. scabies as was shown in the soil sterilization experiments, it would be expected that any factors influencing the development of the soil micro - flora would have a profound effect upon the development at A. scabies and therefore upon the scab-producing power of the soil. This was demonstrated by the soil temperature studies in which the soil was subjected to the desir - ed temperatures for 70 to 90 days previous to tuber formation, after which they were all transferred to a uniform temperature of 22° C. determined by Jones, McKinney, and Fettows (?) and Dippenaar (4) to be a favorable temperature for infection. With sterilized soil the most scab occurred when the soils had been incubated at 22° and 26° C, with practically as much scab at 30°. With soils incubated at lower temperatures the amount of scab was less, reaching a minimum in the soil held at 6°. Contrasted, with this there was no consistent effect of temperature in the unsterilized soils. It is possible that additional experiments involving larger numbers or the incubation of the organism in the soil for longer periods of time might </seg>
         <seg id="p037">Nebraska Agrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 show a greater effect of temperature on unsterilized soils than was evident in this single experiment. It is evident, however, that in experiments where sterilized soil is inoculated and held at constant temperatures from planting to maturity, as in the work of Jones, McKinney, and Fellows (9), the results are due to the effect of temperature not only upon infection but also upon the growth of the organism in the soil, and therefore the differences in scab obtained at different temperatures are magnified. Soil moisture.—High soil moistures have been claimed by various work - res (4, 12, 16) to reduce scab infection, while a few papers record the opposite effect. Records of fields in western Nebraska show that scab is us - ually more severe in seasons of high rainfall than in the dry years. Because of the deficiency of moisture, scab is never a problem in years of low yields. The experiments reported in this paper fail to reveal clearly the effect of soil moisture upon the occurrence of scab as shown by Dippenaar (4). The soil moisture in his experiments was regulated by periodic weighings, but in the few experiments where this was done in the present investigation the results were more variable than where the soil moisture was held approxi - mately at the minimum optimum, and maximum for growth. This method allowed for larger numbers of plants and the plants produced a greater number of larger tubers. The method of recording scab was also different. These differences in methods, however, can hardly account for the great variation in the results. In general, the results agreed with Dippenaar as to the greater amount of scab occurring in soils that were dry during the infection period; however, in Soil Moisture Experiment 3 (Table 10) there was clearly an increase in scab with increased moisture in two of the four sets. In Experiment 6 (Table 11) there was no effect of soil moisture, whereas in Experiments 4 and 5 more scab occurred in the dry soil. In Experiment 7 (Table 15) the only severe scab occurred at medium and high moisture contents, while in Experiment 8 (Table 16) more scab occurred in the dry soil. ' . It is quite possible that the reason for these variable results lies in the lack of proper experimental technique. Even when the water to be added is determined by periodic weighings it is self-evident that the soil moisture is at the desired point only immediately after watering. It is also true that in such experiments we are dealing with the average soil moisture in-the containers, whereas the determining factor is the moisture present at the point of infection. This is best exemplified by the data presented in Table 9 The greatest amount of scab occurred in the dry soils in which the soil moisture was unevenly distributed, and the scab occurred chiefly upon the portions of the tubers that were in contact with moist soil. In general the scab occurring in the high moisture soils was severe and often of the pitted type, in contrast to Dippenaar's observations of high soil moisture allowing the tuber to slough off the scab infection and heal over the pustule. There was no evidence of this occurring in these experiments, nor was there any effective control of scab by high moistures even when it was more severe in the drier soils. </seg>
         <seg id="p038">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab The data in the one experiment conducted to determine the effect of soil moisture in relation to soil type and • moisture-holding capacity were too insufficient and variable to permit definite conclusions. Experiments dealing with soil types are bound to be influenced greatly by differences in organic matter and aeration, which also affect the soil microflora. The limited evidence obtained indicates that the proportion of soil moisture to the moisture-holding capacity is probably of. greater significance than the actual percentage of water on a dry-weight basis, and that caution should be used in comparing the effects of soil-moisture contents of different types o£ soil. . '¦. . . , • : As previously stated, there is very little published information dealing with the effect of st-il moisture preceding infection—that is, upon the development of the inoculum. Working with pure cultures of A. scabies in sterilized soil in flasks Sanford (17) came to the conclusion that the inoculum of A. scabies appeared to increase best at a soil moisture content about optimum for plant growth". Dippenaar (4), employing the Cholodny slide technique, came to the conclusion that high soil moisture favored/the development of bacteria which were antagonistic to the scab organism and that spore germination and growth at A. scabies ¦"were inhibited under these conditions. The Actinomyces in general are usually said to be favored by low soil moistures'but Lutman, Livingston, and Schmidt (11) found the greatest number in field soils in winter with high soil moistures. In the present investigation the largest amounts of scab occurred in the soils that had been held at medium or high moisture contents for some months previous to planting. While the results were not consistent in repeated tests (Experiments 6, 7, and 8) there was no evidence that high soil moistures (saturation in these experiments) have any depressing effect on the scab organisms. On the contrary in.one experiment air-drying of the soil previous to planting greatly decreased the amount of scab. Plate counts and soil slides did not ideal any. consistent relation be - tween Actinomyces and scab, and tee was considerable variation in the effect of moisture on the numbersWd percentages of Actinomyces. In treneral the percentage of Actinomyies was greatest in the dry soils. In two experiments (Tables 10 and 15) both the number and percentage were highest in dry soils, while in another experiment (Table 13) there was a " slight increase in the percentagewith high and in Experiment 8 (Table 17) there was a greater number and percentage of Actinomyces in the high as compared with medium rrjoisture, except for those soils originally at a high moisture. l| &#132;,... . . . The soil slides did not check with the results of dilution plates. Actin - pmyecs were more abundant on tVie sVides in|the dry soils but they were not completely eliminated by high moisture, asm the experiments reported by Dippenaar. The fact that in these experiments the slides were buried in soil containing roots of living plants, while j Dippenaar conducted his tests in soil without plants, may account for the difference. Lutman and co-workers concluded that Actinomyces occur in the soil in the form of mycelial fragments rattier than as spores. Dippenaar </seg>
         <seg id="p039">Nebraska Acrl. Experiment Station Research Bulletin 93 considered that a low moisture content favored not only spore germination and vegetative development but also sporulation. Sanford (17) suspected that the lack of spore germination at high humidities may have been due to a lack of oxygen resulting from the film of water around the spores. While great stress is often laid upon the numbers of Actinomyces as determined by dilution plate counts in relation to soil moisture and other factors, it should be borne in mind that the causal organism must be grow - ing vegetatively if it is to cause infection. High plate counts often indicate sporulation or fragmentation of mycelium. Conversely, low counts may in - dicate vegetative development and this may in turn be correlated with high infection. Of course it is possible that germination, growth and sporulation ail occur at their maximum under similar conditions, as indicated by Dip - penaar, although this is not a common biological phenomenon. At least it is reasonable to assume that conditions favorable for sporulation would in - crease the scab-producing power of the soil and that if this were followed In conditions favorable for vegetative development, more infection would result. This phase of the problem needs more investigation before a compre - hensive knowledge can lie obtained of the development of the causal organ - ism in the soil in relation to the production of the disease. Soil aeration.—Soil aeration was found to be essential for the develop - ment of the disease, as previously indicated by other investigators, but it was also found that a lack of aeration during the period preceding tuber (urination had a greater influence upon the disease than during the infection period. Tins was probably due to a lack of development of the parasite in the soil when insufficient oxygen was present. Type of scab. —In the experiments reported in this paper there was no evidence of a correlation between different types of scab and the strain or species of Actinomyces, with the possible exception of superficial scab of the type shown in Plate 1, which occurred only in the unsterilized soils. Common, raised, and deep scab similar to the types described by Millard and Burr often occurred on the same tuber grown in sterilized soil inocu - lated with a single pure culture of A. scabies. Additional tests have indicat - ed that the type of scab is more closely correlated with the host reaction, the environment, and the virulence ot the culture than with the identity of the species or strain. The difficulty of obtaining uniform results and in interpreting such data as those presented in this and other papers dealing with environmental factors, is largely due to the fact that our experimental technique is inade - quate for a proper investigation of the problem. While we can measure gross differences in the soil mass in which the plants are growing, the conditions existing in the microenvironment immediately surrounding the roots and tubers is not measurable by present methods and it is these undetermined conditions that undoubtedly have the greatest influence upon the development of the organism. </seg>
         <seg id="p040">Influence of Soil Factors on Potato Scab :¦: .-.,.. ..¦;¦¦¦¦ ¦-¦ . ¦ ,-. . ¦ ' •/..•!,. ¦;. -. ) LITERATURE CITED 1. Bcckwith, M. H. |- -. ¦ ' 1888. Report of hie Assistant Horticulurist, N. Y. Agr. Exp. Sta. (Geneva) . . 6th Ann. Rnt. 1887, pp. 307-15. . | 2. Cholodny, N. . .:¦ : ..". ¦ 1930. Ueber cine neve Methode zur Untersuchung der Bodenmjkroflora. ;|V. Arch. f. Mifcrobiol. 1:620-52. ,/jj ']''[ 3. Conn, H. J. . - y.ij, '. ! ,' '.. '*'¦'. 1932. A Microscopic Study of Certain Chances in the Microflora of Soil. N. Y. Agr. Exp. Sta. (Geneva) Tech. Bui. 204. ":¦ &gt;V- 4. Dippcnaar, B. J. - - , \, : 1933. Environment and Control Studies of the Common Scab Disease of Potatoes Caused by Acttoomycesl scabies (Thaxt.) Gfiss. Union oi :, South Africa, Dcpt.. of Agr. Sci. Bui. 136. * 5 Bloductt, F. M., and E. K. Cowan. , : . 1935. Relative Effects of Calcium and Acidity of the S^il on the ': ' Occurrence of Potato Scab. Amcr. Pot. Jour. 12:265-74. ,:,, 6. Fellows, Hurley. . ¦ : 1926. Relation of Growth in the Pottato Tuber to the Potato Scab Disease. Jour. Agr. Res. 32:757-81. i~V' ' 7. Goss, R. W. ' , ' 193-1. A Survey of Potato Scab and Fusarium Wilt in Western Nebraska. Phytopath. 24:517-27. ( .' 8. Jones, A. Powell. . |: •) : 1931. The Histooeny of Potato Scab. Ann. of Appl. Biol. 18:313-33. 9. Jones, L. R., H. H. McKinncy, and H. Fellows. | .• 1922. The Influence of Soil Temperature on Potato Scab. Wis. Asr. Exp. / Sia. Rts. 8u1.53. I V 1 10. Lumian, B. F. . : ¦ ' j ;;¦ 1923. Potato Scab in New Land. Phytopath. 13:2'U-'H. &gt; ' 11. Lutman. 11. F-, R. |. Livingston, and Alice M.,Schmidt. 1936. SuiL AcTixoMvcEs and Potato Scab. Vr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 401. «; .12. Martin, Wm. H. ;.} ¦ t •'¦..'-'¦¦ ¦'¦:. 1923. Influence of Soil Moisture and on thu Development oi&gt; I; ; Potato Scab. Soil Sci. 16:69-73. |j "V 13. McLennan, E. ' ¦ ',' 1928. The Gkowtii of Fungi in Soil. Ann. of Appl. Biol. 15:95-109. ,'¦ 14. Millard, W. A., and S. Burr. .;.'-' '; ' 1926. A Study of Twenty-four Strains of Actinomyces and Their Rela - ¦:¦'-' tion to Types of Common Scab of Potato. Ann. of Appl. Biol. 13:580 - -;:\ ¦'•¦ ' . w- . ' . ¦'.-. ¦¦¦ ¦; .:;'!i. :¦¦' ¦ ./'.':.. ? 15. Millard, W. A., and C. B. Taylor. : ;-¦: . 1927. Antagonism of Microorganisms as the Controlling Factor in the ' Inhibition of Scab by Green-manur ng. Ann. of Appl. Biol. 14:202-16. Sf':' 16. Sanford, G. B. ; . :; . : 1923. Tiif. Relation* of Soil Moisture to; the Development of Common X. . Scab of Potato. Phytopath. 13:231-36. .: ¦ ¦ i:: 17;—— — --. ¦¦':. ¦.' '¦ '¦-''¦¦¦ ¦;]'•¦ ¦i¦'¦.- 1926: Some Factors Affectinc the Pathogenicity of Actinomyces scabies. ;j Phytopath. 16:525-47. T ;':; 18. Smith, Ora. ¦ '-¦ .'¦',-, ¦-.' ji . 1933. Effect of Soil Reaction on the Growth of the Potato. Amer. Pot. :!0] : Jour. 10:118-121. : |j : ;. 1 &lt; ¦'. ¦ ¦"•. ¦¦:' ' ¦ '.-¦¦¦¦''.. ¦"¦! : </seg>
         <seg id="p041">-til Nimi\sK\ Mm.. Expkrimi.nt Station Rusiurcii Bulletin 93 I'l.Ml Tllf RHATIOV t.P Soil. RI.W.TWN TO YIBLD ASD MaHKHT QUALITY Or I'm-ATOKS. Ohm Vcg. CJrow. Ass. I'n&gt;c. 21st. Meet. pp. 123-27. 20. Werner. H. O. „ l'M-1 Till Lllll.T 111- A OINTRIILI.ID NITROUEN SUPPLY WITH DIFFERENT TtMI'tRATI-RtS ASU I'HOTO-PEKIODS Ul'O.V THE JSEVEEOP.Mh.VT OF THE Potato Plant. Nibr. Afjr. hxp. Sta. Res. Uul. 75. </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>