<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00032">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Relative Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold</title>
               <date value="1930-12">1930-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 52 The Relative Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold GEORGE L. PELTIER AND H. M. TYSDAL Department of Plant Pathology Lincoln t Nebraska December, 1930 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY colieitPd^fn^o^Jf 1 " M trO w Ct l° nS °? Tu . rkestan alfalfa and 25 lots Tnrl; ? ♦ ?,, y M - T i Westover J« six seed-growing districts of Turkestan, together with ten introductions from France and 22 SS&amp;SL. Bk W&lt;?re t6Sted f ° r susce Ptibility to AplanoboctJ - . (2) . T he 1929 introductions from Turkestan and France and eight domestic alfalfas were also tested for their cold resistance. * i»JTa . Marke . d differences in wilt and cold resistance of seed lots col - lected in various seed-growing districts of Turkestan were found (4) Provence F. P I. No. 34886, Hardistan, some of the old and new s±toaiK!ra and possibly Ladak were found to b " </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">The Relative Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold George L. Peltier, Plant Pathologist, Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, and H. M. Tysdal, Associate Agronomist, Office of Forage Crops and Diseases, Bureau of Plant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture l The final solution of the alfalfa-wilt problem in Nebraska probably lies in the development of resistant sorts that are winterhardy as well as productive. The first procedure in the search for such an alfalfa is the testing of existing alfalfas grown in this and other countries. Peltier and Jensen (3) have indicated that three sorts, namely Turkestan, Provence, and Hardistan (2), are quite resistant to wilt, whereas Grimm, Cossack, and other varieties, together with a number of domestic Common alfalfas, are rather suscept - ible. They had, however, only three introductions of Turk - estan and one of Provence under observation, and hence no definite statement of wilt resistance of these sorts in general was made. During the summer of 1929, Mr. H. L. Westover, Senior Agronomist, Office of Forage Crops and Diseases, U. S. De - partment of Agriculture, collected a number of different lots of seed in the alfalfa-growing sections of France, eastern Europe, and in various sections of Turkestan. Seed gathered by Mr. Westover, especially from Provence and northwestern France and Turkestan, was supplied for relative-susceptibility tests. A number of domestic alfalfas were also included. The relative susceptibility to wilt of 40 lots from Turkestan, 10 from France, 6 of Grimm from as many states, and 16 domestic alfalfas are reported on at this time, together with hardiness tests of a few well-known varieties and strains and the more recent Introductions from Turkestan and France. RELATIVE SUSCEPTIBILITY TO WILT METHODS Seed was planted in January and February, 1930, in the greenhouse, in plant bands (134x1%x2i/ 2 inches) placed on - top of a 6-inch layer of soil, so that the roots could develop normally and would not be seriously injured when the plants were lifted. The plants were lifted the. first week in May, at which time the average root diameter near the crowns was approximately .5 to .75 cm. . One hundred plants of each lot were then prepared for inoculation. The plants, after being lifted, were freed of 1 1 Th i. s £, rcl i m i n ?P\ buIle », n j s b , ased on co-operative investigations between the Depart, ment of Plant Pathology. Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station, and the Office of Forage Crops and Diseases, Bureau of Plant Industry. United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebb. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 52 soil and debris by washing. Care was taken not to injure the roots unnecessarily. A two-weeks-old culture on potato - lactose | agar from a recent isolation of Aplanobacter insidiosum L. McC. was placed in two liters of water, and the bacterial mass was washed from the agar. The.inocula - tion technique consisted of lightly scraping the roots for a distance of one cm. near the crown with a sharp scalpel, while they were held under the bacterial suspension. They were allowed to remain in this suspension until they were trans - planted in the field. Care was taken to make the wounds on each root approx - imately the same size and depth so that the portal for the entrance of the bacteria would be as uniform as possible in the different lots under test. Further, the roots were left intact, so that the only visible wounds were those made arti - ficially. Twelve to 24 hours after inoculation the plants were set in the field in rows. A record was made one month after planting, and an occasional plant was found that failed to recover from the effects of transplanting. During the summer the plants were cut twice. The scythe used was disinfected after cutting the plants' in each row. Weather conditions at the time of transplanting were ideal and remained so until July, when extremely hot and dry weather set in and persisted until August. A few plants were beginning to show symptoms of wilt the latter part of June, but the dry weather checked the growth of the plants and no further symptoms were observed until late in Sep - tember. When the plants were dug in October, top symptoms were evident on many of the plants of the susceptible sorts. In recording the severity of infection, both top symptoms and the extent of the vascular discoloration in the roots were noted, and the following classification was adopted. Trace — Discoloration of a few vessels in the inner stele. No top symptoms. Slight — Discoloration extending in an arc in the inner stele. No top symptoms. Moderate — Discoloration pronounced and extensive in the inner stele. Slight top symptoms. Severe — Discoloration extending to the cambium, involving more or less the entire root. Distinct top symptoms. It was noted that most of the plants had a pronounced growth ring presumably laid down by the plants with the advent of the rains in August, when new growth was resumed. EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS In Table 1 are listed the various sorts of alfalfa tested, to - gether with the percentage of healthy and infected individ- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Susceptibility op Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold uals. The susceptibility of Grimm to alfalfa wilt has been pointed out by Peltier and Jensen (3), Jones (1), and Salmon (4). However, to determine whether Grimm grown in various localities was equally susceptible, seed lots from five states, Idaho, North Dakota, South Dakota, Nebraska, and Utah, and one from an unknown source were tested. As will be noted from the table, all lots showed a very high per - centage of infected plants. The averaged results of the six lots show that only 5 per cent of the plants remained healthy, 20 per cent showed a trace to a slight infection, and 75 per cent were moderately or severely infected. With normal precipitation during the growing season, no doubt many of the plants would have succumbed from wilt in the field. From the data it appears that the Grimm lots were quite homogenous so far as their susceptibility to wilt is concerned and that irrespective of its origin,. Grimm is highly susceptible to wilt under conditions favorable for its spread and develop - ment. Cossack, LeBeau, and Hardigan, hardy alfalfas, are equally as susceptible to wilt, as Grimm. Likewise, Peruvian, an unhardy yareity, is susceptible. Altho Peltier and Jensen (3) reported that a number of domestic Common alfalfas were susceptible to wilt, five alfalfas of southern and five of northern origin were included in these tests, to determine whether there were any differ - ences in susceptibility to wilt between strains of varied origin. Under field conditions in Nebraska it has been noted that the stands of southern have deteriorated more rapidly than those of northern alfalfas, and the differentiation be - tween the effects of wilt and winter injury under these con - ditions hSs not been definitely determined. The results pre - sented in Table 1 show that all Common alfalfas tested, irre - spective of their origin, are susceptible to wilt, altho a few sorts do not show as high a susceptibility as others. This fact may be accounted for in part as follows. The seed listed as "Nebraska" is grown primarily in Sioux, Dawes, and Sheridan counties in the northwestern part of the state. Some of the fields are old and the original source and history of the seed are unknown. Without question in a number of these old fields the plants are more or less resistant to wilt and when the seed is assembled there is included some seed from these old wilt-resistant plants. In other words, Common alfalfa may consist of a mixture rather than one sort. That such incidents occur is known, in that resistant lines have been selected from a number of old fields in Nebraska, the seed of which was mixed with seed from nearby fields and sold as Common alfalfa. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 52 Table 1. — Relative susceptibility of alfalfas to Aplanobacter insidioswn '■ F. P. I. or Total Infected plants Description F. C. I. plants Healthy accession inocu- plants .■ Moder- Number lated Trace Slight ate ■ Severe Xumbtr P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. Turkestan 25684 100 76 7 5 11 1 Turkestan 25878 100 72 6 7 15 0 Turkestan 25891 100 I 70 6 8 12 -1 Turkestan... 26060 100 69 10 8 12 1 . Turkestan 15942 99 64 4 9 19 4 Turkestan 15754 97 64 12 8- 15 1 Turkestan 2230 68' 63 9 9 19 0 Turkestan 25765 99 63 5 13 17 2 Turkestan 15941 100 60 7 14 13 6 Turkestan 72719 1 100 59 19 7 12 3 Turkestan 2674 • 98 58 7 •' 12 17 6 Turkestan (Amtorg) 100 ! 57 8 16 17 2 Turkestan 15809 99 : 56 3 19 18 4 Turkestan 25392 99 I 53 .11 8 23- 5 Turkestan 26263 100 52 11 16 20 1 Turkestan (Tashkent) .... 84354 97 . 81 2 7 10 0 Turkestan (Tashkent) . , . . 84355 96 80 5 7 5 3 Turkestan (Tashkent) 84383 ; 98 76 9 8 7 0 Turkestan (Tashkent) .... 84380 r ' 99 I 70 5 . 7 11 7 Turkestan (Tashkent) .... 84353 ; 96 I 63 1 lfi 17 3 Turkestan (No. East) . 84371 71 87 1 :i » 0 Turkestan (No. East) 84367 (16 i 85 3 4 7 1 Turkestan (No. East) 84374 89 ! 80 3 3 4 10 Turkestan (No. East) 84373 93 79 2 11.7 1 Turkestan (Fergana) 84382 81 ' 58 5 Jfi 16 7 Turkestan (Fergana) 84403 87 ; 55 7' lfi 10 12 Turkestan (Samarkand) . . 84399 81 85 7 4 4 0 Turkestan (Samarkand) . . 84401 88 85 " 3 10 1 1 Turkestan (Samarkand) . . 84395 !U M 4 8 :i 1 Turkestan (Bokhara) 84407 01 85 3 10 2 0 • ' ' ' I ■ Turkestan (Khiva) 84412 90 86 6 I I 0 Turkestan (Khiva) 84443 96 I 84 1 4 9 2 Turkestan (Khiva) . 84420 78 • 82 1 4 1:1 0 Turkestan (Khiva) 84422 93 .77 0 7 10 6 Turkestan (Khiva) 84435 91 ; 71 . 3 7 12 7 Turkestan (Khiva) 84428 ■ 99 69 3 8 13 7 Turkestan (Khiva) 84424 . 96 : 66 7 15 9 :1 Turkestan (Khiva) 84423 93 : 64 5 10 14 7 Turkestan (Khiva) 84444 • 94 56 3 10 23 8 Turkestan (Khiva) 84445 97 51 2 21 20 6 . France (Niort) 82602 100 I 4 4 9 49 34 France (Turenne) 82606 . 96 | 4 3 19 36 38 France (Thouare) 82609 98 ■ 6 fi IB 50 22 France (Provence) 82601 99 j 7 4 21 35 33 France (Provence) ■; 82615 98 4 6 18 34 38. France (Provence) 34886 50" 76 4 6 14 0 France (Provence) 12694 99 1 10 30 38 21 France (Provence) 15743 99 2 3 10 55 . 30 France (Provence) 15744 100 3 5 16 50 26 France (Sarthe) 15745 40' 2 2 13 35 48 Hardistan • 98 65 13 10 9 3 Ladak 14135 100 60 4 13 18 5. Grimm' 632 100 5 7 10 53 25 Grimm (So. Dak.) 14196 100 3 2 16 55 24 Grimm (Utah) 14464 100 4 5 11 46 34 Grimm (No. Dak.) ... 14467 98 9 6 13 44 28 Grimm (Idaho) 15936 99 3 10 16 59 12 Grimm (Nebr.) 95 4 3 22 43 28 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold Table .1.— Relative susceptibility of alfalfa to Aplanobacter incidiosum — ( Continued ) Description Vcl^ ££ii Hea.thy _^dpUnU_ accession inocu- plants Moder- Number lated Trace Slight ate Severe Number P. ct. P. cl. P. cl. I P. ct. P. ct. Cossack 2204 100 6 2 22 39 31 Hardigan M2621 98 5 1 15 4G 33 LeBeau M2622 100 . 5 3 23 56 13 Peruvian 437 100 6 0 22 38 34 Arizona 15837 99 1 4 21 24 80 £?*&gt;? 97 5 3 17 38 37 Oklahoma . 99 10 6 7 37 40 New Mexico 14470 100 11 3 15 41 30 California.. ; 15880 98 11 1 11 27 50 North Dakota 379 99 3 3 13 53 28 Kansas 435 100 6 2 12 40 40 gSSl-KV 15819 98 9 2 20 39 30 South Dakota gg 10 13 16 34 27 Nebraska , iqq 15 12 IS 27 30 ■Old seed, poor germination. 'Obtained from A. Dickinson Co., Chicago, 111. Salmon (4) also reports that one sort of Kansas Common is more resistant to wilt than other Common alfalfas found in Kansas. It is very likely, therefore, that wherever old fields have maintained productive yields over a long period of years in wilt-infested regions, resistant individuals can be selected from these fields and seed from these may yield re - sistant types. Ladak, a variety of alfalfa recently described by Westover (5), apparently is made up of a number of widely diverse individuals; and while it shows less resistance to wilt than Hardistan, it does contain enough resis.tant plants to make it a desirable variety for further testing." Both Jones (1) and Salmon (4) have reported Ladak as showing some resistance to wilt. Peltier and Jensen (3) reported that one introduction of Provence (F. P. I. No. 34886) was decidedly resistant to wilt under field conditions. At the present time two plats of this alfalfa planted in . 1922 at the Experiment Station are still outstanding from the standpoint of resistance and hardi - ness. A similar report has recently been made by Salmon (4), who has had this same Provence under observation in Kansas. Because of the promise of this introduction, five collections made in 1929 in France (listed first in Table 1) and four previous introductions from France were included, together with Provence F. P. I. No. 34886, in the tests. The results </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebb. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 52 show that all of the nine introductions tested are very sus - ceptible to wilt. The average for the group shows only 4 per cent healthy, 22 per cent with a trace to slight infection, and 74 per cent moderately or severely diseased. Thus the nine collections of seed originating in France are as susceptible to wilt as Grimm. On the other hand, 76 per cent of the plants remained healthy, 24 per cent were infected with a trace to a moderate infection, and no severely diseased plants were found in Provence F. P. I. No. 34886. This introduction of Provence differs very markedly in susceptibility to wilt from the others tested. Further, its growth habits are unlike those of the susceptible sorts in many respects, and, as will be noted later, it is superior in cold resistance. Therefore Prevence F. P. I. No. 34886 is so unlike the other Provence introductions in wilt and cold resistance and growth habits that there is good reason to doubt that the seed was grown in France. Plant selections from the field plats of Provence F. P. I. No. 34886 made in 1927 and increased thru cuttings and seed show a much greater degree of resistance than do plants from the original seed. The behavior of these selections, together with that of other selections from wilt-resistant alfalfas, will be reported at another time. Unfortunately, the origin of this particular introduction is not known, other than that it was purchased from a seed firm as Provence seed and distributed by the Office of Forage Crops and Diseases some years ago. It is also unfortunate that this lot of seed should bear the same name as other highly susceptible introductions from Provence. As stated previously, Peltier and Jensen (3) had only three introductions of Turkestan under observation, namely Com - mercial No. 2230, seeded at the Experiment Station in 1922, and two lots of commercial seed planted in 1908 and 1911 in the Platte Valley. These three alfalfas appeared to be re - sistant to wilt under field conditions. Of the 40 Turkestan alfalfas included in these tests, the first 15 listed in Table 1 were collected from remnants of old introductions and com - mercial lots of seed imported in recent years. Thus, the lot listed as Amtorg reached the United States in the spring of 1929 and two carloads of this seed was distributed in Ne - braska. The tags on this seed indicated that it had been assembled at Tashkent, Turkestan. Of the 25 introductions sent to us by Mr. Westover early in 1930, five were collected near Tashkent, four from northeast Turkestan in the vicinity of Alma-Ata, two from Fergana, three from Samarkand, one from Bokhara, and ten from the region of Khiva, which pro - duces from 80 to 90 per cent of all the alfalfa seed grown in </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold Turkestan. Thus, these tests included alfalfas from all the main seed-growing districts of Turkestan and represent a geographical distribution in some respects similar to most of the seed-growing sections of the United States. All of the first 15 lots of Turkestan show some resistance to wilt, as can be seen from Table 1, altho they differ in both percentage and severity of infection. In order to compare the susceptibility of these alfalfas, it is desirable to have a standard or measuring stick. Since the history of Hardistan (2) is known, and the original field is still standing and quite productive after 19 years, it has been chosen as a standard for comparison. Therefore the Turkestans can be roughly grouped for the present into three classes, those apparently more, equally, and less resistant to wilt than Hardistan. Thus, of the first 15 lots of Turkestan which represent remnants of older introductions or commercial shipments of seed, only one, F. C. I. No. 25684, appears to be more resistant to wilt than Hardistan. The following Turkestans have about the same resistance : Commercial No. 2230, F. C. I. Nos 15754 and 15942, and S. I. A. Nos. 25765, 25878, 25891, and 26060. The following lots "of Turkestan seed appear to be less re - sistant : Commercial No. 2674, F. C. I. Nos. 15809 and 15941 and S. I. A. Nos. 25392, 26263, and 72719, and Amtorg! Salmon (4) has also reported Commercial No. 2230 resistant to wilt at Manhattan, Kansas. Of the five introductions from Tashkent, Turkestan F P I. Nos. 84354, 84355, and 84383 appear to be more resistant to wilt than Hardistan, while F. P. I. Nos. 84380 and 84353 are apparently slightly less resistant, when the severity of infection is taken into consideration. The four introductions from Northeast Turkestan, namely F. P. I. Nos. 84371, 84367 84374, and 84373, are apparently more resistant than Hard - istan.. Fergana represents one of the southern seed-growing districts in Turkestan, and the two lots, F. P. I. Nos 84382 and 84403, are much more susceptible than Hardistan, both in the number of susceptible individuals and in the severity of infection. The three introductions from the Samarkand district (F. P. I. Nos. 84395, 84399, and 84401) are all more resistant to wilt than Hardistan, as is likewise the one lot from Bokhara, F. P. I. No. 84407. From the Khiva district ten lots were tested, and a great variation was found in susceptibility to wilt. Three intro - ductions (F. P. I. Nos. 84412, 84443, and 84420) appeared to be more resistant than Hardistan; five (F. P. I Nos 84422 % 43 £ ? 4 t 28 ' 84424 ' and 84423 &gt; are as resistant; and two iu tt . * 84444 and 8444 5) much less resistant to wilt than Hardistan. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 52 These results with various lots of seed from six seed-grow - ing districts of Turkestan indicate that, while they are all more or less resistant to wilt, there are certain lots that are too susceptible to warrant further testing. Therefore, only those lots more resistant than Hardistan will be included in further trials. RELATIVE RESISTANCE TO COLD METHODS There were included in the hardiness tests the same 25 new introductions from Turkestan and the five new intro - ductions from France reported in Table 1, together with a number of well-known domestic alfalfas. The complete de - tails of the methods involved, together with a description of the equipment, are being prepared for publication. Briefly, the method consisted of growing plants in rows in flats (15x18x6 inches) or in four-inch porous clay pots. A variety of known hardiness was included in each flat for a control. Turkestan F. C. I. No. 15754 was used for this pur - pose since during the past three years it has consistently shown, in control hardiness tests, a slightly higher degree of resistance to cold than Grimm. The plants were grown under optimum conditions for one month in the greenhouse and then hardened off for a period of two weeks in a greenhouse held at a uniform temperature slightly above 0° C. The plants were transferred from the hardening room directly to the freezing chamber where the flats were exposed to an average temperature of —20° G. for approximately eight hours, and the pots to an average temperature of -14° C. for five hours. After freezing, the flats and pots were removed directly to the warm greenhouse and the surviving plants were allowed to recover. In all instances the relative resistance to cold was based on actual counts of the plants before freezing and on the number of survivals which recovered from exposures to low tempera - tures. In Table 2 the relative resistance to cold is tabulated as the mean ratio to the control, which was considered as 100. The actual percentage of survivals of each lot was calculated in terms of the control alfalfa for each replication and the ratios thus obtained were averaged. Each replication con - tained 10 to 30 plants, with a like number of the control. In these tests the introductions from each district of Turkestan and France were grouped as units. The probable errors, cal - culated by the deviation-from-the-mean method, 1 are included in the table. More extensive tests are now under Way to 1 Hayes, H. K. Control of Soil Heterogeneity and Use of the Probable Error Con - cept in Plant Breeding Studies. Minn. A«ri. Exp. Sla. Tech. Bui. 30. 21 pages. 1925. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold determine the relative resistance to cold of the various intro - ductions within each of the districts of Turkestan. EXPERIMENTAL RESULTS The large variability indicated (Table 2) by the high prob - able errors for the new introductions from Turkestan and * ranee does not allow any fine distinction to be drawn How - ever, the results show that differences in resistance to cold occur in the plants from seed grown in the various districts oi Turkestan. The introductions from the Khiva district ex - hibit a marked resistance to cold, while those from Bokhara fu nd xF er ? ana are quite susceptible. The introductions from the Northeast Turkestan, the Samarkand, and the Tashkent districts are intermediate and perhaps do not differ signif - icantly in cold resistance from the control, Turkestan F. C. I. No. 15754. Table 2.-^Relative resistance of alfalfas to cold Description Number of Xcatiot S™ 1 rati ° lots of Turkestan each lot 15754 Turkestan F. C. I. 15754 ....... ~~i ~ J^ Turkestan (Khival io I2i inq ±i rj Turkestan (North East) 4 ?2 89 *b'I Turkestan (Tashkent) . ........ 5 &amp; 84 ±q? Turkestan (Samarkand) .3 12 8n±Kd Turkestan (Bokhara).. i J2 68 2 fit Turkestan (Fergana) 2 &amp; |fl|i France (Provence) 2 3 34*22 France (North West) 3 • 3 23 * lit Provence F. P. 1. 34886 1 7 115 ±2 Q Hardistan ; J ,0 iisto? Ladak F. C. I. 14136 " J 25 \nllti Turkestan Com. 2230 ! 1 3 wat^i Grimm F. C. I. 15713 1 26 87 tli Nebraska J £? °^*2.8 Arizona F. C. I. 15837 1 _7g 26 ±1.3 F. C. F I™1575 0 4! 0 3 ° PlantS '" CaCh re P Ucati:&gt;n to K eth « wl«&gt; »■&gt; eq-"l number of plants of Turkeatan 'P. E. of the mean ratio, calculated by deviation from the mean method. The recent introductions from northwestern France, as well as those from Provence, are very susceptible to cold, ihere is a decided contrast between these introductions and the old Provence F. P. I. No. 34886 in their reaction to low temperatures. The old Provence alfalfa shows a marked cold resistance, comparable to that of the Khiva group. Salmon (4) has reported that m Kansas this same alfalfa showed a greater resistance to cold, both in the field and in the con - trolled freezing tests, than Grimm. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 52 As would be expected from field experience, Grimm, Ne - braska Common, and Arizona are resistant to cold in the order named. Ladak shows a slightly greater cold resistance than Grimm, a difference which may be significant. Hardi - stan shows more resistance than either Grimm or the control Turkestan F. C. I. No. 15754. It is coincidental that Turk - estan Commercial No. 2230 has the same survival ratio as the control. . DISCUSSION The results of the susceptibility tests show that it is pos - sible to find alfalfas which are resistant to both wilt and cold The promising ones are, however, few in number. The most noteworthy alfalfa so far reported appears to be Provence F. P. I. No. 34886. Selections from this alfalfa have shown a higher degree of resistance to wilt than the original seed. Hardistan (2), recently described as a new variety, is also outstanding m wilt and cold resistance and small amounts of seed should be available in the near future. In the search for resistant alfalfas, all old fields in wilt-infested sections of the country should be tested, for it appears that some of the plants from these fields may yield resistant types. Ladak while showing some resistance to wilt and cold, contains a larger number of susceptible individuals than either Provence r. P. I. No. 34886 or Hardistan. While all lots of Turkestan tested have shown some resist - ance to wilt, those showing less resistance to wilt and cold than Hardistan are not considered promising. It is interest - ing to note that some of the Turkestan lots, while quite re - sistant to wilt, are not nearly so cold resistant as Hardistan JJ^ e^ re^ h0 Y eV - er ; a , f e w which are better than Hardistan from the standpoint of both wilt and cold resistance. While the results for the various lots of alfalfa seed from Turkestan dTff.?Z ented W ndividua il y ' lt is not intended to^tress smaH SS, f^to \ Ho T VGr ' the reSults with res P ect to classifica - art?» FJEL? T- /^."P 3 are considered significant. The actual degree of infection may be expected to vary with the environment under which they are tested SlfS ° f ff \"i MeS and strains - All Sstic Common </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Susceptibility of Alfalfas to Wilt and Cold literature cited 1. Jones, F. R. 1930. Bacterial Wilt of Alfalfa. Jour. Amer. Soc. Ag-ron. 22:568-572. 2. Kiesselbach, T. A., Anderson, A., and Peltier, G. L. 1930. A New Variety of Alfalfa. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 22:181-182. 3. Peltier, G. L., and Jensen, J. H. 1930. Alfalfa Wilt in Nebraska. Nebr. Agri. Exp. Sta. Bui. 240. 30 pages. 4. Salmon, S. C. 1930. The Reaction of Alfalfa Varieties to Bacterial Wilt. Jour. Amer. Soc. Agron. 22:802-810. 5. Westover, H. L. . 1928. Alfalfa of Ladak Variety Is Promising for Northern States. United States Department of Agriculture Year - book. 1927:94. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>