<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00080.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION TO THE GOVERNOR</title>
               <date value="1936-11-30">1936-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION TO THE GOVERNOR August 26, 1935 to November 30, 1936 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">STATE OF NEBRASKA LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Honorable R. I, Cochran, Governor of 1 Nebraska. Dear Sir: The Nebraska Public Library Commission has the 1 honor to subm t the following report covering the period August 26, 1935 to November 30, 1936. Respectfully submitted, H. L. WEBSTER, President. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION MEMBERS OF THE COMMISSION H. L. Webster, Tekamah, President Mrs. P. L. Cady, Fremont, Vice-President Mrs. David Simms, Hastings ■ • Annie C. Krameh, North PJatte John W. BeleHuNT, Beatrice STAFF Nellie M. Carey, Executive Secretary Dorothy W. Lessenhop, Reference Librarian and Cataloger C. A. TiLGER, Shipping Clerk and General Assistant ■ Ji-ssii: Rohertson, Traveling Library Assistant OFFICE Room 1508 The Capitol Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">;.;'■'' ■■■• ! :.•■-'■■. ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ■ ■.'.•■■....• s ■ I* it HBBH1 1 . tj ' c/j »o &amp; 1 1 ■' IffflL— — ?W*— — ~*"^" ~ — -?3b»m " °o I fj n i^^gs? m -twf — — ' v ''■' I Hk^^^M lei ■ I- "t^Sfflffi^ ' '^'" 1 IS y| - - ' .^^l I ■-" ' \ I "**^ .IB j■■ lft^i*Vvl — ■--.-■«. | f " 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION August 26, 1935 to November 30, 1936 History and Dutic; The legislature of 1901 passed a law to establish the Nebraska Public Library Cc mmission, making Nebraska the twentieth state to have such' a Com nission. The members of the Library Commission were the State Lit rarian, the Superintendent of Public Instruction, the Chancellor and th : Librarian of the University of Nebraska, and one person who was appointed by the Governor for a term of five years. The duties of the Commission were to encourage and to assist in the formation of new libraries and to give advice and instruction as to tj-e best means far establishing, organizing and administering such libraries; to purch ise books and circulate them; and to collect annually reports from all ibraries in the state together with such facts and statistics as might be deemed of public interest. In 1933 the legislature abolished the Nebraska Public Library C&lt; 'mmission: and established in its place the Nebraska Public Library an-d provided that the Librarian of the University of Nebraska should be ex-ofTicio Pul lie Library Commissioner. During the tiennium 1933-1935 the Neb -aska Public Library carried on work similar to that previously done ty the Library Commission, but was greatly handi - capped by the vitry small appropriation of $10,000 allowed for the two year period. The law crea ;ing the Nebraska Public Library was repealed in 1935 and the Neb -aska Public Library Commission reestablished. The Governor appointed five members, one to serve one year, one for two years, one for three years, one for four years and one for five years. Hereafter one ne-v member will be appointed annually to serve for a term of five yeirs. An appropiiation of $25,000 was made for the biennium. Time Covered by This Report Due to the c langes made in the organization this report covers the period from August 26, 1935, the drte on which the appropriation for the Nebraskf Public Library Commission became available, to November 30, 193( , a little over fifteen months instead of the usual two year period . The law now provides that the Library Commission "make a report of its activities and the progress of its work on or before December fifteentii in each even numbered year." Although there was no appropriation "or this work from July 1, 1935, to August 26, 1935, the office was kept open by the two members on the staff and books were circulated. For the sake of continuity in reports circulation statistics for this jeriod are included in this report. 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Location of Office The Library Commission was formerly housed in the old Capitol Building, but was moved to the Social Science Building at the Uni - versity of Nebraska in 1921. The law passed in 1935 specified that offices should be provided in the Capitol Building. In compliance with the law rooms were allotted on the first floor with storage space in the basement. The preparation of the rooms and the construction of new equip - ment was made possible through a WPA project whk-h called for $3,917.81 Federal funds and $727.80 sponsor's funds. Enough steel stacks were constructed to take care of the present collection of approxi - mately 43,000 volumes and to allow for some growth. The drawing up of specifications which involved technical knowledge and the making of blue prints was done by engineers in the state road department and the work was supervised by the chief mechanic of that department. Old furniture owned by the Library Commission was refinished and several new pieces made. The transfer to the new quarters was made March 1, 1936. Personnel Members of the Library Commission appointed by the Governor July 1, 1935 were: ■ i H. L. Webster, Tekamah, one year Mrs. David Simms, Hastings, two years John W. Delehant, Beatrice, three years Mrs. P. L. Cady, Fremont, four years Annie C. Kramph, North Platte, five years Mr. Webster was elected president and Mrs. Simms was* elected *, secretary. One of the first duties of the Commission was to select an executive secretary. Nellie M. Carey, who had been for two years secretary of the former Library Commission and the executive assist - ant of the Nebraska Public Library, was elected. Dorothy W. Lessen - hop, reference librarian and cataloger for the preceding rive years, was asked to continue in that pcsition. Increased work made it necessary during the first year to employ more assistants, and C. A. Tilger and Jessie Robertson, both of whom were trair.ed librarians, were added to' the staff. The regular staft was ,supplemented during the school year by student assistants employed under the NY A. At the end of his one year term Mr. Webster was reappointed for a five year term and was reelected president of the Commission. Mrs. Cady was elected vice-president. Program The Library Commission has adopted a program looking forward to the corhplete coverage of the state with library service. Fifty per cent of thie population of Nebraska are without local library service. These people live in the country or in towns too small to support efficient public libraries. Other states have demonstrated that the most satisfactory way to get adequate local library service, is through the development of larger tax areas for library support, such as the county or combination of counties into a region. Nebraska has only one i --. • •■". \ ■ 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">county which ha; given a county levy for the support of library service. The immediat ; program is an educational one with a two fold purpose: first, to inform people in the state of the seivice which is available to them through the Nebraska Public Library Commission; second, to explain how the law in regard to the establishment of county or regional j librar es would operate and to show the advantages of such a system. Publicity The publicity for the biennium has centered around the above named objectives. Members of the Library Commission explained the work of the. Libn ry Commission and the plans for library extension at the state, libraiy meeting held in Lincoln, October 16-18, 1935, at the district library meetings in April, 1936, and before other groups. The executive secretary appeared on the programs of the annual) meet - ing of the Home Economics Section of Organized Agriculture in Janu - ary 1936, the state meeting of the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs held in Beatiice, October 20-22, 1936 and the state meeting of the Parent-Teache ■ Congress in Norfolk, October 7-9, 1936, and made brief announcements regarding the service to teachers and rural schools before the rural sections of two of the district teachers' meetings. The reference librarian spoke on the subject of what the Libr.ary Com - mission and other libraries could contribute to the summer recreational projects at n state meeting of recreational leaders in Lincoln in April 1936. Articles about the Library Commission and its Bookmobile have appeared in a nun ber of newspapers and magazines. A mimeographed news letter carrying library news and suggestions is sent out each month by the ex&lt;cutive secretary to librarians and library trustees. Copies of the mu licipal and county snd regional library laws were printed and distributed on request. A study course called "Equali - zation of Library Service" was prepared for the use of the Women's Rural Clubs under the direction of the Extension Department of the r College of Agricul ure. ■ - . ' ' -• Bookmobile •* One of j the most important aids in the program of the Library Commission I has been the new Bookmobile purchased during the sum - mer of 1936 and i rst displayed at the State Fair. The Library Com - mission is indebted to Mrs. R. L. Cochran for her interest in this project and to a group of Omaha business men for their gift of money which made the purchase of the book truck possible. The Bookmobile, which is a specially constructed half ton truck, is used for demonstration , purposes and carries a carefully selected collection of three hundred books. It has dene much to create interest in library extension. Cooperation with « tiler groups Representatives from the Library Commission have had numerous conferences Iwith representatives of other groups to discuss the exten - sion of library sen ice and have prepared for distribution lists of books 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">which could be borrowed from the Commission on such subjects as vocational guidance, social welfare, recreation and summer reading projects, etc. An increasing number of organizations have adopted library service as one of their projects. The A.A.U.W., the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs, the American Legion Auxiliary, and the Nebraska Parent-Teacher Congress have appointed state library chairmen. Participation in library meetings The executive secretary attended the mid-winter meeting of the American Library Association in Chicago, December 30,,1935-January 1, 1936, and the annual conference in Richmond, Virginia, May 11-16, 1936. She conducted a round table discussion of library problems at the eight district library meetings held in Nebraska in April, 1936. Members of the Library Commission and staff members attended the state library meeting in Lincoln, October 16-18, 1935. The executive secretary, reference librarian and one member of the Library Com - mission were present at the state library meeting in North Platte, October 21-23, 1936. Field Work One of the important duties of the Library Commission is to aid in the establishment of new libraries and to give information and help in library problems to those already established. This can be done best through visits to the communities interested and in conferences with the librarians and trustees. Since the staff does not include a field worker the executive" secretary has done as much of this work as possible, and other members of the stall have assisted with the Book - mobile. Altogether seventy-four libraries have been visited during the period covered by this report. Visits were made in response to invi - tations to contact groups interested in library extension, to assist in the formation of new libraries, to make a survey to help a library determine lines for future development, to be present at the opening of a new library building, etc. Correspondence . The Library Commission serves as a clearing house for librnry matters in the state and since the amount of field work which can be done is limited, a great deal of correspondence is involved. The Com - mission maintains an extensive file of material relating to libraries and this is sent out in response to requests for information on such prob - lems as planning new library buildings or equipment, cataloging, selec - tion of books, keeping records and other routine matters. A list of people desiring library positions is kept on file and furnished on request to librarians or library trustees. .■•■'■ Including the news letter, 17,679 letters and 3,366 postal cards were sent out during this period. 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Library conditions in the stale. ■ . . There are fiv« new libraiy buildings in Nebraska. The Lincoln Township Library building at' Wausa was opened October 13, 1935. The Chappell Meriorial Library and Art Gallery was dedicated July 18 1936. A building at Cody is about completed and will be dedicated soon. A cornmuni ;y building at Morrill which will house the library and a library bur ding at Rushville will probably be completed this winter. The Scottsbluff Public Library has increased its capacity by a large addition which was opened this summer. New rooms for children and young people were opened this fall in the basements of the' North Platte and Lincoln Public Libraries. An old church building at Nio - hrara has been bought by the library board and fitted up for th'e library. Several o her libraries which do not have their own buildings have moved to more commodious quarters. Government funds and projects have made it possible for many libraries to make needed repairs and improvements in their buildings. There have been several changes in librarians due to resignations and retirements. In filling vacancies library boards in general .are recognizing the fact that standards for librarians have raised and that so far as funds permit the person who is the best trained and fitted for the place should be employed. The voluntary ' certification plan adopted by the Nebraska Library Association has had some effect on improvement of library personnel. One hundred and eighty-three librarians have be( n granted certificates. Several small ncreases in appropiiations for library support have been reported. So f»e libraries which are receiving the maximum levy allowed by law fird that with the decrease in property valuation the amount provided is too small for efficient library service. The maxi - mum levy is one mill on the actual value of all taxable property, except for towns having a population of more than one thousand and less than five thousand which may levy one and one-half mills for library service. There see ns to be a definite need for finding some other source of income, either hrough a change in the law to raise the maximum levy, or through the formation of more townshin libraries or the establishment of county and repional libraries. Libraries may also enter into contracts with school districts. Comparison with ether states Statistics released by the American Library Association show that Nebraska ranks an follows in library service as compared with the other states: Circulation per capita of public libraries - - 25th with 3.31 volumes Number of volumes per capita in public libraries - 24th with .85 volumes Expenditures per capita for public library service - 29th wit^ 22 cents Per cent of population without local library service - - 22nd with 50% Recommendations if state library planning board The planning board appointed by the Nebraska Library Association to study the libraiy needs in the state and to make recommendations 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">for the improvement of existing conditions, recommends, among other things the following: i . Establishment of county and regional libraries to further the exten - sion of library service and to supplement the work of the Nebraska Public Library Commission. Revival of appropriation for library service in the state penal and welfare institutions and the appointment of a trained librarian super - visor. • ; i A state law requiring the certification of librarians of public libraries. i Improvement of school libraries iby following standards recom - mended by the North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, the certification of school librarians and the appointment of a trained library supervisor of school libraries. . I 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">SUMMARY OF STATISTICS Volumes in Library Volumes in library August 26, 1935 40,597 Volumes worn ou ; and discarded 848 Volumes added 4,218 Volumes in library "November 30, 1936 43,967 Record of Loans* Borrowers Requests Filled Volumes Groups of resident 46 2,779 Public libraries 939 36,889 Schools 1,165 41,419 Study clubs 307 719 Other organizations 30 1,324 Individurls 5,792 11,889 Total L 8,279 95,019 • Includes circulation from July 1. 19H3 to Aucust 28. 1935 ■ Expenditures Salaries S 7,700.20 Supplies - 541.93 Expense 1,989.93 Materials . 644.45 Books, magazines, etc. 6,361.27 Total . 1:..',! §17,237.78 Appropriation $25,000.00 Balance December 1, 1936 _. $ 7,762.22 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">1 *• " ■ STATE LIBRARIES - . Department Location ■ - Volumes Director Legislative Reference Bureau .Lincoln 35,000* Edna D. Bullock Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln 43,967 . Nellie M. Carey State Historical Society •„■ Lincoln "__.• 60,000 Mrs, C. S. Paine State Library Lincoln 103,181 George H. Turner 1 Chiefly pamphlets and clippings U.S. GOVERNMENT HOSPITAL LIBRARY Department , Location Volumes Director Veterans' Administration Hospital Lincoln _TI 2,561 Doris Rowland HIGH SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES School ■ • Location Volumes Librarian Alliance High School Alliance 1,800 Juanita Lang Beattice Schools Beatrice-^r=r^=r^zr^nm 2,000 __^_: — ■ — - — JtmtoT~HiglTScKool ,-v — ' ■ ■' - ' ■•■ -■- -" " Margaret Rutledge Senior High School Mrs. Eula Merwin _-— Broken Bow High School " Broken Bow . 2,740 Inez. Dean Concordia Teachers College Seward ;__ 6,200 H. O. A. Keinath College of St. Mary ._ „_.. .Omaha Sister Therese Marie Creighton University _ . Omaha ... 1... 46,378 Mrs. Lucile M. Reynolds. Dana College ... El ir .... 2 600 Dorthea Jensen Doane College " Crete 27,322 William B. Runt — — - 1 — Duchesne College . Omaha 8,382 Mrs. A. Munch Fairbury -High School l.Ffirbury ... 3,000 "Robert L. Pullen Falls City High School Falls City Mrs. Floy DeWald L_: Fremont High School . Fremont 1,600 Wilma Sargent 16 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">HIGH SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES (Continued) School Location Volumes Librarian Grand Island Schools R. J. Barr Junior High School Grand Island 2904 Catharine Glade Senior High School Grand Island 4,286 Alice E. Paine Walnut Junior High School Grand Island ...^ ' Florence Reese Hnstinjrs Pnllpfra Hastings ......,.,. 21,782 Marguerite Nesbit Hastings High Schools _'- Hastings _ 5,6W Glen H. James Hebron Junior College .-j. Hebron Josephine Schultz Holdrege High School Holdrege 3100 Mrs, Belva L. Melvin Hooper High School Hooper __ 1,025 Mrs. S. L. Whitcomb Kearney Schools Junior High School Kearney 1,700 Katharine Major Senior High School Kearney 2,713 Lucile Hrubesky Lincoln Schools Bethany High School Lincoln Mrs. Gladys Van Camp College View High School Lincoln 1,600 Elma Buchanan Everett Junior High School Lincoln 1,875 Frieda Schmeling Havelock Junior High School Lincoln . 696 Lillian Griffiths Irving Junior High School Lincoln 2,563 Aimee Johnston .Jackson High School Lincoln : Ann Munson Lincoln High School Lincoln 6,371 Emma E. Snyder Whittier Junior High School Lincoln 3,500 Anna H. Bethune Lexington High School Lexington ; 2,000 Jesse B. Thorpe Luther College Wahoo 6,000 Emma Peterson McCook Junior College McCook 1,400 Mrs. Noreen Anderson Midland College Fremont 15,179 Dorothy H. Dysinger Nebraska Central College Central City Milo H. Crosby Nebraska Wesleyan University Lincoln 28,118 Mrs. Ethol Lang-don Bishop Norfolk Senior High School Norfolk 4,200 Lora Heald North Platte Senior High School North Platte 4,000 Lucille Cooper Omaha Schools Benson High School Omaha 5,293 Elsa Smith Central High School ... ..Omaha 26,000 Zorar Shields" 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">HIGH SCHOOL AND COLLEGE LIBRARIES (Continued) School . Location Volumes ' Librarian North High School Omaha ..._ 7,009 Catherine Nichol " South High School Omaha 10,861 Ivae Walker Technical High School ..Omaha 18,732 May Ingles Omaha Municipal University Omaha 24 342 Inez Chesnut ■■ ' Scottsbluff H. S. and Junior College—.— Scottsbluff ~^_ .;— -t^^3|ooo T-EthelPflug Sidney High School Sidney _... 2,600 Verna Robinson • '" State- Teachers College Chadron 21,158 Harriet Wirick State Teachers College Kearney j 32,973 Anna V. Jennings State Teachers College .. Peru .44,380 Grace Mary Petersen State Teachers College __ , Wayne 20,205 Josephine Silvers Union College : ; Lincoln 20,500 D. G. Hilts University of Nebraska 1 .--Lincoln 305,999 Gilbert H. rwu™ -— — ¥ork-4Hgh-Sehool York 2191 Jessie Stewart York College :. ._ York _. 12,910 Edith M. Cone 18 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">LIBRARIES NOT TAX-SUPPORTED There are in Nebraska a large number of libraries not included in the list of tai :-supported libraries. These libraries are usually sponsored and maintained by some club or organization. The list may not be complete die to the difficulty of securing reports. A few other libraiies not mentic ned are in the process of organization. Some of these libraries receive a small amount from the town and in t other cases rooms, heat and li|fht are furnished. fc Avoca Dorchester Nehawka Bartlett Douglas Nemaha Bassett Dunning Niobrara Battle Creek Edgar Nora Beaver City Edison Oak Beaver Cross ng Elm Creek Oconto Belden Ericson Ohiowa • Belvidere Eustis Orchard Benkelman Exeter Palmer Berwyn Giltner Palmyra Big Springs Grant Paxton Bingham Greenwood Pilger Bloomington Gresham Platte Center Boelus Gretna Primrose Broadwater Haigler Ralston I Brock Halsey Republican City Brown % Hie Hardy Rising City Bruning Hayes Center Roseland Brunswick Heartwell Ruskin Burchard Herman Salem ' Campbell Howells Shelby Carleton Hubbell Shubert Chambers Hyannis Stapleton Chester Indianola Swanton Clarkson Ithaca Taylor Cody Keystone Thedford' Concord Lindsay Tobias Cook Litchfield Tryon Crab Orchar 1 Loretto Uehling Crest on Madrid Verdon ■ Crookston Mason City Waco Dalton Maxwell Wauneta Dannebrog Mead Western Davenport Melbeta Whitney - : Daykin Minatare Wilber Deshler Murray Wilsonville Wolbach 19 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">I TAX-SUPrORTED LIBRARIES ' Receipts ' Expenditure! j§ I ... . I ■ -- \\ 11 J II, II Iif 111 Ib 1 Over 30,000 population . „ " •■• 75 933 Lincoln Lulu Home 1 120.224 28.263 745.549 S52.971.38 Sfi.S81.S8 $74,802.47 $14,096.42 $30,926.82 $18,983.95 214 006 Omaha -Bertha Biiumer . 197.109 47.849 Ii88.533 70.000.00 1.834.88 71.834.93 15.471.52 41.427.02 71.834.88 10 001-30,000 population 10,297 Beutrlce -' Maitec Evans 23,864 4.917 122.325 7.000.00 C2.I.12 7.023,12 2.731.41 2 596.63 6.6(9.51 11.407 Fremont Mildred 1'ulmcr 17.009 3.470 81.901 0.300.00 (ifO.01 7.(88 81 1.521.19 1.950.75 0.873.25 18.011 Grand Island Daisy Huuck --.„ 20 312 4.666 89.235 9.000.00 9 000.00 2.128.53 4.048.00 8.807.43 15.490 Hastines Mrs. Ellun D. Smith .. 20.037 7.17S 10H.0I5 7.OCO.0O 750.19 7,756.19 2.225.75 3.316.25 7.209.26 10,717 NorfolK I.nuru I'turlund - 12..S59 4.027 51 548 ... _ „ '— 12.061 North P!atto -—Eleanor M. Wheeler 10,827 4.833 88.508 3.932.81 420.00 4,464.95 " : 779.02 -2.602.50 4,075.42 — 1= OoriO.OOO population » — 6,669 Alliance Mrs. Blanche Prettymun 12 983 4 8S2 00.522 4.0C0 00 4 000.00 f38.38 1.200.00 3.886.37 4.606 Chadron Mrs. Loio- Skilcs 10,576 2.003 47.269 2.690.00 " T «fig."M 3 357 93 739.79 1.1.84.60 2.635.65 6.8M Columbus Rose Kiddi-ll 13.034 4.625 53.202 -1,000.0(1 4.000.00 1053.35 1.54000 3.027.24 .6,192 Fnirbury Mrs. Naomi Ellsworth . 12 684 &amp;071 &lt;.9.712 4.177.27 """50? 42 4 682.69 1.4S8.4O 1.450.30 4,185.44 5.787 Falls City »-Mary HuU'hinw 20.8S9 1.705 07 19S . 3.80O.O0 ' 321.25 ' 4.124A5 1.153.36 1.487.30 4.305.10 8.575 Kearney Mrs. Mary E. O'Brian -. 13.289 5.000 47,576 6.000.00 199.94 6.700.97 8O3..S1 1.870.25 3.9fS9.20 6.fi38 McCuiik — Millicent M. Sluhy 9.181 4.848 W.236 2.nol.f,O IC1.30 3.847.11 753.91 1.258.05 2.925.86 7.230 Nebraska City Anne Stevenson 13.443 1.875 32.249 3.222.79 527.05 5.5:18.00 1,383.47 1.4.VJ.C0 3,815.10 8.465 Scottsbluff Mrs. Nellie Wilson 18.47(1 4.205 73,899 3.S8!i.00 3 S86.46 1.19S.22 2.264.50 3.886.46 5.712 York Ada Haitk-ard 10 076 2.0(10 25.635 3.MI2.80 4.97».33 700.83 1.440.00 3.440.02 2,501-l,0&gt;0 population . -. 3 068 Auburn Lorene Anderson 8,881 3.2.U 32^90 2.105.82 105.82 2 331.16 296.74 903.60 1.957.70 2.715 Aurora Lillian M01.ro 10.140 1.450.00 130.28 1.930.61 597 77 751.(10 2.350 30 2.791 Blair — May MtQuarric 0 500 3.038 28 316 1.400.00 225.13 1.7 J 0 07 381.37 720.00 1.776.09 2.115 Broken Bow — -Either l.nnirfellow 0,353 738 25 5S8 ' 2.633.00 312.33 2.965.33 983.77 657.50 2.261.73 2.S65 Crete Mrs. C. F. Baker" 10 564 3.iB5 20.869 1.300.45 121.01 1.422.09 31.3.77 7:12.80 1.647.32 2.531 Gerinit ;^==--i--— Mm. Nellk- «. IVrfinu . 7.044 2.549 45.490 739.53 261.49 1.534.71 S92.00 600.00 1.523.37 3.263 Holilreuo Hettie Biukman 9*S.i 1.226 44.98:1 1.858.21 ;i;i8«4 2.22S.78 601.25 720.00 2.187.41 2 962 Lexinslon Mary I. Cooper - 7.187. 1S.341 1.731.62 99.76 1.836.58 520.04 780.00 1.986.85 3,973 Plattsmouth C. Olive Junes 20.B29 1.598 43,335 3.000.00 204.78 3.201.78 754.88 1.676.50 3.144.33 2.588 Schuyler Mrs. Alice Carl 7.233 1.9)5 10.617 141.06 600.00 1.16Q.89 t Township library * Includes township populatiun 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">. TAX-SUI'POKTKD LIBRARIES— (Continued) I I Kcrclpts Expenditures • - ■- 1 IMrl! ir ii ill if II? i 2.737 Seward Mr, Emma Bredeknmp . 6.798 1.819 2H.290 &gt;-™g-&lt;» — - " ~i^^ 2.172 Albion Mrs. Jenn o Gradon — 6.222 16.0W 1.4U0.UU.. Vfissis 215^24 60000 1.232.2.1 lion Bdl-vul Mrs. Julia Stark »' - g ,^ X 1.401* "AS?— «U0 mM 1.48C Clarkst Sj?,\ C1 li, SchEnk i 4'WB 1 300 MOT lifiOOiOO IZZZ llsS 00 496.85 320.40 1.600.00 ■S-S^^l^fe'E B Tig as ..ffig-w* 2 g 3$ asas f Township library • Includes township population - 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">gsf^sssss'agss^sssss igsggj^g isssss £ ' ! — ■ ' f I jo; IU8? } o Bgg.gg3ggSSSSSSS.SSS Iggjg !S3SS-:§SBBg 1 »*i«npx» §iiisiii§Pi§g§iii ggg iass ilagss &amp; ~~ «ü ß ,« q » s .°sgsgssg^s;i?a^s^g ;s .gsasg :s?g ,s . »n,pn,S;i iiiiiiiisgggss|gg| g ||g ? ;g| s jg [g « 1 ■■■ ; B§gg !?. :! : ;2£S :aS*B |!3 ; iSSS : iSSS |!3 bf 3 SJ,. J a MSO! j III! """l " ;™ I I — **',[&lt;*&gt; «! —i, | 1 SggigsSSgig3s§?Sgg Ig Igggsg l = 3ggs tl O ■ spun^ I SSiSBiiBSi5SSSgS|i ;S iSSSSS I^SSSSJ = = | „„„ _ M- « „„„ ;„;„„„ !„ „- Q / . '. ' a , __J&gt; . • ' J &#132; f ' Ohi•.-•ii•■•i:iii■;,u, i . i , i ; i &#132; , , , , , . , id . • ■. .u ig :;c■jj i I j 1 1 ilf |; . :-3 :| j ■'. !i I /■' j ■ 5 ""■.;■ '■ Illtijf Jlil^J iSfi Mi y i-iC: is | ■ ' i^i.iiiii^iiiiigisiil i^i i s^i&lt; i illlii{5llllllllljlill!li|;ii|!l J ■ s iiii iHHiHipuiitliUliJlfiii • £? ' 22 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">TAX-SUPPORTED LIHHARIES (Coutinuea) ' I . r Receipts Expenditures 1 479 Stanton ZL-Mm. J. D. Klmore 3.M7 — — 8 367 ----- — Yo.M 650.00 44,40 300.00 473.18 }; 4 320 it?omb n urß--:::::-...Po KK y Halden -- 2 500 S5O s^oo 800.00 f^ IMJO IiU9J4 lilOS Tilden — 6 nna M St F ntO With e Vs" ilw 305 8!(M2 600.00 214.13 M9.49 70.63 176,45/ 838.35 t Township library • Includes township population 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">- TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) . I ~ Receipts Expenditures 6^ Iciih ""Mrs J j Tear" ZZ lS »5 aisiZ 325.00 ...1.... 456.^6 2.5.42 12.00 444.10 t Townshii) library * Includes township population 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Continued) ' Receipts ' -Expenditures If 'I ■ I.:- Jl If- 1 .44- II l|l 1!! 11! I _ 756 Morrill .777.77J7.7.ATma~~wTc1tin7iV\1777"— "1f.318 424 ~6/J«4 ~2fiSUO 161.98 ~2.18Q.a8 16»~Ii» ■ 180.55 439.92 903 Nelson Alice E. Ruddell . 2,fi00 690 7,950 205.98 203.65 487.72 70.40 101.20 297.04 663 Oakdalo Gertrude B. Govo ■:..:.. 5.167 _ 150.00 20.00 204.20 59.50 104.00 - 187.00 843 Osbkosh I_ Mattie Avfdeniturten .. 2.5)4 542 9,133 131.12 30.63 G85.55 94.08 (iO.OO 167.85 718 PaplUion - Mrs. Ernest Ross _. 2.022 683 3,832 120.00 67.26 207.49 34.70 120.00 155.50 532 Polk _ Mrs. J. E. MeDuniel — 1.170 305.00 108.7G 90.00 304.76 920 Ponca" :.• Mrs. M. Lipe i 5.435 500 4,595 350.00 436.41 42.40 182.45 436.41 515 Potter 1^ - — - - 389 lh°ckley _i__lM»Hlllda "Uchtl '. Tiii 160 4,614 "SoToO 16.63 217.W 120.13 52^50 1W.38 908* Silver CreekT" _ Lucille Abel 3,542 547 7.925 1.500.00 59.fi6 1,776.55 386.65 360.00 1,413.83 839 Spuldinß Jill Mrs. Frank Dunnin* ... 2.704 10,801 172.13 125.00 333.61 7.28 180.00 301.80 419 Sprinefield — Verlia Bolen 1.034 3,321 162.86 162.86 10.00 144.00 162.8C 702 Sterlini .— T—lLjlra. Mary Hollenback 207 6.332 350.00 350.00 18.15 210.00 282.15 663 Stratton 763 Stuart Mariruerite Smith — 947 lyraeuse nd _ ~H""Anne°ScelhSfrTrr.".".""7. 2,168 ".".7.7.. "67546 "428"&lt;it 17.66 1.036.08 ~2~72~44 170"oO 876J7 673 Table Rock "II Mrs. Allic Wood 1.433 190 2.45S 270.43 23.17 513.65 94.32 74.00 252.60 474 Talmaee Sophia Moller 1.664 294 3.744 299.78 15.47 325.54 39.99 180.00 249.02 6M TrS ZZZ-ZJmZ.A. T. McCoy 2.925 277 6.«82 100.00 59.97 159.97 100.30 163.17 523 Valparaiso" Mrs. Madga Porter 2.014 ..- 125.00 30.00 1.83.00 69.81 100.00 181.10 432 Waterloo Mrs. W. 11. Jacobson ... 1.500 196 1,500 100.00 100.00 44.25 62.00 100.00 723* Wircoxt Mrs. Emma J. Cox 786 102 1,058 100.00 16.61 244.17 69.88 92.40 187.06 483 W nsidl 7-~7.-Mrs Etta Perrin 2.465 500 4.676 265.72 31.51 490J4 109.17 180.00 327.01 761 Wood River 7. 7-Sabra J. Abbott 4,057 450 10,477 402.63 402.83 89.84 , 180.00 436.56 t Township library • Includes township population 25 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>