<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Convenient Kitchen</title>
               <date value="1920-09">1920-09</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin 60 August, 1920 The Convenient Kitchen THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE LINCOLN U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">of 360 A United States Department of Agriculture survey Nebraska farm homes shows the following facts: 30 per cent have water in kitchen 79 per cent have kitchen cabinets 73 per cent have kerosene stoves 13 per cent have fireless cookers 49 per cent have linoleum on kitchen floor 12 per cent have bread mixers 2 per cent have wheel trays 3 per cent have dumb-waiters 51 per cent have screened porches </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE CONVENIENT KITCHEN EsTHEK WaKNEB harge House Administra, II at L'nkersity of Nebraska The kitchen is the homemaker's workshop. It should be the most convenient and the most cheerful room in the house. As a usual thing not enough time and attention are given to planning the kitchen. It should be equipped with the necessary furniture and utensils for the work to be done there. This equipment should be so placed that the woman who is to spend a part of the 365 days of every year there can do so without the least expenditure of time, strength and nervous energy. With such a workshop the homemaker will enjoy the hours she spends in it and she will take much pride in keeping it, as it should be, the most sanitary place in the house. ESSENTIALS IN A WELL-PLANNED KITCHEN In planning the new house or remodeling the old one, the following things should be accomplished for the kitchen: 1. Properly placed windows and doors which will insure convenience, cross-ventilation, adequate light, with resultant healthful, pleasant con - ditions. 2. Sanitary, attractive finish for walls and floors. 3. Compact working space with the elimination of unnecessary walk - ing and undue fatigue. 4. Good equipment, making possible effective work with minimum effort. To attain these ends consideration must be given to the following: EXPOSURE In what part of the house should the kitchen be located? There are arguments for and against every exposure and one has to make her own choice. East — morning sunshine, relatively cool afternoons. South — prevailing summer breezes, much winter sunshine. West — shady and cool in the morning, hot on a summer afternoon. North — good light to work by, practically no sunshine. The kitchen should have two outside walls for windows in order to insure cross-ventilation. Since many people want the living room with a southern exposure, the kitchen is often put in the northeast or northwest corner, thus securing good light and sunshine. The location chosen will depend on when most of the work is to be done and whether the home - maker prefers to work in the sunshine or shade. In a family where the preparation of a heavy supper comes in the afternoon, west windows would be a calamity. The kitchen should have a pleasant outlook such as the yard where the children play or the main road. It is sometimes desirable to see the barnyard with its activities. GENERAL PLAN After deciding where the windows are to be located other considera - tions enter in: 1. Sufficient wall space must be left by the openings to place to advantage other large pieces of equipment — the stove, sink, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Service Hii.i.ktix No. (&gt;0 2. Windows at 42 to 46 inches from the floor allow working tables and shelves to be placed below. 3. Windows running to at least one foot from the ceiling permit good ventilation when they are lowered. 4. All windows should open at top and bottom. 5. A glass in the upper part of a kitchen door serves as a window for lighting purposes. 6. A transom above a kitchen door in the wall adjacent to or opposite a window will help keep the air fresh in a room where space for many windows is lacking. 7. Light should fall on the working space. If the worker stands at the sink or table with her back to the window or lighting fixture, she is always in her own light. 8. Doors should be conveniently placed. Have as few as possible since they break up much needed wall space. They should be arranged so that the paths of travel from one door to another do not cross Jhe working space. The kitchen should be located with reference to demands for the worker in other parts of the house. There should be a short route to telephone and doorbell. A bedroom and toilet on the first floor save an FIG. 1— ARRANCE WORKING SPACE WITH CAKE Notice the good arrangement of this kitchen. The rii.she* may he slacked at the right of the sink, drained at the left, and after drying placed in the cuplward at the end of the table. The small utensils are within easy reach. There is plenty of well-lighted table space and the view from the window is good. The iron is sometimes attached as shown for convenience in pressing small articles. The table in the center provides extra room for working. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Coxvexiext Kitchen 5 FIC. 2.— CAREFUL PLANNING WILL SAVE STEPS This is the same kitchen as shown in Figure 1. Note the convenience which results when the ice box, cabinet anil range are placed close together. A minimum number of ileps are necessary in the preparation of a meal with such an arrangement. The ice box is built for outside filling. The cabinet was one of the old type where the doors made the table practically useless. The top has been lifted, a board inserted under - neath, so that the doors no longer interfere with the working space. The stove h.'is the splendid feature of having the high oven with the broiler beneath. The coffee tricolater is a decided improvement over the ordinary coffte pot. Cross-ventilation is secured thru the grade door beyond the ice box and the hall door opposite. immense amount of running up and down stairs. The children can take their naps in this room and in case of illness it is invaluable. A screened porch for a play room in sight from the kitchen is a big help. Of course the working area proper, the kitchen, the dining room, back porch, washroom, cellar door, pantry or storeroom, should be planned to make necessary the fewest steps possible. The pantry located between the kitchen and dining room is losing its popularity because it increases the distance from the stove to the dining table, and from the table to the sink. Even if a sink is located in the pantry for the washing of china and silver - ware either the pots and kettles must be carried there or the dish pans carried to the kitchen proper. A more popular plan is to have a storeroom off the kitchen where groceries and meats kept in quantities may be stored, and put plenty of cupboard space in the kitchen. A washroom for men connecting with the back porch and dining room saves much unnecessary tracking thru the kitchen with its resulting dirt and confusion. This room provides a place to hang outside wraps, and if large enough, may be used for a laundry. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Service Buixktin No. 00 SIZE OF KITCHEN The size of the kitchen is the first thing to decide when planning for compact arrangement and small working spaces. No one size of kitchen and no one plan of kitchen will suit every one, but there are some general considerations one must take into account. The size of the kitchen depends on a number of factors: 1. Work to be done in the kitchen. Women are finding it easier to make a kitchen just big enough to accommodate the work of getting meals and clearing them away. The old-fashioned kitchen was a combination of kitchen, dining room, laundry, washroom, and often living room; and it had to be large enough to take care of all these activities. It meant much confusion and the distance traveled three times a day in the getting of meals was often longer and more wearisome than was necessary. If one lives in an old-fashioned house, it is nearly always possible to group the equipment in one end of the room or divide the room, making one part a laundry and washroom and the other part kitchen and dining room. FIG. 3— THE HIGH OVEN DOES AWAY WITH A LOT OF STOOPING Note the hood over the oven to carry away objectionable gases and odors. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Convenient Kitchen 7 FIG. 4— AVOID THE LOW OVEN The low oven necessitates much stooping. Otherwise this kitchen, whicli over one in an old house, has many good features. The work table is under the window ami mixing howl and measuring spoons are hung near by. The lop finish of the wain - scotting has been utilized as a narrow .shelf for spices. Note the long hooked pole for louermg the windows. The refrigerator, which might easily be iced from the outside, and supply cupboards are in a corner to the left. This is a dark corner now but some day a window will be cut in above the refrigerator. The old iron sink has been made more useful by placing it in the zinc table. The changes made in this kitchen might be possible in many others. Oftentimes a woman works to a disadvantage when it is un - necessary. With very little expenditure of money an inconvenient kitchen may be made into a much more desirable one if the one who is working in it gives sufficient thought to possible changes. 2. Size of the family and number of people who will work in the kitchen. If a house is built to accommodate ten persons, it is only reason - able to suppose there will be two workers in the kitchen for part of the time and there must be space for them to work. On the other hand a bungalow built for four people at most would be arranged for one person at a time in the kitchen. 3. Country home or town home. In the country plans must be made for the times of year when there are large numbers to provide for, such as harvesting or haying seasons. Rather than build an immense kitchen it is better economy to utilize a screened porch or some adjacent room for the extra space required at these times. 4. Kind of fuel used. Where coal, cobs, or wood are burned it will take a larger kitchen to be comfortable than if gas or electricity is used. In a country home then where two women will often work together but where good storage facilities are provided and the kitchen is used for preparation of food only, the dimensions of the kitchen need not be more than 10 by 14 feet, 12 by 12 feet, or 11 by 13 feet. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Extension Service Bulletin* No. &lt;&gt;() WORKING ARRANGEMENTS There are two working units in every kitchen, the one of meal preparation and the other of clearing away. The first includes refrigerator, cabinet or work tables, stove, and a shelf or table for "dishing up" the food. The second includes a table for stacking dishes, the sink, drain board, and china cupboards. The problem is to arrange this equipment in the most convenient way with all the small utensils needed for the work in hand grouped near by. The ice box is often set on the back porch or in a nearby entry with the idea of saving ice. Very likely ice can be saved, but the saving is rendered more than useless by the increased trotting back and forth on the part of the worker. The ice box should be near the work table and as near as possible to the dining room. Its most convenient location is to the left of the work table. If an outside door for filling the box can be arranged it saves tracking up the kitchen floor. During the cool months of the year this outside door can be left open and the box used for food storage as in the summer. The stove should be placed to the right of the work table. In the case of a coal stove it had better be on an adjacent wall rather than near enough the cabinet (or working surface) to be uncomforotably hot. An oil stove for summer use is almost a necessity and one handy arrangement is to put the oil stove to the right of the range. A board may be fitted to the top of the stove, with cleats nailed on the under side to keep the board from resting on the burners. Cover this board with oil cloth or zinc and the oil stove becomes a most convenient table for serving up the hot food during the winter. In summer the process can be reversed, the range covered with newspapers and used as a table while the oil stove is used for cooking. The serving shelf or table should be as near the dining room door as possible. Whereas it is natural for a woman to pass to the right each time in going from ice box to cabinet to stove, etc., in washing dishes the reverse is true. The dirty dishes should be stacked on a shel' p* wh°el°d tray to the right of the dish pan, and with the rinsing pan to the left. Farther still to the left are the drain board and china closet. The best place for the china cupboard is in the wall between the kitchen and dining room with doors to both. (See Figure 5.) The plan of the kitchen in Figure 5 has been made with many of these features in mind. It is a country kitchen for a family with several children. The washroom is well-located and makes it unnecessary for the men to come thru the kitchen at meal time. The ice box is as far as possible from the stove and close to the work table. The back door has a large glass in it and a transom above. The range is quite a distance from the work table. If the coal fire were not used to any extent in the summer, the positions of the two stoves could be reversed, but in hot weather the work table would be needlessly hot so close to the range. A woodbox may stand to the left of the stove. A large pantry or cold closet is used for storage of flour and canned goods during the winter. A drop shelf under the window near the cellar way would be a convenience. Additional equipment which could be used to good advantage would be a table on castors in the center of the room or a wheeled tray as shown in Figure 8. LOCATION OF UTENSILS There is a difference of opinion as to whether the smaller kitchen equipment should be hung in the open or put into cupboards and drawers. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Thk Convenient Kitchen 9 If drawers are used make them quite shallow, just deep enough to hold their special articles, and use partitions to keep things in place. That will do away with the necessity of hunting under things for the desired utensil. Those favoring cupboards argue that utensils hung above the table and around the stove collect dirt, make the kitchen harder to clean and are unsightly. To meet these objections, it is suggested that: 1. Only utensils used every day be hung in the open. 2. Taking down the articles and cleaning them is no harder than caring for the drawer and shelf space. 3. A kitchen is a workshop and is most beautiful when it serves its purpose best. A good workshop is convenient and efficient. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Extension Service Bulletin No. (H) 10 THE RIGHT HEIGHT BY PLACING FU, 7.-THIS WOMANMADE HER TABL^THE^IGHT^ </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Convenient Kitchen 11 Over the work table, or in easy reach in the cabinet, should 1 measuring cup 1 mixing spoon 1 case knife 1 steel spatula 1 kitchen fork 1 tablespoon 1 -well-sharpened butcher knife 1 teaspoon 1 egg whisk 1 pastry board 1 Dover egg beater 1 meat board The flour sifter and rolling pin are usually kept in the flour bin, and a cup in the sugar jar. This is a satisfactory arrangement. Screws can be put in knife handles, brushes, etc., and make it possible to hang them up. Muffin pans, pie tins, and other cooking dishes not used every day should be stored in a cupboard near the work table. Near the stove should be skillets suited to the size of the family, a long-handled fork, a cooking spoon, 1 pancake turner, 1 wire potato masher, tea and coffee pots and supply jars. Extra skillets, colanders, skimmers, etc., should be near at hand. About the sink should be found : 1 can opener 1 dish mop 2 sharp paring knives 2 dish pans 1 corkscrew 1 soap shaker 1 vegetable scrub brush 1 sink brush 1 pair scissors 1 sink strainer A kettle for potatoes and a sauce pan or two for vegetables should be near the sink. CUPBOARDS It is a problem to plan convenient cupboards. They are needed for storage by work table, stove and sink; and they must be arranged so as not to interfere with the table space. Following are some suggestions: 1. A cupboard should be built flat on the floor or in the case of a cabinet, be on legs high enough to permit easy cleaning of the floor below. 2. Cupboards may be built to the ceiling to eliminate cleaning the top. If this is done the doors should be divided and the part of the cup - board used for every day equipment should not be more than six feet from the floor. The smaller upper part can be used for the storage of utensils used only a few times a year. One suggestion is to make a sloping top to a cupboard so it can be easily dusted off. 3. Cupboard shelves should be just wide enough to accommodate the supplies to be put on them. Three-inch shelves will take care of spices and extracts. Eight inches is good for cereals and other large boxes. Many small things stored on a wide shelf mean that boxes are set two or three deep and the housekeeper has to move them and search out the desired article. 4. Cupboard doors which open out over the work area should be about 12 inches above it. One woman had a carpenter put a 12-inch board between the zinc top and cupboard part of her kitchen cabinet, stained the board so that it matched the rest, and did away with the nuisance of clear - ing off the table each time she opened or closed the cabinet doors. (See cabinet in Figure 2.) 5. Shelves more than 12 inches deep over a work table create an awkward, inconvenient space back under the shelf. The wider the shelf the higher it must be from the working surface. 6. The farther edge of the work table must be easily reached by the worker — 22 to 25 inches is an average width. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Extension Service Bulletin No. 60 7. In all built-in equipment, it must be remembered that the height of working surface is of utmost importance. Stooping over a sink when washing dishes or kneading bread on a table which is too low will use up energy and "pep" and give absolutely no return. An easy test for the worker to apply to her working surface is to stand erect and place her hands with palms flat on the table. If she can do this without bending her back this height should give her the least strain while working at the table. Some suggested heights are: Base of sink from floor Table tops Worker's height 29 M&gt; inches ::p, inches 5 feet 32% inches 34 inches 5 feet 6 inches INTERIOR FINISH Interior finish must be considered with the items of sanitation, com - foit, and good cheer in mind. For door and window casings a waxed or varnished hardwood, oak, iraile, ash, or birch, with no unnecessary grooves or cracks, is relatively easy to keep clean. White or cream enamel paint is beautiful but a constant care. The side walls require a finish easily cleaned or renewed. A smooth hard plaster can be painted and gives a washable surface. The color would depend on the lighting; a soft gray being good in a sunny room, and the buff tints better where the lighting is not so good. A pure white is hard FI(.. 8.— EVERY CONVENIENCE LESSENS THE HOUSEWIFE'S BURDEN A garliag ■ can with cover operated by the foot is both convenient and sanitary. Where the cupboards are not close a wheeled tray takes all the dishes at one trip. A sink with two drain loards is very convenient. The dishes are stacked to the right, washed :n the sink, and drained to ;he left. A trap under the sink often saves plumbing hills because it is easily accessible for cleaning. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Convenient Kitchen 13 on the eyes and needs frequent washing. A very light weight oil cloth also gives satisfaction. Paper absorbs grease, catches soot and should not be used. A rough- finish plaster is not washable and can only be thoroly cleaned by repainting. The kitchen floor is a big prob - lem to interior decorators and homemakers alike. Hard wear and constant cleaning are a se - vere test for any finish. Here are listed some of the most com - mon ways of caring for the kitchen floor: 1. Hard woods — maple or oak — are easy to stand on. Dressed well with hot linseed oil and the extra oil wiped off in 15 or 20 minutes, these woods give good service. Places which re ceive very hard wear, such as just in front of the sink, can be re-oiled without going over the whole floor again. Oil tends to darken floors and unless well wiped up catches the dust badly. Given two or more coats ot waterproof varnish, a hard-wood floor is not difficult to clean Spots where the varnish wears thru cannot be repaired to look well without refinishing the whole floor. Hard-wood floor? need some kind of dressing otherwise they are hard to keep clean and shrink and splinter under constant scrubbings. 2. Linoleum — inlaid — is a cork composition, comfortable to stand on, comparatively easy to clean, wears a long time and is expensive. It should be laid by an expert and can be used only on an absolutely smooth floor If for any reason it buckles or is uneven, the ridges will catch the bulk of the wear and soon spoil the whole piece. Cement ing it to the floor is one good method. It may be varnished or waxed if desired. 3. Linoleum — printed — is alsc used. The pattern wears off rapidly under hard usage tho its life is prolonged by waxing or varnishing. Fill. 10— A COOP TYPF. OF STOVF. EASY TO CLEAN. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Extension Service Bulletin No. 60 14 4. Cement or tile floors are hard to stand on, but easy to keep clean Tile is very expensive. 5. Paint is often used on old floors, but it wears off rapidly. WATER IN THE KITCHEN In discussing the kitchen plan, the sink has been mentioned as an accepted part of the equipment, and it should be so considered in every home. In some houses the cistern with a pump in the kitchen and some simple system of piping away the waste water is all that will be found possible. Even this is an immense help. Given a force pump, a piece of hose may be attached to the spout, and reservoir, wash boiler, and tubs filled without any lifting of water. By using three-way valves and a force pump, a pipe may be run to a range boiler and hot water be available. (See Fig. 11.) A system a little more expensive but excellent in many ways is the elevated tank located in a nearby hill, on top of the silo, or in the attic. Its one drawback is lack of pressure in case of fire. The pneumatic and fresh water systems have all the advantages of a city water supply. EQUIPMENT The selection of kitchen equipment is a huge and complex problem. One can only state a very few facts and then the buyer must use her own judgment. Enameled sinks are best since they are smooth, easily cleaned, non - absorbent and will not rust. Care must be taken not to hit an enameled sink hard sharp blows or it may chip. Porcelain is ideal but more expensive. The kitchen range must not only bake well and use as little fuel as possible, but must be easy to clean. The enameled stoves are good. All late models have smooth trimmings and very little "fancy work" on them. The oil and coal combination shown in Figure 9 is quite expensive but very satisfatcory. The range in Figure 10 shows the tendency toward plain washable surfaces. THE BUYING OF NEW EQUIPMENT In buying equipment the following points are worth thinking about: 1. Will the utensil live up to the advertisement? For example, some advertisements used to declare nothing could burn in aluminum. The housewife knows this statement is not true. 2. What is the cost of up-keep? In a small family does it take more money and effort to keep the electric dishwasher going than to wash the dishes by hand ? 3. Is there extra effort spent in using the article? If the new cream whip will do its work in half the time of the old one, does it take three times as long to wash it? 4. What kind of handles are best? Handles should not get too hot to touch. Bails with wooden parts fall over and burn off. Utensils to be set in the oven should not have wooden handles. 5. Is it easy to handle? The cast aluminum teakettle may indeed last a lifetime, but its weight may make that fact a doubtful blessing. 6. Is the lip of the utensil in the right place? Can you hold it in the hand you naturally use and pour from it easily? </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Convenient Kitchen </seg>
            <seg id="p016">!&lt;:■ Extension Servick IKxi.etix No. 00 7. Is it easy to clean? Cracks, sharp edges, or corners, and compli - cated parts are a great trouble. 8. Is the material adapted to its purpose? For long, steady cooking close covered iron kettles may be desirable; for bread baking, tin pans; for cooking potatoes and acid foods, enamel ; for general cooking, aluminum. 9. Is the article a fuel saver? Utensils with straight sides, such as a tireless cooker utensil which fits over the gas flame, are better than those with a small base and sloping sides. LABOR-SAVING DEVICES Every woman has her own pet labor savers. Here are some that are being used in Nebraska kitchens: The woodbox on legs does away with needless stooping. Castors on the box so that it may be trundled to the door for the small boy to fill, will save work and dirt in the kitchen. A waste-paper basket near the table where the groceries are undone saves steps. A screened box fastened on the sill outside a shaded kitchen window is a fine place to store food, especially during spring and fall. The bread mixer has proved its right to a place in the kitchen. A box for recipe cards may be bought or made from a box for cor - respondence cards. Put a hole in the top of each card and hang it on a nail over the work table when using it. Cleaning closets with a definite place to store brooms, dust cloths, and furniture polish, carpet cleaners, etc., are invaluable. A small grindstone fastened in some handy place will insure a sharp knife more often than waiting for the man of the house to sharpen it. A hammer and nails should be a part of every kitchen equipment. No kitchen is complete without a clock on some shelf. A "scrubbing chariot" on castors saves sore knees and means less back breaking. The high stool in the kitchen is as necessary as a chair in the dining room. (5Mi Distributed in furtherance of cooperative agricultural extension work. Acts of May 8. 1914, and June 30, 1914. Extension Service of The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture and U. S. Department of Agriculture cooperating. W. H. Brokaw, Director of Extension Service. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>