<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00018">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00018</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fifteenth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Fifteenth Biennial Report OP THE Superintendent OF THE Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska NORFOLK. NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">340 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA, NORFOLK, NEBRASKA RESIDENT OFFICERS G. K. Ohaki.tox. Superintendent J. H. Mattiiai Assistant Superintendent and Physician Win. is Wilson Staff Physician A. J. GlTZMER. Steward Bkktiia Lcbwm Matron La " : v h " ■ , Bookkeeper </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 341 HOSPITAL FOR THE INSANE OF NEBRASKA, NORFOLK, NEBRASKA To his Hiidhiiri/, Honorable Keith Xnilh , Uocemor, and to tin Honorable Member* of the Hoard of Commit - niixsioiiifs of Staff Institution*. Henry Gertie*, sihix .!. Ifolrowb. and Eugene O. Motffirht. !( ntlcmen: In accordance with the laws of the state I beg to sub - mit, for your consideration, this, our Fifteenth Biennial Report for the Hospital for the Insane of Nebraska, ending November 30, 1918. MOVEMENT OF PATIENTS At the beginning of the period there were present in the hospital five hundred and sixty-nine patients, of whom three hundred and nine were male and two hundred and sixty were female. Three hundred and thirty-nine patients were admitted during the period — two hundred and fifteen male and one hundred and twenty- four female — making a total under treatment of nine hundred and eight patients. Of this number fifty-four patients were discharged as re - covered, while thirty-two left the care of the hospital as improved. Among this number several gave promise of complete recovery, and a number, it was thought, would further improve. Many of them were anxious to return to their homes to assume their activities and responsiblities of life. Not all, however, continued to do well, and in a num - ber of instances were returned to the hospital by friends or relatives before the expiration of parole. Thirty-nine pa - tients were removed from the hospital as unimproved, three patients were discharged as not insane, and one hundred and fifty-foux patients died. The number remaining in the hospital at the end of the biennium was six hundred and sixteen patients, — three hundred and forty male and two hundred and seventy-six female. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">342 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF The records, upon admission, of those received during the two years, while obtained at the time in as careful a manner as possible, were shown, by subsequent examina - tions of the patients, and the use of the laboratory, to be very often utterly unreliable and of little value, particularly in regard to the more important features. Among the admissions, covering the past two years, there were seventy-five cases of various types of dementia - praecox. forty-six cases of senile psychoses, forty-six of devel - opment defect, thirty-nine of maniac depressive form, forty - five of paresis, one of Huntingdon's chorea, and one of pellagra, the remaining admissions comprising the various other forms of insanity. The one case of pellagra among our admissions is worthy of special note. This case was actually worked out, in all its phases, by members of our staff. The patient, a woman, had been presented before several well known clinics in Nebraska and elsewhere and the case was not recognized. She was admitted here, suffering with an acute psychoses, and, after careful research, the case was diag - nosed as one of pellagra. This case is worthy of special mention because the disease is one that is very rare in these climes. These statistics very briefly set forth the hesitancy, upon the part of friends and relatives, to commit patients to the hospital until such act is necessary, and, in many instances, not until the active period of the disease has passed, and the patient has become a chronic charge, is the step taken. It is largely due to these facts that more recoveries are not reported from year to year by the hos - pital, even though it is equally well known that the hopes of cure lie in the early recognition of the disease and the care and treatment that can only be obtained in a well appointed institution. One of the remedies for these existing conditions will be mentioned a little further on in our report.. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 343 HEALTH OF POPULATION The general health of the population has been exceed - ingly good and free from epidemics, until nearly the end of the biennium, when we experienced an epidemic of the Spanish influenza. It was deemed advisable, on account of the influenza epidemic in certain localities, to quarantine the hospital. This was done under date of October 7th. The first case of this disease in the institution was apparent on October 24th. We treated something over one hundred cases, in - cluding employees and patients. At the onset of the epidemic an isolation ward was established, and all who showed symptoms of this disease were transferred to this ward. Of the twelve wards in the institution only five developed cases of influenza. This, we think, was due to the strict isolation and the careful management of the physicians and employees. I wish to add, in this connection, that considerable credit is due to the nurses and attendants for the loyal support and good work they evidenced at that time. It was through their efforts and co-operation with the phy - sicians that the death rate was held at a minimum. EMPLOYMENT OF PATIENTS It has been recognized for a long time that there is no medical treatment, of itself, for the insane; and it is also generally known, and has been conclusively proven, that occupation, employment, recreation, proper and abund - ant food, with good care, offers the greatest means for the restoration to normal health, both physically and mentally, for those afflicted with this disease. Realizing this to be true we have endeavored 10 furnish agreeable and useful occupation to as many of the patients as are physically capable of doing any work. Lacking many of the forms of employment that are possible in the larger and better equipped hospitals for the insane, our patients have been engaged lately in farm and garden work, and I believe this form of employment is by far the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">344 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF most healthful, as well as the most profitable form of em - ployment for insane persons. Aside from the outdoor work some of our patients are engaged in laundry, kitchen, sew - ing, art room, dining room, and general ward duties. RECREATION The privileges granted patients are dependent on his or her conduct. Every privilege consistent with their phy - sical and mental status is granted them. To all those, whose mental condition justifies it, many opportunities for amusement and pleasure are afforded. All those patients with good behavior are given the liberty of the grounds and are allowed to do very much as they please. It is found that the great majority of those given these privileges are well behaved and cause little or no trouble to the management. Those patients requiring the attention of nurses are taken out for daily walks when the weather permits, and during the summer spend a portion of the morning and afternoons on the lawns in the shade of the trees. Dances and moving picture shows are given and are enjoyed by all that can attend. Our hall is small and it is impossible to take all those that would enjoy these func - tions. MEDICAL STAFF During the past biennium there have been a number of changes in our medical staff, as follows: Dr. R. H. Foster resigned June 1, 1917, to enter private practice. Dr. H. R. Carson resigned October 1, 1917, to accept a Captain's commission in the National Medical Corps. Dr. M. W. Phillips resigned February 1, 1918, to accept a Lieutenant's commission in the National Medical Corps. Dr. B. A. Finkle accepted the appointment of a first physician September 17, 1917, and resigned September 18, 1918, to accept the superintendency of the Orthopedic Hos - pital at Lincoln, Nebraska. Dr. J. H. Matthai was appointed as staff physician </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 345 February 20, 1918, and is now advanced to the assistant superintendency. Dr. Willis Wilson was appointed as staff physician, September 11, 1918. A staff fully qualified to meet the specific demands ot a hospital for the insane is absolutely essential. It is also essential that the members thereof, in order to achieve the best results, should act with loyalty to the institution and sustain its policies, also establish and maintain harmon - ious relations with others. In realization of the above too much care cannot be taken in selecting for appointment members of the medical staff. STAFF MEETINGS The staff meetings have been held regularly during the past year upon Tuesday and Friday mornings. All recent admissions that are physically able are presented at these meetings. Prior to the patient's entrance into the room a summary of the completed history is read. The patient is then presented and the essential facts are demonstrated or further amplified, if necessary, and the patient retires. Then takes place a full discussion of the etiological, diagnostical and therapeutic aspects of the case and each physician expresses an opinion. The majority determine the official view, but in case of wide differences of opinion the positive diagnosis of the case is deferred and brought up again. When practicable cases are presented prior to discharge. Questions oi discipline and general administrative work are also taken up from time to time at these meetings. LABORATORY On account of the number of changes in the medical staff an accurate laboratory report has not been kept, but this department has been very active throughout the period and all necessary work has been done, such as urinal analyses, blood counts, and some pathological work in con - nection with special cases. It is to be hoped that with a full </seg>
            <seg id="p008">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 346 staff we can again take up the routine laboratory work with benefit to all concerned. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS A survey of repairs and improvements that have been made is summarized as follows: The new building for female patients, as provided for by House Roll No. 443, 1915, has been completed, and on September 18, 1917, was accepted and taken over by the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions. This is a beautiful, modern hospital building and meets with all the requirements for which it was intended. We are now carry - ing sixty-five patients in this building who were transferred from other female wards, thereby relieving a much over - crowded condition. The new male cottage building, as provided for by House Roll No. 777, 1917, is well under construction and gives promise to be not only attractive but very convenient for our needs. Unit No. 1 of the new power plant building is near - ing completion. The warehouse and bakeshop building is also nearing completion and will be ready for occupancy within a few weeks. As provided in House Roll No. 697, 1917, fifty-four and eighty-five hundredths acres of land was purchased one-half mile west of the institution, at a cost of $1,097.00. A badly needed implement shed, 20x24x28 feet, has been built. For the convenience of outside patients there was erected a brick toilet room 6x8x12 feet. A new slop shed, 6x12x7 feet, has also been built. Twenty-two thousand and fifty feet of sewer pipe has been laid. This pipe ranges in size from 6 to 12 inches, and was laid at a depth running from 14 feet below to 12 inches above ground. The greater part of our sewage will be be carried by the new service sewer to a high point in a field east of the institution. From there it will be dis- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 347 tributed over ground for irrigation purpose. This service sewer was provided for by House Roll No. 717, 1917. Three hundred and ten feet of 4 inch cast iron cold water main, and the same amount of 2 inch return pipe to the new building has been laid, extending from the fire main to the east end of the dairy barn. Three thousand cement blocks. 10 by 16 inches, were made to be used in the construction of the bakeshop and warehouse. Six hundred square feet of cement has been laid on the floor of the new tunnel, walks, gutters, and floor of coal shed. EMPLOYEES During the past two years we have experienced con - siderable trouble in securing and retaining a sufficient num - ber of employees to carry on our work properly. The reason for this extreme difficulty was clearly due to an increased demand for labor, with an increased wage. This was proved by the fac.t that a general raise of wages was allowed and at this time we are not experiencing the difficulty that we did previously. We do not feel, however, that the question of help has been solved. In many of the eastern states this prob - lem seems to have been worked out to good advantage by furnishing homes near the institution grounds, where employees can live and go to and from their work. Suf - ficient salaries are being paid whereby a man can support a family the same as if he were employed by some of the larger industries. I can see no reason why the state should expect its employees to work for a less wage than is paid in other lines of work, and I am confident that the help question in institutions for the insane will not be settled until this fact is recognized. LIBRARY The institution library, comprising some seven hun - dred volumes, affords much pleasure and benefit to a large number of our patients, as is evidenced by the large weekly </seg>
            <seg id="p010">348 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF circulation of books. Patients are given the privilege of coming to the library one day each week and choose their own reading material. On account of the size and location of the library room it cannot be used for a reading room. That this department has not received the attention and care from the management of the institution is largely due, as stated above, to a lack of proper facilities. It is hoped that during the coming biennium the library can be placed in a properly fitted room large enough for patients to congregate and read. The State Library Commission has furnished us. during the past two years, with two hundred and eighty-four new books, and has rebound eighty-three volumes. Our thanks are due the librarian for state institutions for the interest taken and for the wise selection of books sent to us. It is to be hoped that the coming legislature will recognize the necessities of this department and will appropriate sufficient funds to properly carry on this work. FARM AM) GRAIN The farm and garden has been very productive during the past biennial period, and has done much toward lessen - ing the expenses of maintenance. The greenhouse has produced some beautiful flowers and plants, and the flower beds on the campus during the summer is the pride of the institution. Full and detailed report cf the farm and garden will be found among the statistical tables at the end of this report. HOSPITAL DENTISTRY For a long period of years the dental profession has sought to teach us the fact that a healthy mouth is the basis of good health. The medical profession was the first to lend an ear and the soundness of the argument begot among them a recognition of the fact that a healthy con - dition of the teeth and their surrounding tissues is of vital importance to the prevention of many of the ailments common to man. In the past the denial work of the in- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OK COMMISSIONEKS 349 stitution has been neglected to a great extent. The cases demanding urgent attention have been taken to the local dentists where the patient's physical condition would permit. Many cases, on account of their physical or disturbed con - dition, are not able to be taken to the dentist, and as their work cannot be handled by the physicians of the hospital they go unattended. i wish to advise that arrangements be made by the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions with local dentists to spend a specified time at the hospitals, or the employment of a dentist to spend all his time at the differ - ent state institutions. I am of the opinion, however, that a local dentist, spending a portion of his time at the hos - pital, would be the better arrangement. PSYCHOPATHIC HOSPITAI of the most urge needs of this state, for the ane as well as the more in - anding of cases, is the estab - and organized psychopathic with the University of Ne- general betterment of the ins telligent handling and underst lishment of a well equipped hospital, or ward, connected braska Hospital at Omaha. Those states possessing such units are well known for their efficient state hospitals and staffs and are the creators and leaders in all new movements for the better - ment and efficient treatment of the insane. This is well exemplified in the new classification of insane that we are adopting for the coming biennium, which has been fostered by those states possessing such units. Obviously many advantages will redound to the state and its population by the organization of this long needed enterprise. It will make this state creative and enable us to have a voice in all new movements as well as be a check toward efficient and well trained hospital staffs. This, in connection with the fact that cases will be brought to us earlier and more complete in history than heretofore, will enable us to effect absolute cures. Here first aid, advice and treatment can be given the borderline cases and hospital admissions lessened. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">350 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF In summary such a unit would exert untold beneficial influence upon public morale in dispelling the antique idea so prevalent, that hospitals for the insane are prisons rather than real needs, and of benefit to the people, and that they are for the people and by the people. Further, the advisory supervision afforded by such a unit would put our hospitals and medical staffs in the foremost ranks, and, as I stated above, make us active rather than passive in relation to new movements along scientific lines. RECOMMFADATIONS In the following recommendations for the coming bien - nium we are only asking for that which we believe is essential and in keeping with the desires of the people of Nebraska in properly caring for our unfortunates. There is no indication that the population of the hospitals for the insane will decrease during the next two years, but, on the contrary, it is rather expected that the population of these institutions will increase more than during any past biennium, as it is known that the Government will expect the state to care for the mental cases which will be returned from the army. In our biennial report of two years ago it was men - tioned that our kitchen, employees' dining room, and the chapel and assembly hall, were among the original build - ings at the institution, and were planned to care for about one-half of our present population. These three units (kitchen, employees' dining room and chapel and assembly hall) are all in one building, which is so arranged and constructed that it could not be remodeled for any of these three units. Our present kitchen, besides being small, has a low ceiling, and is about three feet below the ground level, and is not sanitary. The employees' dining room is filled to its capacity at each meal, and we will not be able to care for the in - creasing number of employes that we are bound to have here with an increased patient population. The chapel and assembly hall are entirely too small for </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 351 our present needs, and we are not able to take all of our patients to picture shows and dances that should attend. The location of this building is ideal for a kitchen. It is centrally located and is connected by tunnel to the several different patients' dining rooms, and I would recommend that the present structure be removed and a new kitchen and employees' dining room erected on the same site. I would further recommend that the kitchen and employees' dining room be a structure of three stories, the third story to be used as a dormitory or living rooms for employees. Living rooms for our employees have not been properly provided for in the past. We now have employees living in rooms off the wards, and, in some cases, in rooms on the wards which were intended for the patients. The cost of an additional story to the kitchen and dining room for living purposes would be comparatively small. In recommending the erection of a chapel and assembly hall, I would suggest that this be a one-story building with a basement, the latter being used for industrial depart - ments. On account of the high cost of material and labor, the appropriation of two years ago, as provided in House Roll Xo. 717, was not sufficient to complete our power plant. The architect, realizing that the appropriation was not sufficient, divided the same into three units. Unit one, con - sisting of pump and stock room; unit two, engine and boiler room, and unit three, the coal shed. The contract has been let for unit one, and it is now under construction. Pro - vision should be made by the coming legislature for the construction of units two and three, as well as for the erection of a new smoke stack, on account of the new plant being considerable distance from the old one. There is a very great need for more tillable land in connection with this institution, and delay in buying is costing the state money every year. Two years ago we had an option on a quarter section of land adjoining the state land on the north, at $125.00 per acre. For some reasor. the legislature failed to make appropriations for this </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF purchase and since that time it was sold to private parties at the same price that was asked from the state. We need every acre of a section of land to handle the needs of the institution, and I earnestly hope that provision will be made for the purchase of more land. Land that is the most suitable for our purpose would cost in the neighborhood of $130.00 per acre. Among some of the smaller needs of the institution, for the coming biennium, will be a silo, milk house, cement for walks, curbing, coal pit and a reservoir. We should also have an appropriation for the extension of our water mains in order that trees, the lawn watered. The amounts recommended tions will be found as follows: and park could be for these appropria- Furniture and Equipment: Furniture, beds, mattresses, pillows, blankets, window shades, etc Equipment for New Power Plant: One, only, 120 H. P. engine, direct cur- rent to So K. W. generator One, only, 17 ft. Italian marble switch board On&gt;-. only, 8-inch double-acting well pumi One, only, 10-ton Ice machine and coils. . One, only, 14 -inch x 6-inch belt-driven ;iipe machine One, only, 72-inch x 16-foot hot water heater One. only, electric control, for blower fan. Total Improvements to Buildings and Grounds: Cement for walks and curbing $ 1,000.00 New Buildings: For construction of new kitchen, dinin room and dormitory 85,000.00 For construction of a new chapel and as - sembly hall 80,000.00 For construction of units 2 and 3 of power plant (unit 2, 20,000; unit 3, 30,000.00 5,000.00 10,000 1 Smoke stack for new power house </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS land: ico acres at $130.1 2II.MIH.IMI Total 221,800.00 Miscellaneous Silo Milk turns 650.00 500.00 750.00 ,000.00 .000.00 Extending water mains rvoir Coal pit ital 6,900.00 GRAND TOTAL $252,200.00 CONCl I SIOX In concluding this report I desjre to express my grate- ful recognition of the support and co-operation given me by the officers and employees of the hospital. Especially do I wish to thank the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions for the unfailint kindness they have shown me at all times, and also for their counsel and support. Respectfully submitted, Sii/h riiltriitlriit Norfolk, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. ART DEPARTMENT Articles Sold 33.06 Aprons, 2 $ 1.15 Hemstitching Bags. S 5.05 Lact ::s.s2 Baskets, 10 5.70 Luncheon set 105.35 Bath sets, 0 2.20 Living room sets, 3 15.75 Bedspread, 1 4.50 Luncheon cloths, 10 49.20 Button holes .16 Napkins, 8 4.95 Pillow rases 35.95 Cap: tlJ Pincushions, 4 IM Centerpieces, 41 111.80 21.25 Collars 1.40 Rugs, rag, 14 Doilies, 82 :.« Scarfs, dresser, 58 167.20 Ends for scarfs, 27 sets 23.85 Scarfs, library, 16 53.50 Finishing work 6.70 Sheets, 10 20.50 Gown set, 1 .30 Towels, guest. 74.3.-, Handkerchief holder .20 Tatting 56.04 Wash cloths. 29 6.85 Handkerchiefs. 118 41.35 Yokes. 85 130.70 Total $1,110.91 (1. E. (MlABLTON, </seg>
            <seg id="p016">354 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF On Hand in Art Department, December 1. 1918 Baskets, 12 Baskets, 12 $ 9.3 $ 9.35 Handkerchiefs, 6 3.75 Handkerchiefs, 6 i. Bags, 3 2.50 Bags, 3 2.50 Hemstitching 9.50 Hemstitching 9.50 Baby jackets, 2 3.00 Baby jackets, 2 3.00 Lace 19.00 Lace 19.00 Center pieces, 6 30.50 Center pieces, 6 30.50 Library scarfs, 3 24.00 Library scarfs, 3 24.00 Caps, 10 12.95 Caps, 10 12.95 Pillow cases, 8 17.25 Pillow cases, 8 17.25 Doilies, 6 12.00 Doilies, 6 12.00 Pillow shams. 2 3.75 Pillow shams. 2 .. Dresser scarfs, 9 24.50 Dresser scarfs, 9 24.50 Wash cloths, 36 8.00 Wash cloths, 36 S.00 Embroidery work 2.50 Embroidery work 2.50 Wash cloths and towel ends, 20 pair 9.00 Wash cloths and towel Ends for scarfs, 10 pair .... 11.05 Ends for scarfs, 10 pair .... 11.05 nds, 2o pair 9.00 Frin.ee ends, 6 2.50 Frinee ends, 6 2.50 Yokes, 28 42.00 Total $256.95 Yokes, 28 42.00 Guest towels, 8 9.75 Guest tcwels, 8 9.7 Total 256.9". MATRONS DEPARTMENT Sewing Room — Articles Manufactured and Repaired Aprons, kitchen 447 Cuffs, nurses, pair 58 Aprons, repaired 305 Collars, nurses Aprons, rubber 6 Curtains, transom 10 Aprons, ward 537 Diapers 43 Aprons, nurses 59 Doilies 17 Aprons, sanitary 2 Drawers 300 Baps, laundry 15 Drawers, repaired 2,016 Bed pads 104 Dresser scarfs 114 Bedspreads, repaired 70 Dresses 396 Bibs, nurses 25 Dresses, repaired 72 Bibs, patients 359 Dresses, strong 93 Bibs, repaired 241 Dresses, strong repaired 45 Broom covers 12 Gowns, baby i Camisoles 44 Gowns, night 409 Camisole strings 70 Gowns, night, repaired 124 Caps., hydro 24 Holders, iron 105 Caps, nurses 59 Jackets, kitchen, repaired 50 Chemises •s 362 Laundry bags, repaired 17 Coats, repaired 47 Napkins, sanitary 488 Commode covers 24 Napkins, table 195 Corset covers 9 Napkins, tray 38f Covers, auto 2 Overalls, repaired 526 Covers, bath tub 3 Pants, repaired 476 Covers, bread mixer 3 Pillow cases 1,799 Curtain, chapel 1 pniow cases, repaired 41 Curtains, screen 5 Quilts, quilted 3 Curtain straps 297 Quilts, pieced and tied . . 25 Curtains, window 244 Rugs, repaired 3 :;o Cushion covers 2 Sacks, candy 1,260 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS COMMISSIONERS 355 Sacks, coffee 24 Sacks, coffee 24 Table cloths, repaired 39 Table cloths, repaired 39 Sacks, coffee, repaired 18 Sacks, coffee, repaired 18 Table pads 4 Table pads 4 Sacks, stocking 8 Sacks, stocking 8 Table runners 10 Table runners 10 Sanitary pads 48 Sanitary pads 48 Ticks, mattress 170 Ticks, mattress 170 Sheets, 7x4 1,810 Sheets, 7x4 1,810 Ticks, mattress, repaired .... 69 Ticks, mattress, repaired .... 69 Sheets, double 11x4 131 Sheets, double 11x4 131 Ticks, straw 41 Ticks, straw 41 Sheets, repaired 40 Sheets, repaired 40 Ticks, pillow 12 Ticks, pillow 12 Sheets, rubber 143 Sheets, rubber 143 Tarpaulin in canvas 1 Tarpaulin In canvas 1 Sheets, hydro 12 Sheets, hydro 12 Towels, hand 1,779 Towels, hand 1,779 Shirts 662 Shirts 662 Towels, roller 830 Towels, roller 830 Shirts, repaired 4,135 Shirts, repaired 4,135 Towels, roller, repaired 56 Towels, roller, repaired 56 Skirts, baby 9 Skirts, baby 9 Towels, tea 3,190 Towels, tea 3,190 Socks, repaired, pairs 3,783 Socks, repaired, pairs 3,783 Tray cloths 317 Tray cloths 317 Stand covers 157 Stand covers 157 I'nderskirU 125 I'nderskirts 125 Stocking tags 30 Stocking tags 30 Union suits, repaired 321 Union suits, repaired 321 Suspenders 75 Suspenders Vests 17 Vests 17 v.i Table cloths 68 Table cloths 68 Wash cloths 26 Wash cloths 26 Culinary Department Apples, canned 349 gallons Apples, canned 349 gallons Pickles, beet 142 gallons Pickles, beet 142 gallons Butter, apple 97 gallons Butter, apple 97 gallons l'irkles. crabapple 15 gallons l'irkles. crabapple 15 gallons Butter, grape 23 gallons Butter, grape 23 gallons Pickles, cucumber 4 barrels Pickles, cucumber 4 barrels Butter, plum 147 gallons Butter, plum 147 gallons Pickles, cucumber, fa - mous 16 gallons Pickles, cucumber, fa- Butter, dairy 827 pounds Butter, dairy 827 pounds mous 16 gallons Cherries, canned 54 gallons Cherries, canned 54 gallons Pickles, string bean 4 gallons Pickles, string bean 4 gallons Chili sauce 22 gallons Chili sauce 22 gallons Pickles, mixed 8 gallons Pickles, mixed 8 gallons Corn relish 6 gallons Corn relish 6 gallons Pickles, peach 12 gallons Pickles, peach 12 gallons Grape juice, canned ... 9 gallons Grape juice, canned ... 9 gallons Preserves, tomato 42 gallons Preserves, tomato 42 gallons Gooseberries, canned ... 67 gallons Gooseberries, canned ... 67 gallons Preserves, gooseberry . . 1 gallon Preserves, gooseberry . . 1 gallon Jelly, apple 31 glasses Jelly, apple 31 glasses Preserves, watermelon . . 2 gallons Preserves, watermelon . . 2 gallons 2 Jelly, crabapple 217 glasses Jelly, crabapple 217 glasses Pumpkin, canned 228 gallons Pumpkin, canned 228 gallons Jelly, currant 352 glasses Jelly, currant 352 glasses Rhubarb, canned 26 gallons Rhubarb, canned 26 gallons Jelly, gooseberry 180 glasses Jelly, gooseberry 180 glasses Sauer kraut 51 barrels Sauer kraut 51 barrels Jelly, tame grape 289 glasses Jelly, tame grape 289 glasses Strawberry, juice 10 gallons Strawberry, juice 10 gallons Jelly, wild grape 48 glasses Jelly, wild grape 48 glasses Strawberries, canned ..119 gallons Strawberries, canned ..119 gallons Jelly, plum 268 glasses Jelly, plum 268 glasses String beans, canned ... 40 gallons String beans, canned ... 40 gallons Jelly, strawberry 24 glasses Jelly, strawberry 24 glasses Tomato catsup 44 gallons Tomato catsup 44 gallons Marmalade, grape 50 glasses Marmalade, grape 50 glasses Tomatoes, canned 845 gallons Tomatoes, canned 845 gallons Marmalade, orange 104 glasses Marmalade, orange 104 glasses Tomatoes, pickled 24 gallons Tomatoes, pickled 24 gallons </seg>
            <seg id="p018">356 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE PATIENTS' FUND December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918 Note —These are the personal funds of the patients held in trust by the Institutior patients and received and expended for their sole individual benefit. these Aopraximate average number of accounts December 1, IMC to December 1. 1918. was 42. PERIOD Debits ( redits Ledger credit balance on hand December 1. 1916 $1150.9. December, 1916 January. 1917 February. 1917 Murch. 1917 t 92.11 11447 69.66 M.9* 64.58 H1.I-. 216.82 109.34 161.08 178.85 63.23 54.41) April. 1917 May, 1917 June, 1917 July. 1917 . August. 1917 227.63 101 .03 199.33 S9.67 72.60 74.50 September, 1917 October. 1917 November. 1917 53.77 318.48 224.04 153.44 134.64 M M Total for year $ 1227.46 1IMJI Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 191 , $1813.88 Ledger credit balance on hand December 1. 1917. $1813.88. December. 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 March, 1918 $ 153.72 s !.,_■»: 1 111.2(1 77.*,) .W8.5O 186.91 188.87 206.66 296.41 175.48 355.55 290.61 174.10 mj» 180.76 m-M April. 1918 May, 1918 . June, 1918 . July, 1918 . August, 1918 188.47 239.85 80.20 312.19 157.28 September, 1918 October, 1918 November, 1918 m.l.i 208.68 Mil Total for year $2162.66 I miJi Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918. $2315.18. Grand total for two years $3390.12 t 4554.34 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 357 RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1 916, to I December 1, 1918 GENERAL SOURCES AMOUNTS RECEIVED Total Dec. 1, 1916 Dec. 1, 1917 I Dec. 1, 1916 to to to Dec. 1, 1917 Dec. 1, 1918 i Dec. 1, 1918 Maintenance Cattle and hoes Special nurse Art room Hides, bones and junk Board Rent Unclaimed funds of patients Sewing Brick and material Coal, refund Reimbursement -services Empty barrels Potatoes Blankets Barb wipe Vouchers Employees wages, refund Freight, refund Excess emergency Totals ... | 12064.14 S 22744.07 $ 34808.21 5520.42 6555.82 12076.24 635.00 365.39 1000.39 402.66 425.85 828.51 136.34 251.18 387.52 171.43 208.25 379.68 108.00 108.00 i 216.00 200.53 200.53 68.13 68.40 136.53 71.92 I 71.92 35.53 35.53 34.82 34.82 7.75 j 19.50 I 2755 9.60 2.00 11.60 7.50 7.50 7.00 7.00 1.93 4.31 654 2.37 2.37 .64 .64 :::: :::::::::: i°___ * . ... $ 19241.51 i * 30997.47 f 50238.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">358 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS. FURNITURE. EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE- MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE November 30. 1918 Acres Acres Cultivated Uncultivated I Total Esti - mmti-d Value Acre- Garden Farm Orchard Campus i Waste age Land owned by institution 64 345.85 5 SO «4.Ki f 73712.50 Land rented by institution (caah) MjM :!2 80.00 8000.00 11000.00 Land rented by institution i shares i 4 4.IMI 44.00 Total 64 437.85 37 50 578.85 » 92712.50 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING AND IMPROVEMENT Building Furniture Equipment Improvement Total Administration buildinc Male west wins $ 40000.00 t 3500.00 I $ 4000.00 S 47500.00 81000.00 5000.00 : 8700.00 94700.00 Male cottage No. 1 ... Male cottage No. 2. . Female cottage, stone . . Female cottage No. 1 . . Female cottage No. 2 . Female cottage No. 6. Physician's cottage .... Laundry, power house Kitchen, bakery, chapel Store room 25000.00 2000.00 3960.00 30950.00 20000.00 2000.00 3100.00 25100.00 78000.00 8000.00 8900.00 94900.00 20000.00 2000.00 , 3000.00 25000.00 20000.00 2000.00 3000.00 25000.00 57000.00 3250.00 , 7500.00 \ 67750.00 3000.00 i 325.00 '■ 575.00 I 3900.00 5000.00 225.00 28500.00 13725 IX&gt; 3500.00 165.00 3550.00 7216.00 6000.00 300.00 350.00 6650.00 Employees' dormitory Carpenter shop 800.00 150.00 100.00 105C.00 1500.00 | 250.00 1750.00 Green house Dairy barn Horse barn 1200.00 2225.00 3425.00 4600.00 500.00 5000.00 2600.00 450.00 2950.00 Slaughter house Chicken house Cattle sheds 600.00 75.00 676.00 800.00 800.00 400.00 400.00 Corn crib. Hog house 400.00 400.00 S40.00 350.00 Implement sheds 500.00 1600.00 2000.00 Ground improvements 42550.00 i 19300.00 61850.00 Total $372050.00 S 28915.00 |122775.00 f 19300.00 I 543040.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS U9 X M • :SS I TT I a, 1 x t- | 3C 2 ax 5 111"" * M lit I f ■&gt; m a U \1 iJH : « $ • i 2S » ■a p - li ji -its | •5 3 ism " g ! &gt; I eig o liiiL I N 1 N 1 i li j 1 1 : 11 M H :■: |5 I! I s j2 ao Si Si It i I J I ■ 1 51 I J|||£ 1 iifl|- 1 " 1 I j —^s ii 1 : : t." ' ' S Mm </seg>
            <seg id="p022">360 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF x r — i - i 5-5x5 k ; 5 n m m m • — ex- x ac »- x — ?. . (t. y e P I S ls |s|22 2-S|S s a ssjj B | s s 2t ?ii s z ? 5 2 -r. MiNiiiftiPfciiyjLMiij t IP • »w « | 11 iilivl Iliiillll2illlli.il ill \ £ , « -«.-i3:m«n m — n © m x — sxo NXiir- S • « » »« p j - : |-i-« - -2= S — S o - B»=, ; . *::-ici-i-toi«it;:.;«;;j&lt;i^S»i.c5esr.J J .I (• j» • — t-*rfrit~w — ■» s&gt;j — x — * — x » — | ' ' i i i — I l&gt; - * r. &amp; ' I** « i •s : s iJii£i£?Jjii2££iJiJ5£iijJ£ij££Ji </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 361 ; 0 '- 1 i ] I II &gt;£ • IS 111 Ille e 1 hIIIIII i *§s 1111 ■--•--3» H 3 iiiliiilH ? ««5»3=?^4 SS5 XXv,v.'j.'S. b Z </seg>
            <seg id="p024">362 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF SSi5S£S5SSS N S NNOXCN«ifl*iOq-X*O5£qNhqifi» : 5CN=OON ! S •muss — oi-^wej |ae -xtct-x C? N t TfNtttK 2 i i: ? - 55££jjiiiiij£ii£iiii i9t|M| r:--ia«« «?SSnn -■ ?j SSSS§SSbs - j s S2SJS2SS39O &lt;P KSSSSSS^SSSSSSoSSt: S§ |&gt; i 3 oj .1 » *• asssssas sagggggggggg gsgggsis 5P55SN55S 2 i 3i&gt; ! N t-— X — m — o: r? A A »i n K Nt-— x'-FN&gt;raiR aSdaKv I a «• e | 3:1 iJi£i£iiiJii££iJiiiiii£ j£i5iJ ii££ijiiiiii£ Uiiii W H ; 8 , S S 1- £ §J — «««*»«o — — io«oi ooc&lt;st-oilS?i «■* ii oa X « r- s&gt; ec ci 5 ? Si 3 N m 5 I E S . i . ::S8.8. ;S:::::::g:g: I 111 8 I?8 ggg s e '! 1- i-i ::s8S •" : : ••» » t^ M £ S j |i Jl ::^" nZS i F- a •» °i iilsl::^;^ 2 :i 3 233 I e fl lJ :: B il t- ggO sag S :: S h 5 Hi! I B •fi 1 .1 iio* V. 2 81 * ill S S | 5^ 2 *i\ — £S j g ;*|S2SS|"°gSgS|S5S N 522g5S t -SSS8S5 Ill £ ; ; I ; : i ; ; ; i ; ; H i N i M ; i M M M M | 1 liiilliiiiif.iiiiriili l n J I • •&gt; O 53 «{ 'j C C 1 &lt; i « S 3 t C </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 363 is Jim" sm *r 1| { : ; :« s — N^S^ONN&gt;oSqs-9C3iSoS5Nt-S2»qqtfc55»! ; • 0 i * » ai n ic - m -• &gt;n x - 1~ r: -i - i- -i *i iff - ?i i- c n *i -• -i t- : — |]1 •*—©»— — — — rt ?i — — — »e — o 5 li i» ©Iff I © &lt;e — ac «e oj «y- :•: r: x « r: c « — — 1« 9- x xst-JNi- H||l « S N 5 N Zg N - H -3" 3 . J j u 2 i i §§g ::::::::::§: : : : :g : : : : g = &gt;i 1 ■ ■- 1* f £ : -g» : . ::::::-::::::«: = * : 2 : •• : i eoo • ■ ■ -ee — c ■ ■ — _ l.l *** • • ■ 9* ■::::::::::::: r* ■» Illll ;" 5 l:i : N3 :::ii : : :: ; ; M :"! i ; ;!§ |||&gt;| : : . : : :::::::::::.::: : : :| *|l I - ■■•» ,f £ j J5£ ::: JJ ::::::::::::: ::: I : ft i r a iMH"'NN.HNi :N*siiii I a : S : : : : ■ • : : • : : : I : 1 !!!i!!!!!!i!!i!!!i!ilii?l: IhH nmHmnynHi — ' : — — -^—^- I Iliiliilii!! 1 ! — ii«l I S 8 . - ! w a II </seg>
            <seg id="p026">364 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 2 ri -a x 7, ~ x y: N*J — ■r, 15 :fl 8 i jijuji! i 15 8 M - s = 3 V, l a ~ X X '— * M T ;j BE ii s ,s 1 rj- " s m x x .AH I •* 3« a "a ■ c c c _: c 3* . I i -] 32- 1 k 5 — m tii : : : r 1 za. o iiaame* « i £ :| : : : S M » : S lie? - N ""*"' - :p z ;■. fl P - !f — : ; — t 2 0 (11 _;rr s s = s ? &amp;9*s*?ai =: s 5 = ._ 2=1 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 365 I X m t- -r M ei » x 33 ? i £ * --, -g no * :/] e I .-v-r - "" - «».l 8 J - 5 5 3, i 5888888 S ' 3 5 5 ,= 3 *t?!?S2d2in i? i -a i - « . 88«U u O i i -g &gt; S N S I S M J &gt; K O 4 ■: EjPL^ : 5 S H !i ■S!&gt; S 4* ± -??J r&gt; — x S I "0 ■» 2 3 j 3 3 I 7 s is I |!3'88 ll'lf^n i kiiiiiiii • ?J s • -a 3l| iiiisii r 2*11 2 1 i j « Ml Ob :::::::. | &lt;2 :.3fe :*E * -a Ji iillii!i I tSHHll ■? Hal z Hi 2 t 2» I a a s&gt; = 2 = 5 Si en ■ — i 3 SI =1 " s i* » &lt; a "H-o : i , "•oBBBbH n x 3 * i i i S </seg>
            <seg id="p028">366 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF is j &lt;s ' ■ '7. Iffij ?i lira z , ,^ ■a [Pag?; jfeLll i] i ifl Ijj « * -| ' I I S « _± i* ' ! ■ i-l k-n H J 1:| ; I |g-°' i 1 a s i oc • £ _I S ■" • Z ;ai| li « II ■i - = ■c 5 * -.£ .JI £ *- I S 15 ■ 2 iM 4 Jill E: ' ' J 'i £:s i- a Is : s- c « y E J 3 1 : 5|S SI ; J5* 0 I i ! II " -; &gt;■ c ? • ! » K- ■ £ 2 5 ; 11 |i k |s&amp; * = l! it 2S- j : i O - „„ ISS88 ?JS a _- :. , I . Egggg .2 | ; i; f {'I ■ I: | | _J| I SS=J si -a S t £" I z Z :i ii .IMS 3 SS? I I Jj ;&lt;;Pj S - ll ;f|;1'= « S . 11 1 iti i P x i ■■ at | i»l ? « £J«S li lE^g£ 6 ■r " ■ « (25 |i i* u •" iz 1 h \t\m ITT^ =: h« |i "• : J ?i*i s I s is : "■ "^ IS -J5!2 ' S6?&gt;j &gt;il^ yiS II S : £ I I"" 5 i is g PPI 1 !!*!; il| S j iii 1 3 Mil: |;: s 1 1 ?! Lu 111 « s ?:?3 -1. s I 5 ills &gt;i ;s r. lfefc&gt; &gt; I ■ • ' ! •» I'll 5 |5I ■■£SS § £ JP ! (l7'a i= i i nil iz J l s2 i 2is x ss « (mi a K^ ? I •» — I* Is i 1*88 II a S,; li» I 1*11 z i SSS I S = •» ** 12 ! ! II! ( is SSE I ?i P |ij 8^ MSx 8- ' 1 ' s |! II IiNb H liiii! ii^r s I h ill </seg>
            <seg id="p029">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 367 I E* I ~ n is\s?° •» I v jL a mm §3:535 z~ -- -5 TO X- r? ir 11 ! 2 ! 85 : fi iji « 58* ! I 1 I Vw Wi li* 1 * h : • i|ii" ■ S IS iii" 5 M a s« likU- 0 1 HlMiill §«; -38 z- X « : : « . . 155 as is _ c £ 1 "3 j OQ -2 o ■g«§SJ ?j| s :* 5 s ii I IT hs|! ~ gsii i 1 sees ' s 31 liliiill z^ — &gt; », s^ 11 4aa ■ I •» ' irss 1* ijjlws- - -- — ri «r £1 ill «25 H Ml H ail 3* A. or; •2 i s* \TT\ T\ — 9 I *c S ! 5 • • • S I s 11 j &gt;!^ s - § 2 s i "" IM ::: i itekfr s ! K 1 1 a \\ M II HISS S I ° h IjtSK" = gl i|i|s§sj: - Hh jlpii U\\ i\si4\i i 4 .im -si? ikl&gt;! &gt;s-ss:a ; -•s. .i!ss : 8 s = &lt;- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">368 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE 1 MOVEMENT OF POPULATION For Year ' For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30. tor 1917 1918 Biennium MOVEMENT U. F. T. M. F. T. | M. F. T. 309 260 56* 340 263 603; 309 260 569 Population at beginning of period Admitted: 112 53 165 84 55 139 196 108 301 7 8 15j S 7 16 16 15 31 For the first time Readmitted Transferred from other institutions Returned from parole granted before commence - ment of period . - .... 1 3 1 3 Returned from ?scape before commencement of period 1 ... 1 1 ... 1 Total under treatment 4:11 322 7531 433 325 758! 524 384 908 Discharged: Recovered Improved 13 8 21 16 IT S3 29 25 54 15 13 28' 2 2 4 17 15 32 Unimproved Not insane 12 4 16 13 6 It 25 10 35 2 2| 1 ... II 3 3 Transferred to other institutions Died 1 1 42 27 69 1 54 31 85 96 58 154 Died on parole I.. 1 1 1 20 23 43 25 16 41 45 39 84 8 8 11 11 It... 19 Paroled and not returned during the period Escaped and not returned during period Total removed 114 75 1891 122 72 194 236 147 383 Remaining at end of period Average number treated 440 263 603; 340 276 616 340 276 616 330 268 5981 353 273 626 342 271 613 Absent on parole or escape at commence ment of period or during period, and later discharged without returning to the institution 16 39 29 23 52 52 39 91 TABLE II -AGE OF THOSE ADM ITTED AGE For Year For Year •■nding ending Total Nov. 30. Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. tnder 15 years . IS and under 20 20 and under 25 25 and under 30 30 and under 35 35 and under 40 40 and under 45 45 and under 50 . 50 and under 55 55 and under 60 60 and under 65 65 and under 70 70 and over Unknown 1 1 2 1 1 2 4 S 7 4 4 8 3 11 12 2 14 6 6 12 18 8 26 16 9 24 14 9 23 29 18 47 14 9 231 8 8 161 22 17 39 13 7 20 11 6 17 24 13 37 11 6 17 4 7 11 15 13 28 11 8 19 7 6 13 18 14 32 6 4 10 8 9 17 14 13 27 4 4 10 1 11 14 1 15 7 1 8 « S 9 13 4 17 6 3 9 6 1 7 12 4 16 10 5 IS 6 4 10 16 9 25 6 4 10 2 1 3 8 5 13 Total* 119 61 18ol 93 62 1S6 212 123 335 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 369 TABLE 111 CIVIL STATUS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE IV EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED CIVIL STATUS I- or Tw NoV"». 1917 For Ywr ending Total No».», for 1»18 Binmium Single MarriM Widowed Divorced Separated Unknown M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 56 16 72 38 34 72, 13 9 22! 6. ... 6 3 1 4 3 ' « 48 13 61 104 29 133 35 41 76 73 75 148 5 6 11 18 15 33 4 2 6 10 2 12 S 1 4 1... 1 4 16 119 61 1M| I 93 62 155 211 123 tW Tn;a :.: = als EDUCATION For Year nm m, 1»17 m. r. t. For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1S18 Btenntum M. F. T. M. T. T. Primary . . ■'ommon school High school or univenity None Unknown 10 2 12 92 41 1S3 7 9 16 1 ... 1 8 4 7 £ 5 11 119 61 180 11 I 15 21 6 27 72 42 114 164 83 247 4 8 12 11 17 28 2 2 4 3 2 f 2 3 5 6 7 It 2 3 5 8 8 1* 93 62 155 212 123 335 Total. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">370 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE V NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE VI -NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED NATIVITY For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium i I M F. T. M. F. T. I M. F. T. Alabama California Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Massachusetts Michigan Miawmii Nebraska New York Ohio. Pennsylvania South Dakota Tennessee Texas Virginia Wisronai n United States Total native born 1 I 2 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 1... 1 1 ... 1 6 2 8 729 13 4 IT ».... 3 2 1 3 5 1 C 11 7 18 10 10 20 21 17 38 2 13 112 3 2 5 I.... 1 2 ... 2 3... 3 1.... 1 1.... 1 1 1 1 . . 1 1 1 2 1 1 2 448 314 7 5 12 33 13 46 23 16 39 56 29 85 2 13 3 14 5 2 7 4 3 7 3 3 7 3 10 1 ... 1 12 3 2 2 4 I 1 2 1 1 2 1 1 .... 1 1 1 ... 1 1... 1 2... X 2.... 2 2.... 2 112 12 3 2 3 5 18 9 3 2 5 4 10 14 75 43 118 63 40 103 138 83 221 Austria Behjium Bohemia Canada Denmark England Finland Germany Gf~« Hungary Ireland Italy 5&amp; Russia Sweden Switierland Total foreign bora Unknown Totals 4 . . 4 112 5 1 S 1. ... lj 1.... 1 213246 459 1 1 2 3 5 3 3 6 4. .. 4 1 2 3 5 2 7 1 . . li 1.... J 1 1 .... 1 1 .... 2 2 15 4 19 6 6 12 21 10 31 1 . 1 1 ... 1 2 .... 2 2. ... 2 2.... 2 3 1 4 4. . 4 7 1 8 1... 1 1... 1 2 .... 2 2 13 112 3 2 5 1 1 .... 1 1 .... 2 2 1 1 2 1 1 2 6 4 10 3 14 9 5 14 1 1 1 1 . 42 15 57 24 20 44 66 35 101 236 6 2 8 85 13 119 61 180 93 62 155 212 123 335 NATIVITY OF PARENTS For Year For Year ending (Tiding Total Nov. 30. Nov. 30, lor 1917 1*18 Biennium Jnited States, both parents r'oreign, both parents "nknown U. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 40 21 Cl 26 21 47 66 42 108 43 25 681 45 33 78 88 58 146 72* 224 9 4 11 . 29 13 42 20 6 26 49 19 6S . 119 61 180 93 62 155 212 123 33! TotaU </seg>
            <seg id="p033">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 371 i i &gt; OCCUPATION Agent Biker Barber Bartender Blacksmith Bookkeeper Butcher Carpenter Catholic sisterhood Clerk Cook Domestic Electrician Electrical engineer Expressman Farmer Farm laborer Gambler Horse breeder Housewife Janitor Laborer Lather Liquor dealer Locomotive engineer Lumberman Mechanic Merchant Minister Musician Packing house foreman Painter Physician Plumber Photographer Printer Ranchman Retired Railroad ear cleaner Railroad conductor Railroad switchman Sail maker Seamstress Shoemaker Shooting gallery Saloon keeper Soldier Student Tailor Teacher Telegrapher Traveling salesman Watchman Waiter Yard master None Unknown Totals For Year For Year ' ending ending Total NovTsO. Nor. ». for 1*17 191S Biennium M F. T. ~M. F. T. 1*7 F. T. I.... 1 I . 1 1 1 2 1 1 2 3 » 1 . . 1 4 4 1 . 1 1.... 1 1... 1 1 .. . 1 I.... 2 I.... 1 1... I 1 1 1 . 1 I.... 2 ».... 3 •.... 5 1 1 1 1 I .... 1 2 1 3 3 1 4 1 . I I.... 1 8 8 ( «.... 14 14 I... 1 1 ... 1 1 ... 1 1 . 1 1 1 1 ... 1 30 . ... 30 17.... 27 57 67 4 .... 4 1 .... 4 1 ... 1 1.... 1 • 1 ... 1 I.... 1 36 M . . . . 4* *$.... 85 85 1 . . . 1 I.... It 39 . .. 39 19 1 20 68 1 9 1.... 1 1 . . 5 1... 1 1 . . 1 I.... 2 2 .... I.... 1 1 ... 1 r... 2 i.... i «... i i.... l i.... a i i i i i... i i.... l i i i. ... i 3 3 1... 1 4 .... 4 1... . 1 .... 1 1 1 1 2 1.... 1 1.... 1 1 1 1 1 1.... 1 I.... 1 1 1 1 1 2.... 2 2. ... t I.... 1 1... 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1.... 1 1... . 1 1 1 .... 1 1 1... 1 1 ... 1 1 1 1 1 1 . . 1 1 . 1 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 11 2 l'"i 2 1.... 1 I.... 1 1 1 2 1 1 &lt; 1 1 .... 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1.... 1 I.... 1 9 9 IM '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 9 9 18 9 4 It 11 1 12 20 5 26 119 61 180 93 62 155 212 123 33S </seg>
            <seg id="p034">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VIII— COUNTY OF RESIDENCE OF THOSE ADMITTED AND OF THOSE REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For Year For Ynr \! Hem, Nov UK ill NTY ( 191T 1918 niwIlIM M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T M. F. T Adams Antelope Boom Boyd Box Butte Brown ... Buffalo Burt Cm Cedar Cherry Cheyer Clay Col'fax Cumins Cluster Dakota Dawn l)ia-it. Deuel Dilon D:&gt;dse 1'ciiKlu- Qtaall Hall lli.li Hooker Howarr Johnso: Grant Keya Paha Kimbal! Knox Lanraste MadiMtti Merrick Mcl'her* Morrill Nanra. Nemaha Pierc* Platte Richardson Rock MkM Sarpy I.... 1 1 1 4 4 SaundiT I.... 1 1 1 1 « * Scotn Bluff. Seward I... I 1 Sheridan Sherman Sioux 1 3 s 1 31 II t! 3 2 5 4 9 13 Stan ton Thomas Thuntton Valley 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 it Washington Wayne Total U» 61 180 93 62 155 12 123 335 34" 278 B16 •tiding ••mli.iK Total Nov. 30. Nov. SO, ! for 1 1 1. . . . 1 1 4 5 4 3 7 1115 4 9 9 I 10 1 10 11 4 2 6 1 5 « I 5 7 12 11 6 17 1 2 3 1 1 1 3 4 7 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE IX— FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE ADMITTED For Titr For Year ! &amp;**$&gt;. I ». DISEASE DISEASE 1917 1918 Biennium M. F. T. I M. F. T. M. F. T 1»17 1918 Biennium j M. F. T. M. P. T. M. F. T. . Infective Exhaustive Psychosis: Infective Exhaustive Psych' Infective delirium . . Exhaustive delirium. 1. Infective delirium 1 1.. 5 5 6 • 1 « 2. Kxhau«tiyc delirium .... 2 . 2 ! 2 2 3. Allied to infective exhaustive psychosis Allied to infective exhaustive psyehom: Intoxication Psychosis: I. Intoxication Psychosis: 1 . Alcoholic -- a. Pathological alcoholism 2 ... 2 2 t b. Delirium tremen* c. Acute hallucinosis 112 112 1. Alcoholic I'ullv. logical alcoh Delirium tremen; Acute hallucinosi: d. Chronic alcoholism hronic alcnholisi e. Paranoid states 1 1 ' 1. . 1 i states 1 . Drug Toxicoses: a. Morphine l&gt;. Cocoaine e. Other drugs Drug Toxic Morphini Cocoai, Other drug :;. Post puerperal 11 i i 1 1. Thvroid Th 5. I remic ;. Organic Brain Disease: 1. Undifferentiated 1 1 1 i 2 . . . 2 2. Arterio sclerotic psychcs-is 11 3 5 8 3 6 9 Arterio sclerotic psyche Cerebral s\philis. Huntington's chorea Pout paralytic psychosi Trauma'ic psychosis 1 1 3 4 3. Cerebral s\philis 4 4 ' 4 4 4 4 1 1 4. Huntington's chorea 11.. 11 5. Post paralytic psychosis 1 1 2 1 1*2 *». Traumatic psychosis 1 1 1 ... 1 1 1 7. Brain lumore . Senile Psychosis: Psych. 1. Simple deterioration 12 7 19. l:j 4 17 25 11 38 2. I&gt;elirium and confused states 1 . . . lj 1 1 :i. iJepn'ss'Ki and agitated states Depressed and agitated state 4. Paranoid states 6 3 9;.. H 3 9 v . Paresis: Pmi 1. Cerebral form 19 4 23 18 2 20' 37 6 43 1 . Cerebral form 2. Tabetic form 19 1 2. Tabetic form 1 . 1 ■ 1 1 1 1 . Dementia Pr«cox Group: 1. I'ndifferentiated 2 4 6 5 4 9 7 8 16 I 15 2. Hebephrenic 3 3 6 2 7 9. 5 10 15 Hebephrei Katatonic Paranoid . 3 6 M 10 15 3. Katatonic 3 4 7 15 8 23; 18 12 30 4 7 15 8 23; 18 12 30 4. Paranoid j 8 4 12 3 2 5 11 6 17 4 12 3 2 5 11 6 17 5. Allied to dementia pnecox I ' Allied to dementia pnecox Manic Depressive Group: Manic states . Manic Depressive Group: 1. Manic states 6 6 12 7 14 21. 13 20 33 2, 7 14 21 : 13 20 33 2. Depressed states 2 2 4 ! 2 2 4 Depressed state Mixed states 4 3. Mixed states 1 1 1 1... . 1 4. Allied states Allied »t» . involution Melancholia Involution Melancholia . Other Depressed States: 1 . Simple ti"i&gt;r- :-siun Symptomatic depressioi 3. Undiffereatiated depression 10. Paranoid States 1 .. 1 1 6 7 5 12 12 6 18 11. Epileptic States 1. Excited . . 1 1 1... 1 Depressed Deteriorated 1 SI 1 1 6 1 4. No mental change 12. Psychoneuroses: 1 1 1 1 2 1. Hysterical type 2. Psychasthenic type 2 3. Neuresthenic type </seg>
            <seg id="p036">374 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OP TABLE IX FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE ADMITTED- (Concluded TABLE X -NUMBER OF ATTACKS OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XI— PREVIOUS DURATION OF DISEASE IN THOSE ADMITTED DISEASE For Yeir endini Nor. 30. 1917 M. F. T. For Year ending Toul Nov. 30, : for 1918 Biennium M. F. T. | M. F. T. 3. Psychopathic Personalities 14. Development Detect!: 1. Idiocy 2. Imbecility 3. Constitutional inferiority 5. I'nclaased 6. Not Insane IT. PeHafra 1 1 I.... 1 .... 20 10 30 « 3 » 1 5 6 119 61 180! I.... 1 2. ... 2 12 . 121 13 IS 1 1 21 10 31 6 3 9 2 2 4 3 7 10 1 1 1 1 I 9S 62 155 212 123 335 rim. n Unknown... ATTACK For Year For Year , endinc ending Total Nov. 30. Nov. SO, ' for 1*17 1918 Bifnnium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 77 S3 110 68 45 113 US 78 223 17 12 29 9 6 15 26 18 44 5 4 9[ 1 2 31 6 6 12 Z I .... 1 1 3 3 415314 729 . . 16 9 25 12 7 19 28 16 44 . . 119 61 180 93 62 156 212 123 335 Totals I I I 1 I I Leaa than 1 year . . ;&gt;» 2 years 2 to 5 yean 5 to 10 yean 10 to IS yean 15 to 20 yean 20 to 25 yean Over 25 yean Unknown DURATION For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, (or 1917 1918 Biennium If. F. T. II. F. T. M. F. T. , . . 28 22 GO IS 12 25 41 34 75 13 3 16 6 C 11 18 9 27 4 4 8 3 3 6 77 14 * 3 12 2 1 3 11 4 15 2 4 « 2 4 6 1... S I.... 1 «.... 4 2 | .... 1 1 2 1 3 6 1 6 2 8 12 3 15 '.'.'. 49 22 71 61 36 97 110 58 168 119 61 180 93 62 156 212 123 335 Total. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 375 TABLE XII— HEREDITARY INFLUENCE IN DISORDER OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XIII -FORM OF DISEASE OF THOSE DISCHARGED AS RECOVERED HEREDITARY INFLUENCE Either Mather Father and mother Brother Sister Two brothers Two brothers and sist er Father and sister Father and brother Mother and sister ... Mother, brother and aunt Two brothers and aunt Grandfather and aunt Four grand parents Great aunt Paternal uncle Paternal aunt Sister and brother Half brother Paternal uncle and brother Maternal uncle . . Two brothers and father Paternal aunt and maternal grandfather Maternal grandfather Paternal grandfather None 1 For Year Nov. 80, 1917 M. F. T. 4 1 5 1 5 6 2 2 . 4 2 S 2 2 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 11 1 1 1 1 1 ! ; I For Year ending ToUu Nov 30. (or 1*18 Biennium M. Y. T. M. F. T. 2 7 9 6 8 14 5 3 8 6 8 14 2.. 2 4 ... 4 8 2 10 4 17 6 3* 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 !! i 1 1 3 3 '. '.'.'. i "i .'.'.'. i i i ... . i i.... i i i i. ... i 3 14 3 14 112 112 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1. . .. 1 1 .. . 1 70 43 113 70 43 113 Total. 22 13 36 93 8Z 115 115 75 190 DISEASE For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1*18 Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 1- Intoxication Psychosis: 1. Alcoholic a. Acute hallucinosis b. Chronic alcoholism c. Paranoid states 2. Post puerperal 2. Paresis: 1 . Tabetic form 3. Infective exhaustive psychosis 4. Dementia pnecox group: 1. Hebephrenic 2. Katatonic 3. Paranoid 4. Undifferentiated 5. Manic depressive group: 1 . Manic 2. Depressed 3. Mixed 6. Paranoid states 7. Other depressed states: 1. Undifferentiated depression . Totals 1 1 t 1 1 2 1... 1 1.... 1 1.... 1 I.... 1 1 1 1 1 1.... 1 1.... 1 4 4.... 4 4 1 1 .... 1 1 I.... I 4 S 7 6 3 8 2 2 4 2 Z, 4 1 1 1 1 7 4 11 7 6 IS 14 10 24 2 1 S 2 1 S 1.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 I.... 1 1 1 1 1 13 8 21 16 17 18 19 25 64 I I I </seg>
            <seg id="p038">376 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XIV DURATION OF RESIDENCE IN HOSPITAL OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE XV -NUMBER OF ATTACKS OF THOSE RECOVERED TABLE XVI -ACE AT ADMISSION OF THOSE RECOVERED DIRATION For Year ; 1917 For Year I mdini Nov. 30, i 1918 Total for Biennium M. F. T. M. F. T. ! M. F. T. 1 a*** than 2 months 2 to 1 months 1 to 9 months 10 to 12 months . . . 1 3 to 18 months. . . 19 to 23 month* 2 years and over. . 2.... 2. ■ 3 5 »l 3 2 5 ■ 1.... ll. 2 2i 1 1. 2 t . ... 2 Zi .... 2 2 6 5 11 8 4 12 2 4 6 2 2 4 3 7 10 9 7 16 1.. 1 10 4 II 2 5 7 2 .... 2 Totals 13 8 2l! IS 17 33 lH 25 54 ATTACK For Year end in* Nov. 30, 1917 For Yemr ending Nov. 30, 1918 Total for Biennium First Second.. Third Fourth Many rnknuwn M. F. T. I 5 5 10 3 1 4i 2 1 3| 1 , ! »■■■■ i M. F. T. I . 8 8 17 6 3 9 2 5 7 ; . I I M. F. T. 1 :! 14 27 9 4 13 4 6 10 1 1 . .. 1 1 2 2 Total* . 13 a ii 16 17 33 29 25 54 AGE For Year ending Nov. SO, 1917 For Year ' ending Nov. 30, ; 1918 Total for Bienr.ium M I. F. T. | M. F. T. j M. F. T. 15 and under 20 20 and under 25 25 and under .'In M and under 35 35 and under 40 40 and under 45 45 and under 50 ... 50 and under 55 So and under 60 . . Inknown Total* 1 I 1 1 2, 2 2 4.... 4 3 1 4 S 8!. 1 2 3 11 1 1 . 1 1 13 8 21 ,. 1, 241 ::::::::::::| 16 17 :W 1 1 5 3 8 15 13 28 4 1 5 3. 3 1 2 3 1 1 1. . 1 1 .... 1 29 25 54 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE XVII— CAUSE OF DEATH For Year For Year F.nditlK Endin* Nov. 30, : Nov. 30. Total CAUSE PSYCHOSI for Biennium M. F. T. Accidental I run over b train) Manic Deprewiv Mixed 1 Apoplexy Port Apoplectic- Dementia Senile Dementia Senile I&gt;ementia Apoplexy Art prior Sell Exhaustion Dementia Praeci IX Katatonia Epilepsy 1 Kxhaust ion Exh auction Exhaustion Huntington's Ch lnvolutional S Melancholia 1 1 Exhaui Exhaui Manic Depress! v Manic Exhaustion Manic Depressive Mixed Exhaustion Senile Dementia Kxhkustiun . Pellagra General Paralyria &lt;»f the General Paralysis ( Insane the Insane K Mitral Insufficiency \ I &gt; ■viopmcntal [&gt;e Mitral Insufficiency Manic Depres.-iv*- Manic 1 3 Mitral Insufficiency Paranoid State Mitral lr; Paranoit Mitral Insufficiency Senile Dementia . Mitral lnsul^cit-nr Myocarciial Degeneration General Paralysis » Myocardial D*?ki ih? Insane Nephritis Interstitial Chronic Imersiitia Nephritis Interstitial Chronic Intcrstit Manic Depressiv Nephritis Interstitial Manic Depre-.isi ve Nephritis Inl Manir Nephritis — Interstitial Senile Dementia NVphrilis Intnrstit.iii DeTnenti: Nephritis I nrlastted Nephritis Pneumonia -Broncho Senile Dementia Pneumonia Itmnchu Pneumonia Lobar I&gt;i-velopniental I&gt;f Pneumonia Lobar Pneumonia -Lobar Pneumonia— Lohar Pneumonia Lobar Paranoia Pneumonia- Lobar Senile Dementia le Dementia Pneumonia Terminal I Senile Dementia Pneumonia Terminal Derrentia Puerperal SepLs Lndaaaed Puerperal Sepi.s 1 1 1 Senility Epilepsy Septicaemia . Senile Dementia. Status Kpilcptiru- Epilepsy 9 Spanish Influenza Broncho Pneumonia Imbecile :i Spanish Influenza Broncho Pneumonia Epilepsy Spanish Influenza Broncho Pneumonia Dementia Praeeox flebephrenia 1 &amp; Suicide Hanging Psychopathic Personality 1 1 Suicide Run-over by train General Paralysis the Insane 1 1 Tuberculosis -Pulmonary Dementia Praeeox Hebephrenia Tuberculosis Pulmonary Dementia Praccox Paranoid 1 6 .1 S Tuberculosis Pulmonary Tuberculosis — Pulmonary Developmental Defect Manic Depressive 1 1 Manic 1 1 1 ... 1 1 1 1... 1 1 1 3 8 Tu berculosis — Pulmonary 1 nclas^fd Typhoid Fever Typhoid Fever Paranoid State Unelaased 1 1 1 Total »;;* 4 31 M 58 154 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 378 TABLE XVIII -PERIOD OF RESIDENCE IN HOSPITAL OF THOSE WHO DIED DURING BIENNIUM TABLE XX— AVERAGE NUMBER OF PATIENTS EMPLOYED Less than 1 month . I to 6 months . 6 to 12 months . 1 year to 2 years 2 years to 5 years 5 years to 10 years Over 10 yean* Total. PERIOD For Year For Year ending andinf Total Nov. A. Nov. 30, for 1917 1918 Biennium ! M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. i 5 4 9 4 4 8 9 8 17 7 6 13 8 3 11 15 9 24 4 5 9 H 2 10 12 7 la 10 2 12 13 3 16 23 5 28 6 4 10 11 8 19 17 12 29 4 4 8 6 7 13 10 11 Zl 628 4 4 8 10 6 16 42 27 69 54 31 85 96 68 154 TABLE XIX- -AGE AT DEATH AGE For Y««r For Year fading ending Total Nov. 30, Nov. 30. (or 1917 1918 Biennium 20 to 25 r*an 25 to 30 years SO to 35 years 35 to JO years 40 to 45 years- . . 45 to 50 years 50 to 55 years 55 to 60 years 60 to 65 years 65 to 70 years Over 70 years Unknown Totals j M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. 2 t 1 3 4 1 5 « 1 2 3 7 2 9 8 4 12 3 2 5 6 3 9 9 5 14 2 3 5 7 2 9 9 5 14 4 2 « 2 1 3 6 3 9 5 2 7 1 4 S 6 6 12 6 1 7 7 6 13 13 7 20 1 1 2 8 . 8 ! 9 1 10 7 2 9 336 10 5 15 5 2 7 S 2 7 10 4 14 7 7 14 7 S 12 14 12 26 1 1 2 1 1 2 42 27 69 64 31 85 96 68 154 Average Number Employed In Ward Outside Ward Aggregate - Population M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. M. F. T. During year ending Nov. 30. 1917 94 62 156 178 96 269 267 158 425 330 26S 598 During year ending Nov. 30, 1918... 97 70 167 185 90 275 282 160 442 362 273 625 Averages for biennium 95 66 161 178 93 422 273 254 527 341 271 611' Per Cent Employed M. F. T. 81 59 70 80 58 69 82 59 70 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 379 TABLE XXI— RATIO OF EMPLOYEES TO PATIEN S •Docs not include superintendent of nurses, assistant superintendent of nurses, supervisor, or general night watches. s umber of physicians, including superintendent Ratio of physicians to patients Number of day nurses and ward attendants Ratio of same to patients 'Number of night nurses and ward attendants Ratio of same to patients 'Total of day and night nurses and ward attendants . . . focal officers and employes Ratio of same to patients I Male I Female Total 5 t 1-111 1.91 IT 19 M 1.21 . 1.15 6 &lt; 11 1.68 1.46 It 24 M 35 40 76 1.10 1.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p042"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>