<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  POTATO EXPERIMENTS.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">KksiTv of Nebraska. Bl'LLETlN THh AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION t.n NEBRASKA XIX. Artki.k I\ POTATO EXPERIMENTS. MERSON A IK. N N I" MR \SK \ A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Kd an.l wilt ent o' iring h of plant ■ medium, an </seg>
            <seg id="p003">OTATO EXPERIMENTS. V. EMERSON Vl'KOW CTION. i two yean the Nebraska Experiment 1 cm lests comparing various methods of i\ dill'* reni sizes of seed pieces ami quantities int kinds of see.l. etc-. Stub tests are not at all ave been tried time and again by Experiment her parts of the country. Some of them were sort of demonstration that thoro, careful ; pays here just as it does elsewhere, s,. aware, the value for seed POipot lir a littei mulch has not been t' LT1VATED POTATOES FOR SEED. &gt;1 weather crop. It is because of this well in the far north. Moreover, pota best development fairly uniform regards soil moisture and Dg tin- case, why should not pot; mulch be especially well developed itrong seed? The soil beneath a mulch lately low temperature during summer re is also exceptionally uniform, varying legree or two between day and night and from day to day. The soil moisture h is also more abundant and much more iniform in amount than in case of bare ground, even latter is given good tillage. n good tillagi </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 he Ex] i l h i ised \ II 1 easily mill that the\ The value for seed pun growl mulch has been tested during two seasons ai i Station, In 1!mm a plal of potatoes was mule and an adjoining plat was given careful cultivi of the two plate was practically uniform and i on the two plats was taken from the same lot of tubers was saved from the muk-hed and cultivated plate se| The use of seed that had been gi preceding year increased the yield of potatoe LM6 and 41 per eeni in 1906. If further t&lt; results reported here, it would seem that mu used for the production of high grade seed p&lt; Moreover, mulching usually results in incr properly handled. Mulching potatoes on a I: course Impracticable, but most fanners cool enough of their potato field to produce the ■under the same conditions during winter, plai ig plats in the spring (it 1905, and given idea vat inn during the summer. In I'.hh; the experime peated with seed grown in mulched and in cultival the vcar In-fore. The same precaution*) were obae the tirst test. Uniform seed \\;is used in start wii The seed saved from the mulched and from the plats was taken as it came, without selection, am over winter under the same conditions. Both kin nit in the same way, planted in the same w joining plats, and treated alike as regards tillage Under these conditions any constani differen* between the two i»lats mod be ascribed to the ef methods of culture employed the pn-\ ions season. obtained from the mulched and from the cult i as folio Cultivated seed . If niched sfi-&lt;\ . .-&gt;•;: </seg>
            <seg id="p005">ll 5 i i\ production per bushel. SPKOI TKD SIKH TL'IIKI "•i| to advantage in hastening growth uidlcl can-fully in planting. I ver, reduce the vitality of seed tuben tatoes thai have sprouted badly and are should never be used for teed if sound, on in be obtained. ason a lest was made of sprouted - witli sound ones. In the fall of ■ Experiment Station were divided into i li was stored in an open bin in the cellar tural Building and the other kept in a doors. The tuben kept in the cellar badly before planting time, while those led very little and were firm when taken diii the two lots were planted on adjoin parate tesis. The gross yields of tuben 1 ill each of the lesis Were as follow Third yield from the sound seed was *7t&gt; pounds as •"•."&gt;»; pounds from the sprouted seed, or •"&gt;»; per 1 the sound than from the sprouted seed. The crop from the poor seed at digging time was 94.88, •oni the good seed was x7.cn. the lirst class tuben sold at si per hundred and ihe seconds at 50 ndred. One hundred pounds of seed taken were ach case. It would therefore have been just as have paid fl.68 per bushel for the good seed as n m lvi-n sprouts sudi as form iu ll'II L'lTi 21 L&gt; ■2-2U :!l&gt;0 321 ►t &lt;*&lt; 1 t \u&gt; jicinr xi-l fri </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Potato Experimt m ll 'I 1 ill lifferen I 1 v I V 1 I J . \ X ' ' I » \ i * 1 f 1 1.1,1 1 * 1 ■ i i i ■ I is not advisable to plant tubers that arc very free from scab can be obtained, became scab made the tubers lijjht ami to have injured or r of the eyes. On the other hand, tubers that slightly scabby make good seed if treat seal) fungus. The method of treatment in common soak the uinut seed tubers for two hours in a solut by adding one-half pint of formalin to 15 gallons Treated seed should of r not produced scabby tubers recently. During tin • ins, demonstration nc\ treatment have I teen made at the Experiment lot was then treated with forn side by side in ground sup] BO record was made of tin ben in the crop, but it v produced a crop that \\a crop from the untrcati were noticed. The per cent the crops from the treated follows v Seed treated with fol nialin Seed not treated QIANT1TY OF SKEI», SIZE OF SE1 HIII.S Km impracticable to treat of one of these subje impossible to experiment with one of them \\ lg at least one of the oilier two. If we plant lioth cases tubers ilia separated into two l« </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Hi in rim i ii tx 7 1 i I I x v i i u I Was tli I llct In I'.mn; it wa mm- anv dill litt'eren r quantity of si listanci iv we iiiusi also necessarily plain s or drop them at different distance*. same tine tenting different quantities stances between the seed piece*. Like- distance between hill* (allowing only oae can be bad only by lisinu different sizes (litlei-ent quantities of Reed. A dUcuarioa e these things ititti consideration is apt to or instance, it is often said that as a rule s increases with the size of the seed piece, ling more than halves, halves more than iteis more than eighths. I Jut this is not 1 * t where the distances between bills arc tame for the different sizes of seel \&lt; it is not true except when; tit.- q ia:i.ii\ increases with the size of the win I pi is impossible to tell wli-ther differeti he difference* in size of seed pieces, i«» .lif- it the Experiment Station produced vk*ld* d ."&gt;14 pounds. The first plat was planted and the second with quarter tuber* It &gt;e said, therefore, that the quarter tuber* vield than the eighth tubers. Itat the dis- Is was the same in both plats. The quantity on the higher yielding plat was therefore the quantity planted on the lower yielding leater vield due to the larger size of seed cater amount of seed planted? The cxperi - 1 threw no light on the question. attempted to plan a test that should show fences ill yield that might lie observed were in size of seed pieces, distance betwcn hills, eed. Eleven combinations of size of seed x ] n-i-i im-iit wit li different uses pi seed, or to both of tlu's;- factor*. In </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 planted, as can he seen from the table below. Th tance between rows \vas about three feet. The vari Bariy &lt;thio. The tnben were of medium izc, avcniiiii M6 \K'r bushel, or about 4| ounces each. The lai pieces used, therefore, averaged about _' ; ounces m-Ii ami tli smallest piece* only a trifle over one half ounce ea ■ as carried out on land that was practically tit The plat was Is rods long. There were 44 rows in tli or four rows for each of the eleven combination seed pieces and distance between hills. A record w the yield of each row. The results given here an tl cured from the four rows, or, in other word ■if each Of the elev uit ions. The 1 II the total yield of tubers, the percentag total value of the crop, and the value of th of seed. Tubers under three OUIM as small. The small tu dred pound* and the larger ones at |1 per hundred p&lt; the prices secured at dicing time. Th&lt; figured at xi.LT&gt; per hundred pounds, the price paid at figured at $12."&gt; per hundred p&lt; ing time. The yields and values per acre are given i table below. The actual yields and values can be fun table below. The actual yields dividing these figures by 12. dividing these figures by 12 Effect of size of seed pieces. Jisla the yield and value of potato Eflect of size of seed pi Size of seed piece, distance between hilla, and Jjg ot y£°d*in £™£ quantity of seed. "null e J " B p. r per 8Ue of seed piece, distance between hills, and ce {^ quantity of seed sm»l pa: tubOT » \m. «■« :*&gt;r 18 inches apart, fl bn - inches apart, fl bu per acre JS 97 io incnes apart, t&gt; nu per a Eighth tubers J 12 inches apart. 0 bu. per a Eighth tubers, J 12 incheH apart. 9 bu per acre : 9 inches apart U bu. per a^re ti inches a)&gt;art, 18 bu. per acre •!" Ill f24 inches apart, 9 bu. [ier acre f] 9 inches apart 12 bu inches apart. 1 f 24 inches ■part, 9 bu. [ier a r 1 18 inch s apart. 12 bu per a tubers, J 12 inches apart. 1« bn. per a « Quarter - inch -s apart. 12 bu per acre 29 110 tubers, j l-_&gt; inches apart. l-&gt; bo. per acre 22 170 BO. 72 inches apart, 'J4 bu per acre 26 1 1 ;j 21 inches apart, is bu per acre 28 Half tubers 18 inches apart, ".'4 bu per acr« 12 inches aDart 36 bn ner hit' IQfi lni </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 ite that the per cent of small tnben in &gt;rc upon tin size of i in- weed pieces (qnan - i than upon the distance between hills or per acre. The pet cent of small tnben ■e of the seed piece, being greatest when vere used and least where small ones were and value of the crop increased with the quantity ited up to certain limits, varying with the si/.,- of and the distance between hills. The l&gt;est qaan - il per acre with different sizes of seed pieces were: !t to 12 bushels .'Hi bushels uantity of seed per acre, the yield and valm cased as the distance; between hills decre le distance between hills for any of the quan- planted cannot bt told from the test. The beat ween hills for different sizes of seed pieces \\ It is indicated by these tests that the yield of potatoes de - nds much less upon the size of the seed pieces (quantity of seed per hill) than upon the quantity of seed per acre or the distance between hills. The Talue of the crop, however, is influenced somewhat by the size of the seed pieces, since the tie size of the potatoes and the per cent of marketable increase as the size of the seed piece diminishes. Large I pieces are best to give the plant a good start under un- favorable soil and weather conditions in spring, but in a dry summer or in a dry region very large seed pieces, very close planting, and a very large quantity of seed per acre are apt to result in many small tubers and comparatively few of marketable size. th tub. ter tubers. tubers .... 9 to 12 inches 12 inches 12 inches </seg>
            <seg id="p010">/ 10 Halves, ll' iiirlii Of seed. B, L'l in. Ik Will, •Kl l'AlilN 'I'lNlS III' (lillclllll III ■i 1 1 li potatoes have been &lt;■ aeaHOU. A piece of land tlui ■cr of years ;m&lt;l had been pl&lt;&gt; for the test. One plat was I he seed dropped in tli&lt;- listei dial the ground was plowed befoi toes. A third plai was treat&lt;il ii the same after-treatiiM'iit, Inn all tin- plats in litli given the same treatment as n&gt; tillage, spray ing plat consisted of lour rows &lt;&gt;() rods long. Tlire tin- plat iwi.ii liill&gt;. iiikI i|ii;iii(iiv itf w^l |»lailtttl lliiil W ilii^ pxperiuwnt, tli«- full.. win- gavi- Imsi rtttultg Pels. 11' inches, is lillshels. Villl f SIMvl Till 1 |HMirr-l I'olllls »'«*1 ■ll&lt;. li ilirlir*. I s lilisllil I s.m-,1. . (Jiiartcr*, 24 i" 1 In*. '•' Ihi*1k &lt;lf S&lt;M'&lt;1 ,i lister, leaving pronounced ridg&lt; scm-.i. A second plat \\;is planti Biddys iiiiidc ill rwvwing iln- ili ;ii him &lt;• iif'irr planting. A Kinjr turn 1 ami tho nerd «1i&lt; &gt;j &gt;] «»-&lt; I in evert iliii land in this pint was aim harrowed initurdu lag. The test, includin*; ;ill i»f tli&lt;- Fonr iihit ted on adjoin in}; land. The two tests wen- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 / iii-rca V I'la I I \ plan plow II S per cell It he weeds the pool llhle I plowing, tli rapped in ever] Tin 1 rcsuli s of ill an. I spring plowing, while one bad wo of the plats wen- left ridged after her two wen- left smooth. The ridded leveled down 1&gt;\ harrowing after the mil just before the potatoes came op. This rtive way of getting the weeds out of the uir the necessity of hoeing. The yields from each test Were as follows : i thai spring plowing in addition to fall plow - he yield over fall plowing alone in the lirst sed it in tile seeolld. The total yield of the •d a gain of ."&gt; per cent for spring plowing 1 and 2). The ground was so loose on in - alia sod that it was difficult to make the lis - was especially pronounced in the case of tin - owed again in the spring. Leaving the ridges IT to lie worked down when the weeds started elds in both tests over leveling the ri«lgi ing, the average gain for the former method &gt;er cent (compare Plata - and .'St. Planting after the plow in every third furrow gave a both tests than planting in lister furrows Tilt 1 average gain of the latter over the former t i compare I'lals ."! and 4i. The yield from ie one that was spring plowed in addition to lit was listed and had the ridges worked down started, was !»."» per cent greater than the yield ■st plat, the (lie that had the seed pieces y third furrow when the plowing was done. I' this one season indicate thai it pavs to take prepare special furrows for the seed rather First itnient. Pounds. ridged »71 and left ri(ln«-il 1 mil left level ■ •il dropped in every 1»:M </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 i r 1 1 than to drop it in the plow furrows, and that it is best ti throw up ridges over the rows in order that the weeds tha start in the row may be killed by harrowing the ridges dowi as the potatoes are coming up. As to whether the same n suits will be secured in other seasons under other condition of soil and moisture cannot be said. It would seem probabl that in a very dry spring, leveling the ridges at once woul save considerable moisture from being lost into the air, pei haps enough to more than counterbalance the los thr greater weed growth in the rows. Further tests should lett between the shallow am from shallow planted seed formed near the surface ground, as was noticeable at digging time, li is p that the irregularities in moisture and temperature surface soil checked the growth of the tubers at certai ami started a second growth at other times, resulting production of knobs on the tubers (compound tubers tubers from deep planted seed, on the other hand. w&lt; down in the ground, where they were less subject i«&gt; tions of temperature and moisture and therefore sho lie second growth. The crop from seed planted ftv&lt; deep contained almost no compound tubers, and that fn need planted three and four inches deep was but little won The crops from seed planted one inch and two inches de&lt; this point readily. DBPTH Of PLANTING. In 1905 two tests were mad.' of different depths of ] Ptoes. Depths ranging from one to five inches we total yields from the two tests were as follows; Planted one inch deep. -182 Planted two inches deep.. Planted three inches deep '-"' s Planted four inches deep. Planted five inches deep 306 There was a very noticeable difference in regular! </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 P» i hi h lad main compound tubers. The l&gt;est depth for i, therefore, from the standpoint of yield was depth from the standpoint of quality. As be- the four- and live-inch depths there is little choice in ind the slightly better quality of the tubers from seed :ed five inches deep is probably more than offset by the l labor in digging them. Of the 3-inch and 4-inch depths anting, the latter gave a somewhat greater yield, pro- I equally as good tubers, and caused no trouble in dig- The indications of this one test are, therefore, that inches is about the proper depth for planting seed tubers r our conditions, and this is in accord with practical ex- oce in this region. The 1-inch and 2-inch depths are nly not to be considered under ordinary conditions, such shallow planting is not only apt to reduce the materially but also to produce irregular, compound HOKO. MKhllM, AND 11K)R TILLAGE. part of potato culture more important than not even good seed. Of course the best of till - rinj; good crops if poor seed is used, lint it is true that the best seed will give only medium returns e is neglected. Comparisons of different degra n tillage have been made during two seasons. In edium, thoro, and very thoro tillage were tested, the ve plats baring Keen cultivated ."&gt;, 7, and 10 times baring been harrowed twice. It will be noted, thin - that the poorest tilled plat was cared for better than iverage potato field. The cultivators were run about • inches deep. Bather late in the growth of the pot; ;round became hard and dry below the loose dirt mulch. ie very thoroh tilled plat the cultivator was run at that deeper than usual, turning up hard lumps of earth and lbly disturbing the potato roots. The yield of tubers </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Potato E.rpi rimentt A i rs w i 1 IV ih I from six rows l'(» rods lon^ of medium tilled potato Ei pounds; from three rows of thoroly tilled potati unds. and from eight rows of verv thoroly tilled p !62 pounds: or 112 poanda, 165 pounds, and 158 p&lt;*r row respectively. The percentages of small tube medium tillage lit. thoro tillage 14. very tboro till The three extra cultivations given the very thoroly til certainly gave no corresponding return. Whether tl would have been greater here than in the thoro nil plat had it not bees for the one deeper cultivation th and up the hard, dry ground cannot of cours important feature of this test is the great differen&lt; Veil medium tilled plat cultivated five ti tivations given the thorn tilli yield of 47 per cent over tl Hut the real difference in fact that one plat was &lt;u after each heavv rain, and not have been dest roved with resorted to in case of either plat. 1 under these circumstances the v as different even if the medium same number of cultivations givei tivating at the right time is jus In 1906 two tests of tillage were ma and thoro cultivation were compared, and poor, medium, and thoro cultivation. In the th poor cultivation plat was harrowed twice an twice. The cultivating in this plat was done with a shovel corn plow. The ground was stirred to a dep least four inches, the aim being to follow the metlu between the thoro tilled i»l;it i-ultiv ■y the t\\&lt;» extra cult i vat li.it one nlal \v:is cultiv B while the ulllt-l- | • I ; 1 1 w; allowing the weeds in « </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 u valu i State. The thoro cultivation plat was and cultivated four times. The culti- tli a 14 sliDvel 2-row cultivator. The ion was from two to three inches. No hoe her plat. Ofting to the fact that the plat* old alfalfa field plowed up the fall before, where le hliieiirass had gained entrance, and that tli IILT- especially with the very small shoveled clllti- The weeds, mostly annual uras^es. obtained a con (othold in the potato rows, even in the thoro nil - it. The poor cultivation plat, however, was much of the two. The difference was likely tine in part Ference in number of cultivations given the two probably nuiteaa mm li to the fact that the ground weeds in the poor cultivation plat before nil inn. while the thoro cultivation plat wa&gt; ;ii fore or as soon as the weeriN Wetcan to -~ 1 1 • &gt; v i ields from the two plats, earn containing Mi long, were 2,902 pounds from the poor niltiva- 3 pounds from the thoro cultivation, or IS l&gt;i&gt;li lishels respect iveiv. This is ):V2 \M'V cent mop- loro cultivation plat than from the poor cnltiva- The weights of small tuben in the two cases weiw ! and U'2U pounds, or lT&gt; per cent from the plat aj_ r e and only 14 per cent from the plat » The value of the crop at the prices received at si per loo pounds for the large tuber* (those •ee ounces iii weight i and 50 cents per lot) ponnda small tubers — was $25.39 for the |M&gt;or cultivation I f62.69 for tin- thoro cultivation plat. Bubtractiag ue of the se&lt;'d. ¥7.."&gt;0 in each case, there remained from the poor cultivation plat and $55.19 from the lilt 1 Vat MM) plat. While llo records were kept of the I'osl of piodiii iii" the crop, it is prolialih- that ill yc-ii in p;irt with an N-shovrl corn culti- (•(I thoroly, ii was difficult to &lt;!&lt;• a jjimmI job of </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 I i of preparing the land, planting, tilling, harrowing very little if any profit from the poor cultivation the poorly cultivated plat just paid expenses, the I cultivated thoroly must have paid from $30 t above all expen- In a second test of tillage in 1906, one plat was i^i \. tillage, a second one medium tillage, and a third on tillage. The kind of tillage and number of times tilh as follows: Sorrowing! Cultivations The land when Experiment Siaii Kany yean. The a ■ thoro cultivation i Kthe potato oil plal the wee The Hied shovel cultivator was usi out the season and on tin the time. In the poor cul eently free" from weeds. The condition fields frequently seen on Nebraska the negleci should not b&lt; xaggera Btructed to lake as his model for a two-acre block of potatoes that la,\ the Station test plats. It is a fact, howevt tilled plat was belter cared for thruout the season neighbor's block. It is of inter that onlv about one-half of the neighbor's block u potato fields ;n tained a good shirt befon shovel corn plow wai tion pl;it was about the avera </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 \ rrenta i thon n. i i i x l lit Mil i i ri in n if ■•stern Nebi or six culti poor that it was doubtless thought too ing. The thoro cultivation plat was • ■tics than the others. The ii from many of the plants before they The gross yields from the three plats were lat 724 pounds lltivation plat 1,162 pounds plat 1,067 pounds of small tubers in the plats of poor, me- thoro cultivation were 27, 18, and 24 respectively, of the loss in vield and size of tubers in the thoro was due to the greater injury from the po how much to disturbance of the vines and itn.-s by the frequent cultivation cannot be of the medium cultivation plat was 80 per hat of the poor cultivation plat, a very no- •e considering that one plat was tilled serea her five tinv • tests it seems fair to com hide that proper the most important parts of potato growing. r in the way of one or two extra cultivations pavs big waives in the increased value of the crop from poor cultivation just about p xtra cultivations at critical times will pay \ great in comparison to the insignificantly f the extra work. It is apparent, how tillage can be overdone. The number of cul - pend upon the soil, the season, and perhaps riie important thing to remember is to soil as soon as practicable after each rain ween rains as is necessary to keep the w • Any farther tillage is usually a was; Iocs not result in positive injury to the crop. raska two or three harrowings followed by i vat ions are usually sufficient to rire good </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Ml IA'III\(i I'uTATu Tin: ritniii.K.Ms Sri i &gt; i i : i &gt; . — Tin- use of a litter muU-li ; substitute for cultivation or a supplement to growing luis been under icsi ai the Experiment Ma i Ik- past seven years. The results &lt;&gt;!' the tests of the ti three yean wi-iv published in Bulletin so. In ii iik'his a number of problem* have been studied, ainoui; t hi ii being comparisons of the yield ai cultivated potato** and &lt;&gt;r ih&lt;- value t»f i \;ili-i| inlicfs for Mi'il. tin- nisi of mull hi rated t niters foi ICi-i'iil inalrriuls for inulrlii's. ilic time f»f 11 of the mulch, tin* siy.&lt;- &lt;»f si-n| |iii-n-s, ■ 1«-| ii l;!hrr lirlwcrli rows. all'l I lie like. I-~ I I I &lt; I ol Ml l.i lll\(. ON VlKI.il AMI Ol Tin- ii'sis show that, on ihc wholr. mi ■ KIT id Ml l.i HI \i, i&gt;\ \ ■ li-sis slmw ihai. on i satisfactory wax s;|l isfih-lurv \\il\ of jJ^POwillg jiolillors Oil ; i;iio.-s wlicn | &gt;r&lt; &gt;| mi-I \ mulched have ut»n latoen when pn than \\ lien pi ven the very lM«nf ciiltivatioi I m i • 1 1 iis iiiiiih ;is III |i&lt;-r cciii in soup I m i • i i as milch as HI pit 10 he sure, the yield h;is liecii leuwm^l U\ In In- sure i In- vii-M ha rule that lias mTiirrwl only v lu-n wrons; rule thai lias iM-euri ing or planting have lieen practice*!. The in^ or plain hi}i have lieen pi ben luis nol lieen hurt hy mulcliing exci'j sons. \\ lien- tlic miilcli luis kc|ii the {iron 11 ran -i I with water [or a considerable tim weir fl&lt;*velopinp, 1 1 1 &lt; * \ have I n rather w; lions are rarely exjierieiM'ed in Nehraska, if the |&gt;ot:itoi's art* prowii oil \\ &lt; -1 1 drained L'xceHHively wet-, cold limen, or in poorly ill icr mulch brings about iln- nuiforiu cowl inrc and temperatiire which an to potatoes. In this connection ihc outward indications of </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 1 \ \ i been stored for mne ami cultivated crop* its on l«m&gt;; exposure Dim- of their smooth ;v ap|H-arailcc uf rill the tulici-s Lav il cellar 1 1 1 &lt; • 1 1 l i i l u of i lie fort iihmiiIiiicss of skill is riic iiitri-i-ciici' iii lien tirsi dug, however, thai tin* mulched the cultivated ones by smooth skin of i In • ilone. riint ill s noi necessarily accompanied bv poor liuiiK'^s or \\ ;itcrincss when boiled, was looking tests made in 1906, the smooth - tubers cooking as dry ami mealy as the ivated ones. The smooth skin of mulche«l lerefore indicate lack of maturity, lm t is In- protection against drying afforded by internal characteristic* known to accoav quality in potatoes are, so far as our ob- just as pronounced in mulched as in Thai is to say, the quite as large and tin n mulched as in culti external medullary internal medullary rated tubers. Potatoes. — Tlie ca t of mulching pota- nein Station, considering the value of both 1. lias been considerably in excess of the ration. A mulch spread four inches deep 15 to l'o tons of straw per acre. .\t the commonly brings in Lincoln markets, its Experiment Station. Bulletin \g i ' ion. Bulletin »r i 1 1 1' U \ **&gt; k. 111. ;il'(* llsu*iil\ iiui-y. |&gt;;ii-i ii-iihirl v when lirst dag, t Ik- smooth ii|&gt;|M-;ii';iii&lt;i' &lt;&gt;!' iiimiai lire WWII Illlllrlii'tl riii- tit 11 i • - 1 1 &lt;• -&lt;• i i nix parated from practically &lt;&gt;nt of the question. In modi </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Potato Experiment* &lt; \ y :::;;:; parti of the State, however, straw has so tittle vali much of it is burned to get it out of the wav. 1 this is not the case, there is usually a lot of old stra fnmi the tops of stacks that can be used for niukhii if this is wanted for bedding, the resulting sra h •d if sufficiently coarse and straw The labor required to spread a mulch is eonsiderab] ticiilarly so when the mulch is put on after tl up. when it must be worked up around the pi u Stable litter, being liner, requires somewhi the spreading than does bay or straw. lit \ Experiment Station show tl if spreading a fo straw mulch to b that this is much mon it does not necessari ployed profitably on results, must no hut it must be given at the other work may be The mulch at intervals at any &lt; onvci i planted and before they are up. When 01 average potato garden is usually neglected a that if it is ever cleaned up considerable han r quired, and this is likely to make the total cos a the cultivated crop about equal to the cost of mulchin Materials Used in Mulching. — The mater ml in&lt; monly used for mulching is straw or old hay from or bottoms of stacks. Coarse stable litter car used to good advantage, particularly on soil kii good results in the way of increased yields hav 11 from its use at the Experiment Station on rather heav (see Bulletin 80). Whether the increase in yield mis: have been equally great if the manure had been ncorn with the soil instead of having been used as a mulch w i lone, no further labor is required unt t il it v. It is especially desirable on lijjht, san«lv </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Potato Experiment* 21 u tan i I t u to give the same increase in yield il at one time without seriously the crop. Potatoes grown under a llv when planted very shallow, have in potatoes mulched with straw. It is id the manure been worked into the soil ■ been muck more injurious. Where land inn ot manure, the mulch of coarse stable t and at the same time serve the pla me season that the mulch does ;eeds of the more vigorous straw will cause no end of reduced yield of pot ivs he exercised eds or th( heat left in tin t i a great I v iw and having crop of small grain spring the weed* grow without •ad as letting Mi i rn. — .Mulches should he deep enoagh ctically all weed growth and to conserve A mulch four inches deep has been found to h of these things as well, on the whol tivation. A mulch deeper than is necessary for these has no advantage, is wasteful of material and labor, a positive detriment to the crop if applied before the ts are up. Tho litter mulches a foot deep are sometimes mmended, many plants fail to get up thru an 8-inch .•h, even when large seed pieces are used. Reducing the f plants is one of the things that must be guarded ling. A 4-inch mulch is about as deep as can V used mk of MULCHING. — Potatoes, unlike most vegetables. can niched as soon as planted without any preliminary cul - ion. tho they start more promptly if the mulch is with - until just before tlie tops break thru the ground. In »se one or two harrowing* should be given before the ful, however, whether a quautitv of </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 i i n i 1 ri i ro, mulch is applied. Mulching i.lie plants after they ;ii inches high ami have been burrowed and cultivated twice usually gives l&gt;est results Inn is more expensiv coucfl of the extra labor required in both ciiltivat i&lt; mulching. The litter iiiusi be spread between the row considerable care to avoid burying tin- plants. Whih potatoes will come up thru three or four indies of sin readily enough if the si raw is in place before they gel a ground, they are easily killed or weak* with litter after they are once up. lied Itv lieini; ■;k or Heed Pieces.- When the in otatoes are up, the plant must not the soil I m i thru the straw l&gt;esi&lt;le ilch is spread onlv fun The plant Ml strong at the start, therefore. While the size of see* has not been tested directly in connection with u has. nevertheless, been noted that w (half tubers) have been used the ] plants have been too weak to pus hi the mulch, thus resulting iu a pool danger of getting too many very potatoes are grown iu the usual w checks the loss of moisture from tin &lt;&gt;f the tubers formed reach a fail SIZ( Dkitii or Planting. — Experience ai the stat that where the seed is planted shallow the pla thru the mulch better than win re it is planted deep especially noticeable when small seed pieces ai seed should, of course. In- planted deep enough to pre\ being dislodged by any harrowing that may be given the mulch is applied, and deep enough so thai tli taken will have room to form for the most part bel surface of the ground. It is probably l&gt;est to plain fr to three inches deep and to depend upon large seed pit ■ iiu-hcs of straw readily, whil pieces (eighth tubers i ha\( sci (l piece* wheii mulching is pract </seg>
            <seg id="p023">( 23 / / 1 in thr to h ifi..;s, pluut &gt; push up thru both soil Bows.- The rows of mulched potatoes nee there is no occasion to run a ii'iu and also because the mulch holds cultivation, thereby Baking it p. on the same amount of land. Moreover, or both labor and Mulching material to •&lt;• together, since the cost of mulching, lependi upon the area covered rather number of rows, it cannot be said just what ance between rows and hills for mulched po- ng depends to a considerable extent upon ■d and the moisture conditions where the )wn. At the Experiment station good results red from putting the rows is indies to two SUMMARY. traduced under a straw mulch the preced - 17 per cent more in 1905 and 4L per cent seed similar to it in every way except that bv cultivation the year before. If further -e results, Nebraska fanners will have a &gt;f producing high grade seed potato hem under a mulch of hay or straw, i I'ap- ilted tubers should not be used for nver winter in an ordinary cellar where 1 sprouted badly before planting time were seed that had been kepi properly and that md unsprouted. The average yield from the raa •".»; per cent greater than from the sprouted separate tests. It would have incurred no finau ave thrown the sprouted seed away and to have ■r bushel for the sound seed, i I\i&lt;;e hills 12 iii'lics to 18 inches apurt </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 use-, namely, soaking them two hours pint of formalin with 15 pilous &lt;&gt;!' water, h;is » Sl/.e (d se, 1 1 Bli depths. The yields fro were decidedly less than iilnis were of inferior qu; •I from second growl li. i II !»(»."&gt; seven cultivations live cultivations, but tei tly below tlnit from se i i vat ions. In l'.tn weedy land, three harrowing*, followed l&gt;.\ four i-ultivatioi produced a yield 132 per cent greater than two harrow ami two cultivations. In the Ban The nu-tlioil of irciiiiii;: results ;it ilie Experiment Station, i l';i &lt; &gt;l eleven combinations i ween liills. iiinl quantity the liest results were old ■ere cut in quarter iiiIm r BNCiiii I rei •&lt;l minis, rut in hfl 9 ti 10. I in hi olil alfalf replowing in i In- spring yield of [&gt;otutu4*N only •"&gt; in fiirrowa made \\ ii h ;i li: i- i cm greater i linn &lt; Jiieres ill eveiv lilir.l llUli ing up the ground over i Ii and harrowing i lio r proved a very effect ive im row . The praci i»-e i ucreu in^ i lie ground lev&lt; I :ili«i\ In l!t(ir&gt; potatoen |il;ini better than plantings i libers \\ ere about equal </seg>
            <seg id="p025">t / i i i i i I I 'a uuvatious increased tin- yield 'i &gt;i\ cultivations the yield de- aiuounl of tillage can be pre In eastern Nebraska, however nd live or six cultivations ai nit thing is to stir the surfa as often otherwise as is net. Cultivating at the ri^ht time is the number of cultivations gives, pays expenses, good tillage will pa] n comparison to the slight added i Pages i:; 17. i e has shown mulching to be a fairl\ wing potatoes on a small scale. A llv increased the yield over tha si eiiliivaiii.il. The quality of the e\i-e|ii under rery wet conditions. T mulch have been better for practicable only when the mulch ined very cheaply. Tin reater than the cos* of good cnltiva - il can be used for a mulch. Old hay We litter, can be used if free from mulch should be about four inches us! before the plants appear, the urowed onee or twiee after plant- give better results than small mulched, since they give the ired to force their way up thru the hould be planted l wo or three inches vationa by GO jht cent, gether w» \* by is indies </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 RECOMMENDATION* The following monimeiidalions are btaed ■{ periments reported in this bulletin: Ivcr use poor seed. Try under a litter mulch. 1 and unaprouted. It th formalin before plantin iou of one-half pint of I rowiug your seed \ lit only tubers that all Hcabb j, by soaking it two h •rinaliu in 15 gallons In eastern Nebraska, plan quarter tubers, about one h medium-sized seed in rows tlia buahela of seed per an B spare the land ib j; and harrow we lour inches deep and rid To clean tile Weeds I it- or two harrowing the ground. Alter I ice as needed, be fort I'd by the harrow. I a small -shovel eultivatoi St ir the surface soil alt ■en rains ;is is necessaiv This is cheaper and bet oe after they gel nicely i tat I grow potatoes by nnih and plant the seed as r •ed can be planted an in need not be ridged up eet apart. Harrow the nine, pr&lt; lllielld ll or so s||;| .Mat ovel round wen Is Eines crusted alter a rain. Spread the litter deep almost any time before the plants be§ ground. Dte old bay. straw, stable litter, &lt; arse material free from grain and bad weed Is enough apart for conveniei </seg>
        
            <seg id="p027">STATION AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD CARI. I. ERN BII A l\ CAI KIN l.l.K.N, Li wm. &lt;;. win i 1 REDERICK \ K TOR G. LI THE STATION OFFICERS K. A. Bl KM &gt;.\l IS WM. \V. M \Ks THE WORKING STAFF II. R. Smi i ii. I \ 1 l'i Kbf.df.kick 1). Ufa F. I. Ai wav, l'i \. L. HAECKEB, : I \\\ KIM 1 Bki NFK. I \IiiS rGOMEKV, 1 I ■ . ( .. M ii i i k EBWIN II liAKBi (', K CH \ I HI KN. A.M., // / Is A Emekson, B.Sc., Hortiatllui X . V. Stout, C.E., Irrigation I ( , A Lovi land, B-Sc., Mi Alvin Kkvsek. A.M.. \ \\ . I'. SnVDEK, MS, SuficinitttiJtiit I B. Maudan/, Jr., A.B , Assistant; . Sti"R»evant. A.M., Assistant rti Ah Martin Nelson, MS, Assistant in I F. E. Denny, A.B., Assistant in Horticulture S. W. Perin, Farm Superintendent I II Gain, M.D.I te in A </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>