<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00002.00013">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00002.00013</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FIFTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL FOR JUVENILE OFFENDERS, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA. FOR THE TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1890. OMAHA, NEB.: HENRY GIBSON, PUBLIC PRINTER. 1890. </title>
               <date value="1890">1890</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-29</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2007-03-27</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>Thomas J. Wattenbarger</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item> 
         </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
s 

UPERINTENDENT 

STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL 

'NILE OFFENDERS 
KEARNEY. NEBRASKA, 

Years ending November 30, 1^90. 

¦ &gt;m mi \ 

V !•( Ill !¦ I'KIM I 1 </seg>


            <seg id="p003">
Superintendent. 

\ ssistant Superintendent. 

Physician. 

Chaplain. 

Family Managers 
and 

Bookkeeper. 

Matron. 

Assistant Teacher. 

Housekeepers. 



Seamstress 

Laundress. 

Roys' Dining-room 

• iirls" Dining-rooru 

Engineer 

First Assistant Engineer, 

Fireman 



shoemaker 

( rardener, 

Farmer 

Musician and Printer, 
Charge &lt;»f Work Force 
Charge of Work Force 

Night Watchman 

Teachers. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
[ Public Lands and Buildings. Lincoln, 

II 

k;i 

N In accordance with the requirements of the 
t the State of Nebraska, I submit for your confifth 
biennial report of the State Industrial 
enile &lt; &gt;ff»'iider&gt;. located at Kearney. Nebraska, 
us ending November 80, 1890, also an inrentory 

E M V. 

ll 

\ 

nal property belonging to the institution. 
Respectfully submitted. 

John T. Mai.i.ai.iki'. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
I 

)i:S( U1PTIVK. 

lea from the depots. The Electric Street 
riding its line to the southeast corner of 

ii 

\ 

to have it completed early next spring, 
liool in direct and convenient connection 

V 

lepots and the city. The farm contains 3 iO acres, 

lapted for agricultural purposes. The 

i 

•s the lower part of the ground, forming 
ile of small lakes. The land situated 
!&gt;&lt;• irrigated and the beneficial effects 
tliis season. Owing to the extreme dry 
• &gt;n]y about one-sixth of a yield except 
be used. Some crops were an entire 

I 

I 

uprise the main building, which is used 
and culinary purposes, and is also the 
Ther.' are also live family buildings or 
arge work-shop, a boiler-house, a vegebarn 
and other out-buildings. All the 
liarn and out buildings are constructed of 

v 

\ 


rial Htehool is located west of Kearney 

iv heated from one steam-plant. A main 

iches in diameter is connected with all 

n&gt; ¦ 'I' lateral pipes. 

gh bluff, thf Rchool lias a commanding 

Inn; country, ami is also a remarkably 

evidenced by the small mortality rate. 

celleni drainage. 

THE FARM. 

"t 320 acres, the greater part of which can 

urincinallv lihiff land and i-- &lt;-ut ini by</seg> 

            <seg id="p008">
\ 

i&gt; 

t 

i 


i 

¦al small ravines. There are about 18 acres below n 
ley canal which can be irrigated. That portion of tl 
situated on the edge of the bluffs is poor and butslighi 

Sictive. The remainder of 
on the farm and we hav&lt; 
sh rough food for stork, 
il has been fortunate, ami 
year at an average cost i 
t to be at least 80 acr&lt; 
ging to the school, as the 

it is fertile. There is no hs 
to depend on leasing land 
In this respect, however, tl 

jood hay land has been securt 
f one dollar per acre. Thei 

-s ..f Platte Valley hay lai 
time is drawing near when 

will be impossible to lease. The products "f the farm consi 

principally of vegetables and -rain tor the stock. At' 

rving pasture html, grounds for buildings, lawn ami 

and sowing and planting oate and com. i1 requires all I 

food for the stock. In the past the cattl 

grades. 1 would suggest thai th« 

common stock and purchasing bio 

them more for milking qualities than 

a scrub, it would be economical in the end 1 

IMPRO\ E.UEXTS 

The improvements during the past two years ha\ 

greatly to the comfort, convenience and general appearan 

of the institution. The grounds have been partly graded 

l-ast as far as the means would permit it. While this is 

expensive part of the institution, yet it i~ one which sho 

not be neglected. There is nothing in which children « 

take more interest than to see the home surroundings beau 

358 


and. as it costs no more to keep a flrei 

remainder for vegetables. It is the aim 

that are consul 1 by our populatio 

years, however, have not brought su 

?ear there was aboul a third 

weather and earlv frost. This 

raised, outside nf tli.' Its acres in 

hence we are obliged t'&gt; purchase 



! 

t 



» 

I 




.i </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
iii'l hence those here look upon the improvements on the 
ids, the planting of flowers, the fixing up of lawns and 

per arrangements &lt;&gt;f drives and walks with a great 
pride. The grounds have been seeded down in places, 

in- well where water eould be used. However, 

ison there was great difficulty on account of 

aving a Miftieient supply of water to meet the requires 
in tiii- direction. This supply was greatly increased 

he J ear, but not of a sufficient amount to meet the de:or 
all purposes. Every effort to procure water near 

ii;» and "ii the hill has proven fruitless. After 
¦iiil wells, one of which was to the depth of 480 feet, 

i of getting water near the buildings was abandoned, 
termaneni water-plant in the valley was decided upon. 

ed. While this meets the demand for purely do- 

ur poses, yel it is not of sufficient capacity to answer 
f fire or for sprinkling the lawns. A storage tank with 

of l .ooo barrels lias been erected. There is needed, 
i large double-cylinder steam-pump in addition to 
w used, so that in case of fire there would be no 

r- mi account of a lack of power or of water. 

water-plant consists of a small frame boiler-house and 
high-pressure boiler, a single-cylinder pump 

iws tlie water through three-inch drive-well pipes. 
r is then forced through a four-inch pipe to the tank, 

which place it is distributed to the several buildings and 
• the tire and water hydrants about the grounds. For 

r fire protection small stand-pipes have been placed in 
one of the buildings, and on each floor there is a piece of 

with a nozzle attached to be used in an emergency. The 
ivdrants are also distributed about the grounds in places 
enieni for use in case of fire. Inasmuch as the state 

iea no insurance whatever on the public buildings, it is 
lutely necessary that all possible fire protection be 
•anteed to the heads of the institutions. It is for this rea- 

359 </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
360 

sou that I ask an ;i 

tf mi in ease a ri 

it « 

can be started a 

! 

iecessarv tliat 

! 

hi 


,.,1..,1 


\ 

t Ililt 1 in 



in in. 

¦•iiiircii 

|)|irin-- thi 

provemi'iil in our st&lt; 

Km. in in our st&lt; 
oa I house e&lt; mil 

and • ¦ i &gt; ; 1 1 In »use c&lt; &gt;mb 


and iif't\- six feel wi&lt; le. 

tftv six feel wide, 
iler-room pro|&gt;ei 
al-house twenty 
ity of ahiKit scv 
are five two-sh&lt; 

rlic boiler-room projx 

the coal-house twenty !• 

capacity of about sevei 

i 

there are live two-shetM ste' 

ran nil be used ;it one tim&lt; 

can all l&gt;e uscil at one timi 

ently, or any two or more j 

arc supplied with the &lt; ulvi 

burning slack coal Th 

re 1 1 ji — 

tial smokestack, the toj 

»f u 

above the prates of the boilers 

.in 

uf about five feet. It i 

ltt&gt; In as 

best steam i.kuits t&lt;i lie f 

unil an\ 

\ 

available modern impnv nu'iit wa 

order that we might tret an eco 

down to the verv low </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
II 

361 

V 

;iilv &gt;killM. and tlii- 

niii.in 

and the entire plant 

iiifii. Provis 

lo for putt iniraurood. substantial stone 

heavy iron plates in front of the 

shot ashes. While this is not an abso- 

I add very materially to t lie comfort. 

the toilers for heating purposes through 
then distributed to the buildings through 

• steam pipes are all placed in a tunnel. 
ich building. The tunnel is four feet wide, 
d lias a total length, including laterals, of 

ii 

Ired feet, and is bo arranged«that in ease of any 

ige in the steam-pipe or hot-water pipe a 
nd work to advantage in repairing it. This 

ika 

(d improvement over the old system, where 
in trenches, and whenever a l&gt;reakage or 

I 

i was necessary to di^j the ground up for a 
irder to locate the defect. It is also a saving 

I 

i 

that the pipes heretofore were so near 

ground as to be affected by climatic changes, 
swer the purpose without being bricked up, 

t this should be done. It may stand fo r 

¦vithout brickinur, vet for safetv this should 

I think if the proper appropriation is made 
services of an experienced workman and 
that the bricks could all be made on the 

toys could assist not only in making them 
them in the tunnel, paving the walks and 
uld require the use of brick. In this way a 
1 be learning something useful, and at the 
Id be a decided saving to the state. 

vin 

A 

1 

woul 

W.- now hav 

a. large work-shop, and when it is furnished 
he most useful adjuncts to the school. The </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
l&gt;jK';irance of the boiler-house. The 


362 

LAN D ' i'.\l.Mi!**&gt;?&gt;iO^t,rk N KKrOKT. 

main part &lt;&gt;f the work-shop, or the new part which ! 


recently built, is eighty-six feet in depth and tin 

xtrei 

length of the entire structure, including the two sma 

11 w 

heretofore erected, is 144 feet. The main part consi 

t 

basement, three stories and an attic, ami is therefore, for 

practical purposes, a five-story building 

( )wing to the fact that the last legislature did not deei 

prudent to make an appropriation for a dining-h 

1 

i 

kitchen, it became necessary that some arrangement 

i 

be made, consequently some deviation was mad 

original plan of the work-shop, 80 that a portion of 

ment could be utilized for a kitchen ami bakerv, ai 

floor for a dining-hall for the boys and officers. Tl 

i 

or parts of floors, will he used for 

n 

! 

with next spring, and will probat 

turn. 

visions are made for an inde] 

¦orn 

after which time tin- rooms wi 

which they were intended, 

The portion of the basement i 

wing are placed the laundn 

plant and engines. The remainder 

for the ironing and drying-room of 

place for the band to practice. Tli 

ing is used by the gardener for hie worki 

ment and for the preserving and cur 

used at present. This is due to the fact 1 .ippi 

was not sufficient to purchase all the fun 

ippar 

material necessary for opening up new trade de] 


In it, however, is the tailor-shop ami shoe-sho] 

id 

on*- room set apart for the store-room of the institution. Tl 

building is a substantial brick structure and refl&lt; 


purposes is occupied by the engii 
i-""in and for steam-tittiny;. In 

Ides Only a portion &lt;&gt;f the remainder of </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
architect ami superintendent of construction, 
mil. one of .the teachers in the school. 
iat the legislature will make ample provision 

ii'l equipping the remaining rooms of this 
ler that the boya may have better opportuni- 

r themselves. It does not seem right that 
! fourteen and sixteen should be committed 

1 kept there for a term of two or three years 
ie advantages of learning a good, useful trade. 
"¦it unity is afforded while here they will g&gt;&gt; 

istitution at &gt;uch an age that no one will care to 
&gt; learn a trade, and hence the state ought to supply 
cy. There are many of the smaller boys who 

KM. Ml 

chool at a very suitable aye for commencing an 
hip, but the trade department should be used 
usiv.lv for boys more advanced in years, to whom 
Ktrtunitv in the future will not be afforded. 

( 

x 

1 

NEW BUILDINGS. 

i\ intention t&lt;&gt; ask the legislature for an appropriarge 
dining-hall and kitchen which we need, but, 
• low prices of farm products which prevailed the 

he scarcity of crops the present year, I consider 

i 

it the amount asked for to the very lowest mininse 
with si .me trade departments which I had 

tion, use ;i pari of the work-shop as indicated 
lining-room, and thus relieve the state of a bur- 

There are. however, some improvements 
be made. First, we have no adequate place for 

ices for the children. We have been using a 
work-shop temporarily, hut this must be aban¦mam 
weeks. We ought to have a comfortable 

t 

lie useo for chapel, literary and society purposes — 
rould accommodate four hundred persons. The 

t 


lii 

ild l&gt;e so arranged and furnished that it would 
double capacity of a chapel and public hall. It is 
I the school to have literary exercises during each 

wer tl 

¦¦-IUI1 

363 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
Bof the winter and early fcprin 
ing should be arranged with th 

Ill' 

Second, we nee 

house f&lt;&gt;r the water 
the same A- this 

Km- should 
d be tire-p 

There are 

large en 

the salan 

supply 

siirm-. .11 

nothing that ch&lt; 

nihlv like wi 

life cheerful and hi 

done. We have a sm 

after it. hence it is not ma nag 

Inasmuch as I have aimed to cul do 

the ensuing two years 

ver 

trust these items will not l&gt; 

\ 

lature will grant the request and maki 

-i 

cordingly. 

IK A IMS' 

It is the design of the institution 

common English education so far, at l&lt;3ast,as in- &gt; let em 

permit. For this purpose the pupils are •li\hle&lt;l in 

grades, four of which are for boys and two for girls, i 

average number in each grade is about 4.".. The inma 

attend school from four to five hours each day and f&lt; 

weeks in the year. They are supplied with books am 

364 </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
fmg should be arranged with t 
iapt'1 services on the Sablratli 
be Deeded. 

any &lt;»i&lt;' to look 

¦A good, 
ings. W 

ploye or iuniat&lt; 

to defray its own expen 


is are t . &gt;i 1 1 n 1 in a good district 

cess tn the library, in which are 
leir ages and conditions. The 

1- replenishing and al&gt;&lt;&gt; additional 

SI 17 44 4s 4H 
U 1(1 11 

11 :?7 47 1\ 

re detailed to work in the garden, on the lawns 
employment can be given. They compose what 

1 

aage of the school the " work force." 

n 

training has been carried on as far and as 

I 

u 

365 

IM 



V2 H7 44 l&gt; 4!l 
U 13 JH 

urnished with newspapers. The Kear- 

very generously donated during the 

ir publications to each &lt;&gt;f the grades, 

iteful. When the facilities will permit 

.veeklj literary exercises conducted by 

e of lectures. 

will show thf range &lt;&gt;f studies and the 

s are made. 

• LASSES IN KAi H K.\\lll.\ . 

/'. 

si 17 1» 1- I ¦ 

SI 17 44 4s 49 

M 47 i\ 4S 49 

II. &gt;. 

IS 

i 

I 

1 

H 

7 

» 

H 

i 

is 

1 

i 

• 

1 1 

- 

1 

i 

.-&gt; 

i 

- 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
practical as the means would permit. All of the un 

t' ll'Ill 

K. underwear and caps are made by the inmate 
tent ion to increase the work in the tailor and sin 

a- -mm as the means fur purchasing i&lt;&gt;"ls. etc., wil 

B. Several new departments, such as printing, 
ing. brick-making, cabinet-making, telegraph 

i 

ography and typewriting are some of the possibiliti 

f u 1 1 1 n * 

specific person to look after them when their term of del 
here is ended. I have arranged a- a part of &lt; !haplain M 

duty for him to lonk up homes for those who hav 

or whose former homes were not of .1 nature to ju 

returning children to them. Tl 

k 

in a successful and gratifying ma 

the work to inculcate the prin 

citizenship at all time- and 1 

B-sl)o]i and on the play-gr&lt; 
he physical training is no 

} 

1 

offset for tin- confinement of 

The food and * I i * - 1 i- such as w 

almost continuously from time of 

own building or cottage in which are the school-room 

torv. play-room and clothes- roon 

irrangemeii 

rise to the distinctive family system, and the teachei 

t 

manager of the family is designated as the family mi 

ma 

The work is vastly different from that of the public 

I 

366 



Since mj lasi report the institution has h 

a resident chaplain. By this arrang 

lia&lt;l tht- privileg&lt; ifular Sabbath servic* 

'•;i-&lt;-s the work in the departnien 

time is given for out-door play an 

j£ular and is personally sup&lt; 

Tin* teachei or familj manag 

one lias charge of a grade or famih . am </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
ttasmuch as tlie former combines the work of the 
school and the physical training. He is obliged to 

luty from ten to eleven hours each day, and dur- 

1 days in each week, whereas the public school 
ly actively engaged six hours per day for live 

week. The managers work is also continuous 
itire year, with the exception of a vacation of 

MILITARY DRILL. 

the cast three years we have endeavored to give 
- some military training, and its good effect is readily 

Lodged. Many of the inmates who come here have a 
kward movement and careless appearance in general. 

iV 

to dei slop the hoy mentally, morally and physically 
many habits which he has acquired in each one of 

which have to be corrected, and there is nothing 
- to accomplish more in correcting these physical 

a good, systematic military training. Heretofore 
ent has been kept up without any expense what- 

te. The guns now in use are such as I have 
ig my own personal bond and obligation for 

ire and keeping and their proper return. The 
¦uction has been voluntarily given, first by one 

s and afterward by the engineer. The guns, 
which we use are very heavy, old-style and many 

is. It seems to me that it would be wise for the 
make a small appropriation in order to properly 

com] 'any with cadet rifles and such other accoutrel 
belong to a well-regulated military company. It 

i 

ii 

ot only be beneficial to the inmates, but would be a 
f just pride to the hundreds and thousands of visitors 

ir 

h 

me to the institution annually. 

Eac 

:h season we have a good band composed of the boys 
sould be used along and as a part of the military com- 

367 </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
paoy, and tin.-- training could be mn 

source u&lt; enjoymeni to the entin 

COMMITTMENT, hKTEXTMX *\ 

There seem 

pretation in reference :to the age ai \' 

i 

committed !•¦ the institution. The &gt;-, 

committed to the institution. Tl 

t 

the ¦¦ Legislature maj provide l&gt;\ lav 

a Bchool or schools for the safekee; 

a -dim.] or schools for the safekeeping, ed 

iiK-nl and reformation of all children 

iin-iit and reformai 

years, who, for wani i&gt;f propei 

years, who, for w 

are growing up in mendicancy and i 

this constitutional provision, t 

this constitutional 

established, and the maximum 

established, and the ir 

in 

he committed to the school w 

&gt;mmitted 

i- 

yean ago tin-; waa amended - 

years ago this was amend) 

here under the 

under the ajre of sixt&lt; 

mitted an offense under the i 

\ 

cepted until pasi the age of sixt&lt; 

-hi 1 ct&gt;nl&lt;l have the same advani 

she could have i he sa 

at the time of committing the offens 

at the time of committing the &lt;&gt;tf 

ever, have construed this to tneai 

ever, have construed this to mean 

liave committed an offense unde 

sent to the industrial school, wl 

sent to the industrial school, w 

the law is that they can onh In- 

the law is that they can only be 

providing the offense has been com 

]ir«iviiling the offense has been comm 
of sixteen. I think it would be a 

age of sixteen. I think it would be 

s.-oti.&gt;M so as to get rid of this indefinii 

formed from observation and experii 

age should not exceed sixteen. I ale 

should exercise all due diligence to as 

fenders and commit only such as arc .i p 

\ 

have had several commitments during 

v 

boys who were nineteen, twenty and even twenty-on 

of age, and who took refuge under the law by stating 

that they were under the age of sixteen 01 eigl 

368 </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
I 



I hope there will he n&lt;&gt; 
lifficulty and requires a 

1 

[uestion which 
md also trouble 

ives rist to a great tleal 
in enforcing discipline. 

that a boy or girl shall be committed until 

!&lt;¦ age of twenty-one, unless sooner dis- 
It is not unfrequently the case that a judge 

•der of commitment " will tell a boy or girl that 

necessary to remain in the school for a few 
specifying five or six months, hence an inmate 

with the expectation of getting out at the end of 
The rules established by the hoard in pursuance 
tes provide that when an inmate is received he 

led a certain number of demerits proportionate 
committed. For eabh day that lie conducts 

r 

perly he shall cancel ten of these demerits, and it 
tirely upon a boy's conduct as to when lie will be 

i leave of absence. This varies in cases of fifteen 
to three years or more. An inmate often gets it 

it regardless of liis standing here he can leave 
gnated by the judge. Not only is this incon- 

trimeni to the boy, but the parents also, at the 

time, expect the child home, and if he is not 
uently the rase that I receive impertinent letters 

something which I had no authority to do. I 
sought to be specific in ail these matters and 

iii enforcing discipline and carrying out the 
school. 

neral discipline of the institution during the past two 
been satisfactory. There have been times of severe 
iti'&gt;u&gt; discouragements and worrying, but the bright 

tution life has in general been the uppermost. It is 
lerelop the faculties of mind and heart through kind- 

I 

esome advice. Many cases yield to this method 

I IX 1 W 

369 

lisciplini 


II 

n 

\ 

n 

I 

i» 


i 

i 

i 

i 

i 

v </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
of treatment, hut there are others whose sense of appreeiati 

seem entirely lost. They misconstrue kindness for condescc 

I and a compromise on the part of the management. Tta 
ine that fear is the controlling motive. Such ditporitio 
obstinate natures must be overcome — gently if p 
bly if necessary — or the general good of the instituti 
rs. Every method of kind, parental discipline is resort 

Bid corporeal punishment at last when all others 
tever may be the theory of the strict advocates of 

elusive moral suasion in public schools, it lias its excep 

when it comes in contact with the depravity, degeneracy 

lascivious natures of many who fail to , mi Hot forgovernm 

restraint and reformation. Such an exception becom 
sary. not only for the restraining for the individual him 

hut also for the protection of those who are dispose 

i.M-cd ti 

from pure motives 

An institution is a rnicr 

made and enforced, not &gt;&gt;i 

member, but also for the pi 

i 

v foi 

¦teCtloll Of 

It is our aim to enforce these laws 

be but one controlling element, and th 

deteriorates. 

I&gt;]\ [SION OF SCHl 

Two years ago I desired to recomn 
i &gt;f a girls' industrial school. It was. ! 

the board that it would be advisable to wail until the mini! 
of girls had become sufficiently large to justify tin divisi&lt; 
That time has now come. The girls need different envin 
ments, more varied sources of amusement, different industii 
physical and mental training, different discipline, differ* 
sanitary care, and different management in general. In 
mixed school they must be circumscribed within too narn 

370 
possible, 1 mt they must be resp&lt; 

in charge, assisted by the hearty cQrop 

officers. Otherwise tin- institution suff&lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
1'J limits. It is the history of all states that 
work j&gt; cot advisable, and nearly all have sep- 

"&gt;N. The superintendents of those who have 
forward to this desired end. We now have 

e boys would also have better opportunities. 
nt system the school-rooms for the boys are 

h buildings. The different family principals are 
plicating to a large extent each other's work. If 
ated the main building it could be used (in ad- 

to "trices. Library, etc.). as a graded school building. 
fficieni work would thus be done, inasmuch as the in- 

¦oulil be classified and graded, and a regular course of 
tion from the primary to the high school department 

. adopted and carried out. This matter of dividing the 
and placing the girls in a separate institution cannot 
¦il too strongly. No one except those who have had the 
(nee can imagine the embarrassments and drawbacks 

b 

with a mixed school. While the sexes are kept 
•t their thoughts are induced in an improper chan- 

h&gt;advantageous effects of a mixed school are very 
after the girls leave the institution. If a boy sees a 
i- lie.. n in the school he is liable to call attention to 
i'l from that time her difficulties begin. No matter 
lie has been doing, or how hard she has been trying 

er identity, the finger of contempt ami scorn is 
r by unmerciful beings. In a separate institution 

hi be none of this contingent embarrassment. For 

al good of the institution, and for tlie general good 
3 s and girls individually and collectively, both while 

ndance ami after being paroled, I hope the legislature 
insider the matter in a favorable light and establish a 
for girls. Unless this is done it will be necessary to 
appropriations for new buildings for their accommodate. 
I do not consider that this would be a wise move, 

i 

A 

ti.m I 

371 </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
Sot &lt;&gt;nly would they be unquestionably 


as the separation would have to a 

expense of putting uj&gt; new building 

be better applied toward the build 

i 

is just riirlit. E 

ward [rirls an 

ilnn't wai 

It ma 

that such ai 

mittfil some criminal offe 

to the industrial sch 

n 

there should lit- a place of detentio 

physically, also a place when 

could be taught. The methods of ai 

meet the requirements of such an in 

has to deal with immature and yoi 

those of a more responsible natur 

between the ages of 8 and 16 requii 

ferent from that of youths and young men between tin 

t 

16 and 25. A great injustice has been dom to our work 

courts permitting young men, even a 21, t&lt; 

their age within the limit prescril 

Hlltt 

372 

•K 




lependent girls' reformat) 

the present sch 

Superintendent ( 'li;i 

me ;is f. . 

like we ha\ 
!&gt;&lt;• injurioui 

Bol ;tn ml 
nee of tin 

Bf young ] 
fht before rl 

penitentiary with hardei 

should be a place of impi </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
373 
r 

ii'- in keep them out of the peniten 
at injustice on us. as such char 

have resorted to extra- judicial 
pect for law, either in '&gt;r out 

inn of judges as a travesty 

f such a character is more tr&lt; &gt;nl .!? 

Che good results obtained thereby have 

:. The intermediate reformatory work has 

stage, and its usefulness has be' n 

I'd. It is one of the coming permanent instate, 
and Nebraska should nut lie the last to 

VI. REMARKS ON KKFOHMATOin WoKk. 

improper to give an outline &lt;&gt;f the general 
ide of reformatory work, inasmuch as great 

been made in behalf of juvenile delinquents in 
ears. From the English workhouse, the n 

with their many conveniences and advan- 

evolved through various successive stages. 
n going on at a constantly increasing ratio. 

t 

in small porringer of gruel repeated each meal. 
iv. and one onion twice a week (except when the 

! 

lilosophical men who constituted the parochial 
1 ttii' "workug" on holiday occasions, at which 

l 1 

and a quarter ounces of bread were given as a 
nstead of this weak gruel diet we find the tables of 

lie t\V 

reformatories supplied with such wholesome food 

er the smaller inmates is iiMr&gt;- pernicious, 

• mi properly committed, and whoare 

emplated by the law. While tin- idea of 

blight of penitentiary life may be a 

¦ 1 should not -utTVr thereby. The 

establishment of an intermediate reforma- 

have realized the necessity of such an iu- 

made liberal appropriation for the estab- </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
as characterizes a good country home. The tattered 

irnic] 

K given place to neat-fitting and 
eds of straw on the rough, hard tli 
tidy cots, warm bedding and mi 
1 wire. The experimental phil&lt; 

attractive m 

i 

ive been 

tr 

..(' \\ 

t lie weakest possible food,"' and demonstrated the then 

niortalitv rate of eififhi out of ten 

obscurity, and the pra 

— the conirretrat 

evolved from tin- f&lt; &gt;rm 

future school will com 

a better system will be ina 

Our western states are alreadi 

are leading the pro 

t 

the good points in other sy 

1!)^ 

an institution is broad a 

i 

to take youth and tram 

\\ 

the institution must I 

child, laughing and playii 

ii 

under the fostering care of 

1 S&lt;-1 

vagrant, the incorrigible, the pi 

teacher it must give its pupils a f 

training. As a true statesman it 

the state and its laws and instruct 

government. As a master mechai 

i 

practical trades as will insure then 

disciplinarian it must embody all tl 

the school-room, society and the church, and noi on 

\ 

374 


woven wire. 1 ik- experimental philosopher who 
that a child could exist "ii the "smallest possible p 

efficacy "f bread, hcf ;n 

Rlii&gt; place, 
our count n 

teni lias its strong and w.;ik roba 

development. ' ' 

of a ministering agent it must pr&lt; &gt;vid&lt; </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
375 

I\I&gt;1 STRIAL SCHOOL. 

il&gt;o to remould some phases of it, and at the 
i guard for those outbreaks which seem inher- 

i 

iii) proportion of criminals who have been accusheming 
and conspiring. "All is not gold that 

her do the happy expressions of those under 
Beet a peaceful mind or kind heart. Back of 
luntenance may lurk a plan for " cussedness " 

ntricate nature. Hence the work is complicated, 
• I a' times discouraging. It taxes all the energies 
d and physique. It takes up the task where some 
d it down in weariness and dejection, and after 

» 

i 

i 

ii 

probably years of hope deferred a glimpse of 
ins to dawn. 

it-&lt;t in the galaxy of reformatory work is 
It is ttie center of this little universe around 

ise proximity, revolve many lesser stars, but all 
I'!, serve an equilibrium. It gives them warmth 

If it suffers an eclipse by some unaccountable 
•-ilium, they all suffer from a withdrawal of its 
building up the present it protects itself into the 

tlie pathway to honor and respectability. 
moral development may be regarded as the 
! imiple, yet educational, industrial and secular 

s close allies. It seems incongruous in this ad- 
Bed age, when public and private schools are so 

lucation so general, that the boy or girl should 

4&lt; of sixteen without learning to read or write in.in&lt;l 
in many .cases not evenNcnowing the alphabet. 

i 

if case. Even were schools limited, the other 
earning to read are so numerous (as evidenced 

isive publication and distribution of newspapers, 
and many gratuitous means for the diffusion of 
that it seems a* if home teaching should at least 
this much of a boy's- education. Nor is this lack 
ry instruction confined to any particular national- 

x 

1 

know 

pplement 

menta 


\ 


id ing .11 

A:i industrial sell 

K me training an 
1 education. ' 

bat is capable 

\ 

By autotna 
he next it 

• 1 citizen 

in m v mind v 

i 

is certain— that when an inst 

¦ &gt;ne in a thorough an&lt;l system 
tiuns there is a minimum 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
376 

¦ 

irenta 

itly develop* 

i 1 long enough, or to uiw- 

eii;ii'!.- him t" learn 

it- [tren 

f. and vi impel ;t ] 
even tli. mi 

in tlif line 

¦ in miii'l Bevera 
in&lt;4 t !"¦ patien 
al terms in suci 

1 'ii tin- rontrar 

Be 1 1 1 i 1 1 1 1 -• w ! 
ionable dej 
mniri' 

¦ducational trail 

tin a livelihood !&gt;v means 

Br. ¦ lierefore, be argued 
e educational. As tin 

elements for tin- advancerru 

r in point of importance 

Bie state, tht&gt; church, the tnunici] 
n&gt;. undertakes the t;i~-k of iml 


y 

H </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
377 

nil- in 1 1 l i — short time, henc© the 

ntcrs ;i trade de- 

n a li.iv 

I to remain in the school until 

jet a smattering during his term of 

1! 

. who, owing tn t lif untimely and unprenticeshiu 
system in our country, are 

mien "ii a meagre expenen 

difficult problem to solve is that of 
y&lt; nrli is brought here in many 

I 

failure of home government. He is 
iates of the same nature. Discipline 

the school suffers. Various methods 
ven corporeal punishment when others 
ubordination in a large family may de- 

I 

f the institution. Hence, when kind and 

Is fail to have the desired effect, more 

must he pursued. Moral suasion may 
is. l&gt;ut there are exceptions to all rules. 

i 

stitution togovern its inmates by humane 
\i&gt;t by indulgence, which is an evil that 
parental control,*' Imt by giving each to 

! 

\ and requiring a strict performance 

¦&gt;! !i"in all classes of society. From 
re indulgence lias been mistaken for 
ailing eventually to have his desires 

irceny in order to replenish his purse 
of juvenile tramps, whose minds hav&lt; 

¦ trash literature of the 'lime novelist 
n-wrecking ami similar daring crimes 

Ik Iii- w.-i v uut in &gt;nt' &lt; &gt;r I w&lt; &gt; 

tilar position can be secured 

e &lt; .in ¦•&lt;&gt;ni[&gt;i&lt; i ti" tli&gt;' work began in the 

tnd join the already too li 

tture: from tli*- haunts &gt;&gt;t' miser </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
where criminal tendencies, in accordance with the law 
heredity, have been transmitted from sire to son, unti 
penal nature of the former has left its impress througl 
physical and moral degeneracy of the latter; from the h&lt; 
of the inebriate, where the intoxicating drink* have broke 
family ties, extinguished filial affection, and domestic hi 
ness has given place to starvation and crime: from the 
dens of iniquity which infest our social system, and whirl 
sapping the manhood and womanhood out of so many .. 
youths of the present day. 

,v 

I] 

1 

'PI 

i 

our lot for correction. Yet it seems strange that par 
have made a failure to raise on&lt; or two children 

li 

/ 

Such is the gravity of the work and 
bilities 

378 


Such an incongruous mass of disturbing elemei 

¦hould come to the sHiool and wain to dictai 270 - 

270 

be managed. 

The secular training 

ilar 1 mean the training whi 

order. .Many boys commitl 

mate law-breakers and iconoi 

devised around tli«- fireside hav&lt; 

tive habits. The laws 

•e well as of the stat.- have beei 

teach them loyalty and thai laws ai 

good of mankind, and therefon 

absolute necessity. T&lt;&gt; bring them ai 

ice that although the pasi may h;i \ 
with many shortcomings, yet the 

of usefulness, is a grave undertaking. V\ hen pel 

the past, ambition fur the future, lo 1 ediei 

duty, regard for law and morality ,u-. ssfully im 

into their minds, then is the goal of an institution rea </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
HAPLAIKS REPORT. 

alieu. A. M.. Superintendent State Indus* 

Sib I have the honor to submit my report as 
State Industrial School for the term dating 

F 

89 

is time we have held stated religious services on 
r hich have grown in interest from the beginning, 
inter months we have given home talks to the 


1 1 w 

\v 

3 in their own buildings tnucWSng upon those 
mportance to the establishing of correct char- 

ilie 

ta 

ilcating the principles of true home life, and feel 
I rt-sults have followed such home talks. 

K( I HINi. HOMES. 

important feature of the chaplain's work is 
r the inmates going out of the school and 

occasion may require, in order to learn of 
ascertain if they are behaving themselves 

if if They are being treated in a proper 

having them in charge. The following 
visdom of your action in coupling this work 

V 1 

m\ 

.plain: I am real glad to tell you that I am 
y home first rate. Mr. M. treats me good and 

k 

good as she can be. Mr. M. gave me a dog, 
i ml 1 go to school when there is any." 

ii a boy whose parents died while he was in 
every citizen should be grateful that an 

A 

a^ luen made to secure homes for such. 
tter sent to me by a gentleman after I had, by 
ited the homes of one of the boys: 

\llot 

379 


NoveniberJW, 1890. inclusive . </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
"Dear Sik: Vour visil t&lt;&gt; was jusi 
lias l)i-a&lt;-t_ j 'l up and is ¦ 1 &lt; &gt; i m j^ nicely . K&lt; 

lias braced up and is doing nicel't . Keei 

lii*. work and \\\&gt; mother is very happ\ ." 

hi* work and his mother is very happ} 

i HAPEL. 

II.VI'KI 

There i- imperative need for .1 chapel for thi 

There i- imperative n 

committed to our care. With h school iA 275 persons, 

committed to our care. With a school iA 275 persons, h 

¦r 

plain to be seen that a suitable building is necessary, &gt; 
gious work ran !»• i-arried or nd 1 

, his work ran be ctirried on s ilh a 

\\ 

such a building can Ix il in the 
1 very heartilj eommeii 
religious and 11 

religious ,ii 


ray siiit ere _ 
il 

H 

I. M 

Hon T. 1. M 
I &gt;EAR v - 

Dear Sit 

¦ 
While uiv » 
r, an g tin 
recoveries and sustained gi ¦ 

While ii]\ w 

ainuuu l 

ception, rewarded my efforts. 
I!;ii 1 me death lias ¦ iccurrei 1—1 
. 1. who diei] in June, i s 
¦ da *inc ¦ the preci ¦! i n^ : .. 
d 1"' ulitai 1 regard , 
stronjfl^ I liseas. Ix 

n 

d). who diei] in June, i^ 

\l 

Ida sini 

fed 

n 

380 </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
io1 been bo uncommon as the youth of the in- 
I one to nuppose. At least four cases have 

hesides this fatal one, but all were improv 
the school. 

pneumonia have been treated, each one 
»very. 

iml .Iifly. 1889, we had an epidemic of 
-(¦-. Six were complicated with capillary 

which entirely recovered. The sixth one was 
-lit- left the school to go home, and I have no 
¦alth. 

n most fortunate as regards fevers, but few 
not of malignant tjpe. 

ts, roughs, colds and bowel disorders among 
male we have had the usual Dumber incident 
vouth. Much time is also devoted to diseases 

t 

most fortunate in the matter of accidents. 
¦xeepting case of drowning) was partial loss 

i\ Christine Worel, result of fingers being 
v machinery. There have been broken arms, 

I 

etc.. with uniform good results from 

1 operated on one of the boys for the cure of 
g standing. The operation was a perfect 

ii 

I VI. REPORT FOR TWO YEARS. 

565 

•2,849 

1,534 

hank you and my co-laborers for the health 
the children, for your unvarying support and 

C. V Bastbn. M. D. 

381 


nor, mi\ tu r*-iiiani. 

Very resj»ectfully yours, 


I 

i 

.i 

\ </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
IFhe total amount appropriated by the last legislature for 
years ending March 31, 1891. was $188,977.06. The t&lt; 
lint asked for the two yean ending March 31, 1893 
,948.00, showing a net decrease in favor of the next hi 
period of $42,029.05. 

There has been no increase asked for in the item 

.1 

ployes" wages so far as individuals are concerned. The 

u\&lt;\ 

ent increase is due to the fact that more belp will lie n&lt; 

&gt;ded 

the girls' department, and also for teaching the trade 

wl 

it is designed t&lt;&gt; establish 

The basis for which the appropriation tor living 

Kand kitchen expense is asked is 16 cents per diem I 
idual. This amount is expected to furnish the table, si 
1 dining and kitchen furniture, tableware, kitchen utensi 

As the state carries no insurance on the buildings, 
comes obligatory that all possible precaution should be 


to protect the property in case of tin-. It would cos 
$8,600 to insure the buildings for the next two years. 1 ha 

asked for $2,850 to extend the water supply and give fir 

1 

382 

APPROPRIATIONS. 

tablf linen — in short, t'&gt; supply everything tba 

consumed in the dining-room and kitchen. 

The estimate for clothing eacfa inmate and 

1 »• -« 1 — . bedding, underwear, and in fan ev&lt; 

clothing, 'bedding and furniture, is 626 

individual. 

All the estimates have been figured 

¦irten&lt; with a proper management oi I 

additional items have been asked foi quipp 

department for extending industrial u 

department for military training of inmates, official u 

expenses &lt;&gt;f superintendent and chaplain w 

homes for. inmates and visiting those for whom horn 

l&gt;een secured, and for erecting such new . - a^ - 

l&gt;e an absolute necessity. </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
I 

ection, and which will serve all these purposes not only for 
••ars but for a term of years. 

he tunnel which was excavated for the steani-pipes will 
bricking and arching. It may stand for several years 
i may cave in at any time. Good judgment and wise 
&gt;m\ would suggest the advisability of attending to this 
&gt;ut much delay. An appropriation has therefore been 

for this purpose. 

i\ e asked appropriations as I believe them to be absolecessary. 
I have not inflated the amounts with the 

ation of having them cut down. The institution needs 
cent as estimated, and I hope the legislature will grant 

t Although the school will increase in numbers during 
tare, yet the contemplated appropriations have not been 
pondingly increased. 

There is one other matter which must be taken into considion, 
should the institution be divided and the girls 

Ba\\ ay, 1 would suggest that the superintendent and the 
of Public Lands and Buildings be authorized to transfer 

unused salary of the two lady teachers, the wages of the 
unstress and one cook, and a pro rata share of the living and 

aid bedding funds to the institution established for 

! 

also all clothing and bedding belonging to the girls 

"fluent 

ESTIMATES KOK THE ENSUINC TWO YEARS 

S,ilan«s toi the year ending March 31. 18'.f2 $ 10,800.00 

intemient per annum f2.uoo.00 

AsMitaut superintendent |&gt;er annum 1,200.00 

rinciral teachers ami family mannfters at $xon 

4,800.00 

per Himii 

soooo 

B k keener 

«00.t)0 

lain 

Matron 

600.00 

One assistant tcact 

tiOO.OO 

Salaries for vear ending U;u&lt; I 

$ 1O.S4HI DO 

383 </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
Employes' wages Engineer, assistant eni 
man, 1 aker, tanner. gardener, printer 
leanutreM, three cooks, three dlnini 
ployes, tive housekeeper*, two forem 
works -For year ending Man-h 31, 189; 

neer 

aundi 

For year ending March 31-, 1* 

K;, dining-roon and Idtcbeo expei 
an ending March SI, l «'.•:; . 
ch 

foi tw&lt; 

Ml 

Clothing, bedding and f 


endii 

Marcli 81. 1^ per annuna am 
Medical attendance, paint-, oils iuid 'I 

Blea for two yean ending Man 
bone, telegraph, railroad, fi 

V. 

Kpense for two years •¦mliiiL: Ma 
1 anil library supplii 

IK 

¦cntal rxpensf 
alld lighU 

Bepaira 

Band amusement 
uk, paving, -.i-w. 

pense 

Inrirasing water 
paratas 

BihingaDd p&lt;|uippinK ira.le de] 
|&gt;iujr military depal I 
1 traveling expenses., 
?ements- Chapel, lcehoi 

• 

Buse and oit buildings ami fun 
ng ami archiag I.SM feet of 4x' 
ency, fuel and lights, plu 

Total 

¦ appropriated by last legislai 
asked for ensuiii}; two years 

1" 

Total decrease 

l^l 

B471 buys and 149 girls commitb 
line period 281 boys and 67 girl? 
role, legal process, escap&lt; 

384 

MOVEMEN1 &lt;'l I 

Since the opening of tin- schtv 

n 

n 

¦ 

r 

n 

¦ 

1' 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
nnber over ninety per cent, have been paroled or discharged 
accordance with the rules of the institution. There have 
Km three deaths during the history of the school — one 
.1 two boys. The former, a colored girl, died of quick. 

tmption. &lt; toe of the boys died from injuries received 
&gt; trifling with a machine; the other was drowned while 

ing in one of the lakes. There are now in actual attend-188 
hoys and 81 girls, which, with six others for whom 
chool is directly responsible, makes a population of 275. 

Ihaa been about the average attendance for several 
The number of inmates has be&lt;&gt;n kept down on acof 
In imes having been secured for many whose term of 
lion lias expired. 

When a small boy is committed here and has no parents 
&gt;"k after him, it is our aim to secure him a good home in 
country as booh as possible. It is a credit to the school 

Kie demand for this class is larger than the supply. It is 
it because of the preliminary efforts to bring about this 
il. In marly every case where homes of this kind have 

trovided the children are doing well. It lias also been a 
¦ 
i that when parents are about to leave the state with 
ention of permanent settlement to allow them to take 

outh with them provided he or she has been doing reasonwt'li. 
By both of the foregoing means the attendance is 

he state is saved the expense of supporting a larger 
il the individuals are benefited. 

following statement of the condition of the inmates 
me of committal may be interesting: Sixty-one per 

of the l&gt;&lt;&gt;ys were idle, twenty-one per cent, were attendichool, 
and eighteen per cent, were at work. The statis- 

: the girls show that thirty-three per cent, were idle, 
.•n per cent, were at work, thirty-two per cent, were at 
;hool, and sixteen per cent, were simply staying at home, apirently 
doing nothing for themselves and very little for their 

385 </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
Of the large number who have been dismissed for good 
conduct, or for whom proper homes have been found, it is safe 
to assert that eight out of every ten are doing well. Many of 
them are holding responsible positions, and have proved loyal 
to their trust. 

Ouming 

Cheyenne 

Custer 

Dawes. 

Dundy 

Dawsou 

DiXOD. 

Dodge 

Douglas 

Filimore . 

Furnas. 

Franklin 

Frontier 

Gage. 

ti 

Greeley 

Harlan 

Holt. 

¦i 

Hail IT 7 

Hamilton 

.t 

Hitchcock 

i) 

Howard. 

4 t 

Jefferson . 


Johnson 4 3 

Kimball. 

2 I! ' 

Keith 3 | i 

386 



(&gt; 

\j\JSXKtMX A l.r*U D A \.\J VIH A i-1-.O- 

Counties. 

Hoys. Will 

I o 3 

Buffalo 
Butler 

27 U M 
I 3 S 

Cms 

•20 t M 

Cherry . . 

1 0 1 

Clay 
Colfax 

.-! : 

Cedar 

i i </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
387 

STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. 

ountles. Boy*. Girls. Total. 

Kearney 3 1* 

Lancaster 63 31 94 

Lincoln 9 0 9 

Loup 11* 

Madison a 0 5 

Merrick . 4 0 4 
Nance 1 0 1 

Nuekolla . 4 1 5 

Xemaha . ...." 8 2 10 

11 9 20 

1 0 1 

ii i is 

5 a t 

i 

5 0 5 
0 1 1 

Willow I) 1 1 

h.mlson. 13 2 IS 

rmaii 3 0 3 

• 0 6 

in- 

-•¦ward 7 2 9 

¦rpy 4 2 6 

Saunders .. 3 (t 3 

Thayei 3 2 5 

lev 5 1 6 

-ter 9 3 12 

lington 2 2 4 

rk 6 0 6 

all 471 149 620 

CONCLUSION. 

[&lt; is with feelings of deepest gratitude that I acknowledge 

many favors, the hearty support, the encouraging words 

and deeds of the board, both individually and collectively. 

' »ur pleasant association of the past two years will always be 

held in sacred remembrance. I am none the less thankful to 

• Jo\ ernor Thaver and other state officials for their courteous 

-tani-t 

To mv immediate associates, whether as officials or em- 

ployes, I am under special obligations. While there have 

been times when duties might have been more cheerfully and </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
thoroughly performed on the part of some, yet in general the 
work has been well done. In the midst of discouraging circumstances 
your kindness and friendship have been cheerfully 
manifested in my behalf. Your frequent expressions of 
interest in my welfare have been duly appreciated. I thank 
you, and hope that the future will be even more succea 
richer in its treasury (if good deeds, and more prolific of _ 
results in this large field of usefulness. By your earnest 
operation, your regard for the rules of the institution, your 
faithful performance of the duties belonging to your department 
and non-interference with others, your interest in I 

placed under your temporary control, and your loyal 
institution and its interests, the stair will have ca 
proud of the record which the school will make. 

Fraternally yo 

John T. Mai 

388 </seg>
         </p>

		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>