<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00042.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00042.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nineteenth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of the State Industrial School</title>
               <date value="1918">1918</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Nineteenth Biennial Report OF THE Superintendent OP THE State Industrial School KEARNEY, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions For the Biennium Ending November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">200 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTIONS R. V. Clark Superintendent F. S. Wallace Assistant Superintendent Dae C. Lantz Steward EMPLOYEES G. W. D. Twymax Company Manager G. W. Cappers Company Manager W. A. ESTE8 Company Manager G. A. Luther Company Manager J. H. Geer Company Manager Is abei.l Estes Teacher Nellie Christexsex Teacher C. N. Phillips Printer J. E. Engstrom Tailor M. Chri8texsex Laundry man William Ollen Shoemaker M. E. Scholze Engineer Frank Elias Assistant Engineer Rudolph Prikop Dairyman James Morgan Gardener A. Newcomb Forceman </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THK BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 201 STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL, KEARNEY, NEBRASKA To hi* Excellency, Uowmiblc Keith Neville, (lonrnor. and to the Honorable Members of the Board of Commix- missionern of State Institutions, llrnry Oerdes, Site* .4. Holcomb, and Eugene O. Mai/field, Gentlemen: It is an honor to be privileged to present to you the Nineteenth Biennial Report of the State Industrial School, located two miles west of the city of Kearney, Nebraska, which biennium closes with the 30th of November, 1918. The instruction given in this school is very similar to that given in the public schools throughout our state, up to and including the ninth grade. One large, well equipped room, in each of the five cottages provided for our boys, is used exclusively for educational work. Four of these rooms are devoted to the instruction of pupils in subjects common to the public schools of Nebraska. The fifth room is given up to the teaching of music, both band and orchestral. One-half of our school day is utilized in vocational instruction, and becomes, in fact, a trades school. The following trades are approached, if not mastered, in efficiency: Carpentering, Tailoring, Printing, Shoemaking, Painting, Laundering, Mechanics, Baking, and Cooking. The boys of this institution thus study the common school branches one-half of each school day, and study some trade or vocation the other half day. Time is economized, and the number of instructors reduced, by arranging to have fifty per cent of the boys study the trades in the morning, while the other fifty per cent of the boys pursue the common school branches. In the afternoon, the two groups of boys are precisely interchanged. Previous to this biennium, each teacher had been required to instruct in two or more grades each half day. In this school year, the school management, we believe, has been improved by inaugurating the plan, by means of which a teacher </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THIRD BIENN'IAL REPORT OF instructs but one grade in the morning, and another grade in the afternoon. This plan permits the teacher to devote a longer period of time to each subject taught each class or grade, thereby permitting the teacher to instruct more thoroughly in each subject of the course. The larger number of our teachers are men, three of them devoting their efforts to the graded school work, while one man is at the head of each of the seven industrial departments. Two women instruct in the graded school, while still two others instruct in the culinary arts. One man conducts the band and orchestra. Our band of twenty-six pieces has been the source of satisfaction and much pride to all those interested in the school. Trips with the band have been made to cities of the state, which trips afforded the boys a pleasant outing, and demonstrated to the people of a new district the sin - cere desire on the part of the authorities, controlling the affairs of the State Industrial School, to advance the boys in culture and refinement, to raise their ideals by training them to play skillfully the varied instruments, and to instill into them a desire and appreciation for the best and most classical music. Our well equipped carpenter shop is located on the second floor of our Trades Building. In this department the boys, under the guidance of an experienced tradesman, advance themselves into that efficiency which enables them to gain employment and earn a good wage when they depart from this school upon parole. This branch of our voca - tional work is a popular one among our boys, and the management is proud of more than one boy who has gone out into the world as a competent and skillful carpenter. Not only to the boys of the carpenter detail are the work and instruction helpful, but also to the institution as a physical plant, because in this department the institution's furniture has been repaired, cupboards and wardrobes have been made, mangers for the horses built, and window frames for the dairy constructed. The boys of this detail have rebuilt the east wall of the boiler house, and placed a new roof thereon. An oak stairway has replaced, in the </seg>
            <seg id="p005">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 203 Administration building, the old and weakened one; while the appearance of the Trades building has been much im- proved by two good porches, — one in front of the laundry and one in front of the painting department. The car- penters, in their department, accomplished the following during the biennium: 11 of boil.T house $ 235.00 way in administration building 130.00 rolling doors for the dairy building 2 front porches on trades building 480.C f on boiler house 210.C Repairing farm implements, wagons, doors, locks, furniture, etc 1,526.73 S2.61C.73 Value of lumber, cement and hardware fur nished $1,123.09 Sa'.arv of instructor :tr.4..s4 .077.93 Value of department to the Institution $ 538.80 he Tailoring Department offers one of the choicest of trades to the boys of this school. Here the boys learn, not by theory, but by actual practice, to cut, fit, and finish all the tailor-made garments worn by man or boy. Not only is this department valuable as a place of instruction, but the various garments, firmly and strongly made, prin- cipally by hand, are of much value to the Institution, be- cause they cost much less than those manufactured at a distance, and give much better and longer service. The following list of articles with their estimated value will de- monstrate clearly both the articles which are made by the boys of the school, and the value of these articles to the Institution : 590 Suits, uniform, citizen and band. @ $11.00 $6,490.00 1148 Overalls. @ 60 cents 688.80 1349 Shirts. @ 65 cents 876.85 27 Denim coats, (a $1.20 32.40 10 Duck suits. @ $1.90 lt.00 663 Sheets and pillow cases, (a 50 cents 331.50 497 Towels. @ 25 cents 124.25 766 Mittens, (a 7 cents 53.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">204 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF Printing is the art which preserves the history of the happenings of today for the teeming millions of the future. It is a pleasure to place a boy on this printing detail in our school, because one feels that the boy will learn a valuable trade, and at the same time absorb through the reading and printing of his daily work, much valuable knowledge. In addition to this, one is making it possible for a young man to take up a trade which is always prevalent, thereby mak - ing it possible for the paroled boy to gain employment promptly in any city of the United States, and to earn through that employment a good and satisfactory wage. Young men have left this school to enter at once, printing offices throughout the state, drawing a good salary, and affording themselves the best possibilities for advancement. Our printing office is modern and thoroughly equipped in every respect. A new modern cylinder press has been added to the equipment. Also a new job press, electrically driven, has very recently been installed. These additional equip - ments make it possible for the printing department to do more and better work than ever before. The volume of the work done in this department has been materially increased during this biennium. Besides printing multitudinous forms for the fifteen state institutions of Nebraska, this depart - ment circulates a weekly magazine known as the "Indus - trial School Times." By the following report of the work emanating from this department, you, gentlemen, will ob - serve the volume of the industry in our printing office dur - ing the last two years: 3378 Aprons. @ 60 cents . 226.80 Repairing, cleaning, pressing. . . 850.00 Total value of garments made. . . .$9,693.22 /alue of supplies furnished .. J5.333.37 ralue of supplies remaining . . . 410.00 4.923.37 Salary of instructor ...$1,209.05 rotal expense 6,132.42 /alue of department to institution $3,560.S0 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 205 STATE INDUSTRIAL SCHOOL. KEARNEY Commercial Co«t Coat Value &gt; Value of Gain to of Stock | of Stock of Stock i Finished Institution Purchased Used on Hand , Produeta Publication of weekly "Times and general School printing . $1932.91 $730.02 $1202.89 j $3305.53 $2575.51 Outside printing 962.02 962.02 2102.64 I 1140.62 Totals $2894.93 $1692.04 $1202.89 $5408.17 I $3716.18 We are pleased with the amount of work turned out by the shoemakers of this school. This department has been so efficient that the superintendent, after six years in his position, has yet to buy the first pair of shoes for any boy who has entered this school during the last three bienniums. The boys of this detail make both the every- day and Sunday shoes. Being made in our own shop, from good leather purchased from the wholesale houses, these shoes last our boys much longer than would the factory- made shoes. Several boys have become so proficient in their shoemaking ability that they are able to make a pair of shoes in one working day. This department serves a dual purpose inasmuch as it teaches its boys a trade by the practice of which they may earn an honorable living, and it also produces excellent and lasting shoes for the 200 boys who are almost constantly in this school. Please notice, as follows, the work with its value, which has been ac- complished by the State Industrial School shoemakers: 3385 Soles. Oi 45 cents : $1,523.25 4048 Heels, @ 15 cents 607.20 2918 Patches, @ 15 cents 437.70 279 Pairs work shoes, @ $4.50 1.255.50 257 Pairs Sunday-shoes, @ $6.00 1,542.00 Repairing of harness, footballs, basket- balls, belts, mitts, music rack cases gloves, etc 206.65 Total $5,572.J0 Value of supplies furnished $3,475.17 Value of supplies remaining 1,993.96 Value of supplies utilized 1,481.21 Salary of instructor 1,243.69 2.724.90 Value of department to institution . $2,847.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">III- •HIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF During this biennium, the department of painting has jeen in active operation only twelve out of the twenty-four nonths, for the reason that labor has been so high in srice and painters so scarce in number. This is an essential lepartment of the school activities which will soon resume ts duties. The boys of this detail paint and decorate the various interiors and exteriors of the school buildings. The ioys who become painters learn a trade which will in later ife permit them to demand a living wage. Our laundry has been wonderfully improved and mod - ernized. We are indeed proud of the following additional equipment which has recently been installed: One large drying tumbler, with woven wire cylinder and elevated header, costing ! L.bbl.UU One tilting type neck band press and cuff press, cos inir :»3.iu One steam collar ironer. c ig ."i i One bosom press, co. u».*u Tntal fI.Ml.ZI We are, indeed, pleased to be able to state that the equipment in our laundry is absolutely complete in every detail, so that the boys working therein may go into the best laundry in the largest city and fittingly apply their labor and demand the wages of the skilled tradesman. In the addition of modern equipment during the biennium this department of our school stands first. The world war has created an extreme demand for the man who is skillful in any branch of mechanics. In the machine shop and boiler room of the State Industrial School, facilities are offered the boys to practice, by actual constructive work, many branches of mechanics, which will demand for their efficiency, high wages in the outside world after their parole from this school. The boys handle three large boilers; clean flues; repair valves, pumps, and stearc lines; cut and fit pipes; do lathe work; and perfect them - selves for later industrial activities. An able engineer oi wide experience directs and controls the labors of the engi - neering department. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 207 During but twelve months of the present biennium, the bakery made it possible for the boys and employees of the school to enjoy the following: 18,000 biscuits, 28,139 loaves white bread, 29,042 loaves bran bread, 480 loaves whole wheat bread, 520 cakes (six # each), 15,600 cookies, 11,700 doughnuts, 1,223 pies and 39,146 rolls. During the world war, bakers have been in extreme demand. The above list of productions will make it clear to any reader that this department teaches the boys therein to become expert bakers, and thus amply affords them num - erous opportunities in the outside world to demand for themselves good salaries. The culinary departments of this institution are two. One kitchen is located in the Trades building, just below the spacious dining room for the boys. The officers' kitchen is in the northeast portion of the basement of the Adminis - tration building. In each of tnes&gt;^ kitchens, the boys, as apprentices- learn through daily experiences, the art of cooking. Especially helpful to the colored boys is the cook - ing art, because throughout the United States, colored men are quite generally employed as cooks. At the present time in the largest and most modern kitchen of the city of Omaha, are boys who learned the culinary art in the State Industrial School. This institution, through the resourcefulness of the dairy, the industry and good management of those em - ployed in the officers' kitchen, has made during this bien - nium, 10,408 pounds of butter. The institution possesses twenty-six good horses which are carefully sheltered in a fine, large, brick barn. The boys of this school who handle the horses are spoken of as teamsters. They enjoy the work and pride themselves in the care, cleaning and driving of the horses. Their experi - ence on the farm and on the road with the teams tends to perfect them in the handling of horses. Holstein cows, to the number of forty-two, compose the excellent dairy herd of this school. The advantages thus afforded by way of milk to drink for the boys, cream and butter for table use, cannot be over appreciated. An ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">208 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF cellent, experienced, and well-posted dairyman controls the activities of the dairy department, and teaches the boys of his detail the proper manner in which good cattle should be cared for and fed. The management is pleased to state that under the care of this department, the number of dairy cows has been doubled during the biennium. Com - mencing with twenty-one, we now possess forty-two Hol - stein cows. We now have 183 pure-bred Duroc Jersey Red hogs, after having sold, in the past twenty-four months, hogs to the amount of $9,141.10. We are proud of this record, and believe that you will coincide with this view. In addition to this financial record, the boys of this department learn thor - oughly how to care for, feed, fatten and market hogs. We are proud of the recent erection of a new and very modern piggery, 22 x 60 feet. This up-to-date structure is com - posed of glazed building blocks, is very convenient, and strictly modern. It is located just east of the dairy barn, and will be both an aid and incentive to the boys and man - agement in the raising of pigs. On the west side of the Administration building, on the first floor, is our spacious, well-lighted and well- ventilated library of 1,150 volumes. Encouraged as we are by the state librarian, our library is constantly supplied with a large number of good books, which are kept in good con - dition. Each Sunday, all the boys who wish come to the library for new books. These they take to their cottages that they may read them during the week when spare time presents itself. The records show that about ninety boys take books each week. Last October the state librarian caused to be furnished to our library, forty-three new and attractive volumes for the use of the boys. To all those directly connected with the school, the discipline is satisfactory and praiseworthy. The boys are obedient, polite and respectful, without that strained de - meanor which is the result of fear. The incentive for good conduct is the merit system in use in this school. By good behavior and industry, a boy earns more rapidly the merits, which, attained in proper number, permit him to be paroled. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 209 The boy's desire to be permitted to return home causes him to conduct himself like a gentleman. If, however, the merit system does not suffice, corporal punishment in extreme cases may be resorted to as a final measure when all other means fail to influence a boy to display his nobler manhood. By our merit system, one boy earned his parole in eight and one-half months. Disobedient, indolent and non-studious boys have been retained in the school eighteen and twenty months. The regular period required of a boy to remain in this school being seventeen months, we are pleased to state that a very large majority of the boys so conduct themselves that they leave at the expiration of twelve or fifteen months. The aim of this system being to instill into the mind of the boy the fact that his good behavior at this school determines his early parole, as his manliness in later life will determine his real success as a citizen of this republic. Constant endeavor is made by the officers and em - ployees of this school to influence the boys to lead pure lives. Their spiritual, welfare is, we trust, improved by means of regular Sunday school and chapel exercises. Each Sunday, the boys study and discuss the Sunday school les - sons as outlined by the "Junior Scholars Quarterly." The regular chapel exercises of the school are held in the third story of the Administration building at 3:00 o'clock each Sunday afternoon. Ministers of all church denominations are asked to address the boys at these services. We do this because we desire to respect the religious belief of any boy who may attend this school. We do not desire that any one denomination shall have preference over another denomina - tion. In other words, we wish the boys to have religious freedom, by means of these services persistently hold before the boys, high and noble ideals. The grandest improvement to the institution during the biennium has been the construction of an ideal $26,000.00 hospital, located between cottages "D" and "E" at the northern extremity of the school campus. Too much praise cannot be given to this magnificent building, which will be of valuable service to us in years to come in caring for the </seg>
            <seg id="p012">210 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF sick boys of the institution. Although but forty-one feet in width, forty-nine feet in length, and but two stories high, it is, I believe, the neatest and grandest little hospital build - ing in the state of Nebraska. Special pride is taken in this valuable structure for the reason that it has been con - structed and is to be paid for entirely from money which has been collected from the industries of the institution. No appropriation from the legislature was called for. It is, therefore, strictly and truly a State Industrial School hospital. The health of our boys has been carefully looked after by the institution physician, who visits the school every other morning, and oftener if his services are desired. Dur - ing the biennium, the doctor has made 4G1 visits to the school; has made 1,860 examinations; and has prescribed and prepared medicine in all necessary cases. All new boys have been given a physical and mental examination by the physician, who also learns from each new boy his family history. The sanitary condition of the school is excellent. One boy, Charles Tizor, by accident fractured two of the cervical vertebrae, was removed to his home in Omaha, and died eight days later. No other deaths occurred at the school. The boys in this school are encouraged to participate in healthful recreations, and popular sports; to skate upon the ice of the lake at the institution; to play lawn tennis, basketball, football and baseball. No school in the state is prouder of its boys as soldiers in the great world war than is this school. More than three score of our boys gave their services to their country, not only willingly but enthusiastically. Anxious to display their valor for the principles of humanity as outlined by this country, our boys stepped freely and patriotically into the ranks, ready to face any danger or meet any foe in the defense of home, liberty and country. Word is just re - ceived that one of our boys, while fighting bravely in the ranks at Argonne Woods, was killed in action. May God bless him and extend his patriotic influence to touch the hearts of young Americans everywhere. May we all realize </seg>
            <seg id="p013">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 211 that true patriotism is not confined to one class or faction; but that it wells up generously in the hearts of true Americans always and everywhere. It Is with pride that I ask your attention to the in - creased amount in the Institution Cash Fund at the close of each successive biennium for the last eight years: Cash on hand November 30, 1918 26,254.59 The sales of products and materials producing the above result will be itemized on a later page of this report. The reports of farm and garden products, which will be found later in this report, are sources of intense pride to the management of the school. More of our boys are em - ployed in the garden and on the farm than in any other department of the school. Our farm and garden, during this biennium, have produced crops whose values have amounted to the high figure of $51,000.00. Certainly these results, produced as they have been by the work and in - dustry of the boys and employees of this institution, will clearly impress upon the minds of these boys the important attention which should be given to the phrase "Back to the Farm." Gentlemen, will you not plan with me in the near future : To build a new dairy barn, modern and complete in every detail; To induce the Union Pacific Railroad Company to run a switch from their main line to the institution ; To construct, by means of an appropriation by the com - ing legislature, a large, modern, much-needed gymnasium building; To construct a new cellar for the storage of vegetables ; To provide means to conduct in a sanitary way, the sewage away from the institution; To add to the list of employees, one whose duties will require him to care for the interests of paroled boys; !"ash on hand November 30, 1912 [ 95.54 on hand November 30, 1914 4.577.20 on hand November 30, 1916 3Kn 58 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF To erect another cottage to accomodate properly the boys of this school? I desire to thank my conscientious and loyal co - workers, the judges of the courts, and the probation officers, who have encouraged and aided me in this important work with boys. Gentlemen of the Board, sincerely do I thank you for all assistance and encouragement you have generously given me; for the steadfastness of purpose, and marked ability displayed by you in supervising the management of the State Industrial School. Sincerely yours, K. V. Clakk, Superintendent. Kearney, Nebraska, November 30, 1918. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 213 STATEMENT OF THE DEBITS AND CREDITS AND BALANCE OF THE PUPILS 1 FUND December !, 1916. to December 1. 1918 Note— These are the personal funds of the pupils, held in trust by the Institution for these pupils, and received and expended for their sole individual benefit. Approximate average number of accounts December 1, 1916, to December 1, 1918, was 170 PERIOD Debits ' Credits Ledger credit balance on hand December 1. 1916, $198.12 December, 1916 . . January, 1917 February, 1917 March. 1917... April. 1917 May, 1917 June, 1917 July. 1917 J mi , a*" i i . . . August, 1917 September, 1917 October, 1917 November, 1917 Total for year Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 191 $298.59 Ledger credit balance on hand December 1, 1917, $298.59. December, 1917 January, 1918 February, 1918 March. 1918 April, 1918 May. 1918 June, 1918 July, 1918 August, 1918 September, 1918 October, 1918 November, 1918 Total for year Ledger credit balance on hand November 30, 1918, $463.23. Grand total for two yean 81.49 102.17 7i&gt;.i&gt;3 15O.5« 81.08 ■Ji ! 27 &gt;V 146.U M,.8M 21«.(&gt;(i 92.46 115.28 t 123.83 94.49 97.M 99.11 161.57 M9.32 123.43 116.28 133.91 161.31 94.2:! 1*7.64 13S2.67 \ t 1433.04 110.62 $ 150.88 MJt 77.08 71.28 58.11 74.48 1S4.51 75.32 1U3.80 118.70 108.87 M7.96 11741 85.95 116 18 85.17 81.51 101.92 140.52 112.99 72.46 60.04 55.60 11052.52 $ 1217.16 i 2385.09 $ 2650 .20 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">214 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF RECEIPTS CREDITED TO INSTITUTION CASH FUND December 1. 1916, to December 1, 1918 AMOUNTS RECEIVED GENERAL SOURCES Total Dec. 1. 1916 Dec. 1, 1917 Dec. 1, 1916 tn to Dec. 1, 1917 Dec. 1. 1918 Dec. 1. 1918 Alfalfa Band. ( 656 .32 $ 656.32 505.80 $ 155.94 661.74 Beets 3794.25 4645.69 8439.94 Blankets Butter 51.00 51.00 412.21 i 1041.90 i 1454.11 Cabbage Cane seed Cattl) ... 1.20 I 5.90 7.10 76.77 i 75.' 598.40 I 89.33 687.73 SSL 111.35 111.35 53.46 77.S0 131.36 3909.79 5231.31 9141.10 27.43 108.32 135.75 Iran (old) Mantel 340.87 99.48 440.35 25.00 25.00 M-als 285.54 300.95 586.49 Miscellaneous Onions 123.03 9.58 ! 132.61 8.50 244.32 252.82 Overpaid 19.61 19.61 Parole money refunded Potatoes 13.56 13.56 mmM 3480.63 9563.49 Poultry Printing Rags 34.80 i 34.80 974.70 I 974.70 24.05 36.73 i 60.78 Rent of land 42.00 42.00 Sacking potatoes Shoes 1309.33 1309.33 30.96 83.05 114.00 Time* 350.84 5.50 356.34 sr:r 146.80 i 52.20 199.00 330.03 j 1316.21 1646.27 Total t 17717.13 $ 19607.29 $ 37324.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 215 INVENTORY OF LANDS, BUILDINGS. FURNITURE. EQUIPMENT AND IMPROVE - MENTS AND ESTIMATED VALUE Acres Acres Cultivated Uncultivated ; Total Esti- Acre- mated Garden | Farm Orchard ! Campus Watte ! ate ! Value Land owned by institution . . 102 Land rented by institution 481 5 60 :! 602 (108120.00 (cash) Land rented by institution (share*) Total 102 4.12 5 CO i 3 i 802 J108120.00 ESTIMATED VALUE NAME OF BUILDING AND IMPROVEMENT Building Furniture Equipment \ Improvement, Total Administration building ' $ 40000.00 $ 5000.00 ! $ 1000.00 j S 46000.00 Barn, cow 2000.00 2000.00 4000.00 Barn, horse 5000.00 3600.00 8600.00 Boiler house 3000.00 12000.00 | 15000.00 150.00 Corn crib 150.00 Cottaf«"A" 20000.00 1525.00 21525.00 Cottage "B" 20000.00 1525.00 21525.00 Cottage "C" 20000.00 1525.00 21525.00 Cottage "D" . 20000.00 1525.00 21525.00 Cottage "E" ' 20000.00 1525.00 21525.00 Chicken houses (2) 1500.00 1500.00 Greenhouse 2000.00 2000.00 Ground improvements 100.00 16615.00 I 2150.00 | 18865.00 Hog houses (2) 500.00 500.00 Hospital 2*000.00 26000.00 Icehouse 1000.00 1000.00 Maehineshed 1500.00 3000.00 4500.00 Pump house 500.00 1500.00 2000.00 Root cellar 1500.00 350.00 1850.00 Shop building 40000.00 1650.00 10000.00 I I 51650.00 Slaughter house 150.00 150.00 1224800.00 $ 14375.00 * 50065.00 $ 2150.00 $ 291390.00 Total November 30, 1918 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">216 THIRL) BIENNIAL REPORT OF Sooo&gt;Aoooooo&lt;o^ot&lt;QQe«oooiaooooaie I *o si g ssrigs § nn gs 2 s 8 a- s «2i 2s g §1 £ 3, t iiij£i£ijj££iJjiiiiijj££iiij fS I =S58|SS228SSgSSSSS8Sg5S8S8SS S \"~ =| S — **3 ■ -8 2 2S 2 - . S8SSSSSg88Sa8fe8888 SSSSgg§§8 g 1 I HiSiiriSS- N g|-g«S |2-SS3|2S g •o - - •■ : " !s 2 I ■, | iiiUieiiiaaiiiiii iiUdiiii *5 8 : : ■ — — — — . I 2 - Mi i iU i \ \ \ ii :- : 99 3 3 J 'IS:- 1 ! $■ i s P I K ■ &lt; Z i;;ti J 1 |!i]jV-V-.---,:-"--.;- § I IS§Sa=^SS88SSSS888S iSSSggggg I 3 H nil \m\mm n S s «- m : — : liifciill l </seg>
            <seg id="p019">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 217 s_- — am 3 £ 3S £ i i-ei i ; : ; ;j 8 5 3 3*1 |i :i 3S5 . SgS§§SSSSSS3CSS§§§3 SSSSSgggS J( 3 eiocitst- : a-n6|P''Nnia*&gt;ontd ocxia-wo?;- w E ■? — *~ ~ x - 1 " — ?i cj ~o o 5 1 I :;:id 2 II e liiMi-i ii hi 5 5 a I (I j i ; :;| ii IS JH — 9 I IS -|3 5 CL !::::«:« :&gt;:; I 3i J7 g;: § I! Ml!" a a « 1 ; ; ; i t 3S- j ; ; S : : 1 2 s i i ii mm a. tills -I JslllJf iiillllllf IIJ£ \ !: I s iinaiaiiiaaiiuii iiiaaiiii * a I- s l -s " NN s' -5 s =8 2 I &gt; :: » a I £--■© ■* -« M» W-^ C4 NCI '. 2O I </seg>
            <seg id="p020">218 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF i _ I.ISSiSSi? ggggggg ggsgggggggljg I 3 88§2S t - -- N i-2l : MN I'S" K&lt;" 2 | .rj ; ___!! L* '&amp; i iiiiai iiisaii ■ iUiiUeii i S«5S»n ScccSSo cSSSSSSoSSS « "C_ 3 d^dnt-n lodfodae tfdd^ooddddcn oc •g «»^ — «t-— M «N . — « — m — K§ &gt; I - . 0&gt; •si s „ iSiiii Siiiiig siiSs |||U 5 2S99SS2 5SS22 S222S 7 3 pooootn iooiooo-'P moor^o cccco « £ 1*5 w — n -*n ■* r-NNrt-«o nnNNo x rt w u; cm — 1 U ; U B 5 I E S5i3SS 2222222 222S2222225 8| , H !l! - i : -Is*"; £3 n h :::::::::::::::::::::::::: ■ I : : :j i M ! : U^ ! ; ; : M ! i !| :| :^ I liililsiJllUlljillillilll !I§? ?a~ "-"•— w - &lt;l i r — i " g Jr a8 S| 8 ; ss §liIl: a22 ll 8 i|i s I •a s : r SSS 3 Is 1 1 853 -• i&lt;$ ; i us s |I; iii] 9 i ii : ; 58 : : : : :»| </seg>
            <seg id="p021">211 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS i . i gggSS : : : : : :g : :g : :gEg : :g :S S I" ! I ! ji jfii ; ; ; i ; ii ; ;i ; iii : *\i \ il ig-sss ; I * • : il 2 : 1 8 : K-|il : S : : : : : ; a : : : :|g : :5 : : I 2 I ■ - ■ I i ' - LigSSSSg :ggSS§§§ :ggS3gggggg|S ° 1 83258? sssssgg : ;g§ t -s3ss &lt;£&gt; ssi| , 1 I ; i~_ 2 \s\iiiiai iiiaaii ■ iiaiiiaaii\ \ | j | «3SS§3 :S28||g| :2S8S3818|S| : »• a E ; -8- :: - - = ' ! : = — i — a : — i i Hi • t' 1 !! ij § i s i U o a L^ , — 1 ijj]m;m;mmnmjm;j;|; "pjij irn---;;-: T T]" *| i ; \i ;* ; ii \ ] ;;;;;;;; : ;i : i if i 1 1 :;-;«;&gt;•;:; I!:! i i i i ::: a : I . . . . o o - m ■ ■ ■ •• - I g 1 — ' ' '. I* '. '. '■ '■ '■ '■ '■£ - - • - ■ •• • ■ ■ -9t ■ S — i ::::::^:^-; : ;i; : ;;;;;::i i o ::::::::::::::::::: : : : : : : : : 1 M UUnnii; H H M Mtiiy I 2 i!!l Hi Iff IMP til ill i '■ — - — = r~ </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT 220 m a 2 15 ss Is "ssii i. II if I iJ SiJil ; 5" I j co o-f on 1 g lj I .- §s H «5 1 ; 1, j s gg sisssis •s I I r: is iiiit ? - ;&gt; j 3 «* .,., ,lg *li| J il li li I I a S Is «§ -|| : i|! I £ N M M ji m r s r- S ■ °e— 58 ■z I j C : II 5 Hi? §i[: I S *, Hi f X M -S 21! ] 5 -jl . S gg SgggSlg 2 - 1 I 5 ai (a -x^doJ I ~ _- i| II s ss sss s sti « 15 s X-t£oi I N M n x &gt; M ; I ; iii lijii "1 si ; si : ii! !J:ii § a g:| : §§ 6g % *- J , Itooooooc J= S N ? £ f- i , L ; = §.S. S2ggS|5 I a. « ST ! S I w 52 ro?r« si I 2 I] J I 51 IgSSSig I I l! I ! iJ JJ;1U ; I I "ja I 5 £| i«8J 1 &lt; ■j. ■ ■ i 5 ?i ,;. I 5 gg gigggis * s i ||J 1 1 p i|hi|| l 5 3 3 15 2 N3&gt; "c;nnn ? ?i 1 [T1 J i! Si Ml ;! B I = 111 * I ! 5 18 g l ;*s ! ; | «2 I P x — , § . gg si .g.3|g I £ ■s- s 55 i |i si ssj 5 s- J ? ■j is I §S 5|S 35 ?■ {ill ilUlil; I S : §2 *S &gt;w * ' • * S S-nr- s -a -a n °t »: 5 « fc .3 ■ „• 5 I] jim^ijil h z ■ a § </seg>
            <seg id="p023">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 221 3C D C i , I . 8 8 88 8 :S : 8 SS I S 1« IS is d las o a : 6 3^ S |a 2 :a S si § s • I a 2i j « -I ■ ' - lJ[T ! 5 i! ! iiTl M| : gg ||| ;« 2 |8 8 |j 2 28 1 I I 38 8 88 8 S2S 8 -S\S •sjl! Si S SS | SSS S -S ff q|,| r ,,8 „, , ;S | | H SI £1 1 i! S SJ; ! : i| : a 1 1 3S - Sg 8 "I : S SI S| g — § ■ "I |fl!|ilM n_n*|j . ill 3: : : II I ii ; m I :|! I I s ! S 3 -I.I 8. 8 8.8. 8 828 8 8 I 2 2111 ;! ! JJ S U I ;J| III I :S "= S§ 8 "S : S S : H|S| °°- g — I ■ I 28 8 88 8 888. 8 88 I S? 1"S 1 ! SS S SS 8 SSS « SS S £ 3,1 S| STTsTsiTi u . ■g I S8 S. 8.8 8 §88 8 88 8 I | P - II 1 "= 8 * 2 5 3I |l s - . S il ! Si ! W ■ ~ §2 * 8 : - ~g ■ .2 . 8 ill 5 .8 1 2 ! j I I 5 .iTl Pi : t\ I : S§ £ GO — ;i : ! ! s ?1 ii|iiSitajisliiii| i* |fc £ So O Bl S CC-55 m ? iliiljs :- 8 SS : 8 S : j 8 § </seg>
            <seg id="p024">rHIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF |! P 2 q ". - i o * J5|?1E Knnii **|l|r « IS •o ! I«»M iiii i ill life l_ •**&lt; I I 2! *" i Sg i I i lw : ! : : 9 I : : I Mil ii » I : : ! I M i! !X9i ! | | I I I f C ! r~ 1 I i i 1 ■ j | J 2 Hi z: .IS3 I I &gt; mm ITTC" 1 i ii ,,|ij5! ft I* I if 2 1 1 2j I. 25 13 Si 1 L : t u i i ,u . H si iri 2t lr? S i i I 1 i " I C C I t •a j i I I s </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE BOARD OP COMMISSIONERS MS II si H il o Ji il I apie I 0 r _/|l!r s jl J illlJjul; i I OO«5 1 IO F •e I S I 55^; t-. o 1 llssa g l mi .... |N : ] : : : : | '.'.'. a. h : : : : -g Q : 1 § J : , ■ o : : : : a b : : : : 3 £ MM sj Mi i P i 1! ill ?! liPI ! I i I. IS :S IS I _ t a I « :-• Ih I ftl&gt;l» i 111 n ? * • • * «i |i 3 .ji . i 2 - •»_!.]§ :8 JS I 1 1 wlpf] 1 2 j 1S1 2 ■ g S - ! U. o l. -a "2 1i si^ ° 5 -■• |i5i|: S I I § I 1 .' „ J 1 I||s I* I ; ' i :M 1 3 Mil i s mi 1 1 ! &lt;"g I I m^-j — 1 ' * Pi - h </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF 1- I . SSSSgS 2 |o |zJ58S— £| : 1. ISSS8SS IS as ! I S82S8S ;'S ~3 ■ ooS 5f o «:■ f i »; i •* 1, t"5 iSl"l- « II ooio ooo en . OON Boo S *- I 3 | do* :n» I a II 'If ill . jSSggg § g 2 £ ass ■S HS2 '°!5 as s 22!? S I «? trglislSSS;:! 3 j?g|l|p;i»i s §§§S SIS 3 I rid-i—o ■a, 3iSS" &gt;e&lt;t - sl -Up &lt;*l|*hpr:»|: a I 'IP* i HI - 4 !i!I!l:5IiS =1 s^j-e«- ; - ; J 21 u ». | . I I I J::::::|l i t si O_ • • s • s iz- 2 ! 1 • g fell *„ I. 8SS..SIS SI jl j &gt;!;""- 1 32 I! l«3| SJ U i|l-«--:-|: I 2= II -h =- gs »" l J i : I : \ Q-l 3-1 "S3 : S : q _- ,, | l§§ggg§g g S 5| i, I gs^gsg :e 5| II Ilii^ssz g f hi fl iwrii si 8LHL- 1 " Is |!|agg--8l : « H * l |Ji " LJ = 1,, I lgg.g|g I 3 S l4l| | H::::j 9 | = Sg&gt; &gt; S :::"|; I .g8gg..jg I •g- i.iggsggs •§. .iggsggggis I Is |Br a i *s |!|8»sp s l ll |z 6 |^S-:g| : || |||«8W-8*|; I A Mi 1 i HP z </seg>
            <seg id="p027">5 THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS .)•! •»» I I2SS :S5 IS ■gx I ISg8§SS§l8 1« . 3SS SSIS •3u —— . — f J|JS« J «li ** # li!^ 34 gQ [llSgS M "'Sg ■o ,1 .j88S888|g c . gg gig f jj ft*: i\i 1 s . .1 •■ ri" I " ** 1 ; ; ; ; :i i " " -3 &gt; : ■ : :E 3 it \\ -A T_ i 3 M ■ si- 2 S a^|° -g^::-| : m I H I 5«""s S 8 1 |I &gt; s s S p* 5*" 1 * 1 1 &gt; -O -II *9 N r — n I . 8§SS§§ § ■5 * M : : % :|i i y |ij M m ;| ; 1 1 1 ll ij 8 i i i £ I S |l|«a :::": : } 3 2 - 1-g . SggiSggh 1 I? I! s^ s " H 1 I ss lilsfs^ass I 2 1 liiv s : :«gs -8|s I ! ;s ; I ■ -M ' &gt; JT3 i^i t** l z i IB g t - gl SiSS-3 I SS : : * S C g&gt; ■ 55-1- . . .« « 3 *i B |||2SS- N S : 11 : g S I"! ! . gss ss 9 111! HULL J? i Pi I 16 |. I 3888 :gg i§ i 52 1 S8ss :gg 2 -° jj |g|l § ;-a|| I gl 1 1 1 5§S» :«S I : | z ucsouxa u |||£S8- N £| ill ill 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">226 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE I— MOVEMENT OF POPULATION Absent on parole or escape at commencement of or during period and later discharged without return - ing to school TABLE II AGE AND COLOR OF THOSE ADMITTED MOVEMENT Present mt beginning of period Admitted: For first time Readmitted Transferred from other institutions Returned from parole (ranted before commence-. ment of period Returned from escape made before commence- ment of period i : For Year ending Nov. 36, 1917 II. Ti&gt;2~ 143 3 22 For Year ending Nov. 30. 1918 If. 226 138 1 3 22 j 1 Total for Bienniun M. 428 2*1 1 i; u l Totals Discharged: Expiration of fixed term Reached majority Transferred to other institutions Released to parents or friends Died Paroled and not returned during period Escaped and not returned during period . Totab Remaining at end of period Average number under care -- 370 3 :i 2 1ZS 11 144 226 220 391 2 1 7 171 16 199 192 218 761 5 4 &lt;l 298 27 343 192 tlf Under 10 10 and under 12. . 12 and under 14. . 14 and under 16. . 1 6 and under 1 8 18 and under U Totals •AGE For Year For Year | ending ending Total Nov. 30. Nov. 30, for 1*17 1918 Biennium M. U. U. W. C. T. W. C. T. W. C. T. 4 16 7 1 8 11 2 13 18 2 20 10 10 28 2 30 38 1 39 23 4 27 61 5 66 . 43 5 48 34 4 38 77 9 86 28 4 32 51 4 55 79 8 87 I... 2 4 4 «... 6 133 13 146 129 13 142 262 26 288 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">* / THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS TABLE III— EDUCATION OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE IV-NATIVITY OF THOSE ADMITTED TABLE V— NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF THOSE ADMITTED EDUCATION None Below 3d grade and including 3d 4th grade 5th grade 6th grade 7th grade 8th grade High aehool College 1 : For Year endin* Nov. 30. 1917 u. 1 26 26 22 ta 2! 13 7 r 1 : For Year Nov.%. 1918 M. ii 11 2» 29 20 22 14 ■ Total for Biennium M. 1 44 37 SO 57 43 35 21 146 142 288 For Yew For Ytv ending endinj Total NATIVITY Nov. 30, Nov. 30. for 1917 1918 Bienuum M. M. M. Nebraaka 87 72 159 United Stun, other than Nebraska 63 59 112 Total nativ* born 140 131 271 Aiulria 3 3 Bohemia 1 1 Brazil 1 1 Denmark 1 I Italy 1 4 I 5 Poland 1 1 Kuni 2 2 4 Servia 1 1 Total foreipi born 6 11 17 Total! 146 142 288 I I j NATIVITY OF PARENTS Jnited Sum (both parenui r oreif n Hixri 'nknown Totals For Year For Yemr ending ending ToUl Nov. 30, Nov. 30, for 1917 1*18 Biennium M. M. M. Ill 61 162 21 M 107 14 4 18 1 1 146 142 288 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">228 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VI— PARENTAL CONDITION OF THOSE ADMITTED FOR THE BIENNIUM PARENTAL CONDITION M M M Both |a^!ll: lifjld F»th*i Hru.i 11 l« M 2(1 :t(l 11 21 Mi 17 21 M 1 1 144 112 :hh For Yemr For Year endinr ending ToUl Nov. SO, Nov. 30, [or 1S17 1918 Piennium Mother ri; ; &lt; l:li &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p031">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 229 REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM COUNTY For Year For Year ending ending Total Nov. 30. Nov. 30, for 1»17 1918 ttiennium All Kemainini Nov. 30, 1918 M. M M M. Adam. Antelope Boyd Box Butte Brown Buffalo Bun Butler Od»r '.'.'.'.'. Cherry Cheyenne Clay Colfax Curaing Dawes Damon Dodte Douglas Fillmorv Fumu Gage Graaiey Hall Hamilton . Harlan Hitchcock Holt Jefferson Key a Paha mm' fr Knox Lancaster . Lincoln Madison Merrick Nance Nemaha NuekoUs Otoe Plimv Perkins SSST..:.::: Platte Red Willow Richardson Saline f«rpy Saunders Scotts Bluff . Seward Sheridan Sherman Stanton V.UV 33£r .:::: York Totals 2 2 2 2 2 2 5 i 1 1 2 2 10 12 1 1 1 1 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 ; i ! ! 2 4 S 2 2 4 71 45 11C 1 .... 1 1 1 1 2 S 2 2 8 1 » 1 1 2 1 1 1 1 2 1 .... 1 1 1 1 .... 1 1 .... 1 2 2 1 .... 1 9 11 20 1 6 7 4 4 8 1 1 '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. .... " « 2 1 .... 1 2 .... 2 1 .... 1 1 1 2 .... 2 1 1 1 5 « 1 1 2 6 6 2 2 1 .... 1 1 1 t 1 1 1 2 S S 3 6 2 2 1 .... 1 3 S « '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. "l '.'.'.'. 1 2 1 S US 142 288 77 « 14 ■"» T»2~ </seg>
            <seg id="p032">230 THIRD BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE VIII -CAUSE FOR ADMISSION OK THOSE ADMITTED . I I I For Year For Year thding ending Total CAUSE Nov. SO, Nov. JO, for 1*17 1*18 Biennium M. M. M. Dependency and neglect 1 S 4 Delinquency: Unclassified 87 51 138 Aiding and abetting 1 .... 1 Assault 2 2 4 Breaking and entering 9 9 Burglary 10 8 18 Felony 1 9 10 Forgery 1 4 5 Hone stealing 2 10 12 Incorrigible 18 18 Larceny 3 6 9 Mendicancy and crime 3 6 8 Theft (Wealing) 8 44 6* Total delinquent* US It* 284 Totals 14C 142 288 I I I TABLE IX— STATISTICS OF PAROLED PUPILS Paroled during biennium 329 Returned from parole: For cause •• Without fault Escaped from parole and not retaken 26 Died while on parole Escaped and not retaken i7 Discharged while on parole a t Discharged reaching maturity § On parole November, 30, 1918 148 TABLE X -DIVISION OF LABOR OF ALL PUPILS NOVEMBER 30, 1*18 Baker. S Barn » Boiler houae » Carpenter shop X Cooks, boys' kitchen and officers' kitchen 18 Dairy 10 Force 47 Green-house * House boys 50 Laundry 10 Paint shop Print shop 11 Shoe shop * Tailor shop 11 Total : 1*1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>