<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00024">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00024</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Value of Commercial Vaccines and Bacterins Against Fowl Cholera</title>
               <date value="1920-06">1920-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Research Bulletin 18 June. 1920 The Value of Commercial Vaccines and Bacterins Against Fowl Cholera L. VAN ES AND H. M. MARTIN AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD (the regents of the university) HON. JOHN E. MILLER, President, Lincoln Term expires January, 1921 HON. JOHN R. WEBSTER, V ice-President, Omaha Term expires January, 1925 HON. EDWARD P. BROWN, Davey Term expires January, 1921 HON. PHILIP L. HALL, Lincoln Term expires January, 1923 HON. HARRY D. LANDIS, Seward Term expires January, 1923 HON. FRANK D. JUDSON, Omaha Term expires January, 1925 SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc., Director W. W. BURR, B. Sc, Vice Director W. H. BROKAW, Director of Extension Service THE WORKING STAFF O. W. Sjogren, B. Sc. in A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. Burr, B. Sc., Agronomy T. A. Kiesselbach, Ph. D., Agronomy H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc., Animal Husbandry L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., Animal Pathology and Hygiene •J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology and Hygiene F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Chemistry J. H. Frand8EN, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry M. H. Swenk, A. M., Entomology Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomology R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture G. A. Loveland, A. M., LL. B., Meteorology George L. Peltier, Ph. D., Plant Pathology and Physiology F. E. Mussehl, B. Sc, Poultry Husbandry H. C. Fiixey, A. M., Rural Economics W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation. North Plane E. M. Brouse, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Valentine J. A. Holden, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell •*L. L. Zook, B. Sc, Agronomist, North Platte J. W. Calvin, B. Sc, Associate in Agricultural Chemistry W. J. Loeffel, B. Sc, Assistant in Animal Husbandry C. K. Shedd, B. Sc. in A. E., Assistant in Agricultural Engineering P. L. Gaouis, A. B., B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy F. D. Keim, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy H. M. Martin, V. M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology and Hygiene J. W. Hendrickson, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry John Luithly, B. Sc, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry C. C. Wiggans, Ph. D., Assistant in Horticulture H. O. Werner, B. Sc, Assistant in Horticulture R. W. Goss, M. S., Assistant in Plant Pathology and Physiology J. O. Rankin, A. M., Assistant in Rural Economics •Resigned. ••Detailed from Office of Dry Land Agriculture, United States Department of Agri - :ulture, Washington, D. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">THE VALUE OF COMMERCIAL VACCINES AND BACTERINS AGAINST FOWL CHOLERA By L. VAN ES AND H. M. MARTIN A great prevalence of the disease known as fowl cholera has naturally stimulated an interest in possible means of pre - vention and especially in those which may bring about a more or less lasting immunity. Attempts at immunizing against this disease date back to the very beginning of the era of modern bacteriology and immunology, and there is no doubt that many investigators succeeded in causing immunity in chickens by one method or other. Apparently, however, it has not yet been possible thru any of those methods to gain a solid footing and general dependability. Vaccines which were favorably reported by some failed utterly in the hands of others, so that on the whole no substantial advantage has been gained. Vaccines and bacterins are nevertheless constantly urged on poultry owners confronted with disease and the Experiment Station is frequently called upon to give an opinion on their value or to recommend any special preparation. In order to comply with those demands in an intelligent and impartial manner, we have thought it wise to make some experiments with the various preparations offered by the pharmaceutical trade in the hope that this may enable us to recommend all or any preparation for the relief of our poultry raisers. A search through the advertising pages of veterinary journals showed that in all six manufacturers offered vaccines and bac - terins against fowl cholera for sale and claimed for them im - munizing powers sufficient to warrant the expenditure of money on the part of poultry producers. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 18 4 From those various manufacturers we purchased a quantity of their products, treated a given number of fowls with them and then tested the immunity of the latter by means of inocula - tions with fowl cholera organisms secured from field outbreaks and cultivated in our laboratory. We hereby submit the details of those experiments in the following tables. Sample No. 148. This preparation was sold to us as "Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccine (Avian)." The details of the tests of this material are given in Table I. TABLE I Fowl cholera Chicken vaccine No. 148 B. bipolaris ' Dates of avisepticus ] deaths 2/3 No. Quantity 1 c.c. 2/11 Strain 38 B. 1. X 2/12 All chickens were very X 2/14 sick the day after the !::::::: * *::::::: | 6 X 7 X 8 X » X X 2/14 virus injection. X 2/13 X .... Very sick. Recovered 2/23 X X 2/17 X 2/13 X .... Very sick. Recovered 10 X- X 2/15 X .... Very sick. Recovered ii I x 12 X X 2/15 NOTE — The fact that an injection was made is indicated by the X. A dash ( ) is used to show that no Injection took place. I 'ne loopful culture </seg>
            <seg id="p005">'owl Cholera Vaccines and Bacterin •&gt; a JK u -I — a. -¥ c S 3-8 •§ s a 2? 'a 1 JS 5- sc c 1 * |ll fl l|il * !l 1 111 * * £ Ih&amp;tli * 1 If! * -o-ao3 • o^° ° Sa°°S-|^.-8 .$J.oSiJ*»5»- .2222 •SSII 8 "" 1 3.«-a-a§^§-S|g-Big-8g. B |8888 •I Ig-a|fc|s s si &amp; §-s I g-g fc-s-g ill (Bh m ""I! v ~^~' "~ N- ~^ ' * • ' ■as S 1-sl 5i i i^i I ft*£g*f*e* s ssss 2r~ W Q £ tO »»NN«N CON NNNNNCO CO NMNN U M &lt;«J g-« Sat- sSl l' s d5 I M HUM I MM M Mini | mm to jg oo r~T7~! ( S N "• *i ijuuijiju u tit) ci «j litiliiiiiii cj S *S Ig &lt;O _ Ba&gt; t_ o o (!&lt;!l)ljui! l! lit! (J o o o ij o ti C 6 {1*3 £ "" - -—&lt;«.—» * -»^ -, m rt ««« Mrt ■ ' ■ ' S J 1 i ::::::::: : : : : : I : : ! I I I j I j •« z :::::::::::: : : : i f-^ *-H *-H H 1— I *-t M f-( »-H r- ( Cg NNNN t- SD "^» O3 Oi O CO &lt;C CO W riri — ocir; co' NNNN </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska 1 iXPEl XP IMENT ITA 1 noN Research Bulletin 1 S.SJS,5&gt; 2^-8 i! "If! 5 illiJ ® $ «S c» t- u O aj ■5 S otj^ * I— I I— I I— I I I •Pi! P s|ls . .1 § ? -Sic eo o^ C fli t- 4) e • J2 — v. r- ta o 5 -- ** ■*■* ■*■» *^ -^ I l-H 1— &lt; CO CO CO X I 1 1 1 X ft X X XXX X 00 ,; 6 o 04 X X XXX X a I i £ - I — » « •5 •*• X H XXX X IM X X XXX X d — C4 m^io » </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Fowl Cholera Vaccines and Bacterins 7 3 H - — ■* I I s l«« 1 I i i ! O 31 sj I" — — U u 338 i-H i-H coco §§ 3 -^l» CM I I i— i w — PQ i «...■* * ° S II ; S -C OO NSNN O *N«O © &lt;-H CO "S'S HH«HHHHartaHHHH«rt«H ?L\ Q» «■« eo-^co^-^eoeoeoweoeoeoeoeoeoeocoeo 5 i I |M» XXX I i-H O5 i— 1 ro co co co II I I -d S I I 1****1 I I I I I I I I I I I I •|.g ■§■3 PQ jd 1 I ■II" HQ, 0 2 e m 00 XIXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX^XX \XXXi «xxx&gt; xxxx • • •c t- o Si «J "TT si ooiiociiioooiSooejoci ooououou'oiiocicJcJd | i v v £ U U ti (j ' ciutit! NNNNC tjuiji! o o o u NNMM d 3 I 2 £ — 5 - It I ' J I s M Si «J N in tjooejiicioocjuiiciouej eJouooeJocSoootioou | MNMNNMNMNNNNMNM t t| v d ; o u o ticjuu NN(NM( U (j (i U O U U ti (idiicl MNNH l) si o c ci «5 li t NNHK "I sl IM u ci u u u u u u u « u u u (i u uuuciuuciuuutiuuuu | C 0 d Z rtefled-*us&lt;ot-od&lt;»©^HjJo2|&lt;jio«Dt^od«© </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 18 Sample No. 676. Sold under the label of : "Avisepticus Bacterin." (Table V.) Chicken No. Injectio bacterin Nc 2 c.c. in &gt;.676 Injection B. bipolaris No. 673 1 loopful 3/30 Dates of deaths Remarks 3/12 i 3/15 I 3/18 1 2 S 4 6 6 7 X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X 3/21 4/3 4/3 4/2 4/1 4/4 4/12 Sick on 3/31 Sick on 3/31 Sick on 3/31 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X X 4/12 4/12 4/6 4/3 4/1 4/5 4/8 4/12 Sick on 3/31 Killed. Chronic cholera. Sick on 3/31 Killed — in good health had not been sick Sick on 3/31. Very sick when killed Sick on 3/31 Sick on 3/31 Sick on 3/31 Sick on 3/31 Sick on 3/31 / Killed. Sick on 3/31. \ Developed chronic cholera Control Control Control Control Control Control Control Control Control Control. Sick on 3/31 Control Control 16 17 18 19 SO 21 22 28 24 26 26 27 - X X X X X X X X X X X X 4/1 4/1 3/31 4/1 3/31 4/1 4/1 3/31 3/31 4/3 4/1 3/31 I _ I X </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Fowl Cholera Vaccines and Bacterins 9 Sample No. 682. A preparation labelled: "Hemorrhagic Septicemia Vaccine (for fowls)." (Table VI.) TABLE VI Injections Injections Chicken vaccine No. 682 B. bipolaris Dates 2 c.c. No. 637 of Remarks No. i : 1 loopful deaths 3/17 3/20 3/23 | 3/30 1 2 X X 4/1 Control 4/8 Control. Sick on 3/31 3 X X I X j X 4/7 i Sick on 3/31 4 XX X X | 4/4 Sick on 3/31 5 XXX X 4/3 Sick on 3/31 6 XXX X 3/31 7 X X X | X , 3/31 8 X X X j X : 3/31 9 XX X X 4/1 10.. XXX 3/31 XXX 11 X 4/1 12 XXX X 4/3 Sick on 3/31 XXX X 13.. 3/31 14 X XX X 3/31 15.. XXX X 4/11 Sick on 3/31 16 XX X X 4/9 Sick on 3/31 17 XX X X 3/31 18 XXX X 4/8 Sick on 3/31 19.. 4/2 Sick on 3/31. Control 20... 4/1 Control 21 3/31 Control £ 22 3/31 Control 23.. 3/31 ! Control 24 3/31 ' Control 25 4/10 Sick on 3/31. Control 4/12 ' Sick on 3/31. Control 26 Recovering when killed 27. 4/1 Control 28 3/31 Control 3/31 Control 29 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Research Bulletin 18 10 Sample No. 741. A product sold as: "Fowl Cholera Bacterin." (Table VII.) TABLE VII Injections Injections bacterin B. bipolaris Dates No. 741. c.c. No. 637 of Chicken Remarks No. 1 loopful deaths I. 2 3 4 5 6 7. 8 9. 10. 11 12. 13. 14 15. 16. 1 1 17. 18. 19. 20 21 22. 23. 24 25 26 27. 28 29. 30 31 4/19 4/22 4/25 5/7 Ill 1 1 1 1 ! 1/10 llll llll 111 1/10 -ill -ill -ill -11 1/10 -ill - — l l - — 1 1/10 - — 2 1 1 1 1 1 1/10 1/10 1/10 1/10 1 ■ /, B / Sick 5/10. Very sick wher 1/18 \ killed i/12 Sick 5/10 |/l i/18 Very sick when killed i/14 Sick on 5/10 ./12 i/13 i/l i/13 i/10 '^ 8 8 /Sick 5/10. Very sick whei 1/18 \ killed /lfl /Sick 5/10. Very sick wher 1/18 \ killed len i/9 f Sick 5/10. Apparently recovered when killec i /1 8 j Necrosis at point of in- oculation. Many organ- isms present. &gt;/9 Control /9 Control i/9 Control /9 Control i/11 Control i/9 Control i/9 Control i/11 Control &gt;/8 Control /8 Control /9 Control i/9 Control i/8 Control i/10 Control i/10 Control </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Fowl Cholera Vaccines and Bacterins 11 Summarizing the results of the preceding series, we find as follows: (Table VIII.) It is evident from the above that no reliance can be placed on the vaccines and bacterins against fowl cholera, which we are able to find on the market and subject to definite tests. We have no doubt as to the possibility of artificial immunity as an aid to the control of fowl cholera, but as yet we will have to get along with the more non specific means of prevention, even if those are far from a universal efficiency. (SIC ±J\D1jCj V-lll I I Resul Results ilts Number of chickens of Number of bacterin r which immunity was or vaccine Chickens tested injections sick or dead ! Chickens immune 18 25 57 18 1 18 25 2 25 67 3 56 1 2 3 0 0 1 </seg>
          </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>