<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1929</title>
               <date value="1930-03">1930-03</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 242 March, 1930 NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS 1920-1929 An Omc,AL Drawbar Test Un»er Way at th B University of Nebraska THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR. Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY OF RESULTS OF THE ] CONDUCTED BY THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA, DEPARTMENT ■ ; INCLUDES ONLY TRACTORS ON THE TQACTOQ_ I E^Q\~^E II i^&gt; nl. ~r te^ts ~ • I^ATED LOAD-»- T\&gt;?o HIJS. MAXIMUM LOAD -v. OA&amp;E HQ. tfArjvi/k. ■IAME- IJVTUIQ As&gt; Ll A/JO t a VMKE- FUEL. £5 HD £)&amp; KiR &amp;&amp; GMA \ UO E^Q QAL&amp;.I H.IJILBi M IS I R. P. M. -:f# % Illiiil i iPiililililillilll " \'Z-zs ls,oooil4K's^|«6siv;eiDELY IKEgo. |« lUs.2 r totil 5-65 1fe.95|0.9a|0.0017^ li9s|zy.9»|i;fe^| 3A&amp; laodaflAJg^ roko&amp;ke^^j izs - t5 &gt;Q-6'oll4la4^&gt;l6solo\v»o iKEDQlialkaisia^l 5.)31a^10.771i.i7T7-.1i6i5R.59 losal 5.75 laraa^ljaTlt^iaof tog ll^l uJf-^ALL I I3SSOIKI3VSHZOOIOWW IV&lt;EOO.I30IIIS.031IIO&amp;I l.flT 19.&amp;410.70|1.ae19l Uio|&lt;o.os \]Zo\ IX. \h- |939|0.7^|| )ol77l4lQ||^ee"|llw : : . 'Hf ' lllliill Iffii |ii|ii;p|i|M|ipiii iiM^ifeliiiifeifeiiMiiiiilite fem Sll|^|ii|lliillllteii ijffi^isiiill iliiiiiiiiiiiiiiii I HIE. If llliiilcaMlipl#illl§iH§feN I ?ii£»^ iiStestifewHii! Irl^iiisl^ffl-fl— l-P^^^l-fs?!^ o* &amp;.-»« 4 M'&amp; 10750WA) QAS 44 5*.371075 3.539 9.15 a&amp;7£ttOO 7S 192 3914 1075 5.96^ 9i8ib.65l 0.00 &amp;S 191 1110 1070 d !ffl^ «*» i&amp;§^^ s is^illlillilllllll 1 1 168 rOUUDQI\?E E..-IS-2S 6SOS 4ABKIIOOWAUK. KEIJO. 46 A5.X9110S SA9a7X&gt;SM76OOO 75 1T9Z6.41 HOO 5.%5 7.W 19KO00 T5 190 1151 HOI Summary of Bulletin 242, Nebraska Tra </seg>
            <seg id="p003">S OF THE NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS &gt;KA, DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING, LINCOLN, NEBRASKA Y TRACTORS ON THE MARKET JANUARY 1, 1930 .UMLOAD^OrtE ■ Hgg *$**. — RATED LO AD ~ A TEE A&gt; " T "^ A X .MUM ,nA rs L B|4.e'sfe.67]O.9y;lasC&lt;lo^lo|Hs^|9 / t6||l9.6A-iZ7O3U 731925|9Ql I bPADE- luiGH k^oU /.fill •s7 T v\\aol7n l, n , c |,,^ ■, &#132; I 1 1 — — i , , , 5 AZ 5.60 1.090.75 SC^IO IO9S 95\ I.Oft ißr.s Zl7 \»S.Zi2S A^KIE -— o'zq ,^f '2^ 529&lt; ?JZ — I&amp;2I 504+ Z.SJu !iilllililllll=fgiilli||ll|E=iHl |U4&amp;£t^6ll477|s.s7|lZ3slK.oo|s.(bO|AAiGL£|lMTj?.6el-^iJ|^ I^=^73 ■5 11.^6 6.580.97a00e7 195 696 65Z 51.51 17654 649 I?! riT ftxS Snl ?^K^ fi ?° 70 7 , 5&amp;3 '- 5O 5i:l1 Wis ZSS «•« «* 3 »•» 104 31 S.IO |9.lo|Q74iatfe|ssHos||sC)o|lj,7Z'i|is«,OU'?o3l^ la. llA^fal A^S &amp; Urtfir. lirtvflU /^IB.a/M. &#132; i — . liiiiillililiriifel ii iEililifebbyiby mm **-&gt;* I 9j5 7" *■*•*' ' ~ 1,. ..-■ 1 ' i, i- — i i ,. - 7 7.94- US 0^5.7509^01 05, B5&amp; SgJlw Ito 111 ztZ WADE HIGH 4 "re HI ft? ?S? aS IS StSg ««« M? 78.!? .1.960 Z.« G5.57 7550 US IK) ililillllilii i iliiiliiSlliiiiilil -^ i g&gt;J/^?!f^ I i.-»e lA&gt;&gt;Q\.c Mt. |5. l so|7.3alas4laod4i 1i5415a551i0837l i.a0Uq.07[6850|^.601X7:551^40^4:05 117 35W 746&amp;8BaOO&amp;7 |7+ !k+ 156S 40 74I4I?) I ? 541 1571 I o' fej laS??^ llrir" l^?l?l?^2 Dii'PJ^ill^SI 163 ! 16 - 53 ! 51^ 0 \*"°° I 1~~ I pft«&gt;3|S»9|S.4l IIW J , I.o?I SSSB2S3S !? !^ 5 -Sg iili If ff |:I| | i| ||| !gi % f.^ s fe 1^ l.!t 58? 5558? ' &lt; **^** I V &lt;c9 *^, ■ I ~~~" — ~~ ~™ 3 4.070 TOOWU6 7* 'l7? II8t" \O&amp;? ?I'wl^?sal «7ttl!iS2 I ?"ZJ- ISISS? I fCJX* P°*° I 6 * 5 * |L&lt;W&gt;p.ls|6S 1183 mac*KS3=&gt; I**''' US&gt;.6&lt;!&gt;|s«7ls.t3 |So.oa|X6 4SK.i6|ISS ;ffisisifi I iiill finUBpSB ■h&amp;.SST K&gt;.l4 o.M&gt;e o.oo 7-t 19T 1151 993 39.54 97» 4.01 &lt;D9i 4 .OS SPADE HIGH 5 07© 5 70 1900 Ql9 91 IST *T 7r SOM aoi mShv?™K ) 7.467 9.79 IKK* U» 90 (U ,093 990 W.^ |«H S.™ .007 5.G? ISSSII W T " fsg tit U&amp; QO5 ll \tl tko7 wS til 1^ SSf M4^ l" ' 5.%5 WO MM O.OO 75 190 1151 WOI 15.»6 1659 5.47 1089 X.53 SW\DE I^7. 5.fc07 4.2.1 1.65Ca0804 .S3 16.97 SOU «3 17.68.879 5.53 AOS 717 165 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">BOARD OF TRACTOR TEST ENGINEERS E. E. Brackctt, C. W. Smith, E. B. Lewis ENGINEER IN CHARGE OF TESTS H. L. Wallace ASSISTANT IN TRACTOR .TESTS C. F. Adams </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS With the close of the testing season of 1929 came the end of the tenth year of tractor testing at the University of Ne - braska. The number of complete tests conducted and re - ported each year was as follows : 1920 1921 1922 1923 1924 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 Total 65 15 5 12 10 8 12 16 7 16 166 This bulletin summarizes the results of 61 of these tests and includes data on all tractors reported by their manu - facturers as on the market January 1, 1930. If a tractor has been tested but is not listed in this bulletin, the reader may safely assume that its manufacture has been discontinued. All tractors tested are certified by their manufacturer as being stock-model machines, conforming to specifications filed with the application for test. No special or high test fuels are used. All results shown in reports are those actually attained in tests and are without corrections or allowances for friction, temperature, altitude, etc. These results are accom - plished with the tractor in charge of skilled operators em - ployed by the University. Beginning with 1928 the "one carburetor setting" was adopted and all results shown -on reports of tests made in 1928 and 1929 were attained with the carburetor adjustment remaining unchanged thruout all parts of the complete test. A three-page report of each test is issued soon after the test is completed, and this bulletin is compiled from these reports and from the specifications filed with the application for test. Copies of the original three-page reports are avail - able at 5 cents per report (on one tractor) from the Departs ment of Agricultural Engineering, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, Nebraska. Those desiring future reports without delay, who remit $1.00, will receive for one year without further requests or other cost one copy of. all reports or bulletins issued, referring to tractor tests; each one will be mailed as soon as possible after its release. A mimeographed pamphlet containing the full text of the Nebraska tractor law, the procedure followed in the test, and the A. S. A. E. and S. A. E. rating code is also available at 10 cents per copy. SUMMARY OF RESULTS This summary will be found on the large folded sheet on the inside of the front cover page. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 summary of specifications and comments The following are extracts from the reports and specifica - tions of tractors tested and now on the market. Test No. 22. GRAY 18-36. The Gray Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. June 11 to July 3, 1920 Bosch "DIM" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. . Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. RPM Diameter n %"&gt; widt * 8". rated speed 950 Chassis: Wide drive drum in rear, 2 guide wheels in front. Clutch, own, cone type. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.25 miles per hour ; high, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: Ground valves and adjusted tappets. Tractor would not develop rated load. Manufacturer was permitted to put on new cylinders and pistons and tractor was given additional limbering up. Put on Stromberg carburetor in place of Bennett. Carburetor float valve ground. At the end of the test there were slight leaks around plugs above valves and around spark plug porcelains. A good deal of lost motion m the steering gear. Test No. 28. BEEMAN MODEL G 2-4. Beeman Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. June 22 to July 2, 1920. Heinze "AX1" magneto. Kingston "J" carburetor. Donald - son dry centrifugal type air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 4i/ 2 ", width 33,4", rotates at engine speed. Chassis: Two drive wheels in front, 2 castor wheels in rear. Clutch own make, both external and internal expanding Rated Speeds: 0.75 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Replaced carburetor. Test No. 29. LA CROSSE 12-24. La Crosse Tractor Company, La Crosse, Wisconsin. August 2 to 5, 1920. « j££? ter ~? en !l " K3^&gt;' ma Sf net o and dry batteries. Stromberg MB3 carburetor. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11", width 7i/ 2 ", rated SpGGQ 900 xv.Jr.IVl. t, C 5^ s: £ our wheels » 2 drivers, own clutch contracting band type. Open gear drive. Rated Speed : 2.50 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests Comments : Line drive attachment was used. Operator had reasonably good control of tractor with 4 Unes. Replaced fan belt, changed 2 spark plugs. Replaced governor springs, changed ignition timing, ground valves. TII . Te ? t N 9- , 43 - AVERY 25-50. Avery Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to 30, 1920. K-W "HK" magneto. Kingston "Dual" carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. JV Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 22", width 8V 2 ", rated Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers. Open gear drive, expand - ing shoe clutch, own make. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: Clutch adjusted twice. New governor spring put in to replace old one which was too weak. In the test the cab needed additional bracing to hold it rigidly to the engine frame. „,?•!* N ?-, 4 t' /? &gt;Y ERY 45 " 65 - Avery Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to August 3, 1920. K-W "HK" magneto. Kingston "Dual" carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball tyne governor. Engine: Horizontal, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 26", width 10", rated speed 600 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, own make expanding shoe clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: The rating of this tractor was changed from 40-80 to 45-65. Test No. 45. CLETRAC 12-20. Cleveland Tractor Com - pany, Cleveland, Ohio. July 29 to August 9, 1920 Teagle "665" magneto. Kingston "L" carburetor. Own make air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head. Mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 8", width 6", rated speed 1265 R.P.M. Chassis: Crawler track, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. B &amp; B disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Normal, 3.5 miles per hour. Variable from 1 to 4 miles per hour. Comments : Fuel pipe broken. Oil gauge did not register. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 Test No. 65. TORO 6-12. The Toro Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. September 23 to 29, 1920. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L" carburetor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Le Roi fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 8", width 414", rated speed 1200 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch double band, own make. Three-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.6 miles per hour ; high, 3.7 miles per hour ; reverse, 3 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments necessary during test. Test No. 68. BATES STEEL MULE 15-22. Bates Ma - chine &amp; Tractor Company, Joliet, Illinois. October 12 to 18, 1920. Dixie Aero magneto. Bennett "J" carburetor. Bennett water type air cleaner. Simplex fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 81/V, rated speed 853 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, clutch B &amp; B dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 3 miles per hour; high, 4.5 miles per hour. Comments: Minor adjustment on oil line. Test No. 73. WETM0RE 12-25. H. A. Wetmore, Sioux City, Iowa. April 6 to 12, 1921. Splitdorf Aero magneto. Schebler "ATX47" li/£" carbu - retor. No air cleaner. Weidely fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6%", rated speed 1088 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, Fuller disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles, per . hour ; intermediate, 3V2 miles per hour ; high, 5.9 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Hand operation of throttle was necessary to control engine speed within safe limits of loads three-fourths rating, and under, when carbu - retor was set for best fuel economy. Heavy grade oil was found necessary for the engine. Test No. 101. BEAR "B" 25-35. Bear Tractors, Inc., New York City. April 1 to 8, 1924. Bosch "AT4" magneto. Schebler "A" 13,4-inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Simplex centrifugal type governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Tractor Tests Engine: Vertical, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Dow metal pistons. Lynite (aluminum alloy) connecting rods. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 9" rated speed 1290 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers; multiple dry disc clutches. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.35 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3.80 miles per hour; high, 6.15 miles per hour. Comments: Slot in governor plunger. lengthened 3/32 inch. Points of one spark plug readjusted. Test No. 104. BEST "S30" 25-30. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 22 1924. American Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Stromberg "MP3" 11/2 - inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 7", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers ; multiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.75 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.63 miles per hour; high, 3.63 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 105. BEST "A60" 50-60. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 29, American Bosch "ZR4Edl8" magneto. Stromberg "M4" Special 1%-inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make centifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 10", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers; multiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1% miles per hour; intermediate, 2% miles per hour; high, 3% miles per hour. Comments : At the end of the test the vacuum tank leaked at the bottom seam. Exhaust valve on No. 1 cylinder would not hold compression. Test No. 110. CASE 25-45. J. I. Case Threshing Ma - chine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 28 to November 9, 1924. Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Kingston "L" 2-inch carburetor. Own make water type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor Madison-Kipp lubricator. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16^", width 8V&amp;", rated speed 850 R.P.M. ■■■"..•. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers ; enclosed gear drive ; ex - panding shoe type clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; high, 3.2 miles per hour. Comments : During the rated drawbar test the right cyl - inder head gasket burned out and both gaskets were then re - placed. Test No. 117. McCORMICK-DEERING "FARM ALL." International Harvester Company of America, Chicago, Illi - nois. September 14 to 19, 1925. Splitdorf "Aero" 937950 magneto. Ensign "3DA600F" 1 - inch carburetor. Pomona Model 118 oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diam - eter 14", width 6V 2 ", rated speed 693 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers ; enclosed gear drive ; multiple dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 119. CLETRAC "K" 1S-2S. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 22 to May 5, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6", rated speed 860 R.P.M. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Chassis: Track-layer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, single disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4.50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: During the half load brake test the oil pressure line sprung a leak. During the rated and low gear maximum drawbar tests the gear shift lever had to be fastened in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. The advertised miles per hour as given should be corrected to: Low, 2.13 miles per hour; high, 4.23 miles per hour; reverse, 1.66 miles per hour at 1375 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 120. CLETRAC "K" 15-25. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 30 to May 5, 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. • Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 6", rated speed 860 R.P.M. Chassis: Track-layer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, single disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4.50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated and low gear maximum draw - bar tests the gear shift lever had to be fastened in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. The advertised miles per hour as given should be corrected to: Low, 2.13 miles per hour; high, 4.23 miles per hour; reverse, 1.66 miles per hour at 1375 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 121. TWIN CITY "TY" 17-28. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 17 to 21, 1926. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Bennett dry cen - trifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Holley "257" carburetor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves; mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, disc clutch, 6" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.75 miles per hour. Comments: During the drawbar tests it was necessary to place two small bolts in the gear shift lock to keep gears in mesh. It was necessary to adjust the -governor several times on drawbar test to maintain proper engine speed. Teat No. 122. TWIN CITY "AT" 27-44. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 20 to 27, 1926. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Wheeler Schebler "A" carburetor. Donaldson Duplex oil fiber type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 21", width 8%", rated speed 466 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, twin disc clutch, 7" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.87 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 Comments : During both the rated load brake test and the rated load drawbar test the fan belt tension had to be read - justed. Test No. 123. HUBER NEW SUPER FOUR 18-36. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. June 7 to 12, 1926. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L3" 1 11/16-inch throttle opening, manifold type A cold bore, 2 3/16-inch Pomona "Vortox" oil fiber type air cleaner. Kingston, fly - ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15yo", width 8", rated speed 695 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, twin disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; high, 3.8 miles per hour. Comments: After the limber-up run and before the brake tests were made, the fan belt was replaced with a new one. Before the drawbar tests were run the fan belt broke and was again replaced with a new belt. During the limber-up run 3 cap screws sheared off the steering post and clutch lever sup - port. Before the brake tests were run a ball and socket con - nection was put on the governor throttle rod. During the maximum test the fuel line broke at the carburetor connection and was replaced with a new fuel pipe. Test No. 125. CLETRAC "A" 30-45. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. August 27 to September 7, 1926. Eisemann "GS6" magneto. Tillotson "ST3A" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly - ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15", width 8i/»", rated speed 690 R.P.M. Chassis : Two tracks, enclosed gear drive, single disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.4 miles per hour; high, 4.75 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.8 miles per hour. Comments: During the low gear drawbar tests the gear shift lever had to be tied in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engi - neers and the Society of Automotive Engineers, the belt horse - power rating of this tractor should not exceed 44 horsepower. Test No. 126. HUBER 20-40. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. September 7 to 16, 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor Tests Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly - ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15i/&gt;", width 8", rated speed 666 R.P.M. . . Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Twin disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.47 miles per hour; high, 3.48 miles per hour ; reverse, 1.94 miles per hour. Comments : During the rated brake test the fan belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. Test No. 128. HART-PARR 18-36. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. October 18 to 25, 1926. Robert Bosch "ZU42" magneto. Stromberg "MB3" carbu - retor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft Sn« s^i?^' Belt P ullev: Diameter 14", width 9", rated speed 800 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Dry plate clutch. Seven-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 miles per hour; high, 3.00 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. Comments: Before the half load brake test was run the spark gap in the spark plugs was adjusted to 0.020" gap. During the maximum drawbar test one spark plug was re - placed. Two small screws were lost out of the carburetor air connection during the test. The crankshaft speed of the rated load and first maximum drawbar tests was low due to an error in calculations made by observer during test which was not discovered until too late for correction. Test No. 129. HART-PARR 12-24. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. October 18 to 28, 1926 Robert Bosch "ZU42" magneto. Stromberg "MB3" carbu - retor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly - ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8", rated speed Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, dry plate clutch. Six-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.66 miles per hour; high, 3.33 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comment : During the varying load brake test both spark plugs were replaced with new spark plugs; one had a cracked </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 porcelain and the other a defective gasket. During the low gear maximum drawbar. tests the gears slipped out of mesh. It was necessary to improvise a method of holding gear shift lever in place. The low gear train of gears was burred slightly due to the gears slipping out of mesh. Teat No. 134. WALLIS 20-30. J. I, Case Plow Works, Racine, Wisconsin. April 29 to May 10, 1927. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Kingston "L3" car - buretor. Wallis dry "cloth screen type" air cleaner. Picker - ing fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18i/&gt;", width 7", rated speed 476 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch dry plate with disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.75 miles per hour; high, 3.331/3 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments : The rate of travel of this tractor is : Low, 2.88 miles per hour ; high, 3.49 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.88 miles per hour. The above speeds are calculated at the rim of the drive wheels and at 1050 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 135. HUBER SUPER FOUR 40-62. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. May 17 to June 24, Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "A" carburetor. Po - mona oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15y 2 ", width 9%", rated Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 to 2.50 miles per hour; high, 3.00 to 3.50 miles per hour; reverse, 1.75 to 2.25 miles per hour Comments: During the rated drawbar test and after ap - proximately 25 hours running, ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced with new ones of the same make but did not remedy the trouble. The Stitt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were then replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was experienced. The left spindle arm sheared off causing the front axle to bend somewhat; the axle and spindle arm were replaced with new parts. The packing gland nuts on the water pump were tightened several times during the test. The flexible oil tube leading to the clutch throw-out collar was leaking at the end of the test. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 136. SHAW MODEL "T25." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 22, 1927. Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS6A" carburetor. No air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, F-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 5i/ 2 ", width iy 2 ", rated speed 275 R.P.M. Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open chain and gear drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated Speeds: Low, 0.50 to 1.50 miles per hour; high, 1.25 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: During the brake tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The exhaust valve stem was found to be sticking. It was removed, polished and the valve ground. The exhaust valve push rod was adjusted to give more clearance and the guide reamed out. The inlet valve spring was found to be somewhat weaker than a standard spring. The inlet valve, spring and cage were replaced with a new assembly. Before the official brake tests were run both piston rings stuck in their grooves. The lower ring was broken in removing and was replaced with a new ring; both rings were given slightly more- end clearance than they had previously. During the drawbar tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The caster wheel arm was broken and replaced with a new one. The clutch shift lever broke and was repaired. The fuel line broke off at the carbu - retor and was repaired. During the limber-up run a stop clip on the cultivator beam control broke. In the advertising literature submitted with the specifica - tions for test of this tractor we find the following claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit "B" page 15 ENGINE SPECIFICATIONS. "POWER RATED CONSERVATIVELY AT 1 H. P. On tests develops about IV2 horse power." Exhibit "B" page 8. "Figure 18 showing SHAW DU ALL Model T25 running in low gear pulling a road drag with scales indicating 450 pounds direct pull on the drawbar, which is sufficient to pull a ton load on a cart or light wagon." Teat No. 137. SHAW MODEL "T45." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 23, 1927. Own make magneto. Tillotson "MS7A" carburetor. No air cleaner. Own make pneumatic type governor. Engine: Vertical, air cooled, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 3", width 2y 2 ", operates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open gear and chain drive, clutch own make expanding band. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 Rated Speeds: Low, 1.00 miles per hour; high 1.43 miles per hour. Comments: In the advertising literature submitted with the specifications for test of this tractor we find the following claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test : Exhibit "B" "T45": "DRAWBAR PULL 650 lbs. On low gear, this pulls a iy 2 ton load on a light cart or wagon." Test No. 138. CONTINENTAL CULTOR No. 32. Con - tinental Cultor Company, Springfield, Ohio. August 6 to 17, Ford Model "T" ignition system. Holly "Ford" carbu - retor. No air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. No belt pulley. Chassis : Two wheels, both drivers, open chain final drive, multiple disc clutch. Rated Speed : 3.00 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test the left main drive chain broke. The broken link was replaced with a new link. During the same test two teeth were broken on the main drive sprocket; the test was completed without repair. Test No. 139. MONARCH 10 TON MODEL F. Monarch Tractors Corporation, Springfield, Illinois. • August 15 to 26, American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Zenith "L7T" car - buretor. United 13,4" twin, dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Le Roi, fly-ball type governor. i E i?? in - e: y ertical » valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. No belt pulley. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, partly enclosed final drive, enclosed gear transmission, chain and sprocket final drive. Clutch own make disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.5 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.6 miles per hour; high, 3.3 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 140. HART-PARR 28-50. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. August 17 to 31 1927 Robert Bosch "ZU4" magneto. Schebler "D" carburetor Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly - ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 9", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make dry plate. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Tractor Tests Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments : After all tests were completed and during the final inspection number 4 cylinder was found to have little or no compression. The piston was removed and the top ring was found to be stuck in its groove, also a small hole thru the wall of the piston in the top groove at the lap of the ring. The ring was released and the hole plugged up. The water passage between the cylinder head and engine block on this tractor had been enlarged to permit freer circula - tion. It is understood that this change is to be made standard on all tractors of this model. Test No. 141. OIL PULL 20-30. MODEL "W." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. September 15 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own make car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7 V-&gt;", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make double disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.7 miles per hour. Comments: After the limber-up run and before the official belt tests were made, the lubricator could not be regulated properly. It was disassembled and cleaned out thoroly. Dur - ing the drawbar tests the compression on number 1 cylinder was found to be somewhat less than number 2 cylinder and there was considerable leakage by the rings on the compres - sion stroke. The piston on number 1 cylinder was removed, the carbon cleaned out from around the rings and all valves ground. Both spark plugs were replaced with new plugs ; the porcelains were found to be defective. The fuel valve and water valve required frequent adjustment during the drawbar tests.. . ■ . Test No. 142. McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20. Inter - national Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 3 to 8, 1927. Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "R" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" Model 118 oil spray type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15V4.", width 7", rated speed 661 R.P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make multiple dry disc. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3 miles per hour ; high, 4 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 143. OIL PULL 25-40. MODEL "X." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 6 to 13, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/2Ed26" magneto. Own make car - buretor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18%,", width 8 V^", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.8 miles per hour. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 144. ROCK ISLAND 18-35. Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. October 12 to 19, 1927. Dixie "46C" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor. Buda fly-ball j type governor. United dry centrifugal type . air cleaner. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18", width 7i/ 2 ", rated speed 660 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin dry disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 3 miles per hour; high, 4.5 miles per hour ; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers, the belt horsepower rating of this tractor should not exceed 32 horse - power. Test No. 145. OIL PULL 30-50. MODEL "Y." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 13 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "DU4/Ed26" magneto. Own make carbu - retor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own fly - ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine : Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 21Vi", width 10", rotates at crankshaft speed. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Nebraska Tractor Tests Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.3 miles per hour ; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.9 miles per hour. Comments : On the rated drawbar test the water pump lost prime for short intervals. At the end of the test and during the inspection of the tractor both intake valve springs were found broken* I . Test No. 146. JOHN DEERE 15-27. MODEL " D." John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 24 to 29 1927 Splitdorf "246C" magneto. Schebler "DLT" carburetor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson Simplex oiled fiber type air cleaner. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 151/4", width 7%", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.5 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Teat No. 147. MONARCH 6 TON. Monarch Tractors Corporation, Springfield, Illinois. November 14 to 24, 1927. American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Zenith "77" carbu - retor. Pierce fly-ball type governor. United dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. No belt pulley. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, partly enclosed final drive, enclosed gear transmission, chain and sprocket final drive. Clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds : Low, 1.86 miles per hour.; intermediate, 2.82 miles per hour ; high, 4.07 miles per hour ; reverse, 3.26 miles per hour; Comments: It was necessary to adjust the water pump packing glands several times during the test. It was still leaking some at the end of the test. In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers, the drawbar horsepower rating of this tractor should not exceed 38 horsepower. Test No. 148. LAUSON "S12" 20-35. John Lauson Manufacturing Company, New Holstein, Wisconsin. April 2 to 16, 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 American Bosch "ZR4" magneto. Tillotson "R2" carbu - retor. Taco fly-ball type governor. Taco water type air cleaner. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 697 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Clutch: Twin disc, dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 2^ to 2V 2 miles per hour; high, 3K to 3y 2 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments : All spark plug gaps were adjusted to 0.025". At the end of the belt tests number 2 cylinder had a leaky exhaust valve. All valves were ground and carbon removed. The carburetor float valve was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 149. CLETRAC "40" 40-55. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 24 to May 10, 1928 Delco-Remy battery ignition system. Wheeler-Schebler AT carburetor. Pomona oil spray type air cleaner. Taco fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15", width 13", rated speed 851 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3.5 miles per hour; high, 5.5 miles per hour; reverse, 3 miles per hour. Comment: The battery cable insulation became defective on the rated drawbar test, causing the ignition to become shorted. The insulation was repaired with tape. Two grease cups on the clutch throw-out collar sheared off during the limber-up run. Oil was leaking from the clutch shaft in front of the transmission and also from the crankcase where the front drawbar is connected, at the end of the test. Test No. 150. CATERPILLAR "20" 20-25. Caterpillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 17 to 29, 1928. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "AE" carburetor. Pomona oil-spray type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly - ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11%", width 6U", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, clutch, own make, single-plate type. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Tractor Tests Rated Speeds : Low, 1.79 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3.07 miles per hour; high, 4.67 miles per hour; reverse, 2.35 miles - per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 151. ALLIS CHALMERS 20-35. Allis Chalm - ers. Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. June 18 to 26, 1928. Eisemann "GS4" magneto. Kingston "L" carburetor. Donaldson and Allis Chalmers centrifugal and oil-fiber type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted, crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8.5", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make expanding shoe type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2*/2 ; high, 3*4 ; reverse, 3'/4. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 152. TWIN CITY "FT" 21-32. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Octo - ber 1 to 8, 1928. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carbu - retor. Donaldson and own make, centrifugal and cypress - moss type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7y 2 ", rated speed 651 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.36; intermediate, 3.17; high, 4.45; reverse, 1.74. Comments: Before the maximum belt tests were run, the packing gland nut on the water pump was tightened. During the maximum low gear drawbar test, the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 153. JOHN DEERE "GENERAL PURPOSE" 10-20. John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa October 22 to 29, 1928. Fairbanks-Morse "John Deere" magneto. Ensign "BJ" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil - fiber type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Horizontal, "L" head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. "Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 6V 2 ", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 21/3; intermediate, 3^8 ; high, 41/3; reverse, 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 Comments: Before the operating maximum belt test, oil was found to be leaking from around the flywheel end of the crankshaft. This was repaired by readjusting the gasket and tightening gasket cover plate. Test No. 154. ADVANCE RUMELY "DO ALL." Ad - vance-Rumely Thresher Company, La Porte, Indiana. Octo - ber 29 to November 24, 1928. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Stromberg "Ml" carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil-fiber type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 5*4" rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speed, miles per hour: Low, 2.625; high, 3.75; re - verse, 2.875. Comments : On the rated and maximum load drawbar tests, it was necessary to improvise a method of locking the gear - shift lever in place to prevent the gears from slipping out of mesh under load. Test No. 155. CASE "L" 26-40. J. I. Case Threshing Machine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. March 16 to 27, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor. Own make oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8!4"&gt; rated speed 780 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2.5 ; intermediate, 3.25 ; high, 4.00; reverse, 2.75. Comments: Before the official belt tests were run, the weighted air valve in the carburetor was given a few thous - andths inch end clearance. Approximately 5/32 inch was removed from the crown of the belt pulley. Test No. 156. McCORMICK-DEERING (Model 15-30) 22-36. International Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. March 30 to April 9, 1929. Own make "E4A" magneto. Ensign "RW" carburetor. Pomona oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly - ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16.75", width 9", rated speed 593 R.P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Tractor Tests &lt;»3&amp;%J2Sf52i P 2 .a4 ri^e 5 : - d - d gear dri ™- Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 157. ROCK ISLAND "G2» 15-25 (Distillate) to^ a ytl92?° W C ° mpany ' Rock Island &gt; Im ™s- April 24 Splitdorf r "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor %ssL7igg;&amp;. mmr ** air cleaner - Gover^ ; wiS lgl ?s e Jt Ye l tica} ' "V head, mounted crankshaft length - 675 R^M P y: Diameter 16 "' 6i/ 2 ", rated speed cfe&amp;^c^ 1^ $pr s ' enclosed * ear drive - non l efhVhr4td;Se S rsri.7 h 5 OUr: 2 - 75 '' inte ™ e *ate, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 158. ROCK ISLAND "G2" 18-30 (Gasoline) S^SL Company ' Rock Island ' Illin ois. May 4 to 'Splitdorf "46T" magneto. Stromberg "M2" carburetor Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - 675 RPM PU " ey: Diameter 16 "' 6%", rated speed ci^^X.'SfW S ers ' enclosed gear drive - L ° W ' 2 - 7?; intermed -te, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 159. CATERPILLAR "15" 15-20 Catemillar 1929 F Company ' San Leandro, California May 9 to PoSoT-v'nrW"" m"!?,? 11^ 0 - E . nsi ? n " BeV " carburetor. SX^y-bSl^e 011 tyPG mr Cleaner - Governor ' own Engine: Vertical "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - 960BPM P y: Diameter 10 V2", width 6y 2 ", rated speed Ow^mafe s^SJe U^' enCl ° Sed CIutch: </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 1.985; intermediate, 2.58 ; high, 3.568 ; reverse, 2.06. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 160. CATERPILLAR "10" 10-15. Caterpillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 6 to 21, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Ensign "BeT". carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 9 1 /'". width 6 1 /'", rated speed 1050 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. Clutch, own make, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.02; intermediate, 2.59 ; high, 3.50 ; reverse, 2.07. Comments : After the limber-up run and before any of the official tests were made, the equalizer spring under front of engine was adjusted. Test No. 161. BAKER 43-67. A. D. Baker Company, Swanton, Ohio. May 16 to 24, 1929. Eisemann "G4" magneto. Stromberg "M4" carburetor. Pomona "Vortox" oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15 1 /*", width 8 1 /'", rated speed 774 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, single plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2 to 2.5 ; intermediate, none ; high, 3 to 3.5 ; reverse, 2.5. Comments: It was necessary to lock the gears in mesh during the high gear maximum and rated load drawbar tests. Test No. 162. MINNEAPOLIS 27-42. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. May 28 to June 11, 1929. American Bosch "ZR4Ed34" magneto. Stromberg "UTR" carburetor. Donaldson "Simplex" oiled-fiber type air cleaner. Governor, own make fly-ball type. . Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15 1 //', width iy*", rotates at crank - shaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : ' Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.69; intermediate, none; high, 3.42; reverse, 2.52. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Tractor Tests American Bosch "ZR4 Ed34" magneto. Strombertr "M4" S^*£S£ftJSR$Sr oil filter type * LaS - ciStrv^T sc ,tfii sc 2 ty^ vers ' enciosed * ear «™ - nonlfhiXiJo^rev^s^^ 1 "-" L ° W ' 3 ° 0; Mediate, turhSS^nnSn^'* 1 } 6 rated drawbar the fan belt was ugntened. During the low gear maximum drawbar test the gears slipped out of mesh several times. It was n?cessSv to lock the gear shift lever in place with a block of wood Test No. 164. WALLIS 12-20. The Massev-Harri&lt;» rnm pany, Racine, Wisconsin. June 18 to 27 1929 American Bosch "U4 Ed2" magneto. Kingston "L3V" zvfrLSfflg'&amp;irViY/h: 21/3; illto ™ ed " te . Comments: During the maximum drawbar tests thp ™,r SSS^asr" were removed " d «- «SSS5 Si: American Bosch "U4Edl» magneto. Kingston »L3" car Wa^sha^b^r fib6r 8ir Cl — C^f S^Ts C W^\ s f^T rS ' enCl ° Sed d" - 3.1 R 0fS d gr6 ed 0';?iv?rs P e ? r 3.9°0 Ur: L ° W ' Comments:^After the limber-up run and before the official tests were made, the clutch was adjusted, the felt walhe7s fn </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 242 the front wheels and the steering apparatus were adjusted to turn an equal amount in both directions. During the rated drawbar test the clutch was again adjusted. Test No. 167. CASE "C" 17-27. J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. August 12 to 19, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4ARS" magneto. Kingston "L3" car - buretor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter lO'/i", width 6i/«", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.30; intermediate, 3.28; high, 4.50; reverse, 2.59. Comments : During the maximum drawbar tests, the clutch was adjusted. During. the rated drawbar test, the fuel line to the carburetor became clogged up and was cleaned out. Test No. 168. HUBER "LIGHT FOUR" 20-36. The Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. August 19 to 24, 1929. Eisemann "GV4" magneto. Stromberg "M3" carburetor. Donaldson oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, Waukesha fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "L" .head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 17", width 8W\ rated speed 616 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch : Twin disc, dry plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.32; intermediate, none; high, 3.08; reverse, 1.83. Comments : During the maximum drawbar tests the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 169. CASE "CC." J. I. Case Company, Racine, Wisconsin. September 10 to 18, 1929. Robert Bosch "FU4" magneto. Kingston "L3V" carbu - retor. Own make, oil filter type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1014", width 6V2", rated speed 973 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Twin disc, plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.60; intermediate, 3.72; high, 5.14; reverse, 2.95. </seg>
            <seg id="p029"/>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Tractor Tests Comments: It was necessary to raise the oil level in the transmission approximately one inch for the belt tests. "IJ 1^^™ 0 ,' AL \l S CH ALMERS "UNITED" MODEL U. Ahs Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee Wisconsin. October 21 to November 7 1929 * ' Eisemann "G4" magneto. Schebler "HD" carburetor Donaldson, and own, centrifugal and oil filter type air cleaner Governor, Continental, centrifugal type cieaner. ™-o gl £ e L Vert"**. "L" head, mounted crankshaft length - s' R]PM P V: Diameter 10 "' width 71 / 2 ", rated speed c^&amp;L^iZ e t^ 2 tAt ers ' epclosed gear drive - 3vI^X e 5i S re^ S e, P 2 e U° Ur: L ° W ' 21/3; -termediate, Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 171. MONARCH "35"-30. Allis Chalmprs f ulfflSZt* C ° mpany ' Milwa «kee, Wiscontin NoVember oirfi^ 1111^ 04 '! 1 ? 1 /^ 0 - Ze «ith -6C" carburetor. Own Sik?Xb;nt^e trifUgal tyPe 8ir Cleaner - Goveraor ' «w» JS^%'bS^ " l " hGad ' m ° Unted cranksh «« length- O^Se, SffSS 8 * 5 ' end ° Sed d "' Ve - CIutch: wefanSjSJsiis 11 ' 5 Low&gt; L84: n JST™? ta: R UTin K the maxim "m drawbar tests the econ - andTad^o S Sldered'Sj beCame l0 ° Se * itS loWer end </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>