<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00020.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00020.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FROM January 1 to December 31</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">OF THE STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS TO THE GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FROM January 1 to December 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">/ </seg>
            <seg id="p003">To the H ir In am lunii statement beginning &gt;rable George L. Sheldon, Governor of the State of Nebraska nformity with Sections 4557 and 4574 of the Compiled f Nebraska for the year 1907, relating to the Inspection ating oils, I have the honor to submit herewith a detailed if the transactions of this department for the year 1907, anuary 1st and ending December 31st of said year. Very respectfully, A. B. ALLEN, </seg>
            <seg id="p004">A. B. Allen state Inspector of Oils TecuiiiM 1 E. Reye Merrill Stenographer Uncoil, Lineoli D. A. Chamberlin Deputy Inspector Beatric E. F. Grimes Deputy Inspector Omah| Otto Zuelow Deputy iMpector Schuvle, Omal Schviy Wm. M. Wheeler Deputy Inspector Fairfiehi H J - HuI1 Deputy Inspector Kearnc </seg>
            <seg id="p005">i:i:i-oi 1 priva r sale, w :ie of th t refused to i ved a number ught to my at tl l nto tf w. I demar 1 •My posi ( Union Pacific K. I s I OF STATE IXSI'KCTOR OF (»II.S. was appointed ai or of oils. May rd. 1!M&gt;, . sue. • and Otto Zuelow nson and B. C. Burns. m receded Deputy D. W. rimes succeeded Di Despain terminated h»-r tth, 1 1&gt; 0 T . Miss E 1 the retiring officers had and on June d to till the vacancy. A &gt;v mor . the illuminating fluids led from 122.71] an increase of eighteen li ii ing] ii ion tee of ten cent - le expense of maintain iingly increased. i increased six per ( after paying all ex Tin The amount turned lit US' of the department. 14 in 1907, an in - ail will be found on the nt. The reports in dt md fall th ijuestii n was repeatedly and gasoline shipped into the ;a viduals and corporations for their own use, and ;ible to our inspection laws and to the payuu onipanies. in particular, y of this department in the premises. The Co., in compliance with a compromise efT. ate inspectors some years ago, submitted one nonth for inspection and paid fees on the same, it further inspections though the said road re - cars each month. When this arrangement waa ntion 1 declined to accede to the one-tar-per - as I had uniformly held that all illuminating late, whether for sale or not, was liable to of the I'nion Pacific R. R. Co., as of other o inspect all the oil received and to collect &gt;n was upheld by an opinion delivered to me by 1, as appears in the following correspondence: stimed the dutiei Ed. A. Church. On the same day Win. M. Wh respectively, succeeded Deputies S. J. Job ill September nth, 1907. D. A. Chamberlln iu&lt; Hoyt, and on November 1st, UMiT. E. F. Qrl .May l»07. M enl has to deal, hav i*5 barrels in I :* tj 7 in 1906, to $1 ur inspection law f the railroad coi </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Lincoln. Nebr., September 16. 19 Hon. Wni. T. Thompson Attorney General Lincoln, Nebr Dear Sir Will you please give me your written opinion upon the folio ing point May a person purchase either kerosene or gasoline outside o -iate. and bring the same into the state strictly for his owi not for sale) without said kerosene or gasoline being llabU to our inspection laws? An early reply will be appreciated Very truly your; A. B. ALLEN State Inspector of Oil Lincoln. Xel.r.. Sept. 16. 1907 A H Allen. State Inspector of Oil Lincoln. Nebr I am in receipt of your communication of Sept. 16. submitting the following question and requesting an opinion thereon: ■May a person purchase either kerosene or gasoline outside of the state, and bring the same into the state strictly for bit not for sale) without said kerosene or gasoline being liable t&lt; our inspection laws?" Section 19. chapter 64, article 2, Compiled Statutes of 1 provides as follows "All products of petroleum known as gasoline, whether manu - factured in the state or not. shall be inspected as provided in this :&gt;efore being offered for sale pose, in the state." for consumption, or for any pur- f*he purpose of this act was of petroleum by requirinj constituted state authority. to protect the public against pro - a test to be made thereof by It is my opinion that a person I not purchase either kerosene or gasoline outside of the state ■ring the same Into the state, even for his own use or consump - without the same is submitted to inspection and Inspected ur department. It is in the use or consumption of these pro - rather than the sale or handling for sale where the greater </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE INSPECTOR OF OILS - )MPSOX A I ill il would T. ■\f met d in sin for Ai and ninant. for the reason ttiat «' heavily loaded with ptraflne or oiher solids. On tin an explosion is likely to occur. It is 1 he sale and use of low test, and Consequent!] Nebraska law was enacted. Our d tht* safety of the lives and property of tho; &gt;r C. I! A: Q U. K •to understand I which n splendid illuuiiuaut and yet t&gt;. that a lov ,f heat will ra </seg>
            <seg id="p008">H ■ in ii|i()ii the use of oil lumps than they did the guaranty The great bulk of the oil consumed in Nebraska is received r load lots at the several distributing stations which the oil companies have established over the state at convenient Some cities have more than one station. There are at it eighty-eight such stations, located in eighty-three cities ■wns. New stations are being established from time to time. I tral stations the oil companies distribute to adjacent - by wagon, and in some instances by railroad in barrels. The inspectors make inspections in car load lots at these dis - tributing stations, visiting each point one or more times each month needs of the service require. A few companies which do not .in distributing stations in the state ship to their customers in barrels, and •■] shipments have to be inspected individu - al &gt;' ■ However, less than one-twentieth of one an importi ina yet no provision is made for a quality ti IS () II n it may be suited that the lighter, or oil is the better its Illuminating properties but danger there \ to its use. The heavier, or less in oil is the poorer its Illuminating power but the to produce a sate burning fluid much of the natural illty of the oil is sail Hired. Whether or not the seemingly • ■ element* of Illuminating power and safety can both be (1 in the same oil 1 am not advised at this time. 1 hope one investigation along this line daring the pi. ir -nit of which will appear in the next annual report. The Hire will be in session at that time and 1 shall lie glad if I recommendation! which will result in such a change • law as will secure quality without sacrificing safety. Frequent complaints come to this office of smoky chimneys. Ighl and other accompaniments of poor burning oil. The of the complainant is that the oil is below test and hence debarred Iron \lmost invariably an investigation ■ Be that the oil, while a poor illuniinant. is well above our minimum a I and. under the law. is a saleable article. ide would give more attention to the condition of their lamps. inn and cleaning the burners and wicks occasionally, much Its would be secured. With n spec t to gasoline, our test is simply a gravity test. with ;&gt; hydrometer. Our standard is sixty-eight degrees. The r a gasoline is the more quality it carries, according to our line is exceedingly dangerous and too much care I be exercised in its use. The law wisely forbids its use illuminant. except under certain conditions, and provides severe penalties for transgreasic </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 i in advantage as the expense incident IV I and the expense will ti&gt; both kerosene and gasoline are high ninared with those of a number of the adjoining si comply are car f careli his department rej. ing the year a total of 768 barrels. During the previous two office show no rejections. 1 am confident and shippers and that "eternal vigilant the use of illuminating fluids ts give a summary of all the busine year. Th&gt;- details of each trati- in the respective monthly re- d to Your Excellency and w Audit itfull Not infrequently a g single barrel. rvice has a salu- A B ALLEX, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">1(1 dii.s i ok mi; vi:\i:. iimit. itv months. A \ I I'll | 96 1 i for the C. B. *i Q. R. K r. and on r, :md on 1 1 ■ barrels insitected for iIih r. I 3 . I! It ivniain unpaid, tlit- companies disputing their SI MMAKV OK KKC'KII*TS KOK TDK VKAK, lfM»T i\ni&gt;i &lt; i h&gt;\s \\i&gt; i{i:&lt; i:ii'is &lt;&gt;i iiik siaik insi'kitois ok 1 K i pi S. I I "ft)] on hand, January, 1! </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 UlSltl KSKMKNTS OK TIIK STATE INSPECTOR OK OILS KOI{ THE YK..IK, IIH.7, IIV \iO\THS. Salaried of In- _ _ M ,. spector, five y""" 1 ""-' • n&lt;1 Pni.l to State Total D Month-* iLiMit^. ....( Omce hxi-u- t.—..-........ bur- ," I I'M , 11*" I ' ■ I tpputimi ami OltiM hxprn- Treasurer bur -* m •• n t - for the Month ap her $ ::r&gt;4 1 2 $ 1545.S1 $ 21 1 n!«7. 1 7 6 1S7.C1 106! \ 1 Ml . |ll 1 1 K -' : If .Inly 736.66 . fil 17»1.1« August ::■■ ».21 Kl l.rtu mber 73« 21 i 1515. II r 441 121 . nber 7S( 4"7 13*1 iber 73( 27011. in $S79S.:.9 $ 3 '.9 »:JS71.«6 $13845.34 »2fi:.l SI MMAKV. SI MMAKV Tulal receipts for tl 127,(15.51 I27.«1 Tmal di' 'Hirseinents for the Ml - •■ S15.5I Balance i&gt;n hand. January, inns $ 1,160.01 Ba t l.i COMPARATIVE STATKMKXT OK TIIK IXSI'KXTIOVS \\n |{K CKIITS OK TUB STATK. IXSI'KCTOIt OK OIKS KO|{ CKIITS OF THE STATK. IXSI'KCTOK OK OII.S K»I THK VKAKS KMili AMI im»7. VKAKS HMXi AMI I1KI7. Barrfl- Bnrnl- Tutnl Bhl-. P\MS Col- Totnl I K Kh r Total Bhl-. Fee- Col- Tot*. 1 fi - in i-l I'll IfCt-il fi .r I I Approved Rej«-rtp&lt;! ln-p. . lected for i : Approved Rej«-rte&lt;! ln-iv let-t»»d for I ...222.711 Nun.- 222,712 t22.271.20 I22.» Not 712 122.271.20 $2 . . . 2*1 .7::.", 7«0 l \TI\ K. STAI KMKM Of THR Dlsltl KsKMKMS ol TtU KTATK INSPKCTOH OK iNU KOIt THK VKAKS IWHi AM) I WIT. Salaries of In- «, .. specUir. B»e T /JU el '¥ Paid u &gt; state T"'* 1 D ' J - DepaliM and Other hxprn- Treasurer hurs»meuts &lt;&gt;i.'rapli»T ~ r&gt; COMPARATIVE STAI KMKM UK THE Dlsltl KsKMK.VTS ol INK HTATK I\SI&gt;K( TOH OK OHM KOK THK VKAKS IWHi AMI 1WI7. Hag and Pajd U) state T , )tal D e r.ipou- Treasurer hursainei \e ... .1- $.!.fi:.n.i l $ 9 $21 " 1 $ 9 $21 " ! 1.66 15.34 lnc-ivasp of 19n7 inspectioni over 1906. is p f .r nal Increase of 1907 traveling and office expense account over IImiH amount turned into stati j.er </seg>
            <seg id="p012">r- n s. i "i v: J: i &amp;a M x^M CSV X &amp; :*' J £ X &gt; c Z ** E "c IT &gt;; .^^a-Z v. ■s. /./S.os-,ix&lt;2 H I i J | I ! H. 2. t s H </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 OIL MISTItllU Tl\(. STATIONS IV Till: STATE OK \Klti;\sK\ TOGETHER WITI1K THK ASSKIXMKVT OF TKKKITOIJV TO BACH OK THK l&gt;K|»l I V ST.ITK INSI'KCTdltH. hav xisiiiu niiilv ilivi rst District- D A. Chamberlin, Deputy, Beatrice, Nebr Nel Ashland Auburn Aurora Beatrice Swai Nebraska City Vulpar Pawnee City Weening \\ ( ward Wvim David ( r Yc lia. Xebr &gt;n oiith 11 ird District Otio Zuelow, Hnpiity. Scbuylei \ii phrf Alhi Niobrara KUidinfleld Norfolk Wain Wavi ON. West I Fourth District Win. M. Wheeler. Deputy. Kairfleld. Nelir Beaver ( Hoi Mind Stratum i'ifth District- 11. J. Hull. I puty. Kearney, Nebr K Sargent Broken Bow ScoMsbliiff -Mason Ci Sidne Central City Spaldln Columbus O 8t. Paul •r 1 H Chadron Fremont Howella Plainview Geneva Guide Rock Rlue Hill Cambridg Curtis Wauneta Alii Callaw North Plait Ravenna </seg>
            <seg id="p014">i / I. ■i s. s. x ■J. 1 I " i i • 5h PQ </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 STATEMENT KNOWING THK M'MItKK OK BARREL8 OF KERO- SENE AND GASOLINE INSPECTED AT EACH STATION IX THE STATE IX KIM. lttO The Standard Oil Co. has a station at each of the points named The National Refining Co. has a station at Omaha, Fremont, Hastings and York, the latter having been opened in November. be Marshall Oil C has but one station, that at Lincoln Omaha and South Omaha Inspections are combined in the Omaha figur 1&lt;1 ned in March. Alma, Emerson and tation «'l Stratton in Jun Valp and Wauneta in July. Ainsworth and ai Mason City in A gust Station Kerosene. Gasoline. Total • Ainsworth Ainsworth 54a Albion 1307 Albion Alliance 1139 10-18 IU7 • Alma l«t 470 939 Alma Ashland 1073 669 1741 Ash land 1073 669 1741 Auburn 1236 1006 Auburn 1236 10«5 Aurora !» 1 .1 low;! 2008 1") low;! 2008 Beatrice 1669 2" 19 .1 7 I 8 Beatrice 1669 2 "19 .1 7 I 8 Beaver City 1320 1 1 ."&gt; 4 2 4 7 4 Heaver City 1320 1 1 ."&gt; 4 2 4 7 4 Bloomfield !M7 m&gt;7 17'.4 Bloomfield 17 17.-.4 Bloomington !t.".4 7".". 16-"&gt;9 Kloomingto St.". 4 16-"&gt;9 Blue Hill Blue Hill &gt;| Broken Bow 1 :: 1 .1 Hit Broken Bow l :: l S 1 1 4 Callaway 2:! 4 Callaway 234 Cambridge 629 i:&gt;68 ('ambridKt . ... !»:!!* 629 i:&gt;68 Central City 70S 1 r, J 8 Central Ci Chadron 10.14 1853 Coleridge 1192 10*1 2285 Columbus 1416 1170 2586 Columbus 1311 HP64 2375 Curtis 1163 0 1163 David City 1128 1340 2768 David Cit&gt; 1428 1340 2768 Douglas 693 1613 Douglas 122 693 1613 Edgar 1372 1605 2977 Edgar 1372 1605 2977 • Emerson 477 1072 Emerson 477 1072 Fairbury 1460 1571 3036 Fairbury 1460 1571 3036 Falls City 149". 1418 2913 Falls City H»:, 1418 291 Fremont 3070 3720 6790 Fremont 3070 3720 6790 Fullerton Hi!*:. 1938 1938 Geneva u7". 1 409 Geneva . ii 7". 1409 Grand Island 12s:j 2772 Grand Island 12s:j Guide Rock 1019 1088 Guide Rock Hit« 1088 21 Hastings 4:;6:i 3607 7970 Hastings Hebron 1243 1141 2384 Hebron Herman I32S 1719 302 669 MS Howells 1 1SI Humphrey 981 &amp; i 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Station Kerosene G a sol in Kearney 1*37 Lexington 1187 183 1187 1063 .» 1 1 it 9 L] oni 1228 1231 Mason City 196 Millard 1 16i 10 70 Minden HKii 978 McCook is«| 86 Nebraska City i»gg 1844 Niobrara 620 :!2i Norfolk 16 7.". 1 2 7 3 North Plattn 1344 1446 Oakdalt 1188 949 Omaha 14881 ONeill 642 429 1 1 88 s Pawne« City 1382 1091 Plainview 1 1 :, s 880 mouth 848 941 lit:.!* 7:si Ravenna 1087 Sargent 823 47: S&lt; huyler 477 4 7.". -bluff 117:', - 1211 1 174 Sidney 828 360 • SpaldiliR 597 .". 1 ."i Bpencer 964 :, g :, St. Paul 1 1 8 .'. 813 Stratton 3 9H 313 Stromsburg r04 1 :'. 1 6 1028 Sutton 679 948 Swanton h»anton s , - T« uniseh 1 «4S 586 1248 1068 Valparaiso 196 Wahoo 1 2 .". 1 1182 Wauneta 388 234 «'ayne ,,,;; ing Water 630 West Point 8 7 Wood River 71 s 1067 715 615 Wvmore 1064 941 York 15 6.-, 1470 Miscellaneous 42 177 Total </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>