<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  GROWING HOGS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">M No. 2. ersity of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION nv NEBRASKA. Volumk XIX. Article VI GROWING HOGS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. imental Substation, North Platte, Nebraska. P. SNYDER, Superintendent. E. A. BURNETT. Director. June, 1907. HOG HOUSE SET INTO SIDE OF HILL. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Experiment No. I. Comparison ol lisht anil medium r Ill for pi jn alfalfa pas Experiment No. II. Comparison of lisht. medium and full ra grain, wi ar Experiment No. III. Compari ar Experiment No. IV Pi* Experiment No V \\ Experiment No. VI. I-' Experiment No VI Experiment No IX Hetl Experiment No. X Experiment No. XI. Comparison of nm- ■mnu fattening Alfalfa Pasture for Ho* Conclusions ERRATA IN BULLETIN In Bulletin No. 95, page M, Table III. pi; read 4 pecks instead of 2 pecks. In sam&lt; c* v rjorin i#-*n t 11 \" 1 1 \**' </seg>
            <seg id="p003">&gt; I 1 ii I ;;: i l GROWING HOGS IN WESTERN NEBRASKA. LPEBINTKNDEUT KXI'KRIMKXTAI. SIliSTATloN . NOBTH I'LATTK, NKISUASKA. March, I!t(l4, 15 sows, about to farrow, were purch;i were from grade Dnroc-Jersey sows ami a registered We have continued to use the progeny of \ id registered males, and also have been adding vs of approved type and breeding. For the past r hog berd has ■umbered from loo to ;&gt;00. Of the 50 rrowing in the spring of 1907, lio are registered and ainder arc li ii^li grades. It lias been deemed advisable only one tweed, as the work of this Station is confined to methods of raising and tests of different rations. •oblcins eaa beat be studied where all the animals in rimeiit arc of one breed. M xperimenta conducted have been mainly to determine t profitable method of producing [&gt;ork with the at and testing the feeding value of grain* commonly n the count rv. A first-class plant for such operations built up as necessity demands and funds permit. .a. nation. — All feed was weighed to bogs which irere riments. and a record of the lead was kept. Each lot X1M as weighed every two weeks, under similar condi - i feed, water, and time of weighing. So far as pos- ■ach lot was weighed on three consecutive days at the ing and end of experiments. ii iny of the following tables the term "per cem ii When we use this in relation to a ration, we mean a d percentage of the live weight of the hogs. A ration itl per cent corn is one pound of corn daily to each 100 n. i. e., a hog weighing loo lbs. receives l lb. of ran of day when on a one per cent ration. The amount of fei'd HTccted after the weighing, at the end of each two-weeks </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 period, this weight being used as a basis for figuring the ra tion for the next two weeks. In all calculations, unless otherwise stated, the on! taken into consideration is that of the grain consumed. N. aecooat is made of alfalfa, unless specifically state*!. Th profit or loss is obtained by subtracting the cost of grain eaten from the value of the increase in weight, assuming the ing prices, which are about the average: Corn bu., barley 30 cents per bu., per bu. i, shorts 88 cents pei lbs. dinner 25 cents per bu. (4(1 100 lbs., and hogs |5.50 per In each table the rate of duce 100 lbs. gain are given tin and the feed required From these two items, th for a given time can be readily figured at the mat of grain and hogs in any loci il t\ In discussing the results of a feedins experiment ri tion as to how to compare results of different metho ing. so as to find which is th nost pi </seg>
            <seg id="p005">0 5 itiuii. The cost of growing the pig until it the experiment should determine somewhat the hog should be marketed. It i. - pig at the market price of hogs. The pig than that amount. Again, the labor gs, the use of pastures and htiildings, the and other diseases, and the interest on the a hearing on the profit and the gains. It grain required for a certain number of ly one of the many factors in the cost. secure a statement which will combine all show the exact cost at any given time in the iiinal. The profit on a given Dumber of 1 oniliines the cost and time required in pro- ertain gain. These in turn include the items &lt;&gt;f red per pound of gain, cost of grain, price of lings. if. and risk. Therefore the item of most ae - ion would seem to he the profit per hog per has been used as the unit of comparison in profit in pork production id medium ration* of corn for piya on alfalfa pasture. 1904, from July lt.th to Oct. 22d, thrw u h were run on alfalfa pasture and fed ra- All lots were quite uniform and of equal weigh Lot 1 was fed ' U lb. ( orn daily per UK) lbs. of weight of pigs. Lot i' was fed I 1 - lbs. corn daily per 100 lbs. of weight of Tot \ W* 1^ II hI *^1 lll^ |&gt;a]M| ll *1 1 1 V 1 M *!' 10(1 lll^ of \Vl*l I'll t l^f EXPERIMENT XO. I. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 w The amount of feed was corrected to conform to t he weigh at the end of each two-weeks period. During the 1 1 x the experiment, the average daily gain of the pigs in Lot 1 .L's |h., in Lot i'. .:!, |h.. ;iik1 in Lot :{. .."H Hi., increasing ;i percentage of grata increased in the three lots. Tlie am percentage of increased in the three lots. Tlie amoun of grain required to produce l(ti» H&gt;s. gain was, by Lot 1, l-l of grain required to produce LOO His. pun was, by Lot 1 U.S.; by Lot 2, I'l'J lbs.; and by Lot :!. 332 lbs.; showing th H.s.; by Lot 2, l':^ lbs.; ;md by Lot ::. 332 lbs.; showing the lighter the grain ration, the less grain was required f tlie lighter the grain ration, the less grain was require* KMi His. gain. The cost of loo His. gain was, in Lot 1. &gt; ion His. gain. The eoal of 100 H&gt;s. gain was, in Lot 1. f in Lot i'. |1J»; and in Lot ::. sj.iin. The cost of the : in Lot i'. 11.39; ami in Lot ::. *2.08. The cost of th eaten in producing KM» lbs. gain with the lot fed eaten la producing loo lbs. gain with the lot fed _ 1.30 ll»s. more than with the lot fed '/&gt;95 snid (&gt;'■) cents i IJSO ll»s. more than with the lot fed l ■/ i and (i!) cents than with the lot fed I 1 -'.. Tlie price received per 1 than with the lot fe&lt;l I 1 -'.. Tlie price received per h corn eaten l»v Lot 1 was S-J.S4 ; l.v Lot L\ $1.38: and bv T corn eaten by Lot 1 was s-j.s4 ; by Lot 2, $1.38; and by T fO.Hi*. All these fignrea indicate tliat the lighter the ; $0.!H\ All these figures indicate that the lighter ration, the cheaper the gain. Bui when we consider ration, the cheaper the gain. I&gt;nt when we consider the pi we tind that the daily profit per pig was, in Lot we find that the daily profit per pig was, in Lot 1, 1.3 &lt;■ in Lot 1'. 1.5 cents; and in Loi .".. 1.7 cents. The profit di in Lot l'. 1.5 cents; and in Lot .",. 1.. cents. Th the 14 weeks on each im.lt was, in Lot 1. |1.28 the 14 weeks on each im.lt was, in Lot 1. -^1.1'S; in Lot and in Lot ."&gt;, fl.64. The ]iii:s receiving '-'- did not do enough to warrant a repetition of the same tout. They I enough to warrant a repetition of the same test. '1 decidedly stunted appearance. Lot - was no4 as thrif decidedly stunted appearance. I. most farmers would demand in profitable feeders. Inn in experiments _'. grain on pasture h </seg>
            <seg id="p007">a 7 I fa p i 1 Lot Lot &gt;rn lXf corn 2 17 its !T 17 100 18 1 1-Jl 332 (XI i, corn (ITS i.l.i 4.11 3.43 l.M 1 4-1 015 .017 of corn eaten... 2.81 1.38 .'.rl iten •Jl .tilt 17 -J7 86 isture is not charged in above table. If I ate of ;!" h for pasture lor the tin* a the light grain ration consum* heavier grain rations. If we charge the gradu ■in light grain. 30 cents for those on nie- those on heavy grain, the cost of lno lbs. gain Lot 1, $2.44; Lot 2, $2.22; Lot 3. $2 EXPERIMENT NO. IF. i medium and full ration* of grain, tcitk growing and fattening hog*. In the simiincr of 1006, thrve lots of thirty pigf each were selected to lest the relative profit in growing and fattening f" :&gt; on alfalfa, with a light, a mediiun ami a full grain ra - n. The plan was t&lt;&gt; run these pigs on a different percentage grain until green alfalfa was no longer available in the fall, and then to put all lots on a full ration, marketing each lot when it had reached near the average weight of 225 ll»s. per 1.39 fc2.08 JOper of 100 lbs. gain would be as follows Lot 1 $2.70. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 O run ing Hogs in Wetttm Nebratka. i ii in 1 re. '1 E After the hogs were removed from the alfalfa ii it ion was changed. from corn to «".(»;, shelled c ground rye. As there was required a larger an to finish Lots 22 and 2:i on the lighter rations t the full ration after the change was made in tin vide permanent winter quartet ration. In order to present the results clearly vided the experiment into three periods. Pert Pel ftime the pigg were on green alfalfa: I ween the green pasture and full feed. I'KKIOI) 1. -!l ■ 22 was fed 1 II,. corn ] 23 was fed i' | |,s. corn ■ 21 was fed a full ration &lt; ration was shelled corn \ During the seventeen W eel. daily gain of each pig in Lot ind in Lot 21, 1.08 lbs. The an His. ; and by Lot 2 1. :!:!() ll.s. The cost of 100 lbs. train was. Lot -2-2. 90.83; in Lot I'. 1 ?. $1.38; and in Lot 21. si'.in. Th price received per lm. of con eaten by Lot 22 was s: Lot 23, |1.40; and by Lot 24. |0.91. All these items show i»micii im; grwn pasture ami 1111 quarters; Pt-riod :&gt; is the finishing on full feed. pasture. dnco 100 lbs. gain was. by Lri I'l'. 1 P percentage of the grain fed to those lots was vet this in so far as possible, we have figured r\ same price per pound as corn. Figuring in this ■should be favorable to the hogs receiving the most r ration of r&gt;o\ ground rye and 509! corn should giv .miiis (MT 100 His. of grain than a ration entirely of to Wintry siornis came much earlier than usual and he hogs in summer shelters. It required three neekt </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 give the cheaper gains. Tin 1 un ration ounted le avenge daily profit per pig was, in ti cents; and in Lot 24, 3.»&gt; cents rhe average profit for the IT weeks on each pig was, for those sj us; in Lot -21}, *3.10; and in Lot 24, $4.27. While iuired about 2\ - times as much corn to produce Umi as Lot 22 required, yet it returned nearly 1.6 times profit as Lot 22, during the time on the experiment. / torn for pigs on alfalj\i Hdcd Oct. j- J Lot 2-J. Lot 13. Lot 24 I corn :t to 4 :»i so 1 119 Hit 11» per pis 101.6 13D.S 171 i-2A 4"J.4 i'2.i .-,;.:{ 7.").i l».8 66 1.08 132 230 ii « 1 l.W 15.50 per cwt.. 4.67 I.W S.« «t 10 oai .!«; ■_\:s:i 1.40 !»i 80.45 W.Oa 128* ach lot after experiment began x pasture is not charged in the above table. If these flat rate of 35 cents per pig for pasture for the time cost of 100 lbs. gain would then be as follows: 84; Lot 24. $2.37. hogs on the light grain ration consumed more r grain ratioil. If we charge the gradu- those on light grain. 35 cents for those on me - r those on heavy grain, the cost of 100 lbs. gain »s: Lot 22, |1.70; Lot 23, $1.84; Lot 24, $2.29 Period 2, Oct. 20 to Nov. 10, 1906 Ration, shelled corn, soaked rye and alfalfa hay During this time, Lot 22 gained 190 H&gt;s., eating 1,512 H»s. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Growing Hoys in Western Nebraska. i i Bund 336 lbs. of rye, and requiring ( J7l* lbs. grain . gain. There was ■ loss of $1.08 on the grain eaten KT.'&gt; gained o&lt;io lbs., eating 1,158 lbs. corn and 426 Ibr d requiring 526 lbs. grain for 100 ll&gt;s. gain. 'Phi - -'&gt;.»&gt;:&gt; on the grain eaten. K,ot i!4 gained 010 lbs., eating ;&gt;.ll7U lbs. corn and ,"&gt;74 lb , reqoiring &lt;i."!o lbs. grain for KM) lbs. gain. This gave lii of *!&gt;.."&gt;! on ill,- grain eat en. It will be noted that all gains were made with an nnnsu large amount of grain. This was due largely to the effe&lt; storms, which tame before the hogs wen' in winter quar and with Lot 23 was also due to too light a grain ration a the green alfalfa was no longer available. During this [»&lt;• r K, the cost of Inn 11, s. gain would then !'•■ as follow l.ot Z\. | rye was red snaked Inn no! ground. Tins also increa (■( ■ &lt;&gt;-i of production. Pekiod3, Nov. iq imii. Beady you M.vrkkt. Lot :U reached an average of l'l's His. on Dee. s. 190 i':: reached an average of SM lhs. on Feb. i'. 1!m»7. reached an average of l'.".."» His. on Feb. 11. 1907. Tabi.k III. — Pigs on li^lit. medium, iim/ pigs in lot ■ lavs in experiment ■t weight, His. per pig . . fir-t gain daily Grain per 100 lbs. gain, lbs if 100 lbs. gain, rye and corn each figured '•'t cents per bushel Profit on 100 lbs. gain, hogs $~&gt;.M per cwt Profit on each pig daily .. 125 108 . . 1 1 . 26 .. 167 500 ea is.18 w.i 8.32 l.i 0.027 t of alfalfa hay is not charged in mate that one-fourth of the food consumed wa the above table. If we M as alfalfa hay valued at $5 If. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">/ l&gt; ening period, Lot i*2, the pigs which liatl ilfa and a light gnus ration, reqaired 4«iT . produce 100 ll»s. gain, at the rate of 1.:U lbs. pig. £ivin&lt;; a profit of ."?.."; cents per head daily. lw pigs that had been grown on a Medium grain ra - alfalfa, produced 160 lbs. gain from ."&gt;&lt;)!&gt; ll»s. grain, e of 1.26 lbs. gain daily per pig, giving a profit of daily per pig. Daring a much shorter finishing Lot '24, the pijjs which had Imh-ii grown on a full grain ind alfalfa, required 7S7 lbs. grain for 106 lbs. gain it the rate of .S Ib. gain' per ]&gt;\&lt;z daily, giving a daily M'i- pig of 1.3 cents. With Lot 24. this was during only four weeks of the fattening jM'riod when the ho&lt;rs iff finished for market, while with the other lots these cover a much longer time. Hence the results of this taken alone, should not he regarded as comparable. mparison in Table TV, where the gains and the profits en for the entire period from July 1&lt;». 1007. until the flg: 2. Hogs grown on medium grain ration until Octobi &gt;wed by a full grain ration, and marketed February 15, 1907; weight pounds. F </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Bwcnt to market weighing approximately i'iT) 1!&gt; I a complete .statement of the profit* under &lt;1 of finding. Profit on end l'mfit on eacl R'e receivt fit on lot 1 The cost of alfalfa pasture and the first three lots were charged a on pasture, and Lot 16, 25 cents each foi charged for the estimated alfalfa hav consumed" th« would then be as follows: Lot 22. $ 6, $2.7 If the cost of pasture were ma ■ nts for Lot 2G. charging for alfal of 100 lbs. gain would then Lot 24, $2.99; Lot 2C, $2.77. Lots 22 and 23 sold on the D figured at the uniform average mark Ll&gt;s. grain eaten nts for tliose on medium grai -Lois a ana Zi sold on the Denver mar dred. In order to make comparisons, all loi </seg>
            <seg id="p013">1 Lot 24 Ihis 1 r on Lot order t rown on a light grain ration of ley averaged 100 lbs. and then finished 1 for the entire period .83 ll&gt;. each per &lt;&gt; cents per head. Those in Lot 23, ;raiu ration of -' \\ of their weight until weight of 1-0 His. and then finished on lined .87 lit. each per day. They required :5'.U r 100 lbs. gain, returning a daily profit of 2.7 The pigs in Lot 24, grown and finished on a eh 100 lbs. gain, and gave a daily profit of grain ration (30 pigs i gave a profit of $17l».io or a profit of $0.78 per day. rain ration I 30 pigs i gave a profit of $17'.U&gt;! i ration (30 pigs) gave a profit of fl68JM in ►rofit of (1.02 per day. (»."&gt; days longer than Lot 21, and gave a more; or stated in another way, bj feedi &gt;ti instead of a heavy grain ration, there was 1.10 ■oping 30 hogs &lt;;."&gt; days, si 1.10. The interest received for Lot 2 1 at 8 per cent for &lt;&gt;."&gt; days rhis would leave s.~».77 for the care and labor ding, wear and tear on buildings and sheds, I hogs for •»."&gt; days. If we compare Lots 2-'5 ve shall find that Lot 23 was kept 56 days longer for it' sio. 71. The interest on the money received from mi. 10 for the care and labor of keeping, wear and sheds and risk on :&gt;0 hogs for 66 days. 6 of Experiment III is also shown in the summary in i give a comparison of a still more extended feeding which ran 250 days, from July 28, 1906, to April 13, lbs. of grain for 100 lbs. gain, ami gained 1.13 U&gt;s. each daily. They al roflt of |0.81 per day. ■&gt;i; dara wonld have araonnted to $4.&lt;&gt;1 a </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 1!&gt;0i, with a continuous light grain ration until tin 1 In this loi tin- daily profit per pijj runs slightly Lot -22 and the total profit per pig slightly below an\ three lots with which it is compared. Had Lot 26 to the final weight of the other three lots, the dillei have heen si ill greater KXI'EKISIKXT NO. Ill Vontparixon o/ i 1 i , • „„,/ gkort*. &lt; tin dim n In a E&lt;- lois of :;o pigs each w&lt;-n- run in alfalfa \&gt; i to Oct. LMi. 1906. .'."&gt; was fed i" , corn. M was fed 2'/, grain, of which 7.". -'7 was fed a full ration, &lt;&gt;f which 7~&gt; « lorta, amounting to between :'. ', and : vi.usi s ( m;\ and Siiiiuts. - -Tin- pii: - &lt;&lt;1 .1 Hi. uioi-ccarli per da \ than ihusc f,.«l a Lot 25 was fed Lot 26 was fed Lot i'7 was fe, coni ami L'.I' , shot-is in I, loo His. gain with i'-! His. h percentage of &lt; oi-n and shorts. The daih nroi Lot i'."). fed corn, was 2.8 cents, and in Lot 2( shorts, 2.1 cents. The pi it per pij: in li' w cents more in Lot 23 than in Lot i'&lt;;. T M gain was :',, cents lews in tin »t fed corn. K\ Eison in the results of this test is in favoi l corn and shorts. MEDIIM VKKSl S I'il.l. IJaTKiN OF ('(PUN AMI SlKlRTs. &lt; poring Lot I'C. fed l&gt;&lt; , grain, and Lot l'7. fed a full ration amounting to between :'.', and 1 ,. we find that the dai gain per pig in Lot 26 was ..-,:{ II,. *nd in Lot i»7 .84 I ii thai tin' grain required to produce loo lhs. gain in f was V.H\ lhs. and in Lot :!7 273 Ibg, These fignren agree with </seg>
            <seg id="p015">1 in emphasizing the fact that with the ms there is required \em grata to produce of KM) lbs. gain in Lot 20 was fl.45 s. Tin- profits per day, however, are all in i. The daily profit per pig was .it cert rotit per pig in 12 weeks Hi cental more in Lot than in Lot 2«. fed a medium ration. d per hn. corn fed to Lots 26 and 27 wire si .1:1 regpectirely, Hjiurinjj corn and shorts as hav- &gt;f corn for pigs on alfalfa pasture. Kx, &gt; bt-^iin July 2$ and ended October &lt;?o, 1906. and nded October to, 1906 Tot B. Lot 26. Lot I Lot 2.").! Lot 2t&gt;. I sture and i%gm. 2* corn -J? grain 3to4*nrn- orn } 4 shorts 1 4 shorts 30 31) 30 "ritnent *^ *** tnent sl sl :lU.lhs.pcrpiK 1«-?, - 53.1 41.3 H.fl B.« 108.8 :».3 | 38.2 531 I 41 3 : 70.6 y 6.3 .68 _ 84 .63 .68 _ M gain, pounds l' :! 196 - T ' 5 ain. corn 30 cents per bu., shorts ,,00 n. corn 30 cents per bu., shorts lbs . * 108 $ 1.4.) I 1.88 )rn^ Ce^ Per . hU :: Sll ° rtS $1.06 •!.« H.88 $ 1.08 * l.» * 1-88 n W^ V a.w v ■*■ • ■" v * •TT n/hogsiySOperewt 4.42 4.05 S.flj ;ain. hogs 16.50 per cwt L* 4 n. hogs 15.50 per cwt 4.42 4.03 '.'.'.'.'.. 0028 oio-Jl - .. 70.50 53.70 71 2.35 1.79 2.55 (lai]v " '.'..'..'. 0028 oio-Jl 0 028 0.0-J1 0.03 &lt;lal&gt; .. TO.50 r^.TO 76.70 lOOlta. of grain fed S.W *•» *•« Olbs.of grain feil f » »•» *« £fcd".'.'.!l...... 2.75 : bu. of corn !•" »•■• 11J )U. of corn 1" *•"■ 11J alfalfa pasture is not charged in above table. If these falfa Dasture is not charged in above table. If these harged in above table. If these ilfalfa pasture is not •d a flat rate of 25 cents per pig for the time on this ex- a Hat rate of 25 cents per pig for the time on this ex - of 100 lbs. gain would then be as follows: I. st of 100 lbs. gain would then be as follows: Lot 25, U.01; Lot 27. $2.23. n a heavy grain ration, were charged only 20 cents for pas 1 100 pounds gain would be $2.16 in figuring the price received per bushel of corn the returns from i and shorts are figured at the same price per cwt.. which, tho only an mate, seems to be the most accurate method available. feeding value in producing gains. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">X — -I t - r x &gt; &gt; tL V. V* V. &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p017">1 \ wh I r I pare the results of all pigs receiving grain ami iv. and use the daily profit per pig as the unit of that the most profitable ratiou has be.-n n the light or medium rations. The low- otit per pig was 1.3 cents from a ration of i and the highest profit ."!.(» cents from a full ra- Lot 24). The daily profits range quite c grain fed. In the summary of these be noted that the gain from the MM ration was in 1906 than in 1904. This seems to be due. thriftier condition of the pigs and possibly to grading up bj the use of good males. xperinients carry the pig from the time it weight is. to ."iO lbs. until it weighs from SO lbs. to 170 lbs.. tg on the percentage of grain fed. They give no indr - f the cost of producing a 50-lh. pig nor the cost of hogs for market. EXPERIMENT NO. IV din ration with n $kori fattening period. : the effect of a medium grain ration on the eatmeiit of Lot 36 may furnish interesting data. onsisting of 30 pigs, was fed in Experiment No. 8 2S to Oct. 20, L906, on a 23 grain ration consist- corn and ' \ short*. This constituted Period I of nt III. ag Period II. from Oct. 20, 190«&gt;, to March 2, 1907, » •ived 'I 1 ', shelled corn except during the first twenty this period, when they received 231 lbs. of rifc eh is counted as corn. hiring Period III, from March 2 to April 13, 1907. rived :V, shelled corn and reached a weight of 215 lbs. or •mximately the selling weights of Lots 22, 23 and 24. hiring Period I they ran on alfalfa pasture. Dur : ng Po - ls J and 3 they pastured upon a field of winter rye and lived alfalfa hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 :: th :;:: of Table VII.— Pigs on light grain ration u f&gt; Dale of period. f3%k oc^, *ar. 2.1807 li l'.i Ration Table VIII girea the results of three test without grain. Lot 4 was composed of 14 hogs that wen a year old, but light in weight and thin in flesh. Tliev grown on alfalfa, with a very light grain ration. It \v noted that during l&gt;i months, when they received do they gained .5 lh. each per day. Lots 5 and 28 were made «p of brood sows from whirl J.igs had been weaned for some time. These rave a dailv of .43 Ib. and .53 lb. respectively. The average of three ti including 42 hogs, gives ; ,n average daily gain per ho I pi);s in lot... . :!(} No. davs in experiment.. i'j-j ',' Av. last weight per j. .,, Av. first •• •• " y. gain per pig 4 &gt;v. " " " ilail •, Grain per 100 lbs. gain 41 1 i r^ Cost of 1U0 lbs. gun .... $ 1 4.-, * •&gt; 57 j Profit on 10U lbs. gain uring hogs 16.50 per lfl 1,1 C, Profit on each pi^. . I.79 _ " ' " " *uly.. Profit on each lot 68. 70 7i 1 Price received per bn- of corn j .-, j : ! ! '231 lbs. shorts fed between Oct. 2"th and Nov. 1( -If we assume that one-fourth of the total dry fo, the pigs were taken from the alfalfa pasture cons ued at lo.Oii per ton. the cost of 100 lbs. gain during th. would be $2.91 and $3.57 respectively. If each pi for pasture during Period 1, the cost of 100 lbs gain fo EXPERIMENT NO. V. Hog* on alfalfa pasture— no am </seg>
            <seg id="p019">May t KM) 11 i 100 l'iill riu'iv v i. This is ltv mature hogs, thin in Utah, I water. Wil t Lot 17 to Aug. A &lt; kt Julv 27 fa .1 it;, nmi 22, l ( .t04 ao, 1900 11 111 is da lit. pounds.. 221 240 t ponndi KM l'.'l 190 34 XI 60 4:; .53 EXPERIMENT NO. VI 1 Lot No. L".). 1 •njx on full ration corn ami alfalfa i»i*ttin . 0 to .July 15, IMC, a lot of from 17 to 1M&gt; bogs, it 130 His. each, vere fed a full ration of enm ran of a 5-acre lot of alfalfa. The total w l 1 1 into tin' hVlil was LV.a") lbs. They ate T.it.'.J nl gained 1,615 lbs. This gaia was at the rate v for each ho«r. They ate 4!»i ( ll»s. of corn for 1 i 1 gained. &lt;»nc handrcd poands train cost ."&gt; cents jM-r bo. This left a profit of 92.49 &lt;&gt;n • f gain. The profit on each hog daily was .','.» vas received for each l»u. of coin eaten (!2 cents. EXPERIMENT NO. VII. i Lot No. 10.) hoq* on ■orn ami alfalfa paxtnn Etliis experiment 29 slioats wen- kept in a ."-acre alfalfa re and fed :! His. of eon daily for cadi 100 Iba. of I April 27 in June 8, 1906, six weeks. The avenge veigbt </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Growing Hoys in Western Xvbraska. on April 27th was 18."&gt; lbs. and six weeks later -~&gt;- His. Tin gained on an average 1..VJ lbs. each per day or &lt;i)i it 1 each in six weeks. They ate S87 lbs. of corn for each 100 1 gain in weight. The coat of 1 .00 His. gain was *2.3(&gt;, leavin a profit of 93.14 on each KID His. of gain. Bach hog i gave a profit of |2.10 on the six weeks" feeding, or a i D«I, or a i' of ."&gt; cents daily. There was received for each bo. of eon eaten 7!» cents. If each pijj were charged 10 cents for alfalf pasture the cost of 1IMI His. gain would he |2.51 Fig. 3. Hogs fattened on three pi r EXPERIMENT NO. VII Corn (mil alfalfa pasture ccr iiuj tmmture hogi This was a test of the value »f alfalfa pasture in fatten re made up of ten brood mature hogs. Lots 20 and 21 w each, from which the pigp had been weaned. Some chfl </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 during the test. Eack lot was fed for 1 the run of a 5-*ere field of alfalfa and daily per loo lhs. weight of hog3, fro;a 23d, 1906. Lot '21 was kept iu a dry lot and s. of i-orn daily per 100 lbs. weight of hogs, from .July \ 11)0* ■ J wilh Lot u on July t$, 1006 Lot OX 1 •orn pasture I0 1 10' 30 ■Mi :m '.'liO .11 l.v, lbs I.e j 55 * ■■M 431 per 1.; 8 1 $ 2.09 3.00 em -J a; 10 .07 .71 28. 00 20.50 ere added to Lot 20 and one taken from Lot 21. This inaccurate if not taken into consideration were charged 10 cents for alfalfa pasture the be $2.00. in Lot 20, on alfalfa pasture, gained daily per than Lot 21, confined in a dry lot, and ate n for each loo ll.s. gain. The hoga on alfalfa t a tost of 81 cents less i»er 100 ll»s. than thosi r- The avenge profit on each bog in Lot 2Q on a I 1 of 30 days was :&lt;1 cents more than on the i pei The daily profit per bog on alfalfa was 10 i in a dry lot 7 cents. There was received for each f corn 'ed to the hogs on alfalfa $1.02, and for each hu. fi-(l In tlio in a dry lot 71 cents. It required nearly I to produce 100 lbs. gain in a dry lot than irhea in dfalfa pa ture was supplied. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Fig 4. Lot rn-meal ar hay fed on the - r;. 6. Lot 35, ground barley and Lot 34 ground barley and alfalfa alfalfa hay, In proportion of hay fed on the ground. ri pounds barley to one pound hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">&lt; EXPERIMENT NO. IX. ilfn Kith grain, for fattening kog*. i&gt;rn and with barley, in fattening bogs. Lots i'.") ;iikI l'T of Experiment N«&gt;. 111. \ uniform ;is t&lt;&gt; condition ami breeding ami of ;il - eightH. All were fi.l ■ full ration. All graia tttemimg kogs. Experiment begun Ac ltd Feb. *j, /yr&gt;/. 33 34 corn 7.V, barley barley bai alfalfa alfalfa alfalfa alfalfa alfalfa i cut 10 cut 10 10 10 !M HI M !»1 •_M ■-•)&gt;; 115 iiy no !K 1.38 1.18 1 Jl 1.07 I JO $ .!.-.l' $3.07' J 4.! 1.89 l.'.Kt il 1.98 l 1.18 JO 17 11 61 wore charged f jr the alfalfa consumed, the &lt; Lot 31, $3.15; Lot 32. $2.70; Lot 34, follows: 906, until Feb. 2:1. l!»i)7, six lots of 10 bofp au experiment t&lt;» determine the advantage I Wet. 11 IK 1J7 1J7 1!&lt;1 tn v.i-2 .U-24 -uin would </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 The results from feeding barley an indicated are in line with those from f but not so much in favor of alfalfa, fait that barley contains so much nml hull that when alfalfa is added it mat food, whereas tin- bulk in the alfalfa Tlure was about 7' , of the cut alfalfa wasted when fed with corn, and about 17'; when fed with barlev. Ther probably a much larger percentage of the uncut alfalfa !' wasted. One noticeable feature thruout the experiment wi that the hogs not having access to alfalfa were much !•&lt; easily put off feed by heavy f ling than the other hogs and Lot yu was fed corn. Lot SI w;is fed &lt;&lt;&gt;iii and alfalfa hay fed on the groun 32 was fed i.V, com and 25'/i &lt;ut alfalfa nix&lt; fed in trough*. I.&lt;&gt;t ."!:&gt; was fed barley. Lot 34 was fed barley and alfalfa hay fed on the grou Lot :;."&gt; was fed 75' i barley and -•"&gt; . cut alfalfa mixc fed in troughs. We sulmiit the results of this test, without di-awin elusions as to which practise is the most profitable, : will (lc]H'ii&lt;l largely on local conditions, conveniences f&lt; linjr alfalfa, and cost of labor. It will be noted thai larger and quicker jjains wen- s when alfalfa was ltd. except with Lot 35, and that II &lt;iaiu was Mcured with less grain when alfalfa \\ . When' alfalfa hav was fed uncut, there was a Baring ■ f grain on each 100 lbs. gain in weight of hog whin- it was fed cut. as 2o'/i of the ration, there was injr of Ids lhs. of Lrrain for each 100 lbs. gain, over coin and 71 lbs. over corn and alfalfa hav uncut. Thii 1-oiinds of cut alfalfa saved LOS lbs. of torn and tin amount of uncut alfalfa saved •'&gt;• lbs. of corn. lbs </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 i Lot !) was fed Lot 11 was f Lot VI was f The same ai lie St All crrain wa of but one test. It is probable that ■ lfalfa would have given equally ai fa- ■ amount stated here is only approximate led at each feeding time, hut ouly surti fairly accurate estimate. The cut al •curately. It is also possible that lfa would have given more rapid j:ains. mi ion to advocate feeding a ration ot &gt;' , grain as the most profitable, hut simply &lt; of this test, which is only preliminary in I'all'a hay. It is probable that maximum will be secured with a smaller proportion of 25' . here used and when the cost of cutting onsidercd it may even he possible that the i the average fanner will result from feeding racks and either shelled or ear corn. .Much •ml on the quality of the alfalfa fed, late rat- bcing preferable to the coarser or dam- EXPERIMENT NO. X. x. The average weight of the shoats was near 80 lbs. corn. 1 einmer (1 barlev &gt;unt of grain was fed to each lot. Lot 0 was indard and was fed \' ', corn — a full ration. ;round, and fed wet. The average daily '^ain atage of grain as those having mmcr, &lt;tn&lt;] barley for fattening hog*. let. 24. 1905, until Jan. L'7. 1 •&gt;(&gt;&lt;•&gt;, «.U (lavs, three lota iree I cadi were fed to determine the comparative value miner (spelts), and barley. All hid access to al- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 I 1 E l.-r n per piji in Lot it \v;is 1.92 His.; in Lot 11, .77 Hi. ; and ii 1l'. .si Hi. The pain eaten for loo 1 1 is. gain was. by I 470 lbs. of eon; by Lot 11. 618 lbs. of emmer; and by L&lt; MM lbs. of barley. The cost of loo Ihs. gain was. in I. $:.\!&gt;4; iu Lot 11. *:'..Sti: and in Loi 1J. |3.68. Tabu; XI.— Comparis /■: xp,i Alfalfa bay and . No. of pigs in lot i No. &lt;it days in ex]&gt;crii Av. last weight pound Av. first Av. j;ain pounds ]&gt;er (rig . . Av. " daily pooadf Grain per 10U lbs. £ftm, jk&gt; 'Co&gt;t of ll&gt;) lbs. gain, cniiner 35c pir bo., baric Profit oo 1001m. Profit on each pi^; Profit on each pig daily . Price merited for 1(») lbs Price received wr bu un Profit on lot 41&gt; 'If we assume thai falfa hay, valued at |S.O0 per ton follows:" Lot 9, $3.33; lx&gt;t 11. $4. of earner. This would indicate that when •th 1'4 cents per bn. of is 11 40 lhs. for fattening hog*, alfalfa ha.v is supplied. The also lie observed in the table cents per l&gt;u.. barley is wo emmer lit cents per lm. of each grain is fed alone and jier hundred pounds should the difference in weight per bushel may deceive the r&lt; or 1.45 lui. of barley. One bn. of barley \\;is e»|ii Corn gave almost twice the daily pronl per pig tha &gt;r barley gave (Table XI). The price received ]&gt;&lt;• grain was Cm cents for corn. 35 cents for emmer, and for barley. One l&gt;u. of corn was equal to 1.83 bu. &lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Hogs in \\ ' • bratka. 27 &lt;; ;ihics per hundred of these different grains. 4&lt;» His. of earner and 4S lbs. of barley to the EXPERIMENT NO. XI. emu &lt;&lt;[ii&lt;il i»trtx corn ami &gt; imm r ami n ami harh // for fattniiiKj fig*. ( 1:! i&gt;iijs cadi were fed from Feb. 3 to .Mar. 17 Mi. The average weight at the beginning was alnmt 106 All grain was ground and fed wet. was fed corn. ivus fed ."&gt;&lt;)', corn and ."&gt;(»', emmet ivas fed ."&gt;0', corn and .~&gt;0' , barley and emtner, and corn and bait Feb. j and ended Mar. 77, 1906. Lot 13. Lot 15. Lot 16 corn ; corn 50j corn .VH tinnier 5O» barley 50S 13 IS 42 i-1 3)2.91 'J15.8 13 13 IS s 42 VI \± per pi K aw. 91 -&gt;i:&gt; a HW 14f. 155 14-, 156 ma go. 83 t; 53 i .as i r. 182 h)2 Ih.t pie I 1.53 1.36 14.-. 470 432 4frJ fclcperliu ri.'.U $3.01 It.H M $3.01 r2.8» M 1.48 n, hot ■ At.. 3.96 -J.l'.t 1 as 1.40 as i.4&lt;&gt; .033 Pr r 100 lbs. of grain 1.17 1.14 1.19 17 1.14 1 lit tio.") emtner .445 lwrle\ rn .655 corn ti miner .445 bnrlev.581 assume that one-fourth of the food consumed consisted of al- v. $-V'i" per ton. the cast of 1 |M| lbs. gain would be as Lot IS, $3.41; Lot IK. $3.2 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 11 i i v 1 wh I The average daily gain per pig ill Lot Jo was 1.53 1 Lot 13, 1.35 lbs.; and in Lot 16, 1.45 ll&gt;s. These are al gains and much more nearly together than where emit barley were fed without corn. The grain required for 10 gain was, by Lot 13, 470 lbs.; l&gt;y Lot 15, 4SL' lbs.; and H',, M2 lb.s. Where einiiier formed one-half the ration, thei required for 100 lbs. gain 12 lbs. more grain than coin formed the entire ration. In Experiment No. X 25, where eniiner formed the entire ration, there was required l for 100 lbs. gain L48 lbs. more grain than where corn forme the entire ration. When barlev formed one-half the ration, there was required 8 lbs. less i see Table XII where it formed the entire main ration 120 His. n Table XI) to produce 100 formed the entire grain l and barley give belie fed alone. This is al per bushel grain in X, where each kin per bushel was »;.""&gt;.."&gt; eel 4 !.."&gt; cents for barlev. In and barlev were fed w alone, the price receh for corn, 4 1..". cent is, when emmer and barlev corn, there was received pel and per bushel of barley 13.5 Birley were each fed alone. y per cent barley and .~»0 th;m corn alone, altho not ALFALFA PASTl'IlE Foil IKxiS In the tests discussed, where the h pas falfa, each lot was kept in a five-acre field. Thre&lt; cut. as in the other fields, tho noi so heavy. A f </seg>
            <seg id="p029">I Th ng herd oss due to tin 1 pasturing of hogs at one-half or season, chargeable to th:- b&lt; :nt - fa at (5.00 per ton in the stack. re would In- due from the bogs, for "."&gt;. Wit li a medium grain ration, 7 ho_;&gt; nsuine more than one-half of the crop To pasture mature hogs without grain i twice this amount. Where hogs were head per acre did not da u of grain, 8 han 20%. The same number on a liu'ht oidd eat and destroy from .lit' ; to 7.~&gt; , of the largely on the amount of grain fed. ' to eight hogs, under ordinary conditions, would riuht number. This would allow enough alfalfa row to make three fair crops per year. The fields should mall rather than large, so that the part nearest the water •op. This wouM be abont I 1 - ions ■ust of running a hoc mi ;ilf;ilfa f&gt;' liii^s thai may !&gt;&lt;■ pastured profitably on ;ui </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 and sheds will not be kepi too clone t&lt;&gt; the ground and that tat the farther end of the Held lie left untouched. We have not observed satisfactory results with sows run alfalfa without grain during tin 1 pregnant period, althoi very little grain is necessary for pregnant sows which an 1 farrow in the fall. From the results of these experiments and oilier tesls i evident that alfalfa is a great aid in pork production and ' when it is available there is a profit in raising hogs, under conditions usually existing in western Nebraska, We beli that there is enough alfalfa growing on the uplands and in valleys in various parts of the West to warrant the statem that there are hut few farms in western Nebraska on wl; alfalfa cannot lie grown with much profit for hog pasture ; winter feed. With sufficient good alfalfa, well stacked, i ture hojrs can lie carried thru tin 1 winter in fair conditi </seg>
            <seg id="p031">II, 31 I N N i Iv f rl lailv n i h s irlev make the ra lone i Exp. No ( i u mav 1 ind investment per bead \n-v dav, and if necessarv with &lt; ONCU SIoNS. nciits are based on (lie result*) «&gt;f the They should be considered in the li^ r lit considered in the li^ r lit ■r peculiar circumstances, when alfalfa i - very high in price, ami market condition! the bogs. It seems probable that two or nn daily per each hundred-weight of boga than a lighter ration i Kxjis. Noa. 1. II. ami !i in flesh mav be expected to gain about ' - hi alfalfa without grain i lv\|&gt;. N&lt;». V, pagel (1 corn in a dry lot while being fattened, re - e-half more grain to produce 1&lt;&gt;() His. gain, profil of •'*&gt; eents less |&gt;er hog than similar alfalfa pasture i Exp. Xo. VIII, page 90). io;_ r s tliat have aness to alfalfa ha.v, con at L'4 cents and eiuiner HI cents should j its. Under these conditions. 4 1m. of barley •h as ."&gt; lm. of einmer | Ebcp*. Nos. X and XI. &gt;r einmer is fed to hogs it is more profitable n one-half coin than to feed cniiner or barley XI. pages 27 28). tin is not a reliable criterion of profit. A ■e so slow as to he unprofitable. Time, labor hoiihl be considered win n reckoning pro isnissiou. All pertain to feeding li&lt;'_ wlicn alfalfa lia.v is supplied uii1&lt;t condi- witli those existing ;&gt;t the Substation at r- liim is not tlic mo-it eronoinical for erowing </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 A full -n.in ration, tho Baking the gain more costlv, usual I v gin* greater profit*, because of the larger amount of bus transacted in a given time with a given number of hog* lExps. Noe. I, II, ami III). The profit and loss account would indicate that com! in western Nebraska are favorable to a large prodi i pork, in every test, where conditions were not i» unfavorable, grain fed to hogs has returned much market price. not make up too 1 proportion of the ration. When cut and tthe ration with ground con gains and increased the pi iteriallv rcdu tits t Alfalfa limy he fed with profit to growing or fatt almost any Conn so long as it does not make im i </seg>
           
            <seg id="p033">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD CARL I. ERNST. /.',, - S. ALLJ \VM G. WH1TMORI FREDERICK H IR C. LVF THE STATION OFFICERS E. A. BLRNE J. S. DALES, \VM \V. MAI THE WORKING STAFF H. K. Smith, B£ A. T. Peti Frederick D. Hka F. J. Ai.way, Ph.D A. L. Hakckkk, Ii Lawkence Hk K. &lt;",. Mi is rGOME I MlLLI K, M.F., / Ekwin H. Barboir, Ph. I G. R. Chatburn, A.M., Hit G. A. Lovei.and, B.Sc, .' Alvin Keyser, A.M., Soils W. P. Snyder, M.S., Superintendent Experimental Su Gain, M.D.t v in Anim F. Magdanz, Jr., A.B., Assistant it, B. Sturdevant, A.M., Assistant in Martin Nelson, M.S., Assistant in F F. E. Denny, A.B., Assistant in 1 /,■&gt;!!, S. \V. Perin, Farm Superintendent 1 Animal Husbandry 1nitnal Pathology R. A. Emerson, B.Sc, Hoit O. V. P. Stout, C.E., Irns^at </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>