<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Immunizing Value of Commercial Hemorrhagic Septicemia Aggressins</title>
               <date value="18??">November 1936</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">The Immunizing Value of Commercial Hemorrhagic Septicemia Aggressins COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 87 L. Van Es and J. F, Obey Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene LINCOLN, NEBRASKA NOyEMBER, 1936 </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003">The Immunizing Value of Commercial Hemorrhagic Septicemia Aggressins L. VAN ES AND J. F. OLNEY 1 In 1924, Gochenour 2 published the results of certain experiments which tended to show that what he regarded as a specific aggressin possessed an immunizing value against hemorrhagic septicemia. The aggressin he prepared, by the use of a highly virulent strain of Bacillus bipolar!*, was described as having adequately protected seven bovine yearlings against inoculations with the same organism which, when injected into four year - lings, used; as virus controls, proved fatal to them. Soon after, if not simultaneously with, the publication of the Gochenour articles, hemorrhagic septicemia aggressin was placed on the market and apparently has since then been sold in considerable amounts. In view of the limited number of animals used in the Gochenour experiments, of the absence of any evidence that controlled observations in the field had been made, and of the vagaries and inconsistencies so frequently observed in connection with the pathogenic and antigenic char - acter of B. bipolaris, this Experiment Station undertook certain tests to determine the immunizing value of the commercial aggressins, when an opportunity to do so presented itself. ; i . A total of thirteen aggressin samples prepared by seven different con - cerns; were subjected to the tests. The samples were secured in original containers and were used well in advance of the expiration dates indicated on the respective labels. As test animals, rabbits as well as fowls were used. The aggressin doses were administered subcutaneously and each series of test animals was divided into three groups, the groups receiving the injections one week apart. The virus, consisting of 24-hour-old bouillon cultures of B. bipolaris, was injected intravenously to all test animals one week after the last group had been treated with the aggressin. This arrangement was adopted in order to determine any possible influence exercised by the length of time between the aggressin treatment "and the exposure to the virus. . , , ... . ¦ .'r"; In a number of the test series, a group of animals was incorporated which received three injections of aggressin spaced one week apart. These animals were inoculated with the virus one week after the last aggressin treatment. ; ¦ "'. ¦ .• :¦¦. ¦'".' An adequate number of virus control animals were included in each scries, or were added to a number of the series when they received | identical virus; injections on the same day. The experimental rabbits and ' "fowls of a given series or number of series were always of approximately the same age and weight. By preliminary trials, the use of excessive virus H. M. Martin, now with the University .of Pennsylvania, participated in the earlier phases of i this inquiry. His efficient collaboration ; is hereby gratefully acknowledged. . . • . : . ¦ I 1 Gochenour, The development of a potent immunizing agent (natural aggressin) by the use of ' highly virulent strains of hemorrhagic scpliccmu organisms.. Vet. Med. 19:351; June, 1924; The development of a potent immunizing agent (natural aggressin) by the use of highly virulent strains of hemorrhagic septicemia organisms,.). A. V. A, 65:433, July, 1924. . . </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 87 doses was avoided. All test animals and their virus controls which sur - vived the virulent inoculations were kept under observation for several weeks and the ones which succumbed were bacteriologically controlled. In the evaluation of the test results, consideration was given to the following factors: (1) The degree of protection against death induced by the aggressin injections as compared with the corresponding virus controls. (2) The possible influence of the aggressin treatment on the periods of survival of animals which succumbed to the virus inoculations in compari - son with those of the virus controls. (3) The possible influence exercised by the period elapsing between the aggressin treatment and the exposure to the virus. (¦i) The possible influence of more than one aggressin treatment. The results obtained in the test experiments are recorded in the tables which follow: Table I.— Experiment with aggressin No. 6759 (dose 2 cc.) and virus (fowl cholera) (dose 1/500 cc), 1925. Vitm inoc I hcjths ' ' i~ " ' " No. of uhrion-- ivtihtn ' . I "«lh. "¦*••• si- i£,; •-»' ; .&amp;. £si ™** J treatment _ urui I period iVo. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. fi ' * 17.00 . . ... 3 50.0 ¦ H 4 28.75 4 571 n 7 2' ' V.W 5 71A q Vtus controls j4 32.25 1 MO 5 55.6 Table 2.—Experiment with aggressin No. 8686 (dose 2 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 8619 (dose 1/1,000 cc), 1926. Virm inm&gt; Delhi i ~ .. , , uljlion— ' wnhin I italhi j "BS""iii fiillawing lutvuil UO-hr. survival j irrjtmrnt viru* period -Vo. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 1(1 " ' -IH.tMt i 857.1) 8 HO 10 H i 27.00 j 1,154.7 6 60 10 21 H 65.25 ... 4 40 fO Virus controls H 27.50 R 80 Table I—Experiment with aggressin No. 21346 (dose 2 cc.) and vims (.jowl cholera) No. 15150 (dose 1/100 cc), 1928. ~~ , Vini. in«- itoihi ======== illation— within Deaths s"."' dayuf.cr 120 hr.. Average after Averacc Total death. "bbl" a ßß re»in followin B lurvi"l 120-hr. mfvivil Total deaths treatment virui ' I period &lt;Vo. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 10 7 « 29.83 .. ... 6 60 10 H 1 19.00 4 40 ln 21 i U-ll 1 312 4 40 10 Virus controls I 18.00 1 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Aggressins i[i Table 4—Experiment with aggressin No. 21347 (dose 2 cc.) and virus |;i (jowl cholera) No. 15150 (dose 1/100 cc). 1928. |; Virusinoc- Deaths Dcathl N»-?t SthTr Uota. A«"?B= .(.« Average TollldclAl |&gt;- ¦•¦•*«».; aggmsm following "rvival 120-hr. .urv.val ; . treatment »im» period j ¦ ___ i ¦ i No. Hk. No. Hrs. No. P.rt. | 10 ' 7 4 22.75 1 H4 5 50.0 i 10 H 4 51.75 .. ' ... 4 40.0 ] 9 -21 ¦'•¦¦¦; 6 31.33 .. ... ! 6 66.7 • :: 20 Virus, controls 1 18.00 ..'. : • ... . !1. 10.0 ;)'¦ ¦ -—-.. i -. : i r The virus; used in these experiments apparently proved to be almost | avirulent, as indicated by the low mortality rate of the control rabbits ; (Tables 3 arid 4). The relatively high mortality among the groups [:.• of aggressin-treated animals seems to indicate that their chances of sue- I cumbing to the infection were enhanced by the treatment. If the concep- ! tiori that aggressin is a substance which has the property of overcoming the normal resistance to infection on the part of the animal body be the correct ' j one, it appears that in the series concerned this action was displayed. j;- Table s.— Experiment' with aggressin No. 43410 (dose 2 cc.) and virus \: (B.bipolarisbovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/500 cc), 1930-31. ¦ ¦'' Vinil inoc- I)ra(hi ~ Deaihi No. of d, a)"°"i7r jlo'h'r". M'tlgc ,»'«' Avcnlfc Total dealhi :' [rcaimenl virui. P"""1 ¦_ ¦¦ : ... . Wo. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P. ct. j 10 7 10 21.80 .. :.. 10 100 •'; ¦ 10 14 . 10 23.20 ... ... 10 100 ' { 9 21 9; 22.55 ... : .... 9 100 j 1 20 Virus ' controls 15 22.66 .. 15 75 ; Table 6.— Experiment with aggressin No. 43412 (dose 2 cc.) and virus (B.btpalaris bovisepticus) No. 42425[(d05e 1/500 cc), 1930-31. ' - j . Virus inoc- Dealhi , D ihl No.of ihyi'aftTr iSohrj. Avcuee alter Average Total dealhi • rabbi.. "^S followmc ""'"' .' 20*r; «"&lt;«' ' ,)¦ ircalment virui penoil . iT~" No. .Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. :' io 7 io 20.60 ¦...¦• ••¦ io ioo - 8 =14 .8 26.00 .. ... 8 100 10 21 ¦ 10 20.00 .. ... 10 100 \ 20 Virus conirols 15 " 22.66 .. ' ... 15 75 </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 87 Table 7.—Experiment with aggressin No. 41418 (dose 2 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/500 cc), 1930-31. 1 Virus inoc- Deaths j ; „ , , ulation- ' within Ucath&gt; s° oi da» after ' 120 hn. Average after Averast TotaMalhi ™bb"&gt; , » E |U,,ir, j (ollowms «"vival 120-hr. .urvival •""I"""" _ I treatment ' virui period So. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 10 7 10 20.60 .. ... 10 100 10 H 9 19.00 1 168 10 100 10 21 10 19.30 . ... 10 100 20 Virus controls 15 22.66 ... 15 75 Table B.— Experiment with aggressin No. 49363 (dose 1 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/6,000 cc). 1931. Virui inoc- i Deaths I " ~~ , ' ulation— within Death* *¦&gt;¦*'«' : liO""- Av"usc. '''" Arel?«^ Total death, rabbits , jggrjLin , following survival 120-hr. survival J trcjimenr ' virus ¦ period Vo. Hit. No. Hn. No. P.ct. 10 7 1 115.0 ... 1 10.0 10 H 1 20.0 3 H6.66 4 40.0 10 21 '/ 21.0 . . 9 90.0 30 Virus a.ntrnk 2 61.5 2 187.00 4 13.3 Table 9—Experiment with aggressin No. 49364 (dose 1 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/6,000 cc), 1931. Virus inoc- I Deaths | i f 1 ulation- within i ""'hs ! v. 'tav.afWl UOhrs. , \""Se after , Averi B e Total dea.hs jreaimem viruv I 1"""1 i Vo. Hrs. ,\o. Hrs. No. P.ct. 10 7 ....... 10 14 1 2100 2 151.5 3 30.0 10 21 X 19.25 ... 8 80.0 30 Virus controls 2 M.50 2 187.0 •) 13.3 Table 10.— Experiment with aggressin No. 49365 (dose 1 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/6,000 cc), 1931. Virui inoc- Deaths i j ulation- with.n I i »«&gt;&gt;» u&gt;. days after 120 hn. Averace ' after Avera ß e Total deathi "bk"' augreslin [allowinc «""»! ' UO-hr. nimnl ; treatment virus I period No. Hrs. No. Hrt. No. P.ct. 10 7 10 14 . . 10 21 9 20.55 . 9 90.0 30 Virus controls 2 61.50 2 187 4 13.3 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">- . ¦'. Hemorrhacic Septicemia Aggressins Table 11.— Experiments with aggressins No. 49363, No. 49364, and No. 49365 (dose 1 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris ¦ bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/6,000 cc). The rabbits received three injections of aggressin, spaced one weel{ apart, and were inoculated with the virus one wee\ after the last aggressin injection. 1931. .-i : S ¦¦;¦ Death. ¦ ¦¦¦. ' No.of Aggrcsjin 120hn. Average after . Average Total deaths rabbits number foltowine survival 120-hr. survival ¦ ¦ ' ¦ . virus ¦¦¦ PcriMi ' .. No. Hrs. No. Hrt. -No. P.ct. 10 \ 49363' .. ... .. " ...' ¦¦ .:.. 9 49364 .. ... ¦&gt;.-.¦¦¦ ... •••¦¦.; 9 49365 .. • ... 2 175 2 22^ 130 Virus controls 2 61.5 2 187 4 13.3 An effort was made to determine the immunity status o£ the rabbits which had survived in the tests recorded in Tables 8 to 11 as well as o£ the animals which survived as virus controls in the same series. Hence the entire group as well as a new set of controls were inoculated with a larger virus dose, three weeks after they received the previous virulent inocula - tions. The results of these tests are shown in Tables 12 and 13. Table 12.— Immunity status of rabbits which had survived an injection of virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/6,000 cc.) after having received one injection (1 cc.) of aggressins No. 49363, No. 49364, and No.. 49365, and of the surviving control rabbits of the original experiment: All rabbits' received a second injection of virus {B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/500 cc.) precisely three \wee\s after the preceding virulent inoculation. 1931. j f ¦¦¦¦&#132;¦ s ¦¦.. ¦&gt;?"&gt;¦ ¦¦ No. of Aggreutn , 20 hftt Average after Average Tolai rabbiu number fnii na .i n[r survival . 120-hr. survival i vinii P'"0" ¦ j No. ¦ Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 13 49363 9 36.00 .1 139 10 692 17 49364 11 25.63 I 187 U 70.6 17 49365 12 V 42.83 2 . 223 14 82.4 24 Original controls 11 .25.18 ... ... 11 45.83 20 Present controls 20 17.95 .. ..." 20 100.0 </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 87 Table 13.— Immunity status of rabbits which had survived an injection of virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/6,000 cc.) after having received three injections oj aggressins No. 49363, No. 49364, and No. 49365, and of the surviving control rabbits of the original experiment. All rabbits received a second injection of virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/500 cc.) precisely three wee\s after the preceding virulent inoculations. 1911. Deaths I wiThin I Deaths rabb?, in 120 hn. A«?SJ ,?'•» Av"«f Tout dath, "&gt;&gt;""&gt; number followinc survival 120-hr. survival viru! period No. Hrs. No. Mrs. No. P.ct. 10 49363 111 22.40 . ... 10 100.0 9 «364 * 23.00 . .. 9 100.0 7 49365 i 49.66 ... 3 42.9 24 Original controls 11 25.1S . ... II 45.8 . 2U Presrnt control, 21) 17.95 .. ... 20 100.0 The results recorded in Tables 12 and 13 indicate that no substantial immunity was secured in the aggressin-treated rabbits which had received inoculations with an almost avirulent strain of B. bipolaris. The fact that the original virus controls showed, on the whole, a much lower mortality rate than the treated animals seemed to indicate that the aggressin injec - tions had materially impaired their resistance as compared with that of the untreated virus controls. Table 14.— Experiment with aggressin No. 54016 (dose 1 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose J/7,500 cc), 1932. I Virus uwk Heat*™ \ _ , I ularion- H-llhm I ""''" -Vo-of | rtayi after 120 hn. Avcraße rfter .Ucr-tRc Total dcalhl rabbin 1 ,„„,„„ C,llo»-ir,B »umial '2°-&gt;"- """"&gt; ! t,,aimenl .tru; I P"'"1 No. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 10 7 II) 16.60 . . 10 100.0 10 14 7 26.55 ... 7 70.0 9 21 X 20.25 I 242 9 100.0 ¦10 Virus cnmrcils 37 2U.5 1) . ... 37 92.5 Table 15.— Experiment with aggressin No. 54017 (dose 1 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris bovisepticus) No. 42425 (dose 1/7JOO cc), 1932. 1 Virus inoc- I Deaths : Itaihs I Illation — f within ' -ifn-r *&gt;:»&lt; ! day. alter 120 b,.. *««" $%. Toul dalh» treaimcnl ' virus I .Vo. Hrs. No. Hrs: No k. P.ct. 10 7 10 26.90 . ... 10 100.0 10 14 6 19.63 .. ... 6 60.0 10 21 9 23.77 . ... 9 90.0 40 Virus controls 37 20.59 .. . 37 92.5 </seg>
         <seg id="p009">i I Hemokrhagic Septicemia Aggressins Table 16.— Experiment with aggressin No. 54018 (dose 3 u\) and virus (B. bipolaris boviseplicus) No. 42425 (dose 1/7,500 cc), 1932. .[ Virus inoc- Deaths . . -. ¦ ¦¦,*- " i . uiation— wuhin Df' 1" &lt;&gt;f days after 120 hn. Avcl?sc after Average Total death. f^ 1" agsressin following «™val 120.hr. lurvival i treatment vtrui ¦ period I No. Hrt. No. Hrt. No. P.ct. 10 7 6 33.83 .: ... 6 60.0 10 14 8 35.50 •-.¦¦¦¦•.. ... 8 80.0 10 21 9 24.00 ,: -&#132;". .;... 9 90.0 40 Virus controls 37 20.59 -.. ... 37 92.5 Table \7.—Experiments with aggressins No. 54016, No. 54017, and No. 54018 (dose 1 cc.) and virus (B. bipolaris boviseptictis) No. 42425 (dose 1/7Joocc). The rabbits had'received'three injections o/ aggres - sin, spaced one week^ apart, and were inoculated with the virus one wee\ after the last aggressin injection. 1932. Deaths : within Death! No. of A B 6rcsiin uohrs. Avera ß e ,»&amp;« Averse Total deathi rabbits number following survival 120-hr. lurvival ' . .' ¦. "' virus . . ¦.: -P"'°&lt;l - .-.-.'-• i No. Hn. No. Hn. No. P.ct. 10 54016 8 31175 ; ... ... 8 80.0 10 54017 9 24.55 .. ... 9 90.0 10 54018 6 28.33 .. ... 6 60.0 40 Vims controls 37 20.59 .. .. ¦ 37 92.5 Table 18.— Total mortality — aggressin-treated rabbits after inoculation with virus and corresponding virus controls. ... . - Mortality Number VirtHinoc- wilhln a EE res.in uUllon- 120 hrs. Morality Toul treated dayi after following . ,"f'« mortality rabbits aggressm vims inoc- 1M»" - -. .-V - ; treatment u | alion - . ; ¦;¦.'.¦. '..¦;¦ P-Ct. P.ct. P.ct. 126 ¦ I" 1- 7 ..-¦' : 59.5 3.2 62.7 125 14 : ,52.0 ' 72 59.2 124 21 • ! 79.8 . 1.6 ' 81.4 58 Treated three times 39.7 3.4 43.1 . with aggressin ; ¦ ' .'. • ¦ ¦ ; . ' ¦ 433 Total mortality of all groups 60.5 3.9 64.4 :--..• ; : Mortality ' \ ~ ' ¦-",-' V ¦ i within ¦ &#132; ¦ it. Total No-vm; l : 120 hn. Momnty momlity ro?™' [¦ following &#132;an f lsr of virus tMxu | vims in- 120 hn. control, oculalion .:-..¦ . P.ct. P.ct. ¦ ¦¦' P.ct. 119 i 56.3 . ' .., 2.5 58.8 70 ¦; 55.7 2.9 ; . 58.61 .'This sroup of virui control*, corresponding with the group treated three times with aggrcijfn, is included in the larger croup above. . ' - </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 87 The results obtained in the preceding series, with the exception of those recorded in Tables 12 and 13, are summarized in Table 18. When the mortality rate ot the aggressin-treated rabbits is compared with that ot the corresponding virus controls, it does not appear that life-savimj prop - erties can be attributed to the use of aggressin. In regard to the influence of the time elapsing between the aggressin and virus injections, the results indicate that the animals injected with the virus 21 days after the aggressin treatment showed a markedly higher death rate than the controls, whereas the ones insetted with the virus 7 or 14 days after the aggressin treatment did not indicate that an adequate protection was secured. That the rabbits which had received three aggressin treatments made a somewhat better showing is probably due to the fact that in half of the series a virus of inadequate virulence was used. Although without practical importance, the aggressin injections seem to have had some influence on the length of the period between the virulent inoculations and the time of death. It could be observed that among the rabbits dying within 120 hours after the virulent inoculations, there was a tendency toward a longer survival period than could be recorded for the corresponding control animals. _ . This phenomenon was less marked in the rabbits which received their virus inoculation 14 days after the aggressin injections than in the groups inoculated with the virus 7 and 21 days after the aggressin treatment. In the 14-day groups the length of the survival periods more closely ap - proached those of the virus controls. In the smaller groups of rabbits which had received three aggressin treatments and which were inoculated with virus one week after the last one, longer survival periods than of the virus controls were also recorded. The same tendency is further expressed by the greaterl number of aggres - sin-treated rabbits which survived the 120-hour period as compared with the corresponding virus controls. In the tests in which fowls were used as experimental animals, the same procedure was followed as in those in which rabbits were chosen for the purpose. The results of the experiments with fowls are shown in the following tables: Table 19. -Experiment with aggressin No. 43412 (dose Vi CC.) and virus (jowl cholera) No. 43501 (dose 1/5,000 cc), 1931. Virui in«- Dcathl D a[hs "W Si SSL 2» &amp; sa —¦ I treatment vimi f^ ___ No. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 10 7 10 27.2 10 100.0 11 M 10 24.8 1 192 11 100.0 10 21 10 34.0 10 100.0 26 Virus controls 24 36.9 1 137 25 96.1 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Aggressins ¦ ¦ 1. ¦ ¦ ¦¦ ¦ - ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦¦'¦¦ Table 20.— Experiment with aggressin No. 43418 (dose '/i cc.) and virus - ; (fowl cholera) No. 43501 (dose 1/5,000 cc), 1931. , Viruj inoc- Deaths „ . ¦ " „ ¦ ulation— within , Dcattu ™-°' i days after 120 hri. Average , ?''" Average Total deathl '"«'» j a ßß reisin following survival 120". h/; survival \ treatment virui period ' ':'• ¦ No. Hrs. No. Hrs. ¦ .No. P.ct. 10 ! 7 10 34.9: '...: ... 10 100.0 10 '] 14 10 31.8 .. ... 10 100.0 10 - 21 10' 26.1 -¦.•¦ .:.-...- ... ' 10 100.0 26 Virus controls 24 36.9 1 137 25 96.1 Table 21.-— Experiments with aggressins No. 43412 and No. 43418 (dose Vz cc.) and virus (fowl cholera) No. 43501 (dose 1/5,000 cc). The fowls received three injections of aggressin, spaced one wee\ apart, and were inoculated with the virus one weel^ after the last aggressin in\ec - tion. 1931. Deaths ~~ T7 ' &#132; , ¦ . . within D«"ni No. of Assrelim 120 hn. Average ,JK r- Avera B e Toul dtMhj fowls number following furnval 120-hr. itinival . ;: • ¦¦ vimi ¦ ; period No. HW. . , No.-: Hrs. No. P.ct. 9 .43112;' 9 34.66 . .. ... 9 100.0 10 43418 . 10 27.70 .. ... 10 100.0 26 Virus controls 24 36.90 1 137 25 96.1 Table 22.—Experiment with aggressin No. 54017 (dose x/z cc.) and virus . -i (fowl cholera) No. 53615 (dose 1/500 cc.), 1932. Virustnoc- Deaths ¦_ ¦.¦¦¦¦ - „ , ulalion— within . Deaths dayiadcr 120 hr.. Avera B e after Averasc Total deaths tmU aggresiin followine survival 120 : hr. survival - . treatment virus ; 1^"°" . . ; No.) Hrs.- No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 10 . 1 7 47.71 .. ... 7 70.0 10 14 9 . 41.66 1 139 10 100.0 10 21 8 32.75 .. ... 8. 80.0 40 . Vims controls 37 57.30 V ..: ... 37 92.5 Table 23.— Experiment with aggressin No. 54018 (dose x/i cc.) and virus (jowl cholera)\No. 53615 (dose 1/500 cc), 1932. Virui inoc- Deaths l : . . ~~: ¦ , ulauon— wiihin Deaths N,°° £ daysaher UOhrs. Averase after Avera ß e Touldalhi 'ow's a ßß ressin following survival l2&lt;Mir. survival treatment . virus period i ; No. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.ct. 10 ¦! 7 ¦ ' 9¦¦!•¦¦ 38.22 1 ,' 162 10 100.0 10 1 14 9 34.22 1 187 10 100.0 10 21 6 : 56.50 1 359 7 70.0 40 Virus controls 37 : 57.30 .. &#132;.. 37 92.5 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 87 Table 24.— Experiments with aggressins No. 54017 and No. 5401S (dose Vi cc.) and vims (fowl cholera) No. 53615 (dose 1/500 cc). The jowls received three injections of aggressin, spaced one week, apart, and were inoculated with the virus one wee\ after the last aggressin injec - tion. 193Z Deaths | Deaths Vo.of Aecreuin p^'" i Averaw after Average Total deaths i,MI, nnmhec foliowin's lvmivll 120*r' '°rv'lv!ll No. Hrs. No. Hrs. No. P.cl. 9 5-JOl" « -16.00 1 Ifil 9 100.0 10 54018 7 33.28 2 163.5 9 90.0 40 Virus controls 37 57.30 . . .. . 37 92.5 A summarization of the results of the tests in which fowls were used is presented in Table 25. Apparently it was not possible to induce, by the use of aggressin, a sufficient degree of immunity to protect the birds treated against a subsequent exposure to the fowl cholera 'organism. Little or nothing could be observed which indicated an influence of the period elapsing between the aggressin injections and the virulent inoculations or that the administration of three injections of aggressin one week apart brought about a manifest protection against the infection. Table 25. — Total mortality — aggressin-treated jowls after inoculation with virus and corresponding virus controls. Vint&gt; incw- Morality Number ulalion— 120 h". Mortality . JtKresun- rUyi »llet (ollowine after J~,liu, treated ! ,g emsw „„¦¦ in- 120 hu. mortality 'p*1 ' treatment ikuUiioq I P. c(. P. a. P. ct. 40 7 90.0 2.5 92.5 41 M ')2.7 7.3 100.0 40 21 KS.IJ 2.5 87.5 3H Treated tlirtc timts S'&lt;.s 7.'J 97.4 159 To«l mt.rulity of all croups N9.i 5.0 94.3 N;^' ! Hi!' ' Mom,uv JSU control followins ," f'" t "'virus fowh virus in- ' '20 ""¦ controls . oculanon __j p. ct. p.ci. r.ct. 66 93.9 In none of the series in which fowls served as test animals could a tendency toward a lengthening of the survival periods o£ the fowls which died within 120 hours after receiving the inoculations of virus be observed. On the whole, they rather showed a tendency to be shorter or to approx - imate the ones recorded for the virus control fowls. • </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Hemorrhagic Septicemia Acgressins If a tendency of. the aggressin treatment to prolong the survival periods of the treated fowls beyond those of the vims controls must be reckoned with, the phenomenon may possibly be expressed by a relatively larger number of treated fowls which lived beyond, the 120-hour period than was observed in the case of the corresponding controls. •"" : ; Advantage was taken of an opportunity to make some further tests of the immunizing value of aggressin against fowl cholera under conditions closely approaching the ones apt to be encountered in the field. Two enclosures (yards No. 7 and No. 8), which had previously served for some studies of the epizootiology of fowl cholera, were available for the purpose. Here follows an account of what was done and observed: February 25,1933.—Fifty-two fowls were placed in Lot 7 and 53 fowls were placed in Lot 8. By March 23, 1933, one fowl in Lot 7 and two fowls in Lot 8 had died from causes other than fowl cholera. March 23, 1933.—Thirty more fowls were placed in each of Lots 7 and 8. Between the above date and April 11, 1933, intercurrent death causes removed one fowl from Lot 7 and three fowls from Lot 8. March 28, 1933.—Forty-one fowls of each of Lots 7 and 8 were each injected with one-half cc of hemorrhagic septicemia aggressin No. 59333. April 11,1933.—Twelve fowls inoculated with Bacillus bipolaris (fowl cholera) cultures No. 59310 and No. 59577 were placed in each of Lots 7 and 8. All of these birds died of fowl cholera within 48 hours. April 12, 1933.—Six fowls were placed in each of Lots 7 and 8, after having their palatine clefts swabbed with a suspension of the blood taken from the fowls which had died of fowl cholera in the lots. The following table shows the deaths of fowls recorded between April 12 and May 9, 1933. .; ' . :-¦-• . Table 26.—Record of deaths, April 12 to May 9, 1933. '. Lor 7 L«8 j - Fowl cholera ~ Imercurrent Fowl cholera Intercurrent /' . ¦ ¦ . - in causes in in cauiestn ¦; ' : ¦"¦-.¦. ;...:": 'No. . No. No. " No. Aggressin treated...... .. " ~\ ;3. . ; 2 . ', 2 Untreated controls .","-¦- 3 2 1 May 9, 1933.—Thirty-seven fowls from Lot 7 and 38 fowls from Lot 8 which had been injected with aggressin No. 59333 on March 28, 1933, received each another injection of one-half cc. of the same aggressin. The following table shows the deaths of fowls recorded between May 9 and May 16,1933.1 :' : ; ' : ... </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Acr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 87 Table 27.— Record of deaths, May 9 to 16, 1933. Lot 7 I Lot 8 nw ' Fowl cholera Intercurrent Fowl cholera Internment in ""'" '" jjj causes in No. No. No. No. Angressin treated - . Untreated controls . 1 1 May 16, 1933.—Twelve fowls were placed in each of Lots 7 and 8 after having their palatine clefts swabbed with a suspension of blood of rabbits dead with fowl cholera infection No. 59310. Of these fowls two died within 12 hours, eight within 24 hours, four within 48 hours, and three within 72 hours. Three died after a subsequent swabbing, two died from causes other than fowl cholera, and two were killed at the close of the experiment. May 23, 1933.—Between May 16 and 23, 1933, one fowl not treated with aggressin (control) died in Lot 8 from a cause other than fowl cholera. May 23, 1933.—A1l fowls in Lots 7 and 8 had their palatine clefts swabbed with a suspension of the blood of rabbits dead with B. bipolaris (fowl cholera) No. 59310. The following table shows the deaths of fowls recorded between May 25 and June 10, 1933. Table 28.— Record of deaths, May 23 to June 10, 1933. |-°' ' Lot 8 v&lt;&gt;* 1 &gt; hnlrr.i j fium-urrem ' Fowl cholera ,' In:crcurrem in tatitrt in in causes in Xo. So. So. No. Aggrrssin treated 21 IK Untreated cnnimU 2 1. 2 30 The fowl cholera mortality rare, as well as that of intercurrent causes in the various groups of fowls from the beginning of the experiment are recorded in the following table: Table 29.— Summary record of deaths to fane 10, 1933. ABjirrsMn-trcalril foivli Control foivh, not treated Group* ¦— ' • of (owh Foul cholera Mortality Imm Foul cholera .Mortality from ¦ morulny imercurrciu cmnci | monaWly intercurrent causes . P- a- P. &lt;rr. VTct. Y~ct. Lot 7 . ! 56.09 7JI : 58.97 12.82 Lot 8 ! 48.7 X 4.H7 89.18 5.40 Both lots 52.43 6.U9 { /j.68 9.21 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">I Hemorrhagic Septicemia Aggressins June 10, 1933.—Eleven fowls which were not treated with aggressin were added to each of Lots 7 and 8 in order to determine whether or not infection sources were still present in the lots or the fowls which occupied them. Three of the birds succumbed to causes other than fowl cholera and two died of cholera, in Lot 8. The remainder of the fowls were killed at the termination of the experiment. Attention is called to the fact that killing was commenced only four days after the fowls were admitted to the lots and hence the results are probably not expressive o£ what might have developed during a longer period of observation. June 14,1933.—Between June 10 and 14, 1933, two fowls (one aggres - sin-treated and one not treated) died in Lot 7 from causes other than fowl cholera. I ¦ ¦ , ¦ June 21, 1933.—Beginning on June 14 and terminating on June 21, 1933, all fowls in Lots 7 and 8 were killed. From each bird a swab was taken from the palatine cleft and the mucus thus obtained was suspended in physiologic salt solution. The suspensions were then injected into rat - bits, one for each fowl. This was done in order to determine the survival of B. bipolaris in the many birds exposed by swabbing on May 23, 1933, and to discover any tendencies of becoming virus carriers on the part of the "groups concerned. The. following-observations were made: Of 28 aggressin-treated fowls which were infected by swabbing their palatine clefts on May 23, 1933, the B. bipolaris was found to be still present in 14 fowls (50 per cent). •••.':..' Of 21 fowls not treated with aggressin and infected at the same time, and in a manner similar to that of the treated birds, the B. bipolaris was to be still present in 5 fowls (23.8 per cent). Of the 17 formal fowls introduced into the lots on June 10, 1933, one had become a virus carrier (5.88 per cent). ; conclusions 1. The injection of hemorrhagic septicemia aggressin failed to induce an adequate protection against a subsequent inoculation with B. bipolaris. The average mortality rate of the treated rabbits was higher than that of the corresponding virus controls. 2. Animals inoculated with virus three weeks after the aggressin treat - ment showed on the average a higher death rate than the virus controls, whereas that of the groups similarly inoculated one and two weeks after receiving aggressin treatment approached the mortality rate of the control rabbits. ! . :,; .¦_'; '•"¦': ¦ - . 3. No substantial advantage was gained by treating the test animals with aggressin more than once. ¦;¦'¦ . \ 4. The only influence of aggressin treatment consisted of an apparent tendency to prolong the survival periods of the animals dying within 120 hours and of a greater number surviving beyond that space of time as compared with corresponding virus controls. •: 5. Aggressin-treated rabbits which survived the inoculation with a B. bipolaris of greatly reduced virulence, showed a conspicuously higher </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 87 mortality rate than the original corresponding virus controls, when three weeks later the entire group was again injected with a larger dose of the same virus. 6. The treatment of fowls with hemorrhagic septicemia aggressin failed to induce an adequate protection against a subsequent inoculation with the fowl cholera bacillus. 7. In fowls treated with aggressin a marked influence on mortality or survival periods by the length of time elapsing between the aggressin treat - ment and the administration of the virus could not be observed. 8. The injection of more than one dose of aggressin into fowls failed to bring about a degree of protection different from that of the birds treated only once. 9. An adequate degree of immunity was not induced in aggressin - treated fowls exposed to fowl cholera by swabbing their palatine clefts with virulent material. 10. In one group of fowls exposed to fowl cholera in the manner indi - cated, the aggressin-treated birds showed a markedly lower mortality rate than the virus control birds although their degree of protection cannot be regarded as adequate. 11. Of the aggressin-treated fowls which were exposed to fowl cholera infection from 22 to 29 days and had survived, 50 per cent were shown to Mil harbor the v,rus; whereas, of the corresponding virus control birds, only Zi.B per cent were shown to harbor the infection. 12. There is no reason to believe that the hemorrhagic septicemia aggressins of commerce can be depended on as a means of protection of livestock actually exposed to B. bipolaris infection. I3MI </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>