<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00017.00011">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00017.00011</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA STATE COMMISSION TO THE Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition AT PORTLAND, OREGON 1905</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">REPORT HE NEBRASKA STATE COMMISSION 3 THE Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition AT PORTLAND, OREGON »5 T His Excellency, JOHN H. MICKEY, Governor of Nebraska IS» </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">CONTENTS r of Traiismittal. Historical Data 5 Act ( !reatinc Board of Commissioners 11 uization and Work of Commission lti Nebraska Pavilion and Exhibit. • ■. -I Nebraska Day. Nebraska I &gt;av Addresses 'Itiulis. Awards ''- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">i i LETTER OF TRANSNIITTAL December 15, VM Mickey, Governor of Wbr; E Excellency, John II coin. Nebraska. We have the honor transmit h srewith th 1 r. P of the Nebraska State Board of Commissioners to tl AY and Clark Centennial Exposition, which was appoint* In as provided for by Act of Legislature, approved Apr .1 IMS. Respectfully submitted. William I\ Warner George L. Loomis Harrison G. Shedd </seg>
            <seg id="p006">■ STORTTAI DATA The acquisition of Louisiana by the United States excited in the mind of President Jefferson the desire for knowledge of the extensive domain lying between the Mississippi River and the Pacific ocean. Little was known concerning it, particularly sf the section west of the divide that separates the Mississippi md coast water-system and extending north of the forty- nd parallel, the territory called Oregon While its shore was not entirely strange to navigators, the few i hat had been made to that region contributed nothing, or the merest particle, to the world's information, ft was not until Captain Robert Gray of Boston visited the nbia River, named after his vessel, and the neighboring in \l\vi, reporting upon them to the Government, that ; though meager knowledge was had. rie entire region lay uninvested by the United States or Britain, without administration or control, unconsidered and scarcely apprehended by c status of this territory at the be tury. President Jefferson, anxi the newly purchased Louisiana Captain Gray's account of the &lt; ther. Such was the political ginning of the nineteenth cen - &gt;us to establish sovereignty in and aroused to inter. Mintry beyond, resolved upon an expedition thither to explore and learn the geography, the natural wealth and future possibilities of the northwest and to treat with its inhabitants the Indians. To make this plan feasible Congress appropriated $2500. Captains Meriwether - and William Clark were appointed to conduct this ex - pedition, which proved epoch-marking in its character and made their names historic. Upon May 14, 1804, the expedition entered the mouth of the Missouri, a party of forty-three men in three boats, and </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 1 upon its important enterprise. Exceptional!; curate and valuable records were kept by the two let minute and almost daily transcript of their tw,&gt; - explorations, the time elapsed before their return: ami it well be said that these records take high rank amon? the la in the archives of the government. The men fol - l up the Missouri: from its source crossed the mountains to the head-waters of the Colombia; and thence passed down Pacific Ocean. They traversed and re-tra versed the then unknown half of our continent, a remarkable achievement. I.i they covered 4133. They opened a road to the wi -howed the wisdom of the purchase of Louia tain of its great worth, established friendly relations with its tribes, and opened the eyes of the nation to the \ bility of greater dominion beyond. It is unnecessary to re - in this brief summary the hardships endured or the diffieu! - vercome. the dangers encountered or the peri whicl. nit with them. What is chiefly noteworthy is that they I'lished what they set out to do. thereby setting the ■hat lias since made the Oregon territory a part of the Immediately upon the publication of the explorer's &gt; the fur companies entered the new region and scattered trappers and traders along every stream. In their wak :. with succeeding years, a thin but steady line of immi - grants who settled in the fertile rail important had the ■i become in the year ISIS the government Britain and the United States, each of whom now d it. were unable ti ipon a dividing boundary, whih eneral boundary treaty, and the «as left undetermined, the territory to be jointly occupied denied altogether England 'i claim to poaaeaaion on the Pacific. At hern limit of </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 i in was marked by the S] bat to the north when Kuss indefinite. Nor was thi&gt; boundary fixed until the year the other two countries upon Three years later England an&lt; •inish settlements of California, a liad established her ti.i- Arctic and almost myii 1S24 when Russia settled with about the fifty-fourth par America, still holding wideh ivergent opinkms as to their respective shares of Or newed the existing treaty. The territory was now partially pnlated, the richness of its valleys and forests and moan - ing) were known, and the imagination had little difficulty in rhting its splendid, though unmeasured, future. For two decades longer it remained the growing of dispute. Towards the beginning of war with Mi itieians of our country seised upon the doubtful issue to eate the north for the questionable reception of Texas in- United States. For a time it appeared as if the latter w be plunged once more into war with England, in additi&lt; that brewing upon her southern boundary. The claii •u were, in the case of each government, vairue. tl those of the United States were bulwarked by an actual si through the settlement there, by this time, i ■and citizens. Against this Britain could op] leniaenahip of her unstable and migratory fur tr. Our government built her title upon the discover}' of the Columbia by Captain Gray, on Spain led ri-rh . ery and exploration in the Florida treaty. Lewi- Clark's expedition, and actual settlement. England's &lt; iiased on the supposed voyage of Drake along the on the worthlcssncss and invalid character of thi shadowy Spanish ownership, on a more extensive ex] tion by an English navigator after (iray. and on the &lt;» tion by the fur companies. Finally, good w </seg>
            <seg id="p009">h 1 1 I i I yielded her intentions of retaining the country nortl forty-ninth parallel and Britain renounced all clair : lying south. Thus the territory now comprisi: Washington, and Idaho became undispute ty of 1 lie American Government. And it w. ffort tliat President Jefferson pot forth through his t\v Lewis and Clark, that was responsible in large laving this rich and beautiful section of country t American people. In commemoration of the services of these two position was held in the city of Portland, calle.. I and Clark Centennial Exposition. Its purpose v th&gt;- progress, development and aeaievment of the whiek I nee their arduous exploration; t&lt; rts. industries, manufactures, and prodn ■line, forest, and sea, not of the Oregon territory ■rid as well. It showed particularly the wo ful advancement of the Northwest and its possibilities, both ii - and in human intelligence by actual den ■;. and, moreover, published the marvelous possiluli ■r the future, of which this is but a beginning. This Exposition celebrating the services of the two \&gt;-\ ued to the world June 1. 1905, and closed it - 14. of the same year. Its wonderful success ampl. justified the faith and patriotic endeavors of those whose effort created it. Participating with the three states which 1 lie original Oregon country was the United S • lit. various of t! of the Union, and si Millions of visitors from all parts of th. i. and of the globe, were acquainted with the greats ii which constituted the third advance of our countrv national expansion. In the opening ceremony ths i of the United States gave official sanction bv </seg>
            <seg id="p010">I </seg>
            
            <seg id="p011">his preaenee, an.l it was the finger of the President hi Eich started to life the mechanism of this international c on. During the four months and a half of its existence, tportanee and dignity we* tin- goYeraon of many federal and civil courts. 1 inferred upon it by tlie pre» f the commonwealths, j . slators of the national and and Navy, and dignitarii bodies, officers of the Army every department of public lif of the great Expositions of th world, measuring the world 'c nulating industrial and intellectual effort in th establishing a closer and firmer h comprise the nation. 1 kited States especially, and liesion among the states whi L Nebraska took more than nial. Bunds of sentiment j a common interest in this lin her to the Northwei haps but few states are bound. The only member of the Lewis and Clark exposition to die during the long jou succumbed while the party was ascending the Missouri river in the neighborhood of the present site of Dakota City. It is uncertain whether Sergeant Charles Floyd died upon Nebl soil, but in an; ■■■ and historic is the association th.'.t mere exactness of the spot is unessential. The first report made of our present state is found in the diaries of these leaders, and thus brought under the eye of the government. It constitutes one milestone which Lewis and Clark set along the road that led through the gates of the Rockies. Since that tini - braska has sent nearly twenty-five thousand of her peo] aid in the development of the old Oregon territory, the three - of the Pacific Northwest. The kinship that thus i ot been forgotten. They have contributed to the up - building of that part of our nation, and in doing it have ; credit to the state whence they came. Lately a battl* named for our commonwealth, constructed upon Puget sound. In every i </seg>
            <seg id="p012">10 liich alreadv united N.-braska to tin Upon the aaaotraeeflttnt that an exposition wa N&lt; rthwest. be held rtland to ciiiiiiin'inoratc the exploren' services to tl at once looked forward to participation. And at n i of the legislature an appropriation w 'am session &lt;&gt;i the iririsiaturt' an appropriation was mail </seg>
            <seg id="p013">L OF COMMISSIONERS Ee board of eoBUuarionen to the Lewis and Clark Exposition was appointed pursuant to ati i tare approved April :i. 1905, as follows: HOUSE ROLL NO. 101. A KILL. For an act to provide for participation by the State of Neb at the Lewis and Clark Exposition to be held in tli of Portland, State of Ore) appointment of a state bo governor : to define the duti in relation thereto; and f( n. in the year 1905; for the thousand dollars ($12,000.00) therefor; and to provid what purposes the said appropriation shall he i INTRODUCED BY C. W. KALEY . 1905. Head second time Janu - tiiimittee on Finance, Waj - •y 111. 1905. tBead first time January If 19, 1905, and referred to C iv Sent to printer Janua irk Centennial Exposition will Whereas. The Lewis and ( In- held in the City of Portlan&lt; in the State of Oregon, in the opening of the trana-Miai the heroic explorations of i liam Clark, and will exhibit year 1905, to commemorate tl territory to civilization through tains Meriwether Lewis anil \Y education of the various bI ; in Europe, in North anil S ordering the agriculture, arts, industries an of the Union, and of the natioi America, and particularly of *rd of commissioners ftg ■s of the board of eonufl r tin* appropriation of tw&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p014">12 ATE COMMISSION ling for ■ market f industrial products; and &gt;r its various agricultural and Whereas. Nebraska is a j art of that great section of settlement and wonderful de - ms of the Lewis and Clark ex- 1 up to civilization mom through the exploratii iind eontaina one of the richest portion! of the trans Whereas, The Lewis and Clark Exposition by its location irtland, one of the gateways to the -western states and nations, affords the people of Nebraska an opportunity to ex - hibit again to the world their products, their agricultural and •leral advancement, culture ■ rity of their state; by means of which exhibit new mar - ■&gt;vill lie reached and much good result 1" the common - li: and Whereas, through the economy of the late Nebraska ■n to the Louisiana Purchase Exposition, held in the of .Missouri, daring the summer of unexpended the sum of fifteen thousand dollars rom the sum set aside by the last legislature for «i r representation of Nebraska's resources and industries at the said Louisiana Purchase Exposition; and Whereas. Tin and is now held by the commissioner of public lands and buildings a great amount of the be - hibit material collected by the late Nebraska state commission and used at the Louisiana Purchase Exposition, eonsisti' nearly ten thousand feet of moving picture negative and film 8_- completely the life, business and resources of and in addition, the best sheaf grain and grasses shown ■ouisiana Purchase Exposition, all in an excellent state rvation and suitable for future exhibit purposes; there- ■ iiri territory ; and </seg>
            <seg id="p015">13 Enacted by the Legislature of the State of Nebraska: ■ction 1. That the state of Nebraska take part in the and (lark Centennial Exposition to be held in Portland state of Oregon in 1!H).") as hereinafter provided. E Section 2. That the governor of the state of Neb and is hereby authorized and directed to appoint a non - isan state board oi' ei.iimiissioiiers of three members for purpose of carrying out the provisions of this act ; and that governor is empowered to till any vacancy that may occur I board of commissioners. on 3. That each member of said board of commis - n appointed by the governor as provided in section 2 i shall receive no salary or other compensation for sc: red as such commissioner; but that each commit shall be reimbursed for hotel, traveling and incidental ex] incurred while discharging the duties created in this act. ion 4. That for the purpose of enabling the state of Nebraska to make a proper state exhibit at the said Lew.- Clark Exposition at Portland; properly to plan, adv. carry on, develop, install and complete the said slate exhibit at the said Exposition, and to provide for the comfort ■• a people attending the same; and for the purpo - the expense stipulated in section :i; and to pay for the salaries of all superintendents and employes which in the opinion of the said board of commissioners may be necessary to I lot the purpose of this act. the sum of twelve tin. ($12,000.00) unexpended by the late state conn Louisiana Purchase Exposition and now in the tn State of Nebraska, be. and the same is hereby appropn - iiii] tlie state treasury. mi 5. That for the purpose of saving expense and of making the largest and best possible exhibit of the state's </seg>
            <seg id="p016">- and buildings be. ami he is hereby directed to tun ;ili t&gt;r &gt;sii&lt;-li part of the moving jiicture films and ik-l - illustrating the rwowwi of Nebraska and all or such part of the trasses, •.-rains and other material now held by him. as the board &lt;&gt;t ooauriaaionen may desire t&lt;i use in eonm with the said exhibit of Nebraska's resources and industr w is and Clark Kxposition. on t&gt;. That the said board of commissioners ap - ted by the governor as herein provided shall act ill junction with the board of directors of the corporation known as the Lewis and (lark Centennial Kxposition company, but the \ hereby appropriated and the exhibit material b&lt; 1 over to the saiil board of commissioners as pn &gt;all be under the control and management of said i appointed by the governor. Min 7. It shall be the duty of the said board of s on being notified of their appointment by the ernor. to meet at the governor's office in the City of Lincoln and to receive from the governor the certiticates of apj and to organize the said board of commissioners by the in of a president, a vice president and a secretary; and in case the secretary is a member of the said board of commit ■eetion 1 of this act shall not estop him from receiving a salary as such secretary. hi 8. The said sum of money or so much then ssary, shall be and does become available for the purpose of carrying oat the provisions of this act. the waking hibit. the providing for the comfort of Nebraska peo - ttteading the exposition and all other things necessary properly to plan, advertise, develop, install and carry on ■ hibit from and after the taking effect of this aci, rein provided: to wit. when said board of commissi </seg>
            <seg id="p017">15 state, ami attach to such certificate an itemized statement uniform voucher attested by the president and secretary ol board, and approved by the governor in writing, the auditor of pubtie accounts is hereby authorized and directed to dn warrant on the state treasurer to the order of the person en - titled thereto. M shown by the said voucher. Section !t. The said hoard of commissioners shall suitahle room in the state of Xehraska for pla&lt; f bus and it shall he the duty of the said hoard of commission. ;i complete and detailed record open at all times to publi; •tion, of each and every act relating to the expenditni said money and an itemized statement of all expenses and in - debtedness incurred. It shall also lie the duty of said bo.r commissioners, by its president and secretary, to make a r in writing every sixty days to the governor of the act - - of said hoard of commissioner* as herein provided. Section 10. That within sixty .lays after the close of the said Lewis and (lark Centennial Exposition, it shall be the duty of the commissioner of public lands and building! and he is hereby authorized to advertise and to sell at public M for cash in hand, of a singular, the property acquired b.\ board of commissioners, to account for the same to th« ernor and when approved by him to pay the sum of mam red from said sale to the state treasurer to the credit of ite general fund. b Section 11. No provision in this act shall be deemed a ant for creating a liability against the state in excess of mm herein appropriated. k Section 12. Wherefore an emergency exists, this act. bein^ led of immediate importance, shall take effect on and after </seg>
            <seg id="p018">c ORGANIZATION AND WORK OF COMMISSION In accordance with the pi with the provisions of House Roll Xo. 101, visions nt' II (Twenty-ninth session, erecting and defii duties Board of Commissaonere to the Lewis and Clark nial' Exposition, we have the honor to report tli : eoniinissii.il sine., its appointment as follows: William P. Warner of Dakota City, George L. Looi mont and Harrison &lt;;. Bhedd of Lincoln, having been n &gt;- venty-ninth session, er ii! It: i of Commissioners to the Lewis and Clark ition, we havt the honor ■d commission since it iponitni William 1'. Warner of Dak L. I &gt;ta Citv, Geor Fremont and Harrison &lt;;. Shed 1 of Lincoln, ha of their appointment as members of the Nebraska 8 I of tlieir appointment as members of the Nebraska 5 In by your Excellency met &lt;y your Excellency, met at your ity of Lincoln on April 11. l!»0. in the City ( .f Lincoln on April 11. 1905, and having their eertinei ppointment under the act r of appointment under the act on, thereupon proceeded to the orgai mmiission. thereupon proe led to the organizatio I commission, as follows: WILLIAM I*. WARNER, J'lvsident. GEORGE L. LOOMIS, Viee-President and Treasurer. HARBISON &lt;;. SIIKDD. Secretary. At this meeting plans for a state exhibit were disci -.on. as follow WILLIAM P. WARNER Tp ur At this meeting plans for a state exhibit w re dis. which resulted the following resolution unaniinou ii which resulted the following resolution unanimously ini led upon, as embodying the poliey which should direct the d upon, as embodying tin on during its term of policy which should direr- mission during its term of existence: K&lt; -solved. That owing to the limited menus at &gt;f the Nebraska Commission to the Lewis ark Exposition, tin- Commission do not build building upon the exposition grounds, but in xisten Ived, That owing to the limited 1! I the Xehrask I Commission to the Lewis i k Exposition, the a state building upon the t addition to providing suitable rooms for the enter- addition to providing lile rooms for tl te tainment, comfort and convenience of Nebraska eiti - nneetiou with its agricultural exhibit. in connection with it pend all money received i a manner which f Nebraska and { hal th exhibit the resour in the most im- </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            
            <seg id="p020">PYour Excellency had prior to the appointment of the mission engaged the exposition officials to reserve • our state in the Agricultural building. It was left for the commission to secure architectural plans, and as the p&lt; •clingly brief for the accomplishment of the u taking of gathering, transporting and placing exhibits, ; dition to erecting a pavilion, no time was lost. Mr. Thou Kimhall of Omaha, one of the ten members of the board ol architects for the Louisiana Purchase Exposition held the previous in St. Louis, generously donated hi - plan for a pavilion. In order to facilitate the commis - sion in their work (i. ( '. Shedd was appointed executive • Killiam James superinten ed in exposition affairs. lent, both of whom w. The contract for construct ion »nd firm the first week in Mm. f the pavilion was let to a Port] 1 Upon the space allotted Meanwhile agricultural exhibits were being rapid: ■I by the superintendent, which number was inei the addition of a loan of the valuable and comprehi Douglas county collection of threshed grain and seeds. By the middle of .May two carloads of exhibit material wi ■ their way to Portland, transported thither by the Burlii and Missouri railway, through the public spirit of its oil at its own expense and with all expedition. Among th hibits were a number secured from the State University w contributed much to the attractiveness of the display. Upon the arrival of th ?xhibits they were installei of the Exposition, June 1. the loor space had been &lt;■■ Elly. and by the opening day s thousand square feet of transformed into a compact of Nebraska's agricultural complete and impressive dis - reaotur industries. 1 i ■ id erection vu rapidly puahe live officer supervising I </seg>
            <seg id="p021">18 1 S limited in time and spaee as well as available mooe ifine its efforts to a chief presentation of Nebi and distinguishing industry, agriculture. Consequently ■edominating note of its exhibit was agricultural and and frain products, with corn primary, constituted the ral cxhil)it, while the moving pictures, for which X. a lias become famous, formed a forcible and attractiv supplement During practically the entire season of the fair, nine ommianoa m at at Nebraska i A staff of assistants was maintained throughout, i'i addition to a number of successive hostesses, Mrs. Alice Mrs. Alice Loomis and Mrs. Charity Hart, who re - el and attended the irreat number of visiting Nebraskanx and others. For the comfort of the latter a commodious wai - room was provided, a reading table, and other venieiices: while for their entertainment were the hourlv set Ering pictures of Nebraska life. Seven thousand visiting skans recorded their names upon the pavilion rey: given a Nebraska badge to distinguish him the grounds. Other thousands of former citizens were t at various ti' Important occasions when the Commission welcomed Ne - at headquarters were during meetings of the .W - i Lumbermen, National Good Roads Convention. Na- I Editorial Association. American Library Association v.ntion. American Medical Association. Charities and Corre ■•- onvention. Civics Conference. Trans- .Mississippi Congress, •ial Irrigation Con grew, Nebraska Day. Educational • -: and conventions, associations and sses of a minor character. August 21. was Bet apart by the Exposition ofti - uhich to celcbrat ml participa- </seg>
            <seg id="p022">19 tion in tin- Lewis and Clark Centennial. Because of th timate relations of Nebraska with the Northwest, the fact that thousands of former Nebraskans took an active intere - whieh the mu'leus was the Nebraska Society of Oregon, anJ ise of the unusually large attendance of state visitors and officials, the day proved one of the most successful, important and historic of the Centennial. During the four months and a half which the stat&gt; represented, the commissioners were assiduous in cultivating ■oeial relations with the Exposition authorities and with men of other states and of foreign countries. Men ■kip in the Executive Commissioners" Association and in the iltural Club was maintained. Ruth the Exposition officials the Commission worke ■st harmony whenever occasion rose for co-openr hvays there existed the friendliest relations, as tesi B letter received by the Commission and here insert ■Ion. Wm. P. Warner. President of Nebraska Stat. . Lewii and Clark Exposition, Lincoln. Nebraska ir: Eermit me to convey to you an expression of the high in which the members of your Commission «re held directorate of the Lewis and Clark Centennial Expo - und to thank you for the splendid manner in whica ate participated, making one of the largest and ve exhibits of resources shown here. "In my judgment, the very best was made of the oppor - tunity for advertising the resources of Nebraska, and it should afford general satisfaction to the citizens of your section to know that the representation attracted a remarkable 1 attention. The exhibits were well arranged, and it ; s </seg>
            <seg id="p023">» f i I "Much good use was made of moving pictures in th pavilion, and I trust that the results to your state will t and marked that your citizens will be amply sal with the money thus expended. Thanking you ami eaeh o :iinissi"iifrs for your iteration at al times, I am, Yours very truly, II. W. GOODE." To this letter Chairman Warner sent the following repl) "Hon. H. W. Goode, President of the Lewis and Clari Exposition, Portland, Oregon, Dear Sir: "Your very kind letter under date of October -!4th. di as President of the Nebraska I and Clark Centennial Exposition, is duly receiv&lt; thank you heartily, both personally and in behalf of the for the kind ex| therein contained, and w&lt; are more than pleased if we were able to contribute to ai tent in tb "f your Exposition "Nebraska entertains the friendliest feeling toward th le of Oregon and the 1'aeitic states. We have thou of former citizens who are now mingled with your p Our interests lie along the same paths; the development of tli not help but aid in the development an I shall always remember with the period - ur city during the past summer, and in behalf of the I sion, and personally. I wish to thank you and the in. of the Exposition for the uniform friendship and ; xhibited and extended to us. I am. Very truly yours \V. 1'. WARNER The exhibits made by the Commission, comprising grain and in grasses and forage crops achieved by I . Shodd, the executive eommii rge here. uplifting of our b1 Superintendent from a </seg>
            <seg id="p024">K I., i. </seg>
            
            <seg id="p025">21 great quantity of available material, with the idea of r sentinir Nebraska'! products in the finest manner. All va - rc shown, tlw idea holding with the members of the m that comprehenan agricultural possibill - tial in the showing made. As has already stated the chief emphi laid upon corn, of which were, exhibited. Altogether some hundred an 1 twenty-five entries were made for awards. Practically all awards, over half tddng the highest award, the L, in the power of the Exposition juries to confer. The ral total was as folio? I Medals 66 Cver Medals &gt;n/.e Medal 18 Honorable Mention 9 Total 121 Eall times the finances of the commission were con - eeonomieally. Only such employees were maintaine-1 iitiea of the exhibit required for its best success. While the entertainment of Xebrasl a was not •ted. it was conducted upon a mod . and with no such ambition as evidenced by some states, and was always justified by tl n. The chief expenditure in this direc - tion was in observance of Nebraska Day. A constant effort was put forth to keep the running expenses at a minimum, and that the Commission was sincere in this endeavor will en in the balance $892.91), returned at the end of the Moreover, the Commission, personally and through its d a continual and careful supervision of the exhibits and property in their charge, protecting them in all respects in installation, maintenance and removal, in order to Mtion to the state treasury </seg>
            <seg id="p026">1 1 ■r i i M the state and the interests of individuals who ha&lt; i.itted them to their stewardship. At the expiration o ;me of the Fair, the grain and minor property wen the act creating the Commission and by th, itive offieer who had been deputised by t ho Commisi inds and Buildings for that purpose. The exhibits whic) had been loaned for the time, and the pavilion which had returned to the state by the Union I 1 railway, through the public spirit of its officers, free of &lt;i On account of tit- tv and effectiveness of tlu pavilion, it was the feeling of the Commission that the would (rain much in reproducing the pavilion upon the mds for permanent presentation of the Boring pi - which v opular at Portland and which as pnui erty of the state can be used for the benefit of its own eiti - ntiment took form in the following resolution imaaimously adopted by the Commission at its meetil r 10: Whereas, the pavilion erected at the Lewi and Clark Centennial Exposition by the Nebraska tand widely known as the "N'e - ska Pavilion."' having been turned over to the -oner of Public Lands and Buildings as pr rled by law. and transported to Lincoln. Nebraska. 1 there delivered to the State Board of Agriculture conformity to the previous recommendation of this Commission, therefore be it ved. That this Commission urge upon the State Board of Agriculture the desirability of erect - iid pavilion on the State Fair fT minds as a per - at building for the purpose of exhibiting therein during each State Fair the moving pictures </seg>
            <seg id="p027">LEWIS AND CLARK CENTENNIAL EXPOSITION. 23 positions at St. Louis and Portland, in advertising the of Nebraska, and that we nee to that end. irees and industri meeting of Commission &lt;1 follows : Be dates and places of i of appointment are ■ Lincoln. April 11: Omaha. April 18; Omaha, April 19; Omaha. April 27: Fremont. May 7: Omaha. May 13; Lin&lt; June 22; Omaha. July 2."&gt;; Portland. August 24; Lincoln it 10: Fremont, December 4. E roughest its work the wisdom of Nebraska It has been convince erne from such reprew Dgthened commercially Commission has felt com being represented at this I moreover of the benefits which •ntation, and that the stat' and otherwise in the Norti and upon the Pacific coast. And as a result of participati great Exposition, it grew more and more apparent during the Fair season that Nebraska has taken high rank among states, that she has secured just recognition of her splendid growth, and that, in fact, she is no longer considered new and untried but stands in the estimation of the country as an old, well-established, well-developed, well-loved state. Her name is synonymous with comfortable living, rich resources, strong industries, numerous schools and churches and eharitii - ally exert our intfn intell: id good citizenship </seg>
            <seg id="p028">The limited mmm &gt;. and the unusually brief tim little over thirty days, j.t the disposal of the Commiatioti Mition to the fact that Nebraska's exhibit would natu -H.-ultural in character, guided the Commission - were projecting such, then- was almost an equal mini . Im-h determined to confine their displays to one or in of the spacious Exposition p Moreover, n l' Nebraska at the the year previous the Louisiana Purchase Exposition state had lx-cn very i 11 a large and expensive state building, warranted such ■ on the part &lt;&gt;f the Commission. To ered a state build - !'"ii the grounds such as would compare favorably with nstruction by other states would have required far funds than lay in the hands of the Commission, leaving - for exhibit purposes and maintenance. Therefi « sidered wise to erect a pavilion within the Agricultural B--. using the same for state headquarters and for th&lt;&gt; m of visit in- \ebraskaas, and the Commission so ,!■■ - •I. -paee which the Exposition authorities informed your was available within its walls, and from which you ml reserved that for Nebraska's exhibit, was well ■pie, and suitable in every respect It WK rth center of the main building, adjacent to the '-rncultural and horticultural exhibits, and situated but t distance from the exhibits of Wyoming, Montana I)ak(ltil T1 ' comprised a full block, loniritu. ■ &gt; by :{l» feet, a main aisle upon each of the four sides; ami here was erected the Nebraska State pavilion. f- ■■■■■ ■" &gt;"«ioi-ii-r. gwueu me lonmission in Deluding not to end ■ rtate building. While ■ nonbei </seg>
            <seg id="p029">25 fThe plan for this was furnished gratuitously by Thomas Kimball of Omaha, one of the board of ten architects for* tbfl Louisiana Purchase Exposition and designer of the splen - did Electricity Pallet upon the grounds at St. Louis. .Much of the beauty of Nebraska's exhibit at the Lewis and Clark Pair was doe to the architectural qualities of the State pavilion. In the style of the Italian villa, the theater was surroui by a massive colonade supporting a trellis, and the whole blended in a color scheme of rich and Striking tones. A warm erome composed the general color, shading from a deep rut orange at the base of the theater and of the pert proportioned colmrns to a subdued cream tint at the top. In contrast the heavy trellis, uniting the columns, and the broad K&gt;s and projecting rafters of the theater were in eho c decorations, consisting of grape-vine entwined about the His. and white and yellow corn pyramids, increased the h. splendid and massive appearance of the whole pavilion. Through the colonade the visitor secured an open an tractive view of the State's exhibits, while the movement of the moving pictures, seen at a distance through the three wide doors of the theater, invited the passing visitor to enter. In the open space before the theater stood two extensile tables, one on either side, built in accordance with the g&gt; architecture of the pavilion and of a heavy and unique 6\ Upon these were exhibited the samples of corn and products which constituted an important part of the State - play and which, towards the end of the Exposition, won nu - merous premiums and awards. Of corn there were shown some eighty varieties of the hundred or more that Nflbl produces, divided as follows: forty-five varieties of field corn, twenty of sweet corn and fifteen of popcorn, and in addition there were on ens of especially bred and crossed </seg>
            <seg id="p030">26 dinjr or BdlBng pvposes. On these exhibits MMUMOD laid especial eni])hasis. and to them gave a] attention, endeavoring to have in greatest ■ Nebraska's chief and most important product. That exhibit did not fail in attracting attention, particu - larly uaoog raisers of cereals, and ainonir visitors generally, wu testified by the constant requests for ears of corn a- L For this purpose the Coniinission had reserved many the trrain and it was so used in distribution. Of th" IMfll yield of the state, which runs into the hun - of millions of bushels, tile visiting public obtained an ite idea from the lar^e and substantial pyramids of corn rating the theater and eolonade at all points of vaa- Betweea the two tallies was placed the mounted specimen. Challenger, the two-year-old priae-winning steer, which swepi the premiums in all classes in which it was entered, high an 1 ■ad won the world's prize at the International Stock Show, held at Chieago two years a&lt;so. Amongr eattle men ally, who examined Nebraska's exhibit, this animal took first place in their attention and elicited strong praise. Being rfect in leoring points, it was a splendid illus - ii of the cattle industry in Nebraska, and reptv - dearly the oonneetidn between corn production and - te. The theater wherein the Boring pictures were given w.is a model of comfort, beauty and progress in agricultural ad - :it. Built for the particular purpose of presenting in pictures, every part of it was so designed as to make most effective. Three larj_'e doors opened upon the front of the pavilion, enabling a far larger Dumber than coull •undated by the theater's seats to 1m- spectators of the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">* ■/. 56 i i , r </seg>
            
            <seg id="p032">27 proven by the unusually large attendance each hour of the day. Just above these doors, and within, ran the gallery which held the electrical machinery for operating the picture*, In all respects the interior was provided against discomfort on the part of visitors. Large ventilators opened in the through which euiieui &gt;li air could circulate arched windows, diamond-paned. lighted the room when the shows were not being given; while nearly a hundred chairs supplied the audience with a resting place durin period of moving pictures, and were in demand at all time;. ial attention was paid to the decoration of this int the Commission taking to Portland an expert decorator. Mr. _■■■ Morse, for the purpose of arranging upon its \\. ,1 and symbolic representation of Nebraska's ear In the rear of the main room of the theater were tli - of the executive otiicer and the storeroom. Along the two of the little building, ami between it and the col.. the visitor could pass beneath the vine-covered trellis to the ■ pen reception room at the rear. Here were to be 1 ■ such as ice-water, a large reading and writing I and easy chairs. Nebraska papers, whicl Ktisly furnished the exhibit by their respective publish - ughout the state, were kept on file, and supplied Ne - s with the latest home news. While the Commission depended chiefly upon the - Bg pictures, to interest and instruct spectators, it did not fail to have on hand an abundant quantity of literature with the state, its products, .resources and iadni A Teal pocket memorandum book, in which were compiled data and statistics of Nebraska, was distributed by the at - tits. Publications along specialised lines, issued by the Kxperiment station at Lincoln, by the various railr If ' 1 wprp k«n t c nutantlv at hand Tn addition </seg>
            <seg id="p033">to these the Conn cured and distributed thousai the report of the Bureau of Labor, and twenty t in account written by Mrs. A. .1. Sawyer of Lin - coln for the Daughters of the Revolution in 1902, dealing wit'i i Clark in Nebraska, which had more than ordinary All of these various publications exploiting Nebi ut upon the reading table for free distribution. As prominent features of the reception room were two immense pyramids of corn in the husk, which drew continual comment from fa: Two sides of the room were ed by pyramid! supporting larye &lt;;lass jars containing threshed grains and seeds. A third side was given up I exhibit o! and grain in sheaf, all of which wer : by experts and so arranged as to show the samp ■plendid high-grade wheats, rye, barley, oats, wild an I and alfalfa which Nebraska produce in rising tiers to the top of the eolonade. enclosing Um ion room and permitting it a certain measure of priv - acy while still leaving the exhibit open and free to the &lt;:• public Here also was exhibited a collection of sampl in 1S77 to I*!t4. loaned to the Commission by S. \. f Homer, Nebraska. ■ ■f the most valuable exhibits at the Nebraska pavilion and headquarters was an early copy of the Lewis and Clark lition. loaned by the state. The edition was published in 1815, about one year after the official report to the goteru* before the public, and about the same tima M Middles Digest, and was printed verbatim from the inal manuscript. The books were well preserved and sb but little effect of the wear of their ninety years' ajre. The rare historic value which they | drew many inquirers from among those who were interested in Lewis and Clark's ind who ad to avail themselves of aa </seg>
            <seg id="p034">rrtimity to moult so authentic and accurate a set of I diarii The Nebraska State Commission in preparing its plans ring pictures which had I ire such a magnificent ac', people and in exploiting thousand feet of film i E early decide. 1 upon the m at St. Louis and which \v to the state in interesting braska's possibilities. Several in the hands of the Commission for use in this manner. Th tater in the pavilion was designed and erected for this pu e. One week before the opening of the Exposition a trician and two moving pictun presenting them. These picture machines were secured for taken in all pan braska. and dealing with practically all of the important in - dustries (if the state, stood as the latest advance in agricultural tvertisenient. How favorably the fact that no less than motion pictures at the Lewis ki&gt;il from Nebraska's achiev itation they held in reaching they were considered is shown four states installed similar md Clark Fair, having )• ement the possibility the public. Under the admin- istration of Thomas Persons, the electrician, these pic) were shown in the Nebraska tin where they were attended by Dispersed among the moving pi uter each hour daring the large and interested crowds, ■tures. giving variety and r opticoD views also ill ftnge of subject was | rtlie eye were scores of step Nebraska life. An entire eh each hour that the same industries and the same parts of the state should not lie exhibited upon the same day. and that itors who desired to see the pictures more than 01 do so without repetition of subject. In many cases peopl turned with friends, several times. While these pic! I before the audience Mr. William Sizer of Lincoln, the rer, told in a full, clear and forcible way the history . f </seg>
            <seg id="p035">- rapid and marvelous development and briefly men: in various industries, stating the prod- I resources. Between exhibitions the attendants, BBttdd, William James. William Sizer, II r, Thorn. ,1 one or another of the hostesses tained visitors, distributed the literature which the ■n had provided and enlisted the interest of the public in the pavilion and siMt-ial exhibits. The attendance at these ■wring picture showa was hn Lering the general at - of the public upon the Exposition grounds. With an laily audience of from ti\ lit hundred this ed nearly 1br&lt;'e per cent in u'eneral admissions, or three ery hundred entering the gates of the Fair, or about fifty ntering the Agricultural building. Further. Ibis does not take into account the many who • r but a portion of an exhibition, or of the many visitors who were present in the pavilion during the time the pietui not in operation. The recorded at - ;it these presentations was fifty thousand for the fourti -on. - of pictures dealt with the following subjects Pint— Plowing and planting of grains in the sprint early bar i Summer and autumn making hay. ing and shredding corn. Third — Cutting, raking and stacking alfalfa Fourth — Care of orchards in spring and autumn, fruit ire, i hies on large scale. Fifth — Poultry, sheep and swine th — The dairy industry, the usual Methods of th« </seg>
            <seg id="p036"/>
            
            <seg id="p037">(Seventh— The eattle industry: the niuf, feeding and rketing of eattle; the South Omaha stockyards. I Eighth — The raage, ranch life, rounding Dp, branding tie, roping and riding wild hon Ninth — Beet sugar industry, the planting and eulti of beets, manufacture of sugar, the use of by-products and During the hours of the day in which the pavilion w.is open to the public the Nebraska State Commission refj •pen upon a stand directly at the main entrance of the colonade where the public who so desired might record their Hie attendance of Nebraskans was heaviest during the two months of July and August, reaching its climax August 21, Nebraska Day. Seven thousand visiting braskans inscribed their names upon the register from June 1 to October 15, in reality aH attendance during praet the two months already stated, an average during that [&lt;■ of almost one hundred a day. When the fact of distance time necessary to reach the Pacific coast from the State &lt;■■ braska is considered, this show Northwest and a large measiirt a remarkable interest in the if comfort and prosperity at The public as a whole show \ ?. warm appreciation of the tuty. originality and characteristic nature of Nebn ibit. Many former Nebraskans now living in Or ans now living in On- Krton or Idaho, or other d a hearty remembran rmer home state; and states of the Pacific country, e and affectionate regard hundreds used the Nebr pavilion as their headquarters during their presence upon the grounds. The Portland newspapers and the papers of the liate vicinity commended the exhibit with their gei 1 'n mnnv r.Qeuc ■ iiIm m it -i rt i *iil*ir m *nti &gt;n bv e«lliiv </seg>
            <seg id="p038">the atteution of the public to the worthiness of its exhibits ally remarking upon the mowing pictures as a new. prehensive and praiseworthy method »if informing Fair Til of Nebraska's wonderful i - and industries, whil. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">•NiiL.Di\..r\o.K./\ U. A 1 While Nebraska made do effort at elaborate ent daring the Exposition season, the intention and - were to have vis specially Piperience a sineer colonade of the Nebraska and cordial hospitality within pavilion. The attendants and relieve their The ade of the Nebraska K endeavored to ;i - and store-room were pi .' of wraps, bandit encouraged to mal ted at their disposal : lunches, while the general use of the reception room as :'lids. Many courtesies were received by the Commission at the Exposition officials, State Commissioners of B, and prominent Oregon citizens. An effort was to return these in so far as was compatible with the the Comni The chief occasion for elaborate ceremony and entertain - ment by the Commission was on Nebraska Day. The 1 K authorities designated August 21st. the anniversary of it h of Sergeant Charles Floyd, who died upon th Kver, as a fit and noteworthy date. This day was elusively to our state for commemoration. ■our Excellency further dignified and sanctioned it proclamation, as follows: E'' Another great exposition, illustrative of the resources ■rid in general and of our country in particular, is in progress at Portland, Oregon. Primarily intend memorate the success of the Lewis and Clark expedition pening Oregon territory to settlement it has been given a ■ broad scope and is really an exploitation of th° ees. manufactures and wealth of the United States, and. of appointment with fr </seg>
            <seg id="p040">re limited extent, of tin- nations of 1! \V(i ■of Nebraska is keenly interested in the enterpria irislature haviii'_ r made a substantial appropriation f" hiliit. Many of our citizens have already visited the ind many more are to follow during tl lam : its continuance. In keeping wi the prevai ,'i of srivine official recognition to each of tl&gt; KqI lias kindly set apart one day for p*r - ci'i-eiiionies appropriate to Nebraska, and I th&lt; [aim Monday, August 21. 1905, as Nebraska I) ly join with the State Commission lial invitation to all Nebraskans who can make it conve ■ent and participate in the program incident t&lt;&gt; the j engraved invitations w 1 among Xebraskans throughout the Northwest to be Nebraskans traveled to Portland to take part in this Early in the day hundreds of former resident .- themselves known at the state pavilion and Ein the New York building. This was an elab. enjoyable function and did great credit to President 1 those having it in charge. Immediately upon eon - the luncheon the party adjourned to the Annex &lt;&gt;f Vork building, where the the day it ilium this occasion. Your Excell i special badjre. These people evinced a warm in- iii the work of the Commission, the Nebraska pavilion. shibited a ttrong remembrance of and affection for their itizenship in our state. Tin- Nebraska Society of ii joined with the Commission in making the day one irable in the history of the Lewis ami Clark Exposition At 1 o'clock President Ooode entertained Four Excellency, in and the official party from Xehrasi </seg>
            <seg id="p041"/>
            
            <seg id="p042">35 1 1 w ( Among the many prominent truest! of our stale 01 on were Governor Chamberlain of Oregon, and 1 nit Governor Bruce of New York. The exerc Btlie simplest and most the entire Exposition. The Auditorium was pro: nth a wealth of Oregon fern: imii-rmis banners and flags, atriotie effect. Here more Hi Usely and beautifully and (ir boughs, and hung with ill of which produced a an a thousand people listen of vocal and instrumental i he program, which consisted ud addresses. Special music f he Administration hand and r the occasion was furnish' by a special quartet from the Eft-Oregon Society of Portland, which arganittttoa in many ways to make the da. ika," written by Will Maupin of Lincoln, and ren- ered by the quartet, was heartily received. Following is the im: .Music — Administration band. Invocation — Rev. ('. Buchler Address of Welcome -I Vi lent II. W. Qoode of tl P. Warner, President of X ■dress of Welcome ill ■rlain. Behalf of Oregon — Governor Song. "Nebraska" — Nebraska-Oregon Society quartet Add] vernor John II. Mickey of Nebraska. .Music — Miss Daisy Small. Address — Lieutenant Governor Bruce of New York. Address — Hon. Willam V. Allen of Nebraska. -Nebraska-Oregon society quartet mpressive held on the Eit 1011 society. Response — Hiin. William ■ika Commission. AddreM — Hon. Gtoo. L. Loomia of Nebi </seg>
            <seg id="p043">&lt; REPORT OF NEBRASKA STATE COMMISSION All parts of the prograa were of a very high order. The addresses were especially appropriate in thought, instructive and entertaining. We regret that it is not possible to give them all in full here. We are pleased, however, to present Vour Excellency and Mr. Looniis. both of which ap - io the appendix hereto. t Following the program a general reception was held from •lock at the Nebraska pavilion for the purpo - ding the Exposition people and visitors an opportunity leeting Your Excellency and party, hundreds of whom ed themselves of the privilege. I A dinner to Your Excellency and party, given by the raska Commission and a lunch and garden fete given to official party by tin- Exposition authorities in the evening. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Bof Hon. John II. Mickey, gOYernor of Nebraska, u Day, Aii-rust 21, 1906: Mr. Chairman, Ladies and Gentlemen: Any great as- of people nr of interests that is not educational in ndency may well he considered of doubtful prop This is a practical age. Tl nlightened world is seeking for improvement. Present standards are not sufficient. Tbx .tinual reaching after better methods of tiring, 1 sanitation, more wholesome and better prepared foods, more adaptable machinery, better and faster means of transp tion, more skilful professional men and women, better i r applied science, more labor-caving and wealth-prod lions, higher art, higher ideals, more practical patri plied to national, state and municipal government, truer and women. Bis in response to this popular demand that the ions of the past half century have found reason for iaeh exploitation* as the Centennial, the World's Ke Trans-Mississippi, the Louisiana Purchase, and expositions of comparatively recent years, have prob - ne more for the general dissemination of human k than any other one agency, and now we are participating in another of these great educational enterprises, the I and Clark Exposition of your own state and city. The ob - ject lessons here presented pre innumerable, comprehensive, far-reaching. It is safe to say there is no one who has passed through these buildings and streets, filled with the products of the best thought of the nation and of the world, but that has had his views of life materially broadened and has re - 1 an inspiration of permanent value. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">38 i r f t I want I ttulate the people of Portland, "f the Pacific m the magnificent public spirit the manifested in eoneedTing ami executing the plant whic -ulted in t his marvelous array of industrial i h is gathered about us. I know aomething of the ieh a task, for it is heroic W&lt; lilar enterprise at Omaha a few years ago, and it was But it required much of self-sacrifice, larg of time and money from our busiest men. man ad great perplexities, and yet from it all a iting pain to our state and to all the other stat. •hereto. Such will be the history of the Portland Ex ■ in. Its influence will be felt not only this year but and through the succeeding years. It will attra re that no other magnet could have drawn and th I the future will be greater, more resourceful, mofi iring, because of it. Eer look at that portion of the Bap which repr. ■ northwestern states without wishing that the boundary ad been pushed up a few degrees farther toward the •it have been at one time had our statesmen of • more than a generation ago been as far-seeing as ar&gt; &lt;&gt;f to-day. It seems to me that no other portion our common country is richer in natural resources than is particular section and that is the reason I wish we had of it. and still I am not covetous. I only regret that at the time the Oregon boundary was agreed on we did not preet our territorial rights to the full limit, thus securing try to the north to which the riirht of di- and exploration entitled us. and. incidentally, complete control of the entrance to Puget sound. I ever look at the portion of the map pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p046">39 tatitnde to that grand old p rough whose efforts we have itriot. Dr. Marcus Whitman, preserved to us as niiiph &lt;&lt;{ now included within man with a far-seeing mind, gratitude to that grand old p triot. Dr. Marcua Whitman thr eh whose efforts we ha preserved to us as inn tis northwestern country ns i: ■uixlaries. If there ever was t pable of penetratiag the veil ranee history by the dim lig e«l, th.Tt man was Marcus Wl thi hwestern country ns i now included within If there ever wa man with a far-seeing mind, of future years and r&lt; of future years and r&lt; if penetrating the veil history by the dim light of the times in which he it man was Marcus Whitman. The wonderful - th li made and the suffering: he endured daring that il midwinter hort midwinter hors ride from Walla Walla I ride from Walla Walla I il and on to Washington, undertaken that Oregon i undertaken that Orepron i Lo, be saved in the nation, is a ved to the nation, is ,' narrative of exceeding ini true American heart. But the narrative of exceeding in1 a and thrills the i&gt;uK and hril the pulse of every true American heart. But the strangest thing is the lethar* st thin'' is the lethar iy and indifference with which y and indifference with which Whitman's account of British scconnt of British afrcression in the northwesi Whit lggression in the north received at Washington, invo r the loss of all this princely empire. Imagine Unii arguing against the possibility of ever settlii rountrv and insisting that the entire area w; worth the energy and expense necessary to the convoy train so irreat a distance, and yet sue! as th peated iii the halls of congress and were participi effort finally enabled to rally sufficient 1 uion one of its brightest finall ibled to rally sufficient t support and thus pr gems. All honor to upport and thus pi i'uion one of its brightest ins. All honor to A l Whitman. If every county in Or in his memory an endorin than merited recognition, Whitman. If every county in Or )regon and Washington si n and Washington sh nir monument it would b&lt; I am triad to know thai monument it would bi a memory an endur merited recognition n I am glad to know thai of the greatest counties of Wm Whitman Walla \ mtics of W uhington bears his name Walla, is one i&gt;t' the lea ishinirton bears his name Whitman ( Walla Walla, is one of the lefl educational institutions of the eo Xeliraska has more than a \ educational institutions of tin ■&lt;&gt;ast country. paanng interesi in ti. t country. Nebraska has more than passing interest in th it Washington, involving as it did, acute dangi in- wiaesi statesmen. Tt was only by the most hereuleai tlmt the friends of Oregon, aided by Whitman, </seg>
            <seg id="p047">40 quired by the Louisiana purchase, and has a rijrht to share in the glory attaching to those intrepid pioneen of wester: tion, Messrs. Lewis and Clark. These gentlemen, with d a number of months in Nebraska ii the records they left are invahiiible to onr state arehiYea "ine of the earliest data of oor history. On An- ( last year there was celebrated at Fort Calhoun, Nebi airing Indian chiefs of that locality. This auni was attended by many of our citizens and w;is at appropriation for the work in hand is small, the comn It tilt 1 !' expended it with such rare discretion that th gratifying. All whom I the subject have been pf _iven much favorable eonun t let me i arketed beyond state lines i have heard express the] v nfuse in praise and 1 1 1 ■ s'ut. We are a great state bid all to your mind that in 1904 urplus products to the amount r to represent is an important part of the territor nteunial anniversary of a famous council participat in by Lewis and Clark, represent in jr the governnier [1 ■ my privilege to be present and to .iKiit rmimioinor.mve address delivered by Bon. William F. Gurley of Omalia. I am also reminded that this ilar date is the one hundred and first anniversary of the ant Charles Floyd of the Lewis and Clark which event occurred in Nebraska territory near the f Dakota City. But recently our citizens have : a monument to his memory and have dedicated it with servanee. Loyalty i irdinal virtue- We who are gathered here are justly proud of the ■ooreea which has been made in the ilturnl building by our State Commission. Though the </seg>
            <seg id="p048">&gt;RN PYRAMID IN KKCKPTION ROOM </seg>
           
            <seg id="p049">41 a number of foreign countries and representing one-se- IT own national exports for that year. This year we l to make a still better showing and our pra warrant the hope. The principal items entering into rarplus of $2 0 are in round numbers, pack - ing house products $60,000,000, eattle 143,000,000, ! 00, corn $23,000,000, wlieat $16,000,000. These ti - nt the assertion that we are something of an "inland empire'' ourselves, and that we have an important part in ation'a balance sheet. ■a in very glad to have tlie privilege of participating in ismopolitan exposition. As 1 said at the beginning have little reason for its existence were it not foi educational tendency. The spei but it is the demonstration &lt; i life and making for a _ impression. My hop L-ular may dazzle for a in ta affecting the pra f higher civilization that lea is that because of this great Eiering of the best t-xp will be the better in all relations. ments of the human mind the ■ial. industrial and goveru- Address of Hon. George L. Loom is, Nebraska Day, A — 1 . I K-. President, Ladies and Gentlemen: It would seem in - riate, indeed, for me to make any extended address ihat has been so well said by the able and eloquent Kery true American is proud of his country, and proud tate. Jle believes that of all countries known to In or modern, his has been most bountifully bles - i her wonderfully varied climatic conditions, her wealth Dtlemeo who have preceded me </seg>
            <seg id="p050">42 i fertile plains, her broad lakes ami count] E empire, through the long yean of the ( another divinely fitted man. the great Lincob bing forever in that straggle oi national sin. slavery: the re-uniting of our c eountry: in these nnd in ■ thousand other things he s guiding hand of a Protecting Providence, working out ml in this people the destiny of the human race; templates what God hath wrought, his heart swel n ami with patriotic fervor, his whole being reap inspiring sentiment of his national song, Sweet Land of Liberty.' And witli that pride and love of country, even as a part •. and inseparable from it. comes the pride and 1 v "f that particular part of his country which he lie who loves his country loves his home, and he whi not home lias no love for eountry. And so it is that we of Whraska love to hear the people sin&lt;r the praises and recount the advantages of their state. For them it is the beat spot on all the earth, the one ] them. &lt;;...! gmdk id .Nature does her I ..] her lovely roses ami eai her 'My Country, 'tis of Thee, lainl prepared for man where every physical want i has been anticipated and provided for by the Booni I' all tin 1 In tlie coming of the Pilgrim Fathers, in the char; irly immigrants, whose ample virtues were as mir and hills they eame i&lt;&gt; subdue: in the Btraa •ly patriots for independence; the raising up i as their leader, divinelv fitted i&lt;&gt;r the preal ta of that stni!_ r L r le : the adoption &lt;&gt;f our ben mi- ben .verniiient : all along our country's inarch fr ireh fi </seg>
            <seg id="p051">43 Cms fruits, as we enjoy 1 water and nncover with we have no feelinf er ideal weather, drink oi reverence to her idolized Mt envy, but rejoiee to know that many bl. ad appn : pie have counted their them fully And we love, too, to hear our brethren from the North e upon the Sound: to hear them ntains wherein the wealth of man; of their fteldi ■ the virtues of tlv their forests and not world awaits the productive rds where nature rew the human touch a hundred ill the glorv of self-exalta- And we love to tion. and to think we hear hf .plates herself. "Am I not great Babylon f" And M her wonderful vision of future comprehension of other mortals. we musingly meditate upon far beyond tlu Grow." Yes. we've lean. ■ve to "Watch Tacoma hthat slogan as the hired man upon the farm love- I of the dinner horn. We love to see it posted up in e y place, we love to rind it stuck upon our plates u tto our daily meals, and whei e to see it flashed across tlu veiling fall wo waters in electric lights i we love to find hanging n. the absence of which from as it later haunts us to our roon the door that prayerful injuncti any home in Tacoma we are told denotes disloyalty unpa - able, "God Bless Our Home, and Watch Tacoma Grow." Thi-. mingling of devotion and business reminds one strongly of the r of the little girl: "Oh. Lord, bless papa and manima and make a real good little girl of me. Oh, Lord, if ai you don't succeed, try and try again." And Portland, too. fairest of the fair, bride of the setting sun, in the fragrance of « ! might almost to dream awav his life and float un sly into an eternity I thousand-fold with exultant priii </seg>
            <seg id="p052">44 of never-ending bliss! Surely the world will excuse, and all admire, the devotion of the loyal ■objects and wonder not that they should I to nrhangs ■ home amidst thy .ess for one in Paradise. manifested everywhere, and in •njr different ways, that spirit of intense loyalty and de - ll to home which characterizes not only the people of Northwest, but the true American citizen 8 by any people to i-n. that they cannot restrain it. but that it i and overflow! in true Seattle or Taeoma style. But, my friends, let Be remind you that there is at I t upon earth that challenges your admin d of broad rivers and countless streams, of vast rolling prairies and beautiful valle\s. A land, not literally flowing milk and honey, it is true, and yet whose fields an with a wealth of grain that almost passes belief, a land re kissed by the rays of the awning sun long before his light is visible over the mountain I that bounds your eastern view; a land of great diversity of where corn and wheat and oats and rye and barley, timothy, clover, Moegraaa, alfalfa, and other useful grains and grasses all seem native to the soil and vie with one an - other as to which shall yield the richest returns to the lius - liandman. A land that, because of its abundant and nutritious wild grasses, was the favorite pasture ground of the wild buffalo, which but a few years ago roamed in vast herds over the plains where now more than twelve million head of cattle, horses, sheep and swme Iced and fatten annually. A land, the value of whose productions last year of five hundred and one million dollars, will be increased this year by twenty to ty-tive million more. A land where illiteracy is all but unknown, and where human I tind rich reward. A </seg>
            <seg id="p053">45 land whose banks are overrl people to such an extent that half the money loaned out, ani to keep the permanent school been compelled to buy several twing with the wealth of the they find it impossible to 1 whom state treasurer, in i fund invested, lias of late hundred thousand dollars v bonds of other states. A land where education is anil ere plenty abounds, and where poverty strange land. Yes. a land d happy in the enjoyment upon them by Divine Provid where the people are eonti of the many blessings be*' ■nee. and envy not the dwi My friends, 1 have not Eie far short of doing it justi di more, and yet she is only ani/ed as a territory more tli &lt; open to settlement by the v in her infancy. Oretron was ban ten years before Nebr white man, or before he could her land. Fifty-one ■ into a territory had just : orial government was not in - &gt;llowing, and this goodly si title to an acre of now. the act erecting Nebra augurated until the Octol of Portland was even then a When Oregon became a territory and was pulsating with the new life of an inflowing tide of immigration, the greater of Nebraska was still practically unexplored, and was d Dated upon the map as the Great American Desert. »\Vhen our good friend and honored citizen, Henry '1'. ■irk. who sits here upon this platform to-day, came to Ne - iiska titty years ago last spring, there were more Indi little Indian village where Omaha now .stands than them white settlers in the whole territory. Yes, it has now &gt;n scarcely fifty years since Nebraska first became the home of the white man. What nl. what th meiit. what I ani Let in other plac&lt; overdrawn the picture; I have stiee. Nebraska is all this, and I by i-imirress. but territ ity of no small pretentious. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">46 hurried j \.-r thai time l'rior lo 1860 the settlement of the territory, while rather (advantages, among which we may mention that ;ri river was then practically t lie western border-lim rilization; that nearly all beyond was the home of the Man: that his title to but a very small portion oi ands had been exting that lie roamed at will, dering both property tended farther west th •■■uri river uecessitated iishe.1 by the general goYern - and committed many depr and lite insecure: that no rail- tng and tedious overland that the distance to market was great, supplies ■ ree, expensive and hard to obtain. The cena the territory a population of a little less than it, but we must not forget that Nebraska then included a ii of what is now Colorado. Wyoming. Montana and the the Civil war. .May 18, of that year, the proclamation calling for one regiment of try. In less than thirty days nx companies had . in and by July 22 the last of the ten companies was later the regiment started to the umniander, Colonel John M. Thayer, soon be ral, was one of Grant's most trusted advisers, and the war became Tinted States senator, and later, for twe vernor. lie is still living, a beloved citizen of our al city. Tlie second Nebraska regiment of twelve MHBV vii in excess of the call, soon followed. In all. the . territory from her meager population sent 3,157 men -i Indian depredations which were then only rly satisfactory, when we consider the inanv ■in eastern Iowa, and to r rganizing an efficient militia to pi </seg>
            <seg id="p055">47 immigration received ii shing means of easy 1 1 mr door. The prairie* i sprang up everywl. lines of steel across the - metits followed far into raska was admitted m- After the close of the w i Railroads came, fur with new life and thriving v The Union Pacific extended her Erarda the Pacific and settk erior. On .March 1. 1867, Nel 1 in 1870 the census rave her i population of nearly 12 Then in the early seventies which has never before or sine our country, and which for so] anil made the future of our st came a visitation, the like of ■ been known to any part otj some years unsettled conditions state problematical. 1 rel n billions upon billions of the Queen '8 dominion to the north, the grasshopper plague, whei little pests, hatched out in the came (weeping down over tin kotas. Minnesota. Iowa. Nebrat Central West, across the Da - ka. Kansas and on to the ' heir wake. Were 1 t thing Imt desolation ■d by the people of that icareely believe me. Wen- I ntly flew over in niulti; ude the rays of the sun if the scenes wit tour country you would tell vou that they freq you that they frequ as to totally ex hadow on the ground u would not believe me rue. Were 1 to tell you that they would light yet I field of corn in cultivating time and in two hours not spear above ground, you would not believe me. ami yet it is ne. During those years, immigration practically ceased and t great many of our citizens left the state for good. Souk em, who came on to Oregon, I have met here in Portland during this Exposition. The spring of 1877 witnessed tb of the iri'asshoppers and speedily confidence was restored and immigration again commenced to How in. Fur about fifteen years nothing further transpired t&gt; \" -I r \\*tb Th mi '•mi ■ th • Iriiiith of the earlv nine- nging markets t&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p056">48 I when the whole western portion of Kansas and Nebraska and the vast stretch (if country lying east of the mountain? and west of the one hundredth parallel, was parched and burned as though a prairie fire had swept over it. thousands of our people moved away and again Oregon an&lt;] Washington profited by our loss. But the drouth years, like tli &gt;pper years, passed away, we believe forever, and during the past ten year ■pment and prosperity of &lt;mr state almost passes one's r of comprehension. The increase in the value of farm agricultural products and live stock has ben phenom- Farms in eastern .Nebraska now sell readily for &gt; ■ me of the poorer ones of course below I far above those figures. , November 10. 1904, the (jti7 banks of Nebraska hell 1104,129,453.26, of which vast sum it was third, or about $35,01 longed to farmers. At this time the deposits will approximate $125,000,000, and me proportion will hold good. At that time $4G.(«" !i hand and unloaned in the banks. Literally our j have more money than they know what to do with. The total production of Nebraska for the year 1904, was I, of which amount over 4U per cent Wl of the principal item- The total acreage of corn, wheat, oata, rye and barley for in over 1904 of 611.2(15 acres. This ■ se. with increase of oth. ,| &lt;; e t e .. indi- Packing f SJ ♦60,453,795.* attic 4.{.010,595.(X 31..343,453.5( ?orn . . . 22,966,018.5! Whmi . 1").741.769.6( </seg>
            <seg id="p057">LEWIS AND CLARK CENTENNIAL EXPOSITION. 49 r)0,000. For several years prior to 1904 the average an- M has been about $12,000,000. The acreage of grains this year is: ('"HI 6,433,585 2,091,871 2.420,624 Wheat Oats . 141,140 Barley Potato 188,360 89,271 88,416 Sorghum 15,548 Sugar beets 11,468,824 Thus you see that the acreage in the eight grains alone would make a belt one mile mile, wide and 17,926 miles long, or sufficient to reach more than two-thirds the way round the earth; or it would make a belt six miles wide reaching from San Francisco to New York. Add to this the acreage in tame grasses as follows: 1,449,409 Pnd you see we have of tame grasses enough to make an - belt a mile wide and 2,264 miles long, or sufficient to reacn from San Francisco east clear into Ohio. But this isn't all. Take our 1,995,000 acres of wild grasses and you have enough for another belt one mile wide reaching from San Timothy 453,553 Alfalfa 315,714 Blue Ghraa 230,621 Millet 141,277 (lover 51,122 Other tame grassi 257,122 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">tn New York city and 200 miles beyond in' Then if you add to this the acreage in smaller crops, such as broom corn. Kaffir corn, speltz. beans, peas, orchards, small fruits, etc.. and your grand total would extend the belt one mile &gt;r around the world. i you begin to see what a wonderful empire Nebraska is? But let us put it in another way. Nebraska's exports in that 1 mean what she marketed beyond the uted to *-_ )|l% \ll&lt;'.r&gt;7i;. !!.-&gt;. or one-third more than tl, • lapaii: two and one-half times more than Mi e that of Sweden: three-fifths as nuieh as Kus^ times thai of ■ ud nearly double that of Spain. It ei)ual' venth of tin- total exports of the United Si Third in production of meat-packing plant Third in production of corn. th in production of wheat •h in number of cattle. ih in number of • Fifth in production of oats Fifth in production of rye. Fifth in production of beet lUgar. •I in the number of acres in farms. :ith in the number of h&lt; Ninth in the value of farm products per acre. Tenth in itter and milk productions To this let me add that she has one of the four largest the I'nited States, a half dozen excellent col - leges, four splendid Normal schools, a many academies, and a public - unsurpassed by that of any other state. For twenty years she has held the proud position of ■ rily. Nebr. good stale. ;i rich and product] </seg>
            <seg id="p059">LEWIS AND CLARK CENTENNIAL EXPOSITION. first of all the states in the smallest percentage of illit . a position that her unsurpassed educational facilities and the rml intelligence and prosperity of her people will enable her to maintain for many years to come. And now, my friends, lest I tire you by talking too long, let me say to you of the Xort Invest : "Gkwy in your home land, be true and loyal to its every interest, sing its pr all you please and tirelessly proclaim its advantages, for it is a pood land and thus it becomes you as Americans t and we would have little respect for you if you didn't do it But remember, that we of Nebraska are just as proud of our ui are of yours. That we see there equally as many adva: ■ here. That Nebraska's sons are just al. just as true, just as devoted to her interests and wel - fare as are the sons of any other state. And let us all remem - ber that God never made a perfect country. He may have pretty near it. but there are always some imperfections. He never put all advantages in one place, and all disadvan - - in another; all perfection in one state, and all imperfec - ni another. Near the n in the best land He has left se he has planted the thorn, and many things to be desired. Be in your homes, wherever they are, and we will be happy ours, and we will all strive with laudable zeal to build up ur own home states and thus add to the glory and grea of our common country. </seg>
            
            <seg id="p060">FINANCES From the hour of organization the finances of the &lt; mission were a subject of close attention and rigid economy on the part of the members of the Commission. George L. Loomis, the treasurer of the Commission, devoted himself to a thorough study of the expenses likely to be incurred, and prepared estimates which were to guide the Commission in its expenditures. Twelve thousand dollars were appropriated by the state, while the Union Pacific railway and the Burling - ton and Missouri railway each contributed the equivalent of several hundred dollars in gratuitously transporting the ex - hibits, the one to Portland and the other from Portland to Nebraska again. The expense of collecting and installing exhibits, erecting a pavilion, maintaining the exhibit and a force of attendants and distributing the exhibits at the close of the expo - tat to $11,257.04. The executive officer of the Commis - sion was authorized to sell the grain used in decoration and exhibition, and certain specific property used in conu. with the Commission headquarters, the pavilion and ni ovine picture film being retained and returned to the state for suoh future use as may be desired. The receipts from these sales amounted m $150.00. It will be seen, therefore, that the cost of Nebraska's exhibit at the Fair was $11,107.04 and there is left in the hands of the state treasurer, out of the appropria - tion of $12,000, a balance of $892.96. Throughout the term of the exposition the Commission exercised the closest supervision and the greatest care in its maintenance, in the expenditure of money for incidentals, as well as in the collection and distribution of exhibits. In this work they were assisted by the corps of assistants who used </seg>
            <seg id="p061"/>
           
            <seg id="p062">53 E effort to preserve the property of the pavilion an ict the incidental expenditure along strictly modest and mical lines. FINANCES— General Statement ■t unexpended and remaining in State Treasury $ 892.96 • ■ral statement of the finances is given below: EXPENDITURES IN DETAIL. 1 Harry Porter, office supplies $ Maud Chevront, A. ( &gt;. Wiggenjoat, stenographic servi J..43 4 Win. . Fames. -hedd, services 6 Win. James, money expended for corn and agricultural exhibits 8 King A Jeasop, oflBce supplies Forbes Stables, drayage Si ; h &amp; Son, corn for exhibit 7 II. (i. Sliedd, coninn RECEIPTS. Appropriation $12,000.00 \hibits 150.00 DISBURSEMENTS. iltnral Exhibit .. $4,080.01 'lisintr ami printing 784.80 Empl 3,108.55 lainment. Cominissioiiers' K\| i-identaN ■■UK Total $11. L' •i- $12.1 Disbursements $11,2 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">54 E W. 1'. Warner, commie Caligan I eting pavilion 1 ' 1 1 1 1 I i l: rntingent fund, maintenance of Ncliraska &lt; dibit X- i &lt; ; I. Loomis, commisc II. A Hober, one-half May salary Win. James, salary. May 1.1. salary. Maj Thus. Persons, salary and expenses, May 19 "0 King &amp; .Ii-ssup. printing 21 til in moving pictures schert, artificial decorative material uses installing exhibit ■ iicr"s e\| M B. Plume, labor A. O. Wiggenjost, stenographic work J- ICeBride Co., painting rm. James, money expended for agrieultur exhibits •al n f. L. 1. ortlaml Gen. Klectric Co.. supplies Holniaii Transfer Co., drayagt Hon.yinan Hardware Co.. supplies Portland Gen. EleHri. ipplies. Shfldd, salary, June H. A. Hober, salary, June Thomas Persons, salary. June M M m Win. James, salary. June J. North &amp; Co., register • In Hardware Co., supplies W. • i. M C. F. Chaae, &lt;-&lt;&gt;rn </seg>
            
            
            <seg id="p064">42 rntingent fund, maintenance of Nebraska ex - hibit 4:! 500.00 17.:!") ath Stationery Co., maps rn Union Tel. Co.. services three months : rax Westerman, money paid for exprw and telephone tin. James, expended for irrain and Chevront. stenographic worl Thomas l'ersons. salary. July Win. James, salary, July 61 mmissioner Wm. James, expenses collecting grain 64 Johnson Bros. Transfer Co., drayag. 116.45 66 Dodge County Printing Co., printing 2&lt;&gt;,(K)0 Ne - braska folders Olds, Wortman &amp; King. Nebraska badges Honeyman Hardware Co., hardware 69 H. G. Shedd, expflom commissioner H. G. Sheild. commissioner's expenses Lincoln Transfer Co.. drayage. Pea l'rintiiif: Co., 2.~&gt;,&lt;KH&gt; Nebraska hand book* atingent fuiul, maintenance of NVbrask. hibit Sbedd, salary. July Win, Sizer. salary, one-half month II. A. Hober, salary. July (I. ('. Shedd, incidental bill Win. Sizcr. expenses as lecturer 0. L. Loomia, expenses commissioner Tlios. Persons, salary, one-half Auirust II. (i. Shedd, expenses Geo. ('. Bhedd, incident*! expeBM of pavilion King &amp; Jewip, letter heads, etc. Lewis &amp; Clark Exposition rnee for sea&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p065">71 Gillespie ic Phil] Nebraska" 2 K ables. dra 73 Alice Wi 74 Alici- I in. Hobart-Curtis hotel, entertaining governor, week of Nebraska Day 76 S. M. Yenard. Nebraska Day quartet Kilhain Stationery Co., I.immi Nebraska badg prio'i Administration band, servi braska Day distributed to Ne- braska visitors 1 B. I'inrlat. dinner r and party. Nebraska Day 1 Mrs. Charity Hart, wro weeks II. A. Sober, salary, August py, August 13-September l' &gt;»4 Wn ilary. August 1 ( Win. .lames, salary. Aujnist Shedd. salarv August I Win. P. Warner, commissioner's 1 John Call . niakinp: tables, pyramid sheh 1 I. If. MeBride, painting - 47.00 Loomis, eommist f+1 H. (i. Shodd. ecilimii- II. G. Shedd. incidentals during mber money advanced 93 I Id. salary. September 1- 94 Wn. .1 100.00 nber I' 1 ry. September 1 !«7 II. A. Hober mber </seg>
            <seg id="p066">LEWI AND CLARK CENTENNIAL EXPOSITION 57 &gt; itobor Thomas 1 'rise .us. salary, 1\\ Fred Echtenkamp, corn Bbedd, money advan ::;; 1 for incident! raph, express, throe i Maud Cfcevront, stenograph; Henry F. Kii-ser. Nebraska 1 Cancelled. Day invitations iLrricnltural su- G. C. Shedd, salar Charity Hart, travelii xpi-nsi's. hostea 114 Wm. Selig, expense, m and supplies A. .Martin, box of displ rasses and gr v 118 Geo. C. Shedd. salary. December. Hammond Printing Co., publishing report C. Shedd, postage, express, incidental expense issuing report and concluding Commissioner's affair: Total pense. pavilion FW in. James, salary, two weeks. Octobc H. 0. Shed&lt;l. telephone, telegraph, ex months Win. James, traveling &gt;-x\ perintendenl ber, November II. A. Hober, incidental exj Wm. P. Warner, commissioner's ex; ;e L Loonk, commissioner'! expei 113 Gta&gt;. C slicdd. expense* Omaha-Portland ; Port- land-Omaha ving picture machines </seg>
            <seg id="p067">THE EXPOSITION OFFICIALS WhniTM, The administrative oAeen of the Lewii Clark Centennial Exposition showed prior to, during the term of the Exposition tad subsequently, ■ keen and aetive ini in the participation of thu of Nebraska in the abov lion: and supplied a liberal and favorable - 'a of the Nebraska State Pavilion and installation and manifested and preserved a fair and luet in its administrative dealings and a uniform ility in its social relations with the Nebraska State I • n and its officers: and appointed, set aside and ngna lay. namely. August 21. as Nebraska Day. for ill ■ad celebration of Nebraska's participation in tb Qtertaining the State's chief executive and his official ■ting to make the occasion and day noteworthy and patriotic: therefore, be it Ived, That the Nebraska 8 mmiiwion extend to EL W. i; !&lt;■ and other administrative ofBeei the I. I Clark Centennial Exposition their thank - appreciation for the above named interest, aid and cooperation; and that the same be engrossed upon the records of the I ■ ii, and made public EMPLOYEES reas, The employees and assistants of the Nebraska -ion to the Lewis and Clark Centennial Expo - have shown on each and ever &gt;n and at all times, a lively and watchful regard for the State's exhibits, interests and ] ;it the above named Exposition, be it x&gt; I itA Th • I lr &lt;4t A h </seg>
            <seg id="p068">K their thanks to the Comn ea and ts for such services, as fellows: G. ('. Shedd, Win. W. A. Sizer. Tims. 1 Vis,, us. II. A. Hober and Mrs. Hart. DOUGLAS COIXTY Whereas, Douglas County, through its Board of Commis - sioners and &lt;i. W. Wattles, generously loaned to tin ili- Commission its complete and valuable coll, of thr.-shed grain* and seeds, which collection attracted wide attention from Exposition visitors and won high awards Imposition's official juries; be it f solved. That the Nebraska State Commission d&lt; their thanks ami appreciation to the Douglas County ■ liimissioners ami Mr. (i. W^Watt THE BURLINGTON &amp; MISSOURI RAILWAY BVhereas. The Burlington and Missouri Railway t' 1 from Nebraska to Portland. Ore., at its own exp uinerous exhibits collected by the Nebraska State ' in for the Lewis and Clark Exposition : and showed dur - tie transportation of the exhibits the greatest care and ition : and, further, during the entire term of the E ■the officers of the above named road evinced a - : in the work of the Commission, and lent their ice ; be it B solved. That the Nebraska Commission do herewith em - leir thanks and appreciation to the Burlington and Mis - lailway and its general manager, Mr. G. W. Hoi ir aid and public spirit tendered and exhibited in that THE UNION PACIFIC RAILWAY. Whereas, The 1'nion Pacific Railway transported from </seg>
            <seg id="p069">60 Elion, and the Nebraska Pavilion, constructed the groundl of the Lewis and Clark Centennial Ex; and showed during their transportation the greates - for their safety and expedition; and. further, during the of t! lion the officers of the above named road »d a constant interest in the work of the Commission ■nt it ready assistance : be it ived. That the Nebraska State Commission do here - with embody their thanks anil appreciation to the I ..lilway and its genera] manager and vice-president. Mr. A. L. Mohler. for their aid and public spirit tendered and I in that behalf. THE NEWSPAPER PRESS Whereas. Tax per pnss of Nebraska lias lent its influential support to the project from its earliest incept! rmination of Nebraska's participation in the Lewi- Clark Centennial Exposition; and, further, has maintained a taut interest in the work of the Nebraska State their appointment, and has liberally contributed by opening its pages and publishing in the plans and transactions of the ComissisMon and full ■ iptions and accounts of Nebraska's exhibit.;. ad awards upon the Exposition grounds; be it ived. That the Nebraska n do here ■ to the newspaper press of the State their thanks ion. and embody the same in formal expri - which shall )■ in the records of the Coinn - and made public. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA Whereas. The University of Nebraska and its Chancellor generously loaned to the Nebraska ommission for ex - hibit at the Lewis and Clark i any valuable </seg>
            <seg id="p070">LEWIS AND CLARK CENTENNIAL EXPOSITH ■ .;] trihuti'MiN. riiit't «i nit*fi i_r winch was tne mounted steer l^nai - r, world prize-winner, all of which exhibits attr, marked attention from visitors to the Nebraska pavilion ; be it Ivcd, That the Nebraska State Commission do I their thanks and appreciation to the 1'niversity and Chancellor E. Benjamin Andrews for this assistance THOMAS R. KIMBALL. k Whereas, Mr. Thomas R. Kimball generously and gratuit - • designed the architectural plan upon which the Nebraska i.m at the Lewis and Clark Exposition was constru ling: the Commission to exhibit Nebraska's products in a and effective manner, and which contributed greatly, ii- beauty, originality and excellence of the exhibit; be it Solved, That the Nebraska State Commission e\ ks and appreciation to Mr. Thomas R. Kimball of for his services. THE NEBRASKA SOCIETY OF OREGON E Whereas, The Nebraska Society of Oregon sh&lt;&lt; ugliout the season of the Lewis and Clark Exposition, a n and constant interest in the Nebraska exhibit; and as - d in every possible way in making Nebraska Da tful and patriotic celebration; be it ■ Ived, That the Nebraska State Commission do here heir full appreciation and thanks to the Nebraska •y of Oregon, and to its officers, for the great and un - diminished interest evinced in Nebraska's work at th. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Total nuinlicr of entries. 12~&gt; -. total number of awards, 121 : as fallow collective exhibit of corn Nebraska, exhibit of sheaf and threshed prain of Nebraska, collective exhibit of Bf Nebraska. eoUeetrre 1 forat exhibit of wild ami tune L'rasses of Nebraska, eollei'tivt torn. exhibit of twenty-six products E Nebraska, m mre exhibition. Nebraska, jiavilimi and beadqaarfc ten] agricultural installation. County, collective exhibit &lt;&gt; id threshed grains. Hard. Rlair. Red Fife wheat. ■ Murphy, ted clover, timothy, alfalfa Morrisy. Dorebeater, corn. rtin. Dubois. Macaroni wheat, sheaf trtilL Dubois. buckwheat. ■laher. Fremont Vellow Dent. Le-ral Tender cm. Howard. Emerald, (iiant Siberian winter rye. ireh. Dubois, Blue Stem wheat. irch. Dubois. Blue Stem chaff. B. F. .Muinma, Friend, timothy. (irau, Bennington, Silver Mine Dent, Calico Dent, Golden Ijw and (irau's White Pride corn. Grau. Bennintrton. Castor Oil beans. :{. .Miller, ilillard. exhibit of corn. Hasik, Abie, exhibit of corn. &lt;;&lt;&gt;M Medala If. Murphy, Crete, Texas re&lt;] i </seg>
            <seg id="p072">63 Chas. Schamle. Emerald, exhibit of corn. C. A. Piirker. Palmyra. Early White Cap, Dent, Calico Dent corn. Ki Seed Co.. Fremont. ran &amp; Son., Waterloo exhibit of corn. White Dent corn. Roy Reed, Palmyra, Golden Beauty corn. rrry Seltz. De Soto. Early Pride of the North, Mammoth Yellow corn. ('. A. Whit ford. Arlington, exhibit of corn Joseph Hall. Tekaniah. Hogue's Yellow Dent corn Smith &amp; Son. De Solo, exhibit of corn C. F. Chaw, Pawnee. Reid's Yellow Dent. Chase's White orn R. M. W'olcott. Palmer. Early Pride of the Xorth. White Flint. lobe Scott. Dorchester, exhibit of corn. Frank Rentier, Pleasant Hill. Big Four oats A. E. Richards. Heaver City. Jerusalem corn Geo. Ross. Wilber, Silver Hull buckwheat Paulson, Brock, White Dent corn F. Mank. Broken Bow, White Winter Rose corn J. F. Olson, Ithaca, Reid's Yellow Dent corn. G. W. Fennerston, Fremont. Reid's Yellow Dent corn Sam Davis. Wilber, Japanese buckwheat. • htt'iikani]). Arlington, exhibit of corn. J. KiiiiK'.v. Dorchester, Reid'a Yellow Dent com \Y. -I. Bryan, Lincoln, sheaf of ry€ Mobery, Dorchester, exhibit of &lt;'&lt;&gt;rn tFellnian, BeeBMT, Calico Dent earn. If. S.vfonl. Lincoln. Silver Mine Dent. iily, Beatrice, Castor Oil beam L. A. Bowden, Winter, Legal Tender corn J. ('. Nelson. Millard, winter rye. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">i, Dorchester. Black Irish oats. • i-hmier. Dubois. Macaroni wheat, sheaf. .1. M. Titterington. Yellow Dent corn. KA. &lt; .iistafson. Oakland. Hogue's Yellow Dent, in Sugar Beet Co., Ames, sugar beet seed. k, Wilbur, Red winter wheat. B Waterloo, Crimson clover, e, Dubois, White rye. ■Calkins, Beaver City, broom corn seed. Vheeler, Crete, Red winter wheat. Dale Floral Co., Beatrice, English i . Red Clover. Ri&gt;d Kaffir corn. Frank Brown. Beaver City, Red Kaffir corn. Farm. Lincoln. Yellow Chernorka. « County, White Dent. Yellow Dent corn. . Dubois. Red winter wheat. H. Ballard, Blair, Black oats. White clover. R. D. Morrisy. Dorchester. Red winter wheat. R. D. Morrisy. DorchtM. r. Bad Top Seed, Red clover. A. Martin. Dubois. Macaroni wheat. Italian speltz. wart, Omaha, Stewart Kentucky bluegrass seed. J. R. Miller, Milford. Red clover. Wood River Land &amp; Loan Co., Eddyville, collection native and tame grasses. Wood River Land &amp; Loan Co., Eddyville, Red winter wheat. Frank Gobel, Dubois, soft wheat, sheaf. Jenkins &amp; Hopkins, Broken Bow, Fife wheat .1. W. Ingalls, Pleasant Hill, broom grass. Noble, Crete, Silver Mine Dent corn. K H"gue, Crete. Hogue's Yellow Dent cor*i. Silver Medals— 28. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">65 Poaola, Pleasant Hill, Milo maize. James, Dorchester, sheaf flax. PL Skinner, Fremont, Red Winter wheat, k Pannerhill, Norfolk, White Dent corn, rush, Falls City, Red clover. R. P. Fairchild, Endicott, cane seed. C. Vistrat, Broken Bow, White hulless barley. Collins, Beaver City, broom corn seed. E. Oft, Bennington, Red clover. D. McLean, Atkinson, Red Fife wheat John Povlish, Crete, speltz, field peas Bronze Me lals— 18. wheat. Keeler, Crete, Red winter . Waterloo, Red citron se&lt; 1, Hubbard squash, early L. W. Howard, Emerald, Giant Siberian rye. J. M. Maher, Fremont, Mediterranean wheat. erks, Bttffiington, Black Russian sunflower seed. (' M. Smale, Emerald, Bluegrass seed. 0. Fink, Dubois, Club wheat t &gt;. Fink, Dubois, Club wheat, sheaf. Quinn, Pleasant Hill. Red winter wheat K!amp, Cheney, Chinese popcorn, ward, Yellow Dent corn, •h. Auburn, Red clover. EHaines. Broken Bow, speltz. att, Omaha, Black hulless barley, try, Beaver City, Sorghum seed. Kny, Pleasant Hill, Bucket gourd seed. leasant Hill. Siberian millet. ie, Bluegrass seed. ilen peas, Jersey Belle muskmelon. J. F. McCardel, Elk City. Kentucky bluegrass, Macaroni wheat. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Honorable Mentioi t, Omaha, ornamental poiawfiamli J. D. H«sik. Abie. Macaroni wheat 1. Iftwmingtoa, Bed spring wheat Williams, Benson. Evolution corn. Combs. Homer, samples of wheat from 18 Martin. Dubois. Silver Mine oats. t 1 •4 D. Link, Millard. German millet. ■Louik, Pleasant Hill, German millet. Robinson, Waterloo. Dixie and Mountain </seg>
            <seg id="p076">'n&gt;rt time ago 1 had the p I visiting the land Exposition and of eonrae weal to im the Xebrask hibit. It was easily found at one of the main entrances cf the Agricultural building. Then. too. everyone in the building seemed to know where the exhibit was. and I was very | 'hat it made the most im ppeanaee of any exhibit in the building. The eorn exhibit is exeeptionallv fine, the 1 and other products of the state are artistically arranged, and. last but not least, the moving ture illustration of the resources of the state attracts the at - ■n and comment of everyone. Those in attendance at the . seemed competent and efficient in the entertainment of lad taken all together I am )■ i.v that in my opinion Nebraska has the best state exhibit there is at the Portland Exposition, at least the best one there is in the cultural Hall of the Portland Exposition. &lt;;. \V. WATTLES, Vice- President United States National Bank. i &gt;n behalf of the people of my state and as their repr? - tive at this exposition, I desire to extend my most hearty itulations on the splendid exhibit which you have made at our great Western Exposition. E Realizing that your state cannot expect in the way of igration to receive the benefits of western states, entitled to greater consideration for assisting in a w&gt; rprise, and I am sure that the exhibit of your corn whicn have made will be of vast benefit to your producers here - r Realizing that it is im | to produce this on the Omaha. Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">western coast and that it is necessary for the raising of th&lt;J large amount of live stock that we now have, I am sure that Nebraska will receive from her western consumers in the next few years many times the amount of expenditure which iave made for your exhibit here, for no people remember a kindness longer than our western citizens and this sideration on the part of your state will long remain in the minds of our people as a debt of gratitude which they owe you. R conclusion, I desire to congratulate your commissioners e citizens of your state for their services and assistance ilf of our western enterprise and to assure them that we will always lie glad tn extend a most cordial welcome « ever they may visit our state. JEFFERSON MYERS President Oregon State Commission to the Lewis and Clark Exposition. CFor many years I resided in Nebraska, hence anything of ortance in connection with that grand old commonwealth is sure to attract my attention. A few days ago I passed through your pavilion and was pleased to note your display ; I beg to congratulate you, you tants and the people of the state on the marked success of the Nebraska exhibit and the attractions connected therewith, all located in Agricultural hall. Lewis and Clark Centennial Exposition. The agricultural displays are excellent and artistically arranged; the moving pictures make an interesting and instructive feature and are intelligently explained. Al - :ier Nebraska is receiving from visitors much favorable I think, merited comment. The money expended is fill f Al XT A T~\V*/"\ il t fl M O 1 Tl \'#*wtT^l^?l t T i \ ¥* t \\ C* Y\€*C\ t\\ £* €\t \\\ *j q4a4a </seg>
            <seg id="p078">I When we take into consideration the small appropriation, e short time allowed fur gathering the material, trai: g it two thousand miles and installing the same we admit it is a remarkable exhibit for the state, and an assur - ke of the efficiency and faithfulness of the Commission and stants. I am proud of Nebraska's exhibit. H. C. M 'ARTHUR, In Charge Department of State Exhibit, United Slates Governmeni Building. Ci me great pleasure to compliment you and h you the Nebraska Commission upon the splendid g made at the Lewis and Clark Exposition. Nebraska tn fairly be said to ha\ re idea and the importance of displaying a rtat ber of states and eorami ■- lead in conduetin exhibitions frequently during your Commission have cured the able re n the pioneer in the movin_ and effectiveness of this method demonstrated in the num - or&lt;_ r n taxations who have foli a theater with moving pie the day. It seems to me that remarkable judgment an^l suits with the amount of money ir hands for expenditure, and I feel that the state is to be congratulated upon the efficiency, faithfulness and popu - larity of those officials charged with her representation at this lion. D. M. ELI. I itive Officer, New York State Commission to Earn in receipt of the copy of the story of the Lewis and Expedition, written by a Nebraska woman. Allow me nk you for the courte- At this time I would like to say that I want to compli- Lewii and Clark Exposition. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">70 Eit that has be«a Bade at this n. Although not had a building, I believe your exhibit has tttra uch favorable comment as any stati- exhibit and that will reap the reward from tl W«1 by on, and especially by its eoni|)etent e\ iffioial. J. W. BENHAM, Commissioner to Lewis and Clark Exposition for Arizona. I ing a Nebraska man myself. I always feel a dm in all matters relating to the state. Considering the I of money available and the limited time in which you prepare your exhibit, and the further fact that you had lding of your own in whieh to arrange your &lt;l ie of the very made by any stale Bur picture displays and II out top and certainly e it than any other feature lectures perhaps atti forth more int &gt; ■: of the exhibit, ami K early show th- rity of many farm meth' i er that of other stat KKNK G. EAGLESON, Surveyor General for Idaho, Boise, Idahi I wish to state that I was very much pleased with the bition altogether. It was very creditable to the state, and to my mind was the most attractive on the grounds. Being a former resident of Nebraska. I was especially inter - ested in the Nebraska exhibition and was very much pleased to call the, attention of my western friends to the state that could pro&lt; h marvels in the way of cereals. Q-I* T nl.j, |"*i * . . T * t fl Vl DR. E. F. ROOT, </seg>
            <seg id="p080">led at the Nebraska pavilion at the Lewis and Clark Exposition hut only stopped long enough to look over the •• r and sign the mm. I expected to return the next day ami make a considerable stay at the pavilion but was un - fortunately prevented from doing - !»■ all rij.'ht there, and the appearance of the pavilion make me still more anxious to return, and to fc my inability to do so. As far as I observed il wu a credit to the state and was in every way try. Supreme Court of Nebraska. I wisli to eongratulate the Nebraska Commission who had in charge the Nebraska exhibit at Portland thk on the excellent showing made, and particularly on th mirable arrangements for taking care of Nebraskans who attended the exposition. Everywhere I heard the Nebraska exhibit commented on in the most favorable and nattering niann. RO8GOE POUND, rn of the University of Nebraska College of Law Lincoln. The Nebraska exhibit at the Lewis and Clark Exhibition was indeed a very creditable one, considering the fact that the appropriation was not Jari sentation with a building ugh to permit of Nebraska's of its own. Anyone who visited the A rieultural building could not ■be impressed with the display of grains and particularly - moving picture show, which was a unique feature and idid advertisement for Nebraska. CHARLES C. KOSEWATKR Publish pany s. H. SEDGWICK, </seg>
            <seg id="p081">72 1 Permit me to express my appreciation to you for the splendid showing you made at Portland for Nebraska, sideling the small appropriation at your disposal and the lim - ited time you had for collecting the exhibit, your showing simply wonderful. The benefit to Nebraska must be in many wa.\ The people appreciate your work for the state and I wish lor the many court* 'nded to us while A. (IAIJSHA. I had the plr. mending the Lewis and (lark sition at Portland while on my western trip last July and I and pleased with the d \hibitimi Bade by our own State of Nebraska, both the excel! 1 he products and also t li • nd abilitv I in the disposition of the same. Considering the limite 1 amount of the appropriation and the short time in which the on had to collect, transport and plan the exhibit, narvelous that such satisfactoi .1 lie obtained. It was a great advertisement for our state. I tli moving pieti town in the theater the 1 Kd the pleasure of observing, and, in my opinion, they great factor in demonstrating to the peopU the mi - irces of the state. C consider the work done by the I ion to be of importance that every man comprising it should be individuals and as a body. I also iat the work of the executive officer should not be passe 1 without a word of commendation. nissioner of Public Lands and Buildings for tary of State of the State of Nebraska H. M. EATON, </seg>
            <seg id="p082"/>
           
            <seg id="p083">73 During the month of July it was my pleasure lo visit the Lewis and Chirk Exposition, Portland, Ore. It has been in my mind for sonic time to write you and express my appreciation of the splendid showing made by our Commission at this Fair. • unds and about the eity, people wit] ■ I complimented the Nebraska pavilion — our King caiifrht all of them. The moving picture feature, novel an! instructive, is a winner for our great state. I was really i Ei tin* Nebraska badg&lt; jit a wonderful succ and I know tin ion for their work, and with limited no and face the world. I con - s for Nebraska, a great stroke people feel grateful towards the which wa [ilished D fans. 11. I. ■ Deputy State Auditor for Nebraska. Pideed I have an abiding recollection of my visit to the ska pavilion at the Portland Fair and of the very me extended by its officers to the visiting citi • state. Fortunate in its location, the big steer arre - attention almost at the start of your tour through the buildings, its construction substantial if not imposing, and decorations tastefully, yes, artistically, arr, •■emed in - dicative of progresssive agriculture and business solidit.s rather than of the mere evanescent loveliness of nature or art, and left the impression of immense natural resources in and under the hands of a people capable of developing them to the utmost. The theater, with its moving pictures wonderfully illustrating both still and active life of Nebraska's farms, orchards and ranges, was one of the central attractions of the Fair as well as the theme of conversation and discussion all over the grounds, and I do not think our state, its resources and advantages, could have been otherwise better advertised </seg>
            <seg id="p084">74 ■sploited at an outlay a double the investment, uch credit is due the Commission for the enersry, ability. displayed in its management R. W. W. JONES, Nebraska State Senator .i visitor at t lie Lewia and Clark Expi ii Portland during the suninier of l!»05 and having \ identified with Ilif int ' Nebraska which ■ I at the Lewis and Clark Exposition, I wish to Micndation regarding this most splendid inter - rial display. Jly wish to mention the exhibit from Nebraska. As a member of the legislature which made the appropriation for this Fair, I labored very hard to have the appropriation r than it was. as I fully realized the importance of having liin^' to do with making such a display and I wi - (iii and the members of the Commission from aska, who had this display in charge. I had the pleasure ■riag people from all over the 1'iiited States OX] pleasure regarding the Nebraska exhibit. The moving pfataN iv. which was explained by Mr. Will Sizer so creditably to himself and the Commission, was especially noticeable as ■ f the important features which the visitors to the Fair wiahed not to miss. The pyramid- a and other agricultural pn ■ creditable. I W • more pleased than « mpany with my wife. the living pictures of the nd dair&gt; among which WM dairy exhibit on the farm of Mr. Honeywell, where he appeare-i to life among his herds of Jersey cattle. Taking it altogether it was a matter of great pleasure to r of the Fair who </seg>
            <seg id="p085">75 I d the Nebraska pavilion, and it will go down in hu is one of the principal eventa of tli ;.lendid exposition. I congratulate every member of the Commission att. he pavilion during the exposition upon its and I leerely thankful that I was one of the members of th ture who took an active interest to have funds appn &gt;riated for this I wish to thank you for the courteous treatment « red while at Portland, and also for the splendid exhibit &gt;vhich was given to the people of the United States and foi •ountries of the products of the state of Nebraska. Representative, Lincoln. Nebraska I am sure that all Nebraskans who visited the Lew Clark Exposition at Portland were pleased to find their home state so much and so favorably in evidence. It prei pleasure to add one to the vote of thanks due our Lewi- Clark Exposition Commission for the very creditable exhibit which earned for our state so much favorable comment." EDNAD. BULLOCK, It was my pleasure to visit the Nebraska pavilion many times dame the two weeki 1 spent at the Lewifl and I Exposition ywas greatly pleased with the showing made by our ri dering the smallness of the appropriation given by our ature, I think you made a most ereditable showing of the Nebraska products. I met many gentlemen from other states who spoke of our pavilion and not one but that commended the work that ill I - t» ii&lt;»pv i ti 1 Jill Wf*!*P Ijlt'HSfMi Wit II H. C. M. BUR' S.-rretary Nebraska Public Library Commia </seg>
            <seg id="p086">76 r f aska's exhibit, and spoke words of commendation of ou commissioners. I am very sure that your work attracted at tention In our state and did us much good. Indeed, then only pood words from President Goode and all the officials o i Clark Exposition for the Nebraska an&lt; for those who had charge of its exhibit. GEO. W. E. DORSEY, an, Fremont. Nebraska. While at Portland viewing the Nebraska exhibit at th&lt; ■ and Clark Exposition. I felt proud of the splendid show of Nebraska products and the skilful manner in which the.. to be readily seen by the hundreds of peoplt ,ns them every day. E Domical appropriation by the legislature and thv iiii&lt;- the state commissioners had to colled and put ir ■ a exhibition, shows wh,v and honest labor can accomplish in a short tini' inly did her share in making the exposition : J. K. H0NEYWEL1 Lincoln, Nebraska During the Bontl :ist I vat a visitor at the Lewis and Clark Exposition and I take this opportunity of congratu - lating you upon the remarkably attractive and instructive ex - hibit made by the Nebraska commissioners. Nebraska cer - tainly out-stripped all of the great corn-growing section in il attractiveness of her exhibit and won from all the warmest praise for her enterprise in installing such a display the limited appropriation available. H. H. NICHOLSON Directing r. Killen Warner, Stewart Com pany, Sniii|&gt;ter. Ore : formerly Prof' ' v Ijiiicolii </seg>
            <seg id="p087">77 was my pleasure to be a visitor at the Lewis and Clark jsition in Portland. I was pleased with the same and the exhibit of Nebraska, which was so instruct i thousands who visited same, and I think should bring many people who saw it to our state, in particular those from the eastern part of the country. I think I saw more good things in half a day on my return home from Sidney to Omaha, than in three weeks of travel which I took to Portland by Wl Green River, from there to San Francisco, and return vi. den. With the fine exhibit that .Nebraska had, and the moving ■ t' Nebraska's industries and productions, and the r,ies extended to all by the gentleman in charge of not help but be attractive and interesting to all who had the pleasure of viewin tl wish to congratulate the state for her repn d thank you all for the kind courtesies extended t&lt; Should you be in Omaha at any time, I should be pleas' m at the Tier Grand. HENRY T. CLARK, Omaha. Nebraska Allow me an expression I I the NV: exhibit at Portland Exposition. When one considers the amount of money placed a ; lisposition, with which to gather, transport and instal the exhibit, it is a wonder to all that you were enabled to make tfreditable a display as was made. After carefully jugh the Agricultural building I am compelled t&gt; jnd to none in setting forth the tate. The exhibit should I the Nebraska exhibit « resources of the soil of our in financial benefit The Commission are to be congratulated on the work ac mpliahed and Um rwnlta seeming therafron J. B. DINSMORE </seg>
            <seg id="p088">78 E-rlatl to add my word of commendation on the work jy the Nebraska commissioners at the Lewis and Clar'j ition last summer. I think the Nebraska exhibit was ■litable one and must have done a food deal to ad - ! the resources of our state. Conally I was well satisfied with the showing Nebraska i I feel sure that the little money at the command of ■ ners was well spent. W. E. HARDY, Lincoln. Nebraska. I think I voice the sentiment, not only of myself, but of other person who saw the Nebraska exhibit at the Port - land Exposition, when I say it was not only unique and interesting but a iucator and I think the committee in charge deserve much credit for their services in making ■ ereditable display of the resources of Nebraska: also for the &gt;'ous treatment extended by you and the other members ur committee to all who visited the Nebraska exhibit. I saw the exhi 1 and, like many others, never ■f looking at it, especially the moving pictures deserve the thanks of all the people of Nebraska for your ef - ln making such a grand exhibit with the small resources yuu had at command. JOHN BRATT, North Platte, Nebraska Iie Nebraska exhibit at the Lewis and Clark Exposition ditable, particularly from the standpoint icting the principal products of the state. I was unable ■ at any of the moving picture lectures given, but them referred to in a very complimentary manner. Nebraska City, Nebraska. WILLARD S. HARDING, </seg>
            <seg id="p089">79 Considering the limited amount of money at the Eof the Commission I regarded the Nebraska exhib •reditable indeed. It seemed to attract the attention of people than did exhibits from other states which much more money. The strong features of the Nebraska exhibit m tin- prize steer and the moving pictures representing N braska agricultural scenes. The splendid location and the attractive and unique features of the exhibit made it next t i impossible for any visitor of the Fair to fail to notice it and think favorably of Nebraska. Pie members of the Commission and those who were in of the exhibit are entitled to great credit for the ser - ro faithfully and efficiently rendered. sett, Nebraska P think th' \hibit at the Nebraska pavilion at Port - were very creditable indeed, in view of the limited ap - iation and the time you had to make it. The little thi the moving picture scenes would give anybody a true idea of how things looked in Nebraska. fOur party was well pleased with the showing made and re to thank the Commission for the courteous treatment received. ft J. COFFIN. Burwell. Nebraska. El was very much pleased with our Nebraska State exhibit he Portland Exposition. 1 may be prejudiced in fav own state, but no other exhibit pleased and impressed me veil. The moving pictures representing scenes from dif - nt portions and showing the various occupations of our people, were. I think, a happy thought. Ainsworth. Nebraska. ,1. A. DOrCJLAS. T. W. SISSOX. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">80 In my judgment it was a most complete and comprehen - • xhibit in every particular. From an artistic standpoint it was very fine and did our great state credit. Einoviufr picture scheme, I think, could not help but lally as interesting to the public generally and as to the state, as a whole, as was the one I is last year. A. F. BLOOMER, York, Nebraska. While visiting the Lewis and Clark Exposition last July I call il times at the Nebraska pavilion and am pleased to say that the display by our state was a credit and honor to Nebraska. It caused me to feel proud that I was a citizen of aska. I do not think it could be improved upon ake into consideration the limited amount of the appro - priation for making a display. A. V. COLE, Hastings, Nebraska I was always pleased to get around to Nebraska while I was at the Fair for it ■ncimod like home. I am sure that it all Nebraskans as well as many ex-Nebraskans glad to see that corn, for I heard many say, "that looks like back to raise just such corn as that when we lived in Nebraska," etc. I was always against making appro - priations for any of the fairs, but I hope to be forgiven and I shall be only too &gt;rlad to give my dun so that my '■an put up as pood a show as she had at Portland, for I think that had there been more money we would have been JOHN B. STEVENS, </seg>
            <seg id="p091">LEWIS AND CLARK CENTENNIAL EXPOSITION. 81 The exhibit together with are attracting fully as much state exhibit on the grounds, obligations, not only to the gentlemen who have bo well ( the lectures and moving pictures commendatory attention as any The state is really under g commissioners but the y carried out the work. DR. BEXJ. F. BAILEY, In Lincoln State Journal. During the month of September I visited the Portland Exposition and, with considerable pride, the Nebraska exhibit, which was unique, well arranged, and I think by far th&lt; arranged exhibit on the ground, displaying to an excellent ad - vantage the various products of our g;-eat agricultural - LFor the amount of means at your disposal you made an llent showing and are entitled to much credit. MATT MILLER </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>