<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00026.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00026.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.  EXPERIMENTS WITH CORN.</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">a BULLETIN NO. 112. The University of Nebraska. B I_J L^ 1^ E^TT I N OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA.. Volume XXII, Article II. EXPERIMENTS WITH CORN. Ear to Row Corn Breeding. Thick and Thin Planting for Growing Seed Corn. Rates op Planting Corn. The Economic Value of Tillers. Uniform Distribution of the Seed in Planting Compared with Varied Distribution. Distributed December 15, 1909. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. By E. G. Montgomery. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (the ntaiNTt of the university) HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD. Falls City HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON. Crete HONORABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha THE STATION OFFICERS SAMUEL A VERY, Ph. D., Chancellor, ex officio E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director J. S. DALES, M. PH., Financial Secretary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE"WORKING STAFF E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany F. J. ALWAY, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry H. R. SMITH, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry A. T. Petebs, D. V. M., minimal Pathology A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandry Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, EnUjmology E. G. Montgomery, A. M., Experimental Agronomy Frank J. Phillips, M. F., Forestry Erwin H. B arbour. Ph. D., Geology G. R. Chatburn, A. M., Highway Engineering R. A. Emerson, B. Sc, Horticulture O. V. P. STOUT, C. E., Irrigation Engineering G. A. LOVELAND, B. SC, LL. B., Meteorology C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc, Soil Agronomy W. P. Snyder, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation, North Plalte J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Associate in Animal Pathology Miss Venus W. Pool, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany R. S. Trumbull, A. M.. Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry P. B. BARKER, A. B.. Assistant in Agronomy (Soils) T. A. Kiesselbach, B. SC, A. B. , Assistant in Agronomy L. B. Sturdevant, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Puthology M. H. SWENK, A. If., Assistant m EnUmwilogy R. F Howard, B. Sc, in Agr., Assistant in Horticulture W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Assistant in SoiU and Crops, North. PlatU Erwin Hopt, B. Sc , Assistant in Crops and Horticulture, North Plalte S. W. Perin, Farm Superintendent *Miss Louise M. Allen, A. M., Scientific Assistant, Seed Testing * Detailed by the United States Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS. Pa^ Ear to row corn breeding 5 Introduction 5 History of the 1903 stock (Class I) 5 Method used 5 Results of test 6 History of the 1906 stock (Class II) 8 Method used 8 How to conduct a breeding plat 11 Variety to use 11 Selecting the ears 11 Number of ears to select as foundation stock 11 The test plat 11 Size of plat 11 Check plats 12 Planting the ears 12 Cultivation 12 Taking notes 12 Harvesting 13 The second year's work 16 The third year's work and after 16 Physical characters of the corn plant to be regarded in selection 17 Shape of ear 1" Size of ear 21 Shape of kernel 23 Height of ear 24 Size of stalk 24 Amount of leaf 25 Tillers, or suckers 26 Barren plants 27 Summary •T Transmission of plant characters 28 Thick and thin planting for growing seed corn 28 Rates of planting corn 30 The economic value of tillers 31 Variation in tillering 34 Uniform distribution of the seed in planting compared with a varied distribution 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">TABLES. Page Table I. Summary, comparing yield of selected strains with original stock. (1907) 1 Table II. Summary, plats arranged in groups of 18 to show com- parative yield of same group of ears on two con - secutive years (1906 and 1907) . Arranged according to yield in 1906. 9 Comparative yield of selected types in 1908. (Class II.) Table III. 10 Table IV. Long smooth compared with ordinary medium-rough type of Reid's Yellow Dent. (Yield estimated on air dry weight February 1. ) Showing relation of yield and size of ear on 200 ear 1-.. Table V. to row plats for two years (1906-1907). 22 Table VI. Classification of 204 ear to row plats into seven classes according to yield and size of ear in each class, in a per cent Five years' selection for high and low ears (Illinois Table VII. Experiment Station) 24 Table VIII. Summary of 120 plants according to relative weight of dry matter 25 Table IX. Summary of 204 ear to row plats to show relation of leaf to yield. 2B Table X. Summary of 204 ear to row plats arranged in six groups according to percentage of barren plants (1906) 27 Showing transmission of characters, 204 ear to row Table XI. plats arranged in classes in each case . . . Summary of yields from different rates of planting for three years (1906-07-08) according to origin of seed Average results from planting corn at various rates M Table XII. 30 Table XIII. for six years (1903-1908) M Table XIV. Effect of removing tillers on yield of grain (1906-1908), — yield in bushels per acre 32 Table XV. Effect of removing tillers on yield of stover for three years (1906-07-08) 32 Table XVI. Effect of removing tillers on the number of two eared plants and barren plants, two years (1907-1908) 33 Table XVII Showing disappearance of tillers from July 10 to Octo- ber 1 for three years (1905-06-07) 34 Table XVIII. Showing variation in number of tillers produced hy different varieties for two ye«rs (1907-1908) 34 Table XIX. Distributing seed in planting in various ways, and effect on yield H </seg>
            <seg id="p005">EXPERIMENTS WITH CORN By E. G. Montgomery EAR TO BOW CORN BREEDING INTRODUCTION For the past ten years there has been a growing interest among farmers in seed corn selection and corn breeding work. While the Experiment Station has been carrying on work for several years, no general report or recommendation has been made up to date. The following is a report on two general tests of ear to row breeding work by different methods and also plans for conducting a breeding plat. The first was started in 1903 (Class I) and is still continued. The second test was started in 1906 (Class II). The two tests will hereafter be referred to by the year in which they were started. The first is a method of continuous selection, the second a method for isolating the best yielding strains from a large number. HISTORY OF THE 1903 STOCK (CLASS I) Method Used. — Seventy-nine ears of Hogue's Yellow Dent were planted in 1903 and 22 more added in 1904, making 101 ears as foundation stock. The plan was to shell all the grain from each ear, and plant each in a separate row, then harvest and weigh the grain from each row, selecting a few of the heaviest yielders, and discarding the rest. Of course, due precautions have been tak - en to secure a uniform stand and accurate comparative weights. From the best yielding rows, a few ears, usually six, were selected BUL. 112, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XXII, ART. II. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I 6 Experiments With Corn to be planted by the same method a second year. For example, from the first 79 ear-rows planted in 1903, 17 rows were selected that had yielded more than 90 bushels per acre. From each of the 17 rows 6 ears were selected. Each of these six ears was planted to a row the second year, but so distributed that no two ears from the same mother row came near together. All the rows tracing back to an original mother plant are called a family. In harvesting the second year, the yield of each row was taken separately. Then the six rows from a family averaged together. If a family did not average up well all of its seed was dropped, even tho one or two rows might have yielded well. For exampfle, from the 17 fami - lies chosen in 1903, two were dropped in 1904, six in 1905, and three more in 1906, leaving six families which had stood the test for four years. No attempt was made to prevent intercrossing with the poorer families, as we wished to see what result could be obtained by this method of continuous selection. Results op Test.— In 1907 we made a thoro test of the yield of these selected strains. Eleven rows from six of the best families in the 1906 crop were chosen. Six ears were chosen from each row. The six ears from each row were then planted in a 12 row plat, and on each side of this plat was put in a "check" plat planted with the same stock of corn from which this was originally selected, but which had been handled in the ordinary way. Therefore, the difference in yield would indicate the progress made. Table I gives the results. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Experiments With Corn 7 Table I. — Summary, comparing yield of selected strains tvith original stock. (1907) Av.of I Difference Av.of I Difference p, , Family Yield checks I between Seed corn checks between ~»jj* No. or i&gt;er on selected yield on selected check acre either .strains and per acre either strains and The summary shows that the selected strains yielded an aver - age of 9 bushels per acre more than the original stock, and about one-half more seed. The improvement in uniformity of the ears was also very marked. In 1908, plats were again planted from some of the best rows selected from the 1907 crop. A summary of the yield per acre for two years is as follows: 2 3-8 9 10-15 16 17-22 23 24-29 30 31-36 37 38-43 44 45-50 51 52-57 58 59-64 65 66-71 72 73-78 79 Averaj V check 79 check 74 73 74 check 0 51 77 check 7ti 51 7!i check 7 / 57 check 73 82 check 76 73 check 7J 57 79 check IS 79 89 check 7 Ki check 76' 46 85 check 73 r ,e increase side [ But. till "I M 70.5 72 74 73.5 7:t.". 74 71.5 74.5 eh hei-ks li .1 10 ■ li.:, II s.: t s Bus. 1J 13.1 11.1 ]().."&gt; 8 7 12.2 5.X 10.2 5.3 I3.fi /(/ 10 7 5.3 10.1 1 1 side Bus. 9.3 6.3 5.9 7.2 7.2 5.5 7.6 7.6 ."..2 5.2 ti.2 SI le check :».- 4.8 4.6 1 I 4.7 5.9 2.4 1.8 S 8.9 S.7 c IW _ . 1 .elected strains 'hecks (original stock) Hfference — — ■ 82 9.5 1906 Averse Bushels Bushels 66 74 59 65.7 7 8.3 Difference i </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Experiments With Corn HISTORY OF THE 1906 STOCK (CLASS II) A second method of selection was started in 1906, according to a different plan, and has also given some interesting results. Method Used. — Two hundred and four ears of the same variety as used in the "1903 stock "(Hogue's Yellow Dent) were taken and careful notes made in regard to each. About one-third of each ear was planted in a row 16 rods long. The remainder of the ear was kept. The yield per acre was found to vary approx - imately from 50 to 90 bushels per acre. However, not feeling satisfied that a single year's test was enough we decided to du - plicate the entire experiment in 1907. It seems that a certain year may favor a particular group of ears and cause them to yield well, while in another year it might be a different group of ears that will yield best. Also having some indication from the 1906 test which ears would yield high, we could watch these closely a second year and perhaps find some reasons for their ability to yield. Consequently the remnants of the 204 ears were taken and arranged in order according to yield in 1906. We then planted the ears in this order, the best yielder first and the poorest last. Results for the two years did not correspond very closely. In Table II the data for two years are summarized, the plats being divided into groups of 20 for comparison. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Experiments With Corn 9 Table II. — Summary : Plats arranged in groups of 18 to show comparative yield of same group of ears on two consecutive years (1906 and 1907). Arranged according to yield in 1906. '%*££% Yield per acr* J™™. Yield ™— l£; LMuerence i leiu K~tww»n inn between 1906 of checks n '; and 1907 1907 J^™ 1 group— 1907 arrangement | 1906 1907 /*iw/l*ki 69. 2 63.6 66.8 64.9 160-180 63 6 67.6 18&lt;i-2O0 60 3 62.4 60.7 200-227 53 8 — 6.9 67.5 —6.8 Average 62.0 64.6 Grand average! 70.1 67.0 •There are only 18 trial plats in a group, as three of the plats are checks. For example, in the second group, plats 20, 30, and 40 are check plats. Note:— The average yield in 1906 was 3.1 bushels better than in 1907. The lack of close relation between the two years is apparently due to two causes, — one being a certain amount of error in results that must be allowed for, due to lack of uniformity in soil ; and the second, variation in season so that the same strains do not always seem to rank first in different seasons. We may divide the plats into two general groups having 108 ears in the first and 96 in the second, (not counting in check plats). Since the yield of the check was 1.8 bushels better in the second group than in the first, we should increase the yield of the first to make results comparable. This is done in the following summary. Yields per acre. 1907 Check plats, corrected corrected 1906 yield yield yield Bushel* ButheU Bushel* 71.0 65.4 First group 108 ears 77 65.4 Second group 96 ears 62 M 6 65.4 Difference 15 6.5 Average | 89.5 67.7 65.4 Bushels Bushels Bnxhels Buthds 69 6 +18.2 64 2 +5 4 68.9 +12.4 64.1 -1-4 8 69 4 f 7.6 62.4 +7.0 67.7 + 6.5 t&gt;4.4 +3.3 70 0 +1.9 M r, +5 5 69.8 — .3 62.4 +7 4 1-20 87.8 20-40 81.3 40-60 77.0 60-80 74 2 80-100 719 100-120 69.5 Average ".&lt;) 120-140 \ 67.0 140-160 65.4 + .2 m.2 -f- .6 M.9 0.0 — 4.0 «2 8 1-4.8 - 2.1 65.8 —3.4 t&gt;5.4 .9 + 3.1 64.4 +2.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Experiments With Corn These data indicate that if we had taken the best half of the ears after the first year's test, they would have given an increased yield of about 3 bushels above the average. There were certain ears, however, that yielded well both seasons. Also notes regarding the quality of the crop and other characters of the plants indicated the general superiority of these ears. Four of the best ears out of the 204 according to the two years' average were selected for further increase. As we still had some of the remnants of the original ears, these were planted; also the progeny of these ears grown in 1907; also, chock plats were planted from the original unselected stock and plats from the rem - nants of the nine poorest ears. Results were as follows : Table III. — Comparative yield of selected types in 1908. {Class II.) The 1903 Glass I selections under same conditions yielded as follows (see Table I) : BuslieU Average yield remnants, 5 best ears 73 Average yield 1907 progeny, 5 best ears 66 Average yield check plats 59 It seems that by the second method (1906 stock, Class II) as good results were secured in much less time and by a simpler method. The progeny of the four best ears yielded 9 bushels per acre better than the checks, while the remnants of the original ears yield - ed 11 bushels better. The method by which these results were obtained was simple and not expensive. Whether the selected strains will maintain their superiority without continued selection is not known, but pre - sumably they will. We have an isolated plat of the best 4 ears and shall be able to report on this point later. ButheU verage yield of remnants, 4 best ears 70 verage yield of 1907 progeny, 4 best ears 68 verage yield of check plats ( original stock ) 59 .verage yield of remnants. 9 poorest ears ... ... . 56 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Experiments With Corn 11 HOW TO CONDUCT A BREEDING PLAT As there is considerable inquiry at present regarding methods of corn breeding, it seems best at this time to outline a plan whick experience so far seems to recommend. Variety to Use. — Select some variety well adapted to the re - gion, and a good yielder. This is important, as one might spend years working on a ptoor variety and in the end have nothing better than the best variety already existing. It may be best to do some preliminary variety testing. Selecting the Ears. — If yield is to be the principal object of selection, }*■ will not be necessary to stick closely to some one type of ear. In faci, since we do not know definitely what particular type of ear in a variety may do best in a new locality, it would seem wise to select several types, the main consideration being that the ears are sound and well matured. Number of Ears to Select as Foundation Stock. — Excep - tionally good ears are not common, probably not more than one in every 50 to 100 ears. Therefore, if one starts with only a small num - ber of ears, 25 to 50, he may not find a single exceptional yielder in the lot. Not less than 100, and better 200 ears, should be tried out in the preliminary trial. The Test Plat. — Great care should be exercised in securing a uniform piece of land for the test plat, as everything depends on being able to compare in an accurate way the yields of the different ears. The land should not be exceptionally rich but only of the average fertility of the region. If the land can be plowed twice, — say fall plowed, then backset in the spring, — and disked several times, it will do much toward equalizing conditions. Size op Plat. — One-half an ear will plant a row 16 to 20 rods in length. However, there will be less error if the rows are dupli - cated, and it is best to plant two rows 8 rods long from each ear. One hundred ears will make 200 plats 8 rods long. This will take a piece of land 32 by 11 rods or 16 by 22 rods; or two test plata one-half this size on different parts of the farm may be used, dupli - cating the experiment in each. s </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Experiments With Corn Check Plats. — No matter how carefully the land is selected, it may lack uniformity and for this reason "check plats" should be planted with a uniform lot of corn. We have found making every fifth plat a check very satisfactory. The simplest way is to make a check of every plat that is a multiple of 5 ; as, 5, 10, 15, etc. Planting the Ears. — The land should first be laid off by a marker into checks 3 feet 8 inches apart. The planting must be done by hand. Carry the ear, and shell off the grains as needed. It is best to plant 4 grains per hill ; then when the corn is 6 inches high, thin down to 3. This will give a perfect stand. Every pre - caution should be used to secure uniform conditions in each plat, or else the experiment would be a waste of time, as the results would not mean anything. Cultivation. — Ordinary cultivation, taking care that none of the rows are unduly injured. Taking Notes. — Some breeders prefer to keep extensive de- scriptive notes for their own information, but for practical results very little note taking is necessary other than accurately to secure comparable yields. Of course, if the breeder is selecting for some particular quality, such as earliness, height of ear, angle of ear, etc., he must take notes on these points. Also taking a set of notes on each individual row furnishes the very best training possible in close observation ; and as a man cannot know too much about the corn plant in order to be a successful breeder, it will usually pay him well to keep as complete a record as possible. Following is a set of the notes kept by the Experiment Station. The breeder can pick out such of these as seem best in his case. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Experiment!} With Corn 13 NOTES ON OBKJINAL SEED EARS. N , Weight Weight 1 Weight Per Per Length Circum. Rough ' of of of , cent of i cent of , of of or ear grain cob ; grain cob ear ear smooth Ounce* ' Ounce* Ounce* NOTES ON CROP FROM THESE EARS *$• *$" *$» Per cent f -• Weight planting Datlon tasseling stalk ear puckers sUlk8 leaveg Per cent Feet Feet Ounce* NOTES CONTINUED. We j ht Yield No. ears Average A , ver *f J? atio Percent Inden - ,* k per acre per plat wt. ears *%* Jug5 graia Uti ° P Ounce* Buthel* Ounce* Indie* Harvesting. — "When corn first ripens, it contains 25 to 30 per cent water, but slowly dries out to about 15 per cent. In the breeding plats some rows ripen and dry out sooner than others; hence, the weights will not be comparable until all are equally dry. For this reason we have found it best to leave the breeding plats in the field for six to eight weeks after ripening, or till about De - cember 1. Any very late maturing or slow maturing rows should be noted and discarded at harvest, as we do not want a type that will not mature well. A very good method of harvesting the plats is to divide a wagon box into two to four compartments. Then husk a plat into </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Experiments With Corn 14 kFig. 1. Weighing a single row. The wagon is divided into two com - rtments, so two rows can be husked thru at once. The corn is weighed the end of the rows, and dumped at the end of the row from which it was sked. Fig. 2. The corn from two adjacent rows. Row 64 yielded 81.2 bushels per acre and row 65 yielded 58.7 bushels per acre. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Experiments With Corn 15 Fig. 3. After the weighing is completed, the best yielding rows are then located and careful comparison is made. Often a heavy yielding row must be discarded on inspection, if it is found to be immature or poor in quality. If the breeder is selecting for type, this affords an easy way of discovering the rows coming true to type. Fig. 4. When statistical data are to be taken regarding the number of ears of a certain length or type, the ears are distributed on a long board where they may be quickly sorted into the desired elasse*. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Experiments With Corn each compartment. At the end of the rows have a platform scale with a box large enough to hold the corn from one plat. Scoop the corn into this box, and as each plat is weighed dump the corn at the end of the row, leaving the plat stake with each pile. Leave the corn in these piles until all plats are husked, then mark the piles from high yielding rows. A careful examination can now be made of these piles to note whether any of the piles seem immature, low in vitality, or otherwise undesirable. About one-fourth of the best plats should be noted, that is, 20 to 25 out of 100. From these, seed for the general crop may be selected for the next year. The breeder still has one-half of the original ears from which the crop was grown. It is from these that he will build up his improved strains of corn. The Second Year's Work.— Having located the 20 or 25 best original ears, the remnants of these are again planted in separate rows the second year. The reason so large a number of the rem - nants are again planted is because the degree of error may be so large — due to the fact that one season may favor a certain type — that we cannot determine exactly, the first year, just which are the two or three best for all seasons. When the second year's results are secured we may decide which to choose on the basis of two years' record. The seed from these two or three best rows may now be used as foundation stock for a select strain of corn. We have given results in the first part of this bulletin with such seed. Where the original ears are large there will be quite a remnant left even after testing two years. The remnants of the very best may be put together the third year and a small plat started of this selected strain. The Third Year's Work and Ajter. — The third year the breeder may increase hia strains from the selected ears in as ex - tensive a manner as possible. The fourth year, if he desires to continue improvement, he could again make a selection from this increase plat and put out an ear to row test plat, repeating the first test. There is no experimental evidence to show how long improvement may be continued by this system, but it seems reasonable to expect new </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Experiments With Corn 17 variations of higher value to occur for at least a second generation. My belief is that if this ear to row breeding plat were put out once every four years, the producing capacity of the corn could be kept at a high standard. Fig. 5 gives the general plan of arranging the breeding plats the first and second years. The length of line in the first year's test indicates the variation in yield to be expected from the different ears. In the second year's test about 20 per cent of the best yicld - ers are arranged according to yield, while the rest are discarded. PHYSICAL CHARACTERS OF THE CORN PLANT TO BE REGARDED IN SELECTION Every practical corn man will recognize the difficulty of laying down any fixed rules regarding characters of the plant to be considered in selection, since corn must be grown under a great variety of conditions, and rules which would apply in one case may be found inapplicable in another. The following report is to be considered rather as a statement of progress than as conclusive statements on the physical characters of the plant considered. Shape of Ear. — Regarding this character, note the following quotation from Wallaces' Farmer under date of Feb. 17, 1909. "Highest Yield from Smooth Ear. "Eugene D. Funk at the Illinois Agricultural College short course gave an object lesson with fourteen samples of corn tha goes farther than any other known evidence to prove a new thin about the increase of yield. He said the corn growers some years ago had arbitrarily selected what they considered an ideal ear o corn, but that there was absolutely nothing to prove that it was the best producing ear. Mr. Funk secured the Coolidge strain o Learning corn from Enox coimty and Chester strain of Leamin from Champaign, and from each strain he picked out seven dif - ferent types of kernel and ear. He has bred these types separately for seven years. Type No. 1 is a rough ear close to the ideal of the Association, while No. 7 was the smooth corn which the corn growers have been trying to get away from. He was surprised to find that for six years out of seven in one strain and for five yean out of seven in the other the comparatively smooth type of </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Experiments With Corn FIRST YEAR SECOND YEAR Fig. 5. Diagram of ear to row test for two years. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Experiments With Corn 19 corn had produced the highest yield of all. He finds that the rough corn gets looser on the cob and is far later in maturing." Also Prof. C. Q. Williams of the Ohio Experiment Station presented a paper before the Nebraska Corn Improvers' Associa - tion in 1908 in which he made this statement: "Ears a little above average length for a variety and locality have yielded mor^e bushels of corn per acre than ears falling below average length, while ears of large circumference have proven lower yielders than those of medium circumference, showing that it is impossible to make up a deficiency in weight due to shortage in length by in - creased circumference." At the Nebraska Experiment Station in 1904 a lot of rather long smooth ears were selected from a lot of pure Reid's Yellow Dent. From this plat the largest ears of a smooth type were again selected and this has been continued since. During the five years' selection the type has changed in quite a marked degree, as is shown by the illustrations and data. During the past four years the long smooth types have been planted in the variety test beside the regular selection of Reid's Yellow Dent. For three years, 1905-06-07, we used for comparison seed grown here at the Station and from the same original stock from which selection was made, but this was discontinued, and in 1908 we used seed secured from a grower in western Iowa. Results have been as follows: Table TV. — Long smooth compared with ordinary medium- rough type weight Pe of Reid's 'en ie estimati on air-' ruary 1.) Smooth type Standard type Year i Bushels per acre Per cent shrinkage Bushels per acre Per cent shrinkage 1905 1906 1907 1908 69.7 47.2 69 9 56.8 6.9 10 0 8 2 15.0 59.4 51 4 64.1 51.2 9.4 7.5 11.7 14 0 60.9 10.0 56.5 56.5 10.6 verage . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Fig. 6. Typical specimens of the rather long smooth type of Reid's Yellow Dent after five years' selection, and the standard type. 1 hae averaged about the same. The percentage of grain is almost the same. While the depth of grain has become less on the smooth type, the size of cob has also reduced some. Bo far as this evidence goes, it indicates that our present ideal type is not long enough in proportion to circumference for best yielders. It might also be said that a large ear of slender type will mature farther north than one of greater circumference. It is possible to do considerable damage in the northern experiments With Corn ig data were tal :en on the l! The folio •08 crop: Type Average weight of ear Average length of ear Average circumference of ear Length of 100 grains end to end Average percent grains imooth type standard type .. Ounce* 8.8 9.0 Inches 8.3 7.6 Inches 6.1 6.5 Inches 50 54 86 85 It is not at all plain why the long smooth type has o the standard type. The shrinkage from husking time to I ityielded February </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Experiments With Corn 21 half of the corn belt by encouraging farmers to grow deep-grained corn with too large an ear circumference. The foregoing remarks relate to the relation of shape of ear to yield. Size of Eab.— Size of ear has been the one most important, con - sideration in choosing seed ears with most corn growers. If all ears in a field grew under identical conditions of soil and moisture, then size of ear would be a fair way of judging Fig. 7. Grain of smooth and standard type of Reid's Yellow Dent after five years' selection. comparative yielding power. We are coming to recognize, how - ever, that when an ear is large simply because the plant upon which it grew had twice its share of space and sunshine, this par - ticular ear, even tho large, may have no special merit as a seed ear. In fact, an ear grown under crowded, adverse conditions but only half as large may be a better producer. A 12-ounce ear produced where most of the ears around it weigh only 8 ounces is a more valuable seed ear than a 16-ounee ear produced under con - ditions where the average ear weighs 16 ounces. It will be shown later in this report (p. 28) where we have secured better yields </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Experiments With Corn from rather small ears grown under adverse conditions than from large ears grown under favorable conditions. Taking up for a moment the comparison of large and small eared varieties it will be found that large eared varieties are sel - dom the highest yielders. In a test of 19 varieties at the Nebraska Experiment Station it was found that the five highest yielders wei ■» not the largest eared strains, but on the contrary the avera^ 1 weight of ear for these varieties was considerably below the aver - age weight of ear for all the varieties. 1 Similar results have been secured in the South at the Georgia Experiment Station. 2 In 1906, 204 individual ears were planted out in our ear to row test plat. Each seed ear was weighed before planting, the averaif? weight varying from about 10 to 17 ounces. One half of each ear was planted in 1906 and the remaining portion in 1907. In neither year could a relation be discovered between the weight of the original seed ears and the yield. Also the average weight of ear of the entire progeny of these 204 ears was taken for both years. The following table shows that we have very little relation between the yield of these rows and the size of ear. Table V. — Showing relation of yield and size of ear on 200 ear to row plats for two years (1906-1907). 'Nebr. Bui. 91, p. 12. 'Ga. Bui. 69, p. 191. 1WW 1907 85+ M B6 T5-80 70-75 65 70 60-65 60- Class (yield er acre) Bvsktlg Oiivct* Bushel* Bushels 12 89 5 9 12 ! 80+ 5 81.9 18 82.0 8.9« 75-80 16 76 6 27 77.3 9.28 70-75 46 71.7 39 72.5 9.12 65-70 62 67.4 42 67.0 9.28 6ii-65 49 62.6 33 62 7 9.28 55^ 19 57.5 29 54.6 9 28 55- 6 47.2 Av. wt. of ear (JUMXX 9.76 9.92 9.76 9.«J0 9.44 9 60 H.80 Tal )le VI showa the distribution of ears of different si zes in the various classes in 1906. For example, in the first class t there was 3 per c&lt; snt of 10-ounce ears, 27 per cent of 9-ounce eaj s, e stc. There </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Experiments With Corn 23 is no larger per cent of heavy ears in good yielders than in the poorer. Similar results were secured in 1907. Table VI. — Classification of 204 ear to row plats into seven classes according to yield and size of ear in each class, in per cent. v . ,. Per cent Per cent Per cent Per cent Per centPer oectPer cent i ieia _» i „# „* i «f „« „» „« of of of of of of of 10-ounee 9 ounce 8-ounce ! 7-ounce 6-ounce 5-ounce 4-ounce acre ears ears ears ears ears ears ears Bushels 86+ 3 •&gt;7 27 &gt;o 11 6 r. B r&gt; 6 80-85 ft 27 ■^ 2(1 13 75-80 I 2* 2.5 21 12 4 ■2-2 13 4 70-75 4 n L'4 65-70 5 M n .)O 13 + 29 19 11 3 60-«6 6 25 HO- 6 21! 2t 21 lti 4 Data were taken on some 40 characters of the plants in each plat for the two years to find out if possible just what characters of the plant, if any, were related to yield per acre. It may be stated in brief that the high yielding rows produced a greater number of ears per plat, due (1) to a less number of barren plants, (2) to a larger number of 2-eared plants, but, most of all, (3) to the large number of tillers bearing ears. "We would not be justified in drawing general conclusions from data at hand, and can only say that at present there seems no reason to believe extra large ears to be more valuable than medium-sized ears for seed purposes. Shape of Kernel. — Regarding this there is very little to say from an experimental point of view. If we finally modify our opinion regarding the ideal shape of ear, naturally we must change in some degree our ideal shape of kernel. At least it may be said that at present we have several very good varieties of corn with only an average depth of kernel. General experience in the West and North is that corn with medium or shallow grains will ripen more sound corn under adverse conditions, such as drouth or cool weather, than deep-grained strains. On the other hand it may be true that under very favorable conditions deep-grained corns are capable of greater yield. Prof. "Williams also stated two years ago </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Experiments With Corn at our Nebraska meeting that mother ears with 82.7 per cent corn had on the average yielded more shelled corn per acre than the ears ranking highest, 86.7 per cent. The data presented on ' ' Shape of Ear" (see page 17) also bear on this point. Height of Ear. — We have arranged the data for two years on the 204 ear to row plats above referred to, in such a way as to show relation of yield to height of ear. Also data on several hundred in - dividual plants were arranged in a similar manner. Our final con - clusion was that the height of ear on the stalk bore no relation to yield. For the past five years, selection has been carried on at the Illinois Station with Learning corn to produce a high ear type and low ear type.* The principal results are shown in Table VII. Table VII. — Five years' selection for high, and low ears. (Illi - nois Experiment Station.) half of the corn belt in order to secure sound corn, and since the selecting of low ears seems to give early maturity without decreas - ing yield, it seems desirable to select low ears. Also in the West where we are troubled with drouth we are coming to believe that a small stalk will withstand drouth better than a large stalk. Size of Stalk. — We have taken considerable data on size of stalk in individual plants. In an average field of corn the heavy •111. BuL lit. Year Heigh of ear Difference in average height of ear Difference in average height of plant Yield high -ear strain Yield low-ear strain High-ear plat_ Low -ear plat 1903 1904 1905 1906 1907 1908 Inehet 56.4 50.3 63.3 56.6 72.4 57 3 Inches 42.8 38.3 41.6 25.5 33.2 23 1 Inches 13.6 12 0 21.7 31.1 39.2 34.2 Inches 11.4 8.8 21.9 30.3 30.7 34 7 Bushel* 72.4 64.5 60.9 Bushels 72.6 68.8 59.5 No mi rked difference in yield has been foui ad so fa ir, but a marked chi age in size of plant and time of maturii smaller and the corn maturing earlier. ty, the lc &gt;w-eared plant being Since i arly maturity is a matter of importanc « thru tl he north </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Experiments With Corn 25 stalks will weigh about four times as much for a given height as the more slender ones. The yield of grain seems to increase with thickness or weight of stalk up to a little above average, but the very heaviest stalks do not yield quite as well as those of average or somewhat above average weight. Amount of Leap. — The amount of leaf a plant should have is a difficult question to determine. Table VIII shows the relation of leaf area to dry weight in about 120 individual plants measured. This shows that for a given leaf area of 1200 square inches certain plants have twice the weight of others. Table VIII. — Summary of 120 -plants according to relative toeight of dry matter. Arranged in groups of ten, beginning with the highest. All data recalculated as tho each plant had 1200 square inches leaf area. No. of Weight of stalk i Weight of ear Total weight Square inches of leaf area per gram of dry weight group l 2 I 4 5 6 7 X 9 10 11 12 Grams 323.8 307 0 250.0 tm.4 m 9 212.2 224 2 187.1 189.3 192.2 161.4 138 5 Grants 369.1 308.1 316.0 296.2 276.0 269.7 233.4 252.5 223 4 206.0 207.7 192.3 Grama 692.9 615.1 566.0 524.6 499.9 481.9 457.6 439 6 412.7 398.2 369 1 330.8 1.732 1.951 2.120 2.287 2.400 2.490 2.R22 2 730 t.ra 3 014 .{.251 3.627 Also l the 204 ear to row plats referred to before in th &gt;aper, we eighed the leaves from a portion of each plat. Resnl re as foil ra • </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Experiments With Corn Table IX. — Summary of 204 ear to row plats to show relation vestigations also show that very leafy plants use more water than plants with small leaves; so it seems that in dry regions we should select productive plants with small leaves. On the other hand, in very humid regions a large water loss by the plant would possibly not be a disadvantage. Tillers, or Suckers. — Most varieties of corn produce tillers abundantly under favorable conditions. At the Nebraska Station we have practiced removing the tillers or suckers from a series of plats to compare with similar plats with the tillers left on. Re - moving the tillers has never failed to decrease the yield. (See Ta - ble XIV). In all of our ear to row work, a record has been kept regarding tillers. The best yielding rows always have a good percentage of ear-bearing tillers. The poor yielding rows may have as many till - ers but they seem to be smaller, and few are ear bearing. In fact, tillers usually develop in response to the needs of the plant. If the stand is thin they thicken it up and increase the yield. If the stand is thick they make only a small development, and do no harm. It is doubtful whether we shall find many cases where it would pay to remove tillers. Class (weight of leaves) Number plats in class Average weight of leaves per stalk Yield pep acre Hpi&lt;rht Ratio of weight Hel f ht of stalk to «t»ik total wei K n » of 8lallc stalk and ear Height of stalk Grams 40- 40-45 46-50 50^55 55-60 fiO-65 65+ 11 30 42 50 32 19 19 Grams 36 43 47 51 56 62 73 Biixhels 66 4 69.6 69.3 70.4 71.1 68.8 68.2 Inclits 113 .321 109 .398 110 .422 112 .457 111 517 111 .555 111 .656 So far as our im estigations have gone ' ve have not been able to find a relation bet veen leafiness of plant If this is true, then 1&lt; s or strains and their productive capacity, we might disregard, •afiness is a character to long as the plant is productive. Other in- </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Experiments With Corn 27 Barren Plants.— These are prodnced by various unfavorable conditions. A small per cent are produced naturally even under favorable conditions. In all our breeding work we have found those rows having a high percentage of barren plants to be low in yield, tho the barrenness seems to be due mostly to other causes than inheritance. (See Table X.) Table X. — Summary of 204 ear to row plats arranged in 6 groups according to percentage of barren plants (1906). Characters of the seed corn plant to be considered as affecting yield and quality: Shape of Ear. — Evidence seems to indicate a rather long type of ear to be best. Size of Ear. — This depends on environment and is only of im - portance when it is known under what conditions the plant was grown. Shape of Kernel. — Medium depth to be preferred under aver age conditions. Height of ear. — Low ears give as good yield and mature earli- er. Size of Stalk. — Large or small stalks do not yield as well as stalks just above medium in size. Amount of Leaf. — Does not seem to be related to yield. Tillers. — Strains capable of producing ear-bearing tillers when occasion demands yield best. In soils where corn does not tiller this might be reversed. Barren Plants. — Decrease yield. Barren plants Per cent 1.6 3.5 5.5 7 5 10.8 19.7 Barren plants Yield per acre Buihels 75.70 74 76 69.29 67 21 65.20 65.9 Per cent stand 75. 76. 74. 74. 71. 74. I SUMMARY </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Experiments With Corn TRANSMISSION OF PLANT CHARACTERS As explained before, when the 204 ears were planted in 1906 only one-half the ear was planted, and another plat was planted from each ear the following year. To see whether the crop from these ears exhibited the same characteristics the second year, the plats were arranged in such a way as to give a direct comparison. In most cases some degree of transmission was shown both years, tho in a few cases it was not apparent. Table XI. — Showing transmission of characters, 204 ear to row plats arranged in classes in each case. however, does away to some extent with natural selection. For ex - ample, we find when planting corn at the rate of 1 plant per hill, 3 feet 8 inches apart, that about 25 good ears weighing 12 ounces or more are produced to every 100 plants. When 3 plants per hill are planted, only about 10 good ears are produced on 100 plants, and when we have 5 plants per hill, only about five 12-ounce ears are produced to 100 plants. It seems that a plant which, when planted as thickly as 5 plants per hill, is capable of producing a good ear must be unusually vigorous. When planted thin, however, it is not possible to tell which of the good ears produced would have been good if the stalks had been planted thick. Again, in thin planting we have only a small number of barren plants, usually less than 2 per cent, but the thick planting averages about 11 per cent barren plants. In other words, in thick planting, natural se- Ears per plat Tillers per plat Barren plants per cent 1900 1907 1906 1907 1906 1907 249 218 196 180 161 139 193 186 186 177 166 162 73 100 118 137 157 181 40 48 48 52 72 83 1.6 3.5 5.5 7.5 10.8 19.7 5.6 4.5 4.5 4.2 6 5 5.0 THICK AND THIN PLANTING FOB GRO IWING SEED CORN It is a general ci istom among seedsmen 1 to plant their corn in- tended for seed rathi sr thin, in order to dev( elop large ears. This, </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Experiments With Corn 29 Fig. 8. Average sample of corn grown 1 plant per hill. Fig. 9. Average sample of corn grown 3 plants per.hill. Fig. 10. Average sample of corn grown 5 plants per hill. The ears are classed in five groups according to weight. The cards show the weight in ounces. A large share of the ears weigh 12 ounces or over when only one plant is grown per hill, while very few attain this weight when five plants per hill are grown. In the latter case most of the ears weigh 6 to 8 ounces. lection determines which plants have the natural vigor to produce when conditions are somewhat adverse. To secure data regarding this, an experiment was started in 1905. Corn was grown at three rates, namely 1, 3, and 5 plants per hill. Qood ears were selected from all three plats. In 1905 seed from each plat was planted at </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Experiments With Corn all three rates. We have selected seed continuously from each rate since 1905. The following table summarizes results to date. Table XII. — Summary of yields from different rates of plant - ing for three years (1906-07-08) according to origin of seed. Conditions under which seed was grown 1906 1907 1908 Average yield yield yield yield One plant per hill Three plants per hill. Five plants per hill. . The average yield for the three years shows a decided advan- tage in favor of selecting seed from the thicker planting, altho the difference has grown less each year. The experiment must be continued some years, before final conclusions can be drawn. RATES OF PLANTING CORN In Bulletin No. 91 of this Station are given results with vari - ous rates of planting corn for the years 1903 and 1904. The exper - iments have been continued up to date and in most cases confirm results reported in Bulletin 91. For these experiments the variety used has been Hogue's Yellow Dent, the hills being 3 feet 8 inches apart each way. Table XIII. — Average results from planting corn at various rates for six years (1903-1908). Bushels ' BtuJiels Bushels Bushels 64 5 65.3 55.6 61 8 66.0 66.1 54.6 62.2 70.3 67.1 55.8 64.4 Plants per hill Yield per acre Average No. ears weight per 100 of ear plants No. tillers per 100 plants •Two- eared plants per 100 Barren plants per 100 Yield of stover per acre 1 2 3 4 5 ButktU 48.3 61.7 75.5 76.7 76.3 Ounces 10.5 10.6 9.4 8 2 7.4 161 115 95 82 77 138 60 25 10 3 Pounds 13.3 4.9 2.4 8 1.1 3. 4 8 6.9 8 3 10 8 5984 5972 6692 6969 Four years only. Cote: There is an apparent discrepi and number of ears per 100 plan the fact that a certain number ol and entirely disappear between f incy betw is (columi the plant rst count ■een number of barren stalks is 4 and 7). This is due to la in the thick plantings die , July 10, and maturity when </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Experiments With Corn 31 Yield of grain has averaged about the same for 3, 4, or 5 grains per hill. As rate of planting increased, the size of ear has decreased, as shown by column 3, while the number of barren plants increased as shown by column 7. Two stalks per hill produced about 90 per cent as much corn as 3 stalks. This was due to the increased size of ears and the large number of tillers producing ears as shown by column 4. Also 1 stalk per hill produced 64 per cent as much grain as 3 stalks per hill, due principally to the large number of tillers bearing ears, the average results showing 161 ears for every 100 plants. It is evident from these experiments covering a period of six years that under the conditions here at the Station about 3 stalks per hill may be regarded as a full stand. If more than this is planted the ears decrease in size and the number of barren stalks increase. With less plants than 3 per hill the plant attempts to adjust itself to the conditions by producing a larger ear, and the production of more ears by tillers. The average yield has been about 75 bushels per acre, and un - der such conditions a stand of 3 to 4 stalks per hill will probably give the maximum crop. Under 50-bushel conditions, however, the stand should be thinner. Recent results published by the Illinois Experiment Station* obtained on a number of soils indicate clearly that the poorer the soil the thinner the stand should be. The yield of stover increases with the rate of planting; hence, if corn is grown for this purpose it should be planted thickly. THE ECONOMIC VALUE OF TILLERS. In Bulletin 91 of this Station it is shown that for the years 1903 and 1904 rows of corn where tillers were left on gave an average yield of 81 bushels per acre, while rows where they were removed yielded only 64 bushels. For the past 3 years the experi - ment has been continued but the corn planted at various rates. Following is a summary of results. The variety used was Hogue's Yellow Dent, with hills 3 feet 8 inches apart each way. •111. Exp. Sta. Bui. No. 126. » </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Expert ■orn i 8 U 00 ©t-_C&lt;100.-t •*as«s»H-* I 8 &gt; &lt; el ao ■«■ •* i to no S F-f- s E o a s o «H(DNt- up eooseocc t r 5 u a c O I* £ &gt; » |*l ~ a*- 5 5 ° e&gt;i r- 1- rH • ' o-i ■♦' n "s * ~ S 08 fl 3 c c . c ill! ? « 00 M •* OS 8cc acoon V J^ •ffif HM • «3 » © r- I s I a&gt; a = o en i « o ■&gt;»&lt; •♦ ■ »l 2 03 a, » « o a &amp; i js fc t~ oo a ?c SiOM &gt;M 3SO a o t- w •4J = ill - QOO r-N r- 5? CQ C*l tO CO d ■&amp;• 3 i-H ■— 0 «i-ooeo Eh I 1! 2 o 5 Up C^J w* O (5 us&gt;a .5 I ■* t-r-aooo O § I. IT Ml ntceqee Hrtrl w *9 I- 85 £ i-lNM'* W 1 I -« C"8 ON 30CO O CO la ? ° </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Experiments With Corn 33 A decreased yield is shown as a result of removing the tillers even with a stand of 4 or 5 stalks per hill. It is possible that on poor soils or in a series of very dry years different results might be secured. However, with fair conditions for producing corn it appears that removing tillers would result in an actual decreased yield. Removing tillers has had a tendency also to increase the number of 2-eared stalks and decrease the number of barren plants, altho this benefit has not apparently been enough to counteract loss of ears ordinarily produced by the tillers. Table XVI.— Effect of removing tillers on the number of two - eared plants and barren plants, two years (1907-1908). The remarkable way in which the corn plant adjusts itself to conditions by developing tillers to thicken up the stand when it is thin is further illustrated by the way these tillers will disappear in large numbers when not needed. For example, we have found the maximum number of tillers are to be found about July 10, when the plants are three to four feet high. However, from this time on they will disappear in large numbers if they are not need - ed. When the plant begins to develop tassel and ears, evidently the nourishment is diverted in this direction, as the tillers appear to perish from this time on. I Two-eared plants per 100 Barren plants per 100 No. ilants per bill Tillers on Tillers removed Tillers OD Tillers removed 1 2 3 4 18.8 8.9 4.4 1.6 28.5 13.3 4.7 I.I 1.15 3.60 2.70 2 05 .50 1.30 1.13 2.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">■menta it, S | II I II 55 &lt; 00 r-— »rH g ! ©|S5S i its S5 «i o.S i|tl! 3 S o a ® S oo 2 » « BXDS a fe I I S cl Zi TT i i i •*» 6 552 C 0 i &lt;* «e&gt; ■♦ t- a&gt; X00 1-MM fe V 6t tfS "5. Is •5 M«OiC •o •*' ■*&lt; &gt;o 1 i §gs no e 3 6 •Z a, s 6 2L"SL "© t-O« t-no O5"3 "&gt; S g&gt; I-I ■ a: ■s e Fri I Mill r-r-t-© O I* § 3 *£ jl rl be 4 B \** *H rH r-4 »^ iijj; Qli ; »^ ; S «1I : j=z — £ZS26 I eoosHM I 33 ! I + 11 I I g i i — SS«2" 3 9 in I III q J8d hjici)«« </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Experiments With Corn 35 UNIFORM DISTRIBUTION OF THE SEED IN PLANTING COMPARED WITH A VARIED DISTRIBUTION. In 1907 an experiment was planned to test the value of dis - tributing the seed at a uniform rate of 3 grains per hill as com - pared with distributing the seed in different amounts per hill, but planting the same number of grains per acre. The object of this experiment was to see whether in planting corn it would be neces - sary to have an absolute uniform drop of 3 grains per hill, or whether a reasonable variation would affect the yield. The first plat was planted uniformly 3 grains per hill, in the second plat we alternated 2 and 4 grains per hill, the third plat was alternate 1 and 5 grains per hill and the fourth plat was alternate 1, 3, and 5 grains per hill. All plats were hand planted, the desired num - ber of grains dropped in each case, just as would be done by a machine. Hills 3 feet 8 inches apart each way, and variety used was Hogue's Yellow Dent. Plats were duplicated each year and check plats placed on both sides of each series. Table XIX. — Distributing seed in planting in various ways, and effect on yield. A uniform distribution of the seed gave slightly better results than an uneven distribution. The variation in kernels per hill is much greater than would result with a corn planter, even if drop - ping very unevenly. The data therefore indicate that ordinary variation in rate of dropping found in corn planters will have very little and probably no effect on the yield per acre. Grains planted per hill i*- per acre per mil 3 2 and 4 1 and 5 1, 3 and 5 1907 Bushel* 71.2 70.4 64.5 70.7 1907 IMS BuxlieU 58.9 Ml 60 6 60.1 Average Bughels «5 5 63.6 a a A verage </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Experiments With Corn *3 &amp; n * &amp;&gt; A g* 2»V Fig. 11. Showing plan of distributing seed in plats where different methods were discussed. * W . f » o %* S^ % </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>