<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THIRTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb FOR THE YEARS 1901 AND 1902 TO THE GOVERNOR Hon. Ezra P. Savage</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THIRTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE— BOARD OF TRUSTEES OF THE — Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb FOR THE YEARS 1901 AND 1902 TO THE GOVERNOR Hon. Ezra P. Savage 1802 Thi Fremont Tribuhi Frimont. Nib. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LETTER OR TRANSMITTAL. NEBRASKA INSTITUTE K( )K THK DKAF AND D1MH. ■ Omaha, Nrb., December 4, 1902. Ezra P. Savage, Governor: Sir: — In compliance with section 12, chapter 22, of the Com - piled Statutes, the Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb have the honor to transmit herewith the thirteenth biennial report for this institution, upon the work accomplished during the period ending December 4, 1902. Very respectfully, Clinton Orcutt, Charles Nownks, Board of Trustees. C. G. Ellwan(;er, </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. Ezra P. Savage Governor HOARD OF TRUSTEES. Ein Orcutt . . es Nownts Ellwangei President, Omaha, Nebraska Secretary, Papillion, Nebiaska Nebraska City, Nebraska OFFICERS. R. E. Stewart, M. A Superintendent and Steward Miss Nora O. Johnson Matron TEACHERS W. H. Rothert, B. A Manual Department Louis A. Divine Manual Department Chas. E. Comp Manual Department Mrs. Ida G. Hendee Manual Department Miss Ota B. Crawford Manual Department Miss May Autenrieth Manual Department Alvin E. Pope, M. A Head Oral Department Harry F. Best, M. A Oral Department Miss Lillian A. Bamford Oral Department Miss Alberta A. Regnier Oral Department Miss Cora Jack Oral Department Miss Mary McNamar Oral Department Miss Laura Robie Oral Department Miss Anna Kirkpatrick Beginners </seg>
            <seg id="p004">INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT, ASSISTANTS, ETC. J. H. Parry Carpentering Lawrence Jamrs Shoemaking Loyd Blankenship Art C. E. Comp Printing E. N. Reynolds Horticulture J. F. Rogers Painting Mrs. Lizzie Scherer Sewing Miss Anna Jansen Ironing W. H. Hanchett, M. D Physician Miss Harriet Whiteman .... Nurse J. W. Robinson Clerk Amelia Gillilan Supervisor of Girls Laura Crawford Supervisor of Small Boys Ann Richards Supervisor of Large Boys Albert Gladwin Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT. NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THK DEAF AND DUMB. Omaha, Nebraska, December 4, 1902. To the Governor: The Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb has the honor to submit the following report CHANGE OF OFFICERS. The term of B. F. Allen, of Wabash, as a member of the Board of Trustees, expired May 15, 1901, and Clinton Orcutt, of Omaha, was appointed to the position for a term of ihree years. The term of J. J. Cardwell, of Nebraska City, expired in May, 1902, and the position was filled by the appointment of C. G. Ellwanger, of Nebraska City. In June, 1901, Charles Nownes was elected secretary of the Board instead of B. F. Allen, and in June, 1902, Clinton Orcutt was chosen president of the Board. On February 6, 1901, the superintendency of this institu- tion was transferred, by appointment of Governor Chas. H. Dietrich, from H. E Dawes to R. E. Siewart. The following table shows appropriations made by legislature for biennium i9Oi-'o2: Appropriated Expended Halaiutr Salary of superintendent. .$ 3,60000 $ 2,850.00 $ 750.00 Salary of matron 1,600.00 973-54 626.66 Fuel and lights 7,000.00 4,336.21 2,663.79 Office expenses-books and stationery, telegrams, school supplies, post- age, etc i,ocooo 799.17 200.83 Maintenance 17,500.00 13,08690 4. 413.10 Furniture and bedding. . . . 1,700.00 1,700.00 00.00 Supplies for industries.... 1,75000 1,59380 156.:© </seg>
            <seg id="p006">398 Telephone and improving internal telephone ...$ 300.00 $ 22564 $ 74-3° Repairs and improvements 3,500.00 3,109.45 39°-55 Water supply 1,000.00 533-26 466 74 Incidentals i,6( 0.00 1,168.89 4.&gt; IIX Drugs and medicines 200.00 1 37-!3 62.87 Furniture and equipment of hospital 200.00 200.00 00.00 Improvements on farm.... 1,000.00 918.50 81.50 [N8TTTUTION (ASH ACCOUNT. ■received from the sale of fruit, vegetables, hogs, shes and receipts from Industrial shops $978.56 Amount expended 656 93 Balance on hand $321.63 KSTIMATKD KXPKXDITU5KS KOI! BIKXNTAL FROM APRIL 1. ltm:{ To .MARCH 31, 19O.V Salary of superintendent $ 3,600.00 ■F 3&gt; Salary of matron 1,600.00 Salaries of teachers, foremen, physician, clerk, super - visors and nurse 25,000.00 Employes wages 8,000.00 Fuel and lights 7,500.00 Maintenance 1 7,500.00 Furniture and bedding 2,ooo.co Supplies for industries i,5"O 00 Office expenses — books, stationery, schoui supplies, postage, telegraph, etc 1,000 00 Telephone and maintaining internal telephone system 250 00 Repairs and improvements 3.500 00 Water supply 1,000.00 Incidentals 1,60000 Drugs and medicines 300 00 Furniture and equipment of hospital 200 00 Improvements on farm 500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">399 SPWIAL. For purchase of additional land $::o,ooo.oo Cold-storage room and machinery 1,500.00 r lections with Omaha city water-works, pipe and f&gt;re hydrants for fire protection 8,000.00 Fish's rotary oven and bakery 1,000.00 We desire to testify to the dtcided improvement and advance- ment in all departments of this school under the new manage - ment and to the increased efficiency of officers, teachers, employes and methods. We suhmit, appended hereto, as a part of this report, the report of the superintendent, giving full and detailed informa - tion as to the progress, present condition, and needs of the We fully indorse all recommendations for appropriations asked for by the superintendent. Respectfully submitted, Clinton Orcutt, (Jhari.es Nownes, Hoard of Trustees. To the Honorable Board of Trustees: Gbnti.emrn: — I respectfully submit to you the thirteenth biennial report of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb, which covers the period from December, 1900, to December 4, 1902. During this biennial period we have had an attendance of two hundred and thirty-eight. Of these, one hundred and forty-one were boys and ninety-seven were girls. Fifty-nine new pupils have been enrolled since February I, 1901. Present enrollment is one hundred and eighty. ■This institution was founded in 1869, and since that time six hundred and thirty-eight names have been registtred as pupil?. C G. Ellwamjkr, SUPERIN I'ENDENTS REPORT. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">400 ris number forty- seven have received diplomas of gradua- LIST OF (JKAW'ATKK. Name Class of Address. Lucy Butrick ( ( oulter) 1889 Redington. Neb ( Self-sustaining) (Dead) Ella Hudd Divine 1887 Etta Stewart (Cain) 188H .Oklahoma (Self-sustaining) Louis A. Divine 1889 Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining) Nettie Burrows 189ti Ord. Neb (Lives with parents l hristian P. Jensen 1897 Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining CXa B. ( 'rawford IMS Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining) Kstella Forbes 18B5 .Omaha. Neb I Lives with parents) William Kipe 18H7 Mamie Hall 1897 Portland. Ore I Self-sustaining Harley Hall. Ha (Self-sustaining John O'Brien 18JW .Nebraska City, Neb. . (Self-sustaining Bertha Bauman ( Hodda) . . 1WI Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining) Jane Lockhart (Bauman) . .18H7 Dixon, Neb (Self-sustaining James Hoggs 1893 .California (Self-sustaining Edward Higgins tM San Francisco, Cal. . (Self-sustaining Mary Donnelly 1895 ( 'olorado Springs, Colo John Zadina 1«97 Omaha. Neb (Ke'f-sustaining Harry Mercer lH!tH Omaha. Neb (Self-sustaining j Wayne Thieman 1897 Portland. Ore (Self-sustaining Patrick Regan 1899 Platte ( enter. Nel&gt; (Self-sustaining Cora Ilexford (Kound) 18»« Akron. Jowa (Self-sustaining Maude E. Zweifel 1902 Omaha. Neb (Lives with mother . Neb i Self-sustaining) Martin Kennealley \HU" Maude Marshall 1902 Lincoln. Neb i Lives with sister Hester Willamn 1902 Nebraska City. Neb. (Taking post- graduate coursei Emma Morse l*9(t Denison. Neb. ... (Attending college at Washington, D. C.) Mary Smrha 1902 Milligan. Neb.. (Taking post graduate course j Alice Prentice (Zadina) .... 190(t Omaha. Neb I Self-sustaining) Effle (ioslin 1«9X Lincoln, Neb. . .(Attending college at Washington, D. C.) Cfust Koberstein 1897 ude Jenkins (Koberstein J.189H Dean Smock 1902 Portland. Ore ( Self-sustaining) Portland. Ore (Self-sustaining) Lincoln. Neb i Self-sustaining Clara Truhlar 1902 Coleridge, Neb... (Lives with parents Rudolph Stuht 189»i Portland, Ore (Self-sustaining Fred Beck 1HM Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining Ella Cornish (Hurt i 1891 Tribune, Kas ( Self-sustaining Lincoln, 'Neb ( Self-sustaining LeRoy Johnson 1893 Am Beahm 1893 Montana I Self-sustaining Ella Ream 1893 Stockton, Neb (Self-sustaining i </seg>
            <seg id="p009">401 Ida Kerr (Boatright) 1891. .Osceola, Neb (Self-sustaining j Alfred Waugh 1891 .. Chicago, 111 (Self-sustaining) Fred Parli 1893. .Pawnee City, Neb. . . . ( Self-sustaining) Charles Kluge 1893. . Saltillo, Neb ( Self-sustaining) Lloyd Blankenship 1897. .Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining) John Flood 1895. .Washington, D.C (Self-sustaining) Henry Porter 1893. .Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining) Kitty Peterson 1899. .Omaha, Neb (Self-sustaining) The several counties of the state have sent pupils to this school as follows: Adams n Fillmore 2 Otoe 18 Antelope 3 Franklin 2 Pawnee 6 Banner 1 Furnas 9 Perkins 1 Boone 14 G»ge n Phelps 3 Buffalo 12 Gosper 4 Pierce 2 Burt 12 Greeley 4 Platte 9 Butler 10 Hall 11 Polk 11 Box Butte 1 Hamilton 6 Red Willow .... 3 Boyd 2 Harlan 2 Richardson .... 20 Cass 15 Hayes 3 Rock 1 Cedar 12 Hitchcock 3 Saline 20 Chase 1 Holt 8 Sarpy 8 Cherry 2 Howard 3 Saunders 16 Cheyenne 10 Jefferson 8 Seward 8 Clay 6 Johnson 8 Sheridan 5 Colfax 11 Kearney 6 Sherman 2 5 Stanton 2 Cuming . 6 Knox Custer 4 Lancaster 34 Thurgton 1 Dakota 9 Lincoln 4 Thayer 8 Dawes 3 Madison 6 Valley 11 Dawson 5 Merrick 5 Washington. ... 12 Deuel 1 McPherson 2 Wayne 1 Dixon 6 Nance 3 Webster 6 Dodge 13 Nemaha 15 York 5 Douglas 117 Nuckolls 5 Total From other states ■d Grand total </seg>
            <seg id="p010">402 E'he causes of deafness, as reported by parents, are shown in following table: LIST OF CAUSES. Apoplexy i LaGrippe 12 Brain fever 38 Lung fever 5 Bronchitis 2 Malaria 1 Catarrh 10 Measles 21 Cholera infaiuuiu 4 Paralysis 3 Cold 10 Pneumonia 1 Congenital 174 Quinsy I Congestion of lungs 1 Scarlet fever 57 Cramps 1 Scrofula 7 Diphtheria 7 Spasms 1 Dropsy of brain 1 Spinal meimigius 72 Earache 10 Spotted fever 1 Fall (in imbutcy) 9 Sunstroke 1 fever (kind unknown j .... 15 Typhoid fever 15 Fits 4 Whooping cough 17 Inflammation of brain. ... 2 Yellow fever 1 Intermittent fever 1 Unknown 101 Inflammation of ear 12 Total 620 Mutes 18 Grand total 638 HEALTH. In point of health our term has not all been smooth sailing. When we took charge, February, 1901, there was a great deal of sickness among the children, especially the younger set — colds, sores, rheumatism and coughs were prevalent. One case developed into diphtheria. The case was treated by Dr. S. R. Towne, then the institution physician. By his advice at the request of the parents this patient, Benjamin Engleman, of Litchfield, was sent home in charge of a member of his own family, but died shortly after. He was a lad twelve years old. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">403 Ethe spring of 1901, we had an epidemic of mumps among hildren. This was brought into the institution by a child had returned from a visit home. There followed over ty cases among other pupils. In October, 1901, scarlet fever made its appearance witnin the institution. Each case, as soon as apprehended, was removed to the hospital which, fortunately, is an isolated building, and there kept in quarantine till all danger of spreading the disease had passed. Notwithstanding the greatest care exercised, new cases kept the hospital full from October, 1901, till the 20th of March, 1902. In all twenty-six cases. About the 1st of May, 1902, an epidemic of measles came to s through a pupil who had gone home over Sunday. Sixteen ases of measles were treated in the institution and a number of hildren after leaving for summer vacation in June were taken own with the disease at home. I am glad to report that our hildren have had good physicians and most excellent nursing, so that in spite of all sickness not a single death is registered within our institution walls during the time we have been in charge. For this, we are profoundly thankful to the Almighty for His preserving care. At present our sanitary conditions are good. The health of our pupils is good. They are well clothed, well cared for and well fed. CHANGES. Not a few changes have taken place among those who labor with us. In most cases these changes have come by resignation and vacancies filled by persons known to possess qualifications fitting them for the work. We hold that, in schools of this character, where special technical training is needed that "fiiness" should dominate the selection of every attache. LITERARY DEPARTMENT. The school has, within the past two years, undergone a thorough and complete re-organization. It is now conducted under methods approved by experienced educators of the deaf. Teachers who have had special training for this work have </seg>
            <seg id="p012">404 been employed. The "combined" system is used. A manual and an oral department are maintained. The individual capacity of each child is carefully weighed. All children fitted to receive instruction through speech and speech reading are instructed that way. Some are taught by written language and finger spelling or the manual alphabet. Others who have a tract of hearing left, are taught as far as practicable through the sense of hearing. This use of a variety of methods gives rise to the name "combined system." Ethe primary department we have adopted a series of ed lessons comprising over three thousand exercises both and manual. These cover the first five or six years of a 's life in school. K classes are graded according to a standard of advance - and no pupil may pass from one grade to the next higher shall have passed a satisfactory test. INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT. The industrial training department has been decidedly improved by additions of tools and equipments never before equaled in the history of the institution. Here pupils are instructed in carpentry, printing, shoe-mending, farming and horticulture, painting, free-hand drawing, laundry, dress-making and fancy needlework. All are encouraged to fit themselves to earn their own living. THE DOMESTIC DEPARTMENT The domestic department is in a most wholesome and improved condition. Cleanliness, neatness, comfort and good taste are displayed wherever a matron's duties pertain. REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS. The buildings were much in need of repairs when we found them and the work of putting them in order has progressed with the following results : All tin and metal roofs have been painted, gutters and spouting renewed, where needed, and </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Institute for the Deaf and Dumb. 405 painted. The shingles of the French roof of the dormer story were painted moss green. The smokestack, was re-topped, pointed and painted three coats. Outer walls of all brick build - ings were pointed, where needed, and painted on basement story. The hospital was painted all over, and the industrial building was painted complete, also the green-house, barn and hen-house. All porches were repaired by a mechanic and well painted. The children's dining-room, the teachers' dining-room, superintendent's dining-room and kitchen were plastered, painted and decorated, and floors of same coated with granite Pe parlor was papered. The office and main halls of the building were ceiled and wainscoted with steel and taste - fully decorated. Two guest chambers were renovated and furnished. All pine floors in halls and dormitories were treated to oil and granite finish, also the floors and wooden-work of the school building. The hospital wards received a thorough painting inside and furnished with white iron beds, blankets, etc. Seventy-two new white iron beds were placed in the girl's dormitory, replacing old wooden ones. One hundred and twenty mattresses were renovated and covered with new tick - ing, and forty new ones added. Ninety new blankets were bought. A complete outfit of sheets and pillow cases were bought and made for two hundred beds, giving each three changes. Forty comforts were made in the sewing department, also a complete outfit of table cloths and napkins were bought and prepared for all pupils' and officers' tables. A new white pine floor was laid in the first floor of large boys cottage and the whole building plastered and painted within, and floors oiled. New locks and fastenings fitted to many doors throughout the institution. All cisterns, reservoir and stand-pipe were thoroughly cleaned and cisterns re-cemented. A new water tank holding thirty-five barrels was placed over the industrial building to assist in case of fire and furnish water for laundry use. New ceiling was put into ironing room. New pillars and supporters were placed under the barn and new floors laid therein. A root </seg>
            <seg id="p014">406 cellar was built for storing apples, potatoes and vegetable?. A new planer and complete outfit of carpenter's tools were fur - nished the carpenter shop. A new printing press and quantities of type, etc., furnished the printing office. A new sewing machine, benches and bench tools furnished the shoe-shop. Two sewing machines were added to sewing department. Two new dining-room tables and a number of chairs were bought, together with quantities of lace and Swiss curtains, carpets and rugs, table silver, dishes and kitchen utensils. New stationary porcelain-lined washtubs were added to the laundry equipment. Two hundred new books were placed in the library. Three good horses, harness, a disc harrow and other farming machinery has become the property of the state. E stand-pipe, pump-house and all machinery in engine- Hit in good repair and painted. All outside doors were 1 and three front entrances of main building grained. Two hundred feet of 2 J^-inch and two hundred feet of 2-inch, high-grade fire hose with connections have been purchased and placed in readiness for any emergency. In short, everything has-been done that could be with the means at hand to give the school and buildings facilities for accomplishing the best resul'.s. Ke enumeration above is a very incomplete list of all the done and substantial improvements effected. Appropri.i - have been carefully and economically used without anv 3 the state. DEFICIENCY. BWe believe there will be no shortage in say fund duiing this nnium. Two years ago the Legislature was a^krd 10 appro - ate for this institution : House Roll 437 — deficiencies $5,5'6 99 House Roll 478 — claims 1,781-32 Total shortage NEEDS. Oae of our most urgent needs is connection with Omaha city water supply for fire protection. Our own plant is wholly </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Institutr for the Dkaf and Dumb. 407 inadequate should fire once get started. This connection would cost about eight thousand dollars. While this seems a large sum, it would certainly be cheaper than the constant risk of losing one hundred thousand dollars worth of buildings. Another very important need to our school is additional land acreage. Most of our boys are from farms and should be taught more in agricultural lines. This should have been attended to years ago, when land was cheaper, but vacant land still lies contiguous to that of the institution, and can be bought at a fair price. The state property here contains about twenty - three acres. All this is needed for buildings and lawn, a small orchard and very small garden. This year we rented twenty acres additional land on which we raised over five hundred bushels of potatoes and approxi - mately one thousand bushels of corn. We also use the qorn fodder. Our older boys have had lessons in preparing ground, planting, cultivating and gathering the crop. They enjoy the outdoor exercise and the state has profited thereby. E r e earnestly hope this Legislature will appropriate a reason - sum for the purchase of land for us, as was done two years for the Feeble Minded Institute at Beatrice. We need a cold storage plant or large refrigerator. We also need a bakery where a trade can be taught a class of pupils and where home-made bread and pastery can be provided for our children. Much repairing is still necessary. The south wing of the main building needs overhauling. New floors, doors, door cas - ings, windows, window casings, plaster, paint and some changes in sanitary piping. More radiators and steam connections are needed in the basement play-rooms. The steam heating system in large boy's cottage needs remodeling. The store-room and basement under the rear of the main building needs fixing and new stairways leading to and from the same. More metal ceiling can be put in with profit and economy to the state. We ask for repairs, an appropriation equal to two years ago. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">408 CHANGE IN NAME. FVe recommend that the name of this institution be changed a "Institute for the Deaf and Dumb" to "Nebraska School the Deaf." The word "dumb" is offensive to the deaf. Other states have adopted this name and we heartily approve of this change. LIST OF PUPILS ENROLLED DURING THE BIENNIUM. Name Age. Residence. Nativity. Date of Admission. Anderson, Peter 13. . Minden Swedish- Am ...Sept. 15, 1897 Anderson, Andrew 16. .Colon. Swedish- Am ...Dec. 12,1900 Andrejewski, Frank . . 10. . Elba . Polish- Am Sept. 17, 1902 , American Sept. — , 1890 Allen, Bertha 18. .Lincoln Adams, Eare 16. .Lincoln American Jan. 13, 1902 Alexander, Edna B... 6.. Johnson American Oct. 1, 1902 Brown, Fred William.13. .Pilger American Sept. 15, 1898 Brouhard, James E. . .13. . Beaver City. .German- Am ...Sept. 16, 1896 Butter ba ugh, Vernon.12. Jansen. American Sept. 16, 1897 Benson, Harry E 12.. South Omaha .American Oct. 12, 1899 Bingham, Richard . 20.. Omaha. American Sept. — , 1890 Beegle, Austin 13. .Grand Island American Sept. 16, 1896 Burrows, Dollie 20. . Bloomington American Oct. 12, 1899 Broekemeier, Frank F.13. .Pilger German- Am .... Feb. 16, 1899 Bosley, Charles A. . . .14. .Norfolk German- Am Feb. — ,1899 Bender, Joseph F 13. .Milford German- Am Oct. 13,1897 Belgum, John 19..Olnes Norwegian- Am. Sept. 16, 1896 Belgum, Gustave 16..Olnes Norwegian- Am . Sept. 16, 1896 Bachman, Charles 29.. Palmer German- Am. . . .Sept. — , 1901 American Sept. 16, 1896 Bass, Nola 16. Wilsonville Bates, John C 19. .Falls City American Sept. 15, 1898 Bramel, Lucious 12. .Omaha. American Sept. 17, 1902 Brant, Clifford G ... .11.. Omaha American Sept. 17, 1902 Bram, Mattie 10. .Grand Island . Russian- Am . . . Sept. 11, 1900 Burt, Mabel L 11. .Elwood American . . . Oct. 12, 1899 Burt, Ruia U 14. .Smithfield American Sept. 15, 1898 Bauman, Hattie 13..Dixon. . German- Am Nov. 7, 1895 American Sept. — , 1893 Batten, Ethel M 17. .Omaha. Bowen, Lulu F 14. .David City American Oct. 25, 1901 Balkovick, Mary. .. .10. .Omaha. Austrian- Am... Sept. 25, 1901 Cunningham, Myron. .22. . Wymore American Sept. 16, 1898 Classen, Willie 14.. Fremont German- Am Oct. 12, 1899 . American Sept 26, 1894 ChMe, Albert 14. .Elkhorn Chase, Frank 17. .Elkhorn. American Sept. 16, 1891 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">409 Claus, Adam. 13. .Kearney German- Am . . .Oct. 12, 1880 Cox, Earl 20. .Elwood . Chappell, Arthur E. . .14. .Omaha. . Christiansen, Chris. M. 9..Minden American Mar. 7, 1892 American Oct. ;"&gt;, 1898 .) Danish- Am Sept. 11, 1900 Cuscaden, Thomas S..10. Callahan, Julia A... 27 Donahue, Walter W. .23. DeGraflt, Charles 9. Dunker, Charles 17 . Duncanson, Clara S . . . 17 . Davis, Frances V 18. Dady, Marie 9. Davis, Hazel C 14. Davis, Edith L 7. Epps, Thomas 21. Eiseman, Joseph 8. Engleman, Benjamin P. 14. Forrell, Frank 16. Fry, Eugene 11. Flanagan, Francis F. . 5. Foy, Lucy F 21. Forrell, Nellie 21. Folsom, Pearl M 12. Gottier, Willie 12. Gabriel, Chester A 19. Gilson, Edward 16. Gaeth, Lydia 13. Gregg, Myrtle 20. Green, Alice 10. Hoffstetter, Claude 17. Hogle, Eugene 12. Hashberger, Dale C ..17. Hladik, Emil 10. Harkins, Ralph 12. Haller, Earl B 17. Hefner, George P. F..11. Higby, Chester L 13. Hanel, Pauline 14. Holmes, Ruth L 21. Horn, Gertrude M 8 . Hanchett, Bessie E... 7. Hefner, Frederike B . . 9 . Human, Floy 11 . American Sept. 16, 1896 Omaha Shelton Irish- Am Sept. 23, 1901 Hebron American Sept. 17, 1902 Irish- Am Sept. 17, 1890 Lexington. Blue Hill American Oct. 12, 18B0 Lemlev German- Am Sept. 28, 1891 South Omaha. .American Sept. 16, 1891 Omaha American Oct. — , 1890 Omaha German- Am .... Sept. 11, 1900 Falls City American Oct. 12, 1800 Lincoln American Jan. 1, 1902 Clara American Sept. 26, 1894 Columbus German. Am Sept. 12, 1900 . Lemley German- Am — Sept. 26, 1801 Hubbell American Sept. 20, 1803 Omaha. American . . . . Sept. 15. 1898 . South Omaha Irish- Am Jan. tt, 1902 Fairfleld American Nor. 2, 1803 •&gt; Hubbell American Oct. 18, 1886 Ashland American Nov. 6, 1805 Rushville Swiss- Am Sept. 22, 1808 Tecumseh American Nov. 7, 1800 Plattsmouth American Mar. f, 1805 Fremont German-Am Oct. 12, 1800 Cheney American ... .Nov. 1, 1802 Omaha Danish- Am . ... Sept. — , 1901 Omaha. American Oct. 7, 1892 Omaha American Nov. 6, 1805 Schuyler. American Jan. 15, 1804 Plainview Bohemian- Am .Nov. 20, 1808 Arlington American Sept. 11, 1900 Cairo German- Am Oct. 15, 1802 Coleridge Geeman-Am Sept. 18, 1900 American Nov. 6, 1806 Oconto. Clarkson Bohemian- Am. .Nov. 5, 1805 Fremont American Sept. 16, 1896 Randolph German- Am . . .Sept. 18, 1901 American Sept. 18, 1901 Omaha Coleridge . German- Am Sept. 18, 1901 Durant, Choctaw Nation, Ind. Ty. American Sept. 20. 1902 Springfield Swedish- Am .... Sept. 26, 1994 Johnson, Wilson R...14. Jonescheidt, Charles J.13 Jenkins, Claude 10. . Omaha American Sept. 15, 1807 Lincoln American Nov. 23, 1807 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">410 Johnson, Nellie 13 Ong American Oct. 12, 1890 Johnson, Orvina C ..21 Elm Creek Swedish- Am Nov. 6,1895 Swedish- Am Oct. 25, 1898 Jackson, Ida 21. .Malmo. Jenks, Viola M 10 Fullerton American Sept. — , 1899 Jensen, Clara A 17 Marquette Danish- Am .... Sept. 20, 1893 Kanaka, August 13. .Omaha German- Am Sept. 19, 1898 Kubat, John 20. .Crete Bohemian Sept. 16, 1892 American Mar. 31, 1809 Kirkpatrick, Ralph... 14 Coleridge Kaiser, Deitrich 8 .Riverdale. German- Am — Sept 18, 1901 Bohemian Jan. 21, 1902 Kyncl, Frank H Clarkson Kyncl, Joseph 11. .Clarkson 11 Bohemian Jan. 21.1902 Kuta, Stacia. 13 Columbus Austrian- Am . . .Oct. 27, 1898 Austrian- Am... Oct. 21, 1898 Kuta, Sophia. 11 Columbus . Kinnier, Anna B 18. .Spaulding Irish- Am Sept. — , 1897 Kinnier, Elsie M 8 Spaulding Irish- Am Oct. 12, 1899 Keimle, Anna M 13 German- Am Nov. 13, 1900 Chadron Kindred, Hattie 1 9.. Blair American Jan. 21, 1901 American Jan. 21, 1901 Kindred, Orletta I 8 Blair Kaiser, August* 6 Riverdale German-Am Sept. 25, 1902 German- Am . . Oct. 31, 1901 Koehler, Frances E...13 Arcadia Irish- Am Sept. 17, 1902 Kilcoyne, Catherine. . . 6 South Auburn Lee, Harold 20 Blue Hill American . ... Dec. 26, 1890 Lee, Clarence 15.. Blue Hill. American Sept. 20, 1893 Leach, George W 14 American Sept. 17, 1897 Edgar Lamm, Adolph G....22. St. Helena. German- Am Nov. — , 1896 American Jan. 21. 1900 Lamphear, Luke 10 Ord. Lewis, Charlie H 14 Valley American Nov. 6, 1895 Lambrecht, William A. 5 Kennard German- Am Sept. 24, 1902 Love, Mary M American 1897 17 Jackson. Losey, Sarah G 14 Liberty American Nov. 6, 1895 Luhn, EmmaC 21..Barada German- Am Oct. — , 1892 Lewis, Bessie. 9 Ruskin American Sept. 23, 1901 Macek, Charles 17 South Omaha Bohemian- Am.. May —,1893 Bohemian- Am.. Sept 26, 1896 Macek, James 13 South Omaha . Marshall, Charles... 10.. York American Nov. 10, 1898 ■den, John D 18. .Cedar Rapids. den, Henry J . . . 15. . Cedar Rapids . den, William . .12. .Cedar Rapids. . American Sept. 26, 18«3 . American Sept. 26, 1S94 .American Sept. 26, 1896 Myers, Harry L 20. . Swan . McKnight, Jesse 14 .. Peru . . . Mullin, Robert W 12. .Omaha American Nov. 6, 1895 American Apr. 23, 1898 American Oct. 23, 1898 Moody, Leo 11.. Grand Island. . Irish- Am Sept. 15, 1900 Meidle, Frederick 17. .Nenzel German- Am Sept. 26, 1894 Mura, Mike 18.. St. Paul. Bohemian Dec. 14, 1898 Moorehouse, Joseph. .15. .Omaha Morter, Silas A 18. .Lyons . American Sept. 11, 1900 American Jan. 10, 1900 McManus, Thomas 22. .South Auburn .Irish-Am ..... . .Sept 16, 1891 Mayfield, Carl. 18..Lemlev American Sept. 17. 1902 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">411 May field, J. 1 13..Lemley Mackay, Mella T 18. Creighton American Sept. 22, 1888 Marshall, Edith A... 19.. York Irish-Am Sept. 19, 1803 Marshall, Maude 17 Lincoln. American Sept. 17, 1880 German-Am... Nov. 6,1896 Menn, Lenora. 10. Dodge Mayerowitz, Sarah 17. .Omaha Russian Sept. — , 18B8 Myers, Ruth. 9. Bwmn American Oct. — , 1888 Macek, Sophia Bohemian- Am. .Sept 25, 1898 9. South Omaha. Murphy, Mary lit. O'Neill Irish- Am Jan. 4 Irish- Am Oct. — , 1901 McKenna, Katie 20. Inman Meyers, Mabel H 8 Arapahoe American Sept. 17, 1902 Nelson, Arthur 13. . Weston. Swedish-Am Dec. 23,1805 Newman, Harold G American Oct. 12, 1889 9. Laurel Neal, Alta J 9. .Friend it. American Sept. — . MM Xy&lt;trom, Sophia 14. .Omaha Swedish- Am Sept. 18, 1902 Osman, Zibe. is. Benedict American Sept. 14, 1882 Opfer, John H 18. .Liberty German Sept. 14, 1882 Pilsbry, Bertram F 20. Plattsmouth . . American Sept. 16, 1881 Pratt, Clarence P 14. Friend American Mar. 18, 1886 Parks, Andrew C 16. .Omaha African- Am Sept. 15, 1888 Porter, Charles 21 Humboldt American . ... Sept. I' 1 German- Am . . . .Sept 17, 1880 "P lenz, Herman 21 Lincoln. Patterson, George 13. Dublin American Nov. 6, 1886 Parlette, Shirley E 13. Bloomfield American Sept. II Pospesil, Louis Bohemian- Am.. Feb. 7,1889 9 PI a in view Pascoe, Teddy 6.. Fremont American Sept. 30. 1!*&gt;2 American Sept. 20, 1893 Patch, Ida M 21 Hardy Patterson, Lucretia B US Dublin Irish-Am Sept. 14, 1891 Pearson, Ellen 9. Tekamah Swedish-Am Apr. 2,1988 •&gt; Petersen, Laura H 19. .Friend. Danish- Am Sept. 16, 1881 French- Am Sept. 19, 1883 Pillard, Cora E 15. .Hampton Patterson, Mary E 20 Dublin Irish- Am Sept. 16, 1881 Parkhurst, Addie 7.. Omaha American May % i Petersen, Rose 7 . . Bennington . German- Am Sept. 11, 1900 i Pequette, Cecelia A Eagle. French- Am Aug. 12, 1886 19 Quillin, John S 12 Grand Island American Oct. 15, 1889 Randolph, Frederick. .24 . South Omaha .German-Am Jan. 6,1902 Randolph, Paul US South Omaha German- Am ...Jan. 6, 1902 Russian Sept. 14, 1892 Rosenthal, Johanne. . .22. .Lincoln. .» Rush, Frederick 10 Redington German- Am Sept. 11. Russell, Charles D lfi Omaha American Sept. 18, 1901 Russell, Thomas 22.. Lincoln English Sept. 18, 1901 Redmon, Eva 13 Omaha American Oct. 11, 1888 Austrian- Am. . .Sept. 11, 1887 Ratter, Rose. 11 Plattsmouth Rima, Cleo 20. .Rising City American Sept. 14, 1900 Ren, Hattie B 17. . David City American Oct. 18, 1900 Randolph, Katie. German-Am . . . .Jan. 6, 1902 27 South Omaha Rutledge, Nellie G 8..tnavale. American Oct. 24,1902 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">412 Roath. Maude E 15.. Lincoln. American Oct. — , 1899 Swanson. Frederick 13. Omaha Swedish- Am... Sept. 16, 1896 Stickler, William. 16. North Loup American Nov. 5, 1895 Strain, A. D 14.. Valley American Sept. 26, 1894 Smith, Herbert G American Nov. 6,1895 19. South Omaha Stover, Weldon 20. Beatrice. American Sept. 17, 1890 Stover, Merrill n Beatrice American Sept. 16, 1891 American Nov. 3, 1896 Shupp, Alfred R 18. Highland. Seaman, Charles D. 16. Grand Island. German- Am .... Sept. 20, 1894 Smith, Thomas M American Sept. 17, 1897 16. Verona Spratlen, Sanford 19. Omaha American Oct. ■-, 1890 Sheffler, Edward 15. .South Omaha. .American Jan. 2, 1899 •&gt; Sheffler, Alvin O. 23. South Omaha German- Am .... Sept. 20, 1893 Schmidt, Henry M. 18. Wolbach Danish- Am Sept. 17, 1902 Seeley, Perry 17 Lincoln. American Nov. 19, 1900 Sabin, William. 19. Tecumseh . American Sept. 20, 1893 Saathoff, Claus J ll..Odell German-Am ...Feb. 20, 1901 Smock, Dean 20. Lincoln American Sept. 18, 1901 Seth, Augusta E 10. Bert rand Swedish-Am Sept. 23, 1901 Schupbach, Rudolph 20 .Columbus Swiss- Am Nov. 4, 1901 Stodola, John 20 Howell Bohemian Oct. 15, 1891 Swan, Christopher 15 Harrisburg. Irish- Am Sept. 30, 1902 Stillahn, Margaret E German- Am. . . .Nov. 14, 1892 German-Am Oct. 3,1898 German- Am Sept. 26, 1902 17 Lorton Stillahn, Gesine 14 Lorton Stillahn, Johanna 6.. Lorton Smrha, Mary 20. Milligan. Bohemian Sept. 16, 1891 Smith, Annie C 21. South Omaha German- Am. .. .Nov. 21, 1892 Schlegel, Bertha 9. .Omaha American Oct. 18, 1899 Slater, Alta J American Aug. 12, 1896 12. Creighton . Stoner, Gwendolin A Liberty American Sept. — , 1901 7. Strumpfa, Rose 20. Clarkson Bohemian Jan. 21, 1902 Schupbach, Hedwig 15 Columbus . Swiss- Am Sept. 22, 1902 Thomsen, George . . .14. .Cedar Bluffs German- Am. .. .Oct. 15, 1891 Thomas, John 18. .Plattsmouth American May 9, 1899 Tatum, Ralph 15. Crofton. American Sept. 26, 1894 Toxward, Chester H. 13. Pender American Sept. 15, 1898 Trenke, Oscar. 10 Omaha. German- Am Oct. 23,1899 Thayer, Orin. 12. Kearney American Sept, 16, 1896 Thompson, Orley 12 Omaha. American Sept. 24, 1901 Thomas, Lloyd J 8. South Omaha .Irish- Am Sept. 21, 1902 Trucka, Frederick 12 Omaha Bohemian- Am. .Oct. 13, 1902 American Sept. 16, 1891 Tatum, Winnie G 18. .Crofton Thomsen, Louise. 9. Cedar Bluffs German- Ana Mar. 15, 1898 Troxel, Tish 1 21 . . Fairbury American Sept. 20, 1900 Truhlar, Clara 22. Coleridge Bohemian Sept. 18, 1901 Urbach, Conrad. 9. Leavitt German- Am Oct. 12, 1899 American Jan. 13, 1888 Vaughan, John F —. .South Omaha VanUorn, James H. IK Norfolk. American Nov. 25, 1901 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">413 Whited, Earnest 25. .Homer . . . Wittwer, Isaac 18. .Salem . . . Wiltrout, Daniel E . . . 13. .Galena . . Wright, John H., Jr. .14. .Basin Wieseman, Christ F. .10. .Osceola. . Warren, Errol 15. .Lynch . . Willman, Hester 20. .Nebraska Wright, Chloe B 19. .Basin. . . . Welch, Anna M 14. .Omaha. . . Williams, May 15. .Omaha. . . Weseen, Effie A 5. .Oakland . Whitlock, Blanche 6. .Ong Zweifel, Maude E 21. .Omaha. . . American Sept. 17, 1880 Swiss- Am Sept. 16, 1801 American Oct. 18, 1888 American Nov. 13, 1886 German- Am . . - Sept. 15, 1900 . American Nov. 8, 1886 City. . .American Sept. 29, 1890 American Sept. 20, 1803 Irish-Am Sept. 28, 1894 American Nov. — , 1883 Swedish- Am Sept. 24, 1902 German-Am Sept. 17, 1902 American Sept. 11, 1889 ELIGIBLE PERSONS NOT IN SCHOOL AT THIS DATE. Name Age P. O. Address Belgum,John K.i8.Olnes Belgum, Gustav i5.Olnes Rima, Cleo . . . . 2O.RisingC'y Stillahn, Marg't . 18 . Lorton Wiltrout.Dan'l E 1 3 . Hudson Wiltrout, Ida ... 7 . Hudson Batten.Ethel M'y 17 . Omaha Cuscaden,Thos S 10 . Omaha Name Age P. O. Address Harkins.Ralph E 1 2 . Arlington Kreifels, Paul. . . 6. Paul Lee, Ruth J 8 . Oxford Zabel, Waltei. .. 9. Western Eiseman, Joseph . 7.Columb's Isom, Bessie .... 10. Allen Nye, Floyd 8. Lincoln Babcock, Kate ..11 Nor. Loup OFFICERS, TEACHERS AND EMPLOYES. R. E. Stewart, M. A. Superintendent, $1,800 per year and living. Miss Nora O. Johnson, matron, $60 per month and liv - ing. W. H. Hanchett, M. D., physician, $25 per month; lives outside. J. W. Robinson, clerk, $55 per month and living. W. H. Rothert, teacher, $90 per month; lives outside. L. A. Divine, teacher, $100 per month; lives outside. Ida G. Hen - dee, teacher, $60 per month; lives outside. Anna Kirkpatrick, teacher, $35 per month and living. Mary McNamar, teacher, $50 per month ; lives outside. A. E. Pope, teacher, $60 per month and living. Lillian Bamford, teacher, $60 per month; lives outside. Cora Jack, teacher, $60 per month; lives out - side. Ota B. Crawford, teacher, $45 per month and living. Laura Robie, teacher, $70 per month; lives outside. Alberta Regnier, teacher, $55 per month; lives outside. H. F. Beat, </seg>
            <seg id="p022">i-*AND COMMISSIONER S XvKPORT. 414 teacher, $55 per month and living. J. H. Parry, teacher, $60 per month; lives outside. Lloyd Blankenship, teacher, $40 per month and living. C. E. Comp, teacher, $75 per month, lives outside. E.N.Reynolds, teacher, $60 per month; lives out - side. Lawrence James, teacher, $50 per month; lives outside. May Autenrieth, teacher, $35 per month and living. Amelia Gillilan, supervisor, $27.50 per month and living. Laura K. Crawford, supervisor, $30 per month and living. Ann Rich - ards, supervisor, $27.50 per month and living. Anna Jansen, teacher, $22.50 per month and living. Harriet Whiteman, nurse, $25 p»r month and living. Lizzie Scherer, teacher, $30 ptr month and living. C. P. Jensen, assistant supervisor, $20 per month and living. Henry Porter, assistant supervisor, $17 per month and living. Albert Glad win, engineer, $75 per month, lives outside. J. F. Rogers, night engineer, $60 per month; lives outside. J. L. Hoiter, fireman, $25 per month and living. Anna Harmon, cook, $25 per month and living. Jennie Johnson, second cook, $18 per month and living. Gertrude Alexander, waitress, $15 per month and living. Esther Johnson, house-girl, $15 per month and living. Hulda Holmberg, house-girl, $15 per month and living. Blenda Dahlman, house-girl, $15 per month and living. Mary Washington, laundress, $22.50 per month; lives outside. Joseph Smejkal, janitor, $15 per month and liv - ing. T. R. Jackson, teamster, $22.50 per month and living. E submitting this report I wish to thank you, gentlemen of board, for your constant sympathy, advice and encourage - t. I wish also to thank His Excellency, Governor Savage, his firm, friendly support and all state officers for uniform tesy. It was no easy task to correct the many errors in school methods, conduct and care of pupils, poverty of facility and dilapidation of buildings. Such was our undertaking two years ago and the time has been full of hard work on the part of all — teachers, employes and helpers in all positions. To these persons I owe much of our present success and improvement, </seg>
            <seg id="p023">415 and 1 sincerely thank them for their loyally and faithfulness in duty. Trusting that the legislature may be disposed to grant liberal support for the coming term and favor, by appropriation, the improvements we have asked, 1 respectfully submit this report of the Nebraska Institute for the Deaf and Dumb for the years 1901 ;md 1902. R. E. Stewart, Superintendent. V </seg>
            <seg id="p024">416 PHYSICIAN'S REPORT. The Honorable Board of Trustees of the Nebraska State Insti- tution for the Deaf and Dumb: E3kntlkmkn: — This is my second year as medical attendant &gt;n your institution. During this time there has not been a gle death. This is gratifying to me and no doubt will be to u. E There has been, however, considerable sickness; yet no more in could naturally be expected where so many children are thered in such close proximity. There have been epidemics of scarlet fever, measles, mumps, and la grippe, to say nothing of the isolated cases of bronchitis, pneumonia, colds, etc. Ee well equipped little hospital has proven a benign factor i isolation and management of all these maladies. At times pacity has been taxed to its limit, and I would suggest as as the state can afford it, additional hospital room be pro- Ij prevent the bringing of contagious diseases to the institu - the superintendent has established a rule that children shall be allowed to visit their homes too frequently. This is , and such action should receive the sanction of the Board rustees. Ijere have been several accidents, such as fractures, wounds, but they have been fewer than would have been anticipated, is largely due to the constant watch, care and good judg - of your superintendent and teachers. Iie hygienic condition in which the buildings have been kept, wholesome food, and well directed physical exercises, ther with the pleasant and healthful surroundings, have sly contributed to the health and comfort of the pupils. Respectfully, W. H. Hanchktt, M. D., Medical Attendant. </seg>
            <seg id="p025"/>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">S. D. BEALS. Superintendent of Public Instruction. 1869 1871 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">J. M. MCKENZ1E, SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION, 1871-1877 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">S. R. THOMPSON. SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC I.VSTHUCTION, 1HTT 1HH1 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">w. w. w. jones. Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1881-1887 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">GEO. B. LANE, Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1887-I8»i </seg>
            <seg id="p032">A. K. GOUDY. SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION, 1K91-1KH5 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">H. R. CORBETT, Superintendent of Public Instruction, ihwmw </seg>
            <seg id="p034">WILLIAM R. JACKSON, SUPERINTENDENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION. 18U7-19O1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>