<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00027.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00027.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska State Penitentiary LANCASTER REPORT FOR THE BIENNIUM, 1911-1912 OF S.M. MELICK, WARDEN TO THE GOVERNOR AND The Board of Public Lands and Buildings</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">&amp; c - EC a y. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">LANCASTER REPORT FOR THE BIENNIUM, 1911-1912 OF S. M. MELICK, WARDEN TO THE GOVERNOR AND The Board of Public Lands and Buildings GOVERNOR Hon. Chester H. Aldrich BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Hon. E. B. Cowles Hon. Addison Wait Hon. Walter A. George </seg>
            <seg id="p003">OFFICERS S. xA.» W&amp;TQGn Mrs. S. M. Melick Matron H. H. ANTLES Deputy Warden N. T. Harmon, D. D Chaplain R. H. Spradling, M. D Physician M. Robb •. . . . Steward Walter M. Wilson Clerk </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">i 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">J. Burke Assistant Deputy Warden H. H. Humphrey, M. D Assistant Physician C. J. McCarthy Chief Engineer J. McCart . . . Night Engineer T. Cokeley Yardmaster C. A. Albright Farm Superintendent George Seuferlein Assistant Farm Superintendent W. Schroeder Day Turnkey F. Morse Night Turnkey A. L. Cavanaro Day Chapel Turnkey J. Rose Night Chapel Turnkey J. L. Hesse Day Keeper W. Cell Building O. Moore Night Keeper W. Cell Building Arthur Johnson Assistant Keeper W. Cell Building J. H. Me Williams Day Keeper E. Cell Building W. W. Bowling Night Keeper E. Cell Building A. C. Walsh Superintendent Dining Room J. Jenkins Gate Keeper C. Berry Guard S. E. Harriman Guard E. E. McWilliams Guard D. G. Kavanaugh Guard J. M. Griffin Guard J. L. Bathel Guard C. Thompson Guard C. L. Stephens Guard J. McNeil Guard T. Slattery Guard J. F. Morgan Guard Patrick Sullivan Guard M. F. McWilliams Guard J. Grimes «. Guard T. Troutt Guard D. E. Price Guard R. Gross Guard </seg>
            <seg id="p007">L. E. Johnson Guard S. J. Spry Guard H. G. Meyers Guard D. C. Topping Guard L. D. Austin Night Watchman G. Connelly Night Watchman D. McMahan Night Watchman </seg>
            <seg id="p008">NEBRASKA STATE PENITENTIARY Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1912. To His Excellency, the Governor, and the Honorable Members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings: r Gentlemen: I have the honor, herewith to submit to you report as warden of the Nebraska State Penitentiary, for the biennial period beginning December 1, 1910, and ending Novem - ber 30, 1912, during which period Honorable T. W. Smith was warden from December 1, 1910, to April 12, 1911, and Honorable James Delahunty warden from April 12, 1911, to March 14, 1912, the date of his death, from which date the prison was in charge of Adjutant General Phelps, until March 18, 1912, when I took charge. It is with sorrow that I report to you, Gentlemen, the loss by death of Warden James Delahunty, Deputy Warden E. D. Davis, Deputy Warden Henry Wagner, and Usher E. G. Heil - man, as follows: About two o'clock on the afternoon of March 14, 1912, three of the most desperate inmates, Charles Taylor, alias Shorty Grey, sent from Hamilton County for twenty-eight years for Pi burglary, John Dowd, sent from Cass County for from ity years to life for burglary with explosives, and Charles ley, sent from Douglas County for fifteen years for robbery, red the office of Deputy Warden Henry Wagner. One of trio shot and instantly killed the deputy warden, another engaged Guard Thomas G. Doody in a pistol duel which resulted in Mr. Doody being wounded in the arm and leg, while Shorty Grey with nitro glycerine blew the lock from the door leading into the turnkey's room. The lock blown to pieces, they entered the turnkey's quar - ters. Warden Delahunty, hearing the shots, rushed into the clerk's office, from where he fired four shots at them. They returned the fire, one of their bullets striking the warden in the left side. He fell to the floor, mortally wounded. The assistant clerk, who was with him during the battle, heard him say: "Oh, my Lord," and these were his last words on earth. He was carried to his room, where he passed away about 2:30 o'clock, </seg>
            <seg id="p009">144 P. M. During the battle a stray bullet struck Usher E. G. Heilman and killed him instantly. When the warden fell, the three inmates compelled the turnkey to open the doors and they fled through the main hall out into the open and soon dis - appeared from sight. LThe governor was immediately notified and Adjutant neral Phelps was placed in charge of the prison. He arrived about four o'clock with Company F, Second Regiment of the National Guard. Sheriff Gus A. Hyers with hjs deputies and several members of the Lincoln police force also arrived at the prison. The sheriff organized a posse, which, reinforced by Chief of Police Hunger of Lincoln and many sheriffs, police officers and private individuals from all parts of the state, set out to locate the murderers. They were located near Gretna, where a battle took place between the sheriffs forces and the murderers, resulting in the killing of Shorty Grey, the suicide of Dowd, and the surrender of Morley. An entry in the prison journal of March 18, 1912, shows that on this date Sheriff Gus A. Hyers delivered the dead bodies of Grey and Dowd, and returned Morley to the prison. About a month previous to this another murder had taken place in the prison, that of Deputy Warden E. D. Davis. On the morning of Sunday, February 11, 1912, the inmates were gathered in the chapel for the usual church services. The notes of the hymn, "Stand up for Jesus," had hardly died away, the men were standing with bowed heads, awaiting the benediction, the deputy warden, while walking across the chapel was fatally by Albert Prince, a negro inmate. The deputy warden 5 taken to his apartments where he passed away about eleven o'clock P. M. The negro was tried for the murder and found guilty and sentenced to hang on August 30, 1912. He appealed to the supreme court, which affirmed the decision of the lower court and fixed the day of hanging for March 21, 1913. I took charge on March 18, 1912. The big prison presented a sad spectacle indeed. The factories were idle, the inmates were locked in their cells and disorder and unrest prevailed through - out. I immediately set out to bring order out of the chaos, to reorganize the force of employees, and to establish friendly relations between the inmates and the officers. On the follow - ing pages I present to you, gentlemen, a complete report of my </seg>
            <seg id="p010">145 work from the day I took office up to the close of the biennium, to which is attached financial and statistical tables showing condition of the prison. I trust the same will prove entirely satisfactory to you as well as to the general public. I have the honor, gentlemen, to remain, Yours most respectfully, S. M. Melick, Warden. FINANCIAL COMMENT EFrom a perusal of the financial tables you will observe that disbursements exceed the appropriations by $13,429.19. is caused by several unforeseen expenses, as follows: After the outbreak of last March it was decided upon to employ a better grade of men as guards and more of them. This item alone accounts for about $8,000 additional expense. More paroles have been granted than before, causing additional expenses for transferring paroled inmates and tracing and trans - porting parole violators. At the end of the biennium one of our boilers went out of commisssion and a new one bought in its place, which, together with a new box car puller, recently in - stalled, add about $1,400. The water supply being entirely in - adequate, a new well was dug, causing additional expenditures for pipes, material and fittings. We are serving a much better grade of food and it costs much more. The above, to which I should add the ever increasing cost of fuel, foodstuffs, and all supplies used in the prison, have caused the deficit. Kthis connection I call your attention to our account ; the state for electric current furnished to the Orthpedic al, the State Capitol, the Capitol grounds, the Governor's mansion, and the Home for the Friendless. This amounts to $9,091.40, and is figured at the rate of three cents per K. W. H., or a daily average of about $14. Considering the size of these buildings you will readily see for yourselves that the charge is too low. For a fact, we are manufacturing this current with a The other state institutions who have furnished supplies to this institution, have, during my administration, been promptly paid, and I will ask you, gentlemen, as a matter of justice, to affix a new rate of not less than five cents per K. W. H. This </seg>
            <seg id="p011">146 will barely cover the cost of manufacture of the current, and if five cents had been allowed us during this biennium, there would have been no deficit. In an institution (like in a business) there are many leaks to be prevented, and one must be ever watchful, otherwise the earnings dwindle away and almost disappear. I have given my personal attention to all the many little details with the result that there is an increase in all departments. The barber shop shows earnings of $160.68, against $132 last biennium. The dining room sold meal tickets amounting to $292.25, against $265, and the cigar stand shows earnings of $643.34, against $511.43. This stand is now doing nicely, although its earnings had dwindled down to almost nothing. There is no waste around the prison, all bones, junk, rags and old metal is gathered together and sold. There is a decrease in the gate receipts. It had been customary to collect ten cents from the visitors, but this I have discontinued, deeming it unjust to collect from the taxpayers a fee to see an institution that they themselves main- tain. Maintenance Fund Balance, 1910 $12,691.67 Appropriated, 1911-1912 121,400.00 Total appropriations $134,091.67 Expended Salaries $12,366.42 Wages 23,519.41 Coal 27,266.22 Clothing and Food 69,570.67 Total $132,722.72 Lapsed 1.67 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">147 Office and Contingent Fund Balance, 1910 $875.88 Appropriated, 1911-1912 5,000.00 Total appropriations $5,875.88 Expended Outgoing inmates $1,615.00 Stamps 765.89 Photos 449.50 Telephone 377.49 Stationery 143.74 Printing 407.52 Adding machine 246.50 Typewriter 102.50 Brooms, etc 118.82 Rewards and traveling expenses 350.30 Insanity examinations 135.00 Disinfectants 37.50 Rewards for Warden's murderers 300.00 Transfer of inmates 165.81 Miscellaneous 12.04 Total $5,227.61 Lapsed 4.56 Balance $643.71 General Repair Fund Balance, 1910 $1,052.60 Appropriated, 1911-1912 15,000.00 Total appropriations $16,052.60 Expended Claims, 1910 $355.24 Implements 145.68 Hardware 721.61 Machinery 2,282.80 Firehose 500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">148 Boilers, repaired 1,045.68 Lumber 903.37 Brick, cement, rocks, sand, etc 1,771.08 Paint, glass 312.16 Electric 1,110.11 Stokers 4,801.43 Freight 115.48 Wells 164.66 Total $16,048.12 Lapsed 2.97 Balance $1.51 Land Purchase Fund Appropriated, 1911-1912 $2,360.00 Total appropriations $2,360.00 Expended Land $2,032.00 Balance $328.00 Bath Tub and Kitchen Utensils Fund Appropriated, 1911-1912 $2,500.00 Total appropriations $2,500.00 Expended Utensils and fixtures $1,441.01 Balance $1,058.99 Cash Fund Received Balance, 1910 $396.55 Appropriated, 1911 10,038.42 Received 15,494.09 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">149 Disbursed Live stock Maintenance from December, 1910, to April 10, 1911 Eard's car fares, etc roll, five months . lity examination rt engineer service Miscellaneous Total On Hand Estate treasurer in vault Cash items 136.77 205.14 In First National Bank, Lincoln Total 4,142.04 Total $25,929.06 Recapitulation Total funds $186,809.21 Total expenditures Total lapses $179,258.48 Total balances 7,541.53 $186,809.21 $186,809.21 Auditor's "O. K." of Funds NEBRASKA STATE PENITENTIARY • S. M. Melick, Warden Lincoln, Nebraska, November 30, 1912. Hon. Silas R. Barton, State Auditor: Dear Sir: I have this date balances, as follows: Maintenance $1,367.28 Land purchase 328.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">150 Eath tubs and kitchen utensils . 1,058.99 General repairs 1.51 Office and contingent 643.71 Cash 3,676.43 Kindly compare and "O. K." Very respectfully, S. M. MELICK, Warden. "0. K." (Signed) J. W. Shahan, Deputy Auditor Public Accounts. The following table shows earnings of the institution during biennium : Lee Broom and Duster Company, contract and special labor $113,209.98 Platte Shirt Company 13,060.00 Handcraft Furniture Company 510.48 Farmers and outside, for labor 323.78 Farm produce (sold) 2,391.40 Farm produce (for own use) 21,123.59 Barber shop 160.68 Gate receipts 1,662.40 Cigar stand 643.34 Hides, for 1911 24.43 Cinders .. 241.25 Safe keepers 391.05 Ice 33.06 Coal 198.33 Uniforms 20.65 Bones, junk, old iron and metals 155.48 Meal tickets ?92.25 Total $154,442.15 The following table shows earnings for which we have not yet received remittances: State treasurer, voucher claim $244.21 From firms on credit memos 173.40 Accounts on Ledger A 72.00 Accounts on Ledger B 15.02 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">151 Employees for uniforms 279.35 Light for public buildings 9,091.40 Contractors for labor 8,793.45 Farmers for labor 116.25 Counties for safe keepers 80.25 Cigar stand, loan for petty cash 5.00 18,870.33 Total earnings $173,312.48 The following table shows outstanding accounts, that I have been unable to collect. Appeals to pay these accounts have brought no replies. These accounts are nearly three years old and former officials do not remember anything about them: Douglas County for safe keepers $23.45 Harlan County for safe keepers 21.02 Holt County for safe keepers 15.75 Total $60.22 The following table shows accounts that I have stricken from the ledger, being unable to collect same, parties insist that they have paid same before I took charge and will not pay again: C. Anderson for meals $3.00 L. L. Klein for barber ticket 1.00 Total The following table • shows total disbursements during biennium, also unadjusted claims: Total disbursements $179,258.48 Unadjusted claims 18,394.07 Pay roll for November 2,785.85 Total $200,438.40 Pay Roll I have discontinued paying the employees in coin. Upon receipt of the warrant for the wages, same is deposited with The First National Bank of Lincoln, to the credit of "Penitentiary Pay Roll" and checks issued against it, thus saving them much </seg>
            <seg id="p017">152 time and inconvenience, besides having. the checks on hand for future reference. This account was opened on July 3, 1912: Total deposits $13,171.12 Total withdrawals $13,171.12 $13,171.12 $13,171.12 Inmates Cash Account Cash on hand, December 1, 1910 $3,760.76 Total deposits 28,694.80 Total $32,455.56 Total withdrawals 29,006.44 Balance on hand, November 30, 1912 $3,449.12 (Of this $2,959.81 in bank and $489.31 in vault.) Letter from bank, certifying to balances on hand at the close of biennium: 1798 FIRST NATIONAL BANK OF LINCOLN Lincoln, Nebraska, December 2, 1912. S. M. Melick, Warden, State Penitentiary, City: Dear Sir: This is to certify that there was on our books at the close of business November 30, 1912, to the credit of your three accounts, the following: Inmates cash fund $3,015.17 Institution cash fund 261.99 Pay roll account Nothing Very truly (Signed) H. B. Evans, Assistant Cashier. Above letter shows that we have more on deposit than we should have. The difference is caused by outstanding checks amounting to $56.85 in the Institution Cash Fund and $55.36 in the Convict's Cash Fund. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">153 REPORT OF THE CLERK Hon. S. M. Melick, Warden: Sir: I have the honor to transmit, for your consideration, the report of the clerk's office: The office has, according to your instructions, been con - ducted on the "open and above board plan." A most careful record has been kept of all expenditures, earnings and accounts. While the foregoing tables show the totals of our expenditures, the books remain open for inspection of those desiring more detailed information about our accounts. There is not a single transaction but what can be exactly accounted for. Below follows a complete report of the office: PThe Archives of the prison are kept in a vault in the base - i of the office building. When I took charge I found them very bad condition. The vault served 1 as abode for rats and mice, centipedes and hundreds of large roaches. I took out all the records and thoroughly cleaned and disinfected the vault, calcimined it and built shelving and painted them. To place the records in rotation required all of my spare time for many months and often kept me busy until midnight. In this con - nection I beg to inform you that nearly all commitments num - bering from 1 to 2100 are missing entirely. These, I under - stand, were destroyed in the fire of the prison in 1901. Also many invoices and transfers and time slips from 1909 and 1910 were destroyed, they having been cut to shreds to serve as nests for the many baby rats I found there. EThe Books. I found many of the most important books ontinued or kept in parts. The ledger, the most important book of the institution, contained only one account, that of the Lee Broom and Duster Company, while on a hook I found slips on which were accounts amounting to over four thousand dollars. Smaller accounts were kept by memory. I have rein - stated all accounts on the ledger and for the very small accounts I have opened, auxiliary to the main ledger, a smaller one. The Indexes. The institution had three, all of which were incomplete. I ordered, with your permission, a new one built to order, and contains sufficient space for all names from the beginning of the prison and for many years to come. It has </seg>
            <seg id="p019">154 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT separate pages for female prisoners, gives a complete list of names of prisoners kept by us for the territories of New Mexico and Wyoming, as well as United States prisoners. Also it shows at a glance previous servitude of inmates and their former numbers, as well as race and color. I have it nearly completed. It will be, when completed, a most interesting book and a great time saver. The assignment book was partly abandoned. I have brought it up-to-date, with exception of four months in 1910, the slips from which to enter were nowhere to be found. The. Inmates Cash Ledger. I found it out of balance for seven months. This was just a matter of carelessness, and the errors were small. I have changed this book from a monthly to a daily balance and. save much time thereby. As shown by the preceding table, the inmates had on hand at the beginning of the biennium, $3,760.76. They deposited $28,694.80 and withdrew $29,006.44, leaving a balance of $3,449.12. About one-half of the deposits represents the earnings for overtime work and the other is money received by mail. The inmates check against their accounts when they send money away or make purchases. In other words, this department does a banking business, and when the many small transactions are considered, it entails as much work as many a small bank. In our safety deposit department inmates may, on entering the institution, deposit their valuables. I have built compartments in the vault for these articles, and opened a "Safety Deposit Record" and entered them. Mail. An average of 2,442 letters and about the same numbers of newspapers and magazines are received each month. Nearly twelve hundred letters are written by the inmates each month, all of which I examine before mailing them. I have opened a record of registered mail and special delivery letters in which receipts are given for each letter. The Picture Gallery. It contains nearly 2,000 photos which I found badly mixed. It was impossible to locate a photo when wanted. I have filed them all systematically and a photo can be located in less than a minute. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">155 The Vouchers have been separated. Each fund has separate numbers and are filed in separate compartments. By this system can be quickly located any voucher, when wanted for reference. rThe Commitments of the inmates and their descriptive Bertillion sheets were filed in different places. These I have consolidated and have separate compartments for regular in - mates, paroled, escaped and furloughed inmates. Separate compartments contain reports to the governor, receipts from the state treasurer, etc. Ee Correspondence of the institution is important, ltgoing letter is copied in the copy book and indexed by il system, letters from the wardens, from the sheriffs, from the police, from the governor, and the miscellaneous letters, all having separate spaces. The incoming letters are filed in the same way. They can all be referred to quickly. I have changed many of the printed forms and much time is saved and many mistakes eliminated thereby. Printing, being expensive, no one is allowed to use printed forms for scratch pads or to destroy them. The stamped envelopes are the most expensive item of the office. I look upon them as I would upon cash and none are given away to employees, nor wasted. I pay for those I use myself. Telephone Calls occupy much of the time, there being an average of forty a day. I have ordered discontinued much foolish and useless telephoning and the office benefits thereby. Eunds. According to your instructions the cash of each has been separated and separate accounts kept of same. : made up a daily statement blank, as shown herewith, by which a daily report is rendered you at the close of each day, showing the condition of each fund, how much cash on hand and how much in the bank. By this method the entire cash of the institution can be checked in less than half an hour. The Furniture and Fixtures of the office are of the most antiquated kind and not at all befitting the dignity of a state office. A small table serves as desk for my assistant. The filing system is most inadequate, outside of one steel cabinet. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">156 I do the filing in empty shoe boxes, while the picture gallery has outgrown the little old cabinet in which it is quartered. I would recommend the purchase of two modern desks, a filing cabinet and a rogues gallery outfit, as well as a railing to keep loafers and curiosity seekers at a distance and from interfering with the work of the office. From the foregoing you will see that the duties of the office are many. It has taken lots of time to put it in order and will require some more before it is perfect. All the details are most carefully attended to and I am at my desk from 7:00 A. M. until way into the night each and every day in the year. The Nebraska Penitentiary has the smallest office force of any prison, I do all the work with but the assistance of one inmate. Many smaller prisons have secretaries, clerks, mail clerks, Bertillon clerks, stenographers, etc. The inmates who have assisted me, have, with one exception, been most faithful and efficient workers. £hey deserve, owing to the long hours, reduction in their sen - &gt;nce. In closing my report, I desire to thank Mr. G. W. Tulleys, expert accountant for the state, for much valuable instruction, and I wish to express to you, Mr. Warden, my thanks for the many kindnesses shown me, and for the guidance and valuable suggestions from you in the performance of my official duties. Yours most respectfully, WALTER M. WILSON, Clerk. The following shows a reproduction of the form of report rdered to the warden at the close of each day. The figures the report show the distribution of the inmates cash on the last day of the biennium: NEBRASKA STATE PENITENTIARY Daily report Convicts' Cash Fund November 30, 1912 Balance on hand $3,388.89 Received 103.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">157 Disbursed $3,449.12 $424.60 In bank $2,964.29 In vault Disbursed Deposited $2,964.29 IS Checks 4.48 Received Total in bank $2,959.81 Total in vault $489.31 Grand Total Drafts, checks, money orders Currency Gold (cash items) Dollars Halves Quarters Dimes. . Nickels Pennies, etc Total B report like this is rendered for each fund. By this method tire finances of the prison can be checked in a few minutes. REPORT OF THE CHAPLAIN C Chaplain's Office, November 30, 1912. arden S. M. Melick: E5ir: I have the honor to submit herewith my report as ain and librarian of this institution, beginning March 13, The moral and spiritual interest of the inmates has been awakened and developed, many have a high appreciation of that higher and better life exemplified in the life of our Savior. Men in prison are like all other men, there is good in their nature </seg>
            <seg id="p023">158 that will respond to practical and spiritual help if touched by the Infinite through agencies, manifesting love and kindness. During the term of my office we have held regularly services in the chapel every Sunday, with the exception of one, that being March 17, 1912, when members of the National Guard were quartered in the chapel. These services consisted of preaching the gospel, music by the prison choir, ably led by Mr. J. E. Enix, who gave no little time in instructing the choir, also splendid music by the prison band. This service was followed by the Bible school classes, taught by proficient teachers from the city. Chapel services have been well attended, both by the inmates and by the visitors who have maintained the expenses of the Bible school. Many a heart to heart talk has been given as we visited in the chapel and we have gone from cell to cell and visited in the shops. The messages and visits have been received with the most respectful attention and in most part with appreciative heart. Four inmates have been baptized and many have expressed a desire to live a Christian life. We are indebted to many of them for their assistance in our chapel services, and to many outsiders for their music, lectures and sermons, and the untiring efforts of yourself and Mrs. Melick, and the kind assistance of the other THE LIBRARY Our library is under the supervision of the State Library Commission, that has shown much wisdom in the selection of books. It has improved much during the last year and is now much better equipped to meet the demands made upon it. RMany new books have been purchased by the commission many undesirable books have been eliminated, and they all been classified and listed. A catalog has been provided for each inmate from which he makes his selection of books. The library is conducted by the same up-to-date methods of any outside library of its size. We have the distribution of all books in the prison, there - fore we feel, that it is our duty to encourage the use of our good books and to discourage the reading of the undesirable ones. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">STATE PENITENTIARY 159 My assistant, an inmate, is very useful in the library. He has, in the last few months, put pockets and made author and title cards for 3,000 of the books and has repaired 125 books. The following tables contain some interesting information relative to the number, kind and circulation of our books: Fiction 1,800 General works 97 Philosophy 92 Religion 172 Sociology 92 Philology 72 Natural science 122 Useful arts. 122 Fine arts 84 Literature 200 History 247 Total 3,100 Total inmates 381 Average monthly circulation 1,170 Number of constant readers of books 309 Two-thirds of the circulation is fiction. One-third of the circulation is non-fiction. re circulation of school books is as follows: Arithmetics 40 Grammars 13 Geographies 9 Readers 80 Slates 35 I trust the foregoing report is satisfactory and remain, Yours respectfully, N. T. Harmon, Chaplain. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">160 THE VALUE OF GOOD READING r'he state library commission is receiving many letters inmates, herewith follows a sample of them: I am doing time here in Lancaster and after my day's work is done then the hardest part of my confine - ment commences, after working all day then having to stay in my cell till morning. If we had no books to read the time would be al - most unbearable, reading is the only way we can pass le time we are not working, and I think the library is ne of the necessities of the prison. I am always glad hen Wednesday night comes, for then I can get a new &gt;ook. I wish it was so that I could receive reading matter more often, and I hope to see it so in the near uture. I think reading good clean books is one of le best ways of getting to the best part of man. Get lim to thinking good clean thoughts and you have rim on the way to reform, for as a man thinketh, so she. REPORT OF THE CATHOLIC CHAPLAIN Denton, Nebraska, December 1, 1912. Honorable S. M. Melick, Warden: Dear Sir: It is a pleasure for me to state that during your administration every facility has been afforded to Catholic prisoners to attend their religious services as often as it was Eible for me to conduct them. Services wore not held more uently owing to the fact that I had but little time at my osal after attending to my regular parish work. I wish to express my appreciation of the hospitality extended to me by yourself and Mrs. Melick, to commend the willingness of the officers of your institution to assist me in any manner requested, that would enable me to be of service to those whom I desir'ed to help in a spiritual manner. I wish also to thank the guards for their courtesy, and to give credit to the prisoners for their earnest attention and respectful behavior during the services, that it has been my pleasure to hold for them. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">161 I might add, that in my humble opinion, formed from a personal observation extending over four years of prison work, the number of prisoners who at one time or another have be - longed to the Catholic faith, calls for the official appointment of a priest who shall be able to give all his time to the work. He could accomplish much for the reformation of character, the maintenance of discipline and good feeling among the prisoners. Very respectfully yours, Rev. Robert F. Moran. NEBRASKA STATE PENITENTIARY Office of the Prison Physician November 30, 1912. To the Warden: P There is probably no public institution in any state that show a lower percentage of deaths, or a lower percentage of actual cases of sickness, than is found in the Nebraska Peni - tentiary at the present time. Most of the serious cases of sick - ness we have, are brought into the prison and not acquired after incarceration in the institution. While there are some changes that should be made, that would improve the sanitary conditions of the prison, they are changes that would necessitate larger appropriations than have been allowed for the prison in the past. That the old bath tubs might be dispensed with and replaced with a modern shower bath would be a change that would be beneficial in every particular and do away with an ever present source of infections. Every precaution is used to keep syphilitics, or inmates with other communicable diseases from using bath tubs other than those set aside for their use, but with the shower baths this source of infection would be entirely removed. Eie addition of a faucet and hot water in each cell would improvement that would greatly tend to improve the y condition of the prison and aid in the treatment of in - when sick, and it is to be hoped that the day will soon </seg>
            <seg id="p027">162 come when our state may equip our penitentiary with these modern necessities. There are other improvements that could be mentioned, that would help improve our sanitary conditions such as better sewer facilities, etc. FAs we are equipped at the present time, it is nearly marvelous we are able to report so low a rate of actual sickness. Syphi - rheumatism and indigestion are the prevailing ailments to be treated in our institution. Tuberculosis is seldom met with, and when a pronounced case is found, it is isolated as much as possible, or either a sick parole or pardon is advised. The use of opiates or dope in the prison is a problem that is ever present, and the most rigid rules are advised to endeavor to eliminate this terrible pest from the prison. Within the last year the use of this drug has been greatly reduced in this in - stitution, and continued efforts must be put forth to eliminate it to the greatest extent. A state law, more rigid than any now on the statutes, to regulate or prevent the sale of habit forming drugs would greatly aid in eliminating this trouble from the Penitentiary. I wish to commend the warden and the deputy warden for the general cleanly condition of the shops and cell houses; it would seem impossible that they could be kept in a better con - dition than at the present time. The quantity and quality of food given inmates is such that nothing better could be expected. It is important that good food in sufficient quantities be given daily to insure health and the best efforts on the parts of the prisoners. Our hospital facilities are sadly deficient, but with the present condition of health of the prison, we are able to get along fairly well. With a senior medical student as intern, the inmates are given the best of medical attention, and in many ways it is the best arrangement possible. Drs. Welch, Hedlund and Humphrey are to be commended for the efficient work they have given as interns of this institution. It has ever been my endeavor to do everything for the comfort and physical im - provement of all the inmates of the penitentiary. I wish to thank you, Mr. Warden, also Deputy Warden Antles, Mr. Burk and Steward Robb for the kind co-operation you have given me in all efforts to improve the sanitary con- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">163 dition of the prison and caring for the unfortunates contained therein. I herewith append the hospital report. Very respectfully, R. H. Spradljng, M. D., Prison Physician. HOSPITAL REPORT REPORT OF THE CHIEF ENGINEER Hon. S. M. Melick, Warden: RilR: I have the honor to present to you my report for the ium, 1911-1912, which has indeed been a busy one in my tment. Two out of our five boilers became useless and new ones were installed to take their place during the fall of 1911. A third one also went out of commission recently, and we are installing a new one in its place. Five new stokers have been installed with very satisfactory results. They cause the saving of much fuel as well as labor. I should dislike very much to go back to the old method of hand-firing. - Dispensary Days Calls for Lost by Medicines Sickness June July August .... September . October. November December 1080 172 999 127 1080 141 1320 180 1380 226 1050 204 1025 167 1310 132 1200 205 1912 Sfk ; : 1215 221 960 202 600 90 ..... 580 130 E August ... September 734 145 940 93 860 112 1015 216 1001 174 SSfc I 724 181 785 150 'reated in ospital Deaths Cause of Death 1 2 2 3 :! 5 4 4 5 1 Endocarditis 6 4 I 4 one stabbed I 1 Valvular Heart disease a a 4 5 4 1 Malignant Testicle 4 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">164 RJe have also put in a new header in the boiler room and a 15 ampere D. C. machine, used for an exiter, the armature I given out. Same was afterwards rewound and now in cases of emergency. Our motor being unsafe, old and subject to breakdowns, a new one was bought to take its place. The old motor has been thoroughly over hauled and repaired and reserved for emergency use. Two new wells were dug and two new boiler feed pumps installed. The water courses have been repaired and the boiler room has been completely overhauled and reconstructed. I would suggest that the boiler room be enlarged and a water purifier be installed, also that the pumps be removed from their present place to the level with the boilers. I would recommend the construction of a tool room and bins for the storage of about ten cars of coal. The electric wiring throughout the institution is in bad condition and a com - plete rewiring will soon be necessary. It would be well in the future to use galvanized pipe for underground service. It costs more but the life of it is much longer and will be the cheapest in the long run. I desire to thank Mr. Edward F. Schurig for many valuable suggestions, and I wish to thank you, Mr. Warden, for your hearty co-operation and wholesome advice in all matters per - taining to my department. I am, sir, Very respectfully, J. C. McCarthy, Chief Engineer. THE FEMALE DEPARTMENT EThe female department is located on the third floor of the inistration building. A spacious hall divides the depart - b into two wards, one for the white and one for the negro inmates. The rooms are large and airy, and resemble rooms in a dwelling more than prison quarters. Bars are nowhere in evidence, only a few on the outside of the windows. The beds are comfortable and clean, there are modern sanitary con - veniences throughout the department. The negro ward has at present seven inmates, while the white ward has but one, a little Indian maiden, in whose veins flows the pure blood of the Sioux tribe. Being the only inmate </seg>
            <seg id="p030">165 of this ward, she has for her exclusive use a suite of rooms, con - sisting of parlor, dining room, bed room and bath. I doubt if any other prisoner in the country is so well provided for. Taking care of their own rooms and wardrobes is about the only occupation of these eight girls. It would be much better for them if some kind of employment could be found for them. The behavior of the girls is splendid, they are all in good physical condition. Statistics of the Female Department Larceny from person 3 Larceny 1 Manslaughter 2 Stab to wound 1 Shoot to kill 1 8 Occupations Cook 1 Domestic 5 laundress 2 8 'resent, December 1, 1910 Leceived on commitments .9 ,3 'aroled and discharged .1 'aroled and not yet discharged .1 'ransferred to insane asylum 2 demanded for new trial .1 5 Present November 30, 1912. .. ; Races h Negro Indian ..7 .1 White 0 8 Crimes </seg>
            <seg id="p031">166 Total women received since the establishment of the prison in 1869 100 Discharged 73 Pardoned 4 Died 2 Suicide 1 Paroled and discharged 6 Paroled and not yet discharged .... 1 Commuted 2 Transferred to insane asylum 3 Robbery 3 Stab to wound 9 Stab to kill 1 Shoot to kill 2 On hand 8 100 Races of All Females Received White 45 Indian-. 1 Negro 54 100 Crimes of All Females Received Aid to rape 1 Abetting shoot to kill 1 Bigamy 2 Burglary 2 Grand larceny 26 Horse stealing 2 Larceny from person 29 Murder 9 Manslaughter 7 Procuring 2 Receiving stolen property 2 Rape 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">167 Occupations Cook 9 Dressmaker Demimonde 13 Housekeeper 55 Laundress 4 No occupations Nurse 3 Snake charmers 1 Teachers 1 100 Notes The first woman received was Kate McNamara, white, from Douglas County. Received December 28, 1871, to serve five years for manslaughter. She served her sentence. Efhe first suicide was Sarah J. Overton, sent from Custer ty to serve twenty-five years for murder. She cut her t in her cell on June 3\ 1888. The first pardon granted to a woman was to Mollie Wilson on January 11, 1871. She was sent from Douglas County to serve fifteen months for larceny. . The first negro woman received was Clara Thomas on August 6, 1885, from Douglas County, to serve one year for larceny. The first death in the female department occurred on August 2, 1901, when Effie Crackall, sent from Nuckolls County to serve twenty years for aiding to rape, died. The first parole was granted to a woman on August 4, 1904, to Vera Simeral, sent here from Douglas County to serve three years for larceny from person. The first commutation to a woman was granted on May 12, 1896, to Francis Martin, sent here from Madison County for three years for manslaughter. The first woman to be transferred to an insane asylum was Ida Terrell, sent from Douglas County to serve four years for robbery. She was transferred to Lincoln asylum on July 30, 190ti </seg>
            <seg id="p033">168 Notable Inmates Efe have had several of national reputation, among them Helen Johnson, alias "Morphine Annie." Annie was a charmer by "profession." Another was Burt Martin, sent from Keya Paha County for horse stealing. "Burt" was received in men's clothing and passed as a man for over eleven months, when she was found out and assigned to the female department. She did not remain there very long. She was commuted by Governor Savage. The most unruly prisoner ever received into the department was Bertha Armstrong, sent here from Lancaster County for larceny. Bertha has a national reputation as a pickpocket. She was transferred to Ingleside Insane Asylum at Hastings. FARM PRODUCTS 1911 1912 1,792 bu. potatoes $1,792.00 2,100 bu. potatoes $1,050.00 1,300 bu. corn 910.00 582 bu. onions 582.00 Pickles 25.00 523 bu. carrots 261.50 30 tons alfalfa 450.00 230 bu. turnips 57.50 150 lbs. butter 45.00 350 bu. beets 87.50 3,000 gallon milk 600.00 140 bu. peas 210.00 700 gallon cream. 700.00 272 bu. radishes . 544.00 253 bu. lettuce ... 506.00 600 bu. parsnips . . 120.00 75 bu. tomatoes. . . 37.50 32,097 heads cabbage 1,604.85 75 heads cauliflower 7.50 50 tons alfalfa 750.00 2,000 bu. corn 1,000.00 500 bu. sweet corn. 500.00 50 rons fodder 250.00 80 chickens, 60c. . 48.00 5,043 lbs. beef 453.87 Chickens killed. 160.00 20,228 lbs. pork 1,517.10 Cows killed 800.00 4,215 lbs. lard 631.75 2 geese 1.92 * 365 dozen eggs 109.50 1 duck .63 266 lbs. butter 79.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">169 8,833 lbs. hogs, at 10c 883.30 5,947 gallons milk . . 738.37 1,700 lbs. lard, at lie 187.00 257 head hogs 3,084.00 900 lbs. veal 108.00 Total, 1911 $6,602.85 400 chickens 200.00 60 ducks 30.00 Total, 1912 Total, 1911 $14,520.74 6,602.85 Total, biennium $21,123.59 Census of the Prison Number present December 1, 1910 426 Received on commitments 450 Returned from furlough 5 Returned from parole 11 Returned escaped 10 Received for safe keeping IS Recommitted 11 926 Discharged by expiration of sentence 294 Paroled 138 Commuted 9 Escaped 22 Pardoned 29 Remanded by court orders 12 Transferred to asylums 16 Executed 1 Died in hospital 3 Stabbed unto death by inmate 1 Killed while escaping 2 Furloughed 5 Safe keepers 13 Present November 30, 1912 381 Distribution of Races' and Sexes At the close of the biennium: White males 280 White females 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">170 Negro females 7 Indian males 6 Indian females 1 Asiatic males (1 Japanese and 1 Philippino) 2 NATIVITY C Foreign tria Foreign Born Born 3 American Born American Born Austria 3 Alabama 3 Alabama 3 Australia 1 Australia 1 Arkansas 7 Arkansas 7 Canada 10 Canada 10 California 2 California 2 Denmark 4 Denmark 4 Colorado 2 Colorado 2 England 3 England 3 Connecticut 1 Connecticut 1 France 1 France 1 District of Columbia 3 District of Columbia 3 Greece 3 Greece 3 Georgia 3 Georgia 3 Illinois 36 Germany 9 Germany 9 Illinois 36 Hayti 1 Hayti 1 Idaho 2 Idaho 2 Ireland 5 Ireland 5 Iowa 45 Iowa 45 Italy 4 Italy 4 Indiana 9 Indiana 9 Japan 1 Japan 1 Kansas 18 Kansas 18 Mexico 5 Mexico 5 Kentucky 9 Kentucky 9 Norway 2 Norway 2 Louisiana 4 Louisiana 4 Philippines 1 Philippines 1 Massachusetts 3 Massachusetts 3 Roumania 1 Roumania 1 Minnesota 6 Minnesota 6 Montana 1 Russia 2 Russia 2 Montana 1 Sweden 3 Sweden 3 Mississippi 3 Mississippi 3 End 2 Switzerland 2 Maine 2 Maine 2 1 Michigan 8 Michigan 8 Missouri 46 Missouri 46 62 62 Nebraska 77 Nebraska 77 New York 19 New York 19 New Mexico 1 New Mexico 1 New Jersey 2 New Jersey 2 Ohio 17 Ohio 17 Oregon 2 Oregon 2 Oklahoma 4 Oklahoma 4 Pennsylvania 13 Pennsylvania 13 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">171 South Carolina 1 Texas 6 Tennessee 2 Utah 1 Virginia I South Dakota 7 Wisconsin 11 Wyoming 2 Recapitulation Total foreign born 62 State of Nebraska 77 U. S., except Nebraska 311 388 Total 450 Number of Prisoners Received From Each County Adams i Antelope 2 Boyd I Box Butte 13 Brown 3 Buffalo 9 Burt 4 Butler 2 Cass 16 Cedar 2 Cherry 12 Cheyenne 9 Clay 1 Custer 2 Cuming 1 Dawson 5 Deuel 2 Dundy 1 Douglas 115 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">172 Dixon 2 Dodge 7 Dakota 3 Franklin 2 Furnas 4 Gage 8 Garden 1 Fillmore 4 Hall 21 Hamilton 6 Harlan 3 Holt 4 Howard 1 Jefferson 4 Keith 4 Kimball 2 Knox 4 Lancaster 36 Lincoln 5 Loup 1 Merrick 2 Madison . 3 Morrill 9 McPherson 1 Nance 2 Nemaha 5 Nuckolls 2 Otoe 12 Platte 1 Polk 1 Red Willow 4 Richardson 19 Sarpy 4 Stanton 1 Saunders 4 Scotts Bluff 3 Sheridan 7 Thayer 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">173 Washington Webster. . . i Wheeler Total The following counties had no prisoners in this institution at the close of the biennium: Boone Kearnev Banner McPherson Cedar Phelps Dundy Pawnee Greeley Perkins Howard Rock Hooker Seward Hitchcock Garfield Sherman Thomas The following counties never had any prisoners here: Blaine Logan Table showing number of prisoners received each year since the establishment of the prison: 1869 17 1869 17 1891 179 1891 179 1870 30 1870 30 1892 167 1892 167 1871 23 1871 23 1893 206 1893 206 1872 25 1872 25 1894 261 1894 261 1873 22 1873 22 1895 193 1895 193 1874 29 1874 29 1896 160 1896 160 1875 44 1875 44 1897 211 1897 211 1876 49 1876 49 1898 139 1898 139 1877 70 1899 142 1899 142 1877 70 1878 63 1878 63 1900 150 1900 150 1879 92 1879 92 1901 178 1901 178 1880 79 1880 79 1902 155 1902 155 1881 74 1881 74 1903 135 1903 135 1882 76 1882 76 1904 208 1904 208 1905 170 1905 170 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">174 1885 1885 137 137 1907 219 1907 219 1886 140 1886 140 1908 204 1908 204 1887 161 1887 161 1909 231 1909 231 1888 153 1888 153 1910 192 1910 192 1889 200 1889 200 1911 291 1911 291 1890 194 1890 194 1912 159 1912 159 Forward 1,856 Forward 1,856 Total 6,010 Total 6,010 Average number received, 136.26 Pleas Entered in Court Guilty 331 Not guilty 119 Total 450 Age of Prisoners on Entering Prison Seventeen 4 Eighteen to twenty 71 Twenty-one to twenty-five 130 Twenty-six to twenty-eight 61 Twenty-nine to thirty-one 49 Thirty-two to thirty-five 45 Thirty-six to forty 38 Forty-one to forty-five 28 Forty-six to fifty 11 Fifty-one to fifty-five ' 7 Fifty-six to sixty 2 Sixty-one to sixty-five 3 Sixty-nine 1 Total 450 Education of Prisoners High school education 8 Common school m 418 Read only ; 7 Illiterate 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">175 STATE PENITENTIARY Domestic Relations Married 112 Divorced 9 Single 329 Father living 212 Mother living 261 Father dead 238 Mother dead 189 450 450 Other relatives living 430 No relatives 20 Have children 98 No children 352 Habits of Inmates Before Coming to Prison Temperate 144 Intemperate 300 Intemperate and opium 1 Temperate and opium 4 Morphine 1 Church Affiliations of Inmates Adventist 1 Baptist 51 Catholic 91 Christian 29 Science 1 Congregational 3 Deist 1 Episcopalean 8 Methodist 87 Mormon 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 176 Lutheran 24 Presbyterian 29 United Brethren 4 Jewish 2 No religion 117 SENTENCES Straight Sentences Straight sentences: Less than one year 1 One year 76 One and one-half years 7 Two years 39 Two and one-half years 2 Three years 20 Four years 6 Five years 8 Six years . . . x. 8 Seven years 7 Eight years '. '. 4 Nine years ■ 2 Ten years 8 Twelve years 3 Thirteen years 2 Fifteen years 6 Eighteen years 1 Twenty years 3 Twenty-two years 2 Twenty-five years 1 Twenty-eight years 3 Life 15 T"\ ♦ V» "1 OOC Indeterminate Sentences Indeterminate sentences: One to one and one-half years 1 One to two years 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">177 gne to three years. . . ne to four years .... One to five years .... One to seven years . . . One to ten years One to twenty years Two to four years . . . Two to five years .... Two to six years .... Two to fifteen years Two to ten years .... Three to ten years . . . Three to fifteen years Four to seven years . Five to ten years ... 6 1 4 56 M 36 1 2 1 8 a l 12 1 1 1 Five to fifteen years Twenty to life 3 225 Total OCCUPATION OF PRISONERS Occupation of Prisoners Attorney 1 Barber I 16 Baker 9 Bookkeeper 6 Butcher 3 Bridge carpenter 1 Bell boy 2 Blacksmith 4 Broommaker 1 Carpenter 7 Cook 26 Cabinetmaker 1 Clerk, office 2 Clerk, hotel 7 Hardware 2 Cigarmaker 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">178 Chauffeur 1 Candymaker 9 Electrician ' 4 Engineer 7 Farmer 80 Florist 1 Fireman 4 Grain dealer 1 Glazier 1 Gymnast 2 Gardener 1 Houseworker 9 Harnessmaker 2 Hostler 1 Horse trainer 3 Interpreter 1 Insurance agent 1 Laborer 106 Laundryman 1 Lather 1 Laundress 1 Lather and plasterer 3 Lithographer .&gt; 1 Lineman 4 Moulder 1 Miner 6 Meat cutter 1 Machinist 9 Painter 18 Porter 1 Physician 1 Printer. 1 Poultryman 1 Pipe fitter 9. Steam fitter 4 Seaman 1 Stonemason 4 Shipping clerk 1 Telegraph operator 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">179 Tailor 5 Telephone work 1 Rancher 13 R. R. ticket agent 1 R. R. switchman 6 Undertaker 1 Upholsterer 1 Veterinary surgeon . 1 Waiter 14 Woodworker 2 Total 450 Crimes of Inmates Received During Biennium Abortion 1 Arson 5 Assault to rape 7 Assault to kill 6 Assault to injure 5 Assault to rob 8 Attempted burglary 1 Abetting forgery 1 Attempt to rape 2 Burglary 106 Burglary with explosives 6 Burglary and larceny 9 Bigamy 5 Blackmail 4 Cattle stealing 9 Chicken stealing 1 Child stealing 1 Carry concealed weapons 1 Carnal know female child 2 Dispose of mortgaged property 1 Embez element : 4 Forgery 55 Felonious assault 3 Give whiskey to Indians 2 Grand larceny 55 Horse stealing 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">180 Incest Larceny from person Larceny as bailee. . . Manslaughter Murder, 1st degree Murder, 2d degree. Mayhem False pretenses Obstructing R. R. track Rape Receiving stolen property Robbery Selling whiskey to Indians Statutory rape Stab to kill . Steal and carry away Shoot to kill Shoot to wound Wife desertion . Total Classification of Crimes Since the Establishment of the Prison in 1869 Abortion 1 Arson 59 Crimes against person 1,205 Adultery 2 Bigamy 13 Blackmail 7 Child stealing 8 Carry concealed weapons 1 Dispose of mortgaged property 1 Give whiskey to Indians 2 Gambling ' 4 Having burglar tools 11 Illegal voting 3 Larcenous crimes 4,649 Perjury 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">181 Selling whiskey to Indians 4 Wife desertion 8 Train wrecking 1 Prize fighting 1 Libel 1 Procuring a felony 1 Obstructing R. R. track 11 Total 6,010 Forward 1,317 Servitude First offenders 360 Second time in this prison 51 Third time in this prison 5 Colorado Penitentiary 4 Nebraska Reformatory, Kearney 6 Colorado Reformatory 2 California Penitentiary I Iowa Penitentiary 3 Iowa Reformatory I Illinois Penitentiary 1 Kansas Reformatory 1 Kansas Penitentiary 1 U. S. Penitentiary, Leavenworth 1 Minnesota Reformatory 1 Minnesota Penitentiary 1 Missouri Penitentiary 6 Oregon Reformatory 1 South Dakota Penitentiary 1 Wyoming State Penitentiary 1 Total 450 Assignments of Inmates at the Close of Biennium Engineer's department 18 Cell houses 22 Laundry, tailor and shoe shop 17 Blacksmith shop 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">182 Shop runners 6 Gatemen 2 Hospital 1 Green house 2 Policing yard 2 Stock yards 2 Farm 6 Painters and carpenters : 3 Teamsters and cartmen 4 Boiler, yard, coal and miscellaneous 15 Barn 2 Deputy's runner 1 Library and chapel 2 Female department 8 Warden's office 1 Warden's house 6 Store room 1 Guards quarters 2 Cooks, bakers, butchers 6 Waiters, Dishwashers 13 Scullions 1 111 and excused from work 7 Working for outsiders 1 Lee Broom and Duster Company 184 Handcraft Chair Company 41 a 1 OQ"| </seg>
            <seg id="p048">183 C UNTIES, CRIMES, SENTENCES, AGES AND OCCUPATIONS OF PRISONERS RECEIVED DURING THE BIENNIUM County Sentence Age Occupation Adams Adams Adams Laborer Laborer Farmer Ticket agent.op'r Cook Burglary and larceny Burglary and larceny Burglary and larceny Horse stealing Cook Machinist Electrician Laborer Antelope Antelope Boyd Larceny Bigamy Laborer Barber Boyd Boyd Boyd Boyd Murder, 1st degree Horse stealing Laborer Gas engineer Carpenter Forgery . Forgery Burglary Burglary Burglary Stealing Larceny Forgery . Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Box Butte. Brown. . . . 1 23 Barber Fanner Laborer Barber Cook 3 22 3 26 1 30 3 23 1 20 Interpreter Cook Attempted burglary Shoot to wound . . . 1 38 1 41 House painter Laborer Shoot to wound Larceny 1 29 1 to 7 22 Fireman Laborer Lineman Farmer Laborer Laborer Farmer Laborer Farmer Grand larceny Forgery 1 to 7 32 1 to 20 27 Forgery 1 to 20 32 Murder, 2d degree Horse stealing .... 25 25 1 19 Brown Brown Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Buffalo Horse stealing . . Attempted rape Horse stealing. Break and enter Burglary 1 to 10 21 12 27 a 36 1 21 Shoemaker Miner 1 to 7 23 1 to 10 38 Laundryman Printer False pretenses Burglary 1 to 10 18 Farmer Laborer Painter Break and enter Break and enter 1 to 10 28 1 to 10 32 Burt Forgery Farmer Burt ..:.... Rape Operator Farmer Fanner Baker Burt Murder, 1st degree Rape Burt Butler Grand larceny Laborer Laborer Laborer Farmer Farmer Farmer Butler Grand larceny Cass Murder, 1st degree Cass Murder, 1st degree Ca&amp;&amp; Forgery and uttering Forgery and uttering Cass Cass I Grand larceny Cass Robbery Stonemason Farmer Receiving stolen property. 5 Cass I Burglary 1 Baker Crime Larceny Mayhem Murder, 2d degree Bigamy 3 20 1} 24 22 24 6 30 1 to 10 20 1 to 10 20 1 to 7 25 1 to 10 23 2 27 7 26 Life 45 1 to 10 23 1 to 20 23 1 to 20 20 Burglary 1 to 5 19 li 5 Life 7 1 to 7 26 22 43 M 49 49 25 22 24 42 42 24 42 19 1 to 7 Life Life 5 5 5 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">184 Crime Sentence Age Occupation Caas Burglary 1 20 Laborer Laborer Farmer Fireman Gardener Lather Cm Burglary with explosives. 20 to Life 32 Manslaughter 2 31 Cub Burglary with explosives. . 20 to Life 25 Cass Murder, 1st degree Life 60 Cass Burglary with explosives. . . 20 to Life 49 Caw Burglary and larceny 1 to 10 21 Laborer Laborer Bigamy Cass 1 to 7 29 Cedar Murder Life 32 Housekeeper Farmer Cedar Horse stealing 1 22 Cherry Shoot to kill 1 22 Farmer Miner Cherry Burglary 1 21 Cherry Grand larceny 1 18 Telegrapher Laborer Cherry Horse stealing 3 23 Cherry Horse stealing \Jrand larceny 1 to 3 21 Rancher Painter Rancher Rancher Rancher Rancher Rancher Rancher Waiter Farmer Farmer Farmer Cherry 1 20 Cherry Murder, 2d degree Life 18 Cherry Murder, 2d degree Life 24 Cherry Murder, 2d degree Life 24 Cherry Murder, 2d degree Life 2* Cherry Burglary 1 to 10 22 Cherry Cattle stealing 1 to 10 28 Cheyenne Obstruct. R. R. track 1 to 20 16 Cheyenne Burglary Carnal knows female child 1 to 10 23 Cheyenne 10 36 Horse stealing Horse stealing Cheyenne 1 to 10 26 Cheyenne 1 to 10 30 Harness maker Laborer Cheyenne Burglary Horse stealing 1 to 10 22 Cheyenne 1 to 10 32 Laborer Laborer Farmer Laborer Farmer Cook Cheyenne Carnal knows female child 5 to 15 36 Cheyenne Forgery 1 to 20 17 Clay Horse stealing 3 30 Custer Forgery 1 21 Custer Receive stolen property 1 to 7 30 Cuming Forgery 1 to 20 42 Cook Cook Dawson Break and enter 1 28 Dawson Obt. money, false pretenses 2 24 Farmer Laborer Barber Dawson Grand larceny 1 to 7 25 Dawson Blackmail 1 to 3 24 Dawson Burglary and larceny 1 to 7 27 Carpenter Blacksmith Chaff euc Deuel Burglary 2 21 Deuel Burglary 2 19 Dundy Horse stealing 6 22 Laborer Laborer Barber Laborer Douglas Murder Life 27 Douglas Robbery Douglas Robbery 15 35 15 31 Douglas Break and enter 1 23 Steamfitter Porter Douglas Robbery 7 25 Douglas Robbery 7 33 Miner Porter Douglas Murder, 2d degree Forgery 12 19 Douglas 2 35 Bookkeeper Porter Douglas Manslaughter 10 25 Douglas Assault to kill 2 41 Fanner Laborer Laborer Baker Douglas Rape 20 38 Douglas Grand larceny 1 42 1 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">185 County Crime Sentence Age Occupation Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Douglas Grand larceny Break and enter Forgery 1 42 1 31 1 30 Laborer Hotel clerk Hotel clerk Cook Break and enter Break and enter Break and enter Break and enter Robbery 1 25 4 20 Laborer Laborer Laborer Teamster Switchman Laborer 4 23 2 30 8 25 Stab to wound . Break and enter Assault to murder Grand larceny tj 26 1 32 15 51 Laborer Cook 1| 23 Forgery 2 25 Laborer Grand larceny Assault to rob Assault to rob Assault to rob . Break and enter 1 23 Electrician Engineer Laborer 6 23 6 18 6 20 Bellboy Farmer Laborer Cook 4 24 3 48 3 26 18 • 28 Receive stolen property Murder, 2d degree Rape Teamster Laborer Engineer Fireman Laborer Waiter Assault to injure Manslaughter Robbery 2 28 I 30 15 27 Murder, 2d degree Stab to wound . 6 26 5 24 Break and enter Forgery 3 23 Barber Butcher 1 23 10 23 10 25 Break and enter Break and enter Forgery Carpenter Pipefitter Bookkeeper Hostler 5 32 Robbery Robbery Robbery 7 22 13 42 13 21 Waiter Waiter Shoot to kill 8 21 Paperhanger Tailor Break and enter Break and enter Assault to rob . . Assoult to rob Robbery 3 24 3 24 2 31 10 19 Cook Lineman Brushmaker Waiter 7 24 9 39 Robbery Forgery Waiter 2 26 Office clerk Candymaker Machinist Larceny from person Larceny from person Breaking and entering Grand larceny 1 to 7 24 1 to 7 27 7 21 Barber 1 to 7 23 1 to 10 22 1 to 7 26 1 to 20 23 2 to 15 47 1 to 10 28 1 to 10 51 1 to 7 17 1 to 7 23 1 to 10 22 1 to 7 27 Engineer Laborer Lineman Laborer Laborer Cook Break and enter Grand larceny Assault to kill Assault to rape Break and enter Break and enter Grand larceny . Grand larceny . Break and enter Bigamy Cook Laborer Steamfitter Baker Baker </seg>
            <seg id="p051">186 Crime Sentence Age Occupation Robbery 3 to 15 18 Clerk Douglas Larceny from person 1 to 7 22 Bartender Douglas . . . Manslaughter 1 to 10 61 Cabinet maker Douglas Assault to murder 2 to 15 49 Hotel clerk Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 30 Cook Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 21 Laborer Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 32 Teamster Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 25 Baker Douglas Manslaughter 1 to 10 33 . Farmer Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 25 Teamster Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 29 Teamster Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 25 Baker Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 28 Farmer Douglas Stab to wound 1 to 20 27 Laundress Douglas Forgery 1 to 20 24 Insurance agent Douglas Bigamy 1 to 7 26 Farmer Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 43 ! Laborer Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 19 Laborer Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 20 Teamster Douglas Forgery 1 to 20 38 Florist Douglas Forgery 29 Carpenter 1 to 20 Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 35 Laborer Douglas Break and enter 23 Farmer 1 to 10 Douglas Assault to rob 2 to 15 22 Butcher Douglas Forgery 1 to 20 22 Farmer Douglas Grand larceny 1 to 7 27 Baker Douglas Manslaughter 1 to 10 32 House work Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 27 Shoemaker Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 48 | Laborer Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 25 Laborer Douglas Forgery 1 to 20 28 Stone mason Douglas Break and enter 39 Laborer 1 to 10 Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 40 Farmer Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 27 Waiter Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 18 Laborer Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 18 Machinist Douglas Grand larceny 1 to 7 21 Tailor Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 19 Tailor Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 26 Baker Douglas Stab to wound 1 to 20 24 Cook Douglas Break and enter 1 to 10 19 Waiter Douglas Grand larceny 1 to 20 20 Actor Douglas Attempt to rape 2 to 15 23 Operator Douglas Break and enter 24 Horseman 1 to 10 Douglas Larceny from person 4 to 7 18 Cook Douglas Robbery 3 to 15 18 Teamster Dawes Horse stealing 1 40 Rancher Dawes Rape 7 I 3 22 Farmer Dawes Received stolen property 36 Porter Dawes Receiving stolen property. 36 Porter Dawes Horse stealing 1 to 7 1 to 4 26 Barber Dawes Horse stealing 23 Farmer Dawes Forgery 1 25 Cook Dawes Carry concealed weapons •&gt; 34 Porter Burglary 1 to 10 1 to 7 28 Horseshoer Reviving stolen property. 31 . Porter </seg>
            <seg id="p052">187 County Crime Sentence Age Occupation Burglary 1 to 10 31 1 to 7 I 18 Life 30 Farmer Farmer Farmer Painter Painter Dawes Horse stealing Dixon Murder Dixon Burglary 2 36 Dodge Murder, 2d degree 15 26 Dodge Larceny from person 1 to 7 27 Life 21 Domestic Laborer Gymnast Farmer Dodge Murder, 1st degree Dodge Murder, 2d degree 12 28 1 25 Dodge Burglary Dodge Larceny from person Clerk 1 to 7 1 to 7 42 Dodge Arson Carpenter Steam fitter Laborer Dakota Horse stealing 2 28 Dakota Burglary 1 to 10 40 1 to 10 28 Dakota Burglary Farmer Painter Farmer Miner Laborer Miner Franklin Attempt to rape 8 40 6 24 Franklin Statutory rape Furnas Break and enter 2 23 Furnas Break and enter 2 23 Furnas Break and enter 1 to 10 28 1 to 10 30 Furnas Break and enter Farmer Laborer Laborer Teamster Teamster M older Fillmore Grand larceny 1 20 Fillmore Grand larceny 1 19 Grand larceny Fillmore 1 to 7 19 1 to 7 33 Fillmore Grand larceny Gage Robbery I 43 Gage Forgery 2 20 Cook Cook Grand larceny Gage 1 24 Gage Burglary 1 24 Teamster Farmer Gage Forgery 1 to 20 30 1 to 7 27 1 to 20 22 Gage Grand larceny Laborer Engineer Plumber Barber Gage Forgery Gage Rape 20 30 Garden Burglary 4 26 Grant Burglary 1 to 10 30 Laborer Farmer Hall Grand larceny 2k 35 1 18 Hall Forgery Electrician Waiter Hall Grand larceny 1 26 Hall Forgery i at 1 19 Cook Hall Forgery Candymaker Painter Hall Burglary 1 to 10 23 1 to 10 46 1 to 10 23 Hall Burglary laborer Blacksmith Fireman Hall Burglary Hall Forgery 11 28 Hall Grand larceny Telephoneworker Teteph'ne worker Farmer Hall Grand larceny Hall Forgery Hall Horse stealing Painter Farmer Laborer Engineer Machinist Hall Robbery Hall Burglary and larceny Hall Forgery Hall Grand larceny ....... Machinist Machinist Carpenter Farmer Hall Hall Hall Grand larceny Burglary Forgery Assault to rape Assault to rape Bricklayer 1 to 7 1 to 7 1 to 20 1 to 10 3 to 15 1 to 10 1 to 20 1 to 7 1 to 7 1 to 10 1 to 20 2 to 15 2 to 15 33 33 28 23 20 30 33 19 19 19 38 31 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">188 County Crime Sentence Age Occupation Hamilton Horse stealing 9 88 Farmer Cook Hamilton Burglary 1 26 Hamilton Safeblowing with explosives 2* 44 Upholsterer Machinist Railroader Attorney Hamilton Safeblowing with explosives 28 •M Hamilton Safeblowing with explosives 28 M Hamilton Embezzlement I 55 Harlan Grand larceny Laborer Lineman Farmer Farmer Laborer 1 to 7 21 Harlan Grand larceny 1 to 7 22 Harlan Horse stealing 1 to 7 52 Holt Horse stealing 1 to 10 22 Hoh Assault 1 to 5 22 Holt I Larceny from person i 1 to 7 22 Blacksmith Laborer Holt Horse stealing 1 to 10 Jefferson Burglary 1 58 26 Laborer Bell boy Operator Operator Jefferson . . . . Forgery 1 Jefferson Abetting forgery 1 to 20 Jefferson Forgery 1 to 20 Keith Obstructing railroad track . 1 to 20 18 22 32 1 to 20 22 Woodworker Laborer Keith ! Manslaughter 1 to 10 Keith Horse stealing 1 to 10 Keith Rape 3 40 19 Laborer Laborer Farmer 25 Kimball Cow stealing 1 to 2 Kimball ... Grand larceny 1 to 7 26 IX Houseworker Laborer Knox Burglary 3 Knox Horse stealing 1 to 7 Knox Robbery 3 to 15 Knox Horse stealing 1 to 10 Lancaster . Arson 1 24 30 Cowboy Farmer Hackman Carpenter Physician Painter 19 88 38 Lancaster . Abortion 2 65 Lancaster Grand larceny 2 Lancaster Forgery 1 Lancaster . . . Grand larceny 1 31 22 Laborer 30 Carpenter Laborer Lancaster ... Blackmail Lancaster . Blackmail 1 24 1 37 Farmer Lancaster Blackmail Lancaster Forgery 1 18 Shoemaker Painter 1 34 Lancaster Assault to do bodily injur. j 22 Laborer Lancaster Grand larceny Lancaster Burglary 3 31 Housekeeper Laborer I 34 Lancaster . Burglary 1 19 Teamster Cook Lancaster . Burglary 1 23 Lancaster Burglary 1 Lancaster . . . Bigamy 1 19 Tailor j 30 Paperhanger Barber Lancaster . . Larceny Lancaster . . Burglary lto 7 34 1 to 10 45 Fanner Lather Lancaster . . . Burglary lto 10 34 Lancaster. . . Pickpocketing Lancaster . Forgery 1 to 7 22 Laundress Undertaker Laborer Lancaster . . Forgery 1 to 20 Lancaster . . . Larceny 1 to 7 Lancaster Larceny 1 to 7 Lancaster Burglary 1 to 10 33 45 22 Farmer Laborer Porter 1 to 10 38 Lancaster. . . Shoot to kill [ 1 to 20 i 29 Lancaster Wife desertion '.'.'. '. 1 22 Waiter Lancaster . . Forgery 1 to 20 37 30 Bookkeeper Farmer Lancaster . . . Horse stealing 1 Lancaster. . .1 Embezzlement | lto 7 34 Railroader </seg>
            <seg id="p054">County Crime Sentence Age Occupation _ p ___ Lancaster. . Lancaster. . Lancaster Lancaster. Lancaster. Lancaster Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln Lincoln Loup Merrick Merrick Madison Madison . Madison Mornll Morrill Morrill Morrill Morrill Morrill Morrill Morrill Morrill McPherson. . Nance Nance Nemaha Nemaha Nemaha Nemaha Nemaha Nuckolls Nuckolls Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Otoe Platte Polk Red Willow Red Willow Red Willow Richardson. Forgery . Murder . I Larceny ... Rape i Rape Shoot to kill Forgery Receiving stolen cattle .... Murder, 1st degree Burglary and grand larceny Burglary and grand larceny Forgery and uttering Burglary Horse stealing Horse stealing Burglary Grand larceny Manslaughter Steal and carry away Steal and carry away Grand larceny Burglary and larceny Horse stealing Horse stealing Cattle stealing Cattle stealing . i Cattle stealing Horse stealing Rape j Wife desertion . Forgery ' Forgery Burglary Burglary Rape Grand larceny Burglary Burglary Burglary Burglary Felonious assault Felonious assault Burglary Burglary Burglary Burglary . Burglary Wife abandonment Assault to kill Uttering forged check Grand larceny j . Arson | . Arson Felonious assault . Felonious assault Felonious assault 1 to 20 Life 1 to 7 10 5 1 to 20 1 to 20 4 Life 1 to 20 1 to 20 1 1 to 10 2 1 10 2 1 to 10 1 1 1 1 to 3 2 to 10 2 to 10 3 to 10 1 to 2 2 to 5 2 3 8 months 1 1 1 to 10 1 to 10 6 2 18 months 3 2 2 2 1 2 1 1 1 1 1 2 to 15 2 to 6 1 1 to 20 1 to I 2 to 4 1 to I 2 to 5 | 39 Switchman I 38 Barber 25 Domestic 34 Cowboy 22 Laborer 24 Houseworker 23 Tailor 30 Ranchman 27 Farmer 18 Laborer 18 Laborer , 41 Baker 23 Laborer 36 Laborer 25 Laborer 1 27 Cook 30 Laborer 26 Glazier 21 Laborer 18 Laborer 46 Cook 20 Farmer 39 Rancher 36 Cowboy 43 Stockman 28 Farmer 27 Farmer ; 29 Fanner 69 ■■ Vet. surgeon I 29 1 Barber 18 Farmer 20 Farmer 23 Farmer 24 Seaman 24 Interior decorat'r 20 Barber 23 Laborer 33 Farmer 25 Fanner I Painter tt Laborer 23 Butcher | 20 Farmer , 27 Laborer 32 Laborer ) 29 Laborer 20 Laborer 29 Laborer 25 Cook 30 Painter 22 Cook 39 Farmer 55 Laborer 21 Farmer 19 Laborer 19 Cigarmi.ker </seg>
            <seg id="p055">190 County Crime Sentence Age Occupation Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Richardson. Sarpy Rape 2 18 Laborer Burglary 2 24 Cook Assault to rape 10 34 Painter Burglary 2 28 Hotel work Grand larceny 1 24 Farmer Forgery i 1 to 20 32 Shipping clerk Cut to wound 1 to 20 17 Farmer Burglary 1 to 10 27 Laborer Horse stealing Horse stealing 1 to 10 27 Farmer 1 to 10 23 Machinist Robbery from person Embezzlement 1 to 7 22 Waiter 1 to 7 29 Bookkeeper Burglary Burglary 1 to 7 33 Painter 1 to 10 37 Bookkeeper Break and enter Break and enter Break and enter Break and enter Break and enter 1 to 10 30 Brakeman Bridge carpenter 1 to 10 20 1 to 10 22 Electrical appren 1 to 10 22 Elect'l apprent'e 1 to 10 27 Lithographer Larceny as bailiff Larceny as bailiff 1 to 7 39 Cleaner and pres. Break and enter 1 32 Horse trainer Sarpy Sarpy Sarpy Break and enter 1 42 Teamster Break and enter 1 29 Cook Forgery 1 to 20 29 Fireman Larceny 1 to 10 22 Farmer Stanton Saunders Saunders Saunders Saunders 1 to 10 22 Farmer Break and enter 2 Laborer 21 Break and enter 2 21 Laborer Burglary 1 21 Clerk 1 21 Clerk Rape 12 41 Chicken raiser Scott's Bluff. Scott's Bluff. Scott's Bluff. Sheridan Rape I 6 43 Hardware clerk Disposing mortgaged prop 1 to 2 27 Farmer Burglary 1 to 2 28 Clerk Murder, 2d degree 20 45 Laborer Sheridan Sheridan Sheridan Sheridan Sheridan Sheridan Thayer Thayer Thayer Thayer Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Thurston. Valley. Shoot to kill 2 41 Ranchman Selling liquor to Indians 2 19 Brakeman Burglary 1 to 10 20 Laborer Forgery 1 to 20 19 Farmer Forgery 1 to 20 Assault to ravish 2 to 15 Shoot to kill 18 month Forgery 27 Farmer 2 to 15 31 Farmer 18 months 23 Laborer Burglary and larceny 1 to 10 33 Laborer Burglary and larceny 1 to 10 33 Painter Forgery 1 to 20 40 Harness maker Giving whiskey to Indians 2 48 Farmer Assault to rape 2 18 Farmer Break and enter 1 24 Farmer Break and enter 1 20 Machinist Assault to do bodily inj. 1 to 5 33 Laborer Giving whiskey to Indians 2 32 Laborer Grand larceny | lto 7 44 Grand larceny 1 to 7 25 Grand larceny [ 1 to 7 27 Farmer Farmer 1 to 7 27 Laborer Receiving stolen property. 1 to 7 31 Farmer Maiming ; 1 to 20 I 24 Stone mason Manslaughter 1 to 10 23 Domestic Incert I 15 I 63 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">191 County Crime Sentence Age Occupation Washington Burglary Washington Burglary Washington Burglary 1 to 10 19 Pack'g house man 1 to 10 18 Laborer 1 to 10 19 Laborer 1 to 7 30 Fanner 1 to 3 36 i Farmer 1 to 10 39 Farmer 1 to 20 24 Cook Washington Horse stealing Webster . . . . Burglary Wheeler. . . Manslaughter York Forgery EMPLOYMENT OF THE INMATES F^he Lee Broom and Duster Company employ about 200 it the rate of 55 cents per day and 5 cents additional per per day for rent, heat, light and power. This firm paid us $113,209.88, as against $81,205.20 diurng the preceding biennium. The management of the broom factory has been most satisfactory to us and the inmates like the work and quickly adapt themselves to it. During the biennium this firm paid to the inmates about $12,000 for overtime work. The highest amount paid an inmate for overtime work was $32 and the lowest was 45 cents for one month's overtime. • The Platte Shirt Company withdrew from the prison in June, 1911. The manufacture of shirts was not a success, it took the men a long time to learn the work and it was a most unhealthy occupation on account of the dust from the blue cloth was constantly in the air. For these reasons we did not epose the shirt factory leaving, although their contract had other year to run. En June 12, the Handcraft Furniture Company began the acture of a high grade line of reed, rattan and fibre fur - . They have contracted to employ fifty men at the rate of 55 cents per day and 5 cents additional per man per day for light, heat, rent and power. This is indeed a model factory, cleanliness and the best of sanitary conditions prevail through - out. There being no other factory of its kind in the state it enters not into competition with outside labor. The most elegant line of chairs and settees are here manufactured and up - holstered in the finest fabrics and leather, some of these selling at $50 a piece. At the industrial show in the Auditorium at Lincoln the products of the chair factory received many com - pliments from the visitors for the beauty and elegance of the </seg>
            <seg id="p057">192 entire line. There is a bright future in store for our chair factory, and it will no doubt, before long develop into a large plant. The inmates learn here a trade that is most valuable, workers in reed, rattan and fibre furniture are scarce and in big demand and earn good wages. Of the remaining, 131 men are required to run the farm and the prison, and only two or three are excused from work. Population We have received 450 men on commitments during the biennium and discharged by expiration of sentence, pardons or paroles, etc., 495. The highest point was reached on December 22, 1911, a population of 471, and the lowest on October 24, 1912, with 370. There were 29 pardons granted, of which ten were sick pardons. Escapes r There were twenty-two during the b'ennium, twelve during predecessors part of the biennium and ten during mine. Of the first twelve, seven broke out of here and five were trusties, of the latter ten all were trusties or yardmen. Out of the twelve one was returned and out of my ten four were returned. I have located two escapes serving time in other prisons and have received two escaped during former administrations. There have been altogether 107 escapes since the establish - ments of the prison in 1869, of these fifty-four were returned and three were killed while escaping, one by drowning and two by shooting. The first escape was James Hogan, sent from Douglas County for seven years for manslaughter, who escaped April 17, 1871, and was never recaptured. One Charles Williams, alias Jacobson, holds the record for making escapes, he escaped twice and was recaptured and made his final escape in 1909, and is still at liberty. Mr. Williams was a third timer and was also wanted in four other places. Paroles The legislature, in its wisdom passed the indeterminate sentence law and the advisory board of pardons law. Both went into effect July 7, 1911. Under this system the judge shall not affix duration of the sentence, but the term of im- </seg>
            <seg id="p058">193 minimum term provided by law for the crime for which the Ewas convicted. This system, while new in our state, is of criminal jurisprudence in many states and has proven ss wherever adopted. RFhe parole system, the cardinal feature of the indeterminate nee law, is, however, not new, nor untried in this state, a e law being passed on April 10, 1893, providing for the parole of prisoners under the direction of the governor. The present board was created to relieve the governor of the enormous amount of work attached to the investigation of each applicant for parole. It consists of three splendid gentlemen, Hon. John 0. Yeiser of Omaha, Hon. Edward G. Maggi of Lincoln, and Hon. J. S. Butler of Superior. Hon. J. A. Piper of Lincoln acts as secretary to the board. These gentlemen take a deep interest in the inmates and have done much for their welfare. All applications for paroles are made in writing on blanks made for that purpose, in which the prisoner sets forth complete details of the crime, the causes leading to the crime, and the history of his life. The board then gives his case a thorough investigation and if the information received is satisfactory, he is called before the board and granted a parole. He is expected to have employment granted him by some responsible party to whom he shall report immediately upon his release. He shall on the first of each month, make a report to the board and to the warden, stating how much earned and how much expended, tmany days worked and how many days lost and why lost. books were read, what amusements indulged in and what ;h attended. EPhis report is signed by his employer, who also certifies he has remained away from pool halls and saloons. If a ner lives up to the terms of his parole for from six to twelve months he is usually recommended for a final discharge. The first parole ever granted in the state was to H. H. Knowland, sent from Douglas County for eight years for assault to kill. It was granted on December 23, 1893. Since then many paroles have been granted and but few have violated their paroles. We have at present eighty men out on parole and all are doing nicely. laws, and, judging from the reports and many letters received, </seg>
            <seg id="p059">LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 194 En pleased to state that the parole system is of immeasurable efit, not only to the men themselves in returning them to manhood, but to the state as well in safeguarding and protecting its citizens. Clothing The inmates all wear the cadet blue uniform during the winter and the dark blue cotton uniform during the summer months. We have on hand a few suits of stripes, to be worn in extreme cases of punishment, but they have never been used during my administration. Food One of the first and most important duties that required my attention was the food. I had the dining room and kitchen throroughly overhauled and all cooking vessels were given a thorough cleaning. Realizing that good food is a most im - portant factor in the health as well as in the discipline, I intro - duced a much better grade of food than ever served before. Not only was it served in much greater variety, but it was thoroughly seasoned, prepared and cooked. The inmates have shown their appreciation by their splendid behavior and their physical condition is much improved. Last, but not least, the good food has been a most important factor in aiding me in exterminating the use of "dope." I firmly believe that no prison in the country feeds their in - mates as well as we do, and that our inmates have better food than many people on the outside. I attach herewith a list of dishes served in as much variety as possible: Served for Dinners MEATS Eoast fresh pork, roast beef, meat pie, beef with brown New England boiled dinner, boiled pork and beans, stew, urger steak, beef roll, vegetable soup, bean soup, etc. Boiled, mashed and fried potatoes, pickled beets. Parsnips, tomatoes, onions, turnips, cabbage, cauliflower, melons, etc., in season. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">195 Served for Suppers Stewed prunes, stewed apricots, stewed peaches, stewed apples, rice, oatmeal, hominy, liver with gravy, fried bacon, meat stew. Corn bread, wheat bread, butter, syrup, tea, coffee. This improved menu, while more costly than the old one, is, nevertheless, the cheapest in the long run, it being a most important factor in keeping the men in good physical condition and diminishes the craving for stimulants, such as dope and morphine. Health rn his report, Doctor Spradling, the prison physician, states there are perhaps fewer deaths and less actual sickne this than in any other prison. Much credit is due the doctor for his good work that brought about above results. Several other factors have served to promote the good health of the in - stitution, such as good food thoroughly cooked and well prepared and seasoned, including plenty of fresh meat and vegetables from the farm. Cleanliness and sanitary conditions are factors well worthy of mention in this connection. Idleness, the socalled root of all evil, is unknown here, and keeping the men at work does much to influence good health. Likewise we must not for - get to mention the splendid music furnished twice a day by our band. I am pleased to call your attention to a comparison, seven months of my administration as compared with the same period tl911. There were only 6,639 calls for medicines, as against 14, and only 1,201 days lost by sickness, as against 1,349. The Dope Habit In his report for the last biennium, Hon. T. W. Smith says: " I am here to assert that any warden who fails to make a heroic effort to prevent the presence and use of dope in his institution, is a positive enemy of mankind." I agree most heartily with the former warden and consider the dope and morphine habit the most demoralizing of all prison features, causing endless grief and trouble, not only to the users of these drugs, but to the management as well, and we must be ever on the alert, or they will find their way in here. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">196 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT I have given much time and thought to this matter and have learned, that if the men are kept in good physical condition they require but few stimulants. Through the never tiring efforts on the part of Doctor Spradling, together with kind treatment, good food and good music, and plenty of work (but not over - work) the physical condition of the men is better than ever before, and I am happy to report that, with the exception of a small quantity that might occasionally find its way in here, the dope habit has been entirely eradicated and shall so remain as long as I am in charge. All kinds of methods were used in bringing dope into the prison. In one instance English walnuts were opened, the meat taken out and dope inserted in its place, and the nuts then care - fully glued together. In another instance a woman brought several sacks of tobacco from which the revenue stamps had been removed and the dope inserted and the stamps carefully replaced. I had the woman detained and turned over to the county court, where she was tried and sentenced to the county Discipline I consider discipline not a mere obedience of the rules, but rather a system of self improvement and self control that should apply to the guards and inmates alike. I have selected for guards men of high character who will set the inmates a good example, and to whom the men can look up to with respect. The guards must be humane, they must treat the inmates with kindness, yet with firmness. There must be no undue familiarity between guards and inmates. Under no circumstances is a guard allowed to ill treat or to curse a prisoner. I investigate each complaint, and see that the inmates get a square deal through - out. There being always two sides to each story, I listen to both. Sometimes the guard is in error and sometimes the in - mate, but usually the matter is adjusted without resorting to punishment. By using the corrective rather than the punitive system, splendid results have been obtained, the men, knowing that they are getting a square deal, have shown their appreciation by their splendid behavior, and I doubt there exists a better behaved lot of prisoners anywhere. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">STATE PENITENTIARY 197 Punishments Officers and guards are not permitted to punish an inmate. All punishments come under my own supervision. A man is punished by taking away from him his privileges, such as privileges to receive visitors, to receive tobacco and chewing gum, and to write letters. A more severe punishment is to place an offender in a solitary cell, commonly known as "the hole." This is now very seldom resorted to, and the most severe method of punish - ment, that of wearing stripes, has never once been inflicted during my tenure of office. Educational and Religious Features k During the winter months school is held two nights each k under the direction of the chaplain, assisted by six of the educated inmates. The library has received a thorough overhauling, the books have been classified and listed and a new catalog issued. Many periodicals and magazines have been donated by outside friends. These have been distributed and received by inmates with much pleasure. The inmates are great readers and many of them subscribe for the daily and weekly papers published in Lincoln, in addition to which the mails bring about 150 metropolitan and country papers and periodicals every day. It is the custom in several prisons, not to permit the reading of newspapers and periodicals, they being excluded as carefully as opium and morphine, but I have never been in sympathy with this system, on the other hand, I consider the newspapers of immeasurable value, not only to the inmates themselves, but as great factors in the education and discipline of the institution, and I shall continue to encourage L unrestricted entrance of the newspapers into the Nebraska e Penitentiary. rThe chapel service takes place at 10:00 A. M., every Sunday, lasts for one hour, consisting of reading of the "scriptures, prayers, and a sermon by the chaplain, the Reverend Doctor N. T. Harmon. Chaplain Harmon has proven himself to be a most faithful and devoted chaplain and the inmates appreciate him immensely and look to him for guidance and help. To them </seg>
            <seg id="p063">198 E Sunday school is held at the close of services each Sunday lasts for one hour, and is under the supervision of the chap - assisted by seven teachers from the City of Lincoln, and is ided by nearly two hundred inmates. The Catholic service is in charge of the Reverend Father Robert L. Moran. For years this good man has served as Catholic chaplain to Jhis institution and never received a penny for his services. His good work is of immeasurable value to the nearly ninety members of his creed who are confined here. Entertainments Many singers and lecturers and speakers have been pro - vided for by the chaplain to the great delight of the inmates. On holidays a foot ball game is played and a vaudeville show is staged. The inmates attend the show in the afternoon, while another performance is open to the public in the evening. The Band When I came here the prison had a band of seven pieces, equipped with old delapidated instruments. This I caused to be reorganized and it now consists of twenty-two pieces equipped with up-to-date instruments and clad in white uniforms during the summer and cadet blue uniforms with dark braid during the winter. It is the owner of much good sheet music. During the state fair week, when thirteen thousand visitors from all over the state visited the prison, the band attracted much attention and many favorable compliments were passed, also small coins to the amount of $325 were dropped into the entribution box, from which fund were purchased much sheet usic and the new instruments. PThe band plays at practice every afternoon in the east cell ding and every evening during supper, during chapel services Sunday mornings and for holiday entertainments. I am pleased to state that music is now one of the most predominating ttures of this prison and I believe, that nothing can be more leficial in its influence. Flowers, Lawns, The Greenhouse The influence of flowers and green lawns is also most salutary. They tend to relieve the monotony and to inspire nobler and DtrLLci LnOUjcnio. UUi grtrtrllllULlStr, LilUU^u ScUJiy 111 IltrfrU Ul </seg>
            <seg id="p064">199 repair, is well worthy of mention. Once upon the inside an immense Lantana vine, ever loaded with bloom, attracts the attention of all who enter. Here are the winter quarters of the large Hybiscus and the beautiful Oleanders that grace and beautify our lawns in the summer time. Also nursery for many geraniums, poppies, asters and numerous other flowers, and a large aquarium for goldfishes. Segregation of the Inmates She importance of segregation of the prisoners cannot be mphasized. Is it not unwise to place young men, who in lent of intoxication or foolish waywardness, have com - their first crime, together with men who for years have life of crime? Would it not be more economical to the state in the long run to place these young men in separate quar - ters, where each individual could receive special treatment or attention, according to his particular weak points, where he could be taught something useful and where he could be pre - pared to become a good and law abiding citizen? Would it not be more humane to send these young men out into the world again without the stigma of "ex-convict" attached to their names? Much as I would like to segregate these young men, I am nevertheless unable to do so, the facilities of this prison being entirely inadequate as they are now. Many states have separate prisons, for the first offenders, these are called reformatories, and there is a crying need in our state for such an institution. If, for financial reasons, or otherwise, it would be impossible to erect such a prison, I beg to submit for your consideration plans for a substitute, that would be practical for many years to come. EWe have at present two cell buildings, known as the east the west cell buildings, both of which, with the exception of of hot water in the cells, are modern. The west cell building has 234 cells and the east cell building has sixty cells. During the present administration we have aimed as much as possible to keep the first offenders and the unfortunates in the east cell building, and assign them to work on the farm, in the yard and in the chair factory, but the good results obtained from this separation have been largely overcome by their mingling in the (lining room. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">200 The dining room is located in the basement of the chapel. It is forty-five feet wide by eighty feet long and entirely too small for our present population. We need a large and modern room, it should be at least one hundred feet long by fifty feet wide, be equipped with modern furniture and have a seating capacity of not less than five hundred. It should be a two story building, the upper story serving for hospital purposes. Our present hospital facilities being most inadequate. In the new dining room we should feed the men quartered in the west cell building, while the young inmates and the first offenders, quartered in the east building, should eat in the present dining room, which would need a thorough overhauling and modern furniture and equipment. It would also be necessary to install another tier of cells in the east cell building, on top of the tier already there. Legislative Recommendations E would respectfully suggest and recommend that the legis - appropriate, in addition to the regular appropriations, needed for the following: For the purchase of a tract of land close to the prison, on which to work some of the first offenders and train them in truck growing and horticulture. Several tracts are for sale, one tract of 300 acres being especially desirable. PFor the building of a two story building within the walls, as lined on preceding pages, for dining room and hospital urposes. The dining room should be equipped with modern furniture and the hospital with baths and sanitary conveniences, and a modern and well equipped operating room. For a tier of steel cells for the east cell building. FFor installation of a water purifier in the boiler room. Also lavatories and toilets in the solitary cells. It is a shame to without these. For installing of a modern kitchen and laundry in the female department. The inmates of this department, outside of doing some mending, taking embroidery lessons, and keeping their quarters clean, are idle most of the time. They could do the cooking for the warden's house as well as for themselves. There </seg>
            <seg id="p066">201 ments. This method would save much time and money, besides keeping these women employed. For electric cook stoves in the inmates' as well as in the guards' kitchen. I For an iron fence with which to surround the entire frontage the prison, also a steel gate for protection of the main entrance. For a cabinet of files for photographs, a photographing and a finger print outfit. This is needed and of great importance. P^or better equipment for the outgoing inmate. Under the nt law he is paid but five dollars, is given but a cheap suit, a hat worth a dollar and a quarter and a two dollar pair of shoes. The last legislature, in its wisdom passed a law, by which the outgoing inmate was to receive ten dollars in money, a ticket to where he was sent from, or its equivalent, and clothes. Through some oversight, appropriations with which to carry out this, were overlooked. I would respectfully suggest that this law be passed and appropriations made accordingly. I would sug - gest that sufficient funds be appropriated to add to the above an overcoat during the winter months, and to purchase a better grade of suits, hats and shoes, that the outgoing inmate may look like a man and not like the typical discharged . inmate of a penal institution. I would suggest that a law be enacted, admitting to parole lifetime prisoners who have served ten years. We have at present fifty-one life termers, many of whom are deserving of a parole. This would be a great help in upholding the discipline. El deem it most wise if a law could be enacted, making it a ly for bringing into a prison dope or morphine. Also severe ishment by law for those who act as mail carriers for the in - es. It would be well to have laws making it severe to ate a parole. Clothes for the Paroled Prisoners There are no provisions for clothes for prisoners going out on parole. I would ask that appropriations be made for that purpose, that we may not be compelled to send them out into </seg>
            <seg id="p067">202 A FEW WORDS FOR THE INMATES I shall not close my report without a few words to the in - mates. Over the portals of a great prison in the east is this in - scription: "All ye who enter here, leave hope behind." To our inmates I would rather say: "Have hope, be happy and look forward to better days to come." I thank you, one and all, for your splendid behavior, for the little trouble you have caused, and for your loyalty and con - fidence. CONCLUSION Looking over the past nine months in retrospect, I must say they have kept me ever busy. To me the work has been most interesting, many difficult problems have presented themselves and have been solved to the best of my ability. ' While good have been obtained, yet there is room for many improve - nts. To those good people who have aided me with worthy suggestions, and to those who have befriended and brought cheer to the inmates, I beg to extend my heartfelt thanks. To those who criticize, I wish to say: "I have managed this in - stitution by open and above board methods, the largest as well as the smallest transaction can be explained, not one penny has been received or expended, but what can be accounted for. The books are open, come, see for yourselves." ETo his Excellency, Governor Aldrich, who, in the midst of many important duties, has given the prison much of his uable time, I wish especially to express my thanks and ap - ciation for his guidance and backing in my difficult task. Palso wish to thank Adjutant General Phelps for his co - tion in restoring order in this institution. And you, Gentlemen, Members of the Board of Public Lands and Buildings, for your courtesy and kindness, I thank you most heartily. I am, Yours most respectfully, S. M. Melick, Warden. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>