<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00002.00020">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00002.00020</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
	           <bibl>
	              <title>APPENDIX:  EXTRACTS FROM REPORTS OF COUNTY SUPERINTENDENTS, REPORTS OF PRINCIPALS AND SUPERINTENDENTS OF GRADED SCHOOLS, REPORT OF THE STATE TEACHERS' ASSOCIATION, COURSE OF STUDY FOR THE COUNTRY SCHOOLS OF NEBRASKA</title>
	              <date value="1891">1891</date>
	           </bibl>
	        </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-29</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>
		       <change>
		          <date>2007-05-18</date>
		          <respStmt>
		             <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
		          </respStmt>
		          <item>Enrichment</item>
		       </change>
	        <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>

         <p>
            <seg id="p002">
APPENDIX. 




\ 

PRINCIPALS AND SUPERINTENDENTS 
&lt;&gt;K GRADED SCHOOLS. 

I'HK STATE TEACHERS' ASSOCIATION. 

DY FOR THE COUNTRY SCHOOLS OF 
NEBRASKA. 

1 </seg>


            <seg id="p004">
I i:&lt;)M REPORTS OF COUNTY SUP ERIN- 

IKNDENTS. 




lt&lt; &gt;.M KKI'( )KTS OF COUNTY SUPERINTEN 
DENTS. 

ANTELOPE COUNTY. 

learn Antelo|&gt;e county ranks with the foremoet in 

I cai 

due largely to work done by S. A. Boyd, ex-super- 

vl 

I 

eacbera arc alive to the necessity of doing good work 
ur annual institutes. 

Mill) 

at our institute this year surpassed any previous 
enrolled was 152. 

mlaii 

1 Ml I 

oiintrv do not seem as well attended as they 
to tlie failure of crops in the county. The 

rowded to their utmost and are doing good work, 
epression that extends over this western country is 

i 

public -chools. When parents are asked why 

i 

¦ir children to school, the reply invariably is, " We 
nd clothing for them." 

1:2 districts in the county, all frame school houses but 
-i nil are supplied with patent seat and other necessary 

ipted N\ fish's Classification Register, and the 
fey can to make it a success. Thev onlv diffi- 

witli i^. no uniformity of books. 

W. II. Block, Superintendent. 

boon?: cor xt y. 

\V. have -ixiv-( 

lit districts in this county, with an equal number 

hool buildin 

The general condition of the buildings is good, 
ave a tew of the old pioneer sod houses. As a rule </seg>


            <seg id="p005">
tough we still h 



our houses are j^&lt;hx1, substantial 

our houses are Mil)st«intial 

the county. We have at Albion 

the countv. We have at Albion 

which ma not lea than $25,000. 

which was not leas than S25.OOO. 

building, value $12,000. Peter 

building, value 112,000. Peter 

frame buildincrs tint are t en i 
_ ... 

frame building tint ire i ered 

[i very fine brick building, the 
( !edar Rapids also has a I'm 

u very fine brick l&gt;uil&lt;lin^. tl 
&lt; iilar RapkLi also iia- ¦ ! 

liiii^, only two years old, i 

burg, only t wo years old, 

with a $6,000 frame. The school officers, a- a rule, are wv 

energetic men, who look well to the interests o( the sch 

teachers ot Boooe countv are a progressive ela»., unwilling 

¦eeond place among the teachers of Nebraska. Tin Tea li&lt; r 

ation ceased to exist in ilii- l-ou 

al 

Institute last fall we resurrected 

111' 

dition. In connection uiili the Association we liavi formed a 1 

Circle which meets monthly. Oi 

attended and deep inteiv-t manifested. We look forward t 

majority of the schools ¦ n visited 

i 

give the districts " val 

ir we shall hav&lt; 

i 

r.u&lt; i\\ \ ( •» 

crease in number of scl 

ent alHint -ixtv-t'oiir school Ikmi 

dilapidated buildings. With but few 

frame buildings, and are hand- 

appurtenances 

The school officers have been verv pr 

¦choola, and to them mucti credit is du 

the public schools of Brown countv 

My first work, on assuming the duties ol supervision, was 

out of the teaching fraternity of 1 1 * i — countv all such teac </seg>

            <seg id="p006">
4 


peroas and profitable year in our cunibined ' i A—. 

bave l)eoii impremed \\ 

The growth of educal 

Pl- luiilt within the lar-t year ; some I 
izeil districts, while others have U 

1 lie school officers have been verv \&lt; 
•n- that I have Beeu lit to make 


rEXDENT OF' JM'BLn INSTRrCTION. 

5 


nt of teaching the children of our public schools. 
ii first-class teachers from abroad, and the result 

)('&lt; 'lilt 

1 

1 1&lt; &gt;&lt; »1~. have l&gt;een under the care of a corps 
teachers. 

king our teachers more proficient in their 
i &lt; Diintv Teachers' Association, which meets 

these meetings the teachers are manifesting 
iltIi them great and lasting good has already 

lociatioo, we liave organized, for the benefit of 

\ 

\ 

it\ Reading Circle, in which nearly all teachers of 

an active part. The State Reading Circle 

i 

lv followed, which is giving to the teachers a 
tin principles of education. All this work on 

,\ 

r- is i ml ispensahle to a healthy and active growth 

id 

: for it is only through the elevation of the teachin 
be raised to the ideal staudard. 

ir the gradation and classification of our schools 

v 

ted, and now the schools are following a definite 

'I 

U 

•li's Classification Record is being used to a 
he -chools of the county. While some districts 

ng up tlie work of gradation and classification, 
•-operation of the teachers, the system is fairly 

to visit each school once a term as far as 
have been instrumental in perfecting this 

uurked increase in the number of schools, 
t' pupils, and the length of terms taught, 

itifying, and is evidence of a healthy growth of 
li..\\ ii county. 

J. M. Mil. lei:, Superintendent. 

idcil into sixty-seven school districts, has sixty- 
:ind has a school population of 4,179. </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
1 

IV 

ll' &gt; 1 1 — t 

hi 

BURT COUNTY. 


Of the school houses, all arc good frame buildings 

xcep 

wliioh are brick. Notablv the town ol Oakland i- a bo 

lit COl! 

a eommodioua school building to cost $10,000, to be heated with 

and bavins all modern conveniences. These buildings ar 

ill in 

repair and the tendency is to make improvements. 
School officers are, almost without exception, ptii natal 

ng, L-ai 

men, seemingly doing the very lx-st possible with the nu 

mis :i 

disposal. Popular interest in education. ] think, keeps | 

i 

material improvement of the county, a 

,vii liv increa 

ance au&lt;l the many yoong nun and women wii 

higher institutions of learning 

best they can, hence a genuine professional spirit exists araoiijj 

as a rule, and as a consequence the Reading &lt; 'irele w 

with zest. 

About one-third of all 

live teachers arc enrolled as i 

11 

Kaded course of -tud\ ami grad 
ntrv districts vet. I lu« 

state course and Welch's &lt; 

i 

t ults arc already apparent. I &gt; ; 
1 much benefit is derived tl. 

equally well attended, and 

h 

The work of the ( 'ounU 

S 

visitation of schools, which 

nean- a 

and to schools in char: 

would be less laborious ami more efl 

official more real power as to grad 
tion, etc., and less advigory power. 

The independent district system ha- -¦ 
mend it, but it certain lv stands in the w 

provenients in district schools, by render 

siole snort duration. h. I ¦. ATKINso.n </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
6 


There seem* to be a disposition on the pi 

truly supervise and to make jrood i 
the statute clothes the Btiiteriutew 


(ASS COUNTY. 

v-i iirht districts ;ind one liuiulre&lt;l ami six 

'lie. fourteen l&gt;rick, and ninety wood. 

M 

.veil furnished, six only are in very had 
replaced. Two districts have no school 

id school ten months thirty-four had nine 

or eight months, and three had less than six 
had DO school. 

the county is exceptionally good. There are 

in- men and one hundred and six women. These 
people of * good character and education, and are 
ay i" prepare themselves especially tor their work. 

in teaching on first jjrade and life certificates. 
,, (rood, several country boards hire for nine months and 

nv-tivc to fitly -five dollan per month. In this way many 
T8 are kept ill the country schools who in other places 

Ri general interest in schools all over the county, 
willingness t" support them liberally. The teachers are willing 
ertake anything that will &lt;jfi ve them letter preparation for their


7 




nerally disregarded us is rappooed. 

if towns. 

\ 

nine \\&lt;il graded schools. Plattomouth and Weeping 

j'-i Bod are a credit to the county. Second prc- 

II the exhibit lent by the Weeping Water schools: 
ition, which is proof of the quality of work done. 
- well attended and hard work was done by all. 

ill new to the teacben of the county, bat 

rork. The Institute work was appreciated, nader 

1j applied. [ see tlii&gt; in ntarlv every school 

¦ 'hi- county miwt be examined, whether they bring 
counties or not. Tramp teacben generally fail 

n, but good teachers do not hesitate to come. 

tiii- oi districts all between the ages of eigfat and 
nd school three months or more, sho wine that the com-  </seg>

            <seg id="p009">
1 Ik 1 iveauing V'lrciG lias t\VGntv~lour nifiuiMT^ ami w i 
manv more. Mucli interest is taken in it. 


&lt; KDAR COUNTS 

Tiif advent uf railroads into &lt; filar county has wrought 
development in our public school*. In 1 * i&gt;&lt; ) there were i 
thirty-three organized school districts. To-day we find e 
tricts with an average enumeration of thirty-five pupils. 
population at present is about twice that of. 1885. A- tli 
increased the county became more wealthy, accounting 
for the wonderful changes that have been made in the m 
Looking at the school boose a- an index to the oommun 
that our people are refined ami like education. Nearly a 

.vc nxi.-rl 

in tin 
&gt;ixtv-- 

riie 

popula 

itlsfa 

&lt;h 

t 

The state course of study lias been adopted and an 

will be put forth to so grade the schools as t" bring each pupil w 

in 

the course. After January 1, 1891, teachers will be reqi 

make monthly reports to the Superintendent of the progress and 

ing of the school. T. Cecil Grimbb, SuperiiUtuden 


8 



&lt;;. W. Noble, 8*pt 

tricts have comfortable house!, well heated and ventilated an&lt; 

plied with furniture of the most approved kinds. Tbt 

districts in the coiiniv without Hchool houses, and 
are preparing to build before the close of the rear. 
Our school board-, as i rale, are energetic and iute 

»&gt; far a.-? finucd \% ill permit, the nec&lt; 
, dictionaries, and in man v cases tb&lt; 

pupils. I think at least two-thirdsol our pplio 

In charge of our schools are manv pi 

B spare no means to make their work successful. Wt then 
vlio ]&gt;ersi&gt;;t in teaching when they ought, bv all justi 

school for several years. A reading circle will !"¦ organized in 

weeks and an etlbrt made to so conduct tin work a- !&lt;¦ reach an 

efit even- public scliool teacher. </seg>


            <seg id="p010">
&lt; OLFAX COUNTY. 

to sixty school district.*, having sixty-three 

I 

general they are in good condition. Many are enid 
shaded t&gt;v ornamental trees. 

I 

1 officers are efficient in their work. As a rule 
rest in school matters, and take pride in advanc- 

u the schools of the county. 

of thr county are earnest and |&gt;ersevering. As to 
iid ability they rank with those of any other county. 

i 

I 

n I interest of our teachers is manifested in our Teachers' 
. We are organised into a County Teachers' Association, 
every three months, and two subordinate Teachers' Assocli 
im-et every month. These meetings are increasing in 
ui'l are becoming valuable in increasing the teacher's effi- 

in 

-\ 

it 

Ah 

Our I {.-ad 

iiil; &lt; irele h \et in its infancy. Thirty-five of our teachilled, 
and wt hope to liave the circle under a better foot¦ar 
future than it is at present. 

W 

¦rrv to state that the getral public does not show as much 
le education &lt;&gt;t tlieir children as we wish to see. They are 

tinir taxes to keep up the schools, but there is a 

hildren regular to get the full l&gt;enetit of the 

ndition ol the schools in this county is letter than it 
I'hev are progreanng right along, both financially 

In my visits, of which I make two to each disir, 
I find that most of the scliools are well supplied 

ipparatus, such as maps, charts, glol&gt;e, dictionaries, etc. I 
to tlie teachers' work, and keep a record of the teachers' 

W 

ntrodnoed State Superintendent Lane's course of study, 
used in everv school in the country districts. This course 

A 

p to our ungraded schools. To aid us in this course we use 
ssification Register ami reporting blanks. This system of 

I 

Velch'a C'la 

i great factor in helping to orgauize and classify the 

pportn 

9 


mil ability to irovern and instruct.</seg> 

            <seg id="p011">
10 

REPOKT OK THE 

Our County Teachers Institute becomes more interesting 

even 

The last one held was conducted on the graded system, :: 

;ui(l w 

eeacfa]. The attendance was large, ami the interest and 

enthi 

manitiested was marvelous. Our instructors were educat 

1 ii 

did their work well. L. C. SPANGLER, Superin 

CUMING COUNTY 

There are, in Cuniiugcotintv, seventy school districts, w 

s&lt; - l»i« d houses, five new houses have been I m i It during 

Those of the towns are elegant structures, built in an 

the latest improved plans, and adapted 

.van 

Manv of the country school Ihwm- are w&lt; II built and a 

It i~ to be regretted thai there ¦ 


is toward improved 

i&gt; toward improvement. 
The school officers, as a rale, 

He. tal- 

aad give their hearty support t. 

and give their hearty support to an\ mea- li tends 

improvement of our schools. I 

improvement of our schools. II 

the |&gt;;iit of a few, in making 

lx.*en caused 1&gt;\ changes in our a 

Bw is thoroughly under 
have Rome permanent 

:chei 

tion for their work. The 

The teachers throughout tli 

iiintv 

interest in the work of education, a- 

our Institutes and Association meetinijs. \ u&lt; 

¦teacben who have had a nornia 
ave recommended the use of tin 

i 

the direction ot State Superintendent Larn 

crs are now guided by this course, and 

ot the work done 

The interest in our County Institutes ha 

the last Institute enrolled the largest i 

ever assembled in the county. Tin 

available m-trn 

employed, and much was done to improve methods ol teaching 

addition to the two weeks' Institute, our &lt; 'ounty Teachers' Associa </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
i years, and ia doing much to improve the teachers, 


¦ui» systematic um 

Dumber of cur teachers are now taking the work of the 

ding &lt; 'ircle, and it i- expected that more will become inter- 

ral 

1). C. Emi.ey, Smpermtemdmtt. 

(TSTEB COUNTY 

i- in this county. Of tliis number 210 are 

houses, fifty-three of which are frame buildings 
\ good per &lt; ent of the s&lt;k! buildings are in fair 

y-seven districts are supplied witll apparatus. One 
ty-eighl teachers did the work of teaching last year, 

.42 per month. 

umber "i school officers are efficient men, and fully 
lie dutii s demanded, but as a ueueral rule then 1 is a 

OoU nil [he part of officers, and more so on the 
he public interest in education is good, but the 
¦&lt;!•¦&lt; I by unavoidable circumstances. LargeneM ol 
ion, and want of a more complete orgaav 

work, are some of the hindrances to 

his county. As an evidence of the zeal 

id thai 13U districts have voted upon thetn\ 
"i twenty-five mills which is the limit of 

1 teachers is full remuneration, and 

uster county. The teachers are per- 

i ( 

manifest quite a good interest. The annual Institute 

Ii contii (1 two weeks, with an average attendance 

t 150 teachers, and an increasing interest. 

•asm 

lli&gt; Association work this fall lias been good in the southern portions 

B county. The size of the county has made it necessary to adopt 
an "t organizing each quarter for Association work. This has </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
11 


relea will toon l&gt;e organized in addition 

work 



I 

work on a sure basis throughout the entire county in the mar t 
A strong sentiment exists in favor of public education, and 


progress is being made every year. The prejudice against &lt;_ r ra 

n 

almost out of the way, and a vigorous effort is being made in tlii 

rection. To accomplish the needed reform in this respect, w 

combined lecturing with the work of visiting, and feel &lt;|iiiti 

by another annual Institute the work of classifying :m 

ii'ly intrusted to the major part ol nur teachers, and would 

The educational affairs of Dal 

ficiencv of our teachers and their mini- 

very encouraging and healthy condition. Th 

¦t's course of studv tor the pu 
have thirty-seven school Ik &gt;u- 

dition of which is in good repair. M 

floating over their roofs. These hav 

board of directors or by the exertions o 
( )ur school officers are generally men 

ficientlv interested in school work to mat 

to -ay. there are some whose narrow-mind 

them for their positions. 

We have an organized Teachers' Associa 

by-laws, the design of which is to promote the intei 

to bring the teachers into closer fellowship with each other and t 

sist young teachers. These Association meetings are held every 

Saturday of each month. The general public lake considers 

terest in the teachers' work, as is evidenced by the numerous vi 

at each meeting and by the hospitality and cordiality shown the t( 


ers whenever thev meet.</seg> 

            <seg id="p014">
12 



\&gt;e welcomed in the majority of ou 

\V. W. Hendrickson, .s'uij 

DAKOTA ( •&lt; H\Vn 

aiming at the uniformity of work throu 
tmduction of Welch's Classification Kt*« 



tutting torth its l&gt;est etiorts to keep the 

&gt;y lectarei at the regular meetings and 
i schools, hence a marked progress is 

year, and I can proudly state that to-day 

mpare with the schools of other eoun- 

( irole i- l&gt;eing organized, ami judging from 

. -uon enabled to present a list oftWOloDonble 
board of tlie circle, 
very successful County Institute of two 

idicr- manifested sneli attention to, 

I.. Kki..\( h, Superintendent. 

DA WES COUNTY. 

ill one school districts now organized in 

¦ t' which have School houses, besides one 
of $15,000. 

..I these achoolhoUKS. They are all in good reliave 
l&gt;'iii built more than five yean. 

f school otlieers might be improved upon, 
he best tbey can, and nearly all are deeply 

Some of our teachers hold state 

ity Teachers' Association and a Reading 

- operated in connection with the State Reading 

ic interest in educational affairs is such that 
founded in some of our towns. 

Superintendent has increased until it requires all 
lo tip duties of the office, there being now one 

i 

riei- in the county. 

tuditioD of the schools id good, and there is a good 

iilv all the districts, and rapid progress i.s shown by </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
i.la! 


presented, that tbey wire repeatedly mmpli 

Etnding of the teachers n at least twenty 



the fact that the pupils of our schools are now developing int 


Under our present state laws it i's next to impossible to 
uniform course of study in any county, and we have none her 

idoi 

Ere has bwn a Teachers' Institute held in this ooanty a 
¦ five consecutive years last past, and the same i« ahv 
ed. R. H. Blakchard, NuperinU 

:l&lt;'!i V 

iv» w 

/ 

DAW SON COUNTY 

Pson ooanty contains a 
chool buildings, eighty 
rec bride. The frame 
the majority "f them 

fventy-five school districts 
•three "t which are frame 
ind brick school liiiiidin^ 
beinir new and well t'nriii: 

and a better understanding of their d 

lie in general, in educational matters, 

\i! 

n 

entire time of the County Superintendent 

ing schools and office work. 

There was an attendance of one hundred 

last Institute, and jrood results have come li 

ceived there. While our educational standard i- not a- higl 

t 

sire it to 1h% our prn^res.- is in the right direction, and i- a 

encouragement to all who are interested in tin 1 great &lt;au-&lt; 

14 


\\ \ i''\v" vi''i % / ' / / 1 1 

rame school buildings were built during ili&lt; la-i \. 

iy in xt year to report no Bod school buildings in 1' 
School officers are efficient, and prompt in most matte 
:o their schools, although the details oi routine bus 

K&gt;rtin^ statistics, etc, seem distasteful to son* . 

The gra'l&lt;' of the teachers has b 

tCBchera of Dawson county are entering their 


M I-KKIM KNDK.NT OK PUBLIC INSTRUCTION. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
15 

lMMMiK COUNTY. 

Ira- Beveuty-eight school districts, and eighty-six 
( )nc hundred wad twenty-three teachers are required 
The majority of the school houses are in good repair, 

&gt;. 

The school buildings of Fremont are 

lU'tlt &lt;1 

crv finest in the west. Two new buildings were erected last 
i school and a ward building, at a cost of about $35,000. 

i 

iow has -ix lai'tit- two Mary brick buildings, and one frame. 
Hooper, Dodge, and North Bend, all have excellent brick 

-. a- ¦ rule, do not t;ike sutHcient interest in school 
wever, they are not obstructionists, and the teachers 

schools to suit themselves. 

en, a- ¦ dam, are tar superior to those of a few years ago, 
tins i- being made to improve them as teachers. During 

tin ( ountv Association was organised and divided 
&gt;n.-. to meet iii different parts of the county. The tir-t 
t on the first Saturday: second section to meet on the 

relay, and n on in their respective places. These sections 
lif State Reading Circle work, and half of the time of each 

to be devoted to it. These five sections meet quarterly in 
eaehers' meeting. The attendance is very good. At the 

\la 

ninety teachers enrolled. 

real is being aroused by the adoption of a course of study 
ea for the graduation of pupils from the country schools. 

nation- are to be held in each township for the pupils 

¦ graduate. This creates rivalry amoug the scholars, 
era! public ifl becoming interested in the matter. After 

lation the graduating exercises are to be held at some 

\ 


nt. 

made about one hundred visits since January. The work 
vi&gt;its has been, mainly, to classify the work and get 

£ 

.1- fitted to the course of study as nearly as possible. The 
midition of the schools is very good under the present cir- 

•eneral 

es. However, they should l&gt;e better, and there is a very perhange 
going on under the present gradation system. Coaaidvreaa 
was made last year, but no records were left to show how </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
uiii-taiict 
¦eptibteel 

iblepr 



111 11C I) Or ilOVV 1 1 1 1 1 1* »\ ILS ilOliC* 1 III.** V (*Jir »Tt.'K"Il^* i il^.^I ll&lt; "t 1 1' *I1 I vt M ' 1st* 
km l&gt;een intradnoed, and a complete record will now be kept ofeac 
school's work. State Superintendent Lane's course of study is used. N 
attempt has been made before to grade the schools : therefore there 
no lack of raw material in the way of teachers and pupil-. Howevi 
it is very good, and do one questions the practicability of the mot 

w 

planned. 

The County Institute was held at the Fremont Normal Scl 
ing the first part of July, 1890, and the u-ual amount of int» 
taken in the work. One hundred and thirty-five teachers \ 
rolled. A coarse of study for the [nstitute will be introdu&lt; 

We have in our county fifty 

are fractional. The old Bchool housi 

three new houses, and at the present 

of erection. 

The supply ol the State Cours 

Lane being exhausted, the County Sup 

selected from among the teacher-, prep 

county, which is now being introdui 

lu mv next report I will be able to 

teets upon the school 

The school officers have never taki 

than they take now. This i- &gt;e&lt; n in 

services of such teachers. They furnish 

vide plenty of blackboards, chalk, era-, re, etc. 11 

further shown bv the fact that nearly all 

i\ i 

course of .study and provided the necessary mat 

Generally speaking, our teachers are competent and pr 

but like all other counties we have a few who ai 

teach at the expense of those upon whom </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
16 


rear. 1&gt;. V. Si iin i 

IX)UULAS D M'Vn 

are beinjj rapidly replaced by Dew 

Intent teachers, and their willingues 


1 

NTKSDENT OF I'lBI.IC INSTRIXTIOX. 

17 

u 

ichools &gt;inij)l\ - us a fulfillment of the law, hut 

in session, whenever ami wher- 

¦(•nook ar 

liu teacher and the school. Tins we regard as mure 

luties 

•av witli considerable pride that 

,\ m 

• rind furnishing the mom with good furniiii 
of texl books: have a course of study : 

moving upward; and, last bat not least, 

I tin- past year from 24,64i! to "29,829, 

A. Matthews, Superintendent 

KRAXKLIN COl'NTY. 

aklin county -ixty-scven school hon-cs, ncarlv all 
lini:-. and well furnished with blackboards, |«it- 


B- iii I outhouses arc, as a rule, ke|&gt;t in excellent 
fen needing paint, blinds, or whitewash. 

ml- :it&lt;- lifinu fenced, and an eflbrt made to rulti- 

niore interest in school matters than tor- 

• in- to In a more general interest felt in education. 

I the districts either furnish the booka or bay direct 
houses, and sell ti&gt; the children at cost price. 
» i "f district school libraries, and all the graded 

liools ii:i\ c libraries. 

ii . ii' tr\'ing to raise their grades, and studying 

liariitT- meetings are li.ld the seewnd Saturday in each moiitli in 

xith part i»f ilic county, and the las! Saturday in each month in 
the north pan. The a Hernia we is fair and the work and interest taken 

liy those in attendance excellent. 

The schools Iwve had Superinteodent Lane's graded course of study 

¦ three rears, and i: I. a- been &lt;&gt;l great vain" in systematizing tli&gt;- 
¦ if tlic schools ami a guide t&gt;&gt; inexperienced teachers. 

We have i fbui vears' normal institute course, and the instruction </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
I* 


I 

r 

11 

I 

I 

I 

¦ ¦ 

E schools. Kight teachers graduated this jew, ami twenty-ei 
paring to enter the class of 1891. 

Etiire of our Institutes which is nut to be overlooked, i~ 
t the leading teachers of the county, who hare bad jrean 
training and experience in teaching, were t&lt;&gt; be seen «v 
as visitors, but a&gt; &lt;tiiilent.~, the busiest &lt;&gt;i the busy. 

I try to visit every school oaee each term, especially it tliey hi 
an iiiexperienced teacher. The two great drawbacks to the advan 
nient of our schools are changing teachers too often and the wanl 
pens, ink. pencils, paper, and books. 

KROXTIEK mlNn 

The rapid development of the school* of il 
ilv shown by ¦ comparison of a few of the it 
perintendent'a report lor 18H1 and the retwrt t 

N'uinlxr of school district- in 1**4 
Number of ~&lt;-h&lt; «&gt;1 districts in 1890 
Numlier of mhool bouses in 1884.. 
Number of -chool houses in 1890.. 
Cost ot schools iii 1884 

( in of schools in 18&lt;J0. 

The great majority of the peopl&lt; 

eaargetk 1 in whatever they undertake. They are awi 

ll/e the |xi\\ 

public schooU in the formation of character, and their inrtn. 
• uir s&lt;K'ial &lt;-ondition, and the 'development of our natural re-mi 
This being the inisc it is not strange thai our school* keep pace 
the growth of the county in population and wealth. Our teatare 
generally active and progressive, and we think compare favors 
with those of older portions of the state. The general characb 
instruction is much superior to that ol a lew years ago. They ta 
lively interest in Institutes, a&gt; is shown by the fact that of about </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
18 


If. S. I&gt;K ( 'LEROQ, Sin,, i 

portaiK* of educating their children; ili&lt;-\ 


I 

nintv. ninetv-two were enrolled iu the an- 

\ 

lerallv efficient and willing to aid in iru- 

( 

¦liuols, but 1 presume no superintendent i- &gt;&lt;&gt; 
We tn say that in hifl corps of officers there 

x 

uialili 

M 

Kioi buildings are at' s&lt;&gt;d, but neat and substantial 

I 

pidlv taking the places of these primitive struct 

t "the old s&lt;k1 house" allow me to sav that no 

Iftl'll 

lint; ix more comfortable or safe when the l&gt;li/.zard 

l» 

ten months I have made ninety-one visits, and in 

:l 

leavored by suggestions to teachers and actual 

i 

t teachers in improving their methods of teaching, 

i 

Nine with pupils have tried to impress them with 

i 

inning habits of honesty, energy, and thorougline*-. 

t 

Geo. I). ChaDDERDOH, Superintendent. 

&gt; 

GAGE COUNTY. 

i nd ret I and fifty-one school houses in Gatje county, 
buildings are in good repair. Our school officers 

t 

in school affairs. Our teachers are anxious to 
&gt;iit many of them lack thorough preparation. It 

ble effort to secure a burn attendance at teachers" 

Phen i- an increasing interest in the county in edura- 

i 

l 

Tin work of the State Reading Circle is being done 

t teachers in the eountv. \V T e had an enrollment 

h 

i 

In- i and eighty-one at our Institute this summer. The 
itnte i- lining more than anything else to improve our 

tv Institi 

( )nr scl 1- are licttir tlian thev were last vear 

M. P. [Tpsoir, Superintendent 


19 


1890. We cannot &gt;|&gt;eak with the »amt: degree of 
endance at meeting* of the ( 'oiinty Teachers' A--- 
aalaries are low they avoid all |&gt;os8ible expen- 

"I building i- mure runirortuble or sate \vh 
tin- steady cnlil ot winter has settle&lt;l down. </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
HOLT COUNTY 

Holt county comprises an area nearly one-fourth 

state "f Delaware. 
Daring the past year 2il(t schooU have been in ies*ion. 
Several districts suffered materially from the migratory &lt; 

their inhabitants, but better crop* and better farmers give a 

their inhabitants, Inn 

ier» iriv 

a water financial and 

greater financial and educatia 
More than 200 school building reasonable 

Mure than 200 soliool building reasoiiah 

i n;i n \ of tlicin contain iinprove&lt;l 

many of them contain improved furnitu 
The new hi^li school building in S 

The ii&lt; - w lii^li sell 

-» 

rivaling in architectural cfl O'N 

prooouuoed a model in all ka apjHjiiitiin m-. 
Our school officers, a- a class, 

tercnt in |&gt;n l&gt;li&lt;- education, and app&lt; 
Tlie personnel ol tin teachers ut" I! 

The personnel ol tin teachers ui II 

comparison with sister counties. \ 

\ 

move "in touch' with the times, ami 

move " in tuiirli w 

-i'liial advanei imn 

-i'lintl advauo meat. 
At our late normal i he quality m 

At our late normal i lie uua 

-|&gt;irit with skill and iiietliix]. 1 1 1 -i • 

i 

stitute proved a period '&gt;i -nnli"ii- 

proved a period 

ainl effective work. The average att 

and effective work. Th 

«-i 

reaching nearly one hundred per &lt; &gt; m 
Welch's system of ulasmticatiou In 

reaching nearly one hundred pi 
Welch's system ot ulawificatiou h 

every country school. Examination report)' . 

every country school, b^xaniiuation 

Bntendent twice each term. 
state course of study i&gt; w 

Superinteodeat twice each term. 
The state course &lt;il study is well i uiuerti 

More time should be devoted to orthography, 

More time &gt;lioultl be devotetl to orthourrapl 

-cliools are turning out j&gt;u&lt;ir speller». I in County Su| 

-cliools are turning out j&gt;u&lt;ir spellers. fhe ' 'outit^ Supei 

aims to pewo— Jly inspect and visit all the schools. In 

aims to penoaaJlj inspect and vi&gt;it all the schools. In gen 

condition of education is upward, and uur schools an pen 

in iicrni' 

-pirit of fidelity ami earaeatness. 

-pirit of fidelity ami earnestoe 

II. W. Dudley, 


20 </seg>


            <seg id="p022">
21 

'KM OF PUBLIC 1N8TBUCTIOX. 

HOWARD COUNTY. 

sixty-seven school dialiiota and sixty-eight 
buildings are usually in &lt;joo&lt;i repair, many ot 

"(I school house lm.a l&gt;eeu replaced by a 
ue nearly all furnished with patent swtt-. 

nt school officers, whose willingness to eoidenl 
greatly ;iiil in advancing tlie cause ,,t 

&gt; 

,uv iniioctic ;iim1 wide awake, and most of 

enables them t&lt;&gt; do good work from the start- 
I are ever readv to avail themselves of even 

lem In their work. They take great interest in 

&gt;ii» and Institutes. At our last Institute ween 
aeherw, with an avenge attendance ot eighty - 

\ 

scher take- some leading e&lt;luoational paper, and manv 
&lt;^iiin a number have works on teaching, aad there 

&lt; » 1 1 to rise iu the profession. 
i Countv [leading Circle, and some fifty teach 

take up the course of reading presented 

on ..t tin schools, I am glad to say, i&gt; iniproviin 
to the general interest in education, efficiency 
uiierintendent. 

I!. I). I! aw, \iu), SuperimtemdemL 

KKARXEY Col' NT V 

inntv sixty-seven school houses. Some ot 

iquate to the requirementa of the school, most of them 
ulition, and a few arc a credit to the districts iu which 

ire bu 


in sxicxl condition and makiac </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
o 

II-. :in(i ntlicr list-till apparatus. 

Dtnparatively new, I think we can compan 
antv in the state. 


jrood progress towards a high standard. 1 lie general int&lt; 

efficiency of achool officers in school :ift'airs is in nianv case- 

of commendation; with others efficiency may Ik? increased l&gt;v exp 

HMe and interest obtained bv the teachers' atforts to l&gt;rini_ r t * &gt; tl 

the work done in the schools. The increasinc demand 

leacbera gives evidence of more general interest in our public nclioo 
Our eleventh annual Teachers' Institute \\;i- a ~uici— and 

Bir the interest and i ntbnmuun manifested. Nearly all 
ended and winit oui into our schools fe&lt; liii" l&gt;etter pn 

I 

work and a greater responsibility in it, also the need 

(•iiinal training. Our County Teachers' Assoriat 
months ami is well attended, 
n pleased to note instances where the who 
rs one &lt;lav in :i term to visit our best schools am 
improvement has beeu derived, tolly as much ;i- ; 
t a teachers meeting. I hope to —•¦ the '!;iv w 

in two months and i- well attetxl 

I am pleased to note instances win 

n 

teachers one dav in :\ term to visit our best schools and 

I 

will \h~ allowed by our -clmol laws term 

the schools recommended by the County 8u|*erinten 

il Si \i 

LANCASTER « &lt; H Nl 

Number of districts 

XuiiiIht ot school !ious&lt; 

Of this number eight are brie 

lllil itUi 

one frame. 

Numl&gt;er of children of school 

:i' r 

Males 

Females 

Total 

Bge number in each district 
les : 

Females t.i 

Total 

22 </seg>


            <seg id="p024">
23 

\ 

N 

N 

IF 1MHI.K IN8TRUCTI05. 

taught clunug the 

twia — 

68 

207 


teacbera — 

\ 

\ 

9601 

2907(1 


lava i&gt;v each — 



m&lt; 1 village schools 10 

t- having six niontli&gt;" school or more 127 

listricta having tour months' school or more, 

in -;\ 2 

haviug three months' school, but less 

1 

f days school in all districts 158 

listricts thai had no school 1 

blackboard to each school, iu square 

2.58 

with do blackboard 0 

houses well furnished with patent desks 


ises built within vear 9 

having mm apparatus, as globes, 

N 

125 

ihool I see $302942 

value of school sites 189104 

value of school apparatus, etc 11127 

value of all school prowrtv 503173 

kmounl paid and due as teachers' wages 96038 

Amiium paid tor buUdingi and repairs 54698 

coat of the schools, including teachers' wages and expeoditarea 
of all kinds, aud whether paid or not 167727 

/ 


Number of districts purchasing text book 

Number of teachers attending annual [nstitute, represent 
120 school districts 

f S 

Average attendance of Association.. 

Aniiiunt of bonds issued during the ye 
Total amount of bonded indebtedness.. 

Amount of bonded debt canceled duriny t lie vear 

Average tax levied in each disti 

Hlment ti&gt;r jrear 
Dales 

Total 

Average attendai 

The 9chool 1 1 • 

condition. The btlili 

and in some cases with slight modii 

made daring the past year 

) 

K roved with little expense. 
tine trees on Arbor dav 

be the means of beautifying many groun 

In general, the public sentiment is in favor of good teachei 

E Pat rons of our progressive scho&lt; 
irage the teacher in his or her wori 
co-operation in grading and ad vain 
was this co-G^ration in some of th 
itted to attend the twenty-fourth S« 

.rk. s 

fficers 

ancement 

\\ 

tin district- that teacl 

Stat' 1 eaeh&lt; 

\ </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
24 



Number "f public lecturer- under the direction 
intendent 

Number of meeting &gt;&gt;t Teachers' Comit\ A — &lt; &gt;• in 

Amount of floating indebtedn&lt; 

convenience, and comfort, sp 

tinn, and heat. Departmenl plai 

¦ and followed my suggestion 
lat (be) be supplied in time 
etnled. A few of the school 

tendency to observe this day is increaa </seg>


            <seg id="p026">
me. However, there are a few school boards 
:•! believe that "any one is able to teach little 

.-«¦ :m uncle, M aunt, or a COOMB to till the 
average wages. In other respects they pur- 

&lt; hool maps or charts at the credit of the tlis- 

of ¦ supply of readers, reference books, 
a -li^ht outlay, would greatly facilitate the 

pupils. Yet I am pleased to note that many 

with these appliance 

he enrollment and attendance during the 

in increase in the length of terms. The average 

1 find great interest among the teachers to improve and 

thods, ami to kindly accept suggestions ami criti- 

it i&lt;&gt;ii baa ltd me to conclude that better school work 

\ 

ploying teachers for the school year, anil that 
etrimental to schools. There are some teachers 
do ii"t use our best methods. In my opinion 

hi- an- due to the lack of arousing interest and 
pupils. For I believe that he who is not tilled with 

reate interest, and should be politely requested 

profession narrow enough for his ambition. 
- who an not creating a sentiment in the district 

v. The sooner the " weeding out " of these 

Believing that system in our school work 

cceae as In the great railroads or telegraphic 
lie teachers and district officers together, and 

irlv one hundred districts tor the adoption 
ly a- the &lt;j;iiide tor our work in this county. 
suggestions contained in the State Course 

Manual of Institute Work are incentives to do 

hi inspiration to many a teacher to take a course 

raining ami to pupils to enter our State University. 

State &lt; 'ourse of Study can ami will be used in any county where 

l&gt;v superintendents and teachers are progressive, 
s course a grade meeting was called September 27th 

the present year. I toe hundred and ten districts were represented </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
arly thirty-two weeks, or ei^lit months. 

( burse of Studv, l&gt;ut are muting ibr it to be 


bv their teachers. The Course of Study was divided in ti 

corresponding to eiglit grades, fur each &lt;&gt;l whksfa 1 have furnisl 

grade cards of different colon with the studies of the gradi 

on each. These are intended as yearly reports, made monthlv 

parents of each pupil, and are promotion card 

The following is the one used in t lie* fifth grade and » 

Fourth Ueader lust p;ui 
Writing No. I copy Umk- . 
language and Elementary &lt; 
Spelling 

Eiptu- Practio) I .. 
phy Advam-ed 
&lt;s in written work 
e in studies 

Kunk in class 

Kof pupils in class 
eral lessons 

Deportment 

No. of days in attendance 
Times tardy 

Hours lost by tardiness 

I Head other side. 

/ 

26 



PI 

MISl'KNT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION. 

27 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
To PARENTS. 

i solicited in order to secure the best results in the 
this report carefully, noting the studies which are 

rttrt— n», rank, deportment, etc., and give such enconrr 
iilvice to the teacher, as will promote the children'* 

iianse. in grading, your children are placed in lower 
"h nticemtnt. Ask yonr teacher for information on 
requested to sign this report each month and retnrn 
the close of the school year. Pnpils must under- 

¦de lielore they will he entitled to next grade card. 

EXPLANATION. 

a. irk— !Hi. excellent— HO, good— 7(1. fair— 60, poor. Should a 

&gt;1 lno it must not l&gt;e inferred that he is perfect in the 
It simply indicates that excellent work has l&gt;een done in 

SiaHATUM of Parent. 

kstions to Teachers. 

&gt;e-t work when in their proper grade and there is pro- 

I 

el vim in this work, I have prepared a yearly report hy 
;is-&lt;- ami rou rses suggested in State Superintendent Lane's 

v 

¦ ml for each claa, and the studies, etc. , are printed thereon. 
iTiiini laidully said course of study and the " Institute Mannwire 
definite system of instruction may be established in our 

\ 

t 

I &gt;n nut ad 

line pupil- too rapidly. Cause them to become familiar with 
t&gt;v permitting them to read it. Encourage oral and written 
at the enil ol each month. Keep a daily record of the pupils 
tins and the reviews make their monthly standing. Give 

I Study 

tions, and in&gt;m 

Mention to wititB, accuracy, and rapidity in written work. 

Frank I). McCl.rsKY. I'ouHlg Superintend™*. </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
To assist teachers aiul encourage papik, seven to eight 
said course of study are sent each school during the year. 
lowing ia a copy of Third Review : 


I'll 

¦ldibg ami Lahsuaoe. — 1. Have each pupil read a 
¦J. Select :i paragraph for pupil- to oopy. •"». Proi 
(or pupil- lo -peli. 4. Select a picture and have pi 

I 

Ndmbebs. — 1. How many 2'* in 1'i'.' How many 4's? II 

2. What part of 16 is 2? U4! I- s .' :;. II, ,w 

naiiv 

are ."} half-dimes? 4, A dealer &gt;"ld picture frames at $ 

I 


2^ and 23 of Institute Manual 


28 



PKIMAKY COUE8E. 
Filial Grade. (( 'ln&lt;s 1 

rweiv^l 815. How manv thun&lt;- &lt;li&lt;l he -ill.' 5. 4x4 

1 h -=- 3 = -.' U 5 

Spelling. — 1. Teacher select ami pronounce ten ¦ 

tour statements suti^ottsl l&gt;v it. 5. I se mu or wen in each ol 

following blanks: (a) The lieu ou the box. (6) Th&lt; 

in the not. (c) Tin- pigs In the pen. i&lt;/) The rat hi 

\\ KiTiNi.. — Teacher write a maxim &lt;&gt;j -lanza on black I 

pupils t&lt;&gt; copy. 
Nimbkks. — 1. -1 inp- and ¦', tops and 1 top an top* 

. (t-nt- each I '¦•¦in buy curds for ti cents, -i li M 

plums and cats ball oi them and gives "in- to Ella she •¦• 

plums left. 4. Mow many 2's in 6? How many 3 - 

part of 6? :! H wliat part ..I 6? 

Speluho. — Have pupils spell by sound and I 
-tuili«*il (lunno the month. Teacher may add to 

ami 46 of Institute Manual for Primary (leading. 

Sbcono ( in \ i&gt;f.. &lt; 'law 2. 

Reading and Lanocage. — 1. Have each i 

grapli. '2. Sel( ii a -hurt ]• — . m i for pupils U 
pupil pronounce and copy ten words taught iuii: 
Select a picture from the reader ami have pupils writ- 
Mggwted by it. 5. \\ rite five sentences in which ha 
rectly. ti. Write five sentences in which have i~ uned correctlv. 
W HiTixt;. — I. Write a stanza or maxim. Write the 

letters five times: /, &lt;l, /,, &lt;/. Note : duriug the 1 1 ¦ ¦ \ t month pra 

writing h, h, /, b,/,j, a, :. </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
I'PERINTEXDENT OF PUBLIC IN8THUCTIOK. 2'* 

NTEKMED1 A T E C&lt; ) IT KS K. 

rd Grade. (( 'la?..- 1.) 

Have pupil-, copy a stanza, iming 

). Have pupils write live sentences alxmt 
4. Select ten words for pupils to write 
Select for pupils ten worth of two ¦yila- 

nbles anil mark tin- accent. 

\\ rite the following numbers in words ami hV- 

John'tf father gave him three dimes ami 

How uiany cents had he then? 3. Five week- arc 

!. How many roils of fence will em-lose a Tillage 
(1- front and 10 rods deep? •&gt;. 40 — 6 = ? 4x7=? 

S6 : 9 

— 1. Teacher select and pronounce ten words tor pupils 
Give tin- diacritical markings of an j five of t lie ten 

Define auy five &lt;&gt;t ten words, 4. Use any five of the ten 

— 1 . Copy from your reader Ive sentence*., each of which 
g about &lt;mt thing. 2. Rewrite the sentences, changing 

bey will state something about more than one thing. 
leclarative -.intences. 4. Change tlie five declarative 

\ 

Togative aentencea. a. Write three imperative x-n 
imatorv sentences. 

RAPHY. — 1. Have each pupil ilraw a neat map of the 


It i- not essential that this bedoneon examination ilay. 
ip to uounty -upiiintendcnt's office. 

KdiKiii Grade. (Class 2.) 

Oral reading. -• Write the leading thoughts •&gt;! a 

N&lt; 

leoted by vonr teacher. 3. Teacher select ten words 

ailcr for the pupils to define. 4. Give the diacritical 
five of the ten words. Syllabify and mark accent of each 

i 

nkii 

ii word 

h 

hmetic. — 1. Define division, dividend, divisor, ijtiotieut. '2. 
325425 by 15. •'!. At $125 apiece, bow ataay horses eaa l&gt;e 
for &gt;-!l.)T") .' [. Bought a farm containing ]'2O acres at $80 

.,;:: 

i. 

and sold ii for $11040. What was gained on an acre'.' 5. 
heal of cattle at S4* a head, and 3 horses at #120 each, and 

i« i 

Id 24 

ujrht :&gt; - • i&gt; at *6 ; i head. How much money had I left? 

., I 



I 

• 

I 

i 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
SfKi.i.iNc;. — See Course of Study and Institute Manual, peg 
Laxci'age. — 1. Write five sentences and draw one line undt 

Ert and two under the predicate of each sentence. '1. Copv 
reader ¦ sentence which contains subject, predicate, and o 
hat is an adjective? 4. Teacher select a short reading I 
lave pupils list all tlie adjectives given in it. 5. ( kxnpat 
ring adjectives : old, good, rich, red. Teachers should rea 
i- Manual, pages 16, 39, and 40. 

GboubapHY. — 1. Name the New England States and their c 
tals. -. Describe tlie Connecticut river ; the Mernmac river. '¦',. 
sailiujr along the coast from Passamaqiioddv bay to Long Island so 
what ini|H)rtant cities would l&gt;e paami? Through what waters w 
the vessel pass".' 4. Make a neat outline tor tlie study of Ma&gt;-a&gt; 
setts. See course of study for model. 5. WhatwaA tohert i- Ka 
din'.' Kennebec? Cham plain? Ann'.' Buzzanls." Teachers 
[please read Institute Mammal, pages 14 and 15. 6. Describe 
country along the Hudson river. 7. What waters are connex'tei 

the Erie ("anal? Describe the Mohawk valley. 8. Locat&lt; 
Write five sentences about it. it. Describe the Adironda 
If V*n/ and where is the Palisades? 'Mohawk? Hun 

&lt; 'h:ini|ilain 

GKAMMAH col l;-t 

Fifth &lt; r i ; a t &gt; n . &lt; 

Kkaih.ng. — 1. Give synonyms t 

w 

troin " (iradatim :"' Mount, summit, wean 

and define: Lowly, grandly, hourh . recall, sleeper, li. 1- 

oiv write a stanzji of '' (iiadatini." 4. Writea 

•I. (i. Holland. 5. Oral reading from reader. Vote. — 1&gt; 

next month carefully study "The American Klae," an 

• •graphical sketch of the author, Joseph Etodmao Drake. 
ARITHMETIC. — 1. Define: Iractiou, numerator, deuominat 

proper traction, reduction. 2. Reduce to lowest terms 

. £*,'§. '•&gt;¦ Give the sum of 5£ and 4 = . Give their diffc 

4. Bought 27| acres of land from one man and -'5&lt;i I from an 

then sold 52| acres. How much had 1 left! 5. Teacher (five pi 

deal problems. 

aaaMs lor pupils to write : Asia, Romania. Behring, Ormw, Hi 


30 


Shmjlimo. — 1. Teacher pronounce the following geograp </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
31 

RINTENDENl OK PUBLIC INsTKlCTIO.N 


v ten worda from the reader 

I iKAMMA 

— 1. Define: adjective, descriptive adjective, definitive 

Write five adjectives which denote color: 
( !onp*re the following adjectives : noble, 

u 

mkI, wearv. 4. Write sentences containing the com- 

¦ / :iiui pun ; the superlative of good and noble. J. 

lion read ing lesson and have pupils list the ad- 


iiii; descriptive adjectives in one column and definitives in 

i 

urn 

iiv. — 1. Buand Asia. Give five products of Asia. 

&lt; ¦ Em; i:a 

Name ai 

icate Ive mountain ranges of Asia. 3. Give the outlet of 
following rivers: Aiuoor, Cambodia, Indus, Euphrates. 

i 

Name five cuuntries of Asia and give their capitals. 5 

i 

and when is LVrsia? Corea? Ceylon? Ararat? Mecca? 6. What 

the earth ? How large is it? How much of it is land? 

I 

nidi i- water'.' 7. How is distance shown on ma|&gt;s? What i« 

3. Nairn- the oceans. Which is the largest? Which iportant? 
9. What is a cape? An isthmus? A penin- 

\ table-Uud? 10. What is meant 1&gt;y the source of a stream* 

I ii stream ? Right bank '.' 

Sixth Grade, (('las- 2.) 

x, — ¦&gt;,., Coarse of Study. Follow directions of Swiuton'- 
Harper's Readers in teaching this important subject. 

— 1. A painter used 7 gal. 3 qt. 1 pt. of raw oil, and 14 

\ KiriiMi- 

1 pi. of l&gt;"ile&lt;l oil. How much oil did he use? How 

¦&lt;l nil than of raw oil? '2. From 31 mi. 6 fur. 8 rd. 

• 22 mi. 7 fur. 30 rd. 4 ft. 8 in. 3. What is the weight 
n-, each weighing 1 os. 12 pwt. it gr..' 4. How many 

I 

1 lui. •'. pk. ii (|t. each will \w required to hold 125 bu. 

nk. 6 qt. of grain? 5. How old are you to-day? Give complete 

— See [iwtitute Manual, pages 18 and lit, and Com 
id's Word Lessooa. 

Sl'KI I.I.N&lt; 

Iv. or 1 

— 1. What is a descriptive adjective? A definitive adje&lt;- 
examples. -. Name and define the different degrees of 
¦ ',. Write sentences in which the comparative degree ot </seg>


            <seg id="p033">
( Jkamma 

Giv 

parisoi 

1 1 iiil&lt; &gt;&gt;t;iii , v vin'ii&gt;, r^ii |)iiriitf&gt;, 1 'aniiLsciift. _. 1 wicht^r 


'/. 

Write sentences containing ihe superlatives of the same adjed 

I. Give tour error* to lie avoided in the use "t Hdjectives. 5. 

Bmore lines on sonK 1 snbjec) selected l&gt;\ your teacher. 
. History. — 1. When did the French and Indian \\ 

End? What caused it'.' 2. Write five 

the Revolution. 3. When m independence declared? \\ 

hical sketch of James ( ) 

whom? 4. Write a biographical Bketcli of James () 
te the following places and t »¦] I how thev are count 

American history: Heights ol Abraham, Bunker Hi! 

American history : I leigh 

Miraham. Bunker Mill. ' 

Valley Forge, l^exinpton. 6. Same tin- [nter-oolonia 

Valley Forge, F^exineton. 6 

Same the I nter 

treatv bv which each one wa- closed. 7. \\ hill cam* 

treatv by which each one wa 

Wh 

ami Indian War? 8. Tell about the battle ol Queh 

DiiC^uesne, Xiagara, ricondproga, Crown l'mii!. Louisli 

the result- of the French and 
&lt; iB «RAPHY. — Teacher w i 

the rwalte of the French and Indian War. 
Gbooraphy. — Teacher will select Ilia own 

\l&gt;\ AM El) ( ul i ¦ 

**l.\ IM1I ( 1 1: \ i'l &lt; la-- 1 . 

l.\ INI 

II 

( 

liKAinM.. — 1. Krora niemoi 

Kkaium.. — 1. From mem 

write a paraphrase of the stanza. _'. Define t hi 

write a paraphrase of the stanza. _'. I '• I 

"vik hi viii- Ibr them : bound, build, air, trailing 

view, van he I. :!. Give th&lt;- anulys 

view, vaulted. :i. (Jive the anal\ 

lives: depone, &lt;upire, vision. Name other .woi 

tli&lt;- -aim' routs. 4. Write a biographical sketch ol J. '¦. 

the game units. 4. Write a I 

hi 

•"i. &lt; &gt;ral reading. Note — During the coming month 

•"». ( &gt;nil readiiiK. Not« — Durint: the com 

"The Anu'iican Flag," and write a biographical sketel 

"The American Flat," and write a l)i«&gt;triai&gt;hieal sketel 

Joaepfa Rcxlniaii Drake; also -tndv the derivation oi 

hiittU, mantion, and tyntboL 

hiittU, nuDision, and symbol. 
Teacben are referred te November iiiinil&gt;er '&gt;t the N 

Teachers are referred te November nnniliei &gt;t the \ 

.li,urnal of Kducdlion, pag« 81, 82, and 95. 
A hi THMKTic. — 1. Sold two li(in~e&gt; for f i'i&lt;&gt; each. &lt; Mi &lt; &gt;n 
and on the other I lost "Jn &lt; ; what did eacli bouse cosl 

Tn &gt; and on the other I lost 20"* ; what did each lion 

How manv bands of apples at^'J a barrel can be bought for 

How mnnv bands of apples at $¦'! a barrel can l&gt;e bought for $672&lt; ' 

after deducting 5% commiaBion? '. What will it e.i&gt;j toin 

after deducting 5% commiaBion? :!. What will it cost toinsu 

torv valued at $12000 at 4-. and the machinery valued at -^l"^ 

torv valued at $12000 at 4-. and the machinery valued at 
."5. How much *U&gt;ek at a premium of 4/ ran be 1 

."5. Mow much stock at a premium of 4/ can I 

$10500, brokerage \ '¦ '.' At what rate iddM property, 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
32 




147". i raise a tax of $7748.75 ? What will be tlie 

x 

x | jii — these per cents decimally 

v 

rules tor spelling aiul write five word- to 
_. What i- a prefix? Write Sye prefixes and 

;. What i- :i oowpoaad wold? Write tivt 
\\ nil are ougnates? (rive tive pairs ol 

a verb? How are verbs classified with 

\ 

icher -elect a short reading lesson and have 
in it, patting the transitive verbs in one li-t. 

utntnsitive in another list. 3. Write the partive 
verb drike. Write the participles of the rerb 

principal parts of the following verl*t in lenteaeaa: 
hint. '&gt;. Xaint- the modes, and illustrate each 

« 

1. Wliat is evaporation ? (iive conditions favorable 
. What iim.-es the formation of dew".' Of froet? 

ii 

ra 

When will the wind from the Indian 

» 

i 

-II'IU 

•rani A-ia .' Why? When toward Africa? Why? 
.Ii -in- and tell how they are caused. 5. Name two 
¦tal.lc- uf cadi of the grand divisions. Two animals. 
German Empire ami name its principal products. 7. 

u 

!!¦ 

1 &gt;escr 

wing rivers: Elbe, Volga, Danube, Rhone. 8. Make 

iln Btodv of Russia. 9. Locate Moscow, Florence, 
Mt. Blanc. 10. Give the capital and form of govern- 

Vl| 

s 

i; 

i- 

Kk.hth GRADE. (Class 2.) 

( lourae of Study and read Current Kvents, and 

Hi 

AI'I S 

\ tjrt/t W&lt; 

Journal, October Dumber, pages 69 and 70. 

— 8ee Course of Study and Institute Manual, page 1«. 

I5I-E1.LIN 

I. Define ratio, pro|x&gt;rtioii, involution, evolution. 

UmiMKi 

1. It 4 men in '-'.I days, mow tJ;- ( acres by working 8^ hours a dav. 

will 1") men mow in 3J days by working 9 hours a 

•iow maiiv u&lt; 

¦ :;. What i- the ratio of 1 gal. 1 qt. to 10 gal.? Of :J5 day, 
,lav- 9 hour--.' 4. -2A&lt; = what? &gt;'19ti.lTj96= what? 5 

what? 

3* </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
33 





6o 

1 pronounce ten word 

1 mine. Italv, Spain, Switzerland. 


* i K.\ M M A If. I. it I Kit lilt 1 t il&lt; * I'lt'Iili'llt"* ''I ;t st'Il tdlttf _. * * 

an adjective element? An adverbial element? Give example' 

\a 

What » a plirast-v A clause.' J. Teacher select a paragraph • 

para 

Htaaav from the reading leaaon and have the pupils li-t ihe phraset 

-tauzij from the reading leaaoa and have tin- pupils 

t 

List tht 1 clauses. 5. \\ rite a sentence containing an adject 

List the clauses. 5. \\ rite a sentence containing an adiectiv 

• me containing an adverbial claua 

• me containing an adverbial elauae, 
I'mtkd Statks 1Iisk&gt;i;y. — 1. Same the presidents from 1M1 - 

United States Hihtoby. — 1. Same the president* from I s ! 

1861 ami tell l&gt;\ what party each one was elected. "_'. What 

18t!l ami tell by what party each one was elected. "_'. W 

the Mexican War? Result? Give the provisions of the Omnibu 

the Mexican War? Result? Give the provision 

n. ( ) 

Bill. 4. What caused the Kansas War? What was th&gt; I&gt;n. 

Hill. 4. What caused the Kansas War? What was tin- I&gt;ivi 

I &gt;e&lt;i-.iiiii v 5. Tell about the invention of the sewing tuacbim 

Decision? 5. Tell about the invention "(' the sewing 

laying of the Atlantic cable. 
Civil Government. — 1. What officers constitute the 

I 

«lej&gt;artnieiit ¦¦(' government in a county? '1. When are count 

sen elected? Length of term of office? .'5. Name 1 1 &gt;untv 

oen elected? Length of term of office? .'5. Name the com 

uf tin- county. I. Ii-iiIkt five questions (See Instituti Ma 

• it thi- countx . I. 1 1 •id 

I nest ions (See In 

M 

inge 26 

ptge 26). 
Penmanship. — (&lt; reneral Clam.) i . Write the' I 

Penmanship.— ((ieneral Class.) I. Writ* 

nine-: '. &lt;/, ji, &lt;j. 2. How far 'I" the*e leters extend 

nine-: t,d,p, &lt;/. 2. How far do r 1 * • — • ¦ leten 

line.' How lar below it' '¦'&gt;. Write the loop 

line? How lar lielow ii ': '¦',. Write the loop letti 

I low tar above the bane line '1" these letters extend".' H&gt; 

Mow far above the base line do these lett&lt; i 

r 

&gt;. Write a stanza of "Gradatim " o 

it" "i. W rite a stansa of "Gradatitn" ot 
N"ik. — During the following month stud' 

NniK. — During the fbllowini' month studv 

letter*: 0, /;. /'. ' . X, If. /. Q. 
Physioloky. — -1. How is nourishment carried I 

body? From what is food obtained? -. What 

bodv? From what is CikmI obtained? 2. What 

¦pan fond? Why mhould food be well cooked? 3. N &gt; 

upon fond? Why should t&lt; &lt;• m I be well i Iced? 3. \ 

of d%estk»? What is digestion'.' 4. Describ 

liver. 5. Give some of the evil effects ot tolw 

liver. 5. Give some of the evil eflR 

t 

Teacher will please follow Institute Mam 

Teacher will please follow Institute Manual, page 20. 
Note to Teachers. — You nhould read mrefully Oours 

Note to Teachers — Von should read carefully 

( 

I raininu for Teachers of Common Schools and Si 

Training (or Teachers of Common Schools and School Government 
- :;."&gt; to 37 inclusive ot the Manual of Institute Work for the n 

of Nebraska Normal Institute*, that yon maybe prepared for ; ; 

of Nebraska Normal [nstitntea, thai yon maybe prepared for the d 

.!is-i,in &lt;if' these subject* in our local institutes. 
I liavu ubstrvwl in man} schools, graded and ungraded, a tenden&lt; 

I have observexl in inan\ acfaooht, graded and ungraded, a tendeu 

in |&gt;as6 the examination in a study, then drop it, to complete anotbt 

34 </seg>


            <seg id="p036">
35 

KSDF.NI OF I'l HI. II INSTFtrcnON. 

isure, In- rented ied by having each das« 


preceding grades. 

u aboul twenty pupils paand a final examina¦&lt;\ 
grade branches, besides a tew that entered the 

n altered the bcancbca in said course is pre- 

niversitv course. By this plan the University and 

ire brought into closer relationship. 

I daring June and July was successful in every way, 
nterest, and remiita would indicate. The zeal of 

¦ : tti. State Superintendent on the culture and spirit of 
.\a- valuable and suggestive and won a hearty vote of 

members »&gt;t the Institute. 

..i the teachers towards self-improvement and lor a 
In profession is on the increase. New teachers of nor- 

ii.l successful experience have joined us the past and 
In tlii&gt; way urn- schools are constantly being improved. 

Imndred teacher* are reading the Chautaiujiia Course ami 
State Reading Circle. Teachers, by donations of books 

hi-, established :i library for their use, and are frequent 
&lt; ininty Superintendent's office. 

t the Lancaster County Teachers' Associa- 

&lt; 'ountv Superintendent's office, averaging an 
I red and eighteen teacher*, not less than one 

present at each of these session 

lucational topic-, methods of teaching, self-train- 

lent were discussed. Supplemental to our 

I local ones to be held following your Manual 

Work as* guide "The Course of Self-Training" and 

igea •')•") and 37 of Manual, are general top 

( 

This work has proved valuable in familiarizing 

i the Institute Manual and State Course of Study, and in 

ition 'it' the teacher-' work by the patrons of the dif- 

I 

it communitu 

li-triit- believing that the reading of good books is a kind 

S 

lucation ranch needed, have, during the past 'year, assisted their 

ipil- to -.tn.e ¦ small library. Only ¦ few books should be pur </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
iou was vci-v marked. 


ii 

i 

la 

n 

Eto be increased as the demand for more i» made. I he* 
•ence. books, supplementary books in reading, geography, li 
nguagc numbers, etc. Book- might be purchased au&lt; 

Ee pupils, not by the district. 
ray, will pave the way for a 
t be well to add that xchoti 

boards -.limilil turiiisli ..In 

papers, magazines, and weekly newsjmper or current news foi 
of the pupils of the district, u- tin- last is too greatly ignored 

11- l.i-t i- too trreal Iv 

Rn schools. Thi- would not only eleval 
tllv in developing Ihouqht in manv liom&lt; 

iv liom 

E conclusion. I would add that I am in favor of mun 
er&gt;, more normal schools, uniform examinations i&lt;" 
Course of Studv, state instructors for all oountv institul 

¦ornial aeboois are estahlishi 
and properly equipped lii 
should l&gt;e normal teachers 

¦inking you for many favor 
two successful term- In tin 

[ am, sincerely yours 

I, teachere' classes in our Sta 
h schools. The instructors 
and compensated by tbi 

and courtesies extended 
Department of Public I 

Prank 1&gt;. McC'i.i'sk 

LINCOLN COUNT* 

¦ 1869, Lincoln county, i!,5i*L' square miles in area, wac 
! County .Superintendent into two district.-, one north 
south of the river. It has now eighty-four districts, am 

buildings. Fifty-one of these are frame, twenty-seven iod,ooe brie 
and one log. Sixteen have been erected this last year, most ol the 
being durable frame buildings. There arc many very neat and 
I'urtable houses and their number is rapidly increasing. It i- com pa 
atively a new thing, however, to bond the districts, and many besiti 
to do so, preferring to build at first of sod, which with can- will 1: 
three or four years. The two beat reports of daily attendance tl 
vear came from little unplastered -od houses having Do floor and u 
having rough boards for seat.s. </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
36 


( tee lunik at a time, porcl 
nt.\ librarv. I d tlii- 

*ocial questions &lt;&gt;t the day 



In x&gt;l officers and patrons a general and very enicbool 
matter-. The idea is much too prevalent* 
any .me en teach little ones, and I am often 

II Mill 

with the applicants for certificates because the 

i 

iu posed entirely of small children. How can 
al -'i'li a school should have the verv l&gt;est 

lie alive and earnest in their work. There 

institute- for -ix i&gt;r seven yean in the 

- certainly shown among the rank and tileot 

\imo-i all of the proauiH corps attended the Institut&lt; 

•(•mi inty this summer, and are taking an educa»sionallv 
one who cannot afford to attend in- 

I 

iapej&gt;, and who i- teaching as he was taught years 

i 

rid schools. I doubt whether the districts can at- 

icher 

,nt&gt; 

sport that as vet little has l&gt;een done either with 
i- or reading circles. 

v l.i 1 

I 

•net of ii\t ix&gt;oks was recommended l&gt;y our last 
nl many of the hoards have adopted it, which is 
teiuatize the work. Many schools are using a elass.1 
are partially graded. 

lent -( 

V 

1 

N.nth Plattc are in excellent condition and have a 
l\ . The schools of Wallace and Wellfleet have now 
In i room, and will doubtless soon adopt a course of 

n 

idation. 

Mary K. Hoskord, Superintendent. 

M.\I&gt;ISON COUNTY. 

M 

eighty school houses valued at about $60,000. 
,v. All the sod and log school houses have given 

i 

milling-. The school officers and people in general 
it-iii I in the schools, and tax themselves heavilv 

i» 

a Ira 

v 

n 

The teachers of Madison county rank high when 
le of other counties. Their regular attendance at </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
rir -iippi 
red with 

37 



all institutes and teachers Meeting ha&gt; l&gt;een ot preftf l&gt;eni 
The ])resent County Superintendent lias been visiting the sc 
county for five years and finds much pleasure in Doting the at 
which lias been made. The school terms average ahoal ae\ 

Ill I' I ( 

llOO 

Ivan 

v 

The Countv Institutes areol a verv lii -li character, as i- sli 
attendance of the teachers, there i&gt;ein_: aboot oinety-five 
all the teachers of the county in attendance. The teaehe 
five Teachers' Associations during the year, whicb are i\&gt; 
and are very interesting. About fifty of the teacher&gt; i« 
State Reading Circle. A system of uniform books i- in 

V 

I the county. Nearlv all tit*- Ikiii-- are -n|&gt;|&gt;lii-&lt;l \vi; 
1 some apparatUH. L. l'&gt;. Bohannon,_#u 

There are in ( &gt;to»' county 
most of them are Biibstantia 
elegant structures, models o 
telligent adaptation to the 

at Wyoming, Burr, Douglas, and 
But those of which all justly r 
Nebraska City and the public scho 
brick .struct u res of' modern stvle, un 

all that it i^ |Hi»iblt; liir human ski! 
to .say either building is su|ierior tci 
jealousy. I am happy to say thai 
than ever before, and many, in l» 

Bously kept as are the elegani and 
i much pleasure I hereby acknow 

\- 

have been well chosen. The care in selecting saidotficvi 
credit on the voters of the various district* oi the couul 
however, a little neglect in making out the neoes-yirv rec 

t 

irv n-]&gt; 

38 


&lt; &gt;tok &lt; orvn 

Pent adaptation to ilic \\:\ 
tly erected ami well equi| 

and efficiency of t tie xchool ntfi&lt; 

•ng the schools, and in having regula </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
KKIM IM'KNT OF 1TBI.K I NSTKUCTIO.V 

39 

• remeu leu and the school work will be the crown 

• ¦omit v 

hers rank with the best in the state ; are now at work in 

il and enthusiasm unsurpassed. The spirit 

i\ 

V**ociations, the [nstitutes. and Mimnx t 

\ 

¦i-liool room and is leading to tlit- nio-t 

&gt;ur Institute was the most successful ever held in 

wa- more regular, the interest greater 

¦ !ii|&gt;li-h'il far superior to that of previous vear-. 
ittended our summer Normals, two hundred 

pportunity for improvement, and how tbeyerakl 

od accomplish &lt;o much work is marvelous. 

n the direction of better methods of instruction and 

igement, and went forth with renewed energy and greater 
achera arc doing all they can to make their work 

nial and at the same time fully prepare thein^elvt- lot 
ltIii to which their noble calling invites them. 

\V. M.Ci.aky, Superintendent 

I'AWNEE COUNTY 

\i iity-.-ix school booses, most of whicli 

\y well furnished with modern seats. A 
nc fairly well supplied with maps, (harts. 

fticer« is shown by their lively inter- 

iii' schools, and by their intelligent effort.-¦ 
it school work. While the schools an- 

it we could wish, yet they arc in a prapsnMM 

lit ion, and fair progress i.~ bein^r made. 

• 'in 

Study arranged bv the State Superintend- 

gradually introduced, until at present a large part of our 

We hope to make it general though- 

It I, 

vi-it every school in the county at least 


•I 

I: teachers deserve commendation for the hisjh standard main 
by them. Their professional spirit is evinced l&gt;v the ta&gt;hey 
have formed a county association, and bave oondnd 
ummm and profit daring the pa&lt;t rear. At these meetings 
per cent of our teachers attend, and a large Dumber of then 
otive part in tbe regular work and discussion-. Much goi </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
Im-iih: done in this way that cannot be accomplished by large a 

J'hc&lt; lounty Teachers' I nstitute lias l&gt;een for manv vear 

Khi ii the boundariea of "Little I'' 
districts, containing sixty-eighi sch 
st l&gt;e»'n formed ha- yet no bnild 

Ea- nianv teachers find emplovmenl in giving ins( 
3,867 children of school age-in the countv win 
sis of ¦ good practical education. \\ ith the exi 
brick structure which adorn- the town of &lt; toceola, 
of frame construction, and nearly all arc conven 

tial buildinira in which the districts to which thev belon 

i-t 

I pride. A&lt; a class our people are alive and awake i" th&lt; 
and advantages offisred the rising generation l&gt;\ our public - 
the school rooms of this county in convenience and equipmel 
¦uipassed by none and equal to any of tli" ether counties 
We have some few exceptions, however, in a few d 

wd 

where the population is largely or whollv foreign 

40 


POLK &lt; &lt; ll'X'n 

an important factor ill our school -v-tem. an&lt;i it i.- highly ; 

:i 

l&gt;v the teachers, :i- shown by the attendance, interest, ami 

work (loin. 1 by them. \\ itli places in m county for eighty- 
ere, the enrollment :it our last Institute »:i- ninety-twi 

-n 

-I 

ot teachers for whom the Institute is believed to liavi 

baviag been excused. 

The people generally appreciate ami encourage &gt;\ 
prove the advantages &lt;&gt;f the young. Pawnee count) is 

nlut«-&lt;l upon the bealthy school sentiraenl of ii- peopK 

F. A. Bartov - </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
41 

I rKltlNTKM'KNT OF IM'BI.K IN»TR1&lt; TIoN 

i 

crs iir* 1 i iio&gt;i i v » &lt; m n ti 111^*11 mid \\oiiit*ii j use ii»K. 1 11 tj '-M' i*ip 
profession. They are earnest, energetic, ambitious, and 
ficationa above the avenge, bat they need experience to 



be &lt;killful teacher. We hope in a meas- 

I 

1MIW 

any difficulty which may arise in this line by rnainfeaehers' 
Association, to which every teacher in the 

h IkiWIs monthlv sessions. Its object is the 

ucatiooal iileas of the day, to give the teacher 

work, and to build up a professional feeling 

ise tin- efficiency of the work done to-day in 

hanks arc due to those older teachers in our 

doing ••&lt; much to make the teacher's work professional. 

no! forget to acknowledge the benefit arising from the loca- 

Stronisburg Normal and Bustnea College at Stromsburg, 

which a supplying- Da with that professional training in 

1. w 

deficient. May its good work continue. 

itimi of our schools according to a recognized system 

¦eing attempted, and it is !&gt;elieved will be quite satisfa&lt; - - 

ndaries' are &lt;|uitf unsjitisfactorv in a number of our 
&lt; iiin|ilainis arc made of the inconvenience and dis- 


houses from many of the homes. W r e would hail 

asure when the school districts would be orgauized 
rea of lour Bqaare miles. 

RED WILLOW (OINTY 

I am glad to report progress all along the "line" in our Red Wil 

There are now sixty-nine s&lt;-h««»l buildings, thirty 

u &lt;• tv 

De being frame, and two of brick. The sod boose and the dugout 

f the past. They an- generally well furnished 


with good seats and blackboard. The number that have Webster's 

Unabridged Dictionary, map-, charts, and globe is constantly increas- 
There are thirty-five districts with apparatus thi~ year against </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
.1. &lt;&gt;. Dktueii.er, Xuperintendeui. 


manifest and the rest* lines- with which tbey co-operate with 

RICHARDS &gt;\ i ' '! \ 

I rind dim my teachers rank 

I rind that my teachers rank « 

the counties with whom I have pome int&lt; 

the counties with whom I have fome inl 

tatei and other educational meetings; the.ii spirit asm 

tute» and other educational meetings ; theii spii 

•¦arnestness is well indicated l&gt;v the tact thai - l&gt;ul 

earnestness is well indicated bv the fact that v\ j . i i . n takes lull 1 

Teachers Id til! our scIiukIs. tin- eiimi imiiii! n| our annual [nstitu( 

teachers to fill our schools, the enrol 1 meni al our annual Iiistitut 

Jlo. with an average dailv attendance of 1 I 11 tor the en 

t 

ton r weeks. Every teacher in ttx untv thai was nol ej 

tour weeks. Every teacher in th' countv thai w i 

tended the Institute. In addition to ;iii- neat teacher ii 

tended the Institute. In addition to this neat 

county takes an educational pa|&gt;er. i | • 1 • •• - n&lt;M </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
42 


iDtendent to necure gin*] results is inont gratifying. Already ih 

maud a higher grade of teacher*, and teacliers are making a great 

to meet the demand. There is a spirit &lt;&gt;i noble ttelf-dissatisi 

aaaoog the teachers which cannot fail to work out good results. 

Laal year the oouatv ciiiMi.ii--ic.ini-- purchased Welch's Re$! 

ami that in connection with Superintendent LaueV b 'C'oun« 

Imw been a great ln-l|&gt; toward grading the.* h &gt;"i-. 

There are mm weventy-ni the countv. i • i 

visit each school onoe a year. 

There are twenty-seven members ol the State Reading ( 

Weliail ;i three week*' Institute last year with lou 

aaee of any previous one. This vear it wa« -till 

-event v-st'vcii in attendance. 

We had :i teacher for primal year i"i 

rocker of Lincoln, and already I note tin u i i 

in our schools. 1 here La- l» &lt; n an 

aad cultivate m taste for L r ".,&lt; 

Li— ons iii Englixh literatun 

¦\ alentine of Mi( 'i iok h 
uwledge. A- m result, I 

of l)iK)ks for reading circles i 

K i . i /. \ &lt; i \ 



\ 


Circle is doing £ood work, and Las a menikhm. 
We have three County Associaal 
are well attended. My teachers respond 

them 

nteresl in education is increasing. 
e general condition of the scuoo 

ht'in i- for the benefit of the children. We 

i list of text-books, and they have been intio- 

ri 

ree-fourths of the schools, and will Ix; in all by 

trying to introduce the State Course of Study 

« 

iiication (iecord, and think I will tinullv suit-eed. 

in 

ihool buildings and at least eighty of them are in 
I bout fiftv are excellent buildings and will last tl&gt;r 

I 

wa- held al Falls City. We held only (oreeutire 
tour weeks. 

i 

my entire time and attention, and I t'eel 
¦eiated by the people in general. 

( '. ('. Pool, Superintended 

IM&gt;KKS COUNTY. 

\ 

one hundred and nine school houses, most ot 
hi. Tlir old school houses of the county 

I 

am and good, new buildings are erected 

IkhiI lota are fenced and many ot 

\ 

u 

plorable condition. 

pecial | »¦ • i iit during inv term ot office to arouse 
i realization of the evil influence of indtM-entlv 

he character of the children. </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
IgS U|X)I 

43 




k] progress educationally during the pa&gt;t 
ndicated by more intelligent inquiry by teacb- 
School boards seem to l&gt;e willing to do any- 


44 

RKPORT OF THE 



II 

p. 

Our school boards are wide awake in the selection ot *^ood teac 
More teachers are now engaged lor the full year than em be 
Saiinders county ranks Meond to none in the efficiency and car 
ness of her teachers. 

E- now have ten village schools in the county, and the priii.-ew 
schools meet monthly at the County Superintendent's offi 
¦ methods, clamification, gradation, rapervisioa, etc. We 
local Institutes in different part- ot' the countv. in which mo 

¦I boards it i- not doing the work it should. I 
•of study &lt;lo the work ii should do and ha 
the schools and teacher- who most need it. 

SAUI'Y (&lt;)IM^ 

I think there has been great improvement m the scholarship 

teachers in this county in the la-i three vears, whicl 

great measure, to the thoroughness of the examinations; A pi 

»re now require* I to possess fair knowledge of industrial drawin 

lore a -second grade certificate is grauted them. There ba 

marked change for the better in the method- of instruction u» </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
our teachers are deeply interested. 
The Superintendent'^ entile time i- devoted to office « 

visitation. 

&lt;)ur taacben are ju-t awakening to a realization of the 1 ¦¦ 

the Reading Circle an it i&gt; now established. While our list 

is not vet very large, we expert t" increase it to one ho 

&lt; 'liristma&gt;. 

\\ i have ¦ graded course of study, prepared l&gt;\ my pn 

but owinir to the fact thai no action has U-en taken upon 

authority back &lt;&gt;l it more than the simple reques 

perintetKlent. Many "t nay besl teachers an 

nic-ely, bat the &lt;mrs who are not doing thie 

Tin- county In &gt; l&lt; 1~ an annnal [ostitufa 

two \vct'k&lt; ot August. At oar \aM meeti 

and iiinetv memberx. R. II Watson 


t 

li 

N'^irlx it 1 1 Hit? tea' 'ticr&gt; taKe one or more educational 
I'll.- annual Institutes were well attended, and the instroe- 

:uv in good condition and furniahed 

with some school apparatus. In a few district*, 

reignen, there is opposition to providing 

U-. \ German school officer remarked: M I want- bo 
Welch's Classification Record has l&gt;cen introduced into 

mix made by me to have the State Cour-e ..t 

wed. In some districts this attempt was defeated bv the 
indifference of the school l&gt;oards or teachers. 

\ss IK -iations have lieen organized from time to time, l&gt;ut 
Lrt flourished, probably owing to the small Dumber of teachers 

visit each school twice during the term, liefore leaving 
1 give the teachers the suggestions that I deem necessary. 

pinion the schools would I* 1 more efficient if the independent 
were established and the town system introduced. In all 

ntaining no large cities;, the fines and liceuses should go into 

\V. J. Xkuman, Superintendent. 

nasiirv. 

SKWARD COUNTY. 

ire at present in this county ninety-one districts, giving em 

ne bandied and sixteen teachers. School houses gener 

llv are in uo&lt;h! condition, and, on the whole, are well supplied with 
irniture and apparatus. She prides herself somewhat on the educaoiial 
qualifications of her teachers. The examinations are pretty 
verc, and the gliding close to the line. School officers, with few exptiona, 
are active in the discharge of their duties, are in sympathy 
it li the Superintendent, and ijive a good deal of attention to the genii 
routine and make up of the school. The public is interested in 
i-e "t education, and public meetings of educational character 

tell attended. County Institutes are well attended, and the 
available instructors employed. Full attendance and good at- 

tion are noted in the grading of certificates, and made well nigh </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
45 


nethods chieflv. 


DeoeMary to Hm &gt;eoumij; ot n license. I iirmg itir jm-i 
advance lias been made by discouraging the lower grai 
and, by io doing, encouraging tlte better qualified and 


I 

II 

Bane of study i&gt; pretty generally in use in thoM 
early contracts, bul in places where teachers ar 
ree, or tour mouths, it meets with opposition, o\ 
of the teacher to perfect the grading. 

I 

n 

iVIll 

B have a County Teachers' Association thai meets 
lontfaa for the purpose of interchanging thought, :i 
:)tis of common interest. There i- a merabershi| 
lly for the purchase of a library. 

n 

tin 1 

M. Mkkiian. &gt;», 

IIKKID.-W &lt; "IVn 

¦ one instructor we have increaHed lo four. 
August, 1889, we organized a( 'mi my I eachers A- 

i 

Kid by turns at Gordon, Rushville, and Hav Spi 
in the county that are situated on the Premo 
ri Val lev railroad i. These meetine^ were well </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
in 

Dt, I 

HI 

46 


rbere are, at this writing, oik hundred and 

r&lt; 'I an 

ilii- county, ninety-two 

value from |50 l" $7,000. 

\\ e have three graded soli 

With few exceptions 

p:t&gt;i year. 

( )n the part of tnosl teacli 

interest i- manifested in the sclui 

BppurteBanoea are in good re|tair, ami 
ving place to substantial franii 
think our teachers are well up with tii 

By aeoood every effort we make to advaix 
work in our county. 
¦re have l«'en five County Institutes held in il 

enrollment has increased from about thirty t« alioul 


uraged in our ¦moriation meetings by the 

w 

i in the excrciwa of the meetings l&gt;y tlie 
ue of Hay Springs. Tliere is a good ami 

educational work. 

perintendent is arduous, indeed, owing partly 
public sentiment and diversity of opinion iu 
torn* relative to school supervision, l&gt;ut princi- 

imty, causing a vast amount of chang 

;iikI organising of new districts — and also to the sire 
ninr thirtv-six by sixty-nine miles in area ; some 
- • 
vcntv-tive miles over land from the county seat. 

\ 

rs great I v nripple tlie efficiency of the Suj&gt;erintendiakes 
it prartirally impoaHote tor him to fulfill the 
sititii: schools." The namber of first grade eertifireat-ine 
each year. Most of the teachers, however. 

ffiii 

!•! in 

i 

and all seem to recognise the fact that teaching 
c a profession. 

I 

I a reading circle was presented to the teacher* 

i 

. and ilicv took hold of the matter with an earue-t-iraging 
to note. The course adopted was that of 

i 

ai there baa been considerable advancement 
if tin teachem in teachers' wages and in paying 
'the districts m well, as increasing the length &lt;&gt;t 

Phere baa as yet been comparatively littlt 
graded coarse of stiuly ; but tlie .subject i- 

vill. «. think, attain in the near future 

JOHN M. Linx, Superintendent 

STANTON CXMNTY. 

W 

count} forty well-quipped school houses. Their 
i\ guud, in tact much better than at the time my 
von i wo rears ago. 

lit 

Ill'l 

|M&gt;rt \\a~ made t 

OnK two -eh 

I houses in oiu couutv are not supplietl with fiatent </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
47 

N 




48 

REPORT OF THE 

desks and seats. Our school officers arc. as a. rule, efficieu 
q— lifted for the potttioae which they hold. The same can 
our teachers. Oar schools have never been in so flourish 
&lt;lition as now. Teacher-" meeting* are lieltl once a mouth. 
tendance is good. We try io liavc a program that is iot 
all wlio attend. Subjects of vital 'interest to the school m 
up the bulk of these programs. Phis year considerable Rea&lt; 
work will Ix- done at-cach meeting. Formerly the meeti 
association wen- held once each quarter, but during the pa 
interest in the work has been such that we have he 
Saturday of each month. Patrons of our schools conn i 

teachers. Work from town and oountv schools is pul on exl 
oar county tiur each year, the board of directors offering 1 
miuoM tur work of tin- kind. Our county corn mis 
fl(H) each year lor defraying the expenses of holding an I 
this place. These Institutes have been of great value ' 
they are well attended. W e endeavor to have such om 
siriietions tor the teachers that none can afford to igi 

(unity for improving themselves in the art of teach in 

Ecord and examination of the work done i 
made at the close, and credit given them for si 
following examination lor teachers' certificates, 
a year of improvement and advancement among as; ¦ 
has l&gt;een formed, and we are studiously following tie 
bv the officers of the Reading Circle board. We ai 
county schools, and expect to have everyone graded 
January. A fine two-story school house is now in cour 

En at Pilyer, and will be ready tor occupancy 
iclusiou, I can say that the prospect tor the eon 
" schools is more hopeful than ever before. </seg>


            <seg id="p050">
49 

I- 

RINTENDEHT OF 1'IBI.IC I NSTRl'CTIOX. 

I 

WAYNE COUNTY. 

school districts ami sixtv school house- in this 

¦ iiiiiliu^- arc in &lt;_i&lt;mk1 condition, and supplied witli 
I 'i some of the newer district! they are not very 

\ 

li apparatus, but quite a number are baying this fall. 
they an- getting to understand tin- economy of fur- 

plenty to work with. 

I 

loioggood work ami will compare favorably with 

ountiea and states. Quite a uuml&gt;er have become 
ite Reading Circle, and I hope to enroll every 

tuny before spring. 

ke the course of study the basis of examination, -.. 
\i summer, after Institute. 

A 

number of teachers who hold first grade, and only 
ade, certificates in the county, and if it were not 

their certificates to be endorsed, it would not l&gt;e 
rade would be a thing of the past. 

W 

graded course of study adopted in the county 
we bad a uniformity of text books we could 

.ipid advancement. I expect to have the hearty 
il officers in this work, which will make it much 

xtv-one teachers in attendance at our Institute la.-t 

school, and all agreed that it was both a plea^rion, 
and voted at the close that next summer 

itendent should colled an enrollment fee of $1 from 
e uaed !•&gt; ilelray the expenses of an additional week 

( 


Kitute worl 
nit'- a inn 

unl thus give u- a three or four weeks' session. 
it ..I districts they arc conceding that it is not wise 

n every term an,! hire by the year, and in a few inhaa 
been known to stay two or three whole years iu 

hange t&lt; ach 

:tne. - ;i tea. I 

I. .1. GlIJ&gt;ER8LEEVE, Superintendent. 

line pla 


mil m ii&lt; -li more effective when once in opt-r- </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
50 

REPORT OF THE 

YOUK COUNTY. 

York county has ninety-nine school district*, one hundi 

i 

i 

thousand two hundred and thirteen cliildren of school age 

i 

property valued at $100,000. The school booiieH, with 

,Y 

lions, an- in repair and fairly well supplied with good 

tcl 

and apparatu-. All district- are supplied with patent desk 
At Hrad-haw a Hue commodious four-room building lia- 

I" 

comiilrted to take the place of the one destroyed l&gt;\ 

¦I une. This building has been erected entirely l&gt;v dona) 

i 

Bradshaw relict committee gave |1,500, the county board 

Si) 

• S 733 was contributed by the school districts of ork count 

pupil- and teacher- of the state. To all donor- the pal 

Tin- number of months school in each distri&lt; 

from five to nine, with an average "t' eight. I he tex 

nearly uniform, about ninety districts using the - 
- \ schools in the county of more than one del 

Teachers' wages in the country sell 

month. Teachers' meetings are well attend 

For live years we have maintained 

(tor county papers, publishing school rep 

program, and report of meetings, etc. 
La-t *prinir Welch- ( 'lassification R 

and 

hi 

placed in the register at the 

Superintendent. The course of study for this county 

liranehe- required for a second grade certiftcate. Pupi 
the course are granted common school diplomas signed 

Supei 

tendent, teacher, and School board. Seventeen pupils w 

t'rom the country schools last veai 

A County Association was held outli unla\ 



¦'•hool houses, employing oue hundred and tweutv-four 

ilistri'-t extern! their liearty tfianl 

them have a hijih school com 

promptly and nearly every teaclii 

placed in all th&lt;.' schools. A complel </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
"t forty. The enrollment at the annual 
¦'1 and ninety-one. 

Circle hat been formed, with a membership of 
uispices of the State Reading Circle. 

• vy satisfactory condition. Superintendent, 
md patrona are working tor more thorough 

•ommon schools. 

K. 8. Frakkuv, Supriniendent. 

51 


s </seg>


            <seg id="p054">

PRINCIPALS AND Si PERINTEND- 
S OF (JRAI)EI) SCHOOLS. 

i:\"i 

rticienl school work i&gt; tbe intelligence and ehar- 

tola ;uv more thoroughly graded and in better conin 
ever before. The year just closed has been the 
nil satisfactory win- since my connection with the 
superintendents ever had more faithful and efficieut 
ive bad the past year. Nearly all of these teachers 
ame positions for the coming season. 

t M'ti 

ilv Hi 

inn-, a 

in. Few 

i 

id il 

more particularly the condition of our high school, 
jtness, the purpose toaooompliah soinethiug worthy, 
I the entire high school, lias been as remarkable as its 
ratifying. The policy our Board lias adopted, of 
eudance of pupils from outside the district has made 

n 

revad 

ii 

i 

tin- educational center of Hamilton county for 
rammar and country schools. The presence of 

ml a constant stimulus to our own young people, 

g tn our treasury over $&gt;'22r&gt; as tuition fees. The 
high school baa enabled eighty or more youug men 

t 

substantial progress toward worthy intellectual 

levelopment of true and strong character. 

,;n- these schools tor a new field of labor 1 sever my coo 

whom 1 «hall always remember with warm es- 

II. It. CoRBETT, Sitjterintendent. 


\i UoiiA ITBLK SCHOOLS. 

i :i pcip]iit' whiiin 1 -.hall alwav 
c|i gratitude. Respectfully, </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
54 

REPORT OF THE 

HKATRK'E ITBI.K SCHOOLS 

The public- schools of Beatrici 

sc-liool building of bric-k. heated bv -team, with the mod 

icaoM i&gt;f water supply and plumbing, and 

ntamiiu 

assembly room, three recitatii 

i r&lt; &gt;&lt; 1 1 1 1-. unices, ami nine 

three brick ward buildings "i 

i \ 

all heated bv steam ; one brick ward build 

bv stove.- : two frame build 

i 

building of one room, all heated l&gt;\ 

The number of teacher 

Mnontr the number, is forty, one of w -p&gt; -• -i:i I teach&lt; 

The schools consist "t [&gt;rimi 

school. The grades are tw 

average child will be abl 

iiihl 

to the next in a vear. I 

riiiiar 

grades, the grammar 

school the last lour grades o 
It is the aim that our sch 

the primary grades the ability 

word.*; a sufficient knowledtj 

transaction.-: a general knowled 

of physiology and hygiene; a 

singing, and to know and ol 

common courtesy. 

To those who complete the gram ma 

give a thorough knowledge of tin 

this to include the power to expres 

correctness in speaking or writing Ei 

best writers of English and son* 

i 

written : a knowledge "t our growth a* a nation and 

and men that have shaped oar develop 

to the present time. 

The high school offers the choioi ¦ uourse* 

course, for those who wish 

tO ecilltlllll 

tions or who wish the sort "1 training and culttir 

etudv of a classic laminate ; a German course lor tb&lt; 

A 

'S </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
!KKI\ II M'K.NT OK ITBLH INSTBUl TION. 

55 

the German) to Latin ; and the English course. 
wisb to tit themselves for teaching, or who prefer a 

led study of the English language, with more of iem-.-study 
nt' another language than English. The 
upon tlic accredited list of the University of Ne- 

. and it&lt; graduates enter the freshman ela-s 
Phe progress of the high school has l»eeii aspetIn 
past and present years ; the attendance bow 

great as that of two yean ago. 
gymnastic exercises have l&gt;een made a part ol 

ill grades below the high school. The exercise* 
i-lartuiv to all concerned. Thev are conducted 

hers. 

Sort and generous emulation tor all worthy 
vade the schools, and both the quality and the tjuan- 

t 

tdanoe upon them leads the school authorities to beililic 
schools are more and more viewed with favor and 

patrons 

Cabbou &lt;i. Pkabbe, SupermttiMdUmt. 

(LARKS lTBLK SCHOOLS 

ehool buildings; one a fine, commodious, two-story 
lesigu, containing six school rooms, and one large 
other a frame of one room situated outside of the 

\ 

«T. I s *'.). sve occupied oar new brick which was erected 
an of 1888-9. 

are six teachers employed, two males and four females. 

ell supplied with blackboards, encyclopedia, di&lt;- 

r maps, globes, physiological charts, organ, air 

tump, Yaggy's Anatomical Study, and other supplies essential to a 

quipped school system 

tr Board is composed of intelligent and enterprising men who aim 
conservative yel progressive, and are ever readv to act when any- </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
tiling is needed by the schools necessary to their 

that no graded school can get along well without 

study, I prepare&lt;l a course of instruction which w 

Boanl at the close of the last year. In future twi 

will be siistaine&lt;l in our schools, an English and a I 

English course will fit graduates to pass the cxai 

for first grade county certificates, with some additic 

Latin course is designed to prepare pupils to enter 

sity. Following the best authorities, the school i 

lows: Primary Department, consisting of fourgrad&lt; 

Grammar Department, consisting "i four grades 

High S'hocil Department, eonsistingof three clas* 

vi/... Junior, Middle, and 

Seni 

The free text-book system is in operation hei 

furnishes supplies for the use of pupils, pens, -jkmk 

used for examinations an 

nil wcirt 

The literary work "I the IhltIi sc:Ikh»I is und&lt; 

¦iK-ietv known a- the Brvanl Literan Society. I 

i «!)(•&lt;• a month, ami sees that ever^ meinlier of this 

suitable work. That ti 

the earnest in .-- and /cai displayed by pii|&gt;ils ii 

increasing interesl nianite 

June we graduated a claa 

fhe enrollment for la~i 

¦ar w 

Bt tor next year will doubtless 
ic sentiment i- a unit in demai 

S,- t&lt;&gt; place the interests "I oui 
moral lose of mir |.mpils i- g 
ressive. I can truthfiiliv &gt;: 
le aim of our school work is 
vtion of which lie in suac*p 

Tin- moral tone of our |'U]&gt;ii&gt; i- good ami tin 

progressive. I can truthfully &gt;a\ 

w 

1 he aim dl our school work is t&lt; 

ii nla 

In conclusion, I wish t 

xpi 

licartv co-operation of both teachers ami patrons, an 

tinsel j advice and support of our worthy School Ii 

mooes)*. Believin 

:i printed cour 

as adopted by tl 

courses "t stud 
itin course I li 

mnations iv./u 

lal -ul&gt;i 

the State I'ni 

jssined 

i 

I 



56 </seg>



            <seg id="p058">
57 

I 

•ERINTENDENT OF ITBI.K INSTRUCTION. 

"LAY CENTER SCHOOLS. 

have been progressing is evidenced by some 

v 

\ 

idy ban been made covering ten years' work, three 
Int,- in the intermediate, and tour in the grammar 

u a Imirlli teacher has l&gt;een added ; the salarie- "t 
been raised five dollars per month, and the prinoi- 

\ 

hing force lias been insufficient to do tlie most 
in each teacher's having so many grades. But 

Id it ion to the teaching force the work can be done in a 
able manner. 

Krinjj the las) two years we have l&gt;een raising money for a library. 
iiinnt- and suppers. With this money we have purchased 

I :&gt; : 1 1 1 1 

mes. These comprise reference books, biographies. 

itandard prose, travel, and fiction. 

iv, 1 mm! 

lli&gt; hiL'li school work has not been steady and regular throughout 
coarse daring the entire year, because a majority of the pupils were 

ii 

it tendance during the whole year. 

.1 

iclano- and punctuality has not been up with the highest 
( )u ( titnlicr i.Stli the schools were quarantined and re- 

,-1 

losed for six weeks. We had hardly begun after this when 
ppe visited as, teachers and pupils suffering alike, and were 

bsenl three or four days. 

&lt; &gt;n tin whole -nine more stringent measures ought to be instituted 

Board i" &lt; |&gt;el a regular and punctual attendance. 

Yours respectfully, 

N. M. Graham, Principal. 

(KETE 1TBLIC SCHOOLS. 

I 

i large ltiu r li bcI I buikiing, with steam heating and 
ippliances, has been completed at a cost of about 2ti,&lt;X&gt;0-iiil'liiiu 
there are three ward schools. 

mm modet 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
Thirteen teachers are employed who have charge of uv 

damned u primary, intermediate, grammar, and high 

higli school comprises four grade 

Pbe course in language aims to give pupils the p 

¦\ 

language in connected diaoourae. (''imposition work irunning 
from the very lowest grade and beginning wit 


ition. At the beginning the child i- led and trained 

simple laws of composition, DmiiiL; seven (ft* 

in description, narration, comparison an&lt;l c 

in description, narration, comparison an&lt;l contrast, 

transformation of poetry to pruae, biography 

tnmtbrmatiun of poetry to pruae, biography. Paral 

proceeds drill in correct forms, clearness and -i 

proceeds drill in correct forms, clear 

and stren 

the study of models as may U- found in the reading let*; 
In the eighth grade technical grammar bejrin 

the -tudy of models as may be found in the rea 
In the. eighth grade technical grammar b 

t •¦!¦! 1 1-. Rhetork 1 commences in the eleventh gra 

t'-rm-. Rhetork 1 commences in the eleventh ai 

ii ii grade an 

study of masterpieces ol ntyle and of much pra 

study of masterpieces of nty 

ami 

vision-, of rhetoric. The English coursi 

visions of rhetoric. The English coura 

jnear with the study of the works o( a few • 

year with the study of tin 

k 

American authors'. Along with thin .-la— wo 

American author*. Along 

nl lei work in the further private stud\ ul author 

study of trustworthy critics. 
Beadiug take- the n-uai 

study nt' trustworthy critics. 
Beadiug take- the usual lim 

work, when the followiog are studii 

work, when the followio 

Traveler. The Lady of the Lake, Sno« Bo 

Traveler. The Lady of the Lak 

Roger de Coverly, Raaaeias, Irving's Sketch i 

Uo^er de ("overly. Raaselas, [rving's Sketch Bo 
I'lie purpose of this part ofthi 

The purpose of this part 

fth. 

books 

books. 
The work in numbers proceeds 

The work in numbers in 

grades. Fractions, denominate numbers, 

this way from the beginning ol 

this way from the beginning of I l&gt; 

grades no text i- used, Inn both 

is given from the board. In 

text-book is put in the pupil's ban 

the board. This plan continue* 

written arithmetic text i- taken a 

three years. Following thi- is a 

of plain and solid geometry, in which the demonstral 

problems is made i&gt;l more importance than the rehears 


58 </seg>


            <seg id="p060">
59 

RINTKNDENT OK PIBI.IC INSTRlcTION. 

TIIK LABORATORY. 

ling wm furnished a well equipped laboratory. 

boratory de-k* at which twenty pupil- may 

irh three teet of working space right and left. 

Each pupil has his own bottles of reagents and 
ratu- for individual work in chemistry. Alxmt 

xpended for supplies in chemistry, and a lain* 

ree and ¦ half hours per weak under the eye nf 
red during one year. 

lucted ii]&gt;&lt; hi a similar plan, with tour hours per week 
for ¦inc year. The physical apparatus cost aboo.1 | 

5y we follow the plan of Cotton's Practical Zoology. 

of dissections and of microscopic animals are made, 
themselves with dissecting pans, scissors, etc. at a small 

,\ -o compound microscopes of about 845 diameters each are 
n ployed. Three hours j&gt;er week required. 

¦V 

iv we follow Bessey's Essentials. Microscopic work and 
form • large part ot the course. Seven and a half hours |&gt;er 
¦eqtiired for tall and spring terms during oue year. All 
work is under the supervision of a teacher and at no time 

i 

i 

\ 

DRAWING. 

grades we follow the usual industrial coarse, with practical 
in plant and animal studies. In the high school are taught 

tive, and elementary crayon sketching. It is made a 
expression in the botany and zoology studies 

required to make drawings {free handiot' all dissec&gt;pic 
examinations. These drawings are carefully kept 

.vc follow the plan of Miss Sheldon. 

if Latin are required, and besides we have au optional 
isiially taken by a pood Dumber of tin graduating das-. 

In -F 

msistilig often girls and nine boys. 

Wki.i..- II. Skinnf.i;, Superintendent. 

k.jit for tins special |&gt;ur|K&gt;se. 

1890, we graduated fifteen pupils ami have now a gradoat- </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
KDGAH l'UBLU SCHOOLS. 

At the beginning &lt;&gt;f the la 

t school year the course. 


remodeled by the removal of 

Greek and German in tin ii 
&gt;n- in tin 1 lower irrades, Mini 

ami tlic addition &lt;&gt;f oKjeet lessons in tbe lower grades. :|||( ' 

tt-rmtiliate and gmmmw grades the addition of tbe element* o 

termed iate and grammar grade 

the addition of the element 

icd sciences, civics, and American literature. These chanj 

our removal from the major or accredited list oi the SI 
The districl owns three buildings used for school pur 
- a third. Taken a- u whole, the accommodation* 

cient, which ili»- district lias taken steps to remedy. v 

cient, which ili»- district lias taken steps to n medy. W 

k.-n -steps 

dationa so deficienl the. gradiug cannot be thoroi i 

nor can the dividing line between the departments be 

nor can the dividing line between the departments 

in assignment of pupils to rooms. Bol with all ¦ 

-j-Ilm.1- have doue reasonably well. The gradual _ 

&lt;'c.n~i-.i^ (it four — two boys and 

consists nl' tour — t\v 

hw enrolled fort} -aeven pup 
The school library, now nun 

ha- enrolled fortj -seven pu| 
Th&lt;- school library, now iium 

umca, lia~ been to the pupils a -&lt; 
d volumes were added durii 
a hen- proves U&lt; me thai ¦ librarj - 

seven volumes were added during th&lt; 

where proves to me thai a library - 

ih«- taster and iu&gt;-k\~ of pupil- •- 

tbe Ihk)1&lt;- an- not of iln' proper character and grad 
ed &lt;&gt;r will develop vicious rea&lt;liu 

tbe fall term of school here, with two hundn 

the tall term i&gt;t school here, with ¦« 

,,ii.. hundred and seventeen books wen drawn 

.mi hundred and seventeen 

.\ 

pupils. In die eleven weeks of the winter term, - 

pupils. I n tin- eleven week 

had Ix-eii added, three hundred and 

had been added, three hundred and t« oks w 

while the number of pupils in 
The district has not been al 

while tbe Dumber of pupils in school did nol materially vi 
The districl has not been able to furnish either a chein 

tory or physical apparatus, hence the study of chemistn ai 

ii- lia&gt; been pursued under some disadvantages. 1 

ii~ lia&gt; been pursued under some disadvantages). l&lt;&gt; 

physiology, Yaggy's Anatomical Stud} hasbeeu a vali 

plijsiology, Yaggy's Anatomical Stud} hasbeeu avail 

jeet lessons in botany, physiology, zoology , awl physics have 

jed lessons in botany, pliysiology, zoolog_v.and physics h 

constantly, almost daily, in all the rooms Irora the first pri 

mmmir (lcn:nt nietit :ind with &gt;r,,, H | r.-ull-. At the 1 &gt;t 

grammar department, and wit 

the spring tern tbepriroaxy rooms I Mi-. I 

v 

60 </seg>



            <seg id="p062">
111 '! 

Reading. The teachers who had well-matured and 

heir own in primary work, found some difficulty in 

1 

,\a\ from their old systems, which were excellent, but they 

igeously, ;ind now take (juite kindly to the mw 

eaehers of the pa&gt;t vear have l&gt;een exceptional in 
jctcr, ;tiid ahilitv, ami to them much credit i- due tor 

r 

the schools of Edgar. 

M. R C. Tki e, PrincijKti. 

EWING ri'BLK 1 SCHOOLS. 

well graded and an in a prosperous 'condition 

i 

grades preparatory to the tour years' course &lt;&gt;t the 
h embraces all the branches required for a first grade 

In 

\ 

hi 

he addition of rhetoric, astronomy, physical 
Btory, general history, elocution, literature, aoology, 

h 

•i &gt;iii uiiy. mental philosophy, elementary chemifliy. 
Latin. 

mrse of study was adopted in 1887 
latinir class will I*' next vear. 

;n the settlen each fnraisbed a loj; to build the 
The people justly feel proud of their high sohooi 

schoulfl i- to make practical men and women out of 
teach them to think, and to develop good moral 

i 

i- mild, \ ut firm and decided, and there has l&gt;een no 
ii or expnUion during the past two vears, and eases 
-liuieni are rarely heard of. 

inn 

u-im-ii 

pom I pun 

"I the schools is good. 

I he moral imi 


61 </seg>


            <seg id="p063">

FALLS ( 

II Y SCHOOLS 

The schools here appear 

1 In- schools here appear to &lt;&lt;&gt;¦ in ,1 ven profperoi 

The liijili s&lt; i li(Hil numlifi&gt; over une hundred pupils. V^e 

lie hundred pupils. W 
studv lead i ni; to entrami 

well arranged tour yearn' course ol mikIv lead ing to entrance i&lt; 

man in tin; State (Jnivereity. The school library in- un&gt;u 

fifty volumes t" about two hundred in tin- ia-t two years. A 

Kaiik baa proven a success, receiving about threi thousand &lt;;¦ 

l&gt;ank has proven a success, receiving about thro thousan 

amounting to over $200, during the last five months &gt;&gt;! 

a ii ion it lint; to over $200, during the last five itionl 

dining hall has been fitted u| 

dining ball has been fitted up in the basement tlwt in 
ge hotel affords. An office "a- fitted 1 1 1 &gt; thi» year, paper 

carpeted by the aenior clast&gt;. N \\ slate blackboards, m 

plentv vt paint add to the comforl and looks o( our ncl 

over six hundred pupil- in attendance, ami a corps 

teachers, hacked by a generous and intelligent 

leel sure our Bchool ran L- well in thx sta 

a 

C. \ w 

GENEVA I'l I'.I.I&lt; -i IK N »I&gt; 

GENEVA ITI'.LI* -i IK 

Among the schools "t the stati 

Among the sen 

may !«¦ touiul the Gieneva schools. 

brief, and presents from yeai I 

with the lalHii incident to 

growth. Tbeschools are, at prw 

¦rrowth. Theschools are, at 

.lit] ¦ corps of nine leach 

\uil-. and a &lt;'&lt;irps of nine teachers. 
The absolute enrollment for the ye-.tr 1889 9U ¦* t- 


The absolute enrollment 

tl 

&gt; '.i 

daily enrollment, 864; average daily at tends n 

daily enrollment, S64; average daily attendan 

absence. 'I'* : number of tardies, 150; nurabi 

IMinishroent, 8; suspensions, 0; expulsions, 0. For 

months of the current year the absolute curollnient i- 4t 

daily enrollment, 400 ; average ilailv atteiulance, 382: 

aheenoe, 18: number of tardies, 135 

Kiment, 3: suspensions, 8; expulsion 
; -idiool is closelv graded into a rou 

62 </seg>




            <seg id="p064">
mary. Meond primary, first intermediate, second 

ramnuur. Each department of the lower grades, exitrv 
ami t lit- second primary, retains the pupils two 

each teacher two grades. We regret that in 
veruge age of the pupils is behind the course. This 

ii the rapid growth of Geneva many cume from 

ad vantages are either lacking or not utilized 

h children have to l&gt;e graded almost invariably below 
For instance, it is not a rare thing that pupils nine or 

I enter the tirst primary. Such diapoaitioa of them i.-iv 
l&gt;\ their absolute unfitoeaa for anv higher work. Dar- 

year we are working to a great disadvantage in iiot 

in 

Bufficienl corps of teachers. Last year the Hoard erected an 
wo-room ward building that accommodates one hundred pu- 

wtm thought that this would suffice tor two years to come, 
ovision was made for the unexpected increase in attend- 

But next summer will undoubtedly witness one or 

\ 

liMint:- in course of construction. At the city election, 

A 

M 

he school management will change from a "board of six 
a "board of education." This change will bring its . lis- 

well'a- advantages, but altogether we think the change 

¦itcr. The high school, having a membership of fifty. 
priiicipalship of Miss L. L. McGrew, B. S. In all 
Biplete system of school records is in force, compris- 

in the teachers to the Superintendent, and from 

m t'&gt; the Hoard of Education. The latter reports 
In city papers, thus keeping the public informed of 

litioil of tile »chool&gt; 

ition paper- air liound together in permanent form and 
i pin "t the records of the school. A complete record 

\ 

ikIcmi- work i- also kept in the " Superintendent'* Record," 
ok capable oi iH&gt;Dtaining such entries for twenty years, thus 

oin year to year a complete history of each student's work 
in' i in. r- ~ih.Mil until he graduates. The American Hag 

1 

•il over our schools since April 22, 1889. We claim that it 

i 

first flag floated over a Nebraska public school by order of a 

1: 

board. Tiii- order of purchase was passed by the Board of 

63 </seg>


            <seg id="p065">
64 

RKPORT OK THE 

Education April 15, 1889. The pupils also march in an 
strains of martial music furnished by some of the student 

in to tl 

P\]y bells are rang to the neond. Our tardy ami a! 
it quite what we would wish them to he, hut still \v&gt; 
i tiie Inmnds of reason. In general, our schools ar 
ctorv condition, hut there is -till much room for ii 
nccess of our schools is due in &gt;jfreat part to the rep 

nt Feeord 

nk tin 

1 1 r iv 

i 

i 

i- 

teachers' meetings, a superior li-^t of text-books, caret 
teachers and continued retention of capable one- in ser 
operation of the public, absence of saloons, and last. I 
¦ school board whose cool deliberation and united, liar 
in times of emenjencv surround 1 1 1* - schools with a 

i 

potent than all other means of success combined. 

II. I.. &lt; IIAI'I.IN 

[Hiring the past two vears Grand Island has 

n educational matters. Pwo \. u- ago then 

lation of two thousand tweutv-fiv 

hundred ninety-five. Now 

last census, is two thousan 

two, an enrollment of scho 

The schools have been greatlv 

dition to each of the Dods 

twelve room building : both heati 

two-room brick constructed in tin 

frame building. There are now th 

ings used tor study and recitation, and 

building tor the accommodation ol pu| 

The work is carried on bv a corps of thirtv-sev 

teachers. K. K. Cole i- -till principal of the Ii 

i 

during the past vear had an enrollment of one hundred 

i 

of two years ago, and from which a class of twenty -one w 

t 

ia 

last June. Mr. J. H. Thompson -till lias charge oi 

Pro!'. M. Eissenbeisa the language 

(iKAXD ISLAND S( H()( 

nii'iit in tin- schools for ih 

buildings was completed, niakin </seg>

            <seg id="p066">
Bhigfa school has practically three courses: the English, German, 
tin. nf three years each, of twenty recitations per week. Some 
however, do the work in less time. It is the aim throughout 
ole oourw, from the lowest grades to graduation, to make puf-helpers, 
to teach them where and how to gain information, 

iiid h' i\\ to do. 

¦ important feature of the schools that has become a part of the 
-ince my last report is the night school, established two years 
&lt; &gt; 1 1 1 y than who are twelve years of age or over, and who do 

Bend the day schools, are permitted to attend. The branches 
1 are reading, spelling, writing, arithmetic, and United States 
The attendance has been greater than was anticipated; not 

w gray beada being among those anxious to improve the opporiffered. 


Kbigb school library, which is constantly increasing, contains 
¦eta of encyclopedia!, with many other works of reference, 

ftrge Dumber of volumes of select reading, for entertainment 
iprovement. It is one of the objects of school to train the 
to know and love the best thoughts of the best minds. 

Robert J. Bark, Superintendent. 

&lt;;ri:kn\vood public schools. 

I Miring the past year the board of trustees at Greenwood adopted a 

¦ ot study prepared by the principal, and the schools are now 
well graded. The course is a little more comprehensive than 
Minor Course" of the University and requires eleven years for 

ipletion. A Has* of three finished it this year. 

yl'he International Encyclopedia has been added to the school liirv 
tin- year. 

( &gt;ne building, interior in architecture and repair, and quite inadeqoate 
tor present demands, furnishes the only accommodations for the 
school. It is hoped, however, that this evil will be at least partially 
remedied before the reopening of the school for another year. 

The school interests of the town was never better, and this year has 
market! an important epoch in the public schools at Greenwood. • 

A. B. Stephens, Principal. 

5* </seg>

            <seg id="p067">
65 



66 

REPORT OF THE 


I. 

¦ 


ut 

HASTINGS PUBLIC SCHOOLS 

I submit a short statement of the pied condition and pn 

the Hastings public schools. 

The line of work pursued daring the past two years has Ixvn 

much the same as that reported two years a^o, having been 

main a continuation and enlargement of the work of previous y 

¦ 

The great aim of superintendent, principals, and teachers has be 

i 

secure more definite and accurate results. 

A few changes have been made in method- and the con 

has l&gt;een remodeled and strengthened. 

The synthetic method has taken the place of other 

teaching reading and with most gratifying results ; Seelev's &lt;&lt; 

Method lias l&gt;eeii introduced in the first and second primary 

place of the method- heretofore used, and i- a ver 

not yet struck our |k-o|&gt; 

ering the expense and general utility of a manual train 

ment, it is very doubtful whether it would be expedient in ¦ city tl 

size of Hastings. 

The high school is growing in namben and advancing rapidly 

interest, earnestness, and thoroughness. Within the past rear it I 

been placed on the accredited list of the University so that n&lt; 

pupils may enter this institution from our classical course withe 

examination. A similar arrangement has l&gt;eeii made with Hast in 

College and with Doane College of Crete. 

Diplomas from our high school are also recognized by a number 

higher institutions of learning outside the state. </seg>

            <seg id="p068">
¦Hyde's Lessons in English have been introduced 
icIhts and pupilr-. 

The grade work as laid down in our course oi sttu 

easily accomplished in the allotted time for* each 

remains tor a reasonable amount of supplementary ««.i 

Musn- is taught systematically in alJ tin- grades und 

&lt;&gt;t' a t*|&gt;eeial teacher. The time devoted t&lt;&gt; tin- stud 

better employed. 

t&lt;i I • :. .: i i 

The manual tnuiiiiiir craze has not vet -truck our tx 

-I 


i 


Ban tun.- have done much toward increasing among our pupils 
tions to enter college. Doubtless more of the graduates of the 
school will, in the future, enter college. The record of the 
m.» baea good in this particular. 

The moral tune of the whole school remains excellent 

Flu- teaching force is among t lie best in the state, and the results 
•cured will hear comparison with the best. 

That the iebool is increasing in public favor is shown by the thouainl 
visit- nade to the schools by patrons during the past year. 

J. H. Moxmx, Superintendent. 

HOLDKEGE PUBLIC SCHOOLS. 

I !,. rloldrege schools have about doubled in size since you received 
esori of their condition two years ago. 

purpose to put the school in line with the University 

It 

ratorv eour* 

Koi ibe oommoii branches, including bookkeeping, civil governphysical 
geography, are completed in the grades requiring from 

halt to nine years. The high school course, as at pres- 

ranged, requires two and one-half years. In the sciences we 

ipparatua to th&gt;' atnount of $250 worth for experimental work, 
e iiis! graduating class received their diplomas "this year, accom- 

rtificate admitting the holder to the second year of the 
tv Latin school. 

synthetic method of teaching reading was introduced at the 

King of the year. The results exceeded our expectations. Some 
zarten work is done. 

In the matter of attendance the average daily attendance was very 

I reduced l&gt;y the prevalence of la grippe, measles, scarlet fever, 
iicken-pox at various intervals during the year. Tardiness has 
reduced to the minimum, there being an average of leas than 
tardy marks [&gt;er month, couuting botji morning and afternoon, 

with an average attendance of over three hundred pupils. 
Ob the play ground quarreling and fighting are seldom found. 

t moral sense of the school is on the side of truth and honesty. 
le matter of discipline, disobedience occurs, of course, but finds 

little if anv svmpathv among the pupils. </seg>

            <seg id="p069">
67 



As to aooomniodatioiM tin- 
There is in process of ered 
readv for occupancy by Oct 
$10,500. 

The board of education 
of a good school, an. I its 

appreciative community. 

.hi and arc imbued with a lies 

school lias grown faster thai 
ion a six-room building, * 
i.Ikt 1. 1890. The buildii 

alive i" i hi' needs a~ vv 

VV. R. IIai 

iir.Mi'.oi.i'i 

|( M 

The pa 

Teachers and pup 
Die people take : 

tod school tl 
ye moved ii 
children to -&lt; 

received from ih« ! 
amounts to $4&lt; I2.6( 

The crowded 

another room and 

seven room- tor stuuv am 
an eiirolhui-nt of 4i »2, ai 
departments — Primary, I 
This year five eraduate&lt;l 

ditiou of Latin to the liitrh scho 
the list necessary to place us oi 
versitv, and 1 believe before an 
to ask that our school be so reoi 

It has !&gt;een the policy of the super 
up a feeling again-t the evils of ah 
been the effect that with an increased 
decrease of 119 cases of tardiness and 

pared with the previous vear. 

Arbor day waa observed as the " Nebraska l&gt;a\ " should be o 
of Nebraska schools. Two dozen tree- were planted, ai mpa 

68 </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
(lilt' [GSChCfB IUV 6Xp8ri6II&lt; 
eir whole dutv. 


69 

RIXTEXDENT OK 1TBI.IC IXsTRVtTIOX. 

Such interest baa l&gt;een taken in these, and also 
been planted heretofore, that not a tree has, to my 

ij tired l&gt;v school children. I have prepared a plat 
-ariety, and date of planting of every tree upon the 
.1 also for whom or what dedicated. This chart 

arranged that future planting! may be recorded 
¦ ! -mil ¦ chart to the children who shall enjoy 

when thev shall have become a.s old as the 

all. 

\ secured to trees and shrubs, but to all school prop• 
led to ted that they are each part owner of all 
ES, etc., on »&lt;hool premise*. The "Damage Fund" 

Prof. Chamberlain'! regime is still maintained. All 
li an author cannot be found are paid from this fund. 

hat 'luring the past year it has been unnecessary to 
hi anv damages whatever. 

Very res] ttully. 

George R. Chatbi kn, dmptrinUmdemt 

XIXGTON PUBLIC SCHOOLS. 

- been our of uniform advancement in our schools. 
i done to litt the school in all its departments to a higher 

i has been given to a closer grading and to a closer 
se of study. Tardiness has heen greatly reduced, 

\ 

which had hitherto Iteen a great evil, has, by the appliroii 
measures) been so thoroughly broken up that cases 

i 

-til indoon and out, has been much improved. The 
pupils is excellent, and all the time growing better. 

N day a programme that was interesting and instructive was 
I iv pupils and teachers, and a large number of trees planted. 
i enthusiasm has l&gt;een created in elocutionary and literary 
pupil&gt; are taking hold of this with much zeal. By means 
nttitaiiimt'iits given by the high school, a number of vai- 
ls have been added to the library, this work having already </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
• •I \ 

( 

rk, and 

i til i 

k 


By the same means a fine, new organ will soon take the place o 
old one in the high school. 

The work in natural philosophy has been grealy stim 
purcha.se of philosophical apparatus, an excellent air-p 
electric machine. 

Six teachers, besides tin- superintendent, are employ 
will l&gt;e added the coming year. 

A chis.- of five or six vounu ladi&lt; 

w 

and graduate tin- com ing year. I 

1 i. 

course hereafter conform to t lit 

\ 

M 

Although i &gt; 1 1 1 |m 

prepare somethii 

sort of response in due \ 

school work. 

The Lincoln m'Ihhi1~ liav« 

time the board « « 1 * education ha 

houses, most ol' which rank in 
cational work, ami in warming 

the large structures referred to, tli 

costly; the " Belmoat " — a four 

ip 

city, and a similar one i&gt; in course 

fur the pupi 

i 

extreme western part of the town. 


70 


VCTM.V. 
Lexington i&gt; havii 
another commodious 
must soon 1» met, to 
roUment. 

I.I.Nt &lt; &gt;L.\ 

to the growth of the sys 

building, until at present th&lt; 

May the Dumber will be increased 
the "Prwoott school," in some resi 

of the city have buiidinga comfortable an 

plau and appearance. This accomnx </seg>

            <seg id="p072">
71 

L KI\ I KNhK.NT OF ITBI.IC INSTRIt TIO.N. 

m of the board and the community is to keep fully 
uind for mure school houses. The high school has' 
urge that the present building poorly meets the wants 


Ifii 

¦d young j&gt;eople doing advanced work, and as this 
le doubled, it is hoped that at an earlv day the city 

v a high sebool building embracing all the best 
¦in evolred in the line of -chool architecture. It 
lierwwe in a city that has sprung from comparative 

¦most rank in rapid growth, that in every departvice 
there should be a seeming lack of crvstalli- 

rily, there must l&gt;e something like crudeness in the 
public aflain when a community is suddenly c.illed 

\ 

he slow, l(H&gt;se busincaa ways of the village to those 
ess and strain of an unervstallized population of 

unqualified pleasure to say that the foundation work 
-or. Prof. K. T. Hartley, as superintendent of public 
ti-w parallel:-. The problem of beginning well was 
The rapid growth of the city tilled her schools with 
I pans of the union. Teachers had to be called in from 

id 

i 

v 

i|i with the increase of enrollment ; there was no time 
ad there been opportunity . 

iic— power and familiar with the details of school 
lageraeot, the schools under his sii|&gt;ervisiou may 
mid a position ahead of the other public enter- 

\ 

ka's ambitious capital. None of the older and more 
11 .1111 country have made opportunity to learn any 

has young Lincoln : and this state of att'airs is 

tiriiiLT superintendent, who, through his ability as 
public sentiment in the noble work of laying 

in tint " that the graded school has not done as 
g tin- people as Horace Mann prophesied. Wher- 
Is ami management it has become iron-clad, moving 

i 

H withoul elasticity, it has doubtless smothered educan 
the part of the child, and been no special help to that 
t pupils which are blessed with individual characteriii 
children arc somewhat alike, but not very alike. </seg>

            <seg id="p073">
ii'-lit 

llllllll'V 

i 

\:n 

r the support of future effort. 


In nmiiv ot the cities ot ijitro|&gt;e &lt;me eun hnd tnultitiidt** ot chil 

1 

who are " classed " bv nature as well as by surroundings, being 

nearly alike in spirit, hopes, and ability. Such material can be ¦ •! 

graded and " taught as one." Hut the children "t our ooantr 

ered in the public schools arc quite unlike in heredity, homi 

roundings, pur|&gt;ose, and capacity; and they can hut suffer 

quired to travel at the game rate in the same educational (jroo' 
The public school should !&gt;&lt;¦ for the one, a- well a- for th 

Grading, rl awning, and ranking, when they run to uniforn 

struction and discipline, are worse than the freedom ami 

where a child comes near hi- personality, he i- benefited forev 
in a sentence, schools, to l&gt;e far reaching in educative 

72 
plane," deplored l&gt;\ Massachusetts #reat secretary. Gradi 

animation, courses of study, when foremost, are like a wired 

hard, rigid, lifeless; when made incidental factors, tin 

bones in the living form, :i support to elasticity, grace, and | 

The work of a school cannol be tested in the present 

method ni' examination. It the riches! fruit of tbe school \ 

held fur ¦ season in the memory, or wth in inti 

pline. it would not !&gt;&lt;¦ ;i difficult mattei i" weigh the I 

¦ upon his pupils in an examination scale. Bui 
of the school i- an increasing mental appet 

load- ap to difficulties and conquer* 

set-k and to find that which affords cultun 

- must go by before judgment tan be r&lt; 

school has done for tin- pupil. S 

sonal " in accord with the old-time maxim, ' \ 

school." Emerson was instruct! 

daughter in answer as to what she sh&lt; 

as to irhaf she studied, lint it was oi 

irltoiii she studied. It is tar from examinatioi 

that is soon forgotten i- merely a scl 

Rigid gradation and narrow line examina 
shield to the school keeper, and a _ 

teacher. The instructor that grows Dierelj in -kill in I 

self cannot l&gt;e called a teacher. The teacher moves on ami i 

Bnstantly in all things that make character intellectual ai 
siirrouiuled by an atmosphere "I hope, irage, and t </seg>

            <seg id="p074">
I- 



il method*, con ran of study, or examinations, 

ichors iii growth, purpose, influence, and pro- 

111 name. 

Hkxhv S. JoHES, Superintendent. 

I I II IM.ATTK ITBLIC SCHOOLS. 

North lMnttc are divided into primary, secondary, 
iiM.ii . and high school, and occupy six buildin_ 
consists of the superintendent and fifteen 

mint last year readied 802, which is alxuit fifty more 
¦-'.'. and tin- ratio of the enrollment to the school census 

than it was for 1888-9. 

li.-i 

me under the present management October 14, 1889, 
lances were anything but favorable. Such is not 

i 

however. A resolution was adopted by the board 
equiring that "studies shall be taught in our schools 
ite- can enter the Freshman class of the State Univer- 

I'lll 

itated nme very radical changes in the high school 

drafted a high school course meeting the require- 

i 

ution, reclassified the entire high school, and put all 
if the course in operatioa. A member of the faculty 
er-it\ vi.-ited the schools January 31, 1890, and as a 

our schools were placed on the minor course of ac\\ 
e were visited again in October, and our schools 

rcourae. The pupils who graduate next June 
Freshman class of any department of the Uni- 

irchased aboal sixty different kinds of chemicals, and 
pparatus, and these, together with &gt;uch apparatus as 

i 

I 

nir interest and profit to the study of chemistry, 
gether with an increase in salary, partially b&gt; 

la 

we are making and the gcxxl feeling which now 

i 


73 </seg>


            <seg id="p075">
\t II 


OMAHA PUBLIC SCH&lt; 

&gt;Ul 

eiently full to excuse more than a brief statetu 

i 

general way the plan of organization, and tin 

tin course of study was then -ii forth, and tlii 

new ii 

I'll*- -rhools have expanded u 

w 

prosperity lias suffered no interruption. The iusl 

thorough and the discipline ax satisfactory as at an 

&gt;rv as at a 


From tin- 

ti&gt;-~ are rather 

Total n ti mix 

NiiinUr cm 

Averai 

Number em 

NiiniUr &lt; in 

Nunilicr 'in 


X mil I mi- enr 


Number en 

Number ol 

Number ¦ ! 

Number of tea&lt; 

From fines 
From Uxe 

74 </seg>

            <seg id="p076">
Tlio report &gt;&gt;t' the schools of Omaha made i» 

r;i&gt;t year— balau 
licenses 

B state apportionmeul . 
other sources 


f~. .\ I r* JN i*i i \_ [^ r*^ . 

3204546 12 

I 

1023.? SI 
30525 15 

29710 30 

13447 48 

11576 89 

5472 54 

«47H 13 

2103 23 

1697 31 


5779 91 

1944 65 

2264 73 
11)04 70 

1091 7.5 
1199 66 

$344394 48 
£2*5*4 19 

1888 were largely occupied with construction, 
six permanent l&gt;rick buildings were erected, 

school room*. Their total uost was £217, 
tijM&gt;!;uv wooden buildings, with two row 

iiu thirty room more. In the last two years 
!&gt;• t" provide room. That mure is needed m 

amount paid for rent. This want is well un- 
I "I education has made several attempt! to 

it lia- asked the voters for authority 

I line: 

purpose, but in every case through diaagraatrstanding, 
or some technical error, the appli- 

I Ilia explains the large item of election ex^&gt;eii-.es 
;iven above. The need of more room has l&gt;eeorue 

activity in building is now inevitable 

ntly instituted a teachers' training school, which 
Deration. Ii oonantsof a theoretical department. 

I, psycl 

itlucatiooal history, methods of instruction, and 

75 </seg>


            <seg id="p077">
school iHtmoinv are studied, and the ooauaoa branch 

teacbera are required to conduct a school, under th&lt; 

critic, for :i sufficient time to (rain a lm&gt;&lt;k1 dec 

teaching. 

&lt; &gt;ne purpose of the 

rules governing it. i- to elevate the standard of instruct 

provided thai no one can enter thi~ training depar 

cation i- nut equal or equivalent to that reqtiin 

the Omaha high school. With tlii- lii^li standa 

y i" 

memlierg, al ! of w f 

While tl 

¦ia bcI 
or teach ii 

inaiiituiii fro 
ichers. 

O'NEILl 

TbeO'Neill scho. 

Tin- -i.\ rooms hav 

required in the grammar de] 

u 

includes all the branches 

general history, zoology, 

law. and commercial arithmi 
Two years ago wo introdm 

results lH)th pleasant and profitable. Las) y 

In 188&lt;&gt; there were tiv&lt;- graduates from our hi 

there were seven; in 1888 there were two; in 1889 there w 

in 1890 there were seven. 

76 </seg>


            <seg id="p078">
a department of practice, in which perrons desirio 

&lt; -« &gt; i &gt; i- — ? - (it mMi hi l ion i&gt; mti 

ited to one year, an 

grades mix! tire hijjli sch 

teachers the | 
all tir&gt;t clast 

3'2u. ( &gt;ur course &lt;&gt;t -u\&lt; 

synthetic method of reading, wii 



¦KM OF PURLIC INSTRUCTION. 

77 

¦ell supplied with maps, charts, globes, etc., 
iterial for both teachers and pupils. 

A 

principal of the O'Neill schools, and we 
mil progress with much satisfaction and 

i school of more than .'500. 

Iuiin Blaxd, P&gt; imvipml 

ipervision ot tin- school two vears ago, 
&lt;\ ju-t voted the chance from a common 

Almost everything coacnttal to moicked 
everything in the way of apparaibrary 
; no 'luck and ooly ¦ few majw 

I 

luge aii' I have printed a course of study, 
'¦&lt;l t" i»&gt; inestimable. The classification 

&gt;\vs 

departments 
partiuents. 

partment. 

ach primary and intermediate, oih 
irs in the hi^h sclioul department. 
we have produced something like order 

ii which we found the school. We have 
t&gt;f attendance, l)iit we have added much 

nil paid for a $65 organ, a fine clock costing 
rv mii band. The people here have been 

n/iiiLT "in" entertainments. 

¦esort tn the exhibition plan for raising funds : 
belief thai a great deal is. -acriticed in the 
nore or lew injustice is done to the school in 
iiinent of any nature or character whatever. </seg>

            <seg id="p079">
i 

in enterta 


&gt;\ PUBLIC SCHOOLS. 

!iini&gt;'iit-i — a necesary evil, it must be ad- 

Kirehaae these school room necessities, the 


i 

The public should be educated to that fact ami boards should i- 

erooa in amply supplying their schools with n 

.:tr\ 

However, a- we enter upon our third year here a- [win 

a- 

eocovraged with the prospects. That we have an enterpi 

intelligent class, of people here is well known, an&lt;l wi i 

the time when their attention will !»¦ il 


Everv vear our I » ian I -i em 

in 

inonev lor tin- well 

to the State Siiiierinteiidi nt 

"71 


i 


ti. 

ii 


w 


\- 


loi 



V to ' V 

' Kir w&lt; &gt;i u is 1 1 1 u ¦ - 

pupil-. Thus tar u 

pupil-. Thus 

pour claw. VVe bel 

text-book sy-iciii is 
That our school i 

that our daw of 18 

Doane college*. 

78 </seg>




            <seg id="p080">
NKI.K.II 1TULK SCHOOLS. 

¦upy two briek buildings and have a 

n teachers. The number of children in t lie 
id the total enrollment for t lie year reached 348. 
portani year in the history of the schools. a- it 
graduating das.- from the high school — a class 

ft'ort9 of the graduates at the commencement 
satly in increasing the public interest in the 
have U-* n led to see more in the schools than 

war liiirli school course, with the usual grades 
.'h school we do work in mathematics, natural 
itorv, literature, and Latin. 

the departments of the school to impart only 
• pupil &lt;-:m fully comprehend and reproduce. 
ivatingtbe power of expression — both oral and 
ii|}|ia-i/i'd. 

healthful tendency of retaining teachers for ¦ 
oritv of tin- teachers of the schools have been 

successive vear. 

vails among the teachers and the Injard, there 
co-operation all around, and the school runs 

: this condition tells u.s that the |&gt;eople realize 
tut schools and are ready to work together for 

hat end. 

II. ( '. Ostikn, Principal. 

( &gt;nl have for the past year occupied three 

• high school building of brick and two rented frame 
The high bcuooI building and grounds are valued at 
the buildings are healed with stoves. The equipments 

mi. A 

harts, a globe, slate blackboards, etc., having been 

r : n i:i I 

time, and a good chemical laboratory, a fair reference 

r 7-oiin 

79 </seg>

            <seg id="p081">
•h 

\ 


• &gt;i;i&gt; ITM.IC SCHOOLS. 


80 

REPORT OF THK 

volants having recently been added. Seven teachei 

ployed and there is urgent need fur another. Tl 

nine grades in the elemeutarv schools and three in 

tlms requiring twelve year.- to complete the present* 

studies. Since the great majority of pupil 

SIDNEY Tl 

Sidney boasts of oue of ih&gt; 

In 1887 the magnificent ed 

Epect, well lighted, ventilated 
npleted and furnished at an i 

iIk.ii! S1K 

time the pablic schools have been | 

\ 

MMciation of principals and superintendents o&lt; \ebra 
adopted, and in .June. 1891, there will be a graduatin </seg>

            <seg id="p082">
i. 

iiUriir\^ iiiKi it ciioiilQiiiii^ li ' )i*nr\* or &lt; ti i* • liiiiiilrttl ;in 

Pile public schools have uetn progressing 
correspond iii£ to three years' Latin cour» 

lii^jli school is reached, very great care i- take 

in the recognized essentials, in busi ness forms, a 

is omitted from the elementary scIkkjIs. I canii 

tin- resulta of the objective methods employed ii 

Rhetorical exercises are made somewhat •¦( . 

cially in the high school. Koine contests for &lt;t&gt; 

been held for two years [»ast, tin successful cont&lt; 

district contest. 

&lt; &gt;i i r higl 

versity, and Ijesides, il aims I 

n Imj i n .- i \ 

&lt; Mir firel 

&lt; Kir selii 

entire enrollment I 

¦ of rea 
public sentiment i- -n- 
is good, the d - 

education is umiisiki 

o 


81
I 

\ I KNDKNT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION. 

i 

based by the high school and much new apparatus 

m school board, ever alive to the interests of the 

) 

a specialist from the east to take charge of the 
lent, which ha» just recently been made a feature 
school will then have six departments, and will 
|uipped schools in the state. The free text-book 

gives universal satisfaction. The prospects for 
iv favorable, indeed. 

i year- the school ha- had the hearty co-opera- 

The press, too, has been always ready to lend a 

\ school column has been conducted by the high school 

weekly papers, and has been productive of mnch 
of the school is due very largely to these facts, 
t that tin' principal has been supported by an ex- 

hers and a live school board. 

rved in 1889 and again in 1890 in as elaborate 

tut Sidney's school children to celebrate. The in— 
n- matter has done much towards beautifying the 

the virtue- that we have striven to inculcate iu 
eve we have succeeded. On Memorial day, 

&lt;i. A. K., presented our public schools with a 

mdsomely inscribed, which cost §o0. The pre. 
made by the Hon. Adam 1 ekes, commander of 

esponded to by Judge Shuman, president of the 
ntlemen laid stress upon the idea that pupils 

the flag, as on that teaching the very safety 

8. On February 5, 1890, amid appropriate 
; 1 1 ¦ flujj, was unfurled from the dome of our 
fwenty-first Infantry band, through the kind- 

\ 

Morrow, was present and enlivened the occasion. 
_: raising by a public school in western Nebraska. 

\ 

shed in the leading dailies, and the agitation of 
lowed has been felt throughout the state. Let 

On Memorial day, 1890, one of the proniiprocessioa 
was a delegation from the school, con- 

n Uncle Sam, a Hag bearer, twenty-three boys repdi 
nt-. and forty-two girls representing the states of 

l ni"d 

Dg our i </seg>


            <seg id="p083">
82 

KKPORT OF THE 

Bnion. We tliink we have not uiv&lt;n too much 
t of patriotism in the schools, for we have certa 
things which will promote aud develop good &lt;ii 

Much more miirht lie said on -til 

w 

oar school, lint nut wishing to occupy 

W. .1. \|, ( 

grades one veai 

Tl. 

provided 

rooms, tw 

raratus 
(¦omiiK 

nini'xl 

gate a 

and beaut i 
Three ti 

Kiate depa 
1 the selii 

general or special 

the past three years specia 
chemical supplies, micros) 
j^arten supplies, eneyclopi 

purchased to the amount of $600. 
eaeli student for a complete one-y&lt; 
and specia] apartments mi apart fo 
has the hoard of education exhibit 
needed educational facility and aci 

progress on the part of both pupils an 
ported tne progressive uleas and actions </seg>



            <seg id="p084">
U'KKh H; iti;!.!i v, 11. m ii 

&lt; &gt;ur com 

mediate, and 
riic-,' three 

Irten has been i 
All l»ifik&lt;, pa 


83 

s 

IKNUKNT OF PIBI.IC IXSTRIXTIOX. 

divided into tour classes or grades one year 

i 

rh -ctinol department during the out-going year, 
boys finished the twelve years' work and were 
ttd nation. These have had three years in Latin, 
oratory work in chemistry (two horn's each school 
- Elements &lt;&gt;t' Physics, one year in general hisii 
in geometry, one and one-third years 
nrtional periods in the other branches, including 
development of English Liter.it tire, with essays. 
¦• -nieiit, of one hundred plants a tm I v/ed, recorded, 

\ 

I 

icli member of the graduating class 

the part of the teachers and superintendent 
irs "ii that unsolved problem of the schools, 

tematixe :i branch of learning as to tiud the protliat 
branch, and so to learn it, lias yielded 

two years, such a rich reward a&gt; lias lifted the 

in w degree &lt;&gt;t proficiency, interest, and pride, 
we can efficiently learn to solve the problems 
we solve them under the guidance of the 

rule-, formulas, and author's conclusions. 
learn (say) grammar, or any other branch, by 
I that branch until we tir&gt;t discover that 

burden of our work is to find out what syshe 
branches. 

SITTON ITHLK' SCHOOLS. 

.1 Sutton occupy two buildings,— the high school 
id building. The high school building, conlins 
eight rooms and the superintendent'i office. 

attractive, :m&lt;l well supplied with the latest 
ind ventilation. The ward building, coutain- 

del of neatness. The grounds are beautifully 
shrubs, and Sowers. 

h tret 

I '&lt;¦ sides the supet 

intendent, who teaches a part of his time, ten 
d. 

hen are employ 

Iv\a&lt; E. Wiijson, Superintendent.</seg> 

            <seg id="p085">
84 

REPOHT &lt;&gt;F THK 

The schools are graded a 

marv departments, two tirst and on 

one grammar department, and one In 

follows: three tirst and iw 

sond intermediate 

high school department there an- two courses of study, the I 

and the classical. Three yean arc required for theconiplet 

course. In the classic course 

w 

up 

Latin. Pupils completing this course are adm 

of VI 

i 

selected literal 

The who. 

also with Vagg\ - ' '« 

( 

i 

:;::: 

•p 

The peopl&lt; 

It has been sub 
efficiency ol t In 

he teacher 

¦&gt; 

The majority of then 
universities in the cou 

work they have ill hand. A 

fth unity of purpose. 
Thus equipped and &gt;u\ 

inrt 

pared lor effective work and w i 
in the furtherance "(' the cause 

li school departi 

yew of tin- Latin school of the Cniv&lt; 
;iml nation. In the |&gt;ninai\ denartmen 

of teaching reading 
been most ijratifvinj 

The seho&lt; 

tkelibe 
edu&lt;-al 

&lt; &gt;ur I.. </seg>

            <seg id="p086">
Eii|i;itli\ wit I 
chers as are 
. U-rii at al 


\H&lt;M) ITBLIC SCHOOLS. 

la are in good working order. Tardiness is deodance 
is constantly increasing. Out of a school 

re were enrolled last year 70&lt;&gt; pupils. The city 
iperintendent made a special effort to enforce the 

ear. The results were highly satisfactory. 
system of reading was adopted last year. Teach- 

re delighted with it. We are making an effort this 
ter readers, writers, and spellers. Drawing receives 

t 

t the teachers and superintendent 

,\ two elegant brick houses. One of these, a four-room 
north ward, was erected during the past summer. We 

ae-room frame buildings in the west ward. The cenmtains 
the high school and seven other rooms. Our 

1 1&lt; It — twelve years, with four of these years in the 

ii\ well equipped with reference books, maps, chart?, 
( Kir 100 volumes of choice books were placed iu the 

i-t year for general reading. This was mainly 
¦ I 1890. This class numbered eleven, six boys 

class of 1889 numbered fifteen, six boya and niue 
iced a magnificent Hag upon the central building. 

employed, besides a superintendent who teaches 
The moral tone of the school is good. Teach- 

sive. Citizens a unit for good schools. Board, 

the best interests of the |&gt;eople, are ever ready to 
1 ma! ion in Wahoo. 

T. H. BRADBURY, Superintendent. 

85 </seg>



            <seg id="p087">
WILBEK ni'.LK 

The school year just dosed has been 

We liavc had an enrollment of S92 pi 

umx has been very poor owing to the | 

of that dread disease, diphthc 

ria. I iv w 

won- taken awav .from us 

\\ i have two buildini; 

n 

room-, ami 1 1 

r;u 

now ilo the work of tin 
iwing raj 

( )ur couix 

admitted to th 
ination. 


SCHOOLS 

uch tortv 

iiiai bru 

\M 

(i 

86 



B700 worth of appai 
volumes. 

pate ;i pleasaul an 

liilv proMM 

)}]l~, Illlt </seg>

            <seg id="p088">
K.\ STATE TEACHERS' ASSOCIATION 

a; Lincoln, March •.'."),-iti, -27, 1890, 

US READ BEFORE THE ASSOCIATION 

\ </seg>



            <seg id="p090">
II 


II R. fdKBKTT, AIRORA. 

I it is -aid there hangs ¦ curioua specuBea 
epresents the scent' from Virgil's iEaied, in 
Si I iv 1 of Cutnea. 

well designed, and its unities are perfect, except 
nl tin- one it is chiefly noted. Tlie hero, .Knea-. 

nan t&lt; «u:i erf Virgil's own tim?, and the co-tutue 
t of a court ladv of the Augustan age. This 

ed out as a warning to young designers, to teach 

I 

i.-- of time. On either hand is hang a sketch 
lie saint' necessity. On one side, Kapoleoa's 
iinn are seen, haranguing a Macedonian pha- 

Egyptian pyramid! &lt; &gt;n the otlier, a knight of 
in full armor, with bared helmet and shining 

¦'I. witli lance in rest, is trying to balance himself 

ning. In the galleries of the mind we are 
And these designs we are u-ing as models in 
D a 

plans, our live-. Now into our ideal pie- 

onal processes, there are likely to creep just such 
nisbed tlie painting in that European art school. 
o of to-day may still go forth to battle equipped 

i 

- of an age we have left l&gt;ehind; or, on the other 

i 

on the bicycle, weighted down with the cuin- 

ior ¦&gt;( present surroundings, he may throw himself into the 

Kble equilibriun 
r-t, then, the t 

i of an Utopian hobby, fit for the future only. 
eaeher of to-day is not the teacher of the past. 
are those who receive his instruction for the actual 
&gt;ince the responsibilities the youth of to-tlay nnw </seg>

            <seg id="p091">
worf 

pie! 

t' lite ; and 

-!. 

igli ¦ telephone; while another knight, simi- 

rtists, lint there u ;i class of pictures we are 


meet, and the demands made upon them, differ • 

from those of the pa*t, he imi-i modify hi- educ 

accordingly 

It seems certain that tin 

her defense or her glorv. &lt; mwaverin 

t 

endurance of (at 

everv gasp "t svmpatm 

ilcniaii'lti 

in 

?'ducat Ion \\ :i- 

What 

w 

want 

moral 
eallin. 

«\ver, 

in 

tin 

Hut 

are a- 

iii-i 

Hei.l) 

trlvphir in 

and method 

cannot rush prernati 

methods untitt.-.i f»n 

cannot materialize idea 

•» 

them. To prepare for them is the work of iim : 

them into untimelv birth injures his pro»j&gt;ec( 

ways, and precipitates an opposition to hi- progi 

will delay still longer the time when they are to pi 


90 </seg>

            <seg id="p092">
Kirm \v:is \u train Sparia.ru 
ed her laws and customs ;i 

tlav. it' he is wise, w 
V^ain. the teacher &lt; 

was one of the errand tlidai 

timl gifted with a penetratii 
itiiii: is more trying than tii' 

ol developing ideal theorii 


lucator'a high privilege ami solemn duty 
tetter things. 1 1*- should not only be abreast 

ii trout of the i&gt;o|)ular line of progress. 

cautiously, judiciously chosen, lest he lose 
attempt ; yet, when he sees that the time&gt; 
hum take it firmly and boldly. So, while 

Ih- future, he must walk in the light of 

lie other 

tlie inquiry, hat are the present social and 

call tin 1 positive characteristics in the teach 
tionably these times are making certain de 

ignored. Prominent among these is the claim 
iliim should be arranged in accordance with the 

if a busy life. Give ua practical traimmg, i-^ the 
v. Probably so one disputes its justice. The 

II hat i.i practical/ It has received a great va- 

ii eat folly such a subject would, of course, Bur 

of this paper. Aa in all vexed questions, twoexlided 
; tui. .hi the one hand there may still linger 

work which have outlived their day, and 

useful and no /exs ditciplinary instruction 
demands of the times. 

, the restless spirit of the age is leading us too 
aii I material we cannot spare in building strong 

laracten for oar boys and girls. Perhaps I can 
le illustration than the disposition to slight lan- 

more practical than to understand the vehicle of 

\\ 

of books and printing, a liberal education i&gt; 
mon — -within the pomemitm of every one who 

nl&lt; i-tand. The study of the construction and exact 
if sentences, the cultivation of a large linguixtic 

lirement of an accurate literary taste, these should be 
tiling- objected to by the man who urges a practical 

i 

for modern times; for a habit of inaccuracy in lannt 
satisfactory results in any line of studv and in anv 

ta 

a ill prev 

And thi&gt; particular subject is merely representative 
lucational prooasaw of perennial usefulness and impor- 

n lit 

91 </seg>



            <seg id="p093">
8ige has ever required of its educators a kerne 
real reforms, and s]&gt;ecious sophistries attacking 
e features of school economy. Never did the »•&lt; 
&gt;re loudly tor men with heart and brain, with 
nitnoa sense. No normal training can ever - 

idgm 

mi 

icationa 

up, 

these innate qualifications; and until such men can liav 
the salaries ami the independence they can command ii 

i 

the character of our educational work will notappruw 

rapidly, although we establish a normal school 

In the midst of the hurry ami enthusiasm 

A 

uj&gt;on a detailed discussion of the evils of foreign en 

we hail with joy the movement all along the line to make ou 

the conservators of true Americanism. The tendency  

92 </seg>

            <seg id="p094">
there i&lt; a marked tendency toward a disregard tor who 

meat. The very w&lt;ml sentimental, vnu know, lias *&gt;m&lt; 

disapproval and repugnance. This facl scarcely n 

it is evident to all. To exall oul ol all due pro 

promises an immediate return iti dollars and cents; 

cut in the race for wealth without excessive scrui 

to prefer the superficial and 
cation by the speediest method, no matter 

ness : in prefer tlu 

to laugh in the sleeve 

noblest sentiments of | 

gether; are not a 

And need I say the teachei 

wavering firmness"' In the* 

what reward will Im- more m 

sacrifice than the consciousness 

the social lite of to-day ol il 

it f &lt; &gt;r all of its splendid individua 

One of these neglected sentiments 

tion to the sentiments of thi 

spire to reduce our patriotism. o\ 

tutions to a minimum. &lt; Iiief among tin - 

raw foreign material into our body politic. Mo 
the world's history ever accepted such a diet witl I 

ysp 

dissolution. We reassure our hearers, however, we an 

nol 



itol here in our enterprising capital city. Two 

have passed within about ¦ month — those of 
Iri-h Emmet. No ball in the city would hold 
\ 

ed to honor the latter. Tlie governor pre-1 
eulogiuma were dispensed with polysyllabic 

birthday of the Father of His Country (tassetl 
xcept for an enthusiastic obaei tanee in lier ex- 
Li this iToiMl work of the teacher go on, I^et 
at Americans be celebrated with joy and pride; 

l«es ti\ from every school bouse tower ; andabore 
American citizen of to-morrow tliat tliev cm l&lt;e?t 

»y preparing to-day lo live noble and useful lives, 
gratification that we turn our attention a nioment 

educational system toward the temperance issue. 
tut rniih from the moral oomscioutntm of the peo- 

umentality now at work to produce that popular 
finally dispose of the whiskey business can i&gt;e 

r 

lul :i&gt; the systematic and sensible temperance inven 
in many, and ought t&lt;&gt; be given in all, of our 

laws are with as here. We need not tight tor 
ipng in this work of paramount importance. 

1 

i are neglecting this imperative and sacred duty, 
hool tike children who will soon U- the nation's 

oroughlv prepared to think and act aright on 
stion nt the age, what excuse will von have to 
r own conscience and that of injured society? 

— the insufficiency of mental training alone 
Statistics do not show that education and 

ratio, but that they sometimes keep pace who 
n have most criminals where we have least 
greatest rascals to-day arc nlncaled rascals. 

r, 1 &gt; 1 1 1 a power which may become a danger and a 
ii ml. like the power of the lightning or the run- 

kcberwbo develops this highest form of energy 
it to-day to see the stay-chaina of morality- are 

1 

- in hi- power to supply or strengthen them. I 
¦ diacuM at length bow this is to be done. I can </seg>

            <seg id="p095">
t 

|o Illlle 111 

93 





94

who is the "foremost man "I tlie world " to-dav, in br 

ship and keen i 1 1 ~ i *_r i 1 1 into the needs 

kI tliem will »av Gladstone. Here i« one of !ii- 

anon: "My only hope for reforming the work! li&lt; 

into contecl with the truth* of divine rev 

whole hope "t human progress is -u~| &gt;&lt;-m 1 

Him ii. i- of the Bible." H"\\ applv these prinoip 

¦ it' long chapters ami the »tai 

ii 

judgment deems that 

judgment deems that the m 
guided li\' the* 

guided bv 'I 

apoki ii, &lt;1&lt; their in 
In com 

w 

III &lt;ii|) 


How ' "p. iiiiii 
induo 


IIKl-i- 


¦I 

i: 

- ()1 tlllKl 

against 

mand an&lt; I 

main! an 

THE BOY !\ I 

THE IKIV IN 

The lii^'li school is with u 

The lii^'li school i- with n 

The f 1 1-— t object of every on( 

The first object of evei 

make it as far reaching in 

make it as far reaching ii 

possible. The subject, therefore, 

in the high school, as those who 
The boy who enters the high 

in the high school, as those who -houKl !»¦ in it 

Tlii' boy who enters the In^li school and conti 

end lms acquired the habits that, </seg>



            <seg id="p096">

] 

i 

i 

\ 

iV 

I 

ire t 

practica 

ition, will iiuikt* hini successful 111 anv etill- 

niry, the graduate! — college and hinh 
ier oeni of the mule population, yet this 

per cent of tin- offices of oar govern meut. 
either supplemented by ¦ college education 

ions cit' honor, trust, and profit. They 
ilia, on the judges' bench, in the minis- 

hools, colleges, and universities, and as ¦ 
and upright citizens. 

rreci of the civil service coannwMOB, 7fi par 
11 high schools, 36 per cent of the graduates 

inivt r-ities. "27 per cent from our oommoa 
i from oar commercial colleges and our nornter 
the examination pass it satisfactorily. 

,-olumes lor the pupils in our high schools, 
in, and of the thoroughness and effectiveness 

Mm what is of still vaster importance, it 

Ilk picture, and to tins 1 would like to 
il ih&lt;- boys wiio should be in the high 

niav in- -aiii of the girl 

i of •lime rolls around, educational journalparts 
of the country inform us that froaa 

graduate, to where there is one young man 

from statistics it appear- that more of the 
high schools are in them than of the Im&gt;v.-. 

lore the question of the hour than shall 
ill on our public schools, whether calislie 
Swedish Sloyd system, or whether pho. 
other graphy shall be taught. These are 

n ran answer, but to answer the question 
in the hiiih school until they graduate, will 

i-t all should have, and all have methods 

eached. The American Ik&gt;v of the present 
iti liis ideas, and is essentially a boy ot one 

95 </seg>


            <seg id="p097">
i; 

!; 


Ill Mil 

• xpression.s 

Bhrnetic, liegin il 
ngts arc made i 
mtinue through 
i- ways. First, 

In 

in 

with these studies as options. St 
ing these. Third, by carrying 

schools adopting either will ueoessarilv depend uj 

96 </seg> 



            <seg id="p098">
' WO ll&lt; 111' h 

i&lt; I*-;! ; u nil , like nil persons » » t one : 
omplish tiif object "! tin- one ii&gt;;i — 

l&lt; 

He forgets, or does nut think 

all cannot be bankers, niouev broker.*, 

exchange. In this fbrgettiilness, 

r directlv uixjn I live. He, 

¦ i" ili'- rourses of stud ¦ 

aii- 1 1 &gt; 'T practical, I' musi 

i &gt; i 


\ 

ui.iu generally will remove another eau&gt;e 

og boya from our high school. It will, 
le in regard to dropping behind thecla»s. 

mil honestly, but fails to complete all 
;ir. i- no disgrace. Thedisgrace lies in 
ters.and all concerned in the welfare of 

the coming man should &gt;eek to iin- 

'the boy that nut failure, bat low 
:iin i- low aim. But a boy should 

ise be ha- failed to make the 
many times, better to let him 

i iihi-t important branches, or all of 
class work, if bv these means he can 

two longer, than a too rigid enforcement 

h grades 

,,f h 
(1 fr 

eradicat 

in the mind of the 

1 !-l'c- 1 )f( 

¦s tor their children is an 
we more often made at 

lip at sacnhi 

also an admitted fact of 
make- sacrifices that his 

uim !iU!'po-e 

\\ 

parent 

good school, and sees to it that the 

',- right, i&gt;ut it the parent does not ste 
u i- required of him, the sacrifice had 

Me, if it were possible, the boy 

lor. Work is frequently urged as a 
When it is urged by .the boy that he 

mi he wants to be doing something; that 
lo nol be deceived, teacher; d&lt;&lt; not be dey-nine 
cases out of every hundred it is not 

iat be want-, it i- work from which he is trvows 
that work will come to him sooner if lie 

II.,', work than when found lounging on street 
sea. Be sure the latter is what he wants, for 

it he i- permitted to have his will. 

1 

in their bovs to school with the determination 
itinue up to graduation, and then live up and 

ild 

n 

97 </seg>

            <seg id="p099">

quirements 

t' tin- school, then a sac- 


makf the boys live up to it. the preseni M 

Give the boys time for recreation and amue 

ni-li them continuous employment during 

ni-h them continuous era ploy men t 

i 

them have do time for loafing, if you won 

them have do time for l'i;iliinr. if vou would 

honorable manhood. &lt; h\&lt; sunin 

them from school. 
I have statistic!! w liicli pro 

I" 

ai ¦ h;i- ii"!. to any greal 

has IV 




n 


98 </seg>

            <seg id="p100">
St. Louis in.ii 

Ji stamlii 

Bur upon speci 
loral character, 

L r ;iiii/&lt;&lt;1 cm liii — plan draw 

them after these precautio 

numv manual tram 

iidt all however are 

Philadelphia, where ii ;¦ 

oiir:ini/cil on a more ration; 

&lt;'itv. places the privileges u 

sidn to the hiirh school, and 

«&gt; 


99</seg>
 
            <seg id="p101">
NI»KNT OF ITJSI.K 

rssTRUcrioN. 

aminatioo, and the recommendation of a priu- 

100I, it as ctlW'ttiiilly excludes the boyi for 

m the manual training schools as does tlie St. 

defect in the organisation than in th&gt; 

bools were so organised that they would 

itch boys in charge instead of the more 

not all woo Id continue through to gradualiowever, 
only a belief*, and so tar the only 

ning open to thete is tin- reform school aud the 
itement that these bova are unfit tor the society 

i~ a pernicioaa one; since tlie community is 
influences wbiefa have made them what they are. 
time that the public school otlicers and teachers 
mi: these pupils, and to begin to give them the 
c&lt;l i me-. 

i 

s them that are worth saving to a noble poipose. 
ii and women, want tlie applause of the world. 

i 

id like them, toil for it. The manual training 
ore no more to be censured than individuals in 

ause thev confine their labora to the verv 

t liiu'h school pupils. At present these schools 
esa and applause; and they seem to fjet both 

ictical results emanating from them yet 

not In- said to add anything of advantage to the 
u-e unless it is willing to open its doors, to put 

who are less gifted and to those who in after 
reform schools, and penitentiaries, and attemp. 
and upright citizens of them. 

i schools are organised on the same plan as the 
m|. the same conditions and results obtain in them 
1 have Keen able to gather them, fail to show 
lame where these schools are in o|ieration above 
•n the natural increase from increase of popula- 

I 

¦i 

I 

1 and 

1 aim of education is to furnish a more complete 
ill the powers of the individual, mental, moral, 
ewed in this liirht, both systems fail to reach the 

\ 

velo] 

ical. then, vi 

•d it most. 

bovs w 



Bual training 
90 as i" br 

what the high 
¦ i&gt;e ali;: 1 

win, geea tin' pitfall- in the pat I 

and convictions that belon 

walk in the path that leads to I 

shrined, peerless forever. 

100 </seg>


            <seg id="p102">
gpondingly increased. 
[f burdens imposed &lt;l" n&lt;&gt;t lessen existing • 

imposed. 

wudbeas &lt;&gt;t the growis 
characterizes tho brute, 


!&lt; head of aflairs. It is lietter that a 

e ¦second generation than that tbcaoa 
ndfather to two or three freoerationa iu 

i- lord it over the father, teachers 
11 attempts it over the teacher, come 

:i- strong home government, and I know 
will take them from school so soon as the 

ne-tenthi; of the disorder and ruffian I ike cook»vs. 
Sometimes even vet vou hear the cant 

liould be made so pleasant and attractive 
ould not even want to stay away. 

I utter contempt of one who advocate 

of the classical language of the nineteenth 
v seedy or verdant, or both. Many times 
i the abodes of the blest, which an infinite 

d for his children, describing its beauties; 
ive the bovs listened to the same. What 

I'rav then do not a»k one to do with a teacher's 

ire tn blame for the non-attend- 

nsciouslv 

11 

ved, and when deserved, but uncalled for, 

when some other method of pun- 

us and "tit nt' the school for no other rea- 

liad not done for them what 

ivored "lies 

\\. for as a rale teachers have a much greater 
of those committed to their care than many 

V 

:- is not enough. The teacher must study and ansposition 
as well aa that of his pupil and eliminate 

101 </seg>

            <seg id="p103">
V 




li will place so many boya in our liigli 

-Imih ran no) do. Pujiils are generally -ensi- 
weak points. And teachers sometimes con- 

rcasjn in respect to his ability, 

-dim 

on's sake to Btine dull and back- 


troiii it all crankiness, vindictiveni 

grudge- against troublesome pup 

i 

philanthropy ami generosity "f soul. \\ lien pup 

it -Imuld be otherwise than with 

i 

¦ lit' till' teU.cllel 
ten, but the w&lt; 
ten. 

I'll 

ikIs 

Li-t it ii"t 

Bovs iiiu-i h*vi 
will so from Iiohx 

t ut uri ¦ w 

tin kill'i 

varioii- kiiii 

up a class 
¦ ¦ar. I- 

ertv. TJi 

¦1 


Buds in tin- n 
ill not Ion:: 

TIil' amusements 

the barroom and tinfact 
there should be w 

home cease to make experts 

there, if suitable amusements are supplii 
It is generally conceded thai the sal 

ami mdirectlv from the Inirh scl I thai 

102 </seg>




            <seg id="p104">

jiii|n! iiiln tin 

automatons. 
1 1 nun '••¦ 

ilv 1 

Bav |iiav 
al influ 
the «l 

in which the ilangei 
It is lull a step ti 


ity to which this institution tit" public favor 
ie scenes of violence, disorder, lawlessness, and 

tccuatonra the boy, only too soon brings him 
estruction of the borne, the unmanly and un- 

I run ken father, the disrespect which it breeds 

is- for a life of shame awl crime. 

tii. 

f these things and the gentlemanly 

tast 

he rights of others, and a quiet, manly Bobity, 
which are the tir»t requirements toevery 

me irksome to him, and it he continues 
imy, sullen, and insubordinate boy : and a 

n the order of the school finally secure- him hi 

ii 

irathi'j. a high, refined, virtuous, and intellectual 

\. vicious, depraved manhood. 

evil but ilif abolition of the saloon. 1 he 
ni much longer continue to exist a- it now 

f drunkards or a nation of total 

nation 

r the salvation of our manhood, 
in- govern men t we most educate 
ovs onlv, l&gt;ut all. And tliis will 

I II IV 

; i&gt; !| tit lllt\ 

iv ot' the I 

t:il al&gt;-tinrm-i 

STUDY AS A MENTAL DISCIPLINE. 

hiANK COI.LKliE, CRETE, NKH. 

it a programme of this sort a half century ago 
bree sucli topics as those we are now eonsiderit-ilt 
striking evidence of the transformation 

the makeup, and even in the formative idea 

1 1 1 tit 11 during this time. A generation ago the tratudv, 
in which the classics and mathematics over- 

\ 

pped everything •i-v. -till held undisputed sway as they had done 

103 </seg>

            <seg id="p105">
\ 


rywhere, isthechief means employed 


i\&gt;r two hundred year- or more. Bi 

t things has come n&gt; pass. Every I 
I with the ajrohies thai have pr 
¦ ]&gt;iv~vnt generation oi ti 
achieved with i»ra1 itiuli . ai 
Ahundanl i • ideiici 

and with the agonies thai have produced it. \ 

"reasoning |&gt;owers." Studies 

¦ 

104 </seg>


            <seg id="p106">

I '.(It 

&gt;llege instruction should seek, not 
¦ason," tlif logical faculty, but the 

¦¦ pure r 

varied functions of the mind. 

much a part of the mental endowle 
of cnltnre, and aa inuoii in need 

pi 

IIiIpIVI 

1 mind aa the ability to think a 
('(illttr' 1 education ought to give 

by "mental discipline" » meant 

i verse power- of tin- mind. Possibly 
v accurately by calling it "The Value 

b" actor in &lt; 'olleee Education 

hat the primary purpose of college in- 

lt' historical study is to 

e work, it must do so mi the ground &lt;&gt;t it- 

wise inferior to that derived from 

tal history ia properly taught. There 
its "ii this topic. In order t&gt;&gt; proper 

ory 1 mean just idea- as t&lt;&gt; what 
idling. •• Which waa the greater 

he more important personage in 

the nameless boor who tir-t 

rasvnn 

spade?" To this question, and all 

in unhesitating answer. The 

tut ions — in brief, to the evolu- 

i il 

&lt; toe baa but to note what the study of 

ince, has accomplished for the history 

\ 

i i- wrought in the whole science of history 
&gt;n ut' it- meaning. 

105 </seg>

            <seg id="p107">
s 



iir ;i tin*.* picture &lt;&gt;r a noble poem 

neeessarv : riirlit oonoeptiooa &lt;&gt;t 
flit methods of teaching. 

the A l|is, ;ui»l gained the 

so much to the riae and downfall 
igainarv campaigns &lt;&gt;t ambitious 
&gt;f Bocietv as a whole, to the growth 

• 1 Stud-, ;iml indeed of all Europe, to appro- 


106 





Shall the teacher of historv aim at the inipai 

-hall he aim to teach -tin 

-. 

i- pal together, and bv 


1'lie mil 


w 

Riiim in teach student 
lio have by heart a 
r iri"idtiates who bv I; 

¦¦I righi ha 
can !«¦ but 

ruoro 

noli tin 

¦ »l- U-itiL! ri 

What, tin -ii. &lt;¦¦ 

I shall discuss 

topics lioiv proposed, i&gt;n 

lack "t time having [ &gt;i ¦ \ enti 

l-i. The relation "t hist 

promioenl faculties &lt;*( the n 

2d. It- relation to the 

3d. Its relation to the stud 

The relation of histoi i 

faculties of the mind. Lei us asm 

functions, the imagination, menion 

tense- pi 

it not possible to show thai histor 

services to these mental activities . 

ii 



107 </seg>

            <seg id="p108">
N 



nation. With a 

ii-tnic-t- ~&lt; inn.- 11 

nl IiImikI. ami 

a I rat; men 1 "' 

processes went on in the earth 

ii- what 

re at work, what conditions 

vvhal forces w 
.1 lial condition 

gave form to the result, — in 
on layer, stratum on stratum, 
i lie same way the astronomer 
and laws to the evolution of 

uilili'il laver 

ime. In 

ut phenomena 

¦ I time, and tells us bow planets were 

i motion. All this is the work of the imafri- 

fragment of Iwne before him 
ighty behemoth (A |&gt;a&gt;t ages, 
causing him t&lt;&gt; live again beandstone 
or carbon or granite 

as it is t&lt;&gt; delight in Homer's Iliad or be awed by 
without the aid of the same faculty. The storv 

heavens i- a mighty poem, most of all to the 

reconstructs in thought what loug since was Sral 
n^ht m| the (rreat World- Builder. 

ggested that history, also, in a very true seas 
iv i- i try — this js his idea — only as it is true to 

I &gt;ut what is history bat the experience of the 
»tai of experience, the quintessence of facts'? 

that the student of history must use his imagina- 

i ut oi' lYutelie marble as eloquent a witni 
c-arveil into a beantifol frieze of the Parthenon, 

nal stratum? I- not a torse from the band of 

hi emblem of departed worth as the lemur of 

se ifiiesticii- answer themselves. The remainit 
offer themselves to the student of history as 
he i- to rebuild the arts and sciences, the pliilo-— 

religions, and industries of past a^es. There is 
avorite idea of Emerson, that each man i- an 
eh day and bour the epitome of all time. "We, 

In, •• must become Greeks, Romans, Turk-, priest 
uid executioner, must fasten these images to mmm 

xperience, or we shall learn nothing rigbtlv.' 

i 

nil 

\ 

dv i- impossible to one who cannot thus brins; the past 

¦ in A n nt critic of Krnest lieuan's leeture- on 

&gt; — i i &gt;1 • • to comprehend these modern sciences </seg>

            <seg id="p109">
Hebrew history attributes hi^- failun 
Ebilitv tu throw himseU back into 
tant uir*'- 

This historical study discipliin 
anv ~t miv can do it better. I n 

nadi 

an&lt;l i)l In 


M 


II. 

nil 

-i|,-rr-~M|-- n| \ 

\\:ir tu tin 

t thirty nutnii t- on whicl 
tout which he know- doI 
jaded out, and. what i- wo 


t 

108 



studies tiir tlii- pur| 

before the i&gt;a&lt;i ; lie partirina 

tse ni the M i ~— I — 1 1 &gt; 
chtigal, taking Marco I' 
uitlines, and from 

lyceum program ni </seg>

            <seg id="p110">
i niany Am6nc&amp;D schools, could 
re 11111111011- to a zealous student. 

r the use of the ruemorv. There are 

me and remain one'l own, only 

I h. proper use of memory consists in 

nstead of a tyrannical master. From 

ieuce, it follows that the memory 

han in other studies. &gt;"o amount 

Mill 

&gt;ring to one's knowledge the isolated and 
int- to know where and tinder what eir- 

M- invaded the lioman empire, or how and 
uinenl began in England, lie must learn these 

knowing them he must retneni- 

nil i ii i it 

•.vav- oi remembering than throogh sheer 

\ knowledge "i history develops somewhat nntain 
tacts, through the two principles of use 

\\ ||\ does every Anterieaii boy know the mean- 

liecaust; If lias met these facts so often that 

i- much of himself a- his own name 

ited these facts with certain other tacts in 

•i yield to oblivion. Here is tlie true stand- 
Ient. It with diligence and fidelity be ex- 

i history, not to remember it, but to appre- 

nl that without a conscious effort 

W I 

mind as part of his permanent 

will not only have these tacts — he will 

ire promises the very h 'st things in the disei- 

&gt;nce, perhaps, but ultimately. The power 

I'd rates to the force with which it impi 

W hat one understands, feels, and enters into 

The historical memory, like tlie 

uctantlv 

- the product of training ; but tlie result re 

effort 

il-m-i\ also proves itself worthy of a place in the discipline 

wen of the mind. By the perceptive powers i« 

\ 

faculties which call tor observation, comparison, analysis 

like. Tin- is the domain ot natural science. Agassiz puts 

109 </seg>


            <seg id="p111">
110 

RKPORT OF THK 

[¦¦ tisli before his aspiring pupil, and keeps it l&gt;et 
irned to use Ins eye-. The botanist supplies hi 
icroscope, and disriecting needle, antl directs tb&lt; 

Kant-life can reveal of its mecha 
scientific studv i- reache&lt;l \\ 

V 

plant with plain, and animal w 
rences, atwl arranging all 

iti"ii. Ami |»ili:i 
nleiit 1 1&lt; -ij: i li — ti 

tenoe, because it has to di 
imals." but it i- a science, and is (lien 

i 

scientific wav. 

i 

handled, will l&gt;e eqaal to any science 
experienced teacher a few days siuot 

mi tin- wav "t tta 

ii 

The natura </seg>

            <seg id="p112">
or rhemistry : for in and 
ruents which baffle inquin 

I am therefore dispose 


which the .student can throw aside the au 

for himself." It the -tatenient is true, my 
«l&gt;ly the student can most easily deterii 
natural acienoe; but lie can do so in 

Let ii- see it' he cannot in history. 

ulr iii the inductive process, and the various 
But these are operations the student ofhiaandagaiu. 
He must analyze and dissect and 
I !•• mu-t u-e lii- eves and the lens and the 

ly the mechanisms and powers of a mighty 
¦ feeble plant or animal is as nothing. Then 

inly at least as much discipline tot the t'acultiother 
studies. There ought o&gt; Ik; as much stim- 

m and close analysis. That this has not always 
n ruainlv due to two hindrances the studv has to 

fact that the historical student never has 

ven case before him. When the botaoiataiti 
nstrmiicnt be knows that no one can have 
ii tn make observations than he has. The 

i that particular no advantage over the tyro. But 
11 college seldom have any original sources of liisu 
the best they are few and fragmentary. Kither 
art inaccessible, or they are no longer in existence. 

lis information at second hands. Suppose the 
work upon such epochs as the Persian wan or 
w and unsatisfactory are the primitive sources 
hen all accessible. Or it' he -elect such periods 
•m in England, or the French Revolution, or 
m own republic, how overwhelming are the 
the history 1 What one lihrurv can command 

mid use them all ! Manifestly it is im- 

hi-toiy must adjust his work to these facts. 

_inal sources as illustrative of all and ile|K?iid 

iln narratives of men who have studied the sources and set 

tbrmal histories. Thus it comes about that the 

results m formal histories. 1 lius it comes about that the 
-indent i- of necessity a little removed from the fundamen 

an not work in the same ease aud liberty as the 

dfllct 


111 



112 </seg>


            <seg id="p113">
scientific student. Hut in spite "I 

tor him truly original work, mid sret the -i 

Hi 




w 


in 

I fiel.l 

itudenl iiim\ 

that historical con 

which characteriz 

ure. Probablv t 

restricting historical stud 

«. and such things? Wii\ i- it not a- 

I 

iiilar Eoven 

The other hindrance u-rows «&gt;ul 

wliicli the historii 

will! 

Bv the niinii 

uriii^ in them to &lt;1" the 

i« not tin- dissection of Achei 

ami the like. ;i&gt; valuab 

i. to trace the progr 


113 </seg>
 
            <seg id="p114">
SPENT '&gt;!•" PUBLIC IXsTRIiTIOX. 

.1 follow the ••v&gt;&gt;l ut ion of brain |&gt;o\ver in the aniislv 
tin 1 one inav beaa stimulating as the other. 

make oar historical study ¦ geaaiM work of 

nt. and place before him the reward of true dis- 

n.stitution," says Edward A. Freeman, **i»a 
classified, and labeled, a- a bailding or an an- 

lied. and label 

I liv those to wliom IxiiUlinir- 

tuih 

latoinv, "i liotany, so there is a comparative history 

The range of our political vision beoomei wider 
&gt;[ the comparative method seta before at the 
eomitin of Koine, a&gt; institutions not inerelv 

\ 

ly the same tiling, parts of the same coaaaMM 
il a— einbli&gt;-&gt; of oar own laud. \\ e carry 
ii it i- oiil ol' those assemblies that our imxlern 


t justice, our modern public' gather 

in 

Iv i if facts,— a larger bodv of facts. 

lie tiif term. I f bv rea-on we 

\ 

In interests of mathematics and 

t-&gt; claim for history any plan 

inductive science, not a dediic- 

¦ the history of the world roakl 

i thai il a Frenchman, an Rnglishman, and 

i 

u 

each on the camel thev would 

Ite i I lean 

The Frenchman would rtisii </seg>

            <seg id="p115">
\\ iiiu niann 

istorinn suggests another thought which I am 
It is substantially, thai as there ia ¦ compar- 

_m &gt;u.i.' Another eminent historical scholar, 
hi- suggested thai the comparative method i- 
lv in iii-t'irv. rn(U)iil)tci|lv it produce* aplw- 
jii.c !-, U the method nt advanced aeieatifc re- 

• ii"! «siy, greater discrimination, closer study, 
than anv ImhIv of scientific truth, Whvnot, 

tut ial place in our w&gt;uwe» »&gt;f stmlv? 

I ii place in the culture a4 

ulty "t the ilciliictivc |&gt;r&lt;wvss 

Ix inir, seems to me iridc of tin 1 


around aniiuis; tli«' lihrariir- For a few weeks, an 
U&gt;ok abounding in the brilliant bits and Hashes 
nation is noted, but conveying not a -.intilla uj m 
iii. .¦aincl: the Englishman would pack hit ten) :i 
and after a painstaking studi of thecamel in hi&gt; i 

I Mil 

,\ 

\V 111 

II 

lativ 

substantial treatise, drv enough, 1 &gt;tit \vorth&gt; 

German, eschewing these more iniiiidune nu'tlnwl 

Ml 

1 1 1 • in hi- -t ii'lv am 

niier I'uiisi'.ii- 


froni the inini- &gt; •¦n- - , . • ¦ i — ¦ ¦ • --. l-'ari- Krst, in 

S 

114 </seg>

            <seg id="p116">
Blest degree inn-t b&lt; 
to accept ;i- final whatever ap| 



thftir opinions at well as their facts at second 
lei- &lt;it books, without anv sufficient effort to 

I 

'I 

tin 1 opinion- set forth. Studying history ha.* 
rtery of other men- opinions regarding the prot 
tic acceptance of them as unquestioned truth. 
(mentally wrong. College students must of ne¦ 
"Hilary authorities, bat they can do their own 
have the intellectual attitude of original investi- 

-i authorities critically rather than passively ; 
lence for every assertion presented ; antl thus 
ii in* investigators on history and independent 

i In- claim* of historical studv as a discipline of 
I. Next to the realm of abstract thought pure 

&gt;\ mental activity demands closer application, 
.! mind, more deep, hard thinkiag than thi- ; 

n i- second to none. It i* magnificent training 
_m t hold of some perplexed historical nuestion. 

i 

1 

I event-, and work into it and through it until 
li. and lie can say he understands it — it i&gt; his. 
nil this prove.' That historical study isthe best 
Not necessarily; though personally I do not be- 

i 

lt proves -that historical -tndy has too manv 
niher good studies, too much in common with 
slighted in our higher education. When we 
discussed we discover that history link- itself 

ieuoe, with pbilosophv. It partakes of the oametlio.l 
of all. It w a- a science, however, that 

lege instruction. It must !&gt;e studied a- the 
It- limitation nui-t U- removed, and it must 

I 

ery teacher should l&gt;e thankful for the lalwrs 
holars in the old world and the new who have 

tin- worthy rank, and should lend a helping 

I 

115 </seg>


            <seg id="p117">
116 




l'IMMAKY Ml'SH 


I have read - 
Highly exhaust thai - 

¦ over uswhen we 
arc moulding il 

that tlic mind is tin- m&lt; 


l-h 

at «c must carefully start the child-thought iuto the 
u channel which will finally lead it tn the highest 

I 

life. Ami we can find no better way lu aid us than 
and influence of a good song. It brightens the in- 

itiou, and paves tbe way i&gt;&gt; a good day s work. 
ith -ii. li material cannot tiiil to bold firmly and 

ioughts and actions built upon it. 

c chord in each young heart thai will l&gt;eset into 
•&lt;l t.\ music's gentle linger and earli young heart 

li rilled with ambition to be good, and t.&gt; &gt;i&lt;&gt; 
1:1 the Lila "!' tin- i-vi tbe bright exUNB 

ml tin- manner m whicli the work w begun. 
ive mu-ir and are eager to In- the first to lean tin 

It i- with a great -leal of liappy pride they at lari 

ril and noli- of it 

ntt tin- new -iin^, every w </seg>

            <seg id="p118">

i 

of n- feel we cannot teach music with oor other work, 
:ither the talent nor tbe education. Bui tlieM.- songs 
u. li pleasure are not difficult to learn, and 1 am sure 
i^lit b\ tin- method called tbe tonic sol-fa system. 
ik briefly of this system a- I have used it for x-veral 
u_;lil\ believe in tbe staff; i. &gt;.. tbe ordinarj and ne¦ 
i music can be learned in less time, with less trouble, 

certainty by using tliis notation and method while 
ering the foundation work ¦&gt;( music. There are sevthai 
miiM be closely observed in whatever method 
ion ot tbe children must be an ca-v attitude of atjulili-r 
back and down, neck jH-rlectlv Hexible, ami 
he teacher. Children learn tirst from imitation, and 

In- utmost importance that the pattern be good. 
u!. -. if carefully observed, are certain to briug the 

nli pa pi let. Let them quietly listen and imitate. 
! -ii Ih- short enough to be easily remembered. 

Nev 

Lit the I 

n must be short and distinct. 

4. Ui i -it th 

pattern until you ¦ clear, soft response. 

in- must lie taken not to strain the children's voices. 
•rally arises from allowing them to sing with too much 
ave and common error in most of our schools. 
117 



I-' &gt;. great «3 
-train gem 
. ;i vcrv « </seg>

            <seg id="p119">
118 

RKPORT OK THK 

¦&lt; touic sol-fa method has been taught smeci 
in the public schools of Great Britain and 
laking considerable progress in America. 

til 

h, 

progress in America 

principle is thai of key re I 

decided by the relation it I 
to keep this constantly bel&lt; 

I- to its " tunic 
the mind of tl 

i-t 

•a! 

to use a notation which should plai 

relationship to the ey« 

their initial-. The tone names are marked dowi 

lator," which shows their exact position in relat 

The learner -itiL r ~ ;ill of hi- earlier exercises from tin* 

an image ol it i- fixed in hi- mind. This re 

he sing- them they rise ai 

nil in then 

lator. which (jives a much truer position thai 

sol-fa pupil- are taught t 

P 

to -iiiir abeolutelv in 

with the same ¦•&lt;¦ 
The first step 

The seoon&lt;1 step in 

step brinjjs i 

and proceeds step li\ 

an intelligent appreeiati 
Time is taught sepal 

to tlu- difterent degrees of ai 

to the eye. Equal span 

are shown by fractions 

bv regular interval- of spa&lt; 

different degrees of accent 

The time is coming when it vril 

llece-sai^ !&lt; 

have some knowledge of mus S *ne of tb&lt; 

I 

* 

stiOnship. The charai 

The plan was adopted ol «iin|&gt;lv writing down 

jeotion that in the writtei 

iii£ the mental impi 

tones of the doh 
harmonious inte 

E ear-tuning process 
• 1m&gt; left behind as 
be smclv of harmi </seg>

            <seg id="p120">
119 

PI 

IXTESDEST &lt;&gt;K 1MBMC I.VKTRCCTION. 

considering this qmatiuu of introducing music into 
i ¦ 1 v and everywhere they Bod encouragement; they 

effect ujMin the children, mod through these 
ile nation will l&gt;e benefited. 
music I do nut mean to sav that one must prei 
— |»*-»-i;» 1 musical college: ;i -iinple elementary 

sufficient, and ~iu'h a one ooald l&gt;e put within 

m^ special teachers in our normal an&lt;l training 

mportance, we all know its usefulness, then 

s, help to place music on a more equal looting 
i ii&lt; I thus hasten the coming of that day, to 

inxionslv looking— the millenniuni school day. 

POVERTY AND WEALTH. 

u R. HAKT. HOI.DBBIiE. NEB. 

emu is reported to have said of his son, " He na 
dvantaee that I enjojed." On Ix'in^ asked what it 

&lt; Hill 

Poverty." The answer is very significant tor it- 

i a.;.- pre-eminently characterised l&gt;y extreoMS. 
in tin industrial and commercial methods dazzle 

the one hand, and the decadence of &lt;&gt;l&lt;l beit\ 
the more thoughtful on the other. As in 

it h i- the complement of life, so in social growth 
y to the ni». Peace, love, joy, and plenty have 

zation that has dislodged from the hidden parts "i 

circuniventioa of the globe 
months, totally annihilated 

reduced space, until the 
irsion of less than three 

i • \ 

¦ t communication, and is rapidly robbing night oi 
with it an accompanying antipode for every achieve- 


i 

proud of our times. </seg>

            <seg id="p121">
u mat 


&lt; "ivilization may !*¦ said to l&gt;e made ii|&gt; of |&gt;aii-. Tli 
the tramp go side by side; the half clad beggar shivers 
&lt;&gt;l' tin- great clothing factory ; wickedness of the diresi so 
tht Bound of the voice from the hol\ sanctuary: ignora 

King, crawl- at the ba 
« at the curb stom i 

III! "I U 

In times pa-;, everv 

w 

u I. A 

nation &gt;•' iin 
ii I. in of it 

1m 

wave as -ti 

nami 

Kven ii 

w ii 

intereeting. Here 
i here tlic active ill" 
broad sweep of pin 

and intellectual develupnten 
laws of matter and force &gt;¦¦— c 

Society may l&gt;c likened to 
and si«-ial upheaval, when tli 

viv 

inirst the fetter? thai Lrw bound them, the 
all elements into one homogeneous niasx ui 
wlien the social mountain-making is over, tin 
ing, silent forces tending to level and stratify, 
forming granite and marble, drawing ir&gt;&gt;ld t 

il 

&gt;\' 

in 

ron 

120 </seg> 

            <seg id="p122">
problem "I liumai 

..here a 
cckoning 
¦ n(lfs&gt; am 

spinning ami «r&lt; 

U'uii&gt; responsi 

Kct is humanity 
teaching.* oi 

"IIKIM &gt;\\(M |&gt; (II |l|l I III ll! ll I c.| 
race &lt;&gt;t' inortaU in an all-ei 
]iarti&lt;'i|iation in i lie IriliU oi 
wna »f rest. 
rhese conHictintr forces 

nuking in 
eold, ami 


ml tbeir crystal kindred, quietly stratifying on 
Mm-. IpIihhI, or color. This in time develops 

.\ nre imt strong enough to break thecrsat, 

tintjuished l&gt;v luxurv and slavery. 

persists in it. like wealth it does not renilv. 
It we divide society into the rich 

eness, the middle class who live in comfort 

i frugality, and the poor wboae life i- an 
ii food and tamine, we shall find :il&gt;ont three 

iplete the circuit of these three pecuniary 
nxury become society's outcasts. Tbet are 

who i- li&gt;n&lt;4 idle is not long innocent The 
gthened by the efforts of self-preservation. 

- ..i character of their own, and reach the middle 
iir children scale the heights of fortune. 
laracteristic example of his own word* in saying: 

he ocean, where ¦ drop may come on from the 
uli-ten on the crest of the highest wave that 

i- ;i- • Nothing great is lijrhtlv won." " Hard lal&gt;or i* 

linment," and "Industry is the handmaid of 

a- trite as our daily greetings. 

ndition of progress, and the world's "fountain of 

•;iil .somewhere in the laboring stratum* of aa- 

¦II lazily done as our thinking. Nee 
tivity as hunger doe* to physical exertiou. 

wo elements are concomitants: thought impart- 

purpose to labor, and labor affording the means 

thought. It irix-s even further, it stimulates 
the hours of recreation and reM real enjoyment 

i meditation. The shadowy outlines of right 

1st ice, and his relation to the n-i of mankind that 

iborer's mind while at work, in leisure take shape 

hus become guides for his future conduct. His prin- 

uid deductions will not 1h&gt; the idle vaporings of ¦ cloistered 

ached by the insane frivolities of dissipation and idleness, 


lied the qualities of the wood he carves, the stone he chis- 


121 </seg>

            <seg id="p123">

II Will ! 



entailing resistaniv ami strife: l&gt;ut an i 
havinir itood the storm of a century. Tb 
injr elm are not products ol the hot-h 
and the comprehensive brail the offBj 
Wealth, luxury, idleness, vice, and rum 
ihort downward road whose end is death 
strife, resistance are those ol an upward 

ik i- an &lt;&gt;nk tl 
stately |»i in - and 

id nor is tin 

nils. 

rh&lt; 

t&lt; 

\ 

.1 

rna 

iv side, :tiul tilt 

ami with hearts resolvi 

ease, who drift downward si nip] 

hal 

.\ 

th 

.VI 

IV 

lea 

altv and bestowiii 

hlv the greatest Kntilislui 

chant, and the 1 1 

UK 


A receul Km 

i In- mem her 

.\ 

branch of the 

.ihiih'i- ; ih there m\ ill 
¦•haracierize thiw who 

B pressure thai breaks the cru 
r, and recognition. 

From the legislative standpoint, t 
rich degrades the poor, and makes a 
' ' I I I' 

'I 

U 1 1 


i 


122 </seg>

            <seg id="p124">
Tlie.-&lt;- paths li 

upward. The dud«", when 
the iMiiipafi-'iii. I [e knov 

frr. t&lt;&gt; In- defeated — tin insl 
ilities "i human eliarac 
exotic, bul bt -!&lt;«« 1 1&lt; 
i&gt; taking politiml j &gt;&gt; • \\ ¦ 

ala, epilepsy, awl insai 

1 1 1 1 ~1 r m m i ~ -mi. &lt; lia 

;h'ii in lite that as the p 
giant, and viee ei '¦¦-¦". - ¦ 

¦I and child. 
iTf are iri:nn 

thrown into life's aetiven 


123 </seg>

            <seg id="p125">
PKKINTENDENT OK ITBI.li INSTKICTFON. 

mplr faith and honest purposes of the toiling 

lifvoiiil their reach anil tliev canuot tiut 

port. Degrade the laboring throng, and you 
&gt;ii. Agitate, and all the complex machinery 

rs responsive. Educate, and you bestow a 

il ennobles every walk in life. 

have not comeat the suggestion of kint:- 

nt the cry of distress, and are the efforts 

mselves of their burdensome loads. 

¦ I thought of centuries to discover alcohol, and 
&gt;tlnT centuries to awaken men to the evils ot 

! iii a speak will for the mames that they repudiate it- 

bieak away from Its thralldotn, while it 

nlv every table of luxury in the land' Is there anv 

,. urgency of the movement of tenij&gt;eraiii-e 
ingest votaries come from homes made de«&gt;- 

tenipennoe ? In all socfa movemenU the mas,-es have their 
'epresentative men, tin- the mn-i part, who are directeil 

¦ wed by their adherents. This is being exenipliore 
every year. It is rather to be desired than not. 

-i- a &lt;lav when a more general diffusion of knowledge 
iiiii - minds that the poorest in our land shall be the 

theory supposed to be. 
condition ot society when men shall I*. 1 n 
i principle, rather than tor blindly followin 

evill lie no democrats "lived in the wool 

tderx hi movement!) for tii&gt; 

,vaya iln most pleasant. It was hemlock 
stonea : the -take for Hues; the ammmin'a 

Him who was "the wav, the truth, and 

in i- usually opposed by constituted authority 

prejudice, an established custom. " What is gray with age, 

D 

i- GSodlike;" hence permanent growth is slow. The mush- 

&gt;rli enough poisonous to attain its full size in a 

lity." and im i 1 1&lt; l&lt; • j»«-u&lt; l« -i i« - for "reveniM 


towering oak or pine requires a im 

t«\ veal n ' 

To swell tin- sun 

an •j-.iiii ai 

mbling catai 

( i 

Wi 

In feudal ,- da 

: urrowif] 

man wa 

swu 
1- il an\ 

iH'twwii mas 

r;n V of ill 

ca me in 

.111(1 lllXII 

i 

was :ii first a paattin 
[9 not tin- the Iw 

have tliefle isin&gt; 

refuse to work in th 

:i fair eompens ticrn for i 

employer waste more than « 

spacious grounds a~ they grow 

;tinl clothing. 1- n possible for him to fieel otherwise than 

¦ge? But every Mew thai drives the ever-accumulating dollars 

1 

11 

the jKx-ket of his master is driving new thooehta into his own bi 

Kre long be experiences the same thrill thai every oooqoeror feel* 

124 </seg>

            <seg id="p126">
single nijrht ; but to mature the t 
&lt;lre&lt;l vcars. 
We Imilil like .dial 

We live upon il 

u'r. Wan 

¦Impair V I 

Expression l&gt;\ 
th.irv Th, •', 
•i-bli-ne— i- 

takes possessii i 

clianic in the factory grow 

Bsrulf between himself ami 
He notes, with a ilespuirine lieai 

decaying for want of any Burp] 


you sba 11 nave achieve* I a mental victory in the coniinv- 

pie or law, you claim it bv right of &lt;-&lt;&gt;n- 

does mil matter. It is yours l&gt;v 

trkmau that gives new value to matter. Am 
Ices ii new forms he feels himself more than 

reator. Vnd to l«&gt; deprived ot' ike 
In- own hand becomes in liis eyes a 

i from day to day with the qm 

¦me"" -till unanswered, he grows re^tle—. 
strength unequal to the accomplishment of 

lellows, whom in- finds forming unheard ot 

ugi that -liov\- the | »r&lt; — u r«- ot pent-up feeling, 
- Hearing it- limit, ¦ ¦! an energy that reckons 

«vertj ami wealth on the school lilt-. 

iburer. ( hi pnterinu !lii~ iirena of i liild- 

( are their ' &lt; &gt;n&lt; I it i&lt; &gt;n~ 1 &gt;&lt; &gt;t i i ot niiml and 
llXlirv. i-ntt i Mi-&lt;l in 1 &gt;&lt; &gt;&lt; I \- . and witli a 

¦ ¦t th&lt;Me \\ lioin } if lia- lutii taimiit in 
ii'h&lt;- scIkmiI lias souk ver^" democratic 

I " h I \ h:i- liccii -lifii^tlu'liitl l&gt;\ 

-liariteixtl liv activity. At marbles 

ii ln~ &lt; -I n —^« — outstrip- 

i! litulne — . respect Tot liis 

leaviH*. 1!h: the child of povertv 

¦ Ivaiila 

»1, sncriticinu the ambitions 

tlini: the desires and aspirations born 

1-oonwioustiess ol suj&gt;erior [tower 

itate institutions ¦¦' higher learning fail to attain the 
s' nol reaching down t&lt;&gt; the poorest l&gt;o\ in all the broad 

125 </seg>

            <seg id="p127">

mlitioii, bv means at once iw»Ul 

mitteral curst "f ili^tmtenl uttered at 

merchant prince i- placet I aide \&gt;\ 

that be is &lt;¦! superior qnality, and 

-I* 

in* ii|i. :i ui 1 tin 1 [lovertv "I 1 ¦ i — 
• t ¦ of Iri- lift- that riches 

undarr whooi, 


i 

land and giving him everv adv 

intake 

moved Ii\ hi- u 

llM 

I 


It is unfair to dismi-&lt; \\\\- phase ol the subject m 

that where there's a will there's a wav, Id-ean-e In 

i \\ :t \ 

yon can take away all public support for education. \\ 

engage* in the task of educating it- vouth, it sho 

\ i 

\tter having kindled the Haine of intellectual fire in 

rtchool, it i- Imt jn-t to (five thai mind all thai is 

\- il i~. it often liapiM'iif thai the mentallv -ti 

development l&gt;\ poverty, ami i- tu 
: ltd the state therein i lepri\ i 
&gt;rtune-fa\ ored dullard |..i— &lt; - 

IMI 

ortmu 

; .. tin IdlPLf h-' 

tinuallv work in^ ,x rpoN - 

linuallv work ii 

¦ &gt; -ii i — • — . i ii 


.'h.r. Ill, 

¦•'In i . The i-omnii 
A ItlllHlgl 

Alth 

rich, the a&lt;t|iiif 

h. the a&lt; 


i- it- \»— ¦ - 
W ¦¦ 1 1 til obtai 

lull- Itnui 

-Kill- 1 1&lt; IS\ 
iinl eiijovnieiii . I 
niiii'1 ililli. 
'I '! 
. «ve yoiii i arnin^ 

Ill'l ellli.VI 

Km I nd I? 
ism t" 
Ith. 'I 

-av&gt;- \ 

(lom, ami an in 

• I' nil. :iinl an unswen in_ 
\i general ion 

Ki iieneratioi 
in the -.in 

to exist in the south, i h i 
il :l &lt;-i'!ltUI'\ . Tin f &gt;• &gt; — • --I' 

Im- the \li.-c- that will lead 

now vein- ic lower above tii 
\\ fll earned monev i- ;il\\ avs ;¦ 

llliW MTIII- III IllWl 

man. it beautifies- his ho 

and bringa to his bean a l«al 
higher things, and in hi- soul 

I 

i 

126 </seg>



            <seg id="p128">
127 

•I 


I OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION. 

&gt;&lt;&gt;!. FURNISH THE MORAL TRAINING 
IT SHOULD? 

state teachers' association. We refit— I no 
•a I organization; do peraooal interest-. We 

it- servantsof the state. We have met to diaication, 
and to tind the just demands of the 

demands thai we shall build up her walls ol 
I citi/eii-hip. who are worthy to rule ami 

will not only vote, bat &lt;a«t an intelligent 

it the -i-liuol- exist because they have a right to 

for the reason that they are the onlv cartrain 
ing the citizenship of a tree country. 

erate voter. l&gt;ui when the illiterate voter 

&lt;&gt;mr&gt; dangerous. This problem, then, of civm 
..; the statesman, the philanthropist, the 

citizen. A tullv rounded man needs the 
the ethical, aixl the physical. 

red bj the »tate, Ibr itoown perpetuation, 
the school, the school i- the one inoM 
1 1 by her. The state take- charge of the 

rightlv does it^ work. Children 

ii -nt i tit-, moral, or intellectual 

I- for expecting thi&gt;. What we do expect, 
I i:i~t and the genius of tlie present warrant 
i society, greater liberality, a l&gt;etter litera- 

i 

nent of such a eharactei as to maintain these. 
H' powerful agencies in this preparation. It </seg>

            <seg id="p129">
in 


U&gt;B&lt; i;V « AHOO, NKH 

lie child young enough to correct many 

\ ami to them ami upon them we ba.-*.- 
11 no! looking turwanl to any Utopian 

il*solute perfection in this world. 


¦ give the vontfa knowledge, self-con 
er. 

E child « itli uiil\ home training 
i ih&lt;- blighting sneers and adv( 
school In ~Ik&gt;uIiI learn that the 
he should Iwirn thai tin- 'M rat&lt; 

U.I 

I justift 1 .' flial an i 

ami how iiaintain t liein. &lt; *i 



\ 






I, 

bil 

128 </seg>



            <seg id="p130">
hi.* 
IIM till II 

Personal influci 

¦ ilfiice uii- 
isli all i- ¦ 

|ll-t COWPptlUII ¦¦ 
¦ 


mid ami thoroughly impress it with the 

When \V 

ike into consideration th*&gt; imprtaai- 

that In' who has the influence 

lelief in Bible morality as shall staaap 
character of the teacher. 

must counteract home inHueiitt 

ichei 

people, thai in the last years of 

\ IIUTK-Illl 

thai shall give prominence to the 

II. who 

itgrowtli ol individual honest v, our 
\ diange ol party power will not 
tii r— t " iiiion our i-oins; we shall l«- 

-i\ 

A I 

he taliii-i- ..I men'- hearts 

tou&lt; ii alike the homes of tin- rich 
!»¦ taught iiol that he i.- as eoml at 

I m~ In-. i hi an- training 

A 

n ma\ l«- religious! or irreligilly 
a &lt; iiii-tian people, with tin- 

ito ..iir government fabric that lit 

i 

in. &gt;i 1m- a good citizen. 

take the child as it timls him tad 

129 </seg>


            <seg id="p131">
N 


iom positive nature; in other word*. 

li all ¦&gt;( its boasted lit;lit&lt; and ~c-i*Mi t ilit- at- 
&gt;n»es whose influence teach profauitv, gam- 
iu - "I ( n»l ;iin 1 man. 

n .ralitv ainl virtu.- under such oirviiin- 
:i mi .ii mural stamiua. It will be 

would tincl equity niu&lt;t ilo equity." 
ul uui'laiicc to othen must l&gt;c men 

n~. fount! in the ways of ritrlit 

In '• |»- with economic iiues- 
ipital and lalmr, long liaui, 

I, and they musl U- td- 
to deal fairlv lietween 

n ' -liniilil l»- inserilied 

\ .iiilil niii-i U' t.iu^ht thai 

uol infringe on tlit 


do what it can in tlic direction "t training hii 
¦¦ It the influence of other ageneie* have he&lt; 

V 

t school \\ ill !»¦ able to do mi 
n cm rt&lt;&lt; I : luit il no ol lier a* 

must assume the « link 
The state demand? tin 

state, while the school, it- &lt;¦! 
lected and forgotten '.' Hut 

l&gt;laci' in the public schoc 
vou Mire that tin reading 

i: 

130 </seg>


            <seg id="p132">
linn, return hm 
of a builder, -' 

Did it ever nccur t&lt; &gt; 
:i chaplain are furui 


t sectarian I k '.' Let the supreme court 

wet thai question. It i- at hand in th&lt;ise, 
the decision given by Justice 

inaninious, recognizing the Bible, with:h 
• purest = 1 1 1 &lt; i l«&gt;-t source of morality 

Dot sectarian in its character or 

:. made a standard for moral precepts iniii 
thai is too often followed. It' the 

issemblies and is the. basis of all law 

iw ii to be read without note or 

..in land " Tlie state should also renod] 
. w i n lt children to teach school. The way 

ti' the discretion of the county 

lll:itt 

¦n carried l&gt;\ personal friendships ami «vmidgruent. 
Certainly the giddy young mi*- 

ukI life. The parent feelt that the 

-h..iil.l not always lie in the line of experi- 

t ii&lt; 1 better trained teachers, old enough 

f the possibilities of childhood. 

.III. 

(mi womanly t" !&gt;¦• offended at the wavs of the 

I'inpathy with child nature to see a d 
nil .¦ i^h of human kindness to see th-' 

mention, manly and womanly enough 

taken, j n~t enough to &lt;leal honestly. 
ipathi/inglv with the child and lead it into 

ndcnl Seaver says, "For better 

skill, and persistence in appealing 

itiem 

d's nature, more loving kindness in 

Iren, more earnestness in the moral side 

t- l&gt;ad effects.' 

.. I am 

tliout the oiilv one who has to 

Ii. 

re he may enter upon his duties, it is also 
nlv i" saii-t'v, in manv cases, the guardian 

sen for what ? Because be was the 

No. I- it not rather often because be "stood 

1 

political ring. Ether the schools must purify the 
-in for a divorce from them on the grounds 

131 </seg>

            <seg id="p133">
s 



mind and knowledge of ethka bart 

&gt;ii|&gt;'Tmt 


132 </seg>


            <seg id="p134">
ot incompatibility. Phe uonnty superint&lt; 
¦»-M man to !»¦ found, Imtli n» a man am) an «lu 

-!\ discharge lii- &lt; 1 1 1 1 

Illlj oil! 

Kl during examinations 
~iiiii- sup 'rintt'ii 

\\ 

Bl to allav iin- 
ii actiou. 1 1' 

in honest toil. &lt; kie of ih 

speculation. We find it even ptra 


133 </seg>


            <seg id="p135">n 



Phe child may be practically taught that 
iiai In- can pay his way. "This gettiag of 
eradicated from th&lt; woof and warp 

ruin); l |! ~ temporal and spiritual 

i w- 

¦ wisely direct hi* energies and tram 

nnal- &gt;li) not all come I com 

Hia 

that manv of them come from this ed- 

|i|iort. find themselves like one of old, who 
I am ashamed." Tlie though! that thev 

tilted fur higher grades of work 

in. -tit aii 

king labor only suited to the ignorant. a* 

state nt affairs vice and crime 

t I &lt; Mil till 

i in taught the dignity ol labor, by tailoring. 

it practiced workmen, directed 

lied by the healthy body. Ijook 
dI house. Look at the lessons of 

Ite |~ lie-t mi 

rane *ch&lt; 

taught by the inadequate 
buildings." Hire i- a Held tor 

-av mdeivncv 
_;iia!iil as ""out 

In t that i lei nand- ear. tul inspection and constant 
h I am sorry to say is often neglected. The 
adequate and suitable accommodations of this 

Id up the tiller -en-ibilities of the soul. 
rity i- a virtue, and as this is the duty of the 
and more effective enforcing clause for our 

¦ in efforts to enforce obedience, absence may re- 

the state cau aid the school. All teacher* 

the street is a living menace to the school. 

ints enumerated which will give us better results 
powerful agent. Now and then some sensational 

pretends that it is a vain boast to talk of the 

ity in teaching, that it is a calling which j;ood men 

n may honor, I &gt;ut from which thev can receive no special 

i turn. Surli idea- are a delusion, " A teacher without a 
without a warm love tor the lieautiful, the true, and the </seg>

            <seg id="p136">n 

n. 

I and farm — the work oeceawn 

lilies ol trade will l»"&gt;t be doae 

hard and employment scarce, beiag 

ktvn tiM. 


who il(n&gt; not reach out 
way teach tnaiiK" virtue 1 and 
*ion, the uoblesl because one i 

after hm 

IMIIV, W 

ti-iiii 

l!\ 

tin 


I le will t'md or tin. I 11 

country- 1 

sentiment.-. N 

rture canu 
111 view ¦ 

trv. in v 

tor good, |&gt;i 

greater eflo 

children t In 

the -im.-hiii 

iwn ainl li 'in 

harvest, then I 

friendly riva 

voted for la.-i v&lt; 

mimiiv as the |&gt;a 

F splay &gt;it the Hau we \n\ 
\\ ln&gt; can measure the 

of the illustrious patriot 

\\ ho lai 

and gave l)loo&lt;l and even life thai 

country, home, and God must be lik 

ii 

must jro hauil in hand. The fires o( liberty ruua 

134 



philosophy, in In 
Cters of the bru 
e, have such a 

\n&gt; life and ;i 
a&gt; a doctrina 
of truth, tlH 

such. Nor wou 
to tio, I'm- tin- &gt;\ 

slow illii MIiciII 

few choic* I 
letting (litlti 

" Flajr day " and Hag rai-ii 
&lt;oogs that stirred to life the 


135 </seg>

            <seg id="p137">N 

KXMEXT &lt;&gt;F Pl'BLM I NslHICTIi &gt;N. 

and, who, with pun_ hauus ami 

l&gt; tli'- work the veteran is ready to lav down, 

ichingg, give, it' need If. their lives to uphold 

y peopl&lt; — tin U nited States of America. 
•d ncu lile last rear, ami in view of it- 

vote to consecrate not oulv the 

I tin- school year to that kind ot teach - 
though it had a moral being, and that 
nd- of lite, this nature should Ik- fully 

Flu- ungraded school is sadlv in need of bet- 
H- rural school Ik- made better without them? 

ft tin- schools to a higher place of u&gt;eliilnes.» 
li i if a tiill grown character '.' " Where do vou 

le remedy for this last defect lies with the peoiit 
willing to put their children's future into 
tciii-v ami immaturity the Mate will not interfere. 
ealize that the teacher of their child inav make 

v 

t the teacher of the child should have is much 
ainer "t their fine cults, then will they rise iu 
eh the avenues I have Urietiv mentioned see that 

utilized by incompetent officials, restricted by 
irroundiDgs; that with the i-ducation of the 

trained, that the cultivated mind shall have :\ 
"U. and a moral character built upon the 

&gt; a- never man And that for this 
i- free from vice, who know the right and 

id can teach it 

s S'KB. 

i i-entun since the scientific ntudy ot' bia- 

i. and verj little more than hall' a oentnry since it ret-eived 

¦ill ii-^e curricula. Since then the development 

i so rapid that to-day the subject of the polit- 


Ull^. ' &gt;I f Ull' 

veai 

11-luUV IN EDIVATIOX. 


the 

Practically the initiative in tin- entire fit-Id was I 

11 : i-'i.i\ 1 he whiM 

•I- both in the field of inv&lt; 

i: 

a prominent place. I he &lt;- 

have nautili 

without ih 

I I'ilt'Vli II 

M-. tiim 

the development 
tracing the begii 
philologist, laid I 

lethod 

|ierfectoi 

Kauke liegan hi- 

and econ 

n &lt; . 

effects of this i i i-i 

open to the student-. 1 n I'. 

The -anie i-onditioi 

i 

other- which niiirhl !»¦ ad 

large ftirther upon thi 

It 

the high place which the p 

tion. In England, both Cambridge with its corps 

and Oxford with its larger coniplem 

Hit 

r\ 

teiidiut; sik'Ii eouix- and bringing t 

thin work -mil' 

has the re 

is dointi some excellent work, and in no country 

vance Ijeen greater. In the "Facultedes Lettres, at Pans, ten 

136</seg> 


            <seg id="p138">
i(-al sciences has a standing scarcely second to an\ 
vestieation. 

mans. To &lt; iermanv in fact 

However, « ithin tli 

sidca ¦ '1 tlic ocean 
pum, and [talv i 

complete. 

!kt of teachers ami 

trated by ;i lew exami 

Ix-siilo several 

immediately allied brawlii 

Bonn, l/dpzii;. Gottinjjen, M 

historians ot' the da v, a- Kitcinan, Stubbs, Seeley, and Bryce. Fra 


- .m liirti.)iy and it- allied branches, 
their time to geography; in other 


now some thirty proJeason giving 

undred. These two example* mnl suffice, 
trend. &lt; &gt;t' iJeluMinn and Italy the 

made. Scotland ha.- Wont' alino-t 

'nited States, we find that the devolnaaent 
been very marked during the last twenty 
il&gt;lislied tor the study of history in tin- I 'nited 

n 1839. This chair, the McLean historical 
ed liv the Rev. Jared Sparks. His methods 

-rntiallv different from those in vogue before 

tin- chair, or even it* establishment, can 

li-making. In 1857, Prof. A. 1). White r. 

years' -tudv in Europe and brought back with liicn 
pirit, which be introduced thai year into Ann Ar&gt;e£Jnning 
(it the real Modv of history in tliiat 
time there had been only an boor or two a week 

ion- iiom -nine drv text-l»ook, organising a 
However, it took some thirteen yean more 
a ell leavened. President Eliot took bis place 

illege in l^til*. From this time on the move- 

that ii may well !«¦ called revolutionary. The 

n ha- been revised ; the elective system liaallotmenl 
i&gt;( time lias been spared. In 1 H7'&gt; 
&gt;n the fingers of one hand the teacher.* of histheir 
whole time to that -iibject ; rather more 
in economy. Now the number is legion. In 
- which I have tabulated there are nearly one 

le voting their whole time to the political sciences. 

Inell and Columbia each have eight s|&gt;eciaiists in history and 
nice; Harvard and Pennsylvania University eacb seven, Johns 
in- University baa live, Michigan tour, while several have three 

I including Vasaar, and the universities of California, Kansas, 
elira-ka. 

137 </seg>


            <seg id="p139">
lie vote their lime to geography ; in other 
ler 1'ijt ut the total iuimiIkt ol teacher- art- 

In "Leoolt i&gt;i-titi&lt;i&gt;ie ties html'" 

are now -mnc thirty professor* giving 
t scientific manner. The iuiidIht of 


Cornell stands* first in the number of hours i«i week 

five, while our own university comes 

hour-. .Miami nolleee thinl, \\ifli thirty-eight, the m 

\l 

:n;t\ i»- (lirlicil 

A 

\ 

• it\ . "i -nnf' 
&gt;i)lv two or i 

a&gt; in IViiiisvlvania * 

Kit' niiiiil 
mv: &lt; 
ka eacl 

II 

a 

1 lere, acai 


may Ik- Hi 

;.ir\ of &lt; ii '•»¦. " J 

he "" Kconomi 

II- 

wuli mii inci 

B- i- that 
l«res tin 

in 

_", M | i r ¦ — r t 

while in ill. 

• lirht. which ratio i~ found 

K. .John- Hopkins, ( !ornell, &lt; 
and Minm— oi:i imiversitit 
¦ Ic-s, l)ciii&lt;r about one to te 

I have also prepared a table to -I 

Krs in, and the relative amount of time given to, the sn 
Latin, mathematics, and the political sciences. The t: 
onlv fifteen, as I had no means of securing reeenl statist 

138</seg> 



            <seg id="p140">¦a- :iinl PenuHvlvani;i next, with iliim 

with twentv-eitrl'l ; the fewest nuni 

VlellxTt college, ( 'levplanil, &lt; &gt;iii&lt; • : i 

I ii -' une cases n i- lianl to &lt;!¦ 

¦ I ¦ ¦ 1 1 1 1 

ratio l&gt;ttv 

nom ics in the whole mini 
&lt; &lt;&gt;luml'i:i ooll&lt;ttp i be nit 

proportiou i» only ;i- r&gt;u 



tl sciences in their various form, inoocupy 
the finM place at the present 

frsity of Pennsylvania has twentv-onc 
it of fifty-seven in the academic depart* 
Missouri there were in 1S87 twelve out 

I'll' 1 proportion varies m different schools, 
re everywhere ahead. In looking at t ln- 

ii. until very recently, formed the bwkiipied 
a large proportion of the time of 

thai in most of these fifteen institutionnice 
bv tin- historical sciences. The Ini- 

only six men in Greek, Latin, and pare 
- veil in historv and economy. In the-&gt; 

liree marked exceptions, it will U- - 
in historv ami economics 1- just about 

i'ii in ( iict-k and Latin, and about Hltv 
number in mathematics. The tendenci 

i- uiiidc very manifest by a study of catalugMs. 
\. B. degree w already Lrraiited without the re- 

r Greek, or at best i&gt;f imlv a *mall amount 

tore noticeable that a large number ol school* 
ior and senior years to election, either wliollv 

mark- this tendency perhaps in its ex¦etained 
as required studies in the junior 

ntal philosophy, history, and Kujflisli. In 
same t&gt; ¦ndeiicv munifests itself. Knt^lish in 

¦quired ; history • r economics is Ireqiientlv 
-li\" ~t nilii'- ha\.- Im-cii ahno-t llllivenallv 

nior Vearg :i- requirpil work. 

I have combitted historv and the varioOB 
whole. This vein- to l&gt;e necessary . siaoe 
ii-tnictiini an -o closeh allied. The ol&lt;l 
an ideal man in ideal circumstances ha* 

vestieation of the social and economic relations 

Ipoint. The whole group of studies of which 

\t Ann Arlior tlie scIkmiI of historv and political econoinv 
¦ i • • 'i 
nrainzed -onii years, and troni it some verv itcrki oriirinal</seg> 
            <seg id="p141">
investigation may well !«¦ known as politicad 


paper* have come. In Columbia college a school pi | 

t 

¦h 

ha» Ix-iii organised within the last few war-. In this 

ha» been organized within tin 

In I 

:im few 

veai 

lent, the historical - 1 1 1 &lt; 1 i &lt; • - are taking h more promim 

east, the historical studies are t:ilv 

ii 

many of the older branches of learning. I j is not knov 

ma ii \ o( the oltler Itrunclies t»f learn ii 

t hut there aream ~'-ji:ir.-i t- ¦ -• -\i&lt;"&lt; 

thai there are am 

mathematics, or e\ en t lie m&lt; 

• i tit I I ¦ • -f t l;i • !¦ •-. n| 

I 


Hill Will 

HI II 
.,1- ,.! 

met \&lt; 

,»nlv aria 

only aila| 
I In- Im 

II, 


• ¦lily give* ' In 
lout . I 


and an 

experteuo 

work, .in' i 
( n- recital 

mi! i ii&gt;' recita 

* &gt;* 1 1 i- .a- 


lu» subjects : ¦ 

Inssul,, 

phrase iiMecl i- uih 

phrase us 

« ork of the pupil. W 

U 

be tn keep the interest 

1 lit' tl'lllll 1!) Spitl 1 

ilic truth in ¦— | » : r 

tt'Utli m aronsetl, the greatest |)ai 

truth in aroused 

li&gt;-t. I he student \\ 1 1 1 ' i- -¦ i I 

ln-t. I he st IK It'll I win 

\\ liicli may have ulreailv I., .n - 

u hii'h mav have ulrwidv heen - 

ii he is nut aware "t the solution 

ul tin 

ifin original worl 

_ r in oriiriniil work in a coruparati' 
Jiut now the quest ioii comes, wh 

in 

'I 

But now the imh-i ion 

Illl 

&lt;tu?li man-ilaus progrtM in this 

• a-y to give, and the uttcmpl 1 - 

l&gt;e the l&gt;a-i~ for the existence "I thi." pa|&gt;er. I; 

new, then there can be nothing in ii 1 i-an la 

new. then there e;in lie nothinK in il I can 

• legnt i&gt;r originality. Before giving tin answer I wi~Ji Ui 

legn-e uf originalit}. Before giviug nn answer I wig 

&lt; 

qualities &lt;&gt;) historical study which tnav help in the solut 

qualities &lt;i) historical study which may In 

prohlem. First, I irwh to notice that it may l« both written and 

140 </seg>




            <seg id="p142">
[ 

turn aside tor a moment, vou notice 

itoric. The lii-- 

1-, scientific and hi 

A 

ntilicallv ; the* 

ietitist stranjielv 

&gt;vi 

netliod of investigati 

i 

pwinij witli the 

nti-t ami tin 

historian ought 

li is de|ien&lt;lent ii|»' 

&gt;n the other tor 

tatement that history i- acientiCr, 
mav In- presented alont! the line ot 

iii- a- eaav to fol- 

i 

t i- believed that 

i 

I 1 : astronomy : nut 

n-i tut urn-- ainoiii; men i- now seen 

..•I- 

one For and t'&gt; give torni to history, 
of the world- development around 

\ 

lie work i- even surer. We mav ail- 

i- -11 !*• at lea-t 

i 

-mi- ot our lootint 
'I -i-iellcr. 

i 

»pi" dirtiiU. and in more sides ot Ini 
i- Ion ixl in tin 1 curriculum. Science 

in -ii 

,\ 

i -I''! v, without which In 

i- a barbarian ; 

hoimv insinuation 

the other that 

i 

:l Stlldv 

I what he ha- 

ure. Again, th» 

lie i ;iii~i— ..I lii- tai 

mtirrowth of the 

¦e—al\ 

\\ ho can 

investigate in tin 

ii.ilitical. or n 

li^ioiis bigotry ot 

W ho can t'i 

o\\ the law- that 

ilevt'lopmenl w 1 1 1 1&lt; 

ui seeing that or- 

u- motives, and to 

them right ooea 

i 

i.mI. mii-t not intoler 

1 1 k -t- cease . J m 

individual man i- 

I 

[he sorrow of the recent war denionht 
throusrh the maw of the people, that 

ihou 

In- will ot' this man or ot' that, but that 


141 </seg>

            <seg id="p143">
&gt;n i&gt; the histor- 

first and lull 

I forward from tare to age in no iimfrtain 

¦i 'in~i - aiHi ivcnt- 

&gt;t her wise rlif-ol 

jioiiji- alone afford him m complete 
&gt; In- « hai In i-. I In- topic i- capable 

illicd !n tin- lln.ii-iil 

nil ntlicr : tin- 


142 




:t ix 1 Persian*!." Will nol nun then i-ease (¦¦ hate i 

li: 

i(k1 :ict upon the principle that it «;i- mil the taull 

aid ' 1 1 1 1 • - 1 ii 

r by ex ten 

linn .i| wh 
hiwton tell n- Uil 

M 

studies will reform tlie \\ 

governed by others; whin part 

Inn the outcome of the enVironmeni Biiil-conm laul 
¦ an ~&lt; ¦&lt; i the struggle 7 Then il will be reci^nia 

KihiiI i-an 
listake in 

perhaps, as j 

when the i«sl w kn 

shall !»• able to iruide i lien 

stream* m iir&lt;»trr&lt;' — i- '"oiii 

but that it will help cann 

H'M : wlii'ii man &gt; ImiiIi was given Inm li </seg>


            <seg id="p144">
lien i! was unrecognised that there wendt' 
the race: when it was siip|M).sed that 
world, then, perhaps, there was little need 

nun!- nt man in the past. To-dav, when 
in need is greal for the widest knowledge, 
orieal science :tre to go hand in hand; the 

elopmenl of t Ik- latter, and the latter 
ward inarch. It' the future i&gt; with demr 
inlli oe- niii-t !&gt;&lt;¦ with history and itinn' 
i- with the historical sciences, studied 

hi -icuiitlit inn-t absolutely honest search 
democracy is at least most sure. 

nil nl these studies will give u- letter and 
iprove our administration, as it liar- already 
¦ 

|)U 

i 

\ D 

.'White -a\-. ""that the admirable BystaaM 
Iministration in Germanv is due to the m- 

liiiii; iii German universities;" and thertii|i|»i~e 
that a large infusion of historical 
ear in their reasoning powers, or lt^ — &lt;-.«|&gt;a- 

i 

itainU will make them broader and give 
he law- and principles governing society. 

i 

tail to the tun her development of the hi.-tor\\;i\ 
:i- tn tear down other studies and otbei 

did to them ; to supplement their work; 
in a nobler, broader, and more tolerant 

\ 

I I V &lt;•! SCHOLARSHIP. 

ve -heil -iieh Ill-tl'i- lljioll the.-e lattel 
iii tin finding of a Unifying principle 

i io exist What was Franklin's acfaierehtning 
from the cloud and subjected it 

iiM some curious toy? Was it uot the idenc 
lightning with the philosopher's electricity ' 

A 

143 </seg>


            <seg id="p145">
KIXTKN I'KN I. II I IXC1IS, 


Was it not that he thus proved tliiii tin- force w 

with its wonderful pyrotechnics iind thai which |&gt;Imv 

the terrible power of the tin nun 2 bolts th 

stn and human dwellings. Manv ol them had 

Kl»'ti\- ruler* kepi 1 
ion, mighty and p 
empire the tnulti 
iphv so impossiljle 

1 

!" 

t 

144 </seg>

            <seg id="p146">
lated 'vlimlcr are ilic name? Mankind, -im 


1 

RNDEN1 OF ITBI.Ir INSTRUCTION. 

145 

1&lt; 

\l,,l tlluM 

I iIim-&lt; unions are an indication of a higher civ- 

livisions were the consequence of a den*- 

W hen the Roman empire went to pieces the 

tnai cohesion seemed to die out among men. 

Every man of influence and jwwer set uj&gt; 

erritory be could, fortified liis castle, and 
pendent sovereign. His hud was there- 

iil every man'- hand \va- against him. A; 

mguished ; the art! were neglected; pop- 

Mutual butchery came to b&lt;- the onlv honorable 

the beneficent energy of Christianity. 

ind tendencies of to-day, though by M 

in dI evil, are yet a &gt;iiru of retnraiag moral and 

1 1 test illustrations taken from other fields, I 
in the worth of \\\\&gt; spirit of unity in the purare 
told that in former limes t lie students and 
»tber universities, were accustomed to decide 
iim! ethics, fMtgnia el oaldbut — with fists and 

\\ 

Ij "i the Greek language was introduced th«-by 
tin- n|i| -clinla»tii&gt; with a violence equaleil 

i 

-liiji'.' I- such :i iliinu ]ros-ii)l( V The greai; 
now ledge is as diversified as the tact of nature 

thought. Here is a child ju-t mastering tbe 
mgiiiige, or the iiualities of the most common 

ii 

ntal treasures. Here, &lt;&gt;n the other hand 

vey ot the universe; or the venerable Von 
it human history and the philosophy thereof 

iai. Here, i"", is the man who is trying to 
book in order that he may l&gt;e helped to hi~ 
until studies in order to make himself a repun 
order that be may more effectually benefit 

( &gt;i 

delves among tlie dusty tomes of ancient libra"iii: 
the rock- and metals of the earth's crust. </seg>

            <seg id="p147">
in. i ) 

lltfS :l ill 

i 


me tlii- terrible l&gt;ia&gt; toward disintegration 

i~i- be is 1*1100 — .lulls ;ni|iiiring kuowl 

tccuniulation of tiict- nut! princi 


146 



What unity &lt;"i'i there !•»¦ amid so much diver 

( 

common principle running through *ueh 

lipUtMMI 

Iii the |mi— ibiliiv of an affirmative mi-u 

Wild the true soldi&lt; 






ir 



: 

r: 






upon differ 
¦&lt;m\. 


ihI-x of ll 

Ktion of the II 
linn- "I ill 

Bml. 1 Ie studies mi 
ist highly endowed 
hat being wax acliie 
efore, a study to bi </seg>

            <seg id="p148">
lelieve, tin- true inspi 

rr«'&lt;l in -a varietv 

boroagh success in it i- 
eaped of his fellow men 

Take now another lui'- of inves 


ivs ' •! mechanic-. lji*t him ix? &lt;i nimi win 

&gt;blems before him. He gives to them 

I [e considers the want.- erf civilised man. 
a- U--i in supply these wants. He in- 

ii|)ii» \a the promoting of human weal, 
itii tin God-ordained canons of this 

i vi - tiie houor ami gratitude of hi- 

¦ i- t..i knowledge have nut always relight. 
Tin' word "scholar" baa l)eeu 
;d &gt;-• &gt;rl ?*•&lt; 1 into lii&gt; consciousness much 

In. by study haa mastered what the nnliiiii; 
about. IJllt the learned Student ot 

iin^ to count the mechanic as a scholar. 
leii hi- knowledge i&gt;t mechanical princi- 

pi'iictical man retaliates by asking what 
nol linn a wheel. It cannot make a nail. 

ii cannot feed and clothe the children. 
material tbrces. li i- a dead language. 

i not In- accurate. The right thing ti&gt; aay 
•ui'Mi-, the truth includes them both. Let 
iiM&gt;ssible for him to see all the faces &gt;&gt;t tht 

iwleilire. i-et each stout I v attirm 

mil refmin from aitirmation concern- 

Let tin- lie done and the truth will 

l\ embract! the-, two. l&gt;nt a thou- 

The efforts of universal 

nn i-stiirator 

lliiman knowledge will l&gt;ecome a 

t ii&lt; 1 thorough methods. I 

nrm view 

lay be called the ''morning star" ot 

dkl three hundred and tittv years 
ike, the Lord Chancellor, some writer- 

inceptions of science are the more just and clear 

147 </seg>

            <seg id="p149">
t 



the truth lies between iln-c two seekers 

iguorunce "i shallow pretense. 
here lived au Knglishnian who appears 
- well as successful in liU search utter 


&gt;t the two. The world al th»- time wa« do4 |m 

ot the two. me world at the time was noi prejwn 

¦ •lie-. The clouds of the medheval barbarinm w&lt; 

Hi- knowledge of mechanics and physics were ait 

His knowledge of mechanics and physics were attribute 

For tea years be was restrained of liin libertv. I *&gt; u t lu 

For tea pears be was restrained of In- liU-rtv. I'.ui 
[perimental science, and his principles, thougl 

i 

:peri mental science, and In- principles, tl 

I 1 

"•••ntnrii's. wen- at last resuscitated t&lt;i the great tteiieri 

centuries, were mi lax) resuscitated to the ijreal l&gt;ene 
A hundred vears after Bacon i-anie anothei 

A hundred vears 

m 

iiani' the work! will not Ui &lt;l i I liavr Mid thai 

name the world 

'-.lllt'd tin- lllonimi: .lollll \\ 

called the moruing John \\ 
• &lt;-n called th( irmal i&lt; 

fore ua- an in &gt;t k •-: man ol L*ommaiMling of 

Ka- an h"ii 
I dauntli 

ami of dauntli — ("ourajj**. Bm his -in.i 

Ri 

predecemoi -. Hi? 

K .«»,,] -. 1 1 1¦I 
morals. 1 1 
1 1 

practical nn&gt;rals. I [i lonmj Ku -. 

potism. M' I 

a |&gt;iu'|&gt;ii~i ' 

a fnitjMi 

mb he could, 

as he could 

tougue, -m i lial 


women, and el 
I take the can i ; 

witinen. an 

I take il 

ill*- union tli 
tii*torv &lt;h'iw 

tin- union thai 

history showf I 

k 

t'orin or subject-m 


Here we Kave tin theo 

spirit 'ial and ni&lt; &gt;ral I ruth, an 

eye, and the laws r»l lijfht, 

and the laws 

the world an indelihli impn • 
It is interesi iiil: I 

thies, pointed &lt; &gt; c 1 1 certain dan ; 

work in lii- day to the in 

work in lii- day to the injun 
ntf to authority. 

toin in tin- fiirtnationM of opinions. \ 

&lt;»t the unskilled manv. And 

show of pretense of knowleg 

in 1885, and uttered these not 

have Keen? Have not the phrases something ol 

These were the daneerc of Knjjland in 1 1 1 * - thirteentl 

of them menace America in the nineteenth. ["be i 

148 </seg>




            <seg id="p150">
. TKXDEJH OF I'lBl.K INS/TRI&lt; TION. 

149 

he truth — it is to get a sight of the iuy?- 

4 tl 

rnal. which only faithful studv can reveal, 

r 

nest, mental toil. This is the true stimulus 

ii. Does :imv one propose something different as the 

ilar? F« he counseled to find not what i- 

I u|) ;t party, will support a theory, what will 

group "t peraoaa? Then he is counseled to 

\ 

I [e - taught to contaminate the truth. Listening 

A 

m be «ti i- not the clear water of the stream of 

-lining to -uch counsel, he rims into all the 

i 

1 I iv tbe "III philosopher, he becomes a slave of au- 

i 

nt' the unthinking multitude. Superficiality 

ber own ; for only one kind of scholar dare to be 

I 

liat i- he who i&gt; willing to accept the truth, whether it 

supposed interest or pre-couceived notions or not. He 

u 

pies the judicial altitude. 

sport nt the commissioner of education, that ha- fallen 
I find the aggregate of pupils eurolled in all the school* 
iblic ami private, put down at about l"2,600, 86&lt;&gt; in 

I 

It the-e figures are any approximation to the truth 

re certainly impressive. Here is an army, by 
ii vad ing horde- of Xerxes wa.» a mere squad. 

A 

inder drill. It is learning the use of arms, the 
en have ever wielded. This army of 1 2,oiM),860 

nil thai might to give it an enormous advantage in 
inav arise. Fur culture means the masterv of all 

&gt;wer. 

\ 

thi- trained army i- neeiled. Our country, 

and viriuuu- a&gt; we would fain believe it, is yet iu 
langer from igoonaoe. Seven million of the people 

, ten yean •&lt;!' age and upwards, are unable to read and 
i- to read and write 1 How insignificant a qualification 
istandanl! And yet these millions fail to attain it! 
ooe-fnurto of these unlearned citizens hold the balance 
&gt;\ver. they arc numerous enough to make a formidable 
elves. UnleM we are willing to l»e ruied by ignorance. 

ial 

Ei made a 
niiT that ( </seg>

            <seg id="p151">
ritiral p&lt; 
li\ them 

I 


" 

ixture, :i deleterious compound, which is fatal t&lt;&gt; 


Kw, if oar Bvstems of education have any value. 
90, now training in our schools, ought to defei 
t least against these impending evils. Bui t"&lt;l 

Spirit &lt;&gt;t union. Thev must aim 
without unity of plan and par 
¦ neeil to fear it. it- brigades a 
th in fighting •¦,-u-li other. So wil 

A 

lucat 

ii 

Krength i- iH'i'ili'il in meeting tt 
&gt;p close up it- rank*. Its 
to the satnt 1 in Pin \ ii 

Men claimed 

IT. \ 

Ktimi- jiut forth in 
¦v there '¦' ¦ 

¦ibnonnal 
Iwajij re 
from t; 

\ 

¦¦ free«loiii 
ml scholi 
irlitterin 

Now. tlii- -tat' 

(rational men. \ 
;m&lt;l tile In^li who 

¦as long a&lt; the 
by which the 
r in the twinkl 

Kirn&gt;ii~ concerns will 
llv conflicts unset tli 
i. W e are unable 
al man. 

I'liis evil, I think. ma\ 

¦ing- of a few simple points. !.• 
college is a good tliiii".'. It is a prom 

r.ol iMviliza 

a stimulant to a sound morality. It- graduates having I 

to haliits of careful thinking, are able in after lite to deal ra 
with great problems. The normal school is i good thins. 


150 </seg>



            <seg id="p152">
&lt; &gt;llc nt' T 1 1 * - |irinc-|i;i! ilanj 
1 &gt;:n-&lt; &gt;n'-- time, was 'ii 

allowed. Thai liai 


ihorl ¦ time for naming the blessin. 
I In' public ln^h school is a good thing. 

u n that has the public spirit to main 

i weigh it&gt; worth. Hut what con 

When shall we proaoaaee 

•a 

ivorthv of commendation ? \\ hat 

ly ami thoroughly thf work which 
t!ii- class".' Does it give substantial. 

•ranches which, according ti&gt; its name, it 

ege, does it insi.-t that it- diplomat -hall 
It a normal school, arc its gradoata tit 

•red in the affirmative, the institution s&lt;. 
lended. Faithful, honest, conscientious 

xtenl indicated by the name of the in- 

ini genuine test. This is a test that everv 

ii the land rejoices to he tried by. 
i such a test i* found the unity tor which 

and in every other institution this requirefaithfully 
labor to do the work it pretend&gt; 

very other beght in honesty to com- 

rhiiii: ti&gt; be avoided is a contemptuous cupthai 
lie- outside of our own s|&gt;ecial field; 
a generous catholicity in our own investivmpathy 
with all forma of thorough stud). 

the friends of thorough culture, from 

it threatens the land, as against the army of 

the lively of culture to serve their own 

present a united and determined front. 
lild, a compact society of teachers and learner* 

in thoroughness and honesty — a brotherhood ten million 
\&lt;*ut seekers ii&gt;r the truth ' 


151 </seg>


            <seg id="p154">\ 


il&gt;lir school**.</seg>
            <seg id="p156">
 I shall Dot profane th&lt; 

which shall settle the point? It 

would !"¦ tin' reasonable inquiry: 

they are nominally prepared? \\ lien 

rgarten, in the primary school, in every 

reity and the professional school. As&gt; 



IThY FoK coi'NTRY schools 

1 



• I- Till- MANUAL. 

isi:tnt limiiiiiiiii ot teacber 

tep, credit for the work :»&lt; 

i 

ring tin- work of different schools, 
iu from a united effort. 

! 

iiini- to iinilcrstaiul more fully what 
tor tlii' children, and thus en- 

! 

vitfa the Teachers' [nstitute Man— I. 
i-ih| together by the teacher. 

uv saperintendente in placing in the 
ntv institute a guide ami course of 

11 

¦ use it. </seg>

            <seg id="p157">
ruofn ;i- practicable :t* j&gt;o-- 

esulting trom a united enort. 
idi' the miml- ot' the pupils principles 
ipli» and pages. 
wlviintage '&gt;i ;i &lt;livcrsnv of tezt-booka by 
iidering il j &gt;» &gt; — 1 1 ? I • ¦ for pupil- to ust svhat- 

i-o|&gt;e ration. 
ivork -d thai when |Hi|)il&gt; have 00B- 
I Missed the required examination 
¦il to ;in\ oi the high wfaoob ol the 
admission. 


Ol'KSK OF ST1 ' \&gt;\ 

I'li.' following explanator 

iVi- 

while i»thers rwiuire ;i longer tinn 

il iliai tin 1 rlasse- will 

ii tin* bee 

beguMtng of th&lt; 

« 

l.-tt off. It 

-hould liegriii ai 


At tin- end 

¦ ¦ xho 

iarv ' 

i 

&lt; I ram mar &lt; 'our* 

Higher Uoursi 


K— Bui fern 

156 </seg>



            <seg id="p158">
¦ our 1 -* of studv. The tim&lt; 

lYerage time nefessarv t&lt;&gt; do th&lt; 

•allinir for n*w&lt; ,, ninths xchnol. Some olas 

B..C tli&lt;- el*8 
repared for 

Intermediate • 


LASSIKK'ATION. 

OUKSJ 

Keader, including Ljanguage, Writing and 

t;\l Kl'l ATI. i iH'list 

I. 

Uygienr, wiib &gt;(«cial refereuce to \h 
.i«m the liuinau 4y«em. 

157 </seg>

            <seg id="p159">\ 



1 ir-i Reader, including Writing, I«an- 

ulei . tirsl luilt 


KA M MA I! CO1 K.SI 

First ( 'i.\— Fourth Read 
1. Reading. 

Languat;*' ;m&lt;l ( 

Writin 

SlM-llll 

i 

Ai'itln 

( leotri 

158 </seg>


            <seg id="p160">

RSE. 

&lt; lew. 

Reader 

methods. Train pupils to pronounce 
tli written and printed forms. The 

ig word. I)o not teach pupils to proelv. 
Phrases should be pronounced al- 

Lei the spoken language be the truide 
¦ 'I IliW to be natural: to talk, not 

_• iliiu^. Train the pupil to see the 

to speak it. Mever train in 

Irani 

¦ •"py a — 1 1 1 ljt 1 &lt; • word, a- " cat. 
Let tin in draw it slowly. After 

Is 

v teach how to draw a 

nil word ~lii.iiM 

ter 

pup 

have learned tin- position 

I the child can be easily 

readv to write. I)., 

hi- best every day. When 
h tlie child to use caphak 

L'i proper marks, at the 

11 their use becomes habitual. Be 
aid form good habits in all his </seg>

            <seg id="p161">x 

&lt; mIKSK &lt;»F STUDY. 

&gt;IioiiM lw pronounoed usually a&gt; if a 
- 

line, then the head lin&gt; 

alee the short Inter* of uni- 
r lines of the scale mav U- 

inrow. Allnw no slovenly 


• 

of numbers d&lt; 

160 </seg>



            <seg id="p162">

N 

161 </seg>

            <seg id="p163">i.l 


\ 

\ 

r 

I! 

. 

. licit 


ivanl ii'iin 1 t 


162 </seg>

            <seg id="p164">Ui 


ill. |..-n 
ki'MH ill! 



163 </seg>


            <seg id="p165">s 

I 

I 

A 1 1 1 i U 

I 

i 

.\ 

I 

i leu 1 hat dues 1 1 &lt; • t bear on i In 

use the child's 

¦re t lie pupil 


hi I- :ili|t 

\ pupil- Ul ''gill 

(W, II|R"I1 lln 

im! ki 

Hav. 

|»r sp. 

ilitficull written again an&gt;l 
mil have class lo..|&lt; at them 

eir forms are ti xed in their 
i 1 &lt; I t"i - 1 1 pronounce each sv Inu-i 
Irani to n uuize ami 

capitals ami |ieriu&lt;Js, ijuesil 
t'i -&lt;c -rill. Her- allll {• 
I" Infill ami how to clow 

margin* un l»&gt;tli sith 

|i lines even In all work 

&gt;n- an win! li mure at tliiwlgi'. 
Peach the pupil t&gt;&gt; 
examples lead him t" see 

drawn tlirotii;li it . 

i gives the child tlie nanii- 
Iter life. See that he dues 

know thai it is a lauin:ain 


I tin i'vv : that i». lir-t 

rapid - il: In -[ &gt;r&lt; -n 11 n»-i- 
IV surf thai tlic clincl 

Mill I1M1I ill -¦ 11 1 Pi 1' •! I - 

&gt;l •• ¦ 1 1 . As in spelling, train 
;is»ijjll li — • •¦ i — to l»- gu&lt; 'I 
easv " ; 1 • &gt; 1 1 ix " &lt;•, marked 

slioi i ¦¦ \ , a breve 

; i ill -i ri|iiiini- etui be given 
ritten — a language !«•— uii. 


164 </seg>

            <seg id="p166">II 

\ 

1". I 


165 </seg>
            <seg id="p167">
stki'i no.N. 

\ 

i.l Reader will be 

nguage is more &lt;litliciili 
• I for some |iii|ni-. 
jinuini; nl 1 1)6 
¦V..I-.I-. l..-t them 
M nli ili' liook* o|ieu. 
ml i- usetl in 

I for somt |iii|ni-. 

ninii of ilic 

word-. l.&lt;'t them 

,\ nit ih. Immik- 

used in 


\ small ilicii 

iiarv -li.'iiiil 

\ small ilii'i ionarv should 
ii t. . i||.i'n\ er 
rhidiny their division 
e — "ii lisi.s been ~ 1 1 1 ¦ 1 u -• I 
ml a si r two 

¦u\ i i 

livisioii 

\ li, i t lit' lessi hi h:i- I). in -I iiilii'il 

line or i « 

--ii i- arrange I in 1 lit 1 i L 
umI read ;i» *u«'h. I lave 
-•- .'! nil wonl.-i uliii-li 
v tin-in often. Have 

rnun 

1. 1 read n- sooh. I bvi 

w&gt;ril- which 

them nften. Hav&lt; 

foil u i-li in '.•-! i he da 

- \ .in m ish to t'--i i lie class. 
il&lt; . ,-- -i-t i-ijt . id 

(- tiir suiiml 

• till' ' r " lias tin- -"illi'l ¦•! 
i i! t ¦-* 1 1 ; &lt; 1 I »\ "ri. In 

~ } • 1 1! t -« 1 1 ; i I I »\ "'i. In 

N ,,ll,,|. A 

ion i il ;i- il is s|telle&lt;l. \ 
learn box t" 
r.l- i 'liiklren can l»e 

imi|i!\ liHtkinu ;it tli&gt; picture 

ik mi j ;ii ili. piotun 

insjle inoineni 

ircsontH I'm i -inuic inoilltfllt 
til tin- el tain ol events 

I hi i n hi event* 

'I that v. liich follows it in 

il lolloU- It III 

¦ 'iii|p;ir;il \vv\\ vhs\ to writ" . 

» i Ii ron^li t Ih I k. &lt; Mu¦ 
I" nion \i I 1" tin- I'll i 1(1 
\- nenrlv all Headers 
;uagf work tin- teacher 
I lie work, bo« 
i letter-w riiiiii; are 

I U) tin 1 rlnlil 

k tin' teacher 

ni'iiasie « 

I in- work, hov 

; ii letter-w riliiii; art 

wtioe in ilii- art, studying 

art, -tmlvin- 

iln- 

io Mini endini&gt; nl ;i letter. 

io ;t i n 1 ending "i a letter. 

labil "I ii-ini: ;i ad form foi 

iliii nl u-iiii; a net form for 

ler should suggest new ideas. 



166 </seg>

            <seg id="p168">
place the English sentence correctly upoi 

which work include- writing, spelling, u 

lar and plural forms, case forms, etc., and 

ami how to do it. I 'se read in 

model-. Train pupils ((/observe pr 

lolle should lie doi 

reading lessons. 1 

Make it a supplementary reader. i;&lt; 

ansuei tin-in 

ati 

\ 

\\ 

'I 


Peacl 

I.. 

let! 

Lead the |Mi] 

-pa 

rail classes below the Third Reader, have I 
hoard, slate, and paper, with chalk and \« 


1..A. -I AiiK . i in," &lt;ih|(vt in tin&gt; grade i- in 

I se blackboard to -how pupil* ext 

tiv letter 

from the li'-^ii 
penmanship is 
quired uiilv bv 

system oi scientific anah 



not tn attempt to shade the Utters. 
pies of letter*, bills, notes, and lni»i- 

tbese ezereira uloin\ tbougta they are 
preparing tlmoti ererj ¦• 

--"ii should be devoted to spelling dull' 
thi- be well done the teacher who 

iiy dames can dispense with a -|&gt;eoial 
( Third Reader grade. Tbe new word* 
ling and other lesson; should be exam'1 
with the hook- open, first by teacher 
at the time of assigning the lesson. 

i 

&gt;.l 

r with the names &lt;&gt;t' familiar objects— 
lines of mouth-, of people and bosi 

I 

i 

w, familiar towns, township-., and 

sale in tbe stores, the cardinal — one, 
"in hundred ; the ordinal: — first 

used in the various studies the 
pertaining to the farm, etc. — mav 

be used, the lemons should !&gt;&lt;¦ pro- 

¦Ml- iKXMBrring in daily conversation should 

ing up other-. :;. The pupil s|| ( , u |,| 

t hi- own inakin 

I Id 

ind -oiiud- ..t letters should !«¦ 

'i!. miikiplii-.itioii, and -hurt divi— 
irntaiv arithmetic. Teach the ninl(Jive 
the claas much work in addi- 

167 </seg>


            <seg id="p169">
S :ii)M all ;iIm)V&lt;* it, will u.-?e t lit? |KMi. 
the following order: 1. O, D, E, (.'. 2. Q, 
V. /. 3. A. \. M. T, F, K, H, S, L. 4. 

ii~, and no spelling 1« k &gt;k need !»¦ 

* — »&gt;n i- assignee!, prom the open 

1. Pronunciation should precede 

o -. dive the i-laaa ranch work in uckli- 
pi'l work. In-i-t upon having neat *l(it&gt; 


168 </seg>
            <seg id="p170">
' •! ¦"¦«.]:. \l' 1 1\ 

file oh 


lap ti 

I 'raw mail 

Have |ui|ii 

represent 

«li-triii. Writ) 

fork and good fiffiirett. Teach lm\\ 

n presental ion ; 
Take |ni]iil- on 

l(ir;iiin&gt;r roads, liro) 
\\ rite a Mm "I nl.ii 




169 </seg>
            <seg id="p171">
the inch. File district map. Work 

ap in the Bame wav as district map. 

permits extend t i it- study over 
¦ pupils are acquainted with. 

imv vou 

and railroads. Teach climate 
¦il it : a- to temperature, liot, 
isture, dry, wet, damp ; as to 

iv tow 

xiHTiem 

to in 

iinl unhealthy. Teach direction)) to trave 
¦to. Teach the useful vegetation of neigh 

ike lists &lt;&gt;t articles raised "&gt;n the farm 

&gt;vith theni ; tbase sent away arc called 
"I vegetable productions brought in foi 

Ma 

¦ottee, cinnamon, rubber, camphor, etc. 
¦ai'h i- produced. Have compositions 

w these are prepared for use after they an 
1 1 |M&gt;8sil&gt;le have pupils learn how they an 

\| 

tgraphies tell thi-. Direct pupils bow 
information. Follow same plan with 

ils. l'» —ii i - « - to -tuilv exports and iiumluial 
and semi-card inal points. 

iijj railroads, towns, rivers, woodlands. 

etc. Develop a definition (or each. 
idicating principal rivers separated l&gt;\ 

towns, three or four railroad 

it tent ion to the fad that a countv 

- are tl»e Mine in all parts. But the 
\ he divided into regions producing 

ieat ami trait in the south. 

It' 1 !' V 

wheat in the noi th. Studv 

prill}; 

11^ I \|M'lt 

( 

I i; 

Hi- iriven for the 

First Intermediate Reading 

? E . ¦ n t" accent, inflection, and emphasis. 


¦ In the work. In-i-t em Btraigbt lines 
• I be straight, a- representing roads, 
ii school liuii-e». churches, and town-, 
ll time permits extend t i it- stmlv nvei 


170 

REP&lt; IHT i &gt;F 

[UK 

Pay much attention to the diacritical mark 

: and all punctuation mart 
I class bring other readi 

thoroughly tau&lt;rlit 
Have members i 
practice reading it 

ore the ola 


(ht pupils and rev • sho 


ti I'AtiK. 
riii- class sbould read, write, and spell well, wri 
and write compositions &lt;&gt;n familiar tliinu- 
work shoukl be mainly narration ai first. N 

Pupil* should f'oi 
hcinc- : ;t~ in </seg>

            <seg id="p172">
sjxlliin/ lessons 
la in/iniifi tWI'i 


V 

he elementary arithmetic, including a 

&gt;f addition, subtraction, multiplication, and 
vision. lie iK-rfa-t in the tallies to twelve. 
for long ami square measure, avoirdupois 
able lit' time. 

Ige : t" iea&lt;'!i geographical vocabulary 
i use; tn enable pupils to l&gt;e&lt;-&lt;&gt;me more 

interpreting, and usin&gt;: maps. The 
I li. use i&gt;l some elementary te.\t-lx&gt;ok ; 

iictai i and directions of author. Have pupils 
mil recite with books open, as in readers. Have 

e questions al-o. Jor others lo answer. Thi» 
ill liiinl words and mispronunciation-. Take 
e for these to lie learned. I se diacritical 

I lave pupils find uti maps all place- a-ked for, and 
complete statements their location. Be care- 

lant;uaee drill. Have new and difficult 

I. divide into xvllablea and spelled. Keep 
I review t'requeiitlv. Have written work 

r plan- ot your own. Study picture 

k hi them ; refer to them often io illu 

the text. All charts and diagram 

.1 with book open. Pupils may !«¦ re. 
in at'terwanls. Map- should be studied 

All marginal explanations as: comiiarative 
latitude, corajwrative heights of 

water, 

I. -tndie.l. and learned. For 

and ot maps, alter intelligent 

XI 

ews, liavejiooks closed; have pupils anfrequently 
have written answers. Relief 


171 </seg>

            <seg id="p173">
Primary &lt; reography. 
ii.K are In give |&gt;ii|&gt;il&gt; a m»*\ outline of 

'onvparative temperature, etc, 

t \ ['lain 

lied :i 1 1&lt; 1 iiii|HM*taul places lcxitnl upon 



172 </seg>


            <seg id="p174">
hill, plain, mountain, valley 
volcanii. island, i-tlmin-. &lt;¦, 

\ 

M 

( 

1/ 

• '' 

\l 

hth 

Vni 

I lie \\l--t 

the iMMindarv i &gt;t K 

and has no mil 
Strait* mi'l &lt; htm tu 

mil ronii'-ii- 

\ 

Mc\ic( 

bjects and pietun 

1 1 1&lt; — . iii nature or in i&gt; 

11). Have I 

1 ', ' ¦ill' ¦ 
¦* 
. — The 
lacliian i 

Sean, (riiffn lln 


north of central Illinois, and baa the 

¦t 

iimd \iy the junction nt the Ailegbany 
n iln western part of Pennsylvania and 

the Mississippi. 

- at tlic [unction "t the Platte ami Missouri 
Nebraska. 

\M MAI 

&lt; H'KSf 

&lt;l ( '/asm 

;• ader for the Kii'-t &lt; 'lass. The Second &lt; 'la* can 
Mi Reader it' tin Fourth is thoroughly mastered. 

the work notiil for 1 1 *« - Third Header. 
thoroughly acquainted with 1 1 it* use oi tlit 

•t a reasonable nunilni 1 of com- 

s 

• liabil oi usiu)i reference i»Hik~ in the 
iding lessons and in connection with out- 

ml explain rlieiorical figures. 
\ /. ili. iln, uulit of an autlioi 

(•cording to authors, reading them 

'ii- 

- will become acquainted with tin 

up 

tioiis read ami tin 1 sketches 

ESTION 

graphical, biblical, scientific, literary, biograpbrical 
allusion to l&gt;e pMsed over without an ex- 

\ 

173 </seg>



            <seg id="p175">
liifal -kitclic- ol eminent author* and 

ir the be»l literature and direct 

eii by the teacher. Pupil." should writi 

mrc l&gt;&lt;&gt;i&gt;k.-, anil the teacher 


|ter»o!iification, ironv, ;i [ &gt;&lt; i~ 1 1 
max. Much c.T the |&gt;leasur 
staixliiii! rliL'torical ti^i; 

RuL II. — Doubling ol linai cou^ 

ileriratiri , a~ applied t" 'la — es of words. Sli 
words are made from simple, and •'¦ 

174 


I 1 1 1 &gt;1 I r- ~MOIll(l llf latlglll 11/ 

each simile, metaphor, hyperbole, metonoi 

¦/. — Final silent &lt; u 
,-..nk 

Biitli ;i great Dumber "t wo 
Ifiealion &lt;&lt;/' Words. — I&gt;etin 
</seg>

            <seg id="p176">
175 

&gt;1 IMKI.H 

[XSTKl'CTIOX. 

S 

N 


t 

l*ii|*il: — -hould select words from 
¦ illustrate the wide use of suffixes 
¦d «t«e "f common prefixes; make 

the wide application ot km, m. 

hx 

\ 

X 

tix 

x din. 

il&lt;l ham a few simple rules for panel 
lailv practice in their written work. 

A 
\ 

ties, naiiK'- written alone, and addn — « 
1 . After a direct question. 
_'. To express doubt. 

\iter the expression of strong emotion 
i t and k . 
ill an. I abbreviated forma of days .. 

year, titles, commercial terms, etc. 
iation- and contraction of word* l&gt;v 

v classified li-ts: as tliost' refer 

weights, and measure*, 

i 

Ex 

vn-t use of the comma here given. 
i off a series of elements, 
t oil elements in pairs. 

1. T 
•J. T 
:;. '1 
4. I 

nclose words in opposition 
ut off words of address. 
iark omissions of a verb. 

6. I 

inpound and derivative won)- in 

iw ainl u-'- i&gt;l common -utlixo. llt-tiii] 

i- . /¦. ¦&lt;/. en, nil, lest, etc.: ruake 

«e -i ntenoea not interrogative &lt;&gt;i i\ 
iiuatory. 
abbreviations. 

preceded by a consonant. 

in mark omissions of a verb. 
I', i enclose parenthetical expression* 


17 </seg>
            <seg id="p177">
176 



\ 

- 

Ill III"-! -dlnnl- 11 \\|1| III- m-i-i — 

ir &lt; 'mirse. I n manv recitations 

I II till' Si-( .,11.1 ( 111-- tW'l 

i. « ¦¦! i&gt;r 




mm 


hn 

Ription — ( a ! developed 1 1 
'inline- giveti bv teacln i 
D) from obeervatiou alum 

Ei I. — Final ii in ;i primitive preo 
dvuition. — I &gt;(¦ nt the colon ; qu 
Jsisli, semicolon, and parenthesis. 

itv \\ 


HOW, HHKS 

• |i;u 

Who, wiik ii. niA'i 

manv blank- 

n lorn 

t'lM •-. 
!'' - l\ III'!- 
ripal, ; B) subonliuii 

&lt; (»m posit ion — Xarrati&lt; 

BUJ troui observation alone, u 
acini forms ; u~c nt apostro] 
HER, Niil! : EITHER, OR 
</seg>

            <seg id="p178">
177 



ik in an elementary grammar ti 

he l'n;&gt;r Intermediate Cl.a 

-I I ink 

thai requires use of t lie dictionary 

important u&gt;c ot' the ilii-tioni'.rv i~ to 
ion; iK*xt, to pet the meaning ; next. 


n that i- not at the 

hat it ran Ik- n-nl in a -cut' me 

iv reiiuirinu oral ami written 

it: 

Be sure that difficult 

riters, and the newsiiapere. 
i. even it' there !»¦ no -|&gt;rll- 

Si. 

roilj/hlv lan 


VARIABLY, VARY : PLAY, 
AN'-Kl:. I&gt;ANOEROUS, 1»AN- 

eading ; (b) tin- addn — ; (c) the 
. ili" gubNcription ; | r) the signa- 
i'l punctuation of the |&gt;;irt- of ¦ 
i nioii use. 

\ &gt;-. t mil 5 copy-bonka. Have tin- pu|&gt;il&gt; 
i, neat '-.i|iv-l k-. Their oopv-book? -how 
it- • than anv "tln-r one lxM«k. 

ivation. Diacritical markings 
ihiwe in iiiimniii] ii-..- niav be 
1 understood when tin ilictioo- 

lial the table &lt;&gt;t' valuer i- tn 

iv page nt the dictionary. Jfo 

Kwii a list i)l mi— •¦¦! u,&gt;r.l- mi lin 

OIUll -(K'llinu 1« — &lt; .11 ;it 

&lt; ;ill for thetn often. ;i» 

Die object of tin reci- 

nt ami lix td.- difficult wonla. 
&gt;nl* in part fr lailv convtr- 


Fir 

( Itlsx 

-•/ </seg>

            <seg id="p179">
A.RITHMETK . 

Begin practical arithmeti 

:uid advano 

( "lilt /''ttt'lll 

Illl 

4, aliquot parttt : ¦&lt;, factoring 

Siiru/estionx : I se ;i good \\ t-i t t &lt; i i arithmeti 

-imIciik iii- "I principles, explanation* illusti 

,\ 

-;i\-&lt; time. W li&lt; ii p 

\\ 

similar ti (¦ 
Have a blai 

problems ii 

not tulerate clovenlv \\ 
in use ol arithmetical 
methuds in teaching n 
Institute .Manual as ti 

rk 

¦lation 

Division. 

Common fractions: Show the ident 

operations as n&gt;e«l with fractions 
In tin- various cases ot reduction o 

berequired to use tin- knowledge ami 
exercises in factoriug uumbere. 

In addition and subtraction, f'ractii 

whole numbers, in column!-. A- iu whole nun 

nomination should \&gt;&lt;- indicated but once. The trad 

be reduced at once to ft tbeir least common denominator, 
may !*• less than any one of the given denominators. 
In multiplication of fractions, divide the denominator, wh 

sible, in preference to multiplying the numerator; and 

178 </seg>

            <seg id="p180">
!i"ii-. a 

llllVl 

[&gt; 

Train in oral ex plu 
given in &gt; "i&gt;k. l'i 

to mak&lt; 

figures than ui i &gt;a&lt; I u ril inj 
school. I 'rael ice « ril in^ ar 
&lt;&gt;r examination [japen- ilurii 
\\ ill husines- I ransa&lt;-l ious ip 

iiiguatr* 1 . I 


n possible, in preference to 

.VII 

ids for teaching them as a ~|&gt;e- 

ilecimal ami of decimal to 

•rations with decimals, showinj 
1 ;i- used with whole iiiiiiiIht 

i 

v work preceding percentage tliat the 

through, i, percentage; 2,mtere*t; 
nnd. lorn; 5, commimion ; 6, mwr': 
9, ratio and proportion; 10, ev- 

~"on&lt;t .m*l First IliritiQtn* 

I 

1'iiit'n' work as given in the text-book 

North America. The several states 

liter the completion of the above 

NKBRA.SKA. 

ide, outline (regular or irregular), 
i miles, area (compare in mzc witli 

i-. liiilv 

'- exact ronptituti il) of home state 
Missouri, Platte, Xiobrara, lilm-. 

&lt; I i mate . Modified 

Natural advantages: &lt; &gt;n the surface, in the earth, on the 

wain 

Occupation: Agricultural, manufacture, transportation 

Internal improvements: Railroads (5), state house, penitentiant&gt;, 
colleges, asylums, .etc. 

179 </seg>

            <seg id="p181">
xactly expressed a- decimals'? 
ii ¦ -ii ex |&gt;n issiw 1 '.' 


180 




9. Name and locate five prominent cil 

officers, teachers. 

11. Number &lt;&gt;t' counties, boundaries of \ 

Vdopt tlii— in- Home other similar t 
needed in \\ ritten reviews. 

Draw map 

A pupil may plat* forms 
I each state ; the teach 
found in tlic outline, 
sufficient interest, he 

-iliniai 
r shou 


SecoHfl &lt; 

Geocjkaphy. 
This class will complete the -tinlv.it Geographv. La 
class should be combined with the Kirsl &lt; 'lass, or tl </seg>

            <seg id="p182">
ii 

10. Education: State Superintendent, county sunerinl 

\ eyetable pnxlurti 
Mineral productioi 
&lt; Hijcri- of intt-n si 

It ill. tl 
ll'Mllll III-' 


ial attention to the mathemat 

rd ni the '-las~ i~ completed. 

niliar with the events of the 

biographies of noted men, 

&gt;vn chronological tables; recite from 

where the armies went, and direr. 

xplorations," or " Monroe's Adinin- 

minor topics from which lie i&lt; to recite. 

• u hat like the following 

1 192 San Salvador 
1493 Isabella. 

198 South America 

&gt;' '- ( 'entral America. 

il"J South Sea. 

St. AtiguBtine. 

Kurope at the close of the 15th 
i\:il ol Learning, Reformation. 

tlement &lt;it America '.' 

~i OVERY 

( 

iwing did if.,'/., Balboa tliscoveretl the 

181 



Lreo^iaphy &lt;&gt;! the places :it 

v ami it- republican institution-. 
¦in 1 K&lt;&gt;od text-book, and should 

ubjevtx in other books. l'upil- 

Ii«t assign letwom by general 

When studying, the imi-ii. should !*¦ trained to 

".]•; Florida. 

v_'o Magellan. 

1 "&gt;4 1 Mississippi. 

&lt; nliiiiiiiii- and ( !ortez. 

ill. expeditious ¦ &gt;(' De 8oto ami Xarvaez. 
</seg>

            <seg id="p183">
182 

REPORT OF TH1 

Pacific ocean): Pome de Leon, Balboa, 1 &gt;" A \ 
Coronado, Cabrillo, Melendez, Espejo. 

rms. — Sootbern |&gt;:in of the I'nited Static. Mex 
Ajrarioa, South America, and Wesl ladies. (Thi 
be shown Kv referring to the language, manners, i 
geographical names &lt;&gt;t' this country at th&lt; present i 

li&gt; present 

French 

I. Stmly of the life of LaSalle ami know -tomel 
Jemitta and tin- Hutruenots, 

rell what the following did: 1 &gt;&lt; n\ . V r errazsoni, ( 
baot, Laudonnierre, Demonto, &lt; haplain, Vfarrjuette 
Joliet. 

Vlaimx. — St. Law ti-ijri' ami NI i — i — !»•! i Vallevs and N 

/•. 

&lt; 

rnx mill s^ 

Between 

Route In India. 1 11 

L r ivea general knowledge of the </seg>

            <seg id="p184">
Henrj VI II 
1. &gt;tudv the lives i»( Raleigh, 1 &gt;i 

rell wiiMt the 
Prine, ( Jilbert 

1. IIiinv Hudson 1 

1. What did Main 

Naming of I lulian* 

Daks.— Mak. 

t following i- - 1 1 &lt; - - 1 . - . I : I i 
1541. 1634, 1541, 1609. 

tttL — The iiKiin point in tin 
what territory was claimed 


• rovernnient, religion, education, industries. Com- 

tti and Virginia in these resets. Thpv are 

studied. Prace their influence down to 

(Mason), Rhode Island (Will- 
Androa, Charter ( &gt;ak). 

Patroons 

Stuyvesant, Swedes, New Arn- 

( ) 

1640. '( liarles 1. 
u hi— freedom '.' 

I 

A 

inenl .' I teiinition of each. 

183 </seg>


            <seg id="p185">
\ • A I I . 1 1 II | I- 1 1 I 
muecticut 

"ik.&lt; onquest, Nichols, Audros, Ljeisler, 

George Fox), Early History, 
\ he 1 nilian~, Philadelphia. 

New Jersey &lt;&lt; 'arteret, I'res- 

1 liarles Weslev, llmne tor Poor 

u i! L Spain. 

1 1 I -t;iliii~li :i rt'pre- 
Illl — !• &gt;ll (»f tile Nt'U 

N 'U( mi id . 

Fohn Smith, London Company, 

Representative AMnmbly, Cot- 

)i \ ¦¦!. ami Bacon's Rebellion. 

education, religion, industries. 

Maryland &lt; :uliolic-. ClayborBe'o Rebellioii), 
- Grand Model and John L(K-ke). 

'. — 1. Plymouth Company, 2. Pnritm: Origin 
Cromwell), European wanderings, Plymouth, First 

Boston. \&lt;w Kngland Union, Kitifj Philip'&lt; war 

Persecution fQuakere, Salem Witchcraft), 


184 </seg>

            <seg id="p186">
/• 

/ 

I. Review carefully with maps the French and Ki 
'1. FinM ihree war- should form one topic, a~ tl 

King George'* War. — 1 &lt; 

land. {2) Event: capture of [xuiisbutv. 3 Tn 

and term 

Frt ncii mitl Indktii II .,¦ — 1 75 

• . — ( onHict of rlai 

Vi 

Objectivt Point*.— 1. DuQue- 

\\ 

\\ 

islmr.'. Wlix 

v 

( 

2. What did William I'ii 
Nations of the NOrtl 

Revolutionary officers t rail 
Stark, Arm. M. ( hites, M 

\l 

Kexitlt* i,f Uiis II 

I;. 

i i 

:.. I ?oiliest k 1 life, (ravelin 
iiion -chiKils. mirth, khiii 1 
iam and Marv's. ti. Re 

( 


does tins -how " 

Anglicizing .!///&lt; 

originated in Europe. 
King William'* War. — (1) Cause (James II. 1688 
Seheneotady ami Acadia. (3) Treaty: (place, I 
t/uet a Anne* War, — (1) Cause, succession to the I 
(2) Event: Acailiii. :-&gt; Treaty: f place, term!&lt;) 

I icomieroga and • 'n ¦« 

i . ( rive a description ol i 
"2. liiiiilddck'- defeat 

"I Louisburi; | Kvan 

1. freaty : place, iirin- 

I'll jilli ¦iltinll 
' iHKiitioii u| the colonie* :n 
ulation, &lt;lave and in-. 

-. Han ii i. 
*l"l 1 1 T 1 1 1 ¦ ¦ i ire»si - 


185 </seg>

            <seg id="p187">
Hill representation. 2. French 
Act. with the measures passed to 
1 in retaliation. 4. Tax on tea, 

irce it. ami the measures u»e&lt;l 

-, Sin- ut' Liberty, Minute Men ' 
pic to action : Otis. Samuel Adams, 

s iii italics are the causes ot them ; 
ilt&gt;. Be al)le to ilex-ril* 1 the&gt;e piv- 

:ind Concord. 2. Bunker HM. 3. 

mi Long I«land. 2. Battle qf Lomg 
h New Jersev. 4. Battle of Trenton. 

2. llntndt/wine or Chad's t'or-l 
4. Battle of Germantown. 

'aptareof Forts on C'hamplain. 2. 
Rennington. 4. Surrender of Bur- 
Franoe. H. Evacuation ut' l'hila- 

ill — Green's Retreat. 2. tkur 
rpoottnized. 

\r, 

&lt; rrwii 

Liiici'ln'-, &lt; 'ornwalli 

I iiilc|.ciMlcnr. . [jong Island, Bur 

l'eri&lt; 

inl religion. -. Love &lt;&gt;(' lil&gt;ertv. 
t. &lt; Oppressive rulen : Andrea, 
\. i. •). lntluenci- of Prance. 

n&gt;j. massacre. "_'. Chern Valley 

pter, l'i' -kcii-. 

. Holland, Poland. 
Ian of United St:it&lt; 


riitient Men. — Give sketches of Franklin, Jeff&lt; 
am-, Hain-ock. Hamilton. Morris, 

\ 

rrinniat. — 1. By what authority were the colonies go\ 
tween 1777 ami 17S1 .' g. Articles of Confederation 
adopted by Congress; b, when ratified by the states. 

W 

were it* powers in general, and in particular, ae to i 
domestic commerce, borrowing mo.nev, collecting reve 

in*; armies? d, Of what was Congress composed and 

tides oi Confederation? 6, How weiv the member 
W hat was the executive department " 

Northwestern Territory. — Ordinance of 1787: slavery 

religion, township survey — Thomas Jefferson 

OnutiltUUm, — The three compromise* : (1) Division ol tl 

lative Body. 2) Slavery. (3) Commero 

( 

Wanhingtoit'x. -1789 '¦'. . 1. I *t 

ernment, remov 
itton's financUi/ 

nut 

W 

ion*. — 1801-09. 1. II 
in!" power " 2. I 

\ 

Mtuliitons. — 1809 M 
BventH. . Iln 

five ii|i the ship 
Vew ( Orleans. 

merce. 10. Ihnit. nl • 
I l;ii ri-oii. Tcciim-'li. \\\\\ 

\ 

\\ 

186 </seg>


            <seg id="p188">
¦ Imv - treaty, &lt; ienei 

¦nm'. — 1797-1801. I. .1 
with France. 3. I &gt;«uli 

ex|&gt;editioii. I 
Steam In mi. 7 
Kuropi i. 

&gt;&lt;-'«.— 1817 

MixHouri CoinnroMMi Masoi 
Mouroe I &gt;&lt; &gt;e -i rh k (South Am 
4. LaFayette'n visit. Mm 

•"). &lt; 'ivek Indian Wai 


fe ; how elected, and why? In- 

\ 

Uric, DeWitt Clinton), roads, 

[V 

&lt; laxt 

the administration to 

Dred -Sooti Decision (Taney). 2. John 
[edition.) 3. — seven States — 
America. 4. Atlantic ('able, Cyrus W. 

\ 

Iwi party cane into power? 2. Give 

Ma. 

&lt; 

I 

Webster, Calboan); Slavery. John 
of Lincoln. Firing on Fort Samp- 

Klert 

( 

il War. 

.vms to accomplish one of the follow 

-1861 2. 1. W. Virginia: Phil- 
Kentueky : Belmont. Fort Henry. 

/ 

Kciinesiiw Mountain. 4. Nash 

Monitor I. 6. ( 'harleston. 7 

M 

187 </seg>


            <seg id="p189">
I. Missouri : &lt; tarthage (Siji 
i ml; t &lt; hi (Fremont), l'e;i 1 1 i&lt; l«r» 

Ml 2-3. 1. Belmont. .'. Fort 
Rosults: «, Island So. 10; 6, 

t Forts St. l'liili|&gt; and Jackaon 

8. &lt; 'orinth. 7. Iuk;i. 8 

1. ( 'hu'kaniauga. '_'. Chat- 

l&gt;;ilt.m : /&gt;. Resacu 

rhrougli the ' '.iroiina 

18m- 2 8- 1. 1. North Carolina 
mi'. '¦'&gt;. Romnoke Island. 4. 
Monitor |. ii. ( 'harleston. 7. 


."». To Capture Ridimond. — 1862-3--4— 5. I. Peninsular &lt; 

(Seven Days' Battle). 2. Fredericksburg (Burns 

Chancel loravi lie (Hooker). 1 Cold Harbor. 

Sheridan's Ride). 6. PeUrthurq and Rickmo 

I To Defend Washington. — 1861-2-8. 1. Bull Run (McD 
•_'. Second Battle of Bull Run (Pop . 3. Intieiam M 
Ian). 4. ( rettysburg I Meade). 

Other /¦&gt;. nts. 

Other I 

¦ii'/n llelationg. — I mn Affair, Alabama. 

&gt;¦ Mi (/.in, &gt;.s. — Greenbacks, •Cooscriptiou Act, Riol X. Y., ] 
'¦i|iaii(in Proclamation. 

\ 

dt. — Sheridan, Early, Stoneman, Morgan, Pol 

ivuxstnus. — Sanitary, &lt; 'hristiao. 

( 

minent Men. — 1. Generals: Name live uromii 
each side; also the prominent umanders killed 
'1. Civilians: Seward, Stantun, Chase, Suraner, I 1 
rison, (ireeley, Beeclier, war b 

t com 

-. Civilians: Sewanl, Stanton, Chase. Sumner I 

¦&gt; 

risoo, &lt; ii 

A 

Turning Point*. — Jtilv 1 
tor. 

Turning Point*. —.July 1, 2, 
tor. 

llh President. — Assassination ' i. 

7 /c Pruidt ni . — A — a — mat i"i 

Cod. — Number of men enlisted, 

Rrriew. — Tra 

Renew. — Trace iii^ can 
iiimii. Karrajfiit, Lee. lieview 

Remifo.— State Rights ; XIII. XIV. \\ \ 

Result*.— .State Rights; XIII. X 

Johnson*. — 1860. I. Kreediufii'« i 
Johnson. ¦¦',. Tenure ot &lt; Mfice B 
whom governed ami upon whal term.--tic 
( Sable. B. Alaska. 7. I 
in Mexico. Monroe I kxtrim . 

whom governed ami up&lt; 
tic ( iable. &gt;,. Alaska. 
in Mexico. Monroe 1 &gt;i 

Grant's. — 1869-77. — 1. Genevn A 

Grant's. — 1869-77. — 1. Geneva I 
¦'}. Northwestern Boundary ol German) 4 I 
BoMton. ."&gt;. Financial Panic, tj. Speci&lt; Uesumptioi 
Centennial, 1876. 8. Civil Kiglit.« I 
partmenl Established. In. Electoral commwsion. 

•"i. Northwestern Boundary ol (rerinani 4 ] 
Bontoii. ."&gt;. Financial Panic. tJ. Speci&lt; I.' 


« 

Centennial. 1876. 8. Civil liight.-i Bill. '.'. W 
[wrtment Established. lOi Eli mmiasiou. 

Hnyes\ — 1X77-.S1. — 1 . Extra 8es 

Hnye*\ — 1877-81. — 1. Kxtra Seasinn. 2 Sped, Ret 
vetosa. i. Civil Service Reform. 5 (Jrai 
1 . &lt; 'liinese I mminratioa. 

&gt; 

/ 

188 </seg>


            <seg id="p190">
ff. 4. Standard Time. 

1 

II 

/ 

\ i ''a, I'ncf. From whom'; Bv 

fferson 

in whom? By whom? Object. 

From whom? Object. William 

\ 

Baltimore Failure. 

\\ 

Jefferson. 

\\ 

David \\ 

I W 

Kan&gt;as- N'el bill, J knitilas 

l»i.'.| Scot I decia eft'ed u|Km former slave legislation 

•an. .ii proclamation, Unroll). 

QIC patriotic pieces committd 

189 </seg>

            <seg id="p191">
Vrea, l'ri&lt;v. Object. Sam Hous- 

I &gt;. 1 1 1-. Area comprise* -what states 
i. Kit ( arson. 

Date, Are*, Price. From whom? &lt; )l&gt;ject 

1 Hiicil States Bunk. 2. Jackson's 

il rax], &lt; 'redii Mobilier. 
iml Battles. 


A I'V A Ni KI&gt; OOU li-l\ 

Wlteu t lie three Foregoing 

nirses arc nmii 

nil 

Elementary algebra 

It the other courses li:i\ 

,\ 

«. 

v 

liraiichi 

in oiirago iiml 

and ! &gt;&lt; &gt;&lt; .k- k&lt;-&lt; j &gt;t 

The entire school should be thorough 

rhe following figures shoald be 
Second Intermediate cla*v&lt;*en sin 

a&gt;«T 

190 

N 





( 'ivil government. 

r aritlim 

l&gt;iM&gt;k-ki'&lt;'|iiiiL r "i" physiology 

Sj-ntence :tnalv 

regular course- I 

i &gt;f dy 

should l» in il 
'inentarv algebra 

For ati • &gt;ui line in Cii 
I 'nited States, «*e T 

inir ami locatiug land aoconlinj </seg>

            <seg id="p192">
N I ) E X 

1 </seg>


            <seg id="p194">
N I ) E X 



n 

13 

i:n iv) 



1 

i 

i 

!&lt; 

j 

I 

' 

' 

II 

t. 


1 

• 

: 

10 


Rwubih of State Ikstiti now 
Institute for Blind 
Institute lor Denf and Dumb 
Institute tor Feeble Minded 
State Industrial Schoo 

¦district record Uvik» 
records and reports.. 
-vsteni of Nebraska. 
•rtiiicatf ~ 

titistical tables 
A 11-1 II A I. T\ 

Uesourti 

Kzpendil 

'¦&gt;. Suiubei teacl 
t. \|I!I|)m'1 

N tin 

u*\ an 

Numlii 

I'lind- 

!/. Names 

lii. I'artia 

Keporti* ol college** and p 
cliers. general statistics 

Kffects ol ma.sculioe ti 
Ratio of males t" leiua 

Teacbent' institutes.. 

Township versus schoo] district -\ 
Benefits of township system 
Olijections to (list i i&lt; t system. </seg>

            <seg id="p195">194 


Stati Normal School ... 
Keport dl principa 

rtc University 
IiciK&gt;rt cil m 

10. Teacher* 
1 1. Resource* w gi 
12. Expenditures ¦ &gt; 
13. Cost Hi edncatii 
1 4. N uiiiIm i pupil.s, 

15. Names ol bu peril 

ichools </seg>


            <seg id="p196">

l.V&gt;-190 

I 

p 

s 

1 

I 

1!. 

: 

1 

u 

:c 


39 

s 

s 

: 

t 

v., 

M 

1 


Kkfokts of Pkikcipals ami City Si pkrintbs 
Aurora 
Diwli Im 
('larks 
Clay ('ci)te i 
Crete 
lMgur. 
Swing ... 
Fall- City 
(•rnrVll.. 
( irud Island 
wood 
Hastings 
Holdrege 
Hnmboldt. 
Lexington 
Lincoln . 
North PUtte 
&lt; Ulialu. 
O'Neill 
Nelson.. 
Neligh 
i ml 
gidne] ... 
Boperioi 

Eahm </seg>
            <seg id="p197">
&gt;l.\ I ¦ TEA&lt; HEKH' \-~ 
The TcatluT t»i To-1 &gt;a\ 
lilt- Boj ill till' llii;ll -¦ l 
Historical Study a~ a Mi 
Primary Music 
INa erty ami Weali h 
l&gt;m-s the SoIkmiI I'llllllsli 
Uistcrv iii Edneation 
The Unity ol Btholanshiii 

196 </seg>
         </p>


		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>