<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00003.00009">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00003.00009</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>SEVENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA SOLDIERS' AND SAILORS' HOME, GRAND ISLAND, HALL COUNTY, NEBRASKA.  BEING FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900.</title>
			            <date value="1900">1900</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-29</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>			
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-05-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
				     <change>
				        <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
				           <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
				     </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Seventh Biennial Report 

OF THE 

NEBRASKA 

Soldiers' and Sailors' Home 

Grand Island, Hall County, Nebraska. 

BEING FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1900. 

LINCOLN, NEB.: 
STATE JOURNAL COMPANY, PRINTERS. 

1901. 



i 

1 

in 

i 

h 

i 

I 

w </seg>

            <seg id="p003">REPORT 

Grand Island, Neb., November 30, 1900. 

His Excellencv, the Governor, and The Board of Public 

,ands and Buildings. 

ntlemen: In pursuance of law, I have the honor herewith 

¦ansmit my report of the condition of the Soldiers' Home 
he past year and six months, and its probable future needs, 

.tinning with June 1. 1899, when I took charge of the institun. 
to November :?(». 1900. 

I desire to call your attention to the necessity of increasing the 
propriations for the Grand Island Home very materially. 

oi- the reason that there has been an unexpected per cent 
¦ase the past two years, and secondly, there has been, a 
rceptible increase in the cost of living. ¦ 

r employees" wages. I would recommend that the sum of 
(Ml be appropriated. This I deem necessary. If the mem- 

n the next two years as it has in the past two, 

l 

&gt;portionment amount of help will be required, and as wages 

of living, it will be impossible 
U the same rate of wages paid 

Ivancing. as well as the cost 

n help the next two year 

1st tw 

I would recommend an approi 
given in the foregoing para- 
The appropriation of f40,000 

Km- maintenance and clothing 
iation of #00,000. The reason 

ade two years ago will be exhausted December, 1900, causing 
four months' deficiency, easily accounted for. as the member- 

p lias increased 25 per cent in spite of more stringent rules 
to grounds for admission to the Home. 

For fuel, engine oil, repairs to steam and electric light plant, 
ask for $10,000. This will be needed in virtue of the fact that, 
ifh the new hospital, and insufficient light and steam for past 

aphs apply also to this fund. </seg>


            <seg id="p004">34 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

needs, future requirements will demand double the sum appropriated 
by the last legislature. Owing to the fact that two new 
boilers were ordered by the Board of Public Lands and Build 

ir.gs, — one to take the place of an old one, condemned, and one 

to increase the plant to meet the needs and enlarge the boiler 

house, — for which something like $2,000 was paid for out of thi 

fund, it was exhausted in twenty month 

For drugs and instruments I would recommend that $2,500 

be appropriated. For the number now on the rolls. this sum 

represents $3.50 per annum for each member for medicine. 

against $2.50 per capita as represented by the last appropriation 

which was exhausted May 1st of the ensuing year 

For furniture and bedding I would recommend $1,000, as I 

know of no extra demands in this direction,' and as the saint 

sum appropriated two years ago has been sufficient. 
Stock and implements. 1 would ask that this fund should 

increased from $500 to $1,000. The Home has land tha 

to be broken out and put into alfalfa hay. as experience ha 

taught the management through several administratioi 

it is the most profitable crop to raise on the land 1 

the Home, and to take care of the hay in proper 

w 

require more teams and vehicle 

For sewerage I would ask that $300 be appropriat 

the present sewer in repair 

For express, telephone, telegraph, and supplies I would r&lt; 

of $500 was exhausted August 1 of the current year 
For library I deem $200 to be sufficient, and thert 

mend that sum. 

For transportation I would also ask for $200. 
For painting and repairs I would ask the sum of $4,000. 
Owing to the destruction of the horse barn early in the sum 

mer of 1809. which made an unexpected draft upon this fund 

of $1,147.12. which cut short many repairs that were needed 

and as all the painting and repair funds of six years ago wer 

used in the new addition to the Home, it has suffered for lack of 

ommend that $1,000 be appropriated. The last approj 


soldiers' and sailors' home. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">35 

means to mend the roof, and in many minor directions. In fact, 
I am convinced that a new roof will be found to be necessary, 
when examined by the proper committees. 

For visiting and examining board I would recommend fl,200. 
Under the law, this board is required to audit all accounts 

drawn against the funds of the Home. Besides four quarterly 
meetings each year, three of the members are required to meet 

nd of each month to examine and audit claims; theres 
fund has already been exhausted. 

hts. and repairs to same, I have estimated will re 

*r,iiii 

Km laundry exj&gt;enses and repairs I recommend the sum of 

Foe transplanting trees and improving grounds I would recnnend 
|6(&gt;0. The increase is necessary to grade up around the 

new hospital 

I would recommend that the old frame fire-trap which now 
nuls between the boiler house and the main building, and used 
¦ commissary stores, be replaced with a more substantial build:. 
with employees' quarters provided in connection therewith 

mployees are depended upon to handle fire apparatus 

w 

it anywhere upon the grounds, and by quar- 

ig them by themselves, they can all be found when needed, 
would further recommend that the physician's salary be 

ni ffiOO per annum to $900, as the membership of the 

han quadrupled since his salarv was fixed bv 

w. and 

the cares of his office are constantly increasing by 
rowing older and feebler with each passing year. 

( &gt;wing To the increased capacity of the steam plant and harder 

work. I would recommend that the wages of the engineers be 

increased, as I have found it very difficult to obtain the services 

of competent persons for the wages paid. 

The new hospital has been a much needed improvement, and 

has added very much to the convenience of handling the sick, 

while the new standpipe make a permanent water supply effica- 

cious in answering needs, and adds to a feeling of safety in all 

directions </seg>


            <seg id="p006">36 

LAND COMMISSIONER 6 

REPORT. 

The new hospital seems to possess the essential virtues that 
is not alwavs found in state buildings, of being substantially 
built and neatly finished. It will accommodate about thirtytwo 
patients without crowding. I would recommend a burial 
fund of $1,0(10, as the average death rate is fifteen or twenty per 

annum. 

When the barn was burned in the summer of ISitS a 

harness, carriages, etc., were burned up with it. and which w« 

replaced; but the sum is not enumerated in the cost of replacing 

the barn. 

For the first time in the hislorv of the Home the cliol 

vaded the herd of hogs, from which about 130 spring pigs died 

and also 14 fat ho 

For the first time in the hi 

iv of the Home we had 

of smallpox last summer, win 
as well as expense, and great 
for his success in quarantiu 
spread. 

I, 

msed considerable exi 

(lit is due the Home ]&gt;li 

i 

mi: 

Last spring a new lot of f&lt; 
and shrubbery, vines, and bu 

and orna 

b 

were planted. Of 

XV.), of different varieties, print 

pall.x 

trees, 110; ornamental ti 

windb 

cattle barns. 2,000; cedar and ] 
asparagus, 300 plants; pie-plant 
shrubs, vines, and bulbs. 174. T 

mi 

i: 

t 

.00: strawl 

ll. ( 

In conclusion. I would say the only unj 
connection with my administration of the 1 
been the constant desire to "make ends meet" 

lion 

v econ 

every direction possible without detriment to service and 

proper care of those who look to the state for protection in t licit 

helplessne: 

There appears to be only th 
and members and employees, 
other. 

best feeling among 

fficei 

in their intercourse with ea« 

in a most efficient and satisfactory manner. I am also happy 

The Adjutant, Hon. J. H. Powers, lias performed liis dutiei 


soldiers' and sailors' home </seg>

            <seg id="p007">S7 

to be able to say the same of Mr. H. M. Swigart, the surgeon, 
an«l Mrs*. M. H. Hall, the matron. 
I also desire to express m.v thanks to the Governor, Board of 
Public Lands and Buildings, and Visiting and Examining Boards 
for courteous treatment during the many questions that are 

mtlv demanding conferen 

for their settlement in an 

Lew 

V. Beltzer, Commandant. 


Names of Funds 

K 

I 

?So 

£ 

= 

X 

.5 

&lt; 

re' salaries $1616 17 

$9720 00111336 17 $9714 50 $1621 67 

Employees' wages , 1639 12 

12000 00 13639 12j 11050 38 2588 74 

Maintenance and clothing 9692 49! 

40000 00 49692 491 48799 92 892 57 

Fuel, engine oil, and repairs 

to steam plant 157 05 

8000 00 8157 05 8157 05 _ 
1500 00 1772 14 1772 14 

Drugs and instruments 272 14 

Furniture and bedding 19 54 

Stock and implements 

Sewerage 1 40 

Express, telephone, telegraph, 

(i 

500 00 506 55 506 54 01 

Library 130 10 

250 00 380 10 370 90 9 20 

Transportation 71 95 

Painting and repairs 3 23 

Visiting and examining board 140 37 

Electric lights and repairs 10 40 

500 00! 510 40, 253 00 257 40 

Laundry, expended 

350 00 350 00! 320 84 1 29 16 

Transplanting trees and 
improving grounds 

500 00 500 00 120 30 379 70 

Defici 

n of this kind. </seg>

            <seg id="p008">ATEMEXT FROM DECEMBER 1, 1S08, TO NOVEMBER 30, 
1900. 

1000 00 1019 54 708 51 311 03 
"&gt;00 00' 507 78 507 78 
500 00 501 40 190 94 310 46 

250 00 321 95 246 32 75 63 
2500 00 2503 23 2503 23 _ 
800 00' 940 37 964 59 «24 22 


38 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

In addition to the above, vouchers on appropriations which 

have been exhausted have been audited and approved as fol 

lows 

Fuel, engine oil, etc |2,218 41 

Drugs, etc 238 47 

R. R. freight, etc 132 40 

Express, telephone, etc 35 35 

Addition to wells of water plant 70 48 

Total $2,(595 11 

CASH RECEIPTS AND DISBURSEMEN 

S FROM DECEMBER 1, 1898, 
;0, 1900. 

NOVEMBER 

December 1, 1898, Balance on hand, cash on $921 13 

Receipts for the year ending X 
From sale of hides 
From sale of hogs 
From members of the Home 
From dividends on receiver' 

vember 30. 1S99 : 

1246 88 

40 00 

jn contracts, 210 00 

rtiflcates, 11 

From all other sources, including $17.10 
premium on warrants turned in 

63 54 

Total cash receipts to Nov. 30, 1809 

$1.4&lt;»2 

Disbursements for the year ending November 30 

1899 591 20 

Cash balance November 30, 1899 $901 60 

Receipts for the year ending November 30, 1900: 
From sale of hides $246 

From sale of hogs 

593 50 

From sale of calves 32 50 

From members of the Home on contracts, 189 00 
From all other sources 75 85 

1,137 4 

Total cash receipts for the year 

ending November 30 

1900 $2,039 03 


soldiers' and sailors' home. </seg>

            <seg id="p009">39 

Disbursements for the year ending November 30, 
1900 |771 38 

&lt;';ish balance on hand November 30, 1900 $1,267 65 

Balance on bank receivers' certificates (worthless).. 112 39 

FARM PRODUCTS RAISED AT THE 

HOME THE TWO YEARS ENDING 

HOME THE TWO YEARS ENDING 

FARM PRODUCTS RAISED AT THE 

30, 1900. 
|3,900 54 

SO, 1900. 

NOVEMBER 

NOVEMBER 

Beef, (J5.009 lbs. (&lt;i 6c 

Pork. _!:?.7«!t lbs, @ 5 c 

1,188 45 

Milk. L'7.i»4!t gallons, (d 12c 

Milk. L'7.i»4!t gallons, Oi 12c 

3,353 88 

Vegetables 118 72 

|8,561 59 

Potatoes in 1N119, 770 bu. (5 25t 

$192 50 

Potatoes in 1900. 300 bu., (a 20c 150 00 

342 50 

Oats in ISU'.K 1S00 bu., Oi 20c 

|360 00 
121 00 

Oats in l'MHt. 550 bu.. (it 22c 

481 00 

Vlfalfa hay 1899, 300 tons (n $5.00. . 
Alfalfa hay 1900, 450 tons (a $5.00 

$1,500 00 
2,250 00 

3,750 00 

$280 00 

Wild hay 1S!(&lt;). SO tons (a $3 
Wild hay 1900. 15 tons Oi $3 

-.ii 

-&gt;u 

52 50 

332 50 

$13,467 59 

I&gt;educt from stock, cattle and dressed bet 

i bought.. 971 20 

t&lt;il raised for use at 

the Homt 

$12,496 39 

• VEMBER 30, 1900. 

VALUATION OF PROPERTY ON 

HANI) N" 

117 cattle, valued at $3,510 00 

36 hogs, valued at 540 00 

7 horses, valued at 500 00 

Farm machinery, wagons, buggies, harness, etc... 520 00 

Clothing, groceries, flour, etc 1,000 00 

Total $6,070 00 </seg>


            <seg id="p010">40 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

I 
I 

IaS§§Sia^§§§g§§ §|*« §§§5§§|I 
E 5 E S S = a s § = J = s S S =-i ?«= S s 5 g § S S 
BBBKaoaEHaeaBXSBSjsBllJSoBSKB 

— 

1 
o 
c 
I 

* 0S OS wt d O^ d O^ wi vtf Ot v « v w v v "^ 
axX'uoxrtiiHi-iXrtXQOQOXKOJwrtffiaiaaaafta 
£gf;f 3" S'f; S S S-3 g*S 8* "*"*¦ S'f &lt;o *5"S" cir&lt;D *S" or S" 
iilllllSlllilllilllllllllil 

s 
a 
1 

a 
&lt;2 

'Z C 'C C "C "C C C C E o C C u C C C ~ 'C 'C "C C o C S "C o 

¦z 
2 
c 
H 
a 
as i 
S5 
Ed 
X 
1 
OS - 
£ 
u 
O I. 

43 
I 
I 
a 
a 

it? ::•::::{?:::::::•:•::: :C« : 
;= = :; = i ; i^ :;:;;::::: i ; i :^5 
lilillfiliiliifitlliilliiii 
°ll!il^ll-:|iirls-i-;:l?"lf- 
|l=|s|||=il|||i||i|i|ii|i|» 
[ M«HWrtTj&lt;O5Nir;'-©t-KlM«VS l CCrt40 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

I 
I 

IaS§§Sia^§§§g§§ §|*« §§§5§§|I 
E 5 E S S = a s § = J = s S S =-i ?«= S s 5 g § S S 
BBBKaoaEHaeaBXSBSjsBllJSoBSKB 

— 

1 
o 
c 
I 

* 0S OS wt d O^ d O^ wi vtf Ot v « v w v v "^ 
axX'uoxrtiiHi-iXrtXQOQOXKOJwrtffiaiaaaafta 
£gf;f 3" S'f; S S S-3 g*S 8* "*"*¦ S'f &lt;o *5"S" cir&lt;D *S" or S" 
iilllllSlllilllilllllllllil 

s 
a 
1 

a 
&lt;2 

'Z C 'C C "C "C C C C E o C C u C C C ~ 'C 'C "C C o C S "C o 

¦z 
2 
c 
H 
a 
as i 
S5 
Ed 
X 
1 
OS - 
£ 
u 
O I. 

43 
I 
I 
a 
a 

it? ::•::::{?:::::::•:•::: :C« : 
;= = :; = i ; i^ :;:;;::::: i ; i :^5 
lilillfiliiliifitlliilliiii 
°ll!il^ll-:|iirls-i-;:l?"lf- 
|l=|s|||=il|||i||i|i|ii|i|» 
[ M«HWrtTj&lt;O5Nir;'-©t-KlM«VS l CCrt^&lt;-iXOlC»hWX?l 
OOS«&lt;hO«h jfeXO«Oi-3aW |*&lt;WOO^t J dS&lt; 

a 
z 

I I ! i i I I JM i j j j j j j j [| I I I I ! I ! i 
JijiliiJi^iJ i jijil 
fill rtllijlilii ffHJlf Hill* lt;-iXOlC»hWX?l 
OOS«&lt;hO«h jfeXO«Oi-3aW |*&lt;WOO^t J dS&lt; 

a 
z 

I I ! i i I I JM i j j j j j j j [| I I I I ! I ! i 
JijiliiJi^iJ i jijil 
fill rtllijlilii ffHJlf Hill* </seg>


            <seg id="p011">SOLDIERS 

AND SAILORS' HOME. 

41 

MEMBERSHIP OF THE HOME. 

Male members present November 30, 1898 186 

Female members present November 30, 1898 41 

Total number 227 

Male members absent November 30, 1898 40 

Female members absent November 30, 1898 7 

Total number 47 

Total membership 274 

admission to November 30, 1900 — men 142 

admission to November 30, 1900 — women 

.... 

Total train 171 

Loss bv death, men and women 

to November 30, 1900 

34 

discharge, men and women, to November 30 

ruin 

72 

Total loss 106 

Net train 

t;x 

November 30, 1900, men present 
November 30. 1900. women urese 

229 

II. 1900. women prt 

56 

ent 

Total present 285 

November 30. 1900, men absent 

50 

November 30. 1900. women absent 7 

Total absent 57 

Total membership 342 

Daily average present from D&lt; 

•ember 1, 1898, to Novem- 

ber 30, 1S99 231 

Daily average present and absc 

nt from December 1, 1898, 

to November 30, 1899 291 

Daily average present from December 1, 1899, to November 
30, 1900 261 </seg>


            <seg id="p012">42 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S EEPOET. 

Daily average present and absent from December 1, 1899, 
to November 30, 1900 334 

Average cost of daily rations for year ending November 
30, 1899 1 0 

Average cost of clothing for year ending November 30, 
1899 21 59 

Average cost per capita for year ending November 30 

Four women admitted have not reported 

REPORT OF VISITING AND EXAMINING HOARD 

David City, Neb., November 27, lllOO 

To His Excellency, the Governor, and the Commissioner of I'i 

lie Lands and Buildings. 

Gentlemen : In accordance with the laws of Nebraska governing 
Soldiers" and Sailors' Homes, the Visiting and Examining 
Board beg leave to make the following report, showing th&lt;condition 
of the Home and a synopsis of the proceedings had 
by this board during the biennial period beginning December 1 . 
1898, and closing November 30, 1900. 

The Visiting and Examining Board have made twenty-six 
visits to the Home during the time mentioned. Eight of these 
visits have been the regular quarterly meetings provided for 
by law. Sixteen of the meetings have beeb auditing committee 
meetings, as is also provided by law, calling for three members, 
who have carefully examined all claims against the funds of the 
institution, before auditing vouchers. In addition to this, the 

1899 

159 77 

Average cost of daily rations for year ending November 

30, 1900 

• &gt;•&gt; 

Average cost of clothing for year ending November 30, 

1900 

IS 4s 

Average cost per capita for year ending November 3ft, 

1900 

152 20 

Twentv men admitted have not reported. 


soldiers' and sailors' home. </seg>

            <seg id="p013">43 

auditing committee is also empowered to attend to all business 
of an emergency nature, which could not well be postponed 
until the regular quarterly meetings. 

On June 1 and 2, 1899, under a call of the president, the board 
met in special session to examine and approve the bond of Lewis 
A. Beltzer; to preside at a settlement with John \V. Wilson, the 
outgoing Commandant; to confirm the appointment of such subordinate 
officers as were recommended by the Commandant; to 
fix the wages of employees, and report the same to the Board 
of Public Lands and Buildings; to afford the Commandant any 
information desired by him concerning the affairs of the Home; 
to hear and decide upon complaints from members and employees; 
to make recommendations to the Board of Public Lands 
and Buildings, of all repairs, improvements, etc., to be paid for 
out of the regular appropriations made for the Home, and such 
sheds and other buildings as are not provided for by specific act 
of the legislature. 

There was also a special meeting held on November 29, 1899, 
at which meeting an annual report was made to the Governor 

us to the condition of the Home, health, etc., of the members, 
ind condition of the several funds. 

At the special meeting holden June 1 and 2, 1899, new rules 
were adopted, based on conditions as they then existed, and the 

results of experience, and to provide against imposition in cases 
where county boards have been more anxious to get rid of undesirable 
persons than to give a reliable account of the property 
qualifications or means of support on the part of the applicant. 
These new rules were duly approved by the Governor. 

In auditing claims against the state the board has endeavored 
to obtain from the officers the history of all claims, whether the 
goods were equal to the samples furnished the Board of Pur- 

chase and Supplies, properly delivered or the service rendered. 
The fact that a board has to audit their claims, composed of 
persons living at a distance, whom they cannot punish, seems 
to prevent annoyance to the officers, and deters dealers from 
"padding" their accounts. </seg>


            <seg id="p014">44 

LAND COMMISSIONER 

REPORT. 

The growth of membership the past two years has been far 
beyond the expectation of those whose duty it has been to consult 
the institution's needs. Those elements in mankind which 
make the men heroic fighters is not evidence of their capacity for 
financiers, so that in their old age and helplessness the Nation's 
defenders find themselves stranded and dependent upon the 

etc.. for themselves. Owing to poor eyesight, rheumatism, 
coughs, sores, etc., only the few are fitted for this service, and 
there would be no justice in making these few do all this kin.l 
of work, even if they were able to perform the service continually. 
If thev are able for continuous service thev are not en- 

state for their support, therefore experts had figured years ago 

that the liiaxiiiiuin of demands had been reached; hence the 

Soldiers' Home is always behind its needs. At the dose of the 

biennial of ls'.ts The membership of the Home was 1'74. and i: 

the present time the total membership is :{&lt;;."&gt;. or a gain of -•"&gt; per 

cent as against a gain of nine and a half per cent the last bieu- 

nial period. 

As to the finances of the Home the board finds that of the 

maintenance and clothing there remains only #1.44*. To. The 

increased cost of living; an abnormal increase of membership. 

along with the fact that all claims against the fuel and lighting 

fund were paid out of the maintenance and clothing fund April 

last, to the tirst of August, depleted it to that amount. For 

the first eight months of the term the claims against this fund 

averaged $1.4."&gt;N.0N, but they are now overrunning that sum at 

the rate of about $:?47l per month. 

Of the employees' wages fund there now remains a balance of 

$2,146.65. The average monthly expenditure at the present thin 

is |454.!t&lt;i. but increased nurse service and other helps will run 

the bills up to $5011 during the winter months. While the fund 

will evidently hold out. the margin left over will be small. Tin 

men are growing old. and more help will be needed in the hos 

pitals and in nearly every direction. One of the erroneous im- 

pressions of the public is that these old soldiers ought to d&lt; 

most of the service, such as nursing, table-waiting, dishwashing </seg>


            <seg id="p015">AND SAILORS' HOME. 

45 

SOLDIERS 

itled to the privilege of the Home, as the Visiting and Examin-11 
jj: Hoard interprets the law. 

Of the fuel and lighting fund we have to report that this was 
xhausted April 1. 11(00. There were emergencies arose which 

gislative foresight could provide against that came out of 
mid. for instance: two new boilers were indispensable, and 

he Hoard of I'ublu- Lands and Buildings ordered the work of 
nlarging the boiler-house, and the purchase of the new boilers, 

which were paid for in part out of this fund, involving a total 
expense of about $2,000. Thus, this fund was exhausted the first 

ie painting and repair fund we have to report that an 
iii-.v arose which drained it early in the bienniuin. During 

early summer of 1S!»!&gt; the excellent horse barn belonging to 
Home was struck by lightning, and the building burned to 

lit- ground by the tire which ensued. It was replaced at an 
xpenditure of $1,147.12, which was paid for out of this fund. 

his unlooked-for misfortune many needed repairs and im 
ements, not having the urgency of emergencies, have gon€ 
efaulr. Misfortune seems to have overtaken most of the re 

iii- funds tin- past half decade. Both the repair and seweragt 

nds appropriated by the legislature of 1895 were all absorbed 
the west addition to the Home, along with the $12,000 appro- 

¦&lt;1 to build said addition, so that not a dollar was left for 
.vo years between April 1. 1895, and March 31, 1897. This 

a as by the order of the Board of I'ublic Lands and Buildings of 
hat time. The next appropriation was not sufficient to make 

by wear and tear for four years, and thus the mi 

hap of a year and a half ago which destroyed the horse barn has 
deprived the Home of the largest share of its improvement funds 
for the past six years, setting it back at least three years for 
necessary repairs. 

The drugs and instruments fund was exhausted the first year. 
When we consider that the appropriation only represented an 
average of about $2.50 per annum to each man for medicine, for 
people who are old and feeble, it hardly seems necessary to offer 
any explanation. </seg>


            <seg id="p016">46 

LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT. 

The fund for the Visiting and Examining Board is also exhausted, 
and as this board does not expect to profit by any future 
appropriation we can recommend with a good conscience a sufficient 
appropriation to pay for the service rendered, or a discontinuance 
of the board. 

Most of the minor funds are in about the same condition as 

the larger ones which have been explained, and for the same 
reason, that the demand on the institution has been greater 
than was anticipated, therefore were not provided for in thr 
appropriations. 

The Visiting and Examining Board have examined and aud 
ited claims to the amount of f 98,252.12, — divided by an averagt 
membership of 307 for the two years. — making an annual ens 

tended to sweeten the tempers of thai class of peoph 

a refuge in the Soldiers' Home; therefore it is not to be ex] 

that so many people can live together without disag 

Again there are always a few whose apj 

their will power to resist temptation, hence some few w 

lent disposition. The board has insisted that the Soldiers" 1 

is a place for soldiers and gentlemen, and the best disciplin 

those who cannot live in peace with their comrades is to d 

charge them from the Home. It has saved the peaeeable from 

annoyance, and has had a more salutary effect on the reca 

trants than anything this board has been able to devise. 
One of our rules makes it incumbent upon the Home physician 

and matron to inspect the buildings once a week and report theii 

drunk, and it becomes necessary to disciplin 

per capita of $100 per member. Should the cost of living &lt;-o 

Ill 

tinue the same the next two years, it is a fair estimate to figu 

on $ 11(1.8(1(1 as necessarv to maintain the Home for the next iv 

years. There is nothing now to designate any decrease in tl 

membership in the Home. but. on the contrary, new applicatioi 

for membership are coining in faster than ever before in tl 

history of the Institution. 

As to methods of discipline, experience teaches that disa 

pointed lives and old age. with* its aches and pains, has n </seg>


            <seg id="p017">SOLDIERS 

AND SAILORS' HOME. 

47 

i 

,i 

1 

1 

\ 

ndition, as well as the health of the members. We are happy 

report that this rule has been observed, and we can report 
easonable degree of health on the part of the members. 

The total membership of the Home at the close of the bienini 
of 1804 were 210, for the biennium of 1896 were 250, for 
e biennium of 1898 were 274, for the biennium of 1900 were 

As the details are fully reported in the recommendations of 
; Commandant, the board deems it unnecessary to repeat these 

tai 

The total quantity of meat raised on the farm the past two 
ars, sums up as follows: 

Beef. 69,009 pounds, at six cents per pound $3,900 54 

Wild hay, 95 tons, at $3.50 per ton 332 I 

12 50 

4,082 50 

Value of vegetables 2 

21 00 

Value of potatoes raised 342 c 

342 50 

480 00 

). Caspi 

Geo. N. Smith 

President. 

Secret 

Julia S. Bowex. 
J. A. Baird. 

Mary E. Ward. 

Pork, L'S.TfiO pounds, at five cents. 
Alfalfa hav raised. 750 tons, at fa 

1,188 45 

|3,750 00 </seg>


         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>