<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00087.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0087.0008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Use of Native Grass in Producing Finished Cattle</title>
               <date value="18??">June 1937</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">The Use of Native Grass in Producing Finished Cattle Bblletin3o7 . . June, 1937 ' •• . Marvel L. Baker j Bulletin 40 of the North Platte Experiment Substation L. L. Zook, Superintendent j -'¦ ¦ ; '¦,¦'¦¦'.'¦.;. ..-/.:; "tv""'; •; 'V' -:. i^J'.^.A.- ¦'.;¦;,' .v. "I---,-'. Steers on Native Grass at the North Platte Substation The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture ¦\ Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
         <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Page Introduction Full-Feeding in Dry Ijit vs. Full-Feeding First on Pasture and then in Dry Lot (Lots I and 2) 5 Full-Feeding ss. Limited Feeding on Native Grass, followed by Full-Feeding in Dry Lot (Lots 2 and 3) ¦ 9 Limited Feeding on Native Grass vs. Grazing without Grain, followed by Full- Feeding in Dry Lot (Lots 3 and 4) \i Comparison of Three Pasture-Feeding Methods /5 SUMMARY Yearling nccrs of ut.od to choice quality r/iat had heen well wintered were fed (turn earl; May until considered ready for market. During the first part of this period the method laried from 3 full Iced of corn on pasture to pasture with no grain. During the last pan all lots were full-fed corn and alhlla in dry lot. One lot was full-fed corn and all.ilfa in dry lot during the whole feeding period for comparison. In three trials in "Inch full-feeding in dry lot (Lot 1) was compared with fuli- Urding ,11 in hi ilays on native pasture and finishing in dry lot (Lot 2), the gains ucrc practically equal, and the lots were of approximately equal market desirability. Results militate thai the method used in Lot 2 will produce more economical gains than tlic Lot I method whenever a ton of alfalfa hay is worth more than 5.3 bushels 1.1 corn and S months of pasture for one steer. In three other trials stcrrs were fed approximately 8 pounds of corn daily on native lusture for Til 10 s-t da;s and finished in dry lot on corn and alfalfa (Lot 3), and arc compared with Lot 2. full-fed on pasture. Lot ? made definitely cheaper gains than Lot 2. and there w.is little difference in the rate of gain. Moreover there was ho apparent difference in the market desirability of the two lots. Apparently steers fed as were those in Lot j should be fed about four vecks longer than cattle fuU-fcd corn during the grazing period. A fourth lot of steers (Lot 4), fed no grain during the grazing period, was included in cadi trial. Compared with Lot i (ted 8 pounds of corn daily on grass) this lot made cheaper gains and sold as well. Slaughter data indicate, however, that they, were not as well finished as the Lot f cattle and it is suggested that cattle grazed with - out grain (Lot 4) cannot he marketed in the same condition as cattle handled as were those in Lot .1 until six or eight weeks later. 'I he higher ihe price of corn in relation to that of alfalfa hay and native grass, die greater the economy of grazing cattle with a limited feed of grain, or with no grain preliminary m full-lccding them in dry lot. Cattle fed a limited amount of grain or m&gt; grain during the grazing pi-rind cannot he marketed, in the same condition, as early as cattle fed as were Lots 1 and 2. but they will make larger total gains and in order to sell a&gt; the same might should lie lighter at the beginning of the glazing season. The sutrs in Lot 2 (full-lcrl corn on grass) consumed approximately 20.0 bushels of corn, and the steers in Lot i (limited corn on grass) ate approximately 11.0 bushels or corn during the grazing season: the value of this corn for hogs following cattle should Ik considered in evaluating the different methods, since it is not usually possible to have hogs follow steers on native pasture. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">The Use of Native Grass in Producing Finished Cattle ¦'.., MARVEL L. BAKER ; North Platte Experiment Substation , Many cattle feeders in southwestern Nebraska are so located that native grass is available. Considerable interest has been shown during the past Sew years in the extent to which it may be, used advantageously in the production of well finished cattle.. ;. : : For the purpose of securing information from which conclusions might be drawn as to the p ace of native grass in a program of finished beef pro - duction, the series o: tests reported in this, publication was begun in the ; spring of 1933 at the North Platte Substation. ; .: ¦ ;.' • :-.'.' GENERAL PLAN OP THE EXPERIMENTS . The cattle were civided into experimental lotsj early in May each year. Lot 1 in each test wis fed corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot throughout the experiment. During :he first part of the experimental period, referred to as Phase 1, Lots 2, 3, and 4 were grazed on native grass pasture. During Phase 1, Lot 2 was given a full feed of corn, Lot 3 was fed approximately 8 pounds of corn per head daily, and Lot 4iwas grazed without grain. Phase 1 was 84 days in length except in 1934|when because of the severe drouth it was deemed best to terminate the grazing period at the end of 70 days. All lots were full-fed corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot during Phase 2. During the first year no Lot 1 was included in the test, and in order to have three comparisons of Lots 1 and 2, these two methods were compared in 1934, 1935, and 1936. .„¦.; ! ; . Each year the cattle from each lot were sold : when they were considered ready for market. This necessarily brought in the element of judgment. / In a. test of this kind, this procedure probably affords a more accurate picture of results than the practice of marketing Jail of the cattle at the same time, when there would necessarily be considerable difference in the finish and market desirability of the different lots. •:¦' ' . ¦ ¦ . ¦ CATTLE USED' | ¦ : The cattle used were high-grade Hereford steers, grading good to choice. All of them came from the same Lincoln county herd. The aver - age initial weight ranged from 645 to 730 pounds: The steers were pur - ; chased for each test as calves in the fall preceding the summer feeding ! period and were well wintered in the experimental lots at the North Platte Substation. ' •¦ ¦' i PREVIOUS TREATMENT OF CATTLE .',•"¦ ¦ During the wintering periods, feeds were used which were most avail - able and which seemed most economical under! conditions prevailing dur - ing the respective winters. During the first winter (1932-33), both corn and alfalfa hay were cheap, and the calves were wintered on those feeds. From November 11 t!o May 5, a period of 175 days, the calves ate an average of 5.82 pounds of corn and 10.99 pounds of alfalfa hay per head </seg>
         <seg id="p004">Nebraska Acrici-ltl-r.il Experiment Station Bulletin 30/ daily and made an average daily gain of 1.73 pounds. They weighed 430 pounds at the beginning and 732 pounds at the close ot the wintering period. During the period these calves ate an average ot 18.18 bushels of corn and 0.96 ion of alfalfa hay per head. During the winter of 1933-34 corn silage and alfalfa hay rormed the basis of the wintering ration. Approximately 2.0 pounds ot corn per head daily were added to this ration during the last 84 days. The silage contained 4.23 bushels of corn per ton of silage. During the 168-day period from November 17 to May 4, the steers ate an average ot 23.2 pounds of silage and 5.8 pounds of alfalfa hay per head daily. They weighed 427 pounds at the beginning of the period and 67/ pounds at the close and made an average daily gain of 1.49 pounds per head To winter each call, I.&lt;K tons of silage. 0.40 ton of alfalfa hay. and 2.92 bushels of corn were required. Mfalfa hay was Kara and high in price in 1934 and the calves were wintered on Alias silage ami a protein supplement ot either cottonseed meal or tankage or a mixture of the two. During the last 28 days the silage and protein supplements were discontinued and all ot the calves were led a uniform ration of alfalfa hay and 4.0 pounds ot corn per head J &#132;X Some corn was also led during the preceding 77 days. From October M to May r. a period ot 1% days, the calves consumed an average of nol bushels ol corn, l.tol tons of Atlas silage, 0.18 ton ot alfalfa hay. 103 pounds ol cottonseed meal. ..ml 41 pounds of digester tankage. At the Ix-'inninj! of this period the calves averaged 379 pounds and at the close the\ iveraged 70 1 pounds in weight. They made an average daily gain ol \.IA pounds lor lite 1% days. The calves used in the l"3n test were wintered similarl) lo those used the preceding year. The calves carried more flesh .it the clo.se ol each wintering period than would have been desirable had the hrst consideration been maximum sum - mer gains In these trials, an important consideration was the marketing til the cattle during the fall and early winter in acceptable market condition. In order to do this it was considered necessary to close the wintering period with the calves carrying considerable flesh. lIMIS AMI PASTIRIS '.'SKI) Practically all of the corn fed was No. 2 yellow. In 1934 shelled corn was fed. and in the other tests the corn was ground. The alfalfa hay was mostly second- and third-cutting hay. It graded U. S. No. 2 andl U. S. No. 2 I eafy The pastures were native grass consisting ot nuttalo (Buchloe dactylo.Jes). blue grama (Boutcloua gracilif), little bluestem, ( indropogon scoparius), western wheat grass (Agropyron sniitfin) and a number of minor grasses. No attempt was made to measure the amount of crass consumed by the different lots. It seems probable, however, that the steers in Lot 2 ate about half as much grass and the steers in Lot 3 about three-fourths as much grass as the steers in Lot 4. As discussed in thw pub - lication the grass consumed is reported as "steer .lays of pasture, one </seg>
         <seg id="p005">Use of Native Grass in Producing Finished Cattle "steer day of pasture'j' being pasture for one steer for only one day. In cal - culating cost of gains, the variation in the amount of pasture represented v by one steer day of pasture charged against the respective lots should be kept in mind. It was planned to have good pasture available at all times; |, This was done with-(jhe possible exception of 1934J Because of the drouth, I. the grass became short and dry before the end of the grazing period in this year. Salt and water were available at all times. &#132;}.¦ SLAUGHTER DATA : Because of circumstances beyond control, the slaughter data are not as complete as would have been desirable. Such data as were secured were obtained through the. courtesy of Swift and Company and of Armour and Company of South Omaha. They are discussed later. , FULL-FEEDING IN DRY LOT VS. FULL-FEEDING FIRST ON PASTURE AND THEN IN DRY LOT (LOTS 1 AND 2) ! Three direct comparisons between full-feedingj steers on native grass pasture and finishing] them in dry lot and full-feeding steers in a dry jot for the entire feeding period are afforded by the work done in 1934, 1935, and 1936. Because of possible interest, the data for the pasture period for Lot 2 are presented in Table 1. No difficulty was experienced in getting the steers in Lot 2 to consume corn. Inj 1934 the steers in Lot 2 actually^ ate more cbrn than the dry-lot steers in Lot 1. This was due perhaps to the dry paiture in 1934. During the next two years Lot 2 ate slightly less corn than the dry-lot steers during Phase 1. In the three years, Lot 1 consumed an average of 9.10 pounds of alfalfa hay per head daily, while Lot 2 had no roughage other than the native grass during Phase 1. For this period, the g;iins in Lot 1 were more'rapid than those in Lot 2. Since the two lots ate approximately the same amount of corn during Phase • 1, the grain requirement per unit of gain was' appreciably lower for the steers in Lot 1. This condition was reversed during the period in which ¦ both lots were fed in 3ry lot (Phase 2). As shown in Table 2, the steers in Lot 2 made distinctly more rapid and more economical gains during ' ¦ this period than the seers in Lot 1. From a practical point of view, the cattle feeder is of course interested primarily in the entire feeding period. The data for the en :ire period are presented in Table 3. There was little difference in the average daily gains made by the two lots of steers. The 1 steers in Lot 2 consurr ed slightly more corn than the steers in Lot 1, but |v i only a little more thar one-half as much alfalfa hay. The steers in Lot 2 i averaged 19 days each on native grass pasture. As an average of the i three years, they consu ned 678 pounds of corn, 168lpounds of alfalfa hay, ' . and 19 steer days of lative grass pasture for .each 100 pounds of gain. The steers in Lot 1 ate 655 pounds of corn and 322 pounds of alfalfa hay for each 100 pounds of gain. Consequently 100 pounds of gain were &#132;'•'.¦ cheaper in Lot 2 wheniver 23 pounds of corn plus 19 steer days of pasture ¦'¦¦ were worth less than 154 pounds of alfalfa hay, or whenever 5.3 bushels . ¦ - ¦ ' : ¦ • '.-¦ ¦'•.-¦..¦ I '¦'-:' ¦¦.-'.'-¦': ¦•..;'¦ .'¦¦'.."¦ . . . .':!'¦¦ .¦ ¦¦ ¦ .' ' ' ¦ • '. ¦ ¦ ' ..": -¦¦'.( , .¦¦".;. ¦ ¦¦: ¦¦.¦• '¦¦,:¦ '¦;¦&lt;¦;]: vV </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 307 of corn plus approximately 8 months of pasture for one steer were worth less than one ton of alfalfa hay. If it is assumed that the amount of grass consumed by the steers in Lot 2 was one-half that eaten by steers grazed without grain, then the cost of gains for Lot 2 would be cheaper when 5.3 bushels of corn and four months of pasture for one steer grazed without grain were worth less than one ton of alfalfa hay. If alfalfa hay had been worth $5.00 per ton and corn 28 cents per bushel, the pasture consumed by the steers in Lot 2 would have been worth about 45 cents per head per month. Since more corn was eaten for 100 pounds of gain by the steers in Lot 2 than by those in Lot 1, it follows that the higher corn is in price, with alfalfa hay remaining at the. same price, the less the advantage of full-feeding steers on grass becomes. For example, if alfalfa hay had been worth $5.00 per ton and corn 56 cents per bushel, the pasture consumed by Lot 2 would have been Table 1— Phase 1, full-feeding steers in dry lot vs. full-feeding on native pasture, followed by full-feeding in dry lot—three trials. ' Fim trial—l 934 Second trial—l93s Third trial—l 936 Weighted Avenge. May 4to July H May 7to luly 30 May sto July 28 three trials •rulais 84 day! 84 days 79 days Loi 1 . l.ot 2 ~LoiT I Loll Lotl lot 2 I Drvloi Pasture Dry-lot Pasture Dry-lot Pasture Lotl Lot 1 12 I 12 11 ! 11 12 I 2 Dry-lot | PMWK itren ilecn Herts ' steers Keen sleets i Ay imtul weigh &lt; t - 0 853 86S jjj gj|gr &gt;'% '-„. ¦% ",* m» wi, "v, Al e d n ailV """"' ,3 45 14.08 14.60 14.50 14.65 14.02 14.27 14.20 .?,"„. &#132;„ I, 05 None 9.75 None 9.38 None 9.10 None S "el day? pa.ture None 1.00 None 1.00 None 1.00 None 1.00 Fred /or 100 Ib,. S a,n. gn ;48 .„ ,«'"„, hay 340 None 432 None 351 None 373 None Sieet da" pasiu^ None 55 None 56 None 40 None 50 T°Co,t,'"bXli l&gt;"&lt;l: 16 81 17 60 21.89 21.76 21.98 21.04 20.18 20.08 Afcfe E, on, VaS None 0.41 None 0.39 None 0.36 Ko« . Steer days pasture None 70 None S4 None 84 None &lt;9 Phase I: Lot I iolWed corn and alfalla hay .n dry lot; Lot 2 (ull-fed corn and sraztd on native pasture: worth 25 cents per head per month, whi\e with corn at $1.12 per bushel the pasture would have been used at a loss, as compared with alfalfa, o£ about 11 cents per head per month. With alfalfa hay at $10.00 per ton and with corn at 28 cents, 56 cents, 84 cents, or $1.12 per bushel, the pasture per month per head would have been worth $1.04, 85 cents, 68 cents, or 49 cents respectively. The cost of gain with corn and alfalfa hay, at different prices may be determined readily by referring to Figure I. 1 ! 1 H H Mitchell. A Graphical Iresentation ol the Financial Phase! of Feeding Experiments, 111 l Acrl. Eip. Sla. Bui. 234, 1921. j </seg>
         <seg id="p007">Use of Native Grass in Producing Finished Cattle Table 2.— Phase 2, full-feeding steers in dryUot vs. full-feeding steers on native pasture'; followed by full-feeding in dry-lot — three trials Fir? t, trifi~ l934 Second uial-1935 TturcS uial-1936 Weighted average. _ July 13 to ; u i,30t00cr.22 /ujy 28to Nov. 3 tllree trials 84 days mday, "&lt;¦»&gt;» ' ®*&gt;P »day« Lot I Lot 2 Lot I Lot 2 Lot 1 Lot 2 : 12 . 12 U 11 12 12 Lot 1 Lot 2 steers steers steers steers steers Keen • . : Ay. initial weight li 843 797 896 BS4 i 870 855 868 831 Ay. final weight... 11042 1096 1092 1076 , 1084 1101 1072 1091 Ay. gain per head.. | 195 299 196 222 j 214 246 204 257 Ay. daily gain. j 2JB 2.67 2.34 2.64/ 2.19 251 2.29 Ul Ay. daily ration: ' I ¦ . i ¦ Com 16.64 1553: 15.95 17.40 1655 18.70 16.53 17.27 Alfalfa hay ; 6.89 «.60 7.41 8.57 4.89 655 6.29 7.11 Feed for 100 lbs. sain: I . 'Corn [700 59S - 682 659 ' 776 744 722 662 Alfalfa hay.. j 290 247 317 325 224 261 274 273 Totai feed per head: ¦..'.!) ¦ '¦ ¦ ' Corn, bushels !l 24.95 3L86 2353' 26.11 29.67 32.72 26.25 3035 . Alfalfa hay. tons.. .. ¦) 0.29 0.37 . 0.31 0.36 0.24 0.32 0.28 OJS . Phase 2: both Lou 1 and 2 full-fed corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot: Table 3.— Entire feeding period {Phases 1 and 2 combined), full-feeding steers in,dry lot vs.ifuH-feeding steers on native pasture, followed by flill feeding in dry lot-j-three trials. , : . First trial-1934 Sttond trill—»Js ThUd trial—W36 Welshie* average. ! n' « N° i May 7to Oct. 22 May sto Nov. 3 three trials ' ".; ;¦¦;-¦ i°" d fy, IHdays Itidayi 182 day. 168 days 178 dayt !lotl Lot 2 Lotl Lot 2 Loll Lot 2 |[12 12 11 11 12 12 Lotl lot 2 .' ¦; steeri steers steers siccri : steers steers . Ay.. Initial weight 5677 677 706 704 i 645 645 675 674 Ay; final weight.......:.. 1042 1096 1092 1076 i 1084 .1101 1072 1091 Ay. gain per head iQ6S .419 386 372 i 439 456 397 417 Ay..daily gain.......;.:.. \ 2.37 2JO 2.30 2.21 ; 2.41 2.50 2.36 235 Ay. daily ration: ¦ . - Corn ;......:.......... 15.19 15.22 15.27 1555 i 15.89 16.54 15.48 15.90 Alfalfa hay....... 7.42 4.06 8.58 4^9 656 3.53 7.61 354 Steer days pasture... None 038 None 0.50 None 0.46 None 0.45 Feed for 100' lbs. gain: f;. • '¦ ' -¦'...¦ Corn •... frtO 66' i 688 721 ) 659 661 «55 678 Alfalfa hay 313 176 373 194 289 141 322 168 Steer days pasture.... .\" iNone 17. None 23 None .' 18 None I9j i Total feed per head:' * . -: ¦ •'. Corn, bushels .......... 41.76 49.46 45.82 47.87 51.65 53.76 46.43 50.43 Alfalfa bay, tons 057 037 0.72 036 0.63 032 0.64 035 Steer days pasture - .None. 70 None 84 . i.None 84 None 79 '.' - Shrink in lhipmcnt, '"¦¦'.)' . i ' per cent.. ............ ! 3.96 14.41 2.97 3.38 I 4.57 5.07 3.59 . 4.32 Selling piict... ) 8.25 *8.25 1150 11.50 11.15 . 11.40 ¦ . Lot 1 was full-fed corn and 'alfalfa hay in dry lot for the entire feeding period; Lot 2 was full-fed ; corn on native grass pasture during Phase .1 (first 70 days of feeding period in 1934 and first 84 day! in 1935 and 1936) and was then finished in dry lot on a full feed.of corn and alfalfa hay. </seg>
         <seg id="p008">Ntuß.\s.K\ Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 307 Obviously, the relative economy of the two methods will vary from year to year, from section to section, and even from farm to farm. From the standpoint of management, there are factors other than economy oi gain which must be considered in the cattle-feeding enterprise. One ot thes.: is the time and the weight at which it is expected to market COST OF- CORN AND ALFALFA fl PER 100 LBS. GAIN 150-1 1 r 1 * - 20- " -30 r*~~ LOT \ * '. ;^^2O_LOT 2 - 2 S 125— ."""""- -25° to -a. a. - 15- ¦ q! 0-100- ~IS - j£ I¦l : : t O - 15 Zi v - &lt; v. .75 —f io- : a. ° - _ -10 . O £ ~ ¦ . '¦ r °- .50- " -a. s- —5 ; .25 J 1 1 L In . i - To rind the .ml vi turn ami ulfalta required for 100 pounds of gain, lay a -iraight edge from the price of torn to the price of alfalfa. The costs for iaz two lots nmII be found .11 the point s where the straight edge crosses the lines that show the osts of gam. In order to include pasture in the total cost for Lot 2, add 30 cents m the co&lt;t .1* *hown hv the Mrai«lit edge for each half dollar charged for pasture t.ir one steer per month. the cattle. In the case of the rattle under discussion, there was an average ot only 20 pounds per head difference in the gain made by the steers in the two lots. The steers were fed for an average of 168 days for Lot 1 and 178 days for Lot 2. This is about the minimum period in which good-quality yearling steers may be well finished. If it is desired to market finished steers of good quality earlier than about October 15 or November 1, they should be started on Iced earlier than is possible with pasture feed - ing. </seg>
         <seg id="p009">Use of N/tive Grass in Producing Finished Cattle Another important consideration in the choice of methods is market desirability of the finished product. As far as can be determined from the marketing and slaughter data, there was'no significant difference in the market desirability of the two lots of steers. At the close of the first , two trials the two lots sold at the same price. On the third trial the pas - ture-fed steers outsold the Lot j steers 25 cents per hundred. In 1934 the steers were sold at the same price on different dates but the market was [ about steady on this! class or cattle. Lot 1 consistently shrank less in ship ment than Lot 2. Why this should have been true is not apparent. Separate slaughter data for t(ie two lots were secured'only in 1934. In this trial the steers in Lot 1 dressed 61.0 per cent and: produced five U. S. Prime carcasses and seven U. S. Choice. The steers in Lot 2 dressed 61.3 per cent and all the carcasses graded U. S. Prime. In t:he second trial the two lots 1 dressed 61.4 per ccm and in the third trial 62.0 per cent. In the trials und:r discussion it was not possible to follow the cattle in Lot 2 with hogs while on pasture. This situation will obtain frequendy I under southwestern-JNebraska conditions. Since these cattle consumed, approximately 20 bushels of corn during this ] period, the probable value of salvage from this corn should be considered in evaluating the two methods of beef production. Aside from this jfactor, it appears from the three years' work ur der discussion that the choice of the method to use depends on the relad x value ot corn, alfalfa hay, and native-grass pasture, and on the time at y, hich it is wished to market the cattle. ¦;• ¦ FULL-FEEDING VS. L MITTED FEEDING ON NATIVE GRASS, FOLLOWED BY ' FULLJ'EEDING IN DRY LOT (LOTS 2 AND 3) Three years' data are available from these trials. Table 4 presents the . . data for the periods during which both lots were on pasture (Phase 1). During Phase 1, the steers in Lot 2 were full-fed corn and the steers in Lot .3 were fed approximately 8.0 pounds of corn per head daily. As might have been expected,!the gains made by the steers in Lot 2 were more rapid but more expensive than the gains rnadet in Lot 3. During the 'dry - lot period (Phase 2):, which followed the pasture season, it was thought necessary to feed Lotj 3 for 28 days longer than Lot 2, except in 1934. In this trial the steers tare on pasture only 70 days and were fed for 112 days in dry lot. During Phase 2, as shown in Tfable 5, Lot 3 (limited feed - ing) made slightly larger and cheaper gains than Lot 2. . .. !'¦ ."" The data for the entire feeding period are presented in Table 6. With 1 the exception of the {first trial, there was practically no difference in the average daily gains made by the two lots. As an average for the three , years the steers in Lot 2 gained 2.33 pounds per head daily, compared with ' a gain of 2.28 pounds for Lot 3. In economy, of gain Lot 3 clearly ex - celled Lot 2. The steers required about the| same number of pasture days per 100 poundslof gain and ate 33 pounds more alfalfa hay but 102 pounds less of corn for each 100 pounds of gain. In other words, for each ' . additional ton of alfalfa hay required per unit of gain by the steers.in Lot </seg>
         <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 30/ Table 4.— Phase 1, full-feeding vs. limited feeding on native pasture, fol - lowed by full-feeding in dry lot — three trials. First trial—l 933 Second trial—l 934 Weighted average. J Third trial May sto |uty 28 May 4to July 13 three trials | May 7to July 30 84 dayi 70 dayl 79 dayi 84 days Lot 3 Lot 3 Lot 3 Lot 2 jjmitcd Lot 2 Limited Lot I Limited Full-fed „„;„ Full-fed grjin Full-fed gtlin Lot I Lot 3 10 ,0 12 ",2 11 II i ¦teen &#132;g er, Iteers , tccr , stecn &#132;K r, Ay. initial weight . 727 725 677 675 704 704 701 700 A., final arclghr 931 871 797 790 85-1 829 h« 828 Ay. sain per head 204 146 120 115 150 125 Ij3 121 Ay. daily gain . 2.-I3 1.74 1.71 1.64 1.79 1.40 ir 1.62 Ay. daily ration: Com ' 14.53 8.00 14.08 7.90 14.50 7.32 14.3 i 7.74 Steer days pasture 1.00 1.00 1.00 1.00 1.00 1.00 1.00 1.00 Feed for 100 lbs. train: Corn 60" -IS) 621 -4fiJ SI2 490 73&gt;1 478 Steer days pasture 41 57 58 61 56 67 51 62 Total feed per head: Corn bushels 21.79 12.00 17.60 9.93 21.76 10.95 20.25 10.91 Steer days pasture S4 84 70 70 94 84 79 79 Phase 1: Lot : full frrl corn nn pasture: Lot 3 fed 8 pounds corn per head daily on pasture. Tabi.i. t.- I'inisc 2. full feeding t'i. limited feeding on native pasture, fol - lowed by full-feeding in dry lot — three trials. I First trial—l 933 ¦ Srrnnd trial -1934 Third trial—l93s Weighted avenge lulviMo ' lulyUto |tily3oto three trial. I 5.,. ¦ 1.,. ; Number 2 Oct. 22 Nov. Vl 98d.i,s i:i&gt;iU«. 'iij^l-__ iB4 days 112 days " d»r' "6 days Iot;,1 ot 3 I lot 2 ] Lot 3 \.oi 2 Lot ; 10 10 j 12 12 I II II U&gt;:l j Lot 3 steer, -tecis i i.cers^ I steeti I .-.m» steers ; Ai. initial n-tight 9il Tl 797 790 829 W 523 A- final we.Rht MT6 1202 11)96 Hull 1076 1142 IIU 1146 to gain per head 2-15 111 299 310 222 313 157 318 Ay. daily gain 2 51 2.6! 2.67 2.T7 2.64 2.83 2.61 2.73 Ay. daily ration: Corn 22.71 20.84 15.93 16.60 17.40 17.15 13.40 18.18 Alfalfa hay 5 M 6.63 6.60 6.54 8.57 9.76 6.93 7.60 Feed for 100 lbs. cam: Corn 907 792 596 GOO 659 614 70' 665 Alfalfa hay 213 252 247 256 325 349 265 278 Total feed per hejd: Corn bushels V) 74 46.89 31.86 31.21 26.11 34.35 32.?; 37.7-t Alfalfa hay. tons 0.29 0.42 0.37 0.37 0.36 0.55 0.34 0.44 Phase 2: both Lots 2 and 3 full fell *orn r.nd alfalfa hay in &lt;lr\ lot. </seg>
         <seg id="p011">Use of Native Grass in Producing Finished Cattle Table 6.— Entire feeding period (Phases 1 and 2 combined), full-feeding vs. limited feeding on native grass pasture, followed by full-feeding in dry lot — three trials. j Firs, ,rial-1933 Second trill—l934l Third uiaV-1935 Wejjhted avenge, • : Maysto May4to M»r7» ¦ thratnali ¦".¦¦¦" ,Nov. 3 Dec. 1: November 2 Oct. 22 Nov. 19 177 dayi 195 dayl 182 day. 210 days 182 dayi 168 day» 196 days ' I Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 2 Lot 3 . Lot 2. Lot 3 . I 10 10 12 12 12 11 "'2 Lot 3 ¦¦. '- ! neeri «ecr» tteeri Keen «" ttee" ; .&amp;&amp;*£,;?¦•••¦•¦;•.;¦¦ 1 ;&lt;% •."« i*. *?« fli» »» Vn 3'11"^.......... i 1854 15.70 15J2 13J7 15.95 -DM \Mg 13J6 Slcer dayi pailure...... . » 18 " '° I ¦ ~ ,__ Sicer dayy pasture ;-M 84 70 70 | 84 M, n 11 :S^tJ' Sm"r '¦ 323 ¦ 1.73 4.41 4Jl' 338 4.02 '3.70 4.42 Durinz Phase 1 (first 70 days of feedin B P«iod in 1934 and first 84 dayi in 1933 and 1935) Lot 2 was fuH fed c"m on na/ivc crass pasture and Lot 3 was led appßnimatdr-8 pound! corn per head iVilf "nd graSd on native'snai pasture; during Phase 2 both [Lots 2 and 3 were full-fed corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot. i . \ . . . ¦ I ". . : ¦ 3, as compared witW Lot 2, approximately 110 bushels less corn were re - quired. Obviously it! is improbable that one ton of alfalfa hay will equal in price the value ofj.llo bushels of corn and consequently under any price relationship likely to' exist, the method of feeding steers approximately 8.0 pounds of corn per (head per day while on native-grass pasture prior to finishing them is more economical than the practice of full-feeding them during the grazing period. ! - a • Such data as were obtained show no appreciable difference in the market desirability of the two lots, except for some difference in shrink in shipment in each trial in favor of Lot 2. The yield was not obtained i ¦ for the first trial. In the second trial the Lot 3 steers dressed 62 per cent, ¦ compared with 613 per cent for Lot 2. Lot 2 produced 12 carcasses which graded'U. S. Prime' while Lot 3 produced 11 U. S. Prime and IU. S. I Choice. In the last trial both lots dressed 61.4 per cent. Except in the last trial the two lots of steers sold at the same price. In this case the steers in Lot 3 sold for $12.25 per hundred compared with $11.50 for the steers in Lot 2, a difference which reflected the market advance during the period intervening between the two sales rather than any difference in finish. ¦•...; - ¦'¦'. ". "\ . - ¦-';¦ ... '.'¦¦¦ ' : - . ¦ -. ¦¦-¦¦-..-- ' ¦¦ ¦ .-..•¦¦¦ </seg>
         <seg id="p012">Nebraska Acriclxtl-ral Expohment Station Bulletin 307 Steers fed 8 pounds of corn per head daily during the grazing season 0 about three months should be fed for at least four weeks longer in dry lot than the steers full-fed while on grass. This means that steers fed a&gt; were those in Lot 3 should not be marketed before November 15 to December 1, and to sell at the same weight as steers full-fed corn durin R j the grazing penod may weigh 50 to 60 pounds less per head when started I on feed about May 1. | If the weight and quality of the cattle justify marketing them about December 1, feedmg them 8 pounds of corn per head daily on native crass pasture tor approximately three months and finishing them in dry lot is on the basis ot these trials, a very practical method of handling them. LIMITED FEEDING ON NATIVE GRASS VS. GRAZING WITHOUT GRAIN FOLLOWED BY FULL-FEEDING IN DRY LOT (LOTS 3 AND •») n w| ata iOCu h v ?"? com Parisons between *c practice of feeding approxi- 2 YTh ful r° l C°r; °? graSS a"d SnZ'm* Steers without grain followed by full-feeding ,n dry lot, are presented in Tables 7, 8 and 9 Gains made during the pasture period by Lot 4 (pastured with no uere inexpensive as shown by Table 7. During the three years the vcrage daily gains ranged from 1.00 to 1.38 pounds per head and aver - aged 1.16, compared with 1.62 pounds for Lot 3 Dnnng the dry-lot period (Phase 2), which was 28 days longer for Lot (pastured with no gram, than for Lot 3, the steers in Lot 3 made sl.gh.lv larger average daily gains. This was due to the fact that Lot 3 1 «li 7.- -Phase I.limited feeding on natwe pasture vs. graz.ng without S^ioll^^J^leedm^n^ry lot-three trials. '¦?,', i '"'-1 L,°' 3 i L.,H Lotjl Lot-t I"~ -«! - - ,L " '' " " &gt;-°&lt;3 &gt; '-4 I, „., , Mccfi | men ] A&gt; f..»l we^, 1 ,:] ,",' s"' "^ 7H.1 mil 701 :=?• •- ij-ii Js^iu^i jl s~ " S" 'S T'2 ¦£•• Torj/ (red p er |, cad . , _f«^L«™ i* -tT 70 W 7g" C 9S N B 7 'Ml Kb. </seg>
         <seg id="p013">Use of Native Grass in Producing Finished Cattle Table B.— Phase 2, limited feeding on native pasture vs. grazing without grain,lollowedbyiull-leedingindry lot—three trials. Pint trhl—l933 Second trial—l 934 Third trial—l93s wdthudavmic &#132;-¦ : July 28 to [ulyl3to |uly3ou&gt; three trials Dec. 1 Dec. 29 Nov. 2 Nov. 30 N0v.19 Dec. 17 &#132;,. 126 days 154 days 112 day. HO day. 112 day. 140 dayi "6 ¦»» "4 day. ~Lot3 Lot 4 Lor 3 Lot 4 Lot 3 Lot 4 flO 10 12 12 11 H L°t3 Lot 4 steers steers steers steers steers ' Ay. initial weight R7l 845 790 7«~ 819 796 818791 Ay. final wcisht 1202 1219 1100 1110 11« 1191 1146 11/0 Ay. sain per head &#132; ,331 374 310 364 3\3 395 I\R J7» Ay. daily gain.., ( 2.6) . 2.43 2.77 2.60 2.80 2.52 2.73 2.62 Ay. daily ration: ' - \ • ' ¦' Corn i ' 20.84 19.79 16.60 16.46 17.18 17 SI 18.18 17.88 Alfalfa hay.. 6.63 6.90 6.54 7.21 9.76 930 .7.60 7.79 F"or^. loo.! b:^'":.... !793 -8,4 -600 632 -614 620" «5 683 . Alfalfa hay &#132; '252 284. 236 277 349 329 278 297 Corn "bSshds "/..'.-....' 46.89 54.43 33.21 41.14' 34J5 43.82 37.74 46.06 Alfalfa hay. tons., ] f1.42 - 0.53 037 0.51 035 0.65 0.44 0.56 I'haw 2: both Lots 3 andlH full-fed corn and alfalfa hay in dry-lot. . . •T . \' ¦ : ¦ ' ' ' • .. '¦¦.'"¦ Table V. — Entire feeding period (Phases 1 and 2 combined), limited feed - ing steers on native-grass pasture vs. grazing steers on native-grass^pas - twe without grain} followed by full-feeding in dry Jot — three trials. • First trial—l 933 Second trial—l 934 Third trial—l93s Weighted avcrase, j May sto May 4 to! May 7to three trials Dec. 1 Dec. 29 Nov. 2 Nov. 30 Nov. 19 Dec. 17 195 j,.., 223 dam ..-.••¦¦ • , 210 days 233 days 182 days 210 days 196 days 224 days ' . " ¦Lot 3 I.m 4 Lor 3 Lot 4 Lot 3 Lot 4 I ¦:¦¦:'-¦ ,10. 10 12 12 II 11 Lot 3 Lot 4 . ¦ facers steers steers steers steers steers __J \v initial wcieht. .:..". \ 725 729 675 f.76 704 703 700 701. 'Ay (iral u-elghi 1202 1219 1100 1110 1142 1191 1146 1170 •\v' B ain per hc.nl ....... '477 .490 425 434 438 488 446 469 ¦ Ay! daily p1r......¦¦:....¦... :, 2.27 ¦ 2.06 .. 2.34 .2.07 2.24 2.18 2.28 2.10 Aror Jn a'ly.""°"\ 15.70 12.81 13J7 10.97 12.96 10.95 13.96 11.56 Alfalfa hay 358 - 4.46 4.03 4.81 5.58 5.81 4.53 5.03 . Steer days pasture ...... 0.40 0.35 0.38 0.33 ,0.43 0.38 0.40 0.35 ¦reed for 100 lbs. .to, ¦ . -¦ \ . : Alfalfa hay 175 217 172. 233 .249 267 198 239 . Steer days pasture ...... \lB 17 16 .16 19 17 18 17 1*2*'.....{ 58.89 54.43 43.14 41.14 45.33 43.82 48.65 46.06 Alfalfa hay. tons i 0.42- 0.53 0.37 0.51 0.55 0.65 0.44 0.56 Steer days pasture !) .84 84 .70 70 **¦'.'. **' /? w Shrinkjn shipment. &#132;„ 4.59 4.51 3.51 4.02 4.12 4.42 4.04 Selling price...'. 5.25 5.10 8.25 8.40 12.25 ... ... DnrinK Ptiasc 1 (fmt 70 dkys in 1934 and first 84 days in 1933 and 1935) Lot 3 was fed approxi - mately 8 pounds of corn per head daily and grazed on native pasture, and Lot 4 was grazed on native pasture without pratn. Dunne Phase 2 both Lots 3 and 4 were full-fed corn and alfalfa hay in dry lot. </seg>
         <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 307 could be brought to a full feed almost at once after being placed in dry lot, while some time was required to bring Lot 4 to a full feed of corn. It may also be observed that the gains made in dry lot were more ex - pensive per unit of gain in Lot 4, although the difference was not great. Table 9 contains the data for the entire feeding period. For the entire period Lot 3 made slightly larger average daily gains, although, because of die longer feeding period, Lot 4 made larger total gains per head. The COST OF- CORN AND ALF-ALF-A # PER 100 LBS. GAIN 1.50 -i T-T 1 " 1 9 ¦- =-|_OT 2 T 3O ~ 20- "^ i_OT 3 z d, I - - -*-LOT A Z O 51.25- - - -25 H ffl _ - -15 m i 0- Sj - 15- " -20&lt; o. i.oo - - ul Z. ' &lt; a. - - - ti O - - " -15-1 U - -10 —l 0 - &lt; &#132; .75 - "a. o - l - ¦ - o - - - -10a, y--. - I H a. .50 — - - - a. : - -s -5 r 5 5 - .25 J 1-t L L o Fig. 2. —To find the cost of the corn .md alfalfa required for 100 pounds of gain, lay a straight edge from the price ot corn to the price of alfalfa. The costs for the three lots wilt be found at the points where the straight edge crosses the lines that show [he costs of gain. In order to include pasture in the total cost, add 30 cents to the cost as determined above for each half dollar charged for pasture for one steer per month. total amount of feed per head was not greatly different for the two lots of cattle. Averaging the three years' work, the steers in Lot 3 ate 2.59 bushels more corn and 0.12 ton less alfalfa hay per head than the steers in Lot 4. The steer days on pasture required per 100 pounds of gum were prac - tically the same for the two lots. Lot 3 ate 62 pounds more corn than Lot 4 and 41 pounds less alfalfa for each 100 pounds of gain. In other words, 41 pounds of alfalfa would have had to be worth as much as 62 pounds of corn in order to make the cost of gains in Lot 4 as high as in Lot 3, </seg>
         <seg id="p015">. Use of Native Grass in Pboducinc Finished Cattle or one ton of alfalfa hay would have had to sell for as much as 54 bushels of corn. On this basis, under any usual price relationship, the cost of gains would be Jess for cattle grazed without grain and finished in the dry lot. ; As shown by Table 9, the steers in Lot 3 shrank more in shipment than those in Lot 4. They also dressed somewhat higher in the two trials for which separate data were secured. In the second trial, the Lot 3 steers yielded 62 per cent, compared with a yield of 61.2 per cent for Lot 4. In the third trial the yields were 61.4 and 68.2 per cent respectively. With - out exception the packers expressed themselves as better pleased with car - casses from Lot 3 than from Lot 4. However, the prices paid for the cattle did not reflect {this difference. Prices paid for the two lots of cattle reflected differences in the market rather than in demand for the cattle. Whether the sale jof cattle in Lot 4 was helped by the cattle from the three other lots of course cannot be determined. It seems that; there is a reasonable presumption that this happened. The cattle in Lot 4 were fed in dry lot 28 days longer than the catde in Lot 3. Apparently they should have been fed for an additional period of two to four weeks, making them go to market after the first of the year. With this suggested difference in the length of feeding period, cattle grazed without grain 1 for approximately three months prior to being put in the feed lot could weigh at least 80 pounds less on May 1 than cattle- fed 8.0 pounds of corn wtiile on pasture, and still sell at the same weight. COMPARISON OF THREE PASTURE-FEEDING METHODS For ease in making comparisons, a weighted average of the data for the three years' pasture vyork is presented in Table 10. As measured, there was little difference in the steer days of pasture required per unit of gain, although, as already pointed out, it is probable that the steers in Lot 4 ate more grass per head jahd per unit of gain than the steers in Lot 3 and that the steers in Lot 2 consumed the least grass. The smaller the amount of corn fed during the grazing season, the smaller the amount of corn and the greater the amount of alfalfa hay required per unit of gain for the entire period. Consequently the higher the price of corn and the lower thei price of alfalfa hay, the greater die advantage of feeding only a limited ' amount of corn or nd com at all during the grazing period. On the basis of these trials, with corn at 20 cents per bushel and alfalfa hay at $5-00 per ton and disregarding any difference in pasture consump - tioh, the cost of hundred-pound gains would have been $2.96, $2.68, and • $236 for Lots 2,3, and 4 respectively. For each 10 cents per bushel of increase in the cost of! corn, the cost of gains for the three lots would have i increased §1.28, $1.09} and ?0.98 respectively, and for each 51.00 per ton of increase in the cost of alfalfa hay, the cost of gains would have increased approximately 8 cents, 10 cents, and 12 cents per hundred for the three lots respectively. Under any price relationship, likely to obtain in south - western Nebraska, th| less corn fed during the grazing period, die lower the cost of gains per Hundred. From the use of Figure 2, the cost of gains may be determined readily at different feed prices. </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 307 Table \fi.—Full-feeding steers on native-grass pasture vs. limited jeeding steers on native-grass pasture vs. grazing steers on native-grass pasture without grain, followed by full-feeding in dry lot—weighted average three trials. Urn, Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot "1 Average days on pasture (Phase 1) 79 /9 /9 Average days in dry lot (Phase 2) 98 116 144 Average total feeding period 177 195 223 Average initial weight 701 "00 701 Average final weight 1113 IH6 1170 Average gain per head 412 446 -169 Average daily gain ' 2.33 2.2? 2.10 Average daily r.itinn: Corn 16.61 13.96 11.56 Alfalfa luy 3.85 4.53 5.03 Steer i1j;« (uMurc 0.44 0.40 0.35 IVcil |* r I'Ht t«-ijiitU luin: Corn 714 612 550 Alfalfa h..&gt; 165 19? 239 Sh-rr t^.i\ s pa^ure 19 IS 17 Tol.ll iciil piT In ail: fnrn bushel- 52.59 46.6? 46.06 Alfjlij hai. i»n&lt; _0.34 _0.44 _0.5&lt;5 Steer day pasiure "9 '9 /9 shrink in shipment, wt icnl J. 70 4.4! 4.04 Selling pric 5H.33 58.5S 58.75 Hum, |i.,M I.. 1 ' t\ , • :..,i:.J urt; lvi 1 m. [Vii ijiprfixiin-tlcly s [wjullti' ".' I'jrn per held &#132;,,1, ,„'.' 1 ... &gt;. .-,¦: ',•-!.: Mi.im :. .1! 1..n mrt inf.. '..rn an.l nlfalfn [•"or i.ntk- tull-k-il corn on (i.vi 2), the minimum Icetling period should lie approximate!) lf&gt;S days or s|j months to put yearling steers on the market from October IS to November 1. Steers fed a limited amount nt grain (.luring the grazing period should be fed tor an additional four weeks, or (i\\ months, which will put them on the market the latter part of November or the first of December. Cattle fed no grain during the grazing period should be fed until about the first of the year to produce cattle as fat as those fed grain during the grazing period and marketed .is suggested. This is somewhat longer than the feeding period in the trials under discussion and would undoubtedly result in narrowing the spread in the cost of gains between Lots and 4. !5M] </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>