<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00067.00004">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Survey of the Cattle Industry in the Nebraska Sand Hills</title>
               <date value="1926-10">1926-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 215 October, 1926 A Survey of the Cattle Industry in the Nebraska Sand Hills HAROLD HEDGES • •', • - THE STAR RANCH IN SHERIDAN COUNTY (Courtesy Conservation and Surrey Division) THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN E. A. Burne t, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">■ ' i CONTENTS Page The Survey 3 The Sand Hills Area : 4 Status of Ranching Industry 5 Size of Ranches 6 Investment 6 Receipts and Expenses 7 The Return to Capital 7 The Ranch Operator's Problems 7 Credit Problems 8 Indebtedness % Sources of Loans 9 Management Problems 11 Size of Calf Crop 12 Death Loss 14 Pasture Management 15 The Labor Problem 16 Diversity of Enterprises 17 Rate of Turnover 18 Control of Land — Ownership or Lease? 18 Beef Production 19 Marketing Problems 20 Age and Quality of Cattle 20 Market Outlets 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A Survey of the Cattle Industry m the Nebraska Sand Hills HAROLD HEDGES • Practically every phase of agriculture has had its period of stress since the close of the World War, the range cattle industry not excepted. In fact, that period for the range cattleman has been severe and of long duration. At the beginning of 1926 his outlook was more promising. The ranch operator who has survived the reverses of the past five years should, m the next few years, reap the reward for his perseverance. Due to the. slow turnover m the cattle business, it is" probable that improvement, like the period of stress, will be extended over a number of years. One main cause of the ranch operator's difficulties since 1919 was the undue stimulus given cattle production by the war demands for food. Cattlemen and credit agencies generally failed to realize that the return of the United States to a beef export basis during the war years was only a temporary situation. The result was continued expansion of the cattle industry even after cessation of hostilities. The outcome of that policy of undue expansion is well known — forced liquidation and reduction of range herds with accom - panying hardship for the ranchmen. It is easy to look back - ward and see how one might have done differently. Even so, it is well to profit from past experiences m planning for the future m order to guard against repeating the errors of judgment. THE SURVEY In the summer of 1925 a survey of the range cattle industry of the Sand Hills area of Nebraska was undertaken by the College of Agriculture of the University of Nebraska co - operating with the Federal Bureaus of Agricultural Eco - nomics and Animal Industry. Thru the co-operation of the • cattlemen of the Sand Hills, detailed figures were secured on the operations of 71 ranches m that region for the period April 1, 1924, to March 31, 1925. The ranches studied are located m Cherry County .and the counties bordering it, and are fairly typical of the whole area. They are operated pri - • This investigation was ' undertaken by the Departments ot Animal Husbandry and Rural Economics of the Nebraska College of Agriculture co-operatinc with the Bureaus of Agricultural Economics and Animal Industry ot the United States Department of Agriculture. ■ . Much credit m due the ranchmen of the Sand Hills area who co-operated bo heartily to mnkp the survey possible. Valued assistance was received from W. T.V. Derrick, Mason Yerkes, and representatives of the Bureau of Agricultural Ecn- [' nomics, U. S. Department of Agriculture, who did the field work on the survey. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 manly as cattle raising and grazing establishments. Altho other classes of livestock may be handled and some crop farming is done, such enterprises are generally incidental to the main enterprise — cattle production. This production is primarily of fleshy feeders rather than of grass fat cattle, tho some cattle lacking good feeding quality go to the. killers. Since this study is based on the operations of the ranches tor only one year, it is well to keep in mind that the results of the survey may be affected by factors peculiar to the year. However, the survey does bring out some of the main factors which influence the well-being of individual ranch operators. These factors, rather than the financial status of the ranching industry for the one year studied, will be taken up rather fully in the discussion which follows. The survey will be continued thru two more years, after which more definite conclusions will be possible. THE SAND HILLS AREA The cattle grazing industry of Nebraska, while not confined entirely to what is known as the Sand Hills, is of greatest importance in that area. The Sand Hills area may be roughly defined as that part of the state lying north of the Platte and •SOIL AREflS FWKNS/ ' "v '"'^fty NEBRASKA , flifSu ,1,-A :NCBRfl5K « P^ 1N if 4 " H w;% »« It * w&gt; j&gt; i u y w»v t «™st ------- r~}— t"iH '™™,-4\ Soil Areas of Nebraska. (Courtesy Conservation and Survey Division) lower Loup river valleys and extending from Holt and Wheeler Counties in the east to Sheridan and Garden Counties in the west. The outlying parts of the area merge, of course, into the general farming lands surrounding it. Then, too, within the region are limited areas where crop growing is the major enterprise but such tracts comprise only a small part of the total area. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills The Sand Hills comprise about 18,000 square miles of land, nearly one-fourth of the total area of Nebraska.* The typical Sand Hills country consists of low lying dunes or hills show - ing a natural vegetation not dense enough to form a sod yet usually sufficient to hold the soil. In some sections where cultivation has been attempted or the grass covering of the soil is lacking, "blow-outs" have resulted from wind action. Among the hills are numerous valleys. The dry valleys, which are well above the water table underlying the area, have denser vegetation than the hills. The wet valleys lying close to the water table show rank vegetation. In some sections of the region are numerous lakes, a few of which are quite extensive. The natural vegetation of the area consists mainly of grasses having fair forage value but it is not of the type, in most sections of the Sand Hills, to produce choice grass-fat cattle such as are produced in some other grazing areas of the United States, tho very well suited for the production of choice feeders. The bunch grass found on the hills has value only for grazing, while the denser vegetation in the valleys furnishes hay. Some of the valleys having better soil are used for cultivated crops. Land in the area included in the survey was devoted almost exclusively to livestock (mainly cattle) production. Less than one per cent of the area in the 71 ranches was used for culti - vated crops; 85 per cent was used for grazing, and about 14 per cent of the land for hay purposes. There is little doubt but that the cattle business will remain as the chief source of income in the Sand Hills, since the land is best utilized by handling livestock — the valley lands pro - viding winter forage, the less desirable land summer grazing The very limited tracts suitable for cropping may be utilized to produce roughage and grain to supplement the winter feed supply. STATUS OF RANCHING INDUSTRY The ranch operators are just emerging from a trying period which has been a real test to their managerial ability and their perseverance. Many were unable to survive and their property has gone to satisfy creditors; others were put to a severe test to save even a part of- the accumulation of past years; only a few remain free from a real load of in - debtedness. The 71 ranches included in the survey are typical.of the survivors of five years of stress. •See G. E. Condra:'The Geography of Nebraska, pp. 8B-94. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 A composite view of the financial status of the 71 ranches in this study is given in Table 1. The table presents the average figures for the 71 ranches. Of course, considerable variation exists as between individual ranches, but even so, it is clearly indicated that ranching in 1924 was not yet on a profitable basis. Table 1. — Average ranch income of 71 ranches in Sand Hills area of Nebraska, 192^-1925 * Average size of ranches (acres) 7,749 Value of ranch real estate $47,813 Value of ranch personal property 29,078 Receipts: Range cattle g7 922 Other livestock 515 Livestock products 132 Crops 105 Other receipts 291 Total Receipts 8,905 Expenses: Current expenses (labor, feed, etc.) $4,550 Livestock-decrease in inventory 1 30 Depreciation — Buildings and fences 46il Machinery 211 Miscellaneous expenses 28 Total Expenses 0,288 P.eceipts less expenses g 3 gfj Less interest on borrowed capital 2,230 Net Income § 1,441 Less wages allowed operator and family 987 Balance j $ 454 Per cent return to capital (operator's equity) I. 0.99 Size of Ranches. — The average size of the 71 ranches was 7,749 acres, or about 12 sections. They varied in size from 1,360 acres to 29,280 acres. Thirteen of the 71 Janches con - tained less than 5 sections of land ; 29 contained more than 5 sections but less than 10 sections; 9 ranchmen operated be - tween 10 and 15 sections; 9 handled between 15 and 20 sec - tions; while 11 ranchmen controlled more than 20 sections. Investment. — The cattle ranching business calls for a large investment of capital as the data in Table 1 testify. The average investment of the 71 ranches in real estate and • Year covered in survey: April 1. 1924. to March 11, 1925. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills personal property in 1924 amounted to $76,891. This figure includes only the valuation of deeded land and not leased land. Of the total investment, slightly more than three-fifths is in the form of real estate and two-fifths personal property The investment in range cattle is the main item of personalty being on the average 85 per cent of all personal property 1 he amounts just given do not represent the operator's equity - much of the property being used as collateral for loans. On the average, the operator's equity in the ranch property amounted to $45,744 or about 60 per cent of its value. Receipts and Expenses.— Range cattle, the main source of income, made up, on the average, about 88 per cent of the total receipts. Other livestock furnished about 6 per cent of the receipts. Current expenses, which made up the major part of all expenses, include labor costs, land leases, taxes, salt, and purchased feed as the main items of cost. Taking the average of the 71 ranches, gross receipts totaled $8,965 and all expenses $5,288, leaving a balance of $3,677. Interest paid on borrowed capital was not included as an item of ex - pense but is considered rather as a deduction from profits. Deducting the interest payment, the net income averaged only $1,441 for the 71 ranches. The Return to Capital.— If the operator and his family ■ were allowed reasonable wages for their work during the year, a balance is left of only $454 as a return on the capital invested in the business. Figuring the rate of return only on the operator's equity in the total capital investment, the rate obtained was only 0.99 of one per cent. A few of the more successful and more favorably situated Operators secured a fair return on their investment after paying all expenses and interest on borrowed capital and allowing a reasonable wage to themselves and their families, but the great majority secured little or no return. In some cases the operators found it necessary to draw upon their capital to pay part of the ranch living expenses. THE RANCH OPERATOR'S PROBLEMS Many problems present themselves to the ranch operator ■ in his attempt to keep his business on a paying basis. The way in which he meets them determines to a large extent his success or failure. These problems are considered as of three /&lt;R d lr m e dlS( i ussl0 , n which follows: (1) Credit problems, (2) Management problems, and (3) Marketing problems </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 CREDIT PROBLEMS The credit problem is not only the problem of getting credit but also the problem of using that credit to advantage. Proper and profitable use of available credit is fully as important as securing it at reasonable rates. Many of the (present dif - ficulties in which the ranchmen now find themselves are partly the result of a too liberal credit policy on the part of loaning agencies a number of years ago. Credit was extended to the ranchmen at a period when the future outlook for the cattle industry was not promising. Credit expansion was highly undesirable in such a period when the prospects for profitable use of the credit were slight. The fault lies as much with the credit agencies under such circumstances as with the borrowing ranchmen. To safeguard their loans they should concern themselves with the future outlook of the cattle busi - ness as well as with the financial standing of the borrower and his layout for cattle production. Indebtedness.— How to reduce the load of indebtedness is a real problem with the ranch operator. An indication of this load is given in Table 1 where it is shown that the average interest charge for the 71 ranches was $2,236. Only 15 per cent of the 71 ranches were free from both real estate and chattel mortgage indebtedness. Five of the 71 ranch operators leased all the land operated. Of the 66 who owned all or a part of the land operated, 50 had real estate mort - gages against their holdings. The average indebtedness per acre of deeded land in 1924 was $2.89 and the interest pay - ment per acre was 19 cents. Three-fourths of the 71 ranches had chattel mortgages out - standing against their cattle. The average chattel indebted - ness per ranch on April 1, 1924, was $14,727. This amounted to $26.49 for each head of cattle, yearlings or older, the annual interest charge per head being $2.04. The chattel indebtedness, and the land indebtedness as well, wals reduced slightly between April 1, 1924, and March 31, 1&amp;25. The reduction on both forms of indebtedness for the year was 1.2 per cent. The operators were making only slight head - way in reducing the load. The average interest rate on land indebtedness was 6.6 per cent and on chattel indebtedness 7.8 per cent. Other obligations borne by the ranch operators were store accounts and the unsecured borrowings made to provide work - ing capital during the busy season. While rather insignificant </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills in amount as compared with other forms of indebtedness, yet they averaged $580 for the 71 ranches. Sources of Loans. — Federal agencies are used extensively " by the ranch operators as sources for loans on real estate. Of 45 operators who reported the sources of their real estate borrowing, 22 secured all or a large part of their loans against Table 2. — Sources of secured loans obtained by ranch operators of Sand Hills area, 1924-1925 ill Ml S M &amp;F __: -■■..-.■ • -i» p m i« Number reporting real estate mortgages ■. 50 '_ : ; ■ ' Sources of real estate loans: | Federal agencies I 22 11,908 5 to 6 5.8 Insurance and trust companies 12 34,413 6 to 8 6 3 Private individuals „ 11 18,436 6 to 8 6 9 Local banks 5 29,140 6 to 9 7.3 Sources unspecified 5 Number reporting chattel mortgages 51 . _ ■ •-■ •-. , : \____ ! _ I- Sources of chattel loans: Local banks .....28 8,306 6 to 10 8.8 Other banks* : 7 34 )541 6to 8 7-9 Private individuals 3 5,333 5 to 10 7.5 Livestock loan companies 2 31,700 7 to 8 7.5 Federal intermediate credit 1 20,000 6 25 625 Sources unspecified 13 I I - : ■ - I • : • Mainly banks at principal livestock markets. real estate from Federal Land Banks and Joint-Stock Land Banks (See Table 2). The average amount of the 22 loans was approximately $12,000 and the usual rate of interest charged was 5i/ 2 per cent not including amortization. Second </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 in importance in number of real estate mortgages held were those held by insurance and investment companies. Twelve ot the 45 ranchmen reporting sources of loans on land had secured funds from such companies. Many of these mort - gages were for large amounts — beyond the limit which the federal agencies can loan to a single individual. Interest rates charged by insurance and investment companies averaged slightly less than 61/a per cent. Private parties were specified as the creditors holding real estate mortgages of 11 of the 45 ranchmen reporting The interest rate most commonly charged was 7 per cent A few of the loans were secured from relatives of the operators 1 1 Hen, too it is a common practice for the previous owner of the land to accept a mortgage as part payment in making settlement Quite likely a number of previous owners were among the holders of the real estate mortgages, but the data give us no inkling as to the number. Local banks held verv few real estate mortgages in the area included in the survey I his is a desirable situation, since local banks have a better financial status when their loans are in more liquid form. The data in Table 2 indicate that the Sand Hills cattleman is making extensive use of the federal credit agencies to secure loans on real estate. It is undoubtedly true that the establishment of the Federal Land Banks has done much to secure greater uniformity in interest rates and terms offered by private loan agencies. The local banks are the most important sources of loans on personal property — mainly cattle — in the Sand Hills terri - tory. Ot 38 ranchmen who reported the source of their V^T.Tk 0 " P 61 '* 0 " 3 . 1^- 28 sec "'-«l all or part of such funds K? K « . situation is to be expected since the local bank officials are in favorable positions to learn the financial standing of the borrower and to keep track of the property used as security. A few of the big operators secured laige loans from banks at terminal markets and from live - stock loan companies to finance their grazing operations Federal intermediate credit facilities were used in only one instance, even tho offering a favorable interest rate Co - operative effort on the part of the ranchmen will be necessary before this source of funds can be used more extensively, but t offers possibilities. Reducing interest charges bv refund - ing loans may offer some relief. The credit problem of the ranch operators has been and continues to be serious. Its close connection to the market situation is scarcely realized. Not current cattle prices but </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills the future outlook of the industry together with the credit standing of the borrower, should be the basis for loans. ■ Cattlemen should give close attention to the unbiased govern- . ment reports on the cattle situation which are issued period - ically. Bankers are missing a real opportunity if their advice to patrons is not based, on a sound understanding of the market situation. Better credit facilities and lower interest rates can be of little benefit to the ranchman who is already so heavily in - volved as to face bankruptcy. His task is to get out from under his load of fixed charges — not a fictitious interest charge figured on his investment but actual outlays for inter - est, taxes, and land leases due on definite dates. Only more careful management that will increase the margin between the production costs and selling prices of his product or higher market prices will bring him relief. This brings us to a con - sideration of management problems. MANAGEMENT PROBLEMS The individual ranchman has within his control many of the factors which influence his production costs. Careful management will, within limits, do much to offset the effects of high taxes and interest charges or of low market prices. In order to bring out some of the factors influencing pro - duction costs and the profitableness of the individual ranch, comparisons are resorted to in the discussion which follows. Comparisons are made between the 15 best and the 15 poorest ranches, and these in turn are compared with the average of the 71 ranches. The basis used in choosing the "best" and Table 3. — Percentage relation of ranch incomes to invest - ments in ranches, Sand Hills area, 1924-1925 I | 15 15 71 Best Poorest Ranches Ranches Ranches Total Investment per ranch (dollars).. I 76,891 62,140 84,684 Total Receipts * per ranch (dollars) I 8,695 9,654 6,666 Total Expenses per ranch (dollars) 1 5,288 3,890 5,823 Ranch Income (dollars) I 3,677 5,764 843 Percentage — income to investment 4.78 9.28 1.00 • Receipts include increases or decreases in inventories of cattle, feeds, etc. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 "poorest" ranches is the percentage relation between the ranch income (receipts minus expenses) and the total invest - ment. This percentage is not the rate of return on invest - ment, since no allowances are made for the labor of the operator or the unpaid family labor. Nevertheless, such a percentage does indicate whether or not the ranch as a whole is operated on an economical and profitable basis. Using ether methods in choosing the "best" and "poorest" ranches, such as ranch income per cattle unit or net return on the in - vestment, the grouping varied but little from the one used here. Table 3 shows the percentage relation of ranch income to investment to be 4.78, 9.28, and 1.00 per cent for all, best, and poorest ranches, respectively. The question may arise as to whether the percentage rela - tions used above afford a fair comparison between ranches operating leased land largely and therefore having relatively small investments, and those operating owned land. Cost of leases is included in ranch expenses. This offsets the dif - ference in investment. Secretary W. M. Jardine of the United States Department of Agriculture, in an address to the Texas-Southwestern Cattle Raisers' Association in March, 1926, emphasized the management phase of the ranching business. He said, in part, that "for the cattleman who is. determined to build up a high grade herd, to cut his unit costs, to get his production on a plane of real and lasting efficiency, it would seem that the opportunity of a generation lies just ahead." Individual efficiency is, without doubt, a big factor in determining suc - cess or failure. In any period of stress, greater attention is always given to lowering production costs and increasing efficiency The survey of 71 Sand Hills ranches has brought out some of the factors of management affecting income. The comparisons made between groups of ranches emphasize the influence of these factors in a material way — in dollars and cents — on the net returns of the ranching business. Size of Calf Crop.— The size of the calf crop is a major factor influencing the status of each ranch. Generally speak - ing the ranch which secures a high percentage of calves from the breeding herd will be in better shape financially than the ranch with the small calf crop. Table 4 gives evidence to that effect. The average calf crop of the 71 ranches in 1924 was approximately 70 per cent. A favorable season undoubtedly </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills contributed to secure good calf crops in 1924 — a 70 per cent calf crop being considered above average. The 15 best ranches had an average calf crop of 78 per cent, one good reason why their net returns for the year were satisfactory. The average calf crop of the 15 poorest ranches was approximately 67 per cent. Table 4. — Comparison of calf crops on all, best, and poorest ranches of Sand Hills area, 1924-1925 • 15 15 .-.'.. 71 Best Poorest Ranches Ranches Ranches ■ .■■■ ■ '.;■ ■:■■•&lt;■ ■ I - Number of cows per ranch, April, 1924 271 247 262 Number of calves raised per ranch, 1924 189 192 175 Percentage — calves to cows (per cent).... 69.8 78.0 66.9 Best calf crop of group (per cent) 96.6 95.7 93.2 Poorest calf crop of group (per cent)... 39.9 59.9 39.9 That the calf crop is only one factor influencing the profit - ableness of the ranch enterprise is evidenced in the lower part of Table 4. The best and poorest calf crops for the ranches within each group are shown. The ranch having the best calf crop (96.6 per cent) among the 71 ranches was not in - cluded in the group of 15 best ranches. One of the largest ranches included in the survey had a calf crop of 93.2 per cent and yet was included in the group of 15 poorest ranches. Omitting this ranch from that group, the average calf crop of the 14 ranches was 60.5 per cent or 10 per cent below the average calf crop of all ranches. A number of factors contribute to influence the size of the calf crop arid therefore deserve the attention of the cattle - man who is interested in increasing his net returns. Main - taining the breeding herd in good condition thruout the year is important. Careful and close culling of non-breeding and irregular breeding cows should be practiced. Most ranchmen are finding it advisable to refrain from breeding heifers until they are two-year-olds rather than to breed as yearlings. The right ratio of good, vigorous "bulls to cows is necessary if best results are to be secured. The average number of cows per bull on the 71 ranches was 28. Breeding practices followed make for variation in this ratio. In large pastures ■ , ''■'•■" </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 twf-M, 8 f0I \ a given number of cows are usually required f,nn f nfT t i m 1 P ° rtanCe in secu ™S good calf crops is reduc - rareliM having calf crops below average Ne"4i-theles s hS Table 5— /)«,/* loss among cattle on 71 rant-hen in Sand HlllH area, lOZ^-litZi) 15 15 1 1 Best Poorest Ranches Ranches Ranches Death loss— all cattle (per rent) au Heath loss-cows (per cent) ZZZ.'Z'Z l'.15 76 jfo on some ranches losses were quite heavy, while 9 of the 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills will help to remedy this form of loss. Among cattle other than cows, we have already mentioned losses among young calves. Blackleg is the most serious disease with which the • ranchmen have to contend; this is in spite of widespread vaccination to control it. Only one of the 71 ranch operators . visited stated that he did not vaccinate. Some death loss resulted from castration, spaying, and dipping. While only a small item, yet such loss is largely preventable if proper care is taken. Considerable loss re - sulted from lightning, a cause beyond the control of operators. The managerial ability of the ranch operators shows itself particularly in years of adverse climatic conditions. Carrying the cattle into the winter in good condition, having reserve - feed supplies to meet unusual needs, providing shelter, — all these things help to keep down the death losses in bad years when they are likely to be unduly severe. Pasture Management. — In the range cattle business, grass is the source of profits. The practical business man safe - guards his source of profits. Methods and means of improv - ing pastures should command the attention of ranch operators. ' Possibly some knowledge of the common native grasses, their palatability and feeding value, and their means of propaga - tion would be helpful to him. There may be possibilities in the use of tame grasses and legume crops, particularly on meadow lands. Overstocking the range is particularly disastrous in the Sand Hills, where a grass covering of the soil is so necessary io prevent wind erosion. About 46 per cent of the 71 Sand Hills' ranchmen were of the opinion that they were running about the right number of cattle, while one-third stated they were understocked and one-fifth thought they were over - stocked. The latter group have the problem before them of reducing their herd or securing more pasture land. Maintenance of range grasses calls for some definite policy of management. Continuous pasturing which does not per - mit the native grasses to re-seed the land occasionally should be discouraged. Some system of rotation or modified rotation should be adopted. The main objection made to this is the need for cross-fencing involving additional cost and trouble. When renting with short-term leases is resorted to, the prob - lem is still more serious. A system of delayed pasturing has been found useful in maintaining range grasses: This system calls for keeping the cattle off of a fourth to a sixth of the pasture acreage each year, permitting the grasses to mature seeds. As soon </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 as the seeds are matured the land may be grazed The follow (juantities of grain on their own TropiS J5f rt^ —I* do not. A few other* hnv &lt;rJL- ?u' ut the ma JO"ty BWfilli months is able to handle A LmSri« working twelve on the different </seg>
            <seg id="p017">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills In the group of 15 best ranches the labor cost per head of . cattle was lower and one man working twelve months cared for more cattle than on the group of 15 poorest ranches. The labor furnished by the operator and his family was in - cluded in the labor item in Table 6. Some of the difference between the best and poorest ranches may be accounted for by the proportion of the total labor furnished by the operator and his family. Fifty-five per cent was so furnished on the 15 best ranches whDe only 40 per cent on the other group. Table 6.— Efficiency in the use of labor * on the ranches of the Sand Hills area, 192b-1925 15 15 : 71 Best Poorest Ranches Ranches Ranches ~~^ ~ ; i ? i ~~ Labor cost per head of cattle (dollars) 4.40 4.21 4.98, Months of labor required for-100 head of cattle (months)....: '. 8.6 8.5 9.3 Number of cattle cared for by one man in a year (number) 139. 142. 130. * Labor costs include estimate of value of labor furnished by operator and family. Diversity of Enterprises. — Whether or not the operators should attempt to secure greater diversity in their ranch business is debatable. As stated previously, cattle production will undoubtedly remain the dominant enterprise. How far the operator should go to supplement it as a source of revenue by adopting other enterprises is an individual problem. Table 7 gives the proportions of the total receipts secured from the various sources. The group of 15 best ranches showed somewhat more diversity in the sources of receipts than did the other groups. It might appear that diversification was therefore desirable. However, the difference between groups is not marked. Then, too, it may be well to keep in mind that cattle prices were not satisfactory in the one year studied, while prices for other livestock and livestock products were in more favorable rela - tion to the general price level. Summing up this matter of diversity, it remains for each operator to consider his own situation and inclinations in " reaching a decision as to how far he wishes to go to supple - ment his main enterprise — cattle production. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 Rate of Turnover.— While the subject of investment and proper use of credit has been discussed, there remains to be considered the efficiency of the ranch operator in using his capital. A measure of this is- given by the rate of turnover. Profits come from making the best possible use of the capital invested in the business. By the rate of turnover is meant the percentage relation of receipts for a given year to invest - ment. In Table 8 is given the rate of turnover on the total investment and on the investment in range cattle for the three groups of ranches used for comparison. Table 1.— Sources of receipts on Sand Hills ranches and proportions from each, 1924-1925 ! 15 ! 15 "1 Best Poorest Ranches Ranches Ranches Percent Percent Percent Range cattle 88.4 84.7 88 2 Other livestock 5.7 5.4 (,0 Livestock products 1.5 3.4 12 Crops and other sources 4.4 C.5 j g 100.0 100.0 100.0 Total receipts amounted to 14.3 per cent of the total invest - ment of the 15 best ranches and only 6.8 per cent on the 15 poorest ranches. On the cattle investment, the best ranches had receipts from cattle amounting to 37.3 per cent while the other group secured only 28.2 per cent. Considering this matter in another way, the best ranches are turning over their investment in range cattle in less than three years while the poorest ranches require nearly four years. Control of Land — Ownership or Lease? — It is a real question of management to decide whether it is the best policy to own all or a large part of the land operated or to operate leased land. The average rental paid for leased grazing land in 1924 on the ranches studied was $99 a section or 15 cents an acre. The average rental on all leased land, grazing and hay, was $147 a section. The average value placed on the owned land was a little more than $5,500 per section. Interest on this valuation at 4 per cent wpuld amount </seg>
            <seg id="p019">■ The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills to $220 per section. Considering the present situation in the light of the above figures, it appears that ranchmen can operate more economically on rented land. There are, of course, other things than cost to be considered. The land owner is assured of his acreage for operation. The land operated by an owner is less likely to suffer. Neverthe - less, considering it from the standpoints of profits from operation; the land owner is at a disadvantage. There is too wide a spread between the cost (interest, taxes, etc.) of owned land and rentals on leased land — enough difference so that operators of leased land have a real advantage. The fact that so much of the deeded land is subject to mortgages may mean that the owners are so heavily involved that they are unable to secure enough credit for working capital and livestock to operate efficiently. Table 8. — Rate of turnover on capital investment of Sand Hills ranches, 1924-1925 15 15 71 Best Poorest Ranches Ranches Ranches ___ | . Per cent total receipts are of total : investment ■. 10.5 14.3 6.8 Per cent cattle receipts are of cattle investment 32.2 37.3 28.2 Beef Production. — It has^ been stated previously that the Sand Hills ranchmen are engaged primarily in beef produc - tion. Large calf crops, small death loss, good pasture man - agement, lower labor costs, these and other factors contribute to large and economical production of beef. This is well illustrated by comparing the volume of beef produced on the three groups of ranches. For each head of cattle, yearling or older, on the 71 ranches, 259 pounds of beef were pro - duced in 1924-1925. On the groups of best and poorest ranches, the beef production was 282 and 262 pounds re - spectively. This estimate of beef production is based on the number and weights of cattle on hand at beginning and end of the year, those bought and sold and those butchered or lost. The 15 best ranches produced beef in greater volume per head of cattle and more economically than did the other ranches. While the poorest ranches produced more beef per </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 unit than the average of the 71 ranches, their costs were evidently so high as to bring down the net returns below the average. The operator should not try to secure large pro - duction regardless of cost, nor should he attempt to hold costs so low as to result in inefficient production. MARKETING PROBLEMS The cattleman has the market as his goal. It offers the reward for his efforts. That being so, he cannot well disre - gard it in planning his operations. In fact, the nearer he comes to meeting the needs of the market, while maintaining efficient, economical production, the more successful he is likely to be. In the discussion of investment problems, the point was made that any investment for expansion of the cattle business should be based on future possibilities of profit and not on existing favorable prices. The .market out - look for the future should be considered in planning the regular operations of the ranch as well as in settling the ques - tion of investment. Analyzing the market situation is no simple task. It in - volves three things: (1) knowledge of the fundamental price - making factors, (2) knowledge of the sources of market in - tormation, and (3) ability to interpret that information on the basis of the price factors. The individual ranch operator seldom has the information available nor the time and ex - perience necessary to analyze it carefully. He can, however. . u ecure careful analyses from reliable sources that may assist him in planning his operations. The cattleman, once his product is ready for market, is seldom in a position to dictate the price on his cattle, nor can he influence the price to any marked extent. He may think he is the victim of circumstances with luck determining whether or not he strikes a favorable market. To some extent that is true, yet he can influence the market prices he gets by the kind and quality of livestock he sells, by the time and place at which he sells, and by the methods he uses in selling. These are the marketing problems to which he should give his attention. Age and Quality of Cattle. — There has been a gradual but definite change from the production of aged steers on the range to younger market animals during the last 25 years. Increasing pasture charges, greater overhead costs, and more risk have combined to make production of aged steers too costly. With free range, the flesh put on an aged steer was made from cheap grass. Cheap grass is a thing of the past </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The Cattle Industry in Nebraska Sand Hills so the slow gains made by aged steers are expensive gains. This fact, together with higher costs of winter feeding and of labor, accounts for the change to younger, quicker-matur - ing animals. Tradition is a strong thing on the range and some of the ranchmen cannot bring themselves to give up the big steer. Much attention has been given to the quality of the cattle on the range and much improvement has resulted in recent years. Fifty-five of the 71 ranches reported the use of pure - bred bulls. Only a few of the 71 ranches, however, reported purebred cows. Improvement of the herd from the maternal side is as important as from the side of the sire. Constant culling and careful selection for type and quality in the cow herd will supplement the use of high quality bulls in grading up the herd. The spaying of market heifers is becoming a more com - mon practice on Sand Hills ranches. Of the 71 ranches studied, 25 reported that spaying of heifers was done. Market Outlets. — The main outlets for disposal of the cattle from Sand Hills ranches are thru the terminal markets (principally Omaha) , direct to feeders, and locally to feeder buyers. Considerable difference of opinion exists as to the merits of each outlet. Off -quality stuff that does not meet the needs of feeders "probably finds its best outlet thru terminal markets where the packing industry is located. The Sand Hills ranchman must bear in mind that the land he operates is adapted to the production of prime feeder rather than fat cattle. That being the situation, he should consider the policy of producing cattle that will meet the needs of the discriminating feeder. With the trend toward younger, early-maturing cattle for market, this means the sale of calves or yearlings of high feeding quality to go into Corn Belt feed lots. The sale of calves means a quicker turnover of capital, but it also calls for more careful management. To meet the needs of feeders, calves should be of high quality and show good growth at time of sale. It is likely that ranch operators will always find it advisable to dispose of most of the surplus cattle in the fall of the year, since a major item of the expense account is the winter feed bill, while the profits are made from grass. If calves are to be sold to feeders to best ad - vantage in the fall, they must have uniformity and size. This means having the calves come early in the spring and within a short period — not scattered thruout the year. Better </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 215 equipment, greater care, and more expense are required but better selling prices are the result if quality calves are pro - duced. Selling older animals — yearlings, or two-year-olds — means slower turnover of the investment and a longer period of risk from disease and accident. On the other hand, less expense and care in the calving season is necessary, since early spring calving and rapid growth are not so essential. It is the job of each ranch operator to determine which method of production he wishes to follow after balancing the advantages and disadvantages of each as applied to his own situation. When emphasis is given to a definite feeder outlet for Sand Hills cattle, co-operative efforts on the part of ranchmen may improve that outlet. In parts of Texas, as an example, the ranch operators have found it advisable and profitable to co - operate in producing- and marketing a standardized product that meets the requirements of the Corn Belt feeder. Such a plan has received some attention and may offer further possibilities in the Sand Hills area where ojrttle production is and will continue to be the major enterprise. Meeting the needs of the market while maintaining efficient and econom - ical production is the task before the Sand Hills ranch operator. His success hinges on how well he meets the situation. C5M1 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>