<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00095.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0095.0005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>State of Nebraska Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission</title>
               <date value="18??">Decemeber 1, 1940-November 30, 1942</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA BIENNIAL REPORT of the NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION xfgfjhjh taiiibii' li I w m Winiiiiiilmi! ill \m </seg>
         <seg id="p002"/>
         <seg id="p003"/>
         <seg id="p004"/>
         <seg id="p005">LBTTIR QP TRANSMITTAL Hunnroltto Hwlhlh UfUwhlil Governor of Nphi'imhn finite Qtpltßl Unmlni NflhFMkß Ppftp Sir i We ftve plrofwl in mtltmlt IwpwHli nn ihp Iwlwlf nf tln» N&gt; hi'ftskft Phlillp Wlwwy Cnmmliwlnn, Hip htonninl ropnrt piivpfliih tlw HPtivitlflß nf Hip Cnmmlsslnn fnr Hip (wind pndliiß Nnvemlw 30. 1043, Yours tn\)y, Tlinmna R, Adnms, Jr. Prmldpm </seg>
         <seg id="p006"/>
         <seg id="p007">MIMBIRB m THI NBBRA§ICA VmUQ MfIRARY 69MMI88IQN Tlinnwm W, AflnniH, Jr., Hpihi'lpp, Pmitteut • Twin w\\\m H*M M\% Pnvlfl Nnrilnifi, Omnhn, WpW'rwMi'Mf Twin wplrwi 104? Mm, 1\ U Cndy, Arllnifinii. ' Turin nicpiroH |H&lt;M Mliw Annie C, Kmiuph. Nnrrh I'liiiip Tpihu explrm HHS 11, f« Wehntor, Tukmuiili Turin wnirm U»4fi STAFF Mlhh Nellie M, Carey, Hxeentive Secretary Mrs, Dorothy W, LowHeiihop, ,-lsd\lanl Secretary and Reference Librarian Mldfl Jflflnlo Rohertflon, Aulttant in charge of School and Community Loans Mlbb Knthryn L, Buck, Calaloger Miss Loriin CollliiH, Stenographer Mrs, Katharine Stcrkcl, Part time Typist Boyd Elliot, Part time Shipping Clerk Ralph Larson, Part time Shipping Clerk Office i Room 1508, Stato Capitol Building, Lincoln Hours: 8:00 to 12:00 and 1:00 to 5:00. Closes at 12:00 on Saturday </seg>
         <seg id="p008"/>
         <seg id="p009">REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA PUBLIC LIBRARY COMMISSION December 1, 1940 to November 30, 1942 In the period covered by this report libraries have been faced with the opportunity and responsibility of providing and promoting the reading of thought provoking books on all aspects of current problems and their his - torical background which would contribute to a better understanding of the war and its causes, our own country's relation to it, what living in a democracy means, the kind of a peace we want, and post-war problems. Immediately after the United States entered the war the Library Com - mission set up a War Information Center to make readily accessible books, pamphlets and other material which have a bearing on the war. Each month the Commission receives from the United States Information Service, Office of Government Reports, packets of up-to-date information on such subjects as air raid precautions, salvage, nutrition, housing, first aid, etc., which sup - plement the regular collection in the Library Commission and this is all available for loan to anyone in the state. The material has been used by those setting up defense programs, by business men, club women, teachers and others. In the purchase of new books emphasis has been placed on books on wartime and peacetime issues, with duplication of important titles as neces - sary to meet requests. Books especially in demand have been those which tell about various branches of the armed service, opportunities and training for war industries, books abut the countries involved in the war and reports of eye witnesses of battles. The following are typical of the topics on which information has been requested: insignia of the United States; the Junior Red Cross; effect of the war on missions; the Alaska highway; songs of the armed forces; children in the post-war world; noted refugees in America; guerrilla warfare, and life in the army. All libraries in Nebraska participated in a nation-wide Victory Book Campaign to raise 10,000,000 books for the armed forces. The executive secretary of the Library Commission served as a member of the executive committee which helped plan and organize the campaign in Nebraska, and also served as the liaison librarian for the Seventh Service Command. The Library Commission was the collection center for the Capitol building. In Nebraska over 100,000 books were collected, about half of which were suit- 9 </seg>
         <seg id="p010">able ior the men in the war service. Books which would be of interest to women and children were sent to VV.P.A. recreation centers in war industry areas. The war has placed additional emphasis on the education of adults. The Library Commission works with many groups and organizations interested in some phase of adult education. The executive secretary of the Com - mission is serving a second term as secretary of the Nebraska Council of Adult Relocation, and represents the Nebraska Library Association on the State Advisory Council for the National Citizenship Education Program. She is also library adviser for the Committee on Home Economics Education Through Libraries. Close contact is maintained with the chairman of the library department of the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs and of the.- Nebraska Congress of Parents and Teachers. During the last few years the rural Project Clubs under the direction of the extension service of the Nebraska College of Agriculture have carried mi ji directed reading program. Reading lists have been prepared by the Library Commission and books on the lists loaned to those who are unable to secure them through local libraries. Reports from 4,624 women enrolled in 1041-42 in the reading project showed that they had read 36,17s books. Dictionaries, encyclopedias, the World Almanac, and other reference hooks are in constant use by employees in other state departments. Books on &gt;m'ial welfare problems ;ire in demand by those workir.g in the State Assist - ance Department and by those preparing lor the merit examinations. Col - lections of books have been loaned on request to several of the state institu - tions. Books from the Library Commission have been borrowed by schools, • ¦rsanizations. or individuals in each of the ninety-three counties in the state during the hiennium. Only .so'/r of the population of Nebraska have local library service and many rural communities depend entirely on the Library Commission for books. The N'ehraska Library Association is a professional organization of li - brarians, trustees and others interested in libraries. The Library Commission and the Library Association work together for the extension and improve - ment of library service in the state. Right district library meetings were held in the spring of 1041 with an attendance of 337. Due to the rubber shortage and war conditions no district meetings were held in 1942. Several members ,i the Library Commission and of the staff attended the state library meeting in Grand Island October 16-18, 1041 and in Omaha October 1-3, 1942. Staff members served on a number of committees, and also compiled and edited a directory of all the librarians in the state and a handbook of the Library Association. Ninety visits to libraries were made during the biennium to confer with librarians and library trustees on special problems of organization, adminis- 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">tration and extension of service. Assistance was also given through cor - respondence and through the loan of books and pamphlets on cataloging, per - sonnel, library laws, county libraries, organization of school libraries, etc. The Library Commission maintains free placement service for librarians and has many calls from libraries in need of trained or experienced librar - ians. - There is at present a shortage of qualified people available in the state for library positions. Through the Union Catalogue which began functioning in 1940 it is possible for librarians to find the location of any of the 1,677,000 volumes in 28 of the largest university, college, public and special libraries in Ne - braska. These books are available to any resident of the state for consulta - tion in the library owning the books, or in many cases through loans to the local libraries. The Union Catalogue is in charge of the cataloger at the Li - brary Commission. A state-wide W.P.A. library project which was sponsored by the Li - brary Commission was discontinued in February, 1942, except for two demon - strations of county library service. A demonstration began in Phelps County in November, 1940 with the Holdrege Carnegie Library and the Phelps County Commissioners as the local sponsors. At the general election on November 3, 1942 a majority of the voters authorized the establishment of a tax-supported county library. A similar demonstration began in Lancaster County in September, 1941 with the Lincoln City Library as the local sponsor. The proposal to establish a county library Inst by a small vote. Voters in two other counties. Grant and Arthur, also authorized the county commissioners to levy a tax for the support of a library. Members of the women's clubs in these counties backed the campaign. Adams County, having voted in 1940 to establish a county library as the result of a demonstration, operated in rg4i with N.Y.A. and local assistance and in 1942 began receiving an appropriation from the county. Two library laws were amended by, the legislature in 1941. Legislative Bill No. 37 amended Sec. 51-40T, C.S. Supp. 1939 to provide that only those people living outside the cities, villages, or townships already maintaining a public library by public tax shall vote on the question of establishing county or regional libraries. Legislative Bill No. 427 amended Sec. 51-205, C.S. 1929 to permit the library board of any city, village, township, or county to sell any real estate owned by the library board or by the public library which is not used for library purposes. The Library Commission receives noteworthy gifts of collections of new books from three sources. Books on family life are given by the Ne - braska Home Economics Association as a memorial to Eva Morse. Twenty - seven books were added in 1041-42. 11 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">A number of publishers contribute recent books for children for a traveling library exhibit. During 1041-42, 267 books were received from this ¦oiirce. Eighty-one adult and children's books on international relations were isiven to the Commission by the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. There was one change in the membership of the Library Commission during the bieunium. Mrs. David Xorthup of Omaha was appointed in June, 1942 to succeed Mrs. C. W. Hevner of Franklin, whose term expired. Mr. 11. L. Webster of Tekamah. was reappointed in June, 1941 for another five &gt;car term. 12 </seg>
         <seg id="p013">SUMMARY OF STATISTICS Volumes in Library Volumes in library December 1, 1940. 57,718 Volumes added by purchase and gift 8,565 Volumes worn out and discarded 3,412 Volumes in library December I, 1942 62,871 Record of Loans Requests Borrowers Filled Volumes Groups of residents 444 32,463 Public Schools 1,913 28,716 Schools 1,955 87,976 Other organizations 51 4,196 Study Clubs 2,640 6,466 Individuals 14,034 33,481 Total 21,037 193,298 Expenditures Expend. Expend. from from Approp. Approp. 1939-41 1941-43 Salaries $ 4,686.12 $12,715.92 Supplies 385.40 910,36 Expense 1,053,61 2,015.11 Materials and repairs , 93,14 9,35 Equipment (Books, magaslnes, etc) 4,JMP4 8,370,57 mmifiKß ii ¦ m - ¦ • -1 ii total $10,832,31 $24,021.31 13 </seg>
         <seg id="p014">STATE H JnR3?aJg?TBS Department Location Vi2nnass az T&gt;iJ=l.u». Legislative Council Reference Library " Lincoln SilVm U«=* A Sjhb Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln -62571! %-Sbr li Czar* Sum- Historical Society Lincoln -nlUffir 3fc» C = Pz=e Statr Library ..... ---- Lincoln 13232S jf33^ H Tgr;cr 'Chiefly pamphlets and clippings Veterans' Administration Hospital Lhicohl — 5-M*l&lt; 51-^ ««t^ Zferiiv HIGH SCHOOL, COULEGE AINB HSmSWMSSSTW JM^iAH-i^S School SLocrtrcrn V&lt;rfVrrrrew *JV^r.-m Alliance High School .... AThanct ...._. SflfflU Sfe S==Ez Beatrice Schools Junior High School Beatrice &lt;- li"- &lt;1" s Senior High School Beatrice ...... -afflffl 1 £== S. Ssxm Broken Bow High School - ffindfaen HStw .... IS^ s*= £&gt;== College of St Mary - "Omaha _ &lt;nSHP =S=r 3Ba=? Juan Columbus High School _Ccunmbns - 2SK S&amp;etc S. Basten Concordia Teachers College Srrcajrn _ SuTHE £n=£ =s=3Bs= Cozad High School iGrogrfl HSBi == sBi"lnu»ri Creighton University ©maha JESEZT) 3Eet? €1 Sum Dana College _ Blair IDISS&gt; aeaa s&amp;rr-fem Doane College -_Onate S'JEH 2=S Duchesne College Omaha HSSHD fSfa£e=-&gt; Seem 14 </seg>
         <seg id="p015">HIGH SCHOOI*. CDULS3SE ASt© TEUSEKTESSinrS' v.mK&amp;mtUHJhsgi {T.'.if,,,. q • School ILnamliirm Vaflmaes HBania Fairbtiry High School __ Fsarhnry =£BBSD JL "ST. Fremont High School Fmsstaxrat . 2550 jggSi Bag Gcring High School . iGenimj SiBS7 S&amp;E saano SBcßsnr* Gothenburg High School .. . (CZmfhrml-nrnjr .___ 2^Effi&gt; 53m Cfeoa Grand Island Schools Barr Junior High School (Grsmu fl.«fcmr! - SSEFS Officii ir iGsa3r Senior High School ...__ ...(Grantl Hsburfl - _ 55ED sir E. Suae Walnnt Jttnior High School (Granfl rKhmrl SfflBI) Eirastr C. Basse Hastings College -.._. F&amp;agfenjs - SffiE Xfc- "SCm. i. mrCaU Hastings High School MasfimjK $S9» *3BShs&gt; &lt;S=b 3- Jams Holdrege High School ffiTcOfb^e . 43*$ Sag- 2nl=a3fl ; Kearney Schools Junior High School Kcaxiir?- 2SEB&gt; Gas Spaiac Senior High School ... Kteame?' . -SHE! Sab SSimo Lexington High School ILeaqngtor SJDIIP 3&amp;n,r«-^n Tonagisi Lincoln Schools College View High School ILimGcirn 1358 3&amp;=_ 3ms 3L :*&gt;rgn=ni Everett Junior High School .ILSrumbi . DiSS) Ezc 'SrlmirTiiig Irving Jtmior High School H.irncrirn — . SjZSB .T%i,»— Jazmann Lincoln High School . Hjmorxbi . . 5228 ~.,:..»j- E. State: Northeast High School fLannohi SSSS7 Tgam &lt;£j~»7if7«i. Whitticr Junior High School llirrirnahi S,fWB) He 2 Loup City High School ILBtro Cat?- . 2SSB UPS^. SSnacaaa Luther College Watou &lt;&amp;«K Sssnxz 'iSL BEfcsnn McCook Jnnior College MadCmft: 34SD ~ lir * a Sag US 15 </seg>
         <seg id="p016">Sv rwitr g /-.. -¦ j i-» Vohanes Librarian ¦lirriTTrrrr £-tifc~ Ftctos: »1.05 i. Dorothy H Dysinger ,!&gt;Jm» &lt;T.-iii..r er-nTfar- — —t*a=ai tx? Milo H. Crosby WiKssa 'KcseCTr GTffaa==i^ I^a.-da 31.401 Mrs. Kthol L. Bishop Sr^iim. i;;-»ri Vctts»&amp; 4jg79 M Dorothy Mathews imu.r- i£h?r Sanai __ N^r~t Flarr«r 1.016 Magnolia Nelson 'oar Sgrr sc=nni X^nrt Pfetc 3.766 Uira Hasenhank 3tea=sm tHg&amp; SrTiwi _ • isoia t,JI7 Alice Horsiall iCcntca: F^&amp; Scanoi Onnfa 27.726 Mrs Haze] C Stewart Sorrfi: Frrgfr Scanni Oma&amp;a _ .. SjOOJ Catlierinc L Nichol Soma t^i Ssnoi: Omafia _.. _..._.. 12.408 Ivae Walker T&amp;=san=ai KhiTi ScSnof. Omaha ._ 3X229 lva Winterfield fjlmsna- S&amp;mgiuali Cuiiaa^a? Omafia . 75.000 Robert F. Lane [E=fj CQnnE H^jn: Scnmri: Bed dond _.. I_29S Christine Lynch -n=rttssßmr Ffrgn- Scsn«ri" .^cotts&amp;uxfs 3L3SO Ethel Pflng sSfhcro FSg&amp;Scfinnr Snfrtey s^oo Verna Robinson 3-Uir TTeanSers. CallesEr CSae&amp;oa 26J830 Irene Fanlder stanr TTcrii iin v (unTe-r- Kearney 37.038 Floy Carroll Mure- "nearfiexs (urili-p- Peraz 49.119 Grace Mary Petersen iasar TTeacSccs. gnTTeaf Wayne 29520 M. Lois Crouch Emmc SaflegE- LnrcnEn 29,802 Floda Snnfh Eiifisnsra: aE '&lt;Srfir&amp;&amp;&amp; Lnmott 378*361 Stephen A. McCarthy Wca&amp; GaDegEr .Varfc __ 16.057 2elda M. Wakeßn ghrSE^^SHhrnF ¥bcfc 3521 Jesse Strsrarc 16 </seg>
         <seg id="p017">TAX SUPPORTED LIBRARIES a _ 1 i Receipts T Cap mnHit m gs [ 3nS« tfl&amp;mfa S&amp;enns. K. g^tugßapt 7* 162256. 36^98 -132264 5-2 $60245 $3210 $64,455 $1X360 $37-261 $£2201! 533 "VMWB Oh»Mi . - — ffi-Tfrx Banne- 76 21530&gt; B&gt;2» «SS2SS 29 53J900 2262 82*62 19228 -44200 K2#£2 _S7 nOE l».,»il- Jtaigr- &amp;a» _ «6&gt; 25252 J^O U«I i 6 7JDOO 366 7266 2267 JUSB ?j« JOS tTMf" FTi — •giSnrrf J- Balim i S3 L9.-PJJ 5.496 18.005 S2 7.449 657 £.605 IJRO6 2336 ?^U7 25 l"ri-»&gt; &lt;*?¦ T GfinE TTHrm SL Cadis' 69 25.430 6354 5239E2 42 lOJSOO 10.800 127 D 5284 9244 3 rST*E 9md«s Trt_ E&amp;sc DL SmitHt £S 35.912 3290 101273 63 9200 79] 10291 2371 525 D 1111382 JE7 asm 3fc™afc ids. c q.™.&gt;» ism- 4«jsis2si 4.45« 34252 sj *.&lt;** . 5342 1354 2/EB3 3343 32 : csg» saafii warn- Eg ,nu se. w» , r«v so z&amp;ass 3357 usksu &amp;s 10221 489 11310 2215 -44033 ¦sjco 27 &gt; EMST riiitnnUT __^ Trim, VESSamx -X 2HSIS 6JO* 76244 62 5352 BS7 7^694 1218 .2325 16333 32 &lt;J-™rZ TOSwi Jiiiiirf^- Ease 55 C6S6 2393 29.204 A« 42D0 313 5.«79 12IS 1.425 53St 3S 452521 fflißJiiw SEs. Ejtmc SE3e* 27 C22M 225Q 43.10 10-1 230 D I*3 2232 -430 1209 2.473 3S 33E23 CQ&amp;aaHac. Bap SafiE-a: 42 £4.457 5323 55256 7JS 5300 33011 ¦999 1230 .3221 30 SiSMS Bafcp, Sis. Sunt XT. ElMortfc 51 M 377 236» 96256 15-3 4,491 501 €JL2S Ufi/3 ajo»9 «.«2S J«7 &lt;xJsfc E&amp; Hap Omijli- Oi,u-ur»r 42 FA9C6 4^293 58.093 9.4 3300 336 3J826 1.^24 2343 S-ES JM MB Btataea Sfagana SE. OffiO: 4S E2JSI 39JK2 4-1 4300 326 5u631 I^7J 2273 -ajas -4S fti-TTT' 'WfTrnf UrnaT-ir 38. Sa6» 3&gt; EIJS42 5.1»&gt; 36234 5-9 4200 179 4338 286 3JE43 AHIB2 -36 5339 V aa»Bjfcl Gsy tone atttßM 72 212SJ 20O&amp; 2329S 3JS 3264 369 52M 3117 HJBOO 4U858 25 -S2BB Pfill l—lfi fat. Banal 35 r3UE9 3239 34.141 7-9 ZJBOD 388 3J833 «6 L.43&amp; 2529 2W 45^» San-^ii Cag His. SEsnV WL SCirnfcr 23fc 7.437 2J845 25.156 6.1 1.417 2248 565 383 BJBOO 2W =3&gt;85 "Kkß; ——, _ . 3i&amp; WttSMtT 72 13239 ZJTOO 212Z» 3.9 3211 10 4292 S4O 1279 3JBS Jt9 £6BX Aaaoß FinrSr- 3taJr ¦"»¦ 3S OT29* 543 24203 6-9 2JJOO 2244 fici lUII2B 2264 ag 3Sg?° .^mrr Sa« f~irHrriii«r 2s&amp;ee 30) 5254 7287 ILSS7 4^ 2217 119 2292 4JS 7SB H_l&amp;6 3S2W HBar SCtSf HcQtBCTK jiß 7272 2256 13274 4.1 IjfiOO 149 1289 -843 ?«7 IiOT 25 22M» Bhmcir BbK IBs- Zinc- TTain/iw 2* 7^«J2 USOO J2329 ILO 2291 263 2.158 UH62 *3" 2287 JBS 33)38? CErae Sis. Sag C BaEtxr 3l&gt; E2233 1233 15.404 5-1 1.403 43 2298 4311 747 13(22 J62 JSBJ4S (Snac JOs. Coi=- 23 321S 4J39 37290 12.1 1243 264 iy97 filO ««5 H»^S5 -«7 Bgg rr*Bi«A. eistifc ffTfrnaTT 25?9EZ272 3221 412H 122 1241 152 3JH2 X3lO "900 34842 SSI j^are rrTinfi»u SEae E_ C3»p«— 4S 92GD 338 24J526 6IS 2.478 161 3j6&lt;3 53S «» 2JB3D -53 17 </seg>
         <seg id="p018">— +— ,—- j^- t-i TTV^ iT . ~ Li 11 *5S — "^^fe- SLUMS' 7Hi_; •1.-m-.T' 3s— .— «t-- -&gt;«— jn«. .»* 18 </seg>
         <seg id="p019">555 !T'"l l(I" r' 3&amp;" r^ SD *=S; 2= *=* 232*3 S2S2*n7S «5523»3 4EHS 3S»S *sis£=£ OSS tTa-rfttgi Sis- fiL-SL 9sr 3* 2=32 HOJS7 HE727 Sa SS «n a^s. 3B 232* JSS V.intc- (Tintllmil 3Es- ji mf Baag ¦* r^EBl 2225 2L23M, tLS 23411 23D 2MT. 3&gt; T?SD -ffl» ts» dflß^ mi'.Jliif! Sis. Sfe=cfir CMirTir we 2JS3D 3S, 213 335 33 «r ? aj, " ITS ~^l |S ™=^ gfe^^SS=„- - * 3«2 2233 — 4= 4» =£1* 3* 0 4IH 52222 T^a—im IBs. Xatc rri,iiii«ißir^s- 3» 23» SSB HC3572 £5 SS «; 2L2S: 2M» .^ «se ggß» l™* S* s*'5*' *»¦«=• 3B S3B"' *:=ffn a* ss ara* 2=3 » arras « ZtUW &lt;S=Ksstt SBs- Is=jr3 SsR 3* 7£*sS&gt; 035 D ES223S 422 33TZ7 3335 2J3M. 2KT *¦&gt; 32=* "S» I22Sa EEa Smmm _ » 22225 SSS2 =JC3S *s *&amp;&gt; JS23 353 7==, ~SS "S Z2SSO fgiffii ilium. SisLCKas-Siß. 3» -5J327 =ren »JS 22807 37 502*5 tag. S3» ~^zi "a - aat FFrmnanffti sis. sosn- atsg 3» sass sv rajs? «* «eu 23»&gt; s^£^ S^ S» "T^ 3s Ul^ nun^iin 2C&amp; tMnrnim mti Tnii" 3P=-23SS Sf 5333 mZ! OSE3 afi. 3L23G2 223 2ST 323 j» 22225?" Hog, Cags- T-Jim-. "giTrarag 3» 3E23ES 22-1117 .H~B» HS3M 33*11 3291.. 3CS 222* «. CJBB* 2*2a«88 ass= Slfa^ lit; 3^ SdaF HSI -535* 2S 223* Sfc 2SN. 2S mil-ill Gnnr Tff--^ 3SS£osm. - ZZ* -^JSS ti«a JEgn 3E3 SJHati «E" H^» sag 33 Ejfc j» "¦JuUB— '* *g&gt; vurg .7-1 ¦Wfe a— c in im-hFm </seg>
         <seg id="p020">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES— (Crmtintiea) 1003 North Bendf 1-aora Ron™,. .»&gt;¦, .i.i.U SoK 7.1.47 7... 5 KSB S KS S 12» ¦&lt; 15" S 57-' 3 IjQSXSJjE I*3Bo Oakland Lydia Hill . 13 «.4&lt;.5 «x 17.117.; 12-3 137fc 123 l_ol* 7u.; 27-' USSi .« 3*159 OgaUala Mrs. E. H. Fahrlandrr 10 3.6(M 1.733 HI.IMB 3 1 Win 127 I^2f 303 31: «4&gt;' 2Jt 3271* O'Nefllt — Mary McUanehlin .._ 1" - - — —- —— — '662* OrdT __-__ Mamie I_ Smith _.... 32 4.61.1 1.552 2ll.ini 7..-. 1.611U -31? 2.l Si. &lt;77T ;=». -U9ll -i - -7*11- Orlranst .- Dorothy M- Mahn 34 7215 523 7.741 t..«. 2"n 2.ov&lt;- 2j77t. 27.; -3» 226*2^1' 1039 Osceola ~ — — Lulu Hcndrickson 12 3.583 233 «,232 62 267 2K 3U7 111 11 jOT 2» - -I*l4l Oxford Mrs- Oren Brown - 138« IS4 1.1 Hi ." 275 21 33i. -44. v* *»&lt;¦ 2S 1*647 Pawnee City Mary E. French 39 6.9U2 IJim 232U1) 14 1 13»ii I£2 13K2 -45~ «»' USE ¦*¦ 1*135 Pender! .Mrs. J. J- Lynch 3&gt;i 4.027 A.UU2 2-t, inn 13 X* —- 337 a«. 1*249 Pierce .Mrs. Hahna Mastalh- 9 4232 700 6.044 4.X V.U42 1 1.1*3 ST 301. 577 34 1411 Plainview Mrs. L. C. Barbonr 22 5324 653 14.421 102 12011 112 13d 389 -481. I**H 3JII. I*oo3 Ponca Mrs. M. Lipe S 6236 57(1 3.090 3-ti 465 -U5 SI 33&lt;&gt; ISC 2=l 1094 Randolph Mrs. C. A. Kerr 17 4274 850 8.121 7.4 966 75 T.D9" 2« 3*. «07 2Js 1 429 Ravenna Rhea Rentfrow 19 4382 550 537-4 4.11 1315 1.-Mn 2UI -AMi &lt;SSH **¦ I*6lo Red Cloud Y. Ola Swartz 33 73"3 1.185 13-865 «.«. 13(111 13«»&gt; 331, 331. 3j&gt;»&gt; S3 1*125 Rnshvffle ._ Mary W. Slohr . 15 3206 K371 7.1. &lt;S5 7-4H UO3 3te 3ai&lt; "U1357 *uj 1 571 St. Panl Mrs. Ina SI. Luick 11 '/. 4.43S 301, 5348 5.4 toll 3«. 1.1U3 tsi*" 223" f*&lt; jol 1*444* Sareenrt Mrs. Flora A. Cropper 33 5.100 12011 1(1233 7.H Willi 32 "S2 185 301' 325 3t 1.479* Sheltont ¦ Mrs. Jessie SI. Bnrkerd — 6.086 7294 7." 995 3 13«S 13.. *tt&gt; r"5" 1 142* Spencert Mrs. Ilildnr SI. Ocren - XIV. 3.644 562 9209 8-3 5« -It, ÜB7 "VU. 3M' 7S jut. 1 526 Stanton Mrs. Jean D. Hoils! ien 28 7354 1208 14.113 92 131S "U«S2 2W. 1311 323** J9" 1.742° StapletonJJ Mrs. Visa Stalnaker 11 2.011 300 5385 3J 369 2" 4»l&gt; 3«n -£»• 337 .3* 1.127 Stromsbure Mrs. Herbert Olson 24 3345 1359 82733 72 70(1 1-13 543 343 335 &gt;»*=&gt; JBb 1.403 Sntton Sibyl B. Jarrett 33 4261 1.491 7398 3-1 3300 333 335 =&gt;V&gt; VS 2.104 Tecnmseh Sirs. R. \V. Campbell 30 5342 1.025 11.0011 52 1,0110 to 331W 372 3JB«p. 32 1 925 Tekamah Sirs. I.ncfle Gates 18 6.956 1250 M 2» 72 1300 134 2221 27* 32333 3* 2.188 Valentine Sirs- Emma A. Sheldon 18 4382 2308 9.475 43 SOU 71 JWin 225 23ffi ffig 278 5 Report {or 1941 tTownship library 'Includes township population (County library 0 Includes county population 20 </seg>
         <seg id="p021">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES —{CrmrhxoerD 1.204 Walthai Sirs. Harry Keefe ; _ _ __ J"4io** }^auS3t ¦}«* Banks __ 30 4282 633 82251 22 *60 3334 ~ssi ~388 IsS 33 fill w ayn&lt;" "ST JI"*S 5 *£ Bfasr 7-BSS =*- 2266 330 333S 523 32286 2Z2SE I"» i'l-Jn *)Xeepi??. Wattr Mildred Hart 12 7259 458 1429 D 322 583 732 23U3 MSB S3 "**rfßs9 i «9 A^S^^^ £" Tie., B- S 3™ 0" « 3.112 315 3.003 32 2*oo 33 320 3843442286^ «o Alexandria Faye Burch _ 6 3294 95 XZlf. *2 ion quo * Iw Is t7 5 lc,lt„ Mrs- C- B- "Oossett 10 1376 766 2264 2-9 230 =4 «7 Sal ?*9 B?"'*l^ eefe S™- wfsB 7 F ."l^" 10 3332 10l 52113 il Juu 23 2^ J| *» S 5 &gt;69 B, B Sprmg Sirs. Fred A. Johnson 6 1283 127 22200 32 27* 373 itu Tb^ rzjfon"^ ffiS S i r nr?Sf'" 1 "0 F-T-^-S 7 , *-£ S0 S5OO 332 32? 30 So 227 *^^2^ 565 Blue HOI Mrs. Carl Hoffman 5J4 1293 137 2370 32 257 32 *D -W -MR 2»»&gt; 3* 232 Bruntus ___ Sirs. F. E. Flessner . 4 599 79 4247 182 3n 33 *a a in « *3B »-i ""™ mCfct H™- ,U;,n. !ta Hndxeth 4J4 1339 SslJB4^32__!:_ S JtjlS 350 Carleton *!»--, D- a Swanson 6 £70 42 1208 *3 —= "5 "2=^ = j» 3jl Carroll Wro.frcd SI. S'ephens 5 3226 236 2487 21 27S "IK 5n z^ "5 tc n"SS 695 Cedar Rapids Mrs. Geonje W. Orshek t W» 737 112K iS Z$ 23 » 2f»S 23 833 Clarkson, Sirs. Josephme Noh 3 1297 150 430n SA 32-=STOS -=; r^S 71 J Clay Center Bertha F- Jessup J^ — — -"" 3rL%* r^f .^XI JJIS-- Ne!?'* BrmTO 9 1232 »LII 3tm 228 ~*222 ~iS 64| Comstockt Slanon Stevens 8 2328 503 3.1137 -1329432«7 il % »^ i * „°° k Mrs- Clara l«acb 8 3.033 280 1336 *S 3S vpn tan. :S&gt; 218 Crab Orchard Sirs. W. F. Vernon 6^ 3304 J?3 13n| 33^2^^ 222 g^^ SRcport for 1941 fTownship library "Includes township population JCounty library 21 </seg>
         <seg id="p022">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES — (Continued) Receipts Kxprndilurcs 1« « I SJ 1! If II 111 |1| IHj 1 fl 815 Culbertsoti Mrs. Elmer Mcßee 11l 2.5.12 4.10 7.40'/ 9.9 $ Sou $ I IX $ 74.1 $ 1,._» $ 142 $ &#132;7(, J.K.I 952 Curtis Anna Marie Hansen 5 1,324 105 2,583 2.7 79 (,X 190 IX 79 10.1 .11 477 Dakota City Mrs. D. M. Neiswanger 4 3.263 378 3.162 (&gt;.(, 12 114 521. 148 02 304 '64 .158 Dalton Wilmn Breiman J'/, 1.146 167 4.362 12.1 51l &lt;¦ xo 47 26 73 20 450 Davenport Mrs. Arthur Jensby 8 2,673 314 5.44S 12.1 3.10 .1", 404 111. ll'i 343 7«, 165 Daykin Mrs. Sidney Schmitt 3 644 S3 1.758 10.6 7K ' IXX 40 24 81 So 490 DeWitt Mrs. Hazel A. Bent .... 378 Diller Alice Specht 30 2.502 296 7.722 20.4 75 71 147 105 137 .36 656 Dodge Barbara I.uddc.i 7'/i 1,506 460 3.666 5.1, 1,111 ... 175 72 60 134 ¦»() i 853 Elgin Mrs. R. D. Wilcox 10 3,218 241 9.534 11.2 .150 53 456 117 120 385 45 &gt; 429 Elkhornf Mrs. Walter Bull Id 1,804 472 3,006 7.1, 125 65 580 57 71 428 99 730 Elm Creek 3 2,463 428 3.00(1 4.1 69 41 113 97 11l 15 633 Elwooil Mrs. Luella B. Dow 109} 3,807 460 4.414 6.9 1(10 4 107 94 94 .15 879 Emerson Mrs. Wm. Hansen 9 1,803 462 6.655 7.5 400 -17 447 120 120 397 45 459 Eustis Mrs. A. L. Hathaway 7 3.265 1,125 4.1611 9.1 75 190 390 138 13 239 S* 858* Ewingt Florence C. Ponton 16 1.082 180 1.281 1.5 .1(1(1 20 320 180 320 37 841 Exeter Mrs. Lillian Perry 1(1 1.481 31(1 11.455 13.6 452 57 142 640 Fairfield Muriel Green 11l 3.356 195 2.004 3.1 484 53 572 2V .160 450 .70 810 Fairmont Zola R. Shoemaker 11l 4.754 (ill 4.854 5.9 234 41 III" 56 100 280 .35 346 Famam Mrs. Minnie Anderson 6 961 141 1,727 4.9 72 7 79 52 55 1(, 596 Guide Rock E. (Catherine Guy 15 3.976 340 4,647 7.8 742 90 1.173 75 300 768 129 704 Harvard Mrs. Paul R. Whisenand IS 3.705 576 7.392 10.5 368 390 8118 181 247 687 97 819 Hay Springs Mrs. Mary C. Goff 8 5.552 315 3.998 4.8 15(1 8(1 180 272 33 314 Hayes Center Evelyn Barker 792 Hemingford Mrs. Grace Olds 5 2.544 107 2.963 3.7 3(iii 24 503 *45 Toil "358 45 427 Herman Mrs. A. 1.. Sullivan 894 1.381 3.2 60 5 70 2 60 64 15 441 Holbrook Edythc B. Christianson 6 797 430 1.547 3.5 25 29 54 7 24 17 08 477 Homer Mrs. K. M. Church 6 1.981 138 2,446 5.1 75 44 151 12 52 78 16 802 Hooper Mrs H. F. Waterman 9 3,074 703 4.245 5.3 270 38 312 101 180 304 18 841 Humphrey -Mrs, E. J. Fuchs 5 1.218 141 3.219 3.8 208 17 225 155 35 204 .24 8 Report for 1941 tTownship library •Includes township population 22 </seg>
         <seg id="p023">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES — (Continued) J Receipts Expenditures 3 s ' ¦ M 800 Iniliaiintajj .Mrs. li. A. Rau-son 12 1,591 170 4,320 5.4 861 Laurel R. L. Lathrup _ _ * 575 Leigh .'..Dorothy Halm 7J4 1,786 171 4,818 8.3 Tl9 25 '.'.".'. 155* ~{"»5 **348 61 58 Lcwiston Mrs. W. \V. Joekcl 3J4 2,134 143 1,716 10.8 60 71 131 74 20 114 72 412 l.ilchneul .. 151 LodgepoleS Mary Helen Groshart 4 1,336 62 1.708 2.5 ""i'oo *28 135 "~79 ~~i ""87 18 824 Long Pine Mrs. M. T. Potter 10 982 450 3,222 3.9 100 23 131 13 96 113 *14 HI Louisville Mrs. Bedella Standcr 8 3.871 388 4,604 4.7 325 129 454 129 118 378 .39 4»° Maxwell Mrs. Rose C. Dolan 5 1.224 120 784 1.6 209 4 213 24 36 213 .44 , 321 Merrunan Mrs. George Mattison 6 1.313 53 1,606 5.0 21 77 102 32 ! "? Mdfonl Mrs. W. C. Cherrington 10 2.635 126 4,797 6.3 150 26 366 121 206 339 45 636 Monroe Vera Sutton II 1.109 68 3,191 5.0 50 21 93 53 67 .09 , Morrill Mrs. Golilie Wilson „ 11 3.552 933 7.698 8.7 1,12(1 77 1 197 '09 11? 546 f&gt; /£ M?i 0" 'A!'"' „E- ,Raddcn 24 2- 5"« 4°S 4,232 4.4 201 49 374 85 132 286 "j(l 629 Niobrara _Elva Randa 2.345 541 1.969 3.1 108 41 211 '7 50 167 27 S?'i kVr, U,,t -/; •.•¦-•••••••"• ? -U46 2.955 2.9 5(1 81 148 41 148 *15 ¦&gt;61 Oakrinlc Gertrude B. Gove a 1.854 49 440 .7 70 50 130 9 49 117 i\ 991 Ocontot Mrs. Ruth Thompson 6'/, 1.579 238 1.340 1.3 2UO 7 '07 51 7(1 216 22 o?n R r£? a"i« ?!"¦ f; B.*"uc'; •; 4 3-705 2-400 4- 8 72 w »« 26 so "so ITo V! Oshkosllg -Mrs. Mattie Aufdengarten 30 3,655 519 8,321 9.1 106 80 323 115 '5 190 n I9'' °s, non, d Pearl E. Record 13^ 1.229 99 3.359 4.2 350 37 387 91 144 332 *42 799 I'ahsadc Mrs. Belle Coker 6 1.375 1,976 2.4 95 4 I'l •&gt;! 70 108 14 401 Palmyra -Mrs. Sarah I. Mcrwin _ ,X\ J'aPillion Mrs. Esther Ruff _ 7 1,894 2,602 3.4 120 169 "294 "Yl4 '"53 207 27 493 Polk Mrs. J. E. Mac Daniel _ 10 1900 1,350 2.7 300 HI i 0 5t *:r5 &lt; J!"' T-S'omi 3 1.782 230 460 1.2 171 37 243 " 3*l 4~ 219 .5b 834 RalstonS -Mrs. Bert Meadows 7 2.165 150 1.835 2.2 ?on §'-, Edward Gertie A. Anderson 12 3.635 1,010 7.815 8.7 400 40 "*440 ""« "555 "Hi .42 JBIJ Salem _ Mrs. Henry Parker 10 75 4 79 52 74 19 453 Scotia Mrs. W. H. Waters 4j4 3.455 105 2.507 5.5 184 16 455 """6*7 59 174 38 ¦ Report for 1941 rTownship library •Includes township population 23 </seg>
         <seg id="p024">TAX-SUPPORTED LIBRARIES — (Continued) Receipts Kxpemiiturrs 904 Scribner Els;, Meyer 1&gt; .'.952 80 1 3.889 4.3 $ 000 $45 S 544 $X 4 $ 300 $ 588 * (&gt;5 342 Shickley Mathilda l.iclm 12k. 1.78S 11,3 0.5.17 fi. 1 200 -o, 4 &gt;0 159 U ¦'2K 67 827* Silver (reekt Lucille Abel ... 395 Snyder Mrs. Marvin Dcrr I, 781 40 2,212 5.i, 7il 11 lli.S 11 49 105 27 830 SpauldingS Mrs. Frank Dunning 10 2.841. 921 9.379 II I 197 i nn lot '67 1' .170 Springfield Mrs. Verba Bolen 640 Sterling Mrs. Mary E. Holleubach 15 .1.000 205 5,589 8.7 451 .... 77' ' 2j '40 262 41 630 StrattonS Mrs. Carrie A. Bailey .10 2.980 369 7.190 11. 4 17.1 17 190 180 ..'. 183 29 760 Stuart Marguerite L. Smith 10 2.300 20(1 5.509 7 ' 75 1 862 Sutherland -Mrs. Roy Wilson ; 982 Syracuse Mrs. Ervin H. Gellermann 15 3,849 79(1 6,210 6.3 1,059 21 1.44(1 275 253 834 85 562 Table Rock Mrs. Alh'e Wood 10 2.027 310 2.301 4.1 293 5 499 103 78 225 40 423 Talmage Sophia Moller 12 1.820 327 2,007 4.7 188 1.1 295 63 180 270 64 984 Tilden Gwen French 21 2,735 1,669 7.152 7.2 800 111 810 46 322 663 67 316 Tobias Anna L. Sakryt 6 1.276 11)0 1,870 5.9 51) II 136 28 5' 86 27 876* Ulyssesf Mrs. Martha F. Withers 7 4.526 293 6.072 6.9 450 659 1.218 253 18(1 1.136 1.32 985 Valley Mrs. Anna Howard 53 4.956 6511 12,132 12.3 85(, 44 800 360 540 800 81 67(1* Wacot -Mrs. Nelson Hughes 1 1.200 70 1,200 1.8 50 _' 08 3 46 SI 07 961 Wakefield E. Ruth Collins 12 6.7811 926 5.006 5.2 1.252 1.497 261 360 810 .85 381 Waterloo Mrs. Wm H. Jacobson 4 1.735 187 1.810 4.8 107 8 115 18 52 82 22 632" Wilcoxt Leah Lippstrew 13 1.341 178 200 200 49 42 133 .21 451 Winside Mrs. Etta Perrin 8 2.500 440 3,345 7.4 300 30 330 48 180 277 62 829 Wood River Sabra J. Abbott 12 4.669 401 9,293 11.2 475 28 512 214 165 50.1 .61 SReport for 1941 ITownship library 'Includes township population Total volumes reported 1,462.10.3 Total borrowers reported 278,821 Total circulation reported 3,712,20(i Total receipts including balance reported $ 430,285 Total expenditures reported ..$ 374,859 24 </seg>
         <seg id="p025">LIBRARIES NOT TAX-SUPPORTED There are in Nebraska a large number of libraries not included in the list of tax-supported libraries. These libraries are usually sponsored and maintained by some club or organization. Some of these libraries receive a small amount from the town and in other cases rooms, heat and light are furnished. Changes in librarians are frequent due to the fact that many of them serve without pay. Amherst Dunning Nemaha Arthur Edgar Nora Avoca Elmwood Oak Bancroft Ericson Ong Bartlett Giltner Palmer Bartley Grant Paxton Bassett Gresham pilger Beaver Crossing Gretna Republican City Belvidere Haigler Rising City Benkelman Halsey Rosalie Berwyn Hampton Royal Bingham Hardy Riiskin Boelus Henderson Shubert Broadwater Hildreth Stella Brock Howells Swanton Brownville Hubbell Thayer Campbell Hyannis Thedford Chambers Kilgore Trenton Concord Lewellen Verdigre Craig Lindsay Verdon Cre«ton Lushton Wauneta Crookston Mead Western Dannebrog Melbeta Wilsonville Dorchester Murray Woodlake Douglas Nehawka </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>