<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>TWELFTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF The Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth AT BEATRICE TO THE GOVERNOR AND BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF rhe Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth AT BEATRICE TO THE GOVERNOR AND BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908 1908 THE WOODRUFF-COLLINS PRESS Lincoln. Nibi.. D. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">For term ending January 1. l ( .t()7 B irge L Sheldon Governor For term ending January 1. 1909 HOAHD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS For term ending January 1. 1*&gt;&lt;)7 HtNKv M. Eaton, Commissioner of Public Land and Buildings President Algernon Gallsha, Secretary of State Sec i. Peter Morti State Treasurer HilAHI) DK l'l'BLM LANDS AND HIILDINI For term ending January 1. 1909 Henri M. Katun. Commissioner Public Lands and Huildings President Seen State Treasurer Hon. Wii.lixm T. Thompson Attorney ' ieneral H&lt;&gt;\. NORSie BbOWN Attorney ( leneral Ks. QbOBGI C. .Ir.NKlN, Secretary of State n. Lawsom ' &gt;. Hkian </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A. JCHNSON, II. I) Superintendent Term ending September 1. 1907 Fk ink E. Osbork, M. I) Phvsician Term ending September 1. 1907 Frank K. Osborn, M. I) Superintendent Term beginning September 1. 1907 Samuel .1. Stewart. M. I) Physician Term beginning September 1. 190"i Miss Kmm\ Howard Miss Anna Y. Cooper Mis&gt; ("oka S( hakfknhkik, Jack O'Donnell.. Kami Instructor William Pollock Supervisor Boys' Department Mis&gt; Harriet Ch ibtree Supervisor Girk' Department or Boys' Department Hospital sor (iirls" Department Hospital In charge of Sewing I! John .1. Wyatt In charge of Laundry HVEHLY In charge of Bakery C. C. S\\is In charge of Farm Department K. M. Ramei Chief Kngineer Carpenter ami Brush Department A. ScHULTl SCHOOL DEPARTMENT Him Lkttie Adams Principal Mi&gt;^ S IRA San DIDGE Mi&gt;&gt; Elizabeth K&lt;&gt;bi\ tC. Ai.vokd. Supervi . NbLLII Ai.vohd Supeiiv . M. Dillon </seg>
            <seg id="p004">A I &gt;M I N1STB ATI ( )N HI I I.I )I \( '. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">I&lt; ientleinen In accordance with requirements of the law ami ir Board, I beg leave to submit the following report exhibiting tisties. recommendations, and other matters connected with the ninistration of the affairs of this institution for the biennium line November M). 1908. I The movement &lt;&gt;t population, together with the per capita t for each semi-annual period, taken from semi-annual reports, been a- follows: !"•&gt; Hon. ( ieorce L. Sheldon. ( iovernor of the State of Nebraska, and the Board of 1'iiMir Lands and Buildings DcccnilxT 1 . 1906 to June 1. l'.M No. enrolled at beginning i»f period N&lt;&gt;. admitted and re-admit led W No. returned from parole A No. discharged VI No. released on parole ."&gt; No. died s -■ No. remaining at end of period „, Pet capita cost M I .."&gt;(i June 1 . l ( .io&lt; to December I, 1907 I. enrolled at beginning of period . admitted and re-admitted... 118 21 No. returned from parole li' ,, No. discharged A No. released on parole. . 14 No. died 8 34 No. remaining at end of period. m </seg>
            <seg id="p006">212 Per capita cost $50.45 tAt the l&gt;eginning of the biennium, Decemljer 1. 1906, the iber of inmates enrolled was 402 and at the close of the period total numlier was 411, an increase of 29. This increase prae - lly re; the excess at present over our normal capacity as lie mentioned later. I At the beginning of the biennium there were 45 applications file. Since that time 115 have been received and 102 admitted that at the present time there are on file in this office applica - &gt;m 58 individuals anxiously awaiting admission. No appropriations having been made for new buildings at the iig of the last legislature, our funds have been used, aside from a few minor improvements and general repairs, for mainte - nance. There has been expended under this item alone a total amount for maintenance and instruction of children including all expenses except clothing. $95,045.85, or a total per capita cost for the biennium of $228.49. While this per capita eod is lower than ember 1, l'.tOT to June 1, 1908 k. enrolled at l^eginning of period 427 . admitted and re-admitted 25 returned from parole 10 — (barged 3 . released on parole 7 No. died 23 33 — N&lt;&gt;. remaining at end of period M Per capita cost $62.33 June l. I'.min to December 1. 1006 rpnrolled at l&gt;eginnin«; of period 429 admitted and re-admitted 20 returned from parole 3 ,v. — t barged 10 released on parole. 6 ied . 5 » — No. remaining at end of period.. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">for any previous hicnniuni in the history of the institution, it has do particular significance, the reduction being influenced la by the increase in the population. At the past rate of expenditure, all of our appropriat will be sufficient until new appropriations are available the (i April. It has been foremost in the mind of the management to keep within our appropriations. For this institution t! priations of the 1907 legislature were not extravagant. With a record of the lowest per capita in the state and a muss appropri- ation figured on this basis then with a decrease in this amount of practically $10.00(1 .00 intended by the legislature for our oat ■ I because of the auditor's ruling, we have found that to ride through the biennium without a deficiency in any appropriation would require the greatest care. Thus far. however, we have within a pro-rated amount for the period of the biennium and we are confident that no deficiencies will exist in any fund April 1st. 1 want to state, however, along with this, that our inmates have never suffered in any way for lack of care. food, or the pri\ which rightfully belong to them. Still I believe the state ought to deal generously with its eleesmosynary institutions and more • dally with the feeble minded. HEALTH KSD MORTALITY The number of deaths for the period was— male, 28; female, 14 ; total. 42, &lt;&gt;r ~i\' , per annum, the causes of death being as follows: Epilepsy. 15 Tuberculosis t&gt; Valvular disease of the heart ■"&gt; Pneumonia Chololithiasig _' Meningitis 2 Nephritis _' Anaemia '_' Hereditary Syphilis 1 Bright's Disea . 1 Cerebral Hemiplagia 1 (leneral Debility 1 Pvemia &gt; 1 f Of this number 40 were custodial cases, the greater numl&gt;er l&gt;eing of exceedingly low vitality. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">X. /. " u ■ '•..•J fct I I ■ I s L A 4B Jfl t . J| I El -y </seg>
            <seg id="p009">215 While there baa been the usual number of minor ailments with which to contend, to our great satisfaction no epidemics nave oc - curred. This result is attributed to a strict enforcement of hygienic and sanitary measures. Ventilation and cleanliness of dormitories and day rooms, encouragement of activity in the manifold duties of the institution, gymnastics, athletics, and manual labor for those who are able, sufficient nutritious, carefully prepared food, and fresh water from a well where contamination is impossible, all are prophylactic measures adopted for the warding off of contagion and the maintenance of health. Tuberculosis exists in a large percentage in some form or other at the time of admission. Many of these cast's can be benefit ted and no new cases need develop if the wards are not crowded and segregation is made as soon as the trouble is discovered. At my E-tion our herd of cattle was tested for tuberculosis by an tnt from the department of the State Veterinary in order that we might l&gt;e sure no trouble was insidiously emanating from the milk. It was pleasing to note that none of the dairy herd were affected ami but one other animal showed a questionable reaction. This animal was immediately destroyed. tThe medicinal work of the institution is largely prophylactic, must l&gt;e so for when our children once become sick they are nearly always seriously sick, due to their normal weakened physical and mental conditions. Then too. "A merry heart doeth good like medicine" so it is our continual aim to keep alive the spark of happiness which illumines bo small a part of the lives of our children. SCHOOL DEPARTMENT During the period there has been an average in the school department of 210. The majority of these children are between the ages of five and eighteen years, our ages for admission, for practically all that can be accomplished by this class in the school department proper will l&gt;e within tbis age limit. This part of our work is essentially prominent but the results are not altogether satisfactory. There was a time when authorities on the subject considered that by proper training wonderful re - tlts could be accomplished and individuals classed as feeble minded uld become practically normal. This theory is now exploited for it is only in cases where there was no impairment of the mental functions but rather an inability through environment to acquire </seg>
            <seg id="p010">216 uere the* marked results have l&gt;een attained. It is 'generally conceded that a feeble minded individual's training will result only in a relative improvement and that he will i idvaneed either as a student or an artisan. This much. • ■rtain. Nearly every case, if taken at a propel be l&gt;enefitted and thus to an extent the burden upon society lightened and his condition in life improved. 6 attempt in our kindergarten and grade work, by singing classes, band instruction and drills, and through sloyd and indus - trial work, to develop both mind and 1 1 1 • to such a 'i&gt; of proficiency as is possible. I The industrial side undoubtedly affords the greatest oppor - ities. Here the training of the eye. the ear. and the ser gment. and the patience required to produce the finished prod- II developmental. In following out this idea I have in - luced the making of a l&gt;ed spring fabric, the making of mattresses, [&gt;et weaving, and on a small scale cobbling in addition to the k that was already )&gt;eing done. Besides the advantajv of work to the children, it has also 1 wen a benefit to the e from a ]&gt;ecuniary standpoint for our springs and matt: I on a large numtier of our wards and other home made 5 department of the institution. RELIGIOUS EXERCISE* I Each Sunday during the school year it has been customary hold two in our chapel of an entirely non ure. Meml&gt;ers of the Ministerial Association of Beatrice talk hildren in the afternoon and in the forenoon a Sunday ool service is held where illustrated truths are presented. KIMI.KPTIO There are in our institution 105 epileptics or 25' , of our total lation. Of these 50' j would undoubtedly do l&gt;etter if segre - i and given the more special l&gt;enefit recommended at this time for their class. I have no cause t&lt;T change my ideas on the subject of the care of these individuals as given in the following quoted from an article written in HK)6. t"In this, as in most states, the epileptics under state control scattered through all the public institutions, but their numl&gt;ers chiefly found in the hospitals for insane and the feeble minded itution. All but a very small percentage of these individuals </seg>
            <seg id="p011">I! mentally defective and might l&gt;e well classed in these institu - ns; but the 'colony idea.' as best exemplified in New York and issachusets. has proven that the results are uniformly I ere they receive care in an especially equipped institution, ndergarten and elemental school work, sloyd and manual train - :. colonies for the adult where his early training may continue I become of productive value, and finally custodial care for the minal. infirm and insane, an application of all these together h the liest hygienic, dietetic, and medicinal measures, exper - ce is teaching us, offer the epileptic the most promising me. In as small a state as Nebraska, a separate institution is not as practical from an economic point of view as it is in a more thickly populated state, but here there should l&gt;e a classification with separate buildings and grounds according to the requirement physical and mental conditions, the whole to l&gt;e under the management of one of the other institution I Since the writing of the above, thought along this line is l&gt;eing en considerable attention by people of our state who are charit - y inclined. The Genoa Indian School property, should it l&gt;e lated by the government to our state, has been suggested :l s a table location for such a colony. This property would offer endid facilities for the care of epileptics and I believe thai institution could in a short time be put upon a practical! •porting basis. Not the least of the many advantages given by h a movement would l&gt;e the relieving of other institutions of the te at the present time housing epileptics whom they cannot iperly care for. It would, while taking from our own institu - 1 many of its most profitable inmates, relieve the congi idition existing here so that our present accommodations would sufficient for some time to come. KAKM AND GARDEN tin addition to the 2'2'2 acres of our own land we have rented ing both years 40 acres of adjoining property. All of this land been under cultivation with the exception of that occupied the buildings and about 40 acres of pasture. Our crops have n l&gt;etter than those of surrounding land localise of our having abundance of help but we have l&gt;een handicapped by the luck implements and horses. </seg>
            <seg id="p012"/>
            <seg id="p013">219 By the purchase of a thoroughbred Holstein animal from the Bey Industrial School, we are gradually building up the grade of our herd and the same is being accomplished with our bogs. More gardening has been attempted during the pa than heretofore and U'sides the large amount of produce used for Burner consumption we have ■ good supply stored for winter low is given a tabulated statement of the principal farm and garden product the biennium. oi IHM PKODCl'T VI SKI) Total i«. to: l'.ION 308 bushels 7ti5 bushels 1500 bushel? 174S bushels 1827 bu 3350 bushels 840 bushels 1062 bushels 1850 bushels Wheat Corn 15 tons 27 tons Timothy and el Alfalfa ' 12 tons V( i :is ton _&gt;() tone is tons 50 tons 165 tons Millet Cane Hay 50 ton •.XI ton 75 toll:- -1 tons 1250 bushels 150 bushels 2IM) bushels 150 bushels 175 bushels 170 bushels 150 bushels 1700 bushels 260 bushels 400 but 600 bu 215 bushels ISO bushels 450 bushels Potatoes Sweet Potato* Sweet Corn.. 150 bushels 40 bushel 100 bushel ■20 bushel 20 bu-hel 25 bu liel: 50 bushel. - 100 bushel - 50 bushels 70 bushels 120 bushel* 75 bushels 60 bushel.~ String Bean 40 bushels 50 bushels 25 bu 90 bu 40 bu 15 bushel 1000 headi 45 bushels 3000 i eads 2000 Lead^ 10 bushel* 50 bushels 50 busheb 75 bushel - 10 dozens 50 dozen? :*5 busheb 100 bw 100 bushels 1 75 bushels 25 bushels 50 bushel - 50 bushels 100 bushelf (ireen Onions Kgg Fruit 10 dozens 55 dozens 40 dozens tibbard Squash mmer Squash tons l.')() bushel 110 bushel •2(M) bushel; Tomato* Pare nipt Turnipc tint:. to.. 10 bushel 20 hu-ht'l Kdishee . cumber Cabb tubarb. tuce Spinach . 5 dozens 40 dozens </seg>
            <seg id="p014">220 I The children's dances twice a week have been continued where - addition to dancing, games are played. Occasionally a purely ial gathering is given where light refreshments are served, udeville. juggling anil stereopticon entertainments have occurred in time to time. During the summer months base ball, fool ball. 1 basket ball are indulged in by the boys while the girls amuse niselves in t heir own way on the lawns. Band concerts and ious contests form a diversion for the summer holidays. On holidays during the school year the teachers and children pre - ■ ial programs to which parents and friends are invited. IMPROVEMENTS I My first work was the enlargement of our oven in the bakery that it will l&gt;e sufficient for our needs for some time to come. This was followed by the expenditure of about $1,900.00 for an addition to our laundry which left a balance of the $2,500 .(Ml appropriation that proved sufficient for putting in steel ceilings in the old part of the laundry where needed and also for the construc - tion of a new and enlarged dry room. t There has l&gt;een added to our fire equipment 250 feet of hose. • usion laddei extinguishers, a fire gong for main building, etc.. and all of these have been placed so that we ready as far as possible to meet anything of this nature that we fortunately escaped in the past. Several hundred square feet of cement sidewalk were laid and ent floors were placed in the vegetable cave and coal bins. tThe dairy barn has long l&gt;een greatly in need of repairs. The were taken out and in place the space below filled with .nd a cement floor and stanchions constructed. This s us a comparatively modern and hygienic structure. iThe $ 1.000. 00 appropriation for porches for the hospital was dly sufficient and it required considerable planning to procure 11 ' ermelons. . 2( M ) 200 ■ 10 bushels 10 bushels y Turnips 15 bushels 30 bushels 4o bushels wherries 4 bushels 3 bushels 7 bushels Aj.,,1,- 10 bushels KM) bushels 10 bushels KM) bushels - 3M0 gallons 3700 gallons 7340 gallons 1M.AY Q BOUNDS \M) AMUSEMENT* </seg>
            <seg id="p015">221 something suitable and yet keep within our appropriation. W« have, however, completed a large roomy porch which adds in ally not only to the appearance of this building but to its utility M well. tAn appropriation of $1.(MM).O() had Ween made for an ice 1 r various reasons this was not built until late in the fall and the v sparse supply of ice in this locality last winter did not give an opportunity to use it but we have a well constructed building ficient for our needs ready for the coming winter. t Other minor improvements such as a new porch Boor witli ck and stone foundation for the old boys" cottage, painting i repairing of practically all the roofs and pointing of brick work I chimneys has been done. The usual amount of painting, •nishing and kalsomining necessary has l&gt;een going on in all of ■ buildings. The greater part of all minor improvements has ■n done by the aid of our own help and without additional ex - lse to the state except that for material. SEEDS There are at present 58 applications on file of those awaiting admission. Added to these 29 whom we now have in excess of our capacity and 6 who are on vacation leaves at the present tit for whom accommodations should be made. In addition to this number, account should l&gt;e taken of the normal increase In-' now and such a time as buildings can l&gt;e constructed and equipped and also for a number desiring admission who have not made formal application beeatlM of the known crowded condition existing here. To this end I would suggest the construction of three new buildings. one each for boys and girls and one school building. The latter should l&gt;e a commodious fire-proof two-story structure, with a bly hall, furnished complete and connected with the power plant. for which should 1)0 expended not less than $40.(MM).(H). Our ut assembly hall on the fourth floor of the main building is totally inadequate for our needs and because of its location ia -ible to many of our children. The school rooms on the upper Boon of this building have the same disadvantages. kThe boiler house and lighting plant is taxed to its utmoi ent. Any increase in dormitories or by a school building will ssitate an enlargement of this structure. The smoke stack, ck by lightning a few years ago and repaired, is. besides being </seg>
            <seg id="p016"/>
            <seg id="p017">223 antiquated anil the source of a great waste of fuel, in a dUapii condition. tl would also recommend the construction of a new horse Warn r which $2,500.00 has been asked. Fire escapes should be placed for the upper floors of both girls' cottages, the hospital and both hoys' cottages. The old I cottage is especially in need of the same as the only exit from the third floor dormitories where there are some forty hoys is by means of one narrow stairway. The wiring in five of our buildings is not modern, the lx»ing concealed and passing through the joists without insulation in some instances. I would recommend that this wiring be cha from the concealed to such as is required by insurance companies. I would also recommend the installation of a telephone connecting the different buildings, to he used for a fire alarm s\ as well, and for the farm the purchase of two work teams and an appropriation for vehicles and farm applian* Baaed on an expected increase in population, I would reconi mend the following appropriations: Maintenance $70,000 on Employes' wages 32,000.00 32.000.00 ."i.OOO 00 Superintendent 'a salary Kvsician's salary 3,000 00 'ward's salary -M00 00 ichers' salaries.. 6,000 00 Chaplain's salary ! 200 00 3.501 Genera] repairs. tse ham 2.500.00 etting boiler 1.500 00 Kngine and generator.. . . 1,750.00 tiiler house repairs and smoke stack 2,500 (M) school building, hoys' cottage and girls' I ur- STEWAKD AND PHYSICIAN The institution has now reached a stage where the servi&lt; both a physician and a steward are needed. All of the superinten - dent's time should he given to the executive work of the institution while the position as purchasing agent and custodian of clothing. all of which is furnished at either private or county expense, would nished complete. 100,000 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">224 occupy the entire time of one individual. The physician's services should t»e devoted entirely to the medical side of the work. &gt; CHANGE UK ADMINISTRATION Ob Septeml&gt;er 1, 1907, Dr. A. Johnson who had credit ably managed the affairs of the institution and brought it to a high de - gree of efficiency, resigned his position to return to the pract My appointment to the superintendence took place on the same date and Dr. Samuel J. Stewart, a successful prac - titioner of Lincoln, was appointed to the position of physician. 1 &gt;I()N tl wish to thank you. gentlemen, for your ever ready and willing tisel and support which has been of great assistance in the lagement of the institution, and all connected with the institu - i for their uniform loyalty and cooperation. Respectfully submitted. Fm\K K. Osborn, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p019">APPENDIX POPULATION OF INSTITUTION BY COUNTIES County M :l le Female Total Antelope .3 v&gt; Adams 4 ,; .0 Boom i; Brown 1 i Hurt 1 ■_&gt; 3 Butler 4 ;} : Buffalo :\ 1 Box Butte 1 1 2 Boyd. 1 4 •■ Cms b 5 n Cedar. :{ (j Cheyenne 2 2 Colfax 1 ": Cuminfj 4 1 Cuater. 4 ■_&gt; Dakota 2 1 Dawm 1 \ .■ Dawaon ."&gt; ■ Dixoa ,-, 2 : Dodge .-, n . DougUu 45 21 M Fillmore 4 ,-, Franklin ] 1 Frontier 3 Furnas _&gt; j &lt;; ;»S ( ' 10 14 ,4 Garfield ] ] 2 (ireeley ■_&gt; Hall 3 ; { 6 Hamilton 1 3 4 Harlan 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p020"/>
            <seg id="p021">227 "Hitchcock H&lt;.lt 1 ■&gt; • &gt; Howard Jefferson Johnson Kearney Keith I 1 » 1 I ■&gt; ■&gt; 1 Knox Lancaster Lincoln 17 Hi I Madison lierriek Nance 1 1 I ■&gt; Xeni ah a Nuekofk Otoe 4 3 s •) II Pawnee Phelpa Pierce I •&gt; I'latte Polk. 1 Perkins ;; Red Willow Richardson Saline i II Sarpy • tnden anl Sherman Stanton ! Seotte Mluflf Thuraton i Thayer Vallev Washington Wayne 1 Webster York 12 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">228 IKK (i\\N QBOWM PBUIT AM) VERETABLB8 PRE8EBVED POI \\ I N T Kl( - \VI HTIt'l 155 &lt;;aL n tonuU 155 gallons preen lonntofii gallons caused peaches KM) gallons peach butter galloM canned peaches KM) gallon* peach butter gallons Baited corn gallons xauer kraut -allnns malted COTB 50 gallons oucunilxM- picklee 50 gallon's cucumber pickle -4* » gallons cherries gallons saner kraut 40 gallons cherries UIH KKFOKT ritOM BEMI-AMNUALfl December 1. L90S to Jum I, l ( .»(i7 Bdaoee on band November Ml 19&lt;N» 92 ved since 54.25 54 25 402 17 303 45 Expended since November M). 1907.... ended since November 90, 1907... 303.45 Halance OB hand May SO, l'.»07 8 7_' June 1. l'.»07 to December 1, 1907 7_' Halance on hand May 31, l&lt;»07 8 72 s 72 ved since 4&lt;^ M uce May 31, 1907 tl36.88 nee May 31, L907... 215.20 Kalance on hand with State Treasurer , on hand and in hank nee on hand with State TreMurer 215.20 on hand and in hank 145.70 4 1 ' 145.70 4\« December 1. ]«&gt;07 to June 1, 1908 i on hand last report — At institution $145.70 State Treasurer 215.20 360 90 tpenditures ceipts 47 . 7o 190.85 balance on han&lt;l May 31, 1908 June 1. 1906 to December 1, 1908 aice on hand last repor $190.85 eipts 70.45 261 • nditures 11 Balance on hand November 30, 1908 148.45 261.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p023"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>