<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00039.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00039.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Eighth Annual Report of the Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner of the State of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1917">1917</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Eighth Annual Report of the Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner of the State of Nebraska 1917 -^s^- W S. Ruiyell Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner Harry F. Kequartte Assistant Miss Mamie Mukioon Secretary B. J. McArdle Inspector Otto Murschel Inspector M. G. McCunc Inspector Wm. Buffum Inspector </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">HIUHTH ANNUAL RKPOBT. Office of State Fire Commissioner. State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska To Him E.nflU'H&lt;y, .John H. Morehead. Governor of the Stnti •/ Wehraxka: l»e;ir Sir In compliance with tlic Fire &lt; 'oinmission Law of Net&gt; - •askii 1 herewith submit t&lt;&gt; you the Kijrhth Annual Report of this I &gt;epai tment. The past vear has Imm-ii a busy one and much &lt;;oo&lt;l has Ht*n accouipliwhed 1&gt;\ the department. Fire Chiefs as a whole have l&gt;een prompt and thorough in sending i" report* of tires cx-rnrHnir in their locality. As the |ie&lt;i|»le of our State Itet-ome more familiar with the Fire Coinmiftsion Law its effectiveness increaw* and each vear bftafp new lM-netits to l&gt;oth the Commission ami the State. We Itelieve onr iMpactM! have covered the state gen - .m-;i11 v and that Nebraska is now in a l&gt;etter condition from a tire standpoint than it has ever Ihmmi before. We ltelieve that practically all the merchants in the state keep their supply of gasoline buried in safe under - jfround tanks. We are constantly watching the carleKs storing and handling of gaaoHnp and we mean to make Nebraska as safe as possible from this dangerous </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 STATIC KIKK COMMISSION Our idea of ■ liii- lui/.iiril is that a (wilding or |»rojtert&gt; must actually Ik 1 . because of its condition, particularh siiweptible t(» tire. Frequently complaints come to us alxmt buildings tha&lt; are not really lUiriirt-i-ous from a fire standpoint. Imt merely old ami unsightly. If the nwnerx of old property keep same in jxood repair, keep the surroundings free ami dean from all rubbish and in flaw mable material. we cannot coiidcnin such property to Ix-autifv a Ti&lt;'it;|i tiorhiMH] . We do not at any time wish to work a hardship on anyone and our constant aim has liecn to Ik' fair ;ind square and broad and at the same time firm in the enforcement of the law. In all condemnation proceedings we have gives ample time to repair and clean up their property ;ind only in ram where they hav&lt;* rpflMWd to do this or where the ItaiMinj; w;is beroud all repair have we condemned same and ordere&lt;l the pMpCVtj torn down. In nearly all nm the |iro]ieity owner has l&gt;een niadt lo see that it w;is for his own as well as for the pnhli&lt; public ijood to remove his property and put up a new I &gt;u i Id in i:. ritizells of the state, as H whole, have co-operiited with us and have willingly coniplie&lt;l wiht our instructioii - ;md orders alono tire prevention lines Having old rubbish and inflammable material lyin - around any premises is 11 condition we treat most severely. There is never a &lt;jood or logical excuse for this accumul:i tion of rubbish on any property and our orders in case* of this kind have Item anil will continue to lie ver\ sevei-e. I'oorly constructed chiinneys stoves s»m up with im metal |»rote»-tion underneath, stoves too dose to unpro - tected walls, stove pijMt* through ceilings or wood jiarti tiinis. poorly installed elwtrir wiring, and numerous othei grossly careless conditions have to l&gt;e constantly liK&gt;ke&lt;] after and remedied. To the average citizen Fire Prevention presents a vaum outline always asHo--iate&lt;l with Fire Insurance. Th&lt; general iflesi is that where a building or its contents i&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">STATK KIKE COMMISSION 5 destroyed liv tire MttMag is lost if the property is insured. (Mir &lt; itizcns must Ik* brought to realize the true economic ( -miilit ions : they must l&gt;e taught that loss by fire is irretrievable, and that tire insurance creates no wealth I nit merely distributes the burden of the lows by collect - ing a tax to reimburse those having tires. As the fire loss increases so must the tax represented in premiums Ik- greater and sufficient to repay the loss. There is no other one business in the country today of such magnitude and such universal necessity as fire insur - ance. Without this jrreat collector and distributor a ureat conflagration would cripple business, cause tremen - dous failures in the commercial world and untold hard - ships to the home owner. Not only, as a power of recovery in the hour of calamity does Fire Insurance jjain its chief purpose or reach its only important service. The stability of the financial world and the demands of civic or industrial activity could not be preserved apart from the credit attained by and impossible to secure with - out Fire Insurance. Frequently the principal security lyiag lH-hind the credit needed in the erection of large structures of every character is the insurance polio pledging the safety of the investment in the event of destruction by tire. The credit of merchants is largely based on Fire Insurance carried on their stocks. This fact applies to every branch of industry and multiplied activity of commerce is based upon this system of cred't universally prevalent. Grossly Cashless Pikes. CigW and cigarette stubs carelessly thrown around caused :U&gt; tires the past year. Every one of these fires could have been prevented by careful habits. Defective Chimneys caused BO tires; these could have Fire Insirance a Necessity. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 STATK FIRK COMMISSION lieeu prevented by careful examining and repairing ba&lt;l chimneys. Defective Furnaces, last winter caused 33 Hies. Bnri winter we have miinerous fires reported as due to defectiv furnaces, stove pipes, flues, etc. A little attention give:, to heating apparatus in the fall would prevent tires trmm\ these causes. Defective Electric Wiring caused :iO tires during 1916. There is no doubt hut that many fires reported as un kn&lt; .wn are ciiused by defective wiring. These are treach - erous fires because they often occur when no one is around to discover the Maze until the fire has prised great headway. Electric wire cords should never Im hung over metal nails or hooks. Our inspectors find many people doing this and it is a very dangerous habit Matches used and handled carelessly caused 10!» tires last year. Twenty-nine of these were in the hands of children, and several were burned to death while playing with matches. All these fires are unnecessary and could Ik- avoided by careful precaution. Hot ashes thrown against buildings is an inexcusable careless habit and causes a great many very bad tires Twenty-six fires were reported to us this year from this cause. (iasoline caused 47 fires last year. We an- constantly warning the public regarding this dangerous explosive yet it is constantly causing fires. Gasoline should always l&gt;e handled and stored with the utmost care, ft should never be stored in the house and every precaution should lie used with the gasoline stove and lamp. Kerosene used for "starting the kitchen fire," in oil stoves for heating and cooking, and in tilling lamps, etc.. caused 58 fires last year. Defective and overheated stoves caused 74 fires. .Most of these fires could !&gt;e avoided if the proper care was exercised in looking after these stoves ;tnd not firing them until the iron Incomes "red hot." Rubbish left carelessly around where a spark will ignite it. or burning same carelessly mi ■ windy day o </seg>
            <seg id="p007">STATE KIKK COMMISSION 7 i near wood buildi»»s caused 17 tires with a large tire low*. Tin- 21 tires caused by Spontaneous Combustion could Im- prevented if jwople would keep their premises free and clean from rubbish and accumulations of useless waste. Of the 37S tires reported to us as 'rnknown" probably three fourths weit- careless and unnecessary and could have Imh'ii prevented if due caution had \m&gt;\\ exercfani. Kkatiis ank In.ii kiks r.v Kirk Fort.v s*-veii lives were dest roved by fire in Nebraska 'luriiif: the year |91f and more than 100 jn^jple painfully burntMl. A jrreat immlver of these were gasoline tires caused l.\ usinj: gasoline in the home, and a still &lt;jreater iiuiuImm were caused by "children and matches." It is time our citizenship was taking an active interest ind making a "Safety First" campaign to preserve life ind pro]H'rtv from untimely death ami destruction. Tliis ippallini; loss of life is alarmin-i an&lt;l in nearly eyerv hnc it is i-aused li\ c;i iclessness. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Five Year- Old Girl MRS. CHARLES POST DIES FROM BURNS Is Burned to Death BEATRICE. Neb., Dec. 9— (Special Telegram.) — Doris, the 5-year-olc daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Prank Van- Liew. living in south Beatrice, was burned to death when she attempted to put cobs in the kitchen stove. Her clothing caught Ore and she was fatally burned before her mother who had stepped out on the back porch could extinguish the flames. WIFE OF WELL KNOWN DAIRV MAN SUCCUMBS AFTER A BRAVE STRUGGLE Five Children Survive. OMAHA, Neb.— Mrs. Alvina Post 30 years of age, wife of Charles Post proprietor of the West Omaha dairy lied shortly before noon as the result of burns she suffered last Monday in i gasoline explosion and fire whirli Jestroyed the Post home at Sixty-sixth ind Dodge streets. For two d ivs ui the Method st Episcopal hospital th&lt; - injured woman made a s'rong fight against death, but from the firs' had little chance of recovery. Funeral arrangements have not been an Former Tecumseh Woman Is Burned to Death TECUMSEH. Neb.. Dec. 10— (Spe - cial ) —Washington Robb, Thomas Robb and D. L. Robb of this city re - ceived the information that their sis - ter, Mrs. Elizabeth H. Robbing had been fatally burned at her home in Wallace. Neb. Mrs. Robbins was en - gaged about a bonfire, when her cloth - ing became ignited and before relief came she suffered burns which caused her death the next day. nounced. Mrs. Post was fatal iy burnt a Jar of gasoline, which had been placed in a pan of hot water on tlu kitchen stove to bs hra'ed. explodeci and sprayed on th*&gt; s f ove and hei clothing. Her husband marie ate efforts to save h&lt; r and he alsc suffered painful burns. Sunnyside Home at Hastings Burned Mrs. Post w.ip well known and ular in Omaha, having been born her» In addition to her h'isbaiid and he mother, Mrs. Halite Raah'e she is sui vived by five children. Xelli-. 8 Clara 6: Henry, 5; Charl.s. 4. and Alice 3. HASTINGS. Neb., Jan 17.— (Spe cial.) — Sunnyside home for children and aged people, a charitable institu tion, was swept by fire wh'ch started at 9 o'clock last night. The house, a three-story brick structure on the north side of town, was a total loss The property was valued at $20,000 and was insured for $10,000. In spite of several close calls none of the in - mates were injured. Miss Margaret Kaely. in charge of the home, superin - tended the rescue work and helped carry the panic stricken people out of the burning building. The fire is thought to have started from an elec- South Side Lad Dies From Gasoline Burns SOUTH OMAHA, Till l«WI—m Stilmo"k, a 9-year-old lad living at 4406 South S'.de. was fatally burned at 11 o'clcok yesterday by a gasoline explosion and was hurried to the South Omaha hospital. wh« re he died at 3 o'clock, his body being so badl&gt; burned that he had no chance for re- tric wire covery </seg>
            <seg id="p009">STATE KIRK COMMISSION 9 4 Sister and Housekeeper Of Priest Fatally Burned Man Fatally Burned By Gasoline Explosion WEST POINT. Neb., Jan. 29— (Spe - cial.)—The funeral of Miss Elizabeth Schoof took place today at Monterey, the body being interred in St. Boni - face's cemetery. Miss Schoof was the sister and housekeeper of Rev. Henry Schoof. rector of the Monterey parish. She arose at 6:30 a. m. and proceeded to light the gasoline lamp in the kitchen. By some unknown means the i fluid became ignited, setting fire to her clothing. Her screams aroused her brother, the priest, who was yet in bed. He rushed from his room and endeavored to smother the flames, but in vain. She was 57 years of age and had acted as housekeeper for her brother for the last twenty years. BEATRICE. Neb., Jan. 16.—(Spe - cial.) — Gus Hanson, an employe of the Union Pacific stone crusher crew at Blue Springs, was seriously if not fatally burned at the bunk house at the plant Friday morning, when hj attempted to start a fire with gasoline, which he mistook for kerosene. An explosion followed and Hanson was frightfully burned about the body be - fore the flames could be extin - guished. He was brought to Beatrice by Dr. Schooling and placed in the Mennonite hospital, where he was re - ported resting well Friday night. Han - son Is 40 years of age and unmarried. His home is at Alsberg, Kan. Bonfire Seriously Gasoline Fatal To an Omaha Girl Burns 6- Year-Old OMAHA. Neb.— Gasoline sold for coal oil resulted Sunday morning in the fatal burning of Miss Jensine Pedersen. domestic employed in the home of Lars P. Jensen, dairyman. 2208 South Forty-second street. She died at St. Joseph's hospital yesterday morning. NORTH PLATTE, Neb.. March 28.- Rosella Palmer, 6 years old. is in a critical condition at the home of her father, J. O. Palmer of this city, as a result of burns about the arms and back sustained when she went too near a bonfire about which she was playing, and her clothing caught fire Attracted by the little girl's scream her mother ran to the fire and as sisted by a neighbor succeeded 1 smothering the flames. In tearing th flaming clothing from the child's bod. Mrs. Palmer sustained painful burn about the hands. Woman Burned to Death In Sod House Near McCook MCOOK. Neb.. Dec. 16.— (Special Telegram.) — Mrs. R. D. Rogers, who lived on a farm about fifteen miles northwest of McCook, in Hitchcock county, was burned to death in her sod farm house yesterday afternoon. No other person was on the place at the time. Origin of the fire is unknown. The body was found under earth and debris of the caved-in roof of the sod house, lying across the bed. Burial occurred in Hayes county this after - noon. Killed by an Explosion HUMPHREY, Neb., Nov. 2.—Mich - ael Parocki was instantly killed while repairing a gasoline can in front of his shop today. He was soldering the can and fumes were ignited. He was killed when an explosion followed. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Fire Threatened Children MANY HORSES BURN WITH SMITH BARN Herman Yonkey Discovered Blaze and Roused Family TWENTY-EIGHT ANIMALS LOSE LIVES IN FIRE AT BRICK PLANT OMAHA. Neb— Charles M Branson carried $2,000 insurance on the two story house occupied by his tenant. Herman Yonkey and family, which was burned down late Monday night. The owner valued the property at $3,000. It was built five years ago and was a large nine-roomed dwelling of modern construction. Mr. Branson thinks that .sparks from the chimney set the roof Caretaker's Close Call OMAHA. Neb.- -Twenty-eight horses perished in a fire which destroyed the barns of the Smith Brick Manufactur ing company, at Twenty-fourth stree* and Woolworth avenue, Saturda\ night. Herman Yonkey had Just finished feeding hie team and was on the way back to house when he saw that the • ast end was on fire. Seven children were asleep upstairs and had the father not seen the fire before it made greater headway some lives might have been lost. Mrs. Yonkers was sleeping down stairs and had her two - year-old infant with her. The frantic father and husband could npt get in the house from the rear door and was forced to run around to the front door. It was some minutes before Mrs. Vonkey opened the door. He then rushed up stairs and aroused the seven children and got them out of the burn - ing house. Daniel Rupp, caretaker, who lived in the barn with his wife and tlirt-r small children, had a narrow escap&gt; - with their lives. The lire started in the south end 01 the barn from some undetermined cause and worked its way through hay and other inflammable material in a remarkably short time. Th. building itself was of brick, but tht - interior was finished in wood, and in less than an hour the big structure was reduced to smoldering ruins. Fire Warden Morris has already commenced makng an investigation of the cause of the fire, which i - believed to be of an incendiarv nature Tecumseh Man is Hurt by Explosion Woman Who Set Fire To Her Clothing is Dead at Mason City, la. MASON CITY, la.. Feb. 22 — (Spe - cial Telegram.) — Clarence D. Riley of Tecumseh, Neb., driller for the Inter - mountain Bridge and Construction company, working on a big sanitary sewer here, probably was fatally hurt this morning when he drilled into an nexploded dynamite charge in a sewer trench. He will lose one and probably both eyes if he lives. A ■ orkman standing beside him wa? GRAND ISLAND. Neb., Aug. 31 — (Special Telegram. I -Mrs. Ida Ban gert. while undergoing intense suffer - ing at the general hospital, set fire to her clothing. She died as the result of the injuries. She leaves five grown children. Mr. and Mrs. Bangert moved here only recently and located on a small tract of land with the view of taking their remaining years more easily. No inquest will be held. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 STATE FIRB COMMISSION Miss Esther Maye NURSE IS BURNED Fatally Burned When PERHAPS FATALY Gasoline Can Explodes CATHERINE BARSTLER'S CLOTH ING FIRED WHEN 8HE LEANS E)RTH PLATTE, Neb., Dec. 1 — Esther Maye. a teacher at a try school near Maywood. died morning as a result of burns sus - ■d when a can of gasoline exploded in her hands. With her clothing in flames she rushed from the school and attempted to extinguish the blaze by rolling in the grass. She was terri - bly burned before help could reach her. AGAINST HOT PLATE Two other Employes at Hos pital Suffer Injuries Ex - tinguishing Flames. LINCOLN. Neb.— When she backed up too close to a hot gas plate that set her cotton uniform on lire Miss Catherine Barstler. 23 years old, a nurse at the Everett sanitarium, was burned, perhaps fatally, about 11 o'clock Sunday morning. Miss Maye. who taught at the High - land school at Maywood, attempted to start a fire in the stove at her school Monday by throwing gasoline into the stove from a can, when the gasoline came in contact with the flames, the can exploded throwing the burning oil over the body of the teacher. She was so badly burned that she suffered igonies for twenty-four hours. Parts of her body were burned to a crisp and nearly all the clothing was burned from her body. Two other nurses. Miss Aletha Nor - veil and Miss Lela Tallon. were burned about the hands and arms in rushing to the victim's assistance with towels and blankets to smother the flames. Miss Norvell also suffered from burns about the face. The flames were only extinguished after the whole of Miss Barstler's body from her shoetops to her waist had been seared. Her clothing was well afire before the accident, which oc - curred in the preparation room close by the operating quarters, was dis - covered. Dog Saved Lives Family Aroused by Barking Found House in Flames fremont. Neb.. April 20— a fox Girl Dies From terrier dog probably saved the lives of Mr. and Mrs. H. E. Gerecke and children, when his loud barkings at their bedroom door aroused them from slumber. Mr. Gerecke threw the door open to find the whole house in flames. Burns Received In Pot of Starch WEST POINT. Neb., July 9— Bessie. the 5-year-old daughter of Joseph Kase. business man of West Point, died Saturday morning from the ef - fects of a scalding. About ten days age she accidentally fell into a pan of hot starch which had been left on the floor and sustained such injuries that she could not rally. In their nightclothes. the family escaped through a window. A general alarm of fire was turned in and the whole Fremont department responded. The house, which is situated In a thickly populated residence district, was completely gutted and the loss is $2,000. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 ' Mother Braves Stockmen Barely Escape From Hotel When Blaze Starts Flames to Save Young Children GRAND ISLAND. Neb. Dec. 11.— (Special Telegram.) — Fire early today destroyed the Union Stock Yards hotel, two miles east of this city. So rapid was its headway that several of the stockmen asleep in their rooms escaped from their beds only scantily clad. One forgot a roll of $90. which he had placed under his pillow. A ■small blaze in the basement yesterday supposedly extinguished, is believed lo have started afresh. Mr. Whitmore, the manager, is in Chicago, and the exact loss is not known but it is esti - mated to be about $8,000 with insur - ance covering the greater part of the OMAHA, Neb— Mrs. Lillian Eu wards. 809V, South Eighteenth street, last night braved the flames caused by an explosion of a kerosene lamp in order to save her four young children from being burned. After she had thrown the blazing lamp out of doors and had extinguished the fire she found her arms painfully burned and her clothing scorched. The lamp was on a table in the din - ing room when it exploded, soon after the evening meal had been eaten by the family. Blazing oil was thrown on the carpet and flames sprang up in the midst of the little circle of children. "I didn't think I had the nerve to do it." said Mrs. Edwards, "but I knew I had to in order to save the children from burning to death. 9o I Just ra:i in and took the lamp and threw ii oui of doors. Then 1 put out the fire." The department responded from the city, but the yards' water system was partially frozen and the firemen could assist only in saving some of the fur- Mrs. Edwards' children are aged ii and 10 years. Gasoline Fire Cause Serious Injury to Young Woman Parents Risk Life To Save Six Kiddies FAIRBIRY. Neb.. Aug. 11.— Minnie Clary, fifteen years old. daughter of Mr. and Mrs. George Clary, residing on a farm six miles southeast of Fair - bury, was seriously, if not fatally burned, Thursday, by an explosion of a gasoline iron. She had placed the generator on a lighted jet of an oil stove preparatory to lighting the gaso - line heater to begin the family ironing. While bending over the iron to turn off the Jet the gasoline tank exploded, burning her frightfully about the face, arms and upper portion of her body. When her clothing caught fire she ran out In the yard where her mother rubbed out the fire with her hands. Mrs. Clary was badly burned about the hands and arms in putting out the From Death in Fire OMAHA, Neb. — Charles A. Johnson wife, and their six children, lost all their belongings and narrowly escapeil in a fire which destroyed the Johnson home. 855 Bryant street, at 4 o'clock this morning. The fire started in the kitchen and had sained considerable headway be - fore Johnson and his wife, asleep in an adjoining room, were awakened The house was filled with smoke They groped their way to the rooms occupied by the children and carried them to safety. The flames prevented them from attempting to save any per - sonal belongings of the family. Th ■ house, one-story frame, was destroyed </seg>
            <seg id="p013">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 13 : . i Tecumseh Family Girl Badly Burned Driven from Home By Gasoline Put Into Storm by Fire In Coal Oil Stove Omaha, Neb. — Gasoline sold for coal oil resulted Sunday morning in the painful, if not fatal burning of Miss Sena Peterson, domestic employed in the home of Lars P. Jensen, dairyman, 2208 South Forty-second street. I'Kc TMSEH. Neb.. Jan. 15— (Special.) The family of Thomas Pohlman, liv - ing nine miles east of Tecumseh, was driven out into the storm and with the thermometer at 20 degrees below ?.ero at 4:30 o'clock this morning when i he house they were occupying burned to the ground. Mrs. Pohlman and her '■ldest daughter. Nellie, had their feet quite badly frozen before they left the -cfne of the lire and sought shelter at the home of Mr. Pohlman's mother on an adjoining farm. The fire evi - dently originated from a defective flue, and the smoke awoke Mr. Pohl - man. He fought the flames with buckets of water and thought he had the fire under control, when it broke out anew in the wall, and the building, with most of the house hold effects and clothing of the family, was lost. The house was owned by Mrs. Sara Townsend. formerly of Tecumseh, but The girl arose early Sunday morn - ing to prepare breakfast and used the fluid in a coal oil cooking store, thinking the stuff to be coal oil. In the ensuing explosion she was terribly burned, but managed to reach the back yard and extinguish the flames which encircled her body by rolling in the snaw. The house was all but completely destroyed by the fire. Mr. Jensen, who has been very ill, managed to reach the front yard in safety before overcome by the weak - ness of his condition. His wife and four children also reached the outof doors iu safety. Police Surgeon J. A Tamislea at - tended Miss Petersen and ordered her removal to St. Joseph's hospital, where she is in a critical condition. The Jensen family is staying with neighbors. now of Los Angeles. Oal. It was two stor M and had eight rooms. It was insured for $800. Mr. Pohlman had MOO insuranec on his effects. The family is now quartered with Mr. I'ohlman's mother. Mrs. Peters of North Plate Dies of Burns Film Fume Fire Overcomes Hyman NORTH PLATTE. Neb., April *.— i Special.)— With her clothing on flre Mrs. .). W. Peters ran out of her horn yesterday calling for help. Neighbo ran to her assistance, but were unab to overtake her before she sank to tl ground. She died a short time late at the Good Samaritan hospital. Mrs Peters had started to prepare th evening meal for her family, and had attempted to touch a match to th gasoline stove burner. Gasoline ha leaked from the tank, causing it explode and throw oil over Mrs. Petei OMAHA. Neb— A pile of film scrap which caught fire in the World Film I'ompany's shop, 1508 Harney street last night, nearly caused the death of Harry Hyman. who was overcome |by the poisonous fumes arising from it. Only prompt action by Police Surgeon Barney K ully . who arrived with a pulmotor. saved him. He was taken home, after being revived, but is still in bad shape. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATK KIRK COM. MISSION rOVE EXPLOSION IS FATAL TO CHILD Child Burned as Dances at Bonfire Mother Is Injured rLE TOT BURNED TO CRISP WHEN GASOLINE STOVE OMAHA. Neb.— Viola Strong. 4 years of age, suffered painful burns Friday afternoon while playing around a bonfire at the rear of her home. 1122 North Twentieth street. The child is being attended at St Joseph's hoo - p'tal. The Strong girl was dancing around the fire when her clothes Ignited. EXPLODES Entire Family in Hospital 1 SOUTH OMAHA. Neb— Samuel ilizia. 20 months old, was burned to t crisp and his parents, his grand - her. and a roomer are in a serious Hurrying to the aid of her little girl. Mrs. Emma Strong fell downstairs and condition in the South Omaha hospital broke her right ankle. She was taken a* the result of a gasoline stove explo- 1 to the hospital with the child The sion at the Galizia home at 3:30 o'clock pirl's clothing was extinguished by yesterday afternoon at 2604 M street ; Mrs. L. Conkling. the landlady of the in a building controlled by L. C. Gib- j place where the StrongB live. Mrs. son. The loss to the building was about $4,000. Conkling wrapped a blanket about th. - child and smothered the blaze. Mrs. Oalizia had but recently re - turned from an Omaha hospital and was in bed. The father was frying steak on the gasoline stove and the baby was in a cradle beside the stove. The father went into the adjoining room to attend to some ow the wants of the mother when the stove evident ly flared up and exploded, instantly enveloping the cradle and the entire room in flames. Falls City Family Barely Escapes Fire FALLS CITY. Neb.. Nov. 28.—(Spe - cial Telegram.) — The family of Roy King at Shubert were awakened thi* morning at 5 o'clock by stifling smok&gt; all through their house, and had bare ly time to escape the burning building The father. Tony Galizia, the grand- .1. —-|in^n iK hr^thes U^e K ,or^ rph Paipavina fought in vain to h the child, even the mother ris - from her sick bed and joining in battle all to no avail. All these were more or less burned about the hands and face, while the mother is in &amp; serious condition from the effort. All are in the hospital. $2,500 and the insurance $2,000. Roy Higgins' house, adjoining, was dam aged to the extent of $50. Burns Are Fatal To 4- Year-Old Boy Mrs. Vozliarodo, who had been visit - ing the family, had Just taken her children with others to a moving pic - ture show and thus escaped injury from the flames. FREMONT. Neb., Dec. 29.— (Spe cial. ) — Walter, the 4-year-old son of Mr .and Mrs. Henry Kuss of Winslow. died yesterday of burns suffered De- Detective Michael Gillan noticed the flames and hastened to the rescue of j the family but too late to save the • ! of j cember 14. when he fell into a tub of the I scalding water at the home of hie parents </seg>
            <seg id="p015">STATK FIRE COMMISSION 15 Mrs. Huddle, Victim 1-year-old baby Marie, who escaped without a single burn. She was car - ried from the structure by Tereaco Cannelo. aged 16 yean, who lives up - stairs and was the flrst in the room after the fire occurred. of Burns, is Better LINCOLN, Neb— The condition of Mrs. Carrie Huddle, burned over her entire body in an explosion of turpen - tine at the hospital for the insane Monday night, is so much improved this afternoon. Superintendent B. W. Williams declares, that her chances Tor recovery are beginning to look en - couraging. Little Tots Lose Father and Mother Sammy, 5 Years Old, and Jacob, Aged 3, Children of Mr. and Mrs. Loui* Share, Who Were Burned to Death on the South Side Monday PUTS OIL ON FIRE, IS FATAALY BURNED SOUTH OMAHA. Neb.— Sorrow su rounds the little former home of M and Mrs. Louis Share. Twenty-sixt and N streets, where last evening th parents of the three children were burned to death. The two little sons Sammy, aged 5 years, and Jacob, age 3 years, are being kept at the tailorin shop in charge of Mrs. Kenney wh assisted in the rescue of the baby. Th baby is also being cared for by Mrs Kenney. MRS. MARIE PINNISI DIES AT ST. HOSPITAL AS RESULT OF BURNS FROM FLAMING LIQUID. Baby Rescued by Young Girl OMAHA, Neb.— Mrs. Marie Pinnisi, 'HVZ Pierce street, aged 28, died at St. Joseph hospital as the result of burns 'received Monday morning when she used kerosene to kindle a fire in the kitchen range. Heroically endeavoring to save her husband from a death by burning. Mrs. Louis Share. 4907 South Twenty - sixth street. South Side, was herself burned last evening at 5:30 o'clock. Her husband was burned beyond recognition. Dr. K. F. Shanahan at - tended the couple. ' Scarcely an inch of flesh on her body escaped terrible burns when the ,koro6ene flared and covered her cloth - -ing with burning oil. 1 She atiempted to escape from the "building to the back yard, but when Ihe back door opened several inches, 'and then caught, the draft nom the L &gt;p«ning whipped her burning cloth - ing into a torch of flame, and it waa In this condition she was found on the floor by neighbors who hurried to "ier aid. Firemen from Engine House No. 16, a block away, responded and Extinguished the fire before the struc - 1 ure, which houses five other families, Vas burned to any great extent. Burns Face and Hands Lighting Oil Burner OMAHA, Neb.— John Rosicky, Twen - tieth and Lake streets, was consider - ably burned about the hands and face while lighting the oil burner in his furnace. The furnace lire had gone out and stuffing some lighted paper into the furnace to ignite the oil, the flames from the paper started the gas In the house at the time and lying n a crib which was scorched by the lames from the mother's clothing, was V -• — — vuu |~|/bl ■&gt;*.•»! ICU U1V |BT the from the oil to burning and an ex - was plosion followed. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 STATE KIKK &lt;&lt;&gt;MMISSI»»N DEATH BY FIRE Firemen from the local fire &lt; • speedily put out the fire, but were un ibl" to save the body of tiie husband. FATB OF COUPLE 1 he three small children of the 'oup'.e were peacefully playing in the rear yard at the time of the explosion. An infant but six months old was res - cued from one of the inner upper rooms by Mrs. F. H. Kennedy, Pioneer block, just west of the pressing estab - lishment. She also took charge of the children. SHARE LOUIS, SOUTH SIDE TAIL- OR, BURNED TO DEATH AND WIFE CANNOT LIVE Explosion of Gasoline Air Kennedy attempted to restrain the mother from going to the aid of her husband, but was unsuccessful Tae body of the husband was found rigidly stretched full length before the couch against which it is sup I ooed that he had been thrown by the force of the explosion. The arms were outstretched in a semi-circle, and ii is supposed that be died with his wife clusped to him. Death occurred only i few minutes after the accident due to inhaling fire and fumes. IOUTH OMAHA. Neb.— Heroically eavoring to save her husband from eath by burning, Mrs. Share Louis, 7 South Twenty-sixth street, South e, was herself enveloped in liames I fatally burned last evening at 0 o'clock. Her husband was burned ond recognition while the wife is the South Omaha hospital await - momentary death. Dr. E. F. Shan - n attended the couple. The accident happened in the up - stairs over the tailor and pressing -hop operated by Louis at Twenty - ixth and N streets. South Side. Little Girl Burned According to the meager informa - tion at hand, the husband had gone upstairs with some clothes, just sat - urated with gasoline, to hang them up. The supposition is that he re - lined on a couch, and. lighting a cig - r, accidentally threw the stub of burning match among the clothes. A loud explosion occurred. The wife, who was downstairs, rushed up to aid her husband, hearing his cries. Starting Fire in Range With Coal Oil CMAHA. Neb.— Maude Richards, aged 10 years, daughter of Mr. and Mrs Will Richards. 502 Pierce street. was serevely burned when she used coal oil to start a fire in the range The flame flared up so suddenly that the little girl's dress caught fire and she was badly scorched about the limbs before her mother, who was sick in bed. could aid her. Mrs. Richards was also slightly burned. The two were attended by Dr. C. B. Folti and the little girl was taken to St. Jos - eph's hospital. tA moment later she appeared at e bannister around the back porch r entire torm enveloped in flames, le fell to the ground eighteen feet below. Jerry Riorden. a laborer Hy - ing in the rear of the two-story Mat in which the explosion occurred, rushed to her aid and succeeded in smothering the flames with two heavy blankets be - fore the police ambulance arrived. Mr. and Mrs. Richards have been separated for several months and, be - ing in straightened circumstances, the iittle girl was the only one who cared for her mother during her illness. Po - lice Matron Ellen Gibbons has taken charge of the case. Mrs. Louis was rushed to the South Omaha hospital, where Dr. E. F. Shan - ah;»n took charge. He pronounced her case hopeless after an investigation, nd said that death \\ as only a matter </seg>
            <seg id="p017">STATE KIBE COMMISSION- 17 FIREMAN MEETS probably die. His shoulder was brok - en and he suffered internal injuries. He was taken to the South Side hos mai. DEATH IN SOUTH SIDE ACCIDENT Eddie Simpson, a chauffeur, 4643 Xortn Thirty-ninth street, son of John Simpson, assistant fire chief, was the least injured of the three. He was .aken to his home. JOHN Q. ADAMS AND TWO OTHER MEMBERS OF "FIFTEEN" ARE CAUGHT UNDER MORRIS PLANT WALLS MRS. TANNER DIES FROM HER INJURIES Acting Captain Injured EXTENT OF THE LOSS SEVERELY BURNED LA8T THURS - DAY MORNING WHEN DRESS CATCHES FIRE Total loss, 1*275,000 to $300,000. Meat stored in plant valued at half million. Loas on meat, $175,000 to $200,000. Damage to buildings, »75,0O0 to Here Forty-Two Years $100,000. Cattle killing department resumed operations this morning, when 120 cattle were killed. CMAHA, Neb.— Mrs. J, M. Tanne a prominent Omaha woman and a re ident of this city for more than tw score years, died yesterday evening at the home, 3333 Pine street, as th result of burns suffered last Thursda morning, when her dress caught afire as she wa3 telephoning, with her bac to a gas stove, the oven door of whic was open. She was conscious yeste day forenoon, but her condition ra idly became worse and she died shor ly aftar 6 o'clock in the evening. Chief Salter says fire will be out to - day. Plant will resume hog killing in two weeks. Started killing sheep at noon. Loss to building and contents fully covered by insurance. Watched by crowd of 25,000 peo - ple, it being the most spectacular blaze in South Omaha in years. OMAHA, Neb. — John J. Adams, 4013 North Twenty-eighth avenue, a pipe - man :n No. IB hose company, was fat - ally injured, dying a few minutes after the accident, and two other firemen injured, one probably fatally, when the south wall of the Morris Packing company plant fell in on them at 2:05 o'clock yesterday afternoon. Gertrude Wilson Overcome by Smoke in Fire in Hotel OMAHA, Neb.— Fire broke out in the storeroom of the Keystone hotel, 1306 Douglas street, yesterday after noon. Gertrude Wilson, sick In bed occupied a room adjoining that where the fire started. Firemen carried her out and she was taken to the hospital apparently dead, but later was resusi - tated. The damage to the building was slight. It is not known how the Ire started. Adams and his fellow firemen were Juried under an avalanche of bricks md debris. The dead fireman suf - tered a crushed head and internal in - juries. He died at the South Side nospital fifteen minutes after the ac - ident. Jensen Seriously Injured James P. Jensen, 5349 North Thir - y-fifth street, acting captain, will </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 STATE KIKE COMMISSION Children Playing BABY LOSES LIFE IN SWEETWATER FIRE With Hatches Cause Many Local Fires CHILD OF MR. AND MRS. N. F JENSEN BURNED TO DEATH IN REAR OF STORE IMAHA. Neb— Chief Suiter's flf - ith annual report of the fire de - ment, being the twenty-ninth re - ; of the paid fire department, shows . during 1915 there were 1,131 ms of tire received and that the 1 loss to buildings and contents $335,600. Blaze From Oil Explosion RAVENNA, Neb.— (Special Tele - gram).—The village of Sweetwater. WMt of Ravenna, was visited by a dis - astrous fire this afternoon. Three buildings were destroyed and the baby of Mr. and Mrs. N. F. Jensen was Lurned to death. Eiiny-eigDt Bremen and twenty-six ens were injured, ten of the latter g from injuries at tires and one g killed by a fire truck. t'areiess use of matches caused 108 fires. Of the days of the week, Mon - day was the busiest day for the fire - men. Gasoline caused thirty-five fires and flues and chimneys caused 211 alarms. The Jensen family occupied living rooms in the rear of a building used for a pool hill and confectionery store. The fire started by the explosion ol an oil stove and flames spread so rap - idly it was impossible to rescue the baby, which was sleeping in its cab A harness store adjoining was com - pletely destroyed with its contents, being the property of the John Olson estate. Chief Salter recommends to the mayor and city council the purchase of 10,000 to 14,000 feet of new hose, standardized motor apparatus and uniform five-men hose companies throughout the system. Ering the year 816 alarms were in over the telephone. The i of Trade building was the most us fire of the year. Little Girl Burned to Death Near Tecumseh A modern fire alarm system is urged liy the chief. The report shows there are 285 men in the twenty-one fire hou«e«. TECUMSEH. Neb.. Dec. 20. (Spe rial i— Little Laura Mae Whistler, the 3-year-old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Riley Whistler, suffered fatal burnt Saturday. The family home is on a farm a half mile from Mayberry. in Pawnee county. Mr. Whistler had gone to his work and Mrs. Whistler stepped out of doors for a pail ot water, neing absent from the house but a few minutes. The little girl went up to the cook stove with a news - paper in her hands. The newspaper became ignited, set fire to the child's clothing, and all the clothing was burned off and the flesh was burned to a crisp in places. The child lived until 7 o'clock in the evening, being conscious most of the time. 2 Burned in Garage When Gasoline Fumes Explode tMAHA. Neb.— Patrick J. Ryan, y, a plumber, of No. 368 Bronx k avenue, and Charles W. Faulk - twenty-three, a chauffeur, of No. Morris street, New Rochelle, are erinc from painful burns today as isult of a fire in the garage of John inedy, No. 155 Bast Thirty-fifth et, due to an explosion of gasoline es in a five-foot pit In which the </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 STATE KIKE COMMISSION BOYS' DORMITORY AT FREMONT BURNS Aged Woman Burned to Death at North Platte FIFTY STUDENTS DRIVEN INTO NORTH PLATTE, Neb., Dec. 11.— (Special Telegram). — Mrs. Mary Jan Applegate, 81 years old, died at th home or her daughter, Mrs. Chris Paulson, here, from burns sustainet when gasoline with which she was kindling a fire exploded. She mis too the gasoline for kerosene. Members of the Paulson family heard he screams and, rushing to the room, su eeded in smothering the flames, tha enveloped her. but not until the age woman had been fatally burned. SIX BELOW ZERO TEMPERA- TURE IN NIGHT CLOTHES One Boy is Slightly Injured FREMONT, Neb.. Feb. 1— Fire which broke out in the boys' dormi - tory of Fremont college shortly after midnight last night, destroyed the west wing of the building, causing a damage of 115,000. There is partial insurance. Several students who jumped from the second story windows in their night clothes were bruised and cut, and a number suffered frosted ears and toes. The temperature was Two Children Burned To Death Near Lyons ■i degrees below sero. Fifty students were in the building when the Ore broke out. LYONS, Neb., Nov. 17 .— (Special.)— Two children of Mr. and Mrs. Leo Evans were burned to death today o the reservation north of here. Th oldest child was about five years ol The mother had gone to a neighbor* for some milk and when she returned the house was burned to the groun There was a gasolene stove and nea it was a heating stove, and it thought that the Ore was started : some manner from these stoves. Firemen prevented a spread of the (tames to the girls' dormitory, where seventy-five girls room. They escaped to residences without any serious re - sults. The origin of the fire is a mys - tery. It is thought to have started from defective electric wires. Ten years ago ihe college building was de - stroy ea by fire. The fire cut off the stairway exit and nearly half the boys were com - pelled to jump from the second story windows. None was injured, except Eddie Echtencamp, whose feet were burned in an attempt to descend by the flanvng stairway. Woman Saved Her Children NORFOLK, Neb., March 31.— The farm home of Ovando Cowles, about three miles from Battle Creek, was burned to the ground while Mrs. Cowles, who is ill, was at home alone with her three children, one of them a baby two months- old. Five Year Old Tot Is Fatally Burned OMAHA. Neb.— Charlotte Alberta Cutler. 5-year-old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Stuart A. Cutler, 529 South Thir - ty-first street, died yesterday at St. Catherine's hospital as the result of burns received Tuesday afternoon when her clothing was set afire by her 3-year-oM brother, Edward. Mrs. Cowles had been lying down. On going into the kitchen she found it in Dames. She grabbed the baby and carried It outdoors and then went back and saved their other two chil - dren. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 STATE KIRE COMMISSION CHILDREN HAVE control. Five carriages aud a ueai&gt; were lost in the blaze. NARROW ESCAPL The loss, estimated at $10 partly covered by insurance. ASLEEP WHILE LIVERY STABLE BURNS — THEY ARE RESCUED BENSON WOMAN IS BURNED TO DSATH DOWN LADDER THROUGH WINDOW MRS. I. N. JONES BUILDS FIRE IN CHICKEN BROODER HOUSE AND BURNS HERSELF TO DEATH Foity Horses Are Saved OMAHA, Neb. — Cut off from the &gt;tairway and other exits by dense smoke, four little children, two ot (bem babies, were taken down a lad - der from the second floor of a burning livery stable early yesterday morning. Alter Attack of Dementia OMAHA, N.-b.— Mrs. 1. N. Jone; years of age, residing on a five - tract at Fifty-ninth and Fowler Elie family of Burt Fox, living over Fox livery and boarding stables, 1-18 CumiiiK street, was asleep n the tire, of unknown origin, was overed. Hie.l yesterday, follow attack of dementia, during win. burned herself in a chicken In house. While her husband was ing in a field she gathered up straw and went into the broodtr where she started a fire. Net) rushed to the woman s rescu&lt; Ethe confusion that followed the tots were trapped in the burning lure. From the street it was im - ble to even see the windows of second floor of the building igh the pall of suffocating ,-moke summoned the husband. Or. J. maun of Benson and a nur i ailed, but the burns were to&lt; Babies Caught in Trap i. W. Johnson, who lived in rooms Dining those occupied by the Fox lily, was one of the lirst to think the fire-trapped babies. He made eral heroic attempt to reach the ond floor by way of the stairway, was driven back each time. He led for a ladder and rescued the Idren by crawling into the smoke - id room and handing them down 1 by one to the crowd below. to save the victim's li Mother Nursing Child, 111 of Scarlet Fever, Burned in Explosion IMAHA. Neb.— Misfortun i;cil the home o; Elliott E. Thomps a second time. Three weeks ago t 10-year-old daughter. Alice, was stric Horses Saved vit. and Erty horses that were in the sta - when the blaze started, were led &gt;y employes and firemen, but not rat some difficulty. One sick ani - was rescued from a burning stall e rear of the bam by a fireman. Last night Mrs. Thompson was burnei about her face, arms and hands, wliei a oal oil burner exploded. They li.i at 1809 Corby street She was filling the burner to u?. in heating a separate room, where litile Alice w*« f-onfii ■&gt;&lt;!. The explosion set her clothing on fire, and ignited ihe interior of the kitchen. f"he fire, starting at 2:30 o'clock this rning. destroyed the entire rear end the stable before it was got under </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 STATE KIKE • o.\l MISSION • WILLIAM SHIELDS DIES FROM BURNS Mrs. Hiatt's Funeral Sunday SOUTH OMAHA. Neb— The funeral of Mrs. L. A. Hiatt, wife of the auto - mobile man, who was burned to death, following a coal oil explosion at her home, 2205 J street, Wednesday even - ing at 5 o'clock, will be held Sunday afternoon. The services will be held at St. Luke's church. Twenty-fourth and Vinton streets. Rev. Schafer offi - ■iating. Interment will be made in Grareland Park cemetery. PIONEER OMAHAN SUCCUMBS TO BURNS WHEN BED CLOTHES ARE IGNITED BY SPARKS FROM A PIPE Was Seventy Years of Age OMAHA. Neb.— William H. Shields, who suffered severe burns last 1 hurs - ilay when sparks; from a pipe he was smoking ignited the bed clothes of the l&gt;ed in which he was contined owing to paralysis, died at 12:45 noon Tues- May at his home at 2124 Binney street. Mr. Shields was stricken with a stroke of paralysis about two months ago. He had been confined to his bed ■•\»r since. Thursday he was smok - ing his pipe when a spark fell from the bowl and set the bed clothes in flames. He was powerless to put out the fire, and before the blaze was ex - tinguished by members of the family had been badly burned It was thought at first the burns would not prove serious, but unexpect - ed complications developed and he succumbed today. Mr. Shields was 70 years of age. He was a retired railroad conductor and had been a resident of Omaha since He was born in Indiana. Pa. He served in the civil war and was prom - inent in Grand Army of the Republic :iii(l Douglass county pioneer circles. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 STATE FIRE COMMISSION ADDRESS OF W. S. KIDGEI.I. AT THK Annual Convention or the State Vomnteek Firemen's Ashociation The worth and efficiency of this Department is steadih growing from year to year and as the officials wfcaw duty it is to co-operate with us are becoming acquainted with the law and its value to the state, its effect is being seen. The firemen of the state whose business is the pre vention and extinguishing of fires are heartily interested in giving us even assistance possible and this Depart ment and the state generally has much to thank them for. During the past year the tire chiefs throughout the state have reported to us promptly and completely each fire occurring in their localities, and whenever we have asked for particular information concerning investigation:* they have most willingly complied with out request. We desire to extend our sincere thanks to every tire chief throughout the state for their assistance and interest in this department and in the worthy cause of fire pre vention. The fireman's duty does not ltegin when the call of fire is made. That is the beginning of the end; his duty begins in prevention : in preventing a fire from occurring. This necessitates constant vigilance on his part; it necessitates his being watchful and firm in making citizens clean up their premises and remove all needless, dangerous fire hazards. Special Depi ties Where a city or village has a local ordinance giving the fire chief the authority to coinjM'1 citizens to reuiov* dangers, repair defective chimneys, store explosives safe Crawford, Nebraska, Jamary 18, 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">STATE KIRE COMMISSION 23 ly, etc., etc., this Commission of oil re gives him State authority as well. We now have over 700 special depu - ties commiss : oned with authority from the State to en - force the Fire Commission Law. These special depu - ties receive no compensation and serve for the good of their particular community. Firemen know fire hazards ant] recognize them quicker than the average layman. It is his Imsincss to not only extinguish the fire, but to as - certain the cause of fire. Then if the local fireman ac - quaints himself with buildings and homes within his ter - ritory in case of fire he knows better how to fight it be - cause he is familiar with the construction of the prem - ises. We have constantly requested and agitated this inspection work by firemen during the past year. In the large cities like Omaha, South Omaha/ Lincoln, Grand Island, Hastings, Nebraska City, York, Fremont. Norfolk, Fairbury, Kearney, Columbus, etc., men from each engine house should be designated to inspect prop - erty in the neighborhood where they might be called upon to fight tire. This would not only prove of great value in reducing the fire waste and educating property own - ers along fire prevention lines, but would be of great "help to the firemen themselves in case of fire. In cities like Omaha, South Omaha, Lincoln and Grand Island, this work of inspection should be carried on by the fire men with no additional expense for their work. It should appeal to the men as a most progressive move - ment ; it will not interfere with any of their duties and will really be a divergence from their ordinary routine, which will be beneficial to themselves as well as to their community. In towns that have volunteer fire departments, the village board should employ a couple of men (prefer - ably volunteer firemen) and pay them about |3.00 per day for two or three days each spring and fall to inspect the town. This nominal expense would be of immense value to the town and would interest the citizens gen - erally in cleaning nj&gt; their premises and freeing them from fin- hazards. Buildings found in good, safe condi- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 STATK KIKE COMMISSION tiHHHl not ba re-inspected for some months, while found in a tafMH state should lx&gt; followed up the dangerous conditions are remedied. Proper and sufficient ire fighting apparatus should In - provided to assist the firemen in their work. Soldiers must have weapons with which to IgM their enemies. We would advise cities and towns that can afford it, to purchase combination chemical and hose wagons for when chemicals can extinguish a fire without the use of water the usual enormous water damage will t&gt;e eliminated. The hand fire extinguisher is a jireat factor in the fire prevent ; on cause, and every business house and store in the State should install one or more, according to the size of the establishment and every home should b" provided with one and the memlters of the family taught how to use it in case of fire. The small e\ tinpuisher will put out a fire in its iiuipiencv and i&lt; ow of the most important appliances in the Safety First. Fin I'receiition movement. The promptness of fire chiefs in reporting tires to this office as* : sts us in our work of investigating and their interest in attending to many matters which we request has done much to make this department a success. While the Fire Commission Law provides a penalty if fire chiefs, or mayors, where the town has no Ire depart ment, do not report promptly to this department every fire occurring in their city or village, yet in many cases these officials are not reporting tires to this office as the law provides. Durinir the coining; year we are ROiag to insist upon mavors and fire chiefs complying with the law. If we could organize a Fire Prevention Society in every town in the state, have the property owners become members, induce the commercial clubs, and woman's clul&gt;s of the town to heroine interested, have the mayors and village clerks set aside a day at least twice a veai Fibe Prevention Bocirrm </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 TATE KIBE COMMISSION A ii I I t •mtv Spring anil Fiill i as a "clean-up" ilay, when every Ham would 1«- reqatntod to dean np his premises and ;ikc them free from Ire dangers, we would have accom- shed intit'li along |k prevention lines. Rubbish, oily pi, excelsior, etc.. breed tire. Old dilapidated build gi are ■ ineiiiice. and carelessly handled gasoline and ill nil is a constant danger. Bonfires and fireworks lim their amount of toll in human lives every year. I. oral tire prevention societies could look into the iminatiuu of these dangers and interest their com - unity in reducing tire losses. We wish we could have iese societies organized generally throughout the State. Statistics prove that 75 per cent of the enormous tire ;i&gt;ie of this country in directly due to carelessness and ignorance. Wf are living at a time in the history of oar nation when the question of the preservation of resources, natural and created, is receiving a great deal of attention. Die preservation of any kind of property from any kind waste should receive the utmost consideration from general public One of our most vital problems, and tie which is calling for rapid solution is the problem of nr enormous, unnecessary and avoidable fires. Two imdred and fifty million dollars of constructed property initially destroyed by tire is a direct reproach upon our ivil governments and u|&gt;on the people. Two-thirds of lie |!2.(HMi.(i(Mt annual tire loss in Nebraska is due to care - ■^siifss. and is an absolute waste and drain upon our i sources. It is depleting the wealth of our state. Wi - re burning down almost as fast as we are building up. No state or nation can long endure this absolute waste ;ind drain without feeling the effects in a most nnfavor - nltle wav. Tin- Mayors of every city and village in the state liould issue local proclamations asking their citizens) to o-o|MM-ate in cleaning up and removing all fire dangers. I'hi- i -it v or village should furnish men and teams free if chars* to haul awav all waste and rubbish. Ml Fire chiefs should make a special inspection of heir territory and coiujm*! the change of any conditions </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 STATK KIRK COMMISSION which would tend to eliminate the possibility &lt;&gt;f a tire Every Commercial Club in the slate should have a Fir* Prevention CtMWittee. The committee sliould send mil a call Mkiag all citizens to co-opeiate in maki 11^. Kin Day a real Clean Up I&gt;a.v. Women's Clubs should take an interest in the l&gt;av and ask every member to look into their home conditions with a view of abolishing every pooaiMe tire danger. Heating apparatus, electric wiring and chimneys shou Ik- carefully gone over and placed in proper conditi&lt; for winter use. Public and private institutions, stores, factories. garage* and iill business houses sliould lie inspected and an\ changes made that will further protect the premise* from fire. The pulilic |iress can lie a powerful factor in the inovt inent of Fire Prevention. Hv instructive ami timelv pul lications they can interest the public as no other facto can. FIRE CHIEFS To REPORT FliiKS office assists us in our work of investigation and then interest in attending to many matters which we ropiest has done much to make this depart nient a success While the Fire Commission Law provide* a penalty ii tire chiefs, or mayors, where the town has no tire depart inent. do not report promptly to this department everx fire occurring in their city or village, yet in mam case - these officials are not reporting tires to this office at the law provides. I Mirinjr the rnnting year ire are Kotef to insist upon mayors and fire chiefs eomplyinjj with tin law which is as follows: "Sec. Wll, Chapter XVII, Cobber'n Annotated statute? of Xebr. l!&gt;09. (Fires. Investigations, Records, i Tin State Fire Commissioner and the chief of the fire depart ineut of every city or village in which a h're department i&gt; established, and the mayor of every incorporated village 01 Tin' ])i-&lt;&gt;]itn«'ss of ire chiefs in reporting I </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE KIKE COMMISSION 27 t&lt; ;\\ n in which ii«» fire department exists, shall investigate, i lie CMMt, origin and circumstances of every Hit occurring in such city or Tillage, and the sheriff of each county when !iM|iiesleil liv the property owner or anyone inter - ested tin-rein shall investigate the cause, origin and cir iiiinstaiici s (if every tire occurring in his county with - out the limits of any organized city or village therein, by which property has lx*en destroyed or damaged and shall especially make investigation as to whether such lire was the result of carelessness or design. Such in - vestigation shall l&gt;e l&gt;egun within two days, not includ ing Sunday after (lie occurrence of such fire, and the (ire commissioner or his deputy shall have the right to sii|k rvise and direct such invest igation whenever he deems it expedient or necessary. The officer making investigation of fires occurring in cities, villages, towns or counties shall forthwith notify said Fire Commissioner, and shall within one week of the occurrence of the fire, furnish to the said fire commissioner •■ written statement of all the facts relating to the said fire and cause and niiiiii of said fire and such other information as may 1m - ailed for l&gt;y the lilanks provided by said Fire Commis- sioner. The state fire commissioner shall keep in his office a record of all tires which may be determined by ilie invest igsit ions provided hv this act: such record shall ill rimes lie upeu to the public inspection ■■i (tfli&lt;&lt; rx. Misfi iisiiiki ■.) Any officer referred to in Section Two herein, who neglects to comply with any of i he rtH|iiirements of this act shall he punished by a fine of not less tluin Twenty-five Hollars, nor more than Two Hundred hollars." </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 KTATI FIRE COMMISSION \ PROCLAMATION HY THK GOVERNOR State Fiuk I'kbvextiox Day — Fkidav. Xovbmbu •!. l!»li It is much more economical to keep a In out than t&lt; put it out after it lias am started. Fire must alwayi have soim-rliiiiy to feed upon iiml the BMMC intiaminaltlt the material upon which it feeds, tin* more daagerow ii heroines. Tlit* fire &lt; 'omniissionei- has issued his anim;i call to the people and lias sounded the alarm. The tlis|Mi sition of people ill regard to this matter is like it is ii many others, patting off until tomorrow the things thai should l&gt;e done today. We have l&gt;eeii prompting th&lt; people to he careful to remove heaps and piles of ruhhisl that have ban aci-uiiiulatiii}; rioting the summer months It would he more rational and sensible to prevent tin accumulation. (Mir public officials are many times i inally negligent in the duty they owe the ronimunit the matter of tire prevention. A pile of iiiHamn rubbish is a greater menace to life and property are thieves and pick pockets, that they are not bsrnoriBg enemies of the public welfar* Kvervone should i ■itller of these wl Therefore, as Governor «&gt;f the State. I wish to iatprex the necessity of paving strict attention to what has bet - set forth iii the statement of the State Fire ('omniissionei and ask the hearty co-operation on t lie part of ofticia! and ]&gt;eople in even city, town and hamlet in the Stat&lt; And that the teachers of our public schools iki all the he can to instruct the youth in matters herein referrei and thereby create a stronger sentiment in regard preventinji destructive ftrca. Given under mv hand and se;il of the State thN il !&gt;th dav of Octoher. 191(1. •Ioh.v II. Morkhrah. &lt;',&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 STATE FIRE COMMISSION FIKK PREVKXTIOX 1&gt;AY Lincoln. Nebraska. Office of State Fire Commissioner. October, 191(1. The Xebraska Legislature of 1911 enacted a law desig - nating the first Friday of Xovemlter as State Fire Preven - tion Day. The purpose of this law is to interest the i-itizeiiK of the State in the matter of conserving life and property from destruction by fire. The United States loses 1250,000.000 annually and Xebraska suffers a loss of about $2,000,000 every year from fire. Fully two-thirds of this amount is a needless unnecessary waste of constructed resources, and could !*• saved if our ]&gt;eo}&gt;le were educated up to the importance of the matter of preventing fires. Our citizenship generally takes little or no interest in the ways and means of preventing tires. When a building is destroyed by fire it is looked ujmn as an unavoidable misfortune, but in many cases it is avoidable. A little care and precaution might have prevented it. Every day we read in the newgpapers of disastrous tires being caused by children with matches, bonfires, defective chimneys, overheated stoves, etc. After investigation in many cases the Fire Commission department finds that ■'gross carelessness'' is the direct cause of a great num - l&gt;er of fires. The average layman does not stop to realize that every fire loss is a direct irrecoverable loss to the com - munity. Insurance does not replace the damaged prop - erty ; it merely collects from the policyholders collectively to pav or indemnify the individual having a fire. The losses from fire constitute an absolute waste and are a drain upon the wealth of our nation. Civic pride should prompt our people to interest themselves in reducing fire losses to a minimum. It was with the above purpose in mind that our State Legislature created the office of State Fire Commissioner and set aside a day each vear </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 KTATK FIUK COMMISSION lint*s. While we observe the Fourth of July each year a* i national holiday in commemoration of our Nation* Independence wt practice even day of the fear acts oi loyalty and patriotism for our country, so wliilr the first Friday of Wowaiber is set aside for special observant- of tire prevention principles we should practice ami studv tire prevention methods every day during the entire year We trust that the interest and enthusiasm manifested in the observance of Fire Prevention Day on \oveml&gt;ei tod, will keep each community alert in reducing tilt losses during the coming year. Mayors should issue proclamations askinjj the citi/.e of their cities to take an active interest in cleaning iij their premises; have them take away all old mhltisl tnd inflammable material; look after their stoves an furnaces and stovepipes anil chimneys and see that tli are safe for winter use. Klectric wiring should 1k&gt; in spected and all defects corrected as many tires oceai Proa defective wiring. The citv should hire men ai teams this da\ and have them HO around and 1 ruhbish from business houses and homes, free of eh This would not cost the citv or village much and won make it an incentive for the citizen* t yards, attics and cellars. RT&lt;a&lt; ilfal in assisting this pood work. They couh name delegations Prom amoiii: their nmnbfni to visi dififerent districts and work up an active campaign fo lire prevention. The tire chiefs throughout the state are the men wh really know ami understand the importance of ihis work They have incidents every day of the flagrant careles ness of our people regarding tire dangers. The fire chiet should appoint as many men as possible to make an inspection of his city and order premises cleaned ii| wherever necessary. If any citizen refuses to eomph with the orders given locally, notify this office and «&lt; will send one of our inspectors to enforce the law to Ik- observed in ■ spi ii;il nuniier alonj; Ire prevention Commercial «']ul&gt;s und Women** &lt;*lul </seg>
            <seg id="p031">STATK KIKE COMMISSION 31 urs iii ii!l our public, private and parochial schools ■«hoiild make November :{nl, u most interesting and in - structive day to all school ( -liililren. lively teacher in I lie ntstc is provided with a school lKM)k "Lessons on Fire Prevention" :nid tram this lniok they c;in arrange pro- grains that will make this vital ■abject entertaining as W»ll as iiisfnu t vc. Fire drills, essays on the CMHH of fire ami how to prevent them; statistics on the tremen - dous tire waste of our state and nation; the hardships suffered tlieivfr. m. etc., are all outlined in the Fire I'nveiition Text Hoiik, and we trust that all teachers in i lie state are doiag their duty as required by law iu liinj; this worthy subject. Let us all organize in a Preparedness Campaign against Kt'd Plague (if tlie Fire Fiend. Last year 1,:US tires were reported to us from different ■ ities and towns in the state with a loss of f 1,908,297.41;. The reduction of our enormous fire loss can be accom - plished by pdaratiag the citizenship of our state alonj; Fire Prevention lines. Nelnaska has the distinctujn of having in her sch(»ols the first complete and comprehensive text I took ever published on this subject. The Ixtok was written and copyrighted by Miss .Mamie Mnldoon. Secretary of this Kepartnieiit, who spent over two years compiling it. As Miss Muldoitii has Keen Secretary of this Department since its organization and has for several years been intensted iii tire prevention work she was most ably &lt;{ii:i MtiiMl to write a Itook of this kind. The book is graded into lessons ranging from the kindergarten through the 1 1 itrli School. It covers every phase of i he subject of fire prevention, contains valuable statis tics m&lt;l an claltorate treatise on fire insurance, rate making, etc. Several othei states in the union reeojjniz - illg the merits of the book, are now making arrangements ri:.\&lt; |||\&lt;; PIRK PREVENTION IN OIK SCHOOLS </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 STATK FIBE COMMISSION to adopt it ;is they recognize its worth jiihI art* anxious to liave a standard, uniform text liook on the wibject to Ik« universally used in schools. One of the leading tire prevention magazines of the I'nited States, and the official paper of the Fire Marshals" association of North America, commenting upon this lw»ok says : "Miss Mamie Miildoon, Secretary of the Nehraska State Fire Commission, has compiled and issued a school l&gt;ook entitled, 'Lessons on Fire Prevention,' for the instruction of children. It is an elaliorate volume, and contains ;i series of lessons on fire prevention and on the effects of fire carelessness for all grades, lieginning with simple stories and rhymeu for the kindergarten and running through such statistical and analytical presentations of the subject as an - appropriate for the last years of high school. The lessons are not long, but they are comprehensive and admirably adapted to the needs of the respective grades. If intelli gently and carefully taught they should prove an effective agency in educating the children of the state to tlie need of fire prevention and to inculcate in them liahits of carefulness ''In effect, this book marks tin- hefrinaing of ;i tire |irevention literature, of which there may Ite said to lie practically none. And one is badly needed The Xational Fin* Protection Association empliasi/.ed thai fact when it issued its program for the observance of Fire Prevention I&gt;ay. a couple of mouths ago. Too much dependence should not lie laid on educating children along this line, because the real work to In* done can lie accomplished only by appealing to the mature judg - ment and common sence of intelligent men and women, or hy compelling them to lie fire-careful where they will not of their own volition ; but as an adjunct to this broader work it has a distinct field of usefulness and should not lie neglected. The book in question may be regarded as a fine start in the development of a fire prevention literature, without which no appreciable degree of success could he hoped for this form of educational work, and Nebraska is to </seg>
            <seg id="p033">STATE KIKE COMMISSION 33 «• congratulated thai aa employee of its Fire Commission ias been able to make so auspicious a beginning in this SpCct Ti.uMiii. the youth of the country habits of care and aution regarding Ire dang« rs must certainly result in mlimited n&lt;«n\ to the nation. Heretofore children of ntry have not been taagfct the value of a match ■or liavc they been told of its destructive fmmm. In Earopeaa mutrin children are not allowed to play with m.itclus and us them as "inexpensive toys." The igner does not throw matches carelesslv about heraoar they are ( -heap. From childhood he hat* l»een taught habits of economy. Not only will the teaching &lt;&gt;f tire jneveiition result in reduciiiir that part of the fire waste of the country due to children's carelessness and i ieji licence, hut tlie rafld will carry home to his parents accounts of the lessons he has been taught and the parents in this manner will have called to their attention illllgrniM habits and conditions which they have never noticed before ami which they will willingly correct. The child, when he leaves school, will have instilled into his mimi priaciplca and advice concerning fire dangers and ham to avoid them that must ultimately tell the value of this branch of education in reduced fire losses in the state. We teach and preach conservation of our natural resources, our forests, our waterways, minerals. etc.. and it certainly must appeal to every intelligent! alert, progressive individual that our ' constructive resources should Ik preserved and a decided reduction made in our nation's annual fire waste of 1250,000,000.00. Insurance is only a distributor of this loss collecting from many policy holders the amount sufficient to indem - nify the policy holders having a tire. We all contribute our share to this ash heap of |25&lt;UH&gt;0,000.00. The insur .nice companies distribute our contributions; the prop erty and material destroyed by tire is absolutely and irre - vocablv lost. We trust oui educational efforts will result in a lecided decrease in the fir,, losses of Nebraska, which </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 STATR KIRK COMMISSION amount to about two million dollars annually. Tin animal fire losses of Nebraska as reported to this oH&lt;r since its organization are as follows: ltlt U.181,058.00 Over thirteen million dollars consumed l&gt;v tire ami relegated to ashes in a short parted! of six years, and the actual losses would probably reach fifteen million dollar*, hecanse undoubtedly, a lame Maker of fires are not reported In this department. This is surely an appalling situation and should make every citizen feel the necessity of curtailing this terrific drain ipM the wealth and l»roam* of our state. SCSlMclors AND INCENDIARY FIRES IXYKSTWATEh A fire occurred in (iothenburg on July 25th. which called for immediate investigation from f hi&gt; I&gt;epartment Mrs. Mareka Hosemlahl was under suspicion and was adjudged insane and committed to the Insane Asylum at Hastings, Nebr. In Beatrice on August 17th. a barn and garage was set on fire by Geo. Rooth and Many T— ag. At the prelimiiiary hearing &lt;Jeo. Poath pleaded guilty and was Ik&gt;uii&lt;1 over to the District Court under *."&gt;00.00 hoiul. Harry Young pleaded "not guilty" and he was also hound over to the District Court; the trial will Im- held in •lanuary. 1917. A fire at Wayne last .Fanuaiy and one at Dannebrog last MiM-ch were beyond all doulil of incendiary origin lint we were unable to secure siitliHcnt e\iden&lt;-e upon which to file a complaint. 1911 1,788,123.30 1912 2,2"&gt;1 .774,3:? Ifl3 1.71.V576.1O 1914 l,S7:?.071.2.") 191.", 1.789.269.00 191(5 1,!MS,297.4&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p035">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 35 At Pilfer. Nebraska, a millinery stock insured for •1700 burned under very suspicions circumstance* hot we i-ould not obtain evidence upon which to connect anyone with the crime. An incendiary fire occurred in Fremont on February 16th in a small building owned by Mrs. Hollenbeek, widow of the late Chief Justice, and occupied as a barber shop by John Pawlyszyn, a (xalacian. From correspon - dents found in this man's personal effects it appears that his father and mother were among the war sufferers over in Galacia and he and a brother in Omaha wen trying to raise money to send to their parents. Tin - value of his stock was about one-half the amount of insurance carried and the apparent motive was to collect this insurant e to send money to his starving parents in (ialacia. Taking these facts into consideration the court gave him a jail sentence. A very nnfortunte fire occurred on Septeml&gt;er four - teenth in Tekamah at the old home of the late Congress man Latta. The building was undergoing some repairs and Mrs. Latta was staying with one of her sons while t lie work was l&gt;eing done. However, two young men were staying in the house and were asleep on an unstairs sleeping porch at the time of the fire. One of these young men was overcome by smoke, from the effects of which he died. On August 21st and 22nd a fire occurred at the home of Lawrence Schwartz and wife at Hartington, the barn liurniuu on the night of the 21st and the house on the night of the 22nd. From the evidence obtained it appears i hat these fires were the result of family quarrels. The property was in the name of Mrs. Schwartz. Schwartz is charged with burning the barn and one Hoy McGregor with burning the house, apparently under the direction of Mrs. Schwartz. These parties are awaiting trial in the .lanuarv term of court. In Duwter of 1915 Alfio I'isci of Omaha had a flash tire in his residence. The evening before the fire the chief of detectives told the fire &lt;hief there that this fir was dati I </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 STATE FIRK COMMISSION to occur that nijilit ami it m |tullcil off on wheduW time. The fore part of this year Altio obtains] insurance on household &lt;;oods at :!44I) South 1."»th St. under the name of Alfio Firchi ami on Ortoker tin- 24th he had another fire. From the Ik's! evidence obtainable tin - value of his household poods was about s."&gt;lllt.(Hi. on which he olttained $1400.00 insurance. No airent or representa tive of any company ever saw this furniture and thc\ wrote it with do knowledge whatever of its value. In l&gt;oth of these tires this man and his wife were away from home and had l&gt;een for sonic time liefore the tire. Ttwi are Italians and claim they cannot understand nor speak Km;lisli and all the evidence must he taken througl an interpreter, which makes it very difficult. OVER INSTRANri: CAUKE OF iXCEXDIAR^ FIRES, Our experience in the investigation of tires lias provei beyond a doulit that over insurance is the predomiuan cause of arson. Fully !»(( per cent of the indemiarv |m are set for the purpose of collecting the insurance mone\ It is very easy for anxone to olitain insurance on house hold goods or st&lt;nks of merchandise in excess «f thei real value. We have had cases that have come to oui department for investigation where dishonest person have olitaitied *:_',. "i(M) insurance mi actually wort! but floO.OO. One can readily see the incentivi- for arsot in I case of this kind. When an insurance atrenl write; t writes a polfcv for a man with a written assurance that in case of tire his company will pay in s|m&gt;i cash f2TiO0 for floods that, are not worth more than -"&lt;l."i&lt;l there is ever\ reason to hcHetc that the stock will l&gt;e lnirned up hefore the insurance expire*. So easy is it to olitain insurance for three, four or even ei»ht or ten times what the insureil property is worth that in several large cities &lt;ranp&lt; of crooks have organized themselves into what are called ''arson trusts" who make it a. business to gu into a town, rent a house, furnish it with a table ami chair and </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 STATE KIRK COMMISSION pMCCHi t«&gt; obtain "insurance" on it. It has proven a most remunerative business to them, they plan their work so well they have all the time for deliberation and operation that they require, they can chose the most convenient time in which to set the fire, and they use the utmost (are to burn every trace of the origin of the fire with the tire itself so that it is almost impossible for police officials, detectives or state officials to find anything but circumstantial evidence against them. Hence very few arson criminals ever pay the penalty of their crimes; in fact they nearly always attain their purpose and collect their insurance. It seems the only way to abolish the rime of arson is to prevent over insurance; then there ,vill Ik- no incentive for it as few cases are committed hroiigh spite or revenge. We know Insurance Companies mil want to write risks for more than they are worth; t is the local agent who is at fault and how best to deal .vitli him is a problem yet unsolved. We know it is a lardship to ask that even- risk l&gt;e personally inspected: lie commissions paid the local agent do not warrant him pend his time in doing this; however it would not lie impossible for each assured to give the local agent a sworn statement of his household ijoods and their value and while of course the agent and company might even iken advantage of then, yet it would have a tendency hold even the dishonest applicant within reasonable bounds for the ageat could give him the impression that as soon as he had time he would go and look over the property and compare it with the statement. Of course we realize that unless all companies agreed to do this it would not 1m- practicable for the assured would take out his insurance from a company that did not make this i-ei|uirement. In time we feel some such method will In - adopted universally by all companies. Kven now Insur - ance Companies can have some understanding with their agents to the effect that they will not stand for the flagrant writing of risks and that wherever possible and convenient the risk must be inspected, ("ases have conic to our notice where agents have insured property to the </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 STATK KIRK COMMISSION point of criminality, ami vet tin* Company in n&lt;&gt; wmy blamed the agent. At Sidney on DecemWr loth, 191."&gt;, we investigated a case whore a lot of newspapers and rubbish were gath - ered together in the basement and saturated with coal oil and evidently set cm tire. The investigation broagfel out the fact that this party l&gt;ought the stock c(tntained in the store for *17."&gt;.00 and obtained insurance on it amounting to $1400. The stock was lxiiight in June ami burned up in I&gt;eceml&gt;er. Both the man and his wife were away at the time tlie tire started i :'.. A. M. in the morning) and had l&gt;een away from the house since 7 o'clock the night In-fore and were aide to prove an alibi. No one was seen around the place and of course this department could have no one arrested for the crime. Thei • is no doubt but that the tire was set by a slow fuse Inn this evidence was destroved with the tire. "To prove the carelessness of the insurance agent* Fire Marshal Stevens of Oregon has made public the result of a test, he recently made. A fireman's helmet and a grand jury subpoena were placed in an empt\ flat. The tire marshal then sent ;i deputv to get the furniture insured. As a result the deputy secured policies from twenty companies, each insuring the furni ture for $500. In a frame shack in another part of the city, a fireman's helmet, a subpoena and a tin cup resulted in the obtaining of almost a score more of policies for $1000 each. Fire Marshal Stevens says that in the deputy's round of the agencies no effort was made by the agents to have the goods inspected l&gt;efore issuing the policies nor did they ask for a list of the goods. Of course the deputy who asked for the insurance deviated from the truth "somewhat" when he asked for insurance on furni ture, but so would a dishonest person who wanted excess insurance in order that he might burn out and collect same." We realize of course, that companies writing city business meet more frequently with the person who </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 STATE KIKE COMMISSION A &lt; l\ I lants excess insurance than do farm mutual companies rko write only oa farm property, but our office has also had uses where the fanner has evidently had horses, cattle. Hiusehold good*, etc.. over insurance and the company has icen suspicious of him when they went to settle the loss. &gt;ften ihe remains of about four horses have been found \ hen the insured insisted that he had lost seven or teu MM in the tire Often the fact that household goods have mmii removed from the insured property just l&gt;efore a fire ias lieen proven. We would not have Companyies and incuts look with suspicion on every one who takes out nsuiaiice. but those who have had experience in settling osses know only too well how often suspicion is well nuiided. It is departments like ours and the members &gt;f insurance companies who have some idea of the imber of dishonest losses that insurance companies have n pay. The average layman has no idea of this con - lition. As the principle that the proper way to control the ire hazard is to study causes of tires, and from each •xpeiience devise remedies to prevent a recurrence of oich loss, so we ought therefore to turn our attention to educing incendiary tires as well as minimizing the loss rom careless causes. </seg>
            <seg id="p040"/>
            <seg id="p041">41 STATE KIRK COMMISSION COLLECTIONS FROM INSURANCE COMPANIES </seg>
            <seg id="p042"/>
            <seg id="p043">STATE KIRK (O\l MISSION 43 col.l.KCTloNS l-'UoM INSIUANCK CO.MI'ANIKS. "For 1 In- purpose iif maintaining the Fire Commission I &gt;epai •fnii'lit every tile insurance company doiii" business in Nebraska 1 except the Fanners Mutual 1 must \m\ to lie Stale Treasurer annually thm'-eiyhts of one |mm- Ml 11 the tire premiums written in Nebraska, after lediicliiij; eaneellations and reinsurance In compliance wit 1 1 this law the following rDiiijianies ive |iaii| the amount set opposite their names: Aarlien \ Miinirli Fire Ins. ('«» x '.t'2,'A\ •Etna Fire Ins. Co :J1C.S&lt;» \^ii«ult ure Fin- Ins. Co ST. Hi Vineriran Fire Ins. Co 1(»9.27 Ameriran Central Fin- In*. Co !M&gt;.:&gt;;'. American ! »i-nji*^ist Fire Ins. Co S£S Atlas Fin- Ins. Co 1'K.Ur, \tlas Fire Ins. Co I'K.Ur, I'.nstoii Fin- Ins. Co ::l\:s»; I'.oston Fire Ins. Co :5l'.:m; I'.iitish Aiiiciit iin Fiif Ins. Co Ii!&gt;.L M .l ISi itisli -Amerit-an File Ins. Co 2tt.2!l I'll f V; i U &gt; (ierman Pll* III*. Co ."Mi.^2 r.ntl'alo (iermaii Fire Ins. Co ."Mi.^2 Caledonia Pii-«&gt; Ins Co 41.:J!t Caledonia Fire Ins Co 41.311 &lt; aiiHlcn Fire Ins ( '• ll'.t»(» Cannlen Fire Ins Co 12.6(1 citizt-ns Fii-c Ins. Co L'li.llU citizens Fire Ins. Co L'li.llU ( Ml \ i&gt;( New York !&gt;.!»&lt;&gt; ( Ml \ of New York !&gt;.!»&lt;&gt; &lt;oinin&lt;Mciiil I'liion Firr Ins. Co., Nfw York... 7.0S Coinineicial Inion Fire Ins. Co., New York... 7.0S Coinmcnijil I Dion Fire Ins Co., London l!IN..!l Coinmenial I nion Fire Ins Co., Loixlon 198.31 Commonwealth Fire Ins. Co 3&amp;7H Commonwealth Fire Ins. Co :'.n-.7n ( 'uncordia Fire Ins Co :»^.."iT Coiu-onlia Fire Ins Co :»^.:»7 Continental Fire Ins Co :MH.."»ri Coutineiitiil Fire Ins Co :t91.3li &lt; 'oimerticnt File Ills. Co 2N."».O4 ( 'oiintv Fire Ins. Co 4.7J Dwelling House .Mutual Ins. Co 19.9." hiilMinue F'ire &amp; .Marine Ins. Co .!!. ."»."&gt; Kijiiitalih- Fir&lt;- Ins. Co lU.AD Fanners Ins. Co.. of Cedar Rapids, la ."!!». ."&gt;7 Fidelitv-Pheiiix Ins. Co :t56.fM </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Federal Ins. Co., New York 1.47 Fire Association of Philadelphia 136.68 Fireman Ins. Co.. of Newark 106.9") Fireman's Fund Ins. Co. 63.60 Franklin Fin- Ins. Co 44.30 General Fire InR. Co 1 1.65 German Alliance Fire Tns. Co 21.2") Globe &amp; Rutjrers Fire Ins. Co., New York 61.37 Grain Dealers Ins. Co.. Indianapolis 25.69 German American Fit* Ins. Co .... 355.26 Germania Fire Ins. Co 11."&gt;.4 Girard Fire &amp; Marine Ins Co :t4.7T Glens Falls Fire Ins. Co 189.0L' Hanbarg-Bremen Fire In Hamburg-Bremen Fire Fus. Co I'd 2'2.'2T&gt; Hanover Fire Ins. Co 106.1:! Hanover Fir*' Ins. To 106.11! Hartford Fire Ins. Co 526.01 Hartford Fire Ins. Co ."»2(i.&lt;»"i Home Fire Ins. Co 874.5ti Home Fire Ins. Co X74..V! Insurance Compaaj &lt;»f North Aincricn i!44.r&gt;T Insurance Company of North America 244 fnsuranoe Company of State of Pennsylvania. . 4l».s&lt;i Insurance Company of State of Pennsylvania. . 4&lt;&gt;.s&lt; Imperial Fin- Ins. Co 19.71 finperial Fiif Ins. Co lf.7 Law. Union &amp; Hock Ins C, Law. rnion &amp; Hock Ins. C&lt;&gt; Liverpool. Lomlon &amp; (Hohp of England i'7»i.!U Liverpool. London &amp; Globe of England i'7»i.! ♦I.'il Liverpool. Lomlon &amp; (J'oIm- of New York 17.77 London Assurance Co 22.64 London &amp; Lanshire Ins. Co li\A'.'- Mechanic* ft Traders Ins. Co %.U Mechanic* Fire Ins. Co v.Vi Mercantile Insurance Co. of America 10.34 Federated Merchants Mutual Fire Ins. Co.... :tt» Michigan Commercial Fire Ins. Co 12.4s Miller's Mutual Fire Ins. Co 21.8M Millers National Fire lux. Co 51.27 Milwaukee Mechanics Fire In*. Co 107.4:: Minneapolis Fire &amp; Marine Ins. Co :{.'&gt;&gt;: Mutual Protective Fire Aiw'n. toward, Xehr... .',."». CO National Fire Ins. Co j,l&gt;l |.:;i, National Secuiitv Fire Fns. ( "o 3."».!KI National Fire [imnranoe Co of Paris 7&lt;is National Ben Franklin Fire Ins Co H p </seg>
            <seg id="p045">STATB HKK &lt;O\IM1.-Mi&gt;\ 45 National 1'nion Fin- of PittMburuli s;{.t;:: Nebraska Luinl&gt;ei mans Ins. Co 18.tt.~i Netherlands Fin- Ins. &lt; 'o 1:5.0:.' Ni'lnaskii Hardware .Mutual Ins. Co 53.1(1 New Hampshire Fin- Ins. Co *:».."» 1 Newark Pire Ins. ( 'o .{."i.fis Niagara Fire I dm. Co 4S.2."&gt; North Hivt'i Fire Ins. Oo 2«.."»."» North Hritisli &amp; Mercantile Fire Ins. Co l»&gt;4.0."i Northern Assni-an«-c Co MlSM Northwestern Fiit- &amp; Marine Ins. Co L'!t,!t4 North \vt*Mtt-in National Fir* Ins. Co )»»!». ."iT Norwich T'nion Fire Ins. Co ."»S.4O Nin-&lt;II)('iils&lt;ln' liisin iiMrc Co 11.19 New r.ninswick File Ins. Co ;».."Hi ultl Colony Fire Ins. Co 12. -IK I &gt;l&lt;l Colony Fire Ins. Co 12. -Ill Orient Fiif Ins. Co itit.L".' Orient Firv Ins. Co ."!!&gt;. 2!l &lt;&gt;lii&lt;&gt; Farmers Ins. Co 2.!M&gt; Ohio Farmers Ins. Co tMt I'iilantine Fire Ins. Co :i."&gt;.4:. I'alaiitinc Fire Ins. Co :i."&gt;.4.-. J'eiinsvlvaiiia Fire Ins. Co IM.7N J't'iinsvlvania Fire Ins. Co 10K.70 Peoples National Fire Ins. Co 44.7.*. IN-oplcs National Fire Ins. Co 44.7.*. I'hoeiiix Ins. Co.. Hartford SM.44 I'hociiix Ins. Co., Hartford 1 ( '_'4.44 I'tuM'iiix File Insiiiaiire Co. of I'aris S.S7 I'tuM'iiix File Insiiiaiirc Co. of Paris S.S7 I'liiM-nix Ins. Co., London S&amp;M Phoenix Ins. Co., London B5.83 I'latte Mutual Fire Ins. Co ::.0C» Provideaf* 1 Wanhiiixton Fire Ins. Co ::4.su Piiissian National Fire Ins. Co 45.51 Qneeo Ins. Co l«4.or, Iieliance Fire [as. Co S4.S1 Retail Merrhant* Ins. Co :;.I4 Rhode Island Fire Ins. Co ■_'((.*!&gt; Roval Fire Ins. Co • &gt; ."&gt;7.::7 &gt;i.:; i Royal Exchange Assinanct' Co 24. ( .r_' Scottish 1'nioii ft National Fin- Ins. Co .")(».!':: Security File Ins. Co IC7.H Sprinjrfield File &amp; Marine Ins. Co .■|»;4.:U Standard Fire Ins. Co 7..-»l St. Paul Fire &amp; Marine 40N..-.N Sun V\if- Ins. ( 'o MKSS </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 STATK KIRK COMMISSION Sve;l File [lis. ( '«» 1 s.ii:, Tniou Fire Ins. Pn. nf Park .*..::&gt; I T nion Fire Ins. ('«».. Liixoln, Win- liMt.Oi 1 rnitiNi States Fire Ins. To 1«.7T Western Assuiiince Cn., Toronto .'.S.97 Westrln-stei- Fire Ins. Co Cl.-Jll WHIiiiiMslnii-i; City I"iic Ins. On T«&gt;t;il illliolilil pniil liv Insiir.inri' !H.l!i &lt;'(Mll|&gt;;l!lic«;. SH.'.rJII 71 sil.ir.'n </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 \TK J-'IKK IO.M MISSION RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p048"/>
            <seg id="p049">49 STATK FIKK COMMISSION KKCKMTS AMI KXPENDITUBE8, 1916. Ukckiits. Amount paid into Shite Tresisnrv datfag veai l'.tir, '. "... .$12,544.24 I'.jiliinrc on hand. Jan nary 5th, li»lt» 2,37li.."iO »1 4,920.74 114,920.71 KXI'KXIHTIKKS. Km'Kxkiti i:ks. Saliii it-s * &lt;«.&lt;&gt;i&gt;0.!»7 * »,(«&gt;!t.!»7 Sjiliii Kailioad fill-.- l.:',:52.}»4 K'iiiliMit.l fin-,. 1,:{.52.!»4 I Intel t'X|MMIHI'S 1 ,4-"&gt;l .94 l.iveiv ;ind l»us liiiv H6.(K"&gt; Strti't (ill- fare 11.4."&gt; Street liir fare 11.4."&gt; 'I'cli-pliuiif ami iflc^rapli l."&gt;7.42 Telephone iiml Icle^rjipli 157.42 I'osia-.- :'.IKKJX» I'osij.-e :uk».jx» Kxprm 2.1!i Kxprm 2.1 !• ( »tti( -e sii|t|ilies urn] printing 4O."».!tl ( »tti&lt; c sii|t|ilics ami |ti*i nt iiiir 40.~i.in Pnraitnrr and Hxtiu-«'s r».(M( I'lirniture ; 1 1 1« 1 fixtures ."».(Ml Stcii(i^r;i|ili&lt;*r"s fi^s JMJ.S2 Steiidi:i;i|ilier"s fin-s !MJ.M2 Witiii-ss fc«-s 14.."»(l Witness fees 14.."»0 I'iir &lt; "liicfs. fws 377.40 I'iie &lt; 'liiefs. fe»«s 377.40 M isrcllaiKHins rxpravn tHJ&amp;4 Total Bxpmwn *l:UWH.s:! M iseellillieolis expenses 2H4.S4 Total K\|K'iises ♦l:{,«W«i.s:; r.alanci- on hand .Ian. 1st. 1!tl7. . . . 1,283.91 r.;il;inee on liiiml .Ian. 1st. 1!tl7. . . . 1,283.91 #14.920.74 $14.!t20.74 </seg>
            <seg id="p050"/>
            <seg id="p051">51 t(\l MISSION INSPECTIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p052"/>
            <seg id="p053">A IK 1 IKK COMMISSION 53 INSI'KCTIOXS. iMniii" i In- vear l'.tlti, :&gt;s.* towns were visited anil Town I.XSPBTEll In niM TMK Ykau 1916. I'.cllianv Ki-nnctt Itcl^iinlc Iti'lviilci-f I'.crw yn l.cnkt'linan Itridneport l!a\ aril \ Hiiiin \iiiswnltl Mkiuson Mvadia M.ia Inoka vxt.-n Vllii«»n \ \slilaih Viil.urn Vuslev (lay Center Crete Itaniston Krnno CollejreView &lt; 'larks \ lie,- Hlaii \ (liil.Orfhard &lt; 'Icar water CriitralCity ConiRtoek \- Itlaileii Viiiliem Arnolil Itliic Spriiifis lleemer \ Rattle &lt; 'reck ( 'hcstfl- ISmwnville liainroft .Viiwlmo Mien ( 'ortland ( 'liapman ( 'otesfield rhadron ( Ollllllhlis Cainbridge Kut t.- lieitiantl I Sell wood Clue Hill licatrirc I SlM'lllS I'.iilin iMi:; iiis|iciti&lt;in&gt; niiiilf Kniilsluiw Blooaiagton llrot-k I leaver City I'.tM-trand r.urchard Burr llridgppori I'.loomtield llarard I'.iiinswick ItiMcvne Hi-' (ken Bow I'xavei- Cii»ssinj,' l'.i ;iin;iril r.yruii 1&gt;i;h1v liiissctt (liiv Center Mliance \il;mis I'ciliii </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 STATK till rilM MISSION Eddyrille Emereon &lt;!l;ltitl Island Herman f'nlhertaoa rcliii- Bluff Clinks II;ii -vjii-iI Kaiyle Ili-niiniii^foi-il Ilickliiiili rkappel] &lt; 'larksou &lt; 'allawaj &lt;'«&gt;rilov;i i 'i-oijiliton ( 'iiinplK'H &lt; "liiwfonl Concord &lt; 'osad Klmwooil I' 11 si is 1 1 iiiiiImiIiIi II owe Klvi-ia Kim Creek Homer Hebron Harbine i:ii.;i I'llwudil Klldiroll Kdear Hiiitiiiiitim Hildreth Rlein Pairbvn Fairmont I'jiirliclil rulls rit.v Pallerton Fninklin Fiitli llnwclls Ilcishcv I [aveloi'k Hitlinsvil Hui'binf ( 'arroll &lt; 'cihn- IJiipi.ls ( 'oltM-iiiljSc Iloskiiis Hynunix ll;u S|.i IluiilMi.l llllllllllllf\ Hooper ( 'nrtis Cook &lt; 'rofton l»«\Vitt Itcslilei- l&gt;avi&lt;l City Fillrv lla\ Spiin Dmnlwtii FarwHl Hnbbarri Dawsoii Friend Hampton l»oi|^c Ft. C;i1Ii.»iim HoMregr l);i\cii|(url Frt-iiioiit I naval* 1 I &gt;&lt;iiiim-1.i &lt;&gt; u Gibbon luman I &gt;; 1 1&lt; n i Gothenburg Imperial lMmliai (iiftn.i liiiliaimla I'oiiiilas Geriag Johmioa OnRoin Oral •lackaoa IMxoii Qrww—d l.insci) Dakota City (Irani ■ImIimsIuw ii I '&lt;mi)&gt;)iaii Glm Bock •lunicata iMiiniiiii; &lt;i»H'lmcr KntMv I &gt;«'\v('«'sc Graftoa Kt'ui uey l&gt;wijrht flum Kil^m-c Kxcti'i- &lt;!ur&lt;lou Kcvstoiii' i:ik Ci(M&gt;k CiMioa Kiinliall </seg>
            <seg id="p055">STATE KlItK COM .MISSION 55 ritv Nioluara I'a-c I.VO1IS IMiiliips Primrose Potter Louisville Lexington Litrhtielil Loiip ( "it\ I.ewcllel) Hushville iai rioml Kulo Wl-elle inlsav Uaveuna Kayniond Rohn Lunu I'iiu &lt; Mnalia Oxtolil Oakdale O'Neill Oakland Oeolito Orleans :h x Repablit-un Uorkvill.- Kuskin Mason Citv M Meadow Orcnri Melliii Kamlol|ili Ralston M«('&lt;M)k .Meii-iinan Miller Monroe Mullen Morrill Mason Minded Mr.|,| Swanton Stlmylei Superior SaltMii Sul ton Sargent Smartvilli Stella Stanton ShulK-rt St. Paul Surprise I'ender Panama Pi.krel Norfolk Neli-1, Neinalia Nelsoii Petersluujr Silver Creek Steiuaner Platte Center I'olk Scotia North l'latte Newcastle N'i-w port I'ottcr N;i|M'r I*il«r«»r Xickt'i-son PfeflM Nfliiaska ritv liuval North Bead Wising Citv Oil«-ll Kivcrton I.IIIW IMK » Melton ( &gt;( niiei- Oj-allala Oceola .Miiilisoii Uivci-dale SlmlKMt St. Kdwaiils SttM-lin&lt;r &lt; &gt;nj: i Hiiow a I »SIII((||(] I'l.VllUMltll \l;is(iu I'lilttsmoiitli Miinlrii Palmyra .Mi-mi Papiilion Miii;ilarc I'onca Milclitll I'iiwiict' f'tiv Mortfteld PlafaiTinr Nfwiiijiii (Jiiivi Pen Nrliawkji I'cnder N"ith Lonp </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 STATE KIKE COMMISSION Talnia^e- Tobias Walmo Shicklev West Point WislHT Tevinnseh Tilden Slielton Mniuner Wyinore Wayne Walthill Tekaniali Stapleton Syiiuuse Stiatton Kraeca T;il.l&lt;' l{(Hk Tliavci- \\'itnu'l»aj«ti \Vi'lltl««et Thedford Trenton Taylor Shelby Western W(Hxlriv&lt;M Wausa Stitinisburj; Sutherland SttH'kham Hnvder I niiiii Cpland WaketieM Winsidc Wvnot. rniveisiiy I'lax I'ti.-a Sewan] Shelton Westoil reiMin&lt;r Verdun Vesta Waterlmry W&lt;mm1 Lak» Wilcox S.otts Hlutt So. Sioux City S;ironville Verdure Vallev Walton W'altasli Voik Stuart St. Edward Sichiev N'alparaiso Valentine Venan;j&lt;i Spanliin; Scrilnier St. I.ilMiiv Viitsin Wilher Weepiii^ Water </seg>
            <seg id="p057">STATK KIKK COMMISSION 57 CAUSES OF FIRES IN CITIES AND TOWNS &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p058"/>
            <seg id="p059">59 STATK KIRK COMMISSION CAIKKK OP KIKES IN CITIKS ANI&gt; TOVVSH Adjoining Wit* G7 Adjoining Wit* 6" Ashes hot, thrown against Imildinus l."» Ashes hot, thrown against buildings !."» Ashen, hot, in wooden barrel or lx&gt;x 4 \shes, hot, in wooden barrel or lx&gt;x 4 AAn, hot, falling on lean m carelessly thrown. ... 7 Awhes, hot. fallin&lt;; on floors or careWslv thrown. ... 7 Auto, hacktirinj: t . 66 Auto, hacktirinj: 4 . titi Auto. taking tire 5 Vuto. taking tire 5 Auto, vulcanizing, fire left burning 1 Auto, vulcanizing, tire left burning 1 Box. hot on ltearinjj pulley 3 Box. hot on lx»arinjj pulley 3 ■• Uontires 9 llontires 9 Moilf!-, caught fi-oin 2 Boiler, caagki tram •&gt; Bake oven, caught from i 1 Make ovt'ii, caught from i 1 ItlackHiuith shoj», spiirks from 1 Ulacksiiiith sJiop, sparks from 1 ('liinim-y. sparks from 14* • 'hiniiii-v, sparks from 14* • 'hiinncvs. defwtive fiO • 'hiinnevs. defective RO t'hiinnev. burning oui 7 t'himnev. burning out 7 » 'hininey, plu&gt;i&lt;r»'il with |»a|wr 1 » 'hininey, pliifijreil with |»a|wr 1 &lt; 'hristtnas tre»&gt; randies on 2 &lt; 'hiinney stop left out 1 i 'Hii&lt;llen left huratefC 4 i 'Riidlen left harninK 4 Candles in kindling wood 1 Candles in kindling wood 1 Candles in -lack O'Lantcrn 2 Candles in -lack O'Lantcrn 2 &lt;M&lt;jar or dpMCttM careh'sslv thrown :{0 &lt; 'leauin&lt;i niarhiiie, sparks from 1 Dvnamo taking tii-e 1 Bketrtt or gas iron l&lt;-fl staixlini; on clotli S Kl»M-tri&lt;- wire or jet j </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 STATE KIRK COMMISSION Electric wiring defective '-W Exhaust pipe over-heated 1 Explosion ( house blown up i 1 Explosion carlMiu 1 Explosion shell in gun 1 Electric wire short circuit 4 Electric motor 4 Electric wire lightning on l Engine overheated 1 Explosion flash tire 1 Explosion incubator or lamp Fireworks Furnace pipe, caught from .* Furnace, defective Furnace, hot or overhi ated. getting tire to kin&lt;11in&lt;r . . S Furnace, hot or overheated, rnhhish ton near to «&gt; Furnace, raacfct from Furnace, expkw'on of I Explosion. sp;irks from 1 Fire place defective Fumigating 1 Fire place, flue defective Furniture polish taking fire 1 Friction of l»elt on wood pulley Gasoline, live wire in 1 &lt; Sasoline explosion or ignition :t»; Gasoline heating 1 Gasoline used in cleaning clothing, etc Gasoline coffee urn caught lire while filling sjiiii.-. ... 1 Gasoline engine Gasoline lamp or lighting plant Gasoline water heater 1 Gasoline m&lt; blering pot Sited when lighteil ( Jas heater upset 1» Gas stove, caught from Gas jef. caught from ) (tiis mantle defective I Gas heater too close t&gt;. furniture 1 Gas furnace left burning '. 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 STATE KIRE COMMISSION H&lt;»i air pijH"s overheated 1 Hut air flue overheated 21 Incubator, &lt;;iuj;ht. from 1 Incendiary 2f&gt; Kerosene can exploded 1 Kerosene oil stove leaking 6 Kerosene oil stove, caught from 3!) Kerosene oil burner defective 1 Kerosene oil burner leaking 1 Kerosene oil ignited 1 Kerosene oil heater left burning 1 Kerosene oil stove overflowed 1 Lamp exploded 7 Lamp or open light, curtain caught from 2 Lantern magic 1 Lighting plant 1 Lamp, caught from •&gt; Lamp dropped on floor 1 Lamp alcohol 2 Laatam 1 Lightning 27 Locomotive, sparks from 26 Match, sparks in clothes closet 8 Matches in clothes 3 Matches carlessness with 22 Matches and children 65 Matches and mice 8 Matches, sparks flying from same 3 Mattress against furnace pipe 1 Motor overheated 1 Metal paint boiling over 1 Moving picture machine 5 Motor short circuited 1 Potash burner 1 Paper bn rnei- 1 IMumlKM-s blow |H&gt;t 3 Rubbish, burning same carelessly 18 Kange hot on floor 3 Radiator overheated in auto 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 STATS KIKE COMMISSION Hegister rag* in 1 Range defective 1 Smoking, nifii and l»ovs ."» Stove overheated '24 Stove caught from wood or rabbisk t(K» dose 4 Stove too dose to wall or woodwork 4 Stove caught from 4 Stove sparks from Stoves, clothing hanging too near Stove soft coal exploded Stove pipe caught from &lt;; Stove ])ipe, through ceiling, poof or wood purtition. . . 2M Smoking in 1x^1 4 SiiKiking cat from under house 1 Sparks from emerv wheel dust 1 Sparks from smoke stack . Slacking lime 1 Sparks from foundry Steam furnace overheated Sparks from grate Shavings in cellar window 1 Spiirks. traction engine Sparks. Hteain shovel Suspicions t&gt;&lt;; Spontaneous combustion 3§ Sun in contact with dustless mop 1 Tramps t'» I'nknowii :toi Water pipes and tanks thawing out Hi Wireless in contact with electric light 134 s </seg>
            <seg id="p063">STATE KIRK COMMISSION B." 63 s;ua^uo3 - r- ,- : ,- - 5 5 i: ,t 5 : 5 z ;5 5 S f f f uo ssoq ! — = ri : 1- !i I « I! Vi 5 ■ 5 S V*i r= 1 — v. . — r: -c — — r. — . tj nx;-&gt; ti -i x ; x SJU3JUO3 uo douejnsui r-. , t i- it i- it i* aouEinsu[ /. z z z z x sjuajuoo '« UO &lt; U "J = - i- ;?999«t';9&gt;acs99e6ee •^■^•*. i* A A A &gt;A Al A i A A &gt;A .^ — .BAA IO A ■^■^». . i . ■— ■ — — ■ •-• * I v 1^ -w ■» i . » -w -». ... |o 3n[wy\ ,.,--. -., .^ ri -., ri x r: x r: x ?i i- i- 7 — / *»!3 "5 E I x uT -t i. w S "^ jo auiEfvi K I = = = = sujpuna = = 1 1 ? = 1 2 *"•**.** 2 i !• 2 uo ssoq - § 1 1 g h § i s § i vi Ei^iiiii k — ' -■ - 3 Sr .? i s ? l&gt; : . i? i i i ; £ 5 S 8uip|ing = uo ,-: Suip|ing o an^ 1^1 : :!• ii 1 d § § 5 s ,- * '•"' ,1 1 § 2 § S3JIJ jo 'ON j M — i- s — r: r; i- — — i- r: -m -r »- — — n </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 STATE FIRE COMMISSION ?? I £ 5 s 'S ■/. It ? I Tl = - - 1" It i" ■X. i* y. r. • it vr i Tl I- it ti — ' -/. •m : i -\ I- it KONC X it / Tl t t 7 ic i-i-fiii:^ § § I § I § § : j= r= 5 : x tii '39 ■ — -^.TiTO^C — — — I-- • o © • s&gt; ' 5 s i( S e c SS s — 'isd ' © !?9*s9QQditis i- ii it x i" it i- i~ i~ i" s 3; c: e ; » «p I : n — _ i$ re n re re a ri it* —■ Tl I 3 5 5 §§§§§?. c 5 5 § = = s o s — ~ &gt;~ ri &gt;~ ~ x it — ~ s s &gt;~ it it rt s — re it it x -rt o re i — &gt;■: — •■£■ 'A ?» ••£ X C -t - :i x* M re' m — ■ tT = :;? : s '■ '■ '• S g {2 S : S3 r^ is 1 * ;^ : : ; ti — 3 ;ri ; -h ' -c' re' ri — x' ■■£ it xxx= ; ; ;x ; i z js z j £ i It S fi re • ■ • 5 • ir, i- r. i- : it — ei x ;x2x= ;=s==s=3== | : s 1 1 1, : § S g 1 1 § | y j! - ' x* 3 - -' - -* - g» e x' * * ~ a ~ • 3^ ." • • T^ * « 5 c S 5 • a 5 S 5 5 5 !S x it ?T -f -£ ' r:^%* m c :r -t — ' p4 vH *-* Tl l-sllilllllilslll • &gt; »» •* A* *^ &lt;yk »^» •» »» A^ •*• r r r- r v </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 Ill'SisiiSli I; </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 STATE FIRE COMMISSION SSSSSSsSS :§§i§ii 5 §§§§§§§§ c&gt; is * o s e — m •■: ' ~ &gt;■: c — c — x s x i = •■: — c 5 n i» 5 - i: i: i- :i -* re ei ;s i- &gt;- — c C 5 it — 3: it c x t- it ri — » ; »a 1- 1- — — ri x i i — &gt;~. — — -r rfift" — * tf rfrfi-' — 1- — • rf itSSSSS$XSSS!S2S5SMSiSSf = re ?: — it = s 1- s s «« &gt;~ C s: 3: o ri s — •-: = I =; = ~ 1- 1* ri — .1 "r — r? "- 1 m ti c t c re ri n :i c •♦ r it i « §§§ :|§ :S8SsSsSsSsSsSSS m c .•■: — ?? .-!■&gt;- ; 01 1- 1- re -» -,r ti 1 -* — vr ti - = — — ri x' «-i M ~* — "—' — ' rt — " — ' xc x" — ' -- 311 -t — — ri f- x • at -3 x li J ; I: ; ~i 1- i~ 5 ;n" - 1- = .: :i - r- 5«|§icJ = s e § c = J 5 § 5 = = § = = = i i-^in 11 le r&lt; ri i 1— ; o^tc t- — r— — s^_~r:i':_ — — -Joe' — * It 9** *f «rf «tf — W eT 1- * »" 1-* — r: t&gt; it w ei — e h ni^ e c -» x •♦ a » 5 b c ti x ti 1: :i 1- c ; r. ; 1- jg" «o" —" — ' — * Histf'H'iaan af &gt;-' ff « 1 - — * — r: rf - i r i- - ri ti - r: - ri m k :i j: 7. - :i ;i n ti -&gt;• -► t: :| i i UJ&gt; ;_ ;::::::. : j : : : : : : : : I * f 1 Eii 'tis* 1;:::::::: = ::::::::::::^ </seg>
            <seg id="p067">STATK i ri s i- x 7 i 1*1 i i •3 s x e e " ■ i i ?i i i i i i * ; i T &lt;■: fi i i / i i: c ■» n 3 ii ? s i: '~ ~t i '" " • i i X -* i x i- ?&lt; — t- i- ri i m — n i i i i ~ u. ■L &lt; w , .— ssss LSl.C &gt;-, XX = KIEK COMMISSION '67 § § § :§§§§§§ :§§£&gt;§ = C s ! ~ d c; o © &lt;£ * © «4 s • © © x . i- ; ; i: o n : © *m ci i- — c re . : -t s n n a r~ — -i 3rf 9 3 | — — ri ■* r. :; n - rt i.: k h i- f« ■ x' sTtT— * c ?i i* i~ is : ess ■* rt t- io « ' : « 3i ' ' M&lt; -»&lt; S I-™ : i § . : is 5 : : i * i s i 5 1 ! -f — ! • " ' ic ~f — ri rf — * 9i — — Lt f I X — Tl — it C — I" M ?t — — y. : ::::::::::::! ::::::: :i :i : :^| !lll]|1i«f^wl ilTllilliiiiliE 2 ~ ~ 'z*. y, t. T. r. y. ~s. ~s. y. y, y. </seg>
            <seg id="p068">i 1 1 1 IT I = 7 i* ~ V\ -\ SB :§ — X ■ x ri 1- x — -* i~ it it / • - :l X -I. ■1. /. / / .' T.-Z - S. ?. ■. .? Z :( '■ fig STATE rUHl COMMISSION 3 X i; C i: ; C £ i: ! = ' C &gt;" C: -r »-' »-' ! »£ C S '" .3 .^ r? p § § = £ VI § § i § § § .^ - .^ i ?? i § |B -t — M 5 — — ri 1- ti i~ r: 3: &gt;^ -&gt;■ ' — H ' &lt;^ &gt;~ ' ?i 5 15 P J &gt;: 5 '" : — ■ x ft i~ ■ x. — • — T\ T-. at — — "i ' — ti ■ — ' &lt;-' ! ! ■/ ti • « Lx X I 1 X 7 7 * Z .» .. " X X .1 "^ • "^ * ri M — ' »*" ri re* i- — ■' /.* — ' — * — — " ri — -r r &gt;t ec c i— ~j t j — i- &gt;~ i ir — 1 1~ c n — x • 71 — ~ — — HHfft- -^ Ti — rt* ijf *f — — ' -- — ' so — ' — ; ri /' — </seg>
            <seg id="p069">STATE FIRE (OM MISSION 69 i z z z ; z 5 5 X ?i • •: 5fi 3 rnt ; 15 i «.t : • ■* « . »* &gt;" ix§3§§§|3x^22S$§§§5§§S§S3 t~ -M — — H — h- X Z iT ."* 5 1 :| s jisrti • x II- • — -r ri ri X I i- XCi rfr- rf « -e '"* j ~ i /. H :- :i r; ™ — — — _- ~ M n - - :i n -c --!■-- :i - :i l :&lt; y. a- 55 — E s * £ &amp; £ /. &lt; r S x x x'Z x '-Z ■/. •/. -7. ■'/. x x: 'X c : »« = : s c i 1 : c i c c c i: c c »": ;' c c i; c c »t »*£ c: »~ s£ it cj c; .11 r p z • 5 :s x • x • rx • x "". •" ~* -• '* •"■—." I *i • *i • |r v i § ?i § : 2 1 1 : : § 12 S i : ,^ § 1" 1" -» rt &gt;t . ?i i~ 1* , m :i t s . 3t ~" |5 ,"= 2 x — , x : = 5 x S !*", 5 2 !k x x .t: .-= 1 = i =1. g 3 r x </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 STATE KIKE COMMISSION • i / it ? — t"i r? tl x —. -i s. r- •t it i /. i ri -f ti i ri / it 7 i I it / / i". i , i ~ it it it •/ = = / 1 -^ -^r ■-• -^ '^ it I x " :; ?• i- -* r t - i* *i /. — -\ rt 7i x* i- — ' i /. / '," i / t- '■ 2 :l ■ »1 x III&amp; l-l.-^ / c i: - s -_ i-_ =; x i- "i .1 ~! : •" '.".'. — — . ~. 2 = = 12 12 -\ i ri 5c — r — — i- i^ i- r **. *£ |I • ~\ — — r (S -i -^ ti [- i- xs — ti — ' ti -/ : ri — ' = *_*—? tS * = ? — f- ~ .— </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 STATK KIRK I OM. MISSION COMPARATIVE TABLES </seg>
            <seg id="p072"/>
            <seg id="p073">s I A 1 K r I IC K * * ' * ' .• 1 1 I ' ' * 73 In Smith (tm.ilui on OiIoIht 2mA, Morris &amp; Company I'acking House \v;is destroyed l&gt;\ tire entailing a loss of *!»::. mil .(Hi If it had not Im'cii for this t it-mentions tire loss our hi— n for 1916 would hav&lt;- decreased and Iteen less than tlicv have for ;m\ rear since the organization of this depart inenl. Norfolk with 9t riles and ;i loss of nearly |i7."»,(M)0 is very larjge for a town of its size, and the c&lt;»iiiin^ year &gt;\i- will look into the conditions there with the object in mind of reducing the tire hazard in this town. Mri'iKik with 1"&gt; fires is not encouraging and York* "_'&lt;• should lie decreased. ro.MPAUATlVK TABLES. Tlie following tallies show the value of MMtagi ami Tlie following tallies show the value of buildings and contents ami the amount of ilnnim^* caused hy fire for the contents and the amount of damage caused hy fire for the v.'iiis fttt, 1911, 191:!. It1«, 1914, 1911 Mi 1916: years HMO. 1!H1. 1912, ltiS, 1!U4. 191 a and I91fi: MM 1*410 Value of Imilcliujjs * Tjtfl,lfHt Vitlue of contents ."&gt;,71S.l."»y.0(l Insurance on huiMiBKM 4,75,'i. 628.00 Insurance on buildings 4,7;%.'{. 628.00 Insurance on content* 3,847,690.00 Insurance on contents 3,847,690.00 LMi to huil&lt;lin-.'s 1,097.403.00 Lous to huildinjrs 1,097,4O:i.O4t Loss to contents 1 ,0Kt,6o5.00 Loss to contents l,t83,IM.tt 1»11 1911 X'alue of Imiliiin^s * S.GK7.414.0O Value of buildings * 8.G87.414.00 Value 1 of contents S,Ofi7.X17 00 N'alue of contents Mf7.817.9t Insurance on huildinps ."(,795.901.50 Insurance on contents 5,289,890. "."&gt; Loss to buildings 1.017,211.6"i Loss to contents 760,91 1.»».~i </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 ST.VTK KIRK COMMISSION l!»12 Value of building)- % 1 l.:{7:'&gt;,2S4.:;s Value of contents r».lt&gt;8,:jJ*7.r» ! Insurance on buildings 4.918.340.00 Insurance on content*- .!.S09.i»7iUMi Loss tr» building X69.06X.40 Loss to contents 1.314.556.!l."&gt; ma Value of building* &gt; ~».4S2;421.:iti Value of content* 4.051.543..'»» Value of contents ijW.HIt fir' Insurance on building* 3^84,455.00 Insurance on contents *,tit,tt1 ft Insnniiice on contents 2.640.961 .Ml Loss to building* 79:'&gt;.K7N.7r. Loss to buildings 793.67ft.7ti l,oss to contents !«LM,SS7.:U Loss to contents !»21.NS7.:M 1!H4 1!H4 Viilue of Idiildin^s .v T,tll r §t&gt; &gt;"1 Value of buildings. * ."..!U!t.s»Mt.!»:; Value of contents 4.fi."4,us»; s| Value &lt;»f contents 1.654.086.S1 Insurance on Iniililin^- 1.735^88.IM» Insurance on buildings 1.7."i."&gt;,2SS.(M( Insurance on ccmtents lusui-ance on contents 1.4S^.217..t:: 1.488^17 lx&gt;ss to buildinpi 757,292.90 lAHis to buildings 757^2t2.3«l Lm to contents I.115,7J*2.!*5 Loss to contents 1.115.782.95 MM i»ir, Value of luiililinpi s 7.u:C».r.4!MMi Value of buildings s 7.u:C».r.4!MMi Value of contents ■V523.168.U0 Value of contents &amp;£0,1C8.§U Insurance on buildings ."».2l'7.1."il (Mi Insurance on buildings SJS7.151.9II Insurance on contents I.(M(7.:!i'7.imi liOsu to buildings I.M81^24.INI I,oss to contents K7d.7B7.INI i!tn; Value of buildings t 7.:{."&gt;O.s71.im Value of contents .V!:{.-,,177.(mi Insurance on buildings 4,567.798.00 Insurance on contents 4.426.480.&lt;Xl Loss to buildings 7fl.2C8.0ti Loss to contents 1 .1 17.021t.lMi </seg>
            <seg id="p075">STATK I IKK COMMISSION 75 FARM FIRES </seg>
            <seg id="p076"/>
            <seg id="p077">STATE KIKE COMMISSION 77 FA KM KIKKS Ihir statistics id' Farm Fin's by no means show the ri losses ii; \&lt;'l»r;isk;i. We have no way of obtaining losses except from Insurance Companies and though up have repeatedly asked the Farm Fire Insurance Com - |.anits to report to us the losses they sustain in Nebraska only a few companies have complied with our request. The law does not provide a penalty and hence we cannot tone them to give us these figures. The Cnion Fiiv Insurance Company of Lincoln ami Central Mutual of Hastings ii* the only Nebraska Companies reporting to us and they have promptly reported their losses to our !&gt;&lt;'partmcnt. The .Etna, the Royal and the Farmers Insurance Company, of Cedar Kapids, Iowa, have also n-|M)ited their farm losses to us. Outside of these Com - panies we have recrived no rejM&gt;rts. The fa rm losses in Nebraska amount to a great deal every year. Farmers are not equipped or situated to fight fire and when mice a fire starts it usually proves a total OSS All farms should Im- equipped with water buckets ever ready for use and ladders should lie convenient to use in reaching roofs. Kspecial care should lie taken by the fanner for lie larks the protection of the Fire Depart - ments that eitv folks have. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 STATK KIRK COMMISSION CAU8E8 OF FARM FIKKS Bunk wagon, sparks fro. Burning out humble bees Bon-fires 1 Chimney, sparks from Chimneys defective || Communicated 1 Cigaret stub 1 Friction from pulley 1 Grease taking fire on the stove 1 Gasoline stove, caught from « Incendiarv Lamp, caught from Locomotive, sparks from Lightning IS Matches, sparks from Matches and mice Matches and children Matches dropped carelessly. Oil stove, caught from Prairie Fires. Rubbish burning. Stove, caught from Stove pipe through roof, floors and wood partitions. . »&gt; Smoking pole cat out of ground Straw stacks, caught from Spontaneous combustion Threshing machine, carnrht from 9 Tramp, set by Unknown 4S Ventilator in floor 1 18* </seg>
            <seg id="p079">STATE FIRE COMMISSION 79 FARM FIRES. The following table shows the number and location of country fires in Nebraska reported country fires in Nebraska reported jka reported to us from December 15, 1916: Comities Number of Fires to us from December 15. 1915, to December 15, 1916 : 15. 1915, to Decembt 15, 1916: !• Towns Counties Towns Counties Number of Fires Adams Gage Angus Nuckolls . Arapahw Furnas . . . Armour Pawnee . . Ashton Sherman Bartlett Wheeler Bartley Red Willow Bellevue Sarpy Bloomington Franklin Belgrade Nance Blue Hill Webster . . Boelus Howard . . Brainard Butler Adams • Gage 1 • Gage 1 Angus • Nuckollx i Nuckolls i Arapahoe Armour Ash ton . • Furnas 3 Furna8 3 • Pawnee j Pawnee j Sherman 1 • s^hermau 1 Bartlett Bartley Bellevue . Wheeler 3 Wheeler 3 Q • Red Willow .........; 1 Red Willow 1 • s «'py '. 1 s «'-py 1 Bloomington Belgrade . . . . Franklin \ Franklin \ . Nance 2 Nance 2 Blue Hill Boelus . . . Webster \ Webster \ . Howard 1 Howard 1 Brainard Crawford Cams . . . Butler 1 Butler 1 Crawford Dawen . Dawep 1 Dawes 1 Carns Keye Pahi . Keye Paha 1 Keye Paha 1 Central City Merrick . . . Central City Chapman . . . Merrick 2 Merrick 2 Chapman Merrick . . . Merrick \ Merrick 1 Cedar Rapids Columbu* . . . Cedar Rapids Boone . Roone 3 Boone 3 .. Columbus Platte . Platte 2 l'latte 2 Cozad Cozad Dawson . . . Dawsoii 7 DawRon 7 Chadron Dawes . . . Chadron . Chambers Dannebrog Dorsev . . . . Dawes 1 Dawes 1 Chambers Holt .Holt 2 Holt 2 Dannebrog Howard . . . Howard 3 Howard 3 Dorsey Holt . Holt 1 Holt 1 Erik Cherry . . . Erik . Cherry 1 Cherry 1 Edison Elsmeiv El wood Fmerson Edison Furnas . . . . Fnrnas 2 FurnaR •&gt; Elsmeiv Cherry . . . . Cherry 1 Cherry 1 Elwood Oosper . . . . Gosper 1 Gosper 1 Emerson Dakota . . . . Dakota 1 Dakota 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 STATK KIRK HIM MISSION Kltia Howard 1 Kustis frontier Fullerton Franklin Friend . . Nance 1 Franklin 1 Saline 1 Fairmont Greeley . Fillniorc Greelev Guide Rock Geering . . . Webster Scotts Bluff Grand Island Gibson Flail 4 Buffalo Glenvil Adams 1 Hurtington Hazard . . Cedar 1 Sherman l Hastings Adams pj Hay Springs Horace .... Sheridan 1 Greeley Humphrey Helca Platte 1 Hooper 1 Knox Knox 1 Kearney Leafdale Lowell Buffalo Kimball 1 Buffalo Lexington Mvrtle . . Morrill Lincoln 1 Mason Citv Mr Cook . . . Custer i Red Willow 1 Mildale Tuster 1 MrCool Junction Maxwell York : 1 Lincoln 1 Meek Holt I Northport Rock % Lincoln I North Platte. North Loup. . NHigh Lonp 1 Antelope 2 Norfolk Madison 1 New Port XelBOn . . Rock 1 Xiickollg 1 Norway Thomas 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">STATE I IRK to\l MISSION 81 Omnoud Pierre * O'Neill Holt 2 Oxford Harlan i •! . Potter Cheyenne 1 IVtersburg Boone 1 Watt* Saunders 1 I'otica Dixon 5 I'i. krell Gage 1 I'oole Buffalo , 1 I'laiuview Pierce 1 Pullman Therrv 1 Pong Lake Rook 1 liiivcnna Buffalo 1 Randolph Cedar 2 •' Kooedale &lt; rartield I St. Michael Buffalo 1 St. Paul Howard 1 Shelton Hall ■ Stiiatt Holt 1 Summerset Lincoln ' Shelton Buffalo • Silver rreek Merrick - ■&gt; Spauldinjj Merrick 1 S&lt;-otts Bluff S&lt;ott8 Bluff I Superior Nuckolls 1 •&gt; Stedward Boone - Thurinaii Rock 1 Tniiiibull flav 1 Verdi^re Rnox 1 Valentine Cherrv 2 •&gt; Wood River Thurston 1 Walthill Thurnt&lt;»n 1 Wood Lake Therrv 1 Walbach Greelev 1 Whitnev ! )awe»» 1 Wallace Lincoln 1 Wa hash Tass 1 IKS </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>