<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00085.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>STATE OF NEBRASKA Department of FIRE PREVENTION Thirtieth Annual Report 1938</title>
               <date value="1938">1938</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA R. L. Cochran, Governor Department of FIRE PREVENTION Thirtieth Annual Report 1938 OFFICE PERSONNEL Horace M. Davis o» , r,. „ . , I.E. Clement, Chief Clerk Omahai Nebraska Chas. M. Horhara, Chief c-i« » • it p n i!i« 1 j Electrical Inspector K. v. Jsloodcooa r&gt;i . • it Claude O. McCoy "S eC, tr! Ca, 1 T lnsP«'°r RoUand A. Fried:::! g^™ 11 nBPector F. H. Shirmer.. Hectnea Inspector W. F. Bouchard.. ~~" "S"o^ J«»Pector Hal A. Pierce, Clerk". ■"?.Im^°' , .« Electrical Inspection </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE OF NEBRASKA SUMMARY AND Records for the Year 1938 COMPARATIVE FIGURES FOR TEN YEARS 1938 Fires 2,037 Deaths 69 Injuries 200 Property Damace 51.929,227 ' 1937 Fires 2.179 Deaths 79 Injuries 562 Property Damage 52.049.723 1936 Fires 2,966 Deaths 92 Injuries 305 Property Damage 52.314.011i 1935 Fires 2,120 Deaths 79 Injuries 183 Property Damage 82,104,899 1934 Fires 2,082 Deaths 69 Injuries 157 Property Damage $2,031-444 1933 Fires 1,969 Deaths 55 Injuries 194 Property Damage SI 833.880 1932 Fires 2,325 Deaths 55 Injuries 212 Property Damage 5:i.0ti0,344 1931 Fires 2,085 Deaths 61 Injuries 214 Property Damage 83,106,633 1930 Fires 2,102 Deaths 34 Injuries 135 Property Damage $2,641,425 1929 Fires 2,001 Deaths 48 Injuries 172 Property Damage 82,945.806 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL Hon. R. L. Cochran, Governor of Nebraska. : Lincoln, Nebraska. Honored Sir: In compliance with the law, Compiled Statutes 81-5529, I have the honor to submit herewith for your approval the Thirtieth Annual Report of the Department of Fire Prevention. /gj§^^*X Respectfully Submitted, /i^^^^^m HORACE M. DAVIS, V Stale Fire Marshal. February 15, 1939. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT'S FINANCIAL STATUS The income and expenses of the department for the past three years has been quite uniform. From 1931 to 1934, the annual income of the department was reduced from §21,024.31 to 815,072.20, but during the same period the annual expenses rose from 518,066.18 to 522,697.93. The balance in the fund was reduced during 1934 from J23.545.48 to $15,040.51. The table below gives the income, expenditures and balances for the past ten years. It has been necessary to limit the activities of the department be - cause of the decreasing funds. The table shows that 5978.60 less was used for expenses in 1938 than in 1937. The office expenses for 193S were 5598.60 less than for 1937, and the field expenses were 8132.21 less. There is still a balance in the department fund of 82.759.55 at the be - ginning of the calendar year. Since the income of the department is limited by law to v'ath of one per cent of the lire insurance premiums of stock companies and foreign mutuals, and J£th of one per cent of the premiums of state - wide domestic mutuals, the activities of the department must be limited to what may be done with this uncertain income. The inter-insurance exchanges pay nothing to the department fund, claiming exemption under the law. The present statute should be reworded to make it clear that under - writing companies shall hot consider reinsurance! collected or ceded, in computing the fire marshal tax. It is now so interpreted. A bill to correct the law is now before the legislature. COMPARATIVE RECEIPTS, EXPENDITURES AND BALANCES FOR TEN YEARS Year Receipts Expenditures Balances 1929 322,330.48 821,086.99 $23,022.96 1930 22,295.13 22,119.50 23,798.53 1931 . 21,024.31 18.066.18 26.750.66 1932 — — 18.429.55 21,640.37 23,545.84 1933 14,456.93 22982.36 15,040.41 1934 15,072.20 22-697.93 7,414.68 1935 15,852.74 17,997.22 5,270.20 1936 15,904.10 16,173.43 5,000.89 1937 16,586.13 18,046.31 3 540.71 1938 16,286.55 17-067.71 2,759.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">r — INCOME AND EXPENSE -, 1928 1929 1930 1931 I 1932 T 1933 I 1934 1 1935 I 1936 I 1937 I man I S 23,000 : 22.000 ■* — - ■- -: 20.000 x /' TISZ.; ~Nr — 19.000 V^^ X — X" laiooo — N *^ — — - — \y \ V 17.000 • V; — =^I = 15.000 V — ~Z^^^Z ~__~^^ == I 1 i i i i i i H — T I I I I 2 . „ INSPECTION ORDERS ISSUED 2 17.000 | I I ..L I 1 T 1 1 1 1 a NUMBER OF ARSON INVESTIGATIONS AND CONVICTIONS 5 0 7*- INCOME V _ 3 g ~} c EXPENSES X iSi. « I Hio *- ORDERS ISSUED &gt; / 2 L ARSON INVESTIGATIONS \ ,• 130 / I ANNUAL CONVICTIONS "\ ? ja* 120 S 2 is^'. — I T 1 \ f — 80 — a &gt;' —~£? V — a S==/ s OFFICE OF NEBRASKA STATE FIRE MARSHAL </seg>
            <seg id="p006">STATE OF NEBRASKA RECEIPTS AND EXPENDITURES INCOME Balance on Hand January 1, 1933 5 s 3,^ 4 °- 7^ Tax from Premium Income r— 1G.25G.55 Total Funds to Cover 1938 Expenditures 519.827.26 EXPENDITURES Salaries $10,038.67 Office Expenses Supplies S 115.49 Printing 246.40 Stamps 215.00 Tel. &amp; Tel. iiG $ G Miscellaneous 159.72 883.57 FIELD EXPENSES Railroad Transportation 52.14 Automobile Transportation 3,070.60 Hotels and Meals 1,959.45 Miscellaneous 130.28 5,212.47 Fire Chiefs Reports—Fees 833.00 Total Expenditures 17,067.71 Balance January 1, 1939 S 2,759.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION FIRES IN BUILDINGS COMPILED AS TO OCCUPANCY Bulldln,, _ : &#132; on,stßU _ Omaha Lincoln Citle. Rural Total lotals 515 158 1170 62i Zf'Tr, --** ~ 5 ~^ l^ -^ Motor Vehicles 36 1Q g? Apartments 9Q ln 28 19 14 0 61 Oarages m b 42 15 95 14 166 atores „~ _ . „ xt.r. •» 5 10S 6 15 « Mf g. Plants 14 3 6 2 25 Offices. -_v 9 ! 23 „ 33 Barns and Sheds 9 8 74 164 255 Hotels c 6 1 15 0 22 Warehouses ~ „ t j • „„, 7.3 14 2 26 Laundries &amp; Cleaning Plants 5 2 6 0 13 Cafes and Lunch Counters 4 0 3-&gt; 0 36 Shops ...... 1 3 0 7 1 11 Filling Stations ._ 2 2 26 0 30 Schools ... , 0 Coal Sheds .... 9 n ,/ , .! Pool Ha„s ....... .. ~ 2 n , 2 0 7 0 9 Bakeries 9 n n „ &lt;! 0 9 0 11 Barber and Beauty Parlors 2 0 11 1 14 Brooders and Chicken houses 1 1 21 100 123 Churches , A ,„ 1 0 12 1 14 Theaters , n . 1 0 6 0 7 Printing Shops 10 2 0 3 Lumber Yards 1 1 11 0 13 Granaries and Corncribs 0 0 0 34 34 Cream Stations 0 0 13 0 13 Elevators 0 0 9 1 10 Hog Houses 0 0 3 10 13 Dance Halls „ „ 2 4 6 Halls and Lodges 0 13 0 4 Miscellaneous 3 1 22 46 72 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">STATE OF NEBRASKA FIRES COMPILED AS TO CAUSE Oatstata Can,M Omaha Lincoln Cities Rural Total Chimneys-Overheated and defective 25 6 63 37 131 Electricity-Except Small Devices 54 13 78 20 165 Explosions 0 0 6 1 7 Exposure 5 4 71 9 89 Friction Sparks 7 0 19 1 '27 Hot Ashes-Open Fires 5 3 17 1 2 6 Hot Grease-Ignition of 5 0 16 1 22 Hot Irons-Including Electric 5 2 10 0 17 Incendiary 11 2 9 7 29 Lightning 9 5 13 47 74 Smoking and Matches 90 22 101 25 °38 Children Playing with Matches 18 6 24 6 51 Causes Known but not Classified _ 4 5 30 14 53 Open Lights-Flame .._ 15 6 18 9 4S Petroleum and Its Products 11 1 33 \\ 59 Rubbish and Litter 5 2 11 1 \n Sparks Arising from Combustion 23 8 43 10 90 Sparks from chimney on Roof 35 23 77 19 154 Spontaneous Combustion 43 3 3(5 29 110 Stoves, Furnaces and their pipes ... 22 S 82 28 140 Stoves-Gasoline and Kerosene 28 7 128 00 223 Unknown 28 23 IG2 ICS 378 PLANS FOR PUBLIC BUILDINGS Blue prints and plans for school buildings, auditoriums and struc - tures where the public will assemble are submitted for the approval of the state fire marshal's office. This is a requirement of PWA and WPA. During the year plans for 37 public buildings were checked for exits and seating arrangements. Architects are urged to spot locations for the proper kind of chemical extinguishers. Some are recommending boxes of sand in the furnace room. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Graphic Report of Fires Reported by Fire Chiefs i nnm ,„ ■ property values and insurancf carried thousands 1929 1930 1931 1932 | 1933 | 1934 | 1935 1936 1937 | 1938 I $45,000 LEGEND 1 *^ \ — — - PROPERTY VALUES INVOLVED 40.000 yS-^ . \ INSURANCE CARRIED I I V PROPERTY LOSSES 35,000 \ d | NUMBER OF FIRES REPORTED * — ' . , 30,000 \ Is^__S I I \S &lt; S \ ° 15.000 s7^ "v \ / ,* : — - g io.ooo z 1 1 1 I I I *s|^' I I I I I 1-3 r— — i PROPERTY LOSSES ° $3,500 I | | [ I I ■"■] I a 3,000 : i 2,500 jS ■ .\~ 2 2 - 000 i 1.500 **- W i 1 I i 2; ■ ■ ■ ■ i ' ' ' NUMBER FIRES REPORTED 2 3.000 I I I 111 I I I I 2.500 ~?~^ 2,000 1,500 '..-"" : : ! I 1,000 OFFICE OF NEBRASKA STATE FIRE MARSHAL </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 STATE OF NEBRASKA SUMMARY OF ACTIVITIES OF THE DEPARTMENT Number of Public Buildings Inspected . 7,289 Inspection Orders Issued " 13'iy.! Dated Orders Issued 6 26° Orders Complied with While Inspectois were in Town I*Bo7 Orders Reported to the Office as Complied With ~ 6,661 Buildings Ordered Repaired "__"" ' 32 Buildings Ordered Removed-Condemned '_ 48 Doors of School Buildings Changed to Swing Outward 32 Doors of Other Buildings Changed to Swing Outward 21 New Fire Escapes Installed on Public Buildings .1.11 6 Fire Escapes Repaired on School Buildings ~ 33 Fire Escapes on School Buildings Lowered to Floor Level .. 1 Panic Bar Locks Installed ti&amp; Fire Alarms Installed on School Buildings 60 Public Buildings Complelely Electrically Overhauled ~_ 107 Public Buildings Electrically Repaired 3,171 Kerosene Tanks Removed from Buildings and Buried 131 Miscellaneous Orders Issued 2 850 Suspected Incendiary Fiies Investigated ' 512 New Fire Chieis Commissioned 7g Fire Departments Organized and Reorganized .) Plans for Public Buildings Examined and Approved " 37 Public Addresses Given 7 c FIRE LOSSES BY MONTHS AS REPORTED BY FIRE CHIEFS 1937 1930 * lonth No. Fires Fire Losses No. Fires I-1.. I os.r. January 215 $ 230-916 198 S 2*5,137 February 176 282-405 157 85 503 March 167 124.291 156 132,498 April 200 173.508 161 1ie!792 May 152 103-249 113 134,359 June H9 98&gt;n , 5 CJ7 &#132;, July 195 170i y ]4 142 221,414 August 156 110,216 189 192,937 September 210 135,460 106 125,054 October 186 155,590 205 173,383 November 233 180,842 205 184 996 December 247 262,272 308 264,198 .2,179 52,049,723 2,037 81,929,227 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DEPARTMENT OP FIRE PREVENTION ARSON INVESTIGATIONS During 1938 investigations were made of 92 fires of unknown origin. Investigations were made in 48 counties, and 43 fires were rural, 49 in cities and villages. In four cases no insurance was carried. Stock fire insurance companies were interested in C3 fires and assessment com - ..panies in 33 (not counting duplications) and reciprocal exchanges were "involved in two cases. In counties north of the Platte River 26 called for 40 cases, and 22 South Platte counties had 52 investigations. In this connection it is significant that three confessions and convictions came from north of the river and, of the remaining twelve convictions, there were six confessions and six jury verdicts. FIRKS OF QUESTIONABLE ORIGIN, 1938. It is the responsibility of every fire chief, peace officer, insurance company, fire insurance adjuster, and of every good citizen to report to the state fire marshal's office 'all fires that are not clear as to their origin. These frequently are proven to be dust explosion, spontaneous combustion of hay or grain, or the revival of a bonfire. Not all are presumed to be incendiary because the cause is unknown immediately but they are often important because they may point to the way towards avoidance of similar experiences. Investigations may reasonably be broken down as follows: Fiies of Questionable Origin 92 Thought to be of accidental origin 39 Thought to be of Incendiary Origin 53 To Collect Insurance 35 Malicious or insane motives . _ 14 Inconclusive Evidence 4 Persons Investigated gj Complaints Filed, 1935: Arson of Different Degrees lg Insanity or Kindred Causes _ 5 Cases Pending 3 Sentenced to Penitentiary or Reformatory 8 Discharged at Preliminary Hearing " 1 Acquitted in District Court 1 Juvenile Court Cases -5 Paroled Under Amended Complaints _ 3 Insane and Incompetent Committed ._ 2 Fugutives from Arrest " j Suicides and Deaths ~ 3 Dismissed-Technicalities 2 Dismissed-Insufficient Evidence '" j Pending Jury Trials 2 Discharged after Plea of Guilty . </seg>
            <seg id="p012">STATE OF NEBRASKA FIREMEN'S TRAINING COURSE The initial effort to organize firemen's schools was taken in Feb' ruary of 1938 when a three-days, state-wide school was held at Grand Island. Fire departments were invited to send four representatives. Nearly half of the volunteer fire departments in Nebraska were repre - sented by 388 enrollees, which was far greater than had been antici - pated. "Smoky" Rogers and J. Burr Taylor came out from Chicago at the expense of the Western Actuarial Bureau of the National Board of Fire Underwriters and were in immediate charge. They had the loyal assis - tance of many Nebraska firemen. Because there is no state money available for firemen's training courses, the Grand Island Fire Department offered their facilities for the school at the new southside station and at the drill tower; aLo with equipment and personnel. In the closing hour of the Grand Island school, it was decided by these in attendance that another school should be arranged for 1939. Demands were also voiced for four divisional schools, at Noifolk, Alli - ance, Holdrege and Seward. The dates for the latter wore fixed for one day each in the last week of February. The .1939 state-wide school will be held again at Grand Island, Tuesday, Wednesday and Thursday, April 25, 26 and 27. The legislatuie has been asked to make a small appropriation to carry the expenses of the schools, but no funi's can be available for the coming year. Hence, the expense of the Grand Island school must be largely financed by a small registration fee. Director Horace Davis and committeemen Van Fleet of Hastings and Mayor Wood of Seward welcome the suggestions of firemen as to the subjects to be discussed at all schools. CARD INDEX ON ALL FIRES With WPA assistance, a card file has been completed of all fires reported to the fire marshal's office since the department was organized. A special file was early made, and is being kept up to date, of all fires of suspicious origin and of the persons investigated. Reference to the "suspect file" affords information to insurers as to moral hazards. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION FIRE PREVENTION WEEK Appropriate activities were carried on the week of October 3-10 in more than one hundred known communities to bring to public atten - tion the hazards of fire to life and property. Generally, the volunteer fire departments took the initiative, and with the cordial and appreciat - ed co-operation of the public school. Probably Seward County took the lead in getting the fire preven - tion theme over to the rural schools. Inexpensive but appreciated awards were given to pupils who wrote essays or jingles to show their interest. Prague firemen followed their custom of driving their rural fire truck to country schools to demonstrate what organized rural fire protection can mean. The fire marshal's office distributed 10,000 home inspection blanks to schools and the response by teachers and pupils was highly gratify - ing. With the aid of a loud-speaker attached to his car, the fire marshal talked fire prevention to more than ten thousand pupils in nineteen schools. He made two radio talks and addressed several civic organ - izations and one fire department. President J. E. Cryan of the Nebraska Fire Prevention Association, Brandeis Theater Building, Omaha, is prepared to furnish speakers to fire departments, schools and civic groups for fire prevention week, or on other occasions. His organization can loan appropriate fire prevention films to those who have projectors. Literature, posters, etc., can be procured from the National Fire Protection Association, 60 Batterymarch St., Boston, or the National Board of Fire Underwriters, 85 Johns St., New York. The fire marshal's facilities are available to all comers. But too frequently requests for dates and printed supplies have come too late to be complied with. SPRING CLEAN-UP CAMPAIGNS Weather conditions are apt to influence the date fixed for clean-up week. Last year the eastern third of the state became active the second week in April, the central third got busy the next week and the northwest section cleaned up the last week in April. One chief in a village of 350 people offered to drive a fire marshal all over the viUage and pay him one dollar for each vacant lot that showed rubbish or that had not been cleared of weeds. Not one neglected lot was found. With poor equipment that little department has kept its fire loss to $28 in five years. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">STATE OF NEBRASKA FIRE CHIEFS, ATTENTION, PLEASE It is the custom of the fire marshal's office to send all fire depart - ment communications to the chiefs. Not infrequently complaint comes from other members of the department that the chief did not pass the letter or circular on to the clerk or members. Mayors and councilmen are often interested as much as the firemen in inspection problems, in fire prevention week, or clean-up week campaigns. In some cases, mayors are directly circularized from the fire marshal's office. But it would cost too much to revise the mailing list to send printed matter to interested chiefs in some towns and interested clerks or secretaries in other towns. The chiefs will be helpful in making all circular matter available to the whole department. 'HOT" TRACTOR FUEL Just as this report goes to the printer, a new matter has come up for attention. Because there is no gas-lax exemption for motor driven farm machinery in Nebraska* some of the oil refiners have developed and are marketing a tax-exempt tractor fuel that is being sold at filling stations at wholesale. Tractor fuels vary widely as to flash point and explosive tendencies. These differences cannot be known without chemical analysis. The state law provides that all containers of flammable liquids in sizes larger than a quart shall be labeled according to their contents, that gasoline shall be kept in all-red containers, that both bujer and seller are equally guilty for filling or keeping wrongly painted or un - labeled containers. It, therefore, becomes necessary to classify all tractor fuels in the same class as gasoline and to require that it shall be handled only in red containers upon which shall be stenciled, TRACTOR FUEL, HIGH - LY EXPLOSIVE. Firemen and peace officers are directed to report all violations to their county attorneys. Many cities and villages will meet the issue locally by passing reg - ulatory ordinances. The tendency for filling stations in up-town loca - tions to handle explosives in wholesale lots is admittedly hazardous to adjoining property. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION SCHOOL FIRES— NO LIVES LOST There were fourteen school fires in Nebraska in seven rural and seven cities and villages where losses ran into considerable sums. There were other blazes reported where damage was slight and fire depart - ments were not called. The estimated value of all the properties- buildings and contents - at hazard was 8466,700, with .$335,250 insurance and damages estimated at 8109,647. The losses sustained were sometimes less than one - fourth of the values and one-third of the insurance carried. Mascot, Burchard and Cedar Rapids school fires were practically total losses, all from unknown causes, but probably spontaneous com - bustion in two of them. Prompt fire department action saved Scribner $165,000 and Beatrice $135,000. Three rural schools in Franklin and Cuming counties were total losses, partially insured, but four other dis - trict school buildings within reasonable reach of volunteer fire depart - ments suffered light damages. Bad chimneys, wet cobs, defective stove - pipes and combustion in coal bins are the most frequent causes of school fires. SCHOOL FIRE PREVENTION MANUAL Twenty thousand copies of a 100 page book devoted to teaching fire prevention to school pupils was issued by the department during the year. The preparation of the copy is credited to Miss Cloe C. Bald - ridge, assistant in the office of state superintendent of schools. The state insurance department paid the printing bill. The manuals were distributed at the beginning of the school year to all teachers through the county superintendents of schools. They are designed as text books for pupils and for the assistance of the teachers who are required by law to devote thirty minutes per month to instruction in fire prevention. The school manuals are unique in that similar publications are not elsewhere issued through cooperation of state school superintendents and fire marshals. The calls for copies from other states are heavy but welcomed. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">STATE OF NEBRASKA FIRE DRILLS FOR SCHOOLS Firemen and school heads are aware that there is a state law that requires monthly fire drills in public and parochial schools. No hard and fast program has been adopted in Nebraska, as has been done in other states. The purpose of drills is to prepare pupils against the frenzy that might result in panic in case of a sudden fire alarm during school hours. Orderly exit is more important than great haste. There should be no pause for anything after the alarm sounds. Pupils should march in order across the street to make way for fire apparatus and rescue traffic. School executives who stubbornly refuse to arrange for fire drills are subject to demerits on their records. It is the duty of the fire chiefs, acting as deputy state fire marshals, to see to it that satisfactory periodic drills are held in all city and village schools. DWELLING HOUSE AND APARTMENT FIRES AS REPORTED BY FIRE CHIEFS Couaty 1938 1937 County 1938 1937 Adams 21 23 Dakota _..... II 19 Antelope 9 7 Dawes 6 5 Arthur, 0 0 Dawson .14 10 Banner 0 1 Deuel . 3 I Elaine 0 C Dixon ... 7 11 Boone 6 6 Dodge _. 18 37 Box Butte 2 2 Douglas -._'. 321 294 Boyd 0 0 Dundy 1 3 Brown 2 4 Fillmore 8 11 Buffalo 19 12 Fianklir. __•- S 4 Burt 10 12 Frontier .-'. 4 3 Butler 9 6 Furnas 7 7 Cass .. .22 16 Gage ..29 21 Cedar 6 8 Garden ,_. 1 0 Chase _ 3 l' Garfield 2 2 Cherry 1 4 Gcsper 2 1 Cheyenne 4 3 Grant 2 5 Clay 4 12 Greeley 9 6 CoUax 6 4 Hall 36 33 Cuming .. .._ 6 3 Hamilton 7 8 Custer 8 16 Harlan 10 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DEPARTMENT OF EIRE PREVENTION County 1938 1937 County 1938 1917 Hayes 2 0 Pierce 10 7 Hitchcock 2 2 Platte 6 5 Holt J 6 1 Polk 6 5 Hooker 0 0 Red Willow 12 16 Howard 4 3 Richardson 7 20 Jefferson 19 14 Rock 0 3 Johnson 2 11 Saline 11 13 Kearney 3 5 Sarpy G 6 Keith 3 2 Saunders 24 18 Keya Paha 1 1 Scotts Bluff 7 11 Kimball 4 2 Seward 8 13 Knox 7 13 Sheridan 1 5 3 Lancaster 108 121 Sherman 3 7 Lincoln __ 19 26 Sioux 1 0 Logan 2 0 Stanton 6 2 Loup 1 0 Thayer.... 4 7 Madison 22 21 Thomas _ 0 0 Merrick __j 7 5 Thurston : 3 2 Morrill 1 4 Valley 7 5 Nance _ 5 11 Washington ;.. 14 10 Nemaha __ ]1 8 Wayne 2 4 Nuckolls . .... 7 2 Webster 4 3 Otoe ....... 8 16 Wheeler .... 0 0 Pawnee ... ... 10 9 York 8 16 Perkins . 5 1 Phelps 8 3 1,074 1,093 RURAL FIRE PROTECTION Despite the unworkable provisions of the well-intentioned law pass - ed by the 1937 Legislature to encourage the organization of Rural Fire Protection Districts, the volunteer firemen have continued with their educational promotional work in their various communities. Probably twenty or more rural trucks have been purchased and put into service through the joint financing of the villages and the farms in their trade territory. Firemen hope that the 1939 Legislature will enact proposed laws to simplify and make practical the organization of Rural Fire Pro - tection Districts. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">STATE OF NEBRASKA RURAL ELECTRICAL INSPECTION When rural electrification came, almost over night, into Nebraska, It seemed necessary to set up some organization for an inspection ser - vice that would establish a uniformity as to class of workmanship and materials used and make for safety of lives and property of the farmers. Upon the invitation of the customers, wiremen and REA officials, and with the approval of the Governor and Attorney General, the fire marshal's office assumed the responsibility for setting up an inspection service. Inasmuch as the statutory income for the fire marshal's office could not legally be used for electrical inspection service, an inde - pendent organization was set up, with Chas. M. Horham as chief in - spector, financed on a fee basis and operating at cost. With the co-operation of, the Department of Vocational Education, more than thirty three-days schools for electrical wiremen have been conducted in different REA districts under Mr. Horham's directions. A fee of $3.50 is charged for each rural inspection, with necessary reinspections at one dollar each. The local inspector does about four jobs each day he works and receives $2.50 each for salary and expenses. The other dollar pays for supervision and office expenses, with nothing for the fire marshal's office. RURAL ELECTRICAL INSPECTION BUREAU FINANCIAL REPORT Prom November 18, 1937, to December 31, 1938 Total Cash Received $13,932.31 Total Disbursements 13,618.13 Cash on Hand ... , , $ 314.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION NUMBER OF INSPECTIONS BY DISTRICTS Orlsinal Dlstrlct Inspection? Ke-insprctlons Lancaster Co. Rural P. P. District 405 101 Chimney Rock " " " " 215 38 Polk Co. " " " " 342 '..".... 1 Burt Co. 423 "__~~~"~~_ 80 Southern Nebr. " " " '• 493 20 Cuming Co. ' « 41 g 2~~Z~1"~~SZ 40 Eastern Nebr. #1 "'."]'! " 21 n #2 379 I~~~™~l~ 72 #3 1 0 Howard Co. " " " " 219 _ . g S&lt;iulheastern Nebr. " " " " 15 q I.oup River 245 " 29 Norris 203 ..-."-.".I"" 40 Roosevelt " "• " " 16 _ _ 5 Cedar-Knox ". " " f* 209 53 Buffalo Co. 74 _ . . 9 3,681 497 COMPARISON OF RURAL FIRE LOSSES There were 459 rural fires reported by fire chiefs in 1938 compared to 391 for 1937. The reports show a total loss in 299 of the fires for 1938 and 236 for 1937. No lire losses were reported by fire chiefs in seventeen counties, all in the western and northern part of the state They are: Arthur, Banner, Blaine, Box Butte, Brown, Cherry, Cheyenne Dawes, Dundy, Hooker, Keith, Keya Paha, Kimball, Loup, McPherson! Morrill and Thomas. In the reports from insurance companies of losses paid, there were four counties in which no losses were reported. They are Blaine, Logan, Loup and McPherson. Rural losses sustained, as reported by fire chiefs, were $635,7^5 in 1938 compared to $674,180 for 1937. The total amount of insurance car - ried on rural property at hazard, as reported by fire chiefs, was 5729, - -865. The insurance companies reported rural losses paid to the amount of $515,345 on 1,352 claims. The apparent discrepency between the number of fires reported and the claims paid is due to the fact that several claims are often paid on one fire, and that small claims are paid on which the fire chiefs are not asked to report. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">FIRE LOSSES IN 34 CITIES WITH POPULATION OF 2,500 AND OVER FIRE CHIEFS INSURANCE COMPANIES PER CAPITA No. of Losses Paid Combined No. or Losies Claims (Not Repotted Losses Loss Loss Cltl " Population Fires Reported Paid by Chiefs) Reported 19SS 6 Yr. Ave. Totals and Averages ..482,628 1,071 $618,376 1,775 $59,789 $677,454 $1.40 $1.51 Alliance 6,669 1 300 11 1,393 1,693 0.24 0.99 Auburn 3,068 10 -1,625 12 696 5,321 1.73 1.70 Aurora - 2,715 9 1,637 9 207 1,844 .67 .80 H Beatrice 10,297 29 6,221 78 1,547 7,768 .75 3.52 o Blair 2,791 17 2,910 8 160 3,070 1.10 2.70 Broken Bow 2,715 6 4,478 7 93 4,571 . 1.61 4.13 g Chadron 4,606 13 8,285 18 600 8,885 1.92 1.06 g Columbus 6,898 7 2.68S 13 837 3,525 .58 1.62 | Cl * ete - .-.- 2.865 6 154 6 572 726 .25 1.16 Fairbury ........ — .6,192 27 3,630 32 992 4,612 .74 1.86 Falls City . 5,787 8 23,850 21 889 24,739 4.25 2.68 Fremont 11,407 26 10,435 55 1,642 12,077 1.09 2.10 Gering 2,531 4 31 4 . 282 313 .12 .24 Grand Island 18,041 5-1 13,945 63 2,689 16,834 .93 1.33 Hastings -, 15,490 47 21,149 40 948 22,097 1.42 2.28 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Holdrege . .. 3263 6 3,590 13 673 4,263 1.30 1.83 Kearney 8,575 8 3 176 25 3,338 6,514 .77 2.38 Lexington 2,962 4 755 4 46 801 .27 2.69 Lincoln ... . .-„..-. 79,592 165 77,432 250 5,578 83,011 1.09 .71 McCook 6,688 16 3,945 18 647 4,592 .68 60 O Nebraska City . 7,230 3 7,115 30 2,435 9,550 1.19 1.53 3 Norfolk .... 10,717 25 21,416 26 524 21,940 2.05 1.65 H North Platte .... 12,061 27 6,528 34 2,538 9,066 .75 .71 1 Omaha 214,006 496 349,911 871 24,264 374,175 1.74 1.55 H Platlsmouth 3.739 9 2,534 11 151 2,688 .70 3.26 *" Schuyler .... 2,588 1 900 6 109 1,009 .39 .36 I Scottsbluff 8,465 15 1,862 29 1,798 3,660 .43 65 B Seward 2,737 4 232 10 109 341 .12 .31 2 s Wn«y — a36 1 1,500 8 458 1,958 .59 54 § South Sioux City 3,927 7 4.042 15 784 4,826 1.23 1.47 5 Superior 3,044 3 17,210 19 666 17,876 5.87 1.54 Wahoo 2,689 5 3,508 3 27 3,535 1.31 2.26 Wymore _ 2,860 11 1,926 9 185 2,111 .73 2.92 I York - 5.712 11 6,556 14 1,907 8,463 1.48 4.03 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">FIRE LOSSES BY COUNTIES AS REPORTED BY FIRE CHIEFS AND FIRE INSURANCE COMPANIES REPORTED UY FIRE CHIEFS REPORTED BY INSURANCE COMPANIES No. or Value of Insurance Losses No. Claims Insurance Losses Counties Fires Property Carried Estimated Paid Carried Paid Totals „ 2,037 $23,985,750 $20,047,427 SI, 929,227 6,142 $54,300,082 . $1,405,292 Adams 53 316,570 250,885 44,651 190 592,590 84,193 w Antelope 22 63,385 38,397 19,143 44 65,090 15,325 &gt; Arthur 0 1 2,600 431 n Banner ... 0 3 5,153 347 O Blaine 0 () Z Boone 19 54.93S 65,500 34,971 38 78,200 7,437 g Box Butte 4 12,450 6,900 2,375 33 474,530 6,449 W Boyd 2 5,050 3,200 417 10 11,600 4,197 » Brown . 5,665 3,400 600 22 43,360 2,365 &gt; Buffalo 40 135.941 68,270 29,789 94 885,227 24,903 Burt 20 55,075 39,075 19,895 43 56,265 5,200 Butler 22 5-1,295 46,710 28,780 54 205,736 17,656 Cass 57 184,448 126,606 74,360 89 158,100 56,948 Cedar , 18 85,690 57,875 2.1,952 44 109,250 9,059 Chase . 6 12,100 5,800 5,423 ' 6 43,710 7,715 Cherry I 16,400 10,700 885 13 28,117 4,770 Cheyenne 5 9,425 5,943 3.350 32 60,920 6,124 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Cfay . 16 38 i230 1538g „ .^ Colfax lo 23^25 .^ j.^ 24 Custer l 6 50&gt;480 27 ;J56 .^ 2y ? Custer 16 50(450 27&gt;350 16658 ( , o 270305 i67i7 Dakota ]2 46(175 ,, 9 y - 0 W6S 15 320 ' 010 173,200 8,945 48 640,720 11,670 M Dawson 24 186,450 .17,300 100,018 73 152,655 22,493 | Deuel 4 16.855 10 ,000 6,460 6 18,600 2668 g "' X ; n I6 (iI ' 85 » "2.095 17,028 27 53,875 10,040 3 Dodge 49 45i)i6 ,5 mm 156 889,096 29 784 5 Douglas 506 12,629,052 11,244,235 392,594 1,883 32,155,886 321,406 3 Dundy 2 3(300 g Fillmore .... 12 57,900 33,070 23.233 35 72,635 11,049 2 Franklm 16 42,795 25,050 10,940 27 33,590 7,877 S Frontier 6 10i213 g^ g Furnas 17 74,570 651500 ]G , 150 ?2 22()&gt;692 g °" Be 56 418 ' 070 283,540 15,086 176 1,132,995 20,640 I ?1 e « 2 5 ' 27 ° 3 ' 575 1 ' 550 9 1M" 2,213 § 9 37,340 15,500 1,718 15 21,150 1,191 3 ?° SPer -- 5 14 ' 950 8-050 9.960 14 16,486 5,901 § Grant 6 18,400 12,050 6,175 6 16,380 1654 Greeley 12 38,365 21,740 8,680 28 331,195 3419 Ha " 73 1.796,810 1,760,805 28,562 144 1,127,333 16*235 Hamilton _ 17 29,025 17,490 4,586 52 65,705 711S Harlan ...... 15 92f 000 75,318 55,620 27 35,375 U US </seg>
            <seg id="p024">REPORTED BY FIRE CHIEFS REPORTED HY INSURANCE COMPANIES No. or Volne of Insurance Losses No. Claims Insurance Losses Counties Flrei Property Carried Estimated Paid Carried Paid Hayes 2 .'•'. 2,750 1,000 810 4 6,400 1,102 Hitchcock 4 18,390 6,800 2,740 26 56,147 7,348 Holt 17 45,595' 28,250 10,758 60 146,049 13*740 Hooker 1 15,000 10,000 35 3 3,300 828 Howard 5 20,400 11,200 3,415 32 49,600 1,645 Jefferson 34 __ 190,890 85,087 7,594 94 655,760 15,'135 Johnson 8 87,435 17,220 5,123 23 43,208 9^380 w Kearney 20 42,060 26.575 28,245 26 40,375 11,427 &gt; Keith 6 62,450 21,650 19,245 19 16,500 4,756 w Keya Paha 1 400 400 9 12,300 4,218 o Kimball 5 30,075 22,590 2,235 8 20,450 1,459 ** 1 Knox 15 47,950 36,385 10,170 27 48,300 8,'501 2 Lancaster ....160 2,875,245 2,597,000 99,288 589 8,018,487 120,010 W Lincoln _.....^__. ........ 37 452,975 373,845— ~^3,341 102 "1J76;099 "29*915 &gt; Logan .... 3 18,650 9,300 7,100 2 6,700 1,701 = Loup 1 1,500 1,000 100 1 1,000 ' 64 **" Madison 37 575,295 364,306 26,952 S6 224,311 12164 McPherson .. 2 2,750 1,000 469 1 1,000 169 Merrick 16 34,495 25,125 11,056 30 46,820 8,689 Morrill 3 10,3i5 7,000 450 10 20,050 1,813 Nance 8 16,350 9,875 4,475 35 48,849 7,829 Nemaha 20 139,605 70,150 64,959 56 87,743 43,789 Nuckolls 10 94,300 56,700 21,863 51 130,817 8,682 Otoe 18 98,935 75,700 15,106 97 246,795 25,009 Pawnee ... 19 83,375 44,875 61,930 33 66,850 39^429 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Perkins 9 56,170 334)90 10,205 13 19,425 3,694 Phelps . 12 32,760 26,720 10,420 39 88,500 7,819 Pierce . 23 80,437 58.060 15,164 29 110,155 U,515 Platte 12 40,170 31,500 14,963 51 213,395 8,580 Polk 13 37,725 26,950 19,272 25 92,440 5,115 Red Willow ... . 21 224,550 155,700 13,362 53 236,248 15,053 Richardson 17 97,565 71.900 46,930 134 562,724 . 5,936 m Rock 5 4,875 3,000 2,140 7 7,000 1.728 g Saline — - 30 117,181 72,858 9,676 65 105,350 6,882 «| Sarpy 11 20,035 13,475 14,010 50 97,072 12,629 2 Saunders 41 140,345 82,625 40,849 62 82,802 19,257 Z ScottsblufT 1!) 80,565 55,600 5,172 74 305,313 6,859 Seward . 19 50,405 28,675 7,551 53 94,535 6,464 «J Sheridan ... 12 54,175 39,300 13,500 24 43,400 3,167 2 Sherman 10 41,060 23,800 11,650 21 30,156 4,334 g Sioux 1 900 500 900 3 2,300 57 m Stanton 9 42,140 34,600 38,130 8 10,680 833 § Thayer 10 16,875 10,576 7,858 28 91,950 12,791 "**; Thomas 0 5 7,400 840 Z Thurston 11 18,075 15,926 11,965 24 51,300 3,955 £J Valley 12 46,123 31-870 10,830 29 82,367 11,075 3 Washington 32 95,671 68,653 16,435 45 78,240 10,963 Wayne 5 57,050 46,000 22,270 20 77,903 12,587 Webster 10 18,305 11,650 6,282 27 67,950 8,438 Wheeler - 1 475 350 475 3 2,200 ' 1,107 York - 20 80,091 51,980 14,908 70 281,281 24,641 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">RURAL FIRE LOSSES IN 1938 AS REPORTED BY FIRE CHIEFS AND FIRE INSURANCE COMPANIES AS REPORTED BY FIRE CHIEFS AS REPORTED BY INSURANCE COMPANIES Number Number Value or Insurance Estimated No. Claims Insurance Losses Counties Reported Totnl Loss Property Carried Loss Paid Carried Paid TOTALS 459 299 $1,107.993 8729,865 8635,725 1,352 51,926,891 $515,345 Adams 6 6 17,060 10,595 17,060 21 25,950 10,648 w Antelope 11 7 17,600 12,675 13,015 25 33,055 12,540 £ Arthur . 0 2 3,600 520 g Banner 0 4 10,153 465 0 Blaine ... 0 ° z Boone ...". 8 5 12,158 6,850 2,795 17 21,000 5,005 a Box Butte 0 6 5,350 2,496 gj Boyd . 0 7 8,100 2,510 §j Brown 0 4 3,700 256 Buffalo 15 6 48,0-10 25,250 23,391 28 37,825 16,142 Buit 12 8 14,40" 0,925 10,265 16 16,100 3,797 Butler 12 10 25,275 11,510 19,185 24 69,785 6,504 Cass 11 9 1 1.1(23 0,800 9,993 21 31,650 6,855 Cedar — . 5 . 5 14,830 11,350 13,830 18 33,375 6,201 Chase 1 0 650 150 I 6,000 2,282 Cherry 0 .6 6,717 2,910 Cheyenne ....'.— 0 11 20,645 696 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">C 'ay 7 5 19.930 J2.600 10,920 22 19,750 6,847 ' Colfax 6 6 14,575 11,35(1 14,575 11 8,525 2,664 Cuming 13 11 24,030 12,275 21,307 11 19,900 5,661 Custer 4 4 9,850 4,000 9,850 27 31,405 12,223 Dakota 4 3 15.900 9,^50 10,925 14 32,410 9,547 Dawes 0 7 12,450 6,849 y Dawson 4 4 82,000 74.50,) 81,500 32 56,690 16,050 B Deuel 2 1 6,685 4,000 6,360 7 19,400 7,147 &gt; Dixon .... 6 5 15,175 12,045 8,350 19 36,250 11,121 g Dodge 17 8 38,490 29,410 17,532 39 54,963 13,960 B Douglas 25 11 87,460 66,625 23,126 60 113,165 34,359 § Dundy 0 4 7,900 6,494 O Fillmore 8 6 23,500 11,650 17,280 17 33,500 10,080 !? Franklin 3 2 9,600 4,600 5,088 13 12,480 7,880 » Frontier 2 0 2,950 2,270 618 17 17,532 7,567 W Furnas 2 0 6,200 4,100 1,040 29 33,525 6,322 f§ Gage 5 4 5,845 3,450 5,345 31 36,279 12,848 Garden . 2 0 5,770 3,575 2,050 6 7,750 2,211 z Garfield 3 2 7,555 4,650 650 7 6,150 893 « Gosper 2 1 3,200 2,550 2,160 6 6,900 1,990 § Grant 1 O 300 300 75 1 1,700 4 Greeley 3 2 12,650 5,900 7,100 18 23,275 1,869 Hall 27 14 99,884 80,385 12,580 18 24,133 2,263 Hamilton 7 5 8,125 3,803 5,649 22 22,405 5,360 Harlan 5 1 11,703 6,002 6,753 18 20,825 8,679 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">AS REPORTED BY FIRK CHIEFS AS REPORTED nY INSURANCE COMPANIES Number Number Value of Insurance Estimated No. Claims Insurance Losses Counties Reported Total Loss Property Carried Loss Paid Carried Paid Hayes 1 0 2,000 1,000 60 1 2,500 26 Hitchcock — 1 1 1,850 1,100 1,850 12 16,092 3,870 Holt 5 4 3,425 1200 2,730 17 20,325 8,616 Hooker 0 2 800 800 Howard 4 1 14,750 7,700 3,215 20 39,050 5,561 Jefferson 2 2 2,000 1,300 2,000 17 27,150 6,967 Johnson 2 1 4,850 3,800 1,928 12 17,460 5,627 " Kearney 15 9 13,960 6,625 11,650 16 20,375 4,651 &gt; Keith 0 6 6,995 ' 603 n Keya Paha 0 3 3,800 767 O Kimball 0 5 5,750 613 *&gt; Knox 7 2 13,125 11,125 3,570 12 9,400 2,981 § Lancaster 6 3 22,250 11,175 12,340 52 67,900 25,340 » Lincoln 6 4 0,950 4,893 4,550 22 23,920 11,470 &gt; Logan 1 0 6,650 2,300 4,950 0 ■£ Loup 0 o &gt; Madison 9 7 21,450 12,450 14,700 13 14,875. 1,850 McPherson 0 0 Merrick 11 7 20,095 15,925 10,511 17 ■ 17,000 7,319 Morrill 0 2 3,500 36 Nance 3 2 4,300 2,475 2,315 16 18,140 3,573 Nemaha 4 4 14.810 0,200 14,810' 24 19,913 10,954 Nuckolls 2 1 6,700 4,100 1,800 18 19,750 3,272 Otoe 4 3 9.500 6,400 4.555 24 34,085 9,630 Pawnee 4 4 5,050 3,500 5,050 15 18,166 6,276 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Perkins 2 2 7,970 3,900 7,970 7 7,925 2,332 Phelps 2 2 2,550 2,500 2,550 5 4,550 1,805 Pierce 5 2 11,827 6,050 2,207 5 3,055 563 P'atte 3 2 4,700 2,400 1,740 14 24,730 5,705 Polk 9 5 24,400 17,550 18,915 20 84,665 4,931 Red Willow 5 3 13,050 8.100 7,203 14 29,200 10,974 Richardson 5 2 8,250 4.450 4,235 31 41,085 10,582 M Rock I 1 1,250 1,000 1,250 3 2,400 1,258 !&gt; Saline ..... 11 10 12,460 8,635 7,360 17 19,410 2,915 J| Sarpy 3 3 6,400 3,175 0,400 21 35,087 3.1E8 | Saunders 21 16 49,360 36,345 20,696 44 38,854 16,222 § Scottsbluff 6 1 2,600 1,100 485 12 6,575 609 q Seward 8 5 12,120 0,415 7,375 20 29,635 4,540 ** Sheridan 2 2 10,700 7,500 10,700 6 3,300 2,671 2 Sherman _ 6 3 15,260 7,800 9,650 14 14,410 3,136 | Sioux 1 1 900 500 900 2 1,200 21 * Stanton 3 3 8,000 4,100 8,000 3 2,400 641 | Thayer 3 3 3,950 800 3,950 9 14,800 9,824 | Thomas 0 i 2,000 9 % Thurston 3 3 4,075 1,925 4,075 12 17,200 4,065 o Valley 3 3 5,000 4,200 5,000 12 10,667 5,267 2 Washington 15 12 26,792 18,360 11,148 17 25,340 7,112 Wayne . 3 0 5,550 3,200 1,230 7 12,550 620 Webster 4 3 6,150 2,050 4,750 18 57,400 7,898 Wheeler 1 1 475 350 475 2 1,100 607 York 8 5 16,570 10,850 4,300 41 39,150 8,323 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">FIRE LOSSES PAID AS REPORTED BY INSURANCE COMPANIES 1937 . 1938 No. or No. of Month Claims Insurance Losses Claims Insurance Losses Paid Carried Paid Paid Carried Paid January _ 686 S 2,848,830 S 191,882 587 S 3,077,261 $ 145,250 m February 643 5,450,824 153,350 413 3,017,228 85,753 &gt; March 531 3,165,271 121,377 615 3,139,995 201,248 H April . 548 2,072,010 101,223 562 1,957,770 146,158 ° May 381 2.802,188 84,048 479 3,356,878 109,638 § June . 468 2,923,450 144,059 233 744,653 32,731 § July 276 1,609,159 57,618 501 3,709,626 148,947 w August . „— 355 6,709,956 90,670 237 1,503,470 65,327 &gt; September 681 2,498,815 162,607 795 2,595,679 136,950 October 456" 3,566,236 112,279 384 1,365,914 81,938 November . — — 755 3,586,403 178,595 887 3,878,424 214,760 December.. 382 1,227,781 53,005 753 4,427,738 282,547 6,164 $38,460,959 81,450,716 6,536 532,774,636 $1,634,247 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Department of fire prevention DEATHS AND INJURIES FROM FIRES Through fire chiefs reports, from the department of vital statistics, from newspapers and all other available sources, it has been the custom to compile a careful lißt of deaths and accidents from fire and to print the details in the annual report. For this report it has been deemed wise not to use so many pages for this purpose, but the cases are on file and available for any inquirers. DEATHS AND INJURIES FROM FIRE City Rami total Came P*ath ißlnrr Dtath Injury Pfalh Injury Totals 32 137 37 63 69 200 Gasoline Explosions 6 26 3 14 9 40 Gasoline Stove Fires 14 0 4 18 Kerosene Slove Fires 2 4 0 0 2 4 Starting Fires with Volatile Liquids 6 4 8 10 14 14 Other Volatiles, Ignition of 3 16 17 4 23 Burning Buildings 6 7 € 4 12 11 Automobiles Burning 0 6 16 1 12 Transport Truck Fiies 0 0 7 1 7 1 Careless Use of Matches 0 2 2 0 2 2 Clothing Catching Fire 3 6 12 4 8 Bonfires and Field Fires 10 3 2 4 2 Lightning 0 6 3 6 3 12 Electricity 3 3 2 4 5 7 Filling Lamps and Lanterns 11 0 0 11 Cleaning Clothes with Gasoline -.0 4 0 0 0 4 Miscellaneous Causes 0 9 0 9 0 18 Firemen Injuried in Line of Duty 33 Deaths Injuries Men 30 95 Women 20 44 Children 19 28 •Firemen 0 33 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">STATE OF NEBRASKA FIREMEN INJURED IN LINE OF DUTY BURWELL — Pat Brenneman, fireman, was burned on hand when a car burned. DALTON — Arthur Pilster, fireman, received a gash on his head when struck by a hook on one of the ladders. DAVID CITY— One fireman was injured when he stepped through the ceiling spraining his back and receiving scratches. GENEVA— W. C. Bruce, Thomas Brewer and Paul Shaner were burned in a fire at the fair grounds. GILTNER— One fireman was badly burned about the face and hands fighting a garage and filling station fire. HARTINGTON— A. L. Mengshol, a member of the fire department for seventeen years, was injured seriously. He boarded the fire truck just as it was backed out to answer a call. His leg was painfully torn and liga - ments bruised when caught between the fender of the city fire truck and the garage door. HASTINGS — Thomas Lay, fireman, was overcome by heat and smoke while fighting a rural fire.' KEARNEY — One fireman was cut from window glass at a rural fire. LINCOLN — Three city firemen were injured in a collision between fire truck and an automobile. LINCOLN — Arnold Scat injured his hand in the Korsmeyer and drug warehouse fire. LINCOLN — Fire Chief Donnelly received a fractured left leg and severe right knee injuries on a roof fire at the Lincoln high school building. LINCOLN— Five firemen were overcome in the Yost Lumber Co. fire. Ben W. Kuhner and Wash were taken to the hospital for treatment. Wash received a broken ear drum when hit on the head by a pumper hose line. Pierce, Kleckner and Captain E. C. Howard were overcome by smoke and heat but soon recovered. PALMER — Edward Barth was injured while handling the extinguishes at a fire in the country. PAPILLION — Bill Boyer was cut by glass while fighting a fire. PILGER — Henry Meyer and Floyd Osch suffered arm burns and Ralph Dye a cut on the hand in the $30,000 fire loss to the Fanner's Union lumber yard and elevator. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION PILGER — One fireman was injured by a window glass cut when the depot and freight warehouse caught fire. PLATTSMOUTH— FrankIin Kief, President of the fire department, suf - fered two very painful injuries in a fire. His wrist was injured when a can of kerosene exploded burning him, and he was struck on the right eye by a nozzle inflicting a cut that required medical attention. SH ELTON— Harold Conroy suffered cuts when water pressure suddenly applied to a nozzle he was holding threw the nozzle into and breaking his glasses. TECUMSEH— Chief William Devenney was considerably shaken when he collided with a car on his way to a fire. SCOTTSBLUFF— Dan Ayres suffered a fractured hip and vertebrae while enroute to revive Jerry Davis, 2, who fell into a shallow pond. The lad recovered. WILBER — Chas. Shimonek injured his hand endeavoring to start a fire truck. WEEPING WATER— One fireman was injured while fighting a fire. STARTING FIRES WITH KEROSENE Sixteen people were burned to death and nine seriously burned dur - ing the year 1938 from starting fires with KEROSENE and GASOLINE. BEAVER CROSSING — Joan Rice, 5, had watched other members of the family start fires with KEROSENE. She tried it in her little stove. Joan burned to death. BRADY"— KEROSENE on hot coals to hurry up the fire. Mrs. John Parkhurst was severely burned by the explosion. CAMPBELL- KEROSENE used to start a fire in the kitchen stove. Mal - vin Koch was standing near by in his pajamas. The usual explosion. Malvin died a week later from the effects of the burns. Louis Koch, the father, was seiiously burned. CRAWFORD— Miss Arlene Nichols, 16, was critically burned When she accidentally threw GASOLINE on a "live", ash pile.. ' ELWOOD Speeding up the fire with KEROSENE. The KEROSENE can exploded. Frank Jerges was critically burned and other members ■of the family less seriously. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">STATE OF NEBRASKA EWlNG— Frank Eppenback, 41, started a fire with KEROSENE. Frank was fatally burned by the explosion that followed. EMERSON— KEROSENE can exploded in Anna Ryan's hands as she was starting a fire with the explosive. Third degree burns and death resulted. FALLS CITY— Mrs. M. F. Laffler, 36, mother of four children, poured KEROSENE on the fire from a five-gallon can. She died seven hours later from the effects of the burns. A fourteen year old daughter was badly burned trying to extinguish the flames. GRAND ISLAND— Two cans just alike — one KEROSENE and one GAS - OLINE. Mrs. Leo Woikaszwski picked up the wrong can to hasten the kitchen fire. She was badly burned. MACY— TRACTOR FUEL used to hasten the fire in the kitchen stove. Helen Sparks, 13, died of burns from the explosion. NORTH BEND— Starting fire with KEROSENE. The can exploded. Mrs. James Fiala, 64, died from the effects of the burns. NORTH PLATTE- C. W. Hendricks started a fire with KEROSENE. He was made wiser by severe burns resulting from Ihe explosion. OMAHA -Starting a fire with KEROSENE, Mrs. Nellie Zelinsky spilled some on her dress. A lighted match did the rest. She died eight hours later. PLEASANTON— KEROSENE poured into the kitchen stove. Hot coals. An explosion. Mrs. Herman Lindner died from the effects of the burns. PONCA— The day before Christmas, Rose Ann Reilly, 9, and her broth - er, 11, were "starting" a fire with KEROSENE. The can exploded. Rose is recovering from serious burns. I ST. EDWARD— TRACTOR FUEL, hot coals Jand air readily mix. Mrs. John Wathen learned it when she poured some oil in the kitchen stove to "hurry" the fire. She suffered severe burns before the flames were extinguished. SCOTIA— John B. Mitchell, 38. and his five year old daughter, Aura Bee, both died from the effects of burns received when Mr. Mitchell at - tempted to start a fire with KEROSENE. SCOTTSBLUFF— TRACTOR FUEL to kindle the fire. An explosion caused the death of Mrs. Alvin Lashley, 28. SCOTTSBLUFF— GASOLINE used to start a fire; painful burns for Richard Walker, 13. SUTHERLAND— Starting a fire with KEROSENE. Twila Weaver, 28, was fatally burned. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION WALTHILL-KEROSENE can exploded from which oil was being pour - ed on the fire in the stove to "hurry" it up. Helen Sparks was fatally burned. WAYNE— Pouring KEROSENE from a bottle to start the fire, Elsie Brockman suffered fatal burns. WEST POINT— KEROSENE on hot coals to "hurry" the fire; Irene Melcher received first and second degree burns. GASOLINE AND KEROSENE STOVES ANSLEY— The oil burner in the stove clogged; Accumulated gas, a match, an explosion. Harry Zimmerman was badly burned. ASHLAND— A GASOLINE stove flared up, an explosion, Mrs. Veryl Livers and Phillip Kline were burned and the house destroyed. BURWELL— Chet Hallock was cleaning the safety valve in the oil burn - er in the furnace. An explosion and bad burns for Chet. CRAWFORD— Mrs. Edgar Phillips died from the results of burns re - ceived from an OIL BURNER explosion. EWING— An OIL STOVE E. S. Adrain was adjusting exploded burning him sevei-ely. * GILTNER— Mrs. Cornelius Murphy suffered severe burns when her clothing became ignited from an OIL BROODER STOVE. GRAND ISLAND— Two year old Jimmy Scott died from burns received when a feed line on a GASOLINE stove broke, spraying the burning GASOLINE over him. His mother was painfully burned and only prompt action of Mr. Scott saved her. HENDERSON— A leaky valve in a GASOLINE stove was the cause of a fire that seriously burned J. H. Frissen. KENNARD-John Ward was painfully burned when he attempted to carry a GASOLINE stove, that had exploded, out of doors. LINCOLN -A KEROSENE stove flared up. Mrs. H. W. Chase was bad - ly burned when she tried to carry it out of the house. LINCOLN— A GASOLINE stove explosion caused severe burns to C. A. Toothaker. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">STATE OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN — Clarence Schmidt and Lloyd Jeffrey suffered first degree burns when an oil burner exploded as they tried to light it. LINCOLN — J. C. Richardson, 74, died from the effects of burns received when an OIL stove flared up setting the room on fire. LOUP CITY— Geo. Wurtz was painfully burned when a GASOLINE stove exploded. McCOOK — A GASOLINE stove explosion caused severe burns to Jean Traphagan. OMAHA — Roland Gochenour suffered severe burns when he attempted to carry a flaming KEROSENE stove from the house. OMAHA— An OIL BURNER in the furnace oveiflowed starting a fire that overcame Emma Navratil. OMAHA — Mrs. Eric Swanberg died from the effects of burns and Mrs. E. Johanson was seriously burned when a GASOLINE stove exploded as it was being filled. OSHKOSH — Joyce Henrichs was painfully burned when she lighted an OIL BURNER at school. REPUBLICAN CITY— A KEROSENE stove failed to function properly. Mrs. Maude Tomkinson was severely burned while throwing it into the street. SCOTTSBLUF.F— Mrs. Paul Moore lighted a GASOLINE burner that had just been filled. An explosion; Mr. and Mis. Moore were badly burned and the house was burned to the ground. SPRINGFIELD— A GASOLINE stove sprung a leak. Mis. Wm. Gless - man was severely burned by an explosion. STANTON— A KEROSENE unit in a refrigerator exploded. Darrell Kmcnt, 4, was burned to death, and her mother received second degree burns. SUTTON— An OIL STOVE exploded. P. H. EHwanger was badly burn - ed. WEST POINT— Miss Elsie M. Hoy, 68, suffered severe burns when her farm home was destroyed by fire caused by an explosion of an OIL STOVE. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">. DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION GASOLINE TANKS AND TRUCKS ALMA— A GASOLINE tank, an open manhole, a lighted lantern -an explosion. Heinie Miller was blown from the top of the tank. He may live but will probably lose his sight. BEATRICE— Louis Imes was badly burned by an explosion while re - pairing an old auto. BLAIR -Alman Gottsch, 9, learned that TRACTOR OIL will burn He lighted some to find out. The burns received will be a continual re - minder. BURCHARD— Roy Mathias was seriously burned when a GASOLINE engine he was filling exploded. CALLAWAY— A plumber's furnace was being filled in-a filling station. The stove ignited the fumes. Pete AUen, R. P. Anderson, Wayne Snyder and Bill Lincoln in flaming clothes ran from the building. All were severely burned. COZAD— Mrs. Albert Simmons was fatally burned when a GASOLINE can near which she was standing became ignited in some way, setting her clothes on fire. FT. CALHOUN— The backfire of a forty horse-power engine set the boat on fire severely burning Dan Mullaly. The other people had to jump into the river to save their lives. The boat burned. FAIRBURY-A GASOLINE t.ansport truck turned over and burned exploding four times. The driver, Roland Rempel, escaped with serious burns. FALLS CITY-A GASOLINE can. a lighted match carelessly discarded, an explosion, and second degree burns for Robert Wing, 16. OMAHA— EmiI Gerit is in a serious condition from burns received when flaming GASOLINE sprayed on him from a tractor cylinder. OMAHA-Reuben Keller, 17. was critically burned when a can from which he was pouring GASOLINE into their auto tank exploded. G J B ,? O ii~ H " R * Li PP incott was refueling his tractor combine and spill - ed GASOLINE on the exhaust pipe. The container from which he was pouring GASOLINE exploded in his hands causing severe burns. GILTNER— A static spark set off the GASOLINE in the car Don Cheney was repairing. He was painfully burned. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">STATE OF NEBRASKA GRESHAM — Rudolph Neujahr's nine year old son was sent to the gar - age for GASOLINE. When the valve to the container was opened, a static spark set off the GASOLINE severely burning the boy. GOTHENBURG— Geo. Clark, 34, left the tractor engine running whi'.e he was filling the tank with GASOLINE. The explosion fatally burned Mr. Clark. HEBRON — E. L. Russell was refueling his tractor. An explosion oc - curred severely burning Mr. Russell. LEXINGTON — Carl Smith, 33, was fatally burned when a spark from an electric switch ignited GASOLINE contained in the tank he was in - stalling. MITCHELL— CIyde Pfeiffer, 33, was sent to the hospital with severe burns received when the pressure weed burner he was operating spray - ed him with burning fuel. NEBRASKA ClTY'— James Rowen, 23, was severely burned when trac - tor fuel exploded. NEBRASKA ClTY— George Hohlmeier, 38, was fatally burned when his transport truck caught fire after a collision with another machine. ODELL — John Koppes suffered painful burns when cleaning a tank with GASOLINE. The GASOLINE exploded. OMAHA— A lighted lantern ignited GASOLINE being used to clean the floor of a dredge. Vincent Mangiapana was seriously burned. OMAHA— Leland Jones, 11, died from burns received in a GASOLINE explosion. OXFORD— Don Leroy, 2, was burned to death when GASOLINE spray - ed his clothing that was being applied to ant hills. PENDER — Wilber Powler, 48, was fatally burned, and his son, Eatl, 21, was badly burned when the car in which they were riding overturn - ed and burst into flames. RED CLOUD— A GASOLINE transport truck and a fruit truck collid - ed. Results, five deaths. All were trapped in the flaming wreckage. Delbert A. Bowers, Ronald A. Percival and Frank Hare died in the wreckage. Lester Elliott and Wm. Lonn died from the effects of the burns. ST. EDWARD — Dickie Baly, 7, is recovering at the home of his uncle from severe burns received when he dropped a lighted match into a 50-gallon barrel of TRACTOR FUEL. An explosion occurred spraying him with flaming oil. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION SCOTTSBLUFF— Backfire of the auto exploded the alcohol fumes from the radiator spraying Thomas Tracy, a mechanic, with the burning fluid. SIDNEY— Herman Jobman had a narrow escape when the GASOLINE he was loading into a truck exploded. He was severely burned. SOUTH SIOUX CITY-An unidentified youth tossed a lighted match into a pool of GASOLINE at a filling station. Melvin Fick was serious - ly burned by the explosion. STROMSBURG -Gerald Anderson was severely burned when a con - tainer of GASOLINE exploded at his home. n A iM?°7~" l ? udd X Meduna ' 6 . lighted a match to look inside of a GAS - UUNL tank. The explosion burned Buddy and his brother Jack. WALLACE— George Downs was seriously burned when the backfire of a truck set fire to oil on the floor of the garage. Flames spread to a 600-gallon tank of lubricating, oil in the building. W.'E. Paxton drag - ged Downs from the truck just before the explosion occurred. He was also burned. YORK— Albert Nelson, 25, an oil station attendant suffered third degree burns when an explosion of GASOLINE rocked the filling station. MORE EXPLOSIONS AND BURNS ARTHUR— A KEROSENE lamp exploded causing severe burns to the seven months old son of Mr. and Mrs. Donald Colburn. AUBURN Fumes from waxing floors, a pilot light on the water heater bad burns for Leah Ericman. BENKELMAN -Cleaning clothes in a pan of GASOLINE, an explosion caused severe burns to Mrs. Bertha Henkel. BENNINGTON— John Grant, 22, was seriously burned when a GASO - LINE blow torch exploded with which he was working. BIG SPRINGS -Verdon Tyttle, 27, died of burns suffered when GASO - LINE exploded while soldering a tank unaware that it still contained GASOLINE. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">STATE OF NEBRASKA BROKEN BOW — Mrs. H. R. Neiswanger died of burns received in an explosion of some cleaning fluid with which she was cleaning clothes. BROKEN BOW— Cleaning clothes with GASOLINE in the kitchen, the fumes were ignited from the stove — Mrs. Geo. Cox was badly burned. FALLS CITY— An open pan of GASOLINE and a blow torch; an ex - plosion and bad burns for Bryan Morris. A loaded gasoline truck near by was saved. HASTINGS— Bert Snoot fell while carrying a KEROSENE lamp. lie suffered some severe burns. HILDRETH— Adding GASOLINE to boiling floor wax caused an explo - sion and serious burns to Mrs. John H. Bornman. LEXINGTON — Accumulated gas in a burner compartment caused severe burns to Ed Latter when he attempted to light the jet. LIN WOOD— Pouring GASOLINE over her clothes and igniting it caus - ed the death of Mrs. Antonie Krivanek. McCOOK— Cleaning the motor with KEROSENE, an explosion. Lee Peters and Merlin Shorey were burned. McCOOK — Using GASOLINE to remove grease from his hands caused some bad burns for Wayne Ashley when it became ignited. OMAHA— The KEROSENE lamp was upset, and burns proved fatal to Mrs. George West three weeks after the accident. OMAHA— Victor T. Klotz, 35, was found dead following an explosion apparently from accumulated gas. OMAHA— Charles Leonard, 3, has seen his mother light the gas stove. He tried it with results that he was taken to the hospital. OMAHA— Mrs. Margaret Treen, 55, died from the effects of burns re - ceived from a gas explosion. Evidently the gas jet had been left open too long before it was lighted. OMAHA— A mother stands helpless and watches her 11 months baby burn to death in its crib. A vapor solution on an electric plate caused the fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">■ DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION STILL MORE BURNS PAWNEE CITY— Wax was being heated on the stove. An explosion occurred causing the death of Roger Dean Savage, 4% years old. SNYDER— A truck caught on fire either from a short in wiring or a cigarette causing severe burns to Wm. Kingbaum. TAYLOR— Vernon Van Houten, while playing with other children, tried to light a GASOLINE torch. He was badly burned. ULYSSES— GASOLINE for cleaning clothes, a static spark, an explosion and painful burns for Mrs. Joseph JakL WAHOO-A GASOLINE torch used to heat a kettle of tar exploded and Floyd H. Schenek was severely burned. WlLCOX— Mixing GASOLINE with hot floor wax resulted in an ex - plosion. Mrs. John Borgman was badly burned. WOODLAKE— Henry Larsen, 72, was carrying a GASOLINE torch when it exploded indicting severe burns. ALDA— A premature explosion of Dynamite while blasting stumps re - sulted in serious injuries to Frank Denman. He will probably lose his hand. ARCADlA— Lightning killed Dominic Chilewski, 23, while listing corn with a tractor. BEATRICE -Mrs. Clementine Evans, 82, was painfully burned when her clothing caught fire as she was working over the gas stove. BLAIR-Billy Gilliland was playing with matches. His clothing caught fire. It is doubtful that he will recover. CLARKSON— Frank Navrkal, his wife and daughter were burned to death when their farm home was destroyed. COZAD— Mrs. James Arnold was electrocuted when she attempted to remove a radio aerial that had fallen across a transmission line. BUR WELL— A fire caused by an overheated lard kettle resulted in bad burns for Vincent Klavica and his wife. CENTRAL ClTY— Lightning killed Louis Prouty as he was fishing in the Loup River. EWING— Mrs. Carl Premis, 45, threw her two year old son from a sec - ond floor window then died in the flames that destroyed the home. The son will live. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">STATE OF NEBRASKA FAIRMONT — A short in the Delco plant set the gasoline on fire burning the son of Arch Steines. FORT CALHOUN— Geo. Van, 83, died from burns and shock when his home was accidentally set on fire. FIRTH — A 33,000 volt high tension line, a telephone wire coming in contact with it — C. E. Moothart was severely burned. FRANKLIN — H. Dyer, a transport driver, lost his life when his truck turned over and burned. FREMONT — Mrs. J. D. Markley, 77, was fatally burned when her apron caught fire as she was burning rubbish. GERING — Playing with matches resulted in the death of Betty Schaub. GORDON — Geo. W. Fowler was burned to death when his home was destroyed by fire. GRAND ISLAND— Roy Sprague was electrocuted when be attempted to remove a live wire that had fallen across his car in a high wind. HOWELLS — Eldon Belina, 3, was fatally burned when his clothing caught fue from burning rubbish. LAMAR — Jack Andius, 10, died four hours after he was fatally burned when the house caught fire from a home-made oil burner. LAWRENCE — -A fire, probably caused by smoking, resulted in the death of Charles McN'ew. LEWISTON — Mrs. J. D. Lewien was severely burned when her clothing caught fire from the stove. LINCOLN — Mrs. Ida Showalter, 39, is in a serious condition, results of a fire at her home. She was given a blood transfusion. McCOOK — Fletcher A. Harrison, 63, was fatally burned when his cloth - ing caught fire from the stove. McCOOK — Helen St. Calir, 8, was seriously burned when her clothing caught fire from a makeshift stove with which she was playing. MARTEL — Mrs. Lydia Spillman, 76, died from the results of burns suf - fered four hours earlier when her clothes caught fire from the stove. MEADOW GROVE — Robert Monson, 3, is recovering from burns receiv - ed when his clothing caught fire while watching his father burn Russian Thistles. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DEPARTMENT OF FIRE PREVENTION ; J_ OMAHA— Two Buffington children, Jimmy, 5, and Peggy, 3, died after being carried from their burning home. Mrs. Buffington -was burned severely trying to save them. OMAHA— Two Negro tenants were burned to death when an apartment house caught fire from an overheated stove. Twenty others escaped in their night clothes. PLYMOUTH — Charles H. Thompson, 68, died from the effects of burns received when his clothing caught fire while burning weeds. SCOTTSBLUFF— GIadys Lillian Steen, 5, was fatally burned when her clothing caught fire. SIDNEY — -Lyman de Freece, 35, was repairing an electric oil burner. It is believed he was electrocuted when the burner was shorted. STAURT — Roy Walker, Jr., was electrocuted when he came in con - tact with a high tension line. WAUSA— A 22,000 volt high tension line coming in contact with O. H. Johnson resulted in third degree burns. W AVER LY— Chester Rockenbach, 14, was killed by lightning while standing in the barn. : </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>