<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00032">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Babcock Testing and Other Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products</title>
               <date value="1936-06">1936-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 53 June, 1936 Babcock Testing and Other Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products L. K. Crowe Department of Dairy Husbandry Butter analysb, Babcock testing, and total-solids determination. The University of Nebraska College of Agriculture Experiment Station, Lincoln W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Milk Defined 3 Composition o£ Milk 3 Variation m Composition 4 Discovery of the Babcock Test 5 Babcock Test Principles 6 Equipment for Babcock Testing 7 Sampling Milk and Cream 8 Babcock Test for Milk 10 Preparing the sample 10 Measuring die sample 10 Adding acid 11 Ccntrifuging (Whirling) 13 Reading the tests 13 Emptying the test bottles 14 Cleaning glassware 14 Babcock Test for Cream 15 Weighing the sample 15 Adding the acid 16 Reading the tests 16 Babcock Test for Skim Milk and Bu termilk 17 Babcock Test for Whey 17 Precautions and Suggestions 1 18 Defects of Fat Column — Causes and Remedies 19 Summary of Procedures m Babcock Tests 20 Causes of Butterfat Variations m Se parated Cream 21 I Causes of Variation m Milk and Cr am Tests 22 Modified Babcock Test for Buttermi' k 23 Modified Babcock Test for Ice Crea n 23 Factory Procedure for Butter Analyst ; (Modified Kohman Procedure) 25 Determining the Acidity of Dairy Products 28 I Determining Total Solids m Milk V roducts by Gravimetric Methods 30 Calculation of Total Solids of Whol !| Milk by Formula 31 Problems m Dairy Arimmetic i 32 Problems m the Standardization of Fat Content of Milk and Cream 33 Odicr Useful Information J 37 ■"■■ .1 ! </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Babcock Testing and Other Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products L. K. CROWE Department of Dairy Husbandry Milk is the whole, fresh, clean, lacteal secretion obtained by the com - plete milking of one or more healthy cows, properly fed and kept, ex - cluding that obtained fifteen days before and five days after calving or such longer period as may be necessary to render the milk practically colostrum tree. The extent to which each of the principal constituents occurs m normal milk is indicated below. COMPOSITION OF MILK CONSTITUENT AMOUNT IN NORMAL^ Avenge per cent variation, p.ct. Lact" se ' (miik sugar): :::::::::: S H 8 1-t%i Protein: Casein ! ! ! ii! ! !! ! i!!: i": 27 it " Albumin 0 7 05-09 Ash (mineral matter) n 7 n'&lt;_ no Milkfat 17.I 7 . °-*-°-8 Total solids (all except water) .'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.[" 127 Serum solids, or solids not fat 89 Milk scrum (all except fat) 962 Milk fat is m suspension or emulsion m the milk serum m the form of small globules of 4/1,000 inch to 6/100,000 inch m diameter. In normal milk one cubic centimeter may contain two to four billion fat globules The size of fat globules varies and is affected mainly by the breed of cows season of the year, and the stage of lactation. Milk fat is a complex mix - ture of at least nine distinct chemical units called fatty acids, which are combined with glycerol. The percentage of each of these fatty acids deter - mines largely the character of the milk fat, particularly its hardness (melt - ing point). Of the protein of milk, casein is the most important. This protein is combined with calcium m milk and occurs as a suspension of fine particles rather than m true solution. Casein is the principal con - stituent of cottage cheese and a very important consituent of cheddar or American cheese. Casein m its pure form is white, odorless, and tasteless, and commercially finds use as a substitute for products such as celluloid, bone, and ivory, and m making glue, cold water paints, etc. Lactose, or milk sugar, is a disaccharide, Le., composed of two simpler sugars, glucose and galactose. It is m solution m the serum, much less soluble than ordinary sugar, and only about one-sixth as sweet. The action of bacteria on the sugar of milk produces lactic acid and the normal sour - ing of milk. (For detailed constituents, see page 39.) </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 VARIATION IN COMPOSITION It is now recognized that ihe percentage o£ butterfat in milk is not normally constant. Certain factors that are responsible for this variation will be indicated by the fact that as the percentage of fat varies the per - centage of the other constituents also varies, as indicated by the follow - ing comparative analysis of milk that is high or low in fat. This fact should not be overlooked. AMOUNT IN CONSTITUENT high-fat milk low-fat milk percent percent Milk fat 3.0 5.0 Milk sugar 4.7 5.0 _ . (Casein 2.5 3.1 Protein | Albumin 067 070 Ash 0.7 0.73 Water .• 88.43 85.47 Total solids 11.57 14.53 Solids not fat 8.57 9.53 Breed of cows. — The average percentage of fat in the milk produced by cows on which official records of production have been obtained is as fol - lows: Holstein-Friesian 3.4, Ayrshire 4.0, Brown Swiss 4.0, Guernsey 5.0, and Jersey 5.4 per cent. While it is true that there is a wide variation in the percentage of butterfat produced by individual cows within the breed, the figures above indicate the general tendency of the cows of a breed to produce milk with a low or a high fat content. These figures of course reveal nothing as to the quantity of milk produced. Individual cows. — Not an unusual variation in the percentage of butterfat is illustrated in the figures taken from the record of a cow milked four times daily during a seven-day period, in which the maximum variation between milkings in one twenty-four-hour period was from 4.5 to 5.9 per cent fat and the minimum variation in a similar period was from 4.5 to 5.1 per cent fat. The lowest percentage of fat during the seven days was 3.7 and the highest was 5.9. The average percentage of fat for the entire period was 4.66 and the daily averages were 5.0, 4.9, 4.8, 4.5, 43, 4.4, and 4.7 per cent. Stage of lactation. — In general the percentage of butterfat tends to be low at first, gradually increases, remains constant for a period, and then again increases as the end of the lactation period approaches. The follow - ing figures represent a complete lactation period for one cow. Month of I Days in Average Average Month of I Days in Average Average lactation [ milk milk butterfat lactation I milk milk butterfat Us. Pxt. ~~ Lbs. P.ct. 1 13 49.0 2.77 7 28 55.5 3.37 2 30 71.3 2.77 8 ....... 31 58.1 3.45 3 31 73.6 3.23 9 30 54.8 3.60 4 30 69.8 3.06 10 31 57.6 3.63 5 31 62.7 3.42 11 30 54.3 3.80 6 31 60.1 3.42 12 31 46.1 4.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products Age of cow.— A slight but consistent decline in percentage of butterfat as the cow advances in age is to be expected. It is only in very rare cases that this change is more than slight. Heat period (oestrum).— The effect of the heat period is not definite but in general the percentage of butterfat is slightly increased, while the amount of milk is slightly decreased. Season of the year.— The butterfat percentage on the average is high - est during the months of December, January, and February and lowest during the months of July and August. This variation cannot be attribut - ed entirely to differences in feeding practices. Time of day of milking.— When cows are milked twice daily at regular intervals the morning's milk will generally contain the higher percentage of butterfat, but the quantity of milk will be less. Weather conditions.— In general, in cool or cold weather cows tend to produce milk containing a higher percentage of butterfat. Hot weather Serf atmosphere is moist, tends to lower the percentage of Feed conditions.— Early spring pasture tends to increase the milk pro - duction and decrease the percentage of butterfat. If cows are well fed the percentage of butterfat cannot permanently be raised by the addition of any particular feed; however, a change in feed may temporarily affect the quantity of milk and the percentage of butterfat. Cows insufficiently ted, when given a well balanced ration, may increase the milk flow and the percentage of butterfat in the milk. Other factors.— The condition of the cow at calving time, completeness of mi king, sickness or bodily disturbance of the cow, changing of milkers or milking methods, or excitement or other disturbance of the routine may affect not only the quantity of the milk but also the percentage of butter - tat in that milk. DISCOVERY OF THE BABCOCK TEST The manufacturing of dairy products on a commercial scale began about the middle of the nineteenth century and was greatly stimulated by the development of the centrifugal cream separator in the late eighties. The invention of the Babcock test in 1890 overcame some of the difficul - ties that had developed in paying for milk upon its butterfat content, since it was early recognized that milk varied widely in that respect. A num - ber of practical methods had been developed by dairy manufacturing plants to determine the butterfat in the milk. Among these were: (1) The creamery inch system, in which a sample A T Vl S WaS Pkced in a S lass tubc and after settling, the depth of the. cream layer was measured. This was far from satisfactory since it took much time, and milk that contained a large percentage of small fat globules gave an inaccurate cream layer. (2) The trial churn - ing, ,n which a small sample of each patron's milk was churned and the butter weighed. Great care was necessary in this method to have the </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 conditions alike in order to keep the moisture content of the butter the same for all samples. (3) The oil test churn, in which a small sample of each patron's milk was churned, after which the butter was melted and measured. If the churning was not complete this method developed inaccuracies. This and the previous methods were slow and bothersome. As the result of much experimentation by the agricultural experiment stations, a number of tests were devised, of which that devised by Dr. S. M. Babcock 2 proved to be the simplest, least costly, most accurate for practical purposes, and most rapid in operation. The economic importance of the Babcock test was threefold: (1) it revolutionized the dairy industry by putting it upon a business basis, (2) it hastened and made possible the rapid development of the factory system of dairy products manufacture, and (3) it provided a rapid and accurate method of selecting individual cows upon their ability to produce butter - fat and thus was a stimulus to better breeding. BABCOCK TEST PRINCIPLES Essentially this method of determining the percentage of butterfat in certain dairy products consists in transferring a definite weight of the product to be tested into a specially constructed and graduated test bottle. Sulphuric acid is then added and mixed with the material in the test bottle. The bottles are then centrifuged or whirled three times in succession, at a definite speed and for a definite time. Hot water is added to the con - tents of the bottle after the first two whirlings. After the last whirling the percentage of fat is measured directly with a pair of dividers. The Babcock test is based on the following principles: That a strong acid will curdle and then dissolve or digest the curd in milk, thus freeing the butterfat; that heat which is developed from the action of the acid upon the water and milk solids melts the butterfat; that difference in the weight or specific gravity tends to cause the separation of liquids; and that the application of centrifugal force (whirling) hastens the separation of the fat from the other constituents of the milk. Milk fat or butterfat has a specific gravity (compared with water, which equals 1.00) of 0.93, while whole milk has a specific gravity of about 1.032. This means that one cubic centimeter (1 cc.) of butterfat would weigh 0.93 gram and 1 cc. of milk would weigh 1.032 grams. The globules of butterfat in milk, being lighter than the surrounding fluid, tend to rise but are retarded by the interference of the other milk solids. Commercial sulphuric acid (H^SO^) first curdles and then digests the proteins in the milk. This frees the fat, and since heat is generated by the action of sulphuric acid on the water and solids of the milk, the fat is melted and tends to rise to the top. The sulphuric acid, being heavier than the milk serum, increases the specific gravity of the mixture, thus making it easier for the fat to rise. In whirling, the test bottle is in a . 'Dr. S. M. Babcock was chief chemist at the Wisconsin Agricultural Experiment Station. The test was Datcntcd and civen free to the world in IR90. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products horizontal position with the bottom to the outside. Whirling produces centrifugal force which causes the heavier material to go to the bottom of the test bottle and in consequence forces the lighter fat to the top. The Babcock test is based upon the use of a definite weight of milk or cream in the test bottle. In the case of cream, 9 grams are weighed directly into the test bottle, which is graduated to be read direct. When testing milk the 17.6 cc. pipette is used for measuring the milk into the test bottle. This pipette delivers 17.5 cc. of milk (0.1 cc. of milk sticks Vw l n$ldC ° f the P'P^)- With milk o£ an average specific gravity of 1.032 the 17.5 cc. will, weigh 18.06 grams (ordinarily figured 18 grams). The milk test bottle tan be read direct in percentage of fat with this amount. ffl. * f=\ &gt; LA iv -'■ « i I I 2* *h V : ■■■' FlG 'fkiy^ 9 ' K '-T id mcasure .L {2 \ 9 " cc - add di PP cr &gt;' &lt; 3 &gt; 17 - 5 -«:. acid dipper; (4) 17.5-cc. acid measure; (5) glymol; (6) dividers; (7) cream-test bottle^ - gram, 50 per cent; (8) 9-cc. pipette; (9) 17.6-cc. milk pipette; (10) floating dairy thermometer; (11) test-bottle brush; (12) whole-milk test bottle; (13) double-neck skimmilk or buttermilk test bottle; (14) sulphuric acid. EQUIPMENT FOR BABCOCK TESTING MILK TESTING EQUIPMENT 1. Centrifuge or Babcock tester— hand, steam, or electric. 2. Sample jars— four-ounce size with tight covers are very convenient. 3. Milk test bottles 3 — either 8 or 10 per cent graduation. 4. Milk pipette s — 17.6 cc. capacity for measuring milk. 5. Acid measure or dipper — 17.5 cc. capacity. 6. Thermometer— floating dairy type, with Fahrenheit graduation to 7. Dividers — for measuring the fat column. 8. Sulphuric acid (commercial grade), specific gravity 1.82 to 1.83 at 60 —70 F. 9. "Vtater bath— a vessel that will hold hot water in which all com - pleted tests are placed before measuring the fat column. 10. Washing powder— any commercial alkali powder, for cleaning glass - ware. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 11. Test bottle brush — a small, wire-handled brush for cleaning bottles and pipettes. I ADDITIONAL EQUIPMENT REQUIRED FOR TESTING CREAM 1. Cream test bottles 3 — 9 gram 50 per cent graduation. 2. Cream test balance or scales 3 — a balance or scale sensitive to 25 milligrams (.025 gram), one-bottle type. (See Figure 2.) 3. Weight 3 — a 9-gram weight tested as accurate. 4. Pipette — a 9 cc. pipette may be used for convenience but must be used with a balance or scales. 5. Acid measure or dipper — 9 cc. capacity. j 6. Glymol— "red reader" — to eliminate meniscus or curved surface at j top of fat column. ' Fig. 2. — Left to right — Cream-test bottles and bottle rack; crcam-tcst scale, 9-gram weight, 9-cc. pipette, and sample bottle; electric centrifuge with heating element in cover. ADDITIONAL EQUIPMENT REQUIRED FOR TESTING SKIM MILK, BUTTERMILK, AND WHEY 1. Skim milk test bottles— double necked— 25/100 to 50/100 per cent graduation. SAMPLING MILK AND CREAM The accuracy of testing depends to a great extent upon the care used in sampling. The sample must be uniform in composition and representa- "j tive of the material from which it has been taken. Careful testing will not correct inaccuracies in sampling. It is impossible to be too careful in sampling. MILK To sample the milk of a cow, pour the complete milking from one vessel to another at least three times. Then dip out a sample of about four ounces for testing, cover tightly to prevent evaporation, and set in a cool 1 Sec Nebraska Standard Dairy Law, Bui. No. 3, Slate of Nebraska, Department of Agriculture, State Capitol. Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products place. Milk should not be tested until at least one hour after milking be - cause of the air incorporated during milking. If milk has stood long enough for the cream to rise, it should be poured back and forth at least six times instead of three times. In pouring do not agitate unduly so as to cause churning. Milk can be tested satisfactorily only when sweet. I CREAM Cream is thicker, more viscous, and consequently more difficult to sample accurately than milk. It should be poured or thoroughly stirred, after which the sample should be taken with a recognized cream sampler (slotted openings in the side throughout the entire length of the tube). If thoroughly mixed, an accurate sample may be procured with a dipper. ABNORMAL MILK AND CREAM Sour milk. — An accurate (sample of curdled milk is difficult to obtain. Pour back and forth until thoroughly mixed; then take sample as with sweet milk. Sour cream. — Thorough mixing of sour cream is not difficult because cream does not contain as much curd as milk does. Accurate samples de - pend only upon thorough mixing. If properly sampled, cream will test the same whether sweet or sour. Churned milk or cream.-plf particles of butter appear on the surface of milk or cream the vessel containing either should be placed in a bath of water at a temperature of lO5°-115° F. When the butter particles have melted, the milk or cream should be poured back and forth several times from one vessel to another and sampled immediately. Even then such a sample may be inaccurate. I Frozen milk or cream. — When milk or cream freezes, ice starts to form at the outer edge nextj to the container. This ice is very largely water, the other constituents being more concentrated in the soft, mushy center of the container. An | accurate sample cannot be taken from the frozen material. To thaw, place in a water bath at 80° to 85° F. or at room temperature until melted, then mix well and sample as usual. COMPOSITE SAMPLING A sample composed of proportionate quantities by weight of different lots of milk or cream is called a composite. A composite sample of milk is readily and accurately taken with a pipette graduated to 0.5 cc. with a total graduation of not less than 25 cc. For example, in testing the milk from an individual cow, a considerable saving of labor is made by com - posite sampling, that is, the testing of a composite sample of the different milkings for the day. Since the several milkings may differ in quantity as well as in percentage of butterfat, proportional samples should be taken from each. The number of cubic centimeters taken per pound of milk depends upon the total quantity represented by the composite. There should be not less than 100 cc. in the completed composite sample. For </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 each pound of milk, use a number of cubic centimeters large enough to insure a composite of at least 100 cc. Suppose a cow is producing about 40 pounds of milk a day in two milkings. On the day the samples were taken, she produced 16 pounds in the morning and 22 pounds in the evening. Take 3 cc. of milk for each pound of milk produced; 16x3 = 48 cc. from the morning milk and 22x3 = 66 cc. from the evening milk or a total of 114 cc. for the day. Mix together and the 114 cc. represent a composite of the milk of the cow for one day. Accurate composite samples may be taken from containers of the same diameter with com - mercial sampling devices available for that purpose. Since cream will not drain clean from a pipette, the composite sampling of cream is advised only when the lots of cream are in containers of equal diameter, in which case a sample may be taken by means of a cream sampler. If composite samples are to be kept for any length of time some pre - servative should be added. Bichloride of mercury (corrosive sublimate) may be obtained from creamery supply houses in tablet form and is usually the most convenient preservative for common use. Directions for the use of these tablets are on the container. Other preservatives are potassium dichromate and formalin (40 per cent formaldehyde). In using the former, which is a powder, add just enough to give the milk a lemon-yellow color. One cubic centimeter of formalin to a pint of milk will usually be sufficient. Each time milk is added to the composite sample it should be thoroughly stirred or mixed. A glass jar for keeping composite samples should have a wide mouth and a tight-fitting cover or stopper. When using a pre - servative that does not color the milk, some coloring matter should be added to indicate that the milk is unfit for food. All the milk preserva - tives mentioned above are poisonous. BABCOCK TEST FOR MILK PREPARING THE SAMPLE Milk samples for testing should be at a temperature of between 60° and 70° F. as determined by a thermometer. They may be warmed or cooled by means of a water bath. When warming a sample, the water bath should not be at a temperature above 85° F., to prevent melting the fat. After having reached the proper temperature, the sample should be poured slowly from one container to another at least 6 times to insure thorough mixing. Rapid pouring will incorporate air bubbles, making the succeeding measurement inaccurate. Care should be taken that no cream is left upon the lid or sides of the sample jar. MEASURING THE SAMPLE Immediately after mixing, insert the tip of a 17.6 cc. pipette into the prepared sample of milk, holding it with the thumb and second finger of the right hand and then draw in the milk by suction with the lips placed a*", the upper end until the pipette is filled well above the gradua- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products tion mark on the stem. Quickly place the dry, fleshy pad of the first finger of the right hand tightly overj the upper end of the pipette. Holding the pipette perpendicular and with the graduation on the level with the I eye, release the pressure slightly on j • ..^H~ I 1 ., the finger applied to the upper end j / j^^\J of the pipette and allow the milk I : Wp iB "V\ ' ■' - i to run back into the sample until : .--? ■■'■?8*|;,iCo-. the surface of the milk is leve with j^^BT- H '"■""-&gt;' j the graduation, disregarding the HHhhS I upper edges of the meniscus (the ' it ' curved surface at the top of the - if I '■-"^•- j milk column). Insert the tip of I i V|?,\;v«« !: "^^^ pipette into the milk test bottle and I I ' ' '" H]^W W. allow the milk to run out. If the ' --^'^M l^lgfeSlSray^wK^ neck is too small to allow the pip- j[ , I L|M ette stem to be inserted, the milk I ' | ' " " !s£&lt; /J^B test bottle should be held at an [ "1lSipj;i||iil||l!i||iS^^'\; angle to allow air to escape and to I ■■■^fr.^iBLS" * "', - j prevent splashing of milk. Blow the j [ ) " i " "V .".." ... ... j last drop of milk from the pipette. To insure accuracy, all tests should Flc - 3 ;7~ Two , mcthcx J s ° £ transferring the • -ii- milk to the test bottle with the 17.6 - be run in duplicate. cc . pipcttc . Adding acid Measure 17.5 cc. of commercial sulphuric acid (specific gravity 1.82- { 1.83) into an acid measure or dipper. The acid should be at a temperature between 60° and 70° F. Holding the test bottle at an angle of 45 degrees, rotate it between the fingers, and pour in the acid very slowly. This will wash all the milk out of the neck of the bottle, and, what' is more im - portant, will prevent the charring of the curd. Variations in the tempera - ture or strength of the acid will necessitate the use of a slightly greater or smaller quantity. It is advisable, therefore, to add the last third of the acid in three portions, shaking after each addition with an even rotary motion. Acid should be added until the mixture, after shaking and upon standing for a minute, has a chocolate brown color. In mixing milk and acid, rotate the test bottle slowly until all the curd has been dissolved, always keeping the mouth of the bottle pointed away from yourself and others to prevent any possibility of injury from spurting acid. Sulphuric acid is very corrosive in action, will burn the flesh and will destroy cloth, wood, etc. Plenty of cold water followed by water in which alkali wash - ing powder has been dissolved will stop its action. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 ffifflffl Qm Fig - 4. — Correct procedure in adding slll - f'^M^^B'l^^jBBHfflEfflKBlO phuric acid with the 17.5-cc. acid pajBlBnjBl * J^BiHnBHIBHllnmnB measure. Fig. 5. — Adding sulphuric acid with the 17.5-cc. acid dipper. Also bottle rack for 24 bottles. ■ " . . I lil I B - ." Fig. 6. — Left-hand bottle — immediately r JSSSBF j B¥" ] after acid has been added. Right-hand RV ' ' bottle — after mixing milk and acid. PfV^I i . . :. .j </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products CENTRIFUGING (Whirling) First time.— After the addition of the acid, place the test bottle in the centrifuge or Babcock tester. Always place the bottles opposite each other so that the revolving disc carrying the buckets or pockets for the bottles will be balanced. Use a bottle filled with water to balance if you have an uneven number of bottles. In centrifuges with double pockets, use the outside pockets if both are not filled. Revolve the bottles at the proper speed, as indicated on the machine, for five minutes after that speed has been attained. Stop the centrifuge gradually to prevent the breaking of bottles. Always be, sure that the centrifuge is level, securely fastened to a firm foundation to prevent vibration, and is well oiled, clean, and free from foreign material. After the centrifuge, add water at a temperature of not less than 180 F. until the bottle islfilled to within one-fourth to one-half inch of the base of the neck. It is impossible to have this water too hot. Soft or distilled water is preferable because sulphuric acid often forms gas bubbles in its action on lime salts in hard water, which collect at the surface of the fat column and make it difficult to read. If hard water must be used it may be desirable to add a small amount of sulphuric acid to the water before it is added to the contents of the test bottles. Approxi - mately a teaspoonful of acid to a gallon of water will be sufficient. A pipette or a small glass nozzle attached to a container by means of a rubber hose may be used to add hot water. Second time.— Centrifuge th«Ttest bottles for three minutes at the proper speed, after which add water at a temperature of not less than 180° F until the lower extremity of the fat column is well above the zero mark of the graduation or scale on the neck of the test bottle. Add water care - fully to prevent overflowing, and if using a pipette, do not let the tip reach the fat column. Third time.— Centrifuge the! test bottles at the proper speed for one minute, then place the test bottles in a water bath at a temperature of from 135 to 140 F. for five minutes, after which time the fat column may be measured. Any vessel of sufficient depth to hold enough water to im - merse all but the upper one-half inch of the top of the neck of the test bottle can be used as a water bath. A frame of metal with compartments for individual bottles is a great convenience. Fat columns can be meas - ured directly from a steam or other heated centrifuge, provided the tem - perature of the air within the centrifuge can be ; maintained between 135 and 140 F. during the time required to measure the fat columns. READING THE TESTS r Remove only one bottle from the water bath at a time. Hold the bottle in the hand with the fat column perpendicular and on a level with the eye. With the other hand place one point of a pair of dividers on the lowest point of the curve or meniscus at the bottom of the fat column, and the other point at the highest point of the fat column, or where the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 extreme upper edge of the fat comes in contact with the neck of the bottle. The curved surfaces at the top and bottom of the fat column are called the menisci (plural of meniscus). Hold the dividers without changing the distance between the points and place one point on the zero mark of the scale of the test bottle and take the reading on the scale as indicated by the other point. Always read to the nearest mark or graduation on the scale. The scale on the milk test bottle is marked in percentage of butterfat, being graduated to 8 or 10 per cent in tenths of one per cent. Fig. 7. — First position o£ the dividers when Fig. 8. — Second position o£ the dividers measuring the fat column of the whole- when reading the percentage of butter - milk test. The extremes of the fat fat in the whole-milk test. This sample column are included in the measure- tested 6.3 per cent butterfat. ment. Note the position of the thumb in holding the lower point of the dividers. * . ■ If the test bottle is held toward the light the extremities of the fat column may be seen distinctly. Readings should be made rapidly as the temperature of the fat column will change, causing an incorrect reading. The dividers should be tight enough at the joint so they will hold any position in which they are placed, but they should move freely. Dupli - cate tests should check within 0.1 per cent. EMPTYING THE TEST BOTTLES Empty the bottles into a stone or glass jar or on ashes. The acid in the test bottles should be carefully handled as it will attack wood, iron, steel, tin and most metals except brass and lead. The test bottles are easier to clean if vigorously shaken during emptying in order to dislodge the white (calcium sulphate) ! sediment in the bottom of the bottle and then washed at once. CLEANING GLASSWARE Test bottles and sample bottles should be rinsed out in warm water. They should then be filled with a solution of hot water in which an alkali washing powder is dissolved. Soap and soap powders are undesirable. Shake the test bottles vigorously, and clean the inside of the necks with a </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products •' .'.'■■ -I i small brush. Then empty and rinse thoroughly with clean, hot water. If this method is ineffective, add a little sulphuric acid, shake thoroughly, and if necessary heat the contents of the bottle by holding it in a vessel of hot water, shake again thoroughly, and then empty and rinse with clean water. A pipette should be rinsed out with water immediately after meas - uring the milk and then cleaned Iwith the other glassware. BABCOCK TEST FOR CREAM WEIGHING THE SAMPLE The sample or cream for testing should lje prepared the same as widi milk, except that 1 greater care should be taken in mixing to insure uni - form composition. Cream must be weighed into the test bottle instead of measured, as in the case of milk, for the following reasons: (1) the same volume of cream may vary much in weight because of the difference in the percentage of butterfat, 4 (2) sour cream or freshly separated B^^Hmi|HBj^^H cream may contain gas or air y . £ ■ -&lt; HHHH bubbles that increase the in- .i-^B^^|l|l||Sl!S|l|ip l ''V::l''- - accuracy of a measured sample, ■' : . and (3) the viscosity or thickness of cream causes it to stick to the inside of the pipette. I IjjiiB WJ^iI&amp;^'^HhK^'j I For weighing the cream sample,' fi'yllilff pi^^^^^St^^^&amp;fe' different types of balances or scales p^^^f'^t^'^l'^ftp 1 may he used. With a common type j "; 1;|&lt;lS|?B^K^§l|SiS^S|^^ ■■' the test bottle is placed on the -^&gt;^|SB^^i^^^S^' I left-hand pan of the balance and I '^J§i|BB?^fi^?^||-^^"i* ' : s - balanced by means' of an adjusting! L^^^^a JgSmBBttBB&amp;BB^^^' ' screw on the right-hand end of thej B''.'-3iM P'w^Sj^^^^iSt'!? 1 'fc' cream-test scale, i It is properly j [ ? 4f&gt;^H E^^^^^^J^^1 : ' I balanced if the) pointer when! ■■''^\J"^'&amp; 'I ' j swyiging free sWings an equal) r^itfpif ' |^^^ i^^^^fef^fe ■ distance to either side of the cen- ' LJ e * ter mark of the graduated scale. ' :- B^SS^^^^^^^^^B A 9-gram weight is then placed on r C •- J" I the right-hand pan of the cream- I 11 {- I test scale. With a|9 cc. or other j j ] 1 pipette, transfer enbugh cream to j B| ' ' t. j the test bottle so that the pointer \^T ■ / again swings an equal distance to i either side of this mark. Add the HHI^HI^^^^^HHH^H last bit of cream slowly, drop by i „ „ . drop. If too much cream is added FlC^^^ h fro^e'^plc Si to the cream test bottle it may be to the cream-test bottle previously removed by pouring it from the balanced on the scale. •Sec taMc. page 38. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 \ test bottle, inverting the test bottle on the finger and removing the cream that sticks to the finger, or by inserting a stick or pencil into the neck of the test bottle and removing the cream that adheres to it. After the cream test scale is once balanced it must not be moved until the desired amount of cream is weighed into the test bottle. Each bottle must be balanced separately on the test scale, as bottles are not of equal weight. If cream is spilled on the test scale pan it must be removed be - fore the final weight is taken. To insure accuracy all tests should be made in duplicate and should check within 0.5 per cent o£ each other. ADDING THE ACID Measure out 9 cc. of commercial sulphuric acid (specific gravity 1.82 - 1.83), which should be at a temperature between 60° and 70° F., into the acid measure or dipper, and add this acid to the I cream in the test bottle, hold- I «nj ing the test bottle neck at an i j i ifid^B^^^. angle to prevent the acid ; LJ j^M I^l. ' from charring the curd. Add | " ~T~ "■ :-/r~~( B^. enough acid to produce as Vy ■ ■';. j |JH&amp; chocolate brown color when j J ; f thoroughly mixed with the j !«^^H """"*""; , H cream. (Cream with a high I •' — ™^B j B^ percentage of butterfat will j /si ,"%JL "S^:lU\ A require slightly less acid than I \ \ ... .'^j^^B^. \ 1 that with a low butterfat I /' : : - ; ; ■* \ '*'^§^^ \^ "'' content.) Then add 10 to 12 J Kgf -- : : . .'v| V ;M cc. of water at a temperature ; Yfei; ir; - ■ '^^1^ or at least 180 F. to retard |^S^&gt;' --;:-■ v'./:., 1 the action of the acid; since I \^c r '• I cream contains a higher per - centage of fat and a lower FlG - 10 - — Position o£ the dividers in measuring -,»-,„„ «f «»U VA l he fat column in the completed cream test percentage of other solids after glymol has beea addc^ Thc measurc . and water than does whole ment includes the portion between thc bot - milk, thc acid is more likely tom "t tn c lower meniscus and the line be - to cause charring. tween the glymol and the fat at the top. The test bottles are centrifuged for the same length of time and water added in the same way as in the milk test. READING THE TESTS The completed tests are read from a water bath at a temperature of be - tween 135° and 140° F. In the case of cream, glymol or red reader is usually added to the upper surface, after which the fat column is meas - ured from its lower extremity to the juncture or union of the glymol and fat at the top of the column. If the fat columns are to be measured widiout </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products the use of glymol, only one-third of the upper meniscus is included. The graduated scale on the: cream test bottle is marked in percentage of butter - fat from 0 to 50, the smallest graduation being 0.5 per cent. After being read, the test bottles are emptied and cleaned the same as milk test bottles. BABCOCK TEST FOR SKIM MILK AND BUTTERMILK In general the same procedure is followed in testing skim milk as in testing whole milk, but there are certain exceptions. Double-necked test bottles having a large filling neck and a small graduated neck are used because of the small amount of fat contained in skim milk. More acid is required for skim milk and buttermilk because of the greater percentage of water and solids not fat. If 17.5 cc. of the available acid are required for the whole-milk test, then from 19 to 20 cc. of that acid will be required for the skim milk test. The contents of the bottle can be more easily mixed without splashing curd particles into the small graduated tube if only approximately three : fourths of the 1 required amount of acid is added at first. When this has been mixed with the milk the remainder of the acid is added and mixing completed, lit is desirable to hold the bottle with the small graduated, tube uppermost when mixing the acid with the skim milk. Skim milk tests should be centrifuged 10 minutes the first time in - stead of 5 minutes to insure the most complete separation of the very small butterfat globules found in skim milk. The skim milk test bottles should be placed in the centrifuge with the filling neck toward the center, so that the passage of the fat into the small graduated neck will not be obstructed by the filling tube. The reading of the test after tempering to between 135° and 140° F. may be madej direct or with a pair of dividers. The graduated scale of the skim milk bottle has a range from 0 to 0.25 or 050 per cent, the smallest graduation being 1/100 (0.01) of one per cent. It sometimes saves time in testing of s,kim milk, buttermilk, or whey, if two whole-milk bottles | are used together with the skim milk bottles, since the percentage of fat in the sample may be too large to be measured in skim milk bottles. BABCOCK TEST FOR WHEY The Babcock test for fat in whey is tlie same as that for skim milk and buttermilk except that less sulphuric acid is used. If 19-20 cc. of the available acid has been satisfactory in the skim milk test, then 8 to 12 cc. will be sufficient for the whey test, since whey has a smaller quantity of solids to dissolve than skim milk in order to liberate the fat. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 ' - '■•"' ■ 11 I I HI ' I ■ ■ ■ • H ~- - II I'J Fie. 11. — (1) Completed whole-milk test, (2) completed cream test, (3) completed skim - milk test. PRECAUTIONS AND SUGGESTIONS 1. Keep sulphuric acid of the correct specific gravity tightly covered, since it will absorb moisture from the air and become weaker. 2. If too strong (too high specific gravity), sulphuric acid may be weakened by allowing it to be exposed to the air. Do not add water to suphunc acid, as it will splash and spatter and cause much damage. If sulphuric acid is to be diluted with water, pour the acid carefully into the required amount of water in a suitable heat-resistant container. 3. Make all tests in duplicate to insure accuracy. Milk-test duplicates should check within one-tenth of one (0.1) per cent; cream test duplicates to one-half of one (0.5) per cent; and skim milk, buttermilk or whey duplicates to 2/100 (0.02) per cent. 4. If foreign matter appears in the fat column or directly below it re - peat the test. ' 5. Glymol or red reader is a white mineral oil colored red with alkanet root so as to produce a contrast with the fat column and is used only in cream testing. Since a lower-grade oil may be used which tends to mix with the fat and make the upper line indistinct, it is advisable to add the reader carefully and just before measuring the fat column </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products .6. Take all temperatures with a thermometer. Accuracy is necessary. 7. Hard water may be used if it has been boiled, or if a few drops of sulphuric acid have been added to it and it has been allowed to stand long enough for all gas to escape. 8. Sharp-pointed dividers are necessary in making an accurate measure - ment of the fat column. 9. If possible, centrifuge tests immediately after the correct amount of acid has been added and mixed with the contents of the bottle; otherwise they must be reheated to 180° F. by placing them in a water bath for at least 10 minutes. 10. Small shot used with-, hot water and alkali will help clean dirty glassware. DEFECTS OF FAT COLUMNS— CAUSES AND REMEDIES The perfect finished test should show a clear fat column varying from straw to golden yellow in color with upper and lower surfaces clear and distinct. A dark fat column or one that has dark specks within or directly below it may be due to any of the following causes: Cause Remedy 1. Acid too strong. Use less acid or the same quantity of weaker acid. 2. Too much acid. Use less acid. 3. Pouring acid directly into milk. Pour acid down side of bottle held at an angle. 4. Uneven mixing of acid and milk. Mix milk or cream with acid with an even rotary motion. 5. Acid too warm. Temper to between 60° and 70° F. 6. Milk too warm. Temper to between 60° and 70° F. 7. Failure to mix milk with acid promptly Mix acid and milk soon after the ad - after addition of acid. dition of the acid. 8. Failure to add water before ccntrifuging Add proper quantity of water before in a cream test. whirling or ccntrifuging for first time. A light-colored fat column or one that has light specks within or directly below it may be due to any of the following causes: Cause Remedy 1. Acid too weak. Use more acid or the same quantity of stronger acid. 2. Too little acid. Use more acid. 3. Milk too cold. Temper to between 60° and 70° F. 4. Acid too cold. Temper to between 60° and 70° F. 5. Curd not dissolved before ccntrifuging. Mix milk and acid thoroughly before rentrifuging. 6. In cream testing — adding the check Contents of bottle should be dark coffee water too soon. brown in color before check water is added. A milky-colored fat column in cream testing is sometimes caused by the use of either a large excess of acid or too-strong acid, together with the failure to add water before centrifuging. A smaller quantity of stand - ard acid, or the same quantity of weaker acid, together with the addition of water before centrifuging, will prevent the trouble. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 SUMMARY OF PROCEDURES IN BABCOCK TESTS Always run duplicate tests •£ SKIM MILK S WHOLE MILK CREAM OR WHEY £ BUTTERMILK f. Test bottles to use 8% or 10% 9-gm. 50% Double-necked Double-necked &gt; whole milk bottles' cream bottles' skim milk bottles skim milk bottles .*• so Amount of sample to use in each test bottle Measure Weigh Measure Measure o 17.5 cc. 9 gms. 17.5 cc. 17.5 cc. [• — Approximate amount of acid to use (sp. gr. H 1.82-1.83) (60°-70° F.) 17.5 cc. 9 cc. 19-20 cc. 8-12 cc. | Centrifuge (whirl) first time _ ■ : 5 min. Add 10-12 cc. 180° F. 10 min. 10 min. w water, then ccntri- * fugc 5 min. g Adding water, first time, 180° F. or warmer Enough to raise the buttcrfat column to within about one-half inch of the base of the « neck of the bottle. w Centrifuge (whirl) second time 3 min. 3 min. 3 min. 3 min. Adding water, second time, 180° F. or warmer Enough to raibc all of the buttcrfat above the zero of the graduated scale on the neck of g the test bottle. - , § Centrifuge (whirl), third time 1 min. 1 min. 1 min. 1 min. Water bath 135°-H0° F. 5 min. 5 min. 5 min. 5 min. 3 Reading— Remove only one bottle from water Use Add a few drops of Read direct or use dividers. P bath at a time dividers glymol and use divid- J° ers. u! 1 See Nebraska Siamhrd Dairy Law, Bui. No. 3,. Department of Agriculture, State Capitol, Lincoln. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products CAUSES OF BUTTERFAT VARIATIONS IN SEPARATED CREAM RICHNESS OF THE MILK \ Milk from a herd of cows varies in butterfat percentage from day to day as has been explained. The cream or skim milk screws of the separator are set to divide the milk into a definite proportion of cream to skim milk. If, for example, the separator is adjusted to deliver 15 pounds of cream and 85 pounds of skim milk from each 100 pounds of milk separ - ated, and the milk tested 4.5 peri cent butterfat, the 15 pounds of cream would contain 4.5 pounds of butterfat or the cream would test 30 per cent (45-*- 15X100, or 30). If the milk tested only 4 per cent, then the 15 pounds of cream would contain 4.0 pounds of butterfat. The cream in that case would test 4.0-5-15x100, or 26.67 per cent. These illustrations assume no loss of butterfat in skimming. VARIATION IN| SEPARATOR SPEED Cream separators are adjusted ] to skim efficiently at a certain speed. If run faster, more skim milk is run through and consequently less cream, and the resulting cream contains a higher percentage of butterfat. Such operation sometimes causes clogging of the cream outlet and a consequent loss of fat in the skim milk. If operated slower than the proper speed, the proportion of cream to milk is increased and the cream contains a lower percentage of butterfat. Slow running is likely to cause incomplete skimming, i] TEMPERATURE OF THE MILK Milk should be separated at temperatures between 90° and 98° F. At those temperatures the separation is usually most complete. Cold milk causes a smaller quantity of richer| cream, since the cream is heavy and viscous and does not readily flow through the cream opening, and conse - quently a larger quantity of skim milk is obtained. Because of the re - duced flow through the cream opening, some fat may be carried out with the skim milk. RATE OF MILK FLOW INTO SEPARATOR BOWL The valve on the supply tank is: adjusted with the float to deliver the proper quantity of milk when the supply tank is full. When the valve is not opened completely, or when the supply tank is only partially filled, there is less pressure forcing milk into the bowl. Under such conditions, the centrifugal force in the bowl acts upon a smaller quantity of milk and consequently produces a smaller quantity of cream with a higher percentage of butterfat. Any condition that increases the inflow tends to decrease the percentage of butterfat in the cream. ■ . \ ... ADJUSTMENT OF CREAM OR SKIM MILK SCREWS The cream or skim milk screws regulate the proportion of skim milk to cream, and thus affect the quantity and percentage of butterfat in the cream. The larger the quantity of cream, the lower it will test, and the </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 smaller the quantity of cream the higher it will test. The cream screw when turned farther toward the center of the bowl produces a smaller quantity of higher-testing cream and when adjusted toward the outside produces a larger quantity of lower-testing cream. In the case of the skim milk screws, the effect is exactly opposite. CLEANLINESS OF THE BOWL If a separator bowl is not washed thoroughly after each separation, the cream outlet may become clogged, thus causing higher-testing cream and probably a loss of butterfat in the skim milk. QUANTITY OF FLUSH WATER In order to prevent the waste of cream that sticks to the various parts at the completion of the separation, it is a good practice to run a quart or two of clean, lukewarm water or separated milk through the separator to flush out the bowl and cream spout. As soon as the liquid flowing from the cream spout becomes watery or thin in appearance, turn it so that the excess flush material flows into the skim milk. If the excess flush material is allowed to flow into the cream, the test will be lowered. VIBRATION OF SEPARATOR BOWL Any vibration of the separator bowl is likely to cause incomplete separa - tion and a loss of butterfat in the skim milk. Vibration may be caused by an improperly balanced bowl, a bent spindle, improper adjustments, worn parts, or an unsteady separator. CAUSES OF VARIATION IN MILK AND CREAM TESTS A true and representative sample of the total quantity of milk or cream is essential to an accurate test. This sample must be at the proper tem - perature and thoroughly mixed at the time a portion is transferred to the test bottle. This portion must be accurately measured in the case of milk or weighed in the case of cream. Carelessness in any particular may pro - duce inaccurate results. The temperature at which tests are read is an .important factor in their accuracy. At the time of reading, the test should be at temperatures be - tween 135° and 140° F. A low temperature tends to lower the reading and a high temperature tends to raise the reading, especially with cream tests. A few actual examples will illustrate the effect of temperatures upon the readings of the same tests: ; MILK TESTS CREAM TESTS Correct Low Correct Low High Temperature Temperature Temperature Temperature Temperature 135°-H0°F. 115° F. 135°-140°F. 115° F. 157° F. 5.1 5.0 • 24.5 24.0 25.0 4.1 4.0 30.0 29.5 . 30.5 3.8 3.7 34.5 34.0 35.0 7.9 7.8 24.0 23.5 24.5 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products Tests may be read differently by different persons. This is illustrated by the following examples where four tests were made by one person and were read independently at the proper temperature by four persons. Chemical Rose- Person Person Person Person Gottlieb' No. 1 No.'(2 No. 3 No 4 3-58 3.6 3.6 3.4 3 5 3.57 3.6 3.6 3.6 3 5 3.96 4.1 4.1 4.0 4.0 3.96 4.0 3.9 3.8 3.9 Failure to read the fat column correctly is quite common and is usually due to not having the tests level with 1 eyes, to the indistinctness of the menisci, or the presence of foreign material (curd or char) in or directly below the fat column. MODIFIED BABCOCK TESJT FOR BUTTERMILK A practical method for the determination of the fat in buttermilk has been given. Although used extensively ithe results of this method do not compare favorably with official ethernextraction methods. A method known as the "normal butyl alcohol", "American Association", or "Mitchell method" gives results comparing quite favorably with ether - extraction methods. The "normal butyl alcohol" procedure for the determ - ination of the fat content of buttermilk is as follows: 1. Measure 2.0 cc. of normal butyl alcohol into a skim-milk test bottle graduated to 0.5 per cent. 2. Add 9 cc. of buttermilk and mix the contents of the bottle thoroughly. 3. Add 7 to 9 cc. of the Babcock testing acid, a few cubic centimeters at a time. The exact amount of acid will need to be determined by ex - perience, since sufficient acid must be used to produce a golden yellow fat column in the finished test. 4. Mix the contents of the bottle thoroughly. 5. Centrifuge 6 minutes at the regular speed. 6. Add sufficient water (180° F. or above) to fill the bottle to within 54 to Y 2 inch of the base of the neck. 7. Centrifuge 2 minutes at the regular speed. 8. Add sufficient water (180° F. or above) to bring the fat column well into the graduated neck of the bottle.; 9. Centrifuge 2 minutes at the regular speed. 10. Place the bottles in a water bath at! 135° to 140° F. for 5 minutes and include both menisci when measuring the fat column. 11. Multiply the reading by 2 to obtain the percentage of fat. MODIFIED BABCOCK TEST FOR ICE CREAM It is impossible to determine the fat content of ice cream accurately by the regular Babcock procedure because of the charring action of the acid • Approved method of the Association of Official Agricultural Chemistl. ■ . ■ • ■ ■ ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 on the sugar of the ice cream. The following outline of the "Nebraska procedure" or "Crowe test" is based upon the results of experimental work reported in Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Bulletin 246. Two reagents are needed. They are designated for convenience as A and B. Reagent A is a mixture of normal butyl alcohol and concentrated ammonium hydroxide made lip in the following proportions: 9 parts of normal butyl alcohol and 1 part chemically pure ammonium hydroxide by volume. This reagent is stable when kept in a tightly stoppered bottle. Reagent B is a mixture of equal parts by volume of sulphuric acid (sp. gr. 1.82-1.83) and ethyl alcohol (95 per cent.) 0 This mixture is prepared by pouring the acid slowly into the alcohol in a glass beaker or other glass container which will withstand high temperature. After all the acid has been added the mixture should be stirred with a glass rod and finally cooled to room temperature before using. This reagent may produce unsatisfactory results when more than two months old. The procedure is as follows: 1. Nine grams of a properly prepared sample of ice cream or ice-cream mix is weighed into each of two 8 per cent whole-milk test bottles 7 or 20 per cent 9-gram ice-cream test bottles. 2. Add 5 cc. of reagent A to each bottle and mix the contents of the bottle thoroughly. 3. Add 30 cc. of reagent B' (at room temperature) and again mix the contents of the bottle thoroughly until all the curd is dissolved. (If the volume of the base of the bottle permits adding only 28 to 29 cc. of reagent B the results are usually satisfactory although it is advisable to select bottles which will hold the full 30 cc.) 4. Place the bottles in a water bath at a temperature of from 175° to 180° F. and heat for 15 minutes. It is important that the temperature of this water bath should not vary more than 5° F. as indicated. The con - tents of the bottles must be mixed at least three times during this heating period. 5. Centrifuge at the regular speed for 5 minutes. 6. Shake the bottle thoroughly and if the contents of the bottle are not up to the base of the neck add sufficient water (180° F. or above) to raise the contents to within about % inch of the base of the neck. 7. Centrifuge at the regular speed for 3 minutes. 8. Again mix the contents of the bottle thoroughly and then add sufficient water (180° F. or above) to raise the fat well into the graduated portion of the neck of the bottle. 9. Centrifuge at the regular speed for 1 minute. 10. Place the bottles in a water bath at 135-140° F. for 5 minutes and measure the fat columns after adding glymol. * If 95 per cent ethyl alcohol is unobtainable, specially denatured alcohol formula 30 may be used. T A milk test bottle with a large base is best adapted for this procedure. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products 11. The percentage o£ fat is read direct from the bottle if a 9-gram 20 per cent ice cream test bottle has been used, but the reading from the neck of the 8 per cent whole-milk test bottle must be multiplied by 2 to obtain the percentage of fat. The test should always be made in duplicate and the results from the two bottles should check within 0.2 per cent fat in the sample. FACTORY PROCEDURE COMPLETE BUTTER ANALYSIS (Modified Kohman Procedure) " ' 1 H — H ■ ! ■ '"■■■' ! I Fig. 12. — Equipment and reagents for making a complete analysis of butter. The following equipment is needed: Sample jar — 4 to 6-ounce capacity with tight-fitting lid. Spatula or similar device (an ordinary table or case knife may be used). Aluminum cup — 200 cc. to 250 cc. capacity. Moisture test scale and 10-gram weight. Tongs. Alcohol lamp, gas flame, or electric hot plate. Graduate — 100 cc. capacity. Burette: — 25 to 50 cc. capacity. Silver nitrate solution 29.06 grams silver nitrate per liter or H.53 grams per liter. Pipette — 17.6 cc. or 25 cc. Potassium chroma tc indicator — 10 per cent solution in distilled water. Distilled water. Petroleum ether. Cleaner's naphtha or even a very high-grade gasoline has been found to be satisfactory. SAMPLING After scraping aside the surface remove at least three portions from different parts of the churn and transfer to sample jar; or cut a slice about '/2-inch in thickness from the center of a pound print; or with a trier re - move three portions from the tub, one portion from the center, another near the edge, and the third half-way between these two. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 If necessary to procure a heavy, creamy consistency of the sample, place the closed jar with the sample in water at a temperature not exceeding 100° F. This is not ordinarily necessary with samples from the churn. (Do not heat the sample sufficiently to cause the fat to oil off.) Remove the sample jar lid and mix the sample thoroughly with the spatula. MOISTURE DETERMINATION Heat the clean aluminum cup, cool, and balance on the right hand scale pan with the 2-gram weight on 0 of the 20 per cent beam and the 1-gram weight on the 10 per cent mark of the 10 per cent beam. Place the 10-gram weight on the left pan of the scale and weigh into the aluminum cup ex - actly 10 grams of butter. Hold the cup containing the sample by means of the tongs and lower it into a small colorless gas or alcohol flame, or set • ■ * IBft 1 ■ ■ ' " i i^ . - «-■». i'mh-i^-.w'l ■ i ■ i ; ' . ■-"■• • " : . ,-•■,.,,. ■'•■ '..'.....'.. ■. \.i. Fig. 13. — Equipment and reagents for determining moisture in butter. it on a heated electric plate (260° ;F.). As the sample is heated rotate the cup gently and take care that none of the sample boils or spatters over the edge. Continue the slow heating until the sample stops sputtering and a light brown color appears in the curd (without any great amount of browning of the fat itself), and a faint odor of burned butter is detected. Cool the cup and sample at once. For greatest accuracy this should be done by allowing the cup to stand on a clean table or metal plate. If the result must be reported quickly, the cup may be immersed part way in a pan of clean, cold water until cool, and then carefully and thoroughly dried with a clean, dry, lintless towel. Replace the cooled cup containing the water-free butter on the right hand pan of the scales (which should not be disturbed in the meantime). Move the rider on the 20 per cent beam to the right until the cup is again in balance. Read the percentage of moisture directly from the beam. Read to the nearest 0.1 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products FAT DETERMINATION Use the residue from the moisture determination. Do not disturb the scales. Pour about 100 cc. of petroleum ether or high-test gasoline over the residue in the cup. Rotate gently to mix, then let the cup stand un - disturbed for not less than 2 minutes. Then carefully pour off the ether or gasoline containing the dissolved fat as completely as possible without losing any of the curd. Complete the removal of fat by adding another 100 cc. of petroleum ether or gasoline and pouring it off as before. Dry off the rest of the ether or gasoline by warming the cup on a heated electric plate or over the flame. (Ether and gasoline are highly inflammable and must be heated carefully if over an open flame.) Heat until the residue in the cup appears as a fine, dry powder which does not stick to - gether or stick to the cup. In case the residue is dark colored and sticky, add another 50 cc. of the petroleum ether or gasoline and pour off as be - fore. This difficulty is experienced more often with gasoline than with ether but may be due to failure to pour off sufficient quantity of the solvent. Allow cup to cool and replace it on the right hand pan of the moisture scales. Remove the 10-gram weight, slide the 2-gram weight to the 0 mark and balance the cup and contents by moving the 1-gram weight to the left. The percentage of salt, ash, and curd is determined by reading from right to left on the 10 per cent scale; i.e., if weight rests on the sec - ond graduation to the left of 7, the percentage of salt, ash, and curd would be 3.2. The percentage of moisture plus the percentage of salt, ash, and curd subtracted from 100 equals the percentage of fat. SALT DETERMINATION ~ /~ --•:-•— - -- - .- — .,, _...._,..„..,_ To the residue from the fat determination add 176 cc. or 250 cc. of distilled . ■ water (use 250 cc. if a 25-cc. | pipette is available, or 176 | cc. if a 17.6-cc. pipette is J to be used). Mix the rcsi- Jt "^Hl due and water by rotating 11 the container or stirring with the pipette. Transfer j - 1 17.6 cc. or 25 cc. (depend- I J ing on amount of water j rJ,._ J added) to a white cup. Add [^^§1 II .Jf 2 or 3 drops of potassium - __^^p^S^^^^^X^^ BP ___^^£iA chromate indicator (10 per &lt; 'feiillffi^* j f ; 7 j cent solution). Then with ; ' -^HaggliS' t "I^~* ■•_ . ! constant rotating of the '. - — &gt;^*.-&gt;^g^s-^-tfJSB5R v 'vi__J cup or stirring the contents mHRI of the cup with a stirring _ ,, _ . . , , j ■ i m . Flc - 14. — Equipment and reagents for determin - rod, run in the silver nitrate ing , he sa | t content of buttcr . </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 solution from the burette until a faint brownish color appears through - out the mixture in the cup. Read from the burette the number of cubic centimeters of silver nitrate solution used, to the nearest cubic centimeter. Each cubic centimeter of silver nitrate solution used represents 1 per cent of salt in the sample when the silver nitrate solution contains 29.06 grams per liter or 0.5 per cent when 1453 grams per liter is used. CURD DETERMINATION This is determined by difference. The percentage of salt, curd, and ash has been determined. Likewise the percentage of salt has been de - termined. The difference between these figures is the percentage of curd and ash or as commonly reported, the percentage of curd. DETERMINING THE ACIDITY OF DAIRY PRODUCTS Normal milk when first drawn from the cow will show a titratable acidity of 0.10 to 0.14 per cent, which is due to the carbon dioxide, casein and acid-reacting salts con - tained in the milk. As the ; . . . milk stands, especially if not kept cold, the acidity increases as a result of nor - mal bacteria of the milk n I acting upon the lactose or I i j milk sugar and changing it to lactic acid. The final i _' 7 j j amount of acid produced """skil may exceed 1.0 per cent. W Milk as delivered at the .^^^^. !j cent titratable acidity. An I isSXsgll I acidity of 026 to 030 per r^Sffi^ ' W i cent can be detected by l-1«K&amp;|§il . -ff-L. t** ' taste - ' j llffiiiiiii \\ r LnmcJ ' In determining the acid- Pi^^MF^'' ■' '--~ '^'IHHHH ity of milk, the chemical [^jJUjjHHf'- 7 '^'- ':' ''?■ -t ■"■■■ v', i - - I principle that acids and ! , % ""''™'™ S^ l^i^S*' 1 *^!-^} J alkalis will neutralize each ■ t^===^0ZS2^~ :=: ~^££.'^Ll?. 1 other and produce water ■ j and a neutral substance called a salt is used. A Fig. 15.— Equipment and reagents for detcrmin - definite quantity of the in S the percentage of acid in dairy products. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products alkali will always neutralize or combine with a definite quantity of the acid; thus, by knowing the strength of the alkali and the amount used in neutralizing the acid in a known quantity of milk, we can readily calculate the amount of acid present. An "indicator", which by a change of color indicates that all the acid in the sample has been neutralized by the alkali, is used. This indicator is phenophthalein. EQUIPMENT AND REAGENTS NEEDED 1. An alkali (sodium hydroxide) solution of a definite concentration known as tenth normal. This solution contains 4.0 grams of the pure alkali per liter (1000 cc.) and should be procured from a supply house. One cc. of this solution will neutralize 0.009 gram of lactic acid. 2. Phenophthalein indicator — made by dissolving 10 grams of the powder in 300 cc. denatured alcohol. 3. A white cup. 4. A 17.6 cc. and a 9 cc. pipette. 5. A 25 cc. or 50 cc. burette with clamp and support. An automatic burette attached directly to the alkali bottle may be obtained from a supply OUSC# PROCEDURES For milk, skim milk, and whey. — Transfer 17.5 cc. of the sample to the white cup. Add 3 drops of the indicator. While mixing the contents of the cup with a rotary motion add the alkali from the burette drop by drop until the first faint but permanent pink color develops. Read from the burette the number of cubic centimeters of alkali used. This divided by 20 will equal the percentage of acid. For cream and ice cream mix. — Transfer 9 cc. of the sample to the white cup and rinse the pipette with 9 cc. of distilled water, adding this to . the cup also. Proceed as in the case of milk. The number of cubic centi - meters of alkali used divided by 10 is the percentage of acid. For condensed milk. — Use 9 cc. of the sample and rinse the pipette with sufficient distilled water to bring the sample to about the same con - sistency as whole milk and proceed as in the case of milk. The number of cubic centimeters of alkali used divided by 10 is the percentage of acid. CALCULATIONS AND SUGGESTIONS Since it has been indicated that 1.0 cc. of the alkali exactly neutralizes 0.009 gram of lactic acid, it follows that the following formula applies to all cases of acidity determinations for milk products when using a tenth normal alkali. Cubic centimeters of alkali used X 0.009 ,«_ . , - Tr . , ? ; 7—. r X 100= per cent acid. Weight of sample used (grams) Dilution of the sample with distilled water has an effect upon the titratable acidity but the above procedures are outlined to give comparable </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 results with various products. Clean equipment and careful following of the directions are essential if dependable results are to be obtained. DETERMINING TOTAL SOLIDS IN MILK PRODUCTS BY GRAVIMETRIC METHODS This method of determining the solids in dairy products consists in evaporating the water from a definite quantity of the product by the appli - cation of heat. I" '-' ""£■'•• ■!!» jjE^'t ;*»-'" J&gt; "j I" 1 f^^fa^J^^fc^'1 1 ■ ] •piiiiiH b&lt; /Nn I r I . Fie. 16. — Equipment for determining the moisture or total solids in dairy products. ■ Water oven (left), usually heated by a gas burner, in which weighed samples are dried to constant weight. Desiccator (middle) with aluminum dishes in which the weighed samples are cooled previous to reweighing after drying. Analytical balance (right) for weighing dishes and sample. EQUIPMENT NECESSARY 1. Balance or scale. For most accurate work an analytical balance must be used; however, results which may be satisfactory for use in regular dairy plant procedure may be obtained when using the torsion moisture test scale or a scale of equal sensitivity. 2. A set of analytical weights ranging from 1 milligram (0.001 gram) to 100 grams. 3. An aluminum, flat-bottom dish about 3 inches in diameter and about 54 inch high. 4. A cover for the aluminum dish. 5. A water-jacketed oven which may be hca.ed to and maintained at the temperature of boiling water. 6. A desiccator — a glass vessel with a drying agent (calcium chloride is commonly used) in the base {and a tight fitting cover. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products PROCEDURE FOR MILK, SKIM MILK, BUTTERMILK, AND WHEY 1. Heat the aluminum dish in the oven at the temperature of boiling water for at least one hour. 2. Cool the dish in the desiccator. 3. Weigh dish and cover and record weight. 4. Transfer 3 to 5 cc. of the milk product to the dish, replace cover, and reweigh and record weight. 5. Place the dish and contents without cover in oven and dry to con - stant weight, i.e., until there is no further loss in weight when the results of two successive weighings (at half hour intervals) are compared. 6. Cool dish and contents in desiccator. 7. Weigh dish and cover and dried contents. 8. Calculate the percentage of moisture and percentage of total solids. Example: Weight of dish and cover, plus milk product 20.05 gram;, Weight of dish and cover 16.01 grams Weight of milk product 4.04 grams Weight of dish and cover and dried-milk product 16.55 grams Weight of dish and cover 16.01 grams Weight of dried milk product. . 0.54 grams 4.04 — 0.54 = 3.50 grams evaporated moisture. 3.50 •^04 X 100 = 86.63 % moisture. 100— 86.63 = 13.37 % solids. PROCEDURE FOR CREAM, EVAPORATED MILK, CONDENSED MILK, AND ICE CREAM MIX Proceed in the same manner as described for milk, skim milk, etc., except that because of the viscosity of these products it may be desirable to add 1 to 2 cc. of distilled water to the sample after it is weighed into the dish; this causes a more even distribution of the sample over the bottom of the dish for drying. CALCULATION OF TOTAL SOLIDS OF WHOLE MILK BY FORMULA For this calculation it is necessary to determine the lactometer reading and the percentage of butterfat of the sample of milk. A lactometer is a hydrometer graduated especially for determining the specific gravity of milk. Either the Quevenne or the New York Board of Health lactometer is commonly used. The first is graduated from 15 to 40, and the latter from 0 to 120. Readings may be made when the milk is between 50° F. and 70° F. but a correction factor must be applied to a reading at any temperature other than 60° F. The correction factor for the Quevenne lactometer is 0.1 for each degree. With temperatures above 60° F. the correction is added to the reading, but for temperatures below 60° F. it is subtracted. A correction factor of 0.3 is applied in the same way with the New York Board of Health lactometer. In obtaining a lactometer reading the temperature of the milk is first adjusted to nearly 60° F., the milk is mixed thoroughly but carefully to avoid incorporation of air and then it is transferred to a glass cylinder of </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 sufficient depth and diameter to allow the lactometer to move up and down freely. The lactometer is inserted and after about a half minute the point at which the surface of the milk (not the meniscus) intersects the stem is recorded, as well as the temperature. The butterfat determina - tion of the sample is also made, using the regular Babcock procedure. The following is an example of the calculations to be made: Quevenne lactometer reading is 32 at 66° F. and the butterfat content of the sample is 43 per cent. Since the lactometer reading was made at a temperature other than 60° F., the correction factor must be applied. The above figures are used in the formula, Vi L+1.2 F=per cent total solids (L=the cor - rected Quevenne lactometer reading and F=the percentage o£ butterfat). 32+0.6 = 32.6 32 6 -J-+ (1-2 X 4.3) =8.15 + 5.16 = 13.31 per cent total solids. The New York Board of Health lactometer may be used, but the read - ing obtained with it must be converted to its Quevenne value. ' This is ac - complished by correcting the lactometer reading for temperature other than 60° F. and then multiplying this corrected reading by 0.29; the result will be the corresponding Quevenne reading. The procedure is then followed as outlined above. PROBLEMS IN DAIRY ARITHMETIC The following examples arej selected to illustrate calculations more commonly encountered in dairy work. 1. What is the amount of butterfat in each of the following? 120 lbs milk containing. . . . ' 3.2 % butterfat 1 HO lbs. milk containing I 3.9 % butterfat 12 lbs. cream containing. :'.' 42.5 % butterfat 340 lbs. cream containing. . . I 27.0 % butterfat 62 lbs. skim milk containing 0.04% butterfat 12,057 lbs. buttermilk containing 0.25% butterfat 3,048 lbs. whey containing. .'. j 0.55% butterfat Procedure: 120X0.032 (3.2%) =3.84 lbs. butterfat 1,140X0.039 (3.9%) =44.46 lbs. butterfat 12X0.425 (42.5%) =5.10 lbs. butterfat 340X0.27 (27.0%) =91.80 lbs. butterfat 62X0.0004 (0.04%) =.0248 lb. butterfat 12,057X0.0025 (0.25%) =30.1425 lbs. butterfat 3,048X0.0055 (0.55%) = 16.7640 lbs. butterfat 2. If the cream, the whole milk, and the skim milk in the above ex - ample are all mixed together, what will be the percentage of butterfat of the mixture?. ; Use the following formula: Total pounds of butterfat := — ; t 1 — : X 100 = % butterfat in mixture. Total pounds or mixture </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products Then 120 + 1140 + 12+340 + 62 = 1,674 pounds in the mixture. 3.84 + 44.46 + 5.10+91.80 + 0.0248=145.2248 pounds of butterfat in the mix - ture. 145.2248 lbs. butterfat 1674 i bs . mbtture X 100 = 8.675% butterfat in the mixture 3. If a farmer separates an average of four 10-gallon cans of milk daily and the skim milk from the separator contains 0.12 per cent butterfat what is the value of the butterfat lost in the skim milk in 60 days if butterfat is worth 28 cents per pound. Procedure: One gallon of milk weighs 8.6 lbs. This may be calculated from the weight of a gallon of water (weight 8.34 pounds) and the average specific gravity of milk, thus 8.34X1.032=8.6. Then 8.6X10X4 = 344 lbs. milk in four 10-gallon cans. Since the separator may be assumed to deliver approximately 10 lbs. cream and 90 lbs. of skim milk from each 100 lbs. milk separated, then 344 X .90 = 309.6 lbs. skim milkX60 days = 18576 lbs. of skim milk. 18576 X. 0012 = 22.2912 lbs. of butterfat, or approximately 22.3 lbs. and 22.3 X $0.28 equals $6,244 or $6.24. . 4. If in the above example the farmer separated milk testing 42 per cent butterfat and the fat loss in the skim milk was so small as to be negligible, (a) What would be the percentage of butterfat in the cream? (b) How many pounds of cream would be procured? (c) What would be the value of the fat in the cream? Procedure: (a) 100 lbs. milk =10 lbs. cream and 90 lbs. skim milk. 100 lbs. milk contains 4.2 lbs. butterfat; therefore, 10 lbs. cream contains 4.2 4 2 lbs. butterfat and— — X 100 = 42% butterfat in the cream. (b) 344 lbs. milk daily X 60 days = 20,640 lbs. milk. 20,640X0.10 (pounds of cream from each pound of milk) = 2,064 lbs. cream. (c) 2,064 lbs. cream X 0.42 = 866.88 lbs. butterfat. 866.88 X $0.28 = $242.73. PROBLEMS IN THE STANDARDIZATION OF THE FAT CONTENT OF MILK AND CREAM The various types of problems in the standardization of milk and cream which may be encountered are illustrated below. In the first problem the details of the method are given while in the later problems these are omitted. The Pearson Square method is used. 1. How much 4.2 per cent milk must be added to 103.5 pounds of 22 per cent cream to reduce the fat content to 18 per cent? First draw a rectangle or square and place at its left hand corners the figures designating the percentage of butterfat in die products to be mixed together, then place in the center of the square the pcrcentaRe of butterfat desired in the final product. Now subtract diagonally across the square, and always the smaller number from the larger, placing Ihc result in the diagonally opposite corner. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 4.2 I 4.0 18.0 I ■ 1 22.0 13.8 The figures on the right hand corners now represent the proportion in which the two products must be mixed. That is, 4 lbs. of 4.2% milk must be mixed with 13.8 lbs. of 22.0% cream to produce 18.0% cream, consequently 103.5 -J3-jj-X4 = 30 lbs. of 4.2% milk needed 13.8 : 103.5:: 4 :X 13.8X = 414 X=30 lbs. 4.2% milk needed. Then 30 lbs. of 4.2% milk when mixed with 103.5 lbs. of 22% cream will make 133.5 lbs. of 18% cream. 2. How much 20 per cent cream must be added to 120 lbs. of 2.8 per cent milk to increase the fat content to 3.7 per cent? The figures are now placed on the square according to the plan illustrated in the preceding problem and we have 2.8 _ 16.3 3.7 20 0.9 Then since 0.9 1b. of 20% cream must be added to each 16.3 lbs. of 2.8% milk 120 jjrj~X0.9 = 6.6 lbs. of 20% cream required 16.3 : 120:: 0.9 :X 16.3X=108 X=6.6 lbs. of 20% cream required. 3. How much 20 per cent cream and 3.2 per cent milk will be required for 120 quarts of 3.6 per cent milk? These calculations must always be in pounds and since a quart of milk weighs 2.15 lbs., then 120X2.15=258 pounds of 3.6% milk wanted. Proceeding as before, </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products 20 0.4 3.6 3.2 ' 16^4 16.8 Here must be presented a slight variation from the procedures previously illus - trated, since a definite quantity of the final product is desired. According to previous illustrations when 0.4 lb. of 20% cream and 16.4 lbs. of 3.2% milk are mixed together, 16.8 lbs. of 3.6% milk will be the result. Therefore 258 16.8 X 0.4 = 6.14 lbs. of 20% cream required. 258 jg-g" X 16.4 = 251.86 lbs. of 3.2% milk required or by proportion 16.8:258:: 16.4 :X 16.8X= 4231.2 X = 251.86 lbs. of 3.2% milk required and 16.8 : 258 ::0.4 :X 16.8X= 103.2 X = 6.14 lbs. of 20% cream required. 4. How much skim milk must be added to 400 lbs. of 4.5 per cent milk in order to reduce the fat to 4.0 per cent? This problem may be worked in one of two ways, only one of which makes use of the square. It is assumed that the percentage of fat in the skim milk is so small that it may be considered as 0. With the square 0 _ 0.5 4.0 4.5 4.0 Then 400 100X0.5 = 50 lbs. skim milk to add or by proportion 4.0 : 400:: 0.5 :X 4.0X = 200 X = 50 lbs. skim milk to add. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 . Without the square, 400 lbs. .4.5% milk contains 18.0 lbs. butterfat. Each pound of 4.0% milk contains 0.04 lb. butterfat Then 18 T-j-: =450 lbs. o£ 4.0% milk can be made by adding skim milk • to 400 lbs. 4.5% milk or 50 pounds of skim milk would be needed. 5. How much skim milk and 20 per cent cream are needed to make 210 lbs. o£ 18 per cent cream? This problem may likewise be worked with and without the use of the square. With the square 0 2.0 18 20 1^0 20.0 Thus 2 lbs. of skim milk and 18 lbs. of 20% cream will make 20 lbs of 18% cream. Then 210 "2Q-X 18 = 189 lbs. 20% cream needed and 210 -2q"X2 = 21 lbs. skim milk needed or by proportion 20:210:: 18 :X 20X=3780 X=189 lbs. 20% cream needed, and 20:210::2:X 20X = 420 X = 21 lbs. skim milk needed. Without 'the square, 210 lbs. of 18% cream will require 210X0.18 = 37.8 lbs. butterfat 37.8 lbs. butterfat will be supplied by 37.8 0 -=q-=189 lbs. of 20% cream 189 lbs. 20% cream + 21 lbs. skim milk = 210 lbs. 18% cream. 6. How much skim milk must be removed from 200 lbs. of 3.5 per cent milk to increase the fat to 4.0 per cent? </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products It is understood that only the skim milk will be removed and that the cream pro - duced will be poured back into the original milk. With the square — 0 0.5 4.0 3.5 4.0 For every 4.0 lbs. o£ 3.5% milk 0.5 lb. of skim milk must be removed. 200 —^ — = 50X0.5 = 25 lbs. of skim milk to be removed. or by proportion 4.0 : 200:: 0.5 :X 4.0X=100 X = 25 lbs. of skim milk to be removed. Widiout the square — 200 lbs. 3.5% milk contains 200 X. 035 = 7.0 lbs. butterfat. Each pound of 4.0% milk will require 0.04 lb. butterfat or there is sufficient butterfat to produce — — =175 lbs. of 4.0% milk. Since there are 200 lbs. of milk, then 25 lbs. of skim milk must be removed. OTHER USEFUL INFORMATION Changing a temperature reading in centigrade to its equivalent in Fahrenheit is illustrated as follows: Since 5 degrees on the centigrade scale is equivalent to 9 decrees on the Fahren - heit scale and 32° F. and 0° C. are equivalent, we may multiply the centigrade read - ing by 9/5 and add 32 if the reading is above 0° C. or deduct 32 if the reading is below 0° C. 60° C. = what temperature on the Fahrenheit scale? 60X9/5=108 108 + 32 = 140° F. Changing a temperature reading in Fahrenheit to its equivalent in centigrade can be illustrated by the following example: 140° F.= what temperature on the centigrade scale? Subtract 32 from the Fahrenheit reading and multiply by 5/9. 140—32 = 108 108X5/9 = 60° C. WEIGHTS AND MEASURES Liquid measures: 1 cubic centimeter (milliliter) is equivalent to approximately 20 drops. 1,000 cubic centimeters = 1 liter =1.056 quarts. 29.57 cubic centimeters = 1 liquid ounce. 473.2 cubic centimeters = 1 liquid pint. Dry measures: 1 gram = 15.432 grains = 0.035274 ounce. 1,000 grams = 2.2046 avoirdupois pounds. 453.6 grams =1 avoirdupois pound. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular. 53 WEIGHT AND SPECIFIC GRAVITY TABLE FOR MILK AND CREAM Specific Weight of Weight of Material gravity * 17.5 cc one gallon at 60° F. in grams in pounds Water . 1.0000 17.500 8.3389 Milk (average 4 per cent fat) 1.0320 18.060 8.6057 Skim milk (average) 1.0360 .18.130 8.6391 Cream: 18 per cent butterfat 1.0152 17.766 8.4656 20 1.0129 17.726 8.4465 22 1.0107 17.687 ...8.4281 24 1.0085 17.649 8.4097 26 1.0062 17.608 8.3906 28 .1.0040 17.570 8.3722 30 1.0017. 17.530 83531 32 0.9995 17.491 8.3347 34. . . : 0.9973 17.453 8.3164 36 ,0.9952 17.416 8.2989 38 '.0.9930 17.377 8.2805 40 0.9908 17.339 8.2622 42. 0.9886 17.300 8.2438 44 .0.9864 17.262 8.2255 46 0.9843 .17.225 8.2080 48 0.9821 17.187 8.1896 50 0.9801 17.152 8.1729 Butterfat 0.9300 16.275 7.7552 ' ' ■ ■ ' ' ; .'"■'■■ '••'■ ;. . ■■'.'. ■ ■ ■ ; 1 ;..-.■ ;.;■.'■ •' '■■■;• .',/.. I ■ ' ■ ■ ■ ' ■'.''■'! 1 According to Hunzikcr, "The Butter Industry," First Edition. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Methods of Analyzing Dairy Products DISTRIBUTION OF CONSTITUENTS OF MILK* ' Olcin 33.95 • - Palmitin .40.51 • Glyceridcs of .. insoluble I a in Stearin 2.95 &gt; (. volatile f "1 acids J Milk fats- Myristin 10 -« ' sssrv.*-* 2 - 57 -J 0.004" to | &gt; ?n°T" But &gt; rin 6 - 23 'l in diam. , . . Glyccndes -v Caproin 2.32 » | of soluble | f volatile f 0.30 Caprylin 0.53 * acidi J ■&gt; Caprinin 0.34 * J f Cascin 2-«O , % ' Total ... (Nitrogen ] }■ solid. Albumin 0.60 containing 12.35 snbstanccs) Globulin, trace \ J- 3.25 -\ Solution and Fibrin, trace colloidal suspension J Lecithin 0.05 Milk sugar 4.50 citrie « id • 0.20 .Solid, not Milk J 8*65 scrum Potassium oxide .175 *\ ' ' Sodium oxide .070 Calcium oxide .140 . „ Ash 0.70 Magnesium oxide 017 solution and Iron oxide 001 colloidal suspension Sulphur trioxide .027 Phosphorus pentoxidc .170 Chlorine .1qq Wat " ! .aa ■ Total 100.00 = Percent o^^llr' " T " hni "' °' °^ P^"'" </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station Circular 53 FEDERAL AND STATE STANDARDS FOR MILK, CREAM, BUTTER, AND ICE CREAM 1 .. Milk Li ht PUin Fruit and sutc j cream, Butter. ice nut ice Fat S. N. F. fat * at cream, cream, !_ fat fat P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.a. P.ct. Alabama 3.25 8.5 18 80" 10 8 Arizona 3.25 8.5 18 80 10 8 Arkansas ... . . g g CaWo™' 1 3.3 k.5 20 80 10 8 Colorado 3.0 .. 16 80 10 10 Connecticut 3.25 8.5 16 80 ' 8 6 Delaware 3.25 8.5 18 .. 12 10 "° nd ? 3.25 8.5 18 80 10 8 °f o /8'» 3.25 8.5 18 82.5',' 10 8 Jd"&gt;&gt;o 3.2 8.0 18 80 "'V? 0 ' 1 3.0 8.5 18 80 8 8 Indiana 3.25 8.5 18 80 8 8 Iowa 3.0 8.5 16 .80 12 10 K&gt;n«* 3.25 18 80 0 0 K'nmcky 3.25 8.5 18 80' 10 10 (mix&gt; Louisiana 3.25 &lt;J.5 18 80 10 8 Ma"&gt;e 3.25 8.5 18 . M i? Ma^nd 3.5 .. 18 80 10 8 Massachusetts 3.35 .. 16 80 in 8 Michigan 3.0 8.5 18 80 2 10 Minnesota 3.25 . 20 80 • 12 n Mississippi 3.0 8.5 18 80 5 8 Missouri •. 3.25 8.5 18 82.5 ' 8 8 Mo,?"" ■ 3.25 8.5 20 80 10 9 Nebraska 3.0 , .. 18 80 14 12 N =vada 3.25 8.5 22 80 4 2 New Hampshire 3.35 .. 18 80» 4 2 New Jersey 3.0 . 16 80 » g I New Mexico .. §, » « New York 3.0 18 80 10 « North Carolina 3.25 8.5 18 80 » in » North Dakota 3.0 .. ' 80' 2 10 Ohio 3.0 18 80 i 2 Oklahoma- 3.5 8.5 18 80" 10 8 Oregon 3.2 8.5 18 80 12 10 Pennsylvania 3.25 . .. 18 80' in i Rhode Island 3.25 .. 8 gO g 5 South Carolina 3.0 8 5 8 South Dakota 3.25 8.'5 is 80 i2 10 Tennessee 3.5 8.5 » 'S Texas 18 " at U'ah •• 3.2 8.8 80 14 ,| V«™ont 3J5 8.5 18 80' H 2 Vj'fJinia 3.25 8.5 18 80 0 I Washmgton 3.25 8.5 18 80 10 10 0 "::::::::::: If K »■ -;. S'.:z:;:::: 3 " " j; j g ji 1 From "Legal Standards for Dairy Products," 1932 ~~ * Sixteen per cent overrun. 'Allowable tolerance of 2.5 per cent. t6M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>