<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1909 AND 1910.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EIGHTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Nebraska Institute for the Blind TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE YEARS 1909 AND 1910. The CUflin Printiaf Co. &lt;^^ggp*» U«i«r»ity PUc«. Nlkmkl 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">:1 Nebraska Institute for the Blind. Nebraska City, Xebr., Dec. 12. 191 Hon. Ashton C. Shallenberger. Governor: tSir: — In compliance with Section 12. Chapter 26, of ion laws of 1896. the Board of Trustee* of the Nebt itute for the Blind have the honor to transmit herewitl teenth biennial report for that institution upon the ' mplished during the period ending November 30, 1!W&gt;. k Respectfully CHAS. R. SHERMAN H. H. HANKS. D. W. DWYER </seg>
            <seg id="p003">TABLE SHOWING SALARIES AND WAGES OF OFFICERS. TEACHERS AND EMPLOYES. Administrative Department. Literary Department. E. C. Cook, Historv and Mathemati Mary Morton, Literature and Geography Music Department. Kioeb, Orchestra and Violin d« Wolfe, Pianoforte and 1 ie Dea Emerick. Void 'r»an Pianoforte tc I Scie nc e Health Department. KS. Marnell, Physician Jennie Erb, None, girls ude Shuster, Nurse, boy* ■ I 65 ihi 45 00 30 00 K. Abbott, Superintendent in Abbott. Matroi ard R. Walther, Clerk lie E. Johnson. Primary ard R. W*lther, Typewritin 1 Industrial Department. k Bruce, Piano Tuning, Broom Making, e Campbell, Sewinir. Beadwork, Domestic K Employes. e ( laraody, Engineer . Yowell. Teamster, etc James Shuster, Night-watch nt Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p004">204 Mrs. J. H. Sneed, Assistant Laundress 15 00 Cynthia Pugh, Cook 30 00 EToliver, Assistant Cook 1 Conkling. Head Domestic ny Rader, Domestic 20 00 18 00 15 00 15 00 Vida Parriott, Domestic Edith Burrows, Domestic. Hedvig Peterson, Domestic Olea Lindahl, Dome* 15 00 15 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">REPORT OF TRUSTEES Nebraska Institute for the Blind Nebraska City. Nebr., Dec. 12, 1910 To tho Governo The Board of Trustees of the Nebraska Institute for the Biind have the honor to submit the following report: IOn February 1, 1909. N. C. Abbott appeared before the d with credentials from yourself as superintendent and ediately assumed the duties of the office. He annoui teachers and employes that all would be retained so long if work was well done. No doubt this broad policy of retaining trained assistants accounts in large part for the success of the school during the past two years. tThc personnel of the board has changed entirely since the rt of two years ago. Mr. John O. Detweiler and Mr. R. B. dliam retired at the conclusion of their respective terms. ]\lr. John \V. Steinhart resigned. Mr. Wm. R. Patrick, after inj? a few months, also resigned. I At the time when the report was sent to your office two rs ago an epidemic of scarlet fever was breaking out. Twelve the pupils were isolated in the hospital and the epidemic i not stamped out till near the close of January, 1909. The ool was fortunate to suffer no deaths. Aside from this iemic and the serious illness of Lloyd Holton from heart ;ase and Dorothy Alexander from pneumonia, the school had only the minor ailments common to children. IThe report of the superintendent, giving in detail the affairs statistics of the school, is raade a part of this report. CHAS. R. SHERMAN. H. H. HANKS, D. W. DWYER. Respectfully, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">SUPERINTENDENT'S REPORT the Board of Trustees. Nebraska Institute for the Blind: Gentlemen: — I herewith present the eighteenth biennial re- port of the affairs of this institution. Graduates t June there was graduated from the Mhool a elai iovs. Lewis Basil Lodwiek and John Henry Behneider, both of MeCook, Nebr. ICr. Lodwiek completed the work in toning only and has returned for the literary studies and is e\|» to graduate from them this next June. Mr. Schneider grad in both tuning and the other industrial studies and writes me that lie is succeeding in building op ■ &lt;:&gt;&gt;.»! bnaineai in toning "ii the Pacific slope. Improvements ■ In the two years of my incumbency a number of impro ta have been made, boom of which I enumerate below: tl A sixteen-foot addition on the west to the cow barn been erected. This allows the state to store enough hay ng the summer, when hay is cheap, to last all winter. During waaffW I filled this barn at five dollars and seventy-five 75 per ton. and the state could more than double its ey at the present time. ■ A new team has been provided. The old team of grays served the state for fifteen years. A coal house has been built at the north of the engine rooat. Previously eoal had been piled on the ground near the laundry, and besides deteriorating rapidly in the open, it had soiled with its dust the clothing in the laundry. We can now easily store one hundred twenty tons of coal — enough to run the institution in ordinary winter weather fifty da,\ The wagonette and surrey have been thoroughly hauled and repainted. Nebraska City, Xebr.. Dec. 5, 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">207 I f (5) The laundry has been repainted, the equipment re - jaired and made up-to-date. If 6) The trees on the estate have been trimmed up generally twelve have been cut down. From the limbs we have stored y enough fire wood to last the domestic science department many years to come. t" The old ice-house (now unused for 3 &gt;een erted into a fuel house. One corner is the kitchen coalbin, in it enough coal may be stored in the fall to last the [itches all winter. In doing this we have eliminated the coal n the main building and have been able to wall up the old open- in&lt;_'. doing awav with a great deal of cold. las been made rain-proof. Musical equipment has been greatly strengthened. rhi&gt; includes the moving and repairing of the pipe organ, the purchase of a concert grand piano and a number of band in- trumen Wherever plastering has fallen, it ! with Bteel-eeiling. This is done at considerable cost but pays in the long run as it is a permanent repair. \'2 The dining room has been steel-ceiled and thoroughly repainted. In addition a new sanitary sink and prism-lights have been installed. This now is one of the most pleasant rooms in the buildin L3 Rubber strips have been laid in the main halls on first and second floors. 14 j The fire-protection has been added to 15; A larger and more convenient room has been equipped ■ the kitchen of the domestic science department. (16) The placing of a machine for the peeling of potatoes in the kitchen has made a saving of about twenty per cent in that chief item of food Three Schools. I The three schools — literary, musical and industrial — have maintained as formerly and the results in each have been ;ly gratifying. Mrs. Annie Vio Gates, in an article appearing in the •hapel h:&lt; and rteel-ceiled and new .■ been added. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">208 I aha Bee, in the Sunday issue dated June 12, 1910, has de - bed the work of this school in a way which can not be im - ved upon. I quote in part: t"The work done at this institution is equivalent to four ■s in the modern high schools, or equivalent to the first twelve '8 of a child's school life, and prepares the pupil to enter state university, which many have done. Reading is learned l letters raised up on the surface of the paper, and the i and girls learn to read very readily with their finger tips. Industrial Department I" The industrial department is under the management of k Bruce and Effie B. Campbell. Professor Bruce having connected with the institution for twenty-two years - Campbell for twenty years 'The Nebraska School for the Blind affords an iiulu i of great value to them. education to its pupils which i fits them for places of usefulne is commenced in the priman through the entire course. Very without having been taught to s the work with 1 M in the world. This training les and continued systematically often a blind child enters school his hands at all. In such of great value, as it at once awakens his interest. He is pleased to know that he is making some article which hi- can sent home to his friends. He is en - couraged to try to use his fingers and he learns to count the various groups of beads and learns the shape of the various objects made. The work with raffia is the next step in his progress, as it presents other difficulties to be mastered. Then the boys are ready for the work in netting. With this tiny make hammocks and nets for horses and for these they find ready sale. As the boys grow larger and stronger broom making and weaving of rags into carpets and rugs is taken up. Piano Tuning. "But by far the most lucrative trade which the boys and young men learn is piano tuning. A young man with an ear adapted for this work and possessing some mechanical ability finds himself less handicapped on account of his lack of sight in this line of work than in any other. Here he can compete more successfully than elsewhere with his brothers who possess </seg>
            <seg id="p009">INSTITUTE FOR THK BLIND 209 P&gt; of the gradual' a comfortable living d them. Thi them by proving to best in their line. &gt;m the tuning department are for themselves and those de - adually overcoming the preju - the public that their work is Domestic Science »'The girls are taught plain sowing, mending and darning. s of the girls become expert in the use of the sewing machine they make many articles used in the house, such as sheets, pillowslips, table linen and towels, besides quilts and comforts. Thf knitting of shawls and many other beautiful and u - articles is an important part of the training. The cooking class affords an opportunity for many practical I lon&gt;f the line of housekeeping, as the trirls are provided with a kitchen and are expected to do all the work necessary to keep it in perfect order. Here they learn to prepare various articl- and sonic of the jrirls become excellent breadmakers, and when they return to their homes tiny are able to take entire charge of the family baking. In a few cases they are earning a living by baking for other families, as well as at home, ai are rendering valuable service in that much-needed sphere, the Literary Department ''The advanced literary department is under supervision of Prof. E. C. Cook and MJm Mary French Morton and the grammar grade is in charge of Miss Jennie E. .Johnson. Professor &lt; has taught in this institut. nsecutively for twenty-three years, having been a student here thirty-four igo. While the management changes with political administrations the teaching faculty remains practically the same. School of Music t"The courses prescribed in the various sections of the music irtment are identical with those of our best schools of music no pupil is advanced until he or she has creditably passed previous course. The work done by advanced pupils is of highest character and will favorably compare with the work eeing pupils of the same grade. The proof of this statement </seg>
            <seg id="p010">210 LAND COMMISSIONERS REPORT can be had by examining the various programs given by the music department of the school for the blind. I "It is a mistaken idea that all blind are musical, as they not. The percentage of talented musical boys and girls ng the blind, is no greater than the percentage among the lg and the work required to succeed is harder. The average ndant of a 'musicale' at the school for the blind listens t admiration and wonder at all well finished vocal or in - mental solos, but has not the slightest idea of the immense r connected therewith on the part of both the teacher and pupil. There are in this state a number of successful music hers and performers who graduated from this school, and e who have not entered the profession have acquired ac - plishments which mean everlasting joy to themselves and r friends. "In addition to instrumental or vocal instruction the ad - vanced pupils study, theory, harmony and history of music." Heating Plant. I The heating plant needs imperatively a complete overhaul- This matter was spoken of in the report of my predecessor years ago. Unless new boilers are installed, new pipes and iators put in and the old hauled out, I fear that the school need to be closed within a few years on account of the apse of the heating plant. Old boilers put in twenty years to heat one-half the present space are naturally not adequate our present needs. Other Repairs. II suggest that during the coming biennium a new floor be on the dining-room and that as fast as the plastering falls ceilings be put in throughout the building. Acknowledgement . I In conclusion sincere thanks are due to the Governor kind support, to teachers and employes for their generous sympathetic co-operation. Particularly to my wife, who. natron, has been my chief adviser, and to you members of board of trustees, am I indebted for a large share of the ess that has attended my administration. Very respectfully, H. C. ABBOTT, Superintendent. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND 211 PHYSICIAN'S REPORT ■ the Superintendent of the Nebraska School for Blind : Sir: — Since my appointment. September, 1910, as physician to the school, the only sickness has been of a minor nature. The building is in excellent sanitary condition, the best that tan be maintained considering the antiquity of part of the plumbing. The building is kept exceptionally clean, the kitchen especially worthy of commendation. Respectfully submitted, Nebraska City, Nebr., Dec. 12, 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">OFFICERS AND TEACHERS, NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR BLIND. Hon Ashton C. Shallenberger Governor Board of Trustees ■is. R. Sherman H. Hanks President Secretary D. W. Dwyer Officers N. C. Abbott, A. B., LL. B. (University of Nebr.), Superintendent Lillian Abbott, A. B., P. B. K. (University of Nebr.) , Matron LITERARY DEPARTMENT. ECook (Nebr. Institute for Blind i. History and Matheni, ie Johnson (Nebr. Institute for Blind). Primary ' Morton (Monroe Collegiate Seminary) Literature and Geography Edward R. Walther (Grand Island Business College Typewriting MUSIC DEPARTMENT A. Loeb (Heidelberg, Germany) Violin, Orchestra and Band Maude Wolfe (University Conservatory of Music) Piano and Organ Jessie Dea Emerick (University Conservatory of Music Piano and Voice INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT. Clark Bruce (Ohio Institute for Blind Piano Tuning, Carpet Weaving, Etc. Effie Campbell (Illinois Institute for Blind Sewing, Beadwork, Domestic Science. Bte. M. Jennie Erb Nurse, Girls Maude Shuster Nurse, Boys t. Marnell, M. D. (Washington University) Physician Teachers. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">j'5 oo in n h ia t)i n oo h w fc K - &lt;B «s bL Sh *ll I iii ill 2S &lt; Sh «-§-? s Sal 55 § |!| * * I a I a a- £ a i i- — i — n K U X X 00 X m * ■ri •ri SB ■ O CC -v - - 71 — w ss q« lOt-rtHNriiritDaiHOj S5O ceaoaocoaoaoaoaoaoaiC5 M , I— II— ll— I 1— li— li— li— |i— 'i— II— 11— ( d . . . . ' U H N H Ifl « o a * — SI ■ a w i 5 ! g ■1 § J5J|J i s H « S S 8 I S-&amp;-S .I-S »l! EQ M -^ w pq 3 S a? Q m O ■V* __ -V^ H oB x. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">TEACHERS L — Denotes teachers in Literary Industrial. T— In Typewriting. Department. KE. Bishop ) Niermeyer ... ?tia Hotchkiss ha Laagford McGinnis L 1875 -1877 M 1875 1 880 M 1877 1887 M 1877 !*7s M b»n i-^t; Kie Chadsev G. Parmelee A. Scott M 1884 M 1884 1892 I 1884 M 1886 L 1887 I 1887 1886 Blanche Bedell M. L. Nichol Clark Bruce. 1889 1891 1891 1893 Ei Delong e Sinclair . Collins M 1887 L 1889 L 1889 L 1891 L 1891 1891 1891 1891 Kter Alexander y F. Morton.. 1893 1893 1908 Cara M. Noble L 1891 L 1891 L 1891 M 1891 I 1903 M 1891 M 1891 Mr-. H. Brinkmeyer. W. W. Campbell 1893 1893 Eflfie Campbell 1893 Julia Noble 1893 1893 .1. M. ( '. Mariager_.. E. Taylor Grant . ie Trask 1 1891 1893 L 1893-1895 L 1893 1895 Carrie McClurken _.. M 1893-1895 Blanch Smith .. _ M 1893-1895 Ivy Hoffhine L 1893-1895 II N Blake L 1894-1896 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">KD. Beghtol . Cook L L 1894-1896 1894-1898 IE. Dawey E. Dawt lie Sidwell H. Wright trude Souslcy L. S. Connor leda Adams C. Abbott M M L L If M M I, tj. Mansfield B. Woods. . W. B. Woods aces Tibbets lie Holland L L L If M E Baker ... . Yolk cTaggart May 1898-1899 -1899 1899-1900 L L &lt; !. McTaggart Allie Truesdale . M K. A. Lyman I. L .Mrs. K. A. Lyman A. Loeb M Flora Bullock L I. II. Marnell Jenuie E. Johnson liurruss I L M ■ W. Newton A. Dull I T T T T T VV. High D. Clarv Kmerick M M L T M 1 wlill 1 (ll I 1 ■ab Voegeli L. B. Efred Bortis . L. Drake., beth Hemler </seg>
            <seg id="p016">216 IF. Hunter le Wolfe e Miller .... Hanner. Towner .... Otis F. Hunter Maude Wolfe T 1907-1908 M 1907-1908 T 1907-1908 M 1907-1908 1909- T 1908-1908 T 1908-1909 1909 Ee Miller Hanner. Towner T 1908-1908 T 1908-1909 M 1908-1908 M 1908-1908 Edith C. Chandler. _._ _. M 1908-1909 Waldemar Vietmeier _ T 1909-1909 Edward R. Walther T 1909- Chas. Zadina _ M 1909-1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">ENROLLMENT FOR THE BIENNIUM DECEMBER 1, 1908, TO NOVEMBER 30 1910. Age. Pupil. P. 0. Address. 14 Adams. Maurice, Norfolk Nativity. Dat&lt; of Ad'm Sept. Sept. Oct. wa Nebraska Nebraska I lie liana Nebraska Nebraska Nebraska Illinois Irinson, Nellie, Dunbar ave, Herbert, Blair., ozad, Albert, Lincoln ozad, George, Lincoln— avis, Grace, Franklin edaler, Frank. Havelock— ienke, Ludwig, Omaha inney, Fern, Pawnee City— leming, Kenneth, Kearney, lood, Axel, Pender Jan. Oct. 1907 2, 1899 Sept. Sept. Sept. Sept. Sept. Nov. Sept. Sept. Oct. 10, 1902 10, 1902 17. 1907 .Nebraska . Nebraska .. Nebraska ..Nebraska ..Sweden . Nebraska ..Nebraska .. Nebraska .. Wyoming Nebraska _ Nebraska Nebraska ..Illinois 9, 19, 1906 R ravel, Chas. AVm., South Omaha, earhart, Bruce, Omaha 17. 1909 Sept. Sept. Feb. Sept. Sept. Jan. Sept. Sept. Oct. 16, 1903 IGierau, Henry, Wewela, S. D Gordon, Bessie, Lawrence. Gregg, Hubert, Lincoln. 19, 1902 14, 1890 14 Griffith, Irene. DuBois 16, 1 IGunn, Carl, Nebraska City- Harris, Frank E.. Omaha Harris, Lyle, Beaver Cii Hawley, Leo, Arcadia 11, 1909 15, 1909 Nebraska Nebraska Nebraska Nebraska Nebraska Nebraska Nebraska Nebraska 19, 1906 10, 1906 IHendricks, Delia, Omaha.. Hill, Ethel, South Omaha Feb. Nov. Nov. Sept. Sept. Sept. Feb. 27, 1908 25, 1906 ■ Hollabaugh, W. E., Nebraska City Holdeman, Clara, Callaway 29, 1898 9, 1902 19 Holton, Lloyd, Albion_.. 15 Huit, Nola, South Omaha. — 17 Hutchison, Eva, North Platte IS Husa Kos&lt;' Omaha 14, 1903 20, 1902 10, 1910 16, 1908 8 Alexander, Dorothy. MilforcL 19 Aubrecht, Elsie, South Omaha 16, 1907 5, 1908 9. 1QO7 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">218 Age. Pupil. P. O. Address. 17 Jennings, Leona, Lincoln 13 Jones. Walter Dale, Ainsworth 14 Jones, Lennie, Lincoln 19 Journey, Wallace,. Arapahoe 19 Kelsey, Don Carlos, Lincoln 15 Kempley, Earl, Grand Island 12 Kerst, Mark A., Wymore 1") Kerst. Marguerite, Wymoi Nativity. Date of Ad'm Nebraska Sept. 10, 1901 Nebraska Sept. 1. 1909 Sept. 16, 1908 Iowa Jan. 1. 1901 Nebraska Nov. 1. 1909 Iowa Oct. 12, 1908 Nebraska Sept. 2. 1909 Nebraska Nov. 27. 1909 20 Koch, William, Sutton Nebraska Sept. 23. 1906 Nebraska Jan. 4. 1897 Eoontz, Edna, College View uster, Elizabeth, Omaha aird, Clyde, Rain Nebraska Apr. . 1907 Nebraska Sept. 6, 1899 Eeake, Tommy, Elm Creek eonard, Elizabeth, Plattsmouth illie, Rena, Reynolds Nebraska Sept. 16, 1907 Missouri March 3, 1902 Sept. 16, 1907 Iinstrom, Anna, Hershey udwick, Lewis, McCook cClure, Ida M., Kearney cCune, Walter, Omaha VMains, Bessie P., Verdon — eisner, Harlie D., Aurora ever. John, Nebraska City iinnig, Beulah, Julian — !ogis. Robert A., Nebraska City onford, Henry, Ashland ielsen, Einar G., Hastings Nebraska Nov. 10. 1897 Nebraska Feb. 27. \w\ Nebraska Dec. 17, 1909 Iowa Sept. 18, 1904 Kansas Oct. 1, L909 Nebraska Dec. 31. 1909 Germany Aug. 3. 1909 Nebraska Oct. 31, 1908 Nebraska Oct. 11. 1910 Nebraska Sept. 10, 1901 Texas Sept. 16, 1910 ]ti Phillips, Cecile, Kenesaw 21 Phillips. Lela, Kenesaw Nebraska Jan. 26. 1909 Nebraska Nov. 10. 1908 A&gt; Preston, Geo. Wm., Springfield H Pritehard, Maud, Sutton Nebraska Apr. 1. 1910 England Dec. 2ti. 1909 .Missouri Sept. 10, 1902 2&lt;i Heed. Minnie. Wymore 1") Kobinson. Gail, Omaha 1- Koeinieli. Matilda, Sutton Jn Hothery, George, Omaha 18 Kupencamp, Nina, Omaha 14 Russel, Laura, Verdon Nebraska Nov. 10. 1908 Nebraska Sept. 18. 1908 Nebraska Sept. 16, 1905 Nebraska Sept. 23. 1!K&gt;H Nebraska Sept. 15, 1910 Nebraska Nebraska Russia 1910 -arratt, Lawrence, Nebraska City 15 Sawyer. Bessie. Fairbury March 6 Sept. 13 Nov. in </seg>
            <seg id="p019">219 A K. 1 2 24 14 »l » II -'4 •1 17 1 i &gt; Pupil. P. 0. Address. Searles, Mildred, Omaha Sheekler, Harry, Nebraska City Nativity. Town Date of Ad'm Sept 19 1905 Nebraska Oct. 24 L9O4 Smith. Harry, Omaha Smith, James, Crai^ Smith. Lena. Craij.' Smith. Walter, Craig Snow, Zeiio. Auburn.. Sn v&lt;ler. Mary, Dodge Nebraska Oct. Nebraska Sept. 13 Nebraska Sept. 13 Nebraska Sept 21 1908 Missouri Nov. 1 1910 Nebraska 28 Sept Stuart, Mona, Omah;i Tappe, Wm. II.. Omaha Tatum. Ralph. liloomfield Tigard, Bessie May. Roco Nebraska Sept New York May 1 Nebraska Jan. 4. Nebraska Feb. 1. 1910 Fell 1 Vak. Joseph, Florence Nebraska Feb. 6 Van Seoik. Muriel, Hoskins Nebraska So. Dak. Iowa Dec. Sept Nov. Jan. Sept Sept 12 IWaddell. May, South Omaha- WakUm, Charlotte, CarrolL _ Walter, Thomas R., Omaha Wood, Walter, Omaha__ 20 a 3 Nebraska ..Nebraska ..Nebraska 17 7 Wittulski, Fred, Beatrice -4 Zadina, Charles, Omaha. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">GRADUATES OF THE NEBRASKA INSTITUTE FOR THE BLIND. ■L — Literary Department. B— Broom-making. V — Violin. P — Piano J iano Tuning. C — Clarinet. I — Industrial Department. Name. Graduated In. Year. P. &lt; ). Address. Sustaining. Aaberg, Albert Bazile, Neb Dec'd Adams, Nellie 1890 Nebraska City, Neb Yea Bail, James.... B. C Baker,. Alice V. P. T Bebout, Isabella Bell, Bertram Beuter, Harry l'&gt; ford, Anna I. Bruce, Clark Tecumseh, Neb...... Battle Creek, Mich Yea 1894 Nebraska City, Neb Yea L897 Jacksonville. 11! Yen L897 Omaha. Xel Lawrence, Kan Yea 1886 Nebraska City, Neb_ Yea Brown, Gertrude L 1890 Madrid, Neb Burns, James T Bush, S. •! T, B Campbell, Lucy L Clark, Roy L, 1' 1896 Kenesaw, Neb Dec'd 1900 Marquette, Xeb Yea 1886 Graf, Neb- _ Yea 1899 Lincoln, Neb Yea «1, Harry _ L, T 1894 Nebraska City, Neb Yes ■&gt; Cozad, Sara L 1894 Long Island, Kan _Yes Coryell, Levi _L 1888 Brock, Neb Yea Crim Emma L 1886 Nemaha, Neb- Yea Crowder, William B 1898 Lincoln, Neb Yea Curtis, Frederick L 1894 Lincoln, Neb Yea Delong, Clara L 1886 Alexandria, Neb Yea Deranleau, Remi..._ _P, T 1899 Rapid City, S. D Yes Duncan, Sylvia L 1899 Stella, Neb_ Dueholm, Christian.. L 1888 Louisville, Neb Yea Gillette, L. B.._ _T 1907 Blair, Neb Yes Gish, Clarence— _ L, I 1907 Nelson, Neb_ Yea Gregg, William 1886 Lincoln, Neb _Yes Harmon, Mary 1886 Buffalo Gap, S. D Yes </seg>
            <seg id="p021">TUTE FOR THE BLIND 221 Name. Graduated In."Y P. 0. Address. Sustaining ir Ilaynes, Frank P 1903 Omaha, Neb Yes Hegel. Paul T 1899 Bexthousen.Hans, L,T,P,B 19&lt;H Omaha, Neb II. .1.1. man. Clara L, I Callaway. Neb Yes Hollabaugh. Wm T, B I Nebraska City. Neb Holliii'Tsworth, Fred...L, B North Platte. Neb Yes Hollingsworth, Nora L Diller. Neb Yes L, I 1908 Omaha, Neb Johnson, Ingwald B Genoa. Neb Johnson. Jennie L, P Fremont. Neb Yes Nebraska &lt; Sty, Neb Jones, Clarence T, L 1898 Frances L 189C Nebraska City, Neb nhine L Nebraska City, Neb Yes Knapp. Anna L, P 1901 Wilber, College View ,tz. Edna L, I, P Lanham, Alma L 1896 Cozad, Neb is, Clarence __ B 1897 Red Cloud, Neb Yes L-wis. Glen L, I, T 1908 Beatrice, Ne: Ilershey. Neb •rom. Anna Xi, I 1908 Hershey, Neb Yes I.instrom. Christiana L. I 1906 Long, Delia I- I 1904 Burr, Neb. Yes Ludwick, Lewis B _T 1910 McCook, Neb Mathews, Golda L 1896 South Omaha, Neb Yea Nebraska City, Neb MeAnley, Mary L. P 1898 Miller, E. J L 1894 Madison, Neb Miller, Stelhi L 1896 Nebraska City, Neb d Martin, Nora L, P, V 1901 Rogers, Neb Guide Rock, Neb... Moore, E. C L, P 1899 Mullins, Julia L 1886 Salem, Neb Noble BelL L 1894 Grant, Neb.. Oleson, Ida L 1901 Stromaburg, Neb Yes Owens, Claire -..._L, P 1898 Burress, Neb _. Page, Adelbert _L, T, B 1899 Omaha, Neb Parrish, Mer L, T 1896 Beatrice, Neb Yes Quandt, Gustav L 1886 Grand Island, Neb Dec ■d Regelin, Minnie _L 1896 Los Angeles, Cal </seg>
            <seg id="p022">222 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Name. Graduate i In. Year. P. 0. Address. Sustaining Schneider. Henry T. I 1910 McCook. Neb Yes son. Anna L. T 1906 Wolbach. NVI&gt; Simpson. Arthur B 1900 Peru. Neb Yes Shikp. Ray .L, V, T 1900 Lincoln, Neb Yes Stinger, May L 1*99 Gering, Neb Yes Tarwater, Kay ...L 1894 Nebraska City, Neb Dec'd Warrick, Maud L 1890 .Dec'd West, Nona L, P, I 1906 Omaha, Neb Yes White. Owen L, B 1904 Albion. Neb Yes Wilson. Austin L 1S!I4 Battle Creek, Mich Yes Zadina. Charles L, P, C 1906 Omaha. Neb Yes L — Literary Department; B — Broom-making; \ Violin; P — Piano ; T — Piano Tuning ; C — Clarinet ; I — Industrial De- partment. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">x cc cc ,- ti ~~ nr- «^ --. - r x m r X t- Tf *r - Q.-S : l~ -t J f - - as •£ -i-:- -^ -i x r- M - = - H 3 S -*■ ■Vr fcij ! 5 2S £ s *~ t* © sr «s ~ --T !M (M O «T O M » 5 c '-c w w c c S - 5 " — — '-" &lt;3C IM -M — /■ CM ?1 O!C(»&lt;eKK I - -i W Q «5 ti ■M — -t - * go 5" _,s^ m c c. c: c c c ooX o h §a £ c t- = i- - o; c~ c i~ — r -r •; t - 5: C »- o: i - c: cr. c (M_ cc OC' t--' 05 OC t- 2 "S c C-. -r -^ 1- — k "^ OQ S C C". C: C". l- £ S * m » «o t- « « X Sgo W «. « -^ 1-1 Z£ CC C^ &gt;— C CJ (CKNNN CC CC t~ O". i— tJ- W&lt;J»-I C tT K N N N Cf 5 &lt;£ O W A4OQ5 S O"^ 3 CCCt^a.i-'* r« — § » m £ w . *5 "* c C cc u- Lt" tr- CC C] i— N ■* -*f C ■M s^s " s • a "• &lt;— C-l C. -t T •M -¥r OS'-'W £«Q .5= c = 5:cc 5 w S £ o © c c 25 »5 « r *« w 5 g* b » *- c I-' t-' ec C I-N- -*- o « Sh — tt ! — AH &lt; 3« 5§ -■-•=?. issotfeg «5| == IziQ &gt; £ = S5Q O * 5C s « - S £ 3 bi x y: ■ r. % n </seg>
            <seg id="p024">TABLE SHOWING CLASSIFICATION OF ALL EXPENDITURES. 1st Year. $ 9,651 88 2nd Year. $10,868 90 Salaries and wage* Apples 49 50 75 30 liuttcr 609 60 491 52 Bread and breadstuff* 278 56 Bran, screenings, etc 174 78 76 33 Band instruments 319 95 Beads and wire 31 76 3 76 Expenses of members of Board Broom corn and other material 14 14 4 29 60 92 95 03 52 61 Books and magazines.. 88 96 Bks for foundation of addition barn 34 00 Bakeoven and fittings 50 00 1,683 1.714 12.") 216 00 Chapel seats 75 00 650 00 kering Grand Piano Corn, ear and shell 19 60 64 09 114 56 C.-irpots centering 75 20 58 21 Dishes Drugs and prescriptions 107 08 83 B5 Dry goods, bedding ,ete 243 03 212 97 Disinfectants ... 28 00 Drayage 6 00 Gasoline engine supplies 105 82 Engineer's supplies and engine re- 113 17 38 65 40 07 pairs 38 97 Elecrical supplies . 32 73 Canned fruits f)AO I?O </seg>
            <seg id="p025">INSTITUTE FOR THE BUND 225 1st Year. Floor polish and oil Replacing flag-pole 50 00 18 50 K extinguishers and fixtures iture, mattresses, etc ral repairs in engine-room 219 30 ;in&lt;l laundry 105 no Groceries 1.9titi 27 Garden seeds i; 4d 218 tin Harness repairs, blankets, nets. tc. 19 75 t Ke-ahoeing and blacksmithin^ [ware, cooking utensils, &gt; -s4 :.:, 115 75 Hose for fire protection Putting in new i Linuleum Landscape plat 25 00 Laundry starch 7 90 Laundry supplies 18 00 Library bureau cabinet and eardt 17 00 Lumber and building material ;10 90 Meats 1,045 84 1,197 01 Medical attendance . 215 33 Musio and musical merchnndU. 86 25 Mix-cllaneous 384 99 I ceiling 272 50 Extra nursing 120 00 Oats 53 47 Pipe organ, moving, tuning, etc _ 63 50 Painting and paints 64 25 Painting vehicles _ 18 00 Plumbing and plumbers' supplies Painting and paper hanging 153 59 Paper, type and point 12 15 Repairing musical instruments W and putty Etingr programs and newspaper bscriptions _ 99 15 ibing and plumbers' supplies 84 79 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">226 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT 1st Year. Repairing typewriters Repairing lawn mowers Rubber matting for halls Range repairs 27 50 10 15 175 28 6 38 Bt for lots ber belts 9 75 70 00 Stamps and postal supplies 48 23 B) and other cleansing articles, gles and other roofing material ionery 187 20 32 00 30 30 19 07 point 30 00 ■ King wood with circle saw phone rental and tolls ie for nettings V.\ 50 64 25 12 20 f)0 10 24 00 Tuner's supplies 11 80 Typewriter supplies. 5 00 .•■tables, potatoes, tomatoes, etc. .-■table peeler . . 35 !)4 Krinary services and medicine er and light 16 00 628 77 15 00 4117 M Water cooler Burning trees et pa; </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DITURE OF GASH. Receipts. Balance on hand December 1, 1908 Kt&gt; Carmody (old iron, scales and cinders 1 irs caned "_' "_'•"&gt; Brooms and corn sold ,-h.ing Beads, beadwork and other work sold &lt; hi'-kens sold Hammocks and cord b and calves sold Hogs sold Carpet weaving r rental s of old musical instruments Total Expended. Butter Beads and wire Broom material One buggy One Holstein cow Drugs and prescriptions Dinner dishes Eiiture and repairs cles of harne&gt; team of horses Kard R. Walther (brooms, hammocks, etc.. M 1151 72 Effie Campbell (beads, beadwork. etc.. sold Tt 29 Misi-ellaiieous </seg>
            <seg id="p028">228 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Miscellaneous 136 32 130 10 Potatoes 13 33 Paper, paint . 6 75 Recovering, painting and repairing wagonette 100 00 Stationery 10 35 Sweeping compound 6 00 Stamps and stamped envelopes, post cards, etc. 28 00 Twine for Industrial department 24 35 Telephone rental and tolls 8 75 Wagon and bob-sled 105 00 Exchange 90 $1,414 27 Balance on December 12 1910 ESTIMATES FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING MARCH 31, 1913 Salaries. For Year. Biennum. $1,800 00 $3,600 00 Superintendent's Matron's 600 00 1.200 00 ."),000 00 10,000 00 4.250 00 8,500 00 Teachers' Employes' wages $11,650 00 $23,300 00 $19,800 00 Maintenance General repairs 3.300 00 $23,100 00 Extraordinary. For installing new boilers, steamfittings, pipes, rad- iators $!UO0 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">rNG THE PAST TWO TEARS PUPILS HAVE BEEN IN STRUCTED IN THE VARIOUS SUBJECTS AND TRADES AS FOLLOWS. Binir. New York point inar. line letters Writing. New York point Typewriting Grammar . Arithmetic I2rraphy :ed States History lish History ient History, ■rican History 10 .) s Biaeval and Modern Hist oric "&gt;rv Phvsi «&lt; American Literature &lt; 8 Physiology 13 Algebra 15 Elocution ... Geometry ... Pianoforte Pipe Organ 6 40 15 Cornet 18 Other band instruments Voice culture 15 trus singing ory Et music o tuning ... m making </seg>
            <seg id="p030">230 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT Hammock netting Cane seating 3 37 11 Bewiag (hand ng (machine Knitting 4 &lt; Crocheting • Bead work Domestic Scienct Articles Made by Pupils During the Biennium. §One hundred and twenty dozen brooms, thirty-five whisk ms, ninety-six yards of carpet and fifty-six hammocks ami . In addition to these, there have been many chairs caned. Domestic Science. t Fifteen sheets, 9 pilow cases, 7 napkins, 18 towels, 31 dish - 19 wash cloths, 3 laundry bags, 1 shoe-bag, 12 aprons, 2 s, 10 mats, 2 shawls, 1 fascinator, 3 pairs of slippers, 3 ies. 1 jacket, 2 hair receivers, 3 bags. Also mending and ing. Nine pieces of raffia work. Three hundred and ninety-two </seg>
            <seg id="p031">k S, n, n,. \ \ 1 C,,, LITTLE FOLKS' PROGRAM. Friday Morning, June 3, L910, 10 O'clock. Welcome, Merry Sprinertiitif funinr &lt; 'I n seven &lt; i iris Ei Mary Snider Happv Farm&lt; zant'tli v Valtfr Mi Uar r*v Lawn Partv : liner Match Third Grail Pinch Busts Albert &lt; Question and A rharlotte W \\ \ Scene in Ljonirfellow 's Honn 'Jail RoL; I);, I Nola Iluit First Grade Alhi-rt ( .1 His ( 'fimriiMisiit Harley Mei Delia Bendr Cecil* Phillips. Mark K E Blue Air AValter Smith r&gt;f Roujk Where The Hll Bells Ring </seg>
            <seg id="p032">232 LAND COMMISSIONER'S REPORT PROGBAM. Friday Evening, June 3, 1910, 8 O'clock. March Grotesque Orchestra Recitation—' ' ' My Philosofy ' Wallace Journey Voice — "Recall Our Love" Lewis Ludwig Recitation— " The Going of the Whil May Waddell Oration — ' ' National Stability ' Piano — "Polacca Brilliant"' Recitation — "The American Girl Oration — ' ' Optimism Lyle Harris Florence Pratt Recitation — "Courting in Kentucky' Clyde Laird Organ — ' ' March Pomposo ' Berridg, By — Rost-s tations — Lena Smith (a) " Under Difficulties " (b) "Little Brown Baby Paul Dunbar Paul Dunhar May Waddell Piano Quartette — "La Dame Blanche" lii.i.-l.lieu Leona Jennings, Rose Husa, Henry Gierau Henry Gierau Leona Jennings </seg>
            <seg id="p033">ANNUAL SERMON Sunday Evening, June 5, 1910, 8 O'clock. AshforH in Voluntary — " Romania" Ijeona Jennings Du.ll.-v I Benediction — Dr. F. M. Sissmi 11 Prayer- Rev. W. W. Barnes 1 1 y inn- — •' ' ( 'oronation. rpture Reading — Dr. F. M. Siaaon hem— "The King of Glory" Choir Knon— Rev. \V. \V. Baino. s — "Fear Not Ye. &lt;&gt; Isra.-l Heiirv Schneider Hymn — "&lt; Ireation </seg>
            <seg id="p034">234 I,A.\I&gt; COMMISSIONER'S HKI'ORT GRADUATING EXERCISES Monday Evening, June 6, 1910, 8 O'clock. Grand March Holla, -n.1. ■'. Orchestra Chopin Poldini \iiic( — Tin- Toreador from Carmen Henry Schneider Scotson ('lark Kelar-Kela Voice— '-O. That We Now Might Wand&lt; W. K. II isla.n r Lewis Ludwiek Henry S •luieidei .Mr. Loeh Mendelssohn tseiitHtioii of Diplomas — President Chi n Henry Schneider — Industry, is Basil Ludwiek — Piano Tuning. t and Peasant Overture R. Sherman ( &gt;rchestra IW (a Prelude Op. 2s. No. 15 I) Miirchi- Mignonne &lt;&gt;p. 1"). So. 2 Li'oiih JenningH &lt; 'nriii't -Sht'plicnl "s Morning Song Lewis Ludwiek &lt;;. Biz.-t ' &gt;i-L r Mii--l &gt; i'nc-rssi(iiiHl March Lewis Lndwick Violin — I)&lt;-r Sohn |)&lt;-r Ilaidc Henry Qierau Trio "Xorma" .Miss Wolfe, Miss ESmerie) Concerto in a. Minor — Presto Henry Gierau, Leona Jenningi </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>