<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A.  THE SEED OF CHEAT, MEADOW FESCUE AND BROME GRASS.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA ruHAi. Experiment Station Agrk NEBR., U. S. A. Pretf^ Bulletin No. -25 ruar OF (HEAT. MEAIMIW FESCUE AND HROME (JKASP IIKALU inner* &lt;&gt;f the state with adulterated alfalfa w vears is alone sufficient to warrant extreme f the seed of our forage crops, but during rant case of seed adulteration and suhstitu V large number of specimens of seed sup er meadow fescue or smooth Itronit- grass have been )ii for examination. A verv considerable miples proved to I*- either cheat or chess alone or lit of cheat seed. The extent to which this tution has Neen practiced calls for a note of bnvc INVOLVED fraud is causing n considerable amount of lo- f our state may be inferred from the following data taken irtment correspondence: en at Kisinir City shipped MMMM pounds of cheat seed tv under the impression that they had raised meadow NTKODUCTION </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 \ fji i'iin*r ill I'rtiruiii^* ihfu^ii * r^ impression that he was buying meadow fescue. A farmer at Nelson lnrnght l,«M pounds of cheat name of English blue grass. Mam I«porti hit on record in which The amour was soiiu-w liat smaller. In sonic for onr valuable Rromus inrrmix T grass swmIs mentioned, the follow,,,- nm, technical **rriptim given i 1. Chess or Cheat. The seed of chess or cheat I Bromma ttcml nnd rounded on the hack with a is a dirty straw color, very thick I&gt;ES&lt;RIPTir*NS Ill order thiit buyers may 1h&gt; ahlf Kroove on tho opposite si^. IF*. 1.1 TKo .-.I rnn ?P s from </seg>
            <seg id="p003">a The £T iftt-n provided with a short awn, kwards. The awn mav !*&gt; entirely broken much enlarged, and natural size. 1 Rromtm neraUau*). t. HunKarian or smooth Meadow fescue or Knglish rnti off. or. in the perfect wed, it mav j'qual the bod.v of the seed in length. ss ma\ also he recognized in the field by the Hiararteristir ap- pi'iirnmi' of rho spikclets. 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p004">rather flattened, aud shows three fairly prominent nerves on tht upper side. The apex sometimes h;is the remains of a very short a but is generally' somewhat fra\ ransii. 2.i The commercial article Keneralh contains a eonsidt of cliaff and empty glumes Meadow Fescue. The seed of meadow fesem cheat seed and smaller, al an awn. (Pig 2.) It is mud aud does not show such prominent incurved edge* ■peciea may Ik- recognized in the ■pikelets. I Fig. spikelets | Fig 1. ( "liess or i lir.it is ;ui annual 1. ( "hess or ch&lt; it is t&lt;&gt; be regarded ;is » weed n to l&gt;e I Some clajniK have Imh»ii made th Some claims have lx&gt;eii made that it prod pasture. Inn in&gt; satisfactory evidf nient. Hacked h\ tliis statement parts of the slate under the natm grass. It may also Im- of ini t&lt;&gt; chess in two of our ueighborinj to chess in two of our ominjr Station the statemen; oniing Station tl en vijrorotis growth and ability to m as a hay prass in some localities, phasi/.ed. as will ;;s the fact that of Iowa. p. 3621 it is classed of Iowa. p. SS2) it is classed a but with ''some redeeming featun but with ''some redeem i spoken of favorably for the South spoken of favorably for the Souther the T'aoific Coast in Orepron and "_'. Hronie L r rass has proved in the I'acific Coast in Oregon and W ■_'. Bronx* mn has proved the &lt;!reat Plains re«rion from Kai tin- &lt;!reat Plains rejrion from Kans; more extensive » ultivation. It is more extensive cultivation for the drier sections of the stat&lt; reliable or ignorant parti* or cheat, on the market under th Some of the failures of brome jrras Meadow fescue, or English blue &lt;rr; than timothy but less so than bronie mass. It h valuable pasture jn-asx. especially in the eastern h but it is not suited to the more arid portions. More eh» been substituted for this valuabi - than for the True bromf jrra ss </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>