<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00031">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Annual Fodder and Silage Crops for Nebraska</title>
               <date value="19xx">[undated]</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Circular 52 Mar. Annual Fodder and Silage Crops for Nebraska W. E. LYNESS AND T. A. KIESSELHACH Department of Agronomy ■* ■' \ r § :, - / Sorgo grown m cultivated rows. Atlas (left) and Kansas Orange (right). THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION | LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Annual Fodder and Silage Crops for Nebraska W. E. LVNESS AND T. A. KIESSELBACH The present shortage m the seed supply of all standard varieties of annual forage crops has created a special demand for information concerning their relative productivity and the"possible use of substitute crops. This circular reports the yields secured from such crops at the Experiment Station, m an effort to help farmers reach a decision as to which crops should be grown this year for roughage, and which ones especially should have their seed supply increased for use m future years. Feed value and pro - duction costs as well as yields should be taken into consideration by the grower. The standard annual fodder crops grown primarily for cured forage m Nebraska consist largely of several varieties of sorgo and millet, and Sudan grass. Although soy beans have not come into extensive use for hay, they command some interest. Oats make good hay but the yield is relatively small. Whereas corn has been the chief silage crop, tests during the last six years indicate that Atlas sorgo should be given preference wherever it will mature sufficiently. CORN AND SORGHUM GROWN FOR FODDER OR SILAGE IN CULTIVATED ROWS Atlas excels. — In a six-year test, 1928-34 (Table 1), Atlas sorgo has proved superior to other varieties of sorghum and to corn when grown m normal cultivated rows. Its yield of cured fodder was 5.54 tons per acre compared with 2.32 tons for corn. The corresponding silage yields calculated on the basis of 75 per cent moisture content were 18.84 tons for Atlas sorgo and 7.89 tons for corn. Atlas surpassed all other crops each year except Kansas Orange cane, which yielded more one year. The average yield of nearly 8 tons of corn silage per acre is about normal for this region. With respect to feeding value, the Animal Husbandry depart- Table 1. — Earliness, height, and yield m tons per acre of cured fodder (15 per cent moisture) and silage (75 per cent moisture) of five varieties of sorghum and corn when grown m cultivated rows 1 during six years, 1928-34. Ovm I Da ": 1 Height I Fodder I ... 2__ | ripe [ (m.) | 1928 | 1929 | 1930 1 1931 | 1932 | 1934 j~Av. I E Black Amber sorgo 9/10 79 1.57 4.63 3.52 4.22 4.10 2.41 3.41 11.59 Kanns Orange sorgo... 9/28 89 3.19 5.85 4.2f, 4.50 5.13 3.47 4.40 14.96 Atlas sorgo 10/3 88 3.40 7.58 6.95 4.57 8.13 2.62 5.54 18.84 Hcgari 9/15 57 1.54 4.08 4.28 3.56= 12.10 » Pink kafir 9/20 72 2.28 4.19 5.27 4.12 5.12 1.57 3.76 12.78 Hoguc corn 9/20 78 1.22 3.35 2.45 3.12 2.27 1.50 2.32 7.89 1 In these tests the sorghum plants were spaced about 2 inches apart ant) the corn 14 indies apart within the row. The avenge planting date was June I. 3 Since Hccari wtl crown only dtirinc 1926-30. its averacc yielt! is calculated relative to that of Orange. Black Amber, and Pink kafir for that period. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Circular 52 ment of this station has fed Atlas sorgo silage to cattle during the last four years with the conclusion that, pound for pound, it is worth 90 per cent as much as corn silage. Other desirable characteristics are superior lodge resistance, leafiness, and value of the seed as a feed and market crop. Atlas sorgo matures in about 130 days after planting, as compared with 120 days for east-central-Ncbraska full-season corn, and is three weeks later than the well-known Black Amber cane. Because of its lateness, it can be depended upon to mature seed only in southeastern Nebraska although in some seasons it may ripen as far west as Custer county. Since it should be harvested for fodder or silage before fully ripe, its produc - tion for forage may extend over a much larger area. The western limit has not been well established. Because of the shortage of Atlas sorgo seed as a result of the 1934 drouth, the seed supply should be greatly increased in 1935. Much of the seed sold in 1934 as Atlas was mislabeled and consisted of Hegari and other grain sorghum varieties. This also holds true for the current year. Unusual care must therefore lie exercised in buying seed if true Atlas is desired. This problem would be simplified by the purchase and produc - tion of certified seed. Atlas sorgo has averaged an annual yield of 42 bushels of seed per acre when grown in cultivated rows during six years at Lincoln. Hegari, a good substitute. — Hegari has yielded four tons more silage and a ton more cured fodder per acre than corn in a three-year test. It produces a good quality of palatable forage and is recommended under present conditions of very limited seed supply of the standard forage sorgo varieties, as a substitute for them. Hegari is grown extensively in the Southern Great Plains as a grain crop and the seed supply is ample and should be relatively low in price. Seed of this crop is being extensively advertised under the name of Early Atlas sorgo. One should not be mis - led by this, as it has no relationship whatever to the true Atlas variety. SORGO, SUDAN GRASS. AND MILLET DRILLED FOR CURED FORAGE Throughout a 14-year period, four varieties of sorgo or cane have been compared for yield of cured forage with Sudan grass and two stand - ard varieties of millet. In this test (Table 2) the three kinds of crop have been sown with a grain drill at the respective rates of 95, 25, and 32 pounds of seed per acre. The Kansas Orange and Honey sorgo, with respective acre yields of 4.8 and 5 tons, averaged about two weeks later ripening than Black Amber which yielded 4.2 tons. Early Sumac sorgo was intermediate in time of [maturity and yielded 4.6 tons per acre. It is apparent that the large, late-ripening varieties yield most in south - eastern Nebraska where the grqwing season is relatively long. Northward and westward within the state the intermediate and early varieties become more dependable. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Annual Fodder and Silage Crops for Nebraska I'k.. I. — I'.l.ick Amber siirjsci (left) and Sudan jjimnn (riv;l)t) planted in 42-inch rows for forage. Sudan grass yielded 3 tons per acre, or only 71 per cent as much as Black Amber sorgo. Its greatest value lies in use as a temporary pasture crop, since it can be pastured by livestock with little danger of prussic acid poisoning. Fie. 2. — HUick Amber si&gt;rjjci (left; and Sudan crass (riyht; &lt;lrillc&lt;l tor forage. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Circular 52 Table 2. — Yields in tons per acre (15 per cent moisture) of cured forage from several varieties of sorgo, Sudan grass, and millet when sown with a grain drill at the respective rates of 95, 25, and 32 pounds of seed per acre— 1921-34. _ Year f!2! Sudan Mi " ct Black Amber | Early Sumac | Kansas Orange [ Huncy Common | German 1921 4.05 5.94 5.26 5.65 3.29 4.31 4.43 1922 4.67 4.05 i 4.53 5.19 2.77 4.26 4.25 1923 5.69 6.30 | 5.28 5.69 4.01 2.45 2.23 1924 4.19 4.31 ; 4.25 4.24 2.93 3.00 2.97 1925 2.68 4.63 ! 4.50 5.47 3.12 1.92 2.20 1926 3.56 2.94 i 3.15 2.B9 0.76 1.39 1. 11 1927 3.79 3.81 i 4.18 4.49 2.93 3.13 3.26 1928 3.45 5.2S ! 5.57 5.23 3.09 3.21 4.85 1929 4.41 5.46 | 5.28 5.83 2.49 2.3H 4.77 1930 3.74 4.89 5.34 5.43 3.43 2.73 3.44 1931 4.41 4.24 4.65 4.41 3.41 2.44 4.01 1932 7.22 4.35 6.21 6.06 4.31 5.32 5.22 1933 4.74 5.63 6.33 6.09 3.70 2.91 1.99 1934 2.70 2.63 2.46 2.84 1.93 0.00 0.00 Average 4.24 4.60 4.79 4.97 3.01 2.82 3.20 Relative 100 108 113 117 71 6T 75 In comparison, alfalfa has averaged 3.35 ions per acre or 79 per cent as much as IMack Amber iorao during this 14-ycar period. German millet, with an average yield o£ 3.2 tons per acre, proved slightly superior in yield to the Common variety but yielded only 75 per cent as much as Black Amber. On the same farm, though grown in different fields, Kherson oats has averaged 1.2 tons of cured forage per acre during the same 14 years. This is 29 per cent of the yield of Black Amber cane. A comparison with alfalfa may be of interest. As an average for the 14-year period, established alfalfa meadows on the Experiment Station farm yielded 21 per cent less cured forage of equal moisture content than Black Amber cane. It must be borne in mind, however, that alfalfa has about six times the protein content of these other non-leguminous forage crops. SOY BEANS FOR FORAGE i The soy bean, an annual le jume, produces very palatable hay with high protein content when prop:rly cured. The most productive variety, the Illini, yielded about 80 per i ent as much cured forage as alfalfa and 45 per cent as much as Black Amber sorgo (Tables 2 and 3) on the Experiment Station farm during! the three-year period, 1930-32. In this test, the soy beans were grown in cultivated rows spaced 36 inches apart. The Manchu variety yielded only slightly less than the Illini. Of the varieties commercially available, these two may be regarded as superior for hay production. They ripen seed about the same time as east-central Nebraska corn. In the year 1932, the Manchu soy bean was tested for forage in both cultivated rows and in close drills sown with a grain drill. The yields </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Annual Fodder and Silage Crops for Nebraska Fic. 3. — Soy beans in cultivated rows. were nearly alike. Drilling requires about 85 pounds of medium-sized seed per acre compared with 35 pounds in rows. Soy beans are commonly much more subject to weed competition when drilled than when grown in cultivated rows. Much may be done toward weed control by working the soil just before planting, followed several times by a harrow or rotary hoe while the beans are small. The questions of seed cost, labor, soil erosion, and weeds should be considered in any decision on the manner of planting. Small fields of soy beans are often destroyed by rabbits. Table 3. — Comparative annual and average yields in tons per acre (15 per cent moisture) of six varieties of soy beans grown in cultivated rows spaced three feet apart — 1930-32. Year | Aksarbcp I Illini ! Ito San | Manchu 1 ] Midwest ] Virginia 1930 1.75 2.18 1.48 2.03 2.H 1.S2 1931 2.20 2.39 1.73 2.00 1.81 1.92 1932 2.66 2.40 1.69 2.56 1.9-1 2.12 Average 2.20 2.32 1.63 2.20 1.96 1.95 1 In 1932, the Manchu was also tested by close drilling with a grain drill ami yielded 2.40 tons, compared with 2.56 tons in cultivated rows. MANNER OF PLANTING FODDER CROPS Drilling, broadcasting, and cultivated rows are used in the growing of sorghum and Sudan grass for forage. The highest yields were obtained from drilling in an eight-year test with Black Amber sorgo and Sudan grass at the Experiment Station (Table 4). In the case of the sorgo, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Circular 52 broadcasting yielded 85 per cent and cultivated rows 66 per cent as much as drilling. With Sudan grass, the broadcasting yielded 92 per cent and the cultivated rows 81 per cent as much cured forage as drilling. Table 4. — Comparative forage yields from Blacky Amber sorgo and Sudan grass when planted by various methods — eight-year average. I Amount of iced Plant Meld per acre of forage method of planting planted height with \S^ moisture content per acre Pounds I hichr* \ Ton* \ Relative Black Amber sorgo Drilled .' ■' 9i . (■&gt; 5.19 100 Broadcast ■..■" Vi 72 4.42 85 Cultivated rows 6 9i 3.42 . 66 Sudan grass Drilled .... M 74 .1.42 IU0 Broadcast ,.; , 31 74 f.15 92 Cultivated row* 4 M 2.77 SI When drilled at a rather heavy rate per acre as in this experiment, namely 93 pounds of sorgo and 31 pounds of Sudan grass, the stems are fine and there is relatively little waste when fed to livestock as cured fodder. A disadvantage of drilling or broadcasting is the higher seed cost. This is partially offset by the extra labor cost of cultivated rows. In these row-tests 6 pounds of sorgo seed and 4 pounds of Sudan grass were planted per acre. While these cultivated rows were sown at the customary rate used for seed production, maximum yields of forage may be expected from planting about double this amount of seed in eastern Nebraska. The time of planting and approximate amount of seed per acre recom - mended for the various crops when grown for forage may be summarized as follows for eastern Nebraska. n _.,.!. Lbs. seed per Lbs. seed per Crop Tune of planting - . ... , v ■. ° acre, drilled acre, in rows Sorgo May 20 to Jiinc 10 90 12-18 Sudan . May 20 to fane 10 25 8 Millet May 20 to June 20 30 Oats ...,...: March 20 to April 5 64 Soy beans May 20 to June 10 S5 35 It is generally recognized that the amount of seed should be reduced somewhat westward within the state to offset the lower rainfall. For seed production of the full-season crops the earlier planting is most likely to result in full maturity. Tn the yield tests reported in this bulletin, triplicate plats of 1/40 acre were commonly used. The yields of cultivated plats were obtained from the interior rows. Special precautions have been taken to assure comparable stands each year. riOMl </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>