<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00036.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00036.00022</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nineteenth Biennial Report OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1914</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-19</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">i i V ti B &lt; Q 2 , &lt; = &lt; _ Q£ i CD is J | CO * ° = o = U. !3 ■ I : 1 . j L ♦ </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Nineteenth Biennial Report « OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska School for the Deaf OMAHA, NEBRASKA To the Governor and the Board of Commissioners of State Institutions FOR BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30. 1914 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">500 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OK OFFICERS F. W. Booth Superintendent Julia A. Schempp Matron Jennie E. Jones Clerk » TEACHERS— INTELLECTUAL DEPARTMENT J. W. Sowell Emily E. Sauter W. H. Rothert Martha C. Bell R. L. Welty Lina Hendershot Ida Hendee Bertha Sellner Alberta Regnier Winnie Goolsbe Ethyl Rogers Mildred Milnes Emma Anderson Esther Sherwood Ota Blankenship Grace Overstreet TEACHERS— INDUSTRIAL DEPARTMENT P. E. Seely Printing Jesse W. Jackson Manual Training Goldie Vawter Art Manual Edith Johnson Domestic Art Julia A. Schempp Domestic Science Wm. H. Chapman Gardening and Horticulture Marguerite Field Laundrying DOMESTIC DEPARTMENT Julia A. Schempp Matron Alfred Jefferson Physician Nannette Schrumpf Nurse Ann Richards Supervisor Mae Witmer Supervisor Milin Trentham Supervisor Mildred Sturdevant Assistant Supervisor Rudolph Schupbach Assistant Supervisor Orin Thayer Assistant Supervisor H. E. Gladwin Engineer Guy Middaugh Assistant Engineer Rasmus Nejlson Fireman </seg>
            <seg id="p004">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 501 i THE NINETEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA SCHOOL FOR THE DlAF To His Excellency, Honorable John H. Morehead, Governor, and to the Honorable members of the Board of Com - missioners of State Institutions, Silas A. Holcomb, Howard Kennedy and Henry Gerdes. Gentlemen : I have the honor to submit to you the Nineteenth Bien - nial Report of the Nebraska School for the Deaf, covering the period from December 1, 1912, to November 30, 1914, as follows: The number of pupils under instruction November 30, 1912, was 162, of whom seventy-three (73) were boys and eighty-nine (89) were girls. Since that date forty-eight (48) new pupils, thirty-two (32) boys and sixteen (16) girls, have been admitted. In addition to these, thirteen (13) former pupils of this or other similar schools, four (4) boys and nine (9) girls, have been admitted. Sixteen (16) pupils, seven (7) boys and nine (9) girls, have grad - uated; thirty-seven (37), nineteen (19) boys and eighteen (18) girls, have been furloughed, or honorably discharged, or have removed from the state; and two (2), a boy and a girl, have died. The total enrollment for the biennium is two hundred twenty-three (223), of whom one hundred sixty-eight (168), eighty-two (82) boys and eighty-six (86) girls, are now in attendance. Since the founding of the institution in 1869, nine hundred six (906) pupils have been enrolled, of which number one hundred twenty-one (121) have completed the course and been awarded diplomas of graduation. Of the 121 graduates, thirty-six (36) have taken more or less extended courses at Gallaudet College for the Deaf at Washington, thirteen of the number being now students at that institution. Naturally the most populous counties of the state have the largest representation in the school, with Douglas coun - ty, the county in which the school is located, leading with 52 pupils, or 31 per cent of the total attendance. (See Table VI for statistics of attendance by counties.) It may be noted that of the 52 pupils, twelve are day pupils, that is, they live at home going back and forth to school daily. An </seg>
            <seg id="p005">502 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF &gt; even larger proportion of the 52 children go home Friday afternoon of each week, returning the Sunday evening or Monday morning following. This living at home and going home over the week end, are encouraged from the fact that thereby not only is the normal home connection maintained but the normal home environment is preserved and its edu - cative values are utilized for the deaf child during the most impressible period of his life. And where the family in - terests itself in the school-work of the child and gives intel - ligent cooperation, the benefit to the pupil is in cases marked, especially in the learning of speech and lip-reading. In a number of instances parents living out in the state have moved to Omaha to reside in the neighborhood of the school, in order that their children may have this advantage of living at home while acquiring their education. Table VIII gives the assigned causes of deafness and the number and percentage of pupils made deaf by each. Thus, 52 pupils of the 168 now in school, or 31 per cent, were born deaf, while 24, or 14 per cent, were made deaf by spinal meningitis. Other more or less prolific causes are whooping cough, with 8 ; scarlet fever, with 7 ; and measles, with 6. The large number reported "cause unknown," namely, eighteen, or 10.7 per cent, leads to the belief that the term is used in the majority of cases because of unwil - lingness of parents to admit the fact of congenital deafness. Attention is directed to tables giving the ages of ad - mission (Table III), also the ages when deafness occurred (Table VII), of the sixty-one pupils admitted during the biennium. The large majority of pupils admitted ranged in age from six to eight years, and this it may be said is the best period for starting a deaf child's education, seven years being the beginning age giving on the whole the best re - sults. The health of the school family during the biennial period has been excellent, if we make exception of an epi - demic of smallpox. The smallpox was of an exceedingly light variety and occasioned only the inconvenience of quarantine and the isolation of the children affected. By direction of the Health Department of the City of Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 503 i all new children who have not been recently successfully vaccinated are now vaccinated by our school physician upon their arrival at the school. Our school physician, Dr. A. Jefferson, makes daily visitations when children are ill in the infirmary, and comes even more frequently in cases of serious illness, being within call at any time by telephone. A regular nurse, Miss Nannette Schrumpf, is also in attendance, residing in the infirmary, which is a detached building. Whenever neces - sary, because of very serious illness or contagious disease, an extra nurse is employed. The infirmary records cover - ing the term from September, 1913, to June, 1914, show seventy-nine cases of children requiring infirmary treat - ment. The following table gives the infirmary record of cases treated during the past term 79 Two deaths occured during the biennium, that of William Lamphear, and that of Ella Anderson. The former was taken with laryngial diphtheria on Sunday, March 21, 1914, and died on the following Tuesday. Prompt measures taken to isolate the case and to disinfect thoroughly pre - vented spread of the disease to other children. Ella Anderson died at her home in Minden, Nebraska, in May, 1913, of dropsy. Acute indigestion Arm broken Arm amputated Boils Billiousness Bronchitis Colds and coughs Chicken pox Diphtheria Ears treated Eye bruised Head-ache Infected finger Itch Operation on toes Pain in side Pneumonia Rheumatism Small-pox Sore-throat Tooth-ache m ni4i_ 1 a l l n 9 14 1 3 l 5 1 2 2 l 7 i 2 i 20 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">504 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF » Since June, 1913, the affairs of the household depart - ment have been under the direction of Miss Julia A. Schempp, the matron, who is a graduate of the Thomas Normal Training School of Detroit, Michigan. The several buildings in all their parts are kept scrupulously clean and the children are carefully looked after in the matter of their health and cleanliness and the repairing or replacement of their clothing. Under contracts made by the Board there is provided an abundance of plain, wholesome food and it is the aim to have this food prepared in variety and in appe - tizing form. In the summer the fruit grown on the place is put up for use on the tables during the winter. More than 600 quarts of cherries, grape juice, etc., and over 1200 glasses of jelly and preserves were thus put up during the summer of 1914 by the matron and her assistants. In ad - dition to her other duties, the matron conducts classes in Domestic Science with the older girls, she having this term two such classes of ten girls each. The girls of the school of all ages except the youngest, have the benefit of a course in Domestic Art under the direction of Mrs. Edith Johnson, who gives instruction in plain sewing, dressmaking, and embroidery. The boys likewise have industrial instruction in Manual Training under Mr. J. W. Jackson, in printing under Mr. P. E. Seely, and in gardening and horticulture under Mr. Wm. H. Chapman. Both boys and girls receive instruction from Miss Goldie Vawter in clay modeling, wood carving, and basketry. Two hours and a half per day of instruction is given to classes in the industrial depart - ment and, as all instructors employ the English language in their teaching, the pupils learn in every trade the special language of the trade while learning the trade itself. Two additional trades could well be added for the boys, namely, barbering and shoe repairing. A two chair equip - ment for the former, entailing an expense of $125.00, and a rotating finishing machine, a sewing machine, etc., for the latter, costing approximately $300.00, would enable us to employ and instruct a number of boys, thus providing our boys a wider choice of trades. The school continues to enjoy the benefits of contribu- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">&gt;^ A ■ J I &lt;d =3 1* 4 I- ff I t •**. * a = i s&gt; g &lt;* s 2 » .•^ k. f (^ [-'^ r i "! 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 505 tions from time to time of library books presented by the Nebraska Public Library Commission. These books are carefully selected by the Librarian for State Institutions, Miss Florence E. Waugh, who visits the school frequently to study its needs and to advise with our librarian, and they oerve most admirably in their purpose to entertain and in - struct, our children. It is expected that the new library room in the Primary building now under construction will afford much more convenient facilities for training our younger children in the use of books. The scholastic training of the school is given by six - teen class teachers instructing grades from the kindergar - ten to the graduating class, the pupils ranging in age from six to twenty-one years. The sixteen classes are in three departments, the Manual Department containing seven classes, under the direction of Mr. J. W. Sowell as super - vising teacher ; the Intermediate Oral Department, contain - ing four classes, under Miss Martha C. Bell, supervising teacher ; and the Primary Oral Department, containing five classes, under Miss Emily E. Sauter, supervising teacher. Eighty-one of the pupils of the school are in manual classes being taught through manual spelling and writing, and eighty-seven are in oral classes taught through speech and writing. At present all the older classes in the school are manually taught and they will continue to be so taught until their graduation, the pupils composing them not having sufficient ability to speak and to read the lips to be service - able in class recitation and instruction. Two classes have graduated during the biennium, one in June, 1913, and one in June, 1914. The 1913 class consisted of six pupils, as follows : Ella M. Cowen. Eugene Fry Douglas County Douglas County James V. Jelinek Bessie E. Lewis Harold G. Newman Effie Wessen Cass County Nuckolls County Cedar County Cuming County </seg>
            <seg id="p010">506 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF The 1914 class consisted of ten pupils, as follows: Four of the above graduates, Ella Cowen and Harold Newman, of the class of 1913, and Regina Olson and Jean Newell, of the class of 1914, are now students at Gallaudet College, Washington. The legislature of four years ago enacted a law making the oral method the dominant method employed in the school, the law providing that thereafter all new pupils re - ceived into the school should be taught by the oral method unless physically or mentally incapacitated for such instruc - tion. Under this provision seventy-three new pupils re - ceived and now in school are distributed in classes as fol - lows: sixty-two, or eighty-five per cent, in oral or speech classes, and eleven, or fifteen per cent, in manual classes, or classes in which speech is not taught or used. In ac - cordance with the spirit, as well as the letter of the law, effort is made to teach every child entering school to speak and to read the lips, and such effort is continued until it may be evident in a given case that a child cannot acquire speech or lip-reading to a profitable degree, in which case instruc - tion is limited thereafter to giving through silent methods such knowledge of written English and other branches as the child may have capacity to acquire. Naturally, success in acquiring serviceable speech by a deaf child is largely a question of good teaching, hence it is the policy of the school to employ teachers specially trained for the work and, where possible, those who have proven their ability in other schools. The course of study of the school carries the children 3. Gerald Brant Douglas County Christian M. Christensen Kearney County Slsie M. Kinnier Boone County ■lattie I. Kindred Foseph Kyncl \ugust J. Mueller \lta J. Neal Douglas County Colfax County Madison County Saline County fean Newell Pierce County ilegina M. Olson Fohanna M. Tikalsky Washington County Knox County </seg>
            <seg id="p011">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 507 from the kindergarten occupations through successive stages of advancement in the acquisition of speech and of grammatical forms employed in spoken and written lan - guage, thence on through the regular common school branches to graduation. The course covers twelve grades and, in the case of pupils of average intelligence, it may be covered in twelve years. The following is an outline of the course of study at present pursued in the several depart - ments of the school: First Grade Sense-training, Lip-reading, Articulation, Language, Numbers, Sunday School Work. Second Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Geography, Arith - metic, Sunday School Work. Third Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Geography, Arith - metic, Sunday School Work. Fourth Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Reading, Geogra - phy, Arithmetic, Sunday School Work. Fifth Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Reading, Descrip - tive Lessons, Geography (local and Nebraska), Nature Study, Arithmetic, Sunday School Work. Sixth Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Reading, Descrip - tive Lessons, Geography (Nebraska and United States), Nature Study, Arithmetic, Sunday School Work. Seventh Grade Speech, Speech-reading, Language, Reading, Geog - raphy (North America, South America, Europe), United States History, Local Biographies, Nature Study, Arithme - tic, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Eigth Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Geography, United </seg>
            <seg id="p012">508 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF States History, Local Biographies, Nature Study, Arithme - tic, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Ninth Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Reading, Political Geography, American History, Physiology, Arithmetic, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Tenth Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Reading, Political Geography, English Biographies, American History, Phys - ical Geography, Arithmetic, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Eleventh Grade Language, Grammar, Composition, Reading, English History, Arithmetic, Physics, Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Twelfth Grade Division A, Graduate Course — Language, Grammar, Composition, Reading, Arithmetic, Physics Reviewed, Eng - lish History Reviewed, Civil Government, Algebra (latter part of term), Manners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Division B, College Preparatory Course — Same course in English as above. Literature, Composition, Algebra, Man - ners and Morals, Sunday School Work. Upon graduation from the school pupils may elect to continue their education by taking the five-year course at Gallaudet College for the Deaf at Washington. Two successful and profitable professional meetings were held during the biennium, namely, the Conference of Principals of American Schools for the Deaf, at Indian - apolis, in the summer of 1913, and the Convention of Amer - ican Instructors of the Deaf, at Staunton, Va., the summer of 1914. This school was represented by the Superinten - dent at the former meeting and by the Superintendent and Mrs. Blankenship of the corps of teachers at the latter. An unusually large amount of work under the head of repairs, changes, and improvements has been done during the two summer vacation periods, principally in the way of painting roofs, dormitory walls and woodwork, renewing </seg>
            <seg id="p013">j \ a +i Kn k. I !kl * £&lt; * si j] &lt; .« cn-g. c «^ « &lt;d c • 5 1:1 s^ Q£ ■= • o lit-i O -SuO I Utfl c/j r: •*■ J «* i. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 509 porches and roofs, replacing old and defective plumbing, and installing additional bath rooms and toilets. Changes were made in the school-house, involving the partitioning of the old chapel on the third floor, making five new and commodious school-rooms, and the changing of partitions in order to secure needed enlargement of a number of small school-rooms. New concrete walks were laid about the auditorium and between that building and the school-house. Remodeling and extending one of the fire escapes rendered it safer and more efficient for its purpose. Further repairs and changes are recommended to be made in the various buildings as follows: In the auditor - ium : the completion of the work of painting or decorating of the walls and ceilings : equipping the stage with a curtain and scenery; and installing some device for improving acoustic properties of the room — to cost approximately one thousand dollars. In the school-house: r'epaintiner the in - side walls and woodwork throughout, and repointing the brick-work outside — to cost three hundred dollars. In the shop building: a general overhauling of all floors, replaster - ing throughout, and painting walls and woodwork outside and inside — to cost two thousand dollars. In the hospital : reshingling and repainting — to cost two hundred dollars. In the main buildine: painting of the pupils' dining room walls and ceilin", painting of walls and ceilings of dormi - tories on the girls' side, relaying floors in the boys' and girls' play-rooms and in the basement halls, pointing and painting the outside brick work throughout, and reconstructing the two west side porches — to cost approximately two thousand dollars. The list above aggregates a total expenditure for reDairs and improvements of five thousand five hundred dollars. Additional machinery equipment for the various de - partments of the school is recommended and asked for as follows: For the laundry: a new steam dryer, to cost $225. For the manual training department : a universal saw table, to cost $350; three wood-turn - ing lathes, to cost $250; and a mortising machine, to cost $125. For the printing office: a cylinder press, to cost </seg>
            <seg id="p015">510 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF $1200; a linotype or type-setting machine, to cost $3000; and a paper cutter, to cost $100. The above list will involve a total investment for machinery of $5250. The modern industrial plant employs machinery' largely in its various operations and, as our boys remain at school until of an age ranging from eighteen to twenty-one years or during the trade learning period, they have a very great need of school training in the use of the special machinery that they are to meet in order to secure and hold positions after they finish their school course. I estimate that the above com - paratively small money expenditure will double to quad - ruple the efficiency of the trade instruction given by the school, thus making the expenditure in high degree a paying one. The equipment asked for would enable the school to make a large part of the furniture used ; also, in the print - ing department, to do certain kinds of state printing such as the Board and other state officers might require. The new Primary Building is well under way, but it will scarcely be ready for occupancy during the present term of school. Its location at the north side of the campus upon ground sloping to the east, will necessitate a large amount of grading about the completed building. This, with other improvements about the grounds in the way of grading, removing trees, laying out of roads and macadam - izing will call for expenditure approximating five thousand dollars. Removing the boys' cottage and the well-house and stand pipe, also the barn and side buildings, and rebuilding the latter in a more suitable location, will also involve an expenditure of three thousand dollars. An extension of the paving on Forty-fifth street, which now reaches the corner of the school property, should be made along the entire west front of the state property. The State's share of the cost of this paving is estimated as $3,300. It is probable that grading will be done to lower the level of Bedford Avenue along our north front. In this event it will be necessary for us to lower our own property grade and probably to build a retaining wall a couple of feet or more high. This may require an expenditure of $1000. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 511 An estimate should also be included for the expense for additional furniture for the new Primary building. This expense will approximate $2000. The various needs and the cost of meeting them may be recapitulated as follows: Auditorium improvements $1,000 Shop building overhauling 2,000 Main buildinsr repairs 2,000 Printing office machinery 4,300 Manual Training machinery 725 School-house repairs 300 Hospital repairs 200 Laundry machinery 225 Oradinsr and improving grounds 5,000 Removinsr buildings and rebuilding barn, etc 3,000 Pavintr 45th street and grading Bedford Ave 4,300 Furnishing new Primary building 2,000 Appropriations for salaries and wa&lt;?es, maintenance, etc., are recommended and asked for as follows: Salaries of officers and teachers : Superintendent $3,600 Matron 1,600 Other officers and teachers 35,000 $40,200 Wages of employees 14,000 Maintenance 44,000 Gallaudet Students 600 In the estimate above for salaries of officers and em - ployees and for Gallaudet Students the amounts asked for are the same as for the last biennium. In the estimate for wacres of employees, an increase of $1 .000 and, for main - tenance, of $4,000 is asked for, these amounts being needed in view of an anticipated small deficiency in one or both appropriations for the biennium and of pxpected additional attendance of pupils when the new Primary building is com - pleted. In closiner this report T desire to express my deep ap - preciation of the Board's encouraging support and cooper - ation during our association in the conduct of this school. Respectfully submitted F. W. Booth, Superintendent. Omaha, Nebraska, November 30, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">512 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE I. MOVEMENT OF POPULATION •Includes all pupils who had attended previously this or a similar school. TABLE II. SEX AND RACE OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year E"Hing Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, "12 July 1. '13 ending Total RACE Nov .30 for tn tl June 30, 13 Nov.30.'13 1914 Biennium MFT MPT MFT MFT White 6 4 10 12 9 21 18 12 30 36 25 61 Neero Indian Totals 6 4 10 12 9 21 18 12 30 36 25 61 For Year Ending For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 Nov. 30, 1913 Dec. 1, '12 July 1,13 to to June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 For Year ending Total Nov. 30, for 1914 Biennium M F T M F T M F T M F T M F T M F T Present at begin- ning of period.. Admitted: For first time... Re-admitted* .... Transferred from other institutions Total enrollment Discharged: Graduated Transferred to other institutions . Exwlled Left school for various reasons. Diod Total removals Present at end of period 73 89 162 71 85 156 4 3 7 12 7 19 2 1 3 1 1 1 1 79 93 172 83 94 177 3 3 6 5 4 9 9 5 14 1 1 8 8 16 9 5 14 71 85 156 I 74 89 163 74 89 163 73 89 162 16 5 21 32 15 47 2 7 9 4 9 13 ..... 1 1 92 101 193 109 114 22M 4 6 10 7 9 16 5 9 14 19 18 37 1 1112 10 15 25 27 28 55 82 86 168 82 86 168 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 513 TABLE III. AGES OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1,13 ending Total AGE to to Nov .30 for June 30, '13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT 6 years 112 123 516 74 11 years .11 4 2 6 3 3 7 3 10 8 years 9 years 10 years 11 years 12 years 13 years 14 years 15 years 16 years 17 years 18 years 19 years 20 years. 21 years Over 21 112 415 235 75 12 1 1213314628 1 1112 2 13 1 1 11 112 2 2 4 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1112 1 1 1 1 2 2 1 1 1 1 112 2 13 .2 2 2 2 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 Totals 6 4 10 12 9 21 18 12 30 36 25 61 TABLE IV. NATIVITY OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, '13 ending Total NATIVITY to Nov .30 for to June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium MFTMFT MFT MFT Nebraska 4 3 9 8 17 11 6 17 24 17 41 U. S., other than Nebraska 112 3 3 6 6 12 10 7 17 Total native born &gt; 5 4 9 1 12 8 20 17 12 29 34 24 58 Italy 1 1 1 1 Russia 1 1 1 1 1 Total foreign born 1 1 1 1112 Unknown 1 1 1 1 Totals 6 4 10 12 9 21 18 12 30 36 25 61 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">514 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE V. NATIVITY OF PARENTS OF PUPILS ADMITTED For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, 13 ending Total NATIVITY OF to to Nov .30 for PARENTS June 30, 13 Nov.30,13 1914 Biennium MFTMFT MFT MFT U. S., both parents 3 3 6 9 6 15 13 6 19 25 15 40 Foreign, both par- ents 213 246 459 Mixed 1 1112 2 2 4 15 Unknown 2 13 11123347 Totals 6 4 10 12 9 21 , 18 12 30 36 25 61 TABLE VI. RESIDENCE OF PUPILS ADMITTED AND OF ALL PUPILS REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year All Dec.1,1?! Jul. 1,13 ending Total Remaining RESIDENCE to to Nov. 30, for Nov. 30, Jun.30,13 Nov,30.'13 1914 Biennium 1914 MFTMFTMFT MFT MFT Nebraska: Adams ! ; 2 2 Boyd ' : ; 1 .... 1 1 1 2 2 Brown 1 1 Buffalo ! 1 1 Burt I 1 .... 1 1 1 2 q Butler 1 1 .... 1 1 1 1 1 Cass 1 .... 1 1 1 ! 1 1 Cedar 2 13 Cherry I I ■ 1 1 Cheyenne „ ' _ 1 1 Colfax 2 2 2 2 2 2 1 1 Cuming .... 1 1 .... 2 2 3 3 12 3 Custer I _......_ 2 2 4 Dawson 1 .... 1 , 1 12 13 Dixon ! ! 2 2 Dodge _ 2 1 3 Douglas 4 1 5 2 2 4 6 3 9 12 6 18 23 29 52 Fillmore .... 1 1 11112 Franklin - .... ; 1 1 Frontier | 1 .... 1 ! 1 1 I 2 2 Furnas _.. 1 .... 1 1 1112 Gage .... 1 1 1114 5 Greeley 1 1 .... 1 1 2 2 2 2 Hall _.._. 112 112 12 3 Hamilton _ _ : 1 1 Harlan I ; 1 1 Hitchcock _... _ 1 1 Jefferson I 1 .... 1 I ..._ I 1 1 , 2 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 515 TABLE VI. RESIDENCE OF PUPILS ADMITTED AND OF ALL PUPILS REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM— (Continued) For year ending Nov. 30, 1913 For year All ending Total Remaining RESIDENCE Dec.1,12 Jul. 1,13 to to Nov. 30, for Nov. 30, Jub.30,13 Nor,30.13 1914 Biennium 1914 MFTMFTMFT M. FTMFT Kra'ney - 3 14 Keith - ! 1 1 Keya Paha _ 1 1 Knox ..Z. Z"..-.._... 1 ... 1 1 ■-. 1 2 2 6 2 8 Lancaster 1 1 2 .... 11 123 57 12 Lincoln 1 1 - 1 I 1 1 1 Madison - 112 Morrill 1 .- 1112 2 13 2 2 Nemaha - - 1 1 Nuckolls : - 1 1 Otoe 1 1 1113 4 Phelps ■"■. 1 1 1 1. 1 1 Pirrce i I 1 1 Red Willow - -.._ 1 1 Saline 1 - 1 1 1 2 2 Sarpy ' 1 1 Sanders 1 .... 1 Z 11112 12 3 Scotts Bluff 1 1 .... 1 1 2 I 1 2 3 Seward ...'.'.'. 1 — 1 ; 1 1 1 -— 1 Sherman - 2 2 Stanton .Z.Z 1 ■- 1 : 1 1 1 ••■- } Thaver - -\ — ] ■■— } Valley .... - - * - - * Washington - - 1 1 1 *! ■• 1 1 Wayne 112 Webster York ZZ-iZ.Z_...l 1 .... 11... 1 2 2 2...... 2 Other States South Dakota! 1 .... 1 ■ I -— - 1 ■--- J ! .--——---■ ----- 1 1 2 1 1 1 2 1 12 Wyoming 6 4 10 12 9 21 18 12 30 36 25 61 ' 82 86 168 Totals TABLE VII. AGES AT WHICH PUPILS ADMITTED BECAME DEAF Number Per Cent M F T M FT 10 6 16 16 4 9.8 26.2 Congenital 4 3 7 6.6 4.9 11.5 Und°r 1 vear 7 6 13 11 5 9.8 21.3 1 and under 2 years 1 mm uuuci jc».~ - - 2 and under 3 years 6 — • 6 9-8 ■— »•» 2 2 4 33 3 3 6.6 3 and under 4 years Hnd under 5 yelrsIZZZZZ....! 1 1 • U « 4 9 5 and under 10 yean. •■ 2 2 3.3 3.3 __.. 2 2 3.3 3.3 4 2 6 6.5 3.3 9 8 Unknown unsniiwn - - 7q O oq r c Not deaf I 2 2 4 3.3 3.3 6.6 ToUls _ ! 36 25 61 59.0 41.0 100.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF 516 82 86 168 49.0 51.0 100.0 Totals 36 25 61 59.0 41.0 100.0 i viii. AOBiuntu iaujm \jr utrtVji lix ruru MITTED AND OF ALL PUPILS REMAINING AT END OF BIENNIUM For the Two Years Ending Nov. 30, 1914 All Pupils in School Nov, 30, 1914 ASSIGNED CAUSES Number Per Cent Numb« Per Cent Number er Per Or nt Per C«nt MFT M F T MF M MFT T M F M T Abscess in head 1 1 2 1.6 1.6 3.3 1 2 Adenoids 1 .... 1 1.6 1.6 3.3 1 1 Brain fever 1 .... 1 1.6 1.6 3 2 Cold 1 1 1.6 1.6 ... 2 Catarrh 1 2 Congenital 10 6 16 16.4 9.8 26.2 25 27 Congestion of lungs _ 1 Diphtheria 1 2 Ear-ache 3 1 Fall 1 Fever 1 1 2 1.6 1.6 3.3 3 1 Grand swelling 1 Inflamation in head 1 1 1.6 l.« .... 1 Kicked by colt 1 .... La Grippe 1 1 1.6 1.6 1 ... Lung Fever 1 Malarial Fever 1 Measles 1 .... 1 1.6 1.6 2 4 Meningitis 7 2 9 11.5 3.3 14.8 16 8 Mumps 2 2 3.3 3.3 2 2 Overdose of chloroform 1 ... Pneumonia 1 .... 1 1.6 1.6 2 .... Scarlet Fever 2 1 3 3.3 1.6 4.9 2 5 Sickness 3 3 Smallpox 1 .... 1 1.6 1.6 1 .... Smothered 1 Typhoid 1 1 2 1.6 1.6 3.3 1 2 Unknown 5 3 8 8.2 4.9 13.1 7 11 Whooping Cough 2 2 4 3.3 3.3 6.6 4 4 Not deaf 2 2 4 3.3 3.3 6.6 ... 1 3 0.6 1.2 2 0.6 0.6 5 1.8 1.2 2 1.2 3 0.6 1.2 52 14.9 16.1 1 0.6 3 0.6 1.2 4 1.8 0.6 1 0.6 4 1.8 0.6 I 0.6 I 1 0.6 1 0.6 1 0.6 1 0.6 1 0.6 6 1.2 2.4 24 9.5 4.8 4 1.2 1.2 1 0.6 2 1.2 7 1.2 3.0 6 1.8 1.8 1 0.6 1 0.6 3 0.6 1.2 18 4.2 6.5 8 2.4 2.5 1 0.6 1.8 1.2 3.0 1.2 1.8 31.0 0.6 l.K 2.4 0.6 2.4 O.fi O.fi O.fi O.fi O.fi O.fi 3.6 14.3 2.4 O.fi 1.2 4.2 3.6 0.6 0.6 1.8 10.7 4.8 0.6 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THE BOARD OF COMMISSIONERS 517 TABLE IX. EXTENT OF DEFECT IN PUPILS ADMITTED TABLE XI. PUPILS ADMITTED HAVING DEFECTIVE RELATIVES WHO ARE OR HAVE BEEN IN LIKE INSTITUTIONS In the first column (M) of this table, two boys, brothers, are repeat - edly entered, they having all the deaf relatives listed. Eight children in all, or 13.1 of the 61 children admitted during the biennium, have one or more deaf relatives. Number Per Cent EXTENT OF DEFECT M F T M No nearing Partial hearing .. Not deaf 24 18 42 10 5 15 2 2 4 39.3 16.4 3.3 29.5 8.2 3.3 68.8 24.6 6.6 Totals 36 25 61 59.0 41.0 100.0 TABLE X. PHYSICAL CONDITION ON ADMISSION OP PUPILS ADMITTED Number Per Cent PHYSICAL CONDITION M F T M Normal Defective Crippled 36 25 61 100.0 100.0 100.1 Totals 36 25 61 100.0 100.0 100j Number Per Cent RELATIVES M F T M Grandfather Grandmother Father Mother Brother _ Sister Uncle Aunt Cousin 2 .. .... 2 ... 2 .. .... 2 .. 4 4 .. 2 .. 2 .. 2 . 2 2 2 2 2 8 4 2 2 2 3.3 3.3 3.3 3.3 6.6 3.3 6.6 3.3 3.3 3.3 3.3 3.3 3.3 3.3 9.S M 3.3 3.3 3.3 For Yeai For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 r Ending i CAUSES Nov. 3( Dee. 1, 12 to June 30, 13 0, 1913 July 1, 13 to Nov.30,13 For Year ending Nov .30 1914 Total for Biennium M F M F M F T M F T Diphtheria Dropsy .... 1 1 1 1 1 ...... _ . 1 1 1 Totals... 1 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">518 FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF TABLE XIII. AGE AT DEATH For Year Ending Nov. 30, 1913 For Year Dec. 1, 12 July 1, '13 ending Total AGE Nov .30 to to for June 30, 13 Nov.30,'13 1914 Biennium MFT MFT MFT MFT Twelve years 1 1 1 1 Fourteen years _ 1 1 1 1 Totals 1 1 1 1112 TABLE XIV. DISTRIBUTION OF ALL PUPILS IN SCHOOL AT END OF BIENNIUM Number GRADE MFT Intellectual departments: Kindergarten _ _ 7 3 10 1st grade 20 15 35 2nd grade _ 12 7 19 3rd grade _... 4 5 9 4th grade 10 9 19 5th grade 5 6 11 6th grade _ _ _ 4 6 10 7th grade _ 3 5 8 8th grade 6 3 9 9th grade 6 8 14 10th grade _ - 3 9 12 11th grade _ „ 2 13 12th grade _ _ _ „ 9 9 Totals _ _ 82 86 168 Industrial departments: Art Manual _ _ _ 13 44 57 Domestic Art« _ _ - 59 59 Domestic Science _ _ _ ■. 20 20 Farming and Gardening _ _ 11 — 11 Laundrying _ _... ... 57 57 Manual Training _ 26 26 Printing _ _ _ 10 10 Totals ' 60 180 240 </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>