<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00026">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Dairy Industry in Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1922-06">1922-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE DAIRY INDUSTRY IN NEBRASKA 1 Li • ■ 0* ■ i -sr BrU^ r it STATE OF NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE BUREAU OF MARKETS AND MARKETING BULL'£TI M No. 119 LINCOLN JUNE. 1922 </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">ial net a iirv Marke Sebraaka FOREWORD iriea for information concerning the dairy state suggest the need of a publication giving condensed form This booklet contains a corn- t« together with terse paragraphs on the present in ir and the opportunity for further development, ■d are from official records in the Bureau of Mar- eting of the State Department of Agriculture, Lin- Secretary of Agriculture. LKofcTTHR. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">State of Nebraska ■1 • INTRODUCTION For a number of years Nebraska's dairy industry has shown a gradual, wholesome development. Much of the western and north-central parts- of the state, being grazing land, is devoted to the growing of beef cattle, altho cows are milked at least a part cream is sold. In early days the ducts consumed in the state were in many instances some of the of the year and more or less greater part of the dairy pro - produced by cows of this type. At the present time the herds kept for milking purposes consist largely of grade cows of the dairy breeds. . Railroad transportation services are such as to make possible rapid transit of dairy products across the state and most of the manufacturing is done by centralized plants in the eastern sec - tion. Outside of local retail milk trade throughout the state, the farm dairy business consists principally of the. sale of butter-fat. Only 4.3% of Nebraska farmers sell milk and 14% sell butter, while 58.7% sell butteiyfat. The total quantity of cream handled by the railroads of the state is approximately 1 "2,000, 000 gallons, annually. The volume of cream shipped comes from many small herds on diversified farms rather than from large herds on specialized dairy farms. Dairy cattle are kept on 80,470 farms, and the value of the total annual production of dairy products is approx - imately $30,000,000. On the basis of last year's values this amount is equal to two-thirds of the corn crop or live-eights of the wheat crop of the state. Distribution of Cows </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Dairy Industry in Nebraska 5 THE PLACE OF THE DAIRY COW IN NEBRASKA AGRICULTURE In thf early history of the state the cow was one of the most valuable assets of the settler and enabled many a pioneer to re - main on his homestead. In the course of development each sec - tion came to be used for the purpose for which is was best adapt - ed and cattle of the dairy breeds found greatest favor in the cul - tivated areas, leaving the grazing sections largely to the produc - tion of beef cattle. As more intensive methods are employed in the farming area of the state, the attention of the farmer is attracted to the kind of livestock that returns the most income, and naturally he thinks of the dairy cow. In production of food, the cow, being twice as efficient as the steer, is particularly well adapted to higher priced land. She is the foster mother of the human race the world over and furnishes 18% of the diet of the average American family. Besides furnishing dairy products for table use, cows bring to Nebraska farmers a cash revenue of $18,000,000 annually. They do this, too, without impoverishing the soil. As a soil builder, the cow has no equal. Instead of taking away fertility, she adds annually to the soil about 12 tons of solid and liquid manure valued at approximately $30.00. Dairy products sold from the farm contain very little fertility. To remove as much fertility from the soil as a ton of wheat or 1.11 tons of corn re - moves would require 3.7 tons of milk or 14.4 tons of butter. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 State of Nebraska SCRUBS GIVE PLACE TO HIGH GRADES High grade cows of the dairy hi Is have demonstrated their uperior qualities as producers to the extent that they are grad - &gt;ally finding their way into the dairy herds in the state, taking he place of low producing scrubs. One good cow will produce as much as two or three such a-s are sometimes classed as dairy ows. The result is that, with 175,000 less cows than were milked en years ago, the total production for the state is maintained The average production of milk per cow increased 60 gallon* ine? 1910. The total average production is approximately 200, 000,000 gallons. The number of good dairy cows has increased ach year and there are more high grade cows in the state today han ever before. The total number of producing cows in the tate, April 1st, 1921, was 412,564 and the total number of cows and heifers two years old and over carrying more or less of the &gt;lood of the dairy breeds is approximately 440,000. So great is the demand for high grade cows that it is nee - ssary to ship them into the state in large numbers eaeh year. In 921, 4,211 dairy cows were purchased in the dairy sections of 17 ifferent states and added to Nebraska herds. In some instances hese cows have replaced cows of the beef breeds that have been sed for milking purposes, but in many cases they have gone into he hands of farmers who never before handled dairy cattle and orm the foundation of a dairy herd. Herds of this kind headed &gt;y a good, pure-bred sir. are the safest assurance of the future upply of grade, dairy cows and of the growth of the dairy in - ustrv in the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">The Dairy Industry in Nebraska 7 Aside from income at the pail, an attractive feature of dairy tannins is the sale of breeding stock. The handling of registered stock is a business in itself and appeals to progressive livestock men. There are in Nebraska more than 1,000 breeders of pure luvd dairy cattle, and the total number of registered cattle of all the dairy breeds in the state, January 1st, 1920, was 5,922 females tiiid 1,951 males. Holsteins were owned in the largest numbers. The total num - ber of farms on which pure breds of this breed were owned was 1,058 and on 637 of these farms, pure bred females were owned. The total number of registered females in the state was 4,051 and the number of registered bulls was 1,317. 1" Farms Reporting Number of Animals BREED Holstein Jersey Guernsey Ayrshire Brown Swiss _ All Others __ *1 1,058 323 92 16 7 153 u "€« o ai £•■5 771 107 71 12 5 123 |l Si I | «&amp;. 637 280 32 10 6 63 ■ _i 1^17 152 245 15 6 216 i ■ I I 4,051 1,123 103 59 32 554 i 536S 1^75 348 74 38 770 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 State of Nebraska A Purebred Dairy Herd t Jerseys were reported on 'i'2'.i farms and pure bred females ?re owned on 280 farms. The total number of registered Jer - ys was 1,275 and the number of females was 1,123. Guernseys were owned in smaller numbers yet pure breds of this breed were reported on 92 farms and on 3:2 of these farms females were owned. The total number of females in tin- state was 103. Ayrshires were reported on 16 farms and the total numbe owned was 74 head. Brown Swiss were comparatively scarce. 7 breeders owning total of 38 head, consisting of 3"2 females and 6 bulls. I The demand for pure breds is such that the herds may be lcreased with every assurance of being able to dispose of sur - lus stock at a profit. If all the pure bred females of all the airy breeds in the state, at the present time, were placed in an verage sized county there would be less than 4 cows and heifers a the quarter section of land. Nebraska is conveniently located Dr supplying breeding stock to Southern and Western states and lie opportunity for develpoing the purebred business in the state 5 practically unlimited. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 The Dairy Industry in Nebraska FACTORIES AND THEIR OUTPUT As early as 1NH5 then- were 38 small, local creameries in the . The first centralized creameries were organized in 1890. he advent of the han&lt;l separator increased interest in milking nd the quantity of butter manufactured in creameries doubled ween 1*90 and 1900 and more than doubled again in the next y.ars, the total make for 1910 being 25,9734«2 lbs. There are now in the state 79 licensed creameries ranging in annual production from 1,000 to 11,345,350 pounds of butter. Five creameries manufactured, last year, over 5,000,000 pounds each; eight manufactured between 1,000,000 and 5,000,000 pounds each, and nine manufactured between 500,000 and 1,000,000 pounds each. The total quantity of butter manufactured in the creameries of the state in 1921 was 64,,S82,949 pounds. In addi - tion to this, approximately 15,000,000 pounds was manufactured on farms. lee cream was manufactured last year by 62 wholesale and 72 retail concerns. These factories produced a total of 2,179,180 over 50,000 gallons each. In addition to butter and ice 5.2OO.2W lbs. of condensed milk cream, 56,900 lbs. of cheese and was manufactured in the state last yew galloni ami 14 of them produced </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 State of Nebraska WHAT DAIRYING HAS MEANT TO THE STATE From the earliest history of the state the eon haa is a&gt; indispensable as the cow bThost' who were willing to ch day have found that dairy erating expenses ami save m put in a few liout niir has enabled 'I \ pay ti inev at times win ii otln farming were hazardous and unprofitable. Wherever dairjri persistently practiced, prosperity prevails and happy mad tended eitixena are found. Nebraska's dairy cows consume annually a million ami half tons of hay besides laijr ■ c|uantities of other nmghayt and sriain. No Other farm animal converts these products into cash as &lt;|iiick - ly or as efficiently as the dairy cow. Fanners far from a railroad have needed no other market for their roilfrhajfe illilll the COW. Those near the railroad have saved considerable freight by feed - iiiK their roughage to cows and gelling dairy products rather than shipping the feed direct. For many years dairying hius added directly each year mill - ions of dollars to the wealth of the state and has provided com - fortable, modern homes for thousands of farmers who otherwise could not have enjoyed such conveniences. pciulcd upon not only for milk ami butter for the tahlr, hut aim for a surplus that may be sold for- cash or i-xchantr&lt; &lt;i for othe food. Wm for any reason, the rewweea of the farm must l&gt; iependfd upon almost exeltunvrly fur food, no other faim anima VI </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Dairy Industry in Nebraska 11 FURTHER POSSIBILITIES AWAIT DEVELOPMENT as it may seem, it is a fact that even yet dairy pro are loo often looked upon as a luxury rather than a neces- With a greater appreciation of these products in the daily ew and broader fields open up in the dairy business. A xt'iisive use of milk and milk products may well be advo- oi only from the standpoint of economy but also for the health. Ik greatest needs of Nebraska's dairy industry is im- Hiality throujrh better handling of milk and cream. ('lean milk, more frequent delivery of cream, better quality of butter means more and better demand for Nebraska's dairy products. Consumers in the East demand butter of the highest quality and the supply is usually limited. Nebraska ranks first in alfalfa, third in corn and compara - lv hijfh in other kinds of grain suitable for balancing the ra- tion of a dairy cow. Silage in abundance, both for winter use and to supplement pastures in summer, may be made from corn stalks that otherwise make comparatively little feed. Plenty of home grown feed enables dairymen to compete on more than a favorable basis with producers in other states as far as cost of feed is concerned — the main consideration in the cost of milk pro - duction. Kor the man who will milk, the opportunity in Nebraska is especially inviting. Feed, water, climate, market and other es - sentials are all that could be desired. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>