<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00029.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00029.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1913</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
           
            <seg id="p001">FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1913 C. A. RANDALL, Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner JOHN C. TROUTON - ... Assistant MISS MAMIE MULDOON - - Secretary MISS LAURA CHRISTENSON - Stenographer F. J. BUCK Inspector </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">CHESTER H. ALDRICH, ( Inw, </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">C. A. RANDALL, Cliii'f Deputy lire Commiiwion r </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT. Office of State Firs Commission. State Capitol, Lincoln, Nebraska. To His Excellency Chester H. AUIrich, (Governor of the State of Nebraska: Dbab Sib — The law governing this department provides that a report of the business transacted and that the acts performed by the Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner and others constituting the department be made to you annually, and I have the honor to herewith submit such report covering the work that we have accomplished during the year, and as the work has been along the same lines of the previous year this report will of necessity be largely a repetition of our last annual report. We have endeavored to carry out and enforce every provision of the law so far as it lay in our power and bring about the greatest amount of good to the greatest number. In oar educational work we have endeavored to call the attention of the public to the enormous waste of property and injury and loss of life from fire. We have warned them against careless practices and dangerous conditions and since our last report have delivered addresses in the schools to 70,000 school children and in the evenings to 30,000 of the citizens in several towns in the state. I believe that this branch of the work has aroused an interest in the schools and towns that will be of lasting benefit We have published and distributed over 500,000 bulletins and cards : they have been published in the newspapers and dis - tributed among the citizens and school children promiscuously over the state. We have resorted to every means at our command to get these facts before the public in such a manner as to be attractive and bring about the desired results. There has been </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 IMMI of the cards "Pledges for the Protection of the Home" ted and distributed in the public schools and to the public a large jwrt of these are now tumping in the homes of the ens of this state. I had 120,00(1 attractive and suggestive :o cards printed and they have been distributed in the homes ugh the medium of the school children. In order to interest school children and get them to remember the admonition ■vent Fires." I had 100,000 certificates of memtership printed n attractive form which reads as follows: "Certificate of ibership. This is to umtitf that (the teacher will fill in the lar's name herei is a member of The Nebraska Fire Scouts in consideration of such membership agrees to use all possible is to Prevent Fires and Protect Life and Property. Given «■ my hand at State Capitol, Lincoln. Nebraska," and signed uyself as Chief Deputy Fire Commissioner. I believe the children receiving these certificates will preserve them for years and every time they look at them they will be reminded of the necessity of a wise caution, and it cannot but result in a lasting benefit, not onlv to those who have received the certificates, but to the citizens in the locality in which they li'. In compliance with the law we prepared and published a text-book and they were distributed to the county superin - tendents as the law provided, bnt in traveling over the state I found that in a great many instances these books had not been distributed to the teachers and I at once, in conjunction with the State Superintendent, issued a circular letter to all county superintendents insisting that they distribute these books to their teachers and cause them to carry out the intent of the law by having the subject taught. This proceeding had a very bene - ficial effect, but even now there are several schools in the state that have not been provided with the books by their county superintendents, or if they have the subject is not being taught in a great many of the schools. It was a very lucky thing that I had several thousand more of the books printed than enough to supply the schools one year ago, for during this fall and winter we have sent out over 5.000 of the books to either supply those who either never had them or to supplant those that had been </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 STATS FIHB CUM.\II&gt; destroyed during the vacation period. There is no penalty con - nected with the law that provides for the teaching of flre preven - tion in the public schools, and in my judgment there should be a penalty attached to it and I know of no more effectual one than that the Board of Education should qualify by affidavit to the State Superintendent that the subject had been taught during the school year as provided by law before they would be per - mitted to participate in the semi-annual apportionment of the state school fund. I know of no subject that the laws of the state provide shall be taught in the public schools that will be of as far reaching and beneficial effect as that of fire prevention. It not only protects the home, the business house and public buildings but insures a greater degree of safety to human life. A large number of the parochial and private schools are teaching the subject and we have endeavored to supply them with printed matter and books so that they could inculcate into the minds of the children under their tutorship habits and practices that would be of benefit to them in after life. We have sent a monthly bulletin to every paper in the state and nearly all of the papers have published them or extracts from them which have called attention to the public and the results attained have been very beneficial. I believe that it is unjust to ask these proprietors of these pa|&gt;ers to print these bulletin* without reasonable compensation and there ought to be some way devised where the income of this department could be made of sufficient volume to pay for this work. I desire at this time to express my gratitude to the public press for their co-operation in this work and they will have to be content for a time at least with the thanks of the department and the public for the part they have taken in spreading the gospel of fire prevention into the hoines of the readers of their papers. While T believe that every bulletin that we have issued has had a beneficial effect there are three that I desire to call your attention to. There has been a falling off in Christmas fires to such an extent that Christmas has become to be a Merry ChristmaB instead of a sad one. It is the exception and not the rule now for the Christmas tree to be made a dangerous agency. Very few people who have these </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 rOUBTH ANNUAL REPORT Icises in charge will permit cotton, celluloid or other in mable material placed upon the trees and other precaution measures are being taken which makes these gatherings very h safer than they have been in the past. I One year ago there was 1235.000 worth of property destroyed flre ignited either from fireworks or fire-crackers. Several e injured and some of the injuries resulted fatally. On the Fourth of July there was only $7,100 worth of property de - ived from the same source and we were only informed of * being injured and no fatalities were reported. These re - 8 alone are worth all the hard work that has been done in department since its establishment and T believe that the irth of July will be celebrated in the future along safer and ?r lines. Irhe bulletins that we have issued to the public admonishing a to examine their stovepipes and chimneys have resulted in falling oft* of defective flue and stovepipe fires to a very great •nt and while all the bulletins we have issued have been the ns of reducing fires the three T have mentioned have brought it the most noticeable results. Section 5 of the State Fire Commission law provides "that it ohall be unlawful for any person to store any combustible or explosive material in any building or upon any premises which is dangerous to the safety of said building or premises and the «une is so situated as to endanger other buildings or property and the same is declared to be a nuisance." Owing to the preva - lent use of the gasoline engine and automobile nearly every merchant (other than the dry goods merchant) were storing and selling gasoline in large quantities in the congested parts of tiiwn without any pretense of safe-guarding either themselves, their customers or neighbors from having either their property or life destroyed by a flre or explosion by reason of the careless storing and handling of gasoline. After having witnessed the burning of a small barn in which was stored a 50-gallon can of gasoline and having my hair and ears singed while over 50 feet away from it and witnessing the entire flre fighting forces of the city of Lincoln endeavoring to extinguish that flre, solilo- </seg>
            <seg id="p011">STATE FIBE COMMISSION 11 quizing on what would be the result if a fire of this kind would occur in the smaller towns out over the state who are not equipped with as adequate fire extinguishing apparatus as Lin - coln, I at once issued an order to all dealers and storers of gasoline in the congested jmrts of town to provide themselves with a safe underground storage system where the gasoline could be run into the tank through a pipe and pumped out with a pump. With but few exceptions the dealers in gasoline have cheerfully carried out the order to bury it in a safe underground storage system and I am pleased to inform you that at least three-fourths of the gasoline now being handled by retail merchants is being stored in underground tanks which reduces the possibility of a flre or explosion from that source to the minimum and if the State Fire Commissioner will follow up this work during the next two years every dealer in the state will be storing their gasoline in a like manner. I have prepared four sample ordinances and distributed them in every town in the state; one providing for the handling and storing of gasoline as above mentioned; one prohibiting the burning of rubbish and trash upon streets and alleys, and pro - viding for a brick, stone or concrete furnace for paper, trash and rubbish to be burned in; one to prohibit the nailing and pasting of inflammable signs upon buildings and fences within the corporate .limits of cities and villages; one providing for a building and chimney inspector for the city or village. Quite a number of the cities and villages have passed and are enforcing these ordinances and they are proving very beneficial to those that have passed them, and I hope that an active campaign will be maintained along these lines until every city and village in the state has adopted them. Nebraska is not an old state, yet, owing to the rapid and experimental growth of a great many of the cities and villages and on account of a lack of funds to build more substantial buildings, during the years past a number of the older buildings have become badly dilapidated and dangerous from a flre stand - point. Wherever we have found this class of buildings, if they could be put in reasonably safe condition, we have ordered them </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 FOI-RTH ANNUAL REPOKT repaired, but where they were not worth repairing and could not be made reasonably safe we have ordered them removed, not. however, until the interested parties had had due notice and an Maple iipj&gt;ortiinity given them to be heard, and in a large number &lt;&gt;f cases the owners have passed sentence on their own buildings and removed them without further process. There has not been an appeal taken in any of these cases, and we have issued over 500 orders during the past year for the removal and repairing of old buildings. There has been over 5,0(KI buildings inspected in over ISt towns in the state during the past year; unsafe con - ditions have been made safer and the citizens generally have Int-n informed on the subject of fire dangers and the inspectors have Im^-ii welcome visitors in every town that they have operated in. The public have wakened up to the fact that their work means the preservation of life and proj&gt;erty and the prevention of flii-s that are caused by the accumulation of rubbish, trash, inflammable material arid defective electric wiring. At the request of the mayors, chairmen of town hoards and ritv ami village councils we have appointed and commissioned twiui.vhix special deputy inspectors in the same number of town*. Their work has been of great benefit to these towns and it is to lie regretted that more towns do not avail themselves of this opportunity to have a resident inspector clothed with all tin- authority that a State Inspector has to have constant watch the conditions in the town. It is inexpensive but very effectual, and I hope that in the coming years every city and village will avail themselves of this opportunity to have per pefnal care exercised over their town by a competent com ■ lied special deputy inspector. After having had two years of experience with the present st;iTe fire commission law I have found that in order to get the best results without any added expense the law should lie amended so that instead of having one deputy to assist the chief deputy and two inspectors to do the inspecting all three should be deputies and all clothed with the same authority so that, in ease occasion required it. they could do the work of a deputy. A deputy can inspect but an inspector cannot act as a deputy. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 and there are times when a fire occurs in the locality in which an inspector is working but owing to the fact that he has no authority to investigate a suspicious fire it is necessary to send the deputy, and at times it is a physical impossibility to do so. as suspicious flres seem to go in cycles, and with only one deputy it is hard to do the work justice and investigate the fire as soon as it should be. There was another omission in the law when it was passed. There was no provision made for service on the non-resident owner of old and dilapidated buildings. If the owner of the building lives in the state service can be had upon him and he is compelled to abide by the decision of the commissioner, but where the owner lives outside of the state, as the law now is, he can inflict an undue hazard upon his neighbor without let or hindrance as there is no provision made in the law for service by publication or otherwise. I would recommend as the first amendment to the law that every appointee in the fire commis - sion office be made a deputy clothed with all the power of a deputy ; that the law provide that service can be had by publica - tion for three weeks in a paper published in the city, village or county where the property is located, and that in case the owner failed, refused or neglected to obey the order of the commissioner that the commissioner would have the authority to have the building or other nuisance removed and the expense be charged up against the property and collected the same as taxes. There is another very important change that should be made in the law and that is the reducing of the penalty for maintain - ing a nuisance. The maintaining of a nuisance under the law is considered a misdemeanor, yet the law provides that the maximum fine may be $500. This takes the case out of the jurisdiction of a justice of the peace, and in towns other than county seat towns makes it necessary to go to the county Mat to commence proceedings and makes the law very inoperative. This maximum fine should be reduced to bring the case within the jurisdiction of a justice of the peace. One hundred dollars would be just as effectual as $500. Tt is not so much the amount of the fine and punishment that is meted out to the violator of law as it is to establish the fart that punishment is certain. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 There is altogether too many suspicious aud incendiary fires occurring in this state and the root of the evil is &lt;&gt;rcriti*urance. It is a fact that the friction between a large-sized insurance policy and a poor building and a depreciated stock of goods is the cause of 99 per cent of the incendiar-y fires that have occurred in this state since I have been in this office. This is not in accord - ance with the wishes of the insurance companies. They and their companies and the public all have to suffer by reason of this condition. A dishonest man cannot be made honest by legislation but there ought to be some law passed that would in some way, somehow (but I do not know how), to prevent the agent and insured from placing a fictitious value upon property and then writing the insurance for more than the property is worth. Until this can be accomplished there will t&gt;e plenty of work for deputy fire commissioners to investigate suspicions fires, for if the fire is a legitimate one the fact that it is overinsured casts reflection upon the insured l&gt;e he ever so innocent and causes an investigation to be made which otherwise would not have been. This fact also causes the legitimate insurer to pay a higher rate than he otherwise would have to because insurance companies have to fortify themselves against this liability by charging a sufficient rate to pay their losses. During the past year we h:tve investigated over fifty incen - diary fires but owing to the n-iture of the crime and the circum - stances surrounding them it is the hardest crime to detect that we know of. It is :• 11 act of due deliberation : parties, engaging in it play the game an they would the game of checkers; they take into consideration the authorities move before they make theirs and in ntost instances they see to it that all damaging evidence goes up in smoke and the most prevalent defense is an alibi and they usually have friends th-it are willing to supply this alibi. Dsjrtasj the war we have taken thousands of pages of testimony; we have apprehended and convicted four for the crime; two h ve nccived long tern sentences and are in the penitentiary; two were given immunity for turning state's evi - dence; two were paroled for the minimum term of the sentence; there is now three out on t »- 1 II awaiting trial and we have two </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 cases that will undoubtedly result in conviction after trial is had. This branch of the work in this department is a very unpleasant duty, but we have used our very best efforts in apprehending the guilty parties and have taken every precaution not to cast any reflection upon the suspected parties until we had sufficient evi - dence to, in our judgment, bring about a conviction. During the past year there have been 1,234 fires reported to this office. Last year there were 1,348 reported. The value of the buildings that were on fire was $11,373,284.38, but the total fire loss on these buildings was only 1869,068.40, or about 7} per cent of the value of the buildings. The value of the contents was $6,168,397.54 and the total loss to contents was only $1,314,556.93, or only 21$ per cent of the total value of the contents. The difference between the value of the buildings and contents and the damage caused by fire is $15,358,056.59 and the paid and volunteer firemen of this state should be given credit for the saving of this vast amount of wealth, to say nothing about property that would have been destroyed that was contingent thereto. Who can place an estimate upon the value of this great army of men who have banded themselves together for the sole purpose of protecting the lives and property of the people of the several towns in which they are located. These men are ever ready to respond to the call of duty, no matter what the conditions of the weather are. they are ready to risk their health and their lives to preserve the lives and property of others with no hope ■of reward other than the consciousness of having done something to make the lives and property of others safer. I wish it were possible for me to impress upon the minds of the public the necessity of a more substantial appreciation of the services of the volunteer firemen. In too many instances their organisation and work is not appreciated. They are not given adequate apparatus* to work with or a suitable place in which to store their apparatus and hold their meetings. The laws of this state should .be amended so that it would permit cities and villages to levy enough taxes to furnish the necessary equipment and build the necessary buildings to equip these men with the very latest improved fire fighting apparatus and buildings in which to store </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 KOUBTH ANNUAL REPORT it and hold their meetings. There should be sufficient revenue provided to remunerate the volunteer firemen not only for the time actually expended in this work but for damage to their clothing, and in case of injury to provide for their care until they recover, and in case of death to in a reasonable degree protect those who were dependent upon them for a living. One of the pleasant memories of my acts when in the senate is that I lent my influence and vote to bring about the double shift of firemen in the city of Omaha, and I wish it were possible for the other cities in this state who have a paid fire department to provide themselves with a double shift so that the men connected with the department might be given an opportunity to be with their families and enjoy the associations of home life; and I hope that some member of the coming session of the legislature will intro - duce a bill and cause a law to be placed upon the statute books that will place the same restriction upon cities, compelling men in their employ to work an unreasonable number of hours with - out being given an opportunity to enjoy the pleasures that are accorded the citizens in other walks of life, as is now placed upon citizens and corporations who have men in their employ. Some may say if these men do not like their job they can quit and let some one else take it. That would not change the right and wrong of the principle if some one else did take it, the injustice applies just as much to the one as the other. "Right wrongs no one;" it may cost something, but it is worth what it cost to be right, and those who are receiving right treatment are actuated with an earnest desire to repay with their very best possible in conclusion, I desire to thank you, Governor, for appointing to a position that has made it possible for me to become ciated with the people of this state who are interested in the ervation of the lives and property of the people, and who 1 to appreciate the individual responsibility that is resting i them to carry on the work when their attention is called B desire to express my thanks to all of the appointees in this rtment who have labored faithfully to bring about the very </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 STATE FIRE COMMISSION best results possible. I believe that they, as well as myself, bate felt the responsibility of their positions and hare enjoyed the work of spreading the gospel of fire prevention to every part of the state and assisting in bringing about practices that will make thf lives and property of the people safer. Very truly yours, C. A. Randall, Chief Deputy Fire CommiatUmer. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT COMPARATIVE TABLES. The following tables show the value of buildings and contents and the amount of damage caused from fire for the years 1910, 1911 and 1912: 1910. Value of buildings 17,661,175.00 Value of contents 5,718,159.00 Insurance on buildings 4,753,628.00 Insurance on contents 3,847,690.00 Loss to buildings 1,097,403.00 Lom to contents 1,083,655.00 1911. Value of buildings 18,687,414.00 Value of contents 8,067,817.00 Insurance on buildings 5,795,901.50 Insurance on contents 5,289,890.75 Lom to buildings 1,017,211.65 Lom to contents 760,911.65 1912. Value of buildings 111,373,284.38 Value of contents 6,168,397.54 Insurance on buildings .• 4,918,340.00 Insurance on contents 3,809,970.00 Lom to buildings 869,068.40 Lom to contents 1,314,556.93 Total value of property on fire during the three years $47,676,246.92 Total loss of property by fire during the three years 6,142,806.63 Total amount of property saved from destruction by fire $41,533,440.29 The firemen of the state are entitled to credit for saving this enormous amount of property from total destruction </seg>
            <seg id="p019">8TATE FIRE COM MISSION 19 "For the purpose of maintaining the Fire Commission Depart- A. Jm - . . ment every flre insurance company doing business in Nebraska (except Farmers Mutual) must pay to the State Treasurer annually three-eighths of one per cent on the gross fire premiums • J_i_ «_ XT _•__■ mm mm mm . . . * written in Nebraska, after deducting cancellations and rein- surance." In compliance with this law the following companies have paid the amounts set opposite their names: Aachen &amp; Munich Fire Insurance Co 117.11 Aetna Fire Insurance Co., of Hartford 288.56 Agricultural Fire Insurance Co 65.95 American Fire Insurance Co 173.36 American Central Fire Insurance Co 39.74 A tliiR Fire Assurance Co 21.03 Boston Fire Insurance Co 22.45 British- American Fire Assurance Co 29.20 Buffalo Commercial Fire Insurance Co 16.92 Buffalo German Fire Insurance Co 27.89 &lt; 'alumet Fire Insurance Co 11.52 i 'aledonian Fire Insurance Co 60.39 Camden Fire Insurance Co 17.03 Central National Fire Insurance Co 10.29 ( itizens Fire Insurance Co 30.28 &lt; ity of New York Fire Insurance 0t 13.00 &lt; 'nmmercial T'nion Fire Insurance Co., of London.... 139.89 • onimercial Union Fire Insurance Co.. of New York. . 11.46 Commonwealth Fire Insurance Co 28.70 ( 'oneordia Fire Insurance Co 53.26 Continental Fire Insurance Co 405.23 Connecticut Fire Insurance Co 292.98 Dubnque Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co 32.78 Empire Citv Fire Insurance Co 14.93 Equitable Fire Insurance Co 11.46 Farmers &amp; Merchants Fire Insurance Co., of Lincoln. . 337.46 Farmers Insurance Co.. of Cedar Rapids, Iowa 9.63 Fidelity Phenix Fire Insurance Co 612.28 Fire Association of Philadelphia 118.37 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Fireman's Insurance Co 190.89 Fireman's Fund Insurance Co 48.71 Franklin Fire Insurance Co 45.32 German Alliance Fire Insurance Co 12.65 German-American Fire Insurance Co MJt nania Fire Insurance Co 115.55 Girard Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co :\C&gt;.2K Glens Falls Fire Insurance Co 166.92 Hamburg-Bremen Fire Insurance Co 37.02 Hanover Fire Insurance Co 102.70 Hartford Fire Insurance Co 521 .."&gt;."&gt; Home Fire Insurance Co 748.80 Imperial Fire Insurance Co 27..'W Insurance Company of North America 170.86 Insurance Company of State of Pennsylvania 68.08 Jefferson Fire Insurance Co 7.1."i Law, Union &amp; Bock Fire Insurance Co 2.Y02 Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe Ins. Co., of England 367.19 Liverpool &amp; London &amp; Globe Ins Co., of New York 14.05 London Assurance Corporation 1 6.99 London &amp; Lancashire Fire Insurance Co 23.70 Mechanics Fire Insurance Co 18.16 Mechanics &amp; Traders Insurance Co 8.50 Mercantile Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co *v94 Michigan Commercial Fire Insurance Co 23.36 Millers Mutual Fire Insurance Ass'n 17.80 Millers National Fire Insurance Co BUI Milwaukee Mechanics Fire Insurance Co 127 .."7 National Ben-Franklin 19.15 National Fire Insurance Co 1,384.70 National Union Fire Insurance Co 128.43 New Hampshire Fire Insurance Co 81.38 Niagara Fire Insurance Co 47.62 North British &amp; Mercantile Fire Insurance Co 206.88 North River Fire Insurance Co Kfl Northern Assurance Co 80.34 Northwestern Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co 23.84 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Norwich Union Fire Insurance Society $51.*&gt;4 &lt; &gt;lil Colony Fire Insurance Co 10.0S Orient Fire Insurance Co ttJI Palatine Fire Insurance Co Pelican Fire Insurance Co 7.59 Pennsylvania Fire Insurance Co 85.55 People's National Fire Insurance Co Hull Plm-nix Fire Insurance Co., of Hartford 196.24 Phu-nix Assurance Co., of London 44.07 Providence Washington Insurance Co Prussian National Fire Insurance Co 39.60 Qwea Insurance Co., of America 155.09 Reliance Fire Insurance Co 64.31 Rhode Island Fire Insurance Co l-'i.Sl Rochester German Fire Insurance Co 63.70 Royal Fire Insurance Co., of Liverpool, England 184.29 Bojal Exchange Assurance Co., of London, England. . 19.50 Scottish Union &amp; National Fire Insurance Co -'.'!.." 1 Security Fire Insurance Co 60.68 Sovereign Fire Insurance Co 16.13 Springfield Fire &amp; Marine 556.98 State Fire Insurance Co., of Omaha, Nebr 232.0") St. Paul Fire &amp; Marine Insurance Co 378.07 Sun Fire Insurance Co MLH Svea Fire Insurance Co 17.31 Western Insurance Co., of Pittsborg, Pa 3.25 Western Assurance Co., of Toronto, Canada 42. 70 \\ c stchester Fire Insurance Co 64.00 Williamsbnrg City Fire Insurance Co 115.09 Union Fire Insurance Co., of Lincoln, Nebr 162.10 Dwel ling-House Mutual Fire Insurance Co. of Nebr. . 9.30 Mutual Protective Association of Nebraska 27.00 Nebraska Hardware Mutual Ins. Co 116.17 Nebraska Lumbermen's Mutual Ins. Ass'n 22.62 Platte Mutual Fire Insurance Co.. of Nebraska 4.07 Retail Merchants Mutual Fire Ins. Co., of Nebraska. . 4.33 Total 111,351 .55 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT RKCEIPTS. Amount paid into the Suite Treasury by the insurance companies during 1912 $11,351.56 Balance on hand December 31. 1911 3,096.17 Total cash on hand December 31, 1911 $14,447.72 EXPENDITURES. Salaries .$7,875.49 Transportation 769.55 I expenses 1,183.10 I.iv. tv 71.45 Stni t . ar tickets 47.00 Telephone and telegraph 143.10 Postage stamps 494.00 Kxj&gt;ress 75.66 Office supplies and printing 1,301.85 Multigraph printing machine 312.75 Stenographers' fees 108.45 Witness fees 1.70 Sheriff fees 13.85 Kodak pictures of dilapidated buildings. . . . 59.48 Fire chiefs fees 307.80 Newspapers for extra copies 21.55 Extra office help 42.00 Total expenses $12,828.78 Balance on hand December 20. 1912 1,618.94 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">8TATB FIBB COM MISSION 23 The following table shows the number and location of fires occurring in Nebraska from December 31, 1911, to December 20, Towns. Counties. of fires. Ayr Adams 1 Alda Hall 1 Arapahoe Furnaa "1 Alexandria Thayer 1 Allen Dixon - Anselmo Cnster « Ainsworth Brown 10 Alma Harlan 3 Ashton Pherman 1 Ashland Saunders rt Aurora Hamilton 5 Auburn Nemaha 1 Albion Boone 3 Bancroft Cuming 3 Beaver City Furnas 1 Belvidere Thaver 1 Bellevue Sarpy 2 Beatrice Gage 2 Benkelman Dundy 1 Blair Washington 8 Bradshaw York 2 Blue Hill Webster 3 Broken Bow Custer 8 Burchard Pawnee 1 Bayard Morrill 1 Battle Creek Madison 1 Bruno Butler 1 Campbell Franklin 2 Clarkson Colfax 1 Clarks Merrick 1 Cambridge Furnas 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 &lt; "ook Johnson 1 Clay Center Clay 1 Concord Dixon 3 Carleton Thayer 1 C«dar Bluffs Kaunders 2 Cedar Rapids Boone 1 Central City Merrick 3 Chadron Dawes 2 •-&gt; Cmlbertson Hitchcock 1 Crett? Saline •&gt; College View r^ancaster \ Colnmbus Platte 10 Cowid Dawson 2 Crawford Dawes 3 Chester Thayer 1 Dalton Cheyenne 1 Dundee Douglas 5 David City Butler 1 ,1 Decatnr Burt 1 De Witt Saline 2 Deshler Thayer 1 l&gt;e Soto Washington . 1 Dnnbax Otoe | Dannebrog Howard 1 El*'*" Perkins 1 Elm Creek Buffalo 2 Emerson Dixon 1 Faii-bury TefTerson 8 Florence Douglas | ■&gt; Fi " e J (iage I Falls City Richardson 3 Fairmont Fillmore 5 Prank!ln Franklin 4 Fairfleld day 3 FrieaA Saline 3 Fremont Dodge 5 Ora ft°n Fillmore 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">STATB FIRE i OM MISSION ■ Geneva Fillmore 3 Genoa Nance 5 Giltner Hatmilton 1 Gibbon Buffalo 1 Gothenburg Dawson '. 3 Gordon Sheridan 3 Goehner (near) Seward 1 Grand Island Hall 29 Grant Perkins I Hampton Hamilton 1 Hastings Adams 11 Havelock Lancaster 2 Hardy Nuckolls 1 Hebron Thaver . . '. 3 Hildreth Franklin 1 Howell Colfax 1 Hooper Dodge 2 Humphrey Platte 1 Hordville Merrick 1 Homer Dakota 4 Holbrook Furnas 1 Indianola Red Willow 2 •Tuniata Adams 2 Kenesaw Adams 3 Kearney Buffalo 2 Kennard Washington 1 Kilgore Cherry 1 Lexington Dawaon 4 Lyons Burt 1 Lynch Boyd 1 Lincoln Lancaster 124 Maxwell Lincoln 1 McCook Red Willow 9 Merna Custex 1 Madrid Perkins 1 Mitchell Scott's Bluff 5 Mead Saunders 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 rOURTH ANNUAL REPORT Nebraska City Otoe 17 Norfolk Madison 1 North Bend Dodge 1 North Platte Lincoln 1« Xemaha Nemaha 2 Neligh Antelope 4 Naponee Franklin 3 Ogalalla Keith 2 Oconto Ouster 1 Ong Clay 1 O'Neill Holt 6 Overton Dawson 5 Otceola Polk 2 Omaha Douglas 557 Phillips Hamilton 1 Palmer Merrick 3 Pierce Pierce 3 Petersburg Boone 1 Plainview Pierce 1 Platte Center Platte 1 Plattsmouth Pass 8 Ravenna Buffalo 1 Randolph Cedar 3 Rushville Sheridan t Rnskin Xuckolls 2 R«d Clond Webster 2 Rockville Sherman 1 Roc* Lancaster 1 Sidney Cheyenne 1 Button Clay 4 Sjneaae Otoe I Spencer Boyd 2 Srottabluff Scott's Bluff 2 Schnyler Colfax 3 8ewa *d Seward 4 Shelby Polk 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">STATE KIBE COMMISSION 27 Polk 2 Surprise . . Hutler 1 Sarpy 4 Kngfield ton .. Kuffalo * Fillmore 1 Shickley Spalding &lt;rTeeley 1 Lincoln • Sutherland South Omaha Tecumseh .. . I &gt;onglas 92 Johnson 2 Upland TTehling Madison 3 Butler 4 Franklin t Dodge 1 University Place T&gt;ancaster S Seward 1 SE Douglas 1 Sannders 3 Weeping Water ■2 Pass Saline 1 Wisner Ornning 1 West Union Wymore . . . Ouster 1 p iage S Wilsonville Wakefleld WaltMll . Furnas 1 Dixon 2 Thnrston Waterloo Douglas I Saline 2 Wavne 8 York 9 Total 1.234 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 CAUSES OF FIRES. Adjoining fires &gt;o Ashes, hot, falling on floors or carelessly thrown JJ Bonfires 20 Boys smoking 5 Boys smoking corn silk 1 Carelessness | &lt; 'hininey, caught from or burning out 2 &lt; "himney, spark from 9l' &lt; 'himney stop left out 9 « and le. caught from I Candle, curtain blown against 1 Candle, testing eggs with 1 Christmas tree, candles on. •&gt; Candy boiling over 1 Cylinder box 1 Chemicals exploding 1 Coal oil, lighting fire with 5 Cigar, tramp with 1 Cigar or cigarette carelessly thrown '_'.'{ Drunken man, set by 1 Furnace pipe, caught from 1 Electric wiring, defective IT Electric or gas iron left standing on cloth 1 Fireworks, sun shining through window on 1 Fireworks 21 Furnace pipe, caught from 1 Furnace, defective 4 Furnace, hot or overheated, setting flre to kindling 1 Furnace, hot or overheated, rubbish too near to 4 Furnace, caught from 15 Films in moving picture show 4 Flues, defective 67 Fireplace, joist too close in floor 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 STATE FIRE COMMISSION Fumigating 5 Gasoline stove, filling, when lighted ."i Gasoline stove 58 Gasoline explosion or ignition 23 Gasoline used in cleaning clothing, plumes, etc 15 Gasoline taking fire in automobile 10 Gasoline can, lamp held near 1 Gasoline coffee urn, caught fire while filling same 1 Gasoline flat-iron ignited 1 Gasoline lamp or lighting plant 5 Gasoline thrown in stove 1 Gasoline used in cleaning bed 3 Gasoline engine 1 Gas jet, curtain caught from Gas heater for bath tub 1 Gas burner, mantel falling from 3 Gas stove, caught from 3 Gas leaking 5 Grease taking fire on stove or boiling over 4 Glue pot, flre under, left burning 1 Incubator caught from 5 Incendiary Kerosene, pouring, on kitchen floor 1 Lamp exploded 13 Lamp, curtain from 3 Lamp, caught from Lamp in clothes closet 1 Lamp dropped on floor Lightning 1 '■' Locomotive, sparks from 20 Match, sparks from, in clothes closet 15 Match, lighting, to see to get coal oil 1 Matches, burglars with 2 Matches, carelessness with 31 Matches and children 60 Matches and mice 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 FOCRTH ANNUAL REPORT 8TATE FIRE COMMI88ION Matches in pocket 1 Match, spark flying from same 10 Oil house, going into, with lighted torch 1 Oil store 8 Oil stove exploded 6 Oil stove too close to wall 1 Oil ignition 9 Oil heating on stove to put on floor 1 Painter's torch, caught from. •&gt; 1'ipe, lighted, in coat pocket 1 Rubbish, caught from • Rubbish, burning same carelessly 14 Refuse in waste paper basket 1 Stove, child attempting to light flre in 1 Stove, overheated 31 &gt;&gt;, no protection underneath 12 e, caught from paper, wood or rubbish too close to. ... 11 e too close to wall or woodwork 16 Stove, sparks from 1 Stovepipe, caught from 8 ••pipe hole, paper over, or filled with rags, etc 13 Ktmepipe through ceiling, roof or wood partition 9 pipe, igniting grease rubbed on stove or stovepipe... 1 &gt;■. explosion water back 2 • ■. clothing hanging too near 3 Store, electric 1 Smoking meat in coop 1 Steam plant 1 Steam pipe, hot 1 ■II boiler set on cement base burned through to floor. . 1 Suspicions 4-4 Sparks from castings in moulding room 1 Spontaneous combustion 27 Tramps, set by 3 Unknown 191 Water pipes and tanks, thawing out 23 Total 1.234 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>