<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00009.00001">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00009.00001</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
		       <sourceDesc>
		          <bibl>
		             <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1901</title>
		             <date value="1901">1901</date>
		          </bibl>
		       </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-12</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-07</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
ANNUAL REPORT 

OF THE 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S 
ASSOCIATION 

FOR THE YEAR 1901. 

Prepared by S. C. BASSETT 

Secretary 
Nebraska Dairymen's Association </seg>




            <seg id="p003">
Secretary's Office, Gibbon, Neb., February i, 1902. ) 
His Excellency, Ezra P. Savage, Governor of Nebraska : 

Kir: — In compliance with the law in this case made and prod, 
I hereby transmit the annual report of the Nebraska 
rymen's Association for the year 1901. 

Respectfully yours, </seg>



            <seg id="p005">
TABLE OF CONTENTS. 


List of Members o 

Program ! , 

General Remarks 15 

Address of Welcome 16 

Landed Homes 

20 

Report of Treasurer 26 

Report of Directors 27 

The Probable Limits of Alfalfa Culture in Nebraska 28 

The Cornstalk Disease 32 

Discussion 36 

The Hand Separators for Creamery Patron-; 40 

Discussion .5 
The Possibilities to be Attained in Dairying in Nebraska. . 51 

51 

Discussion 5^ 

The Care of Hand Separator Cream 59 

Results of Model Dairy Breed Test 73 

Latest Methods in the Treatment of Milk Fever 79 

Progress of Practical Dairying in Central Nebraska and 
Value of Alfalfa to the Dairymen B] 

Discussion S6 

Some Hand Separator Problems 92 

Report of Committee on Nominations 98 

List of Creameries in Nebraska 99 

List of Cheese Factories toi </seg>



            <seg id="p007">
E. S. Smvei.y, Lincoln 

President', 

T. S. Pexton, Neligh 

Vice- President 

Secretary and Treasurer S. C. Hassktt, Gibbon 

DIRECTORS. 

C. A. Clarke, 
J. C. Merrill, 

3. R. Stouffer, 
J. K. HONEYWELL, 

St » £*• 1 R A rii </seg>


            <seg id="p009">
LIST OF MEMBERS. 

HONORARY LIFE MEMBERS. 

J. H. Monrad Winnetka, 111. 

C. L. Gahrilson New Hampton, Iowa 

W. D. Hoard Fort Atkinson, Wis. 

A. C. Tupper Osage, Iowa 

J. G. Lumbard Omaha, Neb. 

LIFE MEMBERS. 

Elijah Allen Omaha, Neb. 

D. P. Ashburn Gibbon, " 

Mrs. D. P. Ashburn Gibbon, " 

J. Dixon Avery . . . .Corner Clark and Water Sts., Chicago, 111. 

L. J. Babcock Gibbon, Neb. 

S. C Bassett Gibbon, " 

Bates, Wilcox &amp; Streeter Omaha, " 

John Baumer Omaha, " 

J. M. Bayley Gibbon, " 

G. W. Bemis Sutton, " 

J. .M. Bennett Hebron. " 

R. Bingham &amp; Co Omaha, « 

Henry Bolin Omaha, " 

W. L. Bovee Gibbon, " 

W. H. Buck Gibbon, « 

W. A. Carpenter York, " 

H. C. Carter, Box 241, Buffalo, NY. 

H. C. Clark Omaha, Neb. 

L. S. Coffin Ft. Dodge, Iowa 

T. D. Curtis 899 North Clark St., Chicago 

I. N. Davis Milford, Mass. 

J. H. Davis Gibbon, Neb. 

J. B. Dinsmore Sutton, " 

W. C. Drury Gibbon, « 

a </seg>


            <seg id="p010">
10 

Henry Eicke Omaha, Neb, 

Frank T. Emerson 422 South Fifth St., Omaha, " 

Germantown Cooperative Creamery Ass'n. Germantown, 

H. Fieldgrove Shelton, " 

Chas. Finch Omaha, " 

T. J. Fisher Gibbon, " 

H. F. Flint Gibbon, » 

F. S. Fulmer Gibbon, " 

R. \V. Furnas Brownville, 

H. C. Glissman Box 685, Omaha, " 

E. W. Gunther Albion, " 

J. \V. Harrel 1 Gibbon, - 

Chr. Hansen 17 Dearborn St., Chicago, 111 

E. J. Hainer Aurora, Neb 

Louis Heimrod Omaha, " 

E. F. Howe Fairmont, " 

S. W. Hoyt 3-5 Harrison St., New York, N. Y 

W. H. Ijams Omaha, Neb 

P. E. Her Omaha, " 

A. Jones Madison, " 

H. B. Kelley Inez, « 

Thomas Kirk Gibbon, " 

Kirschbraun &amp; Sons Omaha, " 

S. H. Knight 218 La Salle St., Chicago, 111 

F. W. Lessentin Omaha, Neb 

Otto Magenau Fremont, •' 

Markel &amp; Swobe Omaha, " 

Martyn Bros Omaha, '« 

J. C. Merrill Sutton, " 

Max Meyer ' Omaha, " 

Dr. Geo. L. Miller Omaha, " 

Frank E. Moores Omaha, •• 

W. T. Mount Omaha, « 

M. H. Noble Gibbon, « 

R. O'Keefe Omaha, •• 

Peycke Bros Omaha, " </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
LIST OF MEMBERS, 

11 

Henry Pundt Omaha, Neb. 

Riddell &amp; Riddell Omaha, » 

Allen Root Omaha, " 

J. H. Rushton Fairmont, " 

Geo. Schroeder &amp; Co Omaha, " 

Louis Schroeder Omaha, " 

Wm. Sievers Omaha, " 

Geo. H. Silvernail Gibbon, " 

J. G. Southwick Bennett, " 

Chr. Specht Omaha, " 

J. T. Stanhope Dubuque, Iowa 

B. R. Stouffer South Omaha, Neb. 

Otto Stuben Omaha, " 

Wm. Sutton Table Rock, " 

Julius Treitschke Omaha, " 

Troxell &amp; Williams Omaha, " 

D. H. Wheeler Omaha, " 

D. H. Wheeler, Jr Omaha, « 

W. G. Whittnore Valley, » 

Whitney &amp; Co Omaha, " 

Wideman &amp; Co Omaha, " 

H. H. Wing Ithaca, N. Y 

Ed. Whittig Omaha, Neb 

C. E. Woodruff Grand Island, « 

T. G. Furgason Beaver Crossing, " 

Haskell &amp; Bosworth Beatrice, " 

F. H. Vaughan Fremont, " 

J. J. King West Point, " 

Chas. W. Stevenson Fremont, " 

ANNUAL MEMBERS. 

John Weitzel Malcolm, Neb 

Mrs. B. F. Marshall York, " 

J. K. Honeywell Lincoln, " 

August Leader Papillion, " 

L. C. Norton Ft. Crook, " </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

12 


F. L. Lewis York, 


A. L&gt;. Lewis Seward, 


R. A. Carpenter Ong, 

M 

St. Paul Creamery St. Paul, 

« 

J. H. Blodgett Beatrice, 

M 

P. F. Wullschlegger Leigh, 

M 

H. C. Young Lincoln, 

" 

C. A . Clark Ravenna, 

M 

S. Pierce W oodlawn, 


W. M. Bucknum Omaha, care Star Union Line 

Morris Friend Lincoln, Neb. 

Led Frederick Crete, 


A. F. Hartwell ... Inavale, 


Elmer E. Place Albion, 

•• 

Guy^ Klumb Osceola 

" 

&gt; 

Geo. E. Everett Osceola 

M 

i 

Hansi n &amp; Templin Archer, 

M 

Ernest Samzelius Schuyler, 

" 

Herbert Craven Pierce, 

« 

Arcadia Cooperative Creamery Co Arcadia, 

¦» 

F. S. Pexlon Neligh, 

.' 

O. Muckle Riverton, 

.. 

E. N. Mussleman Blue Hill 

M 

» 

Frank T. Uehling Hooper, 

" 

A. M. Priest Lincoln 

" 

i 

A. L Haecker Lincoln, 

N 

Ed. Lytle Omaha 

« 

&gt; 

F. W. Graham Omaha, 

» 

L. Kelley Omaha, " 

F. M. Housh Neligh, 

«' 

Geo. M. Weaver Omaha, 

•&lt; 

P. H. Kennedy 308 N. 2 2d St., Omaha, 

» 

L. J. Nelson 2719 Dewey St., Omaha, - 

Charles Harding Omaha, 

« 

t d Housh Lincoln 

« </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
LIST OF MEMBERS. 

13 

in. • i\i Xj fii 1 1 \ ¦ • • • ¦•¦¦••••¦••• . • ¦•»¦¦¦ •••••¦¦¦• y » n tf lj. 

J. A. Conover Kearney, " 

B. A. Lagen Star Union Line, Omaha, " 

W. J. Colvin Omaha, " 

J. C. McDonald Sutton, " 

E. A. Burnett Lincoln, " 

L. D. Siillson York, » 

E. S. Snively Lincoln, " 

E. Sudendorf Elgin, Ills. 

Perry L. Johnson Prairie Creek, Ind. 

Carl Hammerberg Hanson, S. D. 

M. G. Koepsell Wilson,Minn. 

E. J. Henry 14 N. Clark St., Chicago, Ills. 

W. D. Colly er 210 S. Water St., Chicago, " 

F. A. Leighton New Hampton, Iowa 

J. F. Schlappi Lincoln, Neb. 

Ralph E. Woods Gibbon, " 

T. L. Lyon State University, Lincoln, " 

Dr. W. A. Thomas Lincoln, " 

Dr. J. H. Gain U. S. Experiment Station, Lincoln, " 

Genesee Salt Co Mercantile Exchange, New York, N.Y. 

Vermont Farm Machine Co Bellows Falls, Vt. 

The Heller Merz Co 22 Cliff St., New York, N. Y. </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL MEETING OF THE 
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

HELD AT LINCOLN, JANUARY 22-24th, I902. 

PROGRAM. 

WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 22. 

7:30 p. m. — Music 

Address of President. 

Music. 

Address Governor E. P. Savage 

Music. 

"The American Girl in the Home" 

Mrs. Bertha D. Laws, Minnesota 

Music. 

¦Note: — The music for this session will be furnished by the 
Hard Kimball Conservatory of Music, State University). 

THURSDAY, JANUARY 23. 

9:30 a. m. — Report of Secretary and Treasurer. 
"The Hand Separator for Creamery Patrons". 

F. M. Housh, Neligh 

"The Corn Stalk Disease" 

Dr. W. A. Thomas, State Veterinarian 

"Landed Homes" M. F. Greely, South Dakota 

2 130 p. m. — "The Care of Hand Separator Cream" 

F. A. Leighton, Iowa 

"Alfalfa Culture" Prof. T. L. Lyon, State University 

re Possibilities to be Obtained in Nebraska Dairying, and 
What is Most Needed to Attain Them" 

R. K. Emily, Kearney </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
15 

PROGRAM. 

FRIDAY, JANUARY 24. 

tA. M. — "The Advancement Made in the Treatment of 
Milk Fever" Dr. J. H. Gain, U. S. Experiment Station 

"The Sanitary Dairy and Certified Milk for City Customers" 

Charles F. Schwager, Omaha 

"Merits of the Grout Bill" 

tp. m. — "Practical Dairying in Central Nebraska and Value 
of AKalfa to the Dairymen" Ralph E. Woods, Gibbon 

"Some Hand Separator Problems" 

Prof. A. L. Haecker, State University 

GENERAL REMARKS. 

The package of butter awarded the sweepstakes prize will 
become the property of the association. 

Kl sessions will be held either in the chapel or a lecture 
of the State University. 

Kr. J. W. Brewster will furnish a complete stenographic 
rt of the proceedings. 

Mr. W. D. Collyer, U. S. Inspector of Dairy Exports, will 
judge the dairy exhibits. 

Dairy supply men, desiring to exhibit their goods, will find 
ample space provided for that purpose. There will be no session 
on Thursday evening, giving traveling men an opportunity to 
get acquainted and do business with their customers. 

The railroads of the state have granted a one and one-third 
rate from all points in the state to persons attending the meeting 
pf the Dairymen's Association or other meetings held in Lincoln 
the week beginning January 20, 1902. Consult your local 
agent in regard to these rates. 

Kincoln has ample hotel accommodations, at rates ranging 
1 $1.00 per day and upwards, according to the accommo)ns 
furnished. 

The Lindell Hotel will be headquarters for the Association. 

All sessions are open and free. All are invited. Everyone is 
welcome. </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
PROCEEDINGS OF THE ANNUAL MEETING. 

FIRST SESSION — CHAPEL STATE UNIVERSITY WEDNESDAY EVEN- 

ING, JANUARY 22, I902. 

tr. E. S. Snively, vice-president, called the meeting to order, 
in absence of the president, presided as chairman. 

The Chairman: We will now listen to the address of welcome 
by Chancellor Andrews. (Applause.) 

ADDRESS OF WELCOME BY CHANCELLOR 
ANDREWS. 

Mr. Chairman, Members of the Dairymeii's Association and 

Ladies and Gentlemen : 

I am just discovering why I am called upon to make so many 
addresses here this winter. It is because I make them short 
and give hearty welcome. We have the grand felicity in this 
university of seeing, at least once a year, a great many of our 
constituents. We are altogether glad to have you come. I 
hope that the meetings of this association will be eminently sue- 

On the general subject of dairying I defer to the creamerymen 
and the cheesemen as being better judges. I simply wish 
to speak to you this evening on a topic which I hope will be 
taken up by some one in your sessions, the value of beautiful 
grass on the plains of Nebraska which make the best butter in 
the world. It is a pity that any of this should go to waste, for 
it is a very important factor in the life of man. I cannot prove 
from my experience that Nebraska grass makes better butter 
than any other fodder, but I do know that butter which comes 
from the University farm is the most delicious that I ever ate in 
my life. It is possible and of course desirable that our people 
should take pains and have as good butter as is made anywhere. 

(The stenographic report of this convention was made by J. W. Brewster, Wilber 
N.br.) </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

17 

This peculiarity of the succulent grasses on the plains should be 
attended to, and this contribution to the life of mankind put to 
the best possible use. We were forcibly reminded last evening, 
and our agricultural people have been reminded of it again and 
again, that there is a vast difference between land mining and 
agiiculture. A great deal of the so-called agriculture in the 
west has been nothing in the world but land mining. Owners 
have dug into the mine and found a great deal of wealth. They 
have taken it out in the shape of wheat, corn and such things, 
but have put nothing back into the mine and in a comparatively 
few years have robbed it of its riches. By this means farms 
that ought to be rich and inexhaustible have at last become 
impoverished and incapable of raising anything. We do not 
want Nebraska to come to any such end as that. 

Be want to put back something into the land to keep up its 
ity while we take out of it as much as we can. 

From all I can learn there is no industry in which this 
double result of getting wealth from the land and at the same 
time keeping the land intact, getting wealth from the land and 
still leaving infinite wealth in the land — a transforming industry — 
is so sure as in dairying. There is always a market for good 
butter. Mankind has always had a taste for fatness. In the 
pre-historic age men were accustomed to break the bones of 
animals to get the marrow out. The civilized man not only 
wants much fat, but he wants that fat in the very best form. 
Good fat, men will buy and consume. There will always be a 
market for this product. I don't believe the plains of Nebraska 
can grow Buffalo grass enough to make all the butter that is 
wanted. It will not be possible to overstock the market of 
America with first-class butter. 

Recently in California I was informed that it was at certain 
seasons of the year in that state difficult to get good butter. 
The hotels try, but they succeed only by sending some distance 
for it. It would seem that there ought to be no difficulty in the 
great state of California in getting good butter, but the people 
have not turned their attention to dairying. </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
18 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

The time is past when you can get good results farming in 
the old ruts as your father and grandfather farmed and had success. 
You now have to ask Mother Nature for secrets. How 
willing she is to give them up if rightly asked! That is what 
scientific agriculture in every one of its departments means. It 
will be required more and more in our colleges that the young 
men who go out shall have asked her, or be able to ask her, and 
those who ask in a nice way, with patience and scientifically, she 
will answer with riches. Mother Nature loves to give, but she 
loves to be asked with propriefy. Ho ask and continue to ask 
and you shall not only be answered, but you shall be filled. I 
thank you for the honor of permission to address you. I bid 
you welcome to this hall, and to everything that we have. 
(Applause.) 

Eiairman: 1 think the Chancellor has struck the key note, 
time was when the dairy business was looked down on. I 
the pleasure of introducing to you Acting Governor 
e, who will now address the association. 

ADDRESS OF LIEUT. GOVERNOR STEELE. 

Ladies ami Gentlemen and Members of the Nebraska Dairymen'' 's 

Association : 

I 'he chairman was slightly mistaken when he said that I 
ild address you. I am sorry the governor is not here. I 
w that you are disappointed. While I act in some capacias 
governor, I do not in the way of addressing an intelligent 
ience like this. However, I want to say in behalf of the 
e that you are thrice welcome. The Chancellor said "you 
welcome." I say that you are thrice welcome. If there is 
society that is more welcome than another, it is the 
&gt;raska Dairymen's Association. 

The governor has been expected home daily. I do not think 
he had a thought of being away at this time, and I know that he 
will regret not having the opportunity of talking to you. 

I will not attempt to make an address. I went to the gov- </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

19 

ernor's office and tried to rind an outline of what he was going 
to saj-, but I could not find anything. So I will thank you for 
your attention ;ind close. 

I he Chairman: The Hon. J. G. Lumbard is with us and 
kindiy consented to favor us with a selection, which I know 
will all greatly enjoy. 

J. G. Lumbard: Mr. Chairman and Ladies and Gentlemen: 

Before responding to vour invitation for a song, I hope 1 may 
have permission to acknowledge the great pleasure I have in 
being once more in the midst of my friends of Nebraska. These 
conventions are rather unconventional with me, and 1 have 
always great pleasure in meeting you. I have already been this 
winter to -the Iowa and Illinois conventions. I am always 
"treated" well over there, but no better than in Nebraska. (Applause.) 


I will now attempt to sing "I Fear No Foe." (Applause.) 

As an encore Mr. Lumbard sang "Maggie," to the great 
delight of his hearers. In fact, this song as sung by Mr. Lumbard 
always gives great pleasure to those who hear him, no 
matter how manv times it mav have been heard before. 

Elie chairman then introduced Mrs. Bertha D. Laws, who 
essed the association on the subject of "The American Girl 
e Home." 

The secretary regrets exceedingly that the able and eloquent 
address by Mrs. Laws can not be published in this report. 

The following letter will explain the reason: 

¦ Appleton, Minn., March 6th, 1902. 
C. Bassett, Esq., 

Lincoln, Nebraska. 

Dear Sir: Yours of March 5th, requesting me to furnish 
you a copy of mv address before the Dairymen's Association, 
has been received. In reply I beg to be excused from the work 
of making out such a copy — it entails a great deal of work and 
I am very busy, also very tired af'er the rush of last institute 
circuit. As my talk was a general one awct of no specific value </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

20 

as a reference, I cannot see that its absence will detract any 
from your report. 

t thank you most heartily, for the kind things you say coning 
my work in your state; your people are exceptionally 
&gt;itable and encouraging, I think, and their kindness has 
;d greatly to the pleasure of the winter. 

I am, very sincerely, yours, 

Bertha Dahl Laws, 

Appleton, Minn. 

LANDED HOMES. 

HON. M. F. GREELEY, GARY, SOUTH DAK. 

I am asked by those in charge of this meeting to contribute 
a few thoughts to-night upon the farm home — its present standing, 
prospects and possibilities. A more suitable subject it 
seems to me, could hardly be found for a meeting of this kind, 
and I esteem it a great honor to be asked to address such a 
body of men upon a theme so near my heart and life. It is 
possible, though, that one who his whole life has breathed only 
the free atmosphere of the country and the country home, may 
be prejudiced in its favor, and not be an impartial judge in estimating 
its importance. But be the landed home what it may, 
to own one in America will soon mean something — mean just 
what it does to own one in the old country, and to be caught 
without one will mean no less. 

POPULATION INCRKASKS, ACRES DO NOT 

To the amazement of many, who, because they have never 
seen it, could not believe it possible in this country, our population 
has already caught up with our land, and, though our land 
cannot increase, population will, and competition cruel and unrelenting, 
in the overcrowded trades and professions, is already 
making itself felt in every thickly settled community in our 
land. Thousands from the overcrowded centers of Europe are 
still flocking to our shores; but in place of whole states to give </seg>

            <seg id="p021">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

21 

Eas formerly, every surplus acre is now needed for our own 
owing cities, and from the very lands we not long ago 
away, children, growing up upon them, are loudly clamorr 
acres upon which to build their homes. 

THE FARM HOME A SELF-SUPPORTING HOME. 

In addition to this, the fact is dawning upon our people that 
there is a wide difference between a self-supporting home and 
one that must be supported from the outside. This difference 
is often plainly apparent when the one who has built the home 
is by death, or other cause, unable to longer look after it. The 
farm home, then, if properly stocked and managed, will continue 
not only to yield shelter, but a generous support to those who 
have trusted it, while those who are left in the city home, however 
beautiful or costly its surroundings, unless they have an 
outside income for its support, must frequently go out from it 
just when they most need its shelter and protection. 

EDUCATION NECESSARY IN SUCCESSFUL AGRICULTURE. 

Again, our people are beginning to realize as never before 
(and we think that the farmers' institutes have done much to 
bring this about) that it means something to be a farmer, requiring 
as bright young men, as thorough preparation, and as steady 
adherence to, as any other profession, and one as much to be 
proud of. We are learning, and learning fast, that it is no accident 
that, with but a road or a wire fence between them, one 
piece of land is clean and productive, covered with splendid 
crops, stock and farm buildings, tidy and inviting in appearance, 
a home fit for a king, while the other is run out and weedy, 
unstocked and uncared for, unsightly and unprofitable. No; 
these conditions are not accidents. There are reasons for them, 
and what those reasons are, and how best to meet them, is the 
paramount issue in the advanced and advancing agriculture of 
to-day. Nor should it be forgotten that the farm home isn't 
what it used to be. Farmers are waking up from their Rip 
Van Winkle sleep of years to find that, because a home is located 
upon land is no reason why it cannot be as tidy as any other </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

22 

home, as tastefully furnished, and as well supplied with the best 
food, the best of reading, and the best of everything. 

A SUCCESS WHICH IS NOT SUCCESSFUL. 

To be sure, we still, now and then, find a farmer, with thousands 
in the bank, the best of stock and the latest machinery 
crowding his barns and sheds, with his home destitute of a 
single beautiful thing, and his overworked wife bending over the 
wash-tub, as of old, without even a clothes-wringer to help her 
tired hands. But such places are not homes, and, thank heaven ! 
they are fast disappearing before the institutes, the farm paper 
and the agricultural school. Drudgery, too, is being largely 
eliminated from the farm and farm home. How to save labor 
in every possible way is now considered a legitimate part of 
farm management, and it is no longer looked upon as an indication 
of good farming to have wife and children up at four in the 
morning and choring until ten at night. There is something 
wrong with the farmer, and not with the farm, when he has to 
do this in order to get a living out of it. The man in debt 
should, of course, work hard, and, perhaps for long hours, till it 
is paid for, and the whole family should, and will, lend a hand to 
make sure the common roof; but there is no excuse for forehanded 
farmers over-working themselves or their families, and 
the farmer who works his children so hard that they will go 
anywhere and into anything rather than stay on the land, has 
committed little less than a crime. The writer knows something 
of this side of farm life. Since he has been of age he has 
owned land of his own, and for many years before that time 
worked more or less upon the farms of others. Some of these 
places were merely untidy slave pens, from which the overworked 
children fled like leaves before the storm at the first 
opportunity.; 

THE RIGHT FARM HOME LIFE. 

KHhers, and still more prosperous ones, not only found time 
the wife to enjoy life, and also the children, but even their 
:d man found so much of the good and beautiful of life there </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

23 

that he still looks back to the time spent with them as among 
the brightest hours of his life. Children from such homes forever 
remember and look back to them as sacred places, and 
recall the tender words and happy hours spent there through all 
the changing years. The time was when a woman would as 
soon marry a Zulu as a farmer, and she was not to blame for it, 
but to-day, with the changed methods and conditions, our 
brightest girls think twice before they refuse the hand of the 
well-informed, tidy and thrifty owner of an up-to-date landed 
home. The best magazines and papers now find their way to 
the tables of our leading farmers, and many of the Minnesota 
farm homes to-day (the writer knows this from personal observation) 
compare favorably with the finest homes of our villages 
and cities, and these kind of homes are rapidly increasing. The 
telephone and rural mail delivery are doing much to eliminate 
the isolation which, to some, was an objection to farm life. 

COUNTRY LIFE NATURALLY TENDS TO DEVELOP THE INDIVIDUAL. 

However much may be urged against this isolation by those 
who prefer to spend thek" days in crowded cities, there is one 
thing which cannot be discounted by all the advantages of city 
life; it develops and brings out the individuality of a boy or a 
girl, and makes them strong in all that goes to make a vigorous, 
self-reliant personality. For this reason, more than any other, 
the leaders in all great undertakings almost invariably come 
from the farm, backwoods or frontier, or all three. A tree 
cannot do its best in a swamp, crowded and pressed to fit those 
around it; a boy cannot grow up a masterful individual with 
all signs of originality crowded and jammed out of him. Pressed 
and dressed by rule and custom, trained to think as others 
think, he becomes too frequently a piece of a mob — sometimes a 
very small piece — and how his hair shall be parted or tripimed, 
his mustache curled or his necktie worn, almost before he knows 
it, looms up before his narrow vision as the great issue of life. 
The boy and girl on an up-to-date farm must think, and think 
hard. They not only have plenty to think about, but they have </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
24 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

time by themselves to think it in. They are where their mental 
and moral, as well as their physical, muscle is given ample exercise. 
It is not dwarfed by having others to do or think for 
them. The long evenings about the home table are also good 
educators. Their minds are free to work their best there; not 
rilled with the slush and folderol of the street, its gossips and 
excitements. Boys, you have every opportunity and every 
advantage. If there is anything in you, because you are on the 
farm is no sign it cannot come out. Keep good company, read 
good, strong, clean reading, be proud of your calling, and make 
the most of it and of yourselves, and the world will find a place 
for you. I recall how, years ago, I thought the farm boy could 
never hope to become grr at or famous — that only the boy with 
the advantages which city life and schools brought him might 
hope to leave an honored name. About this time with money 
earned on the farm, I set out to visit the City of Washington. 

A LESSON FROM WASHINGTON CITY. 

The day was just breaking when the train rolled out from the 
Virginia hills along the historic Potomac. Mount Vernon, with 
its glorious memories, lay to the right; Arlington, with our 
sleeping heroes, to the left. As the train moved slowly over the 
long bridge, across the river, the first rays of the rising sun 
were gilding the great dome of the capitol, and tipping with a 
blaze of glory, 550 feet above the city bearing his name, the 
marble shaft to the memory of Washington.. I felt that now I 
was to at least stand where great men had stood — that I was 
nearing sacred ground. Leaving the train I passed the spot 
where Garfield fell, and at the foot of the great stone steps 
leading to the capitol I saw, in enduring bronze, a slave, with 
upturned face, the shackles falling from his wrists, and looking 
up I saw the great emancipator looking down. I passed on into 
the rotunda of the capitol, and there, on guard, around that 
great room stood, in granite, marble and bronze, the greatest 
statesmen, warriors and thinkers our country has known. 
Curious to know how many, if any, of the guardians of the </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

25 

Ion's fame had toiled as I had toiled, I took the names of 
n all home with me, and there learned that they had nearly 
spent their boyhood where mine had been spent — had in 
r early manhood surmounted all the obstacles and hardis 
sturdy farm boys know. 

bekcher's estimate of the country home. 

How true, as Beecher once said, "The furrow across the old 
field is oftener than any other the way to true greatness." So, 
do not be ashamed, boys, of the callouses upon your hands or the 
tan upon your cheeks. They are but the badges of future 
greatness. A Lincoln, a Garheld, and a host of others, leaders 
in commerce, war and state, have worn them before you. And, 
above all, let nothing keep you from owning a landed home, 
the place where such boys are made — a piece of the country 
over which floats the flag you love. To stand upon such a 
spot, and realize that it is yours — yours down to the center of 
the earth beneath, and up to the stars above — puts into one's 
being a feeling of true independence, true manhood and true 
Americanism that no other possession can. To make and own 
such a home is a noble and sufficient ambition, one worthy of 
the greatest efforts of the brightest boys of our land. So, if 
you have a piece of land, young man, stick to it; and, if you 
have not, stick to it till you have a piece to stick to. Let nothing 
deter you from this determination. Let it be a cloud by day, 
a pillar of fire by night to your highest ambition, till this 
brightest dream of American boyhood shall bring to you its 
glorious fulfilment. 

SECOND SESSION THURSDAY MORNING, JANUARY 23, IQO2. 
Vice-president Snively called the association to order, and 

stated that first on the program would be the report of the secretary 
and treasurer. </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
26 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

REPORT OF TREASURER 

To the Officers and Members of the Nebraska Dairymen 's Asso~ 

ciation : 

I herewith submit the following report as treasurer of this. 

association, for the year ending December 31, 1901. 

S. C. Bassett, Treasurer. 

RECEIPTS. 


Dec. 18. Cash on hand $ 89&gt; 

Dec. 21. Annual membership fees 43 50 

Dec. 21. State appropriation, balance 1899-1900 170 82 

1901. 

Jan. 21. Cash for premium fund, Genesee Salt Co 10 00- 

Jan. 21. Cash for premium fund, Worcester Salt Co 10 00- 

June 5. State appropriation : 145 00- 

Oct. 22. State appropriation 286 00 

Oct. 22. Cash for premium fund, Genesee Salt Co 10 00&gt; 

Due S. C. Bassett. treasurer 25 27 

ToUl • 701 48. 

EXPENDITURES. 

G. L. McKay, expenses to deliver an address t 20 00 

8. C. Bassett, salary Oct. 1, 1900, to Oct. 1, 1901 300 00- 

Gibbon Gazette, printing 13 65 

Premiums awarded 72 40- 

Wescott &amp; Ferris, stenographers 45 00 

S. W. Perrine, incidentals 1 10&gt; 

W. A. Rodgers. P. \l., postage stamps 30 75 

R. A. St. John, printing and stationery 5 50 

Lindell Hotel, entertainment of officers and guests 27 85. 

Fremont Tribune, printing reports, express and freight 166 15 

S. C. Bassett, secretary, incidentals 19 08 

Total t 7014ft 

STATE APPROPRIATION. 

Amount appropriated for two years, beginning April 1st, 1901 t 2000 00- 

Amount expended Dec. 31, 1901 431 00 

Balance in hands of state treasurer t 1569 Oft 

Accompanying this report is the following report of the </seg>


            <seg id="p027">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

27 

To the Nebraska Dairymen's Association : 

Ke have, this day, examined the accounts of the secretary 
treasurer for the year ending December 31st, 1901, and 
them correct, and also find that the expenditures were 
mate and are approved by the board of directors. 

Dated Lincoln, Nebraska, Jan. 22, 1902. 

Signed, B. R. Stouffkr, 

J. K. Honeywell, 

C. A. Clark, 

Directors. 

On motion, the report of the treasurer with accompanying 
vouchers, was referred to an auditing committee consisting of 
Messrs. Clark, Carpenter and Merrill, who later reported that 
they had examined the report and vouchers, found the same to 
be correct, and on motion, their report was received and 

Ihairmes: The next paper for our consideration this 
ning, has been written by Prof. D. Lyon of our university, 
which, in his absence, Prof. Davisson has kindly consented </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
28 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

THE PROBABLE LIMITS OF ALFALFA CULTURE 

IN NEBRASKA. 

PROF. LVON. 

The history of alfalfa is of interest to us in so far as it indicates' 
what may be expected of it in our efforts to extend its culture 
in this country, and especially in this state. DeCandolle 
says of it in his Origin of Cultivated Plants: "It has been found 
wild, with every appearance of an indigenous plant, in several 
provinces of Anatolia, to the south of the Caucasus, in several 
parts of Persia, in Afghanistan, in Baluchistan, and in Kashmir." 
Of the climatic conditions of these countries Cram's Atlas makes 
the following statements: Baluchistan disputes with Aden the 
record of being the hottest land in Asia. The dryness and 
withering nature of the heat, and occasional stand storms add 
much to its discomforts. Afghanistan depends largely upon 
irrigation for the high state of cultivation which is thus possible. 
The eastern portion is covered by shifting sands, swept during 
the summer by deadly hot winds, and during the winter by excessive 
cold at night. Persia is an elevated table-land. The plains 
which cover three-fourths of the country are most unattractive, 
and in the eastern and central regions practically without water. 

This picture of the early home of alfalfa is not that of a very 
attractive region of country, or of one in which we would 
expect to find plants growipg in great luxuriance. It is doubtto 
the poverty of its early life that it owes its ability to 
fl mrish so luxuriantly when brought into more favorable condi- 

These countries to which it is indigenous lie between the 30th 
and 40th degrees of latitude, are extremely hot in summer and 
sometimes severely cold in winter, but always dry. In following 
the migrations of alfalfa we find it used most largely in 
regions of this same general character, and even growing most 
luxuriantly in warm, dry regions when water has been supplied 
by irrigation or from a subsurface source. 

After being adopted by man as a cultivated plant it was </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

29 

carried to southern Europe, where it has continued in use as a 
forage crop up to the present time. It thus seems to have 
established itself in a humid region, although in a comparatively 
warm one. Its cultivation has, however, never been successfully 
carried into northern, humid Europe nor into the British 

It was carried into Mexico by the Spaniards shortly after 
their conquest of that country, later into Chili, and from there 
into California, where it was first grown in 1853. The ancestral 
stock of our alfalfa had, therefore, been grown for several 
hundred years in the humid climate of southern Europe, which 
does not seem to have curtailed its deep-rooting properties. 
Greater difficulty has been encountered in attempting to extend 
its culture northward than in changing it from a moist to a dry 
climate, but it has been found able to withstand a much greater 
degree of cold in a dry climate and soil than in a humid region 
or wet soil. The northward migration of the alfalfa plant has 
been going on for a long time in this country, and within the 
past ten years the movement in this state has been very apparent. 
It is entirely within the bounds of reason to predict that 
the time will come when alfalfa will be grown in all portions of 
this state where the supply of soil moisture is sufficient. As 
with winter wheat, the effect of growing alfalfa in northern 
regions is to make the plants grown from the northern-raised 
seed more hardy. An experiment the writer conducted here 
illustrates this clearly. In the spring of i&gt;§97 alfalfa seed grown 
in a number of states was planted on contiguous plots of land. 
The seed was from Arizona, Colorado, California, Utah and 
Kansas. A good stand was obtained on all plots and there was 
no apparent difference during 1897 and 1898. The severe 
winter of 1898-99 produced an astonishing difference in the 
stand in the spring of 1899. The alfalfa from Arizona and 
California was nearly wiped out, while that from the more 
northern states suffered much less. The importance of using 
northern-grown seed in a northern region is emphasized by this 
demonstration, and the value of northern-grown seed in more </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
30 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

southern regions during exceptional cold spells is suggested. It 
indicates moreover a considerable degree of adaptability on the 
part of the plant, to which attention has already been drawn. 
The fact that the comparatively short space of time that alfalfa 
has been grown east of California should have been sufficient to 
produce a strain of such markedly greater hardiness encourages 
the attempt to develop this quality still further. 

Still further encouragement is given to this by the recent 
introduction into this country of Turkestan alfalfa, a variety 
unquestionably hardier than that grown here, but whose origin 
is identical and whose hardiness has been developed by its 
environment. Turkestan, the country from which this variety 
was imported, and in which it has doubtless been grown for a 
long time, lies somewhat farther north than the region to which 
alfalfa is indigenous, and has a more severe winter climate. In 
adapting itself to that climate the plant has become more resistant 
to cold, and thus comes to us having already acquired the 
qualities that it would take years to develop in our attempts lo 
push it northward. 

iurkestan alfalfa planted at the Nebraska Experiment station 
898 on land contiguous to that on which the alfalfa from 
Tent states was planted did not winterkill in the slightest 
ree during the severe winter of 1898-99. All the native 
Ifa suffered more or less during that year. At the South 
:ota station in 1900, with a temperature of 40 0 below zero, 
common alfalfa was killed, while the Turkestan alfalfa was 
ijured. 

There is good reason to believe that in regions of limited rainfall 
and light soil the northern limit of alfalfa culture can be 
carried beyond Nebraska. Already it is a well-established crop 
in counties as far north as Stanton, Madison and Antelope. It 
is being grown to some extenfin the south central part of South 
Dakota. Mr. J. M. Greene, of Chamberlain, S. D., reports a 
good stand that he seeded in 1896. When seed of the Turkestan 
variety is put on the market there will be a rapid growth of the 
acreage in northern Nebraska. </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

31 

If there is to be no thermal limit to alfalfa culture in Nebraska, 
is there to be one marked by an excess or deficiency of moisture? 
This is a rather more difficult question to answer. Excessive 
moisture in the soil seems to be injurious to the plant if the cold 
be very severe or if the soil be a compact one, so that the 
spaces between the particles are completely filled with water, 
thus excluding the air for long periods. It is possible that 
either one or both of these conditions may interfere with alfalfa 
culture in parts of extreme eastern Nebraska, but the land in 
other portions of the state that would thus be unfit for alfalfa 
culture is very limited. 

A more serious consideration is the possibility of certain 
elevated lands having too small a supply of moisture to raise 
profitable crops. Alfalfa, like other vegetation, requires moisture 
to grow. It differs from most plants in its ability to procure 
much larger quantities of what moisture there is in the soil. 
The result is that larger quantities of water pass through the 
plant, contributing to its growth, instead of evaporating from 
the surface of the soil. Plant growth, within certain limits, is 
nearly proportional to the amount of water taken up by the plant. 
The most economical utilization of soil water is to pass it through 
a plant. Alfalfa once established is, therefore, growth alone 
considered, the most profitable plant for dry soils. As the 
supply of moisture decreases, the yields of the crop decrease. 
A point is thus reached where it is no longer profitable to raise 
alfalfa for hay. The possibilities of its use for pasturage 
beyond that point have not yet been demonstrated. 

I hat these possibilities are great must be readily realized 
considering the habits of growth of the plant. Its 
ity to lie dormant through long periods of drouth, and to 
ime growth when moisture is available, recommend it 
ngly for the uncertain rainfall of the semi-arid region. On 
other hand, its inability to survive close pasturing is a disadtage, 
and will preclude its use where unrestricted pasturage 
ermitted. It lacks also some of the advantages for pasturage 
the native grasses possess, and can never properly take </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

32 

their place on the range. The greater feed producing power 
of alfalfa will, however, as the land becomes more valuable, as 
pastures are fenced and their use controlled, make it an indispensable 
adjunct to the native grasses in the production of dairy 
products, and of live stock in every portion of Nebraska. 

E airman: The next number on our program this morning 
he Corn Stalk Disease," by Dr. W. A. Thomas, and I now 
the pleasure of introducing to you Dr. Thomas, who will 
:ss you. 

THE CORNSTALK DISEASE. 

Dr. W. A. Thomas, state veterinarian, read the following 
paper on the cornstalk disease: 

I'hen your secretary, Mr. Bassett, asked me to prepare a 
x for this meeting, and then selected the theme, he must 
: had in mind pure food for our domestic animals. The 
is annually in our domestic animals in Nebraska aggregate 
ncalculable sum, still we have no disease or malady that 
s an important part in this great destruction that cannot be 
ded by our stockmen and farmers when they are instructed 
these catastrophes may be suppressed and averted. 

Eiere are a number of diseases that cf.usc small losses from 
to time, but fortunately the number of diseases that so 
rially swell the per cent of loss is small. 

Eackleg has caused great losses in our young cattle, but 
problem is practically settled and our stockmen are preng 
this disease by vaccination. 

tange or itch, a parasitic disease, is making such inroads 
it is doing considerable damage in our range cattle, but hog 
;ra and cornstalk disease are the two maladies that are 
g work of large figures. The losses of cattle and horses 
Jebraska this winter are colossal. We learn of them in 
y part of the state where corn grows. 

For years investigations have been made to determine what </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

33 

is on or in the stalks or in the stalk-fields that causes death to so 
many animals. 

We will glance at a few of the ideas that have been presented. 
Dr. Billings believed the cause of this trouble to be a 
germ. His remedy for relief was drainage. Nebraska 
repeatedly and unintentionally tried drainage, and the more 
thorough the drainage the greater the severity of the disease. 

Suppose the disease is caused by a germ upon the grpwing 
corn, then it seems it must take all summer, all fall and a part 
of the winter for it to assume a malignant form, for the disease 
is not produced when green corn or cured fodder is fed, or 
does the germ begin its growth after the plant has ripened and 
dried? Such a bacterium that could withstand all the various 
inclemencies of the weather and develop would be lusty enough 
to be discovered. Some germs are not destroyed by various 
exposures of fall and winter, but such conditions are not conducive 
to their growth. 

If the disease was caused by a germ our bacteriologists 
would have discovered them long ago. The reward would warrant 
the research. Only last fall I was asked by a representative 
of the largest chemical manufactories in the United States: 
" What is this cornstalk disease?" You see what he had in mind. 
If the cause of this trouble were a bacterium he would go out 
to your place and borrow a few of them, take them to his laboratory, 
soup feed them until he had them just right, then he would 
return to your place and say : "My friend, I have something 
that will interest you. I have the greatest thing on earth. Wiih 
it I vaccinate your cattle and horses and make perfect Bawmills 
of them. They can just go out there and chew up those old 
cornstalks with perfect immunity, and never lose a hoof. It's 
all nonsense for you to pay so much money for that corn-binder, 
then work so hard when you get it. This will cost you only 15 
cents a dose and save your animals." 

Btie cost of a single dose for each animal in Nebraska would 
ver $375,000. 

We frequently hear Dr. Mays, of the Kansas Experiment </seg>


 
            <seg id="p034">
34 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION. 

station, quoted as stating that the cause of death is saltpeter 
(potassium nitrate). A study of his bulletin of 1896, No. 58, 
which he calls a preliminary investigation, shows that he is 
oscillating and undetermined. He discusses the germ and smut 
theories, but is inclined to believe that the trouble is caused by 
indigestion or a poison. He says that the only poisonous substance 
so far found is saltpeter. He makes a statement very similar 
to one I made in my recent paper on the subject, viz: "That 
the leaves have blown away and, exposed to the sun, rain and 
wind, the most that remains is the coarse, dry, weatherbeaten 
and undigestible cornstalks." Yet he states, "In making 
post-mortem, I cannot find cause of death to be from indigestion." 
Again he says: "It is noticed that the disease seldom 
occurs where the stalks are small and fine." In another place 
he says: "Most prevalent in years when there has been a large 
corn crop." We have in Nebraska this year the small stalks 
and the large ones, and animals are dying on both alike. 

Ia recent article from Dr. Mayo, on "Cerebritis, or Staggers 
orses," he states that the disease is the result of feeding 
my, mouldy corn, either when it is fed as a grain ration or 
n obtained by pasturing in stalkfields. His treatment is 
live food, such as thin bran mishes and iodide of potash in 
drachm doses once daily. He also states that mould} or 
my corn does not seem to be injurious to other animals. 

I'he crop of smut was very abundant this last year. A few 
still speculating as to its toxic qualities. Experiments have 
1 repeatedly made by the profession and farmers which 
wr that the fungus is not poisonous in mid-winter. The funis 
made up of a mass of finely divided spores enclosed in a 
f fragile capsule which bursts before the corn is ripe so that 
toxin, if it ever possessed any, is soon lost in the exposure. 

Governor Dockery, of Missouri, requested Dr. Netherton to 
investigate loss of cattle from poison on stalks. Dr. Netherton 
reports that it is caused by decomposition of nubbins upon which 
worms had previously feasted. 

The nightshade has been accused of killing the animals, but </seg>

            <seg id="p035">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

35 

in a recent statement J. J. Edgerton, of the experiment station 
of Iowa, says that the nightshade is not poisonous. 

¦'hen what are the cornstalks, what is the disease, and what 
remedy t 

The cornstalks are a dead, mummified mass of cellulose or 
wood. They are the remains of a crop you have produced, and 
when it was ready for harvest you let it stand in the field and 

PDrnstalk disease is not contagious or infectious. 1 sometimes 
it were so; then by our state law we would be compelled 
larantine every cornfield whr re the corn had not been cut 
harvested properly. 

The disease is indigestion, gastroenteric vertigo. Heath is 
produced so suddenly in most cases that the post-mortem shows 
almost no lesions. In a few that have not died so suddenly we 
find congestion and inflammation of the stomach and intestines, 
a fragile condition of the mucosa of the stomachs. The contents 
of the stomach are in a nice, pulpy condition. There is no 
impaciion. The contents of the third stomach or manifold in 
cattle is sometimes in a drv condition, depending upon the 
length of time digestion has been arrested. 

Death is produced by indigestion and a shock or reaction upon 
the nervous system, a club in the stomach. 

The remedy is plain and easy. In its application you are 
¦doubly paid. First, in not losing animals. Second, the reward 
of feeding animals well and taking them through the winter in 
good flesh and growing condition. 

In Nebraska, corn has been crowned king. It is our chief 
crop. It has been raised principally for the ear; but corn is a 
dual purpose plant, and by failing to harvest it at the proper 
time we waste the most valuable forage crop produced in the 
state. When cut and cured at a proper time, corn- fodder is, as 
Secretary Wilson said to me last summer, equal in feeding value, 
ton for ton, to timothy and clover. 

rere are many who would not harvest the fodder to save 
animals; however, we are just arriving at a time when a </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
36 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

combination or force of circumstances, such as the high price of 
land and forage, and the machinery that is being manufactured 
and pushed onto the farm for harvesting will bring about the 
result. The corn-binder has come to stay, and as their number 
and work increases, the stalk disease will vanish. The shredder 
is a matter of convenience. In the use of it I wish to make a 
suggestion of warning. The cornstalk will become hard and 
woody by allowing it to carry the ear to the point of maturity, 
so that when it is torn up by the shredder and mixed with the 
leaves and husks you may compel the animal to eat the stalk 
which is not a proper food. 

Cornstalk disease is a dietetic error, and the cornstalk that 
has stood in the field until its beautiful green face has turned 
black and brown, hard and horny, is a spoiled product. We 
may as well look at it honestly and acknowledge the corn. There 
is no other forage our animals would eat if treated in the same 
manner as the cornstalks. 

Shere is no use guessing what is on the stalks that causes 
ruction — whether a germ, a smut, a little saltpeter, a toxin, 
jrm-eaten leaf or a nubbin. It is the dead product you are 
pelling them to eat and thus starving them to death. 

DISCUSSION. 

tR. Roberts: This paper gives the most light I have yet 
on this subject. In the eastern states we never heard of a 
from cornstalk disease. Why would not it occur there as 
as here? It is only in Kansas, Nebraska and northwestern 
i that we have any trouble with cornstalk disease, while in 
ois it is never heard of. 

Dr. Thomas: In the eastern states, and in Illinois they raise 
a large quantity of good feed, both in hay and grasses, and perhaps 
cattle run on the grass until very late in the fall. As I 
have said, our best farmers here lose very few animals, simply 
because they have plenty of good feed. 

Mr. Whitmore, of Valley, tells a good story of a farmer who </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

37 

Funning a sawmill, and he said to his neighbor one day, "I 
a great way of feeding my cattle. I am mixing sawdust 
cornmeal." 

His neighbor asked "in what proportion do you mix them?" 

Ke said, "I'll tell you, the less sawdust you put in and the 
; cornmeal the better." 

Iiat is just what is being none in this cornstalk troublehave 
taken the cornmeal all out and left them nothing but 
lust. 

iR. Roberts : I have bought cornstalks in the field and turned 
e in them to run, and had nothing to do with them except 
ive them water, and never lost an animal. When I was a 
we fed cornstalks to cattle, just turned them in the field, and 
fed them the stalks, and never did anything except to see 
the cattle had plenty of water, and never lost a head. 

Kr. Thomas: I have made an estimate of losses in cattle 
horses. Valuing cattle at an average of $25.00 per head, 
horses at $50.00 per head, with a 3 per cent loss, the aggrefor 
one year in Nebraska would be over $2,355,000.00. 

Kr. Anderson, of Seward, told me yesterday that the estimate 
ie loss of horses in that county alone this winter was from 
to five hundred. N 

Member: Why would not this take place in all parts of 
Illinois, where they feed exclusively cornstalks? 

Br. Thomas: Do you mean to say that they never lose any 
e over there from this cause? 

Member: I do not hear of any now-a-days. 

tR. Thomas: The man who does not lose any, as a rule, 
plenty of good feed. 

Mr. Ashburn : Mr. Chairman, it seems to me that the time has 
come in Nebraska when we should change our methods and 
adopt the plan the Doctor indicates. Why should the state 
spend large sums of money and the people devote a great deal 
of valuable time in the pursuit of something which we ought not 
to do. It has been stated repeatedly, by Prof. Burnett, that 
one-half of the value of our cornfields is in the roughage; that </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
38 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

a cornstalk properly saved and properly fed has as much feeding 
value as the ears that grew upon the stalk; that if we 
want to increase the income from our farm, we must take 
better care of the fodder from our cornfields. If the increase 
in the income to the farm lies in that direction, why not encourage 
the farmer in that direction? It seems to me that the time 
has come when we ought to work for the better care and the 
better feeding value of our roughage. As the Doctor states, 
there is no doubt but what a large share of the feeding value of 
the cornstalk has been entirely wasted before it gets to the 

i [ember : I think the difference in climatic conditions 
yeen Nebraska and Illinois has some effect upon the feedvalue 
of cornstalks; that is, that the cornstalk has more 
iment in Illinois than in Nebraska. In Nebraska and Kanwhere 
this disease has been more prevalent, the climate in 
fall of the year is much dryer, the cornstalks contain less 
iture, has become more woody in its nature, which very 
erially lessens its feeding value; in fact, makes it well nigh 
gestible. 

fR. Thomas: I would say that a good time to cut the cornis 
when the inside husks begin to turn yellow. If you 
notice the inside husks turn yellow first, and then the ears 
glazed. 

Member: Last fall I run a corn-binder and there was considerable 
argument as to the proper time to cut the stalks. The 
old way of cutting corn was just as it was glazed, dented or 
out of the dough, and some of my neighbors thought I was a 
little off on that. But I run my corn-binder and cut my 
corn until harvest. I told my neighbors that their corn was not 
then worth cutting, and the fodder was not worth saving. Some 
still held to the idea that the stalk was better than it was before 
the frost came. I was asked to bring out this question, but I 
believe with the Doctor that he has stated the right time to cut 
corn-fodder. 

Mr. Bassett: There is another thought in connection with </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 

39 

this matter of the right time to cut the cornstalk. The climatic 
conditions are much different here from what they are id 
Illinois. I have seen the fodder in cornfield here destroyed in 
twenty-four hours. Let one of those hot south winds that sometimes 
sweep over this state, strike a cornfield early in September, 
and in twenty-four hours' time the leaves will begin toblow 
out of the field. All the moisture is dried out and there is 
nothing left but the woody substance. This is more especially 
true as you go west of here. This is one of the things we have 
to think about in the matter of saving the fodder, even where it 
is ready to cut, a delay of twenty-four hours may cause its value 
as a fodder to be lost. I never resided in Illinois, and do not 
know much about the conditions there, except in a general way. 
If you go farther east you will have no trouble in keeping the 
leaves and husks of the corn if you cut up the fodder. In shocking 
the stalks there it is necessary to leave a space in the center 
of the shock so that it will not mould or spoil. But we da 
not need to do that way here. You can make the shock as big 
as you want them, and then the leaves will dry out so that they 
will crumble. That is one of the conditions here when we 
attempt to save our corn-fodder. 

Member: Doctor Thomas, has not the death loss of horses 
been greater this year from cornstalk diseases than heretofore?' 

Dr. Thomas: It does seem so. I account for it in the high 
price of hay and good feed. We had a large amount of green 
feed this fall. When an animal is changed from one feed toanother, 
it should be gradual. The change this fall has been 
sudden — from that of luxurious green feed to dried-up food. 

Mr. Ashburn: I have been surprised to find that horses, 
and cattle that have been in the same field have died from apparently 
the same disease, the symptoms havv. been dissimilar; 
horses of one man running out in the stalks and those of his 
next neigbor being kept up in the stable and having entirely 
different feed have died from apparently the same disease. 

A Member: Last winter we had those conditions in our 
neighborhood. Some animals died running in the stalks, while </seg>


            <seg id="p040">
40 

others died of the same symptoms that had not been running in 
the stalks at all. They acted like they had the blind staggers. 
They would push through obstructions, and fairly walk over 
you. Their eyes seemed to be affected. We lost two colts. 
They were taken up out of the field every night and turned 
loose into the yard, and fed as we feed colts. We went out to 
them one night as there was such a noise as though they were 
kicking, and found that one of them had pushed over a partition 
in the shed. They would get up against the manger or anything 
and push. Two of my neighbors lost some. They 
seemed to have the same symptoms. The symptoms of those 
that were kept up seemed to be the same as those that run in 
the stalks. 

Doctor: It is evident that they had food of the same value 
that produces the blind staggers. 

Question: Would you recommend bleeding, Doctor? 

Doctor: I would not recommend it. By bleeding you take 
away the strength of the animal, and I would not do it. I am 
not prescribing now ; I believe in prevention. The remedy I 
have given you, and you have a good opportunity to ascertain 
whether I am right or not. 

t. Member: The remedy I used was this: I kept them all 
of the stalk fields or I believe I should have lost them all. 

THE HAND SEPARATOR FOR CREAMERY 

PATRONS. 

Kiat it is and its future to the dairymen and creamerymen 
ebraska. 

Let us first notice the dairyman 

Here he is with his herd of ten or twelve cows. He desires 
to make as much as possible out of them. He i.- too far from a 
creamery to haul his milk, and so he looks about him to see 
what is best for him to do. He has for years been milking and 
setting his milk in deep cans until the cream raised; then his 

F. M. HOUSH, NELIGH, NEB </seg>


            <seg id="p041">
41 

K skimmed off the cream, churned the butter, and after a 
t amount of care and labor, it is ready^. Then on market 
they took it to town and sold it at the grocery for a nominal 

Iut they became dissatisfied with so small returns for so much 
i, disagreeable labor. He was able to make 200 pounds of 
er to each cow under the gravity system. At this period of 
experience the hand separator subject is presented to him. 
is told that the hand machine will gain for him from 16 to 30 
cent over his gravity system. Estimating it from the lowest 
1 per cent, which is 16, he was told that there would be a 
1 of 32 pounds of butter to each cow, or a total gain for the 
cows of 384 pounds for one year. This, at 20 cents per 
nd, would be $76.80. 

His query was, would it pay him to pay $125.00 for a separator? 
The answer was, let us see. First, the cost price 
$125.00, interest at 6 per cent on money invested is $7.50 per 
year; yes, there is a repair bill, and the separator will wear out. 
These two things we will have to assume. Let us put the life 
of the separator at ten years, with a repair bill of $3.00 per year. 
(I could bring you plenty of users of separators who have used 
their machines for three or four years, with less than $1.00 
repair bill for the whole time.) But, for argument, we will put 
it at a high figure. $7. 50 interest plus $3.00 repairs, equals 
$10.50 for one year, For ten years the expense would be 
$105.00 plus $125.00, first cost, which would equal $230.00, as 
against the gain of 12 cows for the same length of time. As 
before shown, the gain for one year was $76.80. For the ten 
years it would be $768.00, making a net gain over and above 
what he was already receiving of $538.00. 

tfter much talk and due deliberation, he consented to try a 
irator, for he argues to himself and family (and with truth 
that it is clear out of the question to ship milk for its butter 
alue, and while he was too far from the creamery in his 
ket town to deliver his milk, yet he found that the creamerythere 
would willingly send his wagon for his cream, paying 

4 </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

42 

him as much for his butter-fat in the cream at his door, as he 
could get for his milk delivered at the factory. He understands 
that his cream must be sweet and test not less than 33 per cent. 

Ke has had no experience with the hand separator, but he is 
it is better than the old way, and the one point that struck 
so favorably was having the warm sweet milk to feed to his 
ig stock as soon as the milking and separating was done. 

He goes to work and follows instructions, and is more than 
satisfied with the results, for he finds it even better than he has 
been told. He is pleased to see how easy it is to produce the 
fine article in the condensed form that the creameryman so much 
prizes. He not only found that he was able to secure the fancy 
price, which was from three to five cents more per pound than 
the old way, but also found that he could produce at least 20 
per cent more butter-fat, from the same amount of milk. There 
is no way conceivable of procuring so fine a quality of cream as 
when the centrifugal separation is made immediately after the 
milk is taken from the cow. This lessens the liability to taints 
in the cream over the old process by setting, while the removal 
of filth from it by the action of the machine can hardly be 
appreciated by one never having seen a separator bowl after the 
separation is made. 

IJethinks I hear someone saying, "This might be true with 
machine in the hands of a very careful person; but not so 
h the ordinary dairyman. He would be so slack in caring 
both cream and separator that the fine quality would be lost." 

Now let us contrast this system with the handling of whole 
milk by the ordinary dairyman. If the ordinary dairyman i 
handling milk at all, and can take care of it so that it is fit to be 
taken to the creamery, he certainly can take care of his cream 
especially so when we remember that it is less work to care fo 
the cream than the great bulk of milk, and too when he see 
he gets a better price for a finer product. Almost any of them 
will learn how it is done, for it is the "price" they are all after 

t dairyman, in handling whole milk for a factory, even though 
auls his milk every day to the factory, still there is one milk- </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

43 

ing stands over, allowing the fiberous matter and germs to 
remain and develop for twelve hours or more, which, with the 
hand separator, are eradicated at once. This, together with the 
advantage of the thorough aeration of the milk and cream (centrifugal 
separation being by far the most efficient of all forms of 
aeration) leaves the cream in better condition to start with by 
the use of the hand separator than his milk could possibly be 
without it. 

the dairyman who lives handy to the railroad is all right, but 
let us consider those who live in that part of our state, so 
from the railroad that it is impossible to reach the station 
n enough to ship the cream. 

We have several creameries situated in such places deprived 
of railroad facilities, and where the country is new and sparsely 
settled, to try to run them on the whole milk plan is a failure, 
since it is impossible to drive far enough to secure product 
sufficient to carry on a creamery successfully, while with the 
gravity plan the product is so inferior when it reaches the creameryman 
that he is unable to make an article that will bring anything 
like a fair price on the market. 

|&gt;low with a hand separator in the hands of the patrons, who 
its use are able to produce so much better quality of cream, 
bling the creameryman to produce a much better article for 
ich he can obtain good prices, he in turn is able to give more 
the raw material, which encourages the dairyman to milk 
re, and so the dairy industry is built up. 

I wish to allude again to the old cry against the "ordinary 
dairyman" not being able to handle the hand separator properly. 
Let us look back to the time when the factory machines were 
first brought into use, and see the trouble the butter makers 
had with the separator butter on the market. You old creamerymen 
all remember it well. 

What was the matter? Why, the "ordinary dairyman" did 
not know how, or would not bring milk to the factory in proper 
shape, neither did the factory men understand just how to handle 
the cream in order to produce the fine butter that they are pro- </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S. ASSOCIATION. 

44 

during now, since they have educated the patrons to bring milk 
to the factory right, and they themselves have learned to handle 
the product, it being an entirely new business to all of them. 

IJow if the "ordinary dairyman" could be educated into caring 
the milk properly, it is only another small step lo educate him 
i to take care of the separator and cream from it. I have 
ady stated, and wish to emphasize the statement, that there 
10 way that finer cream can be obtained than by taking the 
c fresh from the cow and putting it through a centrifugal 
arator. 

Io that I believe that if the creameryman wculd give as much 
ntion to educating the dairyman to take care of the hand 
irator cream as has been given to educating him to care for 
whole milk, there could be a finer quality of butter made 
n the hand separator system than from any other system. 

When instructing the dairyman, tell him in order to have fine 
cream, to first set the separator to make 40 per cent cream; 
and above all, tell him to have everything about the separator, 
pails, pans and cans perfectly sweet and clean. When sepaiating, 
catch the cream in a clean can, and when through, cool it 
down until all of the animal heat is out of it. (Setting it in cold 
water is the best way.) 

teave the cream uncovered while cooling down, and if there 
anger of flies or any litter of any kind, tie a piece of dairy 
1 over it. Never mix warm cream with cream that has 
ed down. After it is cool, pour it in with the older cream, 
stir them together thoroughly. Now, if he will follow these 
¦uctions, you can tell him that he will have a cream that can 
hipped 200 miles, or hauled in a wagon twenty miles to a 
mery, and make "extras." 

Right here I would like to give a word of caution to those 
who are placing the hand separator in the hands of the dairyman; 
Do not tell the would-be purchaser that the separator 
need not be washed but twice a week, and that cream from a 
separator is so pure he cannot spoil it, but just dump it in any 
odd place, and it will be good enough for the creameryman any- </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

45 

way. Do not tell him that his separator will last a lifetime, no 
matter how he treats it; just run it any old way. Instead, tell 
him that he has a high-speeded machine, requiring proper care, 
such as having a good, solid, firm foundation, with the separator 
set on it perfectly level. Tell him to u»e the best oil and see 
that the oil properly lubricates the bearings; to keep all the 
bearings free from sand and grit. Show your purchaser just 
how the separator is constructed, how the oil reaches the different 
bearings, how some of the oilers are easily stopped up so the 
oil does not reach the bearings; in fact, tell him all about the 
separator, and if he will heed your instructions, and he has 
bought a good, well-built separator, that is not too highly 
geared, you can tell him that he has a machine that will last a 
lifetime, (if he does not live too long.) 

While, on the other hand, tell him plainly that if he sets his 
separator any old way, or in any place, runs it just as it happens, 
is indifferent to sand and grit on the bearings, in six 
months he will have a good big repair bill on his hands in 
order to make it run at all. 

Now, if the "ordinary dairyman" can not handle the hand 
separator successfully, there must be quite an army of extraordinary 
dairymen among us, for there are over five thousand 
hand separators in our state, at the present time, giving perfect 
satisfaction. 

As we all know, the producer is master of the situation, so 
if our dairymen have come to the conclusion that tlie hand 
separator is the "thing" and demand it, we can see but one 
ultimate for the creameryman, namely, adjust himself to the con- 

DISCUSSION. 

E[r. Roberts: I have a cream separator! and I don't want 
question dropped without some discussion. I have a neighand 
he has some ten or twelve fresh cows this winter and he 
raid the skim-milk will not be fit for his calves. I want to </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
46 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

ask Mr. Housh now, if he advises setting the separator to skim 
cream to the consistency that will test about 40 per cent? 

Er. Housh : It is very desirable to make 40 per cent cream 
u are going to ship or haul it a long distance, but if you are 
g to haul it a short distance it is not necessary to make such 
nse cream. 

Mr. Roberts: We run it from 33 to 38 per cent. 

Mr. Housh: That is practically 40 per cent cream. That 
is very nice cream. I was on a farm until six or seven years 
ago. In regard to the question of feeding calves skim-milk, I 
would rather have Doctor Thomas answer that question. I 
will, however, give some actual experience, if it is of any advantage. 
Some years ago when the hand separator question was 
first sprung, it struck me as being a very logical proposition for 
Antelope county. I was connected with the creamery, and I 
bought a few separators and put them out among the farmers. 
Fifteen days is ordinarily enough in which to feed a calf new 
milk, and then gradually take it away from them; then give 
them the skim-milk, something to take place of the butter-fat; 
that will balance the ration. There is no question but thev will 
do well. It has been demonstrated. Hand separator machines 
have become very popular, and their use is the best way on 
earth to grow calves. I put in the first machine in 1894. 

Br. Roberts: How do you feed a calf to get it in good 
iiion? 

Ilr. Housh: This was in the winter time. We fed the 
es on new milk until they were 15 days old, then gradually 
them on the separator milk and feeding corn meal, dry. 
en the calves were six weeks old we sold them to the butcher 
veal. When the butcher came to get the second batch he 
id me where their mothers were. I told him the mothers 
e in the barn. He said, "I never saw them with their 
hers." I replied that they had never sucked. "What," says 
"you selling me veal that has never sucked?" Yes, 1 said, 
says, "I don't believe you can do it." I asked him how it 
. with the first batch he got; if his customers complained, or </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
47 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

if he had any trouble. He said, "No, everybody was satisfied." 

Question. Do you feed corn meal in the milk? 

Housh : No, sir. I feed the meal dry. However, I prefer 
shelled corn to the meal after the calf gets two months old. 
Corn is better than meal as soon as calves can grind it, because 
they are apt to eat the meal too fast. I have learned from 
experience that a calf can grind corn finer than any animal on 
the farm. They have good grinders. 

Buesiion. How much milk ought the average calf to have; 
t do you consider a proper amount? 

Eoush: When the calf is four weeks old and reasonably 
ig, it ought to have from four to five quarts. As it grows 
r, feed as you would a hog, keep increasing the amount. 
r quarts is a nice feed. Too many people try to feed too 

A Member: I am an advocate of the hand separator. 

Mr. Ashburn: I believe the subject under discussion is one 
of the mos: important we have had before us. I believe many 
men are deterred from going into the dairy business because they 
think they cannot raise calves on skim-milk. A great deal of 
good thought and good work has been done by scientific men 
along this lne of raising calves on skim-milk. 

I want to go a step farther now that this subject is up for consideration, 
tnd say that we want all that cream. We don't want 
to feed a calf from four to six weeks on whole milk and then 
switch it of onto something it cannot digest. Take the whole 
milk from that calf just as soon as the milk is good. There is the 
profit to tht dairyman. It is generally understood all over the 
state wherever you go, that that cannot be done. I want to say 
to you that the time has come when it is done by many men all 
over this state to-day. I will give you my experience this last 
summer. I have been a dairyman. I have quit the business 
now, but I keep one cow. I raised three calves. I let them 
have whole milk until the milk was good for use, and in a day 
or two afterwards they were eating nothing but skim-milk, 
except perhaps a little flax seed in addition. I would state that </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
48 


E should be sure to see that the flax seed is clean and pure 
Free from foreign substances, as that would bring on a case 
ours. 

I want to say in reference to calf feeding that I am satisfied it 
is not so much the ration as it is the handling of the calf that 
prevents us from raising a good calf and the lack of other conditions 
that bring about the results that we complain of. Take 
for example the practice of feeding a lot of calves in one field, 
altogether at one time, rushing up and each getting wha: he can. 
First one up to-day getting all he can eat, to-morrow sluggish and 
getting his feed the last one and getting very little if anything; 
as to quality, sometimes sweet and sometimes sour. All this is 
very bad practice. One day the housewife under the old 
method, puts the milk pans on the stove to get warm, she goes 
about her work and forgets about the milk. In a little while the 
milk is too hot and she sets it aside to cool. She goes on with 
her work and after the milk has got cold she thinks about it and, 
discouraged, she says, "I can't spend any more time with this 
milk, take it away and feed it to the calves." The next day 
they have some important work and put off feeding the calves 
until some convenient time. The next morning it is, ; 'Feed the 
calves the first thing, and get out in the field to work." 

Suppose a mother should feed her infant child in that manner, 
how long would it be before she would have to call a doctor, if 
she fed it at irregular times and an irregular amount? If people 
would bring the same amount of reason and intelligence in 
the feeding and raising of their calves on skim- milk as they do 
in the care and feeding of their infant children, they would succeed. 
A regular amount at a regular time in a proper manner, 
will bring success. The best way to feed calves is to have a 
row of stanchions, and the calves will learn in a short time to 
put their heads through, and then you can lock it and feed them 
what they require. Feed them regularly, at regular time of the 
day in a clean vessel. You should leave them there for twenty 
minutes after they have eaten, until digestion has set in and then </seg>


            <seg id="p049">
49 

when you turn them out they will not go to sucking each others 

We want people to use ordinary sense along the line of raising 
calves on skim-milk and they will not have any difficulty. 

I think of all the mean things that was ever asked of a woman 
child — and the girls are the ones on many of the farms — I 
k about the meanest thing to ask them to do is to go over 
the field without anyone else around, and try to feed the 
es. (Applause.) 

Mr. Young: The finest lot of calves I ever saw was on 
Brother Honeywell's farm. I remember visiting his farm four 
years ago and found as fine a lot of calves as I ever saw. I 
believe they were raised on separator milk. If he will now get 
up and tell us how he does it, I know we would all appreciate it. 

Mr. Honeywell: I feed them in stanchions and keep them 
there for half an hour after they have been fed. 

Kn motion duly made the chair appointed a committee of three 
as follows: Stouffer, Ashburn and Honeywell. 

On motion duly made a committee of five was appointed on 
nomination of officers. The chair appointed the following as 
such committee: Messrs. J. C. Merrill, B. R. Stouffer, L. D. 
Stillson, F. M. Housh and_ Frank E. Howe. 

Khe Chairman: I will appoint as a committee on largest 
best display of small packages, print "and ornamental but-J. 
K. Honeywell, Mrs. S. Pierce, John McKendry. 

THIRD SESSION. 

Association called to order with Vice-president Snively in the 

K'he Secretary: The committee appointed to award prizes 
the best display of small packages and ornamental butter 
art as follows: </seg>


            <seg id="p050">
.* 

50 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION. 

Co., second premium; South 
premium. 

Platte Creamery Co., third 

[signed 

J. K. Honeywell, 

Mrs. S. Pierce, 

John McKendry, 

Committee. 

Eie Secretary: I wish to read a comunication or request 
gard to the offering of special premiums to exhibitors at our 
al meeting: 

To the Officers of the Nebraska Dairymen 's Association : 
We, the undersigned, respectfully suggest that your associa- 

t adopt resolutions barring all special or side premiums at 
e conventions, believing that it would be more equitable and 
iactory to those entering butter for competition as well as 
e contributors, if all donations are made in cash to be applied 
e general premium fund: 

Creamery Package Mfg. Co., 

C. H. Higgs, Gen. Mgr 

The De .Laval Separator Co., 

E. W. Beach, Manager. 

Wells &amp; Richardson Co., 

E. Sudendorf, West. Agt 

Genesee Salt Co , 

H. G. Piffard, Pres. 

Worcester Salt Co., 

Lorenzo Benedict, Sec'y. 

F. W. Harwood, Treas. 

Diamond Crystal Salt Co., 

Per S. L. Kelley, Mgr., Omaha. 

Francis D. Moulton &amp; Co., 

By J. R. Bagley, Mgr. 

On motion this suggestion was referred to the committee on 

Mower-Harwood Co., 

By R. P. Wood. 
Creamery Package Mfg. Co., </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

51 

Chairman: We have on the program this afternoon a paper 
by Mr. R. K. Emily, of Kearney, on "The possibilities to be 
obtained in Nebraska dairying and what is most needed to 
attain them." 

Ir. Chairman: I find I am placed somewhat in the predicat 
of the woman who had six small children who wished to 
a relative at some distance. After getting aboard the train 
conductor came along to punch the ticket. He looked at 
a few foments — the children all being so nearly the same 
he could not recognize the fact that they were all hers, and 
ly he said, "Madam, are these all your children, or is this a 
ic?" She looked at him and replied, "They are all mine, 
its no picnic either." 

I have been very busy with a new plant, working up some 
outside business, with short notice to prepare this paper and 
sickness in my family. If this paper does not meet with your 
expectations, please remember that it has been no picnic. 

THE POSSIBILITIES TO BE ATTAINED IN NEBRASKA 

DAIRYING AND WHAT IS MOST NEEDED TO ATTAIN THEM 

I have divided this subject into two parts for greater convenience 
in handling. The first part deals with the possibilities 
or results we have found it possible to attain on Watson's ranch. 
The second part deals entirely with the manner or means we 
employ to obtain these results. In the first place, I will say that 
we have a herd of nearly 300 cows at this place, of which nearly 
100 are high grade, or full-blood Holsteins;the balance are halfbloods, 
grades, Jersey's, common stock, etc. Until lately we have 
had no certain knowledge of what any individual cow was doing. 
Of late, however, we have begun a system of weighing and testing 
of these individual animals, which is resulting in more feed, 
and better care for some, and in fattening preparatory to going to 
the butcher's block for others. Taking 20 cows, which were 
under my personal supervision, as far as weighing and testing </seg>


            <seg id="p052">
52 

are concerned, I am able to give the following results for the full 
week ending January nth: Cow number i, Beauty, a Jersey, 
full- blood as nearly as we are able to determine, dropped her 
calf December 26, gave for the week 238 lbs. of milk, or an 
average 34 lbs. daily, average test 7.4 per cent, or a butter yield 
of nearly 3 lbs. per day or 21 lbs. per week. Cow number 2, 
grade Jersey, fresh, gave 280 lbs. of milk for the week, or a 
daily average of 40 lbs., test 3.4 per cent, or a butter yield of a 
trifle over i l / 2 lbs. daily or n lbs. per week. Cow number 3, a 
three year old heifer, second calf, been milking three months, 
gave for the week 217 lbs. of milk, daily average 31 lbs., testing 
4.2 per cent, daily butter yield little over ij4 lbs. or n lbs. per 
week. This cow is half Holstein and half Jersey. Cow number 
4, old General Purpose, been milking 8 months, gives for the 
week 119 lbs. of milk, daily average 17 lbs., testing 4.8 percent, 
or butter yield of .95 of a pound daily, or 6 65 lbs. per week. We 
now come to old Dulcibel, a full-blood Holstein, been milking 9 
months — find her giving 168 lbs., or 24 lbs. daily, with a test of 
3.4 per t cent, with a yield of nearly a pound of butter daily. 
Next comes a bunch of sixteen full-blood Holsteins, comparatively 
fresh, or ranging from three weeks to three months along in 
their milking period — of these I find 4 giving 924 lbs. for the 
week, or 132 lbs. daily, with a 2.8 per cent test, or an average 
daily butter yield of 1.05 lbs. per cow; 4 others giving 910 lbs. 
for the week, or 130 lbs. daily, testing 3.0 per cent, or a daily 
butter yield of 1.06 lbs. per cow; 8 others giving 1,645 lbs. for 
the week, or 235 lbs. daily, testing 3.0 per cent, giving a daily 
butter yield of 1.05 lbs. per cow. This is a fair sample of what 
our best cows will do and what they are doing. The poorer 
ones range from this down to less than y 2 pound daily. These 
are a few of the possibilities to be attained in Nebraska dairying 
and would,go to show that what Nebraska needs is not so much 
more cows as better cows. Now as to the means we are 
employing to get these results. Will say cow No. 1 is fed 12 
lbs. of corn meal daily, worth 1 cent per pound, 12 lbs, of alfalfa 
hay, at $10 per ton, worth }£ cent, 40 lbs. corn ensilage at $2 </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

53 

per ton, or % cent more — daily cost of feed 13 cents. (There is 
an error in these figures. At the prices given the alfalfa hay is 
worth 6 cents and the ensilage 4 cents, making the daily cost of feed 
22 cents instead of 13 cents, as stated. — Secretary.) Allowing 
3 cents more for the care and milking brings her total cost to 16 
cents daily, for which she gives us in return 3 pounds of butter 
worth 24 cents, or 72 cents, leaving a net profit of 56 cents daily. 
Cow No. 2 receives the same ration and care, giving a net 
return or profit of 20 cents daily. Cow No. 3 receives only 10 
lbs. grain, consequently her cost of keeping is 2 cents less, or 
14 cents, for which she returns us 22 cents clear daily, while old 
General Purpose, as we call her, gets but 8 lbs. grain daily and 
costs for keep and care 12 cents and gives a net profit of 
between 10 and 11 cents daily. Dulcibel does virtually the same 
thing, while the 16 Holsteins are fed and cared for at a cost of 
14 cents a day, at a net profit of 10 to 11 cents daily. To obtain 
profitable results the wants and needs of the individual cow must 
be studied and found out. Brains were never in greater demand 
in the dairy business than they are to-day. It is a common mistake 
among dairymen to feed all cows alike, when he should, by 
judicious care and feeding, and by carefully weighing and testing 
his milk, find out which cows respond to high feeding and then 
feed to their capacity, remembering at all times that the cow 
which proves to be a good cow this year will be a good cow 
next year. These figures are further borne out by the different 
patrons at my creamery. I find one man's cows bringing him an 
income of nearly six dollars apiece monthly, with a cost of two 
dollars for feed, while another man's are only returning two 
dollars, feed included; from this we must naturally conclude that 
we must have to begin with, a fair cow of the dairy type. I am 
not here to advocate any breed, what I do advocate to every 
farmer or dairyman is, to take his best cows regardless of breed, 
test them thoroughly, keep the most profitable and then after 
deciding what line or breed he wishes to follow, head his herd 
with the best sire he can get of this type. If he follows this 
course, breeding always toward the point in view, he will find in </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
54 

NKBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

Ei years, at very little cost, that he has a dairy herd above 
verage from the material or stock which he had on hand to 
with. 

When this is done the dairyman will find that his cows will be 
producing from three to four hundred pounds of butter yearly, 
instead of one hundred and fifty, provided that he has the 
knowledge of his cow and her wants, and feeds and cares for her 
accordingly. Unless this is done, even this cow will not prove a 
success; in other words, in the hands of a man of small calibre 
she will still be a failure. 

I thank you for your attention. 

DISCUSSION. 

Eiairman: Is there any member who desires to ask Mr. 
y any questions in regard to the subject under considera- 

Member: I would like to bring up the subject of the breed 
of cattle. I notice he has mentioned different breeds, a point 
that needs to be illustrated before our dairvmen. 

Mr. Emily : I am not here to advocate any particular breed, 
and do not want to get away from the subject of butter-making. 
We have some thoroughbred stock. The cattle that Mr . Watson 
prefers are the Holstein. I don't think under all conditions and 
circumstances that the average Nebraska farmer or dairyman 
believes it is advisable for him (without he has some money to 
blow in) to go to work and buy a herd of blooded cattle. Taking 
it among the general herds of cattle, our dairies in general, 
almost every one of you get a few animals you swear by, so to 
speak. You realize they are above the balance or average of 
your herd. And I say to you that those are the cows that 
should be studied and tested, and if they are proving the results 
you look for, they should be studied, and fed, and their individual 
wants looked after to find out what is the thing to be done in their 
case in order to get good results. As I stated in my paper, 
select some breed you prefer, head the herd with the best sire </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
55 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

you can buy and follow out along that line. Save a good cow's 
heifer calf and begin with that calf to make a dairy cow. Keep 
her in a thrifty and healthy condition and, as stated in my paper, 
in the course of four or five years you have a dairy herd far 
above the average. The majority of farmers feed regardless of 
the cow's wants and that is the reason that to-day we have more 
150 pound cows in the state of Nebraska than that they were 
poor cows to begin with. 

Of course, we are carrying on some experiments at Mr. Watson's 
ranch, and we know what our feed costs us. Cow No. 1 we 

Iw makes three pounds of butter a day. Before she was 
;d a person could have bought her for $50; to-day you could 
buy her at any price. As soon as we found out what that 
would do we began studying how much she would eat, and 
¦ much butter she would produce. 

Question: Are you feeding ensilage? 

Answer: Yes, sir. 

Question: Are you feeding alfalfa 

Answer : Yes, sir* 

It seems almost impossible for the Nebraska dairyman to get 
away from the general idea of a general purpose cow. I was 
surprised at the contrast between the results of the Jersey cow 
and the general purpose cow. It seems to me that a great many 
of our farmers still stick to that idea. Take it back East where 
they do dairying for profit, I do not believe they keep the general 
purpose cow. They keep the dairy cow. I am in favor 
of the Jersey cow. I do not believe a farmer should 
mortgage his farm to stock up with full blooded cows. 
He should secure a sire of the best family and breed 
up, and we will not have the right kind of dairymen 
until we have these men. There is as much sense in raising the 
standard of our dairy as there is in breeding horses. We have 
some dairymen who have nice herds in this state. In the state 
of Vermont I think the dairy herd there will average from 300 
to 350 pounds of butter per cow per year, while in this state I do 
not think it is over 100 pounds. It would be a wonderful thing </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
56 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 

for this country if we could increase our average. I would like 
to hear from Mr. Honeywell. 

Ea. Honeywell: We have been milking, for the past year, 
n average 32 cows, and they have averaged us abour*356 
ds of butter a year, each giving a little over six thousand 
ds of milk. 

Mr. Emily: I would say that I think the gentleman misunderstood 
me to advocate a general purpose cow. I do not do 
that. We have what you might call some scrubs; we have 
some Holsteins, a few Jerseys, some mixed cows, and a few that 
we bought last fall. There had been no record kept and no test 
made before I came there. I was satisfied we were not doing 
what we should with the herd. Some of the boys in the barn 
swore by the general purpose cow, in the beginning of the test. 
I took the general purpose cow along at first, to show what 
she was. She was not so bad as might be. I will say that we 
had some knowledge of what the Jersey cow was doing. Three 
of the cows in the milking gave 34 pounds of milk a day, with 
an average of 7.4 of butter-fat. Our Holsteins we aim to have 
give 400 pounds of milk a week, and a cow that does less than 
that will not be kept. 

Prof. Haecker: We have here another example of the 
importance of having thoroughbred cattle. The vital point with 
the dairyman, it seems to me, upon the question as to whether 
he shall go out or keep in the business, is the kind of cattle he 
shall keep. There is a big difference in the profits in the record 
of two cows standing side by side, receiving the same care and 
feed, whether they shall produce 50 pounds, or 150, or 200 
pounds of butter in a year. Some cows will assimilate more good 
or nutriment in the feed given them than others, and those 
animals that can thus assimilate and turn it in the right direction 
are the animals that have been bred many years for the purpose 
of producing that one thing. I mean the special purpose cow when 
it comes to dairying. It is not possible or logical for the dairyman 
who expects to remain in the dairv business to keeD other than the </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
57 


Bal purpose, or thoroughbred cow, as those cattle are vastly 
rior for him to do business with. 

Mr. Ashburn: Whether I can agree with what has been 
said along this line or not depends on what you mean by the 
word "dairyman." If he is that class of men who take up one 
single line of business and devote their entire energy to dairying, 
then I say, amen, to all that has been said. If this paper and discussion 
is to be understood as applying to the business as it is in 
Nebraska to-day, as to the men who are milking cows and so on, 
I will have to disagree. We have not one man in twenty milking 
cows to-day who is competent to be a special dairyman. We 
would go hungry for butter if w$ had to get our supply from 
that class of men. I want to say that while I am in sympathy 
with all of this discussion, I think we need better dairymen just 
as well as we need better cows. I believe we should take the 
conditions that we have and work from them, both with the herd 
and the dairvman, and elevate both together until the man who 
would not possibly make a success with the dairy cow might be 
enabled to do it in rive years. I think that is along the line of 
work we should give to them as Nebraska dairymen and educators. 
We should throw out little grains of dairy knowledge that 
the world will read in our reports. We have a class of men, the 
largest by all odds, who must become better educated along 
these lines. I doubt the propriety, very much, of discouraging 
or breaking up that class at present. I would rather throw out 
helps, to a better knowledge of feeding and handling of cattle, 
and the education that will come along with this will develop 
success along special lines. 

the man who is only getting a portion of the profits of his dairy 
as a dairy cow, cannot be considered, strictly speaking, a 
.man, because he has another object, or another business out 
hich he draws a certain amount of his income. While it is 
i perhaps, that a calf from a general purpose cow is not 
:h very much more when it is dropped than one that is 
iped from the special purpose dairy cow, yet take the male 
from the dual purpose cow, that will make a fair feeder and 

5 </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
58 


that will develop into considerable beef, that can be grown and 
fattened on that farm, you must give the farmer credit for what 
he makes out of that steer along those lines as to the general 
round up in his pocket book at the end of the year. 

(is out of that class of cattle and it is through that resource 
the dairy business of this country will be built up and as it is 
and running very largely to-day. When you become special 
•men and are competent to be such, and can take care of the 
ous-temperment cow, that sensitive cow, that delicate cow, 
meet her requirements, as has been well said in the paper 
ndorse every word said in the paper) then you are a man who 
realize the most money fjom the special purpose dairy cow. 

Mr. Clark: Mr. Chairman, please excuse me for taking up 
so much time; Mr. Ashburn's remarks are all right, but they 
should be in the Stock-breeders' Association; this is a meeting 
of the Dairymen's Association. 

Mr. Ashburn: It is the stock-breeders of this country who 
produce the dairymen. 

Khairman : We should be pleased to hear from others. Mr 
ce, let us hear from you. 

Kr. Pierce: You will have to excuse me; I can do the work 
king care of the special cow, but am no speaker. 

A Member: I think it is Mrs. Pierce who can speak to us 
on this subject. 

Mrs. Pierce: Replying to what Mr. Ashburn said in regard 
to educating the people for the special purpose cow, I want to 
say that those are true words; I agree with him in all that he 
said. We need to educate the people to take care of the special 
purpose cow. We want many more of such men who will treat 
their cow as they would their wife. We have had several men 
to help in the milking and care of our cows, but we could not 
rely on them. They would not even do as they were instructed. 
The lowest record made by our herd has been 410 pounds per 
cow per year, and the highest was a little over 500 pounds. </seg>

            <seg id="p059">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

59 

"THE CARE OF HAND SEPARATOR CREAM." 

BY F. A. LEIGHTON, NEW HAMPTON, IOWA. 

In looking over the program of your convention, I notice that 
there are three papers pertaining to hand separators, so between 
us very likely all points of the subject will be treated, and perhaps 
many times over; but as I am informed that the State of 
Nebraska is a hand separator state, it will do no harm if one of 
us gets onto the other fellow's territory and talks on the same 
subject, for this question will stand as much discussion as any 
creamery subject before the people. 

Khen the first hand separators came onto the market no one 
at time would have ventured to predict the rapid strides that 
would make in the favor of the milk producer. 

I his hand separator system is becoming a serious problem ; in 
e places the best creamerymen have not quite decided 
ther they are the long looked for machine which is to solve 
creamey business, and put it on a permanent basis, or if it is 
another fad, which bobs up every few years and runs its 
¦se in a short period. 

Ifhe older creamerymen do not have to have their memories 
eshed in regard to the Cooley fad, which cost the creameryi 
of some localities many thousands of dollars. The reason 
the failure of the Cooley system is well known. It was 
ause there were other methods which came up that made 
ter butter than the old system. The creamery business has 
de rapid strides since the Cooley system has gone out of use, 
[ the whole milk system has had a long and successful career, 
I at the present time it seems if it was just as successful 
t has been at any time during the past ten years. 

fVe all know why this system of separating the milk at the fac,' 
has been successful. It is because the system took the milk 
iy from the farm the quickest of any system that has come 
previous to this; and it is a well known fact that any system 
ich relieves the farmer of the care of his milk the soonest after 
wn from the cow will be the most successful. When I say </seg>

            <seg id="p060">
60 

NKHRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

P system, it may be that all will not agree with me 
ressful creamery system is. My idea is that it is the 
ch enables the factory to put a brand of butter on the 
is strictlv fancy. An article that will not need preprocessing 
to keep it or to sell it. 

Iain aware that there are companies whose main efforts are 
cted toward a large quantity of butter, regardless of the 
lity. I do not believe this will prove a successful system in 
long run. It is the fancy article which will always have a 
ket, not the second grade. And it should be the business of 
creamery operators to make the fanciest article of butter in 
r power. 

I he h md separator system is practically a new system, only a 
years old, and whether it will be a successful system 
inds upon just two people; the one who owns a-id operates 
machine, and the one who buys and manufactures his cream 

1 wish to state here that just as good butter can be made with 
the cream from hand machines as whole milk delivered to the 
iv. But there are many things which have got to be 
looked after before this can be accomplished. Some people 
argue that the patrons should be better able to take care of the 
cream from a hand separator than the whole of the milk from 
which this cream was taken. This possiblv may be correct in 
theory, but practice does not prove it. The same attention 
given to the cream from a hand machine will not keep it in as 
good condition as the same attention given to the whole milk. 
The cream needs as good or better care than does the milk. It 
needs to be churned just as quick after it is drawn from the cow 
as cream separated at the factory. Or as we rind with the whole 
milk system — the shortest time it is left in the hands of the 
patrons, the better it will be for the grade of the butter. In 
many localities in Iowa and Minnesota, the hand separator 
system has received a black eye, not on account of the machine 
or the system, but on account of the separator man, and his 
agents, who have been so anxious to sell machines. </seg>

            <seg id="p061">
61 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

Let me give you an illustration of what I mean. While making 
a drive through another state adjoining this, the driver 
stopped to water his horses at a farm-house, and noticing a milk 
house near, I went in and found a woman ;it work, taking apart 
a hand machine, in order to wash it. I asked her how she liked 
her hand separator; she said, very much, because it saved so 
very much hard work. Upon asking how it saved her work, 
she replied that there was not so much washing of cans, and 
that the separator only needed washing three times a week. I 
a&gt;ked her why it only needed washing this often, and her reply 
was that the man who sold her the machine told her that no one 
ever washed their machines more than three times a week. 

Do you think a system conducted along this line will be - 
cessful? I am not of the opinion that it will be, and furthermore 
it ought qot to succeed and the man who sold the machine 
and gave these suggestions ought to be prosecuted by the S 
Board of Health. Now I do not wish you to think that all salesmen 
of hand separators give these instructions. I know many 
of them, and believe they do not take this means of making 
sales. 

iver since John Stewart started the first creamery west of the 
sissippi river, the creamerymen have been trying to edu 
r patrons to furnish them a pure, clean milk, and in many 
es this sysiem of education has been very successful. And 
quality of milk received at some of the factories is nearly 
ect. 

But the hand separator system is new, and people who are 
accustomed to taking good care of their milk would not peril ips 
be able to furnish as good an article of hand separated cream as 
they did milk. The work of handling hand separator cream and 
the machines themselves are different, and it is going to take a 
lot of educating before the patrons are able to furnish the factories 
with an article of cream that has no fault. 

If to-day, I was to start out to inaugurate a creamery system, 
and I was assured by the five hundred patrons in a given territory 
that they would conform to any rules which I might pro- </seg>

            <seg id="p062">
62 


mulgate, I would first put up a creamery that would be a marvel 
of neatness. This would be an object lesson to the milk producer. 
There are too many creamerymen who do not set a 
good example to their patrons in the matter of cleanliness. This 
would be their first lesson. The next lesson would be on buying 
hand machines. I should instruct them to buy five hundred 
hand machines and the five hundred machines would be bought 
of the firm that sold the best ones, and the test should be — light 
running, durability, simplicity and close skimmers. Price would 
not count, but the machine would have to be perfect; these conditions 
are filled by machines already on the market. 

Their next instruction would be on the care of the hand 
machines. They should be taught the mechanism of the separator, 
how to take it apart and put it together right, and especially how 
to keep the wearing parts and gearing clean — something which 
many expert butter-makers have still to learn. They should be 
instructed in the handling of the milk in the vay of cleanliness 
and the importance of separating the milk just as fast as it is 
drawn from the cow, and the skimmed milk fed just as fast as it 
drawn from the separator. They would receive instructions on 
how to aerate the cream, and the method would be very simple; 
merely taking it out in the pure air and pouring it slowly from 
one can to the other. 

Eie next lesson would be one of importance, if a fancy article 
.tter was expected; this would be to lower the temperature 
e cream to 50 degrees immediately. 

J'he next would be to instruct the farmer's wife how to wash 
separator. They should be instructed to wash them twice a 
and the bowl taken apart each time, even if it did contain 
pieces. There is no separator on the market, big or little, 
cannot be washed in fifteen minutes at the outside; this 
ild necessitate one-half hour a day out of the twenty-four, 
mall amount of work to give to such an important part, and 
ork that so much depends upon, if good results are expected. 

The next lesson, and the one that causes all the grief to the 
buyer of hand separator cream, is to teach them that the day </seg>

            <seg id="p063">
63 


they go to town to do their week's shopping is not often enough 
to deliver cream to the factory; and here is another case where 
some of the separator salesmen are at fault. They have told 
the purchasers of hand separators that once or twice every ten 
days is often enough to take their cream to the factory. As I 
said before, every hour that cream and milk is left in the hands 
of patrons, (now I do not mean all patrons, for there are exceptions) 
just so much it will deteriorate, and my instructions to those 
five hundred patrons would be, to deliver their cream four times 
a week in winter and every day during the summer; and I am 
sometimes of the opinion that it is as difficult for the patrons to 
keep their cream in as good a condition in winter as in summer, 
for the reason that many of them have no suitable place to keep 
it in the cold weather. 

I 'here has been considerable discussion during the past few 
¦s as to whether it injures cream to freeze. My experience 
been, that better butter can be made it the cream or milk is 
allowed to be frozen. 

I am aware that my friends, Rushton and Haskell and those 
r gentlemen who hare so many stations, that a few of them 
d get lost and they would not miss them, will say that all of 
is very good theory, but how about the practical part of it. 
y would probably want to know how this would work with 
r thousands of patrons scattered throughout the state. I 
i to assure these gentlemen that I know of no other plan 
;r the sun whereby hand separator cream can be handled 
i good results except the patrons are taught as I have mened 
above. 

§ou have got to teach your patrons three things: First, 
iliness in the handling of the milk and separators. Second, 
&gt;eratures of the cream after it is separated. Third, most 
&gt;rtant of all, quick daily delivery to the creamery or to the 

E'hile in conversation with an expert butter-maker in Icwa, 
has about one-half of his patrons delivering hand separator 
m, the subject came up of what per cent of cream gave the </seg>

            <seg id="p064">
64 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

best results. He informed me that about twenty-five per cent 
cream seemed to come into the factory in the best condition. 
He said if too much milk" was left in, it developed acid faster 
than the rich cream, and if the cream was too rich in butter-fat, 
it had a tendency toward getting oily, especially if hauled a long 
distance. I will say that at this creamery the milk haulers bring 
in the hand separator cream, so that the cream comss to the 
factory just as often as the milk does. This factory is noted for 
its fine butter, and it has sustained this reputation ever since it 
started, years ago. And this gentlemen tells me that the hand 
separator cream is as fine as that separated at the factory; but 
these patrons have been educated to take care of their cream 
right, and to wash their separators twice a day. And they have 
a rule that if the patron fails to deliver his cream on the regular 
separating day, it would be refused if sent in the next day. 
There is only one conclusion to draw after a visit to this factory, 
and that is that fancy butter can be made with hand separator 
cream if the patrons will do their part toward caring for the 
cream. 

One point that creamer}- patrons do not understand, is the 
rapid development of acid which takes place_when milk or cream is 
at a warm temperature, and many butter-makers who pose as 
first-class workmen, are as ignorant on this matter as some of 
their patrons, and many a bad lot of butter dates its down-fall to 
the excess of acid allowed in the cream before it was churned. To 
illustrate this: Sometime ago I made some tests. A vat of cream 
was tested for acid at the conclusion of the separating about 1 1 
o'clock in the morning. It took twelve cc's of alkali to neutralize 
the acid in the cream. The temperature of the cream was 
kept at eighty degrees until 3 o'clock; in four hours it had 
reached a point where it took forty cc's to neutralize the acid; 
this was away past the danger point, and every minute it was 
deteriorating in quality. This shows the importance of temperature 
on hand separator cream. 

There is one more matter of which I wish to speak, and then 
I am through. The creamery men who are in the business </seg>

            <seg id="p065">
65 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

know that to mix the night's and morning's milk together, if one 
lot is warm, injures the whole amount. Many of the creamery 
patrons do not realize that this applies to cream also. Many of 
them will separate the morning's cream into the can containing 
the cold cream from the night before, and in every case the 
whole lot of cream is injured. 

Eie morning's cream should always be kept separate until 
thoroughly cooled; after that it can be mixed with no 
er. 

I looks as if the hand separator system is to grow. It is a 
em which suits the farmer, whether it suits the creamerymen 
ot. If we are to have this system, then let it be run on the 
ectplan; don't let us allow the creamery business to get 
k. to the old gathered cream days; the world is not going 
¦cward now-a-days, but is pushing ahead in every line; should 
creamery business be any exception to this rule? 

Ket us build up the quality of American butter, and if we are 
&gt; this, there is a great responsibility resting upon those who 
e the butter. 

Let us have quality first and all the time, and quantity next. 

If the hand separator system will build up quality, then let 
us help it along; if it does not, then drop it. The last will not 
be necessary, for if it does not produce quality then the system 
will go down without any assistance. But I am not of the 
opinion that it will go down; it rests with the patrons of the 
creamery and manufacturers of the butter. 

Eeir responsibilities are to be great, and many discouraging 
s will arise before the sky is clear, but we believe the 
s will be driven back in good time. 

Khaikman: We can spend a few minutes in discussing this 
ect. 

-Mr. Emily: The temperature of a majority of the wells in 
in this countiy is 58 degrees or less, and I would like to ask -Mr. 
Leighton how we are going to have hand separator milk cooled 
to 50 degrees. The most of the hand separator cream comes </seg>

            <seg id="p066">
66 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 

miles and miles from farmers who have no ice; and this is a very 
important question that concerns us. 

Kr. Leighton: It is a very difficult thing to keep hand 
¦ator cream at a warm temperature. I cannot answer that 
tion. 

Mr. Ashburn: I wish to ask Mr. Clark what the general 
temperature of the wells are in his locality. 

Mr. Clark: I should say from 54 to 56 degrees. 

Ashburn: I notice in the Platte valley, from Sidney to Grand 
Island, the temperature is from 52 to 54 degrees. 

Emily: We have four wells on the ranch, and they run from 
56 to 58 degrees. , 

Mr. Bassett: That variation may possibly be accounted 
for in the thermometers, to the extent of two or three degrees. 

Ashburn: The test I made was with a thermometer procured 
from the University. 

A Member: The water in our well is 52 degrees. 

Bassktt: The care of the hand separator cream is one of 
the most important subjects that can be brought to our attention. 
It was mentioned this morning that there were five 
thousand hand separators in this state, and more were being 
introduced every day. If you remember, we discussed this 
question briefly a year ago, and the creamerymen present said 
it was to the interest of the dairymen to use the hand separator, 
but questioned whether it was for the best interest of the 
creamerymen. Some of them argued that in the use of hand 
separators they were going back to the old gathered cream 
plan; that they did not get the quality of cream they 
desired to make the best quality of butter. In the introduction, 
therefore, of the hand separator the quality of the butter would 
not be as good as it is at the present time from the skimming 
station or the central place, where the milk was brought for 

Eiother feature of this subject is that the moment the dairyhas 
a hand separator he becomes independent in the dairy 
ess, even if he does not wish to make butter. In a can of </seg>

            <seg id="p067">
67 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

separator cream he has a condensed product that he can 
ship a considerable distance to market. He is not compelled 
to sell to the nearest creamery, and he becomes in 
a greater measure independent of local conditions. The man 
who purchases it wants the cream in good condition. That 
is why we should discuss all about how to handle hand 
separator cream to the best advantage, because upon the condition 
of the cream when it arrives at the factory depends the 
quality of the butter that will be manufactured from it. So 
that with five thousand hand separators in the State of 
Nebraska, and the number rapidly increasing, this becomes one 
of the most important questions we have. In our locality we 
have one of the most successfully patronized skimming stations 
in the state; yet it is only a question of time when there will be 
no longer a skimming station. The farmers are buying hand 
separators and separating their milk at home, delivering only 
the cream at the station. Farmers cannot afford to haul milk 
to the skimming station if they have to go any considerable dis- 

Kr. Leighton: I think there is only one way to solve the 
lem, and that is instead of having skimming stations to have 
:urizing stations. 

A Member: I would like to ask Mr. Leighton how the pas 
teurized butter is being received? 

Mr. Leighton: It is growing in favor more and more every 
day. I predict that it will only be a question of time when all 
butter will be made from pasteurized cream. The Continental 
company make a very fine article of butter. I believe they 
make all their butter from pasteurized cream. The largest percentage 
of their butter is made from pasteurized cream. Inconversation 
with a friend recently, he told me he was using a 
carload of their butter every week. 

Ehey have a pasteurizer, and they have a cooler. As the 
m comes from the separator it runs into the pasteurizer, 
from that into the cooler, and by the time it gets into the </seg>

            <seg id="p068">
68 


tit becomes of the proper temperature. They have also hand 
irator stations. 

Kr. Jensen, who was present, then explained to the associathe 
system by which the Continental company pasteurized 
cream. 

BMkmber: What degree of temperature do you use in 
eurizing your cre.im? 

Mr. Lkighton: About from 150 to 160 degrees 

The Chairman: We have with us this afternoon Mr. J. 
Fred Schlappi, who had charge of the Dairy Food Department 
at the Pan-American Exposition at Buffalo, and I know you 
would all be pleased to hear a word from him concerning his 
work there. 

Er Schi.APPI: I think it is quite fortunate for me to be with 
at this time and I feel that it is all owing to your worthy 
:tary that I am here to speak to you to-day. 

It has been my good fortune, I consider it so, to be interested 
in dairying, and have been for many years. I am asked to give 
you a talk on some of the lessons learned at the Pan-American 
Exposition. 

The breeders at a meeting held some time in February, 1901, all 
agreed to bring a certain number of cattle to the Pan-American 
Exposition and exhibit a so-called Model Dairy. As time went 
on some of the breeders thought they would not be treated as 
they would like to be and they wished to incorporate or formulate 
at that time certain rules that would favor them, but it was 
soon found that they could not do that. Each one wanted a 
special rule for his special breed. It was decided not to have 
any special rule for any special breed. The Jersey people withdrew 
from the proposition of furnishing cattle, and also the 
Holstein people; and, here is a point that I wish to emphasize in 
regard to the Model Dairy. The Canadian people, previous to 
this, agreed to bring any breed lacking at the time of the withdrawal 
of the Jerseys and Holsteins. It looked as though there 
would not be any Model Dairy and the proposition of the Canadians 
was gladly accepted. The cattle were brought on the </seg>

            <seg id="p069">
69 


Pan-American grounds about the 24th or 25th of April. In the 
meantime the Canadians said, "we cannot enter the Model 
Dairy under the rules laid down at the February meeting, but 
we must have a test. We want to know who has the best 
breed and the best cow." After wrangling over the situation 
they finally decided that they would have a test. So the cattle 
were entered on the 1st day of May but under the rules formulated 
on the 26th day of April, it was to be a dairy test. 

Perhaps it would be well for me to speak about the shrewd 
Canadians. The South and Central American people were 
looking where they could find other cattle to improve what they 
had. When they came to the Model Dairy they said, "How is 
it that the Canadian people have all the cattle here: 1 " Then we 
began to apologize. Breeders of the United States furnished 
five breeds and the Canadians five. The Canadians had a card 
in large letters over each one of their breed saying, "Canada's 
contribution to the Model Dairy." You would see that as you 
first stepped into the building. The Canadians also had a man 
specially versed in the business, who lived in the barn, to entertain 
and show visitors their breeds of cattle. Those people 
who were looking after new blood were taken in tow at once by 
this gentlemen. 

What have the Canadian people now? They have 
taken away our prestage as exporters of cheese from New 
York and Wisconsin. They are now trying very hard to 
secure the business on butter and breeds of cattle also. This is 
a lesson from the Pan-American of what the Canadians will do. 
When we go to St. Louis lets not make any of these mistakes. 
I have a few figures here, but I hardly care to burden you with 
all of them. 

When the talk was first taken up of a dairy, Mr. Converse 
intended to show the cows and to have the dairy room and the 
office »11 under one roof. It was demonstrated that it could be 
done so with safety. It is a fact that there was not the least bit of 
odor in that building. The milk was handled in one room right 
under the same roof, and the butter was made there. It could </seg>

            <seg id="p070">
* 

70 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION. 

Iiave been done in that condition except that everything was 
thoroughly clean. The conditions there were just the 
: as can be had in an ordinary dairy. We did not have any 
irate barn ; it was a very cheap affair. I presume many of 
have better barns than we had. We practiced, however, 
sugh cleanliness. 

In the question of the hand separator, near the barn, trouble 
arise to separate the milk, in a room partitioned off or a 
1 building attached to the barn. It is done in many places 
e East and it can be done here as well if thorough cleanliis 
practiced. 

If 1 have been asked once I have been a thousand times, 
"What breed of cattle is the best?" I could not tell you what 
is the best breed; I do not believe that we yet have the best one 
breed of cattle. I have here the standing of the best ten cows 
in the way of profit that they have made over and above the 

Kirsty Wallace was sick; had she not been sick she would 

have made a much better record. However, I think it was a 
good deal owing to the herdsman. He was very erratic in his 
feeding. He had the privilege to feed as he liked; he would 
feed irregular amounts. He did not go up gradually or come 
down gradually. It was simply impossible for us to control him; 

he was a man of very quick temper. 

Question: Were the cows all in lactation the same length 

of time? 

Mr. Schlappi: They were in lactation about the same 

XAMK OF COW NAME OF BREKD 

;k- 

:t ph.ikit 

Mary Marshall Guernsey.... 
May Flow, r Hed Poll. . . . 

::::*S:S 

i &gt;]M j ia Guernxc 
Primrosi' Jersey 
is of Pilllin Guernsiy . . . 
Beauty of Norval Holstein 

=i 

i May Jersey 
1st Ayrshii 

:::: £S 

By Walla.-.' " 
1 cif Woodaide " . . . . 

::::JS2 </seg>

            <seg id="p071">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

71 

length of time, not over three weeks difference except one, Justina, 
Polled Jersey, was fresh in December, about five months 
before she entered the test. You could not expect a cow that 
length in lactation to do as well. They made a very good 
showing. The Poll Jersey cows are a new American breed 
and only a few to select from, but they made an excellent showing. 
As I said before there is no breed which has all the good 
points. There is just as much difference between the individual 
in the breed as there is between breeds. These cows were 
selected with care. Each individual cow was looked after 
according to her wants. They did not feed every cow alike. 
It was the herdsman's special duty to look after this business 
and to see what feed would bring the best results. It is not 
altogether the amount of feed that your cattle have; they must 
have care as well as feed. It is also the amount of feed that they 
will assimilate; not the quantity consumed that will tell the story 
of profit and loss. 

I cannot touch upon each one and give a detailed account of 
1 cow. I will speak of Mary Marshall. She gave 5600 
ads of milk in six months and an estimate of butter of 354^ 
nds. Her feed cost $29.16. Medora Fern had just the 
e care and she gave 4224 pounds of milk and 214 pounds of 
er at a feed cost of $24.26. Her feed cost $4.80 less 
1 Mary Marshall's but she made 139 pounds less butter 
1 Mary Marshall. What did she do with the feed? What 
ime of it.' It was lucky to have that cow there just to show 
difference between the true dairy type and one who had not 
dairy form. 

It is not all in the cow alone; there is a good deal in the care 
and feed. In the East the feed question is a serious one, but you 
have solved the problem here with alfalfa. You should thank 
your stars that you can raise alfalfa. It is the best protein feed 
you can raise on your own farm. In the East protein has to be 
bought at high prices in the shape of bran, gluten, etc, etc. 

I want to tell you there is much in dairying. The more we 
study the dairy problem the better care and feeding we find nee- </seg>

            <seg id="p072">
NEBRASKA DAIKYMEx's ASSOCIATION. 

72 

essary. If a dairyman wishes to inform himself and if he takes 
the time he will become convinced of these facts. 

I very interesting and important question mentioned U} the 
last evening by the gentleman from Dakota and thg' lady 
i Minnesota — that it is not necessary doing chores all the 
! — a regular system should be followed. Just as soon as we 
to that point our children, boys and girls, will not be looking 
some of those genteel, so-called occupations in the cities and 
is; they will be only too glad to stay on the farm, the most 
sed home anywhere in the world. I thank you gentlemen 
your attention. (Applause.) 

Below are the tables referred to by Mr. Schlappi: 

Buffalo, N. V.. Nov. 3rd. 1901. 

I hereby announce the awards in the Breed Test in the Model Dairy, as 
r.: 

The prize for net profit in butter-fat is won by the Guernseys by a net 

i&gt;rotit of M.M. 

priae for net profit in churned butter is won by the Ow 

15.88. 

The prize for net profit in total solids i&gt; won by the Holsteins by a net 

pntft of US. 44. 

prize tor net prolit in total solids and &gt;j-ain in live weight is won 
ipv the HoUteinsby a net profit of 131.63. 

T. A. ( oxvkusf. 

Supt. Live S- </seg>

            <seg id="p073">
73 


RESULTS OF MODEL DAIRY BREED TEST. 

Khe following statement shows the standing of the ten breeds 
peting in the Model Dairy Breed Test in the different classes. 

All awards of prizes are based on the net profit determined 
by the value of the product after deducting cost of feed. 

PRODUCTION OF BUTTKR-FAT. 

ICTTIR-FIT 

BREED 

Cost of Feed Net ProBt 

r.i 

Value 

Guernsey 

124*.0&lt;t -MOT (Hi tUt M $230 10 

1234. !*i MSB 137 7* 22.144 

Ayrshire 12111.44 3M titi 1+tt '.is 217 M 

Holstein 1275.86 :5T.. i". 1«4 HM 210 -Vi 

Ked Polled 1141.81 :V&gt;3 &gt;&lt;3 138 03 

Brown Swiss 112:5.1", 330 34 147 2ti 
h Canadian &lt;XU 11 2*!i 44 113 10 

Short Horn 1138.86 334 M Ui2 12 172 *4 

Polled Jersey !i4*.31 27* 1»1 10(147 l«i!' 44 

Duu-h Belted S47.4!' 24!t 2ti 132:12 IM M 
PRODUCTION OF CHURNED BUTTER. 
The yield of churned butter is computed from the actu; 

PRODUCTION OF CHURNED BUTTER 

(he yield of churned butter is computed from the actual 
Its of one day's churning of each breed's cream from the 
: of one day in each week, and the yield for the week detered 
from this churning in proportion to the total milk yield of 
breed for the week. 

results of one day's churning of each breed's cream from th 

milk of one day in each week, and the yield for the week detei 

mined from this churning in proportion to the total milk yield c 

the breed for the week. 
Owing to the lack of machinery during the first three week 

Ewing to the lack of machinery during the first three weeks 
hurnings were made. The amount of butter credited for the 
)d was determined in a similar manner from the actual 
ning during the following weeks. 

no churnings were made. The amount of butter credited for th 

period was determined in a similar manner from the actuj 

churning during the following weeks. 

CHCRHCO BCTTEK 
Lbs. Vain 

CHUKHCO BCTTEH 

BREED Cost of Feed Net Proflu 
Lbs. Value 

BREED 

Cost of Feed Net Profits 

Value 

Guernsey 14211.43 Off! :W *i:W M *22i&gt; 37 

Guernsey 1429.43 

. 1401i.l."&gt; 362 ti 137 7i» 214 .".1 

Jersey 1400.15 

Ayrshire 1415. :i7 363 Si l+» 212 M 

A\ rshire 1415.57 

Holstein !'.'.! 1430.28 

Holstein 1430.2* 3T&gt;7 :&gt;7 lt&gt;4 IW Itt 88 

357 57 1«4 88 M *- 

Red Polled 131n.4."&gt; 321* M 11V* 03 IM 83 

Red Polled 1319.45 

French Canadian 11711. tif&gt; 214 HI 113 10 1*1 

French Canadian 1179.65 

Brown Swiss 125»i.3« 324 1)9 147 2ti 17ii &gt;&lt;3 

Brown Swiss 12Wi.:«i 

Short Horn 1307.55 

32ti 8«i 1.-.2 12 1«4 77 
270 0»i low 47 188 88 

Polled Jersey 1080.25 

244 2* 132 32 111 »6 

Dutch Belted 877.18 

e </seg>

            <seg id="p074">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

74 

PRODUCTION OF MILK SOLIDS AND LIVE WEIGHT. 

TOTAL SOUDS LIVE WEIGHTS T ota l Cost Net 

BREED 

I 'In 4742. R7 HM *i 
Ire 41W.30 sre 8K 
Horn 408« M 367 7* 
iSwIss 3843 .US 3.M SIS 
Oiled S773.73 WH 
He.vs X774.M 338 74 

Holnleln 4742.57 »4M 83 

Ml til 73 M3S 5S tlM M K73 (7 

mi tii n (4*8 5« tiM m era n 
XI8 « M 383 22 1« S6 Ml 24 
802 84 08 381 85 102 12 2» 73 
IH 5 »4 360 89 147 28 213 83 
349 10 47 390 11 138 03 212 08 
IK 585 346M 138 W 21* «O 
18» S «7 344 07 137 78 «U7 1» 
288 8 64 304 SO 113 10 1»1 40 
378 II 28 287 20 132 32 IMM 
f» 8 25 263 10 109 47 151 63 

Ayr.hin ..'.'..'.''."..'.'..'.'.'.'. 418T30 S7« 8H 
Short Horn 408*58 367 79 

XI8 « 54 383 tt 140 96 Ml 24 

MHJ.Wi 387 TV 

802 84 08 381 85 102 12 229 73 

Brown SwIm SM3.IK! SM BS 

IH 5 »4 360 89 147 28 213 83 

349 10 47 350 11 138 03 212 08 

Bed Polled ST7S.7S 339 &lt;M 

(iu.rnaey* 3774 93 338 74 

IK 5 85 345 W 138 W 21* «0 

Jerseys 37W.96 »» 

s trm 90 !O» 30 

18* 5 m 344 07 137 78 «U7 1» 

French Canadian 321*7 38 jWst 

1 Canadian 3*87. M «R W 
Belted MM8. 47 275 98 

888 8 64 304 50 113 10 19140 

Dutch Belted 3096.47 275 98 

tt» II 28 287 » 132 32 IM 94 

Polled Jersey M1.8T 2S4 85 

Jersey J831.8T 2S4 85 

f» 8 25 383 10 109 47 IH 63 

PRODUCTION OF MILK SOLIDS. 

TOTAL SOLIDS 

BREED 

— I Cost of Feed Net Proflt 
Value 

Lbs. 

iteins 4742. 'iT 
hire 41K~&gt;.3&lt;&gt; 
rn Swiss 3943. H2 
nsev 3T74.O3 
Polled 3773.73 

Holsteins 4142.51 

*42ti S3 *1«4 m *2«2 14 

*42ti K\ *1«4 m *2H2 14 
:ra 88 H(i stH ix&gt; to 
354 9.'. 147 2H 2(17 00 
338 74 lM 9&lt;t 2n2 75 
339 tu i:$x o:{ lmi k 
:«» :{&lt;i 137 78 2iii :,i 
:«»7 7it i«2 12 aoe n 
2&lt;t.-) M 113 10 1*2 76 
254 86 KW 47 14.'» M 
27'i M K!2 32 143 M 

Ayrshire 

-Hire 4185.30 
Brown Swiss 394:1.92 

STB 88 14(1 9H 1X&gt; 70 

364 86 147 2H an SB 

33S 74 LM 9&lt;t M 75 

Guernsey 3774.93 

Red Polied'"!""!"!; 3773173 

Xto M i:w M L'nl K 

Jersey 37K9.9K 

•v XMB.S8 

:«9 M) 137 78 SOI 52 

• Bon.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.', i 408 

t Horn 4O8«.5S 

361 79 i«2 12 aos n 

French Canadian I 32*7. 3« 

oh Canadian 32*7. :«i 

2H M 113 10 1x2 76 

Polled Jersey 2831 .H" 
Dut&lt;-h Belted 3066.41 

&gt;d Jersey 2831. H" 

254 86 K»9 47 14.-. 38 

h Belted 3066.41 

:«H«i.47 

¦IV, UK 132 32 14:! M 

Rank of cows in Model Dairy on profit or estimated butter. 

NAMK OF COW 

NAME OF BREED 

NET PROFIT 

Mary Marshall Guernsey Mt.49 

May Flower Ked Poll It 


. ipeia Guernsey 


Primrose Jersey "&gt;&lt;i.i"&gt; 


l'rocris of Paxtanj; Guernsey 4'.'. 4!» 

Beauty of Norval Holstein 


(Jueen May Jersey 47. 


l&gt;t Ayrshiiv 


Pearl of Woodside Ayrshire 4&amp;.4I 

Kir^ty Wallace Ayrshire 4."i.34 

Jersey 44. 70 

•Teisev 

Mossy of H Jersey 44.49 

Hulda Wayne Holstein 44. 12 

Red Polled 43.80- 

MiM Mollie Short Horn 43.01 

yueen Polled Jersey </seg>


            <seg id="p075">
Lb». I V.lue ; Gain I Value Credlt Feed Proflt 


SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

75 

NAME OF COW NAME OF BREED NET PROFIT 

Ve-ra Guernsey 41. 75 
Belle T B. Swiss 41.23 

Tidy Abbekirk Holstein 41. 13 

Denise ( 'hampionne F. Canadian 40.64 

en F. Canadian 40.62 

F.li/.a B. Swiss 40.60 

Turka Mercedes Holstein Mill 

Luna Flora F. Canadian 39.41 

Ora Polled Jersey 39. 17 

Prides Favorite Polled Jersey 38.96 

Lady Flora Ayrshire 38. 70 

IU-xina Jersey 

• r lied Poll 38. lft 

Belle of Warwick Dutch Belted 38.02 

Hope of Minn B. Swiss 37.38 

Mh^' Holstein 36.71 

yueen Bess S. Horn 3K.31 

Princess S. Horn 33. 71 

Liny B B. Swiss 

Phy 1 iss P. Jersey 

Luna Fr. C anadian :t2. 74 

Flora Red Poll 32. 11 

Tryst* lied Poll SLM 

Rom 3rd Short Horn 

Nicola B. Swiss Ml36 

Mtdora Fern Guernsey 29.36 

y D S. Horn 

Madeline Dutch Belted 

Holland Creamery " " 

La Bouchette Fr. Canadian M.'M 
Justina Polled Jersey l."..+c&gt; 

Merletta D. Belted M.M 

Alberta D. Belted 11.49 

The Chairman: We have with us to-day Mr. J. Dixon 

Avery, of Chicago, one of the foremost organizers of this asso- 

ciation in Nebraska, and we will be greatly pleased to hear from 

him at this time. 

Mr. Chairman, I did not come here to make a talk, and I 

do not believe the audience is in a humor to hear an ordinary 

talk. I will say that I am glad to be here with you. As the 

chairman stated, I was one of the charter members of the 

Nebraska Dairymen's Association. 1 was the second one to take </seg>

            <seg id="p076">
76 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

a life membership in this association, and I have never regretted 
it. During the first four, five or six years of the life of this association 
I was present at each one of the annual meetings. We 
had some trouble in those days in getting farmers interested. I 
notice that you have farmers and farmers' wives and daughters 
here as members. This is certainly a move in the right direction, 
for that is the foundation of the whole thing. Unless farmers 
and farmers' wives and farmers' daughters are educated in the 
dairy business you never can make the business the measure of 
success that you ought to make it. 

I have been interested in the papers that have been read and 
the discussions that have taken place. With your permission 
there are one or two things I would like to emphasize, and 
which have been suggested this morning by Mr. Ashburn. I 
have heard Mr. Ashburn speak a number of times, but I do not 
think 1 ever heard him speak as well as I have to-day. He 
says, "Feed your stock regularly and to a certain tick of the 
clock," and I endorse that statement. When I was a boy there 
was a sign or notice put up which read: "A place for everything 
and everything in its place. This must be strictly 
observed." It seems to me there is a time for feeding and for 
doing everything in the right time, and you should do everything 
in the right time; you should have a time to milk your 
cows morning and night. The interval should be as equally 
divided as possible. I was born on a farm, but I do not remember 
when I milked my first cow. I have mixed up with farmers 
all my life, more or less, and I have found that those dairymen 
who pay the most or strictest attention to their milking time succeed. 
If they set a time to milk at 5 o'clock in the morning 
they would milk at 5 o'clock. If they commenced to milk the 
red cow first in the springtime, that is the cow they would milk 
first all the summer. Back in my old home in New York we 
had a dairyman who used to milk twenty-five cows, and he took 
care of those cows. He got rich. This same farmer, if he were 
at work two, three or five miles from home, would be at home 
at 5 o'clock and have his overalls on and be at the barn ready </seg>

            <seg id="p077">
77 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

to sit down at the first cow on time. That is the kind of dairying 
that pays. At that time, in New "York, fifty years ago, 
dairying was not what it is to-day. While the average dairyman 
had cows that gave one hundred pounds of butter, this 
dairyman had a cow that gave two hundred pounds. Why? 
Because he put some brains into his work. He got the best 
cows he could get and he took care of them. He milked them 
regularly. It is necessary to milk a cow regularly, and it is 
necessary to feed them regularly. 

{regard to profits, I might speak of a man named Cole, who 
:d a breed of cattle, which breed I cannot remember at the 
ent moment, but he had thirty cows in his dairy. For three 
lecutive years those thirty cows averaged him, gross returns, 
veen 148 to 151 dollars each. Did his dairy pay? Of 
se; he sold his calves for twenty-five dollars or more, each, 
that was a part of the income of that cow. I have the 
res at home. He improved his dairy by inbreeding, but he 
great results from it. 

Something has been said here about Canadian cows. I 
remember about thirty years ago in Utica, N. Y., when Mr. 

was president of the National Association. There 
were two or three delegates from Canada, and they wanted to 
know about this dairying business. They wanted to know how 
to make cheese and the people of New York State sent 
people to teach them how to make cheese. They have been 
making the best cheese year after year ever since. As this gentleman 
here said, "They have got our cheese export business 
away from us." Why? Because we commenced skimming 
and sending skim cheese across the water as full cream cheese, 
while they were giving or putting in all the cream and putting 
into the business all the skill, brains, ingenuity and capital that 
were required for success. They have made a grand success of it. 
What they will do in regard to the butter business is perhaps a 
little uncertain, but I do not believe they can ever get the 
butter export business entirely away from us. 

In regard to the hand separator business: Four years ago I </seg>

            <seg id="p078">
78 


was as much opposed to the hand separator as any man could 

be. I did not know much about it. I had been in the dairying 

business and thought I knew what I was talking about, but three 

years ago this fall I happened to be in New York with Mr. 

Moody. He and some others of the Sharpies people had a 

controversy for years and years. After a while I became 

thoroughly converted to the hand separator business. I thought 

the great trouble would be, in the first place, that the farmer 

could not afford to pay the price asked for hand separators, and 

tnd, would not be likely to take proper care of the cream, 
have heard of the success of the hand separator here in 

Nebraska. Under proper conditions that is the new way to 

make butter in Nebraska. You cannot afford to transport milk 

to a separator station, thirty- or forty miles, or even eight or nine 

miles; it is too far. You can transport cream two or three hun- 

dred miles if you want to. 
I thank you for your attention 

BUTTER EXHIBIT AT THK NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S 
ASSOCIATION. 

W. D. t'OLLYKR. CHICAGO, JUIXiK 

List of exhibits scoring 9B points or over out of a possible !&lt;*&gt; 

I'. I*. Pexton Neliifh. Neb 

&lt; ). Muckle Riverton, Neb '.'1 

.1. A. Cooover Kearney. Neb. 

M 

&lt; arl Hainmirberjr Han-en. South Dakota 

•Ml 

\V. I.,. NVwbv Fairburv. Neb 

•Ml 

John McKendrv Archer, Neb imi 

.1. C. (lark Ravenna. Neb 

John Wiit/i-1 Malcolm. Neb '.•!• 

trey Tetter Fairmont. Nel&gt; M 
Frederick &lt; ivti\ Nib it-i. 
. Callings Wahoo. Ncl) !n&gt;&gt; 
A. &lt; ar)&gt;enter York. Xeb !«l 
.. Lrwis York. Neb 
i. i 'ai'|M-nt&lt; r Onjr. Keb 
Hill &lt; I'caiiierv St. Paul. Neb !*• 

!&gt;-. Frederick Crete, Neb !*5J 

K. L. Lewis York. Neb *!• 

Sweepstake* premium a solid jroh) incihil J. K. Cullings, W»hoo </seg>



            <seg id="p079">
79 

I ORNAMENTAL BUTTKR. PRINTS AND SMALL PACKAGES 
premium — Fairmont Creamery, Fairmont. Xeb. 
premium — Beatrice Creamery Co., Lincoln. Net), 
premium — South Platte Creameries. York. Neb. 

CHEESE. 

A. F. Hartwell. Inavale. Neb. — Score «."&gt;. 

LATEST METHODS IX THE TREATMENT OF 
MILK FEVER. 

DR. J. H. GAIN, U. S. EXPERIMENT STATION, LINCOLN, NEB. 

I think the chairman has misled you a little in the title of this 
sr. In fact, I have not prepared any paper. I thought I 
d make this plainer in a short talk. 1 will not dwell so much 
he advancement, except in the line of prevention, but give 
the latest methods of treating this trouble. There is no 
ase that the dairyman dreads so much as milk fever. It 
:s not only his best cows, but at a time when they are most 

I he symptoms which usually appear within twenty-four hours 
¦ calving, are first an uneasiness, staggering gait, staring 
i, trembling of the limbs, the animal soon going down. As 
disease progresses there is a gradual loss of the senses. If 
g upon the breast, the head will be laid around on the side, 
arried around straight ahead, it ¦will be at once returned to 
side. If lying on the side the breathing will be loud and the 
insensitive to the touch. There is sometimes considerable 
iting, owing to the stoppage of digestion. 

Iin cold weather, the first thing to do is to get the animal 
m. The word "fever" in connection with this disease is mising, 
as the tenfperature is usually below normal. Perhaps 
most convenient way to warm the patient ; s by the use of hot 
er in bottles, jugs, fruit jars, etc. Put a blanket over the 
lal, then place bottles and jugs around, being careful not to 
any of them against the udder. Some of the bottles may be 
together by twos with a short string and hung across the </seg>

            <seg id="p080">
80 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

t Another blanket is then placed over all and by changing 
in the bottles as they become cool, the patient can soon be 
ed up and kept comfortable. 

We are now ready to give the Schmidt treatment. The veterinary 
journals advise in giving this, the use of a rubber tube 
and a funnel, but I think you will find a quart, screw-lop, fountain 
syringe much more convenient. Put two teaspoonfuls of iodide 
of potassium in a clean quart bottle. Put a funnel, into which a 
bunch of absorbant cotton is placed, into the bottle. Pour hot 
water, that has been boiled, into the funnel until the bottle is 
filled. If the bottle is warm, .boiling water can be used without 
cracking it. Cork the bottle tightly, wrap in a newspaper and 
it may be carried several miles in cold weather and still be warm 
enough for use. The udder is well milked out; the solution 
poured into the fountain syringe, the top screwed in, and, if still 
too warm, dropped into a bucket of water till at a temperature a 
few degrees above blood heat. A milk tube is placed in the end 
of the rubber tube of the syringe and inserted into one of the 
teats. The syringe is held up a few feet and one-fourth of the 
solution run into each quarter. The udder is now well kneaded 
and the solution allowed to remain about six hours when it 
should be milked out. Unless the animal gets up, this treatment 
should be repeated in twelve hours. The bladder should be 
emptied every eight hours by passing a catheter. No medicines 
should be given. When in this comatose condition liquids are 
quite apt to pass into the lungs, causing mechanical pneumonia. 

Ii cases where we have a very comatose condition, a saline 
tion injected into the jugular will be of benefit. Prepare 
tion the same as before, only in place of the iodide of potas-1, 
use a teaspoonful of salt. In injecting, the head is held out 
ight, an assistant places his fingers in the jugular groove, 
ping the flow of blood, which makes the vein stand out 
ninently. A small trocar and canula is thrust into the vein 
the trocar withdrawn leaving the canula. Blood will follow 
withdrawal of the trocar. Let the solution which is now in 
syringe at a temperature of about 104 degrees, flow from the </seg>

            <seg id="p081">
81 


I of the tube until it feels warm to the hand; the end of the 
: is then slipped over the head of the canula, the assistant 
oves the presure on the vein and the syringe being elevated 
w feet the solution flows into the vein. The pressure should 
be taken from the vein until the hose has been attached to 
canula in order to keep the air from entering the jugular, 
before the syringe is emptied the canula is withdrawn, thus 
renting air from being sucked in. The addition of one-half 
n of strychnine to the saline solution has given excellent 
ilts. This treatment should be repeated in twelve hours in 
cases. 

A German veterinarian has given, in over a hundred susceptible 
cases, two drams per month just before calving, followed 
by the same dose shortly after calving, with the result that the 
disease did not appear in any of the cases. If the iodide of 
potassium is a good curative treatment, it is certainly a good 
preventative measure, and we would suggest not only giving a 
dose shortly before and after calving, but would also advise giving 
at least one injection in the udder just after calving, in all 
suspected cases. 

Chairman: The next paper on the program this morning is 
"Practical Dairying in Central Nebraska and the Value of 
Alfalfa to the Dairyman," by Ralph E. Woods. 

I OGRESS OF PRACTICAL DAIRYING IN CKNrRAL 
NEBRASKA AND VALUE OF ALFALFA 
TO THE DAIRYMEN. 

RALPH E. WOODS, GIBBON, NEB. 

I am pleased to say that the dairy business is progressing 
quite satisfactorily in central Nebraska and Buffalo county. 

While the people of our section are proud of the record they 
have made so far, they look eagerly forward to greater develop- 

FIFIH SESSION. </seg>

            <seg id="p082">
82 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

ment and profit. Let us look back for a period of little more 
than three years and see in what an unsatisfactory condition the 
dairying business of central Nebraska was at that time. Farmers 
were milking all kinds of cows, some good, some bad, and some 
indifferent; some were gentle and some unruly. The miik 
was strained into cans, pans or crocks, and the cream was left 
to rise until gathered by the house-wife, then poured into a jar 
of goodly proportions and left to sour until a convenient time 
for churning and to gather a few microbes by the way-side. 
The day of churning having arrived, the cream was poured 
into any old kind of a churn, and then by great effort and 
muttering, turned into a very greasy looking mass. This 
butter, made after great exertion, was molded into rolls of different 
weights and taken to town and sold to the local grocer at 
prices ranging from eight cents per pound and up, which had 
to be taken out in trade; and of course in the general mix-up the 
grocer received a good price for his goods and a small profit 
on the "butter." 

A visit to the rear of the local grocery was amusing if not 
interesting. Here we found all kinds of butter being placed 
in a barrel. Some of this butter was of a poor quality. 
Some was white and some was yellow, and highly colored, and 
other butter of various colors, and the worst of it was that the 
people who did make a reasonably good grade of butter would 
find their product mixed with other butter little better than 
grease, and all at the same price. Quite naturally this was very 
discouraging to all producers as well as consumers, and consequently 
the profits were never very large. The producers said 
to themselves, "We cannot go to all this labor and expense for 
such small returns," and so dairying was decreasing at a very 
rapid rate in central Nebraska. The producers said, "We will 
leave dairying to the foreign born population, arid we will not 
milk cows, for it will not pay us for our troub/e." j This was 
the condition of the dairy industry a few years t&gt;acx in central 
Nebraska. 

Then a new light was flashed across the dark sky in. the form </seg>

            <seg id="p083">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

83 

of the separator station and the day was saved. How well do 
I remember the day the skimming station was opened in our 
town of Gibbon. The farmers had been invited to be present 
with their families and see the machinery in operation, also to 
bring a little milk and a well-filled lunch basket and enjoy a general 
good time. Some of the farmers could not be induced to 
attend, characterizing it as a "lightning rod" scheme, yet there 
was a good attendance. Some were interested, but about onehalf 
were there in idle curiosity. Those who went merely to 
see the working of the plant are to-day the best and largest 
patrons. 

While the Gibbon station has not been in operation very 
long, there were one hundred patrons during the summer 
months, and taking the month of June, 180,000 pounds of milk 
were received at the station. This was in less than two years 
from its opening. W. H. Bell, a patron, has alone delivered 
more than five tons of milk during that month. The business 
is rapidly increasing, in fact almost doubling yearly, and there 
is no doubt that 1902 will be the banner year for the station 
so far. 

All who have tried the skimming station's plan say they have 
been exceptionally well paid for their labor. During the year 
past nearly $14,000 was paid to the patrons of this station, 
direct in cash, and not over the counter of the local grocer. This 
amount will no doubt be doubled during the year 1902. There 
was but one fault found with the skimming stations, and that 
was by those living at a distance. This fault was the great 
expense of hauling, and the milk after being separated and 
mixed with the products of other herds ;ind hauled through the 
hot sun became thick. Many of the calves did not do well and 
became stunted. This fault does not exist a short distance from 
the station, so the hand separator is coming into general use by 
those who reside at a great distance, because hand-separated 
milk is as good for a calf, when kept sweet, as is whole milk, 
and if a calf so fed receives proper attention, it will make as 
good growth as a majority of calves that run with their mother. </seg>

            <seg id="p084">
84 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

I have seen some skim-milk calves that were much in advance 
of those that had run with the cows, the reason being that they 
had learned to eat grain, and hay, and when weaning time came 
they did not feel the loss in any great way, and so kept right 
on growing. 

I) central Nebraska the people have learned that the calf is a 
lable adjunct to the dairy, whether it is a so-called "separator 
" or not, and should receive careful attention. The calf at 
end of the year should be worth $15 to $20, and not $5 and 
The mortgage-lifting cow starts with the calf. 

(. D. Watson, of the great Watson ranch, which contains 
it 8,000 acres, and is located four miles west of Kearney, 
:ves that Holsteins are the ideal dairy cattle, and he has 
e than 300 fine specimens in one of the finest and largest 
y barns in the world. 

As dairying has progressed in central Nebraska, practical 
dairymen have learned that in order to obtain best results, cows 
must not be subjected to the torturing stanchions of other days. 
The new cow barns will contain a separate stall for each cow, 
a rope behind keeping her from getting out, and she will be 
made to "feel at home." It was generally supposed that any 
one could make a great success of the business in central 
Nebraska. Not so. The brutal, noisy man can not successfully 
handle the dairy business. It has been found that the work 
calls for genile, cool and sober men, wilh brains, push and 
enthusiasm, and as in other work, a love and inspiration for the 
business. 

Katurally dairymen want the best and cheapest feed for the 
s, and 

THE VALUE OF ALFALFA TO THE DAIRYMAN 

tnot be too highly estimated. Alfalfa is, and will be the 
test aid to the dairymen of any crop that can be grown in 
al Nebraska. Alfalfa, whether green or dry, is one of the 
test known forage crops to produce a large flow of rich, 
-testing milk. Mr. Watson has 2500 acres of alfalfa near </seg>

            <seg id="p085">
85 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

his dairy barn in Buffalo county. There are 28,680 acres of 
alfalfa in Buffalo county to-day; 21,480 acres were sown last 
spring, and it is thought that 30,000 acres will be sown the 
coming spring, making a total acreage in Buffalo county alone 
the coming season of 59,680 acres, to be increased from year to 
year. As alfalfa roots go down to water or moisture the 
established crop is good for at least ten years, without receding. 
Quite naturally, we hope in time to see these alfalfa farms 
become dairy farms in Buffalo county. 

I wish to illustrate the value of alfalfa as a dairy crop. A 
good cow can be well pastured on a single acre of alfalfa 
throughout the summer months and reserving the product of 
another acre for hay, we cut from three to five tons of the very 
finest hay, which will keep a cow in fine condition throughout 
the winter. Then it is evident that, two acres of alfalfa will 
keep a cow twelve months in the best condition. Milking this 
cow but eight months of this period, and getting but $4 per 
month for butter-fat, we have received $32, besides as an additional 
recompense for our labor we have a fine calf, worth $15, 
that will soon grow into a fine steer or heifer. We have at this 
conservative estimate received $47 for the product of two acres 
of land. I feel that this can be greatly and easily increased. 
This should be of interest to investors. 

Iugar beets are also a great feed and aid in the dairy busi:, 
and a field of sugar beets should be grown by every dairy-1; 
18 tons of beets and five tons of tops can be grown on a 
le acre of land in Buffalo county. Cows will leave almost 
•ther feeds to partake of sugar beet tops, which will increase 
flow of milk very materially, and with alfalfa we have two 
he greatest aids in the feed line to the dairyman. Sugar 
: pulp is valuable when it can be obtained. A ton of sugar 
:s is worth about $3 on the ground, and I believe every cow 
ild be allowed at least one ton of beets during the winmonths. 


There- are about 3,000 farmers in Buffalo county. Of these 
about 500 are engaged in selling milk and hand separated cream. </seg>

            <seg id="p086">
86 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

twe look expectantly forward to the time when the major 
ion of these will be milking from five to fifty cows each, 
re are about eighty hand separators in the county of Buffalo, 
four-fifths of those engaged in the business are as yet withthese 
little, yet great and useful, labor-saving machines'. 
day is surely coming when they and many others will posthe 
ideal hand separator. 

The dairy business is as yet in its infancy, but steadily growing. 
There are thousands of acres of land in Buffalo county suitable 
for the growing of alfalfa and sugar beets. Excellent water 
is close to the surface and 1 sincerely believe that there are 
greater opportunities and better advantages offered in Buffalo 
county to the practical dairyman who possesses energy, knowledge 
and perseverance, for small capital, than any other portion of 
Nebraska. I am proud to say that the dairy business is 
rapidly growing in our progressive section, and generally 
throughout Nebraska. May this progress ntver be hindered 
until our wealthy state carries the banner in this line, and all 
eyes shall be turned upon our great commonwealth — Nebraska! 

DISCUSSION. 

Chairman: Is there any discussion, this morning, on the subject, 
"Practical Dairying and the Value of Alfalfa?" 

Mrs. Lott: Mr. Chairman, do you think it would be 
improper for me to ask a question? I would like to know what 
we are to understand that dairying means. Is it simply the 
creamery business? If it is I have nothing more to say. Do we 
understand that dairying means to us farmers simply to get the 
cows, the separator, the refrigerator and the ice, and milk our 
cows, separate the milk and haul it off to the creameries? 

Chairman: No. 

KIrs. Lott: It seem to me I have heard nothing else since 
have been here along the line of dairying but simply cream-8 
and separators. I am very much disappointed. I expected </seg>

            <seg id="p087">
87 

SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

KMT in this meeting something practical for our farmers and 
ers' wives. 

Chairman: The reason is, I suppose, from the fact that 
those who attend the meeting are mobt interested in that branch 
of dairying in which they sell their product to some creamery 
or manufacturer of butter. The dairy business does not mean 
that a man shall produce cream for sale to any particular individual. 
The dairy business means the production of milk, the 
selling of which shall be done in that manner which will bring 
the greatest return back to the man, no matter how he does it. 
I think it is along this line that the Dairymen's Association in 
the State of Nebraska has been working all the time — to find the 
best means whereby the greatest number of people can dispose 
of their product to the best advantage. We would be glad to 
hear from anybody, any private dairyman, or anyone who is 
making butter to learn the best plan and get the best results. 

A Member: I think one of the reasons why we hear the 
hand separator talked of so much is that we are practically on 
the verge of a reformation in the manner of dairying. We have 
noi tried to create or make a private market for our butter. We 
have been taking our butter to the store and selling it for twelve 
and a half cents a pound this winter. I am simply getting tired 
of it, because every time there is a churning made, with an 
elegant lot of butter — for I must say so, if there is anything that my 
wife can do it is to make good butter — she turns out a nice lot 
of butter and then she will turn around and give me a twentytive 
dollar lecture on having to take that nice lot of butter to the 
store. As I say, I am tired of it. I figured on this matter all 
last summer and fall and I am now ready to put in a separator 
and turn my cream over to some creamery company that gathers 
the cream and I figure I can get double my profits per cow by 
doing so — by managing the business in that way than I can to 
churn butter. If we tried the plan where we are to create a 
private market, we would have to go to the city. It is quite a 
ways to Lincoln. We are offered a very nice thing to furnish 
butter here in Lincoln, but it is such a trouble and expense to </seg>

            <seg id="p088">
88 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

»it here in good shape that I prefer selling the cream. There, 
I am interested in the separator and I am pleased to hear 
matter of separators discussed. (Applause.) 

Krs. L.ott: I would like to say that I am not against the 
rator. If we have only a few cows I would think we must 
separators just the same, because it is so convenient. 

I do not believe there is any need of our taking twelve and a 
half cents a pound for our butter. I do not believe there is any 
need of us going to the city. I realize it costs considerable to 
get butter up to the city, and right across the road from us is a 
neighbor lady who takes from six to eight pounds of butter at 
fifteen cents a pound. We never took less than eighteen cents 
a pound. The lady was telling me the other day that when she 
took butter to the store they dumped it all in a pile, and it was 
put with such butter as I would not have upon my table. I do 
not mean to say anything about anybody's butter, but I say I do 
not think we are educated up to where we ought to be as farmers, 
and it seems to me that these meetings ought to be to educate 
one another. We have had a good market all summer; our butter 
is put up in brick form or wrapped with butter parchment 
paper. What I would like to have done is for us farmers to be 
educated up to where we can all make butter and make it good. 
My neighbor said that when she found the grocers threw her 
butter into a pile with such inferior butter, she made up her 
mind there was no use of making extra fine butter and working 
so hard and getting so little for it. We do not come up to the 
standard of butter making, but we can, just as well as creameries 

Excuse me for taking so much of your time. 

Mr. Bassett: I wish to say a word in answer to the criticism 
of our program. It is very difficult to prepare a program 
of such a meeting as this, as you would understand if you had 
experience in arranging one. 1 have a certain acquaintance 
through the state. I have met the dairymen of the state from 
year to year for the last seventeen years, and when it comes to 
preparing a program, I ask certain parties if they will prepare a </seg>

            <seg id="p089">
89 


paper for the meeting; that if they will we will pay their railroad 
fare and hotel bills. I find it difficult to get them interested 
enough to take a place on the program. I write to a number of 
private dairymen and request them to attend our meeting to discuss 
matters of some interest to the private dairymen. I have 
tried time and time again to work up more of an interest among 
private dairymen, but the fact of the case is a large majority of 
them, those who make and sell butter, say they cannot afford to 
come, or at all events they do not come. That is one reason why 
we have no papers on butter-making on the farm; not because it 
was intentional, but simply from the fact that we could not develop 
enough interest to secure the attendance of persons thus interested. 
Another feature is, that while there are some women 
who love to make butter on the farm, the large majority do not. 
The methods of to-day are largely doing away with the making 
of butter on the farm. Where one has a line of customers to 
whom they can sell their butter at a fair price, they can make a 
fair compensation for their labor, but ninety-five per cent of our 
dairymen can get more money out of butter-fat sold to the 
creamery than they can to make it into butter. 

I should like to say a word here in reference to the value of 
alfalfa. Mr. Woods has mentioned it in his paper, one of the 
most important that we have had here at this session. Those of 
you who live in the eastern part of the state do not realize the 
importance of alfalfa as a forage plant, not only for dairymen, 
but for all classes of stockraisers. 

This last year, as you well know, was exceedingly hot as well 
as dry, and our corn and oats, as well as forage crops were very 
poor, nearly a failure. Yet, notwithstanding the intense heat 
and lack of moisture, the alfalfa fields, without irrigation, produced 
two and some three cuttings of hay of finest quality. The 
alfalfa plant, which produces a paying crop under such discouraging 
conditions, is of almost inestimable value. The fact 
that it is perennial, producing crops year after year, with no 
expense aside from harvesting, is an additional point in its favor. 
Every farm in this state should have its field of alfalfa, which 

7 </seg>

            <seg id="p090">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

90 

I prove by far the most profitable one. It will well pay the 
ers of this state to cultivate an acquaintance with the alfalfa 

G. N. Congers: I have on my place about no acres of 
alfalfa. I don't think it is just the thing for me to say, but 
I am at present feeding my dairy cows nothing but alfalfa hay. 
One reason, perhaps, is that out there where I live I cannot get 
mill stuffs, such as bran, shorts and anything like that. I put 
my cows in the lot last July and filled the racks with alfalfa hay 
and have fed them the same ever since. One cow was making 
nearly two pounds of butter per day when I turned her in the 
lot; to-day after running in the lot with absolutely no feed but 
alfalfa hay and water, she is making i V± lbs. per day. I have 
another cow of the shorthorn breed. I put her in there about 
the 20th of July. She gained 180 lbs. in flesh up to the first of 
January, and has given a nice pail of milk each time, but her 
milk is not as rich. She will make of a pound of butter a 
day. As long as they are doing that well it is not necessary to 
feed high-priced feed or for me to invest in 75 cent corn. 

I am satisfied that alfalfa for hay, is one of the greatest blessings 
for the farmers in this country. As the gentleman said in 
his paper read this morning, a couple of acres of alfalfa hay will 
keep a cow a year. When you consider the expense, I think 
there is pretty good profit in it. I have also figured out the 
hand separator business. It is the best thing for the farmers of 
this country. 

B. R. Stouffer: I find some of my neighbors have been 
using alfalfa in their silos. One of my neighbors says he will 
never grow an an acre of corn for silo use. I think if you are 
going to have ensilage, I would certainly have it made with 
alfalfa hay in preference to corn. Alfalfa comes the nearest to 
being a perfect balanced ration ; I consider you cannot compare 
it to any other crop. 

Prof. Haecker: I would like to say a few words on the 
value of alfalfa hay for feeding purposes. As I have before 
said, I am carrying on an experiment on this subject as compared </seg>

            <seg id="p091">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

91 

11 other hay. I have had some experience along this line for 
past five years. When I feed half alfalfa and half ensilage I 
a much more satisfactory return from my cows. 

Alfalfa alone is too narrow a ration. Alfalfa is not a balanced 
feed of itself. Any authority on feed will acknowledge 
that. When we feed strictly alfalfa hay to the dairy cow we are 
giving her, of course, a good ration, but we are not giving her a 
balanced ration in some particulars. It is a detriment to a cow 
to receive food that she cannot make use of. It becomes waste 
product. It is waste to feed strictly alfalfa to a cow and nothing 
else; but if there is to be only one feed, I believe alfalfa is the 

Then I believe it will pay us in Nebraska, especially in the 
western part, to put in a few acres of sorghum. Cure it up well 
and mix with some other nice hay. Let her get a little of the 
sorghum. It will give the cow some of the carbo-hydrate that 
she needs. We find a great deal of carbo-hydrate in milk. 
Cure up some corn stover, hay, millet, or some forage. That 
little portion of carbo-hydrate will balance her ration and you 
will get the best result. Last year I fed my cows very carefully; 
I fed them nothing but alfalfa hay for roughness; for 
grain I fed them half corn and half bran. I did not get the 
result that I did the first year when I fed alfalfa hay and silage, 
half and half by weight for roughness, and then balanced that 
with grain feed, oats one part, bran one part and corn one part. 
I believe, gentlemen of the convention, in order to get the best 
results in feeding alfalfa hay, you will find if you give the animal 
a little variety, corn-fodder, sorghum, millet, prairie hay, you 
will then get the best results and get them cheaper — because 
corn-fodder is as cheap as any feed, and we can raise it, especially 
sorghum, and it will grow where nothing else will. 

Question: What was your ensilage? 

Answer: My ensilage was made of corn cut up when in the 
dough, which is about the time when the tassel begins to turn; 
cut it up and put it in the silo. That year I got the best results 
from my herd, and I kept the same cows for three years. </seg>


            <seg id="p092">
92 

* 

twant to say further that this year we are feeding sugar beets 
I believe we have a grand feed. I might say that I have 
1 conducting experiments on the state farm for five years, 
have from 10 to 15 cows, all big producers, producing all 
way from 300 lbs. to 500 lbs. of butter a year. I have not 
a single case of milk fever. My success, I think, has been 
le line of succulent feed. I have fed sugar beets to every 
of the cows before calving. One year when we did not 
: any sugar beets, we fed mangel-wurzel. 

SOME HAND SEPARATOR PROBLEMS. 

PROF. A. L. HAECKER, STATE UNIVERSITY. 

iefore taking up my paper I wish to make a few remarks on 
year's program of the association. You have all noticed, 
doubt, that it is one-sided, and the heavy side deals with 
i separator subjects. I do not mean to criticize the secre's 
arrangement, for I believe it is all right, being the result 
xisting conditions. 

ior example, when Mr. Bassett asked me to name my subject, 
ose one which I had been giving thought and study. It was 
oblem of the times, as a result of a new system in dairy 
tice. So the program was influenced in a natural and 
&gt;er way, and the secretary showed good judgment in allowit 
to take such a course. 

As advancements have been made along all industrial lines, so 
has the dairy industry changed. We have passed from the old 
shallow pan and dasher-churn to the present systems. Four 
great changes or systems have marked this dairy development. 
The first general change was that made from the old primitive 
shallow pan to the cooly or shot-gun can. Associated with this 
followed the creamery, run on the gathered-cream plan. This 
step was certainly an advancing one, for it simplified the creaming 
process and brought a market to the dairyman's door. 
This resulted in a uniform article of butter being made, which 
sold for a good price the year round. </seg>


            <seg id="p093">
93 

fhe second change was the result of the invention of the cengal 
separator, which made possible the creamery of to-day. 
usands of these plants are now running, and wherever they 
we know a healthful, soil-enriching and prosperous enter: 
is going on. 

Ksome states they count the number of creameries in a 
ty as an index of its wealth. 

The next two steps were along the line of separator derelopment 
rather than improved invention. 

Etie skimming stations in the west made possible a market in 
ly every township, and wherever a train stopped cream 
i be shipped to a central churning depot. 

The skimming station brought relief to the struggling home 
dairies, encouraging and developing the industry. In sections 
where dairying was considered almost impossible a strong enterprise 
grew up. The range, the arid and the mountain regions, 
until in no section could it be said that dairying was out of place. 

Irom the skimming station we now come to another systemhand 
separator, bringing the market still closer to the farmer 
making him more independent. The hand separator sysnot 
only doing away with the creamery or skimming 
on, but simply filling in a long felt want. 

Iondiiions here in the west favor this system, and being a 
)le quick to take up improvements, we have gone at a bound 
the hand separators. It is safe to say that not less than six 
isand (6,000) hand machines are being operated in this state 
ay. 

fpon this new change and the problems naturally concerning 
wish to make my remarks. 

Iirst, let us remember that when the hand separator comes 
the creamery territory, a great responsibility is shifted from 
butter-maker to the patron. The patron is then responsible 
the quality of the butter more than ever before, for he now 
the creaming process and in part the ripening, whereas he 
1 to have simply milk production. Then he is a cream pro;r 
instead of a milk producer. </seg>

            <seg id="p094">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

94 

Pirn may be disposed of in several ways; as made into 
le farm, sold to the skimming station or creamery, or 
cream buyers. The patron must figure for himself 
which pays him the best. 

The question of whether or not to buy a separator is difficult 
at times to answer. Conditions of course must be considered. 
A man living near a good creamery or skimming station might 
lind it easier and better to haul his milk than to separate at 
home. Distance from creamery lends much enchantment to buying 
a hand separator. It is not only easier to care for, but also 
to haul a small amount of cream, than a large amount of milk. 

»do not believe any man can afford to cream the milk of more 
i five cows by the gravity process. The waste is too great 
his time too precious 

Eie increased value of hand separator skim-milk over that 
uced by skim-station or creamery is worth considering, and 
rises a point which it might be well to mention. 

Where the hand separator is used, the time to separate is 
during or immediately after milking — while the milk is still 
warm from the cow. Then the calves can be fed the fresh, 
warm milk, the cream aired and cooled and the machine easilv 
washed. 

As to the kind of machine, there are many to choose from, 
and I am glad the competition is growing sharp, for it brings the 
price down and the capacity up, with a stimulated desire to 
improve. Where cream is to be shipped, the per cent of butterfat 
should be high, as it is poor economy to pay express on 
skim-milk, and thew the cream keeps better. A separator 
should be able to skim a 40 per cent or 45 per cent cream without 
loss of fat. A water diluting can is not a separator, but a 
gravity-creamer and will not do much better work than the 
cooly-can. I mention this, for they are still being sold in some 
localities as separators. 

Kile it is not wise to separate cold milk, it is often very cont, 
and a machine should do good work at a temperature 
as 70 0 F. </seg>

            <seg id="p095">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

95 

The care of the separator has been well discussed by other 
papers, but I am tempted to still further add to the good work. 
Over-ambitious separator agents in order to strengthen their 
argument, have told some buyers that they would not have to 
deliver their cream but once or twice a week, and that the 
separator needed washing after every other run. 

t:h teaching has caused harm to hand separator butter, for 
under some conditions such practice might be all right, it in 
cases works harm. 

If a high-grade butter is made from hand separator cream 
where it is gathered from many patrons, great care must be 
used to deliver sweet, untainted cream. 

I 'he separator should be washed as often as the strainer or 
:pail, and that after each using. There is a temptation to 
h the separator parts in the dish-water that has washed 
dishes. This should never be done, as it is dangerous and 
initary. With a brush and a little clean hot water the 
:s may be quickly and well washed. A little washing 
rder can be added to good advantage to remove the oily 
ct of the cream. To dry, put the parts near a warm stove, 
&gt;etter still, in the sunshine — Nature's great disinfectant. 

There seems to be considerable trouble and misunderstanding 
in finding the value of cream. We have at best two practical 
methods of testing cream for butter-fat — the well-known Babcock 
test and the oil test, which was formerly used by the 
gathered cream operators. The Babcock test is the one generally 
used at the present time, and while a simply and easily 
manipulated test, it is often improperly used in cream-testing. 

Enyone selling cream, whether to the factory, cream-buyer, 
:ream maker or milk depot, is selling a product having much 
ation, which can only be found by a careful iest. Cream 
be 15 per cent or 45 per cent fat, and only \i the per cent 
it can it be measured. The fat is the basis or true value the 
e as the weight in grains. 

t testing cream having a variable per cent of fat, you can 
get accurate results by using uniform volumetric samples. </seg>

            <seg id="p096">
96 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

¦illustrate this I offer the following table which may be faulty 
general use, but will show the results I obtained from testing 

two samples of cream : 

SOUB CREAM SWEET CREAM 

Bf measure IK OC. pii&gt;ette rinsed down 27.10* fat 23.30% fat 

By measure 17. ti oc. ]&gt;ii&gt;ette rinsed down 2t&gt;.00% fat 22."&gt;O% fat 

By measure 1* &gt;•&lt;•. pipette not rinsed down i"&gt;.."&gt;OSt fat ~.t*&lt;&gt;% fat 

By measure 17.11 it. pi]&gt;ette not rinsed down iVtlOJf fat 21.80% fat 
It will be seen from this table that there is quite a difference 

Konly between sweet and sour cream, but also weighed and 
sured samples. Sour cream having within it more gas is 
ter per volume and a larger sample must be used when made 

by volume than when the sample is made from sweet cream. 
After considering the great variation caused by using an 

tteen (18 cc.) or seventeen and six-tenths (17.6 cc.) pipette, 
whether or not it be rinsed down into the test bottle, and 
itions caused by different temperatures, varying viscosity, 
lopment of acid, etc., I am led to believe that the only fair 

Bto find the value of cream is by weighing the sample, 
the cream samples are not weighed, an eighteen cc. pipette 

Iild be used and the cream adhearing to the inside, washed 
n into the test bottle. The richer in butter-fat the cream, 
more important it is to weigh the sample. Where the cream 
the neighborhood of 25 per cent, an 18 cc. pipette will give 
results; when it is below 20 per cent, a 17.6 cc. pipette, 
ed down, will be nearer, but for accurate results a weighed 

18 grams sample is the best method. 

Question : I would like to ask in regard to the age of the 

cream — that is, whether it makes any difference in the test if the 

cream is old or new. 

Haecker: Cream fresh from the separator will contain a 

tl amount of air and perhaps be a little lighter. Sour cream 
little lighter, which would be old. Where you weigh your 

Kple there would be no difference, as fat will not evaporate. 
uestion : I would like to know if it is necessary to use as 

much acid in testing cream as in testing milk? 

By weight 18 grmmm&lt;-».&lt;m% fat Z\.M)% fat </seg>

            <seg id="p097">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

97 

Answer : No. I use from 14 to 15 cc. Cream has less 
solids to destroy so requires less acid. 

Question: How as to temperature? 

Answer: The warmer the cream and acid, the stronger the 
acid will work and the reverse. Try and get average temperatures 
in testing and regulate your amount of acid by the color of 
the fat in the completed test. A rich straw color gives the best 
results. When too light, use more acid — when too dark use 

Khairman: We will now have the report of the committee 
notations. 

Committee on resolutions reported as follows : 

BetrAved, That the thanks of this convention be extended to Mrs. Bertha 
D. Laws, Dr. W. A. Thomas. If. F. Greeley. Prof. T. L. Lyon. 15. K. 
Kmily. Dr. J. H. Gain. J. F. Schlappi, F. M. Housh. F. A. Lei^hton. 
Kalph K. Woods ami Prof. A. L. Haeeker for their able and instructive 
addresses before this convention. 

Rtaiilreih That we earnestly recommend K. Sudendorf. Kljrin, 111., as 
su|&gt;erintendent of the dairy department at the Louisiana Purchase ! 
sition to be held in St. Louis in IMS. 

E'lrui. That the courtesies extended to the Nebraska Dairymen's 
iation by the University authorities are grcatlj appreciated and 
our annual home coming to this city one of the most pleasan' 
Of the year. 

thai, By the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association in convention 
bled, That we earnestly request our senators and representatives in 
j ss to support the bill recommended l&gt;y the committee on ;i . 
"to make oleomargarine and other imitation dairy |Nufaul 
the laws of the state, territory or district into which they are trans. 
and to change the tax on oleomargarine." 

Huolved, That the secretary be requested to send a copy of this resolution 
to each one of our senators and representatives in congress. 

Bn motion duly seconded, the resolutions were adopted as 

{[r. Bassett: The matter of offering special premiums at 
dairy conventions has grown to be quite unsatisfactory to 
y supply firms and not in favor. I have been handed the 
wing resolution, which I will read : 

•• He&amp;&gt;lrtd, That this association approves of the suggestion of dairy 
supply firms, that no special premiums be offered for dairy exhibits, at </seg>

            <seg id="p098">
98 

NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

the annual dairy exhibit, and it is hereby ordered that no such special premiums 
be received or offered. " 

I move the adoption of this resolution. 
The motion was duly seconded and carried. 

Kh airman : We will now receive the report of the committee 
ominations. 

The committee reported as follows : 

f[r. President, your committee on nominations beg to make 
following report: 

For president — E. S. Snively, Lincoln. 
For vice-president — T. S. Pexton, Neligh. 

For secretary and treasurer — S. C. Bassett, Gibbon 

I or directors — J. K. Honeywell, Lincoln; Frank E. Pratt, 
mont; J. C. Merrill, Sutton; C. A. Clark, Ravenna; B. R. 
jffer, South Omaha. 

Ei motion duly seconded the report of the committee was 
ted, and the persons therein named were declared duly 
ed to the respective office for which they had been nominated. </seg>

            <seg id="p099">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

99 

LIST OF CREAMERIES IN NEBRASKA. 

MANAGER OB PRO- _ o ,_ Ir _ ..„„.,. 
PKIETOR POST-OFFICE COO»TT 

KAMI OF CREAMERY 

Ic. W. Moss Amelia Holt 

¦Creamery Co 
Creamery Co 
Onter Creamery 
in Creamery Co. . 
rd Creamery — 

J. E. Barnes. Sec . .. Arcada Valley 

Hansen &amp; Templln .Archer lierrlck 

J J. Stillson Atkinson Holt 

Harry Splndler Meek Holt 

h.d Me Bride.. '...'.'.'.'. Blue Hill.. ".".'.". Webster 

Blue Hill Creamery. . 
Bismark Creamery 
Beatrice Creamery Co 

J. W James Uolumbus Platte 

Ueo. E. Haskell. PreslLincoln iLnnoartT 

Adams jGatfe 

Answorth Brown 

Alliance Box Buite 

Alma Harlan 

Ansley Custer 

.Ansiey !». usier 
Araeo Richardson 

Arapahoe ... . Furnas 

Ashion Sherman 

Atlanta. Phelpo 

Axtel Kearney 

A m hers t Buffalo 

Brady Lincoln 

Butte Boyd 

Beatrice Gage 

Box Butte Box Butte 

Broken Bow 

Beaver City. . . Furnas 

Benrand Phclps 

! Iheyenne 
K'-iiuoiit IDawes 

Ua«e» 

Benkelman ... Oundy 

Bennett Lancaster 

Bloomington.. .Franklin 

Burwell Garfield 

.Cortland Gaise 
Cullaway .... 

• 

Comstoclt 

Cambridge.... Furnas 

Crawford Dawes 

iCreston Plntte 

Camplwll Franklin 

Cbampion Chase 

Culbenson.. ..Hitchcock 

(happell Deuel 

Curtis Frontier 

Clarkson Colfax 

Denmarx iLinco&gt;n 

Demon Lancaster 

Danbury Red Willow 

nunbar ptoe 
Eustis Fron 

Frontier 

Elmwood Cass 

Eddyville jDawson 

Eauie Cans 

Elm Creek.... Buffalo 

Elsie Perkins 

Elwood Gosper 

Franklin ... .Franklin 

Farnam Dawson 

Greeley Greeley 

Boyd 

Gothenburg ¦ • Dawson 

liihbon |Buffalo 

Grant Perkins 

Gosper . . 
Gordon. . 

Gosper 

. ¦Ssheri.Un 

Guide Rock 
Hemlniiford 
Huntley .. .. 

Humboldt. 


•Sklmmi 

•g Stations. </seg>

            <seg id="p100">
100 


,», 

MAllA , G !iS!L PBO " post-office 

KAMI OF CHIAMEKT 


PHIETOB 

•Beatrice Creamery Co Geo. E. HaskHl 

I 

res Holbrook Furnas 

• 

Holdrege Phelps 

Haigler Liundy 
Havclock Laocae 


Hildretb Franklin 

! H;iy .Springs . . jsheridan 

• nter iHayes 

Imperial Chase 

Indianola Red Willow 

Kearney Buffalo 

Lanham Gaffe 

Long Pine Brown 

Lawn Box Butte 

Lodge Pole .... Cheyenne 

I Lynch Boyd 

Lama r Chase 

Lexington Duwson 

Linwood Butler 

Ma*iol Harlan 

Merna Cu*ier 

Marsland Dates 

May wood... . Frontier 

McCook Red Willow 

Miller Buffalo 

Naper Bojrd 

North Platte.. Lincoln 

Orltans Hurlun 

Oi-onto Caster 

Oxford Kurnas 

Overlon Uawson 

Princeton LancaMer 

Palisade Hiichi-mk 

Ph-asanton Buffalo 

l'cierslmrg Boone 

Kepublic'nCHy Harlan 

Kushville Sheridan 

&gt;ar*reant Custcr 

Cheyenne 


Spencer Boyd 

Straiton Hitchcock 

iSyr^cuse Ouie 

Scribner Dodge 

Sutherland.... Lincoln 

Sparus Chirry 

Sterling Johnson 

SlUart Holt 

Spauiding Greelejr 

Trenton Hitchcock 

ITurlington . . . Otoe 

.Taylor^ Loop 

Verdon . . 
Venantfo 

Kichardson 

Perkins 

Valentine Cherry 

WiKonville . Furna'&gt; 

Wauneia Cha*e 

Wallace 
Welltieet 

Lincoln 

Lincoln 

Wolhach .... Greelej 

Atwood Rawllriirs. Kan 

Baker Brown. 

Bremen Marshall 
Blue H»plds.. 

Barnes WashKfn. ¦ 

Bern Nemaha. 

Cuba Kepublic. 

Herndon KawlingK. 

Hanover Wash'gt n, • 
Haddam ... . 

Long Island... Phillips. 
Luctor 

Morrlll Brown. 

1st. Francis Cheyenne 

•Skimming Stations </seg>


            <seg id="p101">
101 

.ami or ammmm "*" pb'Sto" I&gt;B °" ' w*T-orric« couwtr 

¦ AMI Or CREAMIBT 

Beatrice Creamery Co Oeo. E. Haskell. Pres WaterviUe . . . . Marshall. Ki 

Beatrice Creamer y Co 

Qeo. E. Haskell. Pres Waterville .... ! Marshall. Kan 

•• ¦• Washington... Wuh'n'll. • 

Washington . . . Wash'gt'n. •• 

" •• Julesburg Sedgwick. C 

Julesburg Sedewtck. Col. 

'• •¦ ¦• Brush Morgan 
" ¦• Holyoke Phillips. ¦ 

Brusb Morgan. 

Holvoke .Phillips. 

" •• '• Haxtun 
'• •¦ Campbell Franklin.Ni 

Haxtun 

Campbell 
N. N. Bendz Carleton 

Franklin. Neb. 

Thayer 

Carleton Creamery Co N. N. Bendz Carleton Thayer 

Carleton Creamery Co 
Daanebrog Creamery 

Dannebrog Creamery S. B. Knudsen Dannebrog — Howard 

S. B. Knudsen Dannebrog. 
P. S. Pexton. Secy . Neligh 
I. E. Cahoon Fonlanelle.. 

Howard 

Farmers' Co-op. Creamery Ass n F. S. Pexton. Secy . Neligh Antelope 

Antelope 

Fanners' Coop. Creamery Ass n 

Fontanelle Creamery I. E. Cahoon Fontanelle... i Washington 

Fontanelle Creamery 

Washington 

" •¦ ...... Hooper 
J. Hess NewmanUr've 

" •¦ Hooper Dodge 

Dodge 

Farmers' Creamery Co J. Hess Newman Gr've Madison 

Newman G r vel Madison 

Farmers' Creamery Co 

Newman Ur'vi 
Fairmont 

Fairmont Creamery 

Fairmont Creamery J. H. Rusbton. Pres.. Fairmont Flllmore 

J. H. Rusbton. Pres" Fairmont Ftllmore 

" •• Crete Saline 

Crete Saline 

" '• " Fairbury Jefferson 

Fairbury Jefferson 

¦¦ ¦• DeWltt Saline 

DeWltt Saline 

•• " Ohiowa Flllmore 

Ohiowa Fillmore 

" ¦• iToblas Saline 

iTobias Saline 

•• " Dorchester... 

Dorchester 

'• •¦ " -aline Center. 

-aline Center. 
Wilbur 

•• ¦¦ Wilbur 
• •• Western 

Western 
Beaver Cn&gt;3'g. 

•• " Beaver Croag. Seward 

Sewani 

•• ¦¦ Mllford 

Milford 

•• " Pleasant Dale 
• Plymouth Jefferson 

Pleasant Dale 

Plymouth 
Jansen 

JetTerson 

1 *¦ " " Jensen 

1 •• • " '¦ Bower 

Bower 

•¦ '¦ 'Steele City 

Steele City 

1 ¦ " " " Holland Lancaster 

Holland Lancaster 

" " Hickman " 

Hickman . 

" ¦• Saltlllo 

Saltlllo 

" " iFirth 

Firth 

•' Alexandria . Thayer 

Alexandria . Thayer 

" " Kiowa 

Kiowa 

Grafton Creamery Co Jas. Healey Graf ton Fillmore 

Graf ton Creamery Co 

Jas. Healey Grafton Fillmore 

Gtrmantown Co-op. Creamery Cc 
Grand Island Creamery 

Germantown Co-op. Creamery Co E. H. K£ch Germantown . Seward 

K. H. Kpch Germantown . Seward 

Grand Island Creamery O. Roeser Grand Island.. Hall 

O. Roeser Grand Island. Hall 

Golden Rod Creamery F. E. Pratt Fremont Dcxlire 

Golden Rod Creamery 
Hampton Creamery.. 
Hart ing ton Creamery 

F. E. Pratt Fremont Dcxiire 

Hampton Creamery Joshua Cox Hampton Hamilton 

JosbuaCox Hampton Hamilton 

Hartington Creamery Hanna &amp; Swanson . . . i Harrington .. . Cedar 

Hanna &amp; Swanson . . . Harrington . . . Cedar 

Kohl 

1 ** " " " Constance 
•' •¦ " East Bow 

IConstnnce 

East Bow 

•• West Bow Dixon 

West Bow Dixon 
St. James Cedar 

1 " '• ¦¦ " St. James Cedar 

Henderson Creamery Joshua Cox Henderson York 

Heoderson Creamery 
Hyceia Creamery Co 

Joshua Cox Henderson York 

Hypeia Creamery Co Charles Harding . . Omaha Douglas 

Charles Harding Omaha Douglas 

•• Herman Washington 

Herman Washington 

1 " " ¦¦ " Kennard Washington 

jKennard -Washington 
J. H. Kruger Hadar Pierce 

Hadar Creamery J. H. Kruger I Hadar Pierce 

Hadar Creamery 

Ideal Creamery Co r. F. Bush.. Ons Clay 

Ideal Creamery' Co 

F. Bu?h Oni; May 

Laurel Butter Co L. C. Tolles. Mgr Laurel Cedar 

Laurel Butter Co 

L. C. Tolles. Mgr Laurel Cedar 

Lyons Creamery Co W. H. Lyon, Sec I-.vods Burt 

Lyons Creamery Co 
Legge Creamery Co 

W. H. Lyon. Sec Lyons 
Geo. Legge Rogers 
E. McBrfde Lawrence 

Burt 

Leirge Creamery Co Geo. Legge Rouers Coif ax 

Colfax 

Lawrence Creamery E. Me Bride Lawrence Nuckolls 

Lawrence Creamery 

Nuckolls 

lfartfnsburg Creamery J. E. Shultz Marti nsburg . Dixon 

Martinsburg Creamery 

J. E. Sbultz MartinsburK Dnon 

Minden Creamery C. G. Bendrup Mlnden Kearney 

Minden Creamery 

C'.U.Bendrup Minden Kearney 

Meade Creamery Bishop &amp; Withrow . ICentral City . Merrlck 

Bishop St. Withrow . . ICentral City . . Merrick 

Malcolm Creamery . 

E. Deitch. Sec Malcolm I Lancaster 

Newport Creamery 

P. E. Fisher Newport 
Thos. Hay, Mjrr Newcastl 

Rock 

Newcastle Creamery 

Newcastle ... 

Dlxon 

Nebraska-Iowa Creamery Co 

J.J.King. Pres Omaha 

I)ouiflas 

Murray 

Springneld.! 

Sarpy 

&lt; iretna 

Papillion 

MlUard 

Douglas 

Klkhorn 

Waterloo.. 

Valley 

Bennlngton . 

i Washington 


'Skimming Stations </seg>

            <seg id="p102">
MAHACIB OB PBO- 
PUBTOR 

posT-orricB 

sim or &lt; kiahert 

Nebraska-Iowa Creamery Co 

• ¦¦ 

. •• •• : :¦:: 

. •• 

. •• •• .... 

. •• •• .::: 

¦ 

• 

.::: 

. 

. •• 

. •• ¦• . 

. •• •• ....::...: 

:::..:::.. 

. •• ¦¦ :::::::::: 

. •¦ - :::::::::: 

:::::::¦:: 

. - •• :::::::.:: 

. •• •• :: 

I.I. J. King, Pres.. 

.. 

.. 

.. 

- 

.. 

.. 

.. 

.. 

.. 

Arlington Washington 
Orum Washington 
West Point ... Cumins 
Leigh Colfax 
Dodge Dodge 
Snyder Dodge 
Beemer Cumlntr 
iraml Prairie, 
sherman 
Bismark Cuming 
Loseke 
Albijn Boone 
Norfolk Madison 
Ho&gt;.kins Wayne 
Winslde •• 
Bancroft Cuming 
Logan 
Wisner 
Neligb Antelope 
si union Stan ton 
Pleasant Val'y Dodve 
Battle Creek Madison 
Meadow Grove 
Clearwater . . Antelope 
Inman Holt 
Chamt&gt;er8 " 
Foster Pierce 
Verdiure Knox 
Creighton 
Humphrey .... Platte 
Plane Center. 
Bazile Mills .. Knox 
Guthrie Center Iowa (State) 
Wichita 
North Branch. " 
Dale 
Safeslde 
Montietb " 
Ponca Dixon, Nebr. 
Pierce Pierce 
Plain* lew Pierce 
Pawnee City. Pawnee 
Kavenna Buffalo 
Otd Valley 
LoupClty Sherman 
Kiverton Franklin 
Red Cloud .... Webster 
Savage Antelope 
St. Paul Howard 
Schuyler.. ..Colfax 
Stromsburg.. . Polk 
Superior Nuckolls 
Sutton Clay 
Aurora Hamilton 
Os eola Polk 
Seward Seward 
York York 
Thayer York 
Beulah Polk 
Island Polk 
Clear Creek... 
Tilden Madison 
Wahoo Saundera 
Prague 
Cedar Bluffa.. . " 
Yuun '• 
Weston 
Valparaiso ... 

. •• 

.. 

. •¦ •• :: : 

.. 

Ponca Creamery Co 
Pierce Creamery 
Plainview Creamery 
Pawnee Creamery Co 
Ravenna Creamery 

W. P. Robinson. Sec. 
Win. Becbtor 
W. Courtnatte 
Ruben Lipp, Sec 
C. A.Clark 

RiTerton Creamery 
Red Cloud Creamery 
Savage Creamery 
St Paul Creameries 
Schuyler Creamery 
Stromsburg Creamery 
Superior Creamery &amp; Pro. Co 
Sutton Creamery Association 
South Plane Creameries 

T. N. Moore. Sec.... 
J. A. Holmes 
C. K. Dawson 
A. P. Anderson, Mi?r 
Frank E Moore. Mar. 
C. S. Nelson. Sec 
F. N. HenniiiKren ... 
J. C. Merrill.: 
W. A. Carpenter. Mgr. 

.. 

" 

1_Li= | 
Creamery 
I Hi 

.. 

.. 

" 

.. 

Lorenzo Thompson 
J. E. Culllngs 

.. 

.. 

•• </seg>

            <seg id="p103">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 

103 

LIST OF CHEESE FACTORIES. 

MANAGER OB PBO- 

NAME OF. FACTORY 

pk,«t,?b '""¦ Pos-r-orric. cou»tt 

Clover Dale Cheese Factory W. M. Thomas Platumouth.. Cass 

lnavale Cheese Factory A. F. Hartwell Inavale Webster 
Wilson Cheese Factory Leigh Platte 
AToca Cheese Factory P. E. Garrity Avoca Cut 
Dunlap Cheese Factory |B. Pendrich ..Dunlap |D»«re» 

A voca Cheese Factory 

Dunlap Cheese Factory </seg>


            <seg id="p105">
SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL CONVENTION. 


DAIRY STATISTICS FOR NEBRASKA. 

S. C. BASSETT. 

i 

Through the kindness of Mr. L. G. Powers, chief statistician 
for agriculture, I am enabled to give, in advance of the regular 
publication, some statistics in regard to the dairy industry in 
Nebraska as shown by the U. S. census returns for 1900. In 
the comparisons made as between the census returns for 1890 
and 1900, attention is invited to a few items of more than 
ordinary interest. The increase in the number of milch cows 
was only 7,499, or 1.5 per cent, while the increase in butter production 
for the same period was 12,349,978 pounds, or 36 per 
cent. At first thought this marked increase might be accounted 
for in the larger use by dairymen of improved breeds of daily 
cows, but I am more inclined to credit the increase largely to 
the improved methods of separating the butter-fat from the 
whole milk ; the use of separators for the separation of cream 
instead of the deep can or shallow pan system, which often left 
from 15 to 50 per cent of the butter-fat in the skimmed milk. 
It is true that there has been a marked improvement in the use 
of better bred dairy cows for dairy purposes, but a much greater 
improvement, in proportion, has been in the methods of separating 
the cream from the milk. 

t'he decrease in cheese production is not due to the fact that 
¦ime quality of cheese cannot be made in the state, but rather 
the reason that milk for cheese making must be delivered at 
factory, and owing to the small number of milch cows within 
idius wherein it is practical to deliver milk at a factory, a suffiit 
quantity of milk can not usually be secured to make the 
mfacture of cheese profitable. 

Eluile a contrast is shown in the increase in value of dairy 
lucts in factories, $1,070,893, and the decrease in some of 
items of cost in manfacturing same. In 1890 there were 58 
blishments, giving employment to 428 persons, to whom </seg>


            <seg id="p106">
NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. 

$151,126 was paid as wages, an average of $353 per year, and 
the miscellaneous expenses were $49,563. Total for the two 
items, $200,684. 1° I 9°o there were 93 establishments (including 
skimming stations) giving employment to 333 persons, to 
whom $146,522 was paid as wages, an average of $440 per 
year, and the miscellaneous expenses were $38,823. Total for 
the two items $185,345. 

If we consider as pounds of butter, both the butter and cheese 
manufactured in factories, estimating 10 pounds of cheese as the 
equivalent of 4 pounds of butter, we find that in 1890 the expense 
for wages and miscellaneous items averaged 3.1 cents per pound of 
butter manufactured, while in 1900, the expense for these items 
averaged 1.5 per cents per pound, a saving of 1.6 cents on 
each pound, or 50 per cent. 

Thus it will be seen that the establishment of central factories 
in which to manufacture into butter the cream shipped from 
skimming stations and hand separators, has apparently reduced 
ihe cost of manufacturing a pound of butter 1.6 cents as compared 
with a factory in each neighborhood. The cost of 
materials used in the manufacture of a pound of factory butter 
averaged 14.3 cents in 1890, and 15.8 cents in 1900, an increase 
of 1.5 cents per pound, or 10 per cent. As the cost of materials 
in this case is largely the amount paid for cream, and as the 
amount saved in the expense of manufacturing a pound of butter, 
1.6 cents, is almost identical with the increased cost of materials, 
I paid for cream) 1.5 cents per. pound, it would seem that the 
saving in the cost of manfacture has innured to the benefit of the 
patron of the factor}-. 

I "he increase in average yield of butter per cow, per year, 
n 1890 to 1900 was 21 pounds, or 30 per cent. It should not 
nferred that our milch cows produce only 90 pounds of butper 
cow, per year, as not all the milk produced by them is 
d in the manufacture of butter, a large per cent being used 
other purposes. As before mentioned, much of this increase 
oubtless due to the use of separators, thus saving a larger per 
t of the butter-fat. </seg>



            <seg id="p107">
Total cheese made ( farms and factories) .. 554,770 1,268,449 
Butter production per capita SLtt lbs. 32.M lbs. i:\.2* lbs. 

21.50 lbs. 32.00 lbs. 4:! ..- 

1.22 lbs. l.lli lbs. ."V4 lbs. 

Klg* yield butter i»er cow. per year. . n-l.t*) lbs. M.M lbs. M.M lbs. 
PHkM in butter production per capita. MM to l'.nX). 11. 2** II - 

M production per capita 

I",, 1890 !'«»&gt; 

Pr of milch cows 161,187 506,045 
of milch cows n7,ltt,m 
•ase in number of milch cows. MM to IMS, 343,868, or 213.3 percent. 
¦ase in number of milch cows, 18M to l!M&gt;0, "AW. or Ll per i 
im um mm 

POUNDS POUNDS POINDS 
Butter made in factories K."),7"2 8,078,785 11.7^ 

Butter made on farms i,TS5,18« R,8U,«H ;U..-,18,859 
Total butter made (farms and factories) . . .ii.7J»O,!i7it Sa,M4,8Sl 4ti.244,8» 
m- made on farms tM,819 4O,8» M4,4M 
M made in factories :5i5. (•."&gt;! 804,(08 

Decrease in cheese production per capita. I 1 *!"' to 1!HX&gt;. M lbs. "4 per 

PARATIVE STATEMKXT OF DAIRY PBODfCTS MM TO ISM 

Hater made in factories (increase) ."&gt;.i&gt;4!&gt;.:S!i7 lbs., or M per 

Butter made on farm- (increase 8,700^581 U&lt;s.. or 91 per 
Total batter production (increase) 12,3tt,M9 lbs., or M \*-v 

P&gt; made in factories d.vivase) 401,018 lbs., or d |» 
&gt; made on farms (decrease) 1M.401 lbs., or +:! DM ient. 
production (de&gt;-rease) li!H),41il lbs . or ."4 per ceut. 

FACTOKI 

1890 

Number of establishments 

ijre numlier of jiersons em])loyed ttB 

: WBgM paid * 1J1,126 

ilancou- ex|H'iisi-s M^S63 
(A materials 

Value of product 1,183,000 

Value of all dairy products </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>