<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00082.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Diseases of Poultry--Their Nature and Control</title>
               <date value="1934-07">1934-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-18</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 290 July, 1934 Diseases of Poultry — Their Nature and Control L. VAN ES AND J. F. OLNEY . ■ Department of Animal Pathology and Hygiene A Sanitary Lunch Counter THE UNIVERSITY OP NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. Wj Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">PREFACE ■pi T . , .. CONTENTS Introduction Hygiene, Sanitation, and Management "..." """ o The Control of Transmissible Diseases.... t Sanitation _ Avitaminoses *" "*" Favus .":".."":.. 19 Tuberculosis 21 Fowl Cholera 22 Fowl Typhus ZZZ 41 Bacillary White Diarrhea 7« Roup ' " 46 Infectious Bronchitis • ZZ Pox and Canker lZ Fowl Paralysis Infectious Leukosis Blackhead m Turkeys 1 Coccidiosis Parasites and Pests ' ?jj Flukeworms Tapeworms Z1...Z1'....Z. ll Roundworms 1 Worms and disease ~.......Z..'."..'. 92 Control and treatment of worms «.. Lice L3ZZZZI" "100 Flies, gnats, mosquitoes, bedbugs, mites jno d Red mites °~* Harvest mite or chigger '&#132;„„ Scaly leg mite 'ZZZZZIZ 107 Depluming mite Jl Air-sac mite " '," Flesh mite JJJ </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Diseases of Poultry — Their Nature and Control L. VAN ES AND J. F. OLNEY In any branch of animal husbandry problems associated with health and disease must continually be faced. They frequently determine the difference between profit and loss. As long as the health of a given type of livestock can be main - tained there remains, at least, a possibility of profit, but on the other hand the occurrence of disease always means loss be it small or great. ' In no other type of livestock production is this more ap - parent than where it concerns poultry. It is sometimes maintained by superficial thinkers that disease losses reduce that which is spoken of as overproduction and they may even suggest that as such they may be desirable. Perhaps such losses would be so regarded by some, but certainly not by flock owners, whose property is destroyed by disease and whose livelihood may thus be menaced. Such flock owners are the ones who pay for the possible advantages gained by others. Disease losses constitute a waste of things produced and an additional cost of production, not to mention the dis - couragement and disappointment experienced by a not incon - siderable number of those engaged m the industry. Disease is, and always has been, a burden, and hence it is obvious that its eradication and control must be accepted as objectives desirable to achieve. To do so successfully, the nature of disease, its causes and its ways, must be understood. Only then can principles and measures of prevention and con - trol be established. As m all other areas where poultry rais - ing is carried on m a more or less intensive manner, Nebraska flock owners and others to whom poultry may be of material interest should be aware that there is a definite disease prob - lem to be faced and to be solved by sound reasoning and by effective methods and by those means only. HYGIENE, SANITATION AND MANAGEMENT The successful pursuit of poultry husbandry is to a marked degree dependent on our ability to maintain a flock m such a manner that certain types of disease are not readily con - tracted by the birds and that their spread is effectually pre - vented. When flocks are small and far apart, protection against disease is not an urgent factor, but with the increase m poultry population the time arrives sooner or later when serious attention must be given to this detail of management. Disease problems to a large extent come about as a corollary to increases m the number of animals maintained on a given </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 area, and the mass diseases, unless restrained by artificial means, constitute one of nature's means of making overpopu - lation impossible. The maintenance of large flocks is thus fundamentally a deviation from the scheme of nature and cannot be persisted in for a great length of time unless methods are designed and followed which tend to remove the disease hazard peculiar to a dense population. The remarkable development of our poultry industry with larger and more numerous flocks has by now reached a phase in which the disease problem is cruelly asserting itself. The time when this problem could be wholly ignored lies now well behind us and in the management of flocks a solution must be found so that the considerable assortment of prevalent diseases will not cut too deeply into the profits of our poul - try growers. In the maintenance of poultry health one is particularly dependent on preventive measures, not only because the poul - try disorders which are economically important cannot be affected by medicinal treatment, but also because from a standpoint of flock management hygienic efforts are prefer - able. Aside from the fact that medicinal treatment does not par - ticularly change the final destiny of a sick fowl or of an in - fected flock, its cost would be considerable if all that is in - volved in the care and treatment of individual birds were actually accounted for. It would require individual care and attention, not to mention that in its application a considerable degree of skill might be required. It seems quite apparent that one could readily invest a dollar's worth of time and material in a sick chicken, which, if healthy, would not be worth more than seventy-five cents. The "medicine-mindedness" of many people is being thor - oughly exploited and much money is being wasted which, in - vested in better equipment and other details of flock manage - ment, would yield adequate returns. From every point of view, the most damaging diseases of poultry constitute a flock problem. Flock protection more than the saving of individual birds should be the owner's concern. The owner must learn to function as a sort of health officer for his flock. Even more than in the ills of any other type of livestock is the solution of the poultry-disease problem dependent on the intelligent application of the principles of hygiene and sanita - tion. It will, therefore, not be amiss to call attention to the most basic of those principles, so that flock owners may be informed of the ways and means now recognized as essential </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Poultry Diseases to success in poultry production. The application of the prin - ciples set forth, must, on the other hand, vary under different local conditions, but, on the whole, it is possible to solve the individual problems without deviating very far from a gen - eral plan of action. The task of poultry hygiene is twofold because it aims not only to promote health but also to protect and defend it. In connection with the former, conditions are sought under which the vital functions of the animal body can be performed with the least hindrance and at a maximum efficiency. The latter is designed either to ward off actual causes of disease, to interrupt their free movements, to bring about their de - struction, or, if possible, to do all these things in the same general attempt. Among the factors conducive to health and to body efficiency, mention must be made of (1) soundness of body and constitution, and vigor; (2) adequate nutrition; (3) suitable environment; and (4) the eradication and control of transmissible diseases. Breeding stock. — In the foundation and in the further propagation of the flock it is quite essential that the breeding stock be healthy, vigorous, and robust. Such animals may not be exempt from infection, but a vigorous constitution is a valuable advantage nevertheless. The less vigorous mem - bers of the flock should always be the ones culled out for table use and they should never be used for breeding. The same principle is applicable to the older birds, and the flock from which birds over two years old are eliminated is always the stronger from the standpoint of both productivity and sanitary fitness. Birds, both male and female, should be carefully selected for the purpose of flock propagation and they should be mature, vigorous, active and well developed. There should be no de - fects in body conformation and their health should be in no way impaired. When a new flock is to be started or an old one to be in - creased or improved by new blood, preference should be given to hatching eggs or to very young chicks from other flocks of which the general state of health is well known to the pur - chaser, especially with reference to bacillary white diarrhea, which is commonly transmitted by means of infected eggs. For a similar reason eggs for hatching and chicks should not be procured from flocks in which cases of fowl paralysis have occurred in the course of two or three previous years. Adequate nutrition. — It is no secret that food is an all - powerful factor not only in the maintenance of health and body vigor, but also in the equally important matter of final </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 profits. When the farm flocks were small and of only a limited importance in the general scheme of farming, the wastes around the farmstead and feed lots were quite suffi - cient to maintain such flocks in a fairly good state of nutri - tion and productivity. The birds could obtain what their bodies required and there was no great need for special at - tention to the feeding problem. Since the small 50-bird farm flock of the past has gradually expanded into the 500-bird flock of the present, the wastes on the farm may no longer be sufficient to supply the nutritive substances of which the body is in constant need. All the nutrients may be in default, or only a part, but the result is eventually an undernourished, unproductive lot of birds and there is no lack of evidence to be encountered in dress - ing and feeding establishments that birds taken directly from the farm flock are not infrequently suffering from semi - starvation, either due to a short ration in general or to rations merely faulty in some one particular. As much valuable information on the feeding of poultry is contained in some other publications, the reader may be re - ferred to them for details. 1 It should, however, be pointed out not only that proper feeding will promote egg and meat production, but also that it is of the greatest importance in the maintenance of body health and vigor. It is especially important to know that a good state of nutrition is partic - ularly essential to birds which are to form a part of long - distance poultry shipments. Suitable environment. — The surroundings in which birds have to live are of material influence in the maintenance of the health of a flock. Not only may this influence be exercised in a direct manner but the environment or at least part of it may become a depository of many parasitic or microbic causes of disease and in this manner function as a trans - mitting agency for quite an assortment of infections. Poultry yards and the sites of poultry houses should be selected with a view to dryness and shelter. A sandy, gravelly soil is most desirable for this purpose, while the lay of the ground should be such as to provide a free, natural drainage. If the topography is of such a nature as to render the latter difficult or impossible, recourse must be had to some artificial means of securing dryness. Excessive mois - ture of the environment is always objectionable from the standpoint of poultry production, while, furthermore, the presence of surface water, which birds are apt to drink, o. 1R ?»J? Nebraska Extension Circular 1420. Better Rations. More Eggs; Nebr. Ext Clre. 1467. Questums and Answers on Feeding Hens for Egg Production; and Nebr. Ext Circ. 1478, Slash Formulas for Povlls and Chicks. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Poultry Diseases must be regarded as a very serious source of mischief. For this reason, pools and puddles, filled wagon ruts, or open drains should never be tolerated in yards used for poultry. Shelter against prevailing strong winds is advisable; it may be secured by having houses and yards located on the leeward side of a hill or some large building or by taking advantage of, the presence of trees or tall shrubbery. A southern exposure is usually to be preferred and the shelter should never be so as to exclude direct sunlight altogether. An important detail of the environment is the poultry house where the birds find shelter while at roost and where they must spend some of the time when laying. It affords protection against the inclemencies of the weather and the extremes of temperature. Poultry houses must be designed "with a view to the number of occupants, to the maintenance of cleanliness, and to the comfort of the animals they are to shelter. How this may be best accomplished is adequately described in other publications issued by this institution. 2 However advantageous a well constructed and properly managed poultry house may be, the fact must be recognized that it solves only a relatively small part of what may be •called the sanitation problem of the poultry farm. The value of good housing is above all apparent as a detail influencing production and body efficiency, but its sanitary construction and management are only helpful in coping with the external parasites and possibly with respiratory diseases such as roup and infectious bronchitis. With the exception of flocks kept in laying houses all the time when food and water must be provided there, the most damaging of poultry disorders are more apt to be contracted in the yards than in the houses. The yards, where the birds find their food and water, are much more important in connection with disease transmission than the houses. The soil of the poultry yards presents a hygienic aspect of tremendous importance because on it are deposited the body -wastes of the fowls and those constitute for the diseases mentioned the most common, if not the usual, vehicle for their transmission. The small areas of soil occupied by large numbers of fowls are apt to receive a greater supply of body wastes than the ground can dispose of and when once any of the types of infection mentioned have been introduced into ■a flock, the disease-producing germs or parasites - are not promptly destroyed and the area affected is bound to become &amp; more or less enduring hotbed of infection. -k, u N&lt; £ ras H?, Extension Circular 730, A Colony Brooder House for the Farm Flock, and Uebr. Ext Clrc. 1419, Farm Poultry Howes. , </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 This actually happens on the many farms where disease outbreaks cause havoc with poultry profits. The superficial soil layers of these poultry yards have practically been changed over to dung and sewage and a most rigid sanitary law is being violated, namely, the one which decrees that no animal species can exist in a more or less intimate and endur - ing contact with its own body wastes without incurring an extraordinary hazard of becoming involved in outbreaks of disease. Our poultry industry and the type of diseases by which it is menaced have by now reached a stage which demands attention to this detail of the business in a most imperative manner. THE CONTROL OF TRANSMISSIBLE DISEASES The transmissible diseases, also often referred to as infec - tious or contagious diseases, are the ones which are, above all, of economic importance. Those diseases menace entire flocks. The so-called sporadic diseases, which affect or kill a bird now and then, are of no special interest to the average flock owner and their consideration can serve no practical purpose. It is not always an easy matter to determine how a given disease has been introduced into a flock. The transmissible diseases are always dependent on some germ as the primary cause. Such germs are true parasites, which cannot propa - gate themselves in any other place but the animal body, so it can be readily understood that somewhere back of an out - break is an infected bird which served as the incubator for the germs responsible for the disaster. Infected stock. — Such a germ-incubating bird may carry the infection directly into a healthy flock ; or the movable part of a contaminated environment, in which disease germs can remain alive for certain lengths of time, may in some manner become transported. It is by no means known how such transmissions may come about, but certain it is that newly purchased birds, for instance, should always be looked upon with suspicion. As a matter of fact the function of adult birds as carriers and distributors of infection is so well known that preference must always be given either to hatch - ing eggs or to very young chicks if new stock is to be intro - duced in a poultry yard. Even then one is not always safe, largely on account of bacillary white diarrhea, but this disease need not become a menace to a flock, as it is not long in declar - ing itself and can be readily localized. The offal of birds killed for the table quite readily becomes the means of introducing infection and therefore such mate- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Poultry Diseases rial should always be disposed of by burning. Birds killed or dead as a result of sickness should be dealt with in a similar manner. In the killing of sick birds only such a method of procedure should be chosen as precludes the spilling of any blood, because, in certain diseases, the latter is likely to con - tain the causative germs in great numbers. Flying birds. — While such flying birds as pigeons and sparrows are not easily convicted of carrying disease from farm yard to farm yard, it is quite conceivable that on occasion this actually does take place. Many wild birds are susceptible to the same diseases as the domesticated ones and must always be regarded with suspicion and dealt with accord - ingly. Soil. — The soil upon which a poultry population is being maintained always constitutes a most active factor in the propagation of disease as well as in the duration of hazards associated with the latter. Such disorders as tuberculosis, fowl typhus, blackhead, coccidiosis and possibly others as well are truly soil- or filth-borne because their causative germs are thrown off with the body wastes and enter the bodies of other birds by means of food and drinking water contamin - ated with the droppings. In this transmission, the soil is the most important vehicle and the greater part of the task of poultry hygiene is concerned with dealing with the soil of poultry yards in such a manner that its disease-carrying functions may be reduced to the smallest possible propor - tions. When the soil has once become infected it may remain so for a considerable length of time in accordance with the nature of the infection introduced and the character of the soil itself. Left unpopulated, the infected area will eventually free itself of the disease-producing elements. The latter are apt to succumb gradually in the surroundings furnished by the soil, because they are dependent for their maintenance and propagation on the animal body. They are destroyed by soil organisms which prey upon them, or they die be - cause of the lack of the type of food which they require. Thus the soil tends to rid itself of all organic material and germs which do not strictly belong to it, and this process is known as biologic purification, because the living matter of the soil is almost entirely responsible for this cleansing pro - cess. This process, however, is not continuous during the year; throughout the winter months it is practically at a standstill, while during the warm and moist weather of sum - mer it is the most active. Disinfection of the soil by means </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska. Experiment Station Bulletin 290 of chemicals is, as a rule, not practicable and cannot be de - pended on to remove any infection which may be present. Feeding habits. — The feeding habits of poultry have much to do with the fact that the soil of poultry yards plays such a prominent part in the transmission of certain diseases. Fowls pick up a considerable part of their food directly from the ground and as a consequence no small amount of soil is swallowed with the food. Wild birds roaming freely about, such as pheasants and partridges, do the same thing, but they range farther, their number is smaller, and they rarely feed at one and the same place for any length of time. Hence the soil on which they range is relatively free from con - tamination because the droppings of such birds are scattered widely and do not cause a given area to become overcharged with parasite eggs or the microbes of the more common diseases. In the case of domesticated birds, on the other hand, we find large numbers of the animals concentrated on compar - atively small areas, with the result already explained, that the soil is apt to become surcharged with fecal matter and whatever harmful elements may be contained therein. The fact that a flock may range far and wide does not ordinarily change this situation, because it does not extensively take advantage of this privilege and usually remains in close prox - imity to where it roosts and where it is fed. In the sanitary management of poultry flocks the feeding habits of the birds must be reckoned with and this the more seriously as the number of the fowls becomes greater. Drinking water. — . O As a means of disease transmission, the part played by the drinking ':'■$$ -llfW^ water is probably even : *f&amp;'!&amp;M&amp;^ tors mentioned. Water ■ (^Kp|^|^g' .?fel ularly to contamina- wSj^^^m^^^mCii^^^^^S^^ tion, and the danger associated with pollut- W|telliP ed water is further s =a&amp;=&amp;*utffri--y. n--.v ,-^j~=a^ ! *^ increased by the fact Pig. 1. — A convenient watering device. Not that in certain cases strictly sanitary, but if kept clean and it may constitute a placed well above the ground it provides favorable medium in a datively safe water supply. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Poultry Diseases which disease-producing microbes or larger parasites can be - come more readily disseminated. Even when the water is provided in otherwise suitable vessels, the way for pollution is always open, because either filth is deposited in the watering utensils by means of the soiled beaks or feet or they are often so constructed that the body wastes can be directly dropped into the water. Water - ing devices can be so made or placed that pollution is rendered impossible and then the only remaining danger is offered by surface water accumulations on the ground, in open drains, or similar places where water can gather. No matter how adequately a clean supply is made available, its value can never be superior to that of the worst to which the flock may have access. Only after all possibility of polluted water has been eliminated can one become certain that the use of sani - tary drinking devices is really a factor of value in disease prevention. SANITATION Were it possible to surround our poultry flocks with safe - guards and barriers enough so that the introduction of dis - ease-producing agents could be avoided, there would be but little necessity to take any other step in disease prevention. Under the prevailing conditions of flock management and Fig. 2.— A -watering device commonly used for little chicks. Not strictly sanitary, but if kept clean and well above ground it will lareelv answer the purpose. especially because of the imperfect knowledge pertaining to the initial introduction of infection, this is as yet impossible. Hence, we are forced to adopt methods which tend to render disease transmission and spread impossible or difficult. In this effort we proceed by securing for the birds the safest possible environment and by adopting such methods of feed - ing and watering as tend to reduce the hazard of disease transmission to the smallest possible proportions. This con - stitutes sanitation, which may be defined as a combination of </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 means and measures directed toward the establishment and maintenance of an environment in which it is safe for animals to exist. Poultry yards. — From what has already been said in re - gard to the part played by soil pollution in the dissemination of disease, it is obvious that in the practice of sanitation con - siderable attention must be given to that source of danger and its possible elimination. Soil of which the superficial layers have a considerable admixture of poultry dung is always a menace to the bird population which occupies it, but more in particular to the younger birds. As in the young of all other anirnais. the young of the domesticated bird species are particularly liable to intestinal infections and are more apt to become infested with worms. Older birds are more resistant to any harm which may come from the presence of such agents and as a matter of fact are frequently infected or invaded without sustaining any conspicuous damage. Older turkeys and even the common fowl are often found to harbor the germ of "blackhead"; the cause of coccidiosis is frequently observed in the older healthy birds ; and in other diseases the same thing may be observed, although in such diseases as tuberculosis and cholera the mor - bidity is greater in the older birds. It is thus quite essential or safe to proceed on the theory that if at all possible, young chicks and older birds should be kept on separate ground until the former are at least three or four months old. For the same reason it is best that, at least until that age is reached, young birds should not occupy ground recently vacated by older birds and even the latter will be healthier and more thrifty upon soil which either has remained unpolluted or has been kept unoccupied by poultry long enough to have completed the process of self - purification previously mentioned. Theoretically, at least, it seems possible so to construct and arrange yards as to render them quite safe as far as the like - lihood of their acting as reservoirs of infection and parasites is concerned. Under present farm conditions, however, it is probably not yet necessary to go to such a length in order to secure the sanitary safety of the flock. On the other hand, there is good reason to believe that specially enclosed poultry yards intermittently occupied by the fowls and utilized for other purposes constitute a valuable factor in disease prevention. There is no lack of evidence that on a considerable number of farms the permanently occupied farm yard can no longer be regarded^ as a proper or safe environment in which a poultry flock can be main - tained without risk of losses by disease. Thus, special meas- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Poultry Diseases JSSf 5 USt u e consideration and for the present rbta - genVal SSe^ " the ° ne »«* -«itaWetor 1 can then be occupied by the flock while the other one is in" movable brooder houses, they can be moved from t me to time tVlZ er ff H n «i t&gt; age is reached when they can safety m thCir enclosure wi th a relative degree S fore. In certain experiments carried on by this StSion a SS^SThl.^ i; I feCted Mrds were admittedfo the^a?d and at this tame it seems doubtful that it will prove to be U 1ul a p S r gbab?e Ve A V 1n mea3Ure "^ A^*** *&gt; l*O U3C J.(Ji LllL - average farm poultry Fl^- 3.— Hardware-cloth panel used in yard. It may, however brooders and enclosures for chicks and have its nlace in ?r * S&gt; (Va -5 Es&gt; ■ p ™"«Pfcw of Animal brooder houL^a^'iS fcA^itt the relatively small en- Y -) closures where young chicks may remain until they are two or three months old. By the use of such panels it appearsto </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska. Experiment Station Bulletin 290 be possible to reduce to a minimum the hazards furnished by a dung-befouled soil. Supervision of the water supply. — Preventing the drink - ing water from serving as a vehicle in disease transmission is one of the outstanding essentials in poultry sanitation and no single factor will contribute more to the protection of a flock against the inroads of disease than the elimination of polluted water and the provision of water that is safe from a sanitary point of view. Fig. 4. — A practical arrangement to supply drinking water to poultry. Although not perfectly sanitary, it leaves little to be desired from a hygienic standpoint. As the preceding statement suggests, two things must thus be accomplished and one of those is to render it impossible for poultry to obtain water from any source other than the one deliberately provided and safeguarded. A poultry yard is never an ideal environment from a disease-prevention standpoint as long as surface water is available either periodically or permanently. The value of well-drained yards is entirely associated with this fact and in the protection of a flock against infection the best beginning always is to do away with surface accumulations including pools, open drains, filled wagon ruts, or animal footprints as well as water which may collect in old pans, troughs, tin cans, discarded footwear, and what-not. A yard with a soil so pervious or with a sand or gravel top dressing so open as to preclude the gathering of water even after heavy rains comes very near being an ideal one. The writers have visions that in a not very distant future such yards, deliberately established, will come to be recognized as an essential feature of the permanent poultry fafm. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Poultry Diseases Next in importance after the removal of dangerous water accumulations is the provision of drinking water of unques - tioned purity in containers so constructed as to reduce the chances of contamination with fecal matter to a minimum The watering utensils should be so covered or otherwise arranged that the birds cannot deposit their droppings in the water. , With the type of equipment usually available an absolute protection is not readily accomplished, owing to the fact that birds with soiled beaks or which suffer from any of the roup - like diseases can always befoul the drinking water. Hence most, if not all, utensils of this sort cannot be designated as strictly sanitary even if the gross pollution common to the open troughs or vessels is more or less effectually done away with m the manner indicated. WiniiM 1 • ' I iitM FlG ;,f;T An ! id^ 1 ™ et h, d ° f supplying water for poultry. The drinkiner S5 be^TardfdTs ]£Sff : £3S£ """*• * f^^ In order to reduce or eliminate the danger incidental to con - tamination, it is a common practice to render the water com - paratively safe by the addition of certain antisept cs Tn amounts harmless to the birds. Permanganate of potassium s commonly chosen for this purpose. A standard solutXn" in water to contain 5 per cent of the chemical is prepared and «L £L en ° U ?-\V S aMe ? i° t he drinkin S water to impart to the latter a light purplish pink color. As long as this color </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 Fig. 6. — A device for feeding dry mash. It has some sanitary advant - ages but falls short in the protection of young chicks against coc - cidiosis. It is a convenient feeder for mature fowls. persists the water is mildly antiseptic and disease-producing elements in it will, in a certain length of time, be destroyed. It will, however, prove to be ineffective against coccidiosis and parasite eggs, as well as against tuberculosis. To a large extent the method is a mere makeshift and is not to be regarded as an absolute protection. It is sometimes looked upon as a cure for all possible poultry ills. Of course it is nothing of the kind and the most that can be expected of it is that it will rid the water of some of its impurities. In a large measure the daily cleaning of the water utensils is as dependable a measure of protection as the use of chem - icals. _ l^^yJ _^^ Pig. 7. — Cross section of self-feeder with hardware-cloth approaches. Sanitary but liable to become befouled on top, and hence not alto - gether safe in the face of a coccidiosis hazard. (From Van Es, Prin - ciples of Animal Hygiene, by permission of the publishers, John Wiley &amp; Sons.) </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Poultry Diseases A more efficient method of supplying safe water to poul - try can be proposed in the form of self-cleaning cups on the plan of the sanitary "bubblers" now in common use in public buildings, parks, etc. It can be put into practice only where running water is constantly available, but even the ordinary windmill and tank equipment of many farms could be utilized to advantage in providing this more or less ideal means of watering poultry. Feeding methods. — It is quite obvious that the safe - guarding of the food against fecal and other contaminations is fully as important as the protection of the water supply J^ i \ eagM»*»M»i««^i«»»i w m|| , j^J'^jJ^^ \ . '^,,.,11 ,„„■-..-;.*,: ., „ ~J Fig. 8. — Self-feeder for chicks up to three months of age. The mash can - not be befouled with droppings and none can be deposited on the tops. The hopper is filled from outside the fence. Fully sanitary. and that it constitutes an essential measure in disease preven - tion. In the first place, the mash and grain used for poultry feeding must be so . 3tored and handled that _ L**-__ contamination by the i Ci--p^-^r^----^ body wastes of poultry j can be absolutely exclud- • // ed and in the second ! v // place the food should be • / \ // provided in containers • // \\ // constructed with the '*&lt;// _. \y -// ««««•/*-*■•*-* - same purpose in view. "Y UU \\ / / fT^T^C^^~% There is a more or less : \\ // *-j — ij — ij — ii — ij— * widespread belief that • \] // il HSfl fowls must be made to j n \| // JJLJJ—ILJLJL^ scratch for their food i L // C.^^v^^&gt;x&gt;&gt;^- - for the sake of body ex- ~ —^ — - 1 ercise and that, there- r "|| * 1 r. 3 y. fore, the grain feed must ?J be scattered over the \ g J 0 ""?- J he soundness FlG- 9 ._ C ross section and detail of ele- Of this theory IS cer- vation of feeder shown in Fig. 8. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 fl ''■"" " . ~~~- ~ ■ — - - — i If B* n^^ —^ 'm^^— ' - ' ' ' Fig. 10.— A sanitary feeder for brooder chicks for indoor use. tainly open to doubt, but granting its validity the fact r* mams that the dung-laden soil or fl?or cannot be regarded as a particularly safe dish to eat from when the subjectYs viewed to £ aS^7 angle 'x. For this reason the thioret cSfit cLppIpH h Ve i fr ?F such scratching exercises may be largely canceled by the disease hazard, which is almost certain &amp; to company foraging from the always-polluted soil of the poultry fn nn^f • therefore recommended that the food be provided or Z IT so 1 arran « e d and constructed that an admixture pr5ereS h a f raVrr d h ° PPer ***" Sh ° uM aIso be «"» cautionary measure. ; A On the other hand, : /A\ this type of feeders is j //A\\ almost an impera- : /// \\\ tive necessity for i /// \\\ the younger stock. ; /// V\\ The most effective ! ( U- -Vn ones are so arranged •«• , and constructed that X \ / not only the feed can- i &lt; A\ // &gt; JZZtfZZZZZ not Be befouled but ! I \\™ -■ // I JJ ij i; || |i &gt; that the depositing of : \\ // hlfcll — I — ll — \l droppings on the tops : \| (/ \ || H and other parts is • n N Y n ill-^MI— II— 0— 11— , rendered impossible. i \H _ \^-^^^aa^ The latter arrange- *■ -'■*-"- \ r. s ±i. 3^! A 68156 ?" 7 it PlG - H— Cross section and detail of ele - signed to reduce the vation of feeder shown in Fig. 10. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Poultry Diseases coccidiosis and blackhead hazards of young chicks and poults. No doubt it is also of value in the prevention of other trans - missible diseases. The construction details of this type of feeders, based on the principles of fecal contact elimination, are illustrated in the figures. The need of scrupulous cleanliness pertaining to food and feeding is so obvious as not to require special recom - mendations. AVITAMINOSES Deficiency diseases among Nebraska poultry are relatively uncommon. Occasionally inadequate feeding or faulty rations may bring disappointing results but these factors do not ordin - arily express themselves in actual disease even if they may at times contribute a predisposing cause. This may also be said in regard to deficiencies generally included in the term 'avitaminoses". The word implies a lack of vitamins, or vitamin starvation. The vitamins include a number of more or less known sub - stances which are apparently necessary for the normal de - velopment and maintenance of the 'animal body. They are contained in the various foodstuffs or may even arise in the animal body itself as a result of external influences. Their continued absence may bring about actual disease. Poultry are subject to at least three distinct avitaminoses, but only one of them must be commonly reckoned with by our poultry growers. In fact, fowls kept under the conditions which generally prevail on Nebraska farms would have diffi - culty to escape an adequate amount of the vitamins they re - quire. Only when flocks are kept under extremely artificial conditions or in certain environments can an avitaminosis be expected to occur. Vitamins are usually designated by the qualifying letters A, B, C, etc. Vitamin A. — Vitamin A is contained in cod-liver oil, the yolk of the eggs, milk and butter and to a less extent in food - stuffs of vegetable origin, such as carrots, green leaves and sprouting seeds. With the exception of yellow corn it is absent in the various cereals. As supplied by the food it tends to promote growth and appears to protect certain struc - tures commonly associated with mucous membranes against faulty or morbid developments. Its continued absence from the ration leads to avitaminosis A, which in this country is often designated as nutritional roup. In many particulars this disease resembles the com - mon roup described in another chapter and it is not always an easy matter to distinguish between the two disorders. Generally fowls affected with nutritional roup become un- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 &amp;1 de°i C £ eeSy f ma^, a1 ' an ? the organ may become dZy bmall deposits of a similar substance may also be seen in the Sges and thr ° at The kidneyS "lay 7 show degenerate Fowls affected with the disease usually recover when cod hTra°tion PU ¥hl Car -? tS '-° r leaves are incorp^Sedt" trie ration. This avitaminosis is occasionally encountered iri Nebraska fowls when kept in confinement or when they arS provided with feed poor in the vitamin concerned «-F^ lta J n J H \?*~rT h . is is present in a great assortment of foodstuffs. It is especially present in the outer layS of cereal grains as we 1 as in yeast. Its continued absence S the n at }JJ ca«-eB certain degenerative changes in the nerves and tLt ?nwi /^ nerV ° US ° 1 rgans ' Evid ence has been presented that fowls fed more or less exclusively on starchv feeds are dZbtf^tW in J° lved in thi * aviSminTsis It S ft an^irf S? S dlsorde f occurs a mong Nebraska poultry tion is tLt thP y f Wa K rant ? r mentio «i^ in this pdblica^ SwKv, + infectious disease, fowl paralysis, described o? r vft e amS Btoi&amp;SL 1 " """"^ attribUt6d * 0 * coS^t a^t ffs?? orSe? SfS 6 a^f mal hOdy * ?- Self When the latter is exposed to^he S^3 ? fl^ t i rayB ° f d^ re i Ct sunli « ht °r to the ones produced Sn a Tv 11 !- Only under the influence of vitamin D tSbm'ldiTni 15 ?^ utilize . th \ lim « Prided in the f&lt;£d f or tne building up of its growing bones. a JS^fr,« b - SeilCe ' * Yit ? mino 8is D is apt to assert itself. This avitaminosis must always be reckoned with by Nebraska amoi7h bre H der \- ,? he disorder is commonly encountereS among brooder chicks and poults. The disease is commonly known as rickets and as it occurs in young poultry it is often designated as "leg weakness." It must Specially be ff^SoSSSf ChkkS and Poults SSned r. n ,i^T ? ntS ln Whlch ex P° sur e to direct sunshine is ex - cluded. Leg weakness constitutes a special hazard when pkc D es lng ° peratlOns are in basements and similar In the experience of the writers, poults are uarticularlv XT' H°- d l V - e !? P this disorder ' and P manifest Sses were observed m birds not more than 12 to 14 days old. Affected birds show weakness and a degree of unthriftiness Their </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Poultry Diseases appetite is reduced and there is delay in feathering. Soon the weakness of the legs and wings becomes apparent- the animals are no longer active, become inclined to sit in one place for prolonged periods, and when aroused show lame - ness. The wings begin to droop and finally the legs fail to support the body weight even if the latter may be reduced as part of the general unthriftiness. The chicks lie about in a sprawling attitude and finally suc- S?r ffV/*!?! 0 * emaciation - Th e leg and wing bones of the affected chicks or poults are soft and flexible and can be readily cut with a knife. The ends of the bones are some - what enlarged and the growth line of cartilage is abnormally W1 £ ene^ L The action of the lar * e breas * muscles on the softened breast-bone causes the latter to become crooked, a condition apt to persist even after recovery. In addition rickets may cause deformity of the bones of the head and of the beak. Avitaminosis D, or leg weakness, is a preventable disease, me most valuable preventive measure is exposure to direct sunshine, and when this is not possible the addition of 2 per cent of cod-liver oil to the mash must be depended on In tact it appears to be a good practice to feed cod-liver oil as a matter of routine regardless of occasional exposures to the ultra-violet parts of direct sunlight. It must also be remem - bered that ultra-violet rays, under the influence of which vitamin D develops in the body, do not pass through window glass, kven affected chicks and poults may recover from leg weakness when cod-liver oil or exposure to direct sunshine is made available before the disorder has too far advanced. FAVUS This disorder does not appear common among Nebraska poultry and hence, at this time, it is not of manifest economic importance. It is mentioned here because the infrequent cases which come to the attention of poultry men are always apt to arouse interest. Favus is a disease of the skin of chickens, manifested by the formation of white areas on comb and wattles, which, now and then, may become extended to the feathered parts of the body. Cause. — The disease is due to the presence of a funjrn - {Achorion galliruie). This parasite is transmitted from fowl to fowl by direct or indirect contact. Symptoms and lesions.— In the beginning of the disease small, white, moldy specks appear on the comb and wattles which gradually enlarge and become confluent until the struc - tures involved are covered with a white layer. In the course </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 of time this layer thickens and may finally constitute a thick crust. The infection may then extend to the feathered parts of the body, when the skin becomes thickened and becomes covered by scabs. The feathers have a tendency to fall out, and in the case of the smaller ones the shaft is commonly marked by a moldy, white deposit at a level with the skin. In the more severely affected cases a moldy odor can be re - cognized about the animals affected. Commonly favus re - mains confined to the comb. The moldy deposit scarcely leaves any doubt regarding the nature of the disease, but in cases of doubt a microscopic examination of scrapings made from the areas involved will usually reveal promptly the char - acter of the infection. As a rule the disease is benign in character and especially so when only comb and wattles are affected. In those cases recovery commonly takes place without attempts at treat - ment. When the skin of the body becomes invaded, the pros - pect of the affected fowls is not so favorable, as it is common for them to become emaciated and to die from extreme ex - haustion. Treatment and prevention. — Affected animals should be promptly isolated and treated by the application of a mixture composed of one part of tincture of iodine and six parts of glycerine. This mixture should be applied two or three times a week. It will probably not be effective when the feathered skin is involved, and hence it seems advisable to destroy such animals without delay so that they may not serve as infec - tion sources. TUBERCULOSIS Avian tuberculosis still constitutes one of the major scourges of poultry in many of our agricultural states, includ - ing Nebraska. It appears, however, that its extension since 1927 has not been so rapid as before and that in certain areas it has been halted. After it had been conclusively shown that avian tuberculous infection is transmissible to other livestock, its great economic importance became more gen - erally recognized, with the result that along* with the eradica - tion of bovine tuberculosis, general measures tending to the control of the disorder in poultry yards were instituted and these efforts are now beginning to bear fruit. In the course of the year 1927 the Nebraska State Bureau of Animal Industry undertook a survey of the prevalence of poultry tuberculosis among the flocks of four precincts situ - ated in different parts of the state. The results are revealed by the following table: </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Poultry Diseases _ . t Flocks Flocks Fowls Fowls " ecIncI tested infected Percentage tested infected Percentace Number Number Percent Number Number Percent I 83 77.0 92.7 10,582 883 8.3 H 37 29.0 78.3 5,518 921 16.0 III 81 41.0 60.G 6,225 260 4.1 IV- 90 690 76.6 17,748 1,696 9.6 Summary 291 216.0 74.3 40.073 3,760 9.3 Similar conditions as revealed by this survey are, no doubt, still prevailing in many districts, and hence poultry growers in general should continue to reckon with this source of economic loss and to inaugurate or continue efforts toward eradication and control. The preponderating number of cases of avian tuberculosis is furnished by the common fowl and the turkey. It must not be thought, however, that these are the only birds susceptible to the infection. Tuberculosis has been found in geese, ducks, swans, pigeons, ostriches, pheasants, parrots, and can - ary birds. Wild birds in captivity readily succumb to it but to what extent it is prevalent among the free wild birds is not known. One of the writers once observed it in the sparrow and was able to prove that those birds could be readily infected with material taken from tuberculous chick - ens. It is not improbable that sparrows and other flying birds aid in the distribution of the disease among poultry flocks on the farms. Cause. — The dause of tuberculosis in all animals is the Bacillus tuberculosis. This organism constitutes a specific entity, but it includes certain strains which are more par - ticularly associated with the special kind of animal affected with the disease. The variety of tuberculosis bacillus par - ticularly responsible for the infection in birds is known as the avian strain. It presents certain characteristic features by which it can often be identified. Those features are par - ticularly shown by the manner in which it grows on artificial culture media and by the tendencies to produce disease in some experimental animals and not in others. The avian tuberculosis bacillus is very virulent to most of the birds and especially so to the domesticated species. It is quite resistant to external influences, and an infected poultry yard may remain so for a long time after it has been vacated by the tuberculous fowls. It is not readily destroyed by the common disinfectants, but is easily killed by heat. Low tem - peratures do not affect it in the least. Direct sunlight kills </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 the organism quite rapidly, but is only active on the surface of the substance in which the bacillus may be contained. As in most transmissible diseases, the spread of tubercu - losis takes its start directly or indirectly from an animal previously diseased. The Bacillus tuberculosis cannot under natural conditions grow and propagate itself outside of the animal body. Poultry tuberculosis is not an exception to this rule, and when it is met with in a flock its presence is due to an introduction of the infection from without. This introduction frequently follows that of newly purchased fowls into a healthy flock. This, however, is not the only means by which a flock may become infected. Trimmings and offal from poultry purchased for table use and carelessly disposed of also constitute a certain means of transmitting poultry tuberculosis. In the transmission of tuberculosis from fowl to fowl in an infected flock, the droppings of the infected birds must be regarded as practically the only means. The bacilli are often contained in this material in prodigious numbers, although in not a few cases it may be difficult to find the organism in the bowel discharges. In addition to this mode of exit of the infection, the possibility of escape of bacilli from open lesions of joints and bones must be given recognition. With regard to the entrance of ' the bacilli into healthy fowls, all evidence strongly points to the fact that poultry tuberculosis is usually introduced through the digestive or - gans. In the ordinary course of events the droppings of the tuberculous birds contaminate food and water in which the bacilli are conveyed to the healthy poultry stock. Transmis - sion by means of infected eggs is not impossible, but in the light of the results of an inquiry made by the Minnesota Ex - periment Station the infection danger associated with the eggs from tuberculous fowls can be regarded as negligible. The infection picked up in food or water finds its way into the intestines. There the organisms either become localized in the intestinal walls or, finding their way into the blood stream, are deposited in the liver or scattered throughout the body. In the densely populated poultry yards, the soil be - comes a true reservoir of infection and hence avian tubercu - losis must, to a large extent, be looked upon as soil borne. Symptoms. — It is only after the disease has progressed to the more advanced stages that symptoms begin to appear. Before that time either there are no symptoms at all or they are so vague or indefinite as to be of no value in the recogni - tion of the disorder. During the latter stages, the disease </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Poultry Diseases is commonly indicated by a great loss of flesh, accompanied by dullness, roughness of the feathers, and a certain degree of pallor of the comb and wattles. When one lifts a bird so affected, its marked lightness is at once noticed. Upon closer examination, especially of the region of the breast, it seems that the flesh has entirely disappeared and the outline of the breastbone can be distinctly felt or seen under the skin. In a few cases it is possible to feel the tuberculous masses of the internal organs through the thin abdominal walls. Com - monly such animals die in an extremely emaciated condition, although occasionally a bird is observed in a fair state of health or body in spite of extensive tuberculous disease. In a few cases, more external parts are affected, and then such structures as bones, joints, or skin show features character - istic of the disease. When the bones and joints are involved in the disease, the affected bird is lame or drags one or both wings, while the diseased parts show distinct enlargements, accompanied by ulceration or not. Diagnosis. — If for the recognition of the disease one had to depend on the __-^^. symptoms p r e- .^^fi^B^EW sented by the liv- j^&amp;l wB\ Jfev ing fowls, the fmw\ - 1 '"MmM "BEV majority of the Jj , V ;J.A^O ftijg^ cases would not M \ . / ' ji^Cl / ■$:■ be diagnosed un- m \a \ til the very last am ' / ' - j$y stageswere A ' • , " ,j&amp; reached. Even fl ,; i ' /^ Wk then it would be Jjl ....; K /. - ( Ba. difficult to con- 0 . ' Vgf^ - In elude with any ■ HSP^ H degree of accu- \J ! ; BSaSg racy whether the u '■&gt;■'- ",''.^r\W : .-■' symptoms pres- W ' " : "fc^ ' ent were those of •■■ ' "^7 W "^ tuberculosis o r r , not. Wasting disease may be _ ,_ _ . ,..,., caused by many PIG. 12.— Tuberculosis of chicken hver. factors other than tuberculosis and the swellings of the joints and bones may also be due to a variety of causes. When lesions are near the body surface, they may be sub - jected to a bacteriologic examination, and the same may be done with the droppings ; but on the whole such methods are </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 rather unsatisfactory. The question of diagnosis pertains more particularly to the flock as a whole, and hence the most practical method of gaining knowledge about the absence or presence of tuberculosis is to kill one of the more suspected birds for the purpose of post-mortem examination. Circum - stances, however, often arise which render it desirable to recognize the infection in the living animals. When such is the case, the tuberculin test, which became available twenty years ago, may render valuable assistance. Tuberculin test. — For the purpose of testing chickens for tuberculosis a tuberculin prepared from the avian tuberculosis bacillus is used and the method employed consists of the in - jection of a small droplet of this sub- .^hI SltoR^E.' ~ stance into and .^BSJ^feiPl^-^'^' mnfttolti not under the fitS^ffiz**^' ' \ ''■' '■■'" " skin of one of '*» " : -'t ... v SteV the wattles. Jt(fflsBpr%i;&amp;'- :^%B&amp;&amp;' -— * "^'^ ; JL\ means of a BlK^^2bF^^^&amp;k?^&lt;^''^- *' r * t«\ f-* jPktj k, 'iffy JtTtg^R-^.* 1 tftisr '.""■ * Tj " " Yi very essential ■^^' &lt;^v&lt;^^^/ Bt^V-?' ' •/'%'' -»i that the injec- Majjfi. ■*^T/ Z?%lfe "^-\^^m tions be made ■ u^M?''' - '■' '^%8anSr in a correct 1 "'''"^^^ manner, and, 5 ?^ while this is ufarly* difficult FlG&gt; 13 — Tuberculosis of chicken liver - a certain degree of skill must be acquired before reliable re - sults can be expected. While the wattle of the fowl to be tested is held between the thumb and index finger of the operator, the needle is care - fully inserted into the skin in a slanting direction. Care must be taken not to push the needle through the skin, be - cause tuberculin injected under the skin will not produce a reaction. Neither must the needle be inserted too super - ficially as in such a case the injected tuberculin will break through and escape on the surface. With the needle placed correctly within the substance of the skin, the plunger of the syringe is slowly pushed in, causing </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Poultry Diseases iSt^lKSi 0 * the SK^fe to diffuse around the a ™ri,S2i? ? succes sful injections are those which require fn* witwi* /I 1 " 66 °v P^i^ «P°n the plunger and dur - ing: which the tuberculin diffuses but slowly into the skin tissues. In such injections an increasing whte or Li 0 r 0 f1hf watfle adUally replaCGS thG n ° rmal red Tf- No attempt need be made to regulate the amount Of tuberculin to be used for each injection. When I the injection is made correctly, this amount regu- I lates itself by the degree of resistance offered by II the tissues. About so much can be injected and no more, while the amount used has but little in- __k« ?l nee °" , the de sree of the reaction, if any is to tflflf follow. The smallest dose of tuberculin correctly " ! placed is amply sufficient for the object aimed at I I One cubic centimeter of avian tuberculin should be I i amply sufficient for the testing of twenty fowls. t 1 When a reaction takes place, it consists of a !|ij more or less distinct swelling of the injected wattle '! I | fcuch swelling may show a considerable variation I m size m the birds which react to the test. In Ml some it is scarcely perceptible, while in others I the wattle may be more than double the size of ! its unmjected mate. The swellings are not inflam- I matory and the red color of the normal wattle is ij 1' commonly changed to a lighter hue. In the cen - tral portion of the enlargement, the parts are II usually of a pale, yellowish color, while immedi- W ately around this area a dirty, red tint, occasion- &lt;*4 ally with a greenish cast, may be observed. I .. j The reaction can frequently be observed 24 V*» hours after the injection, but in the majority of \T cases it does not attain its maximum until about \ 48 hours after the injection. From then on the swelling gradually disappears and on the fifth day after the injection signs of a reaction have usually * completely disappeared. The test is not an abso- Fig. 14. - lute one, largely because of the fact that some Tuberculin birds, if extensively diseased, will have lost their "^"we - capacity for reaction. However, such birds can nearly always be recognized by their emaciation and such other symntamJ as may distinguish the disease. In the interpretatioTof the test results, all manifest swellings after inj'ection must bl </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 regarded as evidence of infection and if we also place in the diseased group the fowls which have shown a somewhat doubtful reaction, the danger of missing many cases of tuberculosis can be reduced to a minimum. Lesions. — As the name tuberculosis indicates, the chief characteristic of the disease is the formation of small nodules or tubercles. This is seen in all the typical forms of the dis - ease of all animals, and that in birds offers no exception fyTL. to this rule. The nodules //-' j mentioned occur as whitish, '-■ c itgT grayish, or pearly spherical &gt;gfr' ! "^pN^. bodies either imbedded in the /raaV^^' Rm tissues of the organs affected QJm!tfl$ '^Vn^$« or protruding from their free fs^'/tra^V 1^ surfaces. Commonly of millet- &amp; ' m seed size, they always have a ' ¥^P : f' l^M In tendency to form conglomera- ■Bait^ i\ ■* tions, which may grow to be \ \ I \ yf}. of considerable size. When : \ WrVfm' K the tubercles are found in the M^f*^ ;fl &amp;. skin or mucous membranes, ''' ■ '^ •'"'-' '» they show a tendency to break cm -i &gt; m : . down and to form ulcers. The M.p R older tubercles are composed M&gt; ".?,.•;. of a cheesy substance and in &gt;fe this material the bacillus can mjf£j'~'-r M The distribution 6f the W lesions of avian tuberculosis ? is quite characteristic of the f -j?l~; •.'...- . disease. In fowls the liver is the organ most commonly FlG - 15 - — Tuberculin reaction in affected, closely followed by left wattle - the spleen. The intestines are commonly involved in the dis - ease, while bones and joints are also favorite seats of the infection. Lesions are further observed in the ovary, testi - cles, lungs, and kidneys and more rarely in almost any other part of the body. The appearance of the liver lesions is determined to a large extent by the duration of the disease. In the more recent cases the nodules are small and when only a moderate number of bacilli have invaded the organ their appearance may not be very conspicuous. In the case of an overpowering invasion the number of tubercles may be enormous. In the older </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Poultry Diseases lesions the tubercles are larger, frequently encapsulated and quite sharply differentiated from the surrounding livertf ssue In the more advanced cases the liver may be greatly enlarged either in its entirety or in only one of the lobes. Under the influence of degenerative changes the organ assumes a Hghte? color and its tissues become quite friable, so that fatal hemorrhages may take place. Thp h «nSS!f n * Ott *2 . he l? mes * rea % enlarged and distorted. The nodules found in the spleen are similar to those in the liver, although quite commonly somewhat smaller. In very ?„ J£ ?e £ • i- ?J* a * ""ly be transformed into a cheesy mass In £ S£^ Ual J" be f cl ? S CSn n ° Ionger be distinguished thlt ,Vf, Iv testm 2f, the lesions vary somewhat according to their situation. They may consist of very small nodules in the mucous membrane or of small ulcers with slightly raised edges. More commonly the nodules are prominent on the outer surface of the intestine. In such cas?s the lesions give rise to scars in the wall of the tube and contain a fine grittv substance. Such nodules, either single or combined in mfsse? range m size from that of a pinhead to that of a p ge?n egg They are either imbedded in the substance of the intestS i wall or attached to the outer surface by means of nd e stem or neck. The smaller nodules often present a trans parent appearance, while the larger ones a?e more opaqui, white or yellowish in color, and of a more solid consistency The lesions in the other organs mentioned, on the whole conform to those seen in the liver, spleen, and intestine! Course.— As is commonly the case in tuberculosis of S^iv. mm T? 1S ', th , G diS T Se \ n Wrds is aIso chronkafy pro! Noffi" pS, h Wly and + s " re i v leads to emaciation and death. Nothing can be expected from curative treatment The chronic nature of the disease is responsible for the fact that commonly the older fowls of an infected flock furnish the greater number of cases. They are the more profuse spread - ers of the infection. On the other hand, certain observations made by the writers indicate that young fowls Sleven are more apt to contract the disease in an infected environ-' Year when hatched Percentage of infection 19% 85.71 J-OAU „_ . . iq-11 OO.44 1S1^ - 3.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 The almost equal degree of morbidity shown by the fowls hatched in 1909 and 1910 can be attributed to the fact that these two groups were simultaneously exposed to the initial in ThS°M8ults obtained by the survey undertaken by the Ne - braska Bureau of Animal Industry also showed in a striking manner this influence of age. It was shown that of the 40,073 fowls tested 23,165, or 57.8 per cenVwere of an age of one year or less and that 16,908, or 42.2 per cent, were more than one year of age. The younger birds furnished only 843 which showed evidence of infection, or 3.6 per cent of their group On the other hand, 2,917 of the older birds were found to be tuberculous, or 17.0 per cent of their group. Prevention.— As in many other transmissible diseases, sanitation San important factor in the prevention of poul- S? tuberculosis. Cleanliness of the pens houses, and eating and drinking appliances, as well as sanitary construction of poultThoSs g es,is of the utmost importance. Overcrowding Sould be especially avoided because should an infected fowl be present in the flock its more intimate contact with the healthy, members of the flock can only promote a more rapid ■"■gStabSl^Srf tuberculous birds from without should be particularly guarded against, because such fowls are the common vehicles by which the disease is transported from P^to pllce Either the freedom from disease of the newly acquired birds should be absolutely known or it should be in the disposal of the offal of poultry purchased for the table. This is perhaps not a common means of disease introduction into farm flocks, but SdSS £d villages the small back-yard I flock ■ gwejrf^ monies infected from such a source. Hence, all ottal snouia onTurnS instead of being thrown out or disposed of as gar - blge The transmission of tuberculosis through wild birds or" by means of infected eggs is somewhat problematic, yet fhU should not be left without consideration. Recent investigations completed at this station have shown that thfgreSer part of swine tuberculosis and a small num - ber of bovfne^ are of avian origin and this fact should not be lKstt of whenever meat scraps are Jo be used as poultry feed. The boiling of meat scraps and the like, used Js poultry feed, will thus be desirable in order to eliminate S Section danger associated with such material By the practice of a certain degree of vigilance it will not be difficult </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Poultry Diseases SU"*^ a ,, health y fl °ck against tuberculosis. Much more difficult is the task of coping with the disease, once it is present in the flock. The exclusion of infected birds and of contaminated food - stuffs will, under most circumstances, be sufficient to protect a healthy flock against becoming involved in tuberculosis The safety of flocks is, however, largely determined by the prevalence of avian tuberculosis throughout the region in which they are situated. In the parts of the state where the morbidity rate is relatively low the hazards of clean flocks becoming infected for obvious reasons are slight in compari - son with those in sections where three-fourths of the flocks are tuberculous. The fact merely emphasizes the importance ox the eradication of the disease— a measure upon which the solution of the avian tuberculosis problem must ultimately depend. In the eradication of tuberculosis from poultry flocks, there are at least two important infection sources which must be closed before further progress of the disease can be effectively checked. One is the infected bird and the other the infected soil of poultry yards, premises, etc. It is possible to cull out infected fowls by means of the tuberculin test and in selected flocks this method can be made a very useful factor in the eradication of the disease. In the application of this method all birds showing either a positive or a doubtful reaction should be destroyed and the healthy birds removed to uncon - taminated quarters and to yards to which the tuberculous flock has had no access. The difficulty in complying with the latter requirements is, however, responsible for a consider - able part of the disappointment which often follows the tuberculin-culling method of eradication. In the case of small flocks and of those in which no great breeding value is to be considered, the problem may be solved in a radical manner by the killing of the entire flock and by subsequently keeping the contaminated premises unoccupied by poultry for a considerable period, one to two years This method also offers disadvantages which are likely to restrict its application, useful as it may otherwise be. In regions such as our own state, with a considerable degree of prevalence of avian tuberculosis, the generally applied tuberculin test and general culling, even if this were possible to carry out, would still leave an enormous amount of yard mfection to transmit tuberculosis to a new poultry population Yard infection ultimately disappears if no new supplies of tubercle bacilli are deposited on it. This process may involve a number of years, but it is certain that the infection in- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 cidence progressively declines from year to year and that in time the disease will cease to make its appearance. To pre - vent the renewal of the volume of the infection, the simple expedient of not permitting infected fowls to reach the stage of the disease at which they become infection spreaders is, without doubt, the most rational and practical measure in the control of avian tuberculosis. As has already been pointed out, tuberculosis is essentially a disease of the older members of the flock. Manifest lesions of tuberculosis are rarely seen in birds less than six months old and in practically all cases in which the disease has de - veloped to the extent that the fowl acts as a spreader, the latter is more than one year of age. Hence, one of the most efficient means of coping with the tuberculosis of the poultry yard under the general conditions prevailing in our state is the annual elimination of all birds more than one year old or not later than at the close of their first egg-laying period. In flocks where the disease has not yet made its appearance, the age limit may be extended to two years as a means of protection and as a sound measure of poultry husbandry.. In the absence of more precise information on the preval - ence of fowl tuberculosis the method described above could be regarded as a makeshift, but in the light of the present knowledge made available by the Nebraska survey, the cull - ing of the older birds for the purpose of preventing further additions to the infection of the soil commends itself as the best of procedures. Tuberculosis in poultry, at least, cannot be got rid of by gesture or by unsustained efforts. In many cases it probably is a matter of several years before the con - quest of the disease is complete, but with the systematic elim - ination of all fowls old enough to become spreaders, there can be no doubt of the final outcome. In dealing with an infected flock on infected premises, it is proposed to follow the plan of disposing of the one-year - old birds for two or three years and then to ascertain by means of the tuberculin test if all infection has been elimin - ated. If only negative reactions are obtained, the fowls in the flock can thereafter be permitted to live two years if such be deemed necessary. FOWL CHOLERA This disease must be reckoned with by Nebraska poultry growers. From time to time it asserts itself in more or less disastrous outbreaks. Contrary to the behavior of certain other poultry diseases, the hazards associated with fowl cholera are not marked by a high degree of constancy. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Poultry Diseases ' In the course of certain years, or even in series of years extensive outbreaks may occur with marked frequency and such periods may then be followed by a stretch of time dur - ing which the disorder is relatively uncommon. However the fact remains that losses from fowl cholera are never entirely absent in any year and that the disease has been found to have occurred in the majority of counties in the course of the last fifteen years at least. Cause—Fowl cholera is caused by a microorganism known as the fowl cholera bacillus. This is quite small, non - motile and ovoid in shape, with a tendency to become colored only at the extremities by the ordinary stains used in the laboratory. It can be readily grown on artificial culture media although its growth is but rarely very profuse. The organism is more or less widely distributed in nature and forms part of the microorganisms belonging to the so - called hemorrhagic septicemia group. The fowl cholera bacillus is, as a rule, extremely virulent to the small labora - tory animals, rabbits especially being markedly susceptible ihis microbe may also be found in other animals of the farm although in these it is not apt to play a part as a primary cause of disease. It appears to have a tendency to localize itseli m parts of the body and in tissues which are damaged or impaired by other types of infection or injuries of a non - mfectious nature. Evidence has been presented that outside the animal body the bacillus may survive for periods of considerable length in the droppings they will remain alive and virulent for at least one month, while in soil or decomposing carcasses they have been found to remain alive for three months. Those periods, however, are subject to considerable variation on account of such influences as temperature, moisture, and the complex process by which soil and other substances are puri - fied. * It is obvious that such environmental infection sources should receive adequate attention when preventive measures are to be designed. However, a study undertaken by this btation revealed an infection source, referred to later apparently more potent for mischief than the one associated with the surroundings in which the disease has destroyed many fowls. In the course of these experiments it was found that in a poultry yard in which during a period of approxi - mately three years fowl cholera had maintained itself, the infection hazard had apparently entirely, disappeared two weeks after the yard had been vacated and after the occur - rence of the last death caused by the disease. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 The group of bacteria to which the one causing fowl cholera belongs is marked by variability and instability of their dis - ease-producing qualities. They may be found to be entirely harmless, but through influences of which we know nothing may suddenly assume death-dealing qualities. Outbreaks of fowl cholera may suddenly assert themselves, kill many birds, and then suddenly cease. It is not impossible that the many observations of contradictory facts may have to be attributed to this peculiarity. All species of domestic birds are susceptible to the disease. Chickens and turkeys are common victims, while geese and ducks may become involved in extremely disastrous outbreaks of the disease. Many wild birds are liable to the infection and it is quite probable that they are factors in carrying the infection from place to place. It is not always possible to determine how the disease is introduced into a flock. It commonly follows the introduction of new purchases or the purchase of birds used for the table. All such birds may be of normal appearance and yet be in - fected, as there is evidence which shows that a certain num - ber of fowls of infested flocks while escaping disease or death may become more or less persistent carriers of infection. That apparently healthy infection carriers may play a part in the transmission and spread of fowl cholera has already been established by Webster, Hughes, Pritchett, and Beau - dette. Early in the fowl-cholera experiments of our own Station it became evident that in the transmission of the dis - ease, factors other than purely environmental ones were pre - dominant. The rather explosive outbreak which almost immediately followed the introduction of infected fowls, and which in all respects simulated the usual outbreaks as they occur on farms, indicated a direct-contact infection of great virulence. In the course of further studies pertaining to the mode of trans - mission, results were obtained which fully substantiated the conclusions of the investigators cited above. It was found that healthy birds may carry the infection. In such cases the fowl-cholera bacillus occupies the upper air passages of such fowls, and from there can readily find its way out of the body. The infection is given off by the diseased birds, especially by means of body wastes. These contaminate the soil as well as the food and water of the poultry yard and constitute per - haps the most important factor in the dissemination of the disease. After the death of the infected birds, their car - casses, thoroughly laden with infection, may remain a source </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Poultry Diseases of infection for many months, a fact which is made especially dangerous through the tendency of healthy birds to eat this type of material. In the case of waterfowl, the contaminated water of the ponds and ditches in which the birds swim is probably the most prolific source of infection. Another vehicle of infection may be found in eggs procured from infected flocks. The bacillus of fowl cholera has been repeatedly found in eggs of infected chickens and such must certainly be regarded as potential sources of danger, even if there is little evidence which points in that direction. In fact the danger from infected eggs is somewhat denied by the fact that fowl cholera is relatively rare in chicks and young poultry. This Department has received fowl-cholera fowls from many hundreds of outbreaks and yet in no case was the disease found to affect chicks under two months old. The possibility of fowl-cholera infection being carried by insects always suggests itself. It seems doubtful that this mode of transmission is either common or important under the ordinary circumstances associated with farm outbreaks of the disease. Thus in the poultry yards of this Station exclusively devoted to the study of poultry diseases, nothing was observed to indicate that fowl cholera was transmitted by flies. These yards have included twelve lots, each more or less continuously occupied by an average of about 100 birds for a period of five years. During the first three years of this period virulent outbreaks of fowl cholera were maintained in two of the lots without the appearance of fowl cholera among the remainder of the poultry population which could at all be attributed to fly transmission. The more virulent of the outbreaks in the fowl-cholera lots occurred at the height of the fly season and although these lots were separated from the adjoining ones only by a fence of ordinary poultry wire, the latter proved to be a sufficient barrier against the spread of the disease. In comparison with the transmission hazards associated with infection-carrying healthy fowls, the part played by flies appears to be insignificant. This is also indicated by another observation made in the above-mentioned poultry yard. After an outbreak of fowl cholera had apparently come to a close in the lots set aside for the study of this disease, it was deemed expedient to make use of the surviving birds in lots in which another disease was being investigated. As a meas - ure of safety these fowls were removed to and quarantined in a clean stable on October 10, 1930, and kept there until October 28, 1930. During the 18 days of isolation all these fowls remained in good health and it seemed quite safe to </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 place them among the poultry occupying the other lots as already indicated. All went well until November 25, 1930, when one of the transferred birds was found dead with fowl cholera. More cases developed and between the date mentioned and January 17, 1931, when all fowls were disposed of, nineteen birds had succumbed to cholera. Nine of these were transferred birds eight belonged to the original inhabitants of the lot, and two could not be identified, having lost their leg bands. In spite of such observation it cannot be denied that under unusual circumstances flies, may actually transport fowl - cholera germs. Such an instance was reported by Skidmore, who observed fowl cholera among some poults kept in a build - ing in which flies had access to opened carcasses of chickens dead of the disease, as well as to the cages in which the poults were kept. He succeeded in showing that the flies were capable of bringing about infective contacts. It is commonly accepted that fowl-cholera infection enters the body with contaminated food and water. The feeding of the offal of infected fowls killed for the table may likewise be a p means of carrying the infection. No doubt the germs may also be introduced into the body through small abrasions of the skm, while infected dust deposited on the mucous mem - branes of the upper air passages may lead to a similar result. As soon as the organism has found entrance into the body of J;ne susceptible fowl it is rapidly disseminated through the body; there it swarms into the blood circulation or may be - come localized in certain tissues. In some of the more chronic forms of the disease the germs have a tendency to become localized wherever the body tissues are defective or subject to injury, and it is not uncommon to find them in gangrenous areas which are apt to be present between the skin and the keel of the breastbone. Symptoms — In the infection of flocks by natural ex - posure, from four to nine days, as a rule, elapse between the introduction of the infected material and the first appearance of symptoms, if symptoms there are at all. To this there may, however, be exceptions. In the fowl cholera experiments above mentioned, explosive outbreaks occurred within 48 hours after the introduction of infected birds among the ones occupying the lots which thus far had not been in any wav exposed. The manifestations of the disease present evidence of great virulence and we know of no other disease which in such a short space of time can cause such havoc in a poultry flock. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Poultry Diseases It is especially during the beginning of the outbreak that the infection may be explosively deadly. Birds seen in an ap - parently normal state of health are found dead within the space of an hour or two. The first indication of trouble in a flock frequently consists m } £ ndin £ of one or several fowls dead on the nests or under the perches. In such outbreaks sick poultry is but rarely seen on account of the overpowering rapidity with which the disease kills. When the outbreaks progress the virulence may become less marked and sick birds may be found and examined. Then we find the sick fowls to be dull stupid, with ruffled feathers, and their heads tucked under their wings. There is commonly a high degree of drowsiness which quite often assumes the character of profound sleep or coma. Affected animals still able to move will frequently show lameness, on account of inflammatory joint lesions accompanied or not by enlargement of the parts. The wings droop or are carried in an unnatural position, owing to the same cause. The comb and wattles commonly have a dull, purple color, although this is not by any means a very constant symptom Nostrils and mouth may be filled with a whitish or pinkish troth. Diarrhea is a frequent symptom, sometimes very con - spicuous and then again altogether absent. In the beginning of outbreaks diarrhea may not be observed because the fowls succumb so rapidly that there is no time for its development The bowel discharges appear as profuse watery evacuations of a yellowish gray, yellowish, greenish, or pinkish color. The color is never such as to indicate the nature of the disease The recognition of poultry diseases by the color of the dung is not possible. The bowel discharges soil the feathers and not uncommonly the latter are glued together into a fetid mass about the vent. The sick birds not uncommonly show hard difficult breathing, accompanied by a rattling sound, indi - cating the presence of fluid mucus in the air passages When the virulence of the outbreak diminishes, the fowls die less suddenly; they lie around sick for three or four days before dying or become involved in the chronic form of the disease, when they remain in a stupor for several days without eating or drinking. Such cases waste away in flesh, often to a remarkable degree. Recovery from fowl cholera is very rare .and it is quite probable that many of the birds which do recover develop into more or less persistent infec - tion carriers. It is not always easy to recognize the disease without re - course to a bacteriologic examination. None of the symptoms </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 presented by sick birds is sufficiently characteristic for an accurate recognition of the disease. The unexpected onset of Sffi OJlt &gt; re , ak^ ith . its many sudden deaths 4 ? £ as a ruk be sufficient to direct one's suspicion, at least, to the diseasl £??£ COn f der 1 f tl( t n and especially so if waterfowl also sharl in the outbreak. In outbreaks in which this feature is elthe? have to O b e n^L C T P1^ OU^ a ba . cte "°logic examination wm have to be made for the diagnosis of the disease. As yet it remains impossible to recognize the living infection carriers w E 7 inex P en ?, lv e and yet dependable test. Should such I SSEw^ SeJSEJT step in the »-*« "eta HefS^ ° f SUdden death A number of birds which succumb to a one or two dav*' although occasionally it is enlarged and congested I Cnanged ' fonnH f 6 m0? " e Chroi i ic forms of the disease there may be </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Poultry Diseases the disease disappears as suddenly as it came or takes on the form of sporadic cases which occur one by one at intervals of several days. In other instances, again, the disease begins slowly but steadily causes a greater number of deaths until the flock is entirely wiped out or nearly so. It is impossible to foretell with any degree of certainty what the outcome of a given outbreak will be. The fate of the birds affected can be more easily foretold They nearly all die and if a sick bird occasionally recovers it commonly remains in a decrepit state or becomes a chronic virus carrier. On that account, sick birds should be elimin - ated from a flock by killing them without delay. Treatment. — Treatment of cholera-infected fowls is entirely useless and there is not the slightest reason to be - lieve that the use of medicine of any kind can either save infected birds or be depended on to influence the course of an outbreak in a flock. Hence, money paid for the pills, tablets, and potions alleged to be useful as cures or preventives of fowl cholera is as good as thrown away. Prevention. — Fowl cholera, like the other communicable diseases of poultry, must be controlled by preventive meas - ures, difficult as they appear to be under certain circum - stances. The applications of such measures pertain to the protection of the healthy flock as well as to the management of the one in which the disorder has already appeared. Although the influence of the environment may not be as potent in the propagation of fowl cholera as it is in many other transmissible disorders of poultry, the maintenance of sanitary yards, houses, and equipment should never be neglected. As the essentials of poultry hygiene and sanitation have already received attention in a preceding chapter, the reader is referred to it. Of the utmost importance is the warning that care be taken when new stock has to be introduced. In general the practice of purchasing mature stock in order to recruit a flock is associated with the hazard of introducing disease. In the case of fowl cholera, of which the transmission appears to be associated with healthy fowls which carry the causative germs, this statement cannot be overemphasized. Because there seems to be little or no evidence that the disease is be - ing transmitted by day-old chicks or by hatching eggs it seems prudent to prefer them to the adult stock when new blood has to be introduced or when additions to the flock have to be made. It is obvious, however, that chicks and eggs originating in cholera-infected flocks should be rejected </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 Caution demands that fowls returning from fairs and shows, where birds from many places are brought together, should be regarded with suspicion. Hence it is advisable to keep such fowls in isolation for at least three or four weeks before admitting them to the general flock. As a further pre - caution they should, during the term of segregation, be given some of the healthy birds of the flock as companions. If no disease appears among these fowls they can be set free with a considerable degree of safety. If, on the other hand, fowl cholera should develop among them, it would be folly not to destroy the birds then in isolation. At this time it is not possible to estimate the part played by flying birds as transmitters of fowl cholera. On purely theoretic grounds, however, it seems wise to regard the main - tenance of pigeon flocks as a menace in any area where out - breaks of fowl cholera are at all common. Offal, especially of poultry derived from outside sources and killed for table use, should never be disposed of in any other way than by burning. In infected flocks our first attention should be given to the immediate destruction of dead fowls. Birds showing evidence of sickness should be killed, without spilling any of the blood, and all carcasses burned. The yard in which the disease has gained a foothold should be carefully freed from any insanitary features, and a most thorough search must be made for dead or sick birds in out - of-the-way places «so that they may not serve as reservoirs for future infection. Poultry houses, eating and drinking utensils, and whatever else may have been in contact with the infected flock should be thoroughly disinfected. The yard in which the disease occurred should be left unpopulated by poultry stock until it has had the benefit of the purifying action of from two to three months of warm weather at least. When repopulation of the yard is to be undertaken, a small number of trial birds may be turned into it and their fate observed for some time before risking a greater number. In outbreaks of great virulence the advisability of slaugh - ter, for table use or for canning, of the entire flock, must be given consideration. This may be the only way of saving anything at all out of the general wreck. In times past this radical measure was commonly recommended in all outbreaks of fowl cholera, and in view of the occurrence of germ-carry - ing fowls among the survivors of the outbreak, such counsel is certainly worthy of consideration. We have, however, to reckon with circumstances under which this most radical procedure would be too costly. In such cases the healthy but exposed fowls should be immediately </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Poultry Diseases removed from the yard in which the disease has occurred and be kept in a non-contaminated environment and there divided into as many small groups as possible. This may prove to be irksome, and the fact that some of the fowls may endure as virus carriers for prolonged periods must always be seriously reckoned with. In productive flocks in which fowl-cholera infection has gained entrance, it may be feasible to let the birds remain where they are and then dispose of them for immediate slaughter as soon as production is no longer profitable. Under no condition should fowls thus exposed be permitted to come in contact with the ones which are to succeed them on the farm. The new flock should not be permitted to occupy the ground on which infected birds have been maintained until after three or four months of warm weather have contributed to the self-purification of the soil. The latter may have been consummated within a shorter period but a rather wide mar - gin of safety will certainly do no harm. At the present time there is no reason to believe that any good results can be expected from the use of vaccines. Re - search pertaining to this subject, engaged in by this Station, has thus far yielded results which strongly indicate that such vaccination methods as are used in hog cholera, blackleg and some other diseases, will perhaps never become available for fowl cholera. FOWL TYPHUS Fowl typhus or Klein's disease has been more or less com - mon among Nebraska chickens during the last 15-year period of observation. Its prevalence, however, has been subject to a considerable degree of variation. In the course of certain years many outbreaks were recorded, whereas during subse - quent periods the disease became relatively uncommon. The fact remains that this disorder is always to be reckoned with and more particularly so in the course of periods of abundant rainfall, by which the condition of poultry yards is always apt to*become insalubrious. Fowl typhus constitutes a transmissible disease of a septi - cemic character. In Nebraska it is nearly always confined to the common fowl, although elsewhere it has occasionally manifested itself among the other types of poultry. Hin - shaw has reported disastrous outbreaks of the disorder among turkeys in California, and other investigators have recog - nized the disease among ducks, peafowls, pheasants, and other birds. Chickens are, however, most susceptible to typhus when naturally exposed. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 Cause. — Fowl typhus is caused by the fowl-typhus bacillus (Bacillus gaUinarum) , a germ belonging to the colon - typhus group of bacteria. The causative germs are usually taken into the body with contaminated food or drinking water. From the digestive tract the infective organisms are apt to find their way to the blood, a fact which gives the disease its septicemic character. As a rule the bacilli are present in the spleen in considerable numbers. The intestinal tube of sick birds is practically always infected and the droppings of such animals constitute the usual vehicle by which germs leave the body. The germ of fowl typhus is very , closely related to the one which causes bacillary white diarrhea and there is evidence to show that the former is quite capable of doing the same harm as the latter and vice versa. Symptoms. — For a long time prior to the discovery of its cause it was confounded with fowl cholera and even now it must be admitted that in many cases it is difficult to differen - tiate between the two disorders without having recourse to bacteriologic methods. Although fowl typhus must be regard - ed as an acute disease, it scarcely ever appears to be as pre - cipitate in its course as fowl cholera. The birds sick with typhus tend to linger for a few days before dying, and out - breaks are apt to take a drawn-out course. A few chickens sicken and after that no new cases may develop in the flock during periods varying in length. Then suddenly the disease may again assert itself and this process may be repeated for a considerable length of time. Artificially infected chickens commonly manifest signs of the disease from three to six days after the infective inocula - tion, but this period of incubation is subject to a considerable degree of variation. In experiments carried on by this Sta - tion, the incubation periods ranged between three and thirty - two days and in none of the groups inoculated did all the birds develop the disease. This tends to show that many birds may be quite resistant to the infection. In natural out - breaks also there may be a marked variation in the length of time elapsing between the date of exposure and that of the appearance of the first case of the disease. In the experi - ments already referred to this period ranged between five and forty-three days. Most of the cases of fowl typhus observed in Nebraska pertained to young adult birds, although the disorder was also found to be present among baby chicks as well as among more or less aged fowls. Sex does not appear to influence suscep - tibility. In natural outbreaks the affected fowls show dull- </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Poultry Diseases droon^VhTTl 11638 - Th .*. f 6atherS are ruff led and the ™«* 3 , T h % latter is evidence of great muscular weakness, which also frequently causes the birds to be unable to stand or to keep their heads in a normal position. Commonly the SStarTf Wattl6 f beC ° meS pale ' but occasSSy those structures become purple on account of the backing ud of venous blood due to deficiency of the functioning of the heart of£j, a ?S ea V Very - common Mature of the disease and is *™ e . m ost conspicuous symptom. The escape of a great ZHL° f l md , ?° m * he bowels is responsible for the fart Al?Ln I / f - ed bl^ ds 1 SO commonl y show great thirst. Although food is nearly always refused, the fowls are always willing to drink. The blood is often of a pale color, owing to ?«« f X !J r ? d bl00d cells ' In the more advanced tioi of t&amp; °Zt£ decidedly watery. A microscopic examina - tion of the blood shows that in a majority of fowl tvr&gt;hus number UOOd corpuscles are markedly SeaS in Diagnosis.— The recognition of the disease by takine account of symptoms is practically impossible. The diagnosis wrT^ + ° nl £ P ° SSible by the a PP^ation of ba C te??oy o g c whSi, S7 1 yPh ? S Ca l USUSlly be exclu ded in outbreaks in which all types of poultry are involved. As a rule the dis SSh ir d H than Ch0l -f a ' and the sudden ' ""expected deatS with the latter are quite uncommon in typhus outbreaks Lesions.—On the whole the after-death appearances of HL ?^ S affe ? ed "?S typhus are no morecharacterfsUc 5 J h u svm P toms before death. Some changes however should be recognized as pointing toward the present* Tolfowi typhus with a fair degree of accuracy. One of these is the watery condition of the blood, already mentioned Another feature commonly observed in fowl typhus carcassef "s the enlargement and dark red color of the spleen. In a largl number of cases examined at this Station the liver also was enlarged and quite often had a dark bronze color The orgTn is often quite friable and more or less degenerated The appearance of most of the important organs is somewhat determined by the duration of the disease. In the caseTwIVch have succumbed quite rapidly, either there are but few changes or they consist of congestion, while in those which and'tSe ?Sf,lf ther r Z*™?*? tendency toward degenerates and the resulting lighter tints. In cases which have resisted death unduly long we find pale, soft kidneys and hearts JJ,? 01 ",!* hver th e dark bronze may have made way for a very light brown or mottled yellow. In the more chronic forms the heart may be found to have becom? maSly </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 altered in appearance. The heart muscle then is apt to in - clude relatively large white nodular masses and not infre - quently the sac around the organ has thickened and become filled with an excessive amount of fluid. In the intestinal canal a catarrhal condition prevails, some - times uniformly throughout its entire extent, sometimes con - fined to certain sections only. Here and there the mucous membrane may be congested or even inflamed. Course. — Birds that acquire the disease naturally rarely recover, and there is no method of treatment by which this unfavorable outlook can be improved. No time and money thus should be wasted in trying to save the fowls already sick. As the disease appears in a given flock, there is a prospect that it will not progress as rapidly as cholera and that the losses will be less than could be expected with the latter dis - ease. Yet occasional outbreaks have been observed in which the disease slowly but surely exterminated the entire flock. In young chicks the disease may be quite disastrous. Pre - ventive measures are promising, but under our average farm - yard conditions they cannot always be applied in as thorough a manner as the needs of the case require. Control by sanita - tion is, however, the only means of dealing with the problem. Prevention. — The fact that fowl typhus is a typical filth - borne disease indicates that successful prevention may be based upon sanitary measures. Such measures have been set forth in the sections devoted to hygiene and sanitation. The maintenance of the flock on clean ground (rotation of yards), the protection of feed and water against fecal contamination, and the thorough removal of undesirable sources of drinking water must be accepted as particularly useful. The value of such measures has been fully confirmed by certain experimental results obtained by this Station. Two separate flocks of equal numbers, type, and origin of birds were maintained in two yards of equal size. One of these yards was a fair imitation of the ones commonly found on our farms. It was a dirt yard, with an open drain in the middle. The floor of the house was covered with a bedding of straw, and water and feed were supplied in open troughs. The other yard was reasonably sanitary in its appointments although by no means perfectly so. It was covered by a thick layer of gravel to assure constant dryness and water was sup - plied by self-cleaning fountains (Fig. 5), and self-feeders not open to contamination were put to use. The floor of the house was covered with one-inch-mesh hardware cloth on </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Poultry Diseases wooden frames. These two flocks were fed and cared for in an identical manner. Fowls previously infected with typhus were simultaneously and in equal number admitted to the flocks occupying the yards. This did not always initiate an outbreak but occasionally it did so, to a degree sufficient to enable one to measure the influence of sanitation. Altogether a total of eighty fowls succumbed to fowl typhus in both yards. Ten of these deaths occurred in the sanitary yard and seventy in the yard in which no attempts at sanita - tion were made. It follows that under equal exposure the chances of the fowls occupying the sanitary environment were seven times better than of those which were maintained in the less salubrious environment. * ! u , rth ? r , P recauti °n consideration must be given to the fact that healthy birds previously exposed to fowl-typhus in - fection may have developed into infection carriers. Hence it is prudent not to admit outside adult birds to a healthy flock for any reason. If flocks must be recruited or new blood in - troduced, preference should always be given to the purchase of hatching eggs or day-old chicks. If disease should develop among the latter it is not very difficult to eradicate the infec - tion without placing the adult members of the flock in jeon - ardy. J * Here and there apparently good results have been obtained by serum treatment or vaccination, although the evidence presented on this subject remains more or less contradictory, inus far such methods have not been practiced sufficiently to warrant recommendation, and poultry growers, for the time being, will do well to depend on sanitary measures wherever fowl typhus constitutes a menace. Sanitary meth - ods must also prevail in the management of actual outbreaks. All visibly affected birds should be destroyed and this should be done without spilling blood on the ground or the floor of houses. All dead birds must be disposed of by burning The fowls which are still in a good state of health should be re - moved to ground not previously occupied by the infected flock If possible to divide the flock into small groups, this may fur - ther have an influence tending to check the spread of the dis - order. Some pains should be taken to gather up the droppings of the fowls, and this material should also be burned if this is at all possible. If not, they should be deposited on some field not frequented by poultry stock. The yard previously occu - pied by the infected flock should be plowed up and left un - populated by fowls for several months. Poultry houses, eat - ing and drinking utensils, and tools or appliances used in the </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 removal of the infected droppings should be thoroughly dis - infected. After an outbreak, the hazard associated with surviving infection carriers or spreaders should always be kept in mind. Hence the young flock, not yet exposed, should be kept on clean ground separate from the old flock. It is probably possible to detect such infection carriers by appro - priate blood tests in the manner by which the carriers of bacillary white diarrhea infection can be brought to light. When the disease pertains to brooder chicks the same gen - eral plan of sanitation should be followed. The healthy chicks should be at once removed to clean brooders and the sickly ones destroyed. All the utensils that have come in contact with the affected animals must be most thoroughly disin - fected. Particular care should be taken in the handling of the droppings because this material constitutes the more active factor in the promotion of the disease. No fowl from the infected flocks should be sold except for immediate consump - tion and the same precaution should be taken in regard to eggs. BACILLARY WHITE DIARRHEA This communicable disorder, also known as pullorum dis - ease, constitutes a very important factor among the causes of losses experienced in brooder chicks. Although the disease is most damaging to chicks less than one month of age, it can also be held accountable for deaths and cases of sickness among mature fowls. In the former the intestines seem to be principally involved, although the infection commonly as - sumes a septicemic character. In adults the infection tends to be localized in the ovary. Cause. — Bacillary white diarrhea, as the name indicates, is a disease of microbic origin. The causative germ is known as Salmonella pvllorum. This organism can usually be iso - lated from the chicks dead with the disease, as well as from the infected older birds. There is a direct connection between the occurrence of the disease in chicks and in mature fowls. There exists a definite cycle by which the infection is kept alive and disseminated. This infection cycle should be thoroughly understood because the prevention of the disease would be extremely difficult without this information. When an outbreak of bacillary white diarrhea among chicks is observed it will be noted that a small number of the affected birds manage to survive. An apparent recovery takes place; but instead of completely overcoming the infection, such birds continue to harbor the latter and remain carriers of the virus probably during the </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Poultry Diseases KS? 11 ?' °L their lives ' In such cases the infection is usually localized in the ovary. Here it may actually produce disease and destroy the function of the organ. More cwnmonly the £££?♦ ft* 6 T7- iS n ? sufficien % extensive to completely hv X J? G rt^V^f Some e ** s are th ™ Produced by chronically infected birds, and among the eggs so pro - ved m will be found which contain the specific mTcrobt ?in f^T'S eggs are normal and f «»y capable of being fertilized. When they are used for hatching pur-! poses however, the newly formed chicks become invaded by the infection, with the result that they either die in the sheU SlShST 6 S T lck^ ith bacillary whi &lt;* diarrhea at the time of iSgSLZt^SSZL the cyde is completed and the Young chicks, however, do not become infected from the infected eggs exclusively. The chicks hatched from n?n-in! fected eggs are apt to contract the disease from those hatched from the infected ones by the eating of foodstuffs soifed by the droppings of the latter. Furthermore, evidence is not lacking that even older birds may become infected in an S™ nt contaminated by diseased or virScarrying chicks. However, the latter may not always be the case In experiments carried on by this Station, it appeared that as ong as healthy fowls had an opportunity to eat the eggs of infected ones they showed intermittent evidence of infection But when this was made impossible by the use of trap nests the healthy birds kept in constant contact with diseased ones failed to become infected. uiseasea Symptoms. — Bacillary white diarrhea in chicks is in tho greater number of cases, confined to those less than ten days old. The symptoms are not always of such a nature that the d sease can be readily recognized. Even when present the diarrhea is not a special characteristic of this diseafl since causes other than this infection may sometimes be resp oSe for it On the other hand, the true white diarrhea infection may be kil ing the chicks without any abnormal bowel dl V charge having been observed at all. In such cases thTinfeT tion is so virulent and kills so quickly that a LwS diSurLance' Sfarrhea tO &amp; P ° int &amp;t which {t rise ?o In most outbreaks, however, the latter is a more or les* prominent feature. It is characterized by a whidsh creamv gluey discharge in which from time to time brownish sffi may be observed. The discharges, as a rule, are ncrf Tcopfous A sticky nature causes them to adhere to the down aboS the </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 vent, which may thus become effectually closed up. Evacua - tion of the bowel content is not uncommonly accompanied by pain, expressed by a peculiar cry. Along with those more acute symptoms the chicks are observed to be weak and dull. The appetite fails, the wings droop, and the chicks prefer to remain quietly under the hover. The down is usually somewhat staring, the eyes are kept closed, and little or no interest is shown in what is happening in the immediate surroundings. Loss of flesh can frequently be observed and in the cases which persist for a few days the chicks often assume a rather peculiar form. The abdomen becomes enlarged and protrudes behind and this causes the chicks to appear as if their backs were shortened. Most chicks affected die within a few days after being hatched, although a number may survive for two weeks or more. A small number recover to become adult virus carriers. Bacillary white diarrhea infection cannot be readily re - cognized in live adult fowls without recourse to one or both of the blood tests to be described in another place. At this Station, a number of chickens which later proved to be suffer - ing from pullorum disease, were examined and showed an ill-defined unthriftiness and even sickness for some time prior to death. It is only by after-death examination and blood tests that the disease can be definitely recognized in mature fowls. The occurrence of fatal disease among chicks a few days old, characterized by the symptoms mentioned above, should always arouse the suspicion of bacillary white diarrhea. The only definite manner of recognizing the infection is by bac - teriologic examination of the chicks dead with the disease. In the case of adult fowls the presence of the infection may be ascertained by the agglutination test made with a small quan - tity of the blood serum obtained from the suspected birds. Lesions. — When chicks dead with bacillary white diarrhea are examined, the internal organs are commonly found quite pale in color and the general loss of flesh is marked. The crop, gizzard, and intestines are empty or partially filled with a sticky, stringy fluid. In the intestines a small amount of grayish material is sometimes present, while in the ceca a more or less firm, cheesy substance may be found. The liver is of a pale or dull ochre color and often has its surface marked by reddish streaks or patches. The substance of the organ is soft and friable, and in the more marked cases the gall bladder may be found to be distended. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Poultry Diseases The presence of an unabsorbed yolk within the abdominal cavity is quite constant and many authors who have studied the disease regard this feature as being quite characteristic, ihe yolks found in the abdominal cavities of diseased chicks range in size from that of a pea to that cf a normal egg yolk and vary in color from yellow to a brownish green or almost black. In consistency the unabsorbed yolk may be gelatinous watery, or cheesy. ' The persistence of the specific microbe of bacillary white diarrhea in adult fowls is not uncommonly denoted by ovarian disease. In such cases the ovary contains both normal and abnormal follicles (the sacklike structures in which the eggs are formed), although the microbe may be present in both The normal follicles are like those of a healthy bird and as a rule they show considerable variation in size. In the dis - eased follicles the variations in size are less marked and in ™i5?i^u lnfected , Ovar ? many are found of the same volume. While the normal follicles are usually globular in shape, the diseased ones have a tendency to become irregular in out - line and angular in form. The surface becomes flattened where the abnormal follicles lie in contact with one another They show a mottled coloring and the content has lost its transparency. The color is dull and ranges from a light yellow to a dark greenish brown. The content is more or less firm and may be solid throughout or consist of a cheesy material suspended in a clear yellowish fluid. In not a few cases, probably as a result of the rupture of a diseased fol - licle, a general infection of the body cavity may come about and the birds are apt to die of peritonitis. Course. — Bacillary white diarrhea in chicks is an ex - tremely fatal disease. The mortality ranges between 40 and 90 per cent and there is no reliable evidence that this high death rate can be reduced by any method of medicinal treat - ment. In the adult chicken affected with the disease the death rate is not great and in the case of those birds the principal damage is caused by the fact that by laying in - fected eggs they may become instrumental in perpetuating the disease. Prevention. — When bacillary white diarrhea has to be coped with, preventive measures are the only means at the disposal of the poultry grower upon which dependence can be placed. In the light of our present knowledge the use of nomnfected eggs for hatching purposes must be regarded as the most fundamental measure in prevention. This is espe - cially the case when the incubator is being used for hatch - ing, because there the eggs of a considerable number of chic- </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 kens are used and the chances of disease introduction thus are greater than when a fowl hatches her own eggs. It is there - fore extremely important that only eggs be selected which originated from flocks of poultry yards having a well-known freedom from infection. Eggs from producers who, during the past season, experienced trouble with bacillary white diarrhea should not be used for hatching. The same rule should be followed in the case of eggs orig - inating from flocks in which from time to time fowls with diseased ovaries are observed. In this conection it is always a good practice to examine closely the ovary of any bird which is killed for table use. When diseased ovaries are found in this manner, it is advisable to go to other sources for hatching eggs. Such findings should be an incentive to challenge the healthfulness of the breeding flock by a care - fully conducted blood test. And, even without the findings of an occasional diseased ovary, there is warrant for the belief that systematic blood testing as a matter of routine practice has a place in any and all establishments engaged in the breeding and hatching of chicks. Within the last decade such a weight of evidence has accumulated showing the ■■■■■■■ ■■^■■■^■■■B value of the agglutination Vwffl: . T$*S' test, as well as its constant W&amp;Bm '-'• u l^^wHf J:fe necessity, that the marketing Plffl' , [SlBl' ,\B&amp; of pullorum infected chicks |^H^ can no longer be defended on fflM ■ any ground. S8B^i'^SBiK^''" '■-'-'■ Ilfy-'l The agglutination test, re- HHITIb HbHS 1* B^' 1 peatedly and systematically ffjHi' JlSBii^B' !•' Bl I applied to all breeding stock Mi !' iif : '"! from year to year, the culling Hfiait 11^^^H jl Hi"! of all reacting birds, and the IlfflHBll'' i' fillJ sanitary management of feed, fiSnl; • I iH^H H&amp;f ' \\ wfel water, and environment are, ■ "iBt i without doubt, the most effi- |vaffi|l^ •&amp;&amp;$■' 1 cient measures against the j disease. It should, however, i^HHHIHI be remembered that the test is not infallible, that it must _ f" 1 "" v Neifat!ve be persistently applied, and i^— Tube agglutination test. that the culling out of the reacting birds must be rigidly carried through in order to bring about the results desired. The agglutination test is based upon the fact that in pull - orum-infected fowls certain substances form in the blood which, when the latter or its serum is brought in contact </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Poultry Diseases with a suspension of the bacteria causing the disease and grown in the laboratory (now designated as pullorum anti - gen), causes the germs to clump together and to sink to the bottom of the vessel used for the test or to become plainly visible as small flakes when the test is made on a piece of glass. This reaction is known as agglutination and is always an indication that the bird concerned has become infected. It should, however, be remembered that a small proportion of infected fowls do not react constantly. In view of this peculiarity, tests should be repeatedly made in order to assure a maximum safety. No doubt much can be accomplished by the removal of the reacting birds after one test, but with the tests repeated a much more effective culling becomes possible. Fig. 17, — Method of drawing blood to be used in agglutination- test for bacillary white diarrhea. For breeding flocks, two or three tests made at intervals of one month before hatching eggs are being set aside con - stitute a most effective procedure. Blood testing can be done by one of two methods: the tube method and the rapid or plate method. The former is the one first used, whereas the rapid test may be regarded as a simplification of the tube test, designed to reduce its cost and the work involved and to make it available for a wider application. Blood testing is usually done during the winter </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 months and care should be taken that the testing and subse - quent culling be not done at a time too far removed from the period during which eggs for hatching are to be collected The tube agglutination test is usually made in a suitable laboratory. For this purpose the blood is withdrawn from the wing vein of the fowl to be tested, by means of a small hypo - dermic syringe, and is then emptied into a small vial pro - vided with a label, to carry the identification number to cor - respond with that of the leg band or wing band of the bird concerned. The blood sample is then set aside for dotting and when the serum has separated from the clot the former is used for the test. The latter detail is attended to at the laboratory where the test is to be made. In the collection of blood samples from a flock, care should be taken to remove all traces of blood from the syringe before it is used for the next fowl. This can best be accomplished by three separate and distinct washings in a physiologic salt solution (2 drams of common salt to a quart of water) to which one-half per cent of carbolic acid has been added. The rapid agglutination test, when applied by a person who has become familiar with it, has been proved as depend - able as the tube test. It may be made with blood serum col - lected as indicated above, or with the whole blood immediately after its collection. The antigen (a suspension of dead bacillary white diarrhea germs) is dyed to a purple color, so as to facilitate the reading of the reaction. This substance may be obtained through veterinarians, drug stores, or poul - try supply dealers. The actual test is made as follows: Place a drop of colored bacillary white diarrhea anti- gen upon a piece of clean jS'^-'mk. glass and at once add a drop »;'''''/'»•■ *.£A A~-T~^ J ; «■ r ~~^L of the blood of the fowl to be ' M-';&gt;\v.'i/v:.''1a^Kf:ii^iafe^B tested and stir the mixture »'V'&gt;'*-'^ mT I *- * W with a toothpick, taking a ; '*^r '" r '^r new one for every test. The &lt; -vg8^^ blood can be secured by Po .itive Native puncturing one of the wing Pr _ ia w .. ... , veins of the bird to be tested, G ' 18 '~ Rapid a^ lutinatlon tert. while puncturing the comb may also enable one to secure the amount of blood required. Any clean, dry, white glass may be used for testing. Most convenient are the glass slides used by microscopists. Make one or more tests on one slide and then drop it in clean water. When all slides have been used, wash them clean and dry them and continue the work, if more </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Poultry Diseases is to be done. Such slides can, no doubt, be secured through drug stores. In accordance with the prevailing temperature a positive reaction manifests itself from one-half minute to two minutes after the antigen and blood are mixed. Holding the test glass over an electric bulb or over a piece of white paper in a good light will enable one to read the test result with greater promptness. The heat eliminated by the light bulb will cause the reaction to take place more speedily. A positive reaction to the test is indicated by the blood-test fluid mixture becoming "clumped" or curdled, the clumps be - ing deeply colored. In a negative reaction the mixture shows no changes. The time necessary for the reaction to take place is influenced by the prevailing temperature. Gently warm - ing the glass hastens the reaction, while extreme cold may suspend it altogether. For dependable results, the work must be done in a clean manner and with a certain degree of speed. Care must be taken that the blood of one bird does not get mixed with that of the next one; hence all traces of blood must be removed from the blade used for puncturing and from the glass plate before the next test. This mode of testing has the advantage of making it possible to cull the reacting fowls while the test is in progress. Hence leg or wing banding is not necessary. On the other hand, the reading of results may be a bit more difficult when whole blood is used than when serum only is tested. This is especially the case when the reaction is delayed by a low tem - perature, or when the testing is done in a dark poultry house. Making the rapid test with blood serum is more laborious and requires more equipment. The fowls to be tested must be leg banded, vials containing the blood samples must be labeled, and pipettes must be procured to separate the serum from the blood clot. The latter must be washed out after each use and hence some extra care as to cleanliness must be taken. Aside from these possible disadvantages, the details of the test are the same as when the whole blood is used. The use of serum in the rapid test has, on the other hand, the advantage of being more accurate because errors in read - ing the reactions are more difficult to make. The latter can be more readily read and the actual testing can always be done in good light and in a warm room. As soon as possible after the test has been completed the fowls which have reacted positively to the test should be culled out and marketed for immediate dressing. When they amount to more than one third of the entire flock the advisa- </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 bility of rejecting the whole lot as producers of eggs for hatching purposes is well worth considering, both from a sani - tary and from an economic point of view. Although blood testing and the prompt and adequate elim - ination of reacting fowls are the principal measures in the prevention of bacillary white diarrhea, some other details also deserve attention. Unless incubators are used exclusively for eggs derived from flocks entirely free from pullorum in - fection, they should be carefully disinfected after each setting of eggs. It has been definitely shown that the disease may, in incubators, be transmitted from infected chicks to healthy ones. Infertile eggs and for that matter others also must not be fed to chicks unless they are thoroughly cooked. The question of what to do with a lot of chicks, part of which have succumbed to bacillary white diarrhea, must not be lightly disposed of. Many flocks would today be in a much better state, with reference to pullorum infection if the first lot of diseased chicks had been entirely destroyed. Even now such a radical measure is worthy of consideration. If, on the other hand, one cannot quite go that far, measures should be taken so that the survivors in the infected lot of chicks are at no time used as reproducers. . ROUP The name "roup" is popularly and quite loosely applied to any disorder of poultry which involves the upper air passages as well as the eye, and which shows evidence of being com - municated from fowl to fowl. Difficult as it often is to differ - entiate roup, or, as it is also designated, contagious coryza, from such disorders as canker, pox, or even infectious tracheolaryngitis, for the purpose of this description the dis - ease may be defined as a contagious disease of fowls which manifests itself by a catarrhal inflammation of the mucous membranes of the upper air passages, the eye, and the mucosae connected with the latter, and not caused by the virus of canker and pox or by the one causing infectious bron - chitis. Roup is a common disease in any area where poultry rais - ing forms a part of animal industry. Most frequently ob - served, in chickens, it is also seen in turkeys and it seems probable that other species of birds may likewise be suscep - tible. The younger birds are most liable to become involved by the disease even if the older adults are by no means exempt. In Nebraska most of the outbreaks of roup are observed during autumn, the heaviest incidence manifesting itself </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Poultry Diseases from the middle of September to the early part of December. The disease may also be observed throughout the entire year. It is not always clear that the greater incidence of the dis - order can be charged to direct seasonal influences alone Account should also be taken of the fact that with the begin - ning of autumn the birds are most apt to seek shelter, and hence the overcrowding in houses may also be a contributory cause. Cause. — There can be no doubt about roup being a dis - ease of microbic origin, although, in spite of numerous in - vestigations, nothing of a definite or precise character has thus far been discovered as far as the nature of the causative factor is concerned. On the other hand, it has been clearly shown that the cause of roup is present in the nasal dis - charge of affected birds and that its introduction into the nose of healthy fowls will cause the latter to develop the disease. Certain investigations pertaining to the cause of the disorder have disclosed evidence of a possibility that roup may be caused by more than one microbic species. On the whole, the problem of cause remains unsolved, although there is agreement among investigators that the disease is transmitted through such agencies as contaminated food and drinking water. Symptoms and diagnosis. — An early sign of roup con - sists of the appearance of a thin watery discharge from the nose. In the course of a few days this exudate assumes a mucous character, becomes thicker, and may or may not con - tain fibrinous flakes. It becomes sticky and tends to dry within and around the nostrils as a yellow or brownish-yellow incrustation. At the height of the disease the discharge emits an offensive odor and its accumulation within the nasal passage makes respiration difficult. Owing to such an ob - struction, the birds breathe through the mouth and this is frequently accompanied by a snoring, rattling sound. Not uncommonly the infection involves the mucous mem - brane of the eye and the eyelids. The eyes are closed by the swelling of the eyelids, giving rise to a bulbous deformity of the head. The eyelids are often glued together and within them and around the eyeball the exudate accumulates as a fibrinous, cheesy mass. The infection also tends to enter the mucus sac which, in birds, is present beneath the eye, and the sac becomes filled with exudate which thickens to a dense cheesy plug. In addition to the more localized symptoms enumerated above, the affected fowls are apt to show a degree of consti- </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 tutional depression. They are dull and their appetite is either impaired or suspended altogether. As a consequence they become reduced in flesh, and egg production may be materially lessened in flocks in which an outbreak is under way. Com - plications involving the deeper respiratory organs are occa - sionally observed. Roup, as observed in Nebraska, is usually not marked by a high rate of mortality and when it remains confined to the nose of the more vigorous fowls, recovery can ordinarily be expected. Outbreaks with a case mortality of more than 20 per cent have, however, been observed. The heavier death rates often prevail among the younger fowls during periods of cold, damp weather. Instances of an excessively high mortality have been recorded, but in such cases there is some warrant for believing that the disease has been complicated by some other types of infection peculiar to the respiratory organs. Such complications not uncommonly tend to make a correct recogn.tion of the disease difficult. Owing to a certain simil - arity of the earlier symptoms of canker to the ones of roup, an accurate diagnosis may prove hard to achieve. Canker may, however, be excluded when, after careful and repeated examinations of all fowls in a flock, its characteristic lesions are not at all encountered. As in canker, roup cases may also show deposits of cheesy material on an involved mucous sur - face, but when it is carefully removed the underlying struc - ture or surface of the membrane is not found to be damaged and eroded as is apt to be the case in canker. Lesions.— Fowls dead with roup are commonly wasted in flesh. The mucous membranes of the nose, throat, and eye are red and covered by the exudate already described in con - nection with the discussion of symptoms. The cheesy plug found in the sac below the eye is also quite characteristic of the disease even if a similar lesion may occasionally be observed in other diseases. Treatment.— -On the who'e the results of treatment are not particularly satisfying. If undertaken at all it must be applied as early in the course of the disease as possible. The parts involved, including the nostrils, should be gently cleaned and the obstructing accumulations of exudate carefully re - moved. A four per cent solution of boric acid in warm water may be used for the purpose. It is injected into the nostrils, while the mouth of the fowl is held open so as to permit the escape of the fluid. This may be alternated by instilling into the nasal passages, by means of an eye dropper, a mixture </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Poultry Diseases composed of 5 grains of carbolic acid, 10 grains of menthol, and 1 ounce of liquid petrolatum. Treatment must be re - peated two or three times a day and must be continued as long as nasal discharge is conspicuous. The instillation into the nostrils of a few drops of a 10 per cent solution of argyrol in water may also prove to be beneficial and certainly can do no harm. Accumulations of cheesy matter in the sinuses under the eye are best removed by incisions through the overlying skin, followed by pressing the mass through the wound made. After this the cavity can be washed out with boric-acid so - lution mentioned above. The use of vapor inhalations may be tried, although no method of treatment is of great promise. A 5 per cent solu - tion of liquor-cresolis compound is placed in a pail so that its bottom is covered five or six inches. The pail is then placed in the space in which the fowls are confined, after which a red hot flatiron is inserted into the pail. The birds are left exposed for about ten minutes to the vapor arising and must then be set free in the open air. This treatment may be given once or twice a day. Prevention. — General sanitary conditions in the poultry house and protection of the birds against the inclemencies of the weather are important factors. As a roup case occurs in the flock, the affected bird should at once be removed, either to be kept in complete segregation or to be used for the table or to be destroyed or burned, as the judgment of the owner may dictate. Since the disease is favored by overcrowding and exposure to damp, cold weather, there seems to be warrant for the dis - posal of the superfluous members of a flock before the advent of colder weather. After August or September at the latest, fowls which are not to be kept over should be disposed of so that by the middle of October the flock is reduced to a mini - mum. Overpopulation is thus avoided, a large number of sus - ceptible birds are safely removed, and sanitary conditions for the remainder are materially improved. A quite essential measure in the prevention of roup is the caution exercised in connection with the introduction of new stock into the flock. If at all possible this should be avoided altogether, but if it must be done, the new birds should be closely segregated in a safe place for not less than two weeks. This same practice should be adopted in the case of fowls returning from fairs and poultry shows where infective con - tacts are always to be feared. </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 It appears that little or nothing can be expected from the use of serums or vaccines. Experiments undertaken by the Wyoming Experiment Station (Wyo. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bulletin 172), showed quite conclusively that biologic products sold for the prevention and cure of roup are quite worthless. INFECTIOUS BRONCHITIS The disorder commonly designated as infectious bronchitis constitutes a distinct entity among the ones peculiar to chic - kens. It consists of an acute or subacute transmissible dis - ease involving the larger air pasages, marked by a variable degree of respiratory distress and a high rate of mortality It should here be remarked that the name "infectious bron - chitis is not in exact accordance with the nature of the dis - ease, because it involves the windpipe and larynx far more constantly than the bronchial tubes. In veterinary literature the disease is usually designated as "laryngotracheitis" or tracheolaryngitis". Popularly the disease is also known as chicken flu". It is possible that the disease had been observed prior to 1923 but it was not until 1924 that it mani - fested itself in Nebraska poultry yards and feeding stations Outbreaks of infectious bronchitis were particularly disas - trous when it first appeared in Nebraska. The mortality dur - ing 1924 and 1925 was a heavy one. Since that time there has apparently come about a decline in its incidence as well as in its mortality rate. The disorder still occurs, but not as commonly as in the past and the death rate appears to be less severe. Whereas during the first years of the last decade a case mortality of 100 per cent was by no means uncommon it is the opinion of the writers that at this time it ranges between 10 and 20 per cent. The losses caused by the dis - order are by no means confined to mortality. Production is likewise markedly reduced in affected flocks. Hinshaw and others observed 25 outbreaks involving 14,574 fowls, with an average course of 15 days and a mortality rate of 13 per cent. The egg loss during that period could be estimated at 1,883 dozens. Although some evidence has been presented of a similar dis - order among poultry and birds other than chickens, it is quite apparent that the common chicken is the most susceptible if not the only susceptible species in which it must be reckoned with as a source of loss. Most cases of infectious bronchitis are observed in fowls from four months to a year and a half of age. It has, however, also been described in brooder chicks and m birds several years old. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Poultry Diseases On the whole, the disease seems to be but little affected by seasonal influences. In the earlier Nebraska outbreaks, most cases occurred during the colder part of the year but this was probably more to be attributed to closer housing than to a direct influence of the prevailing temperature. Both sexes appear to be equally susceptible to the infection. After the appearance of the first case in a flock the disorder rapidly spreads to the majority of its members. This was particularly apparent during the earlier Nebraska oubreaks. In some instances every fowl in a flock would be sick within a period of 72 hours. Most outbreaks run their course in from two to four weeks. Cause. — In any communicable disease the cause must nearly always be looked for among the many types of germs, visible as well as invisible, which may be recognized to exist in the affected animals. A number of attempts to discover the cause of tracheolaryngitis have been made and although a complete knowledge of the subject has not yet been obtained, all dependable evidence thus far presented points to the fact that a filterable, ultramicroscopic virus may be the primary cause of the disorder. Beach and Graham and associates, who passed the infective material present in the windpipe of diseased fowls through filters which held back any visible germ which may have happened to be present, could reproduce the disease in healthy birds by injecting some of the filtered material into their windpipes. Beach found this causative virus to be con - stantly present in the exudate within the trachea of infected fowls, in 60 per cent of their spleens, and in 30 per cent of their livers. The virus is quite resistant to drying, re - taining its virulence for from one to five months, depending on the method of drying employed or the temperature at which it has been preserved. Apparently the virus may be retained for prolonged periods by birds which have recovered from the disease and Gibbs could report on observations of carrier birds eliminating the virus for periods up to 467 days. It is, however, not known at this time how common such infection carriers may be and to what extent they will have to be reckoned with in the control of the infection. The degree of virulence of the virus seems to be subject to varia - tions. In the various investigations of the nature of the virus some difficulties were encountered associated with the fact that it was not always possible to differentiate the disease clearly from such disorders as roup and canker. The virus of fowl pox, identical with that of canker, has been found in the exu- </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 ?o a J? °£ bronchitis cases, and this led to the belief that the latter disease may be caused by pox virus. This belief is how! ever, not shared by later investigators. It is by no means :W£2&amp;s i ySH of fowl pox and "^s after an initial exposure to diseased fowls. Kernohan writ! The symptoms are quently marks re - spiratory efforts. F ro. 19— Fowl affected by tracheolaryngitis The affected fowl (»**&lt;* Beach). b S loorFS tUre H 0 J- di ? reSS; its feather s are ruffled and a sticky ExnuiSvf^ 8Charge T- ay isSUe from nostrila a *d moS mSSt fSr5 ? ' sugg f s J in « a cou «h. may be observed. Com - monly there is a complete loss of appetite and the fowls arp apt to stand with their necks stretched and thdr mouths widl open. Many such cases suffocate within from one to thre! SSSrtS 1^ ° n - et ° f the disease ' Death is caused by thl 5ref?S g thPrpSf a M^ SSageS by the bloody ' mucous ex «d a te SJfo herein. Milder cases are now more frequent than some years ago, although most of them present a degree of tSffowf7^ Ulty - SeV , er e 1 inves totors have obJerved 1 had acquired a substantiai im - J^S^^SSSTc^i t^tS^era?/ ,5^ particularly the trachea and the larynx, the*Lrger bronchfai tubes occasionally also being involved. The mucous meS- </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Poultry Diseases brane of these organs is inflamed and the passage is partially or completely filled with a bloody mucus and blood clots. In cases in which the disorder has persisted for some time the exudate may assume a cheesy character and may form a more or less perfect cast of the respiratory tube. Evidence of pneumonia may sometimes be found in fowls which have lingered for some days, but in the more acute cases the lungs, as a rule, show no inflammatory changes. Seifried, who studied the microscopic aspect of the involved tissues, found that the causative virus primarily affects the epithelial cells of the mucous membranes and that subse - quently the deeper-situated tissues become inflamed and edematous. Some of the latter changes may have been pro - duced by secondary microbic invaders. In many of the cases observed by him the cells showed characteristic inclusions similar to the ones seen in certain other diseases caused by a filterable virus. Treatment. — Very little if anything at all can be accompr lished by any sort of treatment. In certain individual cases the removal of the blood clot from the windpipe may bring a degree of relief and the medicated-water-yapor treatment mentioned in the preceding chapter may bring about a cer - tain amount of comfort to the distressed fowls. The occa - sional instillation of a few drops of a 10 per cent solution of argyrol in water into the windpipe has also been recommend - ed. On the whole, however, curative efforts remain quite futile. Prevention. — One of the most effective measures in the prevention of infectious bronchitis is to avoid any direct or indirect contact with infected flocks. The introduction of outside or strange fowls into a healthy flock at its best is a questionable practice. It is especially so wherever infectious bronchitis is more or less prevalent. Fowls returning from shows or fairs, owing to manifest contact opportunities, must also be looked upon as potential carriers of infection. In connection with such birds it is advisable to keep them segre - gated for a number of weeks before they are permitted to come in contact with the flock again. If a few healthy, sus - ceptible birds could be added to the isolated fowls, the failure on the part of the former to sicken could be accepted as evi - dence of the noninf ected character of the latter. Birds entering feeding stations should be particularly chal - lenged before being placed in the batteries. Fowls showing a nasal discharge and other evidence of impaired health should either be rejected or used for immediate slaughter. Such </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 sanitary details as cleanliness and periodic disinfections also have their value. A method of vaccination has been proposed, but its worth in actual practice has not yet been established to such a degree as to warrant specific recommendations. POX AND CANKER Fowl pox and canker, in the light of present knowledge, are two somewhat distinct manifestations of an infection by the same ultramicroscopic virus. Both are eruptive diseases, pox more particularly involving the skin and canker being associated primarily with the mucous membranes of the mouth and the upper air passages. Both forms of the infection may occur simultaneously in the same flock and not infrequently in the same bird. On the other hand, outbreaks of pox may be seen without canker cases and vice versa. In Nebraska the writers have had opportunity to observe this infection only in fowls and turkeys, although it is well known that pigeons, parrots, guineas, pea fowls, pheasants, and even waterfowls must be looked upon as more or less susceptible. In many instances the disease has proved to be a source of considerable loss. Both forms of the infection are capable of assuming mark T edly malignant aspects and of causing considerable losses. From observations made at this Station one is led to believe that the virulence of the causative agent is subject to varia - tions. Some years ago the diseases more frequently presentee} themselves in outbreaks with a higher mortality rate than at the present, when most of the outbreaks show a rather benign type with but few death losses. Cause. — Both forms of the disease result from infection', by a virus called filterable or ultramicroscopic. Those names indicate that the germs are so small that they will pass through filters which will hold back all other bacteria, and; also that with the aid of a highly magnifying microscope they remain invisible. The virus can be demonstrated to be pre - sent only by inoculation experiments in susceptible birds. In the diseased fowls the virus is present in the lesions peculiar to the malady, in the blood, and in many of the internal organs. Healthy fowls in natural outbreaks contract the dis - ease by contact with the infected ones and there can scarcely be any doubt that contaminated food and water play a part in the transmission of both disorders. The virus of pox and canker may enter through abrasions of the skin and mucous membranes, while the latter, even when intact, appear to furnish an open road for the entrance of the infective virus. It has been suspected for many years </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Poultry Diseases that the latter may also be transmitted through the agency of mosquitoes, and this was actually proved to be the case by experimental efforts. Symptoms. — When the infection manifests itself on the skin the name fowl pox is applied to it. The regions more particularly prone to become affected are Jfeju^ft the comb and wattles, !iWt"fl although in the more .T ; ;:',':. -.'■ . : ' ffafch A malignant types of *|j| '•■'■-- •. : - : --- ■:—'''. - ; d9s^^ fowl pox the skin : _,~ '^vilSJi covering other parts Jmk\ '■'■ ]: ''' ■'-* J '\ : '''^ ~~ of the body may also JM ■;.,.-/:' t ? ";Wfi&amp; ■'": '- -' %P be involved. Jm \ &gt;^i &gt;■ t "-' i:^'^^ Usually in from six Mk . W J Mag^ ; fSB to fourteen days after ok ,., Ji&lt; ; V -jj&amp;y the introduction of the am gj j \ &amp; . \ &gt; V ■ ,W' virus, there appear on mm ) '({&gt;; *Uv^-^$y the surfaces affected S ; . /i' ■ ■ ,"v"&gt;r v"( small blister-like ele- M | "\. ■■'/:■ '■' ■■.(•'■ 'm. vations, smooth and M V &gt; *[-'( v"-'--^ of a white or light- mk -&gt; ;\ . t •;';,. : '\V vSi gray color. These Hj ' W~% jjK small areas gradually n v become transformed I rvn [i A j - f v'j'.Va into wart-like struc- m \ y $j I ; A, ; tures with a rather «[ ;, ■»'■'&gt; ■ dry and wrinkled sur- M-if WJ£ '* ■ ;^Jft«wV|4w(l^ face. In color they fg Wy , j/J KalaJM range between a yel- VI ' &gt;• ''U l ti\^ {/,"' % l i .; ;1 Mp««R lowish brown and a ',„,•'/, '' : ' : r mi'MAvk dark brown or black. W ' i ' !f -fliflR^A The isolated pocks M I||MW^ B\^VA. may grow to pea size, 1 n jtjfilwB | ' but frequently several 1 1 1 fo \ ¥$ of them become con- U f&amp;HfjSgfi /l ''MjWW' fluent and then give iJmSotRHkww^'^' '^Jm rise to tumor-like yfM , WmWd ', We masses of considerable w^Ifi'' W W? volume. Such for- Vr^^ mations can readily be *£? m^*^ S^dk an^h" » 2 »- A »* — - *- — ened surface underneath. In some cases, only a few of such pocks appear, while in others they are so numerous as to bring about a considerable malformation of the parts involved. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 This pock formation may be extended to the eyelids, the eyes, the corners of the mouth, and even to the adjacent mucous membranes. As long as the lesions of moderate degree remain confined to the external skin, the affected birds show little or no ill - ness; but with the extension of the disease and the involve - ment of the various mucous membranes, the infected animals become dull, inactive, and show a tendency toward severe loss of flesh. The causative virus of pox is constantly contained in the lesions of the skin. Fowls, after recovery from the disease, acquire a substantial immunity against the infection for a considerable, although varying, length of time. The name canker is principally applied to that form of the disease in which the mucous membranes of the mouth, nose, eyes, or throat participate. In the beginning of the disease the affected mucous membranes show light-colored specks and patches, irregular in form and slightly raised above the sur - face. Those patches grow and become confluent. The super - ficial layers of the membrane die and the surface is covered with a false membrane composed of an adherent, yellow, cheesy mass, a condition which has given the disease also the name of fowl diphtheria. A similar process may involve the eyes, the nose, and the nasal sinuses as well as the deeper air passages, and then it may be difficult to distinguish it from roup, especially during the earlier stages of the disease. Affected birds may not show constitutional symptoms in the milder forms of canker infection ; but when the lesions inter - fere with breathing and feeding, the general health of the affected animal begins to decline. Diagnosis. — The pock formation of comb and wattles and the occurrence of the adherent, white, cheesy deposits and false membrane in the mouth, eyes, nose, and throat are or - dinarily sufficient to establish the identity of the diseases. Lesions. — In fowls dead with the disease there may be found, aside from the lesions visible during life, similar changes in the nasal cavities, the larynx, and windpipe, and the bronchial tubes. Even the intestinal mucous membrane may be involved in inflammatory changes, with erosions of the surface. The spleen is sometimes enlarged and the liver may show localized areas of degeneration marked as small, yellow specks on the cut surface. The lungs may present a dropsical condition, while inflammatory changes are often encountered in the body cavity and in some of the joints. It is, however, quite probable that not all of such organic changes can be attributed to the virus of pox and canker and </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Poultry Diseases that many, if not most of them, are caused by secondary in - fections commonly encountered in fowls of which the resist - ance to infection has become impaired by some primary fac - tor. Course. — Both forms of the disease have a tendency to run a rather protracted course. The mortality varies with outbreaks. In those _ manifesting a high de- Idfi3S^^?Bfr gree of virulence the I^^ISSra?**^.-^ amount to from 40 to y^3 "'■'■ '■ \^^^^^ : :^'^f^ 80 per cent of the JOJk-^wMBb&amp;^j&amp;~'^^-^* cases. Canker cases -^mX"-^:.. are more apt to linger, ''x/L | ■ Bfe2*?gj£—^Rfr__ -\ and during later years y%B S H I • '■•* ~- \ \'^* ii^. Nebraska fowl pox '^fl | , x \ '.-■* - B^ has, more frequently /M H t B?^5 flV. than before, shown a ■/ &gt; /&gt; iT-.l •'-•;*:'&gt;, %^^B^ rather benign char- liw/:'/h : S^M0^^T^4&gt;&lt;^. Wi acter. JtiriB 9 '' ; •''■' J '*^^WKKa&amp;^^^ Treatment. — It is «¥ Ik Y*^S^lL questionable whether ' " R f^Wffl 1 \TO\^k treatment has much of A \\\\ « an influence on the /■If Rl I B 1 u death rate, but no &lt;^Bu 8| y 1 ) doubt in some few I / cases it may be help- x / ful in saving at least some of the birds. There is nothing that „ _. „ . , , can be done to destroy FlG - 21 — Fowl pox and canker ' the virus in the animal's blood or tissues, and all that may be accomplished is to deal with the more local damages. This is the principal reason why treatment is, as a rule, not very successful. The only treatment required by cases of fowl pox should consist of keeping the eruptions covered with a bit of car - bolized vaseline. This has at least the advantage of some - what confining the virus of the disease and to reduce the chances of its reaching other fowls and their food and drink - ing water. Canker cases do not readily respond to treatment, but if they must be subjected to any, it is proper to clean the affected parts carefully by means of some mild antiseptic solution such as a Vfc P er cent solution of liquor-cresolis com - pound in warm water. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 c O i5? e cankerou s deposits on the mucous membranes may be gently removed by means of the loop end of a hairpin care being taken not to injure the underlying st?uctur?s Thl nSS r\ SUrfaCeS ° f , the areas from which thT cheesy material has been removed can then be gently swabbed over Z&amp;ZZSf&amp;SFK ° f ° f SiIV6r in -ter ed A°n V £ repeated from time to time. Affected poultry .^^KKfc.'-™ 1 *^^ i^S^r which is to be treated ik-^W.-^BW should be kept isolated : -'^S^t'«^». from the flock. The re- "^S^?'2*^N^^t suits of treatment are *113ml usually not very good C and in most cases of canker, at least, there is l^P^^^^^^^P money to be saved by \BP^f^^^gl^fcp - destroying the birds as K3$%§mWiBg^~ soon as they become lyp8§ilj|lSfl^~" manifestly diseased. J&amp;«lflSH^ Prevention. — More RmbS^P^ dependence can be placed ftJP^'B'^ on preventive measures J - ' w£ than on treatment. These are practically the same '_/ as those recommended in outbreaks of the other transmissible diseases 22.— A bad case of fowl pox. discussed in this publication. Care in buying new stock and the quarantining of the same for a few weeks after arrival and the segregation or even immediate destruction of affected fowls are measures which tend to prevent further spread of the disease. These measures must be supplemented by the maintenance of sanitary surroundings, including cleanliness, food and water of unquestioned purity, disinfection, etc. beveral years ago attempts were begun to render fowls im - mune to pox and canker by means of a vaccine which con - sisted of a heated suspension of the pulverized, dried pocks collected from affected birds. Although reports indicated that satisfying results were now and then obtained after the use of such vaccines, the various accounts rendered were oiten contradictory and hence the method failed to come into general use. Within a more recent period experimental evidence tending to show that an immunity against fowl pox could be secured by artificial means became available. Various types of vac- </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Poultry Diseases cines and modes of application were recommended or cham - pioned by authors. As yet it remains difficult to correctly evaluate vaccines and methods, even if many of the results of investigations have a favorable aspect. Some of the re - ports concerned with the subject pertain to observations up - on which no definite conclusions can be based because they failed to show that they were always safeguarded by ade - quate control measures. In some instances it was not entirely possible to detach a pecuniary interest from the recommen - dations made. The vaccines proposed by various investigators and more or less used in practice represent three types: (1) pigeon - pox virus vaccine, (2) attenuated fowl-pox virus vaccine, and (3) fully virulent fowl-pox virus. The relation of pigeon pox to fowl pox is comparable to that of cow pox to small pox. It possesses but a slight degree of virulence for chic - kens and when inoculated into the latter causes a benign, localized pox which confers upon the fowls a more or less substantial and lasting immunity to real fowl pox. Attenu - ated fowl-pox virus is directly derived from fowls affected with pox and so treated by drying, heating, or otherwise as to become deprived of its disease-producing qualities to such an extent that its inoculation in the skin of healthy susceptible birds produces only a slight localized pock formation. As Zwick, Seifried and Schaaf could show, an attenuated fowl - pox virus may also be obtained by subjecting it to a series of passages through pigeons. Nonattenuated fowl-pox virus has also been and is apparently being used as a vaccine against the disease. All these vaccines are derived from the pocks of affected birds. They are scraped off from the affected areas, dried, and pulverized. The resulting powder is treated or not, in accordance with the type of vaccine to be produced, and then suspended in water. All investigators are apparently agreed that the most dependable results are obtained when the vac - cine is applied to the skin. Three methods to do so are re - commended: (1) the follicle method, (2) the scarification method, and (3) the so-called "stick" method. In the application of the follicle method one proceeds about as follows: The place of inoculation is the front of the thigh, an inch or two above the point where the feathered skin joins the bare one of the shank ; from ID to 15 feathers are plucked out and the vaccine lightly applied to the open follicles by means of a small, stiff brush. The scarification method is applicable to the same area, but instead of application of the vaccine with a brush it is introduced into the superficial skin </seg>
            <seg id="p068">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 layers by means of a small instrument provided with short sharp saw-like teeth by which the skin i Xhtly abraded' The "stick" method was designed by Johnson who dSbes it about as follows : The area selected for making the^sSck" To'SSn, a ? d K P^ tei T t0 the P rox^l end !f the tibia tXJ m a * StlCk a Sh - arp ' pointed bIade was decided upon The blade is wrapped with a small amount of adhesive tene Toitol v4 U o? Wi - h ,? ne^ hread so as to ma *e 2 SpSSd Sf ?L stkk i a f 3 in ± Tv e ™BP?« re^lates the depth gg Sa LaM 1 Sn1 n \KoS Afi fcer oTfJread" '^ f ° llideS S ° as to eIimina * e If the vaccination is to be effective there must be a "takp" ? n to 10 S birdS S - hOuld be carefully examined from •+v • d . ayS^. after the va ccination. Birds without a "take" either indicate that the vaccination failed and that ft shmM ablf ThP Mi T hen -"J- Wh f re the P ractice w &lt;&gt;"ld be advis - «JI f B 5 eat ma J° nt y of cases of fowl pox in our state f o™ »f th. 1 ? 863 °* va , cci ' la «™ to «ocks where a benign </seg>
            <seg id="p069">• Poultry Diseases upon the belief that the latter type of virus, although it may be suitable elsewhere, is not free from an element of danger. It may give rise to pox cases of a more virulent type than the one now usually encountered in Nebraska flocks and hence may, in the end, confront our poultry growers with a type of pox of a far more damaging character than the one by which they may now occasionally be troubled. FOWL PARALYSIS Fowl paralysis, often referred to as "range paralysis", was described for the first time in 1907 by Marek of Hungary. Since that time the disease has been frequently discussed in European and American veterinary literature. In scientific writings the malady is designated as "neurolymphomatosis gallinarum." The first cases of the disease came to the attention of this Station about ten or twelve years ago, but at that time and during the succeeding period its occurrence was of a sporadic nature and its economic importance did not become apparent until 1930. Since that year the occurrence of fowl paralysis outbreaks became progressively more frequent and at the present time it must be recognized among the more damaging of chicken diseases which are apt to plague the producer. In the light of present knowledge the chicken is the only bird species susceptible to the disease and if other species share in this susceptibility the fact has not yet been conclusively demonstrated. Fowl paralysis is a transmissible malady to which all breeds of chickens are about equally liable. It tends to cling to certain flocks with a considerable degree of tenacity. Most of the cases seen in Nebraska are supplied by birds from three to eight months of age, although the disease is also encountered in older fowls. Fowl paralysis, however, is but rarely observed in chickens more than one and a half years old. On the other hand it seems quite possible that the older birds in an infected flock may harbor the causative virus and transmit the disease to others. Cause. — Careful observations made in flocks affected with fowl paralysis tend to lead to the conclusion that the malady is of an infectious character. This conclusion has been amply confirmed by the transmission experiments in which suspensions of the affected organs of paralytic birds were artificially introduced into healthy ones or in which dis - eased and healthy fowls were kept in close contact. At one time the theory was advanced that the disorder is associated with such parasitic disorders as coccidiosis and tapeworm in- </seg>
            <seg id="p070">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 TT^SS °* v lack , 0f - certain Gamins in the ration The bases for such conclusions at no time amierori taha very solid or secure and at this time VeTarSc orijrin 5 fowl paralysis is no longer seriously considered obviously infectious nature of fowl SysTstimulated ft HHH </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Poultry Diseases All transmision experiments show that the virus of fowl paralysis may be present in a bird for very considerable periods before disease manifests itself. Observations made by Seagar suggest that such fowls, incubating the virus, apparently have as great a potentiality to spread the infection as birds with well developed symptoms. How long the virus may remain alive in poultry yards abandoned by an infected flock is a matter of conjecture, but there is probability that three or four months during the warmer parts of the year would be sufficient to eliminate infection hazards from ground thus left unpopulated. Symptoms. — Before enumerating the various symptoms by which fowl paralysis may be recognized, some other im - portant phenomena encountered in studies of the malady should be mentioned. In flocks previously healthy the intro - duction of infection may come about and usually does come about either by the acquisition of new, mature birds from out - side sources, or by the use of hatching eggs originating in flocks involved in the disorder or by the purchase of day-old chicks hatched from such eggs. The incidence of fowl paral - ysis may be materially enhanced when infected brooder chicks and healthy ones are maintained in very close contact such as may happen to be the case in crowded battery brooders. Whether the infection comes about by contact or through eggs, all dependable evidence now available tends to show that the younger the bird, the more marked is its degree of susceptibility to fowl paralysis. In most instances it may be assumed that birds involved become infected before they have reached the age of ten weeks, no matter at what age actual symptoms may make their appearance. This opinion is sustained also by experimental evidence. Regarding this point, Seagar found that artificial infection is easier to bring about during the earlier weeks and months of life, although it may still be achieved after six months of age. Fowl paralysis is characterized by long periods of incuba - tion. Stated in another manner, the virus which gains en - trance into a healthy bird persists therein for a prolonged period before symptoms of the disease become manifest. In - cubation periods reported by Lerche and Fritsche ranged be - tween 66 days and 7V£ months and the shortest period observed by Seagar was 54 days. Patterson and associates observed the disease in a chick 41 days old and even cases in chicks less than four weeks old have been reported. In view of the tedious incubation peculiar to fowl paralysis, it seems reasonable to attribute such cases to infection acquired within the egg. </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 The early symptoms of fowl paralysis are sometimes vague and may or may not develop rather slowly. A slight wing droop may be observed or the affected birds show lameness not infrequently marked by a jerky, stilted gait. As the dis - ease advances, that which at first appeared as a slight lame - ness or stiffness begins to show itself as an inability to use the affected leg altogether. One or both limbs may be affected and the same condition may pertain to the wings. At last the affected fowl goes down and not uncommonly shows a very unnatural position of its legs. One may be stretched back - ward and the other one forward or both limbs may be extend - ed sideways from the body. The legs or wings may be per - fectly limp or flaccid, or may show contractions of the leg and toes, all these variations depending O^ ! on the part of the |:^^^g^p^^p||^|^|^j|%_ ,; - - £ I nervous system more ri^^aH^Hl^^PB^pgwIPS^- 98 particularly involved. l^m^SSs!^^i'^^^&amp;^^%l'' - ' ' The appetite of the [1hH|H^^ v ' "^^^K|liiBi^ ; S affected fowls, as a r|iljraffi«r t s^i)^_ general rule, remains P«tiEtt -■ - f^S^ good throughout the gE^M^^,. course of the disease, l^^^gBWmHwIBi^^S^^^^" 11^] although in the later iS'unuLifmov* *'°- 23 - A **- — &lt;* *- •— »*• ments of the head are occasionally observed and by some authors they are regarded as evidence of brain involvement. Not uncommonly the eyes of affected birds show an abnormal color. The original color of the part immediately surrounding the pupil takes on a lighter hue ranging from white to a slate gray. Impairment of vision is apt to accompany these changes in the appearance of the eye. In a few cases the abnormal as - pect of the eyes is the only evidence of paralysis infection and such birds may not become paralyzed. Gradually the fowls become helpless and as they no longer are capable of obtaining food and water they soon enter in - to a state of emaciation. In the course of these later phases of the malady the birds may develop diarrhea. Practically all cases of fowl paralysis terminate in death. On the whole the disorder tends to run its course in a tedious manner and birds affected with paralysis may linger as long as two or three months. However, the majority of the cases succumb in two or three weeks after the onset of symptoms, if not sooner. Occasionally an affected fowl dies suddenly on ac - count of heart failure. Cases of fowl paralysis which take on a more acute course are uncommon, although they have </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Poultry Diseases been observed. Instances in which the development of the disorder became arrested have also been noted, but. they must be regarded as of exceptional occurrence. Lesions. — The after-death appearances of birds affected with fowl paralysis do not always furnish a clear indication of the nature of the disease. The most characteristic features of the malady can only be revealed by a microscopic examina - tion of the tissues concerned. Such an examination shows that the affected tissues, especially the ones composing the various parts of the nervous system, are infiltrated by masses of cells of the lymphoid or plasma types. When the brain and spinal cord are involved in such infiltra - tions the fact is not clearly shown by their appearance to the naked eye. This may also be the case with affected nerves which supply the muscles of the paralyzed legs or wings. On the other hand, the cellular infiltration of nerves is apt to give rise to a distinct enlargement or thickening which can be readily recognized. The same feature may also be observed in nerves situated within the body. The thickening may be diffuse and even, or the nerves may be deformed and present a more or less nodular appearance. These nerve lesions are the ones most commonly observed. They may be confined to only one nerve or to several and in certain cases only a part of a given nerve may be involved. The cellular infiltrations of nerves and other nerve tissues are directly or indirectly responsible for the loss of function, which gives rise to the paralysis of the fowls concerned. No doubt they are induced by the causative virus, but although the latter is particularly prone to exert its disease producing action on nerve tissue, there is evidence which shows that it may also be active in such other organs as liver, kidney, heart, etc. It is. especially in the ovary that infiltrations of the sort mentioned may be encountered. In that organ they not infrequently give rise to tumor-like formations. The latter are observed in approximately ten per cent of fowl - paralysis cases. Prevention. — Fowl paralysis is not amenable to medicinal treatment and at this time prevention by the use of medi - cines, serums, or vaccines has not become possible. Preven - tion by certain measures in flock management may, however, be attempted and deserves consideration on the part of all who are engaged in poultry raising. These measures pertain to flocks yet free from the malady as well as to the ones in which the latter has already made its appearance. Flocks as yet exempt from the disorder can best be protected by not </seg>
            <seg id="p074">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 introducing into them mature fowls from outside sources unless it can be definitely ascertained that the flock in which they originated has shown no paralysis cases for a period of at least two or three years. Preference in the choice of eggs for hatching purposes should be given to those derived from the paralysis-free flock itself, provided, of course, that the latter is also free from bacillary-white-diarrhea infection. If outside sources of eggs for hatching must be depended on, care should be exercised in not procuring them frran flocks in which paralysis has established ltself^JCfee-same precautions are applicable to the acquisition-^oTbaby chicks. In incubating and brooding operations^tne eggs and chicks derived from paralysis-free flocks should be kept separate from those of unknown or questionable origin. In the face of the menace associated with the spread of fowl paralysis, commercial hatcheries are in position to render a distinct service to the poultry industry in general by adopting the practice of a thorough challeng - ing of the health status of the flocks from which eggs for hatching are to be obtained. In the management of flocks it is advisable to kill any fowl as soon as possible after it shows the first signs of the disease If such fowls are not suitable for consumption they should be destroyed by burning. If, on the other hand, the birds in the initial stages of the disorder are otherwise in good physi - cal condition, there is no objection to their use for the table or for canning. It is quite obvious that the offal derived from such chickens should be destroyed by fire. It seems possible that removing the healthy members of the flock to clean ground may also be worth while. The thorough cleaning and disinfection of poultry houses and the feeding and watering equipment, after the elimination of the affected fowls, should not be neglected. Even if no further cases of paralysis develop in the flock it appears to be imperative that adequate measures be taken to prevent all contact of the flock with the birds comprising the succeeding crop of chicks. The latter should be obtained from disease-free flocks, as has already been stated. They should be brooded while isolated in clean quarters and kept on clean ground, away from all contact with the older fowls until they are at least ten weeks old. They should not have access to the yard previously occupied by affected or exposed towls until not less than two or three months of warm weather have intervened after the removal of the last chick - ens. If general conditions permit, the older fowls which were </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Poultry Diseases exposed to the infection should be disposed of for dressing as soon as possible. INFECTIOUS LEUKOSIS The name leukosis indicates whiteness or pallor, and the latter is, indeed, quite often observed in fowls affected with the disorder. Leukosis is frequently encountered in the flocks maintained in large poultry establishments and is probably more common on Nebraska farms than is generally recog - nized. The malady must be given consideration as a poten - tial source of mischief and fully capable of producing serious losses. In its apparent cause and in the changes it produces in the various organs of the body, leukosis shows a marked similarity to fowl paralysis, described in the previous chap - ter. The two diseases are apparently closely related. The malady is characterized by cellular infiltration within the organs of the body, the spleen, liver, kidney, and bone marrow often showing its most typical lesions. Such infiltra - tions are also apparent in the blood and in such cases the disease is often referred to as leukemia. As leukosis is encountered in Nebraska, it is seen only in chickens. Certain authors apparently have also observed it in turkeys, ducks, geese, and pigeons and a case in the canary has also been described. That the infection is capable of transmission from such birds to chickens and vice versa has, however, not been proved. Cause. — Leukosis can be readily transmitted from fowl to fowl by experimental injections of the blood and of sus - pensions of organs from affected birds into healthy ones. This is also possible after the material to be injected is passed through filters capable of retaining microscopically visible bacteria. Hence it is apparent that the cause of in - fectious leukemia also is an ultramicroscopic, filterable virus. Very little is precisely known of the nature of the latter. The virus is not readily destroyed by external influences. It shows resistance to alternate freezing and thawing, to dry - ing, and to storage in the dried state and it can be preserved for a considerable length of time in glycerine. If kept at body temperature for a few days, it loses its disease-produc - ing qualities, but when stored at ice-box temperature, the latter are preserved for a considerable period. Symptoms. — The appearance of infectious leukosis in a flock is by no means a spectacular event such as may be observed in outbreaks of fowl cholera. The disorder may make considerable progress in a flock before it is recognized as a real problem. It is most apt to involve fowls in the </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 early adult stage of life and young birds apparently are more susceptible than older ones, although the latter may also be affected. It appears from transmission experiments that the incubation periods observed ranged between one or two and even four months. As observed in the field the disease is most frequently encountered in hens during their first laying season. After being placed in the laying house, while in good condition, in - dividual birds may begin to show impairment in health after a month or two. They become pale and emaciated and finally die. In the more acute forms of the disease fowls may be found dead without having previously been observed to be sick. In the more slowly developing cases, the fowls con - cerned will be seen to lose condition and their combs and wattles become pale in color. The appetite is generally fairly well maintained until the malady has made considerable progress. Then the desire for food begins to diminish and the fowls involved become pro - gressively more emaciated. Emaciation may even be observed in fowls which, in a measure, have retained their appetites. Chickens affected by leukosis in a well-developed form are dull and show weakness and are apt to stand with their eyes closed, their necks drawn in, and their feathers ruffled. The recognition of the disease is often difficult by the mere observation of the symptoms presented by living birds. This is more readily accomplished by after-death examination of recently dead fowls. In some cases the diagnosis may be made in the living bird by the microscopic examination of its blood. Lesions. — Fowls dead with infectious leukosis commonly show the blood to be watery and thin and when taken from the living bird it may show delay in clotting. Microscopic ex - amination may reveal a decrease in the normal number of the red cells and sometimes an enormous increase in that of the white cells. The blood picture, however, is likely to show marked variations. The liver of leukosis cases is usually found to be enlarged and may show small brownish yellow spots evenly distributed over the surface of the organ. Small, light-colored areas may also be observed which on their margins merge into the deeper color of the liver. Occasionally white nodular areas are found in the liver substance which have the appearance of true tumors. There are cases of leukosis in which the greatly enlarged liver has become fragile to the extent that the organ ruptures, thus causing death by internal hem- </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Poultry Diseases orrhage. This condition, however, may also be seen in chick - ens affected with other diseases. Infectious leukosis is usually accompanied by distinct enlargement of the spleen. This organ may even assume a size of six to ten times its normal volume. In the majority of cases the enlargement of the spleen is more moderate. If the enlarged spleen is cut into, the spleen pulp may bulge through the incision. White cellular infiltration is often observed in the spleens of fowls dead with leukosis. The kidneys may be wholly or partially involved. They may be pulpy or show small pin-point-sized, cream-yellow areas as evidence of cellular infiltration. The intestines may also participate in the general infiltration of cells and not uncommonly they show hemorrhages in the mucous mem - branes. Bone-marrow changes may also be observed, although this may not be very apparent to the naked eye. Prevention. — The treatment of infectious leukosis by the use of medicines and other substances is entirely futile. As certain evidence points to the possibility of the disease being transmitted through the egg as well as by actual contacts, the preventive measures recommended against fowl paralysis may be reasonably expected to be applicable wherever the preven - tion of infectious leukosis must be attempted. BLACKHEAD IN TURKEYS The name "blackhead" is applied to a disease of the in - testines, particularly the blind guts or ceca, and the liver, which is especially disastrous to turkeys. The designation is suggested by the fact that the color of the head of the birds affected becomes dark for a short time prior to death. This is, however, not characteristic of this disease and constitutes a phenomenon seen in a considerable assortment of disorders. In spite of this the name has been solidly established and will probably be continued. Blackhead infection has been occasionally encountered in chickens. It is apparently becoming more common in the latter, judging from the frequency of the disease being found in chicks examined at this Station. In young chicks the dis - ease occasionally is observed as a cause of death and although chickens appear to be fully capable of becoming the hosts of the causative parasites, it cannot be said that at this time blackhead contributes materially to the losses by disease sus - tained by this type of poultry. On the other hand the malady must be regarded as one of the more important, if not the most important disease which turkey growers have to reckon with. This is particularly the </seg>
            <seg id="p078">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 case wherever turkeys are raised year after year on the same land or farmyard, and when their range is a restricted one. It further appears that turkeys which are kept together with common barnyard fowls are most liable to become involved in the disease. Aside from turkeys and chickens, the disease has also been found in pheasants, partridges, and peafowls. Cause. — Blackhead is caused by a microscopic parasite belonging to the protozoa. Originally it was called Ameba meleagridis, but from time to time its name has been changed, the last proposed designation being Histomonas meleagris. Its life history is as yet unknown, and although it can be recognized in the tissues involved in the disease, it would be difficult to identify the parasite in other situations. The or - ganism is present in the blind intestines and livers of diseased turkeys and is eliminated from the body by means of the droppings. There are indications of an experimental nature which tend to show that the small roundworm of the cecum (Heterakis gcUlinae) may play a part either in the propaga - tion of the causative parasite or in the transmission of the disease. How this comes about is not known ; nor is it known that the worm is essential in the transmission of the disease. From a practical hygienic point of view it probably makes little difference whether blackhead depends for its trans - mission exclusively on the cecal worms or on the ingestion of food and water contaminated by infective droppings alone. The infestation by worms and the acquisition of the black - head parasite from fecal material must both be derived pri - marily from the same source, namely the droppings of birds which are either affected by the malady or merely carriers of the disease-producing organisms. Experiments undertaken by this Station established the fact that blackhead is essentially a filth-borne disease and that fecal contamination appears to be the principal factor to be considered in transmission. Apparently the causative organ - isms of blackhead can maintain themselves alive in contamin - ated soil for considerable periods. At least in the experi - ments carried on by this Station it could be observed in five succeeding years that ground left vacant by infected turkeys from the middle of November to the middle of June was still infective to poults introduced in the yard when they were four weeks of age and were not exposed to the infection before that time. Symptoms. — The greatest susceptibility to blackhead is shown by the younger poults. This Station studied the age - group distribution of 291 deaths from blackhead among poults which were exposed to the infection at the exact age of four </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Poultry Diseases . weeks and found that 31.27 per cent of the deaths occurred during the seventh week, 14.77 per cent during the eighth week, 6.53 per cent during the ninth week, 8.59 per cent dur - ing the tenth week, and 5.49 per cent during the eleventh week of life. After that period the weekly death rate dwindled until the twenty-sixth week with a 0.34 per cent death rate. It seems evident that the factor of age exer - cises a potent influence on susceptibility as well as on the death rate, although it must be admitted that aside from mere age, some other factor may have to be reckoned with. The periods of incubation after natural exposure in infected environments usually range between eight days and one month. Shorter incubation periods have been observed after the artificial introduction of the infective material. The fac - tor of age probably influences the length of incubation as well as the rate of mortality. The younger poults will, in all probability, show the shorter periods. In the Nebraska ex - periments the first deaths from blackhead among the poults mentioned above, during five succeeding years of observa - tion, occurred respectively on the 15th, 15th, 21st, 21st, and 21st days after exposure. Most of the birds concerned showed evidence of impaired health for three or four days prior to death. The disease shows itself in the younger birds by drowsi - ness, progressive weakness, ruffled feathers, drooping wings, and a more or less constant diarrhea. The dark discoloration of the head, already mentioned, may be observed, but this feature cannot be counted on to be always present or to be unmistakable evidence of the disease. In the older turkeys the symptoms are less severe, the course of the disease is slower, and the tendency to severe emaciation more pro - nounced. Such birds may wholly or partially recover. They remain permanent infection carriers and are subject to re - lapse even at remote periods. While the symptoms described above are always sufficient to warrant suspecting blackhead, they cannot be depended upon for a definite diagnosis. This, however, is made possible by examination of the organs after death. The lesions characteristic of the disease are described be - low. In addition to those, the finding of the parasites by mic - roscopic examination makes an accurate recognition of the disease possible. In young poults the disease is likely to be rapidly fatal. Some of the birds may survive, but as a rule the case death rate is very near the hundred per cent mark. In the more mature birds the mortality is less severe and </seg>
            <seg id="p080">Nebraska! Experiment Station Bulletin 290 even if there is serious damage to the ceca, and liver the animals may survive in a fair state of health. Such birds, in fact all older birds in an infected flock, remain infection carriers and are a menace to the younger generation of birds coming on later. Lesions. — The damage to the affected organs inflicted by blackhead may be slight or severe, depending on the severity of the assault of the infection and on the resistance shown by individual poults. The lesions are practically confined to the blind intestines and the liver, although they also have been observed in other organs. The intestinal .^^^fl^k^^k. lesions are apparently .^^BftflliiSilil"- the primary ones and ■' HHBk. their formation prob- : ' |^ ably precedes the in- 1 :: ' Bk volvement of the liver. £[?ij$gBr '' jjlife,-'' m Either one of the i ',: i^^HHB-&gt;.-' wK blind guts or both may m'^jSi^: .'.*;■}. 1&amp;[3m£ I be found to be affect- r : v &gt;v^^^^S ed. The lesion is of an W^^^^'V'"?^*^^^ \\ ■ inflammatory nature, w m*&amp; jjj r f WW 1H which results in a con- wtN^. 1 ■ B^V siderable thickening W ; ..'^ JS V of the intestinal wall. : ; ?k; : '- ;/; ] W'*' "■'■'■■ . ' y: Bk The latter may be con- p^^' '" ' t r "-'■''' J fined to certain areas xfire^^ ■'"■"» m "'-'■' only or the entire tube »^^^ may be drawn into the process. Partially by Fig. 24.— Blackhead of turkey liver, the inflammatory changes and partially because of secondary factors the mucous lining of the intestine becomes necrotic. The dead tissue debris, mixed with the food material which happens to be pre - sent, forms a dry, cheesy, friable material which may appear as a core which fills and distends the intestinal tube. A cross section of this mass is apt to show a concentric arrangement of the material. In the liver there occur areas of dead tissue which give the organ a very characteristic appearance. The necrotic or degenerated areas are well visible on the surface of the organ. They range in size from one-tenth to three-fourths of an inch in diameter, are more or less circular in shape, and have a light yellowish color. They do not project beyond the liver surface, but may extend deeply into the substance of the organ. More often they are quite distinct, although occasion- </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Poultry Diseases ally, and especially in the older birds, they may become con - fluent. In not a few of the older cases peritonitis accompanies the changes mentioned. The liver of the more chronic cases observed in the older birds may show considerable amounts of scar tissue. Treatment. — Many methods of treatment have been recommended, but the most painstaking search for evidence of success fails to disclose anything which is in the least encouraging. In fact the results reported and the considera - tion of the nature of the disease warrant the conclusion that the course of the disease, once established in a turkey, can - not be changed by any means of treatment now known. Prevention. — Although the knowledge pertaining to the nature and life history of the microparasite which causes blackhead is very incomplete, enough is known of the disease itself and the conditions which govern its occurrence so that certain principles of prevention can be established. These principles are based upon the all-important fact that black - head is a filth-borne disease, which, for its transmission, is dependent on the ingestion of fecal material eliminated by birds either actually affected with the disorder or which are mere carriers of the infection. In as much as there is no practicable method by which carrier birds can be detected and also because actually diseased birds often defy recogni - tion as such, the practice of looking upon all turkeys and chickens as potential infection carriers becomes a definite principle worthy of consideration. Due weight must also be given to the fact that the poults," when less than ten or twelve weeks old, are more susceptible to the malady than during the succeeding periods of life. Hence, the protection of birds belonging in that age group is one of the most essential of all hygienic measures. This, however, does not by any means signify that older turkeys will not contract the disease in infected environments. With - out doubt the total death losses will be reduced if the poults are adequately protected early in life. In the application of the above-named principles the fol - lowing measures appear to be essential: (1) Artificial incuba - tion in order to escape the hazard arising from the close asso - ciation with the parent bird in the same environment. (2) Brooding in an enclosure from which all infection hazards have been previously excluded by such details as hardware - cloth floor covering and all other measures by which actual contact with the soil can be avoided. (3) The maintenance of the poults, at least until they are twelve weeks old, on clean ground, not previously occupied by either turkeys or common </seg>
            <seg id="p082">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 fowls. If such ground is not available some of the recommen - dations made in the next section should be considered. (4) The provision of a wide range for the maturing fowls, if possible one not previously occupied by blackhead-infected fowls. If such an environment is not available and the turkeys must be confined in more or less constantly occupied enclosures, then the latter should be covered either by coarse gravel or by one-inch-mesh hardware cloth. (5) A maximum protection against the fecal contamination of food and water by the use of feeding and watering equipment, especially de - signed for the purpose (see chapters on hygiene and sani - tation) . The salutary effects of the application of the prin - ciples and measures mentioned above are clearly shown by the results of certain experiments carried on by this Station in order to evaluate the influence of environment on the in - cidence of poultry diseases. Part of this experimental project pertained to blackhead in turkeys. For the purpose of this investigation two yards of equal area (30'x60') were provided which differed only in their appointments. In the one, sanitary conditions within the range of economic possibility were maintained. The ground was covered by a thick layer of coarse gravel and for the last two years of the five-year period involved in the ex - periment, hardware-cloth panels were placed over the gravel. The latter measure was primarily taken in order to prevent the poults from swallowing excessive amounts of gravel, a vice which developed among some of them. No doubt the wire covering also contributed to the salubrity of the environment. Rain water and the wastes from the fountains were drained away by a line of tiles covered by the gravel. The feeding and watering equipment available in the yard were so con - structed as to exclude gross fecal contamination. The other yard represented the type of surroundings in which farm poultry are commonly maintained. There the turkeys lived in contact with the soil and their food and water were provided in open troughs. One open drain running diag - onally through this yard carried off the liquid wastes and the precipitation water. Prior to the beginning of the experiment in 1929 both yards were infected with blackhead material in equal amount and manner. After the removal and slaughter of the turkeys at the close of each year's season the yards were left undis - turbed and without fowls until they were again populated with young poults the following year. After the initial infection, no outside blackhead material was added to the yards. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Poultry Diseases Four-weeks-old poults of identical brood were placed in the yards about the middle of June of each of the five years. Usually, but not always, the population was composed of an equal number of poults. Prior to entry in the yards the poults had been hatched in an incubator and brooded in a manner to exclude all infection hazards. The results obtained were as follows : Blackhead morbidity among poults during uninterrupted occupancy of yards Yard Year Poults B^£SjT d Morbidity Number Number Per cent Sanitary 1929 102 6 B88 »".S 193 ° 161 7 4 - 63 &gt;ara 1931 50 3 6.00 1932 50 0 0.00 1933 130 2 1.54 Total 483 18 3.73 1929 101 81 80.19 Farm 1930 151 127 84.10 yard 1931 99 33 33.33 1932 110 29 26.36 1933 70 23 32.85 Total 531 I 293 55.17 It appears that in the course of five years the cases of black - head which developed in the sanitary yard ranged between 0.00 and 6.00 per cent of the turkey population. On the other hand, this rate of sickness from blackhead in the unsanitary or common farmyard fluctuated between 26.36 and 84.10 per cent of the fowls maintained in the yard. When conclusions are based on the total results obtained during the five-year period it appears that the chances of a poult contracting black - head in the unsanitary yard were 14.77 times greater than of a poult maintained in the yard where reasonable sanitary pre - cautions were taken. COCCIDIOSIS The name of this malady is derived from the name of the microscopic parasite by which it is caused. The parasites inflict damage to various parts of the intestinal tract, in the structures of which they thrive and multiply. Various species of coccidia are parasitic in a large assortment of avian species, among which chickens and turkeys also appear as hosts. The disease resulting from coccidial invasion is common wherever poultry raising is more or less intensively practiced and it has a world-wide distribution. In Nebraska coccidiosis is a common cause of losses among young chicks. It is also observed in young poults although not as frequently as in </seg>
            <seg id="p084">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 chicks. Certain observations indicate that the disorder in turkeys is gradually increasing its prevalence. Coccidiosis is most commonly observed in chicks ranging in age from three to ten weeks. In such chicks the disease is often highly fatal and in the more severe outbreaks a flock death rate of from 50 to 90 per cent can occasionally be regis - tered. Not all affected chicks succumb to the disease, but they sustain damage which greatly impairs their thriftiness and growth. Such birds are prone to harbor coccidia for extended periods. After chicks have attained a certain age they commonly exhibit a considerable degree of resistance to coccidial in - vasion and are less apt to develop the more acute form of the disease. However, older birds are by no means entirely exempt, but if they become affected the disease tends to take on a more chronic form and the flock mortality is always less than among the younger birds. The disease is most fre - quently encountered during spring and summer up to the be - ginning of autumn. Cause. — Coccidiosis of fowls is caused by protozoan parasites (Coccidia) of the intestines in which they are capable of bringing about destructive changes in the mucous membrane. There is considerable agreement among investi - gators that the host-parasite relations of coccidia are quite specific or, in other words, that the coccidia, parasitic in one animal species, cannot thrive and cause disease in animals be - longing to a different one. However, observations suggest - ing the contrary have been made. To what extent such obser - vations may have a hygienic importance cannot yet be stated and the results of further studies must be awaited before a final answer to this question can be found. Originally it was thought that the common fowl was host to only one species of coccidia (Eimeria tenella), but in the course of more recent years not less than six different species have been identified in chickens, two of which appeared to be harmless. They all belong to the genus Eimeria. Cocci - diosis of turkeys is ascribed to two species of coccidia. It is, however, not impossible that coccidial species, primarily parasitic in chickens, may also be occasionally implicated in the disease of poults. All species of coccidia show a rather complicated life his - tory. No doubt this may vary somewhat for the different species but on the whole will correspond to the one here briefly related. The more resistant oocyst form of the parasites makes its exit from the infested fowls when contained in the </seg>
            <seg id="p085">Poultry Diseases droppings. At that time the oocysts are not infective, but they become so after they have undergone sporulation outside the animal body. This process is determined and influenced by the prevailing conditions associated with temperature and moisture. It results in the formation of sporocysts, which, continuing their development, bring forth forms known as sporozoites. The latter are capable of free movement and are set free quite soon after the sporulated oocyst arrives in the intestines of a suitable host. There the sporozoites penetrate the epithelial cells by which the intestinal surface is lined. Their development is continued and this results in the formation of a body designated as schizont. The latter eventually fills up the invaded cell. The schizont develops new structures in a considerable number. These are called merozoites and in appearance resemble the sporozoites. After the destruction of the epithelial cell they swarm into the intestinal contents and penetrate new cells, where, as a result, another crop of schizonts is formed. This process may be repeated several times and may thus cause a considerable amount of damage to the intestinal mucous membrane. Finally the merozoites penetrating the epithelial cells no longer cause the formation of schizonts but give rise to sex - ual forms, male and female. The male elements, quite motile, are set free into the intestinal tube, seek the cells containing the female element, penetrate, and fuse with the latter. As a result, fertilization takes place and a new form appears. This is the resistant oocyst already referred to. In time it is set free and appears in the droppings. The time required for the completion of the cycle has been estimated at from eight to ten days. Sporulation may be prevented by the putrefaction of the medium in which the oocysts are contained. The oocysts are also destroyed by tem - peratures above 104° F. and are likewise injured or killed by drying. On the other hand, they are resistant to the action of the disinfectants in common use. Sporulated oocysts are far more resistant to adverse external influences than the nonsporulated ones. It is difficult to state how long the sporulated oocysts re - main viable in the various media in which they may be con - tained. Edgington and Broerman observed that sporulated oocysts remained fully infective for a period of not less than two years, when kept in a solution of potassium bi - chromate. Stubbs states that in the soil they may survive for one year or more. In experiments with coccidiosis under- </seg>
            <seg id="p086">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 taken by this Station, coccidial infection apparently per - sisted in a yard left unoccupied for about seven months. On the other hand, Tyzzer does not believe that coccidia survive outside the body very long under ordinary conditions Although apparently longevity of the oocysts can be more or less accurately determined by laboratory experiments, it is quite possible that the factors which determine survival in a more natural environment are controlled and modified by many influences which cannot be measured and that there - fore it is not possible to state with any degree of accuracy how long an infection hazard may persist in a given poultry yard. The part played by the latter must always be given due weight although there is general agreement among in - vestigators that the older fowls as real or potential carriers of coccidia must be accepted as the principal source of infec - tion. Coccidial infection comes about by the chicks or poults con - cerned taking into their digestive system sporulated oocysts present in food and drinking water as well as in the soil of infected areas. Like blackhead, coccidiosis also is a typical filth-borne disease. Tyzzer has expressed the opinion that actual infection appears to be dependent on the number of infective coccidia capable of penetrating the intestinal structures. Hence the more oocysts that are taken in with food and drink or the the greater the accumulations of these forms in a given en - vironment the greater will be the coccidiosis hazard asso - ciated with the latter. Epizootological observations and de - ductions generally yield support to this view. Symptoms. — The manifestations of the disease are not especially characteristic. In common with other microbic diseases, coccidiosis is shown by depression, ruffled feathers or down, weakness, dullness, disinclination to move, and loss of appetite. In young chicks these symptoms may develop rapidly and soon lead to death. Diarrhea is a common fea - ture, and the soft or semiliquid bowel discharges are often found to be streaked with blood. In adult poultry the disease runs a less rapid course. Such animals present signs of ill health of an indefinite nature. The birds are inactive and stupid and lose flesh and show a pallor of comb and wattles. In some cases there is inability to stand and diarrhea is not uncommonly seen. Coccidiosis is easily confused with some of the other poul - try diseases in which the bowels are implicated. The micro - scopic examination of the bowel discharges, or, still better </seg>
            <seg id="p087">Poultry Diseases of the contents of the blind intestines, is about the only way by which a diagnosis can be established with any degree of accuracy. Lesions. — In the recognition of this disease the after - death examination of the affected birds is very valuable. In such animals the disease damage is principally found in the two blind guts or ceca. These sections of the intestinal canal are found to be inflamed and their walls thickened. The in - testine involved appears larger, shows a red color, and its inner lining may be wholly or partially destroyed. It is filled either with a bloody mass, which may be soft or more or less solid, or with a cheesy material streaked with blood. The latter is more common in older fowls. Both in young chicks and in the older ones evidence of coccidiosis can also be found in the small intestines. There it is usually expressed by inflammatory conditions which in severity may range be - tween a mere catarrhal affection and a rather severe enter - itis. Prevention. — Sufficient evidence has accumulated to warrant the statement that medicinal treatment has no value whatsoever in the cure or prevention of coccidiosis. This like - wise pertains to the use of sour milk, which has been fre - quently recommended for the purpose. If sour milk has any value at all, it probably is entirely associated with its food value and the fact that as a food it may be quite suitable to animals suffering from intestinal damage. Coccidiosis of poultry, owing to some of the characteristic features presented by the causative parasites, is, among all other poultry disorders, probably the most difficult to pre - vent. As a typical filth-borne disease, its prevention must be based upon the same principles as those which are applicable to the control of blackhead in turkeys. The measures to be recommended in connection with coccidiosis, however, require a more rigorous execution, because, as long as chicks in a more or less infected area have access to chicken dung or tc objects befouled by the latter, a coccidiosis hazard is bound to persist. This was shown by certain experiments with coccidiosis carried on by this Station and not yet completed. As in the blackhead experiments, the experimental chicks were main - tained in two separate environments similarly infected with oocysts. In one of these the chicks were exposed without any sanitary restrictions, whereas in the other yard reason - able hygienic measures were applied. In the case of black - head, the latter were quite sufficient to bring about a material </seg>
            <seg id="p088">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 reduction of the mortality. On the other hand in both cocci - diosis yards the mortality was about the same. The sani - tary yard was covered with gravel and although the feed was provided in such a manner that it could not be contam - inated by the droppings, the chicks roosting on the tops of the feeders did not fail to befoul them in a conspicuous man - ner. In addition, a considerable part of the dung remained on the surface of the gravel for a length of time sufficient for the sporulation of the oocysts. It seemed that no headway against the malady could be made until measures could be designed to further reduce the fecal contacts. Experiments with that object in view were undertaken, and the initial results obtained tend to indicate a possible means of improvement. However, as yet, it would be imprudent to base specific recommendations upon these preliminary observations. From a practical point of view there is good reason to at - tribute a definite value to such measures as incubator hatch - ing, brooding in sanitary brooders, preferably provided with floors and sun parlors covered with one-inch-mesh wire panels and, above all, the complete separation of chicks up to the age of twelve weeks from the older fowls. By means of the latter measure alone the coccidiosis hazard may be con - siderably reduced, provided the chicks are kept on clean ground. In commercial flocks, where the hens are kept in laying houses, this separation comes about automatically. If, in addition to this, the younger birds, after leaving the brood - ers, are given a wide range on ground which can be left un - populated for periods of two or three years, it becomes pos - sible for producers to view their coccidiosis risks with a con - siderable degree of peace of mind. It is obvious that the gen - eral measures of hygiene and sanitation, discussed in a special chapter, are particularly to be applied wherever coccidiosis has to be combated. PARASITES AND PESTS Parasitism is widely distributed in nature and it is quite inconceivable to imagine an animal species without its para - sites, no matter how large or how small the individuals may be. Birds in general, and domestic poultry in particular are no exceptions to this rule. Among Nebraska poultry also various parasites are of common occurrence and not infre - quently they constitute a cause of worry for the poultry keeper. Several species of parasites may infest a single fowl </seg>
            <seg id="p089">Poultry Diseases and even in the cleanest of flocks some parasites may be ex - pected to be present. The parasites of poultry may be divided into two principal groups: (1) the endoparasites, which in - fest the internal organs, and (2) the ectoparasites, which commonly inhabit the external surface of the body. ENDOPARASITES Endoparasites, or internal parasites, are the ones which infest the interior of the body of their hosts. They may be encountered in the digestive and respiratory organs, in the blood and in other parts. Most species of internal parasites show a particular preference to the sites they occupy in the body and are not to be found elsewhere. The internal para - sites of poultry are conveniently divided into three distinct groups, namely : (1) the flukeworms, (2) the tapeworms, and (3) the roundworms. The flukeworms. — The flukeworms are also known as the trematodes, and are flat, leaf like, nonsegmented worms. The front part of the flukes is usually equipped with suckers by which they can attach themselves to the surfaces of the organs they inhabit. These parasites are uncommon in Nebraska, although it can scarcely be doubted that some of the species may be found among our poultry. As yet they are of no economic importance in the state. The tapeworms. — Tapeworms, or cestodes, are seg - mented, ribbon-shaped worms. Their foremost extremity, popularly referred to as the "head," is provided with suck - ers and often, but not always, with hooklets, by means of which they attach themselves to the intestinal surface. The segments develop from this part, the youngest being nearest to the "head" and the oldest being farthest away from it. The latter are the ripe segments and contain the eggs of the parasite. These segments drop off and leave the body of the host with the droppings. Tapeworms have a complicated life history and, so far as is now known, practically always require two different host species in order to complete their life cycle. In one of these they pass the immature phases of life and in the other they become adult and sexually mature. The ripe tapeworm seg - ments and eggs eliminated with the droppings are taken in by the temporary or intermediate host in the tissues of which the embryo develops and remains viable for extended periods. When a temporary host thus invaded, or part of it, is taken into the digestive organs of the final host, the worm develops and becomes mature, in time shedding the segments contain- </seg>
            <seg id="p090">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 ing great numbers of eggs. Although there are some notable exceptions to this, most tapeworms, in order to become mature, require a given animal species and, as a rule, the immature worm does not develop in a host belonging to a different species: • Tapeworms are quite common in all types of poultry. They inhabit the small intestines, to the mucous membrane of which they attach themselves by means of the suckers and hooklets. The ones most frequently found in Nebraska fowls are the following : Hymenolepis cariocq. — This worm is from one to three inches in length and about one-fortieth of an inch in width. This thread-like worm may infest a fowl in large numbers and appears to be most common during the latter part of sum - mer and earlier weeks of autumn. It may be encountered in turkeys as well as in barnyard fowls. The common stable fly serves this parasite as its temporary host. Choanotenia infundibulum. — This parasite has a length of from two to eight inches and a width of about one-eighth of an inch. Its intermediate host is the common house fly. This worm inhabits the small intestines of chickens, turkeys, ducks, and pigeons. Raillietina tetragona. — This, one of the most common among the tapeworms of Nebraska fowls, has a length of from one to ten inches and in width ranges from one-twentieth to one-sixth of an inch. It most commonly occupies the posterior part of the small intestines. There are indications that its temporary hosts must be looked for among certain species of small snails. Raillietina cesticellus. — This parasite is most frequently observed in the fore part of the small intestines. It measures from one-half to two inches in length, although specimens with a length of five inches have been observed. Its width ranges from one-sixteenth to one-eighth of an inch. It is a common parasite of barnyard fowls and may also be found in turkeys. The common house fly may be its temporary host. Raillietina echinobothrida. — This parasite is a tapeworm from two to nine inches in length and from one-twentieth to one-sixth of an inch in width. Its temporary host is probably a species of snail, although this has not yet been definitely con - firmed. This worm occurs in common fowls, turkeys, and pigeons. It inhabits the small intestines, in which it causes the formation of conspicuous nodules and ulcers by means of the structures by which it attaches itself to the wall of the gut. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">Poultry Diseases The roundworms. — These worms, also referred to as nematodes, are nonsegmented, spindle-shaped, cylindrical parasites, of which a number of species are parasitic in poul - try as well as in wild birds. A number of them are commonly found in Nebraska poultry. They are: Ascaridia galli. — This parasite measures from 1.2 to 4.8 inches in length, has a yellowish white color, and because of its size is frequently spoken of as the large roundworm of poultry. It is a rather common inhabitant of the small intes - tine of the common fowl, turkey, guinea, and pigeon. In this organ the mature female worm deposits its eggs which are then expelled with the droppings. The fertilized eggs, while contained in the expelled droppings, the soil, or accumulations of surface water, undergo certain changes of development and when this is completed the embryo within the egg remains dormant, although viable for more or less prolonged periods or until the eggs find their way into the digestive organs of a suitable host. This usually comes about through the consump - tion of contaminated food and drinking water. Once the egg has arrived in the small intestine the embryo leaves the egg to continue its development until it becomes adult and sexually mature. This process requires from three to four weeks. Heterakis gallinae. — This is a small worm which inhabits the blind guts or ceca of barnyard fowls, turkeys, guineas, and peafowls. It has occasionally also been observed in ducks and geese. It measures from one-half to three-fourths of an inch in length and not infrequently the parasites are present in great numbers. The life history of this worm is similar to that of the large roundworm described above. Eggs ex - pelled from the body develop an embryo in from seven to twelve days, while contained in soil or water. When taken in by a host bird the embryo is set free and continues its development until maturity. About eight weeks appear to be involved in this process. Heterakis dispar. — This parasite in many respects re - sembles the preceding species, with this difference, that it is considerably larger and that it occurs in ducks and geese. Cheilospirura hamulosa. — This is also known as the gizzard worm. It has a length of from one-half to one inch and has its site in the gizzard of the common fowl. Although not very common, the worm is occasionally encountered. Syngamus trachea. — This parasite, also known as the gape - worm, seems to be very rare in Nebraska if it occurs here at all. It has a forked appearance, caused by the fact that male </seg>
            <seg id="p092">Nebraska Experiment: Station Bulletin 290 and female are more or less permanently coupled. The male is small, having a length of from one-twelfth to one-fourth of an inch, and the female, much larger, measures from one - fifth to four-fifths of an inch. It inhabits the air passages of the common fowl, the turkey, the peafowl, and of a number of wild or semidomesticated birds. Its presence gives rise to a respiratory disease known as "gapes". The life history of this parasite is generally regarded as be - ing direct, that is, by the ingestion of food and water con - taminated with the immature forms of the worm. Some in - vestigators have apparently succeeded in transmitting this parasite by feeding chicks with earthworms obtained from in - fested soil. Worms and disease. — It is obvious that the worm para - sites of poultry cannot exercise a beneficial influence on the host animals concerned. Furthermore it cannot be doubted that when they are present in large numbers the health of the fowls may become manifestly impaired. Occasionally the damage may be such that losses by death have to be reckoned with. This pertains in particular to the younger birds which, like the young of other livestock, are always more vulnerable to parasitic invasions than the adults. The number of the parasites present, the age of the hosts concerned, and certain characteristics of the infesting worms are the more important factors which determine the degree of harm which may arise from internal parasitism. The presence of only a few worms causes but little harm, where - as large numbers may become responsible for sickness of the host animal. Incidentally it may be mentioned that a con - spicuous degree of worm infestation in a flock must be accepted as evidence of insalubrity of the environment in which the latter is being maintained. The harm done by in - ternal parasites may come about in various ways and although the precise nature of the effects of worms on their hosts is not always clearly understood, there is agreement among in - vestigators that damage of parasitic origin is caused by a variety of influences either operating singly or in combina - tion. Worms may do harm in a purely mechanical manner. They certainly do so when they are present in such numbers that they obstruct the intestinal passages. That their movements within the gut may produce irritation cannot well be doubted. Or, by their mode of attachment the parasites may cause abrasions or small wounds in the mucous membrane of the intestines and thus permit the entrance of disease-producing germs into the structures of the intestinal wall or even into </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Poultry Diseases the general blood circulation. Harmful substances may be - come absorbed by the same route. Parasites may abstract blood and nutrient materials from their hosts and recognition must be given to the fact that parasites apparently secrete substances which are poisonous to the parasitized fowls. Symptoms. — The symptoms presented by fowls damaged by internal parasites are by no means characteristic and it is impossible to accurately determine worm sickness by mere appearances of living birds. If a harmful parasitic invasion is suspected, it is always advisable to kill one or more of the worst-affected birds and then carefully inspect the contents of the entire digestive tube in order to determine the presence, numbers, and species of the parasites. Subjects invaded by a considerable number of tapeworms are apt to appear dull and listless and their feathers may be more or less ruffled. Their appetite is reduced and irregular, and a certain degree of diarrhea is commonly observed. On the other hand, bowel evacuations may become suspended on account of obstruction by large masses of worms. There is pallor of comb and wattles as evidence of anemia, and par - ticularly because of the latter condition the birds are wasted in flesh and may show a marked muscular weakness. Young birds may succumb to a heavy tapeworm invasion within a week after having shown the first signs of illness. Older birds may remain sickly for several weeks and then recover or die as the case may be. A few roundworms cause no signs of sickness; but when the infestation is a massive one, symptoms similar to the ones produced by tapeworms may be noted. This is especially the case in the younger birds. Gapeworms in chicks are apparently very rare in Nebraska poultry flocks. Where these parasites are common, the affected chicks, about two weeks after the worms gain access, become dull, droop their wings, and lose their desire for food. They tend to stretch their necks, close their eyes, and keep their beaks open ("gapes"), emitting a sound somewhat sug - gestive of a cough. They endeavor to free themselves of the mucus discharged from the windpipe by frequently shaking their heads by a sidewise movement. Such birds may actually suffocate, but more commonly they linger for a time and then succumb to a general debility. Lesions. — The examination of the intestines of fowls invaded by a considerable number of tapeworms commonly shows a pinkish content rich in mucus. Ordinarily most worms are found in the hindermost sections of the small in- </seg>
            <seg id="p094">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 testines, although some worms may also be found in the more forward portions of the gut. The intestinal mucous mem - brane is more or less inflamed and may show small red points. In the case of one species of tapeworm, there may be conspicu - ous nodules in the intestinal wall. Catarrhal or inflammatory changes of the intestines may also be the result of a heavy roundworm invasion. Chicks dead with "gapes" show the windpipe, the bronchial tubes, and sometimes also the airsacs to be invaded by the small, forked red parasites which are attached to the mucous membrane. The latter is inflamed and covered by mucus mixed with pus. Control and treatment. — In the solution of the problem presented by the intestinal worms of poultry more dependence should be placed on the systematic practice of hygiene and sanitation than on medicinal treatment. For various reasons, the latter can never be fully effective, no more than in the case of many of the important diseases which may come to plague the producer of poultry. As in the maintenance of health among human populations, disease outbreaks must be anticipated by hygienic measures rather than by awaiting their occurrence and depending on pills and potions. Not only are the remedies in use against poultry worms quite often ineffective or only partially efficacious, but even if they were adequate, the treatment would have to be repeat - ed at more or less frequent intervals. In the ordinary poultry flock it would prove to be extremely difficult to prevent the treated fowls from becoming promptly reinfested. To this disadvantage must be added the one associated with the re - duction in production not infrequently observed in flocks re - cently treated, without mentioning the irksome chore of re - peatedly having to subject a flock to treatment. In order to obtain any tangible results at all from the latter each bird should be individually dosed, because a poultry-parasite prob - lem cannot be satisfactorily solved by the addition of alleged vermifuges to the ration. The above statements are sustained by experimental evidence presented by Thomas, who con - cluded that his trials pertaining to the value of vermifuges indicate that the best procedure for poultrymen to follow would be to inaugurate sanitary measures as far as possible. Preventive measures always strike at the root of the evil, while the best that can be accomplished by treatment in con - nection with a poultry-worm problem consists of a mere lopping of some of its branches. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">Poultry Diseases In reality the routine "worming" of entire flocks on the mere suspicion that the birds have worms or because some parasites have been found in some individual fowl, has no place in flock management. It may be advisable, on the other hand, to treat individual birds when there is a sound reason to believe that a state of ill health or a manifest unthriftiness can be attributed to a more or less severe infestation by in - testinal parasites. If such treatment is contemplated the fowls concerned should be carefully culled and placed by themselves. They may then be dosed, but should be kept isolated in order to make it possible to gather droppings and parasites eliminated after the treatment so that this material may be properly destroyed. This is best done by burning. Some of the sub - stances more or less useful for the purpose may now be men - tioned. Kamala. — Since 1923 when Hall stated that it was as yet impossible to make definite recommendations in regard to the treatment of poultry for tapeworms, the use of the drug kamala has attracted the attention of a number of investi - gators as being more or less satisfactory. With reference to the safety of the fowls treated, the evidence is somewhat con - tradictory and most authors recommend caution in its use. ivamala is an oriental vegetable dyestuff, of which the an - thelmintic action became somewhat generally recognized more than 90 years ago. It is probable that it was used for the expulsion of tapeworms long before by the natives of the far Orient. The drug consists of a brownish-red light powder, almost tasteless and odorless. Upon burning it should not yield more than six per cent of ash. A markedly higher ash content indicates adulteration, which -is reported as a some - what common practice. Aside from being active as a tape - worm expeller, kamala has a purgative action which obviates the use of purges when the drug is used in treatment. Kamala is preferably administered in capsules containing 15 grains of the powdered drug, the dose usually prescribed for adult fowls. This dose must be suitably reduced in the case of chickens in a weakened condition as well as of the younger individuals. In this connection it should be remem - bered that with the reduction of the dose, the efficiency of the treatment may also be lessened. It does not appear necessary to subject the birds to be treated to a period of preliminary fasting, and the purgative effects of the drug make it possible to dispense with a purging dose after its administration. </seg>
            <seg id="p096"/>
            <seg id="p097"/>
            <seg id="p098">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 The efficacy of kamala in the removal of tapeworms appears to be subject to a considerable degree of variation. Reports of experimental results indicate an efficiency ranging from 0 to 100 per cent removal. On the whole it is, however per - missible to expect that a large proportion of the parasites will be removed as the result of the treatment. Failure to do so may be due to the fact that some tapeworms so deeply burrow their "heads" into the intestinal mucous membrane as to escape the action of the drug. Another cause of failure may be the use of the drug in an impure or adulterated state Aside from the variations in results which follow kamula treatment, certain other disadvantages must be given con - sideration. Occasionally the drug shows a toxic effect and some of the birds treated may succumb as a result. This is particularly to be feared when the subjects treated are suffer - ing irom disease or have become decrepit because of an un - usually heavy parasitic invasion. In turkeys the toxic action of kamala is more to be feared than in chickens. Hawn reports that the drug in doses of 0.25 to 5 grains did not prove to be safe for turkeys weighing from 2 5 to 28 ounces. The element of hazard associated with the use of kamala should cause one to be cautious Hence it is recommended that before proceeding with the treatment of a considerable number of fowls it be previously tried on a relatively small number, that the results be watched, and that one be guided by the latter. The possibility ot the treatment interfering with egg production should also 5? a il en mt0 account - In this connection, Beach observed that the egg production of laying hens may be greatly re - duced for about two weeks after the treatment but that it invariably reaches a higher point in a short time. To&amp;acco^- Tobacco had already been used for the destruc - tion of external parasites before it was first applied as a possible means to remove the intestinal worms of poultry Its poisonous character had also been well known for a long time. Used as a worm expeller in poultry, tobacco may be applied in two ways, namely, as an infusion and in the form ot a dry dust. In the application of the infusion method the tollowing directions are usually observed: For the treatment of 100 fowls one pound of tobacco stems are finely chopped and then soaked in water for two hours, taking care to use just enough water to keep the chopped material covered. When sufficiently soaked in this manner, the chopped stems and the water as well are mixed with about one-half of what constitutes a daily ration for the 100 fowls. Two hours later one-fourth of the customary daily ration has added to it ten </seg>
            <seg id="p099">Poultry Diseases ounces of Epsom salts, thoroughly mixed and then fed to the fowls. This treatment should be repeated after an inter - val of one week. If preference is given to the use of tobacco dust, the latter, finely ground and containing 1.62 per cent of nicotine, is added to the mash at the rate of two per cent by weight and thoroughly mixed with it. This mixture must be fed during 3 to 4 weeks in accordance with the recommendations of Beach. The latter, however, points out certain disadvantages associated with the uncertainty of the nicotine content, as well as with the fact that especially the birds which may require the treatment the most are apt not to eat enough of the mash to accomplish the intended purpose. Although a certain number of intestinal worms may be re - moved, the results of tobacco treatment are not so satisfac - tory as to inspire confidence. One investigator furthermore indicated that after the use of the tobacco infusion, fowls were occasionally poisoned by it. In spite of the toxic pro - perties of tobacco, the interest in the latter continued and experiments were made with nicotine, a substance found in tobacco and responsible for its poisonous character. It was apparently hoped that a more stable and precise dose could thus be determined. There seems to have been some difficulty in the determination of a dose sufficient to remove parasites without, at the same time, injuring the fowl host. However, eventually it was found that when the nicotine was mixed with a special type of fuller's earth, known as Lloyd's alca - loidal reagent, the danger to the birds could be largely averted without reducing the effects on the worms. Beach, who occupied himself with this problem, recom - mends the following formula : of a 40 per cent solution of nico - tine sulphate (procurable under the name of "Blackleaf 40") take 6.6 cc. and mix it thoroughly with 16 grams of Lloyd's alcaloidal reagent. After a thorough mixing, the powder is packed in No. 2 gelatine capsules in such manner that each filled capsule will weigh from 350 to 400 mg. The treatment must not be administered to fowls with an empty crop. Used in this form (one capsule per adult bird) the nicotine seems to be fairly effective against the large roundworms of the small intestines, but it failed to remove the small worms of the ceca. Bleecker and Smith, who tried nicotine in combination with kamala, stated that "Blackleaf 40" in doses of 0.1 - 0.3 grain plus 15 grains of kamala can be safely and effectively used for the removal of intestinal parasites in poultry. It should be </seg>
            <seg id="p100">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 observed, however, that further evidence should be awaited FZ™i*tt C * T ' SUleS - etC - ShOllld P™*^ beTnt/uat^ to O« o/ chenopodium.— This substance has, for a number n f lAscaridia) of the small intestine, removing 9 out of iq worms. It removed only 2 out of 349 cecum worms but was entirely inefficacious against other nematodes and Sade a poo? showing against the tapeworms. It thus appears^hat the oil administered by the mouth had but doubtful value Better results were obtained by the rectal administration 6 , 06^ ) VOrms by Hal1 andShill n g e °" aDnroxim^tpl v on b i and Ol1 in ten birds ' an efficiency of approximately 90 per cent was obtained cin^fT/aU Wn7, T nf rp n nti^ ■" a , time - ho "ored, popular medi - cine ior all kinds of ills and is yet often used for the exDulsinn of intestinal parasites of man Ind animals Its value as such sSs33S3SSfeS3 aI S </seg>
            <seg id="p101">Poultry Diseases If, however, its value is challenged by actual, carefully con - trolled experiments, turpentine makes but a poor showing and appears to have a very limited efficiency as a remover of poul - try worms. It is generally recommended in 2 cc. doses mixed with an equal quantity of some bland oil. In the tests made by Hall and Foster, the treatment was only so far efficacious that it removed somewhat more than three-fourths of the large roundworms of the fowls treated. It had but little effect on the small worms found in the ceca and practically failed in the case of tapeworms. Of the latter it removed only 8 of the 444 worms. Hall and Shillinger tested its efficacy in the removal of the worms of the ceca by rectal injections and found that in doses of 1/5 cc. of turpentine mixed with 1 cc. of bland oil only 5 per cent of the worms were removed. Carbon tetrachloride and tetrachlorethylene. — These chem - icals have, within recent years, attracted attention as being rather efficient in the removal of certain intestinal parasites of poultry. It appears that both the common fowl and the turkey have a very high tolerance of carbon tetrachloride and that if the prescribed doses are adhered to in the treatment there is but little danger associated with it. Both the carbon tetrachloride and the closely allied tetrachlorethylene have been recommended by a number of authors as very useful for the removal of the large roundworms of the small intestines. According to Graybill and Beach, carbon tetrachloride given by the mouth is nearly 100 per cent effective against these parasites, but against the cecum worms this mode of treat - ment is unsatisfactory. They recommend its administration in I cc. gelatin capsules and state that the dose for adult fowls should be 3 cc. Other writers have suggested that three capsules, each containing 1 cc. of the liquid, be given with an interval of one hour fol - lowing the administration of each capsule, and this procedure may have some advantages. If the substances mentioned are to be used against the small worms of the ceca they should be administered by rectal in - jections. Beach suggests for rectal use injections of from 1 to 2 cc. of the carbon tetrachloride in from 5 to 10 cc. of mineral or cottonseed oil, depending on the size of the bird. A German author recommends as much as from 5 to 10 cc. of the drug in oil and states that from 15 to 20 cc. of the mix - ture will fill both ceca. As a word of caution, he adds that doses of 15 cc. of the carbon tetrachloride are apt to produce toxic effects. Hall and Schillinger observed an efficiency of 66.6 per cent after rectal injections with from 2 to 10 cc. of </seg>
            <seg id="p102">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 this chemical for the removal of the cecal worms from six IOWlS. The doses mentioned apply to adult birds; hence when younger fowls are to be treated they should be appropriately reduced The action and effects of the carbon tetrachloride and the tetrachlorethylene are quite similar. The latter is more costly and may not be so readily procured. ECTOPARASITES ' The ectoparasites, or external parasites, include lice, mites and ticks, in addition to certain pests, such as flies, gnats mosquitoes, bedbugs, and many others. Lice. — Domesticated birds are always more or less apt to become infested by lice and when the latter are present in conspicuous numbers, they may materially interfere with a fowl s health and well-being. These parasites bring about a constant irritation by their movements as well as by their gnawing habits. This causes the birds to become restless which in turn disturbs their feeding habits and digestive func - tions. Thus a degree of malnutrition may come about which lowers resistance to intercurrent causes of disease. Lousiness retards growth and in the most severe infestations may con - stitute a cause of death. In the face of manifest lousiness normal production of the flock cannot be maintained and profits may disappear on this account. Some of the many species of lice which inhabit birds are restricted to only one host species even if they may occasion - ally be encountered on some other one. However such para sites will not persist on the foreign host for a prolonged period or propagate themselves on its body. Certain lice attack only certain restricted areas of the body surface and are not apt to be found in other localities. Some ol the lice are sluggish, almost stationary, whereas others are very lively and move about over the entire body surface in general, lice spend their entire life on one host. There the eggs are extruded by the female and by means of a sticky secretion attached to the down feathers. There they can be readily recognized as "nits", as they are commonly called 1 he young lice are hatched in from 4 to 10 days and after several moultings they reach the adult state in from 17 to 20 days. All the true bird lice have biting mouth parts and sub - sist on fragments of feathers, scales of the skin, and other debris. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">Poultry Diseases Although more than forty species of lice of the domesti - cated birds have been described, only a relatively small num - ber have been observed in Nebraska. Among the latter only three species have assumed an economic importance. The one most frequently encountered is the body louse (Menopon straminewm). It is the largest one of the three and is to be found on the skin, rather than among the feathers. Its favor - ite sites are on the breast, on the thighs, under the wings and below the vent. This louse is capable of rapid reproduc - tion, which may account for a profuse infestation with the accompanying irritation and annoyance to the invaded fowls Aside from chickens this louse may also be found on turkeys guineas, peafowls, and pigeons. ' The so-called shaft louse (Meno - pon gallinae) is closely allied to the „ , preceding species. Somewhat «&gt;J$mt£ smaller than the body louse and less common, it is to be found along the — -^T^rST 4*^ - shafts of the feathers of adult birds. Hence its presence is less irritating \^&lt;ss/^ \v^% - to its host. Tos^^JZ^h^+hVw^^^ The third among the more com- * J^^vr^v^^ mon louse species of Nebraska poul- O^';fflal\ try is the chicken head louse Ji : ffi; ! tiN\\\N \&amp; (Lipeurus heterographus) which, /T»ft/&gt;MMM^ *** as its popular name indicates, is mn\Xl\\"n - most frequently found to invade the Jfri'lli'il 'iml.^ regions of the head and neck. This '^Vi'lWilJ louse may be particularly trouble- 4 \/4rvmii!r some in young chicks, and poultry- men should be prompt in the appli- *m&amp;r cation of treatment when this louse is found to be present. Apparently Fl ?' 25 -~ff JP c JSf i S. ken h ? dy this louse has also been encountered louse - (After Osborne - ) as a parasite of ducks. Of the other species of poultry lice observed in the state, mention may be made of Esthiopterum columbae of pigeons, Goniodes falcicornis and Menopon phaestomum of peafowls, Ornithobius cygni of swans, Goniodes stylifer of turkeys, and Philopterus dentatus of ducks. Control and treatment. — Various delousing agents are in use against poultry lice and the following have found favor in poultry practice. One may choose from among them. Sodium fluoride. — This drug is available in a powdered form and may be purchased at local drug stores. One pound </seg>
            <seg id="p104">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 of the powder will treat from 100 to 300 fowls, according to their size and the method of application. The drug may be applied in three ways: (1) by the pinch method, (2) by dust - ing, and (3) by dipping. The first method consists in placing on the skin of each fowl a pinch (as much as can be held between the thumb and index finger) of the powdered sodium fluoride, one on the head, one on the neck, two on the back, one under each wing, one on the breast, one below the vent, one on each shank and one at the base of the tail. Each pinch can be distributed somewhat by pushing the thumb and fingers among the feathers as the material is released. The bird, when treated, should be held over a flat pan or newspaper in order to collect and save the excess of the drug placed on the bird. The dusting method consists of mixing one part of the powdered drug with four parts of flour, talc, or road dust and applying it by means of a shaker to the bird, ruffling its feathers as the mixture is being applied. This method is not as economical or efficient as the pinch method, and the excess of powder in the air may be irritating to both the birds and the operators. Dipping in sodium fluoride solution is probably the most economical and efficient method of the three, as it requires less material and less time, while it causes no discomfort to the operators. The dipping solution, furthermore, destroys the lice with considerable promptness. The solution may be mixed in a washtub by adding three-fourths of an ounce of the sodium fluoride to each gallon of tepid water. In dipping the fowls, the wings should be held over the back with the left hand. The birds are then placed, feet first, in the dip and submerged until only the head remains out of the solution. The feathers are thoroughly ruffled with the right hand so as to allow the solution to reach the skin. The head is ducked once or twice for only an instant. The bird is then lifted out of the bath and allowed to drain for a few seconds before being released. The dipping is preferably done early on a bright, still day, so that the fowls will be thoroughly dry be - fore going to roost. Kerosene emulsion. — After the fowls have been treated for lice they should not be permitted to occupy their usual quar - ters before the latter have been thoroughly deloused. All litter should be disposed of by burning or by hauling it to fields to which poultry has no access. After the quarters have been well cleaned they should be sprayed or otherwise treated with kerosene emulsion. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">Poultry Diseases This preparation can be cheaply prepared and is one of the most efficient delousers known. It is made by dissolving about one-quarter pound of common laundry soap in one gallon of soft water (rain water) by boiling. When the soap has all dissolved and while the solution is still hot, two gallons of kerosene are poured into it and the mixture vigorously stirred. Of the resulting creamy emulsion, one part is added to eight or ten parts of warm, soft water and this mixture is then applied by means of a spray or a stiff brush. Mercurial or blue ointment. — When this substance is used a small lump of it, pea size, is rubbed on the skin just below the vent. It kills the lice when they go to the vent for mois - ture. Two treatments a year will very effectively control body lice. Two men with a simple catching coop can catch and grease 100 fowls in 45 minutes. About one pound of blue oint - ment will treat 300 fowls. It should be remembered that blue ointment is very poisonous and consequently should be handled with caution. Nicotine sulpltate. — In the nicotine-sulphate fumigation method of delousing poultry, which has come into use since 1928, the roost poles and perches in the poultry house are first cleaned by scraping them and then the tops (or tops and sides) are treated with a 40 per cent nicotine-sulphate con - centrate (procurable under the name of "Blackleaf 40") at the rate of one-half pint of the liquid to each 100 lineal feet. It is applied to the roosts with a small paint brush in a strip about li/o inches wide, or may be applied in drops along the center of the top of the roost from an oil can, shortly before the fowls go to roost. If necessary the treatment is repeated in a week or ten days. The nicotine evaporating from the treated surfaces poisons the lice and causes them to drop to the floor where they eventually die. Nicotine is one of the most potent poisons and should be handled with caution. It should not be applied in a closed space and ventilation must always be provided when the chick - ens go to roost. These precautions tend to promote the safety of both operators and birds. Flies. — The common house fly (Musca domestica) and the stable fly (Stomoxys calcitrans) are of economic importance to poultry growers in as much as they serve as the intermedi - ate hosts for certain species of tapeworms parasitic in poul - try. Therefore it is advisable that precautions be taken in order to prevent the maintenance of breeding places for flies in the vicinity of poultry yards. </seg>
            <seg id="p106">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 All stable manure and garbage must be promptly removed because this type of material is necessary for the completion of the life cycle of the house fly. Piles of damp, fermenting weed or lawn cuttings are very favorable breeding places for the common stable fly and should not be allowed to remain. Gnats.— The gnat Simulium meridionale, or turkey gnat has been found to occur in Nebraska. This species attacks chickens and turkeys, biting combs and wattles. It has been reported to be a cause of disease. Skidmore investigated a Nebraska outbreak of a fatal disease among turkeys, caused by a microscopic blood parasite (Leucocytozoon). He could demonstrate that in the transmission of the disease a part was played by Simulium occidental, a species closely allied to the one mentioned above. Mosquitoes. — These insects occasionally prove an annoy - ing pest for poultry, when the latter are maintained near such breeding places as swampy land or stagnant bodies of water. For many years it has been suspected that they may be held accountable for the transmission of fowl pox. With - in the last few years experimental evidence has been pre - sented that this may indeed be the case. Kligler, Muckenfuss, and Rivers as well as Stuppy, experimenting with various species of these insects, found them capable of transmitting pox from diseased to healthy fowls. It was also shown that an mosquito may carry the pox virus for periods of from 8 to 39 days. Bedbugs. — Bedbugs occasionally attack fowls at night for the purpose of sucking the blood. The principal ones occurring in Nebraska are the common bedbug (Cimex lectu- ULrius) and the related cone-nosed, sucking bug, or big bed - bug. Other species of bedbugs may also be found occasionally attacking poultry. These pests hide in cracks and sheltered places about the poultry house during the day time They may be controlled by following the methods recommended for the eradication of mites. Mites.— There occur in Nebraska at least five species of mites which are known to infest poultry and it is not im - probable that some other species may occasionally be found. Red mites. — The common red mite (Dermanyssus gal - hnae) is the most injurious among the ones which infest poul - try. They are present in many poultry houses in which cleanliness is at all neglected. When present in large num - bers they may prove to be exceedingly troublesome. Indi - vidual mites are scarcely visible to the naked eye but by their </seg>
            <seg id="p107">Poultry Diseases habit of collecting in masses they are easily detected, espe - cially when they are gorged with blood as this gives them a red color. When not filled with blood they have a gray color. These mites visit the fowls only during the night and for the purpose of feeding. . After this has been ac- I, complished they hide f\ /r^ themselves on or under lu \ ( \ t /f the roosts, in cracks and •s^ &amp;.J .jl&lt;- &lt;*f^ crevices, under the "^5^&gt; v ;»-^*^&lt; &amp; ,r. droppings and other 1$^ J$-' filth, and in the nesting _ r^~r^~jVW *$sS y '£*^' material, especially if the latter consists of ;'fc^c-^^c - dirty straw. Occasionally nC^Sfc hens on the nests will be $■ a^^ '' v\j§ r attacked by red mites 1'^^ *&amp;%^!§'l\ during the daytime. $Mi&amp;i&amp;' ' y/JpA After gorging them- selves with blood they leave the fowl concerned. Mites which fail to fill FlG - 26.— Red mite. (After Hutyra and themselves with blood Marek.) during the night will remain on the fowl during the follow - ing day and may therefore be found on the bird during the daytime. The female red mite deposits large numbers of eggs in its daytime retreat. At summer temperatures the eggs hatch in about 48 hours. The resulting larva, slow in its movements, does not feed at all, but after a molt and changing to the nymphal stage it begins its feeding habits, although under unfavorable circumstances it may survive for months without food. When the temperature is favorable the entire life cycle may be passed in a minimum of eight days, but usually this requires from nine to eleven days. In spite of their resistance to starvation it seems possible that in a noninhabited poultry house the red mites will have perished in about four months in summer or in about five months during winter season. Damp, dark, and filthy poultry houses are very favorable to the propagation of red mites, and, conversely, well-ventilated and sunny quarters tend to check their increase. Infested fowls not only suffer from the extreme irrita - tion and annoyance incidental to the presence of the red mites, but in addition are damaged by the extraction of blood. Pro - longed infestation will bring about a progressive emaciation </seg>
            <seg id="p108">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 and weakness, which may terminate fatally. Especially young chicks may become infested with deadly results Ex - cessive mite infestation has been held responsible for in - creased maintenance costs as well as for decided decreases in production. The annoyance caused by the mites may cause setting hens to leave the nests. Treatment and control. — The first essentials in mite con - trol are cleanliness and an abundance of sunlight which are factors antagonistic to these parasites. For the eradica - tion of the pests it is necessary to subject the poultry houses to a thorough cleaning. All litter, such as loose boards boxes, droppings, and nesting material, should be removed and destroyed by burning. After this has been accomplished the house should be thoroughly sprayed with kerosene emul - sion and in this connection particular care should be taken to force the fluid well into cracks and crevices Since this treatment may not destroy the mite eggs and since perhaps some of the mites may have escaped contact with the fluid, it is advisable to repeat this treatment in about one week Instead of kerosene emulsion, used crank case oil to which from 10 to 15 per cent of kerosene has been added, may also be expected to yield good results. _ The harvest mite or chigger.— This small, brick-red mite (Trombidudae Fam.) is parasitic only in its larval stage It is scarcely visible to the naked eye and occurs abundantly in Nebraska. The larvae are hatched upon currant and berry bushes as well as on tall weeds, grasses, grains, etc The chigger attacks a wide variety of hosts, including poul - try. It even may cause a certain '" a " 51 %'?&amp; 5^ j^*^ mortality among late-hatched chicks which may frequent its breeding places. The young lar- jrZ]r? 7^"3&amp;sT\ vae attach themselves in groups f J^^0iM^^r\.\ to the skin under the wing and if IlfeSpilf 1 about the breast and neck. They { / give rise to irritation which \ *--— # sometimes may result in suppura- \ / tion. It has been stated that this irritation occasionally leads to Fig. 27.— Chigger (After symptoms resembling epilepsy Megnin.) which within a few days may be followed by death </seg>
            <seg id="p109">Poultry Diseases means of keeping the mites away, while sulphur ointment, kerosene emulsion, or a mixture of kerosene and lard (1-10) can be used in the treatment of the birds already infested. The scaly leg mite.— This mite (Cnemidocoptes mutans) is microscopic in size and is a very common parasite of poul - try. It infests the nonfeathered portion of the legs and gives rise to an abnormal condition of the skin which is most com - monly designated as "scaly leg" or leg mange. This skin dis - ease occurs in the common fowl, the guinea, the turkey, and the pigeon. It has also been described in pheasants, par - tridges, and other wild birds when they are kept in a semi - domesticated manner. The presence of the mites under the horny coverings of the leg brings about changes which can be readily recognized by the enlarged, roughened appearance of the legs and feet. The mites live under the epidermic scales which cover the front 3urface of the leg and the upper surfaces Df the toes. Their presence causes an Ji&amp;0^&amp;l%£ jy irritation which in time becomes re- BjP)-"" **!&amp; sponsible for the raising of the epidermic MM ' &lt;3* plates and for the formation of a white, if— --=---.-"- - - Vl powdery material which is kept glued »;-J?:\^l^S^# - together by the serum which exudes from xSJjp J)'-. the deeper layers of the skin. The rough -&lt;^y crusts which generally form have a gray- ish color on the outside, whereas on their ■ ) inner surface the color is white. They I / are irregular in shape, are very ad- \ herent, and if they are removed an irri - tated bleeding skin is exposed to view. Fig. 28.— Scaly-leg A. microscopic examination of the crusts mi *e. (After Hutyra reveals the presence of the mites. and Mar ek.) The course of the disease is always slow, persisting for months or for more than a year. In some cases the legs become markedly deformed and are often enlarged to two or three times their normal size. In the more advanced cases the birds may become lame, the joints may become involved or some of the toes may become gangrenous and drop off. In such cases there is loss of appetite, emaciation, and stupor, which may lead to a fatal termination. Control and treatment— As the mites are transmitted from bird to bird, it seems obvious that the infested fowls should be isolated from the flock and that in cases of extreme infesta - tion the fowls be killed and destroyed by burning Birds </seg>
            <seg id="p110">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 which are slightly or moderately affected may be treated with a fair prospect of success. As the parasites may attach themselves to the perches and other parts of the poultry houses, it is advisable that the latter should be subjected to a treatment similar to the one recom - mended against the red mites. After the thorough cleaning of the house, it should be sprayed with kerosene emulsion which, for this purpose, should be diluted with five parts of warm, soft water instead of eight or ten parts. For the treat - ment of affected /fiHi" fowls, the scales / JHrei^ and crusts of ,. feft*^^ for the required |%^.:r.'^8j|fc. v; --~' : ■ -'■ length of time the scabs may be removed by washing the * , FlG - 29 -— Scaly leg. legs with warm water or by the use of the fingers or a brush. In all these manipulations the underlying skin must be gently dealt with. After the scabs are removed, the parts can be washed with some mild antiseptic solution and be permitted to dry thoroughly. </seg>
            <seg id="p111">Poultry Diseases The next step in the treatment is designed to destroy such mites as were not removed with the scales or scabs. For this purpose many agents can be used, but perhaps the cheapest and yet the most efficient among them is kerosene. This may be mixed with lard in the proportion of one part of kerosene to five parts of lard and the mixture can be applied to the legs and feet every other day until all evidence of the disease has disappeared. The depluming mite. — This parasite (Cnemidocoptes laevis) produces a condition known as "body mange or "de - pluming mange". This disorder usually appears during spring and summer and is characterized by the dropping off of patches of feathers from different parts of the body. This commonly begins on the rump near the insertion of the tail feathers and from this region it spreads to the back, neck, head, thighs, and breast. The large wing and tail feathers are usually not lost. This disease is marked by the production of an abundance of epidermal scales, irritation, and itching which may induce the affected fowl to pluck its feathers. A certain proportion of the cases of so-called feather pulling may be attributed to this cause, although there may be other reasons as yet un - known for this habit. The skin denuded of feathers is but little thickened and remains smooth and elastic. The infesta - tion by this mite may reduce production and affected birds may, as a result, have their health impaired. Control and treatment. — The introduction of this para - site into a flock can be prevented by taking care not to intro - duce infested fowls. The cleaning and antiparasitic treatment of the poultry houses should be resorted to whenever the dis - ease makes its appearance in the flock, using the methods recommended for the control of the red mites. The feet of cockerels should be repeatedly ti*eated because mites may be transmitted during treading. Infested birds may be treated by the use of either kerosene ointment (1-10) or kerosene emulsion. The air-sac mite. — This mite (Cytoleichus nudus) has been encountered in chickens received at this Station from widely separated localities of the state and it is quite probable that this parasite is more generally distributed than is com - monly suspected. As the name indicates, this mite is an in - habitant of the air sacs and other cavities of the domestic birds and particularly of the common fowl, the turkey, and the pigeon. It probably enters the air sacs by passing into the nostrils and from there on through the respiratory pass - ages. The mites have been observed in all the structures </seg>
            <seg id="p112">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 290 mentioned as well as in the hollow of the bones which in birds, communicates with the respiratory organs. Aberrant mites have been also encountered in the internal organs This parasite is capable of living for only a short time out - side the body of the host. When the mites are present in small numbers only, they do not cause any serious incon - venience to the affected fowl and even birds in apparently perfect health may be heavily infested. It is probable that this mite is not of considerable economic importance. Yet when the infestation is a massive one, the large number of parasites may be expected to give rise to inflammatory re - actions of the air passages and to mechanical obstructions of the same. Treatment and control. — No adequate treatment of the affected fowls has as yet i/LJM been discovered and all that can be ad- fs»g£jiq vised at this time are preventive meas- T?VHr3rf ures associated with the maintenance of ft^TT^M sanitary surroundings. t^~ m The flesh mite. — When dressing poul- fe*T~^ \ try for table use, one's attention is often JsT , f rSJL attracted to small, white lumps of tissue fW. ' ' m\ occurring immediately under the skin. These lumps are caused by a small mite /£* 1m (Laminosioptes cysticola). This mite is •* \&amp;;Ji&amp;J§ l probably the smallest one to be found in 5^ our domestic fowls. It occurs in the I loose, subcutaneous connective tissue, / 1 especially in the regions of the neck, / breast, sides, and thighs. It is widely dis- / / tributed among Nebraska fowls. The life / / history of this parasite is unknown. In / some manner it finds its way into the \ tissues mentioned and there gives rise to Fig. 30. — Flesh a reaction responsible for the formation mi . te - (After of yellowish-white, oval nodules. The ' M6 en in -) latter are about the size of a pinhead, soft, granular or even chalky, and in these the parasite may still be found. This parasite is apparently harmless and is mentioned only because occasionally it is the subject of inquiry. [IBM! </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>