<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00023.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00023.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THIRTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth, BEATRICE, NEBRASKA, To the Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings.  For the Period Ending November 30, 1910.</title>
               <date value="1910">1910</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
         
            <seg id="p001">THIRTEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Institution for Feeble Minded Youth BEATRICE, NEBRASKA fthe Governor and Board of Public Lands and Buildings. For the Period Ending November 30, 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">HON Hon Hon Hon . ASHTON C. SHALLENBERGER Governor For term ending January 1, 1911. BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS For term ending January 1, 1911. E. B. Cowles. Commissioner of Public Lands and Build ...President ings Geo. C. Junkin, Secretary of Statt Secretary Lawson G. Brian State Treasurer Arthur Mullen Attorney General </seg>
            <seg id="p004">■■i '- r I I I! i: — I K. C 4 M'M mxm 2 — </seg>
            <seg id="p005">INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOl'TH 185 &lt; RESIDENT OFFICERS I.. Roe. .M.I) Superintendent fin ending January 1. lull SCHOOL DEPARTMENT Miss If. Alice Davis Miss Crescent Smith Miss Josephine Brandon Miss Ethel Richardson Mrs. Bertha Gard W. C. Alvord Supervisor Hoys' Depart Supervisor (Jirls' Depart Supervisor Boys' Department Hot Supervisor (iirls" Department Hospital Ers. Nellie Alvord rs. If. Dillon In charge of Sewing I. In charge of Laundry L. R. fiard Max Storken In charge of Ba In charge of Farm Department Robert Carnriehai otto D. Langley- Chief Engineer Carpenter and Brush Department Louis Werner, Steward, in ending January 1. 11U1 T. E. Stewart, Bookkeeper. Term ending January 1. 1911. Ethel Beatrice Woorter, Principal. Jack (Vl)onnt'll. Baixl Instructor. Otto D. Langley I). B. Oillispie In chai </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH 187 REPORT To Ashton C. Shallenberger. Governor of the State of Nebraska, and the Board of Pnhlic Lands and Buildings. Pentlemen : — As provided by l;iw and required by your 1. I submit the following report of the condition of the af - of this Institution for the term ending November 30, 1910: December 1, 1908 to June 1, 1909. No. enrolled 431 idmitted and re-admitted 6 No. returned from parole 2 «. No. discharged. 3 No. released on parole. 15 No. died 7 25 No. remaining at end of period «4 Per capita t mi $65.63 June 1, 1909 to December 1, 1909. No. enrolled at beginning of period 414 No. admitted and re-admitted 7 No. returned from parole 6 «7 No. discharged 7 No. released on parole No. died 5 » No. remaining at end of peri&gt;&gt;l «5 </seg>
            <seg id="p008"/>
            <seg id="p009">189 » December 1, 1908 (the beginning of the biennial the total number of inmates enrolled was 431 ; at the close of period, to - wit: December 1. 1910. the total number is 421. This shows a decrease of 10. which decrease corresponds with the capacity of the Institution. December 1, 1908. there were forty-five &gt; 4."&gt; application idmission on file At the term ending December 1. 1910, there ire 98. At the present time there is in course of construction trong substantial buildings, or cottages to be used for the b fit and protection of the inmates: the same having been pro\ for at the session of the last legislature for which, appropriation duly made by that body. The above buildings will be ample for living purposes and when completed will certainly be dit to the state, which will more fully appear on the follow- December 1, 1909 to June 1, 1910. Co. enrolled at beginning of period Co. admitted and re-admitted 415 8 Co. returned from parole u Co. discharged 1 so. released on parole Jo. died 19 No. remaining at end of period 4,, Per capita *70.86 June 1, 1910, to December 1, 1910. Jo. enrolled at beginning of period Jo. admitted and re-admitted 415 24 Co. returned from parole Co. discharged 10 io. released on parole Co. died - No. remaining at end of period «, Per capita cost 157.5] </seg>
            <seg id="p010">u I. tl J &lt; A k • • • J H i I .1 i </seg>
            <seg id="p011">191 Health and Mortality. The number of deaths during this period was 39, of whi« Of this number 35 were custodial cases and all being of ex - ceeding low vitality. While there has been sickness among the inmates with which to contend, to our great satisfaction no serious epidemics have oc - curred. This is no doubt the result of careful attention to the Cd and clothing furnished, and the sanitary conditions of the titution which are first class. Stock at the Farm. There is at present as follows: Seven (7) old horses; two good horses; thirty-five (35) cows; one (1) bull; fifteen hogs; 100 shoats. Had the stock inspected, first by a government v. nary, and later by a veterinary from the state department, and at the present time no disease exists among the stock. School Department. During the past two years there has been an average in the school department of 275, between the ages of 5 and eighteen years, that being the age of admission. Our mode of teaching is kindergarten, music, grade work, band practice, sloyed and drill. We also make bed springs, mat - tresses and brushes. were males and 15 females, and cause of d leat i as foil Hows : Epilepsy Tuberculosis Valvular disease of the heart Pneumonia Hereditary Syphilis Dropsy Gastritis General Debility Typhoid Fever Chronic Dysentery ' Tonsilitis Inflammation of bowels Total </seg>
            <seg id="p012">u I tl S. ML . i »*' nl -•: pw IH f </seg>
            <seg id="p013">INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH 193 Religious Exercises. We have Sunday School and preaching every Sunday aft.-r - noon, which services are purely non-sectarian. Farm and Garden. The farm consists of two hundred twenty-two 222 acres of land, all of which is under cultivation except that occupied by the building! and twenty-five (25) acres of pasture. The crops on the above lands are far above the average in the county. The following produce was raised on the farm during the two years: Total 190' 1910 Pe 10 bushels Peas, 10 bushels Radishes 100 bushels Radishes, 100 bushels.. 2."&gt; bushels Cucumbers, 10 bushels 3000 heads Cabbage, 5,000 bushels ."&gt;0 bushels Rhubarb, 10 bushels... umber Spinach SO bushels Spinach, 70 bushel Green Onions 200 bushels Green Onions, .iOO bushels. Summer Squash 2.1 dozens Summer Squash, 25 dozen Fodder II tons [Fodder, 20 tons Straw 20 tons Straw, 20 tons to Apples SO bushels Apples, .10 bushels I Of) Peaches 7.1 bushelsiPeache Milk 10OO gallonslMilk, 18,000 gallons 23000 Cabbage 3000 heads Cabbage, 5,000 bus Rhubarb SO bushels Rhubarb, 10 bushe Lettuce 60 bushels Lettuce. 7.". bushel bushels Cherries, 10 bushe Oats 7110 bushels Oats, 935 bushels Wheat . 500 bushels Wheat, ... 500 Corn 1000 bushelslCorn, MM)0 bushels 3000 Alfalfa .. 50 tons xMfalfa, 50 tons *. ■-'.-i tons |Hay. •_&gt; tons. Potatoes &gt;;:.m bushels Potatoes, 600 bushels. Sweet Potatoes.. 250 bushelsiSweet Potatoes, 150 bushels. Sweet Corn 400 bushels Sweet Corn, 400 bushe! 800 Tomatoes .. 400 bushels Tomatoes, 400 bushels 800 Onions 50 bushels Onions, 150 bushels Parsnips .. 100 bushels Parsnips. 150 bushels Turnips Moo bushels Turnips, 200 bushel- 4., Carrots 75 bushels Carrots, 75 bushe! - 1.50 Beets .. 200 bushels Beets, 100 bushels 300 String Beans 60 bushelslString Beans, 100 bushels 160 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">t fa tt </seg>
            <seg id="p015">195 Play Grounds in Amusements. fThe play grounds are in excellent condition and afford for e inmates plenty of recreation in various ways. The lawns upon which they enjoy themselves are grassy and clean and adorned by excellent shade trees. Amusements consist of basket ball, football, baseball, etc. As often as twice per week ib, are given, and in addition, various games. Once per month social gatherings occur, and the programs for these are practically the same as at other public institutions. Improvements. The following improvements have been made. Raised the diary barn six feet, put in new floors, also new siding, and paint - k where the same was necessary. Minor improvements and airs made promptly when needed. Have made new entrance to cave and built new granary, re - arranged the horse barn, and laid 500 feet of cement walks ; made new driveways, also new foundation for scales. Planted 300 shade trees 68 of which are on the road leading to the cemetery. I lu addition to the equipment on hand in the tire depan i have added 200 feet of the best hose. This department is in st elass condition. I The wiring in several of the buildings is in a dangerous con - tion and should be attended to at once for the •afety of the buildings. From the past experience for the best interest of the Institu- don ami on account of the increase of inmates for the two cottages, this being an increase of 30 per cent, I recommend the following appropriations : Maintenance 10 00 Employes' wages 40,000 00 Superintendent's salary 5,000 00 Steward's salary . 2,400 00 Teachers' salary , &gt;ihJ 00 Chaplain's salaiy 200 00 General repairs 10 00 Bookkeeper and stenographer </seg>
            <seg id="p016">196 LAND COMMISSIONERS Kl 2.:,&lt;" Boiler house repairs bool building furnished complete Green house 60,000 nil 5,000 00 Horses, harness, vehicles and eowa Addition to Low Grade cottage for dining room 4.1 in. Total &amp;255,400 mi In conclusion. I thank you and each of you for your uniform courtesy and kindness shown me during the past two year*. G. L. ROE, M. I).. Superintendent Respectfully </seg>
            <seg id="p017">INSIIXlTfci 1* OK I* K K H I.*K M I N I ) K I ' Ol'TH APPENDIX i Population of [nstitutiion by eountit </seg>
            <seg id="p018"/>
            <seg id="p019">INSTITUTE FOR FEEBLE MINDED YOUTH 199 APPENDIX Population of Institution by Couni included Male Female Jefferson Kearney 1 3 4 1 Keit Kno: 2 3 6 1 12 22 34 Ma t 1 1 a Mucl 3 B Otoe Pawn 4 &gt;.) Phelps Pierce Elatte oik t Perkins Red Wil Richards 3 O 1 5&gt; i 4 6 &lt;w 1 1 2 : 3 2 t 4 1 1 5 W Eayn ebsi 1 T </seg>
            <seg id="p020">200 Our own grown fruit and vegetables preserved for winter 600 gallons 200 gftllona .100 gallons 40 gallons 850 gallons Cash Report from Semi-Annuals. Balance cm hand December 1. 1906 ived since 14 s 4~&gt; $ 1,6! Pxpended since December 1, 1908 ce on hand .May 31, 1909 1,531 20 Received since Expended since Eance on hand December 1. 1909 eived since Expended since Balance on hand May 31, 1910 Received since Expended since Tom ( i r&lt;«n Tomatoes Cucumber Pickle* Cherries Sauerkraut </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>