<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00015">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00015</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  HOME MULCHED VS. NORTHERN SEED POTATOES FOR EASTERN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. Volume XXVII, Akticle III. rME MULCHED VS. NORTHERN SEED POTA - TOES FOR EASTERN NEBRASKA. By R. A. Emerson. Distkihuted December 24, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. &lt;TME REGENTS Of THE UWVIBUTt) K ORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. ORABLE GEORGE COl'PLAND, Elgin. ORABLE PHILIP L. HALL. Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Acting President, Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICERS. tUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex offlcio. . Bl'RNETT. B. Sc., Direetoi •; Animal II usliantlrv. . PIGSLEY, B. S&lt;., Director of Extension Service. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Set -return. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. IIkaii Wir.cox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. '. I rso\. Pit. D., Agrii ult ural chemistry. '. Chask, M. E., A. E.. Ainii iiltiiral Engineering. K. Bliss, B. S. A., Animal H nsbunilry. KG.MN, M. D. C, Animal Patholn&lt;i\i. Fkandskn, M. S. A., Dnirti Husbandry. kknce Bimnki!. B. Be, Entomology. . KOMUUCB, A. M.. Experimental Agronomy. . nut, A. M., Farm Management. K\. HnBU, M. Fok.. Forestry. A. Emeksox, D. St 1 ., Horticulture. f. How Alii), A. M.. Horticulture. i. Loxki ami, A. M., Meteorology. W. P. Snyiikk, M. S.. Superintetulint of Experimental Substation. North Plat to. C. B. I.kk, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry. tVAKU .1. Grammch, B. S( ., Associate in Animal Husliandry. H. Swknk. A. M., Ass&lt;i&lt;iatc in Entomology. tm K. K. Link, A. M., Assistant in Agricultural Botany. . Cai.vin, B. St., Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. . Bakkkii, A.. V!.. Assistant i?i Anronomi/ 'Soilm m Hoit, B. Sc, Assistant in Agronomy i( 1 rt&gt;ps). . Ratplifk, B. Si., Assistant in Experimental Aaronomy. . STfUDEVANT, A. M., M. D., Assistant in Animal Pathology. . Woodward, A. M, Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. . Coopeh, B. S&lt;\, Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm, B. S&lt; ., Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. James Cowax. M. E., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine F«IT?! Knokr, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation. Mitchell H. L. Nye, Foreman Demonstration Fmm. Culbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Introduction 5 Stocks of potatoes used 7 Methods of (tmd lifting tests 9 Results of tests: 10115 12 190f! 12 1!MI7 13 LM8 14 190ft 15 10111 17 1911 19 1912 20 Summary Relative cost of mulched and Northern seed 25 Effect of time of mulching on value of seed tubers 29 Kinds of mulching; material 30 Other ways of producing seed tubers at home 31 How to grow mulched patateM 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">KME MULCHED VS NORTHERN SEED POTA - TOES FOR EASTERN NEBRASKA. BY R. A. EMKRSON. INTRODUCTION. Tin- experioMe of potato grower* in southeastern Nehraska. ;is veil as results of experiments reported in this bulletin, in - dicates clearly the impossibility of keeping the same stock of potatoes year after year without change of seed tubers, if the usual methods of cultivation are employed. The comparatively high altitude of the potato districts of western Nebraska (4.000 to .".000 feet i. with its accompaniment of bright, warm days and cool nights, makes the use of home grown seed much less hazardous than in the eastern part of the State and may indeed make possible the development of an important seed potato industry in those districts. Bat, whatever the possibilities may be in western Nebraska, it is out of tho question to produce indefinitely by ordinary methods even one's own seed tubers in a considerable part of the State farther to the east and south. Many potato growers nf eastern Nebraska are convinced of the truth of these state nients and each year, or at least once in every two or three years, procure a new stock of seed tubers from the North (com - monly from the Red River region of Minnesota and North Tho the Red River stock has. in general, a good reputation in eastern Nebraska, it is a fact, nevertheless, that many of the |K)tatocs produced there are from seed grown on the same farms or in the same neighborhoods. In many cases, doubtless. thiR practice is due to a lack of information as to the relative value of seed tubers from different sources, but in some in - stances it is followed because unfavorable results have been obtained with seed from outside the State. Poor results from northern seed come, undoubtedly, in many cases from dealing with untrustworthy distributing agencies. Such difficulties, tho. HIM.. 1«. AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XXVII, ART. Ill </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 are not insurmountable, and if they furnished the only incentive to the discovery of a practical means of producing at home the seed tubers now brought in from outside sources, the problem would be less important than it is. I Results of unpublished experiments in progress at the Ne - ska Experiment Station, as well as similar tests in other 2ea, indicate not only the possibility but the great desirahil - of isolating healthy, productive strains of the varieties com - lly grown. I'nless the potato should prove an exception to general rule, it is to be expected that the strains best suited ■ertain regions may not be well adapted to others. Tt is prob - p, then, that if we are to grow the l&gt;est strain of any variety, must isolate it in our own region. Obviously, however, it is not worth while to test numerous tuber strains if. on account of the unfavorable local conditions during the three or four years required for its accomplishment, even the best strains have so lost their vigor that they are lea productive than the ordinary seed as it comes from the North. Evidently, if anything is ever to be accomplished in potato breed - ing in southeastern Nebraska (or under similar conditions else - where), a means must be devised either of keeping up the vigor of the strains selected while they are undergoing the test or of restoring their vigor afterward. Selection alone li;is been in - sufficient to accomplish this, which is equivalent to saying that it has been found impossible to isolate strains perfectly suited to conditions in eastern Nebraska. A means, however, has been found of maintaining the rigor of potato stocks indefinitely in this region. By its use. potato breeding can M carried on here with the assurance that select strains can be grown here indefinitely without the necessity of abandoning them after a few years for northern stocks. One of the main reasons assigned by advocates of northern pvwa seed for the increased yields obtained by its use is that the cooler soil of the North enables the tubers to mature more perfectly than they can farther south, so that when used as seed they produce a better growth of plants and a greater yield of tubers. If it be true that a cool soil is an important considera - tion in the production of strong seed tubers, it seems reasonable thai favorable results should follow the use of a litter mulch spread over the soil about the growing plants. For many years a few farmers have used mulches of straw or other coarse ma - terial on small potato patches to take the place of summer till - age. At the time the experiments here reported were begun, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Homt Mulched v». Northern Seed Potatoes. ■ the Experiment Station had been testing the value of straw mulches in the production of various garden vegetables, includ - ing potatoes, for about five years.* STOCKS OF POTATOES USED. In 1004, tests were begu to determine the value for seed purposes of mulched home grown tubers in comparison with northern grown tubers and tubers grown at home by ordinary rultivation. In the spring of that year a stock of Early Ohio potatoes was obtained indirectly from the Red River region of Minnesota. This lot was grown at the Experiment Station with - out change for nine years — from 10(14 to 1912, inclusive. It is known thnioiit the bulletin as the '"Experiment Station" stock to distinguish it from the numerous other stocks introduced from time to time. A part of this original Experiment Station stock ■H grown continuously for the nine years by mulching, and another part was grown continuously by cultivation. In addi - tion to this continuous mulching and cultivation, each year a part of the mulched lot was also grown by cultivation, and several times a part of the cultivated lot was also grown by mulching. Thus, this stock has not only made possible eight direct comparisons of continuously mulched and continuously cultivated seed, but has also afforded numerous tests of the effect of several years of cultivation followed by one year of mulching and of several years of mulching followed by one or more years of cultivation. Three other distinct stocks of Early Ohio potatoes have been employed in the comparison of mulched and cultivated seed tubers. Two of these, the '"Lincoln" and the '"Mixed" stocks, were obtained in the spring of 1907 and one, the "Madrid" stock. in the fall of the same year. The Lincoln stock was obtained from a local fanner, who had grown it for two years previously. The Mixed stock included tubers from various sources, all thoroly mixed before being separated into two lots — one to be mulched and the other to be cultivated. These two lots were kept at the Experiment Station during 1907. 1908, and 1909, and each thus afforded two separate tests of the value of litter mulches in the production of seed tubers. The Madrid stock was furnished by E. A. Holyoke of Madrid, Perkins County. Xebr., who. in 1907. had grown a part of it under a straw mulch and a part by ordinary tillage. Only a single test was made with this • Results of these tests were reported in Buls. 80 and 97 of thU Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Uumi Middnil rx. Northern Seed Potmtoea. At different times stocks of Early Ohio potatoes from various sources were DRMgfci in for comparison with tlie home mulched and cultivated stocks noted above. In the spring of 1!HM&gt;. a stock of ""Red River" Mm was obtained thru a local dealer and gnn at the Experiment Station only that year. In the sprint: of l'.HlT. a stock of Minnesota potatoes was obtained from a dealer in the Red Hirer region of Minnesota. At the same time a stock of potatoes was obtained from South Dakota thru a local dealer. These "Minnesota" and ••South Dakota" stocks were kept at the Ex|ieriment Station only one year. The foreign stocks of liMM! and 1007 were obtained in the spring, and nothing is known of the conditions under which they were kept during winter. On this account the comparison !&gt;etween them ami the home grown taken is not so reliable as it otherwise might have been. In IMS, nine new stocks of Early Ohio potatoes weft grown. These are described below. The "GlyndoB." ••Calhan." and "Ifeiningford" stocks wire received in the spring, and. therefore, not kept over winter under exactly the same condi tions as the other stocks tested in ]!&gt;((!&gt;. All the other foreign stocks were secured in the fall and kept with the home mown stocks during winter, so that they were all in practically the same condition at planting time. The foreign stocks of I'.Mi'.t an listed below, together with brief statements as to the ronditisM under which they were "iwvn. Klyndon stock. — Received from E. C. Schroeder. (ilvndon. . Crown on rather heavy Red Hirer Valley soil. B Fargo stock. Received from Mr. Holes. Parka, X. I&gt;ak.. 1 North Dakota Experiment Station. Drown i" Red River ley for 17 years. tLangdon stock. Received thru North Dakota Experiment tion from l.angdon. N. l&gt;ak. Grown within a few miles of ladian line. E.arimore light-soil stork. — Received from J. IT. Pifer &amp; Co. A. Stonehonse, farimtWT. N. Dak. (irnwn on rather light, ■what sandy soil. Il.arimnre heavy-soil stock.— Same source as next preceding, grown on a rather heavy soil. 1 Brooking! stock. — Received from (i. N. Kennard. Brooking*. &gt;ak. &lt;",rown on niedium lisrht sandy loam without change of ■k for seven years. Kreeley stock. Received from Charles Camp. Greeley, Colo. n on heavy adahe soil at an altitude of 4.t!ll(l feet without re of stwk for six years. Irrigated. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Home Mmiekti rx. ffortktrm Seed Potatoes. 9 Calhan stuck. — Received from Russell Ciatcs Mercantile Co., ('allian. Colo, (irown by dry farming on light sanily loam at an altitude of nearly 7.&lt;I(MI feet for three years without change i if stock. Heniingford stock. Received from M. P. Bolberg, Heming - ford. lioxhuttc County. Xebr. Grown on a light sandy loam five years without change of stock. Stocks of tulters were obtained again for a test in 1911) from ({rooking*. S. Dak.; Farjro. N. Dak.: &lt;irecley. Colo.; and Cal - lian. Colo. The Urookings and Fargo stocks were, however, injured by frost in shipment, so that the yields from them can not be used in comparison with the yields of other stocks. The 1!M&gt;S Clvndon and lirookings stocks, grown at the Nebraska Kxpcriineiit Station in l!MI!l, were grown again in 191(1 In the spring of l!ll"_' a stock of "Red River" tulier* was pur chased from a local dealer and used in comparison with mulched and cultivated home grown seed. METHODS OF CONDUCTING TESTS Kxperimcnis with the use of litter mulches as a means of producing high class potato seed tubers at home have not as a rule been planned to test the direct effect of such mulches on the yield of the mulched plants themselves, but rather to test the effect of a mulch of one season on the crop of the next season. It always takes two years to make a single test. The tirst year, the tubers are grown in part by cultivation and in part under a mulch. The second year, these two lots of ned are compared, both the plats lieing cultivated exactly alike this year. Great care is always used to have all the conditions suriuunding the tests as nearly alike as possible except the one thing to be tested. When the original Experiment Station stock was obtained in the spring of 1004. the tubers were cut into seed pieces of approximately the same si/.e. thoroly mixed and all planted at a uniform distance apart on as uniform soil as could be obtained. Hefore the plants came up. part of the land thus planted was mulched with straw to a depth of al&gt;out 4 inches, and this part received no cultivation thruout the sum mer. The other part was given frequent surface tillage in the ordinary way. The crop was harvested from the two plats separately at the same time and kept over winter in a cellar under the same conditions of temperature and moisture. The next spring the two lots of seed were planted on adjoining plata of fairly uniform land. The size nf seed pieces, depth of plant </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 flOWlr .llHIf'fln/ I S. \ it} TH' t H »&gt;f fix I OTflT'/rX injr. distance between hills, and time of planting were the same for both pints, and both were given identical tillage, spraying, etc.. thriinut the summer. The only pronounced difference, in short, between the two plats lay in the seed tnbers planted on them, and the only difference in the seed was that one lot had been irrnwn under a mulch and the other by cultivation. Any difference, therefore, in the yield of the two plats must he ascribed to the methods of culture employed the previous year. All the tests of mulched seed reported here were conducted in practically the Mm way as described for the first test. To be Mm, different suits of mnlritm have been tested and the mulches have liecn applied at different times, but these incidentals will lie discussed later. Tn addition to the comparison of the mulched and cultivated seed in 100T&gt;. as outlined above, sonic &lt;&gt;f the mulched seed was also planted in a mulched plat to furnish seed for the following year. This practice was kept up from 10(11 to VM'2. so that the Kxperiment Station has had a rtork of potatoes that had been ptrowi here for nine years under a mulch and also a lot from the same original Exi&gt;eriment St;i tion stock that had been grown here continuously for nine jean by cultivation. Occasionally some of the continuously cultivated *t»ck has been mulched for a single year. During two years it has lteen possible to compare a continuously cultivated stock, a continuously mulched stock, a cultivated stock mulched one year, and a mulched stock cultivated one year. This has not only made it possible to compare the effects of long-continued mulching and long-continued cultivation with mulching and cultivation of short duration, but has also been calculated to equalize any inequality that may have come about by chance in the original separation of the Experiment Station stock into the two lots. ITn comparisons of seed potatoes from various sources it is &gt;n the practice to collect the tubers just before planting e. but experience indicates that tubers thus collected are ■ly to vary considerably in condition. Some may have been 1 kept and be perfectly sound when received, while others r be wilted or even sprouted. Such differences are likely to ng about as great divergences in yield as is the source of the ers. Tn so far as possible the stocks used in these tests were ured in the fall and kept over winter under identical eondi - is. It was impossible, however, to do this in every case. With a variety that has bee* under cultivation as long as the Early Ohio, there is considerable chance of getting from different </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 sc mi «es rtoeka that differ considerably one from another. Whether i In- Early Ohio lias beta accidently mixed with other similar varieties or whether numerous bud variations have occurred within this variety need not be argued here. Tests conducted liy the writer in 19lM», 19(17. and 1908 and separate tests made by Professor C. W. Pugsley of this institution during 1909. 1910. and 1911 and continued in 1912 by Mr. F. C. Miles, now of the U. S. I&gt;ei&gt;ai-tiuent of Agriculture, and in 1913 and 1914 by Mr. E. R. Ewing, show clearly that the Early Ohio as grown here consists of a mixture of more or less distinct types. Fam - ilies grown from single tuliers have tn-en found to be quite dis - tinct in habit of growth as well as in earliness, productiv ness, etc. Of the several stocks of Early Ohio grown during the progress of the mulching experUaeata, the only ones that were noticeably distinct were the (ireeley and Cal'han stocks from Colorado. Tho the tuliers of these were not unlike those of the other stocks, the plants were noticealily more erect in habit and somewhat later than any otter stock. Just how much the results of any test depend upon the types of stock which one happens to obtain from the different localities, and how much upon the effects of the different soils and climates in which they were grown, cannot be told without growing the stocks in one place for several years — during which time any influence of the environment in which they were previously grown would necessarily disappear and only differences characteristic of the •&lt;tocks themselves would remain. Doubtless, the way to make a scientifically accurate test of the influence of particular en - vironments on seed potatoes would be to start with a stock that had come from a single tuber only a few years previously and to have parts of the stock grown in the desired localities. Until this can be done, however, one must be content with such records as can lw obtained from the stocks as they are commonly grown in localities from which tests are to be made. Such tests, too, are perhaps fully as important from the viewpoint of practical potato growers as would be those of more scientific accuracy. provided only that the stocks obtained are representative of the potatoes generally grown in the localities from which they The arrangement of plats in tests such as those reported here is of the greatest importance, since nothing like sibsolute uniformity of soil can lie had. Since a study of the influence of mulches in seed-tuber production was the principal object of these experiments, and a comparison of stocks from diff««ent </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Ion was somewhat i midcnl al. the plantings were alwavs n»ed so that the Matched and cultivated seed of mm stock lie variously mulched seed of one stock occupied adjoining i. This necessarily separated the plats containing the dif it stocks and therefore made these tests It ss valuable than might otherwise have been. In general, the plats were narrow, consisting of only one or two rows ninnin&lt;: the 111 of the lield. Except in a few cases, wliere the quantity &gt;ed was iiisutiicicnt. the plats were alwavs duplicated, and ime casts each lot of seed was represented in three plats in rent parts of the field. RESl'LTS OF TESTS. The yields in 1906 from approximately tenth-acre plats of the original Rxperimeal Station stock were as follows: Seed mulched the previous year ~Uu\ pounds Sii-d cultivated the previous year :t84 pounds Gain from use of mulched seed 179 pounds 1'er cen1 of gain 4»i.&lt;; This is so pronounced a difference in favor of mulched It unless corroborated by fui-tlier tests it might well be lited whether the difference was really due alone to the lions treatment of the seed. The results of the second year, ever, were quite in keeping with those of the first year, s time the comparison was between seed that had been l'mwii mulching the two years preceding and seed of the same Ex - inient Station stock that had l&gt;een grown at the Station two rs by cultivation. This year a "Red Hiver" stock of potatoes warn also growm. Tin- results ff o\v: f.E l.—YitM »f potatoes / northern xecit tubers — appr 1906. from nmlihcil, evltit •o.ri motel u tirrn fifth -&lt; &lt;i t&lt;il, and won i&gt;intx. Kind of seed tubers Marketable yield Total yield Per rent marketable yield r River seed le grown seed — Mulched two years Cultivated two years 12S lbs. lt&gt;S lbs. 76,, 12o lbs. 80 lbs. 174 n» 123 lbs. S3 I Gain from mulched over culti- vated seed .-&gt;1 lbs. 4.5 lbs. Per cent of gain 50.3' i 41.5% </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Hoini Mulched ik. North? ni Seed I'otatoeti. 13 IIitc a^aiii the mulched home grown seed was much letter Hum cultivated home growl seed and practically e(|nal in pro - ductive power to a frrsh importation of northern seed. A third icsi of tins san; c slock of potatoes was made in 1007. ThN year i lie principal romjiarisofl w;is ajrain luiwcen the two lots of the Experiment Station stuck of potatoes jrrown three yean nndi r mulch and three vears liv cultivation, wpfttlftlr. Tins lots were also compared with two stocks of northern pan potatoes received that sprinj; and described earlier in this ;u cimnt under the d( situation of Minnesota and Souih Dakota slocks. The latter of these stocks was in rather poor condition when received, which may account for the poor showing made bv it. Even the better Minnesota stock, however, hardly equaled the home irrown cultivated lot of the Kxperiment Station stock which, as in the earlier tests, was much poorer Ihan the mulched lot of the same stork. The results follow: r.K 2. — Yi&lt;l&lt;lx of /uttnlixx from northern t/roini and from hoiiie ortHi'fi mulched and citltiratci] xced tnhirx in tenth &lt;icre plats. 1&lt;U&gt;7. fourth trial of the Experiment Station stock and the first trial of three other stocks described earlier in this bulletin as the Madrid, the Lincoln, and the Mixed stocks. For ease of com- I arison all yields jiiven in the following table are calculated for Kind of seed HiImts Marketable yield Total yield Per cent market able yield ■H)iith Dakota stock KxjM'riment Station stock — Mulched three years Cultivated three years •MIS lbs. 498 lbs. 6S7 lbs. 547 lbs. \s.:, 91.0 K40 lbs. 625 lbs. SUS lbs. 696 lbs. I Gain from mulched over culti- vated seed 215 lbs. 202 lbs a.7 Per cent gain 34.4' c 29.0' , Iii IM6 tin- coanpariaoa was cultivated seed tnlM'i-s of rarioiH entirely between mulched and stocks. The tests included tin </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Home Mulched vs. Nc Tahi.k 3. — Yields from mvlchea tenth-acre i Mk 190*. Treatment of seed tubers Marketable yield Total yield Per cent marketable yield Madrid stock Mulched 1907 Cultivated 1907 .502 lbs. 440 lbs. 506 Nm 534 lbs. 83.9 82.4 ■ Gain from mulched seed Per cent gain 62 lbs. 14.1', 64 lbs. 120% " Lincoln stock— Mulched 1907 Cultivated 1907 371 lbs. 297 lbs. 74 lbs. ■24.9% 464 lbs. 384 lbs. 77.4 I Gain from mulched seed Per cent (tain 80 lbs. 20.8% 26 Mix.il Mock- Mulched 1907 Cultivated 1907 358 lbs. 353 lbs. 460 lbs. 347 lbs. ... 72.6 |(iain from mulched seed Per cent gain I 106 lbs. 42.1% 113 lbs. 32.6' o „ »ment Station stock niched 1901-1907 iltivated 1907, mulched 1904-1906 iltivated 1904-1907 380 lbs. 311 lbs. 260 lbs. 400 lbs. -107 lbs. 383 lbs. a 67.9 I Gain from mulching over — Cultivation one year Cultivation four years Per cent gain from mulching 69 lbs. 120 lbs. S3 lbs. 107 lbs. ;? over — Cultivation one year Cultivation four years 4ti.2' ; 2ti..V , 28.0" , Agate, all the tests resulted tuhers. Of the three new stocks, able tubers by use of seed nmlclu seed of the same stocks cnitiva from 14 per cent for the Madri Mixed stock, the Lincoln stock with a gain of about 2." per cen Experiment Station stock, resu cent for four years of mulching three vears of mulching followed in favor of the nmi the increase in yields pd one year over the y ited the preceding ye id stock to 42 per ce holding an internied it. This, the fourth 1 ilted in an increase : and of about 22 pe hv one venr of cultivi ilched of market nelds from car ranged &gt;nt for the Hate place test of the of 4fi per ?r cent for 'ation. over </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Home Mulched vs. Northern Seed Potatoes. 15 the yields {riven l&gt;\ the lot cultivated during the entire four in 1000 three of the storks grown the preceding year, namely. Lincoln, the Mixed, and the Experiment Station stocks, n afforded tests of the relative value of mulched and cul - ted seed tubers. All plats were approximately one-tenth in area except the plats grown from mulched seed, which ained one-fifth acre. The yields given in the following table all figured to tenth acre piats: .— ] Yields from mulched nirimts stocks in tei ta and cult th-acre pi vat it*. ted seei 1909. ll if*r*£ o Treatment of seed Marketable yield Total yield Per cent marketable yield Ifriment Station stock — Mulched 1904-1908 Cultivated 1908, mulched 1904-1907 Cultivated 1904-1908 615 lbs. 510 lbs. 407 lbs. 730 lbs. 691 lbs. 558 lbs. I Gain from mulching over — Cultivation one year Cultivation five years Per cent gain from mulching over — Cultivation one year Cultivation five years 105 lbs. 208 lbs. 39 lbs. 172 lbs. . 25.8% 51.1% 7.0% 30.8% 77.7 foln stock- Mulched 1907-1908 Cultivated 1908, mulched 1907. . . . Cultivated 1907-1908 482 lbs. 449 lbs. 370 lbs. 632 lbs. 578 lbs. 512 lbs. I Gain from mulching over — Cultivation one year Cultivation two years Per cent gain from mulching over — Cultivation one year Cultivation two years 33 lbs. 112 lbs. 54 lbs. 120 lbs. "B 8.9% 30.3% 10.5% 23.4% til .stock- Mulched 1007-1908 Cultivated 1907-1908 447 lbs. 352 lbs. 543 lbs. 506 lbs. s Gain from mulching two years 95 lbs. 37 lbs. 12.7 Per cent gain 27.0% 7.3% </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 In each of the three tests, as in all the previous ones, the mulched seed gave markedly letter yields than the cultivated seed. The increase in yield of marketable taken from the use of mulched seed over the yield from the use of cultivated seed was 27 per cent in the Mixed stock and 30 per cent in the Lin - coln stock, where the mulch had been used two years, and was 51 per cent in the Experiment Station stock, where the seed for one plat had been grown under mulches for five years and that for another plat by cultivation for the same length of time. More - over, where a mulched lot had been grown by cultivation for only a single year, the deterioration was noticeable, tho by no means so great as from several years of cultivation. In addition to the tests of mulched and cultivated seed tubers, as reported above, nine stocks of potatoes were ob - tained for comparison with the home grown stocks. These in - cluded four stocks from eastern North Dakota, one from • ern Minnesota, one from eastern South Dakota, two from Colo - rado, and one from western Nebraska, as descrilted earlier in this bulletin. All lots were planted in tenth-acre plats and duplicated once, making one-fifth acre in all for each lot. The yields are reported in the following table: These yields indicate little difference between the various stocks of northern seed tubers, particularly between the various North Dakota and Minnesota stocks. The single stock from western Nebraska and the two Colorado stocks were decidedly inferior to the northern stocks. While the plats on which these 'able 5.— \r\ '.* roin teed tu ix is of pan mix aource* iw I "■ • i nor pints. 1909. Sources of seed tubers Market able yield, pounds Total yield, IMiunds Per cent marketable yield |&gt;n, N. Dak ire, N. Dak., heavy-soil ire, N. Dak., light-soil ngs, 8. Dak f, Colo., irrigated , Colo., dry farming 936 900 916 0S4 910 836 656 440 604 1,110 1,056 1.056 1,152 1,086 1,036 Mil 1172 774 84.3 85.2 98.7 85.4 83.8 80.7 78. SS. 78.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">H diiii Vuhlnil rx. Xorthmi Soil 1'otntorx 17 one with another, now of them can lie so readily compared with the home pm storks. The several plata of any one stock of home pm seed were located together to give a better com - parison of the mulched and cultivated lots of that stock. Con sequently. the different home grown stocks were at considerable distances from each other and particularly from the foreign stocks. Tt is interesting, however, to note the average yields of the mulched lots and of the cultivated lots of the three home grown stocks in comparison with the average yields of the best five northern i Minnesota and North Dakota) stocks. For this comparison the yields are figured for tenth-acre plats. Only the marketable tubers are included. Average yield from northern grown seed 464 pounds Average yield from home grown mulched seed 515 pounds Average yield from home grown cultivated seed... 376 pounds Altho no great dependence should l&gt;e placed upon this com- Eson. it indicates that home grown seed tubers when pro - ■d under a mulch are at least as good as northern grown rs, but that home grown seed produced by ordinary i-ulti ratios is not the eqval of northern seed. Tn l!)lfl. only the Experiment Station stock was used for a comparison of mulched and cultivated seed. During the previous ■ in a part of this stock, which had been mulched for five (imsecutive years, was again mulched, and a part was culti - vated. Similarly, of the lot which had been cultivated for five years a part was again cultivated and a part mulched. This makes it possilile not only to compare mulched with cultivate*! seed, but to note the effect of one year of mulching on a culti - vated stock and of one year of cultivation on a mulched stock. Two new stocks of tubers were again obtained from Greeley and I'alhan. Colo. The Rrookings, S. Dak., and the Glyndon, Minn., &lt;tnrks grown at the Experiment Station in 1909 were also in - cluded in the ISM plantings. All plats were onetwentieth acre m area except those planted with mulched seed, which con - tained three-twentieths of an acre. All records given in the following table an- calculated for twentieth-acre plats </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Home Mulched is. Nw •theiti Seed Potatoes. t.E fi. — Yield* of potatoes frot in comparison with home grn tiihryn on twentieth-acre pic n seed tubers of various son rax irn mulched and cultivated ts. 1910. Kind of seed tubers Marketable yield Total yield Per cnt marketalilr yield ireeley, Colo., stock, irrigated L'alhnn, Colo., stock, dry farming Brookings, B. Dak., stock, Lincoln, 1909 jlyndon, Minn., stock, Lincoln, 1909 Experiment Station stock — Mulched 1904-1908— Mulched 1909 Cultivated 1909 Cultivated 1904-1908— Mulched 1909 Cultivated 1909 Gain from six years' mulching over — Six years' cultivation One year's cultivation after five years' mulching One year's mulching after five years' cultivation Gain from one year's mulching after five years' cultivation over — Six years' cultivation One year's cultivation after five years' mulching Per cent gain, six years' mulching over — Six years' cultivation One year's cultivation after five years' mulching One year's mulching after five years' cultivation Per cent gain, one year's mulching after five years' cultivation over — Six years' cultivation One year's cultivation after five years' mulching 196 lbs. 133 lbs. 165 lbs. 160 lbs. 222 lbs. 151 lbs. 222 lbs. at iiis. 197 lbs. 150 lbs. Ml lbs. 212 lbs. ,1 ITS lbs. 114 lbs. 236 lbs. 176 lbs. S 83 lbs. 74 lbs. „.„ 47 lbs. 38 lbs. „ 19 lbs. 14 lbs. u 64 lbs. 60 lbs. 10 , 28 lbs. 24 lbs. u 72.8% 42.0' ( 3i. .r c 17.8% 10.7% .-» r , &lt; 56.1% 34.1', 18.7% 11.3' o In 1910. it will be noticed, the Greel&lt; practically as good a yield as any stock grc Colo., stock was much poorer. The stocki both in 1909 and in 1910 differed from having more upright plants and in beinj maturing. Otherwise they were like othe ■y. Colo., f »'n, while t s from the all others ; soiiicwliii r Early Ol stock gave he Calhan. ;se sources grown in t later in bio stocks. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Home Mulched vs. Northern Seed Potatoes ■art Station the previous year yielded slightly better than the mulched lot of the Experiment Station stock, which had been cultivated the preceding year. The results from the mulched and cultivated lots, as a whole, indicate: first, that starting with I sirong stock, one year of cultivation causes by no means so great a deterioration as several years of cultivation ; second, that even with a run-down stock, one year of mulching will make it nearly as productive as will several years of mulching. The poor cultivated stock after one year of mulching was con - siderably better than the good mulched stock after one year of cultivation. The 1911 tests were limited to comparisons of mulched and cultivated lots of the original Experiment Station stock. There were included in these tests one lot that had been mulched for seven years, one that had ln&gt;en mulched six years and cultivated one year, and one that had Iteen cultivated six years and mulched one year. Each lot was planted in triplicate plats, each plat (•■insisting of about one-twentieth acre, making about one-seventh acre for each lot of seed, except the seven-year mulched lot which occupied in all nearly one-half acre. All records in the </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 |.\l&gt;l.fcj l«~~'~" " I I f . I ff »V "'/ /"*(**■ ***•! i i Vt fit /l*'//lf *//'***'* "' ' " I If U ' ' '* , mnh-hcil n&gt;,tl cultivated Kcvcntlincrc jtluix. 1U1I. o r ninou* CHffl Ux o intc. on Previous treatment of seed tubers Marketable yield Total yield Per rent marketable Mulched 1904-1909— Mulched 1910 Cultivated 1910 Cultivated 1904-1909— Mulched 1910 Cultivated 1910 (iniii from seven years' mulching over — Seven years' cultivation One year's cultivation after six years' mulching One yearV mulching after six years' cultivation (lain from one year's mulching after six years' cultivation over— Seven years' cultivation One year's cultivation after six years' mulching Per cent gain, seven years' mulching over — Seven years' cultivation One year's cultivation after six years' mulching One year's mulching after six years' cultivation Per cent gain, one year's mulciiing after six years' cultivation over — Seven years' cultivation One year's cultivation after six years' mulching -&gt;:&lt;-J lbs. 375 lbs. 556 lbs. MS lbs. 267 lbs. 157 lbs. (-&gt;241bs. 291 lbs. 682 lbs. 537 lbs. 724 lbs. 428 lbs. 254 lbs. 145 lbs. (-)42 lbs. 296 lbs. 69.8 619 ,„., - " , 9 181 lbs. 187 lbs. 7.0 100.7' c 59.4% 41.9% 27.0% (-4.3% (-15.8% 109.8% 69.1% 48.3% 34.8 Iks seen from Table 7. the test of 1 1 H 1 — the seven ex]iei-iinenl -§RTC even more pronounced results lie preceding tests. The season was almost imp heat and drouth. 1'uder these extremely unfavti •ns. when the most thoro cultivation could prc, erate yields with the best seed, the stock that rn by cultivation for the past seven years sIk cingiy than ever before its greatly enfeebled coiv n 1912. tests were made with a Red River stoc! i ■ local dealer and the Experiment Station sti been srrown on the Station for eight years. Of f were four lots: one th.it had been mulched ro th year of than any irecedented mhie '-on )duce onlv hud been &gt;wed more dition. k obtained ock, which the latter. intinnoDslv </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 for eight years, imc cultivated eight years, one mulched seven vciirs and niltivjited mk year, and one umlelied six years and cultivated two years. A second stock of Red River tubers obtained from a local gardener was also grnm, but is not com - parable with ilie others for the reason that it consisted of the choicest tuber* selected from a considerable quantity. All the lot* were grow? in triplicate plats. Each contained approxi - mately one eighth acre in all except the eight-year cultivation stock, of which there was sufficient seed for only one-sixteenth acre. The results, as given in the following table, are calcu - lated on an eighth-acre basis: a slightly higher percentage of marketable tul»ers. The increase in yield for Ked River seed over mulched seed was IB per cent for total yield and 17.." per eent for marketable tubers. The several lots from cultivated seed were markedly inferior to the lot from mulched seed. Tn total yield, there was no difference r.K S. ) iilils of jiotntiKs fi mulched and mttimted ttt '■(tii\ northern ami Ik. •&lt;1 tubers, on eighth* &lt;//ic f/rotcn were plain. l!)l&gt;. Kind of seed tubers Marketable yield Total yield Per cent marketable yield Red River stork 471 lbs. HO4 lbs. 78.0 Iio grown stock Mulched eight years Cultivated one year Cultivated two years Cultivated eight years 401 lbs. 2.50 lbs. ■_'-.»ti Dm. 218 lbs. 525 lbs. 372 lbs. 372 lbs. 392 lbs. 76.4 II from eight years' mulching over- One year's cultivation Two years' cultivation Eight years' cultivation 151 lbs. 175 lbs. 183 lbs. 153 lbs. 153 lbs. 133 lbs. £ I cent gain, eight years' mulching over — One year's cultivation Two years' cultivation Eigh&gt; years' culth ution l&gt;0.4' , 77.4', S4.0\ 41.1' ; 41.1', 33.9', Owing to the unfavorable season and to late pi; yields in 101L' were again low. The Red IJiver sto somewhat better than the home grown mulched stoo intinsr. tin .ok yielded k and had </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Home Mulched eg. Northern Seed PotetMt, I&lt;. and both, for some unknown reason, were slightly less uctive than the lot cultivated eight years. The difference &gt;t great and may be due to mere chance. Heretofore, how - one year of cultivation has resulted in less deterioration two years and much less than several years. The excessive and drouth of 1011 evidently caused excessive deterioration le lot cultivated only that one year, but why it should not caused still further deterioration in the lot that had been vated the previous seven years is difficult to understand, ss it may he assumed that the several years of growth under vorable conditions had tended to isolate a stmin of potatoes &gt;what adapted to hot soils by the gradual elimination of riduals not so well suited to such conditions. I While the total yield was nearly the same for all the cul - ted lots without rositect to the number of years of cnltiva - i. the percentage of marketable tubers was very different in several lots, rnnnine from about 07 per cent in the one-vear ivation lot to less tlmn 5(5 r&gt;er cent in the eight-year culti - ion lot. Compared with these lots, the 70 per cent of market - 1 tnbers and the much grenter total yield of the mulched lot sent a strong contrast. The gains from mulching over one. '. and eight years of cultivation were respectively about 60. and 84 per cent. SUMMARY OP RESULTS FROM USR OF MULCHED AND CULTIVATED SEED TUBERS That the great difference in yield between long-time culti - vated and long-time mulched stocks of potatoes — exemplified by the results of 1011 — is due to the gradual deterioration of the cultivated stock rather than to the srradnal improvement of the mulched stock, is shown with considerable certainty bv two outstanding facts — first, thnt the lots cultivated several years are much less productive of marketable tubers than the lots cultivated only one year: second, that the lots mulched onlv one year are in general equal to the lots mulched several years. Thus in 1010 the one-year cultivated lot outyielded the six-vear cultivated lot by 24 per cent, and in 1011 the one-year cultivated lot exceeded the crop of the seven-year cultivated lot by over 40 per cent. While in 1010. the one-year mulched lot w&gt;s ont - yielded by the six-year mulched lot bv about 11 per cent, in 1011 it outyielded the seven-vear mulched lot bv a little over 4 per cent. But notwithstanding the fact that deterioration of potato stocks by cultivation in this region is more or less grad- </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Hum, Mulched vs. Northern Seed Potatoes 23 nal. we must not suppose that it is insignificant during the first rear or so. On the contrary, the results of the tests thruout the eight years indicate tliat. given a strong stock with which to start — a stock directly from the North or a mulched stock, — 8 single year of cultivation greatly reduces its strength. Thus in 1010, the six-year mulched stock yielded 31 per cent more market ■Me tubers than the same stock cultivated only a single year (after having been mulched five years); in 1011 the seven-year mnlched stock yielded -12 per cent more than the same stock cultivated only one year (after having been mulched six years) ; and in 1012 the eight-year mulched stock yielded fifl per cent more than the same stock cultivated one year (after having been mulched seven years'). Of the 22 separate tests con - ducted during eight years and reported in detail earlier in this bulletin, 10 show the ill effects of a single year of cultivation upon the productiveness of several strong stocks of potntoes. The stocks used were, in one case, directlv from the North; in three cases they were Nebraska grown, but of recent introduc - tion from the North: and in the other six cases they were mulched from one to seven years previous to the tests. Not - withstanding these differences in the previous treatments of the several stocks, they were all strong at the beginning. Each stock was divided into two uniform lots at the beginning of its test, and the two lots were treated exactly alike, except that one was mulched and the other cultivated during the one season next preceding the comparison of yields. Tf. now. the yields of marketable tubers from the mulched seed in each of these tests be indicated by 100. the yields from the cultivated seed in the same tests become 02. 68.' 70. 70. 70. SO. 82. 83. 88. and 93. the average of all being 77. Tn other words, with strong stocks of potatoes with which to start, a single year of cultivation in eastern Nebraska reduced their value for seed purposes by 23 per cent. I Only four of the 22 tests show the effect of two consecutive rs of cultivation at the Experiment Station. Tn these four es. as in the nine considered above, the stocks were strong ?n the tests were begun. The mulched lot of seed was in each p mulched two years in succession. Again calling the yields marketable tubers from mulched seed 100. the yields from i cultivated two years were 54. 64, 77, 79, giving an averaee about 08. That is. whereas one year of cultivation, as indi - ed by ten tests, reduced the yield 23 per cent, two years of tivation. as indicated by four tests, reduced it 32 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Home Muh-hcil r». Sarthfni Seal Potatoes. The effect of three or more years of cultivation is indicated by tight tests, one test each for three, four. five, and eight years. and two tests each for six and seven years. In six of these t the seed was strong at the start, and in each test one lot of seed was mulched as many years as the other was cultivated. In the other two tests the cultivated lots of seed were cultivated six and seven years respectively, while the corresponding mulched lots were mulched only a single year, having l&gt;een cultivated previously the and six years respectively. This difference can have little effect upon the comparison because, as has been shown above, one year of amlrhiBg can lx&gt; depended upon to restore a run-down stock to its normal strength practically as well as MVCml years of mulching. If now the yields of marketable tubers from mulched seed in these tests, as before, be given as 10(1. the yields from the cultivated seed are as follows: cultivated three years. 74: fear years. &lt;&gt;S: five years. &lt;&gt;»&gt;: six years. 04 and R, average (il : seven years, ."ill and 18, average -10; and eight years. M. In short, all this means that strong stocks of potato?* it - teriorate more or less gradually when grown by ordinary culti vation in eastern Nebraska. The decrease in yield in these test* ran from 1'."! pet cent for one year of local cultivation to 51 per cent for seven years of such cultivation. While the decrease, of course, is not |&gt;erfectly regular, it is a remarkable fact that in all '2'2 tests not a single one has shown cultivated seed tubers to be the equal of mulched ones. (■ranting, as we must, that home grown mulched tubers are far MOTC valuable for seed than home jjrown cultivated tubers, the question still remains as to whether they are the equal of northern grow stocks. On this point the results obtained in tlv Expettaeat Station tests are not quite so reliable as those secured from the comparison of mulched and cultivated home grown seed. As was explained earlier, the plats have a)wa\s been arranged so as to give a more direct comparison between the mulched and the cultivated seed of any one stock lhan between the different stocks. It is believed, however, to be worth while to make such comparison as is possible 'id ween the yields from northern grown seed and from home grown mulched seed. Such comparisons are afforded by five of the eight years' tests In I9M a stock of Ked Hiver grown tnben obtained thru a local dealer can l&gt;e compared with a two year mulched stock. In 1!M)7 I stuck of tubers received from a dealer in western Minn - m he compared with the Experiment Station stock mulched three years. In 190!) the yields of four stocks from eastern North l»akota and one from western Minnesota are averaged for com- </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 P«r*— with the iivt 'rage vicld of three mulched stocks, two of them mulched two years and one mulched five years. Tn 1910 no fresh northern slock was grown, lmt there is available for the comparison ■ stork received from western Minnesota in 1901) and mown at the Fipnlfl Station by ordinary cultivation that year. Obviously it would 1m- unfair to compare this stock with a stock mulched in 1!MI!I. The mulched stock used for the com narisoii is. therefore, one that had lx'en mulched five years, but which was cultivated in 19(10. In 1912 a stock of Red River taken secured from a local dealer can be compared with the Experiment Station stock mulched eight years. If now the yields of marketable tulx-rs from these mulched stocks be taken as 100. the \ields from the northern slocks for the years 190G. 1907, 1909. 1910, and 1913, respectively, are represented by 102, 73, 90, 107. and !17. Tims one gets :m average of about 98 for the northern seed as compared with 100 for the mulched seed. This is by no means so pttt a difference as that between mulched seed and seed cultivated locally only one year. If one disregards the results for 1!)II7. when for some unknown reason the northern pvwi seed gave poor results, the relative values of mulched and northern seed, as indicated by the tests of the other three years, will stand 100 to 104 — still practically equal. It is plain, there - fore, that so far as these tests indicate anything, they suggest that home grown seed taken, if produced under a mulch, are aliout equal to the best seed ordinarily obtainable from the Red Kivcr region of western .Minnesota and eastern North Dakota. rLATIVE COST OF NORTHERN GROWN AND HOME GROWN MULCHED AND CULTIVATED SEED. It having Iteen shown that home grown mulched seed tutors are the equal of the best northern grown stocks and far superior to ordinary home grown seed, there naturally arises the question of the relative cost of these three kinds of seed. It is safe to that, one year with another in eastern Nebraska, northern grown tubers sell at planting time for 20 to 30 per cent more than home grown taken. Thus a few years ago when home grown seed potatoes retailed at till cents a bushel, northern seed brought 80 cents. Some years the prices have been 75 or 80 cents for the former and *i for the latter. One year the retail prices were fl.60 to $1.75 for home grown and *2 for northern grown seed. At the rates of planting commonly practiced in eastern Nebraska, the cost of northern seed will perhaps l&gt;e from $1.50 to $2.50 more an acre than home grown seed when prices are low and perhaps |3 to *4 more an acre when seed is high priced. If now </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Home Mulched vs. Northern Seed Potatoes. Iorthem seed obtained is the equal of mulched seed, it ma.v peoted to increase the yield by perhaps l'5 per cent over that ed from ordinary home {frown seed. And. with yields and i as they prevail in eastern Nebraska, this difference in should much more than pay the extra cost of the northern Mulched seed, if used at all. will doubtless be produced by the grower who is to plant it. Its relative cost will, therefore, depend mainly upon two things: one, the yield from mulched as compared with cultivated plants; and the other, the expense of mulching as compared with cultivation. The yield of seed tvfcen fjrwra under litter mulches properly applied is ordinarily never less than the yield obtained by cultivation and in most cases is considerably greater. In an earlier account (Experiments in Mulching Harden Vegetables, Bui. 80, 1903), I compared the yields of potatoes from mulched plants with those grown by thoro cultivation. The mulch used was straw about four inches deep applied six to seven weeks after planting, one or two culti - vations having been given in the meantime. The cultivated plats were given five or six cultivations. The tests included one in 1000, two in 1901, and three in 1902, carried out under widely different conditions of soil and moisture. If the yield from tin - mulched plats be taken as 100 in each test, the yields from the cultivated plats in the six tests stand 94, 89, 85, 90. 105. 114, or an average of 90&gt;. Since 1904 the tests have been planned to show the value of mulched seed rather than the direct effect of mulches on the yield of the current year. The trials of 1911. however. afford a fair comparison of the yield from plants cultivated thruout the summer, on the one hand, and plants mulched with straw after one or two cultivations, on the other. The extreme dryne8s of the season made the production low in both cases. The yields were as follows : rR 9. — Yields of potatoes from mulched and ailtiruted plant* on seventh-acre plats. 7911. Marketable yield Per cent Total yield marketable A ulched plants 'ultivated plants lain from mulching 750 lbs. 532 lbs. 218 lbs. 870 lbs. 682 lbs. 188 lbs. 86.2 78.0 Hi 'er cent gain 41 '1' , </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Home Mulched vs. Northern Seed Potatoes 27 On several occasions the mulch has been spread as soon as the planting was done, and the plants thus compelled to push up thru the straw. This method of mulching has often injured the stand of plants and thereby lessened the yield. In 1005, for instance, the mulch hurt the stand so badly that only 100 pounds of tubers were obtained from a small mulched plat, while a cultivated plat of the same size yielded 215 pounds. Tn 1907 a larger percentage of the plants forced their way up thru the mulch than in 1005. hut the stand, nevertheless, was far from perfect. The yields from nuarter-acre plats were 2,046 pounds from cultivation and 1.872 pounds from mulching. Tn 1006, on the other hand, the mulch, tho applied early, did not notice ably lessen the number of plants and materially increased the yieid. The yields from ninth-acre plats were 000 pounds from mulching and (ifin pounds from cultivation. Tn general, mulches applied before the plants came op in hired the stiind only wfcn thr nmlch was too deep, when the seed pieces were too small, or when the seed was planted too deep. Tims in l!)02 (reported in F5ul. SO) with small mm pieeei planted four inches deep a four -inch inuleli. applied before the plant! came up. produced a yield of 1(19 pounds and an eight - inch mulch, similarly applied, gave a yield of only 126 pounds, while thoro cultivation resulted in a yield of 100 pounds and a four-inch mulch, applied after the plants were up, pave 211 ponnds. With seed pieces of the same size, planted only about one inch deep, a four-inch mulch resulted in a yield of 202 pounds — slightly better than thoro cultivation — while an eight - inch mulch brought the yield down to 133 pounds. Not only did the deep mulch hurt the stand more than the shallow one. but the plants seemed also less able to push up thru the mulch when planted 4 inches deep than when planted only 1 inch deep. Tn general, however, shallow planting is not to be rec - ommended. Shallow planting in connection with mulching is likely to give better results in moist seasons than in dry ones. Tn long continued dry weather, the soil just beneath the mulch often becomes hard, a condition that is apt to reduce the yield, even tho the stand of plants may be good. Moreover, in a dry spring seed pieces near the surface of the soil apparently do not sprout so uniformly well as do those deeper in the ground, even tho they are mulched. Thus in 1005. under unfavorable conditions, mulched plats yielded at the rate of 60 bushels an acre, where the seed was planted 5 inches deep; 67 bushels where planted 4 inches deep: 60 bushels where planted 3 inches deep; and only 37 bushels where planted 1 inch deep. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Home Mulrlttil rx. \orthern Seed Potatoes. If the results of sill the tests of mulching reported here wen* iveraged. they would probably indicate .1 slight decrease in yield due to mulching. But since practically every HUM of lessened yield has l&gt;een due to wrong methods of mulching, it would be obviously unreasonable to draw conclusions from average results. The only condition under which mulches prop - erly used may ever be expected to reduce the yield are exces - sively wet weather, or soil that is not well drained, ruder con ditions ordinarily prevailing in Nebraska, proper mulching may be expected to increase the yield from 10 to 40 per cent, much depending upon the season. Tn all the tests at the Experiment Station in wliich proper methods of mulching have been em - ployed, the yields have been increased by mulching on the aver age about "_'O to 2."&gt; pet cent over the yields produced by thoro riiltivation. If the comparison had been hetwwi mulching and the sort of cultivation given potatoes on many farms in eastern Nebraska, the difference in yield weuld doubtless have been CM - siderably greater than "2." per cent. Another factor in the relative cost of mulched and ciilti valed seed, besides relative yield which has just been discus - is the expense of mulching as compared with cultivation. Tn figuring the cost of mulching, no account is taken of the value of the straw or other litter used. Where mulching material his to be purchased, it is extremely doubtful if it will ever he practicable to use a nmlch at all. Tn 1MB, ■" tons of straw were required to mulch Me-mnrter acre of potatoes to a depth of about 4 inches, and in 1007 4} tons were used on a similar area. On almost every farm, however, there is an abundance of straw, coarse stable litter, or old hay from the tops and bottoms of stacks. At current prices paid for labor of men and teams, it ■ &lt;»t at the rate of fll.' an acre to spread the mulch in 1M6 and flSJM an acre in 1900. This is considerably more than it costs to cultivate potatoes tlioroly thruout the growing season. In general it will cost perhaps 91 to ?H more an acre to Spread a mulch than to give thoro cultivation. The mulch must also be removed, of course, before digging. Tf a few rows along one side of the potato field are mulched, the nmlch can be scattered after digging the non-mulched potatoes. The cost of removing a mulch in this way has never been accurately ascertained, hut it should not. it is believed, amount to more than f3 or *4 an acre, thus making the entire cost of growing potatoes by mulch - ing perhaps $1(1 to $12 an acre more than by cultivation. At this rate the cost of producing mulched seed wou,ld ordi- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 aralckJag did not iaereaae the yield. If mulching, however. ;is may ordinarily 1m&gt; expected, increases the yield by as much as •_'•&gt; to -'t per cent, mulched seed tubers will cost the producer little or no more a bushel than cultivated seed tubers. Tn short. •t is possible for one who has waste straw, hay, or other litter at hand lo produce at home seed taken that are the equal of the best northern grow a stock at a cost not greatly exceeding that of ordinary local stock. Tn other words, he can produce high class seed by mulching at less expense than he can buy it from the North. KFFECT OF TIME OF MULCHING ON VALUE OF SEED TUBERS. If mulches are to be used as a means of producing high-class seed potatoes, it is important to know the lK'st time to apply the mulch. The cost of applying at different times may differ, as may also the immediate yields of seed produced by applying the mulch at different times, but these questions will be considered later. We are here concerned with the effect of mulching at different times on the value for seed of the tubers so produced. In 10(111 and again in 101 It four plats were planted to a uniform lot of seed. To insure uniformity, each seed tuber was cut into quarters and the four pieces distributed to the four plats. One plat was mulched before the plants came up; the second plat. just before the plants blossomed and just as the tubers were beginning to form ; and the third plat, when the tubers were perhaps half grown: while the fourth plat was left without mulching. The four lets of seed thus produced in 190ft were tested in 1910. and the four lots grown in lftlO were tested in 1911. [n the tests of both of these years the several lots of seed were planted in single adjoining rows; and the plats duplicated mice. The results of the two years are shown together in Table 10. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Home Mulched vs. Northern Seed Potatoes, 30 I it any dependence. The noticeable feature of the results is fact that mill eh iiifr. when tubers were about half grown, pro- seed that was little or no better on the whole than with mulching. Obviously, to be of value, the mulch must be •ad between the time of planting and the time the tubers n to develop. rECT OF DIFFERENT KINDS OF MULCHING MATERIAL ON VALUE OF SEED TUBERS. In 1909 and again in 1910 seed tubers were grown under three kinds of mulches. One plat each year was mulched with wheat straw, and two plats with strawy stable litter, one from the cow barn and one from the horse barn. The three kinds of mulches were applied at the same time and to approximately the same depth on all plats. The seed tuImtb produced on these three plats in 1909 and 1910 were tested in 1910 and 1911, re - si'cctively. The several lots of seed were planted in double ad - joining rows and diuilirati d once in 1911 and twice in 1911. In the two years together about one-quarter acre was grown from each lot of seed. The results appear in Table 11. rlO.— Total yield of seed U on tenth-acre plats ibers mule. I 1910 an ■hed at diffi id 1911. Tent times Treatment of seed -Marketable yield Total yield Per cent marketable yield Mulched when planted Mulched before blossoming Mulched when tubers half grown lain over cultivation from — Early mulching Medium mulching Late mulching J cr cent gain over cultivation from — Early mulching Medium mulching Late mulching ■_&gt;7ti lbs. 299 lbs. 220 lbs. 209 lbs. 400 bs. 406 lbs. 318 lbs. 322 lbs. 69.0 73.6 69.2 64.9 &lt;i7 lbs. (K) lbs. 11 lbs. 78 lbs. 84 lbs. l-)4 lbs. « 12.1% 43.1', o.3' c 24.2' , -&gt;»i.r, From the above table it is teen that i fubers began to form, made slightly belte t&gt;efore the plants caine n i &gt;. but the differe nulching, j i- seed that nee was td list as the l mulching o slight to </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Home Mulched m. Northern Seed Potatoes. 31 I There was comparatively little difference between the total ds from seed tubers mulched with the three kinds of litter, in marketable tubers cow manure ranked slightly better than others. Apparently, almost any kind of coarse, waste ma al that does not contain grain or weed seed in harmful ntities, that will hold moisture, that will keep the weeds rn, and that, above all, will keep the ground cool, can be d for mulching potatoes for seed production. OTHER WAYS OF PRODUCING GOOD SEED TUBERS AT HOME. I If a rather low and uniform soil temperature is important iroducing good seed tutors, it may be possible to bring about t condition, in part at least, without litter mulches. The old ctice of hilling the ground about the plants at the last culti - ion may have value in this connection. True, the practice has [i abandoned by most potato growers; not, however, because vas injurious to have the soil ridged about the plants, but iuse the roots were injured in getting the soil with which to ;e the plants. No satisfactory tests of this method of seed duction have been made at the Experiment Station. If suc - iful, this method might prove an inexpensive way of producing d seed, even tho less seed is produced on a given area than ;ht be produced by some other method. II&gt;eep planting also suggests itself as a method of seed tuber duction. Tests conducted at the Experiment Station have wn that when seed pieces are planted very deep the resulting prs are formed deeper in the ground than when shallow plant - is practiced, tho the difference in depth of the tubers produced ot so great as the difference in the depth of planting. A single : of the value for seed of tubers grown from shallow and n deep planting has been made. In 190!) three plats were nted with uniform seed, a part of each seed tuber having been :ributed to each plat. In one plat the pieces were planted nt 1 inch deep, in a second plat about 4 inches deep, and in ABLE ) ichh from xved tubers mulrhi teriate, on fourth-acre plats. 191 •d with different ma ) and 1911. Kind of mulch Marketable yield, pounds Total yield, pounds Per cent \Vhr:it straw 3trawy horse manure. . Strawy cow manure . . 881 950 1,163 1,151 1,200 B </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 #7 c l/K (I r Oti/l'/cfl. :i third plat ;il»mit 7 inches deep. These three lots of seed were tested in 1010. in fortieth-acre plats duplicated once. The results are seen in Table 12. rl2. — Yields from teed fuherx prtHM from xeed plantnl nt different tli'jiHis, on tintli-iiiK 1 jihitx. 1910. tvear. the greater the yield the next year. This method has lin disadvantages, however, in that it requires more labor lant the wed deeply than to plant it at the ordinary depth. also in that the diggers have to lte run deeper at h;-rvtst Whether this method is more or less feasible than mnlch - as a means of producing good seed or whether some coin tion of the methods suggested here with mulching will prove remains to lie shown. It is known lhat the planting of whole tubers or large seed ■s results in the growth of very large, much-branched plants, whether the dense shade thus produced will insure snffi Hy eool soil for the production of strong seed tubers for the year's crop cannot now lie told. If satisfactory nsiilt* are red. this may prove the most practicable method of all. le in eastern Nebraska it is undesirable to plant whole rs of the ordinary size for the main crop on account of the t expense for seed and the high peivi'iitage of small tubers in Crop, neither of these considerations need stop one from ting whole tubers or very large pieces on a sufficient area iirnish seed for the next season's crop. HOW TO GROW MULCHED POTATOES. The mulch must lie deep enough to prevent weed growth, to conserve soil moisture *itid to keen the "Pound cool \ mulch rth of plantinj! seed the previous year Marketable yiehl Total yield Per cent marketable yield I inch • inches ii inches. i from planting 7 Mefcai over Four inches One inch cent gain from planting 7 inches over — Four inches One inch 61 lbs. 85 lbs. 116 lbs. 118 lbs. 137 lbs. 171 lbs. 51.7 61 J 67.8 31 lbs. 55 lbs. 34 lbs. 53 lbs. 36.5% 90.1% 24.8% 44.9% A oarentlv, :is mijiht !•&lt;&gt; ex M'fted. ilic dee Mr tin- &gt;l;uititi&lt;; </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 mImhii 1 inches deep after settling will n &lt;-&lt; ■&lt; »i 1 1 j ► I i sh all UHK things. A deeper nmlcli is not only unnecessary, hnt also un - desirable since it adds to the cost of mulching and may hurt the stand of plants, particularly if applied before they conie up. I Any coarse material, such as straw, old hay. coarse stable pi-, and the like, serves well the purpose of a nuilch. if free 11 grain or noxious weed seeds. On very sandy soil or any greatly lacking in fertility, stable litter is to be preferred straw or hay. So far as its effect upon the value of the tubers for seed is concerned, it makes little difference whether the mulch is ap - plied immediately after planting or any time between then and when the new tubers begin to develop. If, however. niching is delayed until after the plants are up. it must ordinarily be postponed until the plants have reached a height of several inches, for otherwise it is difficult to prevent their being buried ;is the mulch is spread. Even when the plants are large, con siderable care must be exercised to get the litter close about them without burying them. While a potato sprout that ha» not been exposed to the light will force its way up thru a mulch of considerable thickness, after once having its leaves expanded, a comparatively light covering will kill it. The extra care necee - *ary makes mulching after the plants are up more expensive thin mulching before they are up. Another item of added expense ill case of late mulching is the cost of the cultivations necessary up to the time of mulching. It is ordinarily tetter, therefore, to apply the mulch before the sprouts begin to appear above ground. There is little trouble in early mulching, if the litter is not too thick, if the seed is not planted too deep, and if the seed pieces are not too small. It is unwise to plant much less than -1 inches deep even tho a mulch is to be spread. Tubers that form at the surface of the ground under a mulch are distinctly more liable to scab than are those that are well covered with soil. Moreover, in a prolonged drouth, the surface soil under a mulch is apt to become hard and dry. particularly if it has been too wet at some time previous to the drouth. With the necessity of pushing up thru 4 inches of soil and then 4 inches of litter, the potato sprouts must be strong, else a poor stand will be secured. It is best, therefore, to use larger seed pieces where the ground is to be mulched than are commonly employed in this locality. (See tig. 1.) Large seed pieces are desirable not only to insure a perfect stand, but also to produce as large a yield as possible on a small </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 E amount of land if that land yields only 100 bushels of 8 as it does if the yield is 200 bushels. Since the greatest back to the use of a mulch is the cost of applying and re- applying and re- moving it. the importance of securing as great a yield as pos- sible for a given area is readily appreciated. A 100- bushel yield makes the mulching twice as expensive for a bushel of seed tubers produced as does the 200-bushel yield. Experiments re- ported in Bulletin 07 of this Station indicate that the total yield of tubers increases with the size of the seed piece from single-eye pieces up to whole tubers (where 6- to 8-ounce are concerned). Hut. owing to the fact that more tubers ]H&gt;r hill when large seed picri. s are planted than can develop ■ 1. — Mulched potato plants. The row at the left was from large seed pieces and the next one from small seed pieces. properly if the weather later becomes unfavorable, it happens that the yield of marketable tubers is often greater from hnlf - tuber seed pieces than from whole tubers. And under ordinary conditions of cultivation the yield of marketable tnl&gt;ers from half-tuber seed pieces is frequently not sufficiently greater than that from quarter tubers to equal the difference in quantity of seed planted, so that for ordinary cultivation seed pieces weigh - ing from H to 2 ounces are considered better than much larger pieces. The more favorable soil conditions under a mulch, how &lt;-ver. make it desirable to use seed pieces of from 4 to 6 ounces in weight, and even larger pieces might perhaps be profitably employed. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">H'niir Miiltlit'il r». \&lt;&gt;rtln'rii Heed Potatoes. 35 It will usually be found convenient to have the rows of petaton in be mulched aaMg one side of the field ro that the nmlcli nil lie applied without driving over and. thereby, injuring !!)&lt;■ other potatoes. Where only a small acreage is grown, a few rows of mulched plants will yield a sufficient quantity of seed tubers for the next year's main crop. SIMMARY. Experiments carried on at the Nebraska Exj&gt;eriinent Station show clearly that it is possible to increase the productiveness of potatoes by proper methods of breeding. Hut potato breeding cannot be carried on successfully unless the same stock of potn toes can 1m- kepi indefinitely. This cannot be done in southern and eastern Nebraska with ordinary methods of culture. The importance of producing improved strains of potatoes for this region makes it desirable to devise a method of producing strong seed tubers at home. Since rather low and fairly uniform soil temperatures *ei m to l&gt;e essential to the production of high class seed tubers, the use of a mulch of straw or other coarse material about the plant suggested itself. This method lias beet: under test at the Ex periiuent Station for eigki years, and during that time '2'2 separate tests have lieen conducted — all with the Early Ohio variety. la every test a uniform stock of tubers was divided into two lots, one grown by ordinary cultivation and the other one mulched. The seed tubers produced on the two plots were kept under identical conditions over winter. The next spring 1 m &gt;1 li were planted ill tlie same way on adjoining plots of as uniform soil as could be had. and both were given the same cultivation thruout the summer. Differences in yield the second year of the test an', therefore, attributable to the ditferent methods of culture by which the seeil tubers wen- produced in the tirst year of the test. Tests were also made of the effect of different numbers of years of mulching and cultivation. Tn 111 comparisons of seed tubers grown one year under a mulch with seed tubers of the same stock grown one year by ordinary cultivation, for each KIM pounds of tubers produced from mulched seed the cultivat'-d seed produced &lt;&gt;1\ fiS. "II 70. Tfi. Sll. SL\ S."!. SS. and 0:&gt; rounds respectively, or an average of 77 poun's. The other twelve tests compared from two to eight vears of mulching with the same number of yean of cultivation. The results from all the '22 tests are that for each 111(1 pounds of marketable tubers grown from mulched seed the average yield* of marketable tubers from cultivated seed were: </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Cultivated 1 year 1 10 tests) 77 pounds Cultivated '- years it tests! 68 pounds Cultivated :? years i 1 test I 74 pounds Cultivated 4 veins i! test) 68 pounds Cultivated 5 years ( 1 test i 66 pounds Cultivated 6 years 1 2 tests \ 61 pounds Cultivated 7 years (2 tests ) 49 pounds Cultivated 8 years 1 1 testl 54 pounds Continued cultivation in southeastern Nebraska remits, then, in a pronounced tho somewhat gradual deterioration of potato storks. One year of mulching, however, restores the ■ormal vigor of the stock, as is indicated by two tests as fol- Mulched 8 and 7 years 100 jwunds Mulched ."&gt; and 6 years and cultivated 1 year 82 pounds Mulehed 0 and 7 years &lt;'ultivated fi and 7 veins &lt;"&gt;7 pounds i 'ultivated 5 and 6 years and mulched 1 ye:ir 100 pounds Comparisons of home grown mulched stocks of Earl; Ohio potatoes with northern grown stocks of the same variety have !&gt;eeii made in five of the eight years. For each 100 pounds pro- iliiicd on the average by mulched seed tubers, the northern grown seed tuliers yielded an average of !IS pounds. Northern grown seed tubers ordinarily retail for about X |&gt;er cent more than home grown tubers. The estimated cost of prodneiag seed tubers by mulching is $10 to $12 an acre more than the cost of producing them by cultivation, but a mulched -■ id plat will ordinarily yield about 25 per cent more seed tubers :m acre than will a cultivated seed plat. The cost a bushel is. therefore, not greatly different for the two methods. The grower i-an produce high-class seed tubers at home by muliliiim at a cost somewhat less than he can buy northern grown awd of equal quality. It is recommended to mulch a few rows of potatoes along niie side of the field to furnish seed for the next year's crop. The mulch should be about 4 inches deep after settling and may iniisist of hav. straw, stable litter, or other coarse material free from grain and noxious weed seeds. It is best applied iK'fore the plants come up and must be spread by the time the new tubers lx'gin to develop. To insure that the plants are strong enough to push up thru the mulch and to produce as large a yield as possible for a given amount of mulching, large seed pieces from 4 to six ounces, should be planted. The depth of planting should be the same as in the rest of the field, about 4 inches. 'l-LM-ll )jm </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>