<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT NEBRASKA State Board of Agriculture FOR THE YEAR 1906-1907.</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Mate A WNl'AL REPORT NEBRASKA Board of Agriculture Prepared by MKLLOR. SECRETARY. LINCOLN , NEBRASKA State Joubnal Company. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">IK TLTl'RE Lincoln, Neb., January 31, 1907 (ton. Governor of Nebraska: law in this case made and provided, I v, he annual report of the Nebraska State Board of Agri v W. R. MELLOR, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p004">In orde It is published, w so that hereaf 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">MI-AN N UAL MEETING . Lincoln, Neb., September 6, 1906, Nebraska State Board of Agriculture n the office of the Board of Managers at }n the State Fair Grounds, according to law n 'olio wing members present: Messrs. Young- Roberts, Russell, Mellor, Rudge, Cook, Hervey, Bassett, ndershot, Mickey. Williams, Leonard, Haws, Lewelling, Arnold, Apperson, Dickman, Morse, Atkins Riley Dinsmore, It was ordered that President Peter Nebraska State Fair Association at the meeting Fair Associations to be held in Chicago in December. y Mr. Atkins, a resolution was passed that the full mem- Nebraska State Board of Agriculture attend the Illinois pringfield the first week in October. •n by Mr. Hendershot, it was carried that each member should p to Springfield and the Secretary should take railroad companies and notify the mem- A Mr. J. B. Itfnsmore was elected as a delegate to attend the jrthorn Breeders' Association meeting to be held in Chicago er remarks on the needs of the Board for better facilities along ations for exhibits and patrons led by Messrs. Her- accommt aws, Atkins. Ollis and others, the meeting adjourned. W. R. MELLOR, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 &gt;AKD &lt;ll &lt;;i ORGANIZED AGRKVL1 II Kepi ;i m J \\ ThP . Bret- Prof Ah Aswxiat Mr Val K* Prof. A E Mr. W. R. Mellor s»'&lt; rt-tai Prof. A. L Bm Mr. I. nr ■lauon Mr. S C. Ba.-.- ary of tbi Direotor E. A. Burnett resident Fan Dr. A. T. Peiers. secretary of Orpaniz*-,! AKrirn Mr. L. M. Rus ,^« d It was voted that an Audit audit the accounts of the las tMellor. Mr. Stilson. and Mr Haecker. The minutes of the last me»&gt;tiiu P^tort, and were approved The Auditing Comnn approved the Secretary's report of deficit of $5.84 for the la </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 nded by Professor Haecker, the re- accepted and the committee dis *A: ■ommittee had been unable to 1 account of his absence from the revious engagement ail a nine sessions very strong men a. good advertisement to have strong men. iave found that during that week re and that if they can attractively quite a number of those people, and for that n« men on our evening program to counteract rly people that come here come to see nd altho he may not give an eloquent address, yet i m. These men from abroad, in addition 1 word to say for Nebraska . stilson, it was voted State Board of Agriculture meets. week that th 4tl .ii -nnient of days and associations was made ar ation of Agricultural Students aI( » Veterinary Medical Association i State Veterinary Medical Association. a. State Board of Agriculture, 4 p. m. braska Duroc Jersey Breeders' Association a Dairymen's Association ate Poultry Association, evening, iay raska Dairymen's Association •aska State Swine Breeders' Association aska State Bee Keepers' Association of Organized Agricultun a Nebraska Stats Poultry Association, evening Organized Agriculture Woman's Sect Nebraska Improved Live Stock Breeders' Association Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association. Nebraska Park and Forestry Association Frida Nebraska Corn Improvers' Association Nebraska Shorthorn Breeders' Association. Farmers' Institute Conference. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Dr. Peters desire ized Agriculture. The wo ar felt he must discontinue the manaKen he was not in as good a he had in ham dered his thanV a for the var genera! arrar Peters and Mr year. The </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 N a. Pa Ml MUKH Lancastt B. Dinsmore, Clay P. Hendershot, Th — Io.N v. January 15, 1907, 4:00 p. m. idem Peter Youngere, Jr., of Geneva, a.ding of the call (or the annual meeting. • lellor, as follows: V.GRICULTURI I All. HOARD Ol ary. Lincoln, Nebraska, December 8, 1906 of the State Board of Agriculture will be held anuary 15, 1907, at 4:00 p. m. COMMITTEES. appointed by President Peter Youngers, Jr., ;1, Lincoln, on Monday, January 14, 1907, at P LIST, RULES AND REGULATIONS Basse! t W. Foster, Gibbon Jamaica. C M. Lewelling, Beaver City. Minden AUDITING COMMITTEE. O E. Mickey O. P. Hendersho: isceola Hebron. EDENT1ALS AND RETURNS, Jos. Roberta J. A. Ollis, Jr. Fremont BERS OF THE STATE BOARD. IHI EXPrBE JANUARY, 1907 sr County County O. E. Mickey, Polk County. G. R. Williams, Douglas County ayer County L. W. Leonard, Pawnee County \.\TAL MEETING. ANNOUNCEMENT. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Or AGKICl I H L.. Cook, Howard County J. A. Ollis, Jr., Valle I W Haws, Kearney County E. M. Searle. Jr.. K Caley. Knox County \v \v. Cole. A Elijah Filley. Jefferson County Samuel R C. M. Lewelling. Furnas County XPIM Chas. Mann. Dawes Countj A Vincent Arnold. Richardsor S C. Bassett. Buffalo Couni ear of I'."" 1 , has passed a able weather, enormous crops, sat agriculture. Values in apriculturs » isfa dreamed of ten years ago. and sa a </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 MEETING money from our eastern aska is doing its full share In N anna at prosperity that spreads at this Board has shared in &gt;ne of the most succm*- he state iairy, machinery and all and in keeping with the -ideal irn xeellent and the results of the was mo: and future generations. The clti- he efforts made to entertain and instruct. that the management was compelled to *te fair ground While the mpr patrons were good natured and ntr t of this patronage we have in our treasury at the ry of the State Board of MPKi p additional swine ban: with the balance of barns on the gr ng all the principal buildings. Tbr r )rders were assigned permanent locations, and have esign and add much ha ind very materially assist in the comf to the organizations that have built th- in a substantial manner and gentlemen's lavatori' m on the ground. The Bankers a most attractive tl hundred people. The moving l This exhibit was free to all vis- lands who desired rest and RAL C( International Live Stock Show delighted to see so many peo- ndance. I found that our Agricultural and made an exceptionally fine exhibit of evidence of the painstaking a n bringing it to the high standard atttained. and was a credit to the state of Nebraska FAIR DATES ed the annual meeting of American Associa- a ns, held in Chi niber 5 last, and the Fa </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AfiKICULTURI date for the Nebraska State Fair was assigned from A ber 6. inclusive, being the same week as last year and las the Iowa State Fair. EXHIBITORS AND In behalf of the Board I sionairee for their hear greatest ever held in the west a a a The exh the thousar seemed very ai trouble of any 1 A A T bring grounc &gt;a effc T fair tv we d- \pres iieir secured, with a Si making r vt-ni air The additional work of the Con machine exhibits was handled </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 HI OF ANNUAL MEBTING. U. With the location of the office In Lincoln, to the exhibitor or concessionaire who desire* Managers after a thorough discussion, have de - legislature to assist the State Board of Agricul- it buildings on the State Fair Grounds, by le necessary to secure a levy of one-eighth of a ate for that purpose. Should such ake a number of years to secure the buildings the exhibits, and I would recommend that the r :ed to prepare a bill for the pur- lame during the present iiiiwIihi etter accommodations by the Burlington nger service to adequately handle the great :er the service the more patrons he efore another season this railroad will service. We should also ne an improve- mds and unload, than to stop where would make it more pleasant for the w avc some assurance that this and we trust for Its accomplishment it ransportation facili ■ail way lines by i EMPLOYEE aents. Every superin - advantage, performing ease and entertain the Managers and each mem- inselfish efforts to alize that it was through the Df Agriculture, that It the record breaker In in the treasury. [Much ap- ave the reading of the Secretary's ra- ary Mellor made the following report: il was certainly a </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 NEB1 u RKI'olII oF THE The say in- tion it is i» h a condition s a State Fair the last fair attain our people fore. The sui Corn 1:.. Kye Potat and l | in ca.- Has If the hi ike thl« a fall, &gt; warrinp na Thai the annua i r form. It is a . department in which to co- a united effort in all departm* "Hov fair benefit tt not acquainted with men in your own nf horses, rat' p and poult W ltd the Incentive f( impefi fthf Of </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 mmediately conceived the ambition to inltate. if not excel Such an ambition reaches out to a degree which easurer of improved machinery, with expert! tunity of itself, oftentimes pays many times xpended; here he can study the educational he day, and when weary, can be entertained e he meets the old friends and forms new nd when he returns, he has many stories of the incidents leen, with which to regale his friends at home. things which I most earnestly desire to impress on the Nebraska interested In agriculture and llTe ail to attend the state fair, and do not fail to take at least ool of Agriculture at the State Farm. This for the benefit of everv citizen of Nebraska who 1b e actual farmer this advice is invaluable im»- to the State Fair the first week of ght week term in the school of Agricul- x hire extra help and come; It will pay &gt;■ and ma&gt; He ural school, is it not a gocd thing for In your community who aspire to hare as your representath ERSITY School of Agriculture and o place the agricul- ec mprove the methods in use :ampaign for the improvement of seed e winter wheat area have notably in- rtant cereals in the state, third state in th« Union wheat. This work alone has farmers annually. Although had undertaken to give a care- rovement and adaptation until n in a thorough manner and gave the rains and station bulletins. Fa calling attention to the need of bettor priced products of our farms, and the ex- uive called attention to the selection of for cattle and swine are of great valne ave shown alfalfa to be greatly sup*- x when fed with corn, and must encourage </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 AGRI' an Increased acreage of this valuable crop. The bu this subject must lead to a more care problem la five years th» : m has the Chicago Internatton ve niiii n record. This year out of nil)' grail' second In yc K manorial at ( lish ju st.-r Kty to mat ,s that th The w Rh will meet tt lem of di wil failure has and. farn the ere bt methods of The question of pork i grown in the country The School of Aim have been asked to mat a. We cannot afford to cripple the and farmers' boys, and sending t) a of strength in the improvement of apr ■lble for the agricultural progrea l broad minded men. who understand the principles of t No state ever paid too much for its agricultural educat Today it Is not only the duty, but the privilege of ■ year rowde </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 V rs and special experts In npensation for irr nt of its farm through the and the impetus it has re- rn and increase STRV w years been under- ing 10 note that this growth ral use of hand separator- rapidly these machines haw &gt;f Separators. ar n carefi ■mpiled, and may be de- aicuracy In the year 1905 practically also in 1903. In 1906 some estimating •vative principles. While the growth has been ear has seen a falling off in the amount of on has been largely due to the pros- r farmers, and the good crop con nd that their time is taK atters and more important, and have In o go back to range condition and allowed Another cause for the shrinkage is the low i It ing discouragement ar, ar who are milking but a few cows. It is for the season of 1906 will be favorable to the dairy business. The price, a good price iu the fall, and farmers who are pra h in their business and were :o winter ention to winter dairying would bring about he great t ilk of butter is made during M July, when th price is at its very lowest. that there has been very little attention to keeping the cows in good milking condition throughout the year. xperienced is largely due to the breed and the uidling. The grain Is largely fed the hogs and steers, and the s compelled to take what they can get. so, naturally, they have </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 K8KA 8TATE BOARD OF AURICTLTUHI given poor returns. Much improvement oo way of improved methods in the care of handling 10 nay that the present conditions are bad, and braska butter is to advance in quality. Those interested are contemplating y of the industry, and hope that a food and dairy commission will b« and that state inspectors can be et all pa ar I a. x * ■ two things ar mor ;»lay. If th proposed bill for one-eighth mill le\ will In time su ssa management to use ■a— y at the expense of ors ai to used for premiun ead of </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 NMA1, Ml \ partments at our Fair, annum nearly, if not quite a year not pay." Have you We will admit that from a temporary Jer or exhibitor who n no better way, and those exhibitors iy. are ir respective lines &gt; carries with it a source of gratiflca- o-called rich men of our com not a false idea that monev VUAL HAL Hall was without doubt equal, if not a tion was caused by mary. Some thought that this was xn exempl card, lmt the score card ther ption of places for v afore had to be carried it and will four districts and the be following numl'- e following number of linn mon. ■im money score not population i far '■pulation ovei filiation under 8.000 i first ■iring above the re&lt;i I "Hi regi :anl to classification. I oard pay actual railroad fare for two exhibit entitled to premiums RTK k here, I can truly say [i raska state fair sets the l h time Nebraska exhibits at </seg>
            <seg id="p020">M DRAgKA STATE BOARD OF AGR1CUI.TTJRI World's or lnT*rnat1onal fairs that the gold medals move The laat Biate fair exhibit was fully up to the same higt as was deeply appreciated along with the Improvements uon* of the building. XTILK MESTI ate that our a »- w r ie glre a (treat d&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 OF ANNUAL MEETING. I A originally seventeen entries, with but three similar. What can be done to better speed a statement of track receipts and expendl - sions at the gate. The number of persons of the track attractions is a matter of estl - &gt; I make no attempt to consider that part of ly credited in this department when pass - ive part of our annual fair. NCIAL STATEMENT </seg>
            <seg id="p022">T ' </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 MEETING. id on the state fair grounds. lie state of Nebraska and all improvement* he state or management are the has no bonded indebtedness. meral fund warrants, which are of the permanent school fund, and out of he total state indebtedness during the 6, the sum of J188.109.47 wa« he sum of $188,109.47 was &gt;l fund and nas enureiy has entirely passed out among 'K&gt;1 appropriation. Only has entirely passed out among ar in the semiannual school a] outside of school funds 'K&gt;1 appropriation. Only in aim erest outside of school funds !ska on the 30th day of November. on November 30, 1906, was i h« state debt of $336,730.00, of which iemption fund levy and $62,769.00 mated that had the railroads ri is amount would have been de- Ma idi nal. The total delinquent out ax. now amounts to $2,574,041.31 railroa ho state is for the purpose a r , desirability of i necessarv to continue to iollar of profits in keeping x such small buildings Owing to ■ rarv nature of is of necessity enormous, and he fair have been made at ids of the Fair Association should and m; r fair, with .Shall we not avored? What buildings ■i and stand for $22,000.00: In oe for |3i md in 1905 a live-stock ■ 00, in 1903 a total of $355,000.00 in six ne appropriated for permanent as with $5 additional each year as ntroduced this year for a live-stock pavilion, and in ral building. The meeting Just dosed n of a bill for $75,000.00 for a new steel grand- barn and pavilion &lt;ka legislature anprr priated $3,000.00 for a ladles" 905 $H 00 for a live-stock pavilion. ie statements are made so that you may intelligently consider our pport In the effort we intend •■•MrabiUty or pr elation? on our state fair grounds 3 grapple with ir grounds? hall for $25,000.00, a water </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Per cent of foreign em Of premiums offered, i Of premiums offered, per ct ■reign exhibitors . . </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Number N^ber Amount Amount Pr^SSw _ °* Foreign Premiums Premiums Paid EntriM EntrtS Offered Paid Foreign Exhibitor* i - 1272 257 $1416.00 $1845 00 I $249 00 ent of foreign entries 20 iiiums offered, per cent paid R ;n exhibitor 20 land-China 479 T.i $354.00 $354.00 $115 00 ri™hires 156 57 354.00 290 98.00 iroc- Jersey Red f,5ti 127 354.00 321.00 4100 ester Whites 354.00 280 .00 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 SHEEP of I F 1 4 (X 149 i » .v^retionary Ui 6 K*i r ' f| Belgian H»r»-~ Discretionary Total • I for^lKTi If premiums off. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Amount r Amount Amount Premium* A mlums Premiums P»M Paid i buyu Eiblbltort 4 li* 0 S444 m TEXTILES Amount Amount F-r» Nu - AiuuuHi Amount i of r^SIion Premiums Premn. Forelun off( , r .. d Pa|d f En: ' Exl Fab $40 50 $36.00 55 .% k, wool, 197 49 n k, wool, w 197 k, we and 42 W _■ and Hand Work 5150 49 SO ring and Hand Work -n rh 97 97 30.00 •h and Engr- : Embroidery 45 22.55 Evelet Embroiders- 45 i 22.55 40.00 IT 00 14 60 21 5d lattenburf? Lace Work 97 bur*? Lace Work 97 40.00 Outline Embroidery 36 17.08 14 50 Embroidery 36 Embroidery 130 -'7 50 Embroidery 130 Mount Mellick Em- 12 oo ierv 28 Hardanirer aud C Work 41 any rr herwi* fied 83 42 50 40 50 Work 76 4 Tatting and N 21.00 80.00 58.50 29.50 28.50 1100 8.00 nee Work 41 Old Ladies' Dep't. 16 Girls' Dep't 81 Bulgarian Work . 6 I* Discretionary 79 ti $612 00 $503 25 1337 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 KASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICTTL,Tt T RF 1 Farm and Dairy Cheese xraeMUkes 8 Bread and 6tk 1 K Canned Fniiu 10 PraMrredFruiU 152 19 12 Discretionary I'oUl </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 C V as.s W a Tota I— EDUCATIONAL Number Amount Amount of Him Premiums Offered Paid Entriei Paid $140.00 1H 16.00 15 10 '.) arder 16 16 10 i i 20 k )rawi 5.00 A 1 5 17 13 ;m ■y 360 - L ! »aid 75 LASS ' K'— BEES AND HONEY. Number Amount Amount Premiums Premium* Offered Paid uf Paid 52 $124.00 $124 00 13.00 J124 00 8 52 $137.00 )f premiums offered, per cent paid ... 90 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">I Received, account of con int of car int of hoi ant of s« int of dray li' ■ red, account of special pren. account of ticket a unt of camp permr Total cash Caak on hand Januar ni of I </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 Fl a a a RES 10U 'J" 600 00 Board of Mana^ and drayag 4.280 00 ffi - ■ ations for buildings 131 70 ill «Xt *nt and association due; 135 00 same - 1,852 14 ting 150 00 inon </seg>
            <seg id="p032">A] r Class "F" — Farm Produ Class "O"— Textiles . . . Class "H" — Pine Arts. Class "I" — Dairy. Bread a Class "J" — Educati Class "K" — Bees and Hon. Class "O"— County Collect; Class "S"— Speed Class Special — Shorthorns Class Special — Winter Corn She Awarded during 1905, and paid Class "A"— Hoit Class "B"— Catt Claae "E" — Pouli </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 FOR YEAR OF Prem $1 00 No 1905 No. 551 4 winter corn 1 m winter corn winter rorn nw 0 Premium w lm winter corn 2 90 iwn m winter corn 35 winter corn 10 winter corn 2 00 ow winter corn 10 m winter corn 2 90 winter corn 1 50 ow ra winter corn 1 90 *' winter corn iw 5 50 winter corn 10 60 </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 NKHKASKA STATE B Dale. To Whom Issued January </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 00 mal Expre; )inaha ■ zz ■hruary ending </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AQRICl a Date. To Whom If March 28 Harry Porter Cha- S' 1 Wood ruff -C RHarr&gt; Fox d Batl June 1 Mrs A E I' 7 M. ' W L. Campbell 1 Chas. ar 7 James H. Tyler * Son . 7 W. R. Mellor 101 7 The Horse Review Co... 1 7 Jacob North * Co 7 Baker Rros 7 Iowa Turf Pub. Co 105 Chicago Horseman 106 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">37 Iss Prem. for "Lad- r "Lena for 'Oak 111b of cinders. . warrant No f 1905 -wine barn. . • June expense and due on ad- — A.ss'n. 118 ■airs for mower... 50 Printing and postage pr walks. . . . 106 50 and labor on walks .... 3o. . 111b 1 46 and postage 16 75 6 88 ivery, etc. . . 262 00 Express etc 27 15 Salary for July 16 66 or July 65 00 or July 166 65 .... North * Co 4 Entry Looks 46 50 •el C&lt; 1 05 ntract, swine </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 ATI 6 Loom is Ticket I Env ( </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 m. i H ( nan lard iir liing OO ary Lot 8 90 ■ I Salary and incidentals Class "M" and R. R. ra Exhibitors' iifk&gt; 8upt. Foragp and Trans|M)r';i' ion R. R. fare ss $100 oo 100 00 112 50 ion r;i' Wondei in Class "G Claw - "G" </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 I </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 m i : 1 : i Prem. ai 50 00 60 00 60 00 41 25 baseball ty fee. Count .... Count 151 80 &gt;enslon collection ind. excess on en- ml. excess on en- uncl entr. in 2:35 en tr. in 2:35 :64 Figure sign 2 50 are sign ense of concession Expense of concession 167 50 ?lp &amp; Paint Co. 226 Glazing, paints, etc... 12 85 zing, paints, etc. . . abor with team 15 00 or with team fare Car fare 2 40 9 Telegrams, etc 10 48 'srams, etc plies let paper iting 4 I iress nber &amp; Son 275 Lumber Mill. 276 Shavings 10 00 vinps nting tching V.-Pres't and help Board 25 00 Comr. represen- ative Scraper 6 00 n ft Sons 284 Premiums 85 00 Remington 2^5 Premiums 6 00 a r) 1]nrfln Premiums 11 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OI A.G I Date. To Whom Issued. N September IS H. W. Seefus. . ■atticks </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 '18 28 40 IS 87 00 42 12 11 00 mi 17 355 117 16 75 10 00 361 Prenr 56 00 36 47 00 Premiums R M ms 8 00 ms 566 Premiums 11 00 61 00 9 Premiums 116 00 91 00 Premiums Premiums 36 50 72 Premiums 43 00 373 Premiums 30 00 T 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 NEBRASKA STATE H&gt; a&lt;;i Date. To Whom Iss No. For ;vha Issue- September 13 W. E. Wells 375 1?, L. C. Kennedy 13 Peter Johnson R. Adams 13 W. Chamberlair ank Howar 13 B. F. R lin II J. I 13 Alvit lis&gt; Jr B ild W 14 B 14 W. H. B. Van K I&gt;?w Paul .J Voi Adda Koi^f J. A. Walwor May Wa r. M. Hall G. R. Williams. H. Van Derbeck 417 13 K. C. Miller 13 S. P. Brij R. Que •rs Bros. Pony Far 13 Cba .ha Bee . ... 414 A A-Sfiap^r Union. .41 Void 416 sot in book. . </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 a What Issued. Prem. Misc. 69 50 Class "C" Supt. Class "C". 27 15 Supt. Class "C". 27 15 to Secretary and Secretary and as "G". • 32 60 G".. 32 50 423 Exhibitions . 180 00 iHions . 180 00 424 Pay-roll 313 01 oil 313 01 Class "D" and R. fare 33 10 ne 200 00 143 85 427 Pay-ro \sst. Supt. Cln -7 »o redeemed 18 95 430 Flagman 7 50 431 Supt. Amphitheatre... 22 00 432 Judge of Speed 15 00 Band.. 433 Contract for music... 500 00 4 Supt. Class "A" 40 00 435 Judge of speed 15 00 436 Judge of speed 15 00 437 Two days on gates ... 8 00 ncessions. ... 60 00 439 Supt. Concessions 50 00 442 zz i and 00 Class -K" 25 00 antile Hail 25 00 lass "I". . 16 00 md rep Hall roof 87 00 454 rnalen 466 Advertising </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 &gt;AKD N Indi'l lia \\ Onial Tw M H O H H H 1. C W A I. Sfarl. J I) ■ Dr. A. T Peters Emerson . 4!' x Wm Foster S Gen. Culver , 492 tt C. 1^. Robinson 49 K Don Russell • • 4! R State Hortlcul SoWety 4 8 C H. Rudpe 49« Es u W H A f n*n7^1 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 MEETING. K 1 00 538 Premiums 539 Premiums </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD O* AGK1CULTUI Date. To Whom ]- For What Issue September 14 T W 541 14 A. H. Smiili Mrs. Howai W. Brahai W. Biehm 14 Fred Hodman . ; Fred Hodman 14 Rayn Ra Agnes W. A 14 A T. Ft A. T. 1 \\. A. l: A. Ben Max Tou k 14 Max Towlt 14 A AK ■ Mousel Bros, Th« 14 Thoi Adolph 14 Adolph 14 (J. \\ :ik Da T. K 1 14 T K 14 Wi Wii F Hart 14 C. F. Siont 14 G. F Hart ■o. A. Ba J. I) F. 4i I)&lt;&gt;ukPr. 14 J. I) Fer 14 Shaver &amp; Df 14 Hal C. y Ha 14 Honeywell &amp; 14 Honeywell * R 14 Ha 14 Ha I John C. Do;. Alex Henry C. Glissman George W. Lindsey 14 John C 14 Alex Snedden 14 Henry C. Glissmam: 14 Branson Bros 574 } 14 A. C. Shallen 14 Ketzleff Bros 14 J. G. Brenizer 1 14 T. J. Wornall A Sons 578 Premhu 14 ('. A. Saunders 579 Prt 14 Cassius L. Laune 580 Pre 14 C. G. Nootz 581 Prpmiums 14 John O'Kane 582 Pr&gt; 14 Stewart Bros 583 14 J R Mansflpld 5S4 Pr </seg>
            <seg id="p049">49 Prem. Misc. ha 4 00 00 34 00 33 00 Clerk to Sec'y- • $21 00 00 16 00 1 00 78 00 00 ras l'j ms 40 00 uo Premiums 1 00 00 6 00 l&gt; 34 00 11 00 &amp; 00 Premium 7 Premiums 99 00 8S 00 f» Premiums 49 00 filO I .... 28 00 15 50 00 15 00 Premiums 103 00 4: Premiums 105 00 11 00 29 00 6 00 7 00 9 00 2 00 7 00 rr iums 5 00 E. K 024 Premiums 6 00 P Jacol ' -"• Premiums 6 00 iums Premiums 70 00 ( Premiums 17 00 18 J E. R </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 \SKA STATK I!«&gt;AHU OF A.GBK Date. To Whom Issued. No. For What Issi September 18 C. E. Pratt J. E. Mendenhall * Son A G. W. IJ A Plat Walter J. Robinson Fremont Matheny \ Finnigar :rnest Balr Griswold 7! 18 Wm. A. May F. \V Wittrock. Le Roy Scbmit2 M. H. Chai nani . . </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 Prem. Ml* It 48 8 1 £ 1 C 1 00 3 5( PriT 1 00 1 50 1 00 r 44 12 4 I 1 5 1 50 1 00 8 50 3 00 50 T 1 50 &gt;miur 4 Premiur 19 50 A 1 00 1 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 NEBRASKA STATE KOAKD OF AGRICUI 1 t,te. To Whom Issued, ptember For What M 19 John Martin 19 D. D. Carpenter KGeo. Car] Thos. Lockett . 9 Ed Ha: 9 Wm. J.t 9 Chas. Swartz 9 G. W. Morse 9 Mads Andersc 9 Julius K 9 L C. Peisige 9 John Brown 9 J. Arm - 9 Walter 9 Z. T. Leftw 9 Harry Schickedant 9 G. W. Humr 19 M B Atl 19 Chas. Hen 1&lt;» W. K. Ml It B. B Henry R. Hogue . Smith ■le Arnc 19 Marion Ar EChas. Schwab Vincent Arnol B Smith T S. R. F EMrs. John Thinnea. H. H. Sprague 9 O. P. Dovel . Robblns. . 9 John Vi'. 9 John Duffin . 9 Arnold Martin 9 Chas. Mann . . 9 G«o. N. Toops 19 Wm. J. Te 19 Frank Teal 19 R. J. 19 S. Ball 758 Pr 759 Pr </seg>
            <seg id="p053">53 K 1 50 17 50 1 50 1 00 6 Premiums 60 1 Premiums Premiums 1 00 mis miums 1 00 1 50 ims 4 00 jms 1 50 50 50 1 50 urns urns 1 00 50 50 00 1 50 ra 00 ims 1 00 50 1 50 1 no 5n l 1 00 1 00 1 00 1 50 •remiums 1 BO 50 1 50 miums </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 NEW AGKK N For What Issued ■ jinnard L'l f 21 Hai L'l lU - Ella L)i S. R. Gn • 21 H«- ■ 21 Lou 830 21 Mrs H Shaw 21 Mrs. If. B Millar J. A. Rudd 834 21 Mrs. W. H Gallup B Park. •; . . 837 ChaB. Smith 838 21 Mrs J. 8. Leonhardt... . 839 21 Carrif C. Welch 840 21 Mrs A H. Tyrer 841 21 Mrs. W. S. Houseworth.. 842 21 Mrs. Albt. E. Perking 843 21 Grace Hicks 844 21 Ethelyn Pierce 845 2\ J 21 J';i </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 .'. hat Issued. Prem. 1 00 luras 1 00 5 00 6 75 hlaenU. I tt 00 2 °° 8 00 audolph K ... 6 00 2 00 'ms I nims 2 00 -vine 865 Premiums •■• 2 00 I n Brungard .. i .... 1 00 luini ... 1 W 4 00 F •remiums urns 7 00 Premium! 11 00 p,^,! 1 00 2 00 Preni 4 00 18 00 1 00 ] 50 7 50 S85 Premiums 3 0() remiums 16 75 4 00 Umb 4 60 Premiums 60 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 KA8KA STA'J I&gt; &lt;&gt;1 AGKUTI.TIHK Date To Whom i September For Whai 21 -Mrs. M. K. 1 21 Blanche Kil 21 Doroiliy Raymond 21 Mrs. Clara Vallis. 21 Bessie Fox 21 Dorothy Watkins 21 Ruth Lahr n. . . ■ m 22 Berniie Heckler -:er». Iwell ,raham I B. Lahr. .. lla Pert [re. F. H. BrookB. .. Kaufman. rs. Emm* laud Duff 22 Mrs. Elisha Wl Cummins. 22 Mrs. C. R. Teft 22 Mrs. R. Hohman. ary E. Towle 22 Mrs. H E. Doollttle. 22 Mrs A H. Drain 928 i 22 Katie D. Smith 22 Mrs. A. F. Smith 22 Mrs. Lena Brady 22 Mrs. S. H. Payne 22 Rosa M. Ackerman . . . 22 Mrs. Mazie Smith 929 I 930 ! 931 I 00 914 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">REPOR1 57 Issued. Prem 50 50 3 00 ■ 1 00 1 00 K man 1 00 2 00 1 00 Premium Maud I. 2 50 2 00 Burress. . . 1 00 M. Cl - rison. 1 Palmer Ruftum I'ri'nilums 5 M niums ■ i 11 00 1 25 i'remiums 1 M Premiums 1 Premiums 1 00 V I'reniiums V 1 M ... 50 I- Brown ys </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 X K BRA8KA ST AT 1 ". BOARD &lt;&gt;1 A I September 'artha Pi( Miss I- I Clara 22 Ada Kuhn I 22 Henrietta Ben. - mger 22 M I'r. Archei 22 A. H. Dinsmorp ■pta 22 Helen \V BTO - Dunbaugh 22 Olpa Thaderman 1 run . . I -&gt;*glat Harri. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 50 3 00 1 50 1 50 1 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AG F AGI Date. To Wboin 1&gt; September mon M. I. II R Harl ( Fran Fran 5 James B. Areheru P. Bryant 10J 5 Eugenf P. Bryant 1 5 Bixliy £ Bixby 5 Bixliy £ Bixby 10&lt; 5 J. K. I 5 J. K. I 6 Mar 6 Mai 6 W. K Mellor H Mellor 6 Cha 6 Chas. Scully 1 6 W. H Mellor 6 W. li. Mellor . .109 6 Globe D . .lOS 6 Ben ton Bros 6 Reimers A ' 6 Vanderslice Bros 9 W. E. Bullo 11 13 G. F. Har 13 BransoD Bros ..1104 13 Retzlaff Bros 1105 P 13 A. C. Shallenberger 1106 P 13 Thos. Andrews 1 ". SM 13 C. L. I&gt;aune </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 Prem. Misc. a 4 00 .ecial 10 ial al 6 50 50 41 a .11 4 al 9 ppcial 1 60 ■rial lms, special 50 special. ... 21 iras, special miums, special.... 50 special. ... 4 00 n Jountv .... 1133 series 50 miums 16 50 Premiums 50 $ 16 °° -5 40 surance on horse barr 5 50 lard bill members 179 25 1144 Salary for October 166 66 Salary for October 66 00 Mar Salarv for October 1« 66 Adams Express Co 1147 American Express Co 8 Melick's Stat 1 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 To Whom Issued. hat Iss ry Co. ... Farm i ad r 8 Hammond Printin 14 M 14 Ju Willia .u m 18 J. \V. Burleipr ne Journal Co .rry \V Olfieroi E. Baker 117 int rnund F. Field ir 27 J J. Cooper as. Srully arv for I I 31 Benton Bros </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 riNu. :d previous to the for payment Amount •■ \G YEAl; Amount •(\ and marked void: Noa. 181. 1 DURING YEAH FOR PAYMENT. , PRE- SENTEI 50 •is a </seg>
            <seg id="p064">• &lt; &lt; ■ ■ \ i«i*h A </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 ?£z S * *m o 9Za fit- ■&lt;i 1 7 •_ 1 E £ i •a c \ ill 1 1 £ 2 s i 1 1 * ff * 3 M m o 1 m s 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">f R Total fron Total received from Shorthorr Total received froir fron Total received from Tota froir Total received froir ■varrat td Total all i warra ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Y E. Z. Rl CULTURK AIT? THE \ 4 4 4 4 8 14 1 A t </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 NEBKASK NF W 1 4 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 NEBRASKA STAT: ■ UICT </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 EETIN N </seg>
            <seg id="p072">'.' IARD NEBRASKA ,11! No m * « 41o 411 412 414 415 41* 419 41 42:! 424 m in 47 10 47 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">50 10 M* Mi 75 40 On XI 54:) 16 tiS 544 546 &lt;4 547 10 549 551 k&gt;:i Vi: </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Warrant No Arar. 61U 611 614 (U7 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 «* 0 741 1 i^ »» 743 744 74fi 747 4 00 7« 762 5»&gt; 763 00 764 :s 788 7* </seg>
            <seg id="p076">NEBRASKA STA'I </seg>
            <seg id="p077">•Jl 1 50 141 942 !U4 « i Ml 951 v 953 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 NEBRASKA STATl I".i IAHD 5 M M Hi 9K( MB ! M m M IM 997 s • 4 50 JO 104 3 00 104 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 MEETING. ant Nc 4 1 11 1114 112: 24 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 Warm 1141 At BO 11&gt; 1142 1164 1165 1143 1144 tia 1145 IK) lit lUti 1U7 114* 1149 1 1511 I KM 1152 1153 1156 1161 1162 KEI pansi' year of 1 • i mak&lt; ■ untry of th&gt; It i - and know the I must !»■ a record I nf Mana^ </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 PKOVKMKNT a and v. ■ land, ami ,i ■ the man. IV A ■ an! of Mana </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 fc </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 3 « II 600 ■ M •o aa 4 i-ine 1 ommittee, present' REPORT $11,079 03 19 36 $37,406 12 ilows $10,906 12 159 2,500 00 Dpp. No. 6689 2,500 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 A SKA STATE BOAK1' I-.i'l|. &lt; tep. N"&lt; Button Platea Bukli i ,tt a ■a &gt; Mr al tomorrow morr framed ft r All in favor of Motion carried and comrr lent Younpers: What pntlemen? Mr. \ inrent Arnold: I move that a to report upon the recommenda' . Board of Managers Mr C. H. Rm:. ond the r Presi&lt;lent Your </seg>
            <seg id="p085">85 Cluli. We I a Farroei la., with an IV ard that as of the w- ow morning, and would like row morning here tomorrow w have heard the motion, tint imorrow mornii 1 helieve it is the proper a wrong thing to take these retarv Mellor: I am 01 who prepared the pro- ion wealth. hird agricultural al meeting Board of Ag asnre make it easier for this -and I d. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 NEBRASKA STATE BO AH Kl say. gent]. well get the use of tl a Of course, as the lawyers say it is alwa think that we will I,.- al our w W Z. Tav owT Mel lor Mr Tayloi Mr. Dinsir a room for certainly b •tan. in of th meet at the St that we adjourn Motion was earri Mr. J. B Dinsmc Shorthorn Br&lt; • at at the annual meeting of try- ing in the city of Chicago on the 6th ol members was not as lari as in general interest. The outlook for the meeting was conspicuous by the n new to the business. The financial a hundred thousand dollars of the fu eminent bonds, and quite a good •as The matter of funds to be offer present year was left in the hands w to act. )RK that w&lt; « of allied atrrirn! out to all iij &lt;i and Mr. Riid have had a I thinK Farnr To t&gt; -entat </seg>
            <seg id="p087">A x i h aociation give a certain amount, I do was; and they would also give $1,000 a much larger amount. I am satisfied •onimend that we give $500 ve proceed to put in nomination new ring this year. p.-rsons placed in nomination: W. Haws, W. W. Cole, H. L. Cook H. Arnold, O. E. Mickey, C. M. Lewel - rshot, William James, G. R. Williams, •s Bessey, H. B. Louden, P. E. Botten- Dr. H. Pritchart Elijah Filley, L. W. withdrawn from at on Nominations : George Sheppard, state what room : them may hare was and the hour for artl are of the meeting? ny more credentials to be handed in we a where a member of meeting he had to have an three or four people whose ord has been received from ar be here and asked that cd !XCU and carried, heard from Samuel Riley or Mr. L. &gt;een that where members were not meeting their places were filled. G. R. Williams. owing Committee lan, T. \V. Smith ittee will please :^ir€ to tDM 87 to do for the Short- i«_9 ;ar? a report made to the Board. It Is ■find the premiums where the I think the same &gt;ort that they would </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 NKBRASKA STATE B&lt;&lt;AI:I&gt; (&gt;i ACItli! TWENTIJ if it is to maintair prosperity of the Vi a the farming *. large part of V in ia. Ken iana, and all s - or rich rolling prairies, inhabited foi luxuriant herbage of thf prairies all ii fertility. During the la.st i-entury tfe the merest fragment of th ■m remainiii. century With incredible toil the farm. ■ The second a ri held in the ctu Mr. Henry W. Walla A vei iry w prosperity of agricultur 1 iarnmiK of the centur&gt; At the opening of the nineteenth and wild beasts. The ma^nifi. . hurned the bri removed the &gt; Mt may 1»&gt; here in thi ■•■re tonight: ; re had t&gt;etter wait for 1 morning. Mr. Bassett: No one doulr Mr 'ion of Mr. R Mr. Mellor: We hare given further 1 mo :uorni r id M Mr YounKei adiourn will l&gt;e in or Farm tomorrow mon </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 *■ niury fan: nt to a greater or •men. diti I yf Hi- human l';i as a cla .tiled in the first ain unimpaired the virgin armers. Without agricultural without an a last deade. and without nbled on methods of farm- he requiremenl But these clearheaded ir the fa&gt; from a hem. from al mi w cultivation 'ertlllzera, heard fir Kngland lortions of Indiana. M y from Iowa and Kansas ai ■ when the furrows of the etor calls for a a he place of Ian tii willingness of the farmer ich can be said— to the credit ol t&gt;e said that as a cla- ■anno ntaining the fertility of the soil and thus putting nduring prosperity; for it should isperity of the United Sta population, nor the wealth of its extensive or valuable, nor he number and extent of its great resources of its trusts; but upon the There is a ton less of gold. mined: and the Creator has in ork of storing these in the bowels of the earth, to be He has not. however, finished His work m the raw material of sunshine ar </seg>
            <seg id="p090">AORICI 90 NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF n sonif hn mist a plain and that when in a is a more tear-furrov- ani ate pla grasses ar haustion of ferti land, and the I. way of ten of the soil is th who have failed land tl There has dou! complain to their o I to a of potash and phosphon glacia a Where this lack exists, it must be re nts of fei ■ ly and inte fanning and a supply 01 mat If the al&gt;ov&gt;- outlines of nii should not be difficult n* twenn ry farmers, if aintain thf and the pr- f the nation, of whl upon this must dejx If « </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 prop. ar sou, a or i i A an .i pt on n of pi. ■ in seasons il of water required for the amour xhai :iK&gt;(i at I a v home of man xhaiif who ma i ' that was kooU to nay farm. Tti mil wtier man has pu he humus. p him from a. farnr ftlin im.lfrstands the A B i] in his ap ther w but I </seg>
            <seg id="p092">5)2 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF soil, a; tural i i .uura all surti </seg>
            <seg id="p093">ated in the twei </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 NEB1 D (II a </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 II se the 1 compel better breeding. It Is will be grown ance from owing o eat grasi r al w ii-r&gt;-3 are rowing of a cow for Dm his pastures 11 *a ;in ■ .i ight n.l r prof ive nt of butter fa which be gives to e that he has in of what wi y preceding or of i iw annot work miracles; can- animal which might well nineteenth century brother. trraation are available far as books, colleges. \11 these are of in the mind of the think themselves whole, lo them any possible good. lick, that will benefit farming, improved annot. afford arbohydrati Jakeh: "Feed me with the ! to the ob- a the twentieth </seg>
            <seg id="p096">- PATE B« 96 inn i Y a A </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 report as follows Bow Chadron Elkhorn kville • r Ci P I. Ban 1'illev nt, Aurora }• Miner. Prcsitlen -hton linden Hall. President. Ha Presiil. Rynearson. Presiden well. President. Pawnee rown. President. Osceola Indianola r •nt. Wahoo I^oup City i A nee. President. Stanton y II Wolt, President, Gehring. Comstock I 'resident. Blair. •lent. York L \V. LEONARD. JOSEPH ROBERTS. J. A. ALLEN. Jr., Committee </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 it- it Etl! be ■I if W 0 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">I K B» *v ■ *u I = </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 each to th a it market pr i to quar make it ! ound in the office of the Board to send to the This will xhibition in third all pay lh~ .ary 1 and prior W. R. MELLOR In in change of animal." ord "and." striking on it^.l in n out and "entry txx&gt;ks" </seg>
            <seg id="p102">I a (I </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 ■ Managers and to be - e a motion that i' applkai ar were ap will have to wai t ay of the &gt;n the part Vr for the question March 1 when application departments? anging the date of these ap February would be better. V d naturally applir lir we never know when the &gt;n secure pens. iianment nment of stalls airs the b </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 I'ATE K&lt; »AUI&gt; bitor this year an In Y A might be well for this m President Y'oungers: The Bos Mr. Hervey: If we would gtri cattle exhibitors to bring a car loac classification, they could not use these an applicable and we have aken that Mr. Herv&gt; so we need not take tha on the cattle premiums. rattle and that the first first premium run clear practically t up. We have and that we a&lt; others $6. $4 $3 $2 etc., making uniform prc three and four w premium shal down th rou eh Mr Mr Boar. the It will umioi Mr the Board of Ma— p befor- and especially in Lincoln amo good for the week a for »l: as some vi family and all ■■ have some concession. J A </seg>
            <seg id="p105">z l\ V Li J r% Iff c lw / / 7 &gt; •^ \ — &lt;^ </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">o a aking the finest *,1 List Committee I t\ ike a change, but we want n from the eastern part. We cannot hi iri river, and what would be just as between all se&lt; ores were so low at the past fair re card «&gt;• irs was in the fact that it pr aste, feature. n ns made ) ars the judges were compelled time for mm par 1- \ hat we call the score card the "Ream n Committee, approved the s- ird arranged by J. D. Ream, was adopted and tt am xhibits in Class "O" being the well to say except for deco- have been coming here year ■af grains and grasses y in every way, shape •ome back year after year. Let w bundles and after the fair turn It go af grain, there is a party, whom he past ten year been bringing the r </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 \SK.\ Si Ma mi a atior same bundle Regarding the rejMirt of ( we find that the sum of $1.1 nt of an nt pa : mount on hai necessary to lie set a*ir ummend the • rsted. and that all the balance c be left to the incoming Board of We recommend that all recommen :or action to the incoming Board In relation to the recommendation! • division of the state on basis of nor said divisions must score as fol' </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 made all I. .1 P. H. BARRY Ha ;i Ma la ransportation. probal .Iy first vision I did not take ii. •ision I did not take in fxhibit. ext hat of Douglas rise the second division n their borders in 1900: about twenty : that goes between 8.000 and akes in most of the A that $2no he given for first premium and ther exhibits scoring above the req | and further, that a sweepstakes of $100 be ; i the second, $30 to the x &lt; »rd to the classification from ible for the best exhibit to al- a war eeard to this prorata proposition that the revision committee have ma! would have a tendency to lower the exhibits. There are men who would think with a wheelbarrow load of pumpkins, beets dow nd a few other vegetables and secure their transportatian and expenses w which has come under my observation </seg>
            <seg id="p110"/>
            <seg id="p111">111 ary for transportation for four was complied with and pon one adopted, what an entire shell Douglas counties ade was . 5V1 at n comparison, am w a' ffl tV w w that are poorer and 1 below S00 points last an it would make no regard to this pro- there la a </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 :: i»&lt;&gt;.\m&gt; * tea and Lar Mr M. M » Mr a ■a I men formerly; it w re up i i was nol wan not on an agricultural malic conditions ■a Iowa )W Iowa nan i - </seg>
            <seg id="p113">113 • ■ i hi way if we ation basis. at ion (v and I mo oval of the Board the Board of Managers to a agree with that report, iliai the Board of Managers will have Managers will have '■(1 in at ha panies will not furnish transportation i fall and we have XI rnisli transportation this fall and we have ay to • n down here with men down here with t and Chairman. til ;n. in I thon •President rriculture, i have appointed Mr. I ive appointed Mi ultur ommittee to wait upon Mr. J. B. Dins- Board of Agriculture. ■ard of Agriculture wait upon Mr. J. B. Dins- urn Board of Agriculture Board of Agriculture e made in looking after the interests during the thirty years of your life after the interests ave mad ;irs of your life during the h e one and all could approach you at any a and all could approach you at any ery position in the gift of the State the gift of the State very position you were just a member of the State a member of the State nagers or whether you were in the Presi- rs or whether you were in the Presi- ig iame J. B. Din ne J. B. Dinsmore, and always ready nore, and always ready ur for the interests of the great state ; grass grow where only iraska has made two blades of rests of the great state a wo bla ass grow where only benefactor. Nebraska has made two blades of •ar bfore, and I want to and I want to D brought about by the man lething to turn u of these change </seg>
            <seg id="p114">* ■ a H &gt; f I a leas ground am </seg>
            <seg id="p115">w -«* v ? ?S ns» I HfiBf I </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 NEBRASKA STA'l I a n A ai Mr ■ a profited in Whereas. The grow Whkrkas. Liberal appropriations state have proved insufficient to me* ma twin &gt;,at no mor. ment gives such generous return ustries as the money appropriated i. y a ir for Resolved. That we heartily endon in the second session of the Fifty -u further appropriation of federal fu h Cot nds f Cp and Thai so with Mm in unprecedented in tl&gt; public for maintenai. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">117 aintena \ i rhe three attend;* motion as amended was car Committee on hat I could be paying these mem- r wai Nominations, reported as fol- I&gt; for the following year are I Mickey, John F. McArdle. L. all members o </seg>
            <seg id="p118">I Mr M iry 1*&gt; lary M </seg>
            <seg id="p119">119 Treasure iiianiniDua vote Treasurer, and jiry and vote of the as- ?ar. but say Rudge; Mr. H. L. Cook. P. Henilershou en, that the appointment Ml in favor of the . gentlemen Board of Man Me it they are things to be taken up at and the Premium List Com- &amp; report. In case they do }metime In fa ing to-morrow ng if possible to- Memorial hat any who will be come forward admitted who hold arr W. G. Whttmore, In the iuced as speaker of the evening, xperlmental Station. at Dean Burnett will </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 Y ar o trar The pro the tanker, an an in lied farme i all be It mipt K which in a large way 38 of the last decade ; ? increase in a. the farmer's pro higher earning powe ,s fundamental, in va la the land must inor solution of this in recognize the m ■ase as tt y of rai land. The avera? figure the labor a ■op a v low profit and which furni.sl I methods are praci King fr Tin: rsiVEKsn \\i&gt; \ </seg>
            <seg id="p121">121 withdrawal of element* 1 millions of acres island an England and the ir th&gt; s« of cause of 1 of nts of fer fertility pra finally ruins the Ian reducing plant or li at of profit. It is a soil infli. mly partial, a ipplying mam. land, de- plant or in profit. It is a soil &gt;artial. a applying man is, immediately increases pro - .1 on your farm during ately increases pro on your farm during on has decreased, tl ns or eveniual ruin will follow. There are - ithern sta^ From a lack of knowledge of the fun- n forced into and. Who shall say that in prairie: wed and reaped no an 9 being occupied and an onight are men and of plenty because of i w h present-day conil importance alone, it is a great iper and year by year sha w her they shall cling to istantlv on the soil and return nothing, ipoverished and disin- ms n in the study of crop ■A\\ increased yields under all rota- I, The variation in the crop, the he application of moderate dress- v for two or three years. jwn to era he vield. A variety of rotations has been and the selection of large yielding Ya- yield of leading varieties avera nd oats has been to practically double the average yields of e average yield of Turkish Red wheat for the five years A while the average for the acre of Hogue'8 Yellow Dent lelds, while the average </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 NEBRASKA TATE BOA HI ' alfa static in and the fan The K </seg>
            <seg id="p123">a V 1 a i y Li a .■e and ition w ns and era studied be crown for win left jq </seg>
            <seg id="p124"/>
            <seg id="p125">125 lan double )on wheat yielded shels; winter a. ten-acre field — a Kherson oats gh tableland of alfalfa upoi sopment of western agriculture he western station barely suggest •oni The results already uch more than the money appro- liter wheat, the durum wheat ach new section to which seed has ion. The \* al work, but must demonstrate that x ■I upon ordinary farms. The exa in a country where good methods ai P - is made slowly method res monf and appropria rstood that this plant it e a few crops are grown in large areas at men are necessary to ation. True, there should be iluable, it is fair to -lion of pro ring results he mi maintenance and nnium. Nearly half of this iuct this experimental work in work must a. man of broad tiflc principles of the nowledge of bu n of the economic and </seg>
            <seg id="p126">nical kn v a a r ar r mini Y and nv </seg>
            <seg id="p127">M n a ai •an an expenditure of the his movement, it is ' the wisdom of pro\ i mold ■ ■if our in- r &lt;-an ilo 1 ami can e ran irp paid fi her rhe La shall man in -I at lire if he is convinced of the low to ap- </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 NKBRASKA STATE BOARD (-1 for which was part thf&gt; far offer an man The w on an ment of a farm. Hor ■ ata, A new men who can -ses cam*' know who have made a to the students attendant uf The horticultural interes W against insect enemies The ravag destroyed thousands of frui' orchardists and nurserymen in ill that we shall study the diseases above them. None of these things can be done w at for work The present building was is a served a good purpose in furnishing a pla&lt; in j&gt;r;i tritiuted. What we need today spread University should offer th&gt; be employed skillful in teaching the </seg>
            <seg id="p129">his time should be adequate to meet up. If this building development of horticulture permanent buildings. It is nd till growing tudents are now doing labora- es which will not properly Before a new building can in the re^ &gt; presen be offered laboratory work at ction. Still further, the es- ill add another sixt; if horticu Ic thing in the rk robs it of the instruction f use on the farm. The lieve that this pra in decreased; that It should ■ enrollment of the erect a permanent for $40,000 for this building. nporary home for horticulture .. '---~ss can not b« made, » m ard, for it cannot stand ilN'G PAVILION ivilion for stock and grain ratory, where classes in these several We also ask for litable location. These. *r,2.000. True, we haye int use. It is ent: and substantial nature Iging must proceed ire so large that good 'hen well done, no work is more practical and sses of one hundred students are now doing in a room which will not properly accommo- 'he work in stock judging now being offered is students, or five classes Even this does not :ore than four hundred ill Vip tin I'omlirion of our laboratory work in &gt;r </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 NEBRASKA STATE BOAKi ami graii work and the present ini i f in laboratories which can a h while to train a their safei riencf w in dai ractica le building I fe. and id- b in which to ti for a' for animal at a »w gra value of annual value of antn: year I year I influenced in th animals, and ol animals, and ol hundred fold if laid out u|uin il hundred fold th animal lines, it would yi&lt; !i gufllcieni work in the l"ni\&gt; i within the present biennium. The adoption of th&lt; Station would In t more thai Experiment Station and the wl Of a single farm industry The University grow man- iiire Univi ; one of ■ the aKricultural school has grown from n which was provided wl. </seg>
            <seg id="p131">131 IN It is a. I: lent, . in on the i the work say that these gran al fund is %2 _ farm .r the sub- Not one dollar if a smaller s&gt; :un lines of work he alt h and i omparable \v - for agricultural ln- ■ n about twice that ot [-(culture, devoting more ( its University alto- re far - ours in value. ag iral hall i Illinois, nmmensurate for four important can be made upon the request it is be - small rather than too large. But the lrgent. They can not wait. improvements may wait until the that time will never come. The needs )ther lines will increase year by year. itly said. "To devote public money to te it to the promotion of our prod Kinship" And so it is the broadest statemanship emotion of those industries which will repay profits on the industries of the state. ■r investment than to develop her agriculture ' last legislature, after visiting the mag- Iowa, said. "This question of appropria- a not a question of poverty or of riches, of state It is a question of disposition. We may cot sand dollars in appropriations and lose a hundred thousand 1 value of our agricultural resources. I believe in University \ few years ago. before the great state of Illinois had awakened to an appreciation of her privilege to support the Agricultural College, a body •. ppeared before the committee on appropria in this m&amp;ttor 1 1 is the &amp;trri- </seg>
            <seg id="p132">■ il associations that ask the passage of tl passage they ask no special privileges an m ■ We only ask to be a put our har vn m&lt; our work, will wheat crop w 'n Nf profit Th bra.-. entire ml The influen this be- the «■ prospo r our industries and it af* Will the tJtxpay rsity has rende support the appropriations ■n forward, inrreasinp permit to languish and . alread her wealthy, ai KlopniPnt of edur lost i ■ As our people hav </seg>
            <seg id="p133"/>
            <seg id="p134">( I. ERINTENL 'Kl \ Barn N Barn N T Frank </seg>
            <seg id="p135">135 ght stalls a </seg>
            <seg id="p136">B </seg>
            <seg id="p137">137 JARN N Imp. Co., Sullivan Imp. Co., Sullivan ran Imp. Co., Sullivan Lincoln Imp. Co., Sullivan iln Imp. Co., Sullivan hamberlain Chas. Beu- v Billeter, Burress * Co. ~ ter, Burress &amp; Co. 3 Billeter, Buitms 4 1 Billeter, Burress &amp; Co. $ y-eight stalls ai iln Itn: .ilivan Imp. C tin Imp. C Lincoln Inr illivan Chas. Casey Billeter, Bi; Billeter, Burress 4 Co., </seg>
            <seg id="p138">.^ -low Frank How »■ P y E </seg>
            <seg id="p139">139 8 full report o! as super - ■ii barns and thirty .Is; of these I coll. il barns and thirty n all 450 stalls; of these I collected rams that I had one vacant stall .Me I kept the and only had to split one herd, Wornall. and by the consent of ms that I had one vacant stall I kept the and only had to split one herd. Mr Wornall. and by the consent of he stalls until the herd arr: n the matter of location I think asked for and there was no partment. We saved thirty-six stalls that putting the floors in the attic, and with the use of ilion for five head, we got along nicely in J. A. Shade, of Kinsgley, la., ten t Osborn, Mo., and six stalls from J. F &amp; accommodate. These were all i prevent their coming. There was som ng a shed or tent to keep the nurse We had sixty of these tied to the fence &gt; very hot two nights, and ide to cool them off. I would ;i polas placed on each of the barns that ly afternoon matinee seemed to please 1 by the people generally a judging card to be used in all live mistakes creeping in in making x&gt;kkeeper and in calling the classes in x&gt;k form, and each superintendent it the close of each class and at the close of exhibiting; and if there aade, the Secretary could refer to the the entry card, and if it correspended -onably sure the books were correct, and if not, the books then and there are superfluous, as they are n their class, and do not require they are shown in their class and win first place rv an mal for sweepstakes that onnous amount of work that he Board for their very </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 I cuus i it'Zl * m *yi t 1 1 om s t sp* lO rln i s o only for the press of m - durii ist that takes me away \r for th a am awav ait \UK Juij. P. O. ord« Checks i ■ ota ho, the office and would be glac </seg>
            <seg id="p141">141 SWINE PEEISTENDC.NT. Num.. September 12, 1906 Managers of the Xebrask . mit the following report ie up of more good animals than that ivere shown 1,428 animals against 1,431 he Nebraska state fair. illl «fore, but the rule nder six months keeps x )r for better quality to the exhibit. I would in force. ip as follows: 9WS 27 head. X hea x 616 head. hea 90 head. ead Id a S head of hogs. Eid of hogi &gt;ts for pens in the swine department was $561.00. in the swine department waa $561.00. ure no entry be required for sweep- no entry be required for sweep- mi premium animals be permitted to premium animals be permitted to earn their eligibility as the show &gt;&gt;■ earn their eligibility as the show n posing a fine upon an exhibitor for osing a fine upon an exhibitor for l out ken out EON'AHD, Superintendent of Swine. HEEP tenil.fr 15, 1906. MER, N rintendent of Class D, sheep, begs to not as many exhibitors, and they were of full better he sheep men are keeping up ainly indicated by the flocks they I were not pleased with the money nh money and add it to the other fo ask to h o have the competition clause cut out to have the judge say in each caa*. </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 for prizes, again in noaejr prizes with one 1" \\V ask for a n anna KUV ask that th in the name of ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p143">' </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 13. Oiv an erg from who wa J K F! Deak Sir w Har Stalk corn, tm \11 ear corn and best crop There are fifty strar agricultural display to one at The fourth premiur wants it and makes ••d east and west for th exhibits. The western couir ■■twins a class where conn Yours truly I L TH II H r. w blacl. hnlleM. Potato^ and o Stalk corn, two olasse of S. -is tt </seg>
            <seg id="p145">145 LE DEPARTMENT KIN Nf aber 20, 1906 ard of Agriculture B at I should give a Textile Department, I cheerfully showing this year, my belief that our 3. work showed off to ar ral comments of fair visitors, and aving had experience in these affairs had a small space devoted to them, at needlework, and fancy p confining their put up according to the w m list. The county revised their pre- state premium lists as far as they were y- er for the good of all, and splay our best colored ork to better advantage, and credit to 5V e economy of space. Our exhibit was more worn hoods, etc., having dia- The newer styles of embroidery &gt;n showed the ladies' ap- mi lis ion. AH the assistants eir efforts to assist in giving entire facilitate the work. Our department awards as it could ever was wholly justified In about the article being re- mium List I have called should be printed to ar epartment, but all members of apinion that the article was never In rned over to owners except in one A gnified her intention of calling for her work ally recommend a third premium in Kensington Embroidery, as a mendations, aa the work and nuni' a </seg>
            <seg id="p146">146 In just one entr Ell not merit as large a premium as w&lt; mendations On &gt;wa ar li an a A hopin altout $132 in prer </seg>
            <seg id="p147">147 V lilies were x in They were Had there been any a ■ii first premium Ann Jenkins, Walton. jmmend for full pre- j. f a difficult and effective pa have the "old ladies" well taken an and a widow, and I am sure ;nd for money waist as as t he bo n raom- - as the books r st last year for the list; perha hirt waist last year for &gt;n the list; perhaps I ndations. Class G, Textil ndation (comm M r . LADD CHANCES IN PF EMILM LIST appended note on old premium list in regard specified, etc.," using the word fit. In article in regard to "Lots mmend adding "5, 7, 9, 12, 15 and and 16." as lot numbers read have numbers read 1 compl not rightfully belong under the nays hav t and woolen-knit rugs, as all the rugs Household Fabrics, and Lot 15, in Old handmade" after "Baby Outfit," erstanding, also "not less than 6 pieces." ear distinct from above," $4, $2. Add "Sofa patchwork, tufted, velvet and old ivill be distinct from the entry which fol- 3 n places indicated on old list. is style of embroidery is very addition of articles designated. See </seg>
            <seg id="p148">148 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGR 1 In Lot 7, add to the entry "Battenburg lace named above." (See old premium list appen appended. In Lot except »uch as are not otherw a rules at the beginning of this Class I which is really Kensin enter ir wt belones. That w larger tha for th For For cei For sofa $2, also ' H was ri 12, * av more systemat In Lot 13, would recomi and larger and mo added some distin premium list an ■'point lace flchu," and pir In Lot 14 (See old mar In Lot 14 (See old mar entry 'tatting lace ' to "a- entry "tatting article not named above," as yoi In Lot 15 and Lot U article not named at In Lot 15 and L respectively, both of which I ar recommend additions. I have appended a rearr recommend additions. I have appended a rearranget out the word "cotton" In two of t out the word "cotton" In two of to include linen or silk crochet: In Lot 16. the "Girls' Depar made in the second and last two Items not being completed, all perhat would like to add the two items, "Best 3-plw above, $1.50, $1.00" Also "Best Ba places Indicated in marked old ] Ing Battenberg center-pieces as \&gt;T&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p149">149 l EPAf r a :a i a must » wl Embroidery not other nbroidery. Perhaps Shailnw Em- I ahead of w and find they \ ntry booka i n also where i premium awa a-- booka if am justified lee fit to add Board n pportunity of going over them most willing »rd. I w m&gt; Old Ladles' and MRS. C. P. LADD MEXT D; a premium, second or fi award excee as merit may 1 half that stipu - i-onimittee must aware •ason for awards. All non and change he Board of Provided, The Board of have power, in extraordinary cases, w h premium premium; red ribbon or card »rd third premium; white ribbon or iremium; orange ribbon ;il purple will be uaed. lasses A, B, C and D; otherwise specified," articles arly (or specially) mentioned compete with its kind — satin h Kensington, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p150">150 NEBRASKA STATE B&lt;&gt;AKD OI ,\&lt;;i Articles in tl. i which first premiums I awarded by thi ion will not again be Article required to be made within I Ix&gt;i :ie exhibitor. All work i No animal, or arti&lt; nipete for more than om silk knit mfu: silk knit nit:-. silk knit infa: woolen knit It woolen knit slippen woolen knit mittens woolen infants' socl woolen knit infant - woolen knit infants' hood woolen knit skirl woolen knit cape or shawl woolen knit afghan cotton knit bed sprea knit tidy cotton knit doili cotton knit lace, 1 yard or mo collection of knitting di- 12 pieces Lot 3— Croteheting Best crotcheted purs- silk crotcheted infant silk crotcheted infant silk crotcheted infant ,aii Competition lin Urtl- H Bilk silk patchwor. solid quii porii' ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p151">151 MKE I 1st 2d Pre. Pre |0 5 1 1 ard or mo from above, not le: ivinK and Hand Work ■ 1 rwear, distinct from abov&lt; 1 ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p152">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD &lt;•!" AGRIC1 pillow shams Bat tern berg sofa pillow display of 12 1 r pillow si. apron . tray cloth six doilies table cover . . . sideboard scarf dresser scarf . sofa pillow . . . display of 12 pieces. </seg>
            <seg id="p153"/>
            <seg id="p154">154 SKRH TATE B&lt;iAKD &lt; * 1 \&lt;;i ■on E Best lunch tray cloth cent- six doilie sofa pillow display Best luinh tray cloth six doili sidetx&gt;ard sea sofa pillow Best lunch cent- six doilies tray cloth sideboard toilet mats sofa pillow Lot 1 table piano lunch cloth center tray cloth . six doilies . sofa pillow laundry bag pincushion . handkerch &gt; sideboard scarf dresser scarf . pin &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p155">155 I 1 1 :: i iliovp. not less than 1 00 1 00 1 00 rom above, not less than 1 00 Indies' Department years nishe.! . .$3 00 $1 50 finished .. 400 200 norsted quilt, finished 3 00 1 50 finshe&lt;t . . 3 00 1 50 00 1 50 00 1 50 00 1 50 1 00 50 1 00 50 1 00 50 nu 3 00 1 50 ■a&lt; 1 00 50 1 00 50 yard or n 1 00 50 x 1 00 50 wine </seg>
            <seg id="p156">156 NEB] -TATE !&lt;■ </seg>
            <seg id="p157">157 y + ate, w We w 1* 3 i so. T methods use i a a and w of purpose and i the line it ave had both Class H. C&lt; Originality is system- ch encouraged We are very another field, en are here drawing jgnlzed at for our last re able to pro&lt; the Lincoln Ind of work fr m was asked ructor of drawing h was tha the Lincoln xcellent object lesson alon these lines i in teachin wing in our iw from objects and memory nal designs by the combination of lines and awings made for The first icoura- ait for stained tal work and em- ither, rr e water colors and crayon drawings Phis section of r Board to allow the addition work, to be iched to this report.) If the would suggest that the jcted to communicate ate, telling them of the xhibits from their respective ihould be given as soon ast state fatr made since I jcators from different sections of </seg>
            <seg id="p158">158 a Ii. ra w hat a Ar pa report an P No animal or article can co; ruort in s»w pstakes or coun By original is meant drawings or pain or studies taken dirertly from nature i Professional is defined as follows: An luneration for the same. Single entries can not be entered in In &lt; hat lot '/** Ml, irtlih IB »K ' • </seg>
            <seg id="p159">159 2d 3d Pre. Pre. Pre *1 25 J 50 1 1 25 1 1 1 50 1 00 1 1 00 1 50 1 00 1 50 1 00 1 50 1 00 1 50 1 00 1 50 1 00 a 00 2 00 1 00 $1 25 $0 1 1 1 00 arcoal $2 50 $1 1 1 00 I 25 (^olors 1 25 1 50 1 00 1 50 1 00 1 00 1 00 1 00 1 00 75 1 00 1 00 1 50 1 00 76 1 50 1 00 1 50 1 00 1 50 1 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p160">r ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p161">161 } 5 *1 On »O 50 ■&gt; $1 00 Id 75 $0 50 5 5 • • s </seg>
            <seg id="p162">SKA STATE BOAKD OF AOBK J B~»' an .•..., fru .» I«. A A B. a» </seg>
            <seg id="p163"/>
            <seg id="p164">164 vA STATE BOARD &lt; &gt;! boo bon 'an karri r«am and sugar plaqu comb and bruib tray balf doaen platea. ■ iiv.-ntional plate with figure plate with flowers cup and saucer . . naif dox«n rupa and saucers half doses ramekins IBJH ■!. ti.. </seg>
            <seg id="p165">165 n let 2d Pre. Pre ; 2 50 1 50 ... 2 50 1 BO 2 50 1 50 1 60 75 1 50 75 1 50 76 . . 1 50 75 enamel on glass 1 50 2 50 1 50 1 00 60 1 00 50 1 00 tO 1 00 60 1 00 50 1 00 60 76 60 read and butter plate* 2 50 1 60 I 00 1 00 1 60 1 00 1 00 76 ieces 2 60 1 00 -China Painting or Ceramics Amateur List 1st 2d Jd Pre. Pre Pre $1 50 $1 00 »0 50 75 50 25 1 00 75 35 ash tray 1 00 75 36 75 50 25 75 50 26 76 50 75 50 25 . ... 1 00 75 35 sugar 1 60 1 00 50 75 50 25 and saucer 1 50 1 00 50 ... 1 00 75 35 ... 1 00 75 36 75 50 25 75 50 26 at- . . 1 00 75 </seg>
            <seg id="p166">166 </seg>
            <seg id="p167">167 Pre Pre. on of the sam $3 00 $1 50 00 1 60 00 1 50 00 1 00 00 5i&gt; 1 00 1 00 50 1 00 1 00 1 00 50 50 25 1 00 50 60 1 00 60 1 00 50 00 1 00 50 25 ap $1 50 00 1 50 00 1 00 00 1 60 1 00 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p168">CARD OF A&lt;;i </seg>
            <seg id="p169">169 1 y ar &lt;va iS 1 60 1 00 in natun s: 15 retionary. red, of what is not provided for In ulass window.. $2 Ou $1 50 $1 00 • Exhibits ot Public Schools. All entries must be properly matted Vater Col' lBt 2d Pre. Pre Pi •a from still life *2 00 *1 oi&gt; J U00 or 1 50 xoo 9 from : es 2 00 1 50 It. rs from fruit 2 00 1 50 | ,00 ayon or Pencil. •il rom still life *2 00 *1 50 noo rom flowers or plants 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p170">170 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICT Hf CLASS I— DAIRY K WILLIAMS, 8UPERINTE • and Board of Managers of the Ne report for tl It is to be regretted that the dairv our All I w inp to ina) that this class at a the expei number v Bid have the la. spa my heartiest thank fair In the history Very &gt;-BR., N braska d&lt; re whc ows entered in </seg>
            <seg id="p171"/>
            <seg id="p172">172 NEBRASKA 8TATE BOARD OF AGR1' I Class I, G. R. Williams lows: The rules whit o to take into a necessitate a too (iifflc the contest was to b Bpective of breed in chance to see oure-bn bred dairy a a good fat, and skim-milk at fifteen made by the experiment station. THE ANIMALS TESTE Twelve cows were entered in the Jerseys. The breeders who exhibited in this 1&lt; body. Kansas, Hoi ,hn C Doubt, Ha I Any and all thoroughbred cows are i Cow to be kept at option of owner, a ee times a day, but shall be fed, wai ler the supervision of a comih As nearly all milk in content ar m-mill these five cents per pound, a pri """*■ «*«•»«■, "oi- ,i, n C Doubt, Havelor H C. GIlRsman. Omaha. Nebr . Holstelns, and H </seg>
            <seg id="p173">173 »m their home* to the lair grounds ineapaci- elr best Nearly every cow In the teat was was quite detrimental to per- Kiven one lor aged cows and one for nals so that seven aged cows and n*e nning at 5.30 o clock orning at 12 Wednesday noon and sis possible during the remainder of the m each cow for just forty- m each cow at each milking wu samples were taken The results of the ana and other data are given in in the amount of ation rom milking to milking. The to the excitement and ay surroundings and different ws because they could not do their was valuable to the thousands of animals and watch their perform- </seg>
            <seg id="p174"/>
            <seg id="p175">175 4935 — HOLSTEIN. :iass B, Lot 10. aged cow*. uigust 15, 1906 Days by Milkings &amp; * ~ &amp; 4 $1 088 lass B. Lot 10, Aged Calved. Jul </seg>
            <seg id="p176">176 Cora Pc atf 4 I'ATE Hour Owned by H. C. OHssman. Omaha Neb Fc VOUDg, I i Febr 1, evening 5.20 r&gt;, morning 5 evening -;, morning 5.50 .1, evening 5 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p177">177 ings 290 I ■'■ ass B, Lot 10, Heifers. F A 0.165 LI) 72118 — HOLSTEIN. - B. Lot 10, Heifers. M likings 4 K 18 in 0.068 I 31 2 005 $0 501 60.2 $0,090 $0,594 in Class B, Lot 10, Aged alve'i August 24, 1906. Product ■Sk Vaiue ™£« 251 205 0.051 564 0.141 229 0.067 </seg>
            <seg id="p178"/>
            <seg id="p179"/>
            <seg id="p180">180 NEBRASKA STATE BiiAltD OF AGR1CULT U Mr. W. K. Mellor, Sec'y State Board of Agriculture. L Deak Sut: Enclosed herewith find report of Class of appropriations made for the Nebraska !onal ex I. First. If will not have ran m Second. If number of depart amount of spa Third. An dated. T exhibit will no Fourth. In preserve work for t early In the year w nouncement &lt;&gt;t befori much better pr&gt; t Fifth. The increase y.-ar liberally fo a Very trul E. C. BISHOf To prize fund, Nebraska tacbed report GENERAL EXPI Mar. 5, Harry Porter, 4 record April 24, Griswold Seed Co., seed 24, Griswold Seed Co., seed CLASS J— EDUCATIONAL steps be t^M for i To prizes awarded, Nebras 906, as per attact </seg>
            <seg id="p181">181 A isped envelopes k 4 iT ii la&gt; )m Kearney and days lay 4 00 40 00 a iterial 9 00 * </seg>
            <seg id="p182">182 NEB] i: HiiAKI Dec To Ja: Jan Apn May July Mm Mia 2,330 short Minieograi'.' Stencils, 21 at 1,700 Nov 12, lo stamps stamps 24, lc stamps Dec. 1. lc stamps lc slam]* stamps. 82 Nov .,ng sheets mim 24. 150 lonp sheets min. 245 total, at $3 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p183">183 ETIN( M bousar :: 5 isan $10' ar,\ »iioo no $itoo oo ND APIARY GOODS F TENDE Friend. Nebr.. September 10. 1906 'ite Board of Agriculture. Lincoln, Keb.: ie 25 of general regulations relative bmlt the following report In relation Goods bow of 1904 seems &gt;as 1905 and 1906 exhibitors and since the fair nor a single a- xhihltlon from without the xhibitors within the state has offered, and it has xhibitors to show their goods, and nds usually remain at home jorrectly we have he past twenty-three yean. ass we were flatly told w feet of common Agricultural Hall where om hat time this industry n and better premiums 3f the attractions of our ve that there was any how and that the hone that the honey interests were oducers must exhibit their own honey this class. We recommend that </seg>
            <seg id="p184">184 s a Of tli' E department mu aequaimai could save botr ■ There are son;' while there ■ rdied by a thorough kn le sho be allowed spa' </seg>
            <seg id="p185">V </seg>
            <seg id="p186">186 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Ol n •pace and also as to the matter of transportat should be I have not fully decided as they are matter very carefully I believe that all of our exhibitor ness that they got while w an «xpense that they were I I would dislike very . .1 I would dislike very much to see an; tend&lt;-- it down tt tende? : down these displays, but on tht miKht be ma: miKht be mai thiirounh' thorough h t! transportation I am of the opinion tt only be a paying inv uld help in a np and transportation ■ I am of the opinion tb ■ building xl buildii than to i depend in ing anxn Board. I rer rriran S horse Anderson M ch( A Co.. lot 7. south at Auiui •■ &amp; Tt Brick Acme Mar A. IJ. Bal. an Broi Brumley Steel F Banner Bu Bridi. Bart I pern </seg>
            <seg id="p187">187 i r A iv a t check lpons ■k </seg>
            <seg id="p188">188 NEBRASKA STATE BOAR1 timnian Impleni Linebarger. 1 &gt;T, Linninger Imp. Cc earn for hay Ann Arbor Machin Lincoln Plow £ Im Lincoln Mfg. * Dev &gt;rs' C H I Tht Moon Bugg) Marshaltown B Moline Plow Murr : 'rill ( T. J. Northwall * Northwestern T P W O'Conner. showing with K Has C Oskaloosa Saddler Omaha Light £ Pow Parsons Hawkeye Co., east of Keys I Parlin. Orendoff t Mar checks. Pattee Pin Parsons Band Ci in Lint Pioneer Imp. Co., lots 73, 74, 8 cou| Page Fence Co., fence exhibit grou Porter Simplex Block Machine, n&lt; Peru Plow Co., west of cattle barns R. H. Quick, fence exhibit grounds, J L. Rowell Mfg. Co., lot 41. 4 Racine Sattly I team, 1 check. ea • . lota 7, 9, north annex Rice Bros., fence exhibit groin Rock Island Stove Co., Fraternity str Rock River Mfg Co., fence exhibit South Bend Chilled Plow Co with L n Implem ■ &gt;n Wagon Pella - Reeves Co.. loU 21, 22, 23 upons </seg>
            <seg id="p189">189 N double team team night watch hecks, 1 double team rth annex, 2 coupons, 1 double team. oupons, 4 checks, 1 night watch, 1 upons, 6 checks, * Heat nee exhibit ground, 2 coupons exhibit ground, 2 coupon 8 coupons, 9 checks jns, 10 checks checks, • ns. pan jupon i. howing with Pioneer Co., 1 coupon. 1 night watch. neer Co., 1 coupon. 1 nil rth annex. 2 coupons. 1 rth annex. 2 coupons. 1 double team Y COLLECTIVE EXHIBITS AND AGRICULTURAL EXHIBITS AND AGR HALL. LL. COLE LTERINTENI'I jnrf Board of Managers of the State Board of Agriculture: superintendent of the Agricultural Hall (or several year* the opportunity of Judging closely. I feel that I am In a was managed better anri presented ■A nee I have had charge of it. Al- tted space was shortened to accommodate all exhibitor*, 1 good taste in arrange- \ ;core card used and mode of judging w be adopted and all exhibitors given to them in the future, yet I regret that tv his mode of judging was used this year, for reasons which I will ex- as great dissatisfaction among those exhibitors \.s and whose exhibits this year were annual report in 1905 on page 144 you guar- ar </seg>
            <seg id="p190">* 3. H I »■ I w I &gt;• </seg>
            <seg id="p191">r. </seg>
            <seg id="p192">192 CASKA STATE BoAKK (U A Kearr Richar Prank] ke, in Dr I go Mowing Vcstalp Aha I)il ily Maiiien I </seg>
            <seg id="p193">193 </seg>
            <seg id="p194">H NKBRASKA STATE BOAltD 01 a </seg>
            <seg id="p195">195 If a. ■ irna has been fully It may ami la a w an n rul and the hoi N. J KON1N SHELS AND NK1 NI&gt; •KROG &gt;wn with i\ W OI.I </seg>
            <seg id="p196">196 NEBRASKA STATE BOAlil five years, and wa&gt; of soil that ha The n, lint I ■ ■ shallow ami at last ' </seg>
            <seg id="p197">197 large weeds which iains to keep the and es- a. dry on said county and upon which the corn and delivered na, Neb. That the said tract round. These affiants further he said Harry us acre measured by not present at the said elevator &gt;ad him delivered and HENRY DREES WH. SIEKKOTTER CLAUS SELK. sach duly sworn, Sarpy and state acquainted with Henry Olderog inder direction of </seg>
            <seg id="p198">198 IK,.. I </seg>
            <seg id="p199"/>
            <seg id="p200"/>
            <seg id="p201">I UK CAROLINA POPLAE </seg>
            <seg id="p202"/>
            <seg id="p203">x ed, a ade. O 'Y w v na; f .1 which, on net from the common c&lt; is a mere variation or sport of that species n or sport ot tnat - followin ITION OF THE TREE broadly heart-shaped, prominently ser - veins rather prominent on the under and both surfaces are quite smooth. The dark green, and the petioles, which are reddish, as is frequently, also, the vigorous shoots, the leaves are often five to hes broad, and their petioles fully three inches shoots, the leaves may be as small as three breadth, and their slender petioles may be ne angled by narrow. iorky ridges which extend and sides of the leaves. Color when mature, are much more prominent on very vigorous wanting on those which are slow-growing ntually become smooth and round by the if the bark as the branch increases in thick- This brownish color should serve to dls- a Poplar from the common cottonwood. m\ which the matelv become wh: rown or "top" of tfc rather narrow owth of the branches. Left to them- .1 to grow upward somewhat as tn ar. bat by no means to such an extreme. Even when been pruned back by having the terminal branches much and somewhat compressed shape. nally prepared at the request of the United f printed in a somewhat revised form •f of the serv e rases ■ aary paper, which may be followed by a </seg>
            <seg id="p204">204 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD O* AGRI This erect tendency of the branches and compat this tree, is in marked contrast to the eommo branches are much more di\ • crown ■ SS f-'UIIlI! wise resembling Trunk. — Darker colored (browr in which the trunk is prayish. Flouers — Only the stamina which are com] slender ar color, but as the Rapidity of ( a strong and v length of six ness a 1. normal fo same rapid grow velopment of ang when sprt and it may w The Carolina life, whieh rend well fit - and make far n not as pretty an nmcult to mal • and it is a cruelty to the w to compel them to wa live and grow rapidly is a boon to th plains. It matters littl as fine looking as Am his family some patches This is the allsuflU olina Poplar today, wh the most beautiful ■ few years I observation </seg>
            <seg id="p205">205 PI.AI NA I row rapidly, than )W a rable trees. Here f otherwise more desi pest," when we take into the we take into the lie shadeless houses, and the houses, and the pon the theory set forth above In he theory set forth above In ?ottonwood for a quick shade. Of wood for a quick shade. Of »es were not as desirable aa elms, the i«M grow, and were not as desirable as elms, could grow, and athers was much more difficult and was much more difficult and otted over with eottonwood groves, over with eottonwood groves. Ith the quick-growing trees, which he quick-growing trees, which w tie village houses into comfortable was forgotten, and the trees, now age houses into comfortable at was forgotten, and the trees, now otton" in increasing amounts, the ncreasing amounts, the i red by the cottonwood trees in the &gt;y the cottonwood trees in the r&lt; roublesome cotton which they now psome cotton which they now •ou a many a village the cottonwoods any a village the cottonwoods ten who as boys played in the shade ho as boys played in the shade hen to be seen — the only shu to the cottonwood which ultimately iely that of shedding a disagreeable ainst the Carolina Poplar, since only at ion. With a more rapid wn it nuisance, this tree must commend quickly-grown shade he dr r olina mmon cotton- areful calculations as to a ommon species of At 10 At 15 At 18 years years years 11 12 12 6 12 LM have but one-half the actual ion), and supposing alnly not the case) it Is still any other of our common trees. It the Carolina Poplar will yield mes the heat value of Ash, </seg>
            <seg id="p206">206 NEBRASKA STATE BOAItl) five i •re qu is cone ,. t m tre« old w I AltJU'k is appa Hons a valid «d in detrimt already tree, even UHfl the n from tt It is the op question of the va recent use prohalily did bi&gt; given in order fr ring sometli ar Br»t edition of the original d&lt; m-ork. pulilishPd in II improved, while he name Pa The mmc Carol i a Popla Arhres F us firs- </seg>
            <seg id="p207">207 \ I tame 'Carolina Pop ire now eonsiit' 1a and Georgia, says that "the young or by the are not effaced for </seg>
            <seg id="p208">208 1- </seg>
            <seg id="p209">209 heart- ultures only rown »o or more a lied th For some time an one • a by Marshall in 17S5 This an y an sna Poplar Carolina am i..i jlant w of the fore answer seems to be i] r&gt; that this Western Cottonwood Cotton wood" and 'Yellow When the tree is and tougher, but as a. yellowish color, and loses much of branchlets. ording Poplar and the &gt; Poplar . My and i "Yellow Cot </seg>
            <seg id="p210">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGlt which ii years, an anguiata. Appar the a Eire </seg>
            <seg id="p211">OF LINCOLN AND VICINITY LLOTSON nt. State I'ntvereity </seg>
            <seg id="p212"/>
            <seg id="p213">the University of Ne- a making of a list of the n, Mr. K G. Steele and ir and then becoming what sp to mat 1 trees were growing in uake a list of such trees as we To do this we examined pretty ts of the ty those at the State Farm, owing along Salt creek as far 0 not els at this list comprises all laim Ic, growi Of the growing sre, for it is highly prob- )f the trees which we found, thirty - seven are native to the United State*. rty-nine are native to Nebraska me are n &gt;s growii rees are ■ wing along Salt creek, it is inter- owi ng, and the majority of n, at the State f it the SI arm, or at Wyuka ceme- it one ti a im( part of the open prairie lat these n pecially those in the 1 from tt ii winds of winter- ly serve serve to bres ak the force of the wind rmth at t the tr at a from their chimneys. fr nn the hot winds of the i npfit from the prot. iear it that it is claimed that the smo iust of a city. In all ■u: nt of smoke and dust w actors seem to exert no &gt;win£ he tvins h - h probably th her do the trees suffer t:h j&gt;roba the larger per cent of the gation is practiced little only a fraction over twenty-eight enough wa ;:,.j r nee d. The nough wi mportant factor in determining the species &gt;rtant fa&lt; on. Bro Broadly speaking, the surface soil i red, loamy clay, which is un- xiu idy subs ive been drawn and verified from aI ani1 ' ihraries. In the arrangement of B followed </seg>
            <seg id="p214">214 NEB1 II * .4 densely pa This growins I --a branch S..|.r ;i about rut a Leav looking tree w -prea native to I trees in i the state tree which attains massiv neral appearap.' liardy and .iroueht r the sandhills repion beavps needle-shap a sheath. This tree T. ponderota. which i Pinut tylvestrig I. Pine Me-shaj rut I Laws. Bull P Lea\ I smpulorum Rydp. Bull PI rrn Nebraska an •lmpnR of this tree may be </seg>
            <seg id="p215">also an excellent tree to the United Stales. </seg>
            <seg id="p216">216 NEB1 E ItoAKI) &lt;H AG1 * or, ar of a r; &amp; f (■ark and I raska. r i*o planted near a </seg>
            <seg id="p217">217 ular 4 inches long, smooth svhite and smooth except near base Kh and dark grey in color. This tree i K&gt;thed, or, on vigorous shoots, ivide, and more coarsely toothed A'inter buds very resinous native to northwestern )ns of 5,000 to 10,000 feet, and like of this tree is IMILT and silvery-white beneath, 'i to 5 lobed I Y. ir in outline. roun&gt; apical and How poplar. It makes a mnK tree on the lawn of the residence &gt;r acuminate, half clasping the stem, dull ted. Flowers white or pinkish, almost (&gt;read- feet in !. :ke so much moss. Na- ver maple owing to the color of If It is not native to the United States, more d than those of the wide. Winter buds h. and very resinous This tree is not tight I &gt; be merely a vari&gt; to northw&lt; raska. The tree is northern Often . -row-]' onwood. ellowgrpen above, paler below, 2 to 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p218">NEBRASKA STATE I » </seg>
            <seg id="p219">219 n and a all around, sparse How, v in color. The on ma )nd V gradually narrow* oles stout, ' 2 to % .luring their first . The and ma seen at thi sma inch an&lt; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p220">220 Leaves oblong ends, irregularly hairy on tl or low tree with and a! ir FAMIL » » » na m. hal ilarker. deeply furrowi-d. ami lnoken ir wood. This is a pr is native to e;i about 14 inch loi.. </seg>
            <seg id="p221">221 Eibove, silvery neath, serrate. ins. Bark smooth, and is Winter buds a 3 all European Lindens, is dis- Lindens, is dis jy the fact that the flowers are e fact that the flowers are linens, which is a marked he stamens, which is a marked A nice specimen of this tree Twenty-seventh and O street*. Line nequally cordate, serrate, 2 to 4 times longer than the imen of this tree cv cordate, serrate. a a 4 tim longer than the pendage, tomentose, globose, and ntose, globose, and , rather dense and appendage, torn s a pyramidal, rather dense and a pyramids e Lime" o: ite Lime" of Europe. Like its shade tree A small specimen Europe. Like its A small specimen f cordate, serrate, smooth and axils of veins beneath whitish, axils of veins beneath whitish shelled, attached to a wing-like shelled, attached to a wing-like ds red and humped. This red and humped. This I ly sold here under the name of under the name of ™. narrc t apex le base on one side and shorter and shorter y doubly-toothed, 4 to 6 inches othed 4 to 6 inches when rubbed one way. Winter way. Winter tibed on Branchl ttened. Branchlets slender and slender and one for lawn or street planting awn or street planting ter, and because it is free from otmd. Native to Ne- free from a Tid Native to »art of the Elm. icted into long, slender points, ted into long, slender points. nort, oblique on the other, more rt, oblique on the other, more Elm, coated below, pspecially on rai it ns. with v ad, roueh when rubbed either </seg>
            <seg id="p222">222 ATE 1 A.RD </seg>
            <seg id="p223">223 aped. Brani o &gt;a&lt;l, fia «t olor ■alyx A £S ir a at the apex and gray and sep- ash-cf' Bran wn very oods A sn may sliphtly grooved </seg>
            <seg id="p224">224 NEBRASK : BOARD ii nt petioli nar ■t Ihe base, and ■ i Brt&gt; open par las ar i oth« n- Leav r Cata to China .Spath. Japan H A hvl w flowered pan This is a Catalpa catalpa Karst. Catj Leaves hear the lower surface Kidribs and prima: heir T»rth. Flowers on slender peudi&lt; ;•' inches long and broac wide, plentifull&gt; Leavi but are much larper an hardy. Original and firm. n am </seg>
            <seg id="p225">225 ( V wings, termlnat- tbick and 10 terminal o be beautiful a ardy this far xcept that they o 20 inch"e long, Seeds 1 Inch wings, rounded at the ends airs. Resembles the common ilso a southern one, but is much Jrows well this far north, but i3 ern part of the state. An ex- Apple Famixt Ast aflets 13 to 17 in number. mded at the base, sharply per and pale on wide. Bark a narrow, round- lawn planting. are doing very a lard in texture appressed and &gt;wers white with sters on wth pubt - Qt for many varying in size, ta- The pear tree bat it is more up- haped head. Native r rounded at the apex, usually &amp;\\ t \v in 1 \e\\ oH </seg>
            <seg id="p226">SKA STATE BOAK1 ar inrh»-s » ir *, I 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p227">227 upper, pale p-shaped minate at Flowers \» in diameter, along streams Native to ilarly sen k in textui 'orming sharp ■ own lo nearly black. of many snap* or pitted. Pi . Flowers white, about ith the lea -:ance. to Europe. the l.ase. I ides. y so. th or on short s when ripe, varying </seg>
            <seg id="p228">228 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Of AGRICULTl Prunus ceratus L. Sour Cherry Leaves ovate or ovate-lanceolate, vario or acuminate, rounded at the base, very resinous when yout h« white, % to 1 inch broad lateral, very sea with the leaves or before them. Fruit globosf (larger in cultivation w brownish-red to dark The cultivated form Europe Prunus padut, L E in loi base n. 8 to 10 mm. broa diameter, on stot Bhru! western par abruptly acumina sionally rounded above, paler &gt;h inch in dian. - many-flowered r.^ almost 1 1 Bark dark, not a beaut contrast when plante.l Prunus persiea Sieb. ar Older bark greenish B appearing before the leav maturity, grooved, the I r common peach. N FAMILY N Cerci* canadensis U. I of the fruit roi. planting. Nath Prunus bes developed into a cc Prunus *&gt; L*av&lt; - Leaves broad-Ian pea preen, 4 to 6 inches Leaves almo- ■ n of axi: putx- w, 3 t </seg>
            <seg id="p229">T N AND VICINITY. 229 h. and in clusters of four to eight arating into thin scales This is a small tree. a very ornamental tree March to May it is which appear before the leaves rees may be seen h pubescent petioles. Leaflets ase, acute or slightly rounded ark green and lustrous above rk green and lustrous above, long, % inch wide. Petioles long, % inch wide. Petioles r and roughened on the surface and roughened on the surface a reading, somewhat pendulous. eading, somewhat pendulous, lally armed with stout, rigid, This is an all-around good lally armed with stout, rigid, This is an all-around good b. It is very hardy and can It is very hardy and can iraska. Not subject to ins*- va. Not subject to inse^ ■ i Coffee-tree. 'o 9 pinnate, the pinnae Nativ* rn Ne a Kfntucky Coffee-tref n n P licuously enlarged at the base, abrupt tip, especially when y enlarged at the base :na a inipt tip, especially when led at the base, dark green inches long, and 1 inch at the base, dark green h led by small, persistent scales, olored lenticels. Fruit wide, dark red-brown. Seed !I an w ark red-brown. Seed *ere once used as a subs' used as a subs- Leaflets 5 to 13, distinctly j to 13, distinctly nded at the base, dark green ith, 1 to 2 inches long. dark green, remaining - which is distinctly stalked. at the base, dark green ■a inches long green, remaining so in distinctly stalked Its flowers and g branches. Its flowers and black locust in appearance, well in rather between H anil J in appearance veil in rather ween H and J r puberulous petioles </seg>
            <seg id="p230">1 !&gt;♦-» » I a </seg>
            <seg id="p231">;i » k </seg>
            <seg id="p232">This tr&lt; Trees w A L. Box F Lea a A 1 a a A arp-f r Kdark es lo- v nativ a ate Fan Rhus typhina L. </seg>
            <seg id="p233">233 \ base and surround- Leaflets 11 to 31. ob- ate, long-point arly white on the lower hairs on the under to 1% inches Sap milky, turning black on airy, and very pithy. The autumn makes it a Native to eastern Sumac a &gt;n he petiole and rachis gla- ite or oblon lanceolate, 2 to 5 inches long, the base, dark green above. at Drupe overed with short, reddish. hape glabrous and somewhat glau- 3s which are white, hoary-tomentose ■anchl Leaf scars heart shaped here. Its fruit has a char- imonly arounc icld taste. Native to Nebraska Nuttall. Wild or American Smoke-tree. all. Wild or American Smoke-tree r slightly obovate, thin, glabrous, or sparingly pubescent ate, thin, glabrous, or sparingly pubescent m-hes long, I 1 ™ to 2'i inches wide, obtuse at the apex 2 to 2»-2 inches wide, obtuse at the apes. y decurrent on the petiole, entire. Flowers green, about .• decurrent on the petiole, entire. Flowers green, about n large, terminal panicles. Usually most of the flowers ] large, terminal panicles. Usually most of the flowers le their pedicels lengthen, branch, and bear long, plum; :«ht. and feathery or cloud-like bunches, either ruddi Drupe 4 mm. long, oval, compressed, ■ all, widely-branched tree, native to lengthen, branch, and bear long, plumy irge, light, and feathery or cloud-like bunches, either pe 4 mm. long, oval, compressed. ill, widely-branched tree, na&gt; * ■IILY JUGLANDACEAJE. Wu.ni t Familt. Black Walnut with hairy petioles. Leaflets hairy petioles. Leaflet shaped. 3 to 3% inches long, 1 to 114 sharply toothed ex- hairy below, especially n rowth covered with rusty, Bark deep, rich-brown color i Nebraska One of high value, the nTal-oblong. pointed </seg>
            <seg id="p234">234 NEBRASKA STATE BOAKIJ </seg>
            <seg id="p235">235 1 M for park l The only are growing on the t large tufts of pale Acorn inclosed only at Dn and In with short, pin-like f the deei Nebraska, but does hes broad, sometimes with small if the veins below Fruit solitary eta broad, inclosed for 1-3 sta-brown on the inner surface, a narrow, open head, and is planted brilliant a iaK &gt;ase, usually . a 11 or some- furnished with small ath. Fruit solitary or a br&gt; gradually narrowed and nch wide, usually *. shallow, saucer-shaped cup, reddish- 3 being highly orna- produces wood a Native to Nebraska sh Oak ■ .etioled. with S to 7 rounded lobes on ish-«reen beneath. 2^4 to 5 inchet jb long, slender stalks; acorn ovate or embraced about one-third of Its length a a anches are rather stout and l is the European oak of » ■atment which ■p sinnses. rounded oothed ami inust*a, ro (&gt;d aiul hi it me to 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p236">236 seems to grow well in this portion of Nebraska. A sma be seen on the University campus Quercut macrocarpa Michaux. Bur Oak. Leaves obovate or oblong, wedge-shaped occaa rounded at the base, divided by wide sinus* nded a sometimes penetrating nearly to the midrib int &gt; 5 to 7 lobes, the termina lobe large, oval or obovate and regularly scallc pc at the rounded apex, covered on the lower surface with soft r •A cence, 6 to 12 inches loru inches wide. Fruit usua varying in size and shape; acorn half to three-fc a cup which is bordered by a conspicuous matted or mossy fringe. Bran lets covered for first three or four years with corky wings. A tree wblct reaches massive proportions an ■r. appea especially in the winte Native to the eastern ha . • </seg>
            <seg id="p237">Hob OF IMPROVING DILAPIDATKb STRUCTURES V ERWIN H. BARBOUR </seg>
            <seg id="p238"/>
            <seg id="p239">1 I I ■ ■ ha ■ h;ic! never t ■ v the house and liav T reiuiir. for thr t btful if it I S </seg>
            <seg id="p240">240 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD Ol A( bare been sold for $."&gt;0. In beha writer undertook to 1 rejia the writer _• that they will find them ■ In order to im I w amateur worker in head eardener of t rn undertook, witho curled an'! regardless of breaks and era&lt; of break ra lumber and rof Rlen lumber and ro - } t*-d over with that |) Wire lath was next nailed o rips aho hes wi. nailir . and t» Nails are better to be covered over with tha Wire lath wai i ai (tripe abc : lonp. Tl Nails are better th lath can 1» lath can be put properly lathed 'oat c properly lathed the first coat of cement was trowe w hand ro as to maki' .-■&gt;ml key hand so as to make crood keys, and at tt cracks and loose joints with c cracks and loose joints with w coat is. in fact it ought I better for the sueoeedinj coat is. in fact it the better for th scratch coat. The "scrat bi.rat.-b coat. The "scrat wire nails through wire nails throuph a small wo&lt; trowel will do. V scratched before it ! scratched before it had set scratch coat is as follow or five part Id do i In carrying out t 1 or five pan In K untrained amateurs, not as prof untrained amateurs, not as A were probably not made and I re hiphly t ent recommend were probably not made and tr hev were \\\irh facturers of cement recommend of sand, thi of lim« of sand, three mea f state that some mas ir leas complex the better it is for tl In mi \ i tic use a platform an box. Put ' V shovel to completely mix J ilK water and turn over rej&gt;. th the made that will spread nicely under th and the amateur n ably pood m </seg>
            <seg id="p241"/>
            <seg id="p242">242 NEBRASKA AI'H </seg>
            <seg id="p243">243 ath, sand, and iding a lar including it walls. $46. Total of labor. all cost that it baa n the ' that sheds, out- their results to the and publish reports for the city park when in **rt.slcH \i J &gt; y*. . V| </seg>
            <seg id="p244"/>
            <seg id="p245">REPORT OF THE ZOOLOGIST. B. WARD. BIOLOGIES 0 THE RHYNCHOPHORA OF NORTH AMERICA. H it.HT PIKK&lt; E. </seg>
            <seg id="p246"/>
            <seg id="p247">K » ■ » i a i WARD </seg>
            <seg id="p248"/>
            <seg id="p249">fruit, seed, stems, and I&gt;e t ant he encounters at He has to any extent mself tha hborhood n inate and technical nd f the six species of ar ne: 1 • were proven to be the D of the boll v onstrate clearly that al ption of two new xc Guatemala, and a Are definitely and a a A' eration of ouisiana. It is not posed to be native. a par an alter their a no necessity a doubtful value, as far as the boll i fact in most cases l present discussion, ationships of n n a Mex :h breed freqi,' most striking fact aitiffl a flight equal nnapH tn I ip narivp. </seg>
            <seg id="p250">1 » </seg>
            <seg id="p251">251 </seg>
            <seg id="p252">252 NEBRASKA 8TATB BOARD OF AGRICl (Scott and Fiske 1902:33). Collected on wild grape 1895). FAM1LT III. AlTELABIDA These weevils are leaf rollers. The adult mat after laying the egg, and rolls the cut section i a nidus, which dries and falls to the groun decaying case and pupates in the earth or •ar Attelabus anah on oa (Hamilton 1895). Rolls leaves of oak and bla Oklahoma: on ap Nebraska (Brun Juring ral bage at F leaves of </seg>
            <seg id="p253">253 A.MKI 10ms (Forbes). On xas. On cucumbers '&gt;ria, T 8S injuring goose Helianthus at G rley Texas, Ma injuring musk er ng onions at Madisonville, Tennessee at Symrna, Delaware (Chittenden a ling on plum trees )tato (Weed 1888); on radish (Corn- Virginia, and feeding on stems enden, Osborn and Mally; Gar- 3 plants at Locust njuring toms 1 and the writer. On watermelon wr t Found in ballast heaps at Sydney Hor Not rar ' at Sari Fran a sir yas v Texas, on Hud a, Texas, May S, ia by J. C. Cr»w- grape ( Schw*rz a wrightii at Ca i Long Island and awbprry (Beuten- (Beu bark of apple and pear Hamilton 1895). </seg>
            <seg id="p254">n«i ■ ■ . 4 / zz </seg>
            <seg id="p255">M ■ i ■ o </seg>
            <seg id="p256">NEBRASKA tTTAJK BoAHD &lt; )F AGK1CULTURI njuries of thit a that the adults feed on ach, app ■ the result thai back considers nit that th appearance. Trees severely injured in 1903 w«i appearance. Trees severely injured in 1903 were killed ir ■om root injur are laid in masses among the fallen dead lea are laid in masses among the fa No known of the immature The species is recorc known of tt a May peach and pear peach an- found. The species ha.- Gra rid Wharf' Aphra tit ni lia and I phthalmi. 83K 8330. O oak and pa re and peach at Dialv nine upon fallen fol to nine upon fallen fo!i;i The egps hatch in from The eggs hatol month. They hatch mostly about the middle o- month. They hatch m&lt; on roots, probably of o of sticky paper around on roots, probably I ■a per around - Tril- i rythropus elegant ( ythropus abundance on Pinus ttrobus ;&lt; abundance on Finns ttrobus at If lostylus tenuis Horn. Taken on Griit a. Nf stylut tenuin Horn. Ta Clarendon. Texas, Si Fo Clarendon. Texas. S' bers at Victoria, T« Mitchell. bers at Victoria, Tes ' D. Mitch erus too rom lenta and other plants in pa lenta and other plants in palmetto tl l wck In copula June 9 (Townsend IS In copula June 9 (Townsend Trib&lt; V Promecopini. 1 jn The larvae probai ■ roots of lepumiiu of lepunr C O A i * t* *i sf i/J (JfifJ II Q f i i J r } t r° T*^fl \~i T*tt \ Tl t) f^^Hirt €F f Tl 1 tt f" Cr A nil TY\ VtAp* </seg>
            <seg id="p257">257 Enterprise, Florida, in May iter found it in large num- Loganspon, Louisiana. At C. M. Walker and on A mdant on leaves and branches aves, June 5 to Ju nsiderable numbers asso- Kansport. Louisiana, by the writer a tBeutenmuller 1890 INIDAI nae. E n the larval stage )ver and lucerne in Europe 5 of fruit trees at Portland, at Dallas, Texas, August 8, f clover (Beutenmiiller clover and lucerne in Europe ■arth around roots of shrubs \ nai atet from small alder bushes in muller 18* H rina imetimes quite injurious to Riley 1871:57). Feeding on i (Quaintance 1899:58). De - und twigs at Sidna, Virginia and hickory. The Found on beach numbers in the galls anil I iy 14 </seg>
            <seg id="p258">258 NKBRASKA STATE BOARD OI AGRICl ! a ga I - Apr ■ ttl IN catch i - ha m I at th in ■omp n 18405. A. walshi Sm. Bred from ( s Conte and Horn 181 8411 •or( EHorn ; in Low- Kb are i a- 1 an val period proai'hPd Phi Ltrvm&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p259">V 259 n on Rumex brit- alks a :iin and Pacific slope sveral species of pine, ng in deformed ound to upper aving the usual am. • Pupa- I terminal, same year. The Hi value In ath of the injured Ash I: ar Wellsley, Ma- </seg>
            <seg id="p260">260 NKBRASKA STATE linAKIi ■ &gt;V AGRICtI 1 8474. P. fatdatut Lee Attack saplings of Douglas bark toward the base and tm by boring beneath tb opkins 1906:253). i! 8475. P. a/finu Rand. F und in bark of w /'. ilulnux Kand Arvae n large saplings of balsam li (Hopkins wt Lu.s p k of the stumps an (Hopkins 1 at k8479. Hylobiut pale mps and roots of 4:34) Beaten frmi 8481. /. Hi/pomolpT p 8483. Eudocimui Css twigs, i -a k of injured and re an elongate, gall-like sw row or gall. 'I he leaves and derson 1904) 8494 /. pa ckier in California i 1; g corn at Shaw tyltui , N. M.I i bwdi also in th&lt; Rumex critpus and I: was bred as a primary paras 69; Q MM (Rheum rapo&gt;i f iarva and the pupal cells are ma the earth, the top of tlic cell lyii breeds also in l //&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p261">AM Kit I and the writer found this spe- m at Clarendon, M&gt;5. The writer also found it breed- Texas, in October, 1906 The eggs are ■he plant feels the attack it forms he attack it forms int. thus allowing the larvae sufficient larvae sufficient *■ twi umeter of the stem and ?ter of the stem and &gt;ng. The adults completely fill the The ad mpletely fill the t of the head and gradually work them- gradually work them it &gt;ernate in these cell* A Pyralid larva rery fond of Lixu* and large num - usumed by these caterpillar Say was the commonest at A Pyralid larva n i and large num caterpilk. ire consu m a was the commonest at e parchment cocoon at the side of the the following May A archmen at the side of the wing May A tma tylodermatit Ashm., Ceramby na tylutlermatis Ashm., l&gt;ha i re bred as primary 1 latter also at Dallas. I See Plate I, E. Hinds and W. W. Yothers have found taehj/a at Victoria. Texas. At Dal - tri/ida. The eggs are laid in long at V oria. Texas. At Dal- ■&lt;i. The eggs are laid in long alk. the rough scars on the outside inn e rough scars on the outside indi ie hollow out the entire hain o w out the entire stem, sometimes form - vils emerge from the old probably in June. Weevil larva&gt; Inhatcli' Acre still found at m, sometimes form- merge from the old probably in June. Weevil larvat- n. on w 11. riter found the first pupae, at Dallas. red at Victoria, T i pri- i ii&lt; I the first pupae, at Dallas bred at Victoria, Texas, as a prl Cr., ' and . and I from the en bred from the &lt;'r is a probable parasite ( Hopkins n at Dallas, Texas. June \ntonio. .May 4. by the m a probable parasite I Hopkins Dallas, Texas. June I Antonio. May 4. by the « C. Morgan ; on strawberry at Denison, I on I s at Kerrville, rratut per end of the burrow - from the * m h y- sm, and the adult </seg>
            <seg id="p262">262 </seg>
            <seg id="p263">263 II AMERICA. Arizona: found by H. G Hunter and Hinds and Hinds 1904) I Hamilton IS:' ■ I in July from t i April ] from Cecidomyid and L'. ' ■ i are as far as known flower far as known flower ar the groin 11 n • i ata ( Hun 'ata ( Hun- 011 cotton at Gurley, Texas, May - ■ I nmla at Clarendon. Texas. Texas, Ma\ on at Gur v Clarendon. Texas, wthu* i the principal host the principal host ling on the tender leaf buds during wliiig on the tend, r leaf buds during The earliest larva was found by W. \V The ovipositioi he earlip.st larva was found by W. \V The larvae feed ii • ■(1 in the lij a hard cell of excrement. Wh« ed and the larva, finding itself on the larva, finding; itself on the nd forms an earthen cell. In tin May Ma ilat. the w • urn! as late a The W II. Otlaon at Arling - and the variety known '. F. C. I 'ins an earthen cell. In thii he writer found n otinrt as late a The \V H. Ciilson at Arling Plate III. roun.l. T Hamilton in. Texas. i Hamilton N't hi. Texas and on .!/■ July Har </seg>
            <seg id="p264">NKBKASKA STATE BOARD OF A.GRICTLTURI </seg>
            <seg id="p265">HOPHORA OF NOHTH AMERICA. Lee. On Ambrotia (Hamilton 1886:114). Breeding and parasitized by Bracon smicronygis Ashm. mm.. July 24. 1879 ■ Hil.-y 1890:350). This species «u Morgan and C. R. Jones at Victoria, Texas, from Cuicuta August 1. The larvae enter the ground for pupation, re- welve to twenty days. (See Plate II arthe aken on Helianthus at Oklahoma City, Okla &gt;y F. C. Bishopp. flatus Fabr. From .s'a/ix discolor in Wisconsin, 01 or in Wisconsin, on aenicher (Knuth:3t&gt;9). * Dietz. Taken by W. E. Hinds on cotton at Victoria Taken by W. E. Hinds on cotton at Victoria. id at Baird, Texas, August 24; and by J. C. Crawfon Antonio, Texas, Juii' Group 3. Eugnomi Group 4. Crytopli. this group are found in low, wet plac at Baird, Texas, Augu t 4: and by J. C. Crawford oup 3. Eugnomi jp 4. Crytopli are found in low, wet places eratus Lee. Two specimens taken on Abutilon sp. anc in the lower Rio Grande Valley (Tow Gyll. Tl is semiaquatic (Schwari Lee. Two specimens taken on Abutilon sp. and wer Rio Grande Valley (Tov Th is semiaquatic (Schwarz i ii on Lemnu I Hamilton U Stenopelmi. II Semiaquatio ( Schwarz U C!rou|) 6. Braehypi. enopelm ii Kii »tlc (Schwarz i a sp wa. ahle damage he writer. On Jhi. isuming the ably o a miafiuatic. One W E. war </seg>
            <seg id="p266">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD I ■ Otuloccphalu ilton 1- On hazel in Nebraska, c Lake Han ■ite and Horn I" .1/ i H8.IT hark ■po •as.-s iron ind. T at Corva is K-.-n.-ra '. V H i in a a i ginia. and paras PI III i imopt ( Riley ] - Tril^ 1 ■ The speoies of this </seg>
            <seg id="p267">A 267 </seg>
            <seg id="p268">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD "1 AGRK I I </seg>
            <seg id="p269">'Kill AMKRI' macha I 3 f appl sa of the limbs &gt;a 1U hwar Louisiana, into read is through xas, an in is the only 1 he limit of cotton ound, where the le foliage. Hibernation ally occurs in the adult. dart n the adults, the adults In laceous on l oilosa. in n ; ibr., in Guatemala and Texas, attack a fc t/hi ii'licd hamaecrista Willow. Larvae yaeglobuli Walsh, n gal h 18 ect which for and eastward ill. Cot luarps or bolls, iseas Huh and Pediculoides ventricosu* in Texas, atta larval staf are Ashm. in rosigalphi = ■ ■ in the bud, he ground ( Lug- </seg>
            <seg id="p270">the lea a I A a T it ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p271">OPHi jnsiderable prolifera- nterior of the anthers, m by means of its ex- sfa I remains in situ when wc or the flower to all. although sometimes i nerally pupates after the a 1m four days. Townsend niir nit of Solatium, eleagni- lit Diaz, Coahuila, in July. ti abundance from plum and peach r ■cords Sigalphus cana- which he calls the plum gouger found around Victoria, as been at Tlahualilo, Mexico, by njurious to pej&gt;i &gt;n Indian corn in the iv subs und to attack it. This f nc pper weevil possibly iden - ed July 22, at Tlahualilo, is been found breeding in nd Bourne. Texas, between - a wart-like swell- about prolifera any I from exuvia. . from ,i nd by C. R. Jones and and September 19. 1905, breed- i nuda. The weevil oviposits le, causing several bracts to turn nd forms a compact cell from he action of the gum of adult emerging from the he writer breeding in the and Eurytoma tylo- from the Clarendon ma- L jund by C. R. Jones and as </seg>
            <seg id="p272">272 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGBIC1 Ki heads of Ueterotheca subaxillans. The weevil's biology is exactly j allel to that of the preceding species. It has been found par* Eurytoma tylodermatis Ashm. 8*57. A. pauperculu* Lee. According to Mr. Schwa bw4i in the buds of Riddelia A. molecvlus Casey Virginia, a ing to F. H. Chittenden 8665. A. nubilut Ler. According to Mi from A$cyrum hypenroides at Plummers Island, Maryland. A. tettaceoiquamosus Linell. llected in hea flower buds and on stems of Abutxlot, -urn, June 1 Tt weevil probably breeds in I if this plant ( Tow 1903 K). MM. Cnemocyllus •!■ atttly from Crataegus by Dr. Hamilton Takei: n at V Texas, by W E Hinds aito July 13, by W. W. Yothers in DipterouB galls ol on B in a twig gall on Bi 11915. C. ligatv- Koeberlinia iptt. July 3 (Towns* 86C1 Psru . - lira- ■:. V 11019 (Kalmia angustifolia) wht July (Forl" Staten Islai Ta Ts al Linn </seg>
            <seg id="p273">KllYNCHOI'Hm. M»KTH AMEKlt A. 273 I arucus Payk. On willow (Hamilton 1895). Aca yptug carpint Hbst. On willow (Harrington 1891) Tribe X. Prionomerini ■^ay. On hickory during July in Can- ada (H on On oak during June in Pennsylvania (Hamilton l Tibe XI. Tyehiini ulmi Lee On elm August 5, 1874. Makes a noise that of the plum curculio (Le Conte and Horn 1876:214). hysanocnemit fraxinx Lee. Several females collected by Mr. 8 i ash trees in Canada (Le Conte and Horn 1876:214). Infests Nebraska, according to Professor Bruner. a, eolus Lee. The same habit as the preceding. The mis Tyihius pupate in the ground trdiduu Lee. This species breeds in the seed pods of teate in Texas (Sanderson 1904), and in B. leucantha pods Louisiana. At the latter place larvae were found June larvae eat the pod clean, sometimes two or three occur- they then eat their way out and pupate in the &gt;ae and teneral adults were found in cells in the ground Taken on i at San a at Morgan. U Abundant in prairii Sanderson h Utacks the fruit of plum, feeding fouml or ruphulana and Yerbatcum Found in abundanee on the stalk of I po Eieuten- 1 anil Alter at Ladonia, nd on at Ardmore, in Florida (Le </seg>
            <seg id="p274">274 SEBRASK tICULTUKI Tribe XIV. Laemosaccini ■iiens of this doubt w taken on stalks of Abu- urn at Santo Tomas, June I June 1S&gt; two specin found in cells nside a deac same plant and one on stems of a live plant 1 stalks. A specimen was taken by Wkkhai 'ton stalk, Jui Iihypor The w« The in the groun Beyond it habit Beyond this there la some are stem weevi and some fruit •-nmuller 871 and some fruit II inhabits »a (Beutenmuller 8713. ( mondii an mondu ann (Townsend 1* (Townsen thorn, plum. i» thorn, plum. , The egg punctm the fruit and pupa the fruit and pupat mom) montt while he larva- whil. !i»- larvat pum ! and 1 Dipterous larvae to toll a Tachinid. is an impoi its host. On J i adul found larvae of punci Dipterous lar\,t in impoi it« host. On July 6 two adui Say. Tli' I- that the writer thin i that the writer think flexus in Maryland, the lai og up&lt; within a few inches of the surface, an earth (Chitten&lt;ien a last of May laying i the partly hickory (Hitaria glabra\ and during tt which hang down, wither and turn I "common on hickory, on the lea\ ■• larvae </seg>
            <seg id="p275">275 &gt;RTH AMI N&lt; It hole uvae in the quince ground, pupating II. .Mi lining alnui and the </seg>
            <seg id="p276">276 NEBRASKA STA'I : . &lt; .] I Brecon thysi, , T Fa , I Ashmeaii Texas (Tov The sr*&gt;. Instead of i beans, and strii •on wli was I . Hit Texa- I 14. b&gt; As Marcli The lar 4 la. and I 4 kills portion and fo Tylo inir in t' South M Indiar on Jur i'Ula. ami feedii ■i foun </seg>
            <seg id="p277"/>
            <seg id="p278">278 NKB1 &gt;AKD i \&lt;;i ! </seg>
            <seg id="p279">279 It II AM EH jf the blue thus From Iris verti- larvae in the seed pods in grapes, the larva feeding lie grape when full was found breeding in the as. The first larvae were found ained Ma&gt; Bret adults were . The puncture is B of injury, until about •ed. The : one when the flower opens and merous larvae were found in the open and but few were dead. t as they grow they become yellowish. power, emitting a liquid lator ave the bud before open- although the writer has arva I Pupation D the ng made, with the head end The larva I ground and three ai least which w.i n of tin- was collected It. Jont ation near water (Har Found on 3111 Mav to July, according to Chittenden Abundant on Oenothera biennit mill- </seg>
            <seg id="p280">280 NEBRASKA STATE BOAKK OF AC]:! UF Group 3. Ceutorhynchi The species of Ceutorhynchut breed in the stem and enter the ground for pupation 8838. Ceutorhynchut rapae Gyll. Injures cabbage at Racine. W son, injures kale at St. Charles, Missouri: taken in lar ge nun: Sitymbrium ofilcinale : turnips and horseradish at Washington (Chittenden 1900b:39): on cabbage in great numbers at Glasgow. M aouri (Mui 'rom Bursa bursa-pastoris at Cabin Maryland (Chittenden 1902a:78&gt;. The larvae burrow he sipd the cabbage mainly, and when full grown leave it near the surfa the ground to pupate in little earthen cells Ompkale livida Ashm. ha.- been bred as a primary parasite at Tennallytown. D &lt; 8852. C. $&lt; his sr D. C, on horseradish, mustard and Barbarea bar ■ stanleya in I'tah. ai C. cpanipennis III. Frot tacks mpiii/iis (i bage. rape, and hoi C. hamilt tendfi 'A plants, cabbage, ka breeds in roots of raj*- P IV l-hyluh in E water on the fllif" plan' plant a vi- a wa </seg>
            <seg id="p281">281 H&lt;&gt;);.\ NORTH AMERICA. R. Jones. Taken on m (Hamil- X. B n roots, channelling the roots ace in the larval burrow Ambrosia puilostachya at Vic- Morgan. May 13; and on Helenium tenuifolium- at Bishopp. J A specimen probably of this species was inadense at Ardmore, Indian Territory, August ThiB new species was bred from the roots of at Dallas, Texas. On August 15. 1906. the writer arcf numbers feeding on the tip stems between the A vils eat out a little cell between two heads and there •oneealment. On August larvae were found bur- On October 2 a pupa was found in a root asey. On September 17. IMS, the writer found of Helenium tenuifolium 17. 1906, the writer found Casey. On September breeding in the root breeding in the roots of Helenium tenuifolium renr of all stages found w •re parasitized, mainly by re parasitized, mainly by Four specimens beaten from Cnit lant in palmetto thicket at Santa Tomas. Texas, copula on the latter date (Townsend a psiloxtarhya at Victoria. Texas. May 13, and Morgan, and at Terrell. Texas. June 9, Bred in large numbers from the roots of Mon - as, Texas. On Jun- • the writer found 4 the majority were in the adult stages. &gt;n ( larvae and pupae. They evidently hibernate in these Tt mental period is at least five months a Boh. Collected on Aster at Jacksonville, Texas, Octo- i Jonf imiar Linell Taken on tida at Punta 1 nftnis lected or &lt;laminefolia at San Mav 4, bv </seg>
            <seg id="p282">282 IJI&gt; Ml v,l;!' \ 8886. P$t VSW p l&gt;er Y P \Y I » p«rmj . aiiul- M07. Madarellut undulatus Bob. I L 11142. M. cuneatus Casey. H- ito Tomas June 10. L4t&lt; • Eitt and J. 1 at Di Hin of f '■ </seg>
            <seg id="p283">283 Only n th A and September, n Ion M ( are primary ii Dallas * ■ *• an il a a I A • </seg>
            <seg id="p284">284 NEBRASKA STATE BoAKK Of AGHICULTTBI ium-album Say. On flower : l«r ISM). Taken l&gt;y Robertson on I purp\ Kne\/!Ui f as a pollen feeden. /' . KnetffUi fruticota (as a pollen feeder i. /V linifolium. Hu rta las a pol | (K Ki HelianthuM at Mathi.s. Texas, Ma \V Morri Hit.' asey. At l.ni:aii&gt;|r Hehanthus at Mathi A Mo 1M6, the writer found large numWrs of l»06, the writer found large numl • ia snectea m Hudbrrkia hirta aii Kudbt i kta hirta ami IM on tip plant at Pan- I Also taken on the former plant at Paris. Te\ I a Bishopp. on yu. nd At -h Durant. Indian Territor ■* at A i$tera m n I ra mxtltxri i Join April tt (Hm era), ami ) . and on (Jone Texas Ma Texas. April 12 ( Bishi ;as. May Texas. April 12 i Bil ■mopus a ' r inoput alt (Hamilton (Hamilton Pachybans m Pachybarix San Dieeo. Tei ber L! I). 11178. Ventrxn 11178. CentruiU tkium virg aid as a : thium ltrgimcum. and Texas. February 1 (W. E Hinds Texas February 1 i\V E Hi. San lo Tonias Town m 8936. L. valra Lee. Tolle 8937 I. Found in wet localities la. or dei.' Pupation occurs in ' par May 894 Minioi </seg>
            <seg id="p285">285 a paychodes in July i of larvae were iy A. 0. Morgan. groun pupating between The larval period Ma period from 7 to 10 pupal urasitized by Sigalphus zygu' d, evidently within r cocoon at" 1 emerge May 3 r-nfore in tl d from. jgansport, Louis - . Numeroi jne ti a y warz 1888 raiaq a Halaninina Sta a all nut weev lowing spring. pate in th ;i a ack to hazelnuts in is of biennia ting oak ( white i annual ing a an is confined to and 9 adn Ell adu 4 larvae. :! papMe, and Tl adul ) it thalic Large quan id », It nto the gro and spin tl jmmeneed t( round 15 erries after the aaks (Chir as a rule, and ies was br&lt; v C. K JOI </seg>
            <seg id="p286">286 BOARD "I AUUIC1 r stray exampli B 4 B son 1 n 1 as H </seg>
            <seg id="p287">nmull. also bred owpea lui he writer pae and an adu an adult of n Indiana, the adults anted in marsh land the firs and Adult For ■ I asionallv </seg>
            <seg id="p288">288 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICULTUK1 ia Fabr. Depredat ored wheat Subfamily II. Rhininat Found under bark of Yu and Horn ii'Orus sp. "This doubtless new as tal In decaying trunks of Yu at Yucca F xa Wirkham took over two hundred from one trunk. They vary greatly a in size. The small ones occurred near the bases of the trunks wl standing upright, and the larger found farther up. Onlj one or two larvae were found, and a few pupaf of adults, all ins he season of their appearam a •^aten from under vuoras logs " (Tow and p. states in oi H I. i poplar tret- i Har walnut bark in Pel i Ha - Ho Say. F . rees at Enterprise. Florida i I nr M \ and Horr found by Srhwarz \inder a log: on the south end of Padre Island, Teza June S. Eleven taken under on the same date finding a coloi le, fla </seg>
            <seg id="p289">289 a in T P Platyp sometimes into th of numerous speci Florida Keys. This genus lives only istline, not on lagoon coasts. It lives in colonies under &gt;inp (not oak) in Florida, or wood without at the larvae can breed in it The weevils g to the wood when turned over, and places. The genus is Antillean. The Kl mitropical (Townsend 1903:99). ves under bark of dead and de- leaving wood of deciduous or coniferous Boh. Found attacking hickory in Pennsyl- tisus Say. Lives under bark of dead and de- wood of deciduous or coniferous Horn. Found on sea shore at Cape Hen- Horn 1876:340). ylin Tribe 3. Rhyncolinl nides Horn. Lives in trunks of wild cherry y muller 1890). on birch, willow, elm, ash (Beuten- Horn. Lives under bark of dead, decay- nen beaten f'om Clematis drum- Rocks Resaca, Texas, June 25 (Townsend 1903:99). narinus Horn. Maritime; lives in old boards and I 19 Mann Found n the wood of Prunut wr- willow bark (Packard 1890:599) Boh. Live under hark of dead and decaying Taken from old maple and poplar stumps Bred from denuded oak (Harrington 1891). At - naple stumps (Packard 1890:381). Family IX. Soolytidae. Subfamily I. Platypodinae latypus are known as "ambrosia beetles. mpositus Say. The adults bore into the sapwood and heartwood of dying hardwoods and coniferous tree* (Hopkins 1904:15 la Boh. Lives in decaying wood of cot- </seg>
            <seg id="p290">290 \ki:i:.\sk \ si aii: BOARD oi AC Subfamily II. S&lt; Tril Tomi Zinm. A sugar mai a roots (Hamilton 1 Ho Pa of Pit art Th galleries from central Inn ■apwood at: vita*, and grand of Pit the thicker I&gt;ark on th a central entrance burrow in tlu white oak (Hopkins from a large, central chamber in the liark a of twigs and branches ot r Hopkins II - Lee Kxcava radiating primary galleri. of western pine (Hopkins 1M4:1 9074. P. nifirfulus Mann Excav from a medium-sized central chaml oak a • HopK ami appi. ard !*■ ■ apple, but a'- Injur ber (Hopi chambers in sapwcx iteg and ( CM galleri* dinal chamber in the ' sparsus Lee. A" 9071. V </seg>
            <seg id="p291">291 V.MK! adiating. curved galleries Monterey pine. an ne. Sitka spruce, and nioun I a w Kl ngrav merous radiating gal- A ne bark and surface of wood e (Hopkins 1904 :1 At hells of foreign nuts bred from June 14. breeds in Marct preceding from dead fig in grape and oak in New Jersey (Hamilton 18H." "ambrosia beetles. " nown as "ambrosia Excavates several branching avates several brand brood developing in si rood developing in short . hfmlock. cedar, fir, hemlock, cedar, fir, and own as "ambrosia beetles "ambrosia a branching galleries in unching gallerie ha bark I Packard 1 - aV 1 (Packard 1890:93). (F 'ackard irk ( Packard 18 i Hamilton i a Ham alleries and broad brood ■Kul and heart wood of Douglas apple and hemlock in West Virginia, spruce, and fruit tree* in ular chambers in bark of xca a Ratz. Ci. of dead Abies excelia </seg>
            <seg id="p292">292 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRK ULTURI nenzietii iPacka ne, a ■a o 4 iC a of yellow a a a a k9117. D. affaber Mannh. Under bark of Abi&gt; 0:857). Bores in terminal shoots of white p L9122. Tomtom calligraphut derm. Attacks bark 1890:711). 9123. T. cacographus Lee. Breeds under ba Florida, and Pinut inopi in Maryland (Schwan b9124. T. cmfusu.i Lee. Excavates one to th ea from a medium-sized, central chamber in e (Hopkins or four short, curved galleries in par shore pine, and Sitka Bpruce (Hopkin T. integer Eich. Excavates several loi from a large, central cham rgepole pine (Hopkins 1* T. oregoni Eich. Excavates two small, central chamber in the ba re, and silver pine (Hopkins 190' 9136. Micracit tuturahs Lee. B Tribe 9144. Scolytut qtutdrispinostw Sa 41). Attacks bark of bitternut, sh ■itized by Spathiut trifatciatut Rile; ard 1890:294). •145. £. fagi Walsh Attacks bark of Celtit 611, 860). 9146. 5. unispinotus Lee. Excavates two short, galleries from an entrance burrow in living bark c western larch ( Hopkins 1904 . 1895). 9141 M. rudts Lee. Br&lt; 9128. T pin 'tacks bark of Abies menzu «,. 9133. T. avulsus I tacks pin' . ly cc ary enemy in company with Dendroctonut frontalt 1904) 9134. T. latident Lee. Excavates two or three lo from a small, central chamber in living bark of brai (Hopkins 1904 9135. T. balsameus Lee. Excavates several radia reree galleries from a small, central chamber in &lt;h bark of balsam fir and red and black spruce (Hopki T concinnu* Mann. Excavates irregular, central c </seg>
            <seg id="p293">PHOR 'Kill AMKIii Packard 18y i nearly straight, transverse gal - xm\ basal cavity in living bark Hopkins 1904 wo long, nearly-straight, trans - irrow and central or side cavity, (Hopkins 1904:21). ach, plum (Hamilton 18951. Breed* kory limbs (Hamilton Excavates three or four short, t m a large, central chamber in the surface of htly grooving the wood of arK a nd rare in balsam flr (Hopkins 1904:: * Harris. Attacks Prunus serotina (Pack ay. Excavates two long, transverse gal - )urrow and side cavity in the living bark ran xcavates one short, longitudinal gallery and small, side cavity in living bark of shore ks bark of elm and ash (Packard 1890 a. moderately-long, longitudinal Ex le bark of white alder (Hop- no transverse galleries from wood near the base of dying tit. longitndinal galleries ra n the living bark of Douglas spruce orange (Hamilton 1895). a single, short, longitud- ava nirrow and basal chamber in the &gt;od of juniper and eastern arborvitae (Hopkins r, parasitized by Spathiu* abdominalis Riley at Salina, a Lee. Excavates a single, straight, longitudinal or asal chamber in the living bark allery giant arhorvitap, in ;ir, and Port Orford </seg>
            <seg id="p294">294 NEBRASKA STATE B«»A1;I k 917-4. Phi Chap. Breeding under tana in V ia and parasitize.; opkii. s trar. attat i raipht. lor ra from a basal chamh . n a /( Crypt through the inner lia Ell kins 1904:26). lllltCH hwa s. with its galleries always ai ■u* autigraphu* 1&gt; hwarz Mann. Excavat OolurguM in dying and dead bark of Sitka spruce ( Ho Phi. Hopt ■ypress in Califoi mm. Attacks |&gt;in»- ( Har </seg>
            <seg id="p295">295 ing bark of Sitka s short, slightly-curved, long! gar pine, western white pine Hopkins 1 * ilHIIIU jpini. fungus found on dead oak writer found numerous spec- base of a water oak at from the fungus ( ystnpux n Ohio (Webster and Mally Cham- i was bred by the writer in i at Dallas, Texas. m buds and at the base of atera narrowly separated cells and anthonomi Cwfd. is a primary imens bred from dead fl^ from flower heads of • utenmulU i n t Ham- Mi Sell war/, from the smut of Tri' "ni- ls in the St. Igtiatius bean hag round in Ahirh I Pound on dry palmetto leaves in Flor- PAE OF THE ANTHONOMINI (Plates V-VIII.) n able to study well preserved pupae of seven ip : two other species, not well pre- - that all nine of U ■■ '&lt;« presenting </seg>
            <seg id="p296">296 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRIC1 </seg>
            <seg id="p297">297 a ni to "t T a a o i wo principa a a a a I o inthona pae ha ceptacle, and were Identified Messrs. E. A. Schwarz, E. S union boll weevil parasites was desirable to know the wn weevil with a newly-dlscov- ve as an introduction to acters of the immature stages study. The writer now has in hat of Anthono mus grandit. In and prominent, apically bilobed iflated at middle, and the apical mgth of process; medianly apex of emargfnation, each lobe 'the prothorax are convex with pair which are more or less heir own breadth. (Plate V « resembles that n many respec it considerably less produced, y, apically emarginate; emar- The prothoracic tubercles ar« pair, which axe quadrate and and separated by about their al tubercles are laterally spined. large number of abdom- nevertheless to be quite close and broadly, roundlngly, quad - rothoracic tubercles are .large. ated by less than their breadth. a similar abdominal structure, . grandis and A. sqvamotvt are i the genus Anthonoirnu and A. hus he anal process narrowly cleft. arge number of species, all of me permits. r, without difficulty. i known in the pupal stage by the ent, and its differentiation into a either pointed, cleft, or truncate- r of approximate tubercles on th« her prothoracic tubercles and gen- the shortening and indistinctness inal seements. </seg>
            <seg id="p298">NEBRASK A ' ;! 298 PLATE V </seg>
            <seg id="p299">299 I A M ! </seg>
            <seg id="p300">300 AGRK i y The pupae of Anthonomut aineulus have an elon ;ate, na with a deep cleavage, which does not approach the preceding do Mfmeni, and with the tips of the lobes slightly d acic tubercles are all rounded, with the large, mediae about their breadth. (Plate VIII, Pigs The pupae of Anthonomux nigrinut are very i preceding species, but readily separated by ha vie ana robust, with the cleavag and the tips more diver almost reaching the prec&lt; :nt. The two anterior me a rack- tubercles are without spine, the larger being more than their breai apart. These two species have like ha tion. (Plate VIII, Fi The pupae of Anthonomu* aeneotinctut are distln elongate process, laterally sinuate, basally broad, a narrowly -deeply last ventral segment is medianly-apically lobed, the lot* pairs of tubercles occi All of the pro thorn An lmperl- proved to have a prominen with two elongate par rill. Fig. 2.) The third typ. The pupae of Antho awl shaped. Tl approzimat' pterus quaa The abdomen of this spec Of the pupae which w tut had the beak extending aln in the others it only reached to th As this paper is only preliminar acterize less obvious characters BIBLOGRAPHY Aldrich, J. M 1905. Catalogue of North American Dii vol. XLVI. No. 1444, p. 427. Ashmead, W. H. 1880. Orange insects; a treatise on the in a sects found on the orange trees of Florida. Ashmead I Jacksonville, Florida, pp. 61-62 1888. Descriptions of new Braconidae in the &lt; National Museum. Proc. U. S. N. M., N 1890. See Riley and Howard 1890. This refere nee w credited to Ashmead in writing the paper 18*6. Descriptions of new parasitic Hymenoptera II Trans. An Ent. Soc.. rol XXIII. pp. 218. 219 </seg>
            <seg id="p301">301 :TH AMERICA. — J* Til **•* \/ L T u .,,rc,. f \ a«4o»-t«Bj«i Sir. ' "^*^»W)kJ^" ' /l-r.. f /»| S.,V«" -V;/ «■ /=!£ V,\ / / «r\ ' XX:-;^ /^S^ : - — £jr \ minx O.«rx. »» V*'^ /. &lt;O»4»f Ot&lt;rx </seg>
            <seg id="p302">302 NEBRASKA STATE BUAKD .\G1 V S: Tr Banks, Nathan 1902. Principal insect* liable Div. Ent , bull. 34, n. s., p. 4 181*1 1 .-atalo V S A pp. 1 Blanchard iptera. 1. Bridwell. J C 1904. Repoi pp. ; Brow; on il N. V : ■ J17; plum -". - Em., bul - 18H1. R&lt; The pota vol VII. pf Ent bull LI SoMM ins.- The bronze a 1902a The potato stalk weevil, pp 1X&gt;6. A revision of ihe Tyroglyphidae of Bur. En nil. 13, p. 17, pi. IV Beulenmuller. William. un the food hah. vol. XXII. p| 1894. Sugar !■■ H Ins- l»OOi a the in. ■■&lt;: PP- 31 currulio. pp » &lt; he food ha t Ce common rhul - Div. Ent.. ball ! •s injurious lo the viok-t rase, and Thf jialm and palmetto w&lt; • </seg>
            <seg id="p303">303 Ent.. bull. 43, p| &gt;n other nut-feeding specie*. litional observa- nt., bull. 44. pertinax Ol., with 'inax oi., witn Proc. Ent. Six Wash., vol. VII, ■ for I'omni. A a north of Mexico, a fam- o. a fain B l&gt;iv Km . tech. bull. 7. \nihonomini inlia f Anthonomini inha \m. Ent XVIII. pp. 11 North Amer North Amer XXI. pp. 113 XXI. pp. 11 ; hynehini inh» hynehini inha; km. Ent Sor., vol. XXIII. p\ Am. Ent Soc., vol. XXIII, p i' »nd shade trt. York tull. 31. p fifth Rep't Fish. Game and nnth Rep't Forest. Fish and in i Rep. Entomologist Fifth Rep't Fish. Game and nth Rep't Forest. Fish and Horn I Rep. Entom S. I &gt; i v . Ent.. bull 2U. n I Proc. A A A S for 74 :itions of the food of the 'i Rep't St. Ent on Not and n report for 1*01. Trans 111. Eighth Am. Rep Ky Ac. Eip. II. pi vol. XV. pp. ■ J fomm Apr 1SK4. p. 9%. a. Can Ent.. vol. XVIII. pp ra — No. 4. Can. Ent., vol XX. •f "an. Ent . vol. XXI. p. 34 Ent.. vol. XXII. pp. IS n Pennsvlvania with Ent. Soc. vol. XXII, pp. </seg>
            <seg id="p304">304 1 '!■ XX a and Mis V Harrington. W. Hague tlhynchophora weevils. Eleventh Ann. Kept Enc s pp. 49-57. B Additions to Canadian lists of Coleoptera. Can. E pp. 118-119. 1885. Are curculio larvae lignivorous? Ent Am., vol. 1891. Notes on a few Canadian Rhynchophora. Can. Er pp. . Harris. Thaddeus William. 1862. A treatise on s*ue of the insects injurious to II studies in the sand regions of the Illii River Valleys. Bull. 111. St Lab. Nat. H N'ew genera and species of North American C NT Y. Ent. Soc, vol V, pp. 49-56. Lurarer O. W9. Suborder Rhynrhophora Minn. Aer Rt 262-318. Mally. F. W. Report on the boll weevil Austin, Texa^ p. : 1892. Some bred West Virginia Braconidae. Insect ! 18S» m observations in -rinia. 47. 1902a. Insects &lt;il and d&gt; to forest p 1902b. I hk. let of tb. the Black Hills alogue of - - at I-ouisiana Porch* r. - I Pi 1, g L 1906. Ins' PS of for' Howard, I. 1900. The New York weevil in n. s. p. 107. ind Hinds, W. E. m boll wi 1905. The Mexican boF Fohnson, W. G 1898. The clover-leaf w&lt; all. 17 1900. Notes on insects of economic Importance for Ent., bull. 26, n. s., p. 81. William 1889. Two beetles new to the N. A. fauna. ICnaus. W 1885. Are rtircullo larvae lignivorous? Proc Br. En Knuth. P. • n Biolopie. vol. Ill, p. 369. nt« and Horn. 1876. The Rhynchophora of America north of Me Phil. Soc., vol. XV, No. 96. </seg>
            <seg id="p305">experiments on Fuller's rose beetle iiU alifornia. U. S. Ent.. bull. 4, pp. 46-50. engenu). Com. Paras. Agr i apt). U. S. D. A., Ann. shade trees. U. S. Ent Comm., shade trees. U. S. Ent. Comm., ain weevils related to the cotton En 11. 63, part II, pp. 39-44 ation. U. S. Bur. Ent. ,ira A jrgia. U. S. Dlv. Ent, bull. 30, peach. U. S. D. A., Year- em algoilon ylnsanthonomu* a n '•.•■ la Comision de Parasitologia Ag- &gt;, pp i del picudo del algodon (Itiaanthonowuu Boletin de la D de Parasitologia t Am., vol. I, p \nn. Rep. Noxious Insects of Missouri, iver-root borer, Hyle&amp;inua Rep. Noxious Insects of Missouri, T root borer, Hyletinu* Aramigiu fulleri Xramigu* fulleri Rep. U. S. Comm. Agr. furious to cultivated plants. Am. of Apioninae Bull. Brook. Ent. Sloe., S. Comm. Agr. is to cultivated plants Am. Apioninae. Bull. Brook. Ent. Soc, tomologist: The water weevil, Littorhoptrtu The water weevil, IA*»orhoptru* The corn bill bus, Sphenophorxu robuttut. I; The corn bill bus, Sphenophonu robvttu*. ver-leaf beetle, Phytonomus punctatus. pp. 111- tie, Phytonomus punctatus. pp. 111- r. S. Comm. Agr., 1881, 1882. enemy to pear from Oregon (Aragnomiu Agr., 1881, 1882 ( pear from Oregon (Aragnomut Life, vol. I. p. 16 North American Calandridae. Insect Life, tOL Wash., vol. I. p. 33. Howa R asitic Hymenoptera in the National ■ii rollfvtion. Insect Life. vol. II. pp. 348-353; vol. Ill, '1-464: vol. IV. pp 122-128. Hist., vol XII, pp. 81-S2 </seg>
            <seg id="p306">306 A- Sanderson. E. i Apr bill Schaupii. F (; on larv warz, I /• \ I lar a hn I XI Town Lowi h, K I). A new f ■■&lt;■ sail The srape curoulio {( on of Illint Some insert notes of the year I" - r. F M and Mally. C W. of the year in Ohio. I 1889. A new enemy to the potato: Thf Rep. Ohio Sta. tot ham. H. F Zimmermann. C ol. XV Thomas. PP- • r. F. M me studies of the dpvelopm&gt; 1 Report of olis- swan [)iv F </seg>
            <seg id="p307">307 N ( )F PLATES W. E Hinds cut to show eggs of Lirus on stem of Polygonum prnnsyhani I, in stems of Cuscuta in head of •I ranthus rubigino- &gt;arasitized by Tetrastivhus •thonomus aeneotinctus. h a of A are sh wing pupa of Catoi &gt;-tus granriis. in enemy (if AiithuiiniHus gin with larva of larva of A. 1 itthon a &gt;&lt;l&gt;ha untia </seg>
            <seg id="p308">308 KA ST.Vl 1' Ml s rl 0 INDEX T( PLANTS Abie* (fir Baechar excelsa, 2'.«i balimfc Bapti&gt; menziesii Abutilon, 2 holosericeum, 271, 274, 284 Barbara ar alder Althaea, 268 graecizan, - retroflexu- i Ambrosia. 253, 2G1 artemesia- trifida. 253, 261 Amelanrhier Ampelops^ quinquefolia Amphiacbyr dracunn. Anogra. 284 palli :66 arborvitae. 290, 21' eastern. 293 giant, 290, 29: Argemone, 254, 263 alba, 263 platyceras. 254 Canna a anf Artemesia, 257 Carduu carnation. Cassandra Aruncus. 283 aruncus, 283 repias. 275, 276, 283, 284 oornutl, 276 eorymbosa, 275 latlfolia. 275, 283 calyeulata Cassia chamaecrls marylandic obtusifolla ocddpntall Ascyrum, 272 hypeiicoldes, 272 Ceanothus, 279 ash, 273, 289, 293 Aspergillus, 269 Alter, 273, 281, 283, 284 Astragalus, 258, 263 Aricennia, 281 nitida 281 Port Orfor CpU1s. 274. 292 Acacia, 276 greggn, . Achillea, 273, 280, 1 lanuloaa. millet'oli Achyranthes, - :■;, 254, 256, 25 J68, 16», 274, 290, 291 aprico* amerlcanus cedar. 291. 293 incense. 29: </seg>
            <seg id="p309">309 C dewberry, Dracaena, egg-plant (Solanum), 282 261 - Ehretia, 255 ellipUca, 255 elm, 266, 273, 289, 291, 293 i2, 266, 269, 274, Elymua, 296 virginicus, 295 286 Empusa sphaerosperma, 2E 1 Entoruophthora, 258 Empusa sphaerosperma, 258 Entomophthora, 258 phytonomi, 258 pbytonomi, 258 sphaerosperma, 258 Epilobium, 276, 279 sphaerosperma, 258 4 &gt; -» y Epilobium, 276, 279 253, 257, Erigeron, 260 57 Erigeron, 260 canadense, 260 canadense, 260 Eupatorium, 283, 284 purpureum, 284 serotinum. 283 Eupatorium, 283, 284 purpureum, 284 ■. 282 serotinum. 283 Euphorbia, 275, 280 Euphorbia, 275, 280 marginata, 275, 280 •seradlsh), 280 marginata, 275, 280 radish), 280 Euthamia, 283 graminifolia, 283 Euthamia, 283 281 gramlnlfolla, 283 28 251, 256, 281 287. 288, 295 295 4 ,_. fir (Abies), 260, 290, 291, 2 fir (Abies), 260. 290, 291, 292, 293 balsam, 260, 292, 293 California white, 293 grand, 290, 291, 293 274 ■ ' balsam, 260, 292, 293 ■» ?fii 2B1 2«5 I California white, 293 , 7 r ' | 7fi ' I?! 1 ' erand- 290, 291, 293 265, , as, £it&gt;, tia. fr08tweed (Helianthemum) Galpinsia, 279 frost weed (Helianthemum), 268 Galpinsia, 279 hartwegl, 279 I hartwegi, 279 Gardenia (cape jessamine), 2S6 geranium, 255 Gardenia (cape jessamine) 275 284 geranium, 255 S4 gooseberry, 253 m grape, 252, 253, 279, 282, 2 grape, 252, 253, 279, 282, 291 wild, 252 wild, 252 grass, 253, 255, 258, 273, 2 grass, 253, 255, 258, 273, 287 blue (Poa), 287 Hilo, 255 prairie, 273 blue (Poa), 287 ) Hilo, 255 prairie, 273 greaseweed, 253 Grindelia, 256, 263, 271 inulioldes, 271 14 squarrosa, 263 4 squarrosa nuda, 256, 263, 271 squarrosa nuda, 256, 2&lt; 294 hawthorn (Crataegua), 253, hawthorn (Crataegus), 263, 274,275 hazelnut, 251, 252, 266, 285 ,T 294 295 hazelnut, 251, 252, 266, 285 oea-panduranae. 275, 295 anae. 275, 295 Helenium, 263, 281, 283, 29 Helenium, 263, 281, 283, 295 tenuifolium, 263, 281, 283, IK Helianthemum, 268 tenuifolium, 263, 281, ' ra, 282, 283 Helianthemum, 268 neteloldes. 282, 283 itramonlum, 282, 283 283 canadense (frost weed) canadense f frost weed), 26S 2, 283 Hellanthus, 251, 253. 254, Hellanthus, 251, 253, 254, 260, 261. tatula. 283 265, 268, 279, 287 growMerratui, 260, 261 278, </seg>
            <seg id="p310">310 VSKA STATE WiAllH &lt;•! \&lt; 1:1 !: i hemlock, . I locus western, . lirum subaxillaris Ian. mocbeutuK I Macrophc mal alba. mahogan : mapl Klalirn hickory (Hicoriai ■lam) k m --* ; ■ shellhark. korarradish iCochlearia rsionia purpur- ••t&gt;erry pandurata olor jessamim- cape (Gardenia juniper (.lunipt-: Juniperus. 294 virginiani. Kalmia angii mtleoM «pinosa 284 multiflora, 2&gt; • rtana. 2 camara Lemna. MS lemon I&gt;pptilon. 2S1 canadpnse. 2S1 Oeno Impede?;, onion Leucaena nntia pulvenilenta. 27&gt;&lt;\, 275 lept •&gt;7&gt;; 75 Illy. 255 ! orar lime (Tif 291 </seg>
            <seg id="p311">'■■;i -74. iincum, '!■ potato I Solanuni I. ilia. ■aim. prim rot* F'rionops PriiTin I'soraU in. 1!K4 inifolium. 284 Quereus iak nsea imliri( aria (laurel oak) ilieifolia. J nana ibra ana. 2', rpini mi. 4 radial ■1. rape ( Brassica I. -&gt;M nwpbei dwood reed I Phra^i Rheum rapontirum (rhubarb I rhubarb (Rheum). 2K0 Rhu&gt;- aromaiicum. :'7S Riridelia Robinia. 258 ia. 258 </seg>
            <seg id="p312">312 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF AGRICL * Ignatius bea Rudbeckia, 253, 284 straw berry. nirta. 284 8. 28 Rumex, 259, 260, 2SU Strychninoi bri tunica sweet potato, ! crispus, 260 obtuaifuii. Tephrosia Sabai, tM virginica palmetto, this- palmetto (.cabbage 2^ tobac Sagitun.. latifolia, vanabil; natc Tr di»co. strobiioi.it-.- 8clrpu fluvia Scrophularij reaicaria Sid era rul Sinapis nsis, 280 nigra (mustard rmbrium, 280 offioina Solanum 8 carol lnena«, 270 ■ eleagnifol i ': i melongena (egp plant) nwtratum. 2R toireyi. Wa 0 fll taberosum I potato) Solldago, 272, 2S3. 1 - miMOuriensis. 283 nemoral! wa watf whea willow ■ m. 25: Rlobulii 2C6 ■pot, black (M;. •pruce, 259. 260, 290, 291, 292, 293, Xant 294. 295 anar Mark. 292, 293, 294 ■mr PlMlM. «••. »• 291 292, 293 ruma Xanthoxvlun 292, 294 pterota, white. 293, 294 </seg>
            <seg id="p313">NORTH AMERICA. 313 REFERENCES (PARASITES) tract 1. Hydnocera pubescens Microdus simillimus Myiophasia aenea, 2 Nematus gall, 269 Neocatolaccus tylodermae, 260. 261 Pediculoides ventricosus, 269, 271 Phanerotoma tibialis Phylloxera gall, 27 Podapion gall, 278 Porizon eonotracheli ratf S curculionis, MS zygobarldis Tenthredinid gall, 269 Saliois desmodoldes. 269 Salicis nodus, 269 Salicls pomum, 269 Tetrastichus, 283 Torymus anthonoml, 269, 295 Tyroglyphus breviceps. 2fi9 lermatis, 261, 269 Urosigalphus,. 269 anthonomi, 269 schwarzl, 269 a Vlpio belfragel, 261 Glyptomorpha, 259, MO, 261 mavaritus, 261 novitus, 2bl rugator, 259, 261 Ompbale livid . Sigalphus, 269, 271. 274. 27 f. 278, 285 canadensis, 271 copturi, 275, : Solenopsis geminata Spathlus. 266, 291. it abdominalis, canadensis, 266, 291, 294 trtfasciatus, 292 </seg>
            <seg id="p314">314 1 IXUEX TO WEEVILS rlaihr&amp;ius nobili lur ii Apliras carpini. AcMtboacclia nalus Al Achra- ■ Ani|" sratniiai • An.honon, aeneoltis aeneotinrti albopi oorvulus disjun i. 271 ■ mis. (Tramii A pilari - juniper-inns. Baeoi Balar mexicanii - molpcnltis. 27? miisrulus. 2"n aryat niprinns. 251, 27" mihilus. 272 paiipfrrnlus. 2 pomonim. 2fifl quadriciWii mflnennis. 2fi9 S'-ntpllatns 271 sicna snnxmosiiR 271 </seg>
            <seg id="p315">315 !l! ligatus, aiuca auricephalus, 'iflus. L'7-t affi-ni&gt; ilbtcinctus. J74 ia minat iglaml aeati ■an 274 rorlf^ irola. 288 &gt;l&gt;liiilu!'ia&gt; adrilineaiu marmoratu anaslyiit rrataesi. nuphai Cortlr. ptin&lt; piniphilus. 2R8 nlatalea. : Craponius. 279 inaeoual' Cratoparis. 295 lunatiis alus. 291 torhynchng, 278 hislenatus. 27S fallax. 2TS lanathi. 2"S parn </seg>
            <seg id="p316">316 Crypturus, 294 Eupsalis, 286 minuta, 28( atomus, 294 Cylma, 286 Kusphyrus. 295 walshii, 29; fomiicarius. 286 punctati Exomias, 25 Dendroctonus, . approximatus. 294 brevicornis. 294 frontal is piceaperda, I ponderosae, . ■implex. 294 terebrans. 294 valens. . pellu GpUis. 278 oculatus Grathotrichus materiarlus suloatus Gononotu- lutomis. 28 Graphorrhlnus, Dlamimus, 254 ■tibserire Dirotnpnaitius. 254 ■ordidus, 254 rlurjnis. 294 pumi. Dorytomuf brevieoll: mucidus. 263 squamos- Dryocoetes, 291, 292 affaber. 292 autoRraphus, 291 rophthoms, 288 corticalis. 288 E&gt;ryotribuB. 288 mimetlcns, 288 Elassoptes m mariTius. 289 FK-bus, 272, 273 bipunctatus, 272 ephlpplatus, 272 Bcanicus. 273 rdalus. 265 aeratus. 265 Epic*eniB. 252 lmbricatr, Eudlacnci. pulrher P0«en8rho«»ldl. 257 rjclmus. 260 mannerheimll. 260 &amp;lutaceu8, 294 Euxenus. 295 Deunoris. 263 constrictus. 263 scapalis EufrnamptiiF, 251 ansmntatus. ?F&gt;1 ooliaris. 2K1 itim. 2K1 </seg>
            <seg id="p317">I HOPH \ I NORTH AMERICA. 317 LAt lineicollis, 284 Notaris, 263 puncticollls, 263 Notolomus, liasalis. sr Omileus roides Onyohobar; mystiea. 281 Ophr&gt; bituberosus, 253 latirostris, 253 sulcirostrN vittatus, 253 Orchestes, 272 annatu ephippiatus, 272 niKer pallieornis subhlrtus, 272 Orthoris, 283 orotchii. 283 oylfndrifer, 283 Otldocephalus. 266 rhevrolatii. 266 dichrous. 266 laevioollis. 266 robicollis. 266 Otiorhynchus. 254 ovatu sulcafi Pachnaein- listan- opalu Pachyharts. 2R4 xanthoxyli. 284 260 hilarls, 254 Pansoopnp prinacpus Paranthonomu- profundns. 268 nomns, 280 sulcleollis. 2«0 Poritaxla. 254 Mi hfsplda. 254 Mor Phaoppholls. 2F!5 plejrans Phlopophagiis, 289 aplonidf- Neo </seg>
            <seg id="p318">318 Pbloeosinus 4 I dentaius. yranu K I'liin 'aius Km-&lt;; .' -.a- K * la ■are ra.-nia: ill mi Podapion rata^-^ Pseudobari- dlsorf ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p319">A r eoni pini obar. ompac nsoli: nucor. xana trinotata Trigon pilosa Trypodendn bivittatii Tvchius. . sibiiis sordidus suloatus Tvloderma g baridium. 27S foveolatum fragariae. 278 Wollastoniella. 2H9 qiMrclcol </seg>
            <seg id="p320">II u i i Kl 1! r~: Is i II 0 ? ! 1 4 3 ! ii I n If B { | y p I 11 i € n y &gt; ? o • e I « » ii 0 V: I li s* \tt- w I 9 li I U : * Q| If M ill P §2 h li ll I! si *r ® * m h n • 5 e I* o II II or u M It s: ■ 5 S h i i h * I* l! I! m « * i It S s I' ) k - I fc </seg>
            <seg id="p321">321 I ii li I V) * 0 m P &gt; CO li ! I 4 » lii {At 3 •or .5 3 s /fl if o li H c&lt; P- M S «| V 0 W of !? 2 5S 4c i'' 5 -S V [ 9 J ii Us 41 if i r 8 4. » I* I If IS« u 0 b OT-0 1 1 I 5 3 s * 1? n !i I I! i I '-3 5 it s 2 S &gt;r 5 S K • ; x l ! % - 3 "5 * 5 - V ?&lt; 25 5 * * r; £5 -I H ni ICQ -4 17 '3. r O H O si o O r • i g 5 * </seg>
            <seg id="p322">XI x ?M n i r—j ■ I 5 r~ JJ t * * » | | m « t- I 1 i * Li • ,! !l r ♦ s * fr * L t T 3 ff- U-^ r — i 3 - ■ . JC h ■ 9 I -^fH ? 1 j- P - - i | 9t i 3 12 — r 3a It* hi o | m &gt; „ r » </seg>
            <seg id="p323">Um.Y OF NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p324"/>
            <seg id="p325">which ar it -akota, March 6, 190 • \VM. .T. .TOII pecial ln- 1 with have found op - ilt of OLOG'i ted in this ithi-r fully the cli - r. rock formations agricultural condi- nh iii(|iiir by the Depart- ive |,i epart- • ■ in agri- t. hoping of suitable maps I great </seg>
            <seg id="p326">326 </seg>
            <seg id="p327">t K \ to. </seg>
            <seg id="p328">328 NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OI AGRK </seg>
            <seg id="p329">329 that whi linairi' but ■ I and i it mail a ra not rainfall. Oi w underground il, the same as that :y the liistory and many aiH&gt;ration. Its </seg>
            <seg id="p330">SAND HILL DRAIN/\GL\TOP0GRAPH y LEGEND- B^l aU IJ5J teJ \$ Contourt Depression Lakes Intermittent Ma Contours (.«*&lt; LOCATION- T.22N..R.46W. ARLA-36 SQUAR h </seg>
            <seg id="p331">331 J \ </seg>
            <seg id="p332">332 fac* ■ hard. are iii ten t&lt; h The w ful kii a h format lag a \ from fine t. proj*! ■ rerj- fine sa Foil. H. </seg>
            <seg id="p333">333 Y I xkbi: Kearnev. Lexington, the last named. ' • &lt;1 in due which have similar It is simply t may help in maintaining a ;inp open ! &lt;andy soils Clay soils are characterized by th great power to retain water. r between sandy soils and clay inic ■ they do not ha»e I and gravel to make in tex- ly thouph not always are tain more than the usual • hard pan is subsoil fiich are carried Nebraska are the timable value to farmers. now known. The demand for with the development of reclamation schemes Ticultur i more than fifty years geologists have studied the iing the surface and deed-buried formations. ington, D. lii'i I i ii n v 'he ..viM'ctpH in /In* e most fertility to l&gt;e I under a f the vari :&gt;r t» are of no if alkali or alkaline l&gt;enetrable, Anv hard • - com- </seg>
            <seg id="p334">334 NEBRA." p»" £ ' 2 — , :^ m 3ci r % ■ *^^* 1^^^^«hi^^»j» i S a 5C £ &gt;■ ' '■■ *^m s If -J - - </seg>
            <seg id="p335">335 I Viltil ( ' U. \i I h thicker Ix the glacial and the !'• hf M iKsouri from * ( ttMimiith : at KiM-a. in the </seg>
            <seg id="p336">336 </seg>
            <seg id="p337">KASKA 337 Black Hill- and iron ike the al reak in the lairhnry. Htil&gt;l)ell and fair q </seg>
            <seg id="p338">H \i:r.i:\ tin' it </seg>
            <seg id="p339">339 h the M i h 11 T I V m mill I.oup Kur . </seg>
            <seg id="p340"/>
            <seg id="p341">uadron and -hown r mi &gt; 1 in the V to the Wvoraine line. It uluff to the Wyoming line. It iit-a. The material rium rem.i of large rhino&lt;cros-like anim run and Xorth 1" The materi tanotherium remains arge rhinoceros-like anima e the Chadron and out Ige, and in North thicki • ff, it the it uration, it iticm jht variation in hai ight var t nl la i id. The formation in Lo t M - which, from • neral leral of the I the ling from the It' idiiifr from the North 1'latte Valley. sorth Platte Valley. ■■hen- it • att»' where it ■ . ■ Q&lt; ling are iind together inak - ■ stand out ring are 1 tog-ether inak- : he formation is 200 irmation whose texture is f concretions and irregularly dis- m t locally. The formation lies older formations and occupies and 88 and in Profes- :il Surve </seg>
            <seg id="p342">342 \ ,i </seg>
            <seg id="p343">343 iTh nu </seg>
            <seg id="p344">44 NERBASKA !'.&lt; 'A lil&gt; mi v -1 \ buff ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p345">345 IT, </seg>
            <seg id="p346">346 </seg>
            <seg id="p347">347 PLATTE VALLEY SOILS </seg>
            <seg id="p348">348 NEBRASKA - lARP &lt;•! chemically quit. t food nitroeen and ' salts of | or aboui - I 'i 1 .liff. • v ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p349">349 &gt;F NKBRASKA rn region. It 'ward and i broad, smooth table lands. ttom land, in all sandy loam. ti vall&gt;- The following me- airly rep iirh 1'lains i W\ M • t w adapt imiKir i </seg>
            <seg id="p350"/>
            <seg id="p351"/>
            <seg id="p352"/>
            <seg id="p353">hour </seg>
            <seg id="p354">Monthly, An.n, </seg>
            <seg id="p355">355 npitationf ka t with Departure* rmal Annual !CropSe«»'» = c v *• . </seg>
            <seg id="p356"/>
            <seg id="p357">1 ,1 </seg>
            <seg id="p358"/>
            <seg id="p359"/>
            <seg id="p360">360 NEBB H L. ■ ■ n Bou *"alla»ay Daweoi Hall Buffalo Dawson North I. - ; B.aln. • Ravenna Buffalo </seg>
            <seg id="p361">s &lt; * E Z : w 1 I 1 1 1 n »■ w A 4 171 I 1 11 F a nw a </seg>
            <seg id="p362"/>
            <seg id="p363"/>
            <seg id="p364">364 </seg>
            <seg id="p365">365 • I ' I 1 I &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p366">£" K M W If ] K K1n-.-« N Ha K S, V» V* p»r.» » </seg>
            <seg id="p367">« t 4 47.4 -0.4 I « </seg>
            <seg id="p368">«a i v- K IV v * H Z </seg>
            <seg id="p369">X T. ' fT • </seg>
            <seg id="p370">» • • z • </seg>
            <seg id="p371">371 : ■ •» &lt;T. r &lt;l </seg>
            <seg id="p372">v----i-i. </seg>
            <seg id="p373"/>
            <seg id="p374">374 8 f» T I K 1 n KJ </seg>
            <seg id="p375">» •• 1 • a —0 41 1 14 52 1 15 I -* </seg>
            <seg id="p376">AT10M A B K </seg>
            <seg id="p377">R DICMB&gt; s ■I 1 S&lt; 52 </seg>
            <seg id="p378">\ A : *• A A ■v </seg>
            <seg id="p379">379 </seg>
            <seg id="p380">4 i </seg>
            <seg id="p381">4 J 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p382">382 • </seg>
            <seg id="p383">&lt;.k.\ii;n </seg>
            <seg id="p384"/>
            <seg id="p385"/>
            <seg id="p386">386 I </seg>
            <seg id="p387">387 </seg>
            <seg id="p388"/>
            <seg id="p389">II'K(&gt;\ KMI.M </seg>
            <seg id="p390"/>
            <seg id="p391">« </seg>
            <seg id="p392">392 </seg>
            <seg id="p393">.1 </seg>
            <seg id="p394"/>
            <seg id="p395">' </seg>
            <seg id="p396">396 </seg>
            <seg id="p397"/>
            <seg id="p398"/>
            <seg id="p399">» </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>