<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00013.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00013.00001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1903-1904</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Nebraska 1903-1904 
            AffT«t, UNOX AND men mt nuathhm B 1949 »• 
            Vol. II. 1. Biennial Report of the Adjutant General 2. Biennial Report of the State Librarian 3. Biennial Report of the State Library Commission 4. Seventeenth Biennial Report of the R&gt; Univers 5. Ninth Biennial Report of Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics ■ Bulletin No. 4 of Bureau of Labor and Iudustrial Statistics 1904 Twelfth and Thirteenth Annual Reports of Department of Banking 8. Eleventh and Twelfth Annual Reports of the State Banking Board in regard to Building- and Loan .\ I 
            
            Im-tLA N IAJj rihj I O bv 1 OF THE ADJUTANT GENERAL OK THE STATE OF NEBRASKA 1903-1904 </seg>
            
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY ADJUTANT GENERAL'S REPORT HEADQUARTERS NEBRASKA NATIONAL. GUARD ADJUTANT GENERALS OFFICE. Lincoln, Nebraska, December 1st, HON JOHN H. MICKEY, Governor and Commander in Chief SIR In compliance with the provisions of the military code of th&gt; of Nebraska, I have the honor to submit my biennial report of the tran - sactions of this department, for the term ending November 30, 1904. Receiving my appointment as Adjutant General, to take effect February 20, 1903, I assumed the duties of the office on that date, re - lieving, Brigader General L. W. Colby. S. D. Davis was continued in the position of clerk and store k and on March first Major E. H. Phelps of the second regiment inf was appointed chief clerk, and Miss Mary Greer of Tecumseh app&lt;&gt; stenographer. On February 13 and 14, 1903, just prior to his retirement from office, General Colby conducted an examination of officers for commiss - ion, under general order number 10, series of 1903. Thirty-nine of passed successfully: six others failing to report or offer adequa: cuse, were discharged from the MILITARY LAW The new law passed by congress entitled "An Act to promo; efficiency of militia and for other purposes," approved January repealed the old militia law that had been in existence for hundred years, and had become obsolete and inoperative. It plac&gt; national guard in a position to become the effective re- the country, making it unnecessary to sustain a large standing; The new law is intended to hai • militia, knn &gt; "National Guard" of the variou md territories, with the &lt;v zation, equipment, and discipline of the regular army, to be in for an immediate call in- by the President a term not to exceed nine months), to participate in army n and military schools of instruction at the expense of the general go ment. It repuires an annual inspection of the guard by an off regular army appointed by the secretary of war. 1 derived by the state from the law depend upon the efficiency and equip- ment of the guard, and the disposition of the state government to meet the requireni. ipport &lt;&gt;• l </seg>
            <seg id="p003">2 • militia and saf' 'quipment furnished under its provisions. Realizing the import:. forming with the national military law, a bill w. d with this end in view, which was introduced in th- of 1903, by the chairman of the military committee of the sen&lt;v a its final passage in the ho An earnest effort ,le to harmonize t the provisions of both laws wit 1 i Its. Considering the inadequate ippr&lt; :iade TION ducted in accordant ordc by the following named officers: Bi ueral J. H. Culver, Colonel C. J. Bills, Liutenant Colonel V. C. Talbot, Major J. A. Storch, Major Richards, and Captain O. M. Newman— which developed the con dition of the guard and its prepardness for a in compliance with the I. The troops were found to be fairly well equipped, but somewhat discouraged; the passing of the preceding year without an encampment for want of funds, th' imposed for !he payment of armory rent and company ■ con- tributed to i his feeling Many excellent officers had resigned of the time and expense n vo be devoted to the interest of their commands, and for which they are held under bond, furnished at their own expense The on was followed by an inspection of the first and second i troop, signal and hospital corps, by regiment, and Captain Cronin of the regin S. infantry, detailed by the Secretary of War . This tour of inspection by these efficient officers was beneficial to the guard in in: racts from their reports are submitted herewith TOUR OF THE PRESIDENT EXCHANGE OR EXCHANGE OR ARMS -KHAKI UNIFOR1 KHAKI UNIFORMS •ked by a tour of President Roose- The last days of April were ma The last days of April \ ked by a tour of President Roose- velt through the 1 all con velt through the I inies along the line of travel were inies along the line of travel were ordered to assemble at their. home stations and pay proper respect to ordered to assemble at their. home ations and pay proper respect to the it hich order was promptly and cheerfully obeyed. Company "B" and "I" of the flfst regiment and companif "F," and "K" of the second regiment, with the hospital corps, reported for duty without pay at t! i on the day of his visit to.thi- The various com it in the Memorial Day ex&lt; of June and Jnl Largely d. A. Eberly, Captain E. H. Phelps, Captain respo- of state and government property </seg>
            <seg id="p004">the Springfield rifle, calibre I &gt;f th &lt;»d in June, 1903. On requisition th An ex&lt; magazine khaki uni •d from the quartern! &gt;'ral and d for&lt; to exp 190 (U a tl and I) as &gt;nd i Tl it The Os in b4 01 r f se Tl n adj Per th to noted and deport n( and extended oni' to target prac discharged, * o fill n and &gt;n the Wisnpr bn' bage h of th - »rt of </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 present, drill, and discipline of troops, the chief commissary's report showing in detail the issue of commissary stores and cost per capita. The camp and drill grounds, hay, straw, and electric lights were fur - nihed by citizens of York, who contributed to the success of the encamp - in various ways not to be forgotten by the guardsmen. ARMY MANEUVERS On invitation of thet Secretary of War, the second regiment and signal corps were ordered to report to the commanding officer of Camp Sanger, Fort Riley, to take part in the army maneuvers on October 17, 1903. Detachments from each company of the first regiment were ned to corresponding companies of the second regiment to make up the ocmplement of men permitted. The troops thus designated were concentrated at Beatrice and proceeded by the Union Pacific railroad to Fort Riley, arriving at Camp Sanger on the morning of October 18. The second regiment, under command of Colonel J. W. McDonnell, waa ned to the brigade of Brigader General Thomas H. Barry (U. S. A). The signal corps, under command of Captain J. Rex Henry, was ordered to report to the chief signal officer of the Provisional Division, and en - camped with the signal corps of the regular army. The maneuvers ex - tended over a large territory and afforded an excellent opportunity for officers and men to perform many duties that would be required in active service. Attention is invited to the' accompanying reports of Colonel McDonnell and Captain Henry for details of this tour of duty. The Nebraska troops returned on October 28, greatly benefited by the experience in camp and field with the regular army. The transportation, subsistence and per diem (regular army rates) were paid out of the general appropriation for the suppodt of the army. The amunition, forage, and fuel were charged against the state apportionment. The balance of pay required to make the sum equivalent to one dollar per day for enlisted men for the twelve days was paid from the state funds. The adjutant general, quartermaster general, surgeon general, and brigade cor .lander accompanied the troops to Fort Riley, attended all of the maneuvers, and joined your Excellency on the day of the grand review. We were afforded every facility for witnessing the maneuvers and were - of -many court* a the brigade and division command* 1904. On request of the Governor, Brigade General A. S. Dagget, A (retired) was detailed by the Secretary of War, under the pro - visions of section 20 of the Act of Congress approved January 21, and reported for duty January C, 1904. His gallant and con - spicuous service during some of the most trying ordeals of our country's history made him a welcome addition to the official family of the com - ier-in-chief. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">5 INTERSTATE XATIONAL GUARD ASSO&lt; The Interstate National Guard Association was called t&lt;&gt; Augustine, Florida, on January 21, 1904. This state was ei I five delegates. Three delegates, Brigader General Patrick H. I Colonel C. D. Evans, and the Adjutant General, responded to thi and represented the state at that meeting. Officers from the Ta ons "of the War Department designated by the Secretary of uted interesting papers for discussion, and the experience of the Cous states under the new conditions were given by their r&lt; os. This association was instrumental in drafting and securi:. snent of the "Dick bill," and is proving to be an international si of great value to the heads of departments of national &amp;'■ of i he various states, and recognized as such by most of the ally providing for representation. EXPIRATION OF TERMS or BRIGADIER GENERAL The term of service of the brigadier general having expired, and ollowing the precedent established by the adjutant | :i leaving he position vacant from 1898 to 1901, no election was called, and the vis that would have been used for the brigadier general and his icial staff were devoted to the interests of the guard. This plan has idopted in a number of the states where all the troops are combin - ed in one brigade, the general staff performing the dut: iy re - quired of the brigade staff, thus obviating the duplication of officers that perform the same duties and economizing to I BOAK INSPI CTION AND SURVEY A board of inspection, consii t Inspector General, Major • •nvened (gen. for the purpose of examining uni erty, with instructions to inspect iting of Major \V. R. IfcLaughUi E. H. Phelps and Captain I •der numb ble and unsuitable publii unpanies at their hon I this jurisdiction. The officers constituting this board were appi ioard of survey, in order to lessen the expense of the exhaustive work itemplated under the instructions. All government ■ prop - y was inspected and evidence gathered to fix the responsibil t or stolen property. Through the excellent and thorough wo i board of survey of 1903 and the boards ot 1904, the state has been relieved by the War Department from bility of a large amount of quartermaster's and ordna cumulation of losses for a number of years, for which the state had en held responsible which will now be dropped from the annual returns by competent authority. ions of tl </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 making a tour of the state, inspecting each organization at its post. His inspection, as well as that made by the assistant insp most thorough and very profitable to the guard in ually and collectively. Extracts from General Daggett's report am! mghlin are herewith subi OFFICERS SCHOOL An officers school was convened June 20, 1904, with 67 per c&lt; tthe officers present, and, continued for four days, after which mination of officers for commissions took place. On invitation, G 1 Daggett acted as instructor. The following subjects were c sidered: administration, drill regulations, small arms firing regula manual of guard duty, fire discipline, military law, minor taci field eiu and militar: i of question mitted under each head and taken ui&gt; seriatim, d: Klained by the instructor. Tex^ were in demand, and sers applied themselves diligently and with p 'Stness du the term. Tli &gt;^d to lei &lt;1 pap Captain Ha , Chief Co Captain Ha • , Chief Co y, department v i, on Su u Ca of the 30th U. S. Infantry, on L-ines of Communication: Colonel Jenk . on Transportation: Colonel Ehrhardt, Ju Gene on Individ on In ral: Tar.set Practice and and Th' were ful The . re ft *■ informatio 1 the vari subje&lt; clearn and abl and I- and 1 ann' Ml IUT OF SOCTH OMAHA CAVALRY. &gt; vin amply with the i wa r .1 men lonorab uonal guard was ordered into camp of in n for eight d David City, Butlei was chosen for the location Kcamp as affording economical c«&gt; on of troops, being cen on the line of thr of that city tender the free use ot mds, a 1 in of land foi i purposes, and t for ma ip a Y^i™ An n 1 f*^ i ot* &amp; 1 1 C'O ni oil^i v oT*Eftini 7ftt i on^ </seg>
            <seg id="p008">The i regiments, with the ipany nd ho? to David I' r£ n £ ) ifai B 1 Or )cto r t&gt;nt, was burned at Ge: «gim i and staff, accompanied mid the dedication of .the Lou the dedication of .the Lou se E April 30, 1903; the launching of tl April 30 October 7, 1904, and Octob at St. Louis on October 25, 11 )4 RY. V Through the efforts of D Thro v the adjutant general's office, which had been neglected for a number the adjutant general's office, which for a number of years, had been wr; and the reco d th&lt; f- of years, h erence. It was found that a large amount of pro along on reports that did not exist, having been lo A board of survey was convened and evidence obtai; h enabled this dep tate relieved through the War Department &gt; of the sure $10 The Secretary of War . i he proceedii. survey and relieving the SI ?ka from "It in thnn?Yit that* "iv ttct" ef* i!d he TO he ofHoerfl </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 responsible for the safe keeping of this government property to prevent these losses by theft, and the Governor should be asked to take such steps as will secure better protection of the supplies issued for th of the state troops." The loss of property has been mainly traced to the unsafe and Inadequate company quarters. The meagre sum of one hundred dollars appropriated for the payment of armory rent is insufficient to secure desirable locations or halls. A comparative table showing the money value of stores for which company commanders are responsible is sub - mitted for your information. In many cases the members of the com - pany are taxed monthly to pay armory rent. With few exceptions, the rent for adequate armories does not range less than three hundred dollars per annum, and from that up to eight hundred dollars. The young men composing the national guard, impelled by patriotic mo giving freely of their time in preparation for the defense of their country in time of need, or to uphold the laws of the land, should not be required to bear the additional burden of providing adequate ;md comfortable quarters, and I trust that the legislature in its wisdom will make suitable provision in this direction for the encourage' of the citizen soldier, one of the most potent factors in sustaining 'he integrity of our country and the preservation of peace. During the present, administration there has been collected outstanding claims, accountable officials, and from lost and improperly disposed stores the sum of $2008.69, turned to the United States Treasurer, and $688.16 turned over to the State Treasurer; $554.09 has been collected from the general govern to reimburse the state for expenses incurred in the Spanish war, and additional claims are now pending before the department. The present hospital corps which has proven to be a very efficient organization, was mustered into the service February 10, 1903. EThe incongruity of the combination of a signal and engineer ps in one organization was recognized, and it was changed to that a signal corps, which under capable leadership has won deserved ipliments. No money has been drawn in bulk for the support of the National guard, excepting that portion for armory rent which was drawn a' the close of each quarter and paid out at the commencement of the eding quarter to the companies entitled to the same, and practice was abandoned at your suggestion after June 30, 1904. money has been drawn in advance, as formerly, for the payment of encampment expenses. The money was borrowed on my per credit from the local banks at' York and David City for the encamp - ments, and afterward paid by warrant drawn on properly exe&lt; vouchers, with receipted bills and pav rolls attached. The cost of subsistence at Camp Pershing, York, was tv - and one fourth cents a: at Camp Victor Vifquain, it was </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 as provided for field service by the U. S. regulations was issued and general satisfaction given. By close economy sufficient funds were saved to pay the expenses of an officers school, the first session ever held in this state. During the biennium there have been 273 special orders and 79 general orders issued. There have been 144 officers elected and Einted, and 100 of this number commissioned; 43 officers discharged ?&lt;i^nation, 24 by expiration of commission, and 15 by order. The law requiring the assessor to enumerate the number of men Hilary age had apparently been a dead letter, as no returns could ind in the records of the office. A printed form was adopted, and sent out to all county clerks with a circular letter, referring to s&gt;- 12, chapter 56. of the compiled statutes, requiring the enrollment and urging compliance therewith. Prompt re made from a number of- counties, but extensive correspondence was require q reports from other counties. All have responded with the ex- Eon of- the counties of Greeley, Blaine and M&gt; •arison with the returns of adjoining counties, estimates has been made of the number in these four counties, and added to those rei&gt;' . the other counties, making the total mi h of the e 121 MILITARY EDUCATION" instruction is given in the State Un versity, Kearney Military Academy, Doane College, and in a large of high schools in the ietailed from the regular army, Captaii. se of the ■ brought this department up to a His last quarterly report shows an is divided into six companies. The Uni\ many of the military department of the State University furnishes many of the officers of the guard and who are among the tern. The eommandu; ;ired rocters of our national guard sy report the names of the three graduates thai ained the highest standing in the military departu the Those having gain. onor T, and J. D. Ringer, for 1903, and ;ir ending June 30th are W. R. McGeachin, J. R. Fame The secretary of war has consented to make a detail from the retired list of the U. S. A. as military instructor at the Wesleyan Uni - versity, who will probably be installed the next semester. I would recommend that sufficient appropriation be made to arm, and equip the Boys' Industrial School at Kearney in compliance with report of the superintendent of that institution. tate. has an Infantry, U. S. A., who ha tndable state of efficiency. ollment of 479 students, whict I. P. Hewitt, E. D. Stanley, and C. A. Mohrman. for 1904 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">CONCLUSION. The labor ai. &lt;f this office y largely increase*! ! the compensation is far from being conim obligations required. The ] :nmander-tn-chiel at the maneuvers at F ■ our to the guard n the effo to attain y prevails among the officers and men and a unity of pit il aloi it In conclusion, I beg leave to invite your attention to the varlou reports, tabulated returns, and statements herewith submitted. lesire to ion of the e »f your c fidem •&gt; suppo ed by :he gi and td and compan . without whose assistance the present state efficiency of the national guard could not have been attained. My thanks are esp' ionel George E. Jenkins, Quartrmast General, Colonel C. D. Evans, Surgeon General, and Colonel Ehrhardt, Judce Advo ral and I am under many obligati to the office force who have given me faithful and intelligent support J. H. CULVER. Adjutant Gene </seg>
            <seg id="p012">OF THE NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD </seg>
            <seg id="p013"/>
            <seg id="p014">'KASKA NAT I JOHN 11. Mil I GOVERNOR AND COMMANDER-IN-CHIEF riiE GOVERN 1AKK Jacob H. L'uh Jenkins. . diaries J. Bills... ii I). En John A. Ehrhanlt . . ndon E nee .). Mi Adit. &lt;;pii Co: Com' Suri: Aide Supe Jacob S. I&gt;ew Samuel M. Meli Wai ilber Aug.2 'K-oln MILITARY BOARD Jacob II. Culver, Adjutant General, President John \V. McDonnell. Colonel Second Regiment Joseph A. Sti Dt John A. Ehfhardt. .Iu eral, Becorder Joseph W. Tl R-t P. Shuniwav s \V. k .1. Lani,'&lt; W. Garouttf . Red( </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Organized by General Order No. 4, July 13. 1881 .Joseph A. Storch. Colonel. Fullerton, July 15, I!to4 Warren R. McLaughliD. Lieutenant Colonel, Beatrice, July 2ii, 1904 Charles M. Richards, Major. Omaha, August 4. i George Ly on. Jr.. Major. Nelson. August 17. 1903 Fred &lt; n. August 9, 1904 PH. Boldeu Adjutant. York, Juh I II. Hull. Captain, Quartermaster, Fremont, July 31, 19()3 Davis, Captain, Commissary, Fremont. July 22, 1904 V. Fifer, Captain, Chaplain, York. July 31. 1101 I. Nicholson, Major, Surgeon, St. Paul, August 11, 1904 B. Hungate, Captain. Assistant Surgeon, Weeping Water, July 31, 1903 Emile C Underburg, Firat Lieutenant con. Stanton, August 24, 1903 NON-COMMISSIONED STAFF James II. Duncanson, Sergeant Major. South Omaha, August ti, 1904 John F. Steele, (Quartermaster Sergeant. Geneva August 6, 1904 A. Benj. Currier, Commissary Sergeant. August 13, 1 tt.-m. t &gt; —i t {') \'\ rrf i^\ i i pf \t n**i(* inn \V i^ii( j !" A lit' n^ </seg>
            <seg id="p016">( L'ANIES i A H.L.DuhSPll 2nd Lieut. Apr. 10 M ! 1st Lieu; n Bow W.Ohnisterte . 2nd Lient. Julj I Mar. 10, IE. Haebr.... W.G.Browne 1st Lieut. A.pi 'maha L.Burmester.. 2nd Li. Captiin 2nd Lieut. •! o J. H. I i in .':i(i Lieut. &lt;&gt;1 Apr. ■ ■:• . ... Captain P.C.Zeitfler 1st 1 .il Lieut. Captain st Lieut. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">SECOND INFANTRY— FIELD AND STAFF Organized by General Order No. 8. August 13, 1887 EW. McDonnell, Colonel, Fairbury. January 24, 1903 J. Bolshaw, Lieutenant Colonel, Lincoln, January 24. 1903 C. Hartigan. Major, Fairbury. February 13, LOOS 6. Osborne, Major, Omaha. March, 12, 190.'! ■ H. Phelps, Major, Schuyler, August 17, 1M3 II. Elton Clapp. Captain, Adjutant, Fairbury, August 11. q E. Culver. Captain, Quartermaster, Sutton. September 20, 1903 i trd K. Hum, Captain. Commissary, Lincoln, September 20, 1903 Addison E. Knickerbocker. Captain, Chaplain. Nebraska City, January 28, 1903 ,.rd W. Waldeii, Major, Surgeon, Beatrice, July 31, 1903 Alva S. Pinto, Captain, A Surgeon, Omaha. April 1. 1904 First Lieutenant. NON COMMISSIONED STAFF ias A. DeNoon. Serjeant Majir. Lincoln, August 15, Quartermaster Sergeant Kiam C. Ra t, Plattsmouth, August 9, 1904 I. II. Salsbury, Hospital Steward. August 15, 1!K)4 W. Gregg. Jr., Chief r 14, 1903 Jasper F. Cole, Color S </seg>
            <seg id="p018">&lt; COMPANIES Rank From When ™*Tc£Z. Station Captain 1st Lieut. 2nd Lieut. •Inly Aug. 02 W. F. Sammons ;. A. West 01 Mav .Jacob Kanzler 2nd Lieut. Sept. -- II. .1. I'nul Paul. W. S. Pine. II. .1. Paul . Captain Sept. » Captain 1st Lieut 12nd Lieut. I; VV. S. Paul 1st Lieu W. S. Pine, Jr.... 2nd Lieu' l'. Shannon. &gt;t*in Oct. •hick l;;'.ison. .ieut. .lime 1 S. F. Shannon Jack Reason. tin |Oci 1st Lieut. -In 2nd Lieut. tod Lieut U. A. Clmpp. . II. A. ( I&gt; H..1. 1 H. .1. Enir Wee icllt. M ) 2nd Lieut :iid Liein V J.-P. Cameron. ' ■ p I A. H. liar: •'■&gt;■ '04 3&lt;5ilkers 2nd Lieu II. Dean E. Weaver . Lieut. Oct. 1.. '&lt;•:; F. II. Gmytord 2nd Lieut. July 1 - 1 &gt;. F'alconer V. Furij 2nd Lieu - (). If. Newman tain F( inton nenriks Lieut. M. - -nd Lieut. May 24, '(M I 1st Lieut. Aug. H». 2nd Lieut. Aug. 1 I 1 1 1. V. Fuiav 2nd 1 i i m.lan i:s 11 i 11. Johnson 1st L 2nd I R .1. C. Ehernl)er&lt;ier. I F. Bashberger. . 2nd I A. Fuller. . . .■■r .1. A. Raine -nd Lieu', vug. 1&lt; K C. A. Y I C. II. 1'i 2nd Lieu' M 'tain Mar Mar, Apr. 12 '00 Dei- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Wvn I . ALKY TKOOT &gt;ewar ! 2nd Liei SIGNAL CORPS "lw; stati °- Name J. B. Henry . . Captain Sept. 1&lt;&gt;, ¥. H. Richard- Lieut . Sept. 1 r. II, l!*q Kremon -nd Lieut. Aug. 13, '04 L. H HOS1MTAL CORPS FromWhen 1^ 1 "!*^! Static! , n Originl Mus-: ter of Conr.vj Name Rank J. M. Birkner Captain Aug. E. A. Carr l-t Lieu &gt;. 10. 19 G. K. Spear... -'nd Lieui :. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">OF </seg>
            <seg id="p021">• </seg>
            <seg id="p022">REPORT OF INSPECTIONS. STATh OK NEBRASKA The Adjutant General State of Nebraska, Lincoln. Nebraska I taav onor to communicate to you the following ex' from the report of Captain J. Kreps. 22 Infantry, of 1 of the Hospital Corps: Bat Troop "A" and 8 Omaha Cavalry Troop, Compair orapan and "L," 1st regiment of Infantry, and "B," "C," "D tr "H." and "I," 2nd Regiment of Infan from May 18 to June 15, 1903, Inclusive: Complete records of organization and property !&lt;■ Genl's office and appeared up to date. Examination ha- All inspections were under arms and except five, in heavy march- Ing order with blanket roll (blanket, poncho, shelter* haversack (with knife, fork, spoon, meat can or tin plate and cup). The excepted five had some part of the equipment missing. The equipment not mentioned in "Memoranda being noted in separate reports follows: Uniform-blouse, trousers, d. b. f. shirt, cap, camp, hat, lc Equipage-mess tents. Buzz ns or Hunt Field r;r No encampments have been held in the State at since 1901. as the appropriation for that purpose for 1 I nai all used up in one camp. The state authority I it more advantageous to hold one ten day encampment in 1901 than one of five days in each of the years 1901-2. The appropriations made by the state for its organized militia •re not sufficient to pay the armory expenses of the different organi - sations. Each receives $100 per year for this purpose and in cases covers the actual rent; but in no case, the addition light, heat and janitor care. In consequence, compare w of the organizations have store rooms secure enough for the valuable property stored therein. In all cases money must be raised by the organizations to cover expenses. The Adjt. Gen'l of the State is trying to arouse enough interest in the Guard to cause the towns to build armories for their respective organizations. 1903 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 The officers all show great interest in their wark, although in every case the position entails more or less pecuniary loss. tThe company schools are not organized in accordance with our ing orders, but are in my opinion, rather assemblages more or leas mal for discussions. Some metod of assembling officers fo: tematic instruction would be advantageous. Where enlisted strength as given by Co. Commander from his ils was found to differ from same according Adjt. General's records, same is noted in organizations "Memoranda." Enlistments are made by Co. Commander, copy of enlistment paper being forwarded to Ad - jutant General of State within 5 days. (See copy of paper marked "B." kCo. Commonders responsible for Q. M. and Ord. stores are under d for $20000. (See copy of bond "C The arms and equipment inspected by me have been in the poss - n of the organizations since 1900 and defects are dHe to usage and age, not to material or manufacture. weather during my inspection could not have been worse for purpose. Heavy rains impeded railroad traffic and made roads almost impassable. Most of the organizations inspected by me depend on men from the country and surrounding towns for their strength, and the condition of the railroads and roads undoubtedly accounted for many absences. In drills, the companies could not do justice to themselves as I was able to have but four drills out of doors, three of being at night. Respectfully, (Signed) J. Parker, Lieutenant Colonel 13th Cavalry. Acting Assistant Adjutant General. EXTRACTS FROM THE 1903 REPORT OF INSPECTION OF COMP - ANIES "B," "F," AND "K" OF THE FIRST REGIMENT AND COMPANIES "A," "E," "K," "L," AND "M" OF THE SECOND REGIMENT, AND WEST POINT RIFLES BY CAPT. M. D. CRONIN, 2 5TH, U. S. INFANTRY ■e.) Captain Cronin recommends and urges increased ap - propriations for armory rent; and artificer to keep guns, racks, and lockers in repair, and receive extra pay for the same, in all compan FIRST REGIMENT. Company "B," at Stanton The company is in good condition, fairly well instructed, and re - cruited to the full strength authorized in Nebraska: it is well worth developing into as close an approach to a regular mpany as nfltinnnl enard conditions will Dermit </seg>
            <seg id="p024">en pu spr U ty and I &gt; well eu 1 cor any ufficie ideas in is com pa fi t rooms in towr Company "F." at y. adison now small, has an experienced captain, fair in drill, an excellent armory and equipment. The co struction in com Company of good quality, under a good captain, who has seem field service in the Phillipines, and who uses the company books as genuine company records kept up to date. The armory is excellent; su the Q. M. stores and ordinance kept conveniently and with system. The appearance and intelligence of the men were good; clothing good; accoutrements very good; arms effective and fairly clean; close It now, and t! at once proi to be fin capt d I d accoutermonts to I at the company stor&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 RECOMMENDATIONS. 1. Physical examination, U. S. Army standard, , officers and men. 2. Care now given not sufficient to preserve rifles in good con- r3. Insistance on preliminary drills and gallery practice. Mater - for gallery practice to be furnished. The present captain seems de - us of having all these and target practice as well. He is arrang - to have a little known distance target practice, but lacks material gallery practice. 4. Wagner's Security and Information to be furnihed: I think it probable that good use will be made of the ideas therein. The la for Nebraska, well adapted topographically, for problems in patrolling and minor tactics. 5. A full company of 65 men, with attendance probable in this farming community, will be comfortably accommodated in this excell - f armory. If this company does not approach the strength of 65, latoon with a 1st or 2d lieutenant can be organized readily in an acent town, to unite with this company at camps only, not at weekly drills. Experience seems to show that divided companies do not succeed, unless treated as independent unities receiving allowances direct from I d practically separate, except at encamp - ments. Company "K," at Columbus. iThis organization is worth an effort to develop it. The lieuten - are not well instructed, the captain saw service in the Philippines, seems very well fitted for his position and for the training of his company. Reorganized, practically, and within a few months; the com - missions of all three officers are dated April 10, 1903. The officers and most of the men, however, are not new to the servi' The appearance of the men was fairly good; their intelligence apparently good; the clothing, arms, and accourtements in the hands ie men were not sufficiently clean, nor properly cared for, though cable at present. The drill in close order was fair as to the movements executed, but not all the company drills had been taught; the drill in extended order was poor, due chiefly to the imperfect training of the squad leader. The captain showed a sound and comprehensive knowledge of both drills. RECOMMENDATIONS. 1. A more careful selection of recruits. 2. Physical examination. U. S. Army standard, officers and men. 3. Insistance on position and signting drills and gallery practice, all possible in present armory. Materials for gallery practiceschould be </seg>
            <seg id="p026">25 back-stops will be read by those who have used the Firing Regulations. 4. Wagner's Security and Information to be furnished company as a suggestive guide for outdoor exercises; officers of company not now informed on this book, and have no knowledge of this kind of work. Company "M," at Broken Bow. Present condition of company shows lack of attention to details and incompleteness of instruction; condition, however, is fair according to standard of state. Medium sized company: captain has seen mi in the Phillipines. The physical appearance and intelligence of the men was good: clothing fair; accouterments good; rifles fairly clean but effe' drill was limited by the weather to the manual of arms and ti which displayed no more than fair instruction, a perceptible recruit air being noticeable. RECOMMENDATIONS. CMore attention to completeness and thouroughness on the f the captain in the manner of instruction. Physical examination. my standard, officers and men The men do not give enon rifles in good con- dition. t Materials for gallery practice to be furnished. Wagner's Security and Information to be furnished. This company will be ready to use it after a time. 6. Present armory is sufficient only a room. Nebraska's allowance of $100 per annum is not at all en&lt; SECOND REGIMENT Companv Keari This company has good offi •»ceived in t'V parts of company drills, and is well worth an effort I &gt;p into close an approach to a regular army rompan company rHas a good armory, a good captain who has had field The intelligence and appearance of men are sioocl: clothir good: arms in fair condition and Drill U ireme good or be RECOMMENDATION Phy Animation. Army standard, of Mate will use them if furnished. and Inform: %&amp; a guide t&lt; "rise llery pm be furnished: tl </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 .ork. ■in has had field and all the offii tit in the work now being done: id in all the companies of not getting ; drill of a compan m into I order. The drill covere 11 of the compan and was fairly well done. 'any is in a health v co for ■ nded instruction. Tl. was good, their I •MMEXDATIO \bout $3.00 per month extra pay through^ *o an to supplant the care of the rifle by individual. This com of member? 9 method of caring for Their rifles are cleaner than those of most ance on position and arming drills and All but target practice are easily taught. il for brief pamphlet on preparation of and back-stop will be here used w when the firing regulations are left un-us« irity and Information to be furnished the com- iive guide for outdoor work. The outdoor work ibis com- pany enough advanced in drill to a- in patrol and other problems. nt armory is very good, but a good deal of the energy of the company necessarily goes to work designed to pay the increased Comp -ohuyler. 'iition of the company ning of officers and Comp -ohuyler. dition of the company 3 now fair, indicating a mild but now fair, indicating a mild but 'ining of officers and en. Has maintained itself quite en. Has maintained itself quite noticeable an i f vim and steadily in its present state; there i steadily in its present state; there i noticeable an 1 &lt;f vim and ness, but on the other hand tliere is a steady though mild atten- tion to business. The inspection was made at a time when the roads of th&gt; were muddy; the weather too was rainy; both may account for the small attendance. The physical appearance and apparent intelligence of the men were good; the clothing an irments clean and in good condition; Com i h the effort to develop II close an ap ional Guar .tlons permit. . and really eff 1. Physical e </seg>
            <seg id="p028">27 RECOMMENDATION'S Army standard, officers am! 1. Physical examination, U Materials for gallery praeti. now prepared to use them profitable &gt;repared to use them profitably. Wagner's Security and Informal Wagner's Security and Information to The present captain has had field service, and fit resent captain has had field service, and f: ir gently at once. Tho i The !' aller than it should be. is. smaller than it should b« Cc 'he i ndition &gt;ndi t ment, and as to li Q of offii illy improved much in th&lt; red, it would ha v imoi imend t li • - any suffered f nominally in il men of some in' : rompany m for drill. rhe physical app* : Their clothing was in fair com! i w ; rill un ab to the new admini rhe "company is not pi of serious work. The is apparei rious work. Thf- did not did n to ure value is sion tna 5 after providing for companies now In gooi! now in good funds would be probably well spent in developing i be probably well spent in developing a large town and railroad junction. ge town and railroad junction. EUSCOMMSNDATIO1 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">28 2. Care insufficient for preservation of rifles in good condition. 3. Insistence on position and sighting drills and gallery practice which can be had in this company armory. These are attractive in idea to the company. Material for gallery practice to be furnished and a brief pamphlet on preparation of ammunition, target, and back-stops will be read, when the firing regulations will be left unread. 14. Wagner's Security and Information to be furnished company suggestive guide for outdoor exercises. Officers hesitate to go be - drill regulations or to do anything without . basis on a written 15. The company by aid of dances, etc., expects to pay the present , some three times more than the state allowance; present armory but too narrow for drill. This company needs a drill master for several drills; a ser - geant regular army would be of great value for this purpose. Enlistment confined to men in Norfolk or immediate vicinity, En now at Norfolk Junction , a circumstance that retards or ;lopment of the company. and other places remote from Nor - makes impossible the himogeneous tpany "M," at Albion. The company has three very good officers, and is prepared to e immediate benefit from any assistance; is in a healthy state :i excellent (lass of enlisted men. ' By the use of the town or their weekly drills, they have practically an excellent arn.n The physical appearance and apparent intelligence of the men is i;ood; their clothing good; accouterments good, some new; rifles clean but effective. Close order drill fairly good; extended order drill fairly good All officers well posted on both drills. RECOMMENDATIONS. 1. Physical examination, U. S. Army standard, officers and men. 2. Individuals do not give quite enough care to rifles. 3. Materials for gallery practice to be furnished. Insistence on small arms firing course. 4. Wagner's Security and Information to be furnished company, aptain unacquainted with minor tactics and does not look beyond any drill; he is more prepared to use this book as a guide to out - door work. Point Rifles (Independent), at West Point. The company are at present interested in their work and making fair progress, yet not quite up to a good standard possible for them. Their immediate prospects of improvement are sufficient to warrant an • r. It is an Independent Company of the Nebraska National Guard. During the past year there was an interval of some months </seg>
            <seg id="p030">29 i Recently interest has been revived and good progress made d efficiency. The membership includes a large per cent of un - ly desirable men. The captain is a man very busy with several employments, and unable to take personal interest in or to attend and practice work. To him, however, is largely due the revival nterest in the company and the increase of membership. H nee in the community is of value to the companv a; at some t } himself p obably he would be glad the company to anot The physical appearance and intelligence of the men ■ an: close order drill barely fair, no extended or RECOMMKXDATIOX Arms to be kept at armory or store-roo ed o\ iany square miles at men's houses as now 2. A captain is needed who lias time to give personal military studies and to the company. ■ Articifer to supplant care given rifles by individuals: the latter now exercise sufficient care. A course in small arms firing to be insisted upon: materials rallery practice to be furnished. R Wagner's Security and Information to be furnished. At pres - e company is not sufficiently advanced to n i after a time. The company has now no real meeting place of its own. The work of drill of the company is now practically done by the I the 2d Lieut., being absent and the captain busy with other m:. Lincoln, Xebr., June 4, 1904. Adit. Gener Lincom, Xeb I have the honor to submit the following report of the march and neampment at Camp Pershing, York, from August 25, 03 to August The command ass&lt; I the armory at Lincoln, Tuesday, Aug- 5, '03 at 4:30 a. m Strength: ommissioned • 11 non-commissioned officers. riing good, accoutrements good, mostly new. No tentage on hand pt shelter tents; rifles effective and in fai airly \ physical examinaiio \rmy standard, of officers and Gen. J. H. Culv </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 i 1 cook. 24 privates 2 civilian teamsters, 1 ambulance, nsport wagon. Command started on its march at 5:10 a. m., reaching Emerald at a. m. On account of the heavy rain during the previous night. the roads were in a heavy, muddy condition. Left Emerald at 8:30 a. m. for Pleasant Dale, where it arrived at 11:00 a. m., after a march over heavy, mudd impelling the command to take the railroad track for a distance of three miles sending the ambulance and transpoi wagon by wagon road. Dinner at Ple;&lt; Ip furnished by tr On the journey from Dale to Milford, Lieut Spear wa ival at M •d Tie r\ (1 (1 I for tl Dinm 1 ' U bath f six mi ordere. &gt; 1 had cc lan k d« egg farmer for and tl for miles tr Left PI' living th on the ground of the Seldiers Hor overcome by the heal and had to be transported in the ambulance, but Supp. p. m in durin ,ht. purcha m. a he; a halt &lt; ad ma ditional teams u ■I'm necessi m. with the </seg>
            <seg id="p032">31 \d (1 ii at this point, and at about one o first few miles i fretting horse hitched to guns for i grounds at Mi M the Quart &lt; Qua 1 Supper of pot;i &gt;read and co: ad and i t\ gle with shelter tenti that had been re. V a.t hau home station, and were now issued to i 1 d t( light was gone and only one corporal ar (1 onlv one corporal and shelter tent and knew how shelter tent and knew how lanterns, such assi- lanterns, such as? up, but when daylight up, but when o&lt; men were tired and th i then en were tired and the tents protected them from n that fell again that night. Reveille was sounded at 5:30 a. m. on tl ome needed instructio. ven the m again tha ded at 5:30 a. m. on th tents and the I 'nding nts and th« 1 the spirits of the old veterans o the spirits of the old veterans 01 ing or watching us from th At nine o'clock \\ ing or watching us fron \t nine o'clock w&gt; ! e of one hour by the roadsi* Du </seg>
            <seg id="p033">32 caned meat, heated coffee, bread and three gallons of milk bought of an accommodating farmer for forty cents. kThe route in the afternoon was through Beaver Crossing, thence i towards Utica. The camp ground that night was on the public near a farm house where we purchased forage and obtained water .nee covered that day about twenty miles. I Reveille on the 2 8th, was at 4:30 a. m. and our column was in tion at 6:30. When near Utica we were struck by a severe rain rm which continued until we reached Waco. This caused a number galled shoulders on horses using leather collars with sweat pads ler them. Large raw sores, something that cannot occur with th^ r regulation metal collars. tCamp Pershing, at York, was reached by a tired, muddy lot, es - lly the horses showed severe fatigue, after the twenty two or three trip since 6:30 over muddy, heavy roads. We reported at about one o'clock August 28th Very Respectfully (Signed) S. E. Yoder Captain Commanding Battery "A Armory Troop "A" N. N. G, Seward. N'ebr., Sept. 5, 190 ■ The Adjutant General Lincoln, Nebr., LI have the honor to submit the following report of practice march Seward to York and return. I In obedience to General Orders No. 37, Troop "A" was assembled the Armory and proceeded to march, at 9 a. m., August 16, 190::. rsuing a westerly direction, crossing the Blue river. A disagreeable n had set In the day previous, and continued, making the roads ivy, and progress slow. We went into camp near Utica that evening: 1 call at 5 a. m. the following morning and took up the line of march 7:00 a. m. It continued to rain until about- 11:00 a. m., when we preached the vicinity of York, and had entirely ceased when we ar - ed at Camp Pershing, distance marched, twenty seven miles. tl reported to the comanding officer, and went into camp as direi -t- On the 31st day of August, at close of the encampment, pursuant General Order No. 38, my command broke camp, and proceeded to urn overland, arriving at Seward on the following day, without ident. The transportation consisted of two teams, which transported the camp equipment and rations. Very Respectfully W. S. Baldwin, </seg>
            <seg id="p034">r ( Y 1) &gt; \ ( l&gt;u f \ nd i tw x cellen commanding 3 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">34 lhat the work of this organization throughout th than strong, including thre&lt; iip. The equipment included one ambu w, th was drilled in 1 first aid wounded. This drill ,ie hand litter, th( e wound 1 ■ounded. The wounded when brought in were pn and labeled, describing the injury in en md the banda imiliar with their duties. * 16. Each com: thirteen common and tt ; f with pins and i on hand at capitol. including • ; all in hod of ally the ratio of th •nd all enlisted $1.00 per df of ten days Adjutant General of in or in the open ma When in i or in a&lt; turn t under in- .nneral or t li • or. 21. At home . drills per month and per month and have dismounted drills as ordered f drills. . market Exhibit A. I T 1 and company drills of the infantry clearly showed that in the drills at home ■ us the details had not received the attention thai lonld. rule the men up, their movements were loose, and lacked a military snap. In the marching the attention of the men was not required or upon, they being ai; and watch other things. One particularly foul was " of the men in ranks while marchins that tion pouches with cont' urly equipped field dis wen 1 oth bility, ired. Tl ; in wa Officers are paid of tr i the nd all purcha re required of all organizations. Inl drill Troop and b re required to drill moun </seg>
            <seg id="p036">( he feet instead of straight to the front. As a rule the squad and company drills were poorly doni i be 1 ds were w Irills at the homo stations should have pro hi batallion drills the: apportunity foi illng the battalion n h the commands and n nortunitv for assembling the battalions. Tl itv in -line the with the commands and move! book, and they sir and thev sho nations. With one possible exception ihi- ii a rered their comam ml v handle them well. Their ui tions to be slow, and ments. One p to be n hanilK h plat-ing them they pull them around and The parades wen T x ed improvement during camp. The ed urday, Au ies in line in in line in tv in that the faulty in that did not turn ; nform m » The salutes with I n • iitly bn salutes should be mad. drill re. I in the dri P a m The -first guard inouni . TV noti&lt; • nd the result of his I IK 1(1 nd the result of his in formity in the dress at the- Th band of this regiment which had been in tk ek, did exceedingly well. Its mus ally the man good. The time in its marches was Jo When column in a march p the column. One day the battalioi out on a p'ra olumn ;ent out on a pra. One day the battalions w went out alone, with lustre throw out advance a: nt out alone, with instruct!. &lt;&gt;w out advance and n and then go into camp with shelter tents and throw o^: ) with shelter tents and throw out a s and then outposts. I was able to visit only two of the battalions while on 1 outposts. I was able to visit only two of the battalions while did i! on of the advance and re; did not- see the execution of the advance and re: which formal prineipli </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 the case of the third battalion an at : 5. This was not done in with the principl lawn, and the Major when questioned did not evidei iliar- ith the methods laid down It is ordered in be maintained The p&lt; out an ; ■ ry. Tin T ly come under 30, and pei il condition is sood. Tti 1 condition is sood. Tin behavior while in ramp. I of drunkenness or in- behavior while in ramp. offit •' ons and nor ons and no: It r f and e i 1 ' the diffi- the diffi- ill have ivided by tin- i 11 have &gt;vided by the l h v. a ■ ■ - quired, adopted </seg>
            <seg id="p038">bis d f j \ tie end of the » r - t 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p039"/>
            <seg id="p040">ENCAMPMENT AT RT RILEY, KANS 1903. </seg>
            <seg id="p041"/>
            <seg id="p042">ENCAMPMENT AT FORT RILEY, KANSAS \ The A it (12 com |' nents of the ii 5 id nationel guard neral i on the trip to and from Fort Riley , follow off Hosp Aggregai men which joined the various companie to which they had been enroute Each organization travelled from its home station in charge of its own officers, by the train schedule given, though each of the trains ■were delayed, and ran somewhat behind the times exp&gt; Field and staff officers left their h'ome stations and the ranking officer assumed charge of trains on which they travelled, so tha' train was under command of a field officer. The first company to move started at 5:05 a. m. the 17th, and the latest one to move, at 5:00 p. m., and the entire command was at Fort Riley by 1:00 d. m. the 1Mb., when camp made on Pawnee Flats, a part of the U. S. military reservation, near the Kansas river, about one mile from the mill the town of Junction City, Kansas. This reservation lies on both the Kansas river, m upon the north side, and Is in extent an average of 6 miles one way n total 12 :r cent of the aggrega ■tachments from the H orders from your offic </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 $ the other; is mostly of rolling grass land, with occasional small streams of water and of timber, and is quite rough ne;- rr; this terrain affording an ideal field for the manein The entire f&lt;&gt; &gt;nal d lne entire ton U Tli wtai- Tin uunted II for w) pon bridg- and remain on ong « and remain on th'- nation : om oth» offi t work The fol issued by the brigade c work The ■ er issued by the brigade com- niandi lona! lonal i here « • • • « * • •• O&lt; ' to the "blues' and placed •■rnor Hardy road, right rt ms on line, one trenchme' of the bayonet: about 1 "brown" forces appeared about 1000 yards in front advancing ove open ground, when we opened fire: the "browns' continued to ad under fire of the "blues' until within 130 yards, when -ring was sounded at 1 : and u Jied to ramp The regiment partook of lunch, r marched about 10 miles. In his report of the exercises, he umpire makes this comment well conducted, control of fire, on the regiment, "Exercise generally excellent." problem leploymen ■ division," in which the entire forces of the camp were deployed to cover Fort Riley against an imaginary force marching again i of all arms of the service, was about 7 miles long. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">43 deployment being completed in about ;5 hours; a feature oi II cise was the work of the signal corps, which brought all pa command into communication with each other, and with the h mgh Fort Riley and the Western Union &lt;h Company, in one lour and- forty minutes: ten miles of wire, with the with th&lt; and- for ty mir "field buzzer" and heliograph bei; 'field buzzer" and heliograph being used, I October 2:\. Th- opos - - of all arms," in w! at of the October '!:',. Th&gt; s "problem No. I I of opo» forces of all arms," in which the rep h army made a " &lt;ance in force" agaii M in for IV vho were marching to attack our camp. ack our can We left camp at .S:00 a. in., and in iwo and one half li il one half fa d and were in aad win two boars, and aad wire fences, field- ind timta Our alion w Our ■ i tterv of artille- irtillery so suddenly tl ;i rush with a tn i're turned back ' dion and i a rush with a troop hird battalion and nh an efft Ire 1&gt; nv "M" v imp, arriving the d dii i thi e urn: ind controlled." 1 ittended Divli boring i ied the balance of tlv vork, and with receivi: rmy quartern! October 26. Th' in which tt lied from camp a ■ rth and west, from where at, made 01 nd with receiving p army quarter 1 October 20. Thi o i which the re from i chet from whe: ;d and intrenched position, were defending i and intren of Fort Riley, and the passage of the K ind the passage of th^ r; in thi deal of ammunition was expended le advancing in three lines over open ground, the first line advancing in three lini nd, the first line, in « . , ' • da one he "blue" intrenchm*-! The umpire the third </seg>
            <seg id="p045">44 to have boen carried out bv subordinate cocmmanders as intend - vhile this attack formation was judicie :d over which It was made rendered it practically ho 1 &gt;m the beginning nd over which this brigade had to attack, was one of the worst ■\ be imagined, and the "brown" force at this part of the line was compelled to come over a hill within short range of the ached infantry, which swept the hill with a fire that probably noth - &gt;uld ha\- od." The exercise was concluded at 12:30 p. m. and the regiment re - turned to camp, distance inarched about 10 mil |)n this afternoon the greater part of the equipage was loaded cars and the regiment went int&lt;&gt; . preparatory to entraining home stations the next morning. If our trains between 8:00 and 0 a. ii riving at their stations on the ling and all by afternoon of the next day. The train carrying the K. Mbion. Norfolk. Schuy - ler and Fremont companies, which was the first to leave Fort Riley, was delayed at Lincoln four hours, from 7:00 until 11:00 p. m., for the following were all furnished with transporta - tion from Fo! lations, via Ihe I'nion Pacific road, but entraining at Fort Riley, the railroads arranged to divide the train at Lincoln and divert the Albion, Norfolk and Fremont companies to the Cli Northwestern road, which was done, but as the bag - gage had originally been loaded for shipment through by the V Pacific road, the trains were necessarily held until new baggage cars could eloaded. The officers on this train the drinking water in the coaches became exha - in the day, and that thereafter, none was furnished: also that In some of the coaches the oil in the lamps was gone, and the men sat in darkness all night : also, that in some of the coaches there were no flres and no fuel to make them, and as the night was chilly the men were not at all comfortable. I The subject of this camp cannot not be left without mention of Its ndid arrangements, and the excellent methods of sanitation, much g learned by us on these subjects. I On several evenings lectures were given by officers of the regular y to national guard officers, on medical, quartermaster, commis - , strategy, projectiles, etc. The weather was very appropriate, being cool and clear, and, while so cool nights that fires were used in officers tents, there was no suffer - ing on the part of the men. </seg>
            <seg id="p046">45 The regimen n repor the'total \. follow \cu Thi 1 o ic vananrf g tht ;i which was whol imp even •&gt;, this diversity of arms being greater than at any ■ • d by the Nel uctive to the officers and men. t'ul eomparisn of our regiment with national ■ in other &lt;»d me to believe that the second was among the very 1&gt;- The officers and men of th hard to learn and profit from the 1 nd I sir,' John nnell. Colonel Commanding Sutton, Nebraska, November 7. 1903 To the Commanding Officer 2nd i Nebraska National Guard. EIn compliance with verbal orders from regimental headqua ber 27th, 1903, I have the honor to submit a report of the quar - aster's department from October ICth id. From general orders 42, dated Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's office. October 5, 1903, I proceeded to Lin - coln, Nebraska, on the 15th, and made arrangements for the checking out and loading of the quartermaster's stores and equipage that were required at Camp William Carey Sanger, Fort K Kansas. were 1 ' in this ramp, representin thank them for tlr Your . tion is tailed 10 the R </seg>
            <seg id="p047">46 One box and one flat were required to transport the equi; ich were loaded, the 16th, and the entrainii K at Srhuyler. L at Norfolk, M at Albion, Signal ;ont. the l&gt;ari' i oni Hospital Coi lver at Sutton, and d k, B at - pr. F at Madison. G Union Pacific, and out ir ! rom fou m. F ;^hed for fift ion ! d anil ought throi allot hundred and all on 1, 1 barrel of lime on in ,nd fresh r&gt;'nt and coni] id equipage i Tekamah. I &gt;ln. G at Omaha, H at Aurora Adjutui Iirbur- Col. Bo! pt. Hurlz at Lincoln, Major I Omaha &gt;n, an Vork, B at St£ E at Will Columbus. L at Omal B n Bow, all on lpmei i'ling the ambulan .•amp of &gt;rds of wo( ,; tut for their u.sp while in i iih the Quar t'lid iresn k ammii' eipt from tlv </seg>
            <seg id="p048">. R i . ( Hi T1 Idir (1 four him e hundred and and, a- &gt;n to i only one third of that number of irt uired ibmitted. Capt, and Qr. Mr. 2nd bal report t the itrtermia card </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 T. P. to Norfolk, and detachment to P. to I Paul huyler 3 Albior Lincoln Si Quartermaster. Co. F. and detachment from Hospital Corps, ir. 1 flat car. V . P. to Lincoln. Oiv &lt;r for 10 ho airbury, viz: Colonel ilartigan. 2. R. K R. E. Riley, 2. which made up the forth, fifth and sixth trains, with the exception of the coaches w noon on the 2Gth By recommendation from the Chief Quartermaster, through d Ion and brigade headquar^ ihird brigade went into bivoui the night of the 26th, which made it possible for all tentage and 1 headquarters of tl it four p. m.. and at once all te down and each company provided with one wagon for transportation and in less than one hour and thirty minutes all of this equipage was loaded on their special cars, all camp equipment received from the quartermaster's department was now returned and the memorandum receipt taken up, with the exception of twenty cords of wood. three hundred and twenty bales of hay, twenty six sacks of oats, one barrel "" of lime and one half barrel of crufle oil, which were expended in in- . 1 ba Pulli frown, ! 1. Lieut. Marr, 1. Major I Phoi 1 . • ial. irora. I'. P. to Omaha. \ to Beatrice, B. &lt;fc M. t&lt;i X. \Y. to One stock car foi 2 horses to Omah. V. Walden, 2, Lieut. &lt;"&lt;&gt;! Regimental h&gt; r. P. to Beatrice P. to O^ 1 pi hen transferred to Omali; U. P The above report was tions tbaggage to be loaded on this </seg>
            <seg id="p050">.li nd «1 r ■i * 1 ii d of the 29th. i \djutant &lt; National Lincoln. Ne honor to report that in compliance w tted Lin raska, October olh. 1 a National in compliance with (i nor to report that ting of forty-four (44) enlisted men and ti rain con\ I men and th "remont. il train conveying troops A., 0 inniand, baggage and : p. m.. and my command, baggage and 1 time the train depai P The trail. P Wllltal M., and after some delay 1 was directed to tlu- 1., and after some delay I wi 1 to the Camp of Company "B," United States Signal Corps, to which m pany "B," United States Signal Corps, to which « I rep Captain Mitchell. Signal Corp I ing the camp, at :'. p. m On Monday. October 19th, Lieutenants Richards and command of squads consisting of regulars and mill for signal work They established stations about five mi . and </seg>
            <seg id="p051">50 opened communication with camp a) dark; both hello- ed with entire On O \iljui;i nd niili' uilt a i to the artille • On in communication ! I wai ion 1 Man On O. It ■ Gibl nrk with Field communica i he 1 field buzz On 'i On ()■ d the corps to the Armor} property, and pu 4 a. m. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">REPORT OF [NSPECTIONS 1904 </seg>
            <seg id="p053"/>
            <seg id="p054">Lincoln, N • ibmit the follow u B-ka National Guard, which wasmade !■• April 2.",, 1904. nd&lt; are forwarded duplicate "Memo 1 Inspection, " and a return of field | is, and appurtenaii' an Inspectic The 1 out and enclo organization The returns u£ strength of or from the number counted by m\ ;o note under head I have thought to have this r turn made by the t unaided, in order to show their k. I have made copies of these returns for the dui returns for the duplii to have thein randa, but it has not been convenien fission is only technical, I presume it is of no It will be noticed that none of the organizations have winter t* ,nor do I deem it advisable to issue it to them for the following sons: them have not sufficient store room It would seldom be needed and in some, perha; caaes, to become moth-eaten and never be worn. It would be likely wise damaged. be called out in \\ If an organization should probably be supplied within a reasonable time. Measures should be taken to give the national gua ege of free p&gt; Most of the time given to the ser\ and enlisted men is without compensation, and in addition to many Incidental expenses are incurred. In some cases the pecu burden is heavy. One company in Omaha pays $1100 a t for an armory, over and above the amount allowed by tb i in th&lt; icjuipm manders were made out by them without my aid, and in many caw are incorrect, but where the number of men i tiffei 1. It would be a burden to company comman </seg>
            <seg id="p055">54 aend that materials for gallery practice be furnished to the national guai In the v. and in inclement weather when weekly are confined to armories, drills become monotonous and many i way. Gallery pi &gt;nie an attraction and might be of incalculable And in some to 'here no tar: - ie found this will be the only method by which rifle practice can be in command of eompani' and 1 knov made bj tllery The personnel of the orted upon at tin In the manner indicated ii Jamii; S. DAGGETT of the state ha iply of wooler p. m. on the 12th Ordinance and camp equipment was i&gt;ed in armory We left Wynioie at th, on p. train !ayed a half hour in getting cars placed so they could be unloaded, but in spite of this delay, had ba ansferred to two shipped id sounded boois and til o'clock. 1 Dinner by side of road three miles fro; the home of ig farmer. Plenty of tin oked fresh beef, potatoes, eoff' I The afternoon march was uneventful, except that horses and men ered greatly from the heat — the m&lt; M in shade. \.. I ford onth€*sit£o' n^ourii* Wymore. Xebr.. Seji' To The Adjutant General. Lin I have the honor to e following repoi to David City during 1 ' In obedience to cqpamands, B. bled in tl </seg>
            <seg id="p056">\ to pull. Th understood that th mmediately ■ The trailing of the loned oV, to his duty, providing were h infinitly W officer. ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p057">56 ii. Nebr., In compliai il Or morning of A to David I somewhat hill &lt;led to i road wa llent condition, ni iped in the vicinity of I'lyses the .&lt;iuain n( - of tt nor- Mon. il Order ■!&gt; brc 1 p. m., April 23rd and mi ■ the home station, arrivin ard late that niglr The h havin lrill, the march did not injur- Very K \V. S. BALDWIN Commanding 1 Fort Crook. Nebraska, An 1904 Horn Sir led order, I have the honor to make report : I report- vernor Mickey at 1 1 orders, and to General Culver the evening same day at David for duty with the National Guard of in the vl&lt; The annual encampment of thi :al Guard. -tie of two regiments of Infantry, under command of Brigad ! . H. Culver, the first regiment of infantry mandcd by Colonel J. A. Storch, second regiment commanded b; J. W. McDonnell, Signal I nmanded by Captain J. R. Henry, ital Corp nded by Captain J. M. Birkner, Bat manded by Captain S. E. Yoder, and Troop "A" commanded by tenant W. S. Baldwin, was held at David City, Nebraska. The ground selected for the camp lies immediately south and adjoining the It occupied about fifty acres of land, extending one and one-half miles . and a quarter of a mile north and south, at the eastern extreme, forming an L on the south and east of the Chautauqua Park. "That portion occupied by the National Guard was on a gentle slope to the north, ami ip ground occupied by the battalion of the ' ieth Inf T he south, with artificial ponds </seg>
            <seg id="p058">' I Rt ( I r&lt; w a Qii i red REF" ound clns •nal G Th •lal Gu i aid mom and offlf sun ,,1 and I </seg>
            <seg id="p059">58 liering. The ed into ■ ■ on the la : the encampment from that evidenced on the The men behaved the- I did no soldier under the influence of liquor during tl ' was al1 The mi the d ,,-d lnO |,, of which then of each, that is, by thi (1 lar battalion, was full d with co 1 drills, both in day the 29th of ,] solution of a proble Hiino drafted and planned by General Culver. Adji: order for which pended. Th. . the troops in the main dexteriously handled, al - to th. from th. In my opinion the Browns, command! meat deal of ammun - im battle, for I noti. of consul. 'luine and intensity « of a hill or ■ liring line at the base. The Ik o be. but affords i in practical war work and methods. One thin:: hy of this connection, Leadership is one of the important f;i ains and majors of li a the in th Ional Guard and who were well up in theii managed and lied their men more readih ad efficiei them line of battle quickly an. than did o little itoniaUng how racrul neve line of battle mnlated, before this, were e quickly effective, in the hands of expert ptains and ma the majority ot the &lt; men, her in the Cuban or Phillipi; oth, and would m lent officers in actual warfare. Many service in the Phillipines In erg's ■ rviee in tha&gt; iiialed by few and by none. following named offi. !fil the duties of their grade. I consider them efficient and re - &gt;nld an en miring t! - the country: Adjutant General Culver is an en. .fleer, having the inn no efforts to bring it up to rd. Cole n&lt; \ Ehrhardt are thor - ough 1 relial)le men in jjjg good ;■. - i 'ilit\" Colont?l^Si orch in d \' '*&gt; n tipII nf fliA </seg>
            <seg id="p060">59 ndled th tendin ment ii prove ird mountine, guard • \ener and Captain Holdeman Phillipines. They are rel; li . ,.■■■, the latti ent, the latn in y will be found iiid energetic offlr&gt; Surgeon Pin The and ) f The field ariille' nch R animated nondescript the wh' annu hnsnital and Sisrnal ( I 1 wounded, and field or taken ofl woun al ■ in having a well drill' in having a well dril! both flag and I 1 man* in the use of both, and found tin ad found thei promptly by both promptly by 1 ?n in arnn Th»- on and ■ in the correction of in the correction of movements pertaining to professional n movements pertaining to professional n is herewith appended. The transportation of the troops from t! is herewith appended. The transportation of the troops from thf towns of the •mpanies, and sent din :up from home station undi towns of the state to the a rnpment nipanies, and sent din mp from home station undi of company command' The encampment wa Duratioi: ion about half mile from David C of company command The encampment was Duration, eight da ion about half mile from David &lt; good: is on a trunk line, no buildings on half mile long and one hundiv </seg>
            <seg id="p061">60 s are for. Boiled water v ■or it. luipment for fiei i uniform wa brought, but no ■ik or caterer t its gi The - ' 11 IV ' ! time cii The ■\ Da n who uard. ial Guard of the ■•■If, shon </seg>
            <seg id="p062">61 HEADQUARTERS FIRST BRTC To The Adjuts andt 1 ( " ond </seg>
            <seg id="p063">62 Supper. ]). m Dress parade • the hours of in. and 7: HO p. m The infantry regiments will alternate in the hour of drt- the second regiment havinu parade a \i. m..and the f raent at 7:10 p. m., Wedn ■ ngnst 17th. Retreat will be sounded at close of parade of inent When there is no pai vill be sound ■ companies will be paraded in com; Tattoo, ... p. r Call to q II. The' and drills will bt iion of the colonels, trooi m! of thf ill can it forth their utm ions to accompli :- mended ' 1 stations. IV*. ed. All orcli barn-yards and corn fields will be considered &gt; anc '&gt; all enclosed fields which emitted to use will In on entering and retirli V . (1 will be pla&lt; all du' red. Thi i the mei mal Gua will no' No honorable soldier will ;&lt; se privileges thus granted. Oth« will be deprived of all abject tli (heir conduct may demand. J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General, Commanding First Brigade, X The hours of drill were largely devoted to extended order, o\; rear and . d. The pasture lands of Mr. And' ontributed the use of it to the guard, afforded ample space for these formations. rd mounting and iments ■ ■■ agged and faulty: improved with each formation, aided materially 1&gt; ;&gt;le of the ret f the national d. The two n made rapid advancement and ted in no small degree to the of these ceremonials. tation oi 'efully watched by the Surgeon 1 from the Hospital ide the rounds of the ■i) a dressing of s </seg>
            <seg id="p064">63 &gt;n c h \ )n Saturd FIRST Bl; 1 Ordf The First divi 0111 ba ," one platoon of cavalry. pital an. rv from b 3on each from the hospital and signal Store! Major B K and L. under command of lit, with Col. McDonnell, commanding Fir and of Lt. Lawton, 30th Inf., commanding the Second division. ntion is called to field order orchards, etc., being considered impassable t Public roads will be 01 bble land of s. of which permission has been granted for the pui I Company officers will make a careful ii .at no ball cartridges are carri - the fi; fter leav T^ «3 C I* 1 1 ♦ f JM »m* i 1 1 \\ I *^1 Tl s .and and q a HEADQ1 imp i division will one platoon of cavalry 1; Nich' t division and Cos. I an </seg>
            <seg id="p065">64 No firi: grounds and id ever will ammunition will bi (hey will halt alt their commai ammunition will he turned in return t On &gt;n will 1m mp ip. Gi in will Ix and other pi • d th; and oth&gt; 1. ( The first division will wi The Si liirts, and wll unifo Brown I and M and will ill be i 1 i t l id on i ■ If in coi tion I with tin to a&lt; Lit on and I nd. ;■ and l.i Ion and rod. plain Hi will re; rith the First division, as imp h Inf. Regt. with the rid. iand of n. Culver Id. mand of Bris- Gen. Cuh O. G. OSRORNE. Colonel McUoniK'H i to mo\ ■ on line a imp for and a ; one half move one and one h :ip and then north three i ap and then north 1 1 &gt; ii undub' , </seg>
            <seg id="p066">65 canvon. Colonel Storch, maneuvering and ad-. to halt in order to give Colonel McDonnell time I commander of the "Blues" was only ai P*rt of his command promptly," and the "Browns" had to halt in ord lime for the signal corps to straighten out the tangle. I meantime the artillery got into position and a Both were then permitted to advance. The cavalry was thrown out « &lt; ■ :he flanks. A number of excellent movem - both commands and some mistakes made, prim understanding of orders. I The nature of the terrain &lt;&gt; afford an excell' ity for artillery range which was improved The signal corps by the use of the heliograph kept tht - tiding officer in touch with each army. The I m followed advancing to o care for the d about two hours and afforded frequently duplicated in ai vice. The I • m. The for. mbled by the regimental commanders I returned to camp by different routes, with advance and rear irds thrown out the same as when advancing to th&gt; airy was ordered to repair the fences and close all gates along the »s of maneuvi- The following is the report of the Chief Umpire: The Adjutant ( Camp Victor Vifquain David City, Nebraska. I have the honor to submit the follow* relative to the exercises of the 2»ith instant: tThe ground selected for the ex and map ;d under directions of the commanding general) was appro, the opposing columns (the Browns under Colonel McDonnell and Blues under Colonel Storch) about five o'clock p. m. The original plan was for the Browns to take position near the northern extremity and the Blues near the southern id on I from commanding gene' cular objective being to gain possession of and control a narrow passage or defile situated about midway between the front of forces Owing to the short time allowed for p quent lack of knowledge of the theatre of m « were 01 ued by the commanding general up to the momc contact of the opposing forces, which naturally &gt;me cont and uncertainty and hampered the actions of commanding offt&gt; This operated particularily to the disadvantage of the B This force, after having ntageous p« 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">66 E:h considerable skill was shown in taking advantage of the folds irregularities of the ground, was ordered back by the commanding ral, the movement being considered premature, having: been I re the Browns had a-ttained their assigned position. tin the meantime, through misunderstanding of the orders of the imanding general, the Browns were advancing and making their hile the greater part of the Blues were retiring (about on not receiving or understanding the orders continued to hold . ed /position.) At about th. commenced and continued little interruption to completion. tThe action developed into an attack on the whole force of the he advanced and practically isolated battalion of the M, which was pushed through the defile and up to within 100 yards he Brown- Ir center and left (where they were strong company making a diversion on the right of the Browns and ing in some effective firing, but from a position that render. ender or distruction inevitable in the face of overwhelming numbers lose range. nt on the part of the Blue ■one gun (at about 1200 yards) and long range infantry i opposed by the Browns with one gun and I ; .led on the left and center. The action terminated with the opposing forces holcli&gt; cally their original positions, the Blues having lost one 1 both sides suffering severe loss in killed and wounded LA relative comparison of the general dispositions of the oi s shows that of the Blues to have been the better. Special commendation is due the Signal Corps for its zealt i efficient performance of duty, showing careful train! officers. ctfull CHAS. BYRNE, Major 30th U. S. Inf Chief Dm On Sunday. II, all exercises were omitted, with U ,n of the ne uard mount and dress parade. Devoi held at the A. tent by Chaplain Fifer of the regiment," and in the evening etary Mayne of the 1 On Monday morning the usual guard mount and drill, followed in the afternoon by grand review by the Governor and staff, General Daggett commanding the brigade during review. The troops kept a SplCDulu all^DIDGDl an </seg>
            <seg id="p068">67 selves with great credit and showed decided improvement over the marching column? of the first days in drill. t Returning to camp, the troops were mustered and paid. On 1 morning the general was sounded tti ■ : the troops were dly entrained, transportation having been furnished the qu;&gt; ters of each regiment for that purpose. The rapidity with which was performed is creditable to the regimental quartermasters and pany officers. All troops returning by rail with th&gt; &gt;n of p "A," which marched overland to its post at Seward. IThe camp site was carefully inspected by Colonel Jenkins and ilf after the departure of the troops. Four companies in tht three in the second regiments, and the cavalry troop had failed to properly police their quarters or fill and the same has been noted on the up the sinks before leaving camp recoi The Brigade Commander desire valuable services of Brigadier Genei to express his apprec il Daggett, Colonel Jenkins ;ry General: Colonel Evans, Surgeon General: Colonel Ehrhardt. Judge Advocate General and acting mustering officer; Colonel O ommand. Colonel Storch I endeavors to the accomplishme K Inspector: Major Byrne and nel McDonnell gave their best and Major Osborne proved an effl- The field and line officers and men . mention for the zeal and devotion the purpose of the encampment, cient Assistant Adjutant General, of their commands deserve specia duty evidenc J. H. CULVER Brig idier General Con Brigade. fully. </seg>
            <seg id="p069"/>
            <seg id="p070">REPORTS OF K&gt;lRXErivi aster General, In - pector General, Surgeon General, Judge Advo - cate General </seg>
            <seg id="p071"/>
            <seg id="p072">[PORTS OF QUARTERMASTER GENERAL. IN - SPECTOR GENERAL, SURGEON GENERAL, JUDGE ADVOCATE GENERAL X( \ ih.. and in ' ■ Yo I of Infantry, Band, Troop of Infa and Hospital Corps. The selected wan I one, u (1 and aeral onl ion of General Culver, I eral i the merchants of York for all col and qu •■(1 during said enc-anipmen id re- v York for led during turned home. Mi turned dun . ined until the ei pment. Th&lt;&gt; &lt;l me in departm duty, and ;d my headqua ned until lpment. The he en ■ 1 me in ! of t iv departn and now to acknowledge the unifon (led to Hie by him during the encampment, for w! . i* me nd now to acknow uniform nd man; helps xtended to Hie by him during tt lg me full authority to make all pun id man:'. nd nian;'. full authori all purchase to my own liking, yet he held me I to my own liking, yet he held me to mntabili' Statt both of vhich I most highly appreciated. I desire to acknowledge the most excellent work done 1. ire to acknowledge the most excellent work done by Captain ental 'fleer </seg>
            <seg id="p073">72 I also desire to commend of Regimental Quartern; Sergeant Steele as one of the most efficient helpers I have ever had In my department. Through the coutesy of Captain Cook of the missary department — Military Department of the Missouri — we led to Camp Pershins. Mr. Whiting, an ant from Fort Crook, to assist us in issuing rations, and other duties that might be assigned to him. We found Mr. Whiting a most compel' I gentleman. I ordered a school of the Company Quartern. Sergeants, at my quarters. Mr. Whiting presiding, and giving th&lt; valuable talk on their duties and as to cooking an He 'ed in the issuing of rations, this being the first time in the history of the Nebraska Nationel Guards, when most of the rations drawn from a Government Military Post, each ration carefully •ied in our quarters, and issued under the new law of 1902 and We required the requisition made out by the company Quar - termaster Sergeant, approved by the Captain and Adjutant of the Regiment. These are all attached to and made a part of this report. i he regular army field ration, adding a few luxuries, such as milk and butter daily, and green vegetables on two separate da I Through the untiring energy of the Adjutant General, we re&lt; d by wire, after our arrival at Camp Pershing, that we could draw ;rnment rations through the commissary department at Fort Dk. General Culver immediately placed me in communication by ne with Captain Cook of the commissary department — Military artment of tli irl — at Omaha, and I ordered most of the ons used during our camp, these to be charged against our money wance by the U. S. Government for encampment purposes. They red most excellent in quality, and were appreciated by all the troops, balance of commissary and all quartermaster stores were pur - sed in York. Every day in camp I visited the company quarters and kitchens, and inquired of the Quartermaster Sergeants as to the quality and quantity of food furnished, and I take great pride in saying in this report that I had no complaints, but on the contrary, was told i ■where that the rations were amply sufficient, and of the very best quality. L(The Quartermaster and Commissary General made a complete comprehensive report of the purchase and issue of commissary </seg>
            <seg id="p074">73 Bs, which has b *! will be found in th - rt of the Annual I illy siiliin ned) GEO. E. JENK Quartermaster and Coinn I have the honor to her- "&gt;rt of \V. 1: -hlin, Lieutenant Colonel and ral. n submitting this report, 1 •t of armories. During nv connection with the ■ vering a period of nearly twenty years, I ha lorn time to time, the great n&lt; idlng rmories for th' ion of tli hat the dama. in Blon^inK to the state, including loss thereof in m d justify the state in building armories for the ■ «t of the building would be no more than tl in a very few (Officers and men can not I hands unless they are provided with tates that have tried the experiment of Inn report that, as a financial investment to the is a ig proposition. Again the state would derive much benefit ■ that of the preservation of property, by encoui up their organization to a higher standpoint, ha ; in which to drill and keep their propt- K strongly recommend the introduction of a bill in the next lecis - i providing sufficient funds for the building of armor: ns, especially at such stations as seem m ible. Very respectfully C. J. BILLS, Colonel and Inspe Headquan- r. Culver, Adjutant General Lincoln, Nebr., </seg>
            <seg id="p075">74 the ei he uniform ! ■ I that n should refl .lit upon it The Guard, as a whole if young men. IFrom such examinatli per i examination i 1 prt hie under an ordinary in^ • f the rank and file could pass r into the U. S. Vol- Ind the importance of their tary i iving to increase their Administration i mental headquarters were not in Company records tsea are incomplete and in some ii 'ion on the part len in the The ild be more impn h th be a marked improve' Lincoln, Xebr.. November Charles J. Bll Inspector Genei ; Lincoln, Nebr., I have the honor to herewith submit my report of the annual in- &lt;&gt;n of t!' 'ial Guard, made under G. O. No. 1. The oidcr ha 1 upon i; 'JEN. Rl EIGHTEEN. Mmpany Comman renderii. o the [B - limited to one &gt;n. Personnel. I some reful training i an will rea ■nr soldier, but It irable and quite .ndard b&lt; There is too much famili. veen the and men I and military relatio y interw . Dermit of a </seg>
            <seg id="p076">all papers, but in most cases the ■ been overlooked or not understood In this connection it is proper to where, met with the complaint, from Company Commanders, tha 1 Regimental Headquarters delayed an. 1 orders for promotion of non-eommi and forwarding of di- Equipments. ent The arm ally, do not show the 1 IV upon them. Thi&gt; illy due to tl; ht ally due to tl of the o, Armor With om md builfi ■ &gt; the needs of thi d buil' 1 jnstru small, do not have the proper and all, do not have the proper and and cannot be arra military requiienn-; This is directly c! for arnii inadeqmi iue ■ nadequate qn u and the difference annual allow i the difference t Eil all of $l&lt;iO has to made up thv de to the he Adju Recommendatioi R ndations ■comme The following recommend lion. llowing con T! • Troop, Battery and ( an annual an at allowance of - h Company, Troop, B nander n ■ h Company, Troop :ander n- an annual allowance of $~ in line of ■! an a wane . cover property returns be made semi-annually and upon ■ he War D« Battery " partment. Tha A." be equipped with the 3.2 inch rifles now used Arm tThat, at an election for Company officers, onl performed at lea ut of stated duties, durin - nionths pi -&gt;rmitted to vote. That some ; be made to enable RiflY different Companies, to compel </seg>
            <seg id="p077">76 and efficiency in riflle i&gt; oth in the gallery and on the range. tin conclusion I desire to acknowledge the universal court' ded by all officers with whom I came in contact during this tour duty. Very Respectfully W. R. McLATGHLIX I. 1st, Inf'y. X. X. G.. Assistant Inspector Gn rGEOX GENERAL'S OFFICE, Columbus, Nebraska. roll D. Evans, M. D., Surgeon General. December in, 190 1 fiver, Adjutant General, I have the honor to submit my report on the medical department of thi National Guard for Ui&lt; and lit' (Regarding the equipment of the medical department, I m;t t outside of the hospital corps there is nothing. The medicine and ■elonging to the first and second regiments are in &gt;r condition and so antique in structure that I will only mention them of the past, and recommend that the medical department re enough money appropriated that In this particular they may be line with the regular mill The medical department in the past two years has shown very imical administration. The expenses at the regimental camp at York, and the brigade camp at David City, did not exceed $150, and at least one-half the supplies purchased for the medical department are still available. The improved condition of the soldiers, due to the scientific sani - tation, very materially lessens the death rate and sickness in ■ All of these propositions have been carefully watched and carried out, so that in the camp of the National Guard of our state no deaths have occurred and the sickness has been so slight that no men - tion need be made in this report. tin the month of June, 1903, I attended the school of instruction "braska national guard at the state house, Lincoln, st of the medical staff was in regular attendance. I read a paper :ie school, entitled "Individual Military Sanitation and Hy- giene." I was much gratified to see the interest taken by the officers of the guard, and I am sure that if all the officers received as much good information and profited as much as did the medical department, </seg>
            <seg id="p078">\djutant General can feel himself well :iis of corded where an&gt; lent or cause for II ■nie condition of the camp and the careful means pro ition to and from the camp. )f the camp and men at Camp Pi 9tatM Infant' the medical depart! tal corps of the Nebraska national guard, as folk) B'l wish to state here that the work of this organization thi the encampment was highly satisi ; he drill care, first aid, transportation cf the wounded, including the u Kd litter, travois. cavalryrn n the field. All members of the r respective dttl horse, and bringing corps seemed equally familiar In response to the request of C ind maneuvers of the troops at Fort Riley October l ly of military sanitation and hy racks, marches, hospital, camp eneral J. H. i regular army anil ••clal Uiding food, i anliness, exercise, and ondition of the soldier on mai ' in actu ! mlao made a special study of drainage and sewerage. T! most vital part the medical department has to deal with in the on of disease to the soldier, either in can racks. I may add that the detachment of the hospital corps am medical officers of the Nebraska national guard detailed to partii in the maneuvers acquitted themselves with much credit in the m;: they executed their parts in the work, and indeed with much i to the commanding officer of the state militia. It was my pleasant 10 stay at Fort Riley until the terminal day attending the engagement on the field, at &gt;ol of ii to include in .tt irt of ill- of th ishinK the school. amp Pershing, York, Nebl 1 l ad report for dir The ground selected for the camp was well adapted for th&gt;- pose. The draina:. md the « and quality, and in e\ icular the loi of thorough hygiene and a. Dorii .lerable rainfall, e inconvenit- t During this tamp the No injuries of any 1 character that it requires no mention wl The most import i re which I « ommands had returned to Ive homes not on. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">78 instruction given by the able men in the regular service, all of \ was of vast interst and of great profit to the national guardsmen. I The plans for transportation of the troops to and from Fort Riley uch credit upon the adjutant general of the state, but were ;iy managed by the railroads. Some of the cars were without II le of them without water, and the water that was in the coolers in as not fit for any use much less to drink. The officers the different companies deserve mention for the excellent way and nner in which they controlled their men under these advert istances, and the medical officers should be given credit for the itary condition in which the cars were kept, enroute. This in some Ijr hard to regulate, as the character of the cars to the necessities of travelers on a long iijutant General Culver, I reported at 1 raska, August 10th, 1904, for the purpose of looking ow and proposed grounds for the &lt;ncampment. I found the inds in excellent condition. The grounds lay in such a way that slope was towards a lake almost in the centei 1 of .the proposed en - ure and made an excellent site for latrines, placing them ar hundred feet to the rear of each company, and the lay of the ind afforded the best facilities for removing the slops and I i the company nation was well adapted for a camp. In compliance with General Order N \djutant General's Office, I reported for duty at Camp Victor Vifquain, David &lt; raska. on the morning of lftf&gt;4. I'nder directions of the brigade commander, I assisted in the general preparation of the ■ for the reception of the troops, as well as looking after tin of the latrines, water supply, and general hygiene. The entire ni« staff and hospital corps arrived August ICth, on which date a thoro organized medical lished, using one hospital for a bri- This form of hos; ■:•&gt;•. not only ti medical officers, but very agreeable to the officers and men of the command; as far as the sanitation of the camp and care of thi was concerned, the duties of the medical department was successfully performed. The garbiu u-ared every morning by ten o'clock: the latrines purified by nine o'clock. Ther on of quarters and kitchen. le, and latrines each morning soon after ten o'clock by a medical officer detailed for that purpose, and a personal report received by me before noon, so that in no instance could there be anything left undone in looking after the comfort and health of the men in camp. II would like to commend the medical officers for the pleasant ner in which they instructed the company officers, ■ mm ■! ind more beneficial to give practical Ini than and; and to especially commend I com- </seg>
            <seg id="p080">79 Fiders and non ioned officers for the soldierly mann«i ructions wen I and the efficient execution of the same. On the fourth day oi .impment, I arranged an ■ On the fourth day ot ampment, I arranged an drill and field ex* ierein th iff and b orps partlcpated. The p drill: detachments; litter drill; improvision of li Dg wounded without litters; the travois: thi partlcpated. The folio ool of ti up drill: dei drill; ini] movins and 11 hospital: field hospital: work at dressin ;&lt; front: tagging and marking at dressing station. These Instrui -h to th: ind Company "L," fii ■Hi hospital: field hospital: work at dressin ind marking at dressing station. id Cor efficient manner in which the:- •nt manner in which th&lt;-: i and in the skillful manner in which The ; iful manner in which 1 from the field field: first, in ad, at the md durin ind .mand. i From At: From A i hospital thirty men. .tion. One was admitted with esult of i &gt; any mention. One was admitted with result of &gt; is and shouli should b' to the siik call at the disi - ■lit and trivial to make mention of, a' B, I have not learned of an could be ascribed to the: In conclusion I deslrt hould 1» 1 all at the disp- ( too slight and trivial to mat 1 to an.- telligent manner and I on to duty which . : of the medical department The work of my pleasure. The B. The work of my i The i of the \ national ination, has been placed upon a much li en my ambition I animation, has licen placed upon a much department of the Nebraska national guard raised to th;&gt; rtment of the Nebraska national gi the further support of li the further support of Hi : the continued aid. counsel, and jntinued aid. counsel, and al. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">80 Office of the Judge Advocate Gt ! Nebraska National Guard. Stanton. Neb.. Nov. 25th. General J. H. Culver, Adjutant General, Lincoln, Nebraska. 1 have the honor to mak&lt; mi ending on the 1st day of December, It KThe discipline of the National i&lt;a is llent. only on &gt;'d to me in the pas' ■ idge Ad neral I hi .rmed all duties assigned to to th »I have attended all ma ihe military board and the encanip - t of the First Regiment at York in 1903, and the Brigade en&lt; t at David City in 19o4. and performed such duties as wen Very respectfully. (Signed) JOHN A. EHRHARDT Judge Advocate G. </seg>
            <seg id="p082">CONSOLIDATED REPORTS </seg>
            <seg id="p083"/>
            <seg id="p084">83 ABSENT ITotal Pres- Governor's Staff, PRESENT Camp Pershing, ent and Absent York. Neb. Officers Officers August 24, 1903 •&gt; 5 5 5 August 25, " .. 4 1 Augn • .. 4 1 August 27, " .. 4 1 August 28, ". 4 1 August I".*. 0 August 31, ' 4 1 5 September 1/ 3 September 2. " 2 3 •&gt; i First Regiment, j PRESEyT ABSENT ItoUI Pre* ARSENT Total Pre. Camp Pershing, otfl- Enlist- T t . Offl- Enlist- Tntal ent and York, Neb C ers ed Men lolal cers ed Men lotal Absent August, 25, 1903.. 3 40 . . 17 17 60 August 2' 43 460 503 3 119 122 August 27, " .. 43 460 3 119 122 August 28, " 43 :{ 120 123 August 29, " .. 43 • 502 3 120 123 A-ugust 30 -12 456 4 123 127 August 31, " .. 41 497 5 123 September 1 ".. 3 40 .... 17 17 60 Battery "A" 1 PRESENT ABSENT p^ PRESENT absent; i Total p^ Battery "A" Camp Pershing, ()ffl . Enl j st O ffl- Enlist- T, ntal ent and York, Neb. cers ed Men lotal cers ed Men Total Absent PP Pershing, offl . Enlist- Tnta , Offl- Enlist- T, nta , ent and ork, Neb. cer s ed Men Total cers ed Men Total Absent August 25, 1903. . 2 39 41 1 14 15 56 14 15 58 August 2ti, " .. 2 39 41 1 14 15 14 15 August 27, " .. 2 39 41 1 14 15 14 15 August 28, " .. 2 39 41 1 14 15 14 15 2 I 40 42 ! 1 August 29, August 29, " .. 2 40 42 1 13 14 5tt 13 14 56 August 30, " .. 2 40 42 1 13 14 56 August 30, 13 14 Aujrust 31, " .. 2 40 42 1 13 14 56 August 31, 13 14 J6 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S REPORT. 84 e« in -~ PRESENT Signal Corps, ■ r Camp Sanger, O ffi- Enlist- L ntal Fort Biley, Kas. cers ed Men ToU1 Offl- Enlist- t,^«, ent and cers ed Men Total Absent October 17, 1903 to October 28, 1903, Inclusive...! 3 43 | M 11 11 57 ABSENT | Tota , prfs . PRESENT TotalPres _ Offl- Enlist- T . e «'and cers ed Men lotal Absent ABSENT Troop "A" Camp Pershing, York, Neb. Offi- cers Enlist- ed Men Total August 25, 1903. . 2 2 1 2 2 2 32 :ri 32 :i2 :\&gt; :i2 34 ;« :« 84 34 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 11 45 45 45 45 45 45 45 fsspital Corps, imp Pershing York, Neb. Offl- Enlist- cers ed Men PRESENT T Total Offi- Enlist- T t , cers ed Men lotal ABSENT Total Pres ent and Absent Aug August 28* " . . :{ 3 3 3 .! ;{ 37 37 37 37 37 37 37 40 40 40 40 40 40 40 16 16 16 hi it; its l« 16 it; 16 16 16 16 lti 5ti M 66 66 66 66 R6 Second Begiment Camp Sanger Fort Kiley, Kas. Offi- cers PRESENT Enlist- ed Men Total Offi- cers ABSENT ABSENT Enlist- ~ _, ent and ed Men Total Absent October 17, 1903 to October 28, 1903, inclusive. . . 648 162 162 I 810 47 601 t* 22 per cent of si isf erred from First I .rength .egimen present consisted of men temporaril </seg>
            <seg id="p086">ADJUTANT-GENERALS REPORT. 85 Detachment of PRESENT Hospital Corps, ABSENT 1.1 Pl» ent and (amp Sander, Enlisted Men At Fort Riley, K Enlisted Men rober 17, 1903 Octal &gt;• 1903, inclusive... 12 None 12 Aggregate present: Officers. 50; enlisted men, I Aggregate absent: Officers, none; enlisted men, 173. General Camp Victor Vifquain, PRESENT ABSENT Total ABSENT Total Present %£\ Colonels &lt;gne£l I Colons A £j n | Sfr 1 Lionels David City, Neb 1904. Aug. 11-12-13-14 . Aug. 15 1 1 1 1 2 3 o Aug. 16-17 1 Aug. 18-19-20-21- 22 1 1 1 4 3 Aug. 23 Aug. 24 1 1 First Regiment r»n-ccTrKiT Camp Victor PRESENT ABSENT Total Vilquain, — V^A David City, Neb. Offl- Enlist. T .?" a t 1904. cers ed Men lotal n lotal Ah&gt; August 14 1 1 August 15 . 4 1 August 16 44 4 ISO August 17 44 47!) ." 4 II!) Earust 18 ....... 4o 479 U&lt;» rrnct 1(1 AS 1 1 .1 1 1 II AUgUSt 1!) 4.") I llti 11!) August 20 45 ! 115 117 44 481 4 117 121 August 21 August 22 August 23 44 4 117 121 Align* ..2 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S REPORT. 86 Second Regiment Camp Victor Vifquain, David City, Neb. 1904 PRESEN ABSEN Offl- Enlist- cers ed Men Enlist- ed Men Total Offl- Enlist- cers ed Men Total August 19 August 23 1 3 42 44 44 45 45 45 45 45 479 488 489 484 4£&lt;2 482 482 1 3 521 532 533 532 529 527 527 527 I 3 3 2 1 2 2 2 232 223 222 2&gt;4 227 229 229 229 337 226 225 22t&gt; 229 231 231 231 PRESENT ABSENT PX&gt;p"A",Camp ;tor Vifquain, vid City, Neb. I Offl- Enlist- cers ed Men Total Pres- ent and Absent Total Offi- cers Enlist- ed Men Total August 15 August 16 August 20 August 22 August 23 August 24 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 2 27 27 28 29 29 29 29 29 5» 29 29 29 30 31 31 31 31 31 31 31 12 12 11 10 10 10 10 10 10 10 12 12 11 10 lo 10 10 10 10 10 41 41 41 41 41 41 41 41 41 41 PRESENT ABSENT I Battery "A," Camp Victor ifquain, David ty, Neb., 1904 Enli8t-l Tntal ed Men lotal Total Pres- ent and Absent Offi- cers Offi- cers Enlist- ed MeD Total August 23, in- 49 I 52 7 59 I </seg>
            <seg id="p088">ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S REPORT. 87 PRESENT ABSENT SigDal Corps Camp Victor Vifquain, David City, Neb.. 1904 1 Total Total Pre* ent and Absent Offi- cers Enlist- ed Men Total Offi- cers Enlist- ed Men 3 3 t 3 a 3 3 3 2 32 32 a 32 32 30 30 30 5 36 35 36 35 36 33 33 33 7 17 17 11 17 17 l!i lit 19 44 17 17 17 17 17 19 19 19 52 52 52 52 52 RESENT BSENT IispiUl Corps amp Victor quain, David ,y, Neb., 1904 Total Pr« ent and Absent Offi- cers Enlist- ed Men Total Offi- cers Enlist- ed Men Total August 16 to 23 inclusive 40 43 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">88 ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S REPORT. OOST OF ENCAMPMENTS ENCAMPMENTS HELD IN 1903 AND ] IN 1903 AND 1904. fi^r ' pShYng ™,ufin Paid fror mw vnrt David State Vifquain Paid from f aid David State / T rom City Appropri- b Neb. ation. A PP&lt;&gt;r- Camp Camp hEMS OF J* n gZ v F ¥%i ng ■pv-pir-vcir 1 * l - Klley: i ork, EXPENSE Kansas I Neb. F KarWi IS' gity Appropri 1903. 1903. fjgj- atlon - tionment tdiem, office and men $4008 65 $5876 $4008 65 $5876 85 813850 64 $10776 04 36 41 1466 43 2889 94 12 - 25 76 61 220 70 J532 07 00 346 90 475 50 906 40 $13850 64 I $10776 04 $12960 10 Transportation of troops 36 41 1466 2889 94 3106 11 Freight, drayage, etc 220 70 :$32 07 Hire of Cay. and Art. horses . . 475 50 906 40 Fuel and Forage.. 498 87 194 498 87 194 42 1!*7 85 413 17 197 85 I 413 17 477 97 L'mber for Latrines etc 49 49 05 35 77 84 82 35 77 Subsistence 8160 977 81 60 977 03 1785 22 1066 63 1785 22 1066 63 177 Hospital Supplies.! 17 49 I 17 49 30 104 34 188 13 104 34 188 13 Telegraph, Tele phone and Exp. i 13 33 17 13 33 17 86 16 28 47 47 Labor and lnci dentals 43 00 43 00 80 90 98 203 78 Total $4809 11 $9150 25 $4809 11 $9150 25 $19667 22 $15305 18 $19667 22 $15305 18 $18321 40 •Average cost per ration, Camp er ration, Camp Pershiog, 23 1 4 cents, Pershiog g, 2.1 ' 4 cents, n, 19 4-5 cents. Average cost per ration, Camp V Per diem officers and men, trans] er ration, Camp Vifquain, 19 4-5 cents. ifquain •s and men, transportation and subsisten ation and subsistence at Fort Riley maneuvers, except as stated in :cept as stated in above table, paid from ' table, paid from "Appropri- ation for the Army." </seg>
            <seg id="p090">ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S REPORT. 89 Subsistence Property. ARTICLE RECEIVED RETURNED EXPENDED ED Imissary chest •I bags, lbs ims 1 1 "34* 22 31 3 Consolidated report on Subsistence Stores received and issued at Camp Victor Vifquain, David City, Neb,, August 16 to 23, 19&lt;&gt;4. ARTICLE RECEIVED ISSUED «-,5t«« "AST Pork, fresh, lbs Bacon, lbs . ... 2L&gt;70 2270 . fresh, lbs. 8731 6731 Beef, corned, lbs Bread, hard, lbs ' 263" i. soft, Iba .. 7734 Rice, lbs, 407 331 Tomatoes 3 1b. cans Wl .lam, B. H., 2 lb. cans 5OU 40 Sugar, issue, lbs 2o45}$ M£ 100 Salmoo, canned, lbs 24 Candles. I 210 170 40 Means, lbs !)73 Potatoes, lbs 1 IM6 373 Onions, lbs 2015 HO Salt, table. sk&gt; Pepper, lbs. .... J4 1 4 17 Prunes, lbs. 10 10 Soap. W. R , bars ... Vinegar, gal., 31 31 ... lbs. ! 1700 1700 •age. lbs '. Corn, sweet, lbs 13« Matches, pks 100 100 </seg>
            
            <seg id="p091">FINANCIAL REPORTS </seg>
          
            <seg id="p092">The financial transactions of this office for the portion of the bi- ennium, December first, 1902, to the date of my assumption of the office, Febbruary 20, 1903, as taken from the record kept by General L. W. Colby, are as follows: OFFICE EXPENSE, APPROPRIATION 1899, H. R. No. 501 Dec. 1, 1902. Balance $ 1.88 Amount lapsed to State General Fund 1.88 Feb. 20, 1903. Balance on hand, nothing FLAG CASE AND VAULT DOOR FUND. APPROPRIATION 1899, H. R. No. 501. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance, $ 11.01 Amount lapsed to State General Fund, .... 11.01 Feb. 20, 1903. Balance on hand, nothing. OFFICE EXPENSE, APPROPRIATION 1901, H. R. No. 446. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance $ 334.32 Disbursements 263.69 Feb. 20, 1903, Balance on hand $ 70.63 NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD SUPPORT, APPROPRIATION 1901, H. R. No. 477. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance 9 694.05 Disbursements 670.29 Feb. 20, 1903. Balance on hand $ 23.76 SALARY ADJUTANT GENERAL, APPROPRIATION 1901, H. R 436. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance $ 450.00 Disbursements 300.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">92 SALARY OF CHIEF CLERK, APPROPRIATION 1901, H. R. No. 436. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance $ 333.35 Disbursements, 166.68 Feb. 20, 1903. Balance on hand '.% 166.67 SALARY STOREKEEPER AND CLERK, APPROPRIATION 1901. H. R. No. 436 Dec. 1, 1902. Balance $ 266.68 Disbursements, 133.34 Feb. 20, 1903. Balance on hand $ 133.34 REFUND TO FIRST NEBRASKA VOLUNTEER INFANTRY, APPRO PRIATION 1901. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance % 2600.00 Amount reverted to State General Fund, . . 2600.00 Feb. 20, 1903, Balance on hand, nothing. ACCOUNT GENERAL L. W. COLBY. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance $ 2750.40 Receipts 52 2803.15 Disbursements, 2788.72 Feb. 20, 1903 Balance on hand paid to Gen. J. H. Culver, 14.43 SUSPENSE ACCOUNT. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance % 312.18 disbursements 312.18 Feb. 20, 1903. Balance on hand, nothing SALES U. S. GOVERNMENT PROPERTY. Dec. 1, T-902. Balance $ 2492.33 Receipts 52.75 25.45.08 Disbursements 2545.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">93 U. S. GOVERNMENT APPROPRIATIONS. Dec. 1, 1902. Balance $ 12,235.52 Disbursements, nothing. Feb. 20, 1903. Balance '. $ 12,235.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">94 The statement for the period covered by my administration, Feb- ruary 20, 1903 to November 30, 1904, is as follows: SUPPORT OF THE NEBRASKA NATIONAL GUARD, 1901 APPRO- PRIATION Feb. 20, '03 Balance $ 23.76 Received from Gen. L. W. Colby, armory rent, .. 300.00 $323.76 Disbursements 323.47 Lapsed to State Treasury, 29 323.76 Balance, nothing. OFFICE EXPENSE, 1901, APPROPRIATION. Feb. 20, '0?. Banance, $ 70.63 Disbursements, 70.60 Lapsed to State Treasury 03 70.63 Balance, nothing. DEFICIENCY APPROPRIATION, 1903, ARMORY RENT. April 1, '03. Amount $1600.00 Disbursements $1600.00 Balance, nothing. DEFICIENCY APPROPRIATION, 1903, OFFICE HELP. April 1, '03. Appropriation $200.00 Disbursements $200.00 Balance, nothing. DEFICIENCY APPROPRIATION, 1903, OFFICE EXPENSE. April 1, '03. Amount, $100.00 Disbursements $100.00 Balance, nothing. SALARY OF ADJUTANT GENERAL, 1901, APPROPRIATION. Feb. 20, '03. Balance $150.00 Disbursements, $150.00 Balance, nothing. </seg>
            <seg id="p096">95 SALARY OF CHIEF CLERK, 1901, APPROPRIATION Feb. 20, '03. Balance $i66.67 Disbursements $166.67 Balance, nothing. SALARY OF CLERK AND STOREKEEPER, 1901, APPROPRIATION. Feb. 20, '03. Balance $133.34 Disbursements, 133.33 Lapsed to State Treasury 01 133.34 Balance, nothing. OFFICE EXPENSE, 1903 APPROPRIATION. Amount of appropriation $2000.00 Disbursements 1714. 7: 3 Balance, $ 285.25 ARMORY RENT, 1903 APPROPRIATION. Amount of apppropriation $6800.00 Disbursements 4850.00 Balance $19 PERDIEM OFFICERS AND MEN, 1903 APPROPRIATION. Amount of appropriation $17000.00 Disbursements 153' Balance $1C PAYMENT FOR HORSES 1903 APPROPRIATION Amount of appropriation $650.00 Disbursements 415.50 Balance $234.50 EXPENDITURES IN INSPECTION, ETC Amount of appropriation 6800.00 Disbursements 4902.98 Recredits 28.35 4931.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">96 SALARY OF ADJUTANT GENERAL. Amount of appropriation, $2700.00 Disbursements 2250.00 Balance $ 450.00 SALARY OF CHIEF CLERK Amount of Appropriation $2000.00 Disbursements 1666.66 Balance $ 333.34 SALARY OF CLERK AND STOREKEEPER. Amount of appropriation $1600.00 Disbursements 1333.32 Balance, $ 266.68 SALARY OF STENOGRAPHER. Amount of apropriation $1680.00 Disbursements 1400.00 Balance $ 280.00 SUSPENSE ACCOUNT. Feb. 20, '03. Received from Gen. L. W. Colby $14.43 Receipts 22.36 36.79 Disbursements 18.47 Paid to State Treasury 18.32 36.79 Balance, nothing. COLLECTIONS .NEBRASKA STATE FUNDS. Receipts $120.27 Paid to State Treasurer, 120.27 Balance, nothing. PROCEEDS FROM ORDINANCE AND QUARTERMASTERS STORES Receipts $322.22 Deposited In U. S. Depository, 322.22 </seg>
            <seg id="p098">97 U. S. GOVERNMENT FUNDS, APPROPRIOTIONS. Feb. 20, '03. Balance to credit of state $122:: Appropriations 50821.63 Recredits 7192.03 70249.18 Amount of stores issued to State . . .$33067.92 Placed to credit of distributing officer, 29179.91 62247.83 Balance to Credit of State, $80' </seg>
            <seg id="p099">98 Approximate value of military property in possession of the Nebraska national guard. Ordinance Stores Quarter- master Stores Total Value —FIRST REGIMEXT— Id and Staff nd ni pany A b : " C lt D " E " F G H 1 K L M Total 470 66 104 35 li: 1167 81 11 1 - 1- 1181 77 lllti 22 422 11 1179 96 1171 27 • 240 11 2066 30 1896 83 154!) 67 2012 38 1725 2&lt;i 1834 96 1571 53 14887 08 22312 53 37199 HI I -SECOND REGIMENT— 1 and Staff pany A ' B C D ¥...."".'.'.'.]".'.".'.'.. • H 11 1 [j K yi '.".'."".".'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Total . 414 84 108 76 1143 67 1170 84 1256 22 12il&gt; 07 m&lt; ii 2305 94 1238 68 1167 06 1345 77 12H4 06 2009 41 2 1 01 46 2714 14 2112 &lt;i2 2014 94 16435 45 P'ARATE ORGANIZATIONS— A" Cavalry "A" Lt. Art Corps !orps int Rifles maha Cavalry Total 2458 53 407 77 2125 til 1706 92 1549 28 ■ 9480 70 10431 48 19912 IS —RECAPITULATION— First Regiment Second Regiment Separate Organizations U. S. property in store-room Stut e " " Schools and Colleges Grand Total 16435 4.-&gt; 9480 70 - 22312 53 26533 55 10431 48 19025 69 173 90 7X447 15 Total U. S. Property Total State Property ]27&gt; ] = 159 70 </seg>
            <seg id="p100">MILITIA LIST FOR 1904 BY COUNTIES </seg>
            <seg id="p101"/>
            <seg id="p102">■ MIL1T A LIST— 1904. 1900. Ratio niili ■ COUNTY Popula- tion Num- ber Exempt number Antelope...! '......'... 11344 box Butte Brown 3470 Buffalo 20! Burt 13040 enne Cunfing'. '.".I! '.'.'.'.".'.'. '. . . 14~&gt;84 Dakota Dawson'. '. '. .'.'.'. '. '. . '. '. '. '. '. '. 12214 Rtxon 1' Dodne 2i Douglas 144(o!X) Fillmore . 1 Franklin Frontier Fumas 12373 Gtrteti. ............. 2127 Greeley . . .... ......... 5691 Hamilton ........... 13330 Harlan Haves Hitchcock . 4409 2131 •10 441 1401 li*&gt;0 1442 *710 2()til 1584 11157 37* 74«i 17i uS 111 • ) 114 *44 •t~ 134 t&gt;4 121 37 103 24 a 101 44 35 142 143 tilt 53 7* 14 10 *16 60 31 IS 79 1433 104 •79 1194 754 * 1 1 1 0 11M7 BM l'.»21 12(&gt;0 9234 324 1341 3O7ti 274 52ti ♦HSU 1584 llOti 731 71 11.4 7.6 7.9 7.0 11. H 15.1 7.2 7.05 7.1 I </seg>
            <seg id="p103">102 MIL T1A LIST— 1904.— Continv 11I I I I XTY 1900 Popula- K £?" 1 *" 10 tion cent of a Paria s Lancaster Loup Madison McPherson X' Perkins ;trdson Saunders Scotts Bluff idan man Thomas Thurston Valley Washington Wheeler 11197 1371 34 8.3 !»3ti 7 10.5 1961 22 7 17 610 810 5.04 10 1434:{ 2349 74 2275 (&gt;. - &lt; 4177 4115 15.7 11416 1147 10.7 116 2 114 215 10 1697 ( 2:47 .-&gt;17 *71 *2 7.4 104.-, 7 1792 103 8.8 12414 1477 66 1411 :i349 11770 7.4 1702 21 2ol 10772 1230 74 1158 9.3 1101 1 1100 7.U 17747 2:47 77 2470 7.1 10542 1.-44 1.-44 6.1 9604 1350 1312 7.3 19614 7.7 219 36 5.8 252 67 1799 10.1 9080 1315 50 1265 7.1 .5030 193 7.7 492 24 468 5.4 15690 2145 112 2033 1.4 6033 52 751 8.03 15 7.1 315 7.5 1161 til 1106 6.2 14.V. 93 1596 8.9 10.6 8756 608 14.4 7339 1225 56 1169 6.2 13086 1706 1651 7.6 9862 1404 34 1370 7.1 11619 1195 64 1131 10.2 1362 293 30 5.1 18205 1996 1996 9.1 11197 1951 i4:$4.-{ 11416 r,n. 12414 11770 1702 10772 17747 9604 19614 9080 15690 6033 8756 13086 9862 11619 1362 18205 1371 610 2349 4177 1147 116 215 •71 104.", 1477 3349 1230 1101 2:47 ir&gt;44 1350 2 lit 1315 3030 2145 1161 1225 1706 1404 1195 293 1996 ,,„ </seg>
            <seg id="p104">GENERAL ORDERS FOR 1903 </seg>
            <seg id="p105"/>
            <seg id="p106">GENERAL ORDERS Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office. Lincoln, Nebr., Januar rral Order No. 1. I. Under the law of Nebraska, the commissions of the staff 0 of the Commander in Chief expire with the term of office of the officer appointing: by reason of this, the following commissioned officers are honorably discharged from the militar of the - take effect January Colonel George E. Jenkins. Quartermaster and Commissary General, Colonel Charles J. Biles. Inspector General Colonel Carrol D. Evans, Surgeon General, Colonel John H. Brown. Judge Advocate General AIDES Colonel Clarence A. Miles. Colonel Charles M. Keefer, Colonel Frank E. MotM Colenel Samuel M. Melick. Colonel George A. Murphy, Colonel Henry p. Eutton, Colonel Conrad F. Scharmann Colonel Joseph W. Thomas Colonel Ira W. Waynick, Colonel John B. Watkins, Colonel James G. Martin, Colonel Elmer E. Bryson. Colonel Frank M. Rublee, Mil. Attache. tThe Governor wishes to assure these officers that he will i him to private life an appreciation of their high official char conduct, and a grateful remembrance of their personal coi: kindness on all public and private II. At the close of his official duties the Governor desires further to compliment and thank the officers and enlisted men of the Nebraska National Guard for their soldierly conduct, and the high state of tary proficiency they have achieved, as shown in their company, regi - mental and brigade maneuvers, witnessed at encampments and on public ceremonies; and as Commander in Chief of the unitary f of the state, he bespeaks for his successor the same e«rnest zeal and Brigadier General L. W. Colby, Adju ,ral. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">106 loyalty to duty that have characterized members of the Guard during his official term. The citizen soldiers of Nebraska have ever responded promptly when needed to protect lives and property from lawlessness or savage foes, and have always proven themselves worthy of the highe - and confidence of the people. Their record in the past and their standing in the present entitled them to a generous support from the law making power of the state. mmand of EZRA P. SAVAGE Governor and Commander in Chief L. \V. COLBY Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, January I General Orders, No. 2. I. The resignation of Colonel William Hayward. Second Infantry item. Nebraska National Guard, is hereby accepted and he is honorably discharged from the miltary service of the state to take effect January 24, IS II. In accordance with the provisions of the military code of the state, an election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy which will occur in the office of Colonel of the Second Nebraska Infantry, vice William Hayward resigned. III. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward proper bal - lots to the commissioned officers of the Second Nebraska Infantry Reg - iment for their use in the election ordered in the preceding paragraph. These ballots indicating the officers' choice of person for appointment to such office, will be signed by the officer voting and returned to the Ad - jutant General's office on or before 10 o'clock A. M., Friday, January IV. A Board of Officers, to consist of the Adjutant General, Cap - tain James J. Grimm of Company "E," and Captain John T. Crozier of Company "D," First Nebraska Infantry, will convene in the Adjutant General's Office at 10 o'clock A. M. on Friday, January 23, 1903,, for the purpose of canvassing and recording the votes at such election vote will be received or recorded after the hour named for the meet - ing of said board. The junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor, L. W. COLBY, </seg>
            <seg id="p108">107 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, Januar General Order No II. Jacob H. Culver is appointed Adjutant General of the Nebraska, to rank as Brigadier General, and will take rank from &gt;ruary 20, 1903, at which time he will assume the dutif :e, and will be obeyed and respected accordingly. II. Brigadier General L. \V. Colby, the present ai General of the State, will continue his term of office until Februa' at which time he will turn over to his all books, papers, records and property in his charge and for which he in till. In assuming the duties of the office of Governor, and by ue thereof, those of Commander in Chief of the military forte* of State of Nebraska, it is a pleasure to learn from my honored pre - ;ssor of the high standing, character and efficiency of th&gt; rd of the State, and to assure the members thereof that re to do everything proper and right to maintain, and aid tli • ease, if possible, their good reputation for soldierly qualities so I established. By Command of JOHN H. MICKEY. Governor and Commander-in-C Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, January. 23, 190 No. 4. §1. The election of Lieutenant Colonel John \V. McDonnell Second raska Infantry Regiment, to the office of Colonel of said Regiment, ereby approved, and Colonel McDonnell will take rank from Janu - 24. 1903. II. The following officers upon the staff of Colonel William Hay - ward Second Nebraska Infantry Regiment, whose term of office will expire under the law, with that of the officer appointing them, are here - by honorably discharged and mustered out of the military servi. the state, to take effect January 24, 190 3. Captain Arthur P. Ginn, Surgeon, Captain A. E. Knickerbocker, Chaplain, 1st Lt. Allan B. Wilson, Adjutant, 1st Lt. Tim McCarthy, Quartermaster. By Command of the Governor, L. W. COLBY, Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">108 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, January 19, 1903. General Orders, No. 5. tl. An election is hereby ordered to fill vacancy in the office of tenant Colonel of the Second Nebraska Infantry Regiment, tenant Colonel John \V. McDonnell, promoted. II. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward written ballots to the commissioned officers of the Second Nebraska Infantry Regiment for their use in the election ordered in the preceeding para - graph. These ballots, indicating the officers' choice for person for ap - pointment to the office of Lieutenant Colonel must be returned to the Adjutants General's office on of before 11 A. M. of Tuesday, February '03. III. A Board of Officers, to consist of Brig. Gen. L. W. Colby, Ad - jutant General, Captain George Lyon, Jr., Co. "H," and Captain Charles Smrha, Jr., of Company "G," First Infantry Regiment, will convene in the Adjutant General's Office at 11 A. M., on Tuesday, ruary 3. 1903, for the purpose of canvassing and recording the votes. No ballots will be received and recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said election board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor, L. W. COLBY, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, January 3i&gt;. ' General Orders, No. C. tThe following Regimental Staff Officers have been selected and ointed by Colonel John \Y McDonnell, commanding the Second In - try Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, and such appointments e been approved by the Governor: Robert A. Clapp of Company "D," Second Regiment, to be Ad jutant, to rank as First Lieutenant, from January 28, 1903. 1-taut Surgeon, Clifford W. VValden, of the Second Infantry imcnt, to be Surgeon, with the rank of Captain, from Januai IAcidison E. Knickerbocker of Company "C, " Second Regiment, to Chaplain, with the rank of Captain, from January 28, 1903. Said Officers will be obeyed and respected accordingly. By Command of the Governor, L. W. COLBY. Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p110">109 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office. Lincoln, Nebraska, Januar General Order No KThe following Act of Congress is published for the inform government of all concerned: An Act to promote the efficiency of the militia, and for other purposes. |3e it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the ted States of America in Congr^ bled. That the militia shall gist of every able-bodied male citizen of the respective States, Terri - es, and the District of Columbia, and every able-bodied male of (lgn birth who has declared his intention to become a citizen, who lore than eighteen and less than forty-five years of age. and shall be ided into two classes — the organized militia, to be know ional Guard of the State, Territory, or District of Columbia, or by h other designations as may be given them by the laws of the re - etive States or Territories, and the remainder to be known as the ;rve militia. I Sec. 2. That the Vice President of the United States, the ofl licial and executive, of the Government of the Unit s, the •mbers and officers of each House of &lt; la the nn naval service of the United States, all custom-house officers, with ?ir clerks, postmasters and persons employed by the I'n the transmission of the mail, ferrymen employed at an&gt; post road, artificers and workmen employed in the armories and renals of the United States, pilots, mariners actually employed in the i service of any citizen or merchant within the United S persons who are exempted by the laws of the n States or rritories shall be exempted from militia duty, without rgard to age; ovided, That nothing in this act shall be construed to requ mpel any member of any well-organized religious • present organized and existing whose creed forbids rticipate in war in any form, and whose religious convictions are ainst war or participation therein, in accordance with th id religious organization, to serve in the militia or any other armed volunteer force under the jurisdiction and authority of the I SSec. 3. That the regularly enlisted, organized, and uniform* militia In the several States and Territories and the I .umbia who have heretofore participated or shall hereafter pa e in the apportionment of the annual appropriation provided by tion sixteen hundred and sixty-one of the 1 ited States, as amended, whether known and d« • ional ard, militia, or otherwise, shall constitute the organized militia. The ;anization, armament, and discipline of </seg>
            <seg id="p111">110 the same as that which is now or may hereafter be prescribed for the Regular and Volunteer Armies of the United States, within five years from the date of the approval of this Act: Provided, That the Presi - dent of the United States, in times of peace, may by order fix the mini - mum number of enlisted men in each company, troop, battery, signal corps, engineer corps, and hospital corps: And provided further, That orps of artillery, cavalry, and infantry existing in any of the States at the passage of the act of May eighth seventeen hundred and ninety - two, which, by the laws, customs or usages of the said States have been in continuous existence since the passage of said act under its pro - visions and under the provisions of section two hundred and thirty - two and sections sixteen hundred and twenty-five to sixteen hundred and sixty, both inclusive, of title sixteen of the Revised Statutes of the United States relating to the militia, shall be allowed to retain their ac - customed privileges, subject, nevertheless, to all other duties required by law in like manner as the other militia. I Sec. 4. That whenever the United States is invaded, or in danger invasion from any foreign nation, or of rebellion against the auth - ty of the Government of the United States, or the President is un - e, with the otheivforces at his command, to execute the laws of the Ion in any part thereof, it shall be lawful for the President to call th, for a period not exceeding nine months, such number of the itia of the State or of the States or Territories or of the District Columbia as he may deem necessary to repel such invasion, suppress h rebellion, or to enable him to execute such laws, and to issue his ers for that purpose to such officers of the militia as he may think Sec. 5. That whenever the President calls forth the militia of any State or Territory or of the District of Columbia to be employed in the service of the United States, he may specify in his call the period for which the such service is required, not exceeding nine months, and the militia so called shall continue to serve during the term so specified. unless sooner discharged by order of the President. tSec. 6. That when the militia of more than one State is called the actual service of the United States by the President he may, is discretion, apportion them among such States or Territories or le District of Columbia according to representative population. iSec. 7. That every officer and enlisted man of the militia who shall failed forth in the manner hereinbefore prescribed and shall be found for military service shall be mustered or accepted into the United tes service by a duly authorized mustering officer of the 0 tes: Provided, however, That any officer or enlisted man of the itia who shall refuse or neglect to present himself to such mustering cer upon being called forth as herein prescribed shall be subject to il by court-martial, and shall be punished as such couvt- martial may </seg>
            <seg id="p112">111 Kthe militia, when in the service of the United States, shall b ed of militia officers only. tSec. 9. That the militia when called into the actun ited States, shall be subject to the same Rules and Articl. the regular troops oi the United States. 10. That the militia, when called into the actual United States, shall, during their time of service, be entitled to the e pay and allowance as are or may be provided by law for the I: Army. Sec. 11. That when the militia is called into ths actual service of the United States or any portion of the miljtia is m inder the provision of this act their pay shall commence from day of their appearing at the place of company rende/ But this provision shall not be construed to authorize any species of expenditure previous to arriving at such place of rendezvous whi not provided by existing laws to be paid after their arrival at places of rendezvous. I Sec. 12. There shall be appointed in' eac . and itrict of Columbia, an adjutant general, who shall perform ties as may be prescribed by the laws of such State, Territory, and itrict, respectively, and make returns to the Secretary of War, a - les and in such form as he shall from time to time prescribe, of the ength of the organized militia, and also make such reports as. may m time to time be required by the Secretary of War. That the •retary of War shall, with his annual report of each year, tr;r Congress an abstract of the returns and reports of the adjutant gen - ii of the States, Territories, and the District of Columbia, with servations thereon as he may deem necessary for the information of Qgress. Sec. 13. That the Secretary of War is hereby authorized to issue, on the requisition of the governors of the several States and Terri - tories, or of the commanding general of the militia of the District of Columbia, such number of United standard service magazine arms, with bayonet, bayonet scabbards, gun slings, belts, and such necessary accoutrements and equipments as are required for the array of the United States, for arming all of the organized m iitia in said States, Territories and District of Columbia, without charging cost or value thereof, or any which have been issued since Decemberl. nin hundred and one, or any expense connected therewith, against the allot - ment to said State, Territory, or District of Columbia, out of the an - nual appropriation provided by section sixteen hundred and of the Revised Statutes, as amended, or requiring payment therefor, and to exchange, without receiving any money credit therefor, ammuni - tion, or parts thereof, suitable to the new arms, round for round, for ccorresponding ammunition suitable to the old arms theretofore issued to said State, Territory, or District by the United States: Provided, That said rifles and carbines and other property shall be receipted for </seg>
            <seg id="p113">112 and shall remain the property of the United States and be annually inted for by the governors of the States and Territories as now required by law, and that each State, Territory, and District shall, on lit of the new arms, turn in to the Ordnance Department of the United States Army, without receiving any money credit therefor, and without expense for transportation, all United States rifles and carbines now in its possession. To provide means to carry into effect the provisions of this sec - tion, the necessary money to recover the cost of exchanging or issuing the new arms, accoutrements, equipments and ammunition to be ex - changed or issued hereunder is hereby appropriated out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated. Sec. 14. That whenever it shall appear by the report of insper - which it shall be the duty of the Secretary of War to cause to be made at least once in each year by officers detailed by him for that purpose, that the organized militia of a State or Territory or of the let of Columbia is sufficiently armed, uniformed, and equipped for active duty in the field, the Secretarw of Dar is authorized, on the sition of the governor of such state or territory, to pay the quar - termaster general thereof, or to such other officer of the mliitia of said he said governor may designate and appoint for the pui so much of its allottment out of the said annual appropriation under ixteen hundred and sixty-one of the Revised Statutes as ameHded as shall be necessary for the payment, subsistence, and I portation of such portion of said organized militia as shall engage in ac - tual field or camp service for instruction, and the officers and en men of such militia while so engaged shall be entitled to the same pay. istence and transportation or travel allowances as officers and en- I men of corresponding grades of the Regular Army are or hereafter be entitled by law, and the officer so designated and appci shall be regarded as a disbursing officer of the United States, and render his accounts through the War Department to the prop* - counting officers of the Treasury for settlement, and he shall be re - il to give good and sufficient bonds to the United States in sums as the Secretary of War may direct, faithfully to account for the safe keeping and payment of the public m • intrusted to him for disbursement. lu. That the Secretary of War is hereby authorized to pro - for the participation by any part of the organized miltia of any or Territory, on the request of the governor thereof in tli. nient, maneuvers, and field instruction of any part of the Regular Army at or near any military post or camp or lake or sea coa - of the United States. In such case the organized militia so par - ating shall receive the same pay, subsistence, and transpoi' provided by law for the officers and men of the Regular An foe paid out of the appropriation foi tation of the </seg>
            <seg id="p114">113 Ked shall remain with the regular commander of the post without ird to the rank of the commanding or other officers of the milita porarily so encamped within its limits or in its vicinity. I Sec. 16. That whenever any officer of the organized militia shall, m recommendation of the governor of any State, Territory, or gen - 1 commanding the District of Columbia, and when authorized b ;sident, attend and pursue a regular course of study at any military ool or college of the United States such officer shall receive from annual appropriation for the support of the Army the same travel jwances, and quarters, or commutation of quarters, to which an cer of the Regular Army would be entitled if attending such college under orders from proper military authority, and shall also eive commutation of subsistence at the rate of one dollar per day lie in actual attendance upon the course of instruction. Sec. 17. That the annual apropriation made by section sixteen huunder and sixty-one, Revised Statutes, as amended, shall be available for the purpose of providing for issue to the organized militia stores and supplies or publications which are supplied to the Army by any department. Any State, Territory, or the District of Columbia may, with the approval of the Secretary of War, purchase for cash from the War Department, for the use of its militia, stores, supplies, material of war, or military publications, such as are furnished to the Arn addition to those issued under the provisons of this act, at the price At which they are listed for issue to the Army, with the cost of transpor - tation added, and funds received from such sales shall be credii' the appropriations to which they belong, and shall not be covered into the Treasury, but shall be available until expended to replace there - with the supplies sold to the States and Territories and to the I): of Columbia in thp manner herein nroviried I Sec. 18. That each State or Territory furnished with material of r under the provisions of this or former acts of Congress shall, dur - ; the year next preceding each annual allotment of funds, in a&lt; •e with section sixteen hundred and sixty-one of the revised tta amended, have required every company, troop, and battery in its ;anized militia not excused by the governor of such State or Territory participate in practice marches or go into camp of instruction at .st five consecutive days, and to assemble for drill and instruction at npany, batallion, or regimental armories or rendezvous or for tar - t practice not less than twenty-four times, and shall also have re - ired during such year an inspection o"f each such company, troop, and ttery to be made by an officer of such militia or an officer of the Reg - ir Army. Sec. 19. That upon application of the governor of any State or Territory furnished with material of war under the provisions of this act or former laws of Congress, the Secretary of War may detail one or more officer of the Army to attend any encampment of the organized mir^a, and to give such instruction and information to the offlcers and </seg>
            <seg id="p115">114 E assembled in such camp as may be requested by the governor. 1 officer or officers shall immediately make a report of such en- Dment to the Secretary of War. who shall furnish a mov thereof ie governor of the State or Territory. Sec. 20. That upon application of the governor of any State or Territory furnished with material of war under the provisions of this act or former laws of Congress, the Secretary of War may, in his dis - cretion, detail one or more officers of the Army to report to the govern - or of such State of Territory for duty in connection with the organized militia. All such asignments may be revoked at the request of the governor of such State or Territory or at the pleasure of the Secretary I Sec. 21. That the troops of the militia encamped at any military t or camp of the United States may be furnished such amounts of munition for instruction in firing and target practice as may be scribed by the Secretary of War, and such instruction In firing shall carried on under the direction of an officer selected for that purpose the proper military commander. tSec. 22. That when any officer, non-commissioned officer, or pri - of the militia is disabled by reason of wounds or disabilities re- Bd or incurred in the service of the United States, he shall be enti - to all the benefits of the pension laws existing at the time of his ice, and in case such officer, non-commissioned officer, or private in the service of the United States or in returning to his place of lence after being mustered out of such service, or at any time, in equence of wounds or disabilities received in such service, his »w and children, if any, shall be entitled to all the benefits of such ion laws. Sec. 23. That for the purpose of securing a list of persons speci - ally qualified to hold commissions in any volunteer force which may hereafter be called for and organized under the authority of Congress, other than a force composed of organized militia, the Secretarw of War Is authorized from time to time to convene boards of officers at suitable and convenient army posts in different parts of the United States, who shall examine as to their qualifications for the command of troops or for the performance of staff duties all applicants who shall have served In the Regular Army of the United States, in any of the volunteer forces of the United States, or in the organized militia of any State or Ter - ritory or the District of Columbia, or who, being a citizen of the United States, shall have attended or pursued a regular course of instruction in any military school or college of the United States Army, or shall have graduated from any educational institution to which an officer of the Army or Navy has been detailed as superintendent or professor pursuant to law after having creditably pursued the course of military instruction therein provided. Such examinations shall be under the rules and regulations prescribed by the </seg>
            <seg id="p116">115 the practical capacity of the applicant. The record of pre - vious service of the applicant shall be considered as a part of the ex - amination. TTnon the ronHnsion of each examination the board shall certify to the War Department its judgment as to the fttness of the applicant, stating the office, if any, which it deems him qualified to fill, and, upon approval by the President, the names of the persons certified to be qualified shall be inscribed in a register to be kept in the War De - partment for that purpose. The persons so certified and registered shall, subject to a physical examination at the time, constitute an eligi - ble class for commissions pursuant to such certificates in any volunteer force hereafter called for and organized under the authority of Con - gress, other than a force composed of organized militia, and the Pres - ident may anthoriTP wrsnns from this rlpss. to attend and mi I mm a regular course of study at any military school or college of the United States other than the Military Academy at West Point and to re. from the annual appropriation for the support of the Army the same al - lowances and commutations as provided in this act for officers of the or - ganized militia: Provided, That no person shall be entitled to receive a commission as second lieutenant after he shall have passed the age of thirty; as first lieutenant after he shall have passed the age of tl five; as captain after he shall have passed the age of forty; as major after he shall have passed the age of forty-five; as lieutenant colonel after he shall have passed the age of fifty; or as colonel after he shall passed the age of fifty-five: And provided further. That such ap - pointments shall be distributed proportionately, as near as may be, among the various states contributing such volunteer force: And pro - vided, that the appointments in this section provided for shall not be deemed to include appointments to any office in any company, troop, battery, batallion, or regiment of the organized militia which volun - teers as a body or the officers of which are appointed by the governor of a State or Territory. tSec. 24 That all the volunteer forces of the United ailed by authority of Congress shall, except as hereinbefore provided, rganized in the manner provided by the act entitled, "An ■ ide for temporarily increasing the military establishment of the ed States in time of war, and for other purposes," approved April ity second, eighteen hundred and ninety-eight. tSec. 25. That sections sixteen hundred and twenty-five to six - hundred and sixty, both included, of title sixteen of the Revised utes, and section two hundred and thirty-two thereof, relating to militia, are hereby repealed. Sec. 26. That this act shall take effect upon the date of its appro- Approved, Januuary 21, 1903 By Command of the Governor L. W. COLBY, </seg>
            <seg id="p117">116 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 2, 1903. General Orders. No. 8. Second Lieutenant Justin M. Sarbach of Company "D", Second Infantry Regiment, has been selected and appointed by Colonel John W. CcDonnell, commanding the Second Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, as Regimental Quartermaster, and such appointment is approved by the Governor. Quartermaster Sarbach will take rank as First Lieutenant from ruary 2, 1903, and will be obeyed and respected accordingly. By Command of the Governor, L. W. COLBY Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 3, 1903. General Orders. No. 9. tl. The election of Major Frederick J. Bolshaw, Second Nebraska mtry Regiment, to the office of Lieutenant Colonel of said Regiment, iereby approved. Lieutenant Colonel Bolshaw will take rank from uary 24, 1903. III. An" election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy in the office Major of the Second Nebraska Infantry Regiment, vice Major Fred - ck J. Bolshaw, promoted. III. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward written ballots to the officers of the Second Nebraska Infantry Regiment for their use in the election ordered in the preceeding paragraph. These ballots, indicating the officers choice of person for appointment to the office of Major, must be returned to the Adjutant General's Office on or before 11 A. M. of Friday, February 13, 1903 IV. A Board of Officers to consist of the Adjutant General, Cap - tain Harry L. Hull of Co. "A" and First Lieutenant Albert L. Rollin. Company "K", First Nebraska Infantry Regiment, will convene in the Adjutant General's Office at 11 A M. on Friday, February 13, 1903 for the purpose of canvassing and recording the votes. No ballot will be received or recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said Board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor L. W. COLBY Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p118">117 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 3, 1903. Beral Orders, o. 10. tl. Pursuant to Section 24, Chapter 56 of the Compiled Statutes ebraska, a Board of Examination will convene in the Adjutant iral's office, Lincoln, Nebraska, at 10 o'clock A. M. on Friday, Feb - y 13, 1903, for the purpose of examining such officers as may b« red before it, as to their qualifications for commissions as officers le Nebraska National Guard. The following officers are detailed for such Board: Brigadier General P. H. Barry, First Brigade, Colonel H. L. Archer, First Infantry Regiment, Lieut. Col. V. Claris Talbot, First Infantry Regiment, Major Charles A. Vickers, First Infantry Regiment, Major R. Emmett Giffen, Brigade Surgeon, Captain John C. Hartigan, Co. "D," 2nd Infantry Regiment. Captain Fred J. Nack, Co. "M," 2nd Infantry Regiment. II. The examination ordered in the foregoing paragraph will be El in accordance with General Orders No. 7. A. G. O., series of , with such modifications as may be prescribed by the Adjutant ral to the Board of Examination 1III. The following officers of the Nebraska National Guard will rt in undress uniform with side arms, for examination to the ident of the Board, convened by paragraph I of this Order, to-wit: Colonel John W. McDonnell, Second Infantry, Lieut Col. Fred J. Bolshaw, Second Infantry, Major Eli Hodgins, Second Infantry, Captain Samuel E. Yoder, Battery "A", Captain Jesse C. Penrod, Co. "C ", 1st Infty... Captain George A. Eberly, Stanton Rifles, Captain James C. Elliott, West Point Rifles, Captain William R. Brooks, Eng. &amp; Sig. Corps, Captain Albert L. Gooden, Co. "B " 1st Infty., Captain Walter F. Sammons, Co. "A," 2nd Infty., Captain John T. Crozier, Co. D. 1st Infi Captain Oliver G. Osborne, Co. "G" 2nd Infty., Captain George W. Sues, Millard Rifles, Captain Otis M. Newman, Co. "H," 2nd Infty., Captain Ernest H. Tracy, Co "L," 2nd Infty., Captain Charles Smrha, Jr., Co. "G", 1st Infty., Captain Bruce McCulloch, South Omaha Cavalry, Captain Clifford W. Walden, Surgeon 2nd Infty. 1st Lieut. Nelson N. Barber, Co. "B" 1st Infty., 1st Lieut. Ralph L. Sabin, Co. "C". 1st Infi 1st Lieut. Daniel Templeton. Co. "I " 1st In: </seg>
            <seg id="p119">118 1st Lieut Iver S. Johnson, Stanton Rifles, 1st Lieut. Arthur G. Secton, West Point Rifles, 1st Lieut. William E. Baehr, Co. "L", 1st Infty., 1st Lieut. Clayton J. Norton, Co. "B" 2nd Infty., Jst Lieut. J. Rex Henry, Eng. and Sig. Corps, 1st. Lieut. Willard E. Bailey, Co. "E," 2nd Infty., Tst Lieut. James Allen, Co. "G" 2nd Infty., 1st Lieut. Raymond J. Pool, Co. "D" 1st Infty., 1st Lieut. Clinton W. T. Garrison, Battery "A", 1st Lieut. Frank H. Brown, Asst. Surg. 2nd Infty.. 1st Lieut. James B. Hungate, Asst. Surg. 1st Infty., 1st Lieut. Frank S. Nicholson, Asst. Surg., Battery "A," 1st Lieut. Harry M. Tagg, South Omaha Cavalry, 1st Lieut. Robert A. .Clapp Adjutant 2nd Infty., 1st Lieut. Earl H. Shankland, Co... "H" 2nd Infty., 1st Lieut. Earl M. Shankland, Co. "H," 2nd Infty., 1st Lieut. Justin N. Sarbach, Quartermaster, 2nd Infty., 1st Lieut. Roy H. Walker, Millard Rifles, 2nd Lieut. Lewis G Wremer, Co. "R" 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. Fred J. Feyerherm, Stanton Rifles, 2nd Lieut. Amos Thomas, Troop "A," Cavalry. 2nd Lieut. Ralph N. Dech, Co. "I" 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. Geo.. F. Broodfuehrer, Co.. "H," 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. Fred Hills Richards, Eng. and Sig. Corps, 2nd Lieut. Harry W. Majors, Co. "L" 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. Lawrence E. Jones, Co. "C" 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. Marion Foster, Co. "B" 2nd Infty., 2nd Lieut. Edmund H. Mulloney, Co. "H," 2nd Infty., 2nd Lieut. Clare D. Peebler, Co., "H," 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. Oliver A. Fairchild, Co. "A" 2nd Infty., 2nd Lieut. William Diesing, Co. "C," 2nd Infty., 2nd Lieut. E. E. Baumann, West Point Rifles, 2nd Lieut. Edward L. Fodge, Co. "D", 1st Infty. 2nd Lieut. Chas. W. Taylor, Co. "G" 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. James H. Duncanson, South Omaha Cavalry, 2nd Lieut. Anton Henriksen, Co. "H", 2nd Infty., 2nd Lieut. Hardy B. Klump, Co. "M", 1st Infty., 2nd Lieut. Albert Herman Barker, Co.. "E" 2nd Infty., 2nd Lieut. Edward V. Cooper, Millard Rifles, tlV. The officers comprising the Board of Examination and the ;rs to be examined will be furnished transportation from their e stations to Lincoln and return. By Command of the Governor, L. W. COLBY, Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p120">119 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, Febru '903. General Orders. No.ll. I. The election of Captain John C. Hartigan of Company "D", Second Infantry Regiment, to the office of Major of said Regiment, is hereby approved, and Major Hartigan will take rank from Februar 1903. til. Major John C. Hartigan, Second Nebraska Infantry Regiment, report to the Board of Examination convened pursuant to General ers No. 10 for examination as to his qualification to receive a mission, according to his rank. By Command of the Governor, L. W. COLBY, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 16, 1903. No. 12. I. The Board of Officers convened in pursuance to General Orders No. 10, c. s., for the purpose of examining officers, as to their qualifica - tions for commissions in the Nebraska National Guard, report the fol - lowing officers as duly qualified for the positions to which they have ben elected and appointed, from their own personal knowledge of their efficiency, military experience and fitness, and recommend that such be commissioned, which report and recommendation are hereby approved, and said officers will be commissioned accordingly: Colonel John W. McDonnell, Lieut. Col. Fred J. Bolshaw, Major John C. Hartigan, 2nd Infantry Regiment 2nd Infantry Regiment 2nd Infantry Regiment. 2nd Infantry Regiment Major Eli Hodgins, 1st Lieut. Robert A. Clapp, Adjutant, 2nd Infantry Regiment, 1st Lieut. John E. Buckmaster, Co. 'E' 2nd Infantry Regiment. II. Said Board of Examination having further reported that the following officers passe a satisfactory examination as to their fitness for the positions to which they have been elected or appointed in the Nebraska National Guard and recommended the same for commission, the report and recomendations of said Board are hereby approved and </seg>
            <seg id="p121">120 ■aid officers will be commissioned accordingly; a list of said officers, with a table showing the percentage attained by the various successful candidates in their examinations is published for the information of all concerned: </seg>
            <seg id="p122">ADJUTANT- GENERAL'S REPORT. 121 u 1 5 NAME OF OFFICER R4NK A ORGAN /.ATION * &lt; ii M v: Iri C &lt; a o s — Samuel E. Yoder Capt. Battery A Jesse C. Penrod .... Capt. Co C. 1st Regt George A. Eberly .. Capt. Stanton Rifles. Wm. R. Brooks. . Capt, Eng. &amp; Sig. Corps ~ Walter F. Sammons . . Capt. Co. A. 2nd Ben John T. Crozier . . Capt. Co. D. 1st Regt George W. Sues Capt. Millard Rifles * mi OtisM. Newman Cap. Co. H. 2nd Regt Chas. Smrha, Jr Capt. Co. G. 1st Reg.T - Bruce McCulloch leapt. So. Omaha Ca\ Fred W. Ludwig Capt. 2nd F. 2nd Regt. . 8&lt; H *ti 4-7 Iver S. Johnson 1st Lt. Stanton Rifles Wm. E. Baehr . . . . 1st Lt. Co. L 1st Regt 10&lt;)S0 Raymond J. Pool 1st Lt. Co. D. 1st Regt 78 1 no HOI Clinton W. T. Garrison 1st Lt. Battery A. Harry E. Tagg. .. lst,Lt. So. Omaha Ca LN.H4 I KarfM. Shankland .. 1st Lt. Co. H. 2nd Re^ Justin M. Sarbach ... 1st Lt. Q. M. 2nd Re^ Rov H. Walker 1st Lt. Millard Rifles 1st Lt. Co. F. 2nd Re^ Wm. T. Linder 2nd Lt. Co. F. 2nd Re - 2nd Lt. Troop A. Ca\ Chas. A. Dean Amos Thomas Fred J. Feyerherm . . '2nd Lt. Stanton Rifles. Fred Hills Richards! .|2nd Lt Eng. &amp;Sig. Corp loo 1-3 Harry W. Majors 2nd Lt. Co. L. 1st ReRi 7» Lawrence E. Jones... 2nd Lt.Co. C. 1st Regt. 65 Ed. H. Mullowney . . . 2Dd Lt. Co. M. 2nd Re^' Oliver A. Fairchfld . 2nd Lt. Co. A. 2nd R. K. M. Baumann 2nd Lt. Wes» Point R: Edward L. Fodge 2nd Lt. Co. D. 1st R&lt; Chas. W. Taylor 2nd Lt. Co. G. 1st R&gt; James H. Duncanson 2nd Lt. So. Omaha ( Anton Henricksen . . . 2nd Lt. Co. H. 2nd R&lt; Albert H. Barker . . 2nd Lt. Co. E. 2nd R« Edward V. Cooper . . . 2nd Lt. Millard Rifle Clare D. Peebler 2nd Lt. Co. H. 1st Regt. • - 81 1-3 I - Ml Clifford W. Walden. . jCapt. Surg. 2nd Regt. Medical Examinat Frank H. Brown jlstLt. Ass't. Surg. 2ndRe^ </seg>
            <seg id="p123">122 III. The following officers ordered to appear before said Board of Examination, were excused from taking the examination at the timo designated, upon good cause shown, subject to an examination to tx % ordered hereafter, before being commissioned: Captain Oliver G. Osborne, Co. "G" 2nd Infantry Regiment. Captain James C. Elliot, West Point Rifles, Captain William L Dowling, Co. "E," 1st Infantry Regiment 1st Lieut. Willard E. Bailey, Co. "D," 2nd Infantry Regiment, 1st Lieut. James Allen, Co. "G", 2nd Infantry Regiment. 1st Lieut. Arthur G. Sexton, West Point Rifles, 1st Lieut. Frank S. Nicholson, Asst. Surgeon, Battery "A", 2nd Lieut. Hardy B. Klump, Co. "M", 1st Infantry Regiment, 2nd Lieut. William Diesing, Co. "G", 2nd Infantry Regiment. IV. The following officers, having failed to report for examination before said Board in compliance with General Orders, No. 10, and having failed to make any excuse therefor, and the Examination Board having recomended that they be discharged from the military service of the state, such recommendation is hereby approved and said officers mre discharged from the service to take effeffct from the date of this order, to- wit: Captain Albert L. Gooden, Co. "B", 1st Infantry Regiment, 1st Lieut. Ralph L. Sabin, Co. "C", 1st Infantry Regiment. 1st Lieut. Daniel Templeton, Co. "I", 1st Infantry Regiment., 1st Lieut. J. Rex Henry, Eng. and Sig. Corps, 2nd Lieut. Ralph N. Dech, Co. "I", 1st Infantry Regiment.. 2nd Lieut. Marion Foster, Co. "B", 2nd Infantry Regiment. V. The officers of the Guard attending such examination deserve especial mention for the high state of proficiency shown by them gen - erally upon the various subjects submitted, and especially so when it is considered that many of the candidates having been recently elect - ed had no time for preparation. By Command of the Governor L. W. COLBY, Adjutant General. .Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, February, 19, 1903. General Orders, No. 13. I. General Orders No. 12 c. s. are hereby amended In this: First Lieutenant Ralph L. Sabin, Company "C", First Nebraska Infantry Regiment, is excused from taking the examination at the time designated upon good cause shown, subject to an examination to be ordered hereafter before being commissioned. II. Paragraph 4 of General Orders No 12, c. s. is hereby revoked </seg>
            <seg id="p124">123 Eir as the discharge of First Lieut. Ralph L. Sabin, Company . Infantry Regiment is concerned. The order for the discharge of tenant Ralph L. Sabin is countermanded and he is restored to the ary service of the State and to his rank therein. By Command of the Governor, U W. COLBY, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska Nation!" Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 25, 190 General Orders, No. 14. II. First Lieut. J Rex Henry of the Engineer and Signal Corps, raska National Guard, having shown good cause for being excused i taking the examination which occurred February 13, 1903, pur - lt to General Orders No. 10, c. s., and it appearing to be for the interests of the military service of the State, said General Orders 12 are hereby amended so as to excuse First Lieutenant J Rex ry from taking such examination, subject however to an examina - to be ordered hereafter before being commissioned. til. Paragraph 4 of General Orders No. 12, c. s. is hereby re - jd so far as the discharge of First Lieutenant I Rex Henry. Engi - 1 and Signal Corps, Nebraska National Guard, is concerned. Said ir for the discharge of Lieutenant Henry is countermanded and he ereby restored to the military service of the State and to his rank ein. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVKK Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, February 25, 190S General Orders, No. 15. II. The resignation of Major Eli Hodgins as Major of the Second intry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby accepted, and is honorably discharged from the military service of the State, to e effect February 25, 1903. II. In accordance with the provisions of the Militarv Code of the State, an election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy which will oc - cur in the office of Major of the Second Infantry Regiment, vice Ell Hodgins, resigned. </seg>
            <seg id="p125">124 III. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward proper bal - lots to the commissioned officers of the Second Nebraska Infantry Reg - iment for their use in the election ordered in the preceding paragraph. These ballots indicating the officers' choice of person for appointment to such office, will be signed by the officer voting, and returned to the Adjutant General's Office on or before llo'clock, A. M. of Thursday, March 12, 1903. IV. A Board of Officers to consist of the Adjutant General, Cap - tain George A. Eberly, Stanton Rifles, and First Lieutenant W. R. Mc- Laughlin, Adjutant First Regiment, will convene in the Adjutant Gen - eral's office at 11 o'clock A. M. on Thursday, March 12, 1903, for the purpope of canvassing and recording the votes at such election. No vote will be received or recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said Board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, March 12, 1903. General Orders, No. 16. I. The election of Captain Oliver G. Osborne of Company "G", Second Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, to the office of Major of said Regiment, is hereby approved, and Major Osborne will take rank from March 12, 1903. II. Major Oliver G. Osborne will turn over to his successor, when elected, all of the property for which he is accountable, and take his receipt for the same, and hold himself in readiness to report to the next Board of Examination when convened for examination for the rank for which he has been elected. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headqparters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, April 4,1903. General Orders, No. 17. I. All companies of the Nebraska National Guard will be in - spected at their home stations during the month by an officer detailed </seg>
            <seg id="p126">125 Rthe regular army and each company, troop, battery, corps and will make immediate preparation for the same. II. The inspection will disclose the numerical strength of each company, the proficiency in drill, company administration, care and con^.aon of arms and equipments, the number of company drills had during the year (which should not be less than twenty-four), the per - sonal character and seal of the members of the National Guard. Company commanders will at once recruit up to the full lgth and see that all extra arms including bayonet scabbards, car - le belts and boxes, and the company armories and storage rooms in presentable condition. 1IV. The "Articles of War" will be read at one of the regular or ial meetings of the company during the month of April, 1903, as as all General and Special orders of the current series. tV. Xon-commissioned officers' schools should be held at least ; a week. Special attention is called to extended order,, outpost r. artvanrp anH rpar enarri. and m«»morizine flenpral and Snecia . ers pertaining to sentinels on post. Lieutenants may be profitably doyed to conduct such schools of instruction. tVI. All absentees must be accounted for; leave of absence may granted for a period not to exceed seven ( 7 ) days by company com - nders while at home stations. Application for a greater period st be forwarded to this office through channels. A list of ab&gt; - 1 reason for absence must be prepared and ready to be given to th« pector. I VII. The attention of company commanders is called to the ne - ity of promptness in sending in quarterly reports. The printed in - ctions on back of reports should be closely followed. By Command of the Governor, J. H. Cl'LVElt. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, April 11, 1903. General Orders, No. IS. I The following staff appointments are hereby announced for the ormation of all concerned. On General Staff. Colonel George E. Jenkins, Quartermaster and Commissary Gen- eral, Fairbury Colonel Carroll D. Evans, Surgeon General, Column Colonel Charles J. Bills, Inspector General, Fairbu Colonel John A. Ehrhardt, Judge Advocate General, Stanton </seg>
            <seg id="p127">126 Aides-de-Camp. Colonel Ernest H. Tracy, Norfolk, Colonel Clarendon E. Adams, Superior, Colonel Clarence J. Miles, Hastings, Colonel Jacob S. Dew, Tecumseh, Colonel Wilson Chase, 21st inf. U .S. A., Lincoln, Colonel Warren R. McLaughlin, Beatrice, Colonel Samuel M. Melick, Lincoln, Colonel Joseph W. Thomas, Omaha, Colonel Herbert P. Shumway, Wakefleld, Colonel Charles W. Kalev, Red Cloud. The above named officers will take rank from January ninth, 1903. They will be obeyed and respected accordingly. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, April 16, 1903. teral Orders, No. 19. following changes in the officers of the Governor's staff and le commisioned personnel of the Nebraska National Guard, for the &gt;d beginning December 10, 1902, date of publication of last ros - to March 21, 1903, are announced for general information. General Staff. Adjutant General J. H. Culver, Lincoln, rank of Brigadier General, to date from February 20, 1903. Quartermaster and Commissary General, George E. Jenkins, Fair - bury, rank of Colonel to date from January 9, 1903. Surgeon General Carroll D. Evans, Columbus, rank of Colonel, to date form January 9, 1903. Inspector General, Charles J. Bills, Fairbury, with rank of Colonel, to date from January 9, 1903. Judge Advocate General, John A. Ehrhardt, Stanton, rank of Colonel, to date from anuary 9, 19 • Aides-de-Camp. Ernest H. Tracy, Colonel, January 9, 1903, Norfolk. Clarendon E. Adams, Colonel, January 9, 1903, Superior Clarence J. Miles, Colonel, January % 1903, Hastings, Jacob S. Dew, Colonel, January 9, 1903, Tecumseh, Wilson Chase, Colonel, January 9, 1903, Lincoln, Samuel M. Melick, Colonel, January 9, 19003, Omaha, Jn&lt;w&gt;nh W Thomas Colonel January 9 1903 Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p128">127 Herbert P. Shumway, Colonel, January 9, 1903, Wakefleld, Charles W. Kaley, Colonel, January 9, 1903, Red Cloud. First Regiment Captain Harry L. Hull, Company "A," re-elected, rank from Janu - ary 25, 1900. ■ Captain William L. Dowling, Company "F", rank from February 1903, vice Fred Gegner, discharged, expiratoin of term. Captain George Lyon, Jr., Company "H" re-elected, rank from March 21, 1900. First Lieutenant Albert L. Rollin. Compan rank from February 1?., 19' Second Lieutenant Otto K. Hagel. Company "K". rank fron ruary 19, 1903, vice George F. Broodfuchrer, resigned.. Second Lieutenant Hardy B. Klump, Company "M", rank from mber 20, 1902. vice C. W. Layton, resigned. Second Regiment. Colonel John \V. McDonnell, rank from January ! Wm. Hayward, resigned. 1 Lieutenant Colonel Frederick J. Bolshaw, to rank from January 1903, vice J. W. McDonnell, to Colonel. Major John C. Hartigan, to rank from February I, vice Frederick J. Bolshaw, to Lieutenant Colonel. Major Oliver G. Osborne, to rank from March 12, 1903, vice Eli Hodgins, resigned. I Robert A. Clapp to be Regimental Adjutant with rank of tenant, from January 28, 1903, vice Allan B. Wilson, discha ration of term. 1 Clifford W. Walden, to be Surgeon with rank of Captain, from uary 28, 1903 vice Arthur P. Ginn, discharged, expiration of term. KAddison E. Knickerbocker, to be Chaplain with rank of Ca: m January 28, 1903, re-appointed. 1 Justin M. Sarbach, to be regimental Quartermaster with rank of 3t Lieutenant from February 2, 1903, vice T. F. McCarthy, rged, expiration of term. Second Lieutenant Roy E. Riley, Company "D", to rank from February 11, 1903, vice J. M. Sarbach to Quartermaster. K Second Lieutneant* Albert H. Barker, Company "E", to rank from uary 14, 1903, vice A. H. Wilson, resigned. Captain Frederick W. Ludwig Company "F", to rank from F ary 2 1903, vice Frank I. Ringer, resigned. K First Lieutenant William T. Linder, Company "F", rank from ry 2, 1903, vice F. W. Ludwig to Captain. . Second Lieutenant Charles H. Dean, Company "F", to rank from February 2, 1903, vice W. T. Linder to First Lieutenant. Captain James Allen, Company "G", to rank from March 18, 1903, vice O. G. Osborne to Major. , </seg>
            <seg id="p129">128 r'irst Lieutenant William Diesing, Company "G", rank from March 1903, vice James Allen to Captain. Second Lieutenant John B. Lindsey, Company "G", rank from March 16, 1903, vice William Diesing to First Lieutenant.. Captain Otis M. Xewman, Company "H", rank from February 4, 1903 vice C. A. Phillips resigned. First Lieutenant Carl M. Shankland Company "H", rank from nary 4, 1903, vice O. M. Newman to Captain. Second Lieutenant Anton Hendrickson Company "H", rank from February 4 1903 vice Carl M. Shankland to First Lieutenant. First Lieutenant Dee D. McLeod, Company "K", rank from March 3, 1903, vice Gerald Bednar resigned. Captain Chester A. Fuller, Company "L", to rank from March 18, 1903, vice Ernest H. Tracy, resigned. E'aptain Fred J. Mack, Company "M", rank from March 6, 1900. rst Lieutenant Wilbur S. Price, Company "M", re-elected rank l March 6. 1900. Independent Companies B Captain George W. Sues, Mi Hard Rifles, to rank from February 9, 3, vice T. A. Baughman, discharged.. First Lieutenant Roy H. Walker, Millard Rifles, rank from Feb - ruary 9, 1903, vice H. C. Stafford, discharged. Second Lieutenant Edward V. Cooper, Millard Rifles, rank from February 9, 1903, vice R. H. Walker, discharged. First Lieutenant J. M. Birkner, Assistant Surgeon Hospital Corps transferred from First Regiment. Second Lieutenant E. Arthur Carr, Hospital Corps, transferred from Company "F", Second Regiment, to rank from February 18, 1903. Announcement of changes will hereafter be made in General or - at the end of each quarter. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, April 18, 1903. General Orders, No 20. (Company Commanders of the Nebraska National Guard occupy - posts along the route to be traversed by President Roosevelt in state between the 25th and 28th of April, 1903, are hereby author - to turn out their commands on the dates of the arrival and depart - of the President at their home stations, and will co-operate with local authorities in paying honor to the President, preserving order </seg>
            <seg id="p130">129 and performing such duties as may be required to contribute to the success of the occasion By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, Ma' General Orders, No. 21. I The members of the National Guard of Nebraska are reminded that icred day awaits them on the 30th of May, when they will bei d to take part in the exercises commemorating the valor and pat - ic devotion of the American soldier. The various organ i Guard will attend divine worship at some church on Memorial Sun - in uniform without arms, and the commanding officer of each npany, Troop, Battery, Corps and Band will tender the servii command to the Post Commander of the Grand Army of the Repub - or the executive committee having the exercises of the 30th of May charge and render such assistance as may be required to fittingly erve the day made sacred to the memory of those who died that country might live. On every battlefield along the contending lines from 1861 to heroic devotion to duty marks the last resting place of comrades whose sacrifices made possible many of the blessings and enlarged privileges of to-day. In honoring their memory we honor the country and our - selves. As the great conflict recedes in the distance, its lesson grows brighter, the sons of the blue and gray marching side by side under the Stars and Stripes in the Spanish and Phillipine wars, is evidence of the thoroughness of this lesson and its general acceptance. Many of these have gone to join the Grand Army over the river and should be included in the number to whom we pay tribute on this memorial day. I Competitive drills, games and sports will detract from the solem - of the occasion and should not be indulged in by members of the rd during this day. K Blank ammunition will be furnished on requisition and Company manders will exercise due diligence to avoid accident, inspecting s on assembling and dismissing the Company. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER. 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">130 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General'* Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, May" 19, 1903. General Orders. No. 22. KI. In compliance with the military code of the state of Nebraska, election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy in the office of Major the First Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, vice Major irles A. Vickers, whose term of office ■will expire May 31, 1903. II. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward written bal - lots to the commissioned officers of the First Infantry Regiment, Neb - raska National Guard, for their use in the election ordered in the pre - ceding paragraph. These ballots, indicating the officers' choice of person for appointment to the ofice of Major must be returned to the Adjutant General's Office on or before eleven o'clock A. M., Ma 1903. III. A Board of Officers to consist of Brigadier General J. H. Culver, Adjutant General; Captain Otis M. Newman, Company "H," Second Regiment, and Lieutenant William P. Linder, Company "F." Second Regiment, will convene in the Adjutant General's Office at eleven o'clock A. M., on May 28, 19Q3, for the purpose of canvassing the votes. No ballot will be received or recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said election board. The junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, May 18, 1903. General Orders No. 22%. The National Guard of Nebraska will be Inspected at the home stations by the following named officers on dates indicated: Brigadier General J. H. Culver will inspect Company "F" of the Second Regiment, on May 18; South Omaha Cavalry Troop, Companies "G" and "I" of the Second Regiment and Company "I" of the First Regiment, on Saturday, May 23; Company "C" of the Second Regi - ment, on May 25; Company "D" of the First Regiment, on May 26: Company "I" of the First Regiment and Company "K" of the Second Regiment, on May 27; Signal Corps and Hospital Corps on Ma; Company "B" of the First Regiment, on May 29; Company "A" of the Second Regiment, on June 2, Company "A" of the First Regiment, on </seg>
            <seg id="p132">131 re 4; Company "H" of the Second Regiment, on June 5; Troo) June 6. , ■ Inspector General Colonel C. J. Bills will inspect Company "D the Second Regiment, on June 1. 1 Colonel J. W. McDonnell will inspect Company "C" and Band of First Regiment on June 2. Colonel C. E. Adams will inspect Battary "A," Wymore on June Lt. Colonel V. C. Talbot will inspect Company "M" of the First Regiment on June 1. Major J. A. Storch will inspect Company "M" of the Second Regi ment on May 23. Major J. C. Hartigan will inspect Company "H" of the First Regi - ment on June 3. Company "G" of the First Regiment on June 4 Captain George A. Eberly will inspect Coi i." of the Sec - ond Regiment on May 23. Captain E. H. Phelps will inspect Company "E" of the First ment on June 1. Captain Otis M. Newman will inspect Company "B" of tl; ond Regiment on May 29. S Captain Charles M. Richards will inspect Company "E" of the cond Regiment on June 4. II. The hour of inspection will be at 8 P. M. unless otherwi - ected by the inspecting officer and company commanders will have their commands assembled at the time designated. III. Officers performing the duty of assistant inspector will fully note and report any deficiency in equipments for active fleM vice, condition of armory and storage rooms, personal character and proficiency of the men composing the commands. Travel enjoined is necessary for the public service. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Linccoln, Nebraska, May 20, 1 General Orders, No. 23. In compliance with General Orders No. 49 c. s. Headquarters of the Army, A. G. O., the Commander of the Department of Missouri has appointed Captain Jacob F. Krepa of th« 22nd Infantry and Captain Marcus D. Cronin of the 25th Infantry, as inspecting oMcers for th« National Guard of Nebraska. TT The at tt?nt ion of ConiD&amp;iiy connH&amp;iidcrs is c&amp;llod to 'G€Xi6r&amp;l </seg>
            <seg id="p133">132 ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S REPORT. Orders No. 17 c. s. Returns properly certified to should be prepared by the commanding officer of each company and submitted to the in - spector on his arrival. I III. Members of the field, staff and non-commissioned staff will rt at the armory of the Company at their respective home stat - at the time of the inspection. tlV. The inspection will be made in heavy marching order, blanket , including shelter halves and ponchos, should be carefully rolled hung from the left shoulder, canteens and haversacks as previously ucted. V. Companies will be inspected by Captain Kreps on the dates and in the folowing order: » Company "L" 1st Regiment, "G" and "I" 2nd at Omaha and ith Omaha Cavalry Troop May 25, 26 and 27 as may be designated the inspecting officer. Company "C." 2nd Regiment, at Nebraska City, May 2S. Company "D" of the 1st Regiment at Weeping Water May 29. Company "F" 2nd Regiment, the Hospital Corps and 1st Regi ment Band at Lincoln, June 1. Company "E," 1st Regiment at Wilber, June 2 L Company "C," 1st Regiment, and Regimental Headquarters 1st ment and 2nd Regiment Band at Beatrice June 3. Battary "A" at Wymore June 4 ■ Company "D," 2nd Regiment, and 2nd Regiment Headquarters Fairbury June 5. Company "H" of the 1st Regiment at Nelson June 6. Company "G," 1st Regiment at Geneva June 8. Company "H," 2nd Regiment at Aurora June 9. Company "H," 2nd Regiment at Aurora June 10. Troop "A" at Seward, June 11. Company "I," 1st Regiment at Wahoo June 13 VI. Captain Cronin will inspect the Companies designated in the following order: Company "L," 2nd Regiment at Norfolk, May 25. Company " F," 1st Regiment at Madison, May 26. Company "M," 2nd Regiment, at Albion, May 27. Company "K," 1st Regiment at Columbus, May 28. Company "K," 2nd Regiment at Schuyler, May 29. Company "B," Second Regiment, at St. Paul, June 1. Company "M," 1st Regiment, at Broken Bow, June 3. Company "A," 2nd Regiment at Kearney, June 4. Engineer and Signal Corps at Fremont June 5. Company "E," 2nd Regiment at Tekamah, June 6. West Point Rifles at West Point, June 8. Company "B," 1st Regiment at Stanton, June 9 VII. The Infantry Companies, Corps and Bands will assemble at their respective armories at 8:00 o'clock P. M. and the Troops and </seg>
            <seg id="p134">133 Battery at such hour as may be designated by the inspecting officers on the dates named. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, May 28, 1903 teral Orders. No. 24. §1. The election of First Lieutenant Warren R. McLaughlin, of the First Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard to the e of Major of said Regiment, is hereby approved, and Majo: ghlin will take rank from June 1, 1903. III. The following appointment has been made by Colonel Harry Archer, Commanding the First Infantry Regiment, Nebraska N Guard, and the same has been approved by the Governor. Orien \V. Fifer, to be Chaplain, with the rank of Captain from May 1, 1903. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, June 15, 1903 General Order No. 25. §1. The official inspection of the Nebraska National Guard indi - s favorable improvement, but continual effort will be requin part of all officers to bring the Guard up to the standard des II. All comunieations of an official character to regimental head - quarters should be addressed to the "Adjutant of the Regi - ment." Those to the headquarters of the National Guard to tne "A tant General, Lincoln, Nebraska." Hi. A careful study of the Rules and Regulations will obviate the necessity of many communications. IV. The attention of the company commanders is called T printed instructions on all blanks. Record of previous service should be entered on enlistment papers upon proof of such service. Re-c ment must be plainly indicated. I The removal from the state will vacate a commission and ers and enlisted men should be reported for discharge upon proper rmation of such removal. VI. Company commanders may appoint reliable local mil jTCioni </seg>
            <seg id="p135">134 Ixamine recruits for enlistment, or recommend soldiers for discharge physical disability, such service to be rendered without expense to state. I VI. Target practice with the new magazine rifle will commence ion as received, and the selection of ranges and preparation will be ediately made by company commanders. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, June 19, 190 General Orders. Xo. 26. I. The resignation of Colonel Harry L. Archer, First Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby accepted, and he is honorably discharged from the military service of the state, to take effect June 22, 1903. III. Lieutenant Colonel V. Claris Talbot will take command of First Infantry Regiment until the election of Colonel of said Regi - t is held and such election is approved by the Governor. till. In accordance with the provisions of the military code of state, an election is here"by ordered to fill the vacancy in the office Colonel of the First Regiment of Infantry, vice Archer, resigned. IV. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward proper bal - lots to the commissioned officers of the First Infantry Regiment for their use in the election ordered in the preceeding paragraph. These bal - lots indicating the officers' choice of person for appointment to such office will be signed by the officer voting and returned to the Adjutant General's Ofice on or before 11:00 o'clock A. M., Wednesday, July 8, A Board of Officers to consist of the Adjutant General, Major Oliver G. Osborne of the Second Infantry Regiment, and Lieutenant Arthur A. Murdock, of Battary "A," will convene in the Adjutant Gen - eral's Office at 11:00 o'clock A. M., Wednesday, July 8, 1903, for the purpose of canvassing and recording the votes at such election. No vote will be received or recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said Board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p136">135 Headquarters Nebraska National G Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska. July 1, 1903 General Order No. 27 following changes in the commissioned personnel of thf a National Guard, since publication of G. O. 19 c. s., are announced general infoimation. FIRST REGIMENT Colonel Harry L. Archer, resigned, to take effect June 22nd, I Captain Orin W. Fifer, appointed Chaplain, to rank from May 1, 1903 Warren R. McLaughlin, First Lieutenant and Regimental Adju - , elected Major to rank from June 1, 1903. I Captain Willis E. Talbot, Surgeon, Captain Orien W. Fifer, Chap - and First Lieutenant Arundle M. Hull, Quartermaster, terms of expire June 22, 1903, by reason of resignation of Colonel Archer. I The "Stanton Rifles" having been assigned to the First Regiment, company B, Captain George A. Eberly, First Lieutenant Iver S. nson and Second Lieutenant Fred J. Feyerherm names are trana - sd to the roster of the First regiment. t Captain Albert L. Rollin, Compank "K," to rank from April 10, 3, vice Hockenberger, resigned. 1 Captain Edward H. Kennedy, Company "F," to rank from May 9. 3, vice Dowling resigned. First Lieutenant Otto K. Ha"gel, Company "K," to rank from April 10, 1903. First Lieutenant Emil Placek, Company "I," to rank from May 26, 1903. First Lieutenant Samuel E. Esh, Company "F," to rank from June 8, 1903. First Lieutenant William H. Osborne, Company "M," to rank from May 23, 1903. First Lieutenant Percy C. Zeigler, Company "H," term expired June 8, 1903. Second Lieutenant Harvey W. Majors, Company "L." resigned April 30, 1903. Second Lieetenant Charle3 E. Fraser, Company "F," to rank from May 9, 1903. L Second Lieutenant Lewis G. Kremer, Company "B," honorably harged by reason of muster out of Company, May 2 0, 1903. Second Lieutenant John H. Linton, Company "E," re-elected, to rank from May 5, 1900 Second Lieutenant Fred C. Gibbs, Company "I," to rank from May </seg>
            <seg id="p137">136 Second Lieutenant Harley L. Dussell, Company "K," to rank from April 10, 1903. K Second Lieutenant Dell F. Lough, Company "L," to rank from May 1903. SECOND REGIMENT. I The "Millard Rifles" having been assigned to the Second Regiment Company "I," Captain George W. Sues, First Lieutenant Roy H. lker, and Second Lieutenant Edward V. Cooper, names are trans - •ed to the roster of Second Regiment. Captain William Diesing, Company "G," to rank from April 2 8, 1903. First Lieutenant Allan D. Falconer, Company "C," to rank from April 28, 1903. ■ First Lieutenant Jack Beason, Company "C," to rank from June 1903. Second Lieutenant Clarence P. Childress, Company "K," to rani from April 16. 1903. I Note. General Order No. 28, prescribing the uniform of the Neb- La National Guard, to conform to that of the U. S. Army, is omitted the reason that a number of changes are now contemplated by the • Department. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, July 9. 1903 General Orders. No. 29. I. The election of Lieutenant Colonel V. Claris Talbot, First Neb - raska Infantry Regiment to the office of Colonel of said Regiment, is hereby approved and Colonel Talbot will rank from July 8, 1903. 8, 1903. III. An election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy in the offlce Lieutenant Colonel of the First Nebraska Infantry Regiment vice utenant Colonel Talbot, promoted. I III. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward proper bal - 3 to the commissioned officers of the First Nebraska Infantry Regi - nt for their use in the election ordered in the preceding paragraph, sse ballots, indicating the officers' choice of person for appointment the office of Lieutenant Colonel, must be returned to the Adjutant neral's office on or before 11 A. M., of Monday, July 20, 1903. tlV. A Board of Officers, to consist of Brigadier General J. H. ver, Adjutant General, Captain Fred J. Mack, Second Infantry and m. Fred Hills Richards of the Signal Corps, will convene in ss uniform without side arms in the Adjutant General's Office at </seg>
            <seg id="p138">137 ■o'clock A. M., on Monday, July 20, 1903, for the purpose of canvass - and recording the votes. No ballot will be received and recorded er the hour named for the meeting of said election board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, July 21, 1903 General Order No. 30. kl. The election of Major Joseph A. Storch, First Nebraska In- Lry, to the office of Lieutenant Colonel of said Regiment, is hereby roved and Lieutenant Colonel Storch will take rank from Jui 3. III. An election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy in the office Major of the First Nebraska Infantry Regiment. jor Joseph Storch, promoted. II1I. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward written bal - 3 to the commissioned officers of the First Nebraska Infantry Regi - nt, for their use in the election ordered in the preceding paragraph. Rse ballots, indicating the officers' choice of person for appoin the office of Major must be returned to the Adjutant General's Office or before 11:00 A. M., of Tuesday, August 4. IS I IV. A Board of Officers to consist of Brigadier General, J. H. [ver, Adjutant General: Captain Herbert J. Paul, Second Infantry giment, and Second Lieutenant James H. Duncanson of the taha Cavalry, will convene in dress uniform without side an i Adjutant General's Office at 11: On A. M.. on Tuesday, )3, for the purpose of canvassing and recording the votes. No bal - will be received and recorded after the hour named for the mi said election board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. Bv Command of the Governor: Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, July 3 ! reral Orders No. 31. I. In compliance with the provisions of S j. h. en. </seg>
            <seg id="p139">138 act to promote the efficiency of the militia, and for other purposes," approved January 21, 1908, the Second Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, will participate in the encampment, maneuvers, and fl«ld instruction of the regulr army at Fort Riley, Kansas, at such time as shall be designated in subsequent orders. II. The First Infantry Regiment, Battery "A," Troop "A," South Omaha Cavalry, West Point Rifles, Signal and Hospital Corps will en - gage in field and camp service for instruction commencing August 26, and closing August 31, 1903, at such place or places within the state as shall be designated in subsequent orders. till. Further enlistments will be suspended until after the en - pments. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, July 31, 1903. General Orders, No. 32. By virtue of the authority granted by Section 14, Chapter 56 of the Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, and in compliance with General Order No. 108, Headquarters of the Army, A. G. O., the regiments, com - panies, troops, battery and bands constituting the Nebraska National Guard will be organized as follaws: I Each infantry regiment shall consist of one band, twelve com - ies, one colonel, one lieutenant colonel, three majors, and one sur - n with rank of major, one adjutant, one quartermaster, one com - sary, one chaplain, one first assistant surgeon, each with the rank of tain, one second assistant surgeon, three battalion adjutants, three talion quartermasters, each with the rank of first lieutenant, provid - in time of peace the battalion adjutants and quartermasters shall detailed from the first lieutenants of their respective battalions by - regimental commander upon recomendation of the battalion com - ader; one sergeant major, one quartermaster sergeant, one eom - isary sergeant, one hospital steward, one chief trumpeter, three talion sergeant majors, and two color sergeants. I Each regimental band shall consist of one chief musician, one cipal musician, one drum major, four sergeants, eight corporals, cook and twelve privates. Each company of infantry shall consist of one captain, one first lieutenant, one second lieutenant, one first sergeant, one quartermaster sergeant, four sergeants, six corporals, two musicians, two cooks, one </seg>
            <seg id="p140">139 artificer and not less than twenty-eight, nor more than forty eight privates. Each troop of cavalry shall consist of one eaptain, one firs' tenant, one second lieutenant, one first sergeant, one quartern sergeant, six sergeants, six corporals, two cooks, two farriers, one sad - dler, one wagoner, two trumpters, and not less than thirty, nor more than forty-three privates. Each battery of artillery shall consist of one captain, one first lieu - tenant, one second lieutenant, one first sergeant, one quartern sergeant, one stable sergeant, six sergeants, twelve corporals, two cooks, two artificers, two trumpeters, and not less than thirty, nor more than sixty privates. The Signal Corps shall consist of one captain, one first lieutenant, one second lieutenant, four first class sergeants, six sergeants, six cor - porals, two cooks, two trumpeters, one artificer and not less than twenty nor more than thirty-five privates, one half of whom shall be designated as first class privates and the other half as privates. A first sergeant and quartermaster sergeant may be selected from the first class sergeants. The Hospital Corps shall consist of one captain, one first lieutenant, one second lieutenant, two first class sergeants, five second class ser - geants, six corporals, two trumpeters, two cooks, one artificer, and not less than twenty nor more than forty-one privates one half of whom shall be designated as first class privates, and the other half as privates. A first sergeant and quartermaster sergeant may be selected from the first class sergeants. By Command of the Governor Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, August 5, 1903. General Orders, No. 33. I. In compliance with General Orders 32, A. G. O. cs., the elect - ion is hereby ordered of an additional Major of the First Infantry Regiment; also an additional Major of the Second Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard. II. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward blank bal - lots to the commissioned officers of the First Nebraska Infantry Regi - ment; also to the commissioned officers of the Second Nebraska Infantry Regiment, for their use in the elections ordered in the preceding para - graph. These ballots, indicating the officers' choice of person for ap - pointment to the office of major of the First or Second Regiments, J. H. CULVER. </seg>
            <seg id="p141">140 respectively, must be returned to the Adjutant General's Office on or be - fore 11:00 A. M., of Monday, August 17, 1903. I III A board of officers to consist of Brigadier General J. H. Cul- Adjutant Gereral. Captain J. C. Elliott of the West Point Rifles, Lieutenant J. M. Birkner of the Hospital Corps, will convene in the e of the Adjutant General at 11:00 A. M., August 17, 1903, for the lose of canvassing and recording the votes. No ballot will be ived or recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said tion board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, August 10, 1903 General Orders, No. 33 %. I On recommendation of the Military Board the insigna to be worn the officers of the Nebraska National Guard shall be the word "Neb - ka" attached to and in crescent form over the United States coat arms, extending between the tips of the eagle wings, the letters to one-eighth of an inch in height; the coat of arms and insigna com - te, to be one and one-eighth inches in height; the color and mater - to be U. S. regulation. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, August 14, 1903. General Orders, No. 34. Brigadier General J. H. Culver, Adjutant General, is hereby ap - pointed disbursing officer, in accordance with the provisions of Sec - tion 14, Act of Congress, entitled "An act to promote the efficiency of the militia, and for other purposes," approved January 14, 1903; and he will give good and sufficient bonds to The United states in sums as The Secretary of War may direct, to faithfully account for the safe keeping and payment of the public monies so intrusted to him for disbursement. JOHN H. MICKEY, Governor and Commander in Chief. </seg>
            <seg id="p142">141 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, Au- 1903. General Orders, No. 35 tl. Company commanders to whom are issued the magazine rifle, bre 30, will make a record of the number of each rifle and immed - ly forward to the Adjutant General's office, a certified copy of the The Quartermaster Sergeant of each company should be required to keep a record of the rifle number and to whom issued. III. On receipt of the new issue of rifle, the Springfield rifles, slings, t ridge belts and accoutrements, also all caliber 45 cartridges, most securely packed as directed in Circular No. 1 c. s. and shipped prop - y invoiced, to this office; each article should be separately named the invoice. Springfield arm chests should be used for the rifles and ronets only. Ill All broken and unserviceable parts of arms or equipment should be forwarded to the Adjutant General's Office. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, August 18, 1983. General Order No. 35%. II. By authority of General Order No. 32 A. G. O. c. s., the follow - promotions in the Second Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National rd, are hereby made, to take rank from July 31, 1903. II. Captain Clifford W. Walden, to be surgeon with the rank of Major. LIII. First Lieutenant Frank H. Brown, to be first assistant sur with rank of Captain. I IV. First Lieutenant Robert E. Clapp, regimental Adjutant, to Captain. By Command of the Governor: J. H. Cl'LVER, Adjutant General. </seg>
            <seg id="p143">142 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, August 18, 1903 reral Orders, No. lie. The following Regimental Staff Officers have been selected and appointed by Colonel V. Claris Talbot, commanding the First Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, and such appointments have been approved by the Governor: Dr. W. E. Talbot of Broken Bow, as Surgeon, with the rank of Major. IDr. J. B. Hungate of Weeping Water, First Assistant Surgeon, with rank of Captain. BLieutant A. M. Hull of Fremont, as Quartermaster, with the rank Captain. Rev. O. W. Fifer of York, as Chaplain, with the rank of Captain. ISaid officers will take rank from uly 31, 1903, and will be obeyed respected accordingly. Captain William R. Brooks will report to the commanding officer of the First Regiment for duty. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, August 20, 1903. General Orders. No. 37. tl. In accordance with the provisions of paragraph XI of General rs No. 31, A. G. O. July 31, 1903, the First Regment, Battery Troop "A," and the Hospital Corps will go into camp of instruct - at York, Nebraska, August 26, 1903. KII. The name of the Engineer &amp; Signal Corps is hereby changed at of Signal Corps and will hereafter be known and designated at title. till. That portion of General Order No. 31, paragraph XI, refer - to the Signal Corps, West Point Rifles and South Omaha Cavalry reby revoked. The commanding officer of the Signal Corps will his command in readiness for camp duty in October. The South la Cavalry and the West Point Rifles will be permitted to go into of instruction at their home stations at a future date. IV. The annual camp of instruction 1903, will be called "Camp Pershing" in honor of Captain John J. Pershing, in appreciation of his gallant services in Mindanao, and past efficient services in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p144">143 tV. Colonel V. C. Talbot, First Regiment, Nebraska National rd is assigned to command of Camp Pershing, and he is authorized the purpose of discipline, to extend his jurisdiction for one mile ind said camp in compliance with Section 34, Chapter 56, Compiled utes of Nebraska. VI. The Governor's staff will report at Camp Pershing for duty as follows: Brigadier General J. H. Culver, Adjutant General, Colonel George E. Jenkins, Quartermaster and Commissary General, Colonel C. D. Evans, Surgeon General, on August 25th; Colonel John A. Ehr - hardt, Judge Advocate General on August 27th; Colonel C. J. Bill Aides-de-Camp on August 29th for one day's duty. General P. H. Barry will report at Camp Pershing for one day's duty on August 29th to take part in the Governor's review of that date. KVII. The officers and men not otherwise directed, will proceed to ip with their respective commands on the dates and by the following tes: Troop "A" will march from Seward to York, starting August Battery "A" Wymore, leave by B. &amp; M. 8:00 a. m.; Arrive Crete E. from which point they will march to York. Hospital Corps, Lin - , will march from Lincoln to York, starting from Lincoln on August ,• with permission to move without expense to the state on the pre- ceding day. VIII. Regimental field and staff officers will move to Camp Per- shing on the first regular or special train leaving their respective sta- tions on August 26th, 1903. IX. Requisitions for transportation will be made upon the Adju- tant General as follows a. The Colonel of the First Regiment will make requisition for transportation for the commissioned and non-commissioned staff of his command b. Field officers will make requisition direct to this office c. The commanding officers of the various companies will make Route Leave August 26. Arrive York 2o. "B," Stanton, C. &amp; N. W. 6:49 a. m. 11:30 a. m 2o. "C," Beatrice, B. &amp; M. 6:30 a. m. 4 p.m 2o. "D," Weeping Water, M. P. Lincoln, 5:15 a. m. 12:54 p. m 2o. "E," Wilber, B. &amp; M. 9:11 a. m. 12:54 p. m 2o. "F," Madison, V. P. Columbus &amp; B. &amp; M. as ordered. 2o. "G," Geneva, B. &amp; M. 11:00 a. m. 12:55 p. m 2o. "H," Nelson, B. &amp; M. 9:00 a. m. 12:55 p. m 3o. "I," Wahoo, C. &amp; N. W. 7:55 a. m. 11:30 sC. m Zo. "K," Columbus, B. &amp; M. 7:25 a. m. 12:54 p. m 2o. "L. " Omaha, C. &amp; N. W. 7:30 a. m. 11:30 a. m Co. "M," Broken Bow, B. &amp; M. '7 a. m. 11:45 a. m </seg>
            <seg id="p145">144 Iiisition for the transportation of the officers and men of their re - live commands on which will be entered the actual number of ers and men transported; the original, signed by the officer receiv - the transportation will be delivered to the railway agent, the du - ite signed by the officer and the railway agent will be delivered to Adjutant General's office on arrival at camp. IX. The following instructions for the wearing of equipment will observed; blanket rolls, made with the shelter tent half, from the shoulder; haversacks from the right shoulder to the left side and the rear of the hip, strap under web belt; canteen from the left ulder to the right side, rear strap under web belt; poncho folded ite side out to size of 6 x 24 inches, then hung over the web belt ler the haversack; tin cup buckled in fastener at bottom of haver - k; campaign hats creased from the back along the middle, and must be marked, mutilated or pressed into any other shape; insigna of l of service, attached to front of the hat. XI. The blue and khahi uniform as prescribed by orders and regulations with D. B. F. Shirts will be worn by the officers and men while on this tour of duty as may be ordered. The khaki should be worn to and from camp. XII. Fatigue caps and other clothing for the various commands should be boxed and shipped to camp with other baggage; also company record books, the enlistment paper of each member of the command, copies of the last quarterly reports and the calibre 30 ball and blank ammunition. I XIII. Officers and men should bring to camp whatever clothing bedding absolutely necessary for the health and comfort of the men imp; also shelter tents. tlV. Commanding officers will be held to strict accountability for care and use of government property, and also for the conduct of to and from the encampment; and all damage to cars or other terty through carelessness or wanton destruction will be deducted l their pay. Any soldier absenting himself from camp will forfeit pay and become liable to court martial. XV. The allowance of baggage of officers will be limited to two hundred pounds. I XVI. Regimental Commissary William E. Brooks will report at p Pershing on Monday, August 24th, for the purpose of establishing arranging the camp. I XVII. Battalion commanders are directed to meet the several ipanies comprising their battalions on arrival at York, and superin - d their disembarkment and wagon transportation employed in the vement of company baggage to camp. Each company on arrival will into camp at once, and submit requisition for commissary and other res; making the ration returns for two days, when further instruct - 8 will be given. XVIII. Company "A," York, will report to Captain Wm. R. </seg>
            <seg id="p146">145 Rks, Regimental Commissary and acting Adjutant, for duty in the iration of camp Pershing, August 2 4th. I XIX. No member of any of the organizations named in para - ph 1 of this order will be excused from attendance at camp except surgeon's certificate of disability or serious illness in their immed - ! family. I XX. The officers and men named in this order will receive pay six day's service only, except where special instructions to the con - y are given. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. INote. General Order No. 38, Regulations for the care of the azine Rifle, having been issued in pamphlet form, is omitted from publication of this report. Lincoln, Auk General Orders. No. 3 6. The following Regimental Staff Officers have been selected and ap - pointed by Colonel V. Claris Talbot, commanding the First Infantry- Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, and such appointments have been approved by the Governor. Dr. W. E. Talbot of Broken Bow, as Surgeon, with the rank of Mayor. Dr. J. B. Hungate nf Weeping Water, First Assistant Surgeon, with the rank of Captain. Lieutenant A. M. Hull of Fremont as Quartermaster, with the rank of Captain. Rev. 0. W. Fifer of York, as Chaplain, with the rank of Captain. LSaid officers will take rank from July 31, 1903, and will be obeyed respected accordingly. ■ Captain William R. Brooks will report to the comanding officer the First Regiment for duty. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, September 19, I rneral Orders, No. 38 V4. Upon recommendation of Colonel J. W. McDonnell, and in accord </seg>
            <seg id="p147">146 Ei with General Orders No. 32, First Lieutenant Justin M. Sarbach, mental quartermaster is hereby promoted to Captain, and Captain &gt;ach will take rank from August 18, 1903. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Camp Pershing, York, Nebr., August 31, 1903. Keral Orders, I*. »The First Regiment, Battery, Troop and Hospital Corps, with the eption of Company A, First Nebraska regiment, will break camp August 31st, 1903. LThe troop will move from camp at 10:00 a. m., and march over - to home station at Seward, Nebraska. LThe remaining organizations leave by the routes and on the time dicated below: Companies B, I, and L at 12:30 p. m., by the Chicago and North- western. 1 Companies C, D, E, F, and K of the First Regiment, Battery A the Hospital corps on the Burlington at 3:50 p. m. Companies G and H on the K. C. and O. at 3:50 p. m. Company M on the Burlington at 7:22 p. m. Companies G and H will load and take train at lower depot. Battery A will load baggage, artillery and horses at the Burlington §The baggage cars for C, D, E, F, and K will be set in at the lower jt, where the baggage will be loaded. Companies will march to the lington depot where they will entrain. K Baggage wagons will be furnished each company one hour and ty minutes before time of departure and must be loaded promptly, etail sufficiently large shall accompany each wagon to train. commanding officer of company "A," first regiment will hold command in camp until September 1st and nntil all public property emoved therefrom, safely guarding the same, and will break camp be dismissed on verbal order of the Adjutant General. KThe Adjutant General and the Quartermaster General will remain York and pass upon all claims which may be presented and approve </seg>
            <seg id="p148">147 such as are just and correct against th» state of Nebraska, and report to their home stations on September 3rd. Members of the field and staff not in possession of the return trans - portation will report at this office by 9:00 a. m. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, September General Order No. 39 II. The Second Infantry Regiment Regiment, the Signal Corps and letachment of the Hospital Corps, Nebraska National Guard e part In the Army Maneuvers at Fort Riley, Kansas, be ober 18 and 27, 1903. The commanding officer of the regimen ling field and staff) and the various company commanders will hold ir commands in readiness to move from their respective stations the lines indicated by the commanding officer of the Department of Missouri as may be hereafter directed. II. Camp equipments should be carefully overhauled, securely packed ready for shipment, plainly marked with company and ment. Any equipments lacking should be immediately reported t.&gt; office. The number of non-commissioned officers and privates in company should be reported to this office without delay, as it is designed to fill the ranks to sixty-five enlisted from the First Regiment. till. It is the intention to have horses for mounted officers for at Fort Riley. The Regimental Quartermaster will be supplied i saddles and bridles for those who do not own equipments, which -sued on memorandum receipts to be returned to the Qaa ter at the close of the encampment. The men should be required to re for themselves heavy underwear. IV. Company commanders of the First Regiment will select as a reward of merit for efficiency in drill and soldierly conduct the number that may be designated (which will probably average fifteen) from each company to be assigned to the Second Regiment during the Army maneuvers at Fort Riley. Each soldier finally selected will be fully equipped by his company commander and in addition to the soldier's personal receipt for each item of equipment with the number of rifle, Ac, the issuing officers should invoice all of the individual equipments and necessary camp equippage to the commanding officer of the com - pany to whom the detachment will be sent, and take his receipt for the same. A copy of both invoice and receipt will be immediately sent to this office. On the return of the troops from the encampment to their home stations, equipments will be invoiced back and re&lt; exchanged. The issuing and receiving officer will be held strictly ac - countable for the earning out of these instructions and the rece </seg>
            <seg id="p149">148 officer will be held responsible for any losses of property receipted for. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, Nebraska, September 20, 1903. f'neral Orders. No. 39% (The resignation of Captain Justin M. Sarbach, Quartermaster, Sec - 1 Infantry Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby accepted, 1 Captain Sarbach is honorably discharged from the military service the state to take effect September 20, 1903. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, September 28, 1903. General Orders. No. 40. I. Company commanders of the Second Infantry Regiment and Signal Corps, Nebraska National Guard, will at once report to this office the number of non-commissioned officers, musicians, cooks and pri - vates that will be able to report for duty at the maneuvers of Fort Riley. As it is designed to fill the ranks of the Second Regiment from those of the First, company commanders of the last named Regiment will forward to this office at once the number of non-commissioned officers, musicians, cooks and privates that desire and can conveniently go into camp with the Second Regiment. As a rule detachments from the First Regiment will be assigned to the companies most convenient to their home stations. til. Company commanders are instructed to divide the company 3 squads and sections as prescribed under the head of "The School the Company," in Section 179 to 184 of the Infantry Drill Regula - 18. III. Drill hours must be largely devoted to extended order, ad - vance and rear guards and outpost duty in the preparation for the duties that the companies will probably be called upon to perform at the army maneuvers. IV. Non-commissioned officers' schools should be held by a commissioned officer as often as it is possible up to the time of going </seg>
            <seg id="p150">149 to encampment with a view to improvement in any lines in which the company may be found deficient. §V. Attention is called to the necessity of securing heavy under - r and reducing the baggage to the minimum. No caps will be a by the enlisted men, the campaign hat constituting the head dress the encampment at Fort Riley. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. General Order No. 41, Manuel of Tent Pitching, issued in phlet form to the Guard, is omitted. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, October 5, 1903. General Orders. No. 42. 1. The commanding officer of the Second Regiment, Nebraska National Guard, is hereby ordered to report with his command to the commanding officer of the Department of the Missouri at Fort Riley. Kansas, October 18, 1903. til. The Signal Corps and detachments from the Hospital Corps companies of the First Regiment, as may be hereafter designated hereby assigned to the Second Regiment for duty during the army leuvers at Fort Riley, and will report to the commanding officer of Second Regiment on the 17th of October, and will be relieved on the l, when they will report to their home stations as may be directed. I III. In accordance with the instructions of the commanding officer the Department of the Missouri, the various companies will move m their home stations on October 17, 1903, in the following order: Co. "A" will leave Kearney at 9:45 a. m., D. P. R. R. Co. "B" will leave St. Paul at 9:30 a. m., U. P. R. R. Co. "L" will leave Norfolk at 10:50 a m., D. P. R. R. Co. "M" will leave Albion at 11:10 a. m., U. P. R. R. Co. "K" will leave Schuyler on the U. P. R. R. on special train carrying companies from points named above. Signal Corps will leave Fremont on the same train. The ranking officer of this special train will ascertain from the railroad authorities at Grand Island the probable time of arrival of train at Schuyler and Fremont and wire this information to company commanders of Co. "K " and Signal Corps. This train will run through to Fort Riley via Valley and Manhattan as a special. Co. "E" will leave Tekamah at 7:15 a. m., C. St. P. M. &amp; O. R. R. Cos. "G" and "I" will leave Omaha at 9:30 a. m., on U. P. R. R. This train will run as a special from Omaha and pick up Company </seg>
            <seg id="p151">150 tat Lincoln, and Company "H" from Aurora, Company "D" from jury and Company "C" from Nebraska City at Beatrice, and run special on the l T . P. R. R. to Fort Riley. Company "H" will leave Aurora at 7:35 a. m., B. &amp; M. and arrive at Beatrice at 12:40 p. m. Company "D" will leave Fairbury at 5:05 a. m., C. R. I. &amp; P. R. R. and arrive at Beatrice at 6:03 a. m. Company "C" will leave Nebraska City at 8:30 a. m., B. &amp; M. R R. and arrive at Beatrice at 12: 25 p. m. KThe Field and Staff will move from their respective stations and their commands as per special instructions. The places where the detachments from the First Regiments will join these special trains will be hereafter designated. The transportation requests will be forwarded from this office direct to the company commanders at their home stations. IV. Baggage car will be furnished with each train for the com - missary department, with range and conveniences for cooklag coffee. Travel rations will be issued from Grand Island and Omaha on train en route. Two coaches will be provided for each company and a stand - ard sleeper for the officers of the regiment. tV. The khaki uniform will be worn enroute; blue uniforms will iken with the company property, except the cap which will not be ed. Officers will take both dress and service uniforms and pro - themselves with cots, blankets, toilet articles and stationery, nted officers will procure their, own mounts for which transportation be furnished. Blanket roll, including shelter tent, will be made ccordance with instructions in General Order 41. Under clothing be included in this roll unless barrack bags are supplied. tVI. The following instructions for the wearing of equipments be observed: Blanket rolls, from the left shoulder: haversacks i the right shoulder to the left side and in the rear of the hip, ) under web belt; canteen from the left shoulder to the right side, strap under web belt; poncho folded white side out to the size of 24 inches, then hung over the web belt under the haversack; tin buckled in fastener at bottom of haversack; campaign hats creased i the back along the middle, and must not be marked, mutilated or sed into any other shape; insigna of arm of service attached to front VII. Each organization will bring its own camp equipage, cooking outfits and company records which should include a complete file of general orders, current series, from the War department, the Depart - ment of the Missouri, these headquarters, and circulars and orders from the headquarters of Provisional Division, Camp Sanger. Each man should bring two suits of heavy underwear, straw for bedding will be issued at camp, but bed sacks will be brought if practicable. The field allowance of baggage as fixed in Army Regulations and Orders will not be exceeded. Forage will not be supplied to horses, but can be pur- </seg>
            <seg id="p152">151 chased from the depot quartermaster at the maneuver camp at con - tract rates. Enlisted men will not be allowed to transport trunks, etc., their bedding and extra clothing should be neatly rolled and packed. Each company should take fifteen wash basins. VIII. Company property must be transported through as bag - gage, in charge of quartermaster sergeant or special detail (company commanders will see that arrangements are made with the railroad agents for this purpose), and all baggage should be plainly marked with the company and regiment and compactly stored in the car. Com - pany commanders will carefully inspect their commands before en - training, as no ammunition will be taken by companies or men. IX. Troops will draw rations on properly made out ration returns on arriving in camp, which will be issued in bulk to the regimental commissary by the chief commissary. Extra rations in excess of those provided by the United States will be at the expense of those purch them. All travel rations will be accounted for on arriving at camp. Blank returns will be furnished each company before starting for camp. These returns must be carefully prepared ready to be turned in to the regimental commissary for consolidation and approval by tka regi - mental commanders enroute. tX. The entraining and detraining of troops will be considered as of the exercises, and reports thereon will be rendered by the corn - ding officers of all separate commands to the Adjutant General, isional Division. In this connection, attention is invited to paragraph 144 to 151 of "Troops in Campaign" and paragraph 1206 of the Army Regula - tions. The commanding officer will report the time of departure of the separate trains, also the designation of the commands, the number of officers, men and horses, and the probable time of arrival at camp, by wire to the Chief Quartermaster, Provisional Division, as soon as the train is ready to start from Beatrice. XI. The United States will pay per diem of the regular army to enlisted men according to rank from the time of departure from home stations until their return and the state of Nebraska will pay enlisted men the difference between the per diem of the regular army and the per diem as established by state law for the N. N. G. I XII. Company commanders will be required while In camp to e four pay rolls on U. S. blanks and three pay rolls on the blanks for the Nebraska National Guard. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General </seg>
            <seg id="p153">152 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office Lincoln, October 5, 1903. No. 43. »The following regimental staff officers having been selected and &gt;inted by Colonel J. W. McDonnell commanding the second regi - t of infantry, Nebraska National Guard, and said appointments hav - been approved by the Governor. I Private Elwin E. Culver, Troop "A," as regimental quartermaster, the rank of Captain. Private Culver is hereby honorably dig - ged to accept promotion. I Sergeant Leonard E. Hurtz, Company "F," Second Regiment, as nental commissary, with the rank of Captain. Sergeant Hurtz is by honorably discharged to accept promotion. Said officers will take rank from September 20, 1903, and will be obeyed and respected accordingly. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. K There were 166 Special Orders issued for the year 1903, covering harges, and subjects special to Companies, or Individuals. </seg>
            <seg id="p154">GENERAL ORDERS FOR 1904 </seg>
            <seg id="p155"/>
            <seg id="p156">155 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, .T;mn • General Ordei No. 1. General Victor Vifquain. who in 1S91-2, died on January 7th Adjutai: il of this '. having been in failing health result of disease contracted in the for the past two years, largely the service of his country. General Vifquain was born in Brussels, Belgium At an early age he entered the Imperial School of Polytechnics to pre - pare for the naval service. At the age of 1C&gt; h&lt; where he remained two years, returning to Belgium to continw study of his chosen profession. He was graduated two In as second lieutenant of cavalry. He remained in service but one year, coming back to the United States and settling on a homestead on the West Blue in Saline county, Nebraska. In 18G1 rumors of the n;r peril reached his ears. He responded with alacrity, gotaj York. He enlisted as a private ! i company "C," 63rd N. Y. Ini participated In Newborn campaign, and rose to the rank of flr&gt; ant and adjutant. At the expiration of his term of enlistment Secretary Stanton recommended him to Governor Yates of Illinois who on July commissioned him as first lieutenant and adjutant of the Illinois Infantry. He was twice promoted on the field of battle. His promotions, owing to his bravery and ability were rapid, and he ad - vanced to major, lieutenant colonel, colonel and brevet brigadier gen - eral. Congress recognized his merits by voting him two medals of h- At the close of the Rebellion he returned to the pursuits of civil I Nebraska. tin 1886 he was appointed by President Cleveland a - aranquilla and Colon, South America and in ■ral to represent the United States at Panama, which position he I with great credit until 1897. When the Third Nebraska was recruited ii mish- American War, General Vifquain, although suffering from his former service, again volunteered, receiving a commission as lieutenant colonel, and returning to his home as Commander of the regiment, with the rank of Colonel. General Vifquain's life during the last half century has been identi - fied with the state of Nebraska. He subordinated party and other affiliations to the service of his adopted country. His unswerving loyalty presents a worthy example to the national guardsmen. As a mark of respect to his memory, company armories will be draped in mourning for the next thirty days. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER. </seg>
            <seg id="p157">156 rdquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, February 6,1904. General Orders, No. 2. KA Board of Survey will convene in the Adjutant General's office incoln, Nebraska, at 2 o'clock p. m. on February 10th, 1904, for purpose of passing on the serviceability of government military erty and fixing the responsibility for the loss of or damage to same. The Board is authorized to sit at the following named places at such times as are most convenient. Wisner, York, Stanton, Beatrice, Weeping Water, Wilber, Madison, Geneva, Nelson, Wahoo, Columbus, Omaha, Broken Bow, Osceola, St. Paul, Kearney, Nebraska City, Fairbury, Tekamah, Lincoln, Aurora, Schuyler, Norfolk, Albion, Seward, Wymore, West Point, South Omaha, Fremont. Detail for the Board: Major Warren R. McLaughlin, President; Major Ernest H. Phelps Member; Captain George A. Eberly, Recorder. Compensation for such services will be determined by the Military Travel and hotel expenses are necessary for the public service. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office. Lincoln, February 7, 1904. General Orders, No. 2Vt. N In accordance with Circular number 9, War Department, series of 1903, a Board of Inspection will convene at 2:00 p. m., February 10, 1904, at the Adjutant General's office, Lincoln, Nebraka, for the pur - pose of examining unserviceable and unsuitable public property, as pro - vided for in section 4 in the Act of February 12, 1887, and section 7 of the above named circular. I The detail for the Board of Inspection shall consist of Major Warren McLaughlin, President; Major Ernest H. Phelps, member; Captain irge A. Eberly, Recorder. The board is authorized to sit at the following named places: Wisner, York, Stanton, Beatrice, Weeping Water, Wilber, Madison, Geneva, Nelson, Wahoo, Columbus, Omaha, Broken Bow, Osceola, </seg>
            <seg id="p158">157 Schuyler, Norfolk, Albion, Seward, Wymor6, AVest Point, South Om&amp;hft, Compensation for such service shall be fixed by the Military Board. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln. February General Orders, No Upon the recommendation of Colonel C. J. Bills, Inspector Gen - eral of the Nebraska National Guard, Major Warren R. McLaughlin of the First Regiment is appointed Assistant Inspector and will proceed to inspect the various companies of the Nebraska National Guard under direction of the Adjutant General, compensation to be fixed by the Military Board. Travel and hotel expenses enjoined are necessary for public ser- By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office. Lincoln, February 20, 1904. General Orders^ No. 4. (Section 32 of article five of the rule* and regulations or the Neb - ska National Guard approved by General Order No. 5 series of 1896 hereby repealed and the following section substituted therefor. 32. Whenever the oiBce of any field officer in any organized regi - ment is vacant, or about to become vacant, the Adjutant General shall cause a written or printed order to be served on the officers of such commands calling an election to fill the vacancy, and also shall pre - side thereat. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, _ 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p159">158 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, March 2, 1904. General Orders, No. 5. II. The Annual inspection of the Nebraska National Guard under provisions of section 14 of the act of Congress, January 21, 1903, Brigadier General A. S. Daggett, (retired) will be made upon the es following: March 11, Hospital Corps, Lincoln, 7:00 p. m. March 11, Company "F" 2 reg't, Lincoln, 8:00 p. m. March 14, Company "L" 1st reg't, Omaha, 7:00 p. m. March 14, Company "G" 2nd reg't, Omaha, 8:00 p. m. March 15, Cavalry Troop, South Omaha, 7:00 p. m. March 15, Company "I" 2nd reg't, Omaha, 8:00 p. m. March 16, Company "C" 2nd reg't, Nebraska City, 8:00 p. m March 17, Company "D" 1st reg't.. Weeping Water, 8:00 p March 18, Company "E" 1st reg't, Wilber, 8:00 p. m. March 19, Company "C" 1st reg't, Beatrice, 8:00 p. m March 21, Battery "A" Wymore, 8:00 p. m. March 22, Company "D" 2nd reg't, Fairbury, S:00 p. m. March 22, Headquarters, 2nd reg't, Fairbury, 4:00 p. m March 23, Company "H" 1st reg't Nelson, 8:00 p. m. March 2 4, Company "G" 1st reg't, Geneva, 8:00 p. m. March 25, Company "A" 1st reg't, York, 8:00 p. m. March 26, Company "H" 2nd reg't, Aurora, 8:00 p. tn. March 28, Troop "A" Seward, 3:00 p. m. March 30, Company "L" 2nd reg't. Norfolk, 8:00 p. m. March 31, Company "K" 1st reg't. Madison, 8:00 p, m. March 30, Company "L" 1st reg't, Madison, 8:00 p. m. April 1, Company "M" 2nd reg't, Albion, 8:00 p. m. April 2, Company "K" 1st reg't Coluumbus, 8:00 p. m. April 4, Company "K" 2nd reg't, Schuyler, 8:00p. m. April 5, Company "B" 2nd reg't, St. Paul, 8:00 p. m. April 6, Company "M" 1st reg't, Broken Bow, 8:00 p. m. April 6, Headquarters 1st reg't, Broken Bow, 4:00 p. m. April 7, Company "A" 2nd reg't, Kearney, 8:00 p. m. April 8, Signal Corps, Fremont, 8:00 p. m. „ April 9, Company "E" 2nd reg't, Tekamah, 8:00 p. m. April 11, "West Point Rifles," West Point, 8:00 p. m. April 12, Company "B" 1st reg't, Stanton, 8:00 p. m. II. Commanding officers will assemble their companies in ac - cordance with the time indicated for the inspection, attention is called to circular No. 2 c. s. "Inspection will be made in heavy marching order." Blue uniform, forage caps and leggins. Bill. Field and staff officers residing at home stations of compan - will report in person to the inspecting officer. Company commanders will personally examine all uniforms </seg>
            <seg id="p160">159 Ere the inspection and see that they are serviceable and clean, with ons in place and polished, shoes blackened, the men cleanly shaved hair dressed. V. The armory must be in condition to pass inspection for clean - liness. Company record books, together with files of orders, and returns will be arranged so as to be submitted to the inspecting officer when called for. VI. As the standing of the Nebraska national guard at the war department for the ensuing year will be based on the favorable or un - favorable report of the inspector, it is confidently expected by this department that no effort will be spared by officers and men to make the inspection creditable in every particular. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, MarrI No. 6. The term of office of Brigadier General Patrick H. Barry and the members of his staff, consisting of Major George E. Gascoigne, Major R. Emmet Giffln, Captain John R. Quein and Captain William M. Stoner. having expired, they are honorably discharged from the service to take effect February 22, 1904. Each of the above named officers will immediately turn over to the Adjutant General any State or Government property that may have come into his possession, not previously accounted for, and take his receipt therefor. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln. March 25, 1904. General Orders, No. 7. The attention of all company commanders and officers account - able or responsible for Government and State property, is called to section 27-28 of Military Code of Nebraska, found in the Rules and Regulations governing the National Guard of Nebraska, and also in </seg>
            <seg id="p161">160 Bon 7226-7 of chapter 33 of Cobby's Annotated Statutes of Neb - a of 1903. as follows: t"Sec. 27. Commanders of regiments and companies, and all r officers who are responsible for public military property, shall ate and deliver to the adjutant general a bond payable to the State ebraska, in a sufficient sum and with sufficient sureties, to be ap - ed by the governor, conditioned for the proper care and use of public property, and the return of same, when ordered by compe - authority, in good order; ordinary wear and unavoidable loss damage ezcepted; and in case of such loss or damage, to immed - y furnish the adjutant general with properly attested affidavits, set - forth all the facts attending said loss or damage. I Sec. 23. All public military property except when in use in the ormance of military duty, shall be kept in armories, or other terly designated places of deposit; and it shall be unlawful for any on charged with the care and safety of said public property to «r the same out of his custody except as above specified; and any iber of the Nebraska National Guard who shall fail to return any lerty of the State or the United States to the armory or other place eposit, when notified by the commanding officer so to do, shall be 1 in any sum not exceeding fifty dollars ($50), to be prosecuted and scted as in other cases of misdemeanor." I The articles of war should be published to the company at least each quarter and special attention called to such articles as refer e conduct, discipline of the soldier and care of public property. This order must be read at the first assembling of the company after receipt of the same and posted conspicuously in each Armory. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General- Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, April 30, 1904. General Orders, No. 8. I Target practice will be conducted in accordance with "Special rse C" as prescribed in memorandum of small arms firing regula - s issued by the War Department February 13, 1903. I The practice season will commence May 1st and close October 31st. ges should be carefuully selected and well protected in order to re safety. k Every officer and enlisted man in the infantry will be required to ice with the magazine rifle, calibre 30; in the cavalry, with the ne ; signal corps with the revolver and rifle; members of the- </seg>
            <seg id="p162">ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S REPORT. 161 hospital corps and bands will be permitted to qualify with the maga - zine rifle. I The revolving target commonly known as the "Texas Target" is ly constructed and well adapted to the service in this state. It is ;ribed in section 390, S. A. Firing Regulations, 1S9S edition. The should be at a sufficient elevation to admit of easy drainage. tAll target practice must be under supervision of a commissioned er who will exercise great care and due diligence in the perform - ! of his duties. Monthly reports should be made in triplicate, one ' to be retained by the company commander, one to be sent to the mental commander, and one copy forwarded to the Adjutant Gen - before the fifth of eeach succeeding month. KThe new Firing Regulations will be issued as soon as pul&gt;i our requisition honored. I Company commanders are urged to make thi - a profit - one along the line of this order that the ann° ;iy be itable to the Nebraska National Guard. By Command of the Governor, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska. General Orders, No. 9 SThe 30, of May, dedicated over a 3d of a century ago by the surviv - j soldiers to the memory of their dead comrades, legalized Congress anl state legislatures, and emphasized by the patrio ta grateful country, should appeal most earnestly to the militai &gt; lizations whose members have voluntarily assumed the same obli - :ions and pledged fidelity to the same flag, with the determination to low the example to those who mourn, when duty requii- t Commanding officers of companies of the Nebraska National Guard 1 tender the services of their commands to the I' Kinder of G. A. R. at their home stations, and render such as.-, s may necessary for the propjer observance of Memorial Day, in accordance h the published order of the Commander-in-Chief and Department nmander of the Grand Army of the Republic. I The flag will be raised to half staff on the Capitol and all state ldings from sunrise to sunset on the 30th of May, in honor of the enders of our country who have answered the last roll call. By Command of the Govei J. H. t Adjutant General 9 J. H. CULVER, </seg>
            <seg id="p163">162 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, May 20, 1904. General Orders, No. 10. The following regulations are prescribed for the examination of candidates for commissions in the Nebraska National Guard: All persons appointed or elected to any grade of commissioned officers in the guard, excepting members of the Governor's staff, will be examined as to their qualifications for the position, as soon as practi cable after such election or appointment, and will not be commissioned unless having passed a satisfactory examination. Boards of Examination will consist of not lesc than three or more than seven, the organization of the same will conform to that of courts - martial, and the members will qualify by subscribing to an oath to faithfully and impartially conduct the examination of the candidates, which shall be made a part of the records. The right to challenge any member of the Board shall be accorded to each candidate for cause, and the full Board shall determine the validity of such cause, accord - ing to the procedure of courts-martial in like cases. Further instruction as to the method of procedure of the Board fh order to facilitate its work will be given as occasion requires. The examination will be under the following general heads: 1st. Character. 2nd. Physical condition. 3rd. Prefessional efficiency Oral and practical examinations will be made whenever practicable. L Assuming that an average of ten questions will be asked under head, the total value and relative weights of all subjects shall be as follows: ToUl Relative Per Value Weight Cent Administration Drill Regulations Small Arms Firing Regulations. Manual of Guard Duty 100 3 Fire Discipline. Military Law. Minor Tactics 100 3 Bttary Field Engineering ipology (For Cavalry and Artillery) 100 100 2 Total Average percent. each candidate will At the conclusion of his examination and submit a certificate in his own hand writing to the effect that 100 2 100 3 100 2 100 2 100 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p164">163 nicated or transcribed any of the customs submitted for his use during the examination. Until further orders the scope of examination as to professional efficiency will be as follows: For Second Lieutenants Administration — U. S. Army Regulations, National Guard Regu lations, General Orders and Circulars now in force. 1 Drill Regulations. — To include the school of the company, troop battery; extended order, to include company or troop, according to i of officer. Small Arms Firing Regulations. Manual of Guard Duty. Field Engineering. — Camp Expedients. FOR FIRST LIEUTENANTS. § Administration. — U. S. Army Regulations, National Guard Reg - ions, and import General Orders and Circulars now in fi making of all reports and papers required in the administration of affairs of a company. § Drill Regulations. — Same as for Second Lieutenant, including the mand of a company or troop in the battalion or squadron, close extended order. Artillery. — Mechanical maneuvers. Small Arms Firing Regulations. Manuel of Guard Duty. Military Law. — The Articles of War, the Military Code of the state; Company Courts-of-Discpline; Charges and Specifications. Minor Tactics. — Formation of Advance and Rear Guards. Field Engineering. — Camp Epedients. For Captains. t Administration. — U. S. Army Regulations, National Guard Regu - ns and important General Orders and Circulars now In force; making of all reports and papers required in the administration ■ the affairs of a company. Drill Regulations. — To include the school of the squadron of Artillery. — Mechanical maneu- batallion; close and extended order Small Arms Firing Regulations. Manual of Guard Duty. Military Law. — The Articles of War; the Military Code of the State; Practice of Courts-martial; Boards' of Survey. L Minor Tactics. — Advance Guard; Outposts; Rear Guards; Char - ristics of the Three Arms. Military Field Engineering. — Camping Expedients, For Majors and Lieutenant Colonels. Administration United States Army Regulations; National </seg>
            <seg id="p165">164 Erd Regulations, and Important General Orders and Circulars now orce. The making of all reports and papers required in the ad - istration of the affairs of regiment. I Drill Regulations. — School of the company and batallion. Close Extended Order. The command of the regiment in the brigade; monies. Small Arms Firing Regulations. IFire Discipline. — The trajectory: limit of individual fire: con - led fire; influence of ground; kind of fire; the fire unit; supply of nunition, and rapidity of fire. » Military Law. — The Articles of War; the Military Code of the te; Composition and jurisdiction of general courts-martial; practice courts-martial: the court of inquiry; summary court. Minor Tactics. — Advance Guards; Outpost; Reconnaissance; Rear Guards. I Military Field Engineering. — General Principles; hasty entrench - ts: clearing the ground; obstacles: field work: working parties; ping expedierr For Colonels and General Officers Administration. — The United States Army Reguulations; National Guard Regulations, and important General Orders and Circulars now in force; the making of all reports and papers required in the adminis - tration of the affairs of a regiment or brigade. Drill Regulations. — Formation of regiments and brigades: cere- monies. Small Arms Firing Regulations — Fire Discipline. Military Law. — The Articles of War; the Military Code of the m position and jurisdiction of general courts-martial; piv courts-martial; Summary Courts; Courts of Inquiry. t Minor Tactics. — Advance Guards; Outposts; Reconnaissance; the valry Screen; Rear Guards; Characteristics of the Three Arms; in - ltry in attack and defense: cavalry in attack and defense: and ar - lery in attack and defense. t Military Field Engineering. — General Principles, fire proje. penetration. Field geometry. Hasty entrenchments. Clearing ground. Obstacles. Field work. Working parties. Demolitions, ping Expedients. For Staff Officers Quartermaster and Commissary. Administration. — United States Army Regulations. The National Guard Regulations, and important General Orders and Circulars now in force; the making of all reports and papers required in the adminis - irallUu Oi III" ttuai. </seg>
            <seg id="p166">165 Military Law. — The Articles of War. The Miltary Code of the Military Field Engineering. — Camping Expedients. Medical Officers. I Administration. — United States Army Reguulations. The Nation- Guard Regulations, and important General Orders and Circulars r in force: the making of all reports and papers required in the ad - tistration of the affairs of the medical department. Military Law. — The Articles of War. The Military Code of the State. 1 Medical and Surgical examinatioi may be prescribed by Surgeon General. Regimental Adjutants I Administration. — The United States Army Regulations. Nation- Guard Regulations and all important General Orders and Circulars *r in force. The making of all reports and papers required in the ministration of the affairs of a company or regiment. Drill Regulations. — School of the battalion and evolutions of the regiment. Ceremonies. Manuel of Guard Duty. t Military Law. — The Articles of War. The Military Code of the te. Practice of court-martial. Minor Tactics. — Advance and Rear Guards Chaplains. k Administration. — The United States Army Regulations. National rd Regulations and important General Orders and Circulars now in Military Law. — Articles of War. The Military Code of the State. For Officers of the Signal Crops. I Administration. — Army Regplations. Nebraska National Guard gulations, State Military Code and laws relating to the Signal Corps. Oral. b Theoretical and practical knowledge of modern methods of i aling, including ability to transmit and receive messages by flag, h and heliograph. — Oral and practical. Theoretical and applied knowledge of electricity and telephony, covering (a) installation of telephones, testing for faults, ect., (bl in - stallation of permanent telegraph lines, testing for faults, etc. : ( stallation of field lines, testing for faults, etc.; (d) skill in transmis - sion and receipt of messages on telegraph lines. — Oral and practical. Proficiency in at least one foreign language. </seg>
            <seg id="p167">166 Balloons, captive and their operation in the field. — Oral. I Photography and topography, (a) topographing and reproducing scapes under field conditions; (b) map reading and field sketching, and practical. Military Law.— Oral. Courts-martial. Summary courts. Courts of inquiry. The laws of war. Civil functions and relations of the mili - tary. Instructions for the government of armies of the United States In the field. (G. O. No. 10, A. G. O. W. D., 1863, and G. O. No. 8, A. G. O. W. D, 1892.) I Any candidate who fails to obtain fifty percent in each of the writ - oral and practical examinations, will be rejected by the board as qualified to fill the position to which he has been appointed or ed. It should be borne in mind that the object of examination is to determine the actual professional efficiency of candidates for the posi - tion of commissioned officers in the National Guard. Mere cramming is not a desirable feature in examinations, and boards should so con - duct them that the qualifications of the candidate may be fully de - veloped. Special study of the following books is recommended Winthrop's or Davis' Military Law; Manuel of Courts-Martial Or - ganizations and Tactics. — Wagner; The Service of Security and In - formation. — Wagner; Catechism of Outpost Duty. — Wagner; Manual of Guard Duty U. S. A.; United States Army Regulations; Small Arms Firing Regulations. — Blunts; Manuel of Field Engineering. — Beach; Infantry Fire (Discipline) Batchelor. Any member of the National Guard having been appointed or elected a commissioned officer, who fails to report at the time ana place appointed by the Commander-in-Chief, for his examination as to his fitness for the position, shall be deemed to have declined the posi - tion to which he has been appointed or elected. By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, May 31, 1904 General Orders. No. 11 I. The Officers' School and examination announced in Circular No. 4 c. s., will convene in Representative Hall, Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebraska, at 7:30 p. m., June 20th, 1904, and will continue four days. All officers of the Nebraska National Guard will be required to attend. </seg>
            <seg id="p168">167 unless excused by the Adjutant General on surgeon's certificate o/ serious illness of himself or any member of his fain. II. Officers attending the school and examination will be fur - nished transportation from their home station to Lincoln and return and 'will receive pay at the rate of $3.00 per day for the time actually In attendance, which is designed to cover the necessary expeii III. The school will be under the immediate supervision of Brig - adier General A. S. Daggett, U. S. A., retired, and lectures on impor - tant subjects under consideration will be delivered by competent officers front the General Staff and Regular Army. IV. The examination of candidates for commission will take place on the last two days of the session and will be conducted in com - pliance with section 24, chapter 56, of the compiled statutes of Ne - braska, and in acordance with General Order No. 10, c. s., with modifications as may be prescribed by the Adjutant General. V. The Board of Examination will consist of Brigadier General J. H. Culver, Colonel C. D. Evans, Lieutenant Colonel F. J. Bolshaw, Major J. C. Hartigan, Captain J. J. Grimm, Captain H. J. Paul, and Cap - tain Charles Smrha, jr., who will report at the Adjutant General's office at 10:00 a. m., Tuesday, June 2Ht. The members of this board shall be allowed such compensation for their services as may be by the Military Board. &gt;VI. The following officers of the Nebraska National Guard ort. for examination to the President of the Board of Examination 10:30 a. m., June 21, 1904: First Regiment. Colonel V. Claris Talbot, Lieut. Col. Joseph A. Storch, Major Warren R. McLaughlin, Major Charles M. Richards, Major Ga»rge Lyon, Jr., Major Willis E. Talbot, Captain William R. Brooks, Captain Arundle M. Hull, Captain Orien W. Fifer, Captain James B. Hungate, Captain Edward L. Fodge, Captain Clarie D. Peebler, Captain Emil E. Placek, Captain August Wagner, Captain WMlliam E. Baehr, First Lieut. Emil C. Underburg, First Lieut. Melvin H. Giles, First Lieut. Emory B. DeWolf, First Lieut. John H. Linton First Lieut.Samuel E. Esh, </seg>
            <seg id="p169">168 First Lieut. Otto K. Hagel, First Lieut. William G Browne, First Lieut. William H. Osborne, Second Lieut. Charles A. Calkins, Second Lieut Ernest H. Stoner, Second Lieut Charles E. Frazer, Second Lieut. Nathaniel L. Moore, Second Lieut. Fred C. Gibbs, Second Lieut. Harley L. Dussell, Second Lieut. Harry M. Primeau, Second Lieut. Edwin C. Pickett.. Second Regiment. Major Oliver G. Osborne, Major Ernest H. Phelps, Major Clifford W. Walden, Captain Robert A. Clapp, Captain Elwin E. Culver, Captain Leonard E. Hurtz, Captain Alva S. Pinto, Captain Fred Carey, Captain Royal E. Riley, Captain William T. Linder Captain Allan D. Falconer, Captain Chester A. Fuller, First Lieut. Frank S. Nicholson, First Lieut. Clayton J. Norton, First Lieut. Jack Beason, First Lieut. Harry J. Engels, First Lieut. Charles H. Dean, First Lieut. Earl P. Hervey, First Lieut. William Z. Bales, First Lieut. Carl H. Pilger, Second Lient. Jacob, Kanzler, Second Lieut. Willard S. Paul, Second Lieut. Samuel F.. Shannon, Second Lieut. Frank Brown, Second Lieut. Joseph H. Turner, Second Lieut. Guy V. Furay, Second Lieut. James F. Hashberger, Second Lieut. Arthur S. Hardy, Second Lieut. Anton Henriksen. West Point Rifles Captain James C. Elliott, First Lieut. Arthur G. Sexton, Signal Corps. Captain John R. Henry, </seg>
            <seg id="p170">169 First Lieut. Fred H. Richards, Second Lieut. Zach M.. Marr. Hospital Corps. Captain John M. Birkner, First Lieut. E. .Arthur Carr, Second Lieut. George E. Spear.. The Service Uniform will be worn without Side Arms By Command of the Governor: J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office. Lincoln. June 1. General Orders. No. 12. K Permission is hereby granted to National Guard organization several States and Territories of the United States to enter and through the state of Nebraska, armed and equipped, but without nition, enroute to and return from the Louisiana Purehas* ion at St. Louis, Missouri, from June 1st to November 30th, 1904. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, June 20. No. 13. I Major J. C. Hartigan is hereby relieved from duty on the 1 xamination as provided in General Orders No. 11. and Captain F. tack is detailed to fill the vacancy thus created. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General Headquarters Nebraska National ('■ Adjutant General's Office, Lineocln, June 30, 1904 General Orders, No. 14. I. The resignation of Colonel V. Claris Talbot, first iafai </seg>
            <seg id="p171">170 discharged from the military service of the State to take effect June 30, 1904. II. Major Willis E. Talbot, Surgeon; Captain James B. Hungate, Assistant Surgeon, Captain Orien W. Fifer, Chaplain; Captain Arundle M. Hull, Quartermaster, Captain William R. Brooks, Commis - sary, and Lieutenant Emil C. Underburg, 2nd Assistant Surgeon, are honorably discharged by reason of expiration of term of service, due to resignation of Colonel V. Claris Talbot, to take effect June 30, 1904. I III. Lieutenant Colonel Joseph A. Storch will take command of First Regiment until the election of Colonel of the said regiment :ld and such election is approved by the Governor. I IV. In accordance with the provisions of the military code of the , an election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy in the office of el of the first regiment of infantry, vice Talbot, resigned. V. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward proper bal - lots to the commissoned officers of the first infantry regiment for their use in the election ordered in the preceding paragraph. These ballots Indicating the officers' choice of person for apointment to such office will be signed by the officer voting and returned to the Adjutant Gen - eral's office on .or before 4:00 p. m., Friday, July 15, 1904. iVI. A Board of Officers to consist of the Adjutant General, Colonel W. McDonnell, commanding second regiment, and Major Oliver G. 3orne of the second regiment, will convene in the Adjutant Gen - ,1's office at 4:00 o'clock p. m., Friday, July 15, 1904 for the purpose canvassing and recording the votes at such election. No vote will received or recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said ard. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, July 9, 1904. General Orders, No. 15. I. The Board of Officers convened under general order number 11, c. s., for the purpose of examining officers as to their qualifications for commissions in the Nebraska National Guard, having reported that the following officers passed a satisfactory examination, and recom - mended that they be commissioned, the report and recommendations of said Board is hereby approved, and the said officers are commiss - ioned, viz: </seg>
            <seg id="p172">171 Surgeon FIRST REGIMENT. V. Claris Talbot. Colonel, Joseph A. Storch, Lieutenant, Colonel, Charles M. Richards, Major, George Lyon, Jr., Major, William R. Brooks, Captain, Commissary, Arundle M. Hull,, Captain Quartern Orin W. Fifer, Captain, Chaplain. James B. Hungate, Captain Edward L. Fodge, Captain, eon. Clare D. Peebler, Captain, August Wagner, Captain. William E. Baehr, Captain, Melvin H. Guiles, First Lieutenant, Emory B. DeWolf. First Lieutenant, John H. Linton, First Lieutenant, Samuel E. Esh, First Lieutenant, Otto K. Hagel, First Lieutenant, Charles A. Calkins, Second Lieutenant, Ernest H. Stoner, Second Lieutenant, Charles E. Fraser, Second Lieutenant, Nathaniel L. Moore, Second Lieutenant, Harley L. Dussell, Second Lieutenant, Edwin C. Pickett, Second Lieutenant. SECOND REGIMENT. Oliver G. Osborne, Major, Ernest H. Phelps. Major, Clifford W. Walden, Major, Surgeon, Elwin E. Culver, Captain, Quartermaster Leonard E. Hurtz, Captain, Commissary, Alva S. Pinto, Captain, 1st Asst. Surgeon, William T. Linder, Captain, Frank S. Nicholson, First Lieutenant, 2nd Charles H. Dean, First Lieutenant, Anton Henriksen, First Lieu-tenant, Myrl S. Mather, Second Lieutenant, Jacob Kanzler, Second Lieutenant, Willard S. Paul, Second Lieutenant, Samuel F. Shannon, Second Lieutenant, Joseph H. Turner, Second Lieutenant, James F. Hashberger, Second Lieutenant, Asst \L CORPS. J. Rex Henry, Captain, Fred H. Richards, First Lieutenant. </seg>
            <seg id="p173">172 HOSPITAL CORPS John M. Birkner, Captain, E. Arthur Carr. First Lieutenant, George E. Spear, Second Lieutenant, II. The said Board of Examination, having reported that First Lieutenant William Z. Bales, second regiment, failed to pass a satis - factory examination, and recommended that he be discharged, the re - port and recommendation are hereby approved, and First Lieutenant Bales is honorably discharged, to take effect from date of this order. III. The following named officers not having reported for exam - ination to said board, in compliance with general order number 11, c. 8., and having failed to render good and sufficient excuse, for their absence, upon recommendation of the Board of Examination, they are hereby discharged from the service, to take effect from the date of this order: » Captain Royal E. Riley and Second Lieutenant Frank Brown, sec - regiment; Second Lieutenant Fred C. Gibbs and Second Lieuten- Harry M. Primean, first regiment. IV. The following officers ordered to appear before said Board of Examination under general order number 11, c. a., were excused from taking the examination at the time designated, upon good cause chown, subject to an examination to be ordered hereafter, before being com - missioned, viz: Major Warren R. McLaughlin, First Regiment Major Willis E. Talbot, First Regiment, Captain Emil E. Placek, First Regiment, 1st Lieut. Emil C. Underburg, First Regiment 1st Lieut. William G. Browne, First Regiment 1st Lie«t. William H. Osborne, First Regiment Captain Allan D. Falconer, Second Regiment, Captain Fred Carey, Second Regiment, Captain Robert A. Clapp, Second Regiment, Captain Chester A. Fuller, Second Regiment, -st Lieut. Clayton J. Norton, Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Jack Beason, Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Earl C. Hervey. Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Carl H. Pilger, 1st Lieut. Harry J. Engels, Second Regiment, Captain James C. Elliott, West Point Rifles. MThe Commander-in-Chief desires to especially commend the taking the examination upon the high markings generally re - upon the various subjects, to thank the officers attending the )f instruction for the zeal and interest manifested, and to express </seg>
            <seg id="p174">173 his high appreciation for the valuable service rendered by General A. S. Daggett, t*. S. A. (Retired), as instructor. By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office. Lincoln. July No. 16. I. The election of Lieutenant Colonel Joseph A Storoh, First Nebraska Infantry Regiment, to the office of Colonel of said Regiment, is hereby approved, and Colonel Storch will take rank from Jul §11. An election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy in the office Lieutenant Colonel of the First Nebraska Infantry Regimen' utenant Colonel Storch, promoted. I III. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward proper bal - i to the commissioned officers of the First Nebraska Infantry Regl - nt, for their use in the election ordered in the preceding paragraph. zse ballots, indicating the officers' choice of person for ap the office of Lieutenant Colonel, must be returned ti utant leral's office on or before 11:30 a. m., of Tuesday, July tlV. A Board of Officers to consist of Brigadier General J. H. rer, Adjutant General: Major John C. Hartigan. Second R Captain J. Rex Henry, Signal Corps; will convene in the Adjutant eral's office at 11:30 a. m.. on Tuesday, Jul&gt; . for th. t of canvassing and recording the votes. No ballot will l&gt;. recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said el' rd. The Junior member will record the proceedings By Command of the Governor J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant Generals Office Lincoln. July 21. General Orders, No. 17. I. In compliant! statutes of Nebraska, and in accordance w </seg>
            <seg id="p175">174 Culver, Adjutant General; Lieutenant Colonel, F. J. Bolshaw, Major E. H. Phelps; Captain L. E. Hurtz and Captain J. M. Birkner, will con - vene in Representative Hall, Capitol Building, at Lincoln, Nebraska, Monday, August 8th, 1904, for the purpose of examining such officers as may be ordered before it, as to their qualifications for commissions in the Nebraska National Guard. The members of this Board will be allowed such compensation for their services as may be fixed by the Military Board. The following officers will report for examination to the Presi - t of the Board at 8 p. m., Monday, August 8th, 1904: Colonel Joseph A. Storch, First Regiment, Major Warren R. McLaughlin, First Regiment, Captain Emil E. Placek, First Regiment, 1st Lieut. Emil C. Underburg, First Regiment, 1st Lieut. William G. Browne, First Regiment, 1st Lieut. William H. Osborne, First Regiment, Captain Allen D. Falconer, Second Regiment, Captain Fred Carey, Second Regiment, Captain Robert A. Clapp, Second Regiment, Captain Chester A. Fuller, Second Regiment, Captain Edward V. Cooper, Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Clayton J. Norton, Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Jack Beason. Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Earl C. Hervey, Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Carl H. Pilger, Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. Harry J. Engels, Second Regiment, 1st Lieut. John H. Bath, Second Regiment. 2nd Lieut. Frank H. Gaylord, Second Regiment, Captain James C. Elliott, West -Point Rifles. tThe above named officers will be required to attend unless excused the adjutant general upon prompt showing of unavoidable absence, surgeons certificate of serious sickness of himself or member of his .ily. I III. Officers attending the examination will be furnished trans - ition from their home station to Lincoln and return and will receive at the rate of three dollars per day, for the time acually in at - ance which is designed to cover the necessary expenses. Service uniform without side arms will be worn. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, </seg>
            <seg id="p176">175 rral Order No. 18. tl. The following regimental staff officers have been selected and inted by Colonel Joseph A. Storch, commanding the first infantry nents, such appointments are approved and they will take rank the dates indicated and be obeyed and respected accordin- George H. Holdeman of York, to be Adjutant, with rank of Captain from July 22, 1904. Arundle M. Hull of Fremont, to be Quarterm;* h rank of Captain, from July 31, 19' Orien W. Fifer of York, to be Chaplain, with rank of d from July 31, 1903. Jamesu B. Hungate, of Weeping Water, to be First Assistan geon, with rank of Captain, from July 31, 1903. Emil C. Underburg of Stanton, to be Second Assistant Surgeon, with rank of First Lieutenant, from August 24, 19'- JII. First Lieutenant Otis E. Davis, having been recommended by nel Joseph A. Storch, commanding first infantry regiment, for posi - of Regimental Commissary, such recommendation is approved and s hereby promoted to Captain taking rank from the date of r. He is therefore relieved from further duty with company infantry regiment, and will report to the commanding officer of first regiment for duty By Command of the Governor, J. H. Cl'LVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, July 26, 1904. General Orders, No. 19. I. The election of Major Warren R. McLaughlin, First Nebraska Infantry Regiment, to the office of Lieutenant Colonel of said regiment, is hereby approved, and Lieutenant Colonel McLaughlin will take rank from July 2C, 1904. III. An election is hereby ordered to fill the vacancy in the office ajor of the First Infantry Regiment, caused by the promotion of r Warren R. McLaughlin. I III. The Adjutant General will prepare and forward proper bal - to the commissioned officers of the First Nebraska Infantry Regi - for their use in the election ordered in th prceding paragraph, e ballots, indicating the officers' choice of person for appointment </seg>
            <seg id="p177">A **i* • * \T-irK\ER A T . S REPORT. 176 to the office of Major, must be returned to the Adjutant General's office, on or before 11:45 a. m., Tuesday August 9th, 1904. IV. A Board of Officers to consist of Brigadier General J. H. Cul - ver. Adjutant General; Captain Allan D. Falconer, second regiment, and Captain Robert A. Clapp, second regiment, will convene in the Adjutant General's office at 11:45 a. m., Tuesday, August 9, 1904, for the purpose of canvassing and recording the votes. No ballot will be ved or recorded after the hour named for the meeting of said elec - tion Board. The Junior member will record the proceedings. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, July 26, 1904. Genera! Orders, No. 20. tl. In compliance with the provisions of Section 32, Chapte lpiled Statutes of Nebraska, the First and Second regiments of .ntry, Battery "A," Troop "A," West Point Rifles, Signal and Hospi- Corps, Nebraska national Guard, will engage in field and camp ser - i for instruction, commencing August 16 and closing Augu^-: 4, at David City, Nebraska. II. The Governor's staff will report at David City for duty as follows: Brigadier General, J. H. Culver, Adjutant General; Colonel George E. Jenkins, Quartermaster and Commissary General, and Col - onel Carroll D. Evans, Surgeon General, on August 15th; Colonel John A. Ehrhardt, Judge Advocate General, on August 16th; Colonel Charles J. Bills, Inspector General, and the Aides-de-Camp on August 22nd. I III. Captian Arundle M. Hull, Quartermaster, and Captain Otig Davis, Commissary, First Regiment; and Captain Elwin E. Culver, irtermaster, and Captain Leonard E. Hurtz, Commissary, Second ?iment, and the commanding officer of Company "K" First infantry iment, with his command, will report to the Adjutant General at rid City, for duty, on August 15th, 1904. I IV. Regimental, field and staff officers will move to David City the first regular or special train leaving their respective stations August 16th, 1904. tV. Requisition for transportation will be made upon the Adju - iollows: a. The Colonels of the First and Second regiments will make </seg>
            <seg id="p178">177 Kiisition for transportation for the commissioned and non- commis - ed staffs of their command. b. Field officers will make requisition direct to this office. Ic. The commanding officers of the various companies will make uisition for transportation of the officers and the men of their resp- Ive commands, on which will be entered the actual number of offl - s and men transported; the original, signed by the officer receiving transportation will be delivered to the railway agent, the duplicate ned by the officer, will be delivered to the Adjutant General's office arrival at camp. VI. The following instructions for the wearing of equipment will be observed: blanket rolls, made with the shelter tent half, from the left shoulder, haversacks from the right shoulder to the left side and in the rear of the hip, strap under web belt; canteen from left shoulder to right side, rearstrap under web belt, poncho folded white side out to size of 6 x 24 inches; then hung over the web belt under haversack; tin cup bucketed in fastener at bottom of haversack. tVII. The service uniform (which includes the khaki) with blue : will be worn. The blue uniform will be carefully stored at the e station. Each company will report at camp equipped for field ice, ranges included. VIII. Government and state inspections by designated officers will be made during the encampment, and should disclose that each enlisted man is provided with campaign hat, coat, trousers, blue shirt, and canvas leggins, shelter half, pole and pins, woolen blanket, poncho, canteen, haversack, meat can, knife, fork, spoons and tin cup. Company equipped with regulation tents, field range and prescribed cooking utensils. I Unnecessary canvas and baggage will subject the company eom - der to adverse criticism. Camp equipage will be limited to U. 8. y allowance. IIX. Company officers will be held to strict accoutability for the e and use of government property, and also for the conduct of men and from encampment; and all damage to cars or other property ough carlessness or wanton destruction will be deducted from their '. Firing from car windows at any time without proper authority 1 subject the soldier to severe discipline. Any soldier absenting lself from camp will forfeit his pay and become liable to court X. Only blank ammunition will be brought to camp and com - panies will be carefully inspected by a commissioned officer before en - training and detraining to see that no fixed ammunition or ball cart - ridges are carried by members of the command. Company commanders will make requisition for two days rations which will include traveling day, on arrival at camp. XI. No member of any of the organizations named in paragraph </seg>
            <seg id="p179">178 Kthia order will be excused from attendance at camp, except on n's Mrtlfloate of disability, or serious illness in tbeir immediate ■ By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, July 30, 1904. reral Orders, No. 20%. ■ General Order No. IS, A. G. O striking out the word "detailed series of 1903, is hereby amended in the seventh line of the second Exaph, and substituting therefor the word "appointed;" by striking he words "one chief trumpeter" in the tenth and eleventh lines Id paragraph, and inserting in lieu thereof the words "two color ants;" by striking 'out the seventh paragraph of said order, and Ling in lieu thereof the following: "The Signal Corps shall consist of one captain, one first lieutenant, on* second lieutenant, five first-class sergeants, ten sergeants, ten cor - porals, two cooks, two trumpeters, one artificer, thirty first- class pri - vates, and twenty second-class privates; an acting first sergeant and quartermaster sergeant may be selected from the first-class sergeants. Th« minimum strength of the company shall be thirty enlisted men." Said General Order is further amended by striking out the words "second class" in the fifth line of the eighth paragraph thereof. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, August 9, 1904. No. 21. &gt; The election of Captain Fred Gegner, Company "F," first Infantry regiment, to the office of Major of said regiment, is hereby approved. </seg>
            <seg id="p180">179 Headquarters Nebraska National Guard Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, August 10, 1904. General Orders No. 22. I. In compliance with General Orders Number 20, A. G. O, e. a., the officers and men of the Nebraska National Guard will proceed to the camp at David City on the dates and by the routes designated as follows: FIRST REGIMENT. Leave Arrive Co. A. York Aug. 16 12:30 p m 1:46 p m Co. B, Stanton Aug. 16 6:40 a m 11:30 p m 1:30 p m Co. C, Beatrice Aug. 16 8:00 a m Co. D, Weeping Water M P Lincoln &amp; U P Aug. 16 6:00 am 1:30 p m Co. E, Wilber 12:45 p m 6:30 pm 4:30 p m 4:30 p m Aug 16 9:11am Co. F, Madison, Aug. 16 11:33 Co. G, Geneva Aug 16 11:00 a m Co. H, Nelson Aug. 16 S:50 a m 11:30 a m 8:0» a m tK, Columbus L, Omaha 11:30 a m 4:30 p m 11:30 a m Broken Bow B &amp; M d, Wisner, C ft SECOND REGIMENT Co. A, Kearney B ft M Aug. 16 9:00 a m 4:30 p m 4:30 p m Aug. 16 11:57 Co. B. St Paul B ft M Co. C, Nebraska City B ft M Aug. 16 8:30 a m 12:45 p m 1:30 p m Co. D, Fairbury C R I ft P Line, ft U P Aug 16 8:05 a m Co. E, Tekamah B &amp; M Aug. 16 7:45 a m 11:30 a m Aug. 16 10:45 a m 12:45 p m Co. F, Lincoln B ft M Co. G, Omaha B ft M Aug. 16 8:50 a m 12:45 p m Co. H, Aurora B ft M Aug. 16 7:35 a m 12:45 p m Co. I, Omaha B ft M Aug 16 8:60 a m 12:45 p m Co. K, Schuyler U P Aug. 16 1:20 p m 6:30 p m Aug 16 6:20 a m 11:30 a m Co. L, Norfolk C ft N W Co. M, Albion U P Aug. 16 11:10 a m 6:30 p m Aug 16 8:04 a m 9:05 a m Band, Osceola U P Signal Corps, Fremont C ft N W Aug. 16 10:00 a m 11:30 a m Aug. 16 11:30 1:30 p m 1:30 p m Hospital Corps, Lincoln U P West Point Rifles, W. P. C ft N W Aug. 16 7:43 a m 11:30 a m II. Battery "A" will entrain at Wymor.9 on August 18, and laar* Co. I, Wahoo fc N W Aug. 16 7:55 a m B &amp; M Aug. 15 7:25 a m C &amp; N W Aug. 16 8.05 a m 3 &amp; M Aug. 16 10:22 a m C &amp; N W Aug. 16 7: IS </seg>
            <seg id="p181">180 by B. £ M. at 8:00 o'clock a. m., arrive at Crete at 9:32 and proceed to march by the most feasible route to David City. Troop "A" will march from Seward to David City, starting :00 a. m., August 15. ilV. Colonel George E. Jenkins, Commissary General, will report the Adjutant General's office for duty August 11th; Colonel J. W. Donnell and Colonel J. A. Storch will report at David City for duty nday evening, August 15th; Captain A. M. Hull, Quartermaster of i first regiment and Captain E. E. Culver, Quartermaster of the sec - 1 regiment, will report at David City for duty on Saturday, August h. KV. A strict compliance with General Orders number 20, c. s., and Rules and Regulations, enroute to camp is enjoined. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, August 11, 1904. General Orders, No. 23. tl. First Lieutenant Frank S. Nicholson, assistant surgeon second ment having been recommended by Colonel J. A. Storch, command - first infantry regiment, for the position of surgeon first infantry ment such recommendation is approved and he is promoted to ;eon first infantry regiment with the rank of Major, to date from ust 11, 1904. He is therefore releved from further duty with the nd infantry regiment, and will report to the commanding officer he first regiment for duty. II. Sergeant Major H. Elton Clapp, second infantry regiment hav - ing been selected and appointed by Colonel J. W. McDonnell command - ing second infantry regiment to be captain and Adjutant second regi - ment, such appointment is hereby approved and Captain Clapp will take rank from August 11, 1904. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, August 13, 1904. General Orders, No. 24. I. The Headquarters of the Nebraska National Guard will be </seg>
            <seg id="p182">181 removed to camp at David City, Nebraska, on August 15, 1904 III. The Signal and Hospital Corps are hereby assigned to the t Brigade, Nebraska National Guard, and will report to the Com - ding Officer at David City, Nebraska. till. Brigadier General, J. H. Culver, Adjutant General, will as - ne temporary command of the Brigade of the Nebraska National ard, assembled in encampment under General Orders No. 20, c. s., G. O. By Command of the Governor. J. H. CULVER Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Camp Victor Vifquain David City Nebraska. August 18, 1904. General Orders, No. 25. I. General Orders number 20 and 22, c. s., are amended as follows: L(a) Colonel C. J. Bills, Inspector General will report for duty at p Victor Vifquain on Thursday, August 18, 1904. 1(b) Troop "A" will break camp at 1:00 p. m. August 23, 1904, march to home station, reaching there at a convenient hour on nesday, August 24, 1904. III. The headquarters of the Nebraska National Guard will be re - ed from Camp Victor Vifquain, David City, Nebraska, to Lincoln, raska, on August 24, 1904. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER. Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard. Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, August 25, 1904. General Orders, No. 26 I. The board of officers convened under genera] order number 17, c.s., for the purpose of examining officers as to their qualifications for commissions in the Nebraska National Guard, having reported that the following officers passed a satisfactory examination, and recommended that they be commissioned, the report and recommendations of said Board is hereby approved and the said officers are commissioned, viz: FIRST REGIMENT. Joseph A. Storch, Colonel, Warren R. McLaughlin, Lieutenant Colonel, </seg>
            <seg id="p183">182 Emil E. Placek, Captain, Edwin C. Pickett, Captain, William G. Browne, First Lieutenant Emile C. Underburg, First Lieutenant and Asst. Surgeon. SECOND REGIMENT. Robert A. Clapp, Captain, Chester A. Fuller, Captain, Allan D. Falconer, Captain, Fred Carey, Captain, Edward V. Cooper, Captain, Earl C. Hervey, First Lieutenant, Harry J. Engles, First Lieutenant, John H. Bath, First Lieutenant, Charles R. Weeks, Second Lieutenant. BATTERY "A." Frank E. Crawford, Second Lieutenant III. The following officers ordered to appear before said Board Examination under general order number 17, c. s., were excused tn taking the examination at the time designated, upon good cause wn, subject to an examination to be ordered hereafter, before being imissioned, viz: Captain James C. Elliott, West Point Rifles, First Lieut. Jack Beason, Second Regiment, First Lieut. Carl H. Pilger, Second Regiment. I III. The Commander-in-Chief desires to especially commend the ers taking the examination, upon the high markings generally re - ed, and the interest manifested in the science of arms. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, October 17, 1904. General Orders ; No. 27. I. Guy V. Furay, of Company "G" second infantry regiment, hav - ing complied with General Order number 11 c. s., and passed a sat - isfactory examination, upon recommendation of the board, convened under said order, is commissioned as Second Lieutenant to take rank from September 21, 1903. II. First Lieutenant, Frank S'. Nicholson, surgeon first nfantry regiment, having reported for examination under General Order number </seg>
            <seg id="p184">183 ts., and passed a satisfactory examination, upon recommendation e board convened under said order, is commissioned as major to rank from August 11, 1904. JIH. The resignation of Captain Orien W. Fifer, chaplain first ntry, is hereby accepted, to take effect November 1, 1904, and Capt- Fifer is ordered honorably discharged from the military service of State of Nebraska, to take effect same date. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Headquarters Nebraska National Guard, Adjutant General's Office, Lincoln, Nebraska, November 21, I General Orders, No. 28. II. There will be issued to each infantry company three copies of Infantry Drill Regulations, 1904, which will be taken up on prop - returns. III. Company commanders will forward to this office a certificate triplicate showing the loss of any of the following named books, or it are unserviceable, for which they may be accountable: Morning Report Book, U. S. Army Regulations, "The Enlisted Man," Army Ration Issue &amp; Conversion. Manual for Courts Martial, Manual Field Engieering, Descriptive Book, 1st Serg. Roll Call, Rules &amp; Regulations N. N. G., Catechismal Drill Reg Manual for Army Cooks, Co. Book, Letters Sent, Co. Book, Letters Sent Index, Company Orders, Infantry Drill Regulations, Drill Reg. Hospital Corps, Sick Report Book, Appendix U. S. A. Regulations, Manual Board of Survey, Manual Q. M. Department, Troops in Campaign, Manual Visual Signaling, Property Book, </seg>
            <seg id="p185">184 ADj UTANT-CxlfiNifijvALi O KK"UKI. Manual of Guard Duty, Catechismal Outpost Duty, Hand Book Military Courtesy, Manual for Medical Department. Co. Book, Letters Reed Co. Book, Letters Reed., Index, Company Council, Manual of Arms, Firing Reg. for S. A. 1898. till. The new company descriptive book should be commenced January 1st, 1905, and the old descriptive book forwarded to this for safe keeping. By Command of the Governor, J. H. CULVER, Adjutant General. Elere were 100 Special Orders issued for the year 1904, covering harges, and subjects special to Companies, or individuals. </seg>
            <seg id="p186">INDEX Army Maneuvers Board of Inspection and Survev . . 5. 136 Battery A , March to Encampment, 1903 and 1904 Brigade Staff Byrne, Major Charles, U S. A.. Report as Chief Umpire, 1904 i in, Capt. M D ., U. S. A., Report of Inspection, 1903 Culver, Brig. Gen. Jacob n.. Appointed Adjutant General 107 Culver, Brig. Gen. Jacob II., Appointed Disbursing Officer 140 Dick Militia Bill .109 ett, Brig. Gen. A. S., U. S. A , Detail of Daggett. Hrig Gen. A. S., U. S A., Report of Inspection. 1904 . 53 I )istnirsing OtHcer. Appointment of 140 Encampment. 1903 ... I General Orders Covering 142. 147. 149 1st Regt. Report of Colonel ..33 2nd Re^t. Report of Colonel 41 2nd Regt. Report of Quartermaster 45 Report of Quartermaster General Report of Signal Corps . . Report of Hospital Corps, March to Report of Battery A, March to .. Report of Troop A , March to ... S2 Consolidated Reports of Cost of ... Inspection of, by Major Abner Pickering, V. S. A Encampment. 1904 General Orders Covering Report of Brigade Commander 61 Report of Battery A, March to Report of Troop A. March to Report of Major Charles Byrne, U. S. A . «5 Subsistence Stores .. ieports Ul OO </seg>
            <seg id="p187">186 Educational Institutions, Military Education in «* Examination of Officers, Regulations for Ml Examination of Officers, 1903 117, 119 Examination of Officers, 1904 166, 170, 173, 181. lsj Field &amp; Staff. 1st Regt 133, 134, 136, 137, 142, 169, 170, 173, 175, 178, 180, 181 Field &amp; SUIT, 2nd Regt . .106, Io7, 108, 116, 118, 123, 124, 141, 169 Financial Reports of Adjutant General 91 General Orders, 1903 105 General Orders, 1904 165 Governor's Staff, Discharge of, 1901 105 Governor's Staff, Appointment of. lfl03 j-_»7 Hospital Corps, March to Encampment, 1903 II Inspections, 1903 2.21,22,124,130,131 Inspection, 1904, U. S. A 53, 158 Inspector General, Report of, 1904 Insignia, for Officers, N. N. G 140 Judge Advocate General, Biennial Report of Kreps, Capt. J., D. S. A., Report of Inspection. 1903 Hi Militia List by Counties, : 904 lrtl Military Property, Value of Military Law, National low Officers' School &lt; O'Connell, Col. John J., U. S. A.. Inspection of Encampment, 1904. .5t&gt; Pershing. Capt. John J. , U. S. A., Oamp Named For 132 Pickering. Major Abner, U. S. A. Inspection of Kncampment. 1903 33 Roster of Officers 12 Surgeon General. Biennial Report of Target Practice 1(1&lt;l Troop A, March to Encampments. 1903, 1904 32. M </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>