<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00032">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00032</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  A COURSE OF STUDY FOR HOME ECONOMICS CLUBS</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebr., U. S. A. A COURSE OF STUDY FOR HOME ECONOMICS CLUBS DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION Distributed June 27, 1913. By Alice Loomis and Mrs. A. K. Davisson. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">1. Alfalfa Management. 2. Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska. 3. Testing Seed Corn. 4. Cooking and Sewing ( Boys' and (iirls' Clubs). I Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle (Boys' and Girls' Chili- &gt;. Part II.— Corn. Part III.— The Home Garden. 6. Spraying Apple Trees. 7. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. S. tare of Milk and Cream on the Farm 9. The Selection and Care of Seed Corn. 10. Organization of Nebraska Hoys' and Girls' Clubs. 11. Cooperative County Farm Demonstrators. 12. Nebraska Hoys' Potato Clubs. (Growing Potatoes.) 13. Agricultural Extension Short Courses. 14. The Climate of Nebraska. The above bulletins will be sent free to residents of Nebraska upon request to College of Agriculture or NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION, Lincoln, Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">These outlines have been prepared in answer to ntjmerous requests from women interested in Home Economics who de - sired a few suggestions which would aid them in their study of this work. Much of the literature dealing with Home EJconom - ics is either technical or inaccurate and vague or else not easily obtainable where library facilities are limited. The books given under the list of general references have been collected into a circulating library by Miss Charlotte Templeton of the Ne - braska Public Library Commission. These libraries may be obtained with no expense beyond transportation charges for periods ranging from six weeks to nine months. Communica - tions regarding a circulating library should be addressed to Miss Charlotte Templeton, Public Library Commission, Lin - coln, Nebraska. Farmers' bulletins may be obtained free, until the supply is exhausted, by writing to the Representative or Senator in Con - gress from your district. Other government publications may be obtained by sending the necessary price in coin or post office money order (not in stamps) to the Superintendent of Docu - ments, Washington, D. C. The places of publication of all other bulletins and pamphlets have been given. If a club so desires, Mrs. A. E. Davisson of the Extension artment will arrange to meet with the members at the first ion and give whatever help is desired in organizing or plan - \ the work. Questions regarding the work should be ad - sed to Mrs. A. E. Davisson, College of Agriculture, Lincoln, raska. Suggestions regarding this outline or other work is desired will be appreciated and will aid the Extension artment in fulfilling its aim of usefulness in the State. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 OUTLINES OF LKSSONS IN HOME ECONOMICS FOR USE IN WOMEN'S CLUBS. Lesson I, Balanced Rations for the Family. Roll-call. Current events given in one-minute talk. 1. The five food principles, — a five-minute talk. 2. Protein foods and their cookerv. 3. Carbohydrates. 4. Balanced meals for a day. References. "Principles of Nutrition and Nutritive Value of Food." Farmers' Bulletin No. 142. rnning and Serving Meals." Home Economics Circular No. 1. Second edition Agricultural Extension Dept., Iowa State College of Agriculture, Ames, Iowa. "Chemistry of Food and Nutrition." — Sherman. "Lessons in Cooking through the Preparation of Meals. Questions for Discussion. rame four foods which are important because of their pro - tein, carbohydrate, cellulose, fat and mineral salts, respect - ively. 2. State a menu which is too rich in protein foods. 3. Make this into a well balanced menu by substituting fat and carbohydrate foods for a part of the protein. Lesson II. Food Preservation Roll-call. One-minute suggestions regarding preservation of any food. 1. Canning and preserving of fruit. 2. Canning and preserving of eggs. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 3. Jelly-making. Panning of vegetables ickling and pickles. References. "Canning Vegetables in the Home." Farmers' Bulletin No. 359. »ining Fruits. Preserves and Jellies." Farmers' Bulletin Xo. 203. "Infection and Preservation of F.ggs." Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 55. Storrs. Conn. Questions for Discussion rompare the quality and cost of food canned at home and in factories. 2. What are the objections to the use of chemical preservati 3. Explain the necessity for observing the five rules of canning. i . — e» --.- — — p,. 1. Fruit or vegetables must be sound and well developed — neither over ripe nor under ripe. 2. It must be fresh and unbruised. 3. No metal must be used which is readily attacked by acids in the fruit. 4. Food and container must be completely sterilized 5. Jars must be sealed at once and thoroughly so that n organisms can enter. Lesson III. Preservation and Cookery of Meats. Roll-call. Favorite Meat Dishes. 1. Cuts of meat. K reparation of sausage, head-cheese, and similar (pods ooking of the cheap cuts of meat. 4. Use of left-over meats. References. tlative economy, composition and nutritive value of the var - ious cuts of beef." Bulletin No. 158. Uni. of 111. Agri - cultural Experiment Station, Urbana, Illinois. "Economical use of meat in the home." Farmers' Bulletin No 391. "Mutton and its value in the diet." Farmers' Bulletin No. 526, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 ■at on the Farm; Butchering. Curing and Keeping." Farm - er-' Bulletin No. 183. Questions for Discussion. 1. Why should there be a variety in the preparation of meat dishes? 2. State the methods of preparation best adapted to the differ - ent cuts of meat. v Compare the cost and food value of the different cuts of meat. Lesson IV. House Sanitation Roll-call. Favorite quotation. Music or recitation. 1. Insect pests, ants, flies, cockroaches and mosquitoe 2. Ventilation. 3. Disposal of liquid wastes and garbage. References. Hygiene and Public Health." Parker and Kenwood t\v Insects Affect Health in Rural Districts." Farmers' Bui letin No. 155. "House Flies." Farmers' Bulletin No. 459. "Wastes and Their Disposal." Booklet. Health-Education League. 8 Beacon St., Room 36. Boston, Mass. (4c.) »dern Conveniences for the Farm Home." Farmers' Bulle - tin No. 270. Questions for Discussion 1. In what ways may the garbage become a source of danger to the health of the communitv? ttate the means which are best adapted to your community for the disposal of all kinds of household wastes. 3. What insect pests are most troublesome in your community and what means are you employing to eliminate them? Lesson V. Home Dressmaking. Roll-call. One-minute description of former periods. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Bmple clothing for the school-girl, ire of clothing. References. fling. Some Fundamental and Fancy Stitches." Cour-c 5. Circular 22. School Section of Extension Department of the Iowa College of Agriculture, Ames, Iowa. ■'Sow ing. ( irnamental Stitches." Circular 24. Same as above. Questions for Discussion. 1. What are the essential points in the choice of a baby's ward - robe ? Lesson VI I Selection of Cotton. Woolen, and Silk Materials oil-call. Mistakes I have made in buying cloth, or recitation. 1. Quality in woolen goods. 2. Purchasing linen. Selection of silks, olor combinations. References. Color charts sent out by Ladies Home Journal, Curtis Publish - ing Company. Philadelphia. Pa. Ints on Clothing." — Mary S. Woolman, Second Series No. 13 Teachers' College. ?2&lt; \Y. 120th Street, New York City 10c. Lesson VII. Lawns and Gardens. 6 oil-call. Favorite flower, usic or recitation. 1. The home lawn. 2. The vegetable garden. 3. Shrubs and trees for Nebraska. 4. Planting and care of flowers. References. "Lawns and Lawn Making."— F. Lawson. Scribner. Reprint </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Outline of Home Economics Clubs. from Yearbook of Dcpt of Agriculture tor 1897. "The Kitchen-Garden." Cornell Reading Course for Farmers' Wives. February 1903. Series L, No. 4. "The Home Fruit Garden." Farmers' Bulletin Xo. 1?4. Questions for Discussion. 1. What are the essentials in planning the space about the house ? ■n the arid region what can be done to beautify the home rounds? 3. What tret's, shrubs and plants are best adapted to your com munitv? Lesson VIII. Labor-saving Devices in the Home. Roll-call. Inexpensive apparatus I would not part with. Music or recitation . 1. Value of system in house work. 2. Arrangements that save steps. 3. The fireless cooker. 4. Labor-saving cooking utensils. References. "Hi •me Economics," — Maria Parloa. ft Up-to-Date Home. Labor Saving Appliances." Bulletin of the American School of Hume Economics, 606 West 69th Street. Chicago. Illinois. Questions for Discussion. 1. What materials and apparatus should be found in every cleaning closet? row can each member of the family help to lighten the housework ? ■n what other ways can the housewife's work be made lighter? Lesson IX Home Furnishing and Decoration. Boll-call. My favorite picture, usic or recitation. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Outline of Home Economics Clubs. 9 Iimple and home-made furniture, urtains and other hangings. ,'all-papers and other wait finishes, olor in home decoration. References. "Furnishing of a Modest Home," — Daniels. "The Home, Its Plan, Decoration and C'are," — Bevier Questions for Discussion. 1. What requirements should guide a person in the selection of each article in the home? ■ow can we develop in children a love of beautiful things? ow can we obtain bright, cheery effects in home furnish - ing without using large quantities of brilliant colors? Lesson X. Emergencies and Home Nursing Roll-call. Home Medicines [usic or recitation. 1. The home medicine box. B/hat to do until the doctor comes reparation of the sick room, are of patient at home. References. "Home Care of the Sick." — Pope. "The Mother's Guide." — Tweddal. Questions for Discussion. Biscuss the cleansing and care of small wounds. 'hy are patent medicines objectionable? r hy is it necessary to have a sick room very clean? ow can this be accomplished under ordinary circumstances? Lesson XI. Recreation. Roll-call. Games all children have loved. Music. 1. The value of recreation or play in the development of chil - dren. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 2. The school as a social center. References. "Games fur the Home, the Play Grand and the School." "Wider Use of the School Plant." — Perry. ('. A. Articles in magazines. Questions for Discussion. I. Arc any of the kinds of recre to objection? ;itinn in your community 2. What new forms of pleasure connmunity with profit? can be introduced into Lesson XII Home Problems. Roll-call. Current events dealing- with the home Music. 1. What the home stands for. 2. Making home attractive to the family. Question for Discussion 1. What can we do to increase the interest of our children in the home? Bancroft. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>