<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00010.00018">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00010.00018</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>
			      <sourceDesc>
			         <bibl>
			            <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION.  LINCOLN, NEBR., U. S. A., Press Bulletin No. 18, PIG FEEDING EXPERIMENT AT THE NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION.</title>
			            <date value="1903">1903</date>
			         </bibl>
			      </sourceDesc>
		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-07-18</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Laura Weakly</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Validation</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
			         <date>2007-06-15</date>
			         <respStmt>
			            <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
			         </respStmt>
			         <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-11-29-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
Agricultural Experiment Station. 

LINCOLN, NEBR., U.S.A. 

PRESS BULLETIN No. 18 

Distributed March 16, ffoj. ) 

PIG FEEDING EXPERIMENT AT THE NEBRASKA 
EXPERIMENT STATION. 

THE RELATIVE VALUE OF ALFALFA, WHEAT SH0RT8, AND 
SKIM-MILK TO SUPPLEMENT CORN FOR FATTENING PIGS. 

The object of the experiment just performed at the Kt- 
ItMka Experiment Station and described below was (1) 
to show that corn can be fed more economically in conjunction 
with foods rich in protein and mineral matter, and (2) 
to determine which of three common foods is the cheapest 
source of protein. 

PLAN OF THE EXPERIMENT 

Twenty pigs, uniform in type, all in good condition, were 
plated in four lots, five pigs in each lot. They were put on 
their experimental rations long enough to become accustomed 
to the change before the initial weighings were made. </seg>



            <seg id="p002">
Pj5 Ilia ftjs &amp; 1 Is h 
JifLrjM |ll j* | V I'J Ik.1 

Pounds. Pounds. \Pounds.\Pounds. Pounds. \Pounds. 

Lot I I 127.0 ! 206.2 78.6 .83 7.4 

Corn meal ....... 587 

Lot II 129.2 261.8 132.6 157 5.2 

Corn meal | 585.4 

Milk solids (in 1170 

pounds skim-mi.k) 110.5 

8B6.9 

Lot III 126 227.6 1101.6 1.2 5.8 

Corn meal 80 per cent 473.9 
Shorts 20 per cent 118.4 

5*2.3 

Lot IV 128.4 230 101.6 1.2 58 

Corn meal 80 per cent. 474.8 

Alfalfa 20 per cent. ... 118.7 

GS8.6 

The alfalfa fed in this experiment was in the nature of 

chaff, consisting mostly of leaves which had fallen from the 

hay as it was thrown from the mow to the barn floor for 

cattle. For the purpose of making a true comparison of 

these leaves with the whole plant an analysis was made. The 

leaves were found to be 40 per cent richer in crude protein 

than the entire plant, 30 per cent higher in fat, 15 per cent 

higher in mineral matter, and 50 per cent lower in crude 

fiber, which substance is largely indigestible matter. This 

chaff was first mixed with the corn meal, then placed in the 

feed trough, where it was made into a thick slop with water. 

The other lots were fed in the same way, except that the feed 

for Lot 2 was mixed with skim-milk instead of water. 

FINANCIAL STATEMENT, 

With the alfalfa hay worth |7 per ton, the leaves, contain 

E *% j im 4 i k . . , . b |^ 4~ — T^j^ T A T'/ \ f*£^ 1 f\ \\ * t v 111 i\ I Lf i \\ " i \ T* f 1 1 'I T"»v |T*| h \ r 1 VY) Q T^~1 1 \* </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
skim-milk used. Corn was delivered to the barns at thirty 
cents per bushel. Adding the usual rate of six cents per 
hundred for grinding, the corn meal cost |12 per ton. At 
these prices, each hundred pounds of gain in the several lots 
cost as follows: 

I he skim-milk pigs were the most hearty feeders and made 
heaviest gains, but it proved a more expensive source of 
ein at the prices quoted. 

I is experiment shows that at the market prices quoted 
in the proportions used in the experiment, skim-milk 
make corn bring four cents more per bushel, wheat 
s eight cents more, and alfalfa leaves nine cents more, 
ming that only 5 per cent of the 252,520,173 bushels of 
produced in Nebraska this year is being fed to hogs as 
agle food, these figures would go to show that over 
0,000 more wealth would be added to the state if wheat 
s or alfalfa were substituted for one-fifth of the corn 

THE SLAUGHTEU TEST 

tice corn is deficient in protein and mineral matter, we 
d naturally expect that pigs when supplied more of 
materials from other sources would have a greater pro&gt;n 
of lean meat, more blood and bone, better developed 
organs, and therefore greater bodily vigor. 

After the pigs were finished for market, one was selected 
from the alfalfa lot to represent the pigs that were supplied 
more protein. A pig twelve pounds heavier was taken from 
the corn-fed lot. These were both slaughtered and crosssections 
of the carcasses placed before the students of the 
School of Agriculture for examination. All were quick to 

Lot 1. Corn alone |4.48 

Lot 2. Corn and skim-milk 3.97 

Lot 3. Corn and shorts 3.53 

Lot 4. Corn and alfalfa 3.40</seg> 

            <seg id="p004">
Kliinner layers of fat meat. Both the pigs dressed 83.7 
snt of their live weight. The iDternal organs weighed 
lows: 

This slaughter test shows that by supplying more protein, 
iu this case by feeding alfalfa, we get a greater development 
of internal organs and more health and vigor. Undoubtedly, 
if more attention were given to supplying such foods as will 
bring about a healthy organism, losses from cholera and other 
diseases would be greatly reduced. 

The strength of the thigh bones was tested by providing 
supports at both ends, applying pressure in the middle. This 
list was made in a machine for testing strength of materials. 
The bones of the corn-fed pig measured one-sixteenth of an 
inch larger in diameter. One bone from the corn-fed pig 
broke under a pressure of 320 pounds and the other 330 
pounds. One of the bones of the corn-and-alfalfa-fed pigs 
broke at 500 pounds and the other at 520 pounds. From 
this test it is evident that breakdowns, which often occur in 
heavy corn-fed hogs, are the fault of the feed rather than 
tin- animal. It further shows that the ability of the ho&lt;j to 
stand up well on legs is a matter of density of bone rather 
than size. 

t another experiment varying quantities of alfalfa will 
I to determine the best proportion for making the most 
mical gains. 

E. A. Burnett. 

n. R. Smith. 

Com pi* *%£$?¦ 

Pounds. 

Pounds. 

intesliDaiUt.'.'.'.'.'.'.'..'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. 

.7 
l.-J 
3.4 
5.4 
5 

3.9 
5.7 
5.7 </seg>

         </p>
		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>