<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00053.00028">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00053.00028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fourteenth Annual Report of the State Fire Marshall for the Year 1922</title>
               <date value="1922-12-01">1922-12-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-13</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">STATE OF NEBRASKA Department of Trade and Commerce DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Fourteenth Annual Report OF THE State Fire Marshal For the Year 1922 State Fire Marshal --Deputy Fire Marshal C. E. Hartford L. J. Butcher. E. E. Hayduk- F. F. Dowling. Inspector Inspector W. B. Anderson (part time)__ O. W. Rhoads, (part time) Inspector Inspector Blanche Johnston. _ Clerk and Stenographer </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">FOURTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE STATE FIRE MARSHAL OF STATE OF NEBRASKA Office of the State Fire Marshal State House, Lincoln, Nebraska. December 1st, 1922. To His Excellency, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor of the State of Nebraska: Dear Sir: In compliance with the law in this state, I herewith submit to you the fourteenth annual report of the Division of Fire Prevention. During the past year this department has used every effort to reduce the fire loss of Nebraska. We understand fire prevention is a subject which must be popularized with the people before the best possible results can be obtained. Our aim has been to so popularize the subject as one of vital im- portance to every one in the state so each individual will feel i personal responsibility in conserving life and property from iestruction by fire. First of all, by bulletins published each month on preva - causes of fire and how to prevent them, we have endeav- iken an interest in the unnecessary fire waste, and to have each community work with the end in view town take pride in having the lowest fire record a\ A total of 247 cities and towns have been thoroughly in - spected during the year. A small number of these towns have been gone over the second time. If our inspection force had been sufficient each town could have been inspected at least twice during the year and in my opinion, the more often in - spections are made, the greater the good accomplished. During the year 18,296 inspections were made and 12,330 orders issued for the correction of minor defects that appeared necessary to the inspector. The gasoline and kerosene hazard is the most deplorable of all fire dangers because in nearly every gasoline or kerosene fire, lives are destroyed. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 I A report of the work in the Division of Fire Prevention hereby respectfully submitted for your information. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. INSPECTIONS I During 1922 our regular inspectors inspected 247 towns i cities of Nebraska. We were handicapped by having to ;ak in several new men. and therefore the number of in - sctions are less than last year. Deputy J. H. Hauser re - ■ned in March, and Inspector L. J. Butcher was promoted to puty. This called for a new inspector, and Lee Carey of rk was placed in that position, working for two months en he resigned, finding the work too strenuous for a man his age. Jess Cain, of Lincoln, then took his place, and i the making of a fine Inspector, but resigned at the end two months to accept a bettt&gt;r paying position in the elec- trical wiring game, he being an old timer in that line. We then started Wm. B. Anderson ot Hildreth part of August. In September we were given permission to inci force by adding one more man, which was badly needed. Si O. W. Rhoads of Scottsbluff started to work on September lot! and was injured in an automobile accident on September 24th as was also Fire Marshal C. E. Hartford. Mr. Hartford w« rally laid up for two months and Mr. Rhoads is st to be around. FIRE CHIEFS REPORT FIRES The promptness of the fire chief in reporting fires to this tee assists us in our work of investigation and their interest ittending to many matters which we request has done much make this department a success, while the law provides a laity if fire chief or mayors where the town has no fire ef, do not report promptly to this department, every fire urring in their city or village, yet in many cases these off i - ls are not reporting fires to this office as the law provides. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 5 with i tot I yeai lisht ■t mi v ii cum till a re However, I do wish to report that we have been furnished reports of fires on 1,676 fires during 1922, aggregating tal loss of 2,140,081.12. This is a little less than the fire reported for 1921. But the number of fires reported was 195 more than last NEWS BULLETIN This office issues a news bulletin each month, giving the is of interest in connection with this work which is pub- ■d and circulated to the fire chiefs, newspapers of the state, ial agents of insurance companies, the fire insurance com - es, all the fire marshals in the U. S., and a large miscella - s list of interested parties who have requested that their s's he placed on our mailing list. At this time our mailing 1.600. While the time has been limited to prepare this bulletin, we have endeavored to compile some ach month showing the inspections made, orders issued allng the number of fires and the amount of losses, as tc. In addition to this list of the buildings complaint has l&gt;een filed in this office requesting [tensive repair, is also published which fur - to the insurance companies regarding prop - often find they have policies. We believe 01 )eople have a right to know what is being done and ved from numerous sources, we feel it is FIRES INVESTIGATED We have been called upon during the past year to make stigation of seventy-one fires, there being suspicious cir - stances in connection with these fires. In addition to the arrests made, there are many cases in the hands of the county attorneys for consideration as suit of the investigations made by this department. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 FIRE PREVENTION WEEK October 2nd to 9th, 1922 EThe week of October 2nd to 9th, 1922, was observed in braska as Fire Prevention Week. Governor Samuel It. Mc - vie caused to be issued the following proclamation : PROCLAMATION By the Governor "Having a deep interest in the welfare of the people of Nebraska, and in order to aid them in their efforts to secure the blessings of life and to preserve that which, by their in - dustry, they have accumulated, I at this time and season of the year, when great care should be taken to prevent loss by that most destructive element, fire, wish to sound a note of warning. I "Men of the fire departments of our towns and cities are ting with listening ears, ready at any moment to respond the sound of the fire alarm calling them to scenes of de - uction threatened by the devouring flames. In an hour a endid home is converted into a heap of ashes and a happy nily is transfomied into a sorrowing group, mourning the 3 of that which is most dear to them, their home. Someone i said, 'Etelnal vigilance is the price of liberty', and I may I that continued watchfulness is necessary in order to pre - it the wanton waste and loss sustained by the fury of the I "With ordinary diligence, the fire loss could be reduced e-half. Fire Prevention Week, by a majority, if not all, the States will begin on October second and continue until ; ninth. This fire waste must be reduced. The causes in st cases are preventable. The utter abandon with which xi dispose of half-smoked cigars and cigarettes is criminal, upled with the presence of inflammable material which is &gt;wed to accumulate, it is a miracle that the fire loss is not ich greater than it is, and were it not for the presence of r splendid and well organized fire departments, our losses uld be astounding. Notwithstanding the fact that our gov - lors and mayors are continually thundering their proclama- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 7 tions into the ears of the populace, destruction goes on, the red riot of the flames makes lurid the night, and the cry of the helpless rends the air. "What shall be done? Clean up! Watch the ash heap. Regard a pile of rubbish as a crouching enemy, ready to de - vour. Remove these heaps of waste as you would vipers, re - garding them as a 'pestilence that walketh in darkness and destruction that wasteth at noon-day.' Do not wait until Octo - ber second to begin. Now is the time. Clean up and keep clean. "In order that Nebraska may be in harmony with other states, I, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor, do hereby set apart and proclaim the week beginnig October second, 1922, Fire Prevention and Clean-up Week. "Given under my hand and the great seal of the State of Nebraska, this, the twelfth day of September, A. D., 1922. By the Governor (Seal of State of Nebr.) SAMUEL R. M'KELVIE, DARIUS M. AMSBERRY, Secretary of State. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">PROCLAMATION CLEAN UP, PAINT UP and BEAUTIFY, and KEEP IT UP! Know all Men, Women and Children by These Presents: I That Whereas, the National Clean Up, i*aint Up and utify Campaign has resulted in many advanl ijres to coir - utj and life throughout the United States, In Rdieveing Unemployment; In Safeguarding Health and Life ; In Promoting Thrift ; In Furthering Fire Prevention : In Stimulating Civic Pride, and In Making the Home and City Beautiful. Now, Therefore, be it known that plans should be per - fected at once if not already done) for a thorough clean-up and beautifying campaign in all the cities, towns and on the farm in this, the finest state in the union. Remember our state ranks first in having the smallest per cent of illiteracy in the United States. Therefore, let us get busy and have first honors in the list alxtve. Being an educated people can not plead ignorance as an excuse for not doing the things. We must lay the blame of carelessness and shiftle ness on the pail of nearly ninety per cent of the people. Fire Prevention is one of the most important bee this danger is eradicated, it tends to get rid of the me health and untidiness. Every individual is under as much obligation to keep his E! of occupancy free from fire hazards as he is to keep his free from disease. Fire Prevention is simply good house - ing upon a larger scale. Therefore, each and everyone is i to do their part in cleaning up their own homes and premises and seeing that every safeguard is used to prevent a fire, then if your neighbor has failed to see the light, go to him and in a nice, kind, brotherly or sisterly spirit, show him the benefit it will be to not only himself but others around him. If you will think back to the causes of the fires you know about, you will probably see that most of them would not have happened if all necessary precautions had been taken to pre - vent them. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 9 NEW FIRE EQUIPMENT We are pleased to state that 1922 has shown a big in - crease in better Fire Fighting Equipment. Motor Trucks are fast taking the place of hand drawn carts, and the Electric Siren Whistle is taking the place of the Bell and Steam Whis - tle. Scores of towns have reported to us that they have got - ten new hose, and the following places have reported that they have installed Three Phase Electric Sirens: Dodge. Hebron, West Point, Gothenburg, McCook and Wood River. The following towns have reported the purchase of trucks, 1 them being equipped with chemical tanks and some be- al m pumper type: Kearney, Schuyler, Pender, Fairbury, Herman, Western, Wymore, Potter, Odell, Table Rock, Wakefield, Fremont, Emerson and Genoa. VOLUNTEER FIRE DEPARTMENTS TAX The law passed in 1921, Section 1, S. L. Page 720. in which the City Councils in cities and boards of trustees in vil - lages having only volunteer fire departments or companies may levy a tax annually of not more than four-tenths of a mill on the actual valuation of the property within said cities for the maintenance and benefit of such fire departments or com - panies. This was a mighty good law and a number of towns in the state took advantage of it to get themselves fire fight - ing equipment. But this law should be taken advantage of by all the towns that need better fire fighting apparatus, and in this way put new spirit in their volunteer firemen. FIRE DEPARTMENTS No one can doubt the value of well equipped and well manned Fire Departments. Our cities and towns bear the cost of their establishment and upkeep because of their recog - nized value in protecting life and property. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 THEY SHOULD BE HELPED AND NOT HINDERED Firemen should be used to prevent as well as put out fires. They should, under the direction of their chief, inspect all premises, point out dangers, and have them removed. This serves the double purpose of getting acquainted with all build - ings in the city, as well as clearing them of conditions that will start and feed fires. Don't allow automobiles to park within twenty feet of fire hydrants. Don't allow vehicles to rush to fires and with people crowd and hamper the firemen in their work. Give your fire apparatus the light of way to fires. They must get there quickly but not at excessive speed. It is dan - gerous to them and to their apparatus. An accident might mean not only much damage, but a conflagration. How is the fire department in your city or town? Is it properly equipped and supported? What interest is shown in it by your city officials ? By your citizens ".' When you need it, you will need it mighty bad Your Fire Department is not a charitable institution seeking alms whereby it may equip itself to protect YOUR property, YOUR life and those of your loved ones. It is a It body of self-sacrificing, public spirited men. who stand ready to answer YOUR call in case of fire. Help them as willingly and generously as they are willing to help YOU. It is a body of men banded together to help YOU when no other power or department can do you any good. Whenever you contrib - ute a few dollars to add to the efficiency of the fire depart - ment, you are making an investment which some day may pay you enormous dividends in saving. Help the fire boys. BUILD TO PREVENT FIRES We Americans are tolerating an annual file loss of over $500,000,000 in physical property alone. Each year over 60, - 000 people are injured and over 18,000 lives are lost by fire. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DIVISION OF FIRK PRFVEN'TIOK 11 What a sensation is would create if all these injuries and deaths occurred in one great fire, or even in a dozen great fires. But they occur, usually, a few at a time, but time after time, so the result in the end is the same. The bare figures should be impressive enough to the dullest, without considering the sensational aspects ol the case. Each injury, or each death, has a personal significance to some individual or family which dwarfs the economic loss, great as that is. But the economic :epiesented bv these injuries and deaths is at least as hat due to the destruction of property. IT I losses fix fire insurance rates and in paying our in - emiums we all pay tribute to uncontrolled fire. Those have files must still help to pay for the fires of others, while those who have fires do well indeed if they are able to make good their losses by insurance. Of course there can be no adequate compensation to the man who suffers the experience of a fire in his home or place of business. Even if he is compensated for the property loss he never can be com - pensated for the trouble and anxiety experienced. The enormity of the figures given may be sensed when one reflects that the great public debt could be paid off in a few yeai.» if we could apply to it each year the money we are now burning up. Think how this would simplify the problem of taxation which is now so dif fcult for us all ! Viewed from anv angle the fire loss is a total loss and is as ruinous as it is inexcusable. Everything that can be done to lessen this loss must be done. We must have the best of fire-fighting facilities and we must also fight fire when we build — u well as afterwards. Here, as always, prevention is much better and cheaper than cure. So iar as possible we must build structures of the type which are either fire-proof or of the highest type of fire resist - ing construction, and this applies to both public and private buildings whether in city or country. The week commencing October 2nd is to be observed throughout the country as Fire Pre%ention Week. This is very good, as far as it goes, as it will serve to direct public atten- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION tion to what preventable fires are now costing. But we should have 52 fire prevention weeks each year. Engineers, architects and contractors know how to build structures that will not burn. Since their professional knowl - edge enables them to build against fire, is it not their duty to act in the public interest and to recommend and insist on fire - proof construction whenever and wherever possible? We be - lieve it is. k Finally, our fire loss has reached the proportions of a na - al scandal and disgrace. Instead of feeling sorry for our - es about it, we should be ashamed of it. FIRE SAFETY The fireman who is paid to protect life and property from fire has the inherent right, not only to put out a fire after it K5 started, but to prevent a fire if he finds someone in the act kindling a blaze, or of maintaining conditions which seem •e to result in a fire. It is not only a fireman's right, it is duty. The moral responsibility sets squarely upon the shoulders of the fire-fighters-and-more directly upon the shoulders of the man in charge of the fire department, who, in nearly every case, is the chief engineer. Years ago, it was well enough for a fire chief to sit in his quarters waiting for the bell to hit be - fore he got busy. Once started he never let go until he and his men had conquered the fire. But times have changed, and the progressive fire chief must know something about fire prevention. The more he knows of fire prevention the better fire chief does he become. Conventions of fire chiefs now devote as much attention to the subject of fire prevention as they do to the subjects of fire protection and fire extinguishment. ,In these latter days it has become the duty of every fire chief to familiarize himself with the conditions which confront his fire-fighting forces. He must know all about the buildings which he is paid to protect. How foolish, therefore, for him </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 13 to;sit idly by, waiting for the gong to call him to a fire which is possible only because neither he nor his men made any move to remedy conditions which were plainly hazardous. And the fire chief has a further duty than that which in - duces him to become familiar with buildings in his municipal - ity. It is his place to see that his subordinate also learn about such conditions as may be dangerous. It is well to start his fire prevention work within his own official family circle. This can be done in no more effective manner, than by issuing an order at once that every company in his department shall im - mediately begin the inspection of buildings. KEEP FIRES FROM STARTING" The caution which is being broadcasted is "Keep fires from starting." All fires, except those that start by explosion, are the same size at the beginnig — tiny flames that can be and should be quickly put out. Examine carefully, the chimney and stove pipes in your ome, see that metal pipes are not in contact with woodwork and that the chimney is clean before starting fire in stove or furnace. Matches, stoves, furnaces, lamps, candles, kerosene or gasoline stoves and heaters, automobiles, benzine or naptha cleaning solutions, greasy and oily waste and rags — all of these are the cause of a great many fires. Many fires result from throwing smoldering match stems or live tobacco ashes into waste baskets, where they continue to glow, and eventually ignite waste paper or cloth scraps, per - haps after everyone has left the room. Half-bumt matches, hot ashes and live cigar or cigarette stubs should always be deposited in a metal dish or tray. Putting kerosene on kindlings or in a stove when starting the fire is an exceedingly dangerous practice. Better use paper. It may take longer, but it is much safer. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION t Hundreds of fires start from placing live coals from the e or furnace in a wooden box or basket. Never remove ashes from your stove or furnace unless you have a metal in which to put them. If you use kerosene lamps, be sure that you have the safety type which will not explode when overturned. When you are using candles or open-flame gas jets, be sure that no inflammable material is within three feet overhead, or two feet from the sides. By all means be sure that there are no lace curtains or fabric shades that can be blown into the flames and become ignited. t Never attempt to refill a kerosene or gasoline stove when burning. Be sure that every burner is turned out and that e is no flame nearby. Always keep matches in a metal receptacle, far enough from the stove so that they will be quite out of danger. Some - times a box of matches will blaze up when overheated or when carelessly handled, and the effect is that of a miniature ex - plosion, and the flames easily set fire to everything within One of the most innocent causes of fire is the pile of greasy or oily rags, for oil and grease have peculiar properties which make them susceptible to spontaneous combustion. They are likely to blaze up at any time when no one is near them. perhaps in a closet or a cupboard where the blaze can get a good start before it is discovered. Always destroy such things before they have a chance to start trouble. tOne cannot be too cautious when handling benzine and ;ha. Never use them near the stove or near any flame, don't light matches until the fumes from the fluids have away. tWhen you are through with your electric flatiron. or ter, or curling iron, be sure that the current is turned off. best way to be positive is to detach the plug entirely. I If there is an open fireplace in your house, always be on alert for chance sparks that may snap out upon the floor rugs. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 15 Never leave an open fire without placing a fire screen in front of it, even though the fire may be merely a handful of embers. Not infrequently fires are started in the basement through overheated furnace flues and hot-air pipes. See to it that the rafters and all woodwork above the furnace and hot - air pipes are well covered with asbestos. A little bonfire in the back yard or alley may be the source of widespread disaster. Never start such a fire near a building or fence, or in any place where the wind can blow the flames or sparks toward buildings. And, by all means, see that the fire is completely put out, embers and all, before you leave Look out for the automobile and the garage. Fire may be started here very easily, for there are always gasoline and oils bout and oily rags and waste that are highly inflamable. Don't scratch matches in the garage. If there is no elec - c light, use a hand electric flashlight. Carelessness is the big note to destruction. Conserve our urces for the promotion of our own welfare. ATTENTION EDITORS OF NEBRASKA We fully realize the important part the newspapers play ng the public along all lines. And as there is a very g,l lit need at the present time, to get the people of the United States awakened to the terrible loss each year by fire, which statistics show eighty or ninety per cent is due to carelessness and are preventable, we are suggesting and requesting that each newspaper in the state set aside a particular space in each issue of their paper, headed, "Fire Prevention Items" and in that space run such items and articles as you wish to write, or the items from this bulletin and other papers on that most important subject. You will be doing an untold amount of good, as nine-tenths of the people are willing to cooperate when they understand the danger to themselves and their loved ones and by constantly driving the idea of Safety First rules </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 in Fire Prevention at them, they hear of things they never knew about, and they become impressed with the idea and im - mediately begin to do their part. If you know of any news - paper in the state that is not receiving this bulletin, send in the name, and it will go on our mailing list. We thank you for your cooperation, and assure you that the people will be bene - fitted and helped. Miss Eva Anderson, our Clerk and Stenographer, who has been in this office since January first. 1919, and had made her - self invaluable, knowing all the ins and outs of the office, re - signed on September 9th to take up a course of study in the State University. I Miss Anderson was an enthusiastic Fire Preventionist and several occasions had read a paper on Womens' part in Fire •vention. Twice she has appeared before the Nebraska State Volunteer Firemen's Association in Convention, and was elect - ed as an Honorary Member. Miss Eva was loved and admired by everyone that kne Eand this Department while feeling her loss are pleased i w that she is taking a higher course of study, in order 1 &gt;me even more proficient in the business world. Mrs. Blanche Johnston, a very proficient and able young woman, took up Miss Anderson's duties and is going ahead with them very nicely. Words of Appreciation For the splendid aid and cooperation that the Division of Fire Prevention has received from the fire chiefs as well as members of the fire department, the district attorneys, sheriffs, and from all fire prevention organizations in the in - terest of the elimination of fire hazards and the investigation of incendiary fire, I wish to express my sincere appreciation. Also, to Governor, Samuel R. McKelvie, and Secretary of Trade and Commerce, J. E. Hart, who have assisted us in this work, I wish to express my thanks. Very respectfully. C. E. HARTFORD, State Fire Marshal. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 17 NORFOLK CONVENTION The 40th annual state convention of the Nebraska State Volunteer Firemen's Association was held at Norfolk, January he 17th, 18th and 19th, 1922, and it was the largest conven held in the point of delegates registered, and num tior tier of visitors recorded. The following exceipts from the report of Chaplain Rev. and Walter C. Rundin, of Mitchell, will give some idea of the nstructions the Firemen received to take back to their tive departments. 'Tuesday evening was given over to addresses of wel - by officials of Norfolk and responses by officials of the state association. At 9 p. m. the annual Memorial service for departed brothers was held. The service was in charge of Mr. Mike Sandm and was very impressive. The Memorial address by the state Chaplain, Rev. Walter C. Rundin. Wednesday morning was devoted to business and Mutual The session was very interesting and the reports of the Aid Society most gratifying. About 75 new members red during the morning hour. Last year three broth - d r.nd their loved ones were immediately handed checks paving funeral expense. Every volunteer fireman age of 40 should belong to this society. Wednesday afternoon and Thursday morning Mr. Leon L. Wolf of Cincinnati, Ohio, gave us instructions and demonstra - tions in the matter of becoming more efficient fire fighters. His work alone was worth the price of coming to the conven - tion M he gave us such a wealth of practical suggestions and information that will aid us to become more proficient in our tasks. The only regrettable feature was the inclement weath - er, or rather cold weather, thus preventing Mr. Wolf from giving us out-door demonstrations. The splendid showing made by the state fire warden and his assistants was appreciated by all present. Mr. Hartford again this year had literature of all kinds relative to fire pre - vention ready for free distribution. His first assistant, Mr. Hauser, was ever ready to answer questions, as were the vari- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION ous state fire inspectors. Wednesday afternoon Miss Eva An - derson of the state division of fire prevention, read a very fin* paper which was enjoyed. The annual report of State Firt Warden, C. E. Hartford, was great, and he is to lie compliment - ed for such a strong and accurate report. The moving pictu &gt;•?&gt; thrown on the screen the first evening of the convention prov- t mighty popular. For this fine service we are indebted tr . Hartford. Every city in the state should be eriven tht privilege of exhibiting these films; and every fire iepvtlM should see that they are exhibited, and that they are run di ing the day and the school children be allowed to attend, the educational lesson to be derived from these films canr be measured in dollars and cents. In the way of entertainment, we must admit the ci1 Norfolk and its fir? department did all they could to makt stay pleasant. The second evening all firemen were invit* r.ttend a free show at the auditorium followed by a sin &gt;ki and Dutch lunch. All firemen seemed pleased because e tainment and lunch were both up to "snuff." Thursday e\&gt; was the big banquet with approximately 850 men waftf the tables. It was a splendid banquet served by the Rel&gt;el The service was prompt and it elicited much praise ; the was excellent and this, too, brought forth appreciation all the guests. The principal speaker was Go\ S. R. } Kelvie. an honorary member of the N. S. V. F. A. His ad was along lines of work hoped to be accomplished by special session of legislature. He gave us a very stronj hopeful message, full of optimism and good cheer. A Conclusion of his address he was given generous applau.- The following is a paragraph from the letter of Mr. Martin, President of the State Association, written foi Bulletin : "The Norfolk boys certainly did themselves proud in en - tertaining the convention. There was no time during the whole convention that the town wasn't ours for the asking, and Oh, Boy! what a banquet and program with the governor as the principal speaker. We certainly appreciated their hos - pitality. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 19 "The good work of the state fire marshal and his assist - ants is more in evidence each year. Last year at York we had a splendid exhibit, and instructive literature from their office, but this year their work was par excellent, and I hope the coming year the State Association will give them a closer OO - operation even than we have heretofore had. They are doing great work for us. and we should show our appreciation by giving our best support in return." KIRK CHIEFS OF THE STATE ORGANIZE AT NORFOLK During the second day session of the 40th annual con - ion of the Nebraska State Volunteer Firemen's convention. State Fire Marshal Hartford, succeeded in organizing a state association of fire chiefs, with a membership of over 100. This association is to meet each year with the state association. Addresses by Fire Marshal Hartford, H. J. Hauser, and L. L. YYolt, athletic di lector of the Cincinnati Fire Department, took up most of the day's program. "There is no department of a city government that is of more vital importance to the com - munity than the fire department," stated Mr. Wolf. The officers of the new chief's organization elected were )lk&gt;ws • C. E. Hartford. President, Lincoln. H. L. Boyce. Vice President, Hebron. H. J. Hauser, Secretary, Fremont. F. B. Tobin, Treasurer, Sidney. LEON L. WOLF. CINCINNATI. OHIO. Leon L. Wolf, physical director of the Cincinnati fire de« partment and a member of the National Board of Fire Under - writers, in his address to the N. S. V. F. A. at Norfolk, Nebr., said one of the things most needed by the cities throughout the country is more liberal support for their fire departments, and less political interference with their activities. There is no department of a city government that is of more importance to the community than the fire department. He also wants to see a school of instniction for fire chiefs in Nebraska start - ed. Mr. Hartford, State Fire Marshal of this state also says </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 that Nebraska needs a fire school. Mr. Wolf is one of the leading authorities in the United States on questions of med - dei-n fire fighting and rescue work. He is known to the fire chiefs and firemen from coast to coast. We hope to have him with us again at North Platte in 1923. 1923 Convention to be Held at North Platte January 16th 17th and ISth. 192:5. tThe 1923 convention of the Nebraska State Volunteer imen's Association will be held at North Platte this year we predict a great meeting, a.s the officers of the organiza - have been working hard to have an interesting and in - ictive meeting. It is not known at this time whether or this office will participate, on account of the change of ad - istration. but. we feel that the meeting of the Fire Marshal his inspectors, for the last two years, with the Fii^emen at r convention, has brought them closer together in their duties of preventing and fighting fires than EDUCATION A I. WORK Fire Prevention Lectures and Addresses Delivered During 1922. I On January 17th, 18th and 19th. C. E. Hartford, the State e Marshal, his Deputy and Inspectors attended the Nebras- State Volunteer Firemen's Association, at Norfolk. They on a fine display of fire photographs, also put out a lot of e Prevention Literature, furnished by different societies. Hartford was instrumental in getting Leon L. Wolf of cinnati. Ohio, to address the convention and to demon - ite the up-to-date methods of Fire Fighting. Mr. Hartford e an address before the convention, also to the schools in nected with the Fire Films. The Films used at Norfolk the other towns in his lecture were "The Danger that rer Sleeps," "The Women Fire Fighters," "The Locked &gt;r," "The Unbeliever Convinced." "Fox Fire News Reel" I "Dow Spiral Fire Escape Reel". These films were shown ler the auspices of the five departments in the following </seg>
            <seg id="p021">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 21 towns to the schools in the afternoon and to the general pub - lic in the evenings, Mr. Hartford giving a short talk on fire prevention at each meeting: Newman Grove, February 14th, Central City, Febi-uary 22nd, Scottsbluff, March 21st, Gering. March 22nd, Sidney, March 23rd, Lexington, March 27th, Minden. March 2Hth. Beatrice, April 10th, Tecumseh, April 11th. Syracuse. April 12th, Nebraska City, April 13th, Platts- nouth, April 14th. Butte. May 8th, Spencer, May 9th, Bris - ow. May loth. Lynch, May 11th, and Hampton, May 12th. Many other towns were clamouring to have the lecture i films put on in their towns, but owing to shortage of ds and help. Mr. Hartford was ordered to discontinue this tional work. Other addresses made by him during the year were as us : At Hastings. February 23rd, to Delegates of Nebras- a Association of Mutual Insurance Companies, University Mace. April 26th. to the Firemens' Annual Banquet, Lincoln, f :&gt;rd to the Pathfinder Club, David City, May 4th, to the ?men and Commercial Club Rally, Central City, September l.°,th to the Commercial Clubs, Ashland, October 20th to the Fire Department, Commercial Club and Citizens, at a get to- gether meeting, which resulted in a great good. The City Council got busy and ordered more equipment for the firemen. The following letters received will show the sentiment in regard to the lectures and films, dozens other than these quot - ed having been received: •'Scottsbluff, Nebr., May 4, 1922. Mr. C. E. Hartford, State Fire Marshal, Lincoln, Nebr Dear Friend and Brother: I am sending you a few lines in regard to our doings out here in Scottsbluff. As you may know we were successful in getting our electrical ordinance through and we are having great success with it. There is hardly a day that we do not have a call to go and inspect some defec - tive or dangerous wiring. It seems as though the fear of fire has spread amongst the people here since you were here with your pictures on fire prevention. Even though we did not </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 fare so well financially in the evening, we are seeing the re suits of them now. At the installation of officers of our fire department, our mayor was present and gave us a fine talk in regard, to the good work of the department. But he also praised highly the good work your pictures had accomplished and also the many good comments he had heard from people that had seen the pictures. He said that he was sorry that he did not have the pleasure to see them himself. Sincerely yours, (Signed) ALBERT W. PETERSON, Fire Chief." We are in receipt of the following letters from Mitchell t Mitchell, Nebr., March 21. 1922 . C. E. Hartford. Lincoln. Nebr. Dear Mr. Hartford: tjust a few words of commendation for the wonderful ures shown us relative to fire prevention. They made a ing impression upon everyone who was privileged to view m. Your talk was also very acceptable. I feel sure you rendering a valiant service by preaching the gospel of fire mention. Would it not be possible to interest the Under - iters to the extent of having them furnish suitable films tc shown throughout our state. I feel sure such a service ild be more than repaid in the lessening of fires. Sincerely yours. (Signed) WALTER C. RINDIN. Chaplain. State Association of Nebraska Volunteer Firemen.' Mr. C. E. Hartford, Lincoln, Nebr. Dear Mr. Hartford: tl take this occasion to thank you for the excellent service did the city of Mitchell. Your pictures were a great treat the children, and the lessons were impressed in such a way t they are not liable to soon forget them. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 23 I hope that some arrangement may be made whereby this mode of teaching Fire Protection may be presented to our ;chool children often. Yours very truly, (Signed) J. A. GUTTER Y, Supt. of Schools." STOP, LOOK and LISTEN! What we want is to enlist eiv man. woman, bov and girl into the American Safety Fiist Army, armed with the sword of Carefulness, to figft ijrainst Demon Carelessness. Do you realize the awful loss of and property each year that Carelessness takes as toll with sword of fire ! Statistics show that the loss of life is over , that those injured will bring that number to 60,000 at the property loss is close to one-half billion dollars /ear. This does not count time lost out of business or \tra expense in maintaing fire fighting organizations rteir expensive equipment. e State of Nebraska has a fire marshal's office, and his I helpers consists of one deputy and three inspectors »e young lady stenographer. The duties of the Fire ill and deputy are many, but most of their time is tak - \ith the investigation of fires supposed to be of incen- the condemnation of old buildings and places rda. The duties of the fire inspectors are to in- :t all buainwj pieces and others that need it, for conditions at might eaose me. making written report of same to the »ffice, at the same time giving the occupant of the build- owner, orders to clean up and get rid of the hazardous condition. This state is a large one and with only three in - spectors to do the work, it takes them better than a year to make all the towns once. Then nearly evey town has a paid or volunteer lire de - partment, but they are mostly volunteers, men of the town organized together with the purpose of putting out fires if one should start. You can readily see that the task is so large that it is necessary for everyone to get in line and push be - cause it is everyone's work to be careful around his own home </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 and business place, to be absolutely sure that none of the con - ditions exist which might cause a fire. It is possible that you are not aware that carelessness is in your home or business he is a sly fellow and hides where you least suspect him. Therefore, in order to be sure he is not there, you must look for him very carefully. In fact, you should study everything you can obtain on Fire Prevention. When you have done this, you will be surprised to see the villain hiding in places you never dreamed of. You say, I never heard of such and such a ihiag causing fire, and it has been that way for years and caused trouble. Why should it NOW? But, my dear reader, fires are happening every day as statistics will show, if you will only read up on these things. These conditions do cause fires, and it may be yours will be the next. Then get busy and make conditions safe in your own place. This will show your neighbor that you believe and practice what you prrach in Fire Prevention. Just stop and think about this .'tviously. Uncle Sam needs you in his Safety First Army, al - so your state, your county, your town, and your family. Are you going to be a sacker? If not, then get busy and get busy now, and help recruit this army to kill off carelessness. You grown-ups teach it to your children, and see that they practice it. See to it that it is taught in the schools, and be sure tho&gt;« schools are safe places for your children and your neighbors children. See that your picture shows and theatre- are salt and not fire traps. Be interested in saving the dollars you al- ready have, as well as making more I And now, boys and girls, you are the coming men and en of tomorrow and so much depends on you, in fact, we looking for you to help us more in this big battle with care - less than your parents. Your keen young minds grasp e things quicker than theirs, and again you ha%"e more ! to devote to it. So won't you all get busy and do your I best to get the cooperation of your parents in making • own home safe and also the community in which you live? following pledge is one given by Columbia to the little boy girl, in the film entitled "Danger that Never Sleeps." n they kneel before her: "I pledge myself to good citizen - i as a Knight of Carefulness, first by safeguarding others ; </seg>
            <seg id="p025">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION t 1 econd, by learning to recognize and correct dangerous condi - ions in my own house; third, by pointing out dangerous con- &gt;ns in my own city, and fourth, by helping to teach others nake carefulness a habit." By L. J. BUTCHER, Deputy Fire Marshall." INVESTIGATION OF SUPPOSEDLY INCENDIARY FIRES This office has been asked to investigate seventy-one during the year 1922, which were supposed to be of in- ondiary origin. We have been very careful to go into the matter in each case as thoroughly as possible in the short ime allowed us for investigation ; and we have in each case iied to be fair with those whom we have had to question. Vhere the evidence was insufficient to warrant presentation to county attorney, the case has been dropped, but greater Dion of these cases were without a doubt of incendiary ori- nd the evidence was submitted to the county attorney, n a majority of the cases decided the evidence was in- ent for conviction. Yet we feel that if these cases had tried, evidence would have been secured after the trial tarted. and in some cases a confession would have been Kut it would seem that a number of county attorneys to do their duty and prosecute in the name of the State. &gt;el that even though a conviction were not secured in cases where we have such good circumstantial evidence hat it leaves no doubt in any ones mind but that the party eeaaed is guilty, it would have a very beneficial effect in pre - enting others from attempting the same thing. Louis Whitacre arrested on October 30, 1921, at Colum - bus. Nebraska, and bound over to the District Court for set - ting fire to his home in five different places, his trial coming up January 18, 1922, at which time he was acquitted by a jury. Paul Barnard and George Murbell were arrested on June 22. 1922, at Omaha, Nebraska. Paul Barnard confessed that he and Murbell were hired by John Updahl to burn Updahl's </seg>
            <seg id="p026">M 117 Lexington Touring Car, to obtain the insurance of $600, i were to have been paid $25.00 each for this act. Case still the courts. William Cheney and wife, Eva Cheney, were arrested on April 12th, 1922, at North Platte, for having attempted to bum their residence. Cheney was Clerk in the McCabe Hotel, on duty nights. He moved their keepsakes and clothing to the hotel at midnight, then persuaded his wife to set the home on fire. The fire department put out this fire about 11 P. M. «n April 9th. On the morning of April 10th, about 8 A. M. the house was again discovered to be on fire. Mrs. Cheney had fired the house in six different places. The fire boys got it out without much damage. After a searching investigation, evi - dence was secured that plainly showed Cheney and wife were guilty. A confession was obtained from both Cheney and wife, Cheney being tried and sentenced to a term of from one to seven years in the State Reformatory and his wife was given a bench parole, on account of the small child of the Cheneys. KMrs. Vada Davis, of Scottsbluff. Nebraska, had a fire at residence on February 27th, at about midnight. The place i found to have been set on fire in five different place. Mrs. vis was home alone, claming to have been in bed from 10:80 I til she was awakened by the smoke ; that she had barely time save herself from the fire, getting out in her night-gown. e firemen on arriving at the scene quickly eot the fire out I the file chief put a guard on the house and sent for an in - &gt;tigator from the fire marshal's office. On arriving at Scotts - iff the investigator found the fire was incendiary, beyond a ubt, and that Mrs. Davis was suspected of same. Her story s that she had been in bed, but the bed showed no evidence having been occupied. Evidence was submitted to the county ;orney, who agreed to prosecute the case, but up to the pes - t time has failed to do so, and can offer no excuse whatsoever, is to be hoped that this case will still be brought to trial. tM. W. Stogsdill and Tom Bisgard of Benkleman, Nebras - were arrested on August 15th, 1922, and bound over to district court for having burned Stogsdill's stock of goods July 14th. Evidence goes to show 15 gallons of gasoline e used in assisting to burn these goods. Trial was to have </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 27 come up November 13th, but was continued to the next term of the district court in 1923. It is the opinion of this department that the laws must be made more strict and made in such a manner that conviction can be had on good circumstantial evidence, as well as can murder or theft. Another thing, the law must be remedied so that agents writing insurance will be forced to get the sound value of the property insured, because in practically every case investigated by this department, we find that the property and contents were overinsured, sometimes for twice or three times the real value. Every person insuring his property should be forced to carry at least one-fifth of the riak himself, and inspections made often by the companies' traveling inspectors to ascertain whether or not the property had been reduced below the amount for which it had been insured. DEATHS AND INJURIES IN NEBRASKA CAUSED BY FIRE. FROM DECEMBER 1, 1921, TO DECEMBER 1. 1922 Tecumseh, Nebraska, December 20, 1921, Leta Oldfield, aged fourteen, was fatally burned while pouring kerosene into ■ cook stove. The can exploded, burning the clothing from her body, and the child's mother's hands and arms were quite bad - ly burned helping the daughter. Leta died the following day. Wayne, Nebraska, December 23, 1921, Wilson Heister was badly burned when fire started from an oil stove in his room after he had retired for the night. Pleasantdale, Nebraska, December 23, 1921, Prof. N. Clay Null, superintendent of the Pleasantdale schools, was severely burned when his Santa Claus robe caught fire at the school building. Professor Null's coolness as he walked out of the building probably averted a serious panic. Miss Riley and -Mrs. Eberspacher also received painful burns in extinguishing the flames. Nebraska City, Nebraska, December 28, 1921, the nine months old infant of Mr. and Mrs. Earl Cummings was fatally burned in an explosion which occurred when Mrs. Cummings poured kerosene on the fire. The mother ran into the yard and </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Mr. Cummings extinguished the flames which enveloped her and then rushed into the house to rescue the children. The baby died the following day. Columbus, Nebraska, December 30, 1921. Mrs. Lavina Kahart, 82 years of age was found burned to death, lying be - hind the heating stove in her home. Early in the morning the granddaughter, Miss May Eahart, had started a fire in the heating stove and had then gone to visit her parents. It is supposed that the aged woman had opened the stove door, and that the newly kindled wood had exploded in her face, igniting hei clothing. Lincoln, Nebraska. January 12, 1922. Miss Mary McKim. (&gt;0. was burned to death, when her clothing caught fire from a kerosene stove which she was attempting to light. Thomas Muiphy, a roomer in the McKim home, heard her screams and severely burned his hands in attempting to extinguish the tWinside, Nebraska. January 21, 1922. Mrs. Mabel Ho b was badly burned about the face, when she heated som •line, intended for use in dry cleaning. Omaha, Nebraska. January 2b, 1922. Mrs. James Ym - man, 22, and her seven month's old daughter, Selma Mae, were fatally burned, when the child's clothing caught fire from a kitchen stove while the mother was out of the house. Mrs. Yroman received fatal injuries in attempting to rescue the b.abe, as well as another two-year-old child which received only K Ulysses, Nebraska, January 31, 1922. Verna, eight year daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Stewart Bell, was severely burn - when a heating stove in the Bell home exploded. The child's dashes, eyebrows and hair were burned close. I Bethany, Nebraska, February 6. 1922. Alice Robb. 4 W old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. G. W. Robb, was burned to ith wiien her dress caught fire during her mother's absence she tried to put something into the coal heater. The moth - was badly burned about the arms and neck in extinguish- X the flames. Mrs. Robb had stepped over to a neighbors 1 a moment, hearing the child's screams, she rushed out to d Alice on the porch, a pillar of flames, the breeze fanning </seg>
            <seg id="p029">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 29 the flames. Although the fire was comparatively quickly ex - tinguished, the little girl had received fatal bums. Omaha, Nebraska, February 25, 1922. Emil Pankratz, 50. who was serving his first night as watchman in a printing com - pany building, where he had been employed to watch for thieves who recently broke into the place, was burned to death n a fire believed to have been stalled from a gas stove in the •fTice of the building. The property damage was slight. Winnebago. Nebraska. February 17, 1922. Oliver Simp- met death near VVinnebago. caused by a gasoline explosion, ■ he had warmed the carburetor of the tractor he was op- ating with cobs and then poured some gasoline out of a ree gall»n can into the carburetor to prime it. The gas nd ignited the gasoline in the can, causing an ex- Ainsworth. March 4. Dorothy, the 12 year old daughter A. M. Robinson, died as the result of bums received, and old sister is in the hospital undergoing treatment or burns. The accident occurred when a baking powder can ontaining oil was upset on the range, and the oil ignited the lothing of the children standing near the stove. Clinton. March 23rd. Lizzie Hill, aged 7, was seriously burned when a lighted match was thrown into her clothing by one of a number of children with whom she was playing. Little hope is entertained for her recovery. The child's mother, also a neighbor who happened to be passing, were quite badly burn - ed on the hands trying to extinguish the flames. Lincoln, April 4th. Mrs. William Pillard of Lakeview was latally burned when her clothes took fire while she was at - tempting to stait a fire in a stove with kerosene. Her hus - band's hands were seriously burned when he attempted to ex tinguish the flames. Fremont. April 4th. Samuel Meckathorn, 72 years old, was latally burned when he suffered a sudden stroke of par - alysis just after he struck a match in anticipation of lighting his pipe, the match falling from his lifeless fingers igniting his clothing. When discovered by neighbors the aged man was so badly burned that he died a few hours later. Lincoln, April 5th. Lillian Krieger, four ,was seriously </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 burned about the hands, chest and left shoulder, when her clothing caught fire while she was playing with matches. I Lincoln, April 6th. Lennie Abels was seriously burned on arms, abdomen, legs and face when a tank of gasoline ex - ed and covered him with liquid flame, as he was endeavor - to transfer gasoline from one tank to another. It 16 ight he will recover. Omaha, May 1st. Fourteen firemen were injured by an explosion as they fought a fire on the second floor of the Gard - ner building. One of the injured, Capt. Robert Dunlap, is in a critical condition. He was overcome by gas and badly burn - ed about the hands and face. Bellevue, May 8th. F. E. Sh river's body was found, badly charred, in the post-office at Bellevue. It is believed that an explosion occurred when an attempt was made by Shriver to blow up the safe, which destroyed the building re - sulting fatally for Shriver. Crofton, May 9th. Mrs. Rudolph Kohls and daughter. Elsie, were seriously burned last Friday when a can of varnish they were heating on the stove became ignited and set fire to their clothing. Mrs. Kohls was badly burned from the knees to her waist and she also received bad burns about the face and head and one hand. Beatrice, May 16th. Harry Whiteside. fire chief at Beat - rice sustained a broken rib and severe bruises when he fell through the floor while fighting a blaze in the home of Mrs. Anna Lenz. The fire started when the little son of Mrs. Lenz thl*ew a lighted match into a box of papers in the kitchen shed. Fullerton, May 23rd. Katherine Virginia Horn, four year old daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Homer Horn, perished in a fire which destroyed the barn on the Horn place. The little girl and her seven year old brother were playing in the hay mow when it is supposed spontaneous combustion set fire to the hay. The little boy who had escaped from the burning building stated he had tried to pull his sister down the feed hole to escape, but his hold broke loose. We believe it was playing with matches. Belmont, June 8th. Donald Hutson, six years old, was burned to death, and his mother, Mrs. Forest Hutson, was </seg>
            <seg id="p031">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 31 probably fatally burned in a fire which destroyed their home at Fifth and Judson Streets. It is thought that Mrs. Hutson ire in the kitchen stove with kerosene and that in the stove. The house and con- ed. Struck by a lighted gasoline can he was standing near, had M Popper, of Belgrade, was seriously domen and legs. Mr. Pepper had &gt;urned in extinguishing the fire. IS lune 2»». Elaine, little daughter of Mr. and Mrs. iller. was badly burned when playing with matches ting the bed clothing on fire. » North Platte, June 26th. Mrs. Tenny was fatally burned three children seriously injured as a result of a gaso- e explosion. The explosion blew down the poles of the i hich the family was living and imprisoned the mother children in the burning canvas. Doniphan, June 26th. Mrs. Charles Redman and Mrs. ha Seibert were badly burned when the gasoline in a pan hich they had been cleaning a stove, exploded. The had thought the flame in the burner completely ex- shed, though apparently it was not. Nebraska City, June 27th. O little four year old girl was fully injured when she bit into a torpedo which exploded mouth. Fremont, July 6th. Verna Dunn, twelve, suffered painful borna while manipulating a roman candle. Lincoln. One little girl at Capitol Beach, was slightly burned by a fire cracker on the 4th of July. Gordon. July 12th. Mrs. McClullen and two children, living 15 miles south of Gordon, were seriously burned when a can of kerosene that Mrs. McClullen was using to start a fire in the kitchen stove, exploded. The mother and one child were brought to Gordon, where their injuries were dressed. Al - though badly burned, it is believed they will recover. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Decatur, July 14th. A little Indian boy, five years of age. was burned to death when he and a white lad of the same age started a fire in the basement of the store of Charles H. Taylor. The Indian boy became frightened and ran farther back into the basement but the white boy escaped uninjured. Hubbell, July 26th. Mrs. Lloyd Hubka was seriousl burned when her clothing caught on fire. Lincoln. July 26th. Al Barney, Lincoln fireman, was in - jured while fighting fire. An oil stove exploded in the house of John Anderson, 1144 L. St.. setting the building on fire. David City, July 30th. Mrs. Henry Fuller and son. Re were badly burned when ■ pan of gasoline exploded at tht home. The young man was cleaning some clothes near an » Havelock, August 3rd. Schell Young and Geoff ley B were slightly burned about the back of the head and neck burning embers when the roof fell in at the Simcho dwelli: fire. Agnew. August 4th. Vincent Menu son of Mr. and Mrs. Dave Hennessey, was serious about the body as the result of the explosion of a eai line with which he was playing. Blair, August 8th. Mrs. Ed Pyles was seriously 1&gt; when a can of paraffin ignited and set fire to her clothir Broken Bow, August 10th. Judge Sullivan was seriousl burned about the head and upper part of the body when hi clothing caught fire while he was filling his car with gasolin&lt; The fumes of the gas were ignited from a burning cigar. Omaha, August 11th. Twenty firemen were overcome when fire broke out in the H. P. Bowen Furniture Store, none seriously injured. Fairbury, August 16th. Mr. L. Duffey was badly burned when an oil torch being used in setting a tire on an engine exploded. Lincoln, September 8th. Mark Grass was painfully in </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 33 jured when gasoline from an overflowing tank on his truck flared up. being ignited from an overheated muffler. Mr. Graff burned about the aims painfully. Norfolk, September 9th. The nine year old son of Harry ilein was badlv burned about the face and head when he P&gt; companions dropped lighted matches into the gaso- d abandoned automobile, resulting in an ex 01 urned about the face, neck and arms, when a ch he vu using to seal cans, exploded. \insworth; September 13th. Mrs. Chris Eddy was latal- ,vhen kerosene which she was using to kindle fire i burning Mrs. Eddy so seriously that she died in a Omaha, September 25th. Tom McAdams, fireman, was badly cut by flying glass while fighting a fire that gutted the Rusy Bee Cafe on south 14th Street. Columbus, September 26th. Mrs. Edward Schober was lly burned when her clothing caught fire as she attempted I pan from the stove, using her apron as a lifter. Lincoln. September 25th. Four firemen were injured ? fighting a fire in an abandoned livery stable, used as a I Julius Schmidt was the only one seriously injured. lias, September 26th. H. G. Otto was slightly injured ng in the way of firemen. bv Nebraska City, September 28th. Mrs. William Gunn was quite badly burned about the head when a celluloid hairpin she was wealing became ignited from water being spilled on an oil stove, causing the flame to flare up. Superior, September 28th. Oswin Hawley was badly burned at the Nebraska Cement Plant, when an electric start - er box blew up, the fiery blast enveloping his face and arm. Ray Smith, an electrician whose home is in Omaha, went to the assistance of Hawley and was also burned, his injuries being more severe than those of Hawley. Norfolk. September 11th. F. G. Nassman, 33, died here </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION Central City, October 4th. Edith Enquist, aged twelve. daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Frank Enquist, was so badly burned that she died six hours later at a hospital. The accident occur - i«d when the little girl tried to start a fire in the kitchen range with kindling and in some manner her skirt caught fire. Beatrice, October 5th. Miss Mary Fuller, was seriously burned about the face, right arm and shoulders, when the flames of a dry print machine which she was operating flared up, setting fire to her shirt waist. Alliance, Nebraska. October 7th. Mrs. Bell Brown, an elderly woman was severely burned about the face and hands when a small can of gasoline with which she was trying to destroy vermin, exploded, setting fire to her clothing. Central City, October 12th. David Eakin, old and respec ed citizen, was burned to death, when a gasoline stove explo&lt; ed, immediately setting fire to the house. Mr. and Mrs. Ste 1 ens who also occupied the -house were seriously burned. M Grigor was slightly burned while rescuing the &lt;&gt;the of the sleeping household. North Bend, October 14th. Mrs. A. F. Sea ly burned by the explosion of gasoline when k the kitchen stove, using the gasolii can exploded, enveloping Mrs. Sea juries from which she died shortly Athens, October 21st. Ruth Bi death while playing with several small dren were playing with fire when the cl came ignited. Mrs. Wandal Berry, an ; was seriously burned in attempting t( Beatrice, October 31st. Carl Oleson was terribly bun about the face when a gas blow torch exploded in while he was welding an automobile part. Lincoln, November 1st. Prompt action b\ Alex Troudt, a boy of 13, in pulling off his coat and wrapping it around his sister, Lydia, aged 10, when her dress caught fire from a jack - o-lantern, probably saved the little girl's life. The girl's right </seg>
            <seg id="p035">c t DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION ■ badly burned and the brother suffered a few slight his hands. November 2nd. Marcel Austin, 4, and her 18 colored, wore smothered to death ?n had been left by the parents, who work .vith another child. Margaret, 14, who left nts. It is thought that Marcel found t»'i e rtnii, November 9th. John Linderman, pioneer at- Lexington, was badly burned about the face and n in some manner an oil stove in his room was over - tting fire to the bedding. )ln. November 13th. George Hernandex, 28 years lainfully burned on both legs below the knees, when &gt;f boiling asphalt exploded about 1 :20 A. M. Monday •chrane Construction Company's plant at Fifth and J. .•ausing a fire which destroyed a shed, platform, and rels of asphalt. b, November 17th. Jack Jones, 4, burned to death in the Jones farm, 8 miles east of Lyons. The child is ive been playing with matches in the barn and to bain j.fire. Frightened by what he had done, he have hid in the manger. It was there the moth- s body after the fire had burned low. ska City. November 18th. Mrs. Agnes Theis was ieath when her clothing caught fire when she start- \ D her heating stove. It is thought she went to stir d the blaze caught her clothes. Norfolk. November 24th. Jim Renish looked into the gas of his car. lighting a match to see better whether or not contained gas. It did. An explosion followed. Benish was msiderably burned. C. 0. Hedrick threw kerosene into his furnace, causing an xplosion which seriously burned Hedrick. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 TABLES SHOWING CAUSES OF THE PRECEDING DEATHS AND INJURIES. The preceding tables will show for themselves that n than three-fourths of the deaths and injuries caused by occur among women and children. FIRE ESCAPES In compliance with the law passed in 1911, sj kind of buildings that should be equipped with fire escapt herewith submit the following list showing the buil which have complied with the law by reason of orders i from this office during the past year. Alliance, Public School. Alma, Public School. Belgrade, Public School. Bennett, Public School. Cedar Bluffs, Public School. Chambers, Public School. Dodge, Public School. Falls City, Convent School. Gresham, Public School. Genoa, Public School. Grand Island, College. Death is Injuries itarting Fire With Kerosene . 9 6 lasoline Explosion taught on Fire From Stove or Open Flame- - !hildren Playing With Matches &gt;ther Causes issisting to Save Others On Fire lelping to Put Out Fire 'iremen Injured In Fighting Fires 4 . 5 6 3 . 0 0 0 21 6 4 16 4 4 41 Vomen and Children Burned to Death len Burned to Death 28 .-22 ._ 6 102 Injured 41 Injured 20 28 61 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 37 Hayes Center, Public School. Holdrege, Public School. Lincoln, Public School. Maywood, Public School. Omaha, St. Joseph's School. Lincoln, Windsor Hotel. Palisade, School Buildings. Utica, School Building. York, Lutheran Hospital Association York, Odd Fellow's Hall. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION CAUSES OF FIRES DURING 1922 Balance of State Number Lincoln Omaha Number Numbei 25 9 Ashes, hot v Backfire From Engine 9 .&gt; Bonfires and Burning of Trash Candles __ 11 Chimneys, Defective Cigars or Cigarettes Communicated Electric or Gas Irons 54 Electric Wiring. Defective Fireworks __ Furnace and Stoves, Defective Gas If, 6 Gasoline and Kerosene Grease Becoming Ignited Incendiary, Presumably Inflammables, too close to fire Lightning __ 26 2\ Matches Matches, in hands of Children Mice and Matches Overheated Exhaust Pipe Overheated Stoves and Furnace Oil Stove Explosions I t Oil Lamp and Lanterns Sparks from Chimney Sparks from Engine ITS Sparks from Stoves or Furnace* Stove and Furnace Explosions. _ Spontaneous Combustion ■•"i ;.; Vulcanizing 1 1 Thawing Frozen Pipes Fumigating •&gt; it 1 Films Exploding Unknown u o °.-&gt; 54 225 ■&gt;■&gt; • &gt;.&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 39 During 1922, our regular inspectors, inspected 247 towns and cities of Nebraska. During this time, we are pleased to 18,2% inspections were made, and nearly 12,- *de in the interest of fire prevention. n.spection record shows the following orders issued: ■i. 711 oline 2,995 730 mm trie Wirin 2,979 1.071 Metal or aabasfeM under stove Red light and fire escape 149 Miscellaneous 3,695 Total orders issued 12,330 )tal inspections made 18,296 :luded in above inspections, Investigated 71 Schools Inspected 304 Theatres Inspected 251 ilaints received and Condemnation orders issued for December 1st. 1921. to December 1st, 1922, are as ■ceived 563 455 d Inspection Made and Final )rder Given _475 Reported Torn Down 259 Buildings Reported Repaired 251 ations on which time has ?\pired, and not reported as complied with 85 Probably half of these aie com- plied with.) Condemnations that time of remov - al has not yet expired 31 Complaints not yet having final order issued 107 INSPECTIONS DURING 1922. ■r&gt;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION FARM FIRES REPORTED FOR 1922. We wish to thank the State Farmers Insurance Company. of Omaha, also the Farmers Union Cooperative Insurance Company, of Omaha, for the following information in regard to farm fires. This is the first time we have received reports on fires happening in the country, although the law specifies that the sheriff of each county shall report these farm fires, yet it has never been done. It is going to be the aim of this Department in the future to try to get an accurate report on farm fires. For this year the farm f $33,010.30, cause of these fires sources. •es reported number S2. loss. are lightning and from othei This undoubtedly is a very small percentage of the losse incurred upon farms, but is the only information this Depart ment has at hand at the present time. This Department this coming year will do its utn extend fire prevention to the farmer, who needs it ever rhis brother in the city. There are many things tli lives in the country can do to make his property safe from fire, and it should be done. FIRE LOSSES DURING 1922. The total fire loss from December 1st. 1921, until De V 1st, 1922, is as follows: Lincoln SS2 | -.1.117.21 Omaha 437 ¥MJUUB» Balance of State K7 1. 685,01 2. :V2 Total 1.676 t2.140.081.12 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 41 TOWNS INSPECTED The following is a list of cities and towns that have been nspected during the past year. The figures in parenthesis ng the one inspection. Albion \lda Burwell Duncan Dwight Crawford Aller Cedar Rapids Callaway Doniphan Elsie Alhaiic A i At Campbell Edison Elgin Central City Columbus Eddyville Edgar .At Comstock Cowles A Elba \ \ Cozad E'.khora Croft on Elm Creek El wood ('rote (2) Creston x Emerson Eustis Craig College View- Coleridge Exeter Fullerton Fail-field Fairmont Falls City Farnam Claikson Clay CVntei Clarks Chappd Chapman Calhoun Curtis Farwell Fordyce Franklin r, B B Cambridge Culbertson Douglas Fremont (2) Friend Bertrand Bethanv Garland Geneva Genoa Dickens Dannebrog Deweese Big Springs Bladen Gering (2) Gibbon Bloomington Blue Hill Dakota City Dalton Giltner Bostwick Brainard Bradv David City Dixon Gothenburg Grant Dodge Greeley Broken Bow Dorchester Greenwood \vn indicates more than </seg>
            <seg id="p042">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 42 Guide Rock Hildreth Melbeta Miller Republican City Rising City Kiverdake Riverton Rosalie Hyannis Howe Mina^are Mitchell Moorefield Morvill Bolbrook oldrege Randolph Seward Humphrey (2) Hartington Mullen Scottsbluff (2) Stratton Havens Havelock Hazard Sargent Scotia Hebron Herman Hickman Holstein Hooper Howells Harvard Inavale Imperial Indianola Jackson Juniata Kearney Kennard Kimball Lyons Schuyler (2) Scribner Newcastle Norman Seneca Shelby Shelton North Bend North Loup Silver Creek Snvder Nebraska City Oxford Sidney Smithfield South Sioux City Spalding Stanton Overton Palisade Palmer Papillion Primrose Plainview Pierce Staplehurst St. Edward Stella Lawrence Lindsay Laurel Leigh Paxton Pender Pilger Lexington Litchfield Lodgepole Loomis Sutherland Sutton Trenton Taylor Tekamah Thurston Trumbull Ulysses Loup City Lincoln Potter Phillips Madison Maywood Maxwell Raymond Ravenna Red Cloud University Place Newman drove Naponee Nortolk (2) North Platte Nelson Omaha Oaklapd Oconto Ogallala Ord Stockvilk St. Paul Sumner Stunner Superior Platle Center Ponca </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DIVISION OF FIRE PREVENTION 43 Upland Valley Venang( Yerdon Wallace Walthill Winnebago Wisner Waterbury Waterloo Washington Waverly Wolbach Woodriver Wynot Valparaiso Wauneta Wakefield York West Point </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>