<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00064.00005">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00064.00005</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Fourteenth Biennial Report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska
November 30, 1928</title>
               <date value="1928-11-30">1928-11-30</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>


		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06-26</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-06-21</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2006-12-20-05:00</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Initial Creation</item>
			      </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Fourteenth Biennial Report OF THE Nebraska Public Library Commission Lincoln, Nebraska November 30, 1928 American Printing Company lincoln. nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p002">4 18 YOUES A MODEL TOWN LIBRARYT </seg>
            <seg id="p003">5 THE MODEL TOWN LIBRARY MAS Income of $1.00 per capita (minimum) of 5 books per capita One assistant for every 20,000 books circulated EXPEIDS 50% of Its income for salaries 25% for books and periodicals 10% for binding and supplies 15% for maintenance OFFERS Trained service Carefully selected books Extension service through branches and deposits Cooperation with schools, dubs, and all other community interests Poster prepared for the Model Town Exposition, Boston, by the Massachusetts Division of Public Libraries </seg>
            <seg id="p004">6 Nebraska Public Library Commission EDITH TOBITT, President Omaha, Nebraska E. A. BURNETT Chancellor of the University of Nebraska GILBERT H. DOANE Librarian of the University of Nebraska CHARLES B. LETTON State Librarian CHARLES W. TAYLOR State Superintendent of Public Instruction NELLIE WILLIAMS Secretary MARGUERITE NESBIT Reference Librarian EDNA BOOTH Clerk for Traveling Libraries </seg>
            <seg id="p005">7 I jP/|' r |*t*jr\ \Jjf Txv^*J'l " vHL I "I"!. 1 * ' J Honorable Adam McMullen, Governor of Nebraska: Dear Sir: Complying with the requirements of the law, I herewith present the secretary's report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission for the biennium ending November 30, 1928. Respectfully yours, EDITH TOBITT, President </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">9 IXebraska rublic Library Vjommission SECRETARY'S REPORT THE COMMISSION Soon after the printing of the last biennial report o£ the Library Commission there were three changes in its personnel. On January 1, 1927, Charles B. Letton and Charles W. Taylor, by virtue of their respective offices as State Librarian and State Superintendent of Public Intruction, became members of the Commission. On January 15, 1927, E. A. Burnett, succeeding Samuel Avery as Chancellor of the University, also became a member. It was due to illness that the resignation of Chancellor Avery became effective at this time. In be - half of the Commission we wish to thank him for service rendered during the seventeen years of his administra - tion. Miss Tobitt, the president and appointed mem - ber, and Mr. Doane, librarian of the University, are also members of the Commission. In compliance with the law, a meeting of the Com - mission is held annually in April. Precedent has estab - lished the holding of a meeting in the fall. The mem - bers are regular in attendance, helpful in suggestions, in accord with the policies which we are trying to con - sumate and appreciative of the limitations which curtail our efforts. The secretary wishes to thank each of the members for the support given her. P tangible evidence of the interst which Profes - or feels in the Commission is shown by devoting his biennial report to the work of this depart - We are glad to report that the only changes in the staff are by addition. Miss Nesbit continues as ref - erence librarian and Miss Booth as clerk for traveling libraries. Martha Thomassen and Alice Martin are em - ployed as half-time assistants. We also have four Uni - versity students as extra helpers. The added hours of service are possible because of a slight increase in the salary fund. We here record our thanks to Governor McMullen for his recommenda - tion covering this item and to the legislature for its approving action. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Field Work 10 forward. It does at times seem not unlike a three-ring performance on which it is impossible to concentrate equally. We try, however, to keep a just balance in the work, which consists of aids to library extension, a sys - tem of loans and the supervision of libraries in the state institutions under the Board of Control. Variety attends these three phases of the department's aim to foster library interests in Nebraska. Not infre - quently people say to us, "How interesting your work must be!" Always we answer them that verily it is. In degree of importance the Library Commission has always given first place to the establishment and fur - therance of libraries. It has been its aim to visit each library during a biennium. With the increasing number of these libraries, and the growth of the work along all lines, it has been impossible to cover the state in a two - year period. We are glad at this time to report the goal in sight. The increased number of visits made during the last biennium is due to the addition in hours of service previously mentioned. By the employment of Miss Thomassen. Miss Nesbit has been able to give some time to assist the secretary in the field work. The following: is a record of visits made since the last report of the Commission, the greater number having been made since July, 1927, when the increased appro - priation became available. Visits in answer to call 29 Other visits 84 Total 113 The visits in answer to call have been to libraries about to organize or in need of cataloging. Of the twen - ty-nine visits, fifteen were made in the interest of or - ganization, eleven to give assistance in cataloging, three relative to building plans. In a number of instances there is need of return visits of greater length for classifying and cataloging the libra - ries. The requests for such help will be met as rapidly as possible. Visits of the Commission are made without expense to the library receiving help. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Though aid in organizing and in improving existing libraries seems to us the most important phase of the Commission's activity, of necessity the greater part of its time is given to the daily requests for books which »« stnt here, there, and everywhere in Nebraska. The Commission continues also to answer a few Mac- edonian calls, though most requests from across th&lt;* borders are referred to the states from which they come. Exceptions are sometimes made in case of states which do not have library commissions. In connection with the reference work which the Commission does for the Exten - sion Department of the University, requests have coma from widely scattered registrants. The material needed is oiten Nebraska bulletins which cannot be secured else - where. The following is the list of twenty-seven states to which loans have been made during the biennium: Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, California, Colorado, Flori- t Idaho. Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, lesota, Missouri, Montana, New Jersey, New Mexico, York, North Carolina, Oregon, Pennsylvania, South jta. Texas. Utah, Virginia, West Virginia, and Wyo- ming. Three loans were also made to Canada. We are probably best known by our traveling library loans, and letters are frequently addressed to the Travel - ing Library or Circulating Library, though the secretary is wont to say that we come by any name whereby we are called. A few of the less obvious names under which we have answered recent requests are The Library Mis - sion, Pnbl' Library Missission, M-i-donble s-i-double s-i-o-n, State Library Association for nse in H. S. work, Bazaar of Nebraska. State University, Picnic Circle No. 2, University of Nebraska, (this from a far-off state), and Postwick American Public Library. In this case the tower was returning Dr. Bostwick's book of that title, le reonests from groups and individuals for the bien- ■ number 10,882. The loans number 118,684. following: is a classified arrangement of the re- quests and loans from December 1, 1926 to November 30. 1328: Borrowers Reonest Gronos of Residents 308 Pnblic Libraries 664 School nnd Colleee Libraries 887 Stndy Olnbg 1.197 Other Organizations 34 ts Volumes 22.161 17.332 43.380 4.958 2.898 rndividnals 7.70'? Total 10.882 81JW 118.684 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">12 The method of loans is explained in the following let - ter of information: "Books are sent out by the Nebraska Public library Commission according to two general plans. There are traveling libraries which are loaned for three months with the privilege of extending the time. Usually a gen - eral group contains adult fiction and children's books in about equal numbers but a group consisting of only adult books or only children's books will be sent if desired. To any general traveling library non-fiction along special lines will be added on request. The number of books loaned is determined, in part, by the size of the com - munity to which they are sent. E&gt;ups of books for special study are sent to individ - and clubs, the number of books and the time limit iding on the special needs of the case. The time is ly a month, however. In either case the only ne - ry procedure is to write and ask us to send them. In all loans there is no expense to the borrower except the transportation charges. Traveling libraries are sent by freight, special loans by parcel post. K'e have no printed lists of our books but depend on patrons to tell us what they want and we meet their ies as far as our resources will allow. I traveling library will be sent on receipt of an ap - ation card properly filled out and SIGNED BY AT lST THREE TAXPAYERS. We are greatly assisted ur selection of books if in the space for remarks, we told the number of pupils and grades of a school, if library is for the school, and something of the read - tastes of the community, if the library is for general ling," For three years correspondence has been in progress in the interest of a lower postal rate on books. We are gratified to announce that by act of Congress under Sec - tion 444% library books may now be sent within the state for 3 cents for the first pound and 1 cent for each additional pound. This is an appreciable lessening in the rate. It should increase our loans to the fourth zone where people have felt that the charge was too great. A five-pound package to that zone formerly cost twenty - four cents. It now travels that distance for seven cents. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Traveling Libraries 13 F)ur traveling libraries are loaned, as indicated, on ;e eleven, to groups of residents, to pub - libraries, to schools and to other organizations. The schools lead in the number of requests. During the bien - nium 87 counties have received traveling libraries. Custer county takes first place, 54 libraries having been sent to 10 stations. Lancaster follows with 51 libraries sent to 14 stations. Next in order are Gage 37, Thayer 36, Saunders 29, Cedar and York 24, Valley 23, Merrick and Butler 22, Burt and Saline 21, Hitchcock 20. Many of our borrowers express themselves as grate - ful for the books received. When they say that they are pleased with the selection, thanks are due to Miss Booth for her careful choosing. A few of these appreciative patrons wish to testify. I think first place goes to one from Pleasant Dale on whose card was written, "100% satisfaction". Others speak as follows: Bdren derived more value and pleasure from this l ever before," Emmet. "Sincere appreciation for use of books. You can never guess how much they mean to us." Milford. "Very well pleased. Fine books. Look for another box soon." Dalton. "I am a booster for the traveling library." Stapleton. From a. sod bouse in western Nebraska where we sent a collection of particularly lovely books for children, came this letter: "I am writing to say that we wish to renew the library which we have. We have enjoyed it very much and we should like to keep it so that the child - ren can get more benefit out of it. They will have more time when school is cut. I keep the library at my house and people either come and get the books or we exchange them at our club which meets every two weeks." Bridgeport. A regular borrower and staunch friend from Deshler writes "The enclosed letters are the result of a sugges - tion of mine to ask for a library. I am sending them all to please the little third and fourth graders who wrote them." The children speak thus: "Pleased Madam, I wish you would send us some books. I like to have a book of bears. The books are so well to read in." Edgar. "I surely am missing the books after they have been sent back. I would like to have a few books that have Indian stories. I sure like my teacher." Roy. "I liked the library very much last year. I liked many </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Reforenct i 14 &amp; few circus books. negro books &amp;nd oth6r kind of books 7 LiOnn. "Have you some books? I would like to have some animal books to read in." Elmer. "Will you please send a few books so that We do not waste time during the day. Please send an airplane book." Clarence. "Will you please send us a library book. I would like to have one about wild animals.' Gladys. "We sure enjoyed your books last year. I would like to have some books where there are stories of Indians." Lorna. Reference loans have been sent into every county in the state during the biennium just ended. They have gone to 528 communities. As in any reference department great variety attends the requests which are a considerable part of the daily mail. It is gratifying to note the increasing use of books for courses of study. The Reading with a Purpose courses supply the desire of many. We feel that we are thus adding our bit to the great work of Adult Educa - tion as fostered by the American Library Association through its board. We are also happy to send books to people who are as greatly in need of recreational read - ing as others are desirous of serious study. Many letters pay tribute to Miss Nesbit's selection and promptness in filling requests. We appreciate the good words which come in return for the service which is cheerfully rendered. A few letters are herewith quoted: "You have the happy faculty of sending: just what is desired. Better than I could select for myself." "We will stop using your good services and will leave soon for New York to board the U. S. Liner 'Republic'. Part of the enjoyment of this trip will be due to you and your good help." Brock. A rural borrower, registered for the Reading with a Purpose course on Our Children, writes: "I want to tell you that I am overjoyed at the opportunity which your Commission gives me." A month later she says, "I can not refrain from saying again how much I appre - ciate the opportunity for improvement which you offer. It is almost as good as college work. There is no ex- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">15 cuse for any one in Nebraska to be without profitable reading." Gibbon. Another rural borrower writes: "In asking for the address of a second hand store I "was advised to write to the Library Commission. Our family of four are all readers, living on a farm twenty miles from town with no chance to go any where and reading material scarce. Would like something different for a change." I other •writes to Miss Nellie Williams: "Dear d: For though a stranger I feel that you are a 1 to all who are in distress about books. Listening 1 the radio about the Library Commission, I re - d the inspiration to write to you about some travel 3." Fairbury. We appreciate such expressions of dliness as indicating that our borrowers do not upon us as a mere mail order machine. From a Superintendent of schools comes this: "I re - ceived that book of Durant's. It is excellent. I just literally revel in it. It is a real thought provoker. Thanks very much for sending it. P. S. Oh, yes, I also received those articles on Child Labor." A mother writes: "I hope to become a regular cus - ■er for such a good chance to get such helpful liter - •e means much in my life." Meadow Grove. In attorney whose confidence is reassuring says: iase find blank check on which I am requesting you ill in the amount due you for the following Reading a Purpose pamphlets And will you please loan The universe of stars, A beginner's star book and ;ory of the French revolution. I am indeed glad to w of the service you are giving. I am receiving a it deal of pleasure and profit therefrom." t young woman acknowledges help derived from the s -which she has been borrowing for more than a . "I am returning Saleeby-Worry, and Hutchinson- Itinct and health. My health is very much improved readiner these and other books which I have had from ir library. I have been helped especially by books tling with the control of nervousness, such as Jack- son's Outwitting our nerves." Guide Rock. "My order came today. Thank you. We have read iFurman stories for many years and perhaps that is my daughter has set up a community center about y miles from Hindman. The bed of the Creek </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Institutional Libraries 16 the story where the two teachers took a short cut home and discovered a still, is a familiar trail to my daughter. This summer she caught a glimpse of 'Amy', though Amy objects seriously to being looked at. The library and your obliging self are a great convenience to me." Franklin. The human element enters largely into the work of the Library Commission for those who constitute our shut - in citizens. We feel a peculiar interest in the readers in the hosiptals, homes, and schools, in the penal and cor - rectional institutions. The majority of those who are physically able to read, or have the time for it, make good use of the books which are provided for them. The circulation for the eleven institutions reporting is 95,286. This is an increase of 27,261 over the pre - ceding biennium. The greatest increase is at the peni - tentiary. The circulation there for the past two years is 54,151, which is an increase of 24,011 over the two years preceding. This is not a padded report, nor is the number of prisoners much greater. The men are reading more. This is largely due to the reprinting of the catalog at which time many new books were added. The librarian in charge faithfully exchanges the books daily. He writes frequently in appreciation of the libra - ry. He is also leader of the orchestra. A recent letter from him reads:- "I have written and published some songs and should be glad to send you copies. I have a new number placed with a New York City music publish - er on a royalty basis. The books on music which you have added to our library have been the source of a great deal of interest to "me in my few spare moments. There is a great demand for these splendid works." Space forbids more than excerpts from a few of the letters received recently from the "boys." We quote from these as follows: "Upon entering my cell sixteen months ago I was delighted to see a library index upon my table and upon perusing it I was more than glad to know that I could study even though in prison. I have secured many technical books in drafting and architec - ture. Not being financially in position to obtain these books otherwise I am very grateful to have borrowed them from the library. I shall continue to benefit by them for another three months when I hope the gates </seg>
            <seg id="p015">17 "I have been in prison since 1920 and have received a big benefit from the books in the library I have read Orison Swett Marden's books about six times each. Oh, what a help that man has been to me!" Beep up the good work, especially so in the line of 1 and useful arts." tdo not care much for fiction but I have benefited ly by the books on drafting. I feel safe in saying I can obtain employment in an office by just what in? I have done while here." Kie boys from the Reformatory also have a word to "In my short period that I have been here I have many of the library books and I appreciate them they help me to pass my time and make it much ;r to do right." thave been benefited by the privileges given me lgh the librarian and my choice of book friends. I incerely believe that the library here is one of the test helps in reforming ones self. I have found •rood literature is the foundation of clean living. q one who has been greatly helped through the in - tion library." thave been talking to the guard on t ne floor and he that he thought you would like to know how the boys ,• the library. Personally speaking I think it's great, have read close to 30 books in the short time that I : been here. And I have talked to several other wb and most of them agree that the Library is one leir greatest pleasures." E greatly appreciate the library privileges extended e inmates of this institution. On the average I read )k a week." thave read several books that have put me to think - of the best part of life. If all the fellows would interest in reading books, they would be surprised hat they would get out of them. The library is one great help to the school. Every nine out of ten fellows I have talked to about different books agree with me, so I thought I would write and tell you the interest the fellows are taking in the reading." "I think the library should be continued at all costs. Now in regards to new books. We do need a few more. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">18 We are letting a boy from the Industrial School speak for many there: "It is with great pleasure I take this opportunity to tell the Nebraska Public Library Commission of my sin - cere appreciation of the work they are doing. I am sure that I voice the sentiment of almost two hundred other inmates of this Institution when I say the library provided free for us here is one of the greatest factors for promoting contentment among us. The books, both of fiction and non-fiction, are of the highest possible standard and of a kind that tend to improve one's mind as well as afford great pleasure in reading." Another boy writes: "I like to read of boy scouts and have succeeded in obtaining a book called 'Don Strong Patrol Leader'. It is a very interesting story and shows what a boy of the great outdoors can do. It tells how a boy can go straight. I enjoy and appreciate the use of all the li - brary books as they teach sports of outdoor life." B eighth and ninth grade girls at the Geneva Train - chool have expressed their pleasure in the library imes written for their English classes. "Our family manager has read to us the book 'Vesper Talks for Girls'. We have also read in the dormitory in the evening 'The Covered Wagon'. We all enjoyed it Ily teacher gets some books from our library and fs them over to our school room and that way we use them to help us with our studies." K appreciate your kindness very much and I know I go out of the Institution I will be better all the around from reading these good books. Before I here I didn't read at all, but my mind is educated r and I hope I will keep on reading." Kie first book I read, I just had to force myself to it. Now I cannot read enough. I have found a pleasure in reading." "The library provides great variety of books from ■which one may pick. The library provides a practice of system as all books must be checked in by a certain time and taken out a certain way." Softer I have finished a book that I think is better the last one I read, I go over some incident and &gt;are some of my traits, with the traits of the charac - that have been brought out in some part of the book. ;houghts after reading an especially good book are </seg>
            <seg id="p017">19 "By reading good books I have become acquainted with people which any one would like to know person - ally; but after reading about them I can count them as my friends." "In my outside leading in English I see there are many things we can learn from different books such as the character of different people, and of the days long ago, and many, many other things that are interesting. I have thought this over, and decided to let my interest grow. When I have an opportunity to make use of a library I will not let it go by." "When I was about the age of twelve I used to go to the library once a week and choose from two to four books. I thought if they did not have any pictures in them they were not interesting but now I have passed that stage and it is mostly the books that do not have pictures that are the most interesting. KThe stories of children and animals are interesting to because I love them." S"When I get lonesome or blue I get a good book and sit wn and read it. I can always find a good story if I 7." "I travel all over England when I read Dickens' books. On a cold winter day I am in France or Spain with some interesting character. Any one can travel by reading books." kThe teacher from the School for the Deaf who has arge of the library writes: "As you can tell by the monthly report the pupils enjoy the books from the libra - ry. With the smallest children it is the pictures or very simple stories, as the Potter books, which are taken. The effort they make to be the first one at the library indicates how eager they are. The next grada asks for books on subjects which they have in school, about the Eskimos and Japanese and the like. The older pupils use many of the books for their Liter - ary Society and Christian Endeavor meetings. Many of them read purely for pleasure. The books play a very important part in the children's lives." The children themselves say: "I like many kinds of stories to read. They help me </seg>
            <seg id="p018">20 with my language. I wish to thank you very much for your kindness." \ \ \ "I enjoyed reading 'Little Women' and stories like it. In doing so I improve my language and get pleasure at the same time. Thanks for sending us nice books." Pam proud of our library. We have many kinds of s here, and on library days many of us go to the ry. The books I like to read are stories of girls boys of my own age. I am 15 years old." E surely am interested in reading the new books. ' will make us use our brains and will help us im - e our langugage." Ene of the books, I picked up, 'A Man Without a try,' I enjoyed so much and think that it was the interesting." The children at the Home for the Feeble Minded tell why they like the library: E^he reason I care for library books is I like to read i. The nest I will get is Captain John Smith of the a times. And next will be an Indian story. The one ve now is called David Crockett Scout an adventure y. All "way through it is a good book. I will get her a little different from that one." Ecare for library books because when you are not dng why you can sit down and read. Sometimes find things that ■will help you in your school. I like s of wars and great men of wars." "I like to read a real good book for it helps me in my reading. Some Library books I read are very good and the stories are so interesting that I hate to finish them." One of the older "boys" "writes : tl think the Library is one of the finest things we . I am quite a reader myself. I think eood books magazines give us good knowledge of the past life present. And reading is a good passed time." It is with the permission of our Japanese and Filinino friends that their names are used respectively in the following letters, written from the Tuberculous hospital: "I am one of those who enjoy the sisht of books and love to fondle them with full devotion; m other words I feel that 'we do not love them because they help us here and there; or make us wiser or better: we love them be - cause they are "what they are and we are what we are,' as admirable Mr. Powys writes in one of his essays. Knt, especially, ever since T came to this hos^i^al I s learned and found out what it truly means to be a </seg>
            <seg id="p019">21 lover of books. Indeed if it were not for these books this life would be unbearable. Anyhow it was here in this little library that I first got acquainted with that delightful bookshop owner in Motley's 'The Haunted Bookshop,' and there is Conrad's 'Lord Jim' and 'Victory' which thrilled me with their sheer inagie prose; alsc I can not forget Miss Cather's memorably beautiful 'My Antonia'. In the recent books which you have sent us, I was deeply impressed by Rol - vaag's 'Giants in the Earth', and E. W. Howe's 'The Story of a Country Town', also Crane's 'The Red Badge of Courage'. Kith these books, you are responsible for bestowing on lese significant pleasures and my only regret is that n't thank you enough for what you are doing for us. I beg of you to forgive my artless way of expressing humble gratitude, and hoping that you "will bless us some more good books in the future, I remain." (Signed) Leo Toyama "Being one of the many constant readers at this in - stitution's library, I can not express in words, my ap - preciation toward your thoughtfulness in making pos - sible my access to the educational and entertaining books l&gt;v Joseph Conrad. Thomas Hardy, and K. Norris. They mean a lot to me — not only in relieving my mind from harboring nnpleaasnt thoughts, but keeping me quieter nn&lt;! greater satisfied which are very essential toward my cure. R consider my stay in this institution a rare luck be - ;p I take my cure under a good management and with Favorite books close at hand." (Signed) Augusto Franco Another patient writes: "To be in bed all the time would be an unbearable thinsr, but to have books to read is quite different. Such books as those by Zane Grey fill my hours with pleasure. Through their heroes I get more encouragement to fight valiantly and conquer the adversary — mine being T. B." Onr friends at the hospitals for the insane are also grateful for- books, as voiced in the following letters: "We, the inmates of the State Hospital for the Insane, appreciate very much your efforts to make life more pleasant for us by supplying all the nice books. During the nine years of my stay here I think I have read sev- </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Publicity 22 eral hundred of them. Reading makes one forget close confinement part of the time." "Libraries in institutions serve as a medium of great benefit and satisfaction, to which free access to patients is accorded at all times. The books are carefully read by a number." "Two years since I was able to read much, but before that, 0, my! Every book I considered worth reading I read. It's the best part of any one's life to be able to assimilate the ideas that live in books." "I wish to express my appreciation and enjoyment of access to books of the library. Being my favorite mode of recreation, the opportunity is especiallv welcomed by me." "I read little but facts, and find several excellent works along these lines : historical ; biographical ; habits, haunts, and other matter pertaining to wild animals and birds; customs of all peoples of the world. Fiction I seldom read, although some is elevating; also I might add that description and treatment of insanity was very in - teresting and instructive." "The books about children and home always interest me. Books of travel I like, especially the late ones." A woman patient writes: "We have a new supply every week and I always like to get hold of the Shake - speare books. I'm especially fond of a man's writing 1 ." "It is hard to say which are the best books in an in - stitution of this kind. Some read only fiction to pass the time away and I think never remember what they read; while some whose minds are not affected with de - lusions, like to read books pertaining to history. I like to keep well posted through the newspaper. I also like to study books in practical mechanics, being an engineer myself." The Library Commission publishes only a biennial re - port. Funds are insufficient for issuing a bulletin as is done in many states. Printed publicity is therefore confined to circular letters, sent as need determines, to space in the bulletins, of such organizations as the Parent-Teacher Association, the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs, the American Association of University Women, and to occasional editorials in state papers. An article in the November 1928 issue of the P. T. A. bulletin written by Miss Jennings, directs its readers to the Library Commission for the list of "Forty books all </seg>
            <seg id="p021">23 with requests for the list. "It pays to advertise". In its issue of March 5, 1927, the "Nebraska Farmer" made known the Library Commission's loan service to the state through its Home Circle department under the caption, "Study at Home." We quote from the article as written following an interview on the Reading with a Purpose courses : "Have you regretted not being able to study literature, psychology or art? If so, you will be interested to know that you can go to school at home and study along these and many other lines. Courses are offered in this home school on widely different subjects. Who is going to teach your school and "who will buy your books? The American Library Association which has organized these courses will be your teacher. A short introduction has been prepared and a short list of books on each subject is recommended. Your own Public Li - brary Commission at Lincoln will furnish the books free except for transportation." Then follows a list of the courses with annotations. This advertising brought im - mediate returns. We are quoting from a few of the I'e desire to enter your study at home courses on Children'. We are wondering if you have anything fer on Agriculture, Poultry or Dairying". "I am returning the booklets which I enjoyed immense - ly. With the notes I have taken I can study for months to come. Will send for other short courses when I ran out of fresh material for my mind." "I regret very much having been unable to study liter - ature but the public schools did not include it in their courses in Virginia twenty years ago when I went to school. I am just bubbling over with joy at this oppor - tunity. Kindly send me books for history and literature The foregoing, with many other requests came from towns which do not have public libraries. "Why not" county libraries for such? January 24, 1928, "The Omaha Daily Journal-Stock - man" gave considerable editorial space to the work of the Library Commission under the heading "State Libra - ry Commission offers books on almost any subject to rural readers." We appreciate this publicity which showed an understanding of the work which we are try - ing to do. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">24 Following the reading of the secretary's annual letter in March 1928, it was suggested by Judge Letton that a digest of it be sent to the newspapers of the state. Ac - cordingly a circular letter was mailed to about two hun - dred Nebraska papers. It is not possible to check the returns, but we received some interesting letters and marked copies of a few papers. The article was given front page space by some. By return mail one editor wrote: "Your request for publicity not only met with favorable consideration but spurred us to the point of writing to ask for a volume that would assist the writer in improving his efforts in public speaking." Is has been stated, the biennial report of the Library mission is the department's only publication. It is desire by that means to give an idea of the nature scope of the work. We also incorporate notes re - e to our public libraries and library associations, its library statistics alone a complete file of the re - should be in every library in the state. It is our :estion that the reports be bound, six issues to a me, and be kept at hand for ready reference. When a biennial report has gone on its way after all the ups and downs of issuance, it does not make us feel badly to receive letters of acknowledgment. We are quoting from two letters from across the sea which came upon receipt of our last report. Mr. Savage wrote Miss Nesbit, "It is very kind of you to send iis a copy of the Biennial report of the Nebraska Public Library Commis - sion. We are glad to have it. I am delighted that you enjoyed your visit to Edinburgh and am only sorry that we were not able to make more adequate preparation Another acknowledgment by J. M. Mitchell, Secretary to Lord Elgin, President of the Carnegie United Kingdom Trnst reads: "On behalf of my chairman, Lord Elgin, I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt of the in - teresting biennial report of the Nebraska Public Library Commission. I am desired to say that Lord Elgin is much interested in its contents and trusts that the work will continue to develop on the same satisfactory lines." t addition to printed publicity the Library Commis - has made known its resources by talks to audiences, and unseen. During the 1927 observance of Book Week the secre - tary gave six talks, five of which were on joint library </seg>
            <seg id="p023">25 Havelock (2), and Lincoln. She has also talked on the Library Commission to High School, College, and Uni - versity classes at Chadron, Fairfield, Hastings and Lincoln. Talks on the Commission have been given to clubs at Douglas, Edgar, Harrison, Shelby, Lincoln, and University Place. At the 1928 meeting of the N. L. A. at Xorth Platte the secretary told of the work of the Commission under the title "Ask me another." In December, 1927, in connection 'with the meeting of Organized Agriculture at Sidney, the secretary gave a talk to the women on children's reading. She is to talk at similar meetings in December, 1928, at Alliance and in January, 1929, at Lincoln. In 1927, she also gave talks at the Library Institute on Library administration, Books "As readable as fiction" and Poetry for children. Miss Nesbit gave a talk op Reference work. The institute was arranged by the Commission and was held at the Commission office. the radio has also been used as a means of publicity the Library Commission and in disseminating a gen - interest in books and reading. In 1927 the secre - ' prepared a series of six radio talks on the Commis - and other library topics. Due to her illness three hese were kindly read by Mr. Diers of the University lio. Eiring 1927 and 1928, Miss Tobitt and members of Omaha public library staff gave 15 minute radio i each Saturday evening. Talks were given daily IK Book Week by members of the staff. {1927, Mr. Doane gave a series of fifteen radio talks ubjects relating to libraries, the history of printing, books. From February to July of 1928, he again dcasted on each Friday. During the fall of 1928, 'Library Hour" comes at 2 :30, once a month on Mon - when his talks are a half hour in length. This gives irtunity for clubs to have Mr. Doane's talks as s of their program Exhibits have come to be a regular part of the Com - mission's program. We regard these as means of pub - licity. Extensive exhibits were arranged for the library institute and for the N. L. A. meetings of 1927 and 1928. Exhibits were sent to Kearney in 1927 and to Omaha in 1928 for the meetings of the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs. The secretary attended both meetings </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Needs 26 and explained to many interested women the work of the Commission. At Kearney she was assisted by the state chairman of Library Extension, Mrs. W. T. Fried of Beemer, and at Omaha by Mrs. Mae Durbin of Bloom- An exhibit was sent to Grand Island in 1927 for a dis - trict meeting of the Nebraska State Teachers' Associa - tion. We also placed an exhibit at the Park school, Lin - coln, for the Teachers' Association in 1928. An exhibit was sent to the 1928 meeting of the Parent-Teacher As - sociation held at Kearney. The publications of the American Library Association were featured in all these exhibits. The Library Com - mission is glad to supply the list of A. L. A.'s publica - tions on request. At the suggestion of Professor Gooding of the Agricul - tural College, a collection of books for a farm home li - brary was exhibited at the State Fair in 1927. Two hun - dred books were made available during the 1927 summer session of the University for the class in children's liter - ature by the late Professor Searson. A like collection was arranged for Miss Pyrtle's class in 1928. An exhibit of children's books was used to illustrate a talk to the women of the Organized Agriculture meeting at Sidney in Posters and books have been sent for exhibit during Book Week of 1927 and 1928 to Beatrice, Beemer, Coler - idge. Hastings, Havelock, Hooper, Kearney, Madison. North Platte, Plattsmouth. Scribner, Superior, Wayne, and Winside. For several years we have registered the need for additional service to the state by the Library Commis - sion. Comparing the tenth biennial period with the fourteenth, the requests filled and the volumes loaned are as follows: Biennial period Requests Loans 1918—1920 4.020 58.540 1926—1928 10,882 118,684 This is an increase cf 167% in requests in ten years. Over the same period there has been an increase of 102 per cent in loans. This has been accomplished by a staff augmented by the half time of one person and a slight increase in hourly assistance. We have stressed the need of a sufficient staff to visit all libraries of the </seg>
            <seg id="p025">27 I! each two years. As previously referred to in this rt the increased appropriation oi the last legislature of material help in meeting the requests for special and in systematically visiting the libraries. Ie have kept faith by using as advantageously as ible the fund available. There remains much to be . Visits of longer duration for definite assistance needed. We have therefore submitted in our legis - e estimates, a request for a salary fund that will be nensurate with these needs. Extra travel requires a maintenance. Request has been made for an in - ise in the maintenance fund. Iiere has been no increase in the book fund in ten s. It was cut one third during one two-year period. ie requests for books are at all adequately met, more ey must be provided. At midwinter last year, there : forty-five requests for traveling libraries which d not be filled within a reasonable period of time, patience of both borrower and staff is unduly taxed uch a condition. Our estimate accordingly includes iquest for a substantial increase in the book fund. PUBLIC LIBRARIES There were 134 tax-supported libraries in Nebraska two years ago, 21 of which were township libraries. The number of towns now levying tax for municipal and township libraries is 141. One of these, Hemingford, is not given in the libraries listed elsewhere in this report because the tax was but recently levied and no statis - tics are yet available. Soon after the printing of our last ,report, Ord passed from an association to a taxed library, the levy being made by the township. As the only Nebraska town of over 2000 population, which did not maintain a library, with the exception of South Sioux City, we were glad indeed to welcome Ord. The other towns added within the past two years are Crof - ton, Dakota City, Merriman, Oshkosh, Scotia and Spring - field. Crofton is a township librbary. Axtell has also received township support for the past year. Merriman has a meager income but its library beginning is of pecu - liar interest due to its location in big Cherry, a county of 5,979 square miles. Cambridge. Oakdale and South Sioux City each receive a small amount annually for li - brary use. We hope they may soon be listed as or- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">28 ganized libraries. By annexation we have lost one li - brary, University Place no* being a part of Lincoln. On comparing the last biennial period with the preced - ing one, we find that the general status of Nebraska li - braries is improving somewhat. Forty-five show an in - crease in income, twenty-two a decrease while the re - maining sixty-seven have made practically no change in the amount received. Twenty libraries report an increase in salaries, three a decrease. The report on expendi - tures for books is regrettable. Only twenty-eight libraries report an increase in the amount spent for books while thirty-four have decreased their book fund. Extensive repairs in eight libraries and unusually high overhead expenses in eleven others probably account in part for inroads into the book fund. Seventy-two libraries show a gain in circulation, twenty-three a loss. Kie following list of twenty-five towns report a libra - lcorae of $1.00 or more per capita, the amount which A. L. A. considers a reasonable ' minimum revenue, i is an increase of five in a two-year period. Arcadia* Lexington Arnold* Loup City •• Clarks* Madison Clay Center Merna* College View Orleans" David City Shelton* Fairbury Sutton Fairficld Wakefield Geneva . Wansa* Oothenburg Wayne Hartinsrton Winsido Harvard TYvmorc Hebron B'hose starred are township libraries, the population idered being that of the unit taxed. twns having within $100.00 of $1.00 per capita are: i, Friend, Morrill, Newman Grove, North Bend, Stan - and Tilden. There have been 23 changes in librarians in the past two years. By death we have lost three. Marearet God - den of Ashland, Mrs. P. H. Parker of Plainview and Belle Schick of Seward. A member of the Ashland li - brary board writes in appreciation of Miss Godden: "Margaret Godden. librarian of the Ashland Library, passed away October 14, 1927. She served the city as </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Gifts and Buildings 29 librarian for nearly five years and during her term of of - fice the library prospered. She tried to make it a vital part of the community. Miss Godden was uniformly helpful and courteous to all classes of patrons and as a consequence was beloved by the children and highly re - spected by the older readers. Her work was character - ized by a high quality of efficiency and conscientious at- Ri to details. She was retiring by nature and even in close touch with the library were not always of the patient labor which she put in to make it a to the community. Her passing is not only a loss library but to the "ntire community." SMrs. Parker died AdhI 16. 1928. The following is ien from a Plainview paper in tribute to her service as rarian: "The library was dedicated twelve years ago d the predominating personality of these years is that the beloved woman who served as librarian for that ne. Mrs. Parker's task was a labor of love. Each detail of her 'work was carefully done and because of her efforts our library is reaching a large number of readers young and old. She remains with us a sweet memory and a hallowing influence." Miss Schick died a little more than two years ago. 'he fact of her death was not known to us prior to rinting onr last report. Therefore no mention of it was iade at that time. A member of the library board; of Seward says of Miss Schick: "She was appointed li - vrarian in 1913 and held that position until her death November 7. 1926. She was a faithful and efficient ibrarian, especially anxious to improve the quality rath - r than the quantity of reading done." We regret that Mary McQuaid of the Pairbury public library has left the Nebraska field of library service. We are glad to report that she is happy in her work in Oakland, California, 'where she has charge of a branch library. ■ Nebraska has been the recipient of gifts from the Carnegie Corporation in the building of sixty-eight libra - ries. "The corporation has by no means abandoned its interest in library service, but it feels that in so far as buildings are concerned its work has been accomplished," "wrote Dr. Learned of the Corporation some time ago. Nebraska libraries are, however, receiving gifts from the same source in the form of books known as the Inter - national Mind Alcove. In explanation of this gift we are </seg>
            <seg id="p028">30 quoting Dr. Nicholas Murray Butler, President of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, who says, "An important function of a well-trained librarian is to select for the serious reader books that will broaden his outlook. To aid librarians in this work of selection, so far as may concern the field of international relations, the Carnegie Endowment has established in certain pub - lic libraries what are known as the International Mind Alcoves. The books placed in these alcoves are chosen from the most recent publications that bear upon the customs, the art, the culture, the government, or the ge - ography of foreign nations and peoples. The Internation - al Mind Alcoves are to stimulate the international mind." In answer to application, several Nebraska libraries are receiving small shipments of these books, for which they are very appreciative. There are other libraries which are on a waiting list and will receive their gift as promptly as the Corporation finds it possible to supply the books. The Library Commission made application in 1927 for the I. M. A. and has received several ship - ments. We are using these books in the spirit that prompts the gift, trying to aid in the purpose for which they are intended. An exhibit of the Commission col - lection was enthusiastically received by the members of the Nebraska Library Association at its state meeting in 1928. It is onr hope to have Amy Heminway Jones, the Division Assistant throncrh whom correspondence is car - ried on, as a speaker on the program of our next N. L. A. meeting. Iifts for Nebraska library- buildings are now coming n within our borders in a generous snm sufficient to t a building or by popular subscription representing interest, perhaps sacrifice, of manv citizens. In each ; peculiar interest attaches to the -ways and means which these new homes have been made possible. |»r a number of years Central City has been agitating question of more adequate library, quarters. The ilem has been solved by a generous gift from a eer resident. Mrs. Melvin C. Hards, who has given 000.00 for the purpose of erecting a library as a me - ial to her husband. "Mrs. Hards has been deenly rested in the advancement of education and has ed as a member of the library board for several ■s. The library is to be well located near the new ral building. The city provided the site. Construe- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">31 Ewill be pushed as rapidly as possible and the library Id be ready for use in the spring. Every resident le city feels grateful to Mrs. Hards for her public ted act." Iiridgeport, Nebraska, is occupying a new library ne. The secretary of the library board writes: "The man's Club had wanted a home of their own for years. s main thing was financing it. They decided to erect milding and allow the library exclusive use of the st floor, they to use the basement. The building of iwn and white stucco is 36 feet by 26 feet, and cost 400. The library board pays the club twenty dollars a month rental. It is a very satisfactory arrangement Kthe parties concerned." Elsewhere in this report the active, home-like building is" pictured. After a long period ci waiting for library quarters, Sargent now has a well-located building, adapted to its needs, with space for growth. The library board purchased a residence for about $3,700 and remodeled it at a cost of $1,000. Sargent is a township library. Soon after Dakota City was given a tax levy for libra - ry purposes, a building program was launched. To show how the hope of this building was realized through the energies of a small group of women, we are quoting from one of them who writes: "Years ago in the heart and mind of one of our members was a dream of a pub - lic library for our village. This idea was voiced in the Wednesday literary club as early as 1918, but met with incredulity that a dozen women could build a library. In 1920 it %vas voted 'to talk of the matter again', and in 1922 a motion was passed ' to start the movement to build a library for the use of the citizens of Dakota City.' The town board offered its assistance and levied a small tax. Money was also raised by socials and subscrip - tions and the venture was launched. Then followed a book reception which made the beginning of the book collection. For some time the library Was located in the town hall, but there has long been need of more room. In April, 1928, the club decided to start a building fund, and voted 'that a committee of men be asked to help with the building project.' Committees were appointed and plans to raise money were started. The men were asked to decide upon the site. A lot was purchased for $100. Work began on the building in the early summer and it was opened for use November 10, 1928. The building which is of brown brick is 22 feet by 28 feet. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">32 Davenport Public Library It was erected at a cost of about $2,200. One of the most interesting library situations is that at Davenport, where the town en masse has taken a part in erecting a community building in which the libra - ry is housed. The building was dedicated November 23, 1928. Davenport does not have a tax-supported library though it will no doubt become such. "The Woman's Club of Davenport is responsible for the new $10,000 library and community building, dedicated to 'the youth of the community' on November 23, 1928. Mr. M. M. Jennings gave the site. The growth of the library and the raising of the bud - get would make an interesting tale. Beginning with a book shower of 200 volumes and cash donations of $350, in 1921, the library has gradually increased and has made itself a real institution in the town and community. The members of the Clubs serve as librarians. With a be - quest of $1,000 and the promise of $500 and a building site these energetic women raised the budget by means of dinners, home talent plays, rummage sales, ball games, traveling fond sales, vanishing luncheons, and pledges. More than fifty pioneer citizens are memorialized through gifts to the building fund. Their names will ap - pear on a bronze tablet placed in the library. The reading room with an alcove for club meetings is on the first floor, and a -community room, in the base - ment with full equipment, including a kitchen, will ac - commodate more than 100. Davennort is justly proud of its achievement." </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Book Week and Vacation Reading 33 Eok Week grows in favor. Many libraries are ob- Dg it regularly. Suggestions issued by the National ciation of Book Publishers are useful in arranging programs ■which include costume plays and pageants, movie slides and radio talks. Because of frequent in - quiry we are here giving the address of the N. A. B. P. It is 25 West 33rd Street, New York City, Miss Marion Humble, Executive secretary. Vacation reading is also becoming a part of the libra - ry's summer program. We are quoting Mrs. Anderson of the Beatrice public library regarding their plan to in - terest the little vacationers of 1928: "We tried this summer to make the reading in our juvenile department of an educational nature without having our purpose too obvious. This idea was carried out by our 'Travel Club' in which the children took a trip around the world in books. Each child who wished to join the tour was given a ticket with his name, the countries he visited and the books he read. The tourists were required to visit at least ten countries, reading one book on each country, and to report briefly to the librarian some of the things that he learned. The following letter was sent to the children: T)ear little Friend: tDid you know about our 'Travel Club' in which We are king a trip around the world in booksT It is such fun read about how "Wretched Flee" got his queer name and how differently the children of other lands dress. There is still time to join our club and read these books. The last week in August We are having a party to which all who have read at least ten books are invited. At this party will be children from many lands. Each child may dress in the costume of his favorite country. Oh, yes! of course you know about our honor roll. Everyone who doesn't have a fine on his card has his name on the honor roll. If you have fines be sure and pay them soon so we may add your name. Goodbye until next week. Sincerely, The Library.' The trip lasted three months after which the library gave a party for the tourists who had completed the journey. The children dressed in the costumes of their favorite foreign country. Over 100 children enrolled in the 'Travel Club' and the number at the party was be - tween 40 and 50." </seg>
            <seg id="p032">34 COUNTY LIBRARIES "The County Library Comes Home to the People" The days are growing shorter; the long evenings are at hand. The weather is not so warm, and ourminds naturally turn to indoor things to do as we drawabout the fire. We find after the chores, the dishes, and other things are dona, the paper read and the lessons ready for tomorrow, that the members of the family, especially the children, are wanting something to do until bedtime. A small boy of the family, restless, as small boys some - times are, breaks upon the family by saying, "I wish I had a good book to read". Rather wistful looks on the faces of some of the other members of the family be - tray the fact that a book might not come amiss with K other says, "Why don't you bring a book home from .olt" "I've read all of those; but when I was at Beatrice I saw a book I want to read. The boys over there say it is a dandy. It's 'Treasure Island'. And then there was a book called 'Smoky' that they said won a prize last year. It is a story of a cow horse. And there was an - other prize story that the boys and girls both liked. It was about a carrier pigeon. I think its name was 'Gay Neck'." "Where did they get these books T Had they bought them? They must have cost a good deal", said Mother. "No, they had borrowed them from the Library." If ew days later the boy comes home from school 5 excited than usual. "I wa3 telling the teacher it wanting some books, and then she told us that t is a way to get books, so we could have them here ome, almost any book we want. Not just books like e Jim had, but books that you and Father and Sis d like, too. She says a lot of people get books that » "But son," Mother patiently explains, "Miss James doesn't realize how little money we have to spend for such things. It would cost us more money than we could afford to pay to have all the books we would like to "No, Mother, Teacher says it wouldn't cost each of us any more than it would to buy one common book or take one magazine. You see everyone in our county could </seg>
            <seg id="p033">35 I one library. They call it a 'county library,' Mother, the whole county buys the books and passes them nd. Then we would have as much chance to read s as they do in big cities. I wish I knew as many !8 as Jim's cousin does — that one that comes from ha. The last time he came to visit Jim he told Jim me the most stories about other countries and every - :. He says he has library books at home all the time. Kut, son, he lives near the library. When there is one library in the whole county, it might be too far for us to go often. And maybe when you wanted )k it would be at the other end of the county." "No, Mother, we woudn't have to go to the library to get books. We could go any time we wanted to, but teacher says they'd send out books to stores or schools. She says sometimes they send out trucks of books and the trucks have shelves in them and they are just like book cases on each side. The trucks go around to every farm house and we could each pick out our own books. If there was any book we wanted like 'Smoky', or Treasure Island' or that one about the pigeon, we'd just tell the truck driver and he'd bring it to us next time. And if the truck couldn't come the librarian would mail us the books we wanted. We'd just have to phone her what we wanted. And any time you wanted to call her up and ask her about anything, you could." f other catches some of her son's enthusiasm. "Do suppose a librarian could tell me what was the mat - with my cucumber plants t" I She could find out anything in books. Teacher told about one woman who saved her turkeys by n-abing librarian what to do. She lived in Wisconsin, and her keys were all sick and she tried everything she ught might cure them. Finally she asked the librarian a book on turkey-raising. When she read it she raed exactly what to do for her sick turkeys and she ed them. Turkeys were high that year and she made ee hundred dollars on the turkeys she saved by read- "Miss James says it is better to have a county library Ei a small one in each town because one building for whole county doesn't cost so much to build and the ltry people have just as much chance to get books Bthe ones living in town do. The whole county can buy re books and they can get a better librarian. She </seg>
            <seg id="p034">36 who has been to a school where they teach them just what kind of books to buy for everyone to read. It costs more to hire that kind of a librarian, but Teacher says she goes around over the country and gets acquainted with everyone so she can know what kind of books they will want. I wish we had a county library. "I wish we did, my boy. But I don't suppose anyone in this county would start one; I have never heard of any in this state." i*Jo. Miss James says there aren't any in Nebraska But there are good ones in some other states, and knows what they have to do to start one. I suppose •yone would have to want one first, don't you, herf I know everyone would like it if they had it. bet we would read a lot if we had the books. I've 1 every one of those books at school. Some of them ive read over and over." K [other, as she folds away her sewing, thinks much e of their nsed for books than she lets her son know, will be time for you to help get the cows up by the &gt; you get your clothes changed." KFes, Father will be wondering whew I am. I wish had a county library though. I wish our county d be the first one in all Nebraska to have one." As she watches her boy Mother thinks of his future. L:ke all mothers, she wants her children to have as many advantages as possible. What if there could be a county library in her very own county! She could find a few spare minutes between her busy hours to read bocks she has always wanted to read. She would like to know more about the people who live in countries she can never visit. She would like to know about the people who have become famous; she would like to know more convenient ways of doing her work. And then some - times she would enjoj going far away from her work, in some story. -How much their whole community would be helped by a library, by a library large enough to fur - nish anything that anyone wanted. The only way they conld have one that large would be by having a county tr son's last "words, "I wish our county could be the one in all Nebraska to have one !" come back to her* has the same wish, just as some others she knows </seg>
            <seg id="p035">The N.L.A 37 splendid opportunity for her club to help the community ! If there are other mothers 'who would like to have theii count} be the first one in Nebraska to have a county library — if they see the advantages of it and would like to know more about it — the Nebraska Public Library Commission at Lincoln, will gladly furnish information to anyone who is interested. The foregoing story is found in Extension Circular 592, prepared by the Library Commission for Miss Brown of the Agricultural College as a part of her 1928 year book. Twenty-five hundred women are enrolled in her clubs for this year. Copies of the circular may be obtained from the Nebraska Public Library Commission. The A. L. A. has pamphlets on the subject which we send in quantity to a county requesting it. There is also good material in Farmers' Bulletin No. 1559, called "Rural Libraries" issued by the U. S. Department of Agriculture. Lit is true, as the small boy said, that we have no unty libraries in Nebraska. However, there is active interest in several counties. Deuel and Sioux counties have put on programs to acquaint the people with the county library idea. Other counties are making inquiry and requesting material. In writing for Circular No. 592, quoted herein, the borrower says, "I wish ours might be the first county in Nebraska to get a county library." It was with regret that the Library Commission in 1927 declined the use of a book truck offered us by the A. L. A. through Miss Merrill of the Library Extension Di - vision. There is nothing which makes a greater appeal to the secretary than a "Parnassus on wheels", but it seem - ed at that time impossible to finance its use. Efforts to interest a few libraries of the state in the book truck were unavailing because they felt that they could not meet the problem of equipment. It is our hope that the practical demonstration of a county library by means of a book wagon may sometime be accomplished. Per - haps we may not have to decline so kindly an offer a second time. LIBRARY ASSOCIATIONS The 1927 officers of the Nebraska Library Associa - tion sent out May and September news of the state meet- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">38 ing to be held in Lincoln, October 13 and 14. In answer to the question "Why go!" they said: Eo keep the trend of the library profession, the only means of a library get-to-gether, Because we really want to go." Perhaps this helped in securing unusual attendance at the 32nd annual meeting of the N. L. A. The registration reached 123 which is 20 more than at any previous meet - ing. The sessions were held at the city and university libraries, the president, Miss Langdon, librarian of Ne - braska Wesleyan University, presiding. Miss Wheeler, North Platte, was vice president. Miss Nesbit of the Library Commission was secretary. Members of the Commission had part in this meeting. Miss Tobitt gave a talk on Library Personnel and Mr. Doane read his "Legend of the Book." Judge Letton greeted the librari - ans at the state library in the beautiful new Nebraska Capitol. Mrs. W. E. Minier, of Oakland, president of the Nebraska Federation of Women's Clubs, talked on the Club Women and the Library, tracing the history of women's clubs and giving a survey of the relationship between the Nebraska Federation and Nebraska Libra - ries. One session of the program was devoted to School Libraries, Miss Harris, of the Teachers College of the University, presiding. There were two evening programs of especial interest. Miss Jennings gave us glimpses of libraries of other lands together with many other things gleaned while on a world tour. George B. Utley, a former president of the A. L.* A. and librarian of the Newberry library, Chicago, gave a delightful talk on Rare Books. As an added feature of the evening, Mr. Doane had on display some of the rare books in the University library. Invitations for the 1928 meeting came from Beatrice, Kearney, Lincoln, and North Platte. I a October 11 and 12, 1927, preceding the N. L. A. :ing, the Library Commission held a library institute i several former years. We are particularly pleased eport an attendance of fifty-five, the largest pre - s registration being thirty-three. Seven of the num- Were trustees. Forty-fonr libraries in thirty conn - were represented. They came from Otoe on the east, ttsbluff on the west, Boyd on the north and Harlan the south. Obviously, considerable distance was eled by some of those attending the institute. When goes three or four hundred miles, we feel that it be- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">39 Iiks a genuine interest. The secretary was assisted in institute program, by Miss Taylor of the Omaha pub - ibrary, Miss Nesbit of the Commission, Miss Wheeler he North Platte public library and Mrs. Anderson of Beatrice public library. The executive committee of the N. L. A. chose North Platte as the meeting place for 1928. Miss Wheeler as president was also hostess to the enthusiastic group which gathered in the library to attend the sessions of October 4 and 5. The news letter sent out by the secre - tary, Miss Harris, read: "You don't want to miss the western hospitality of one of Nebraska's friendliest, growingest cities." Those who did miss it, missed one of the best things that the library association has been privileged to enjoy. The attendance was sixty which is very creditable considering distances traveled. We are quoting from Miss Harris' report of the pro - gram: "Miss Kramph told in most interesting fashion of her experience as trustee of the North Platte library since its early history. She also spoke an enthusisatic word for county libraries in Nebraska. An interesting P. T. A. session occupied one afternoon. Mrs. Crosby of North Platte talked on the relation of the parent to the public library. Mr. Anderson of the Teachers College, Kearney, spoke of co-operation between the 'P. T. A. and the libraries. Mrs. Reed of the Lincoln city library told of their work with the P. T. A. She gave much in - formation about children's books from her fund of know. ledge. Mr. Matthew S. Dudgeon, of the Milwaukee public li - brary in his address on Adult Education mentioned the emphasis that is now being placed on reading as an im - portant method of instruction. As chairman of the A. L. A. committee on the library and adult education Mr. Dudgeon was interested in knowing how the board can best help the smaller libraries. fr. Malcolm G. Wyer of the Denver pubic library e on the Ethics of librarianship. Mr. Wyer received rdial welcome as a former member and as a friend any of those present. In his pleasant conversation - anner he brought out by story and incident some of finer points of ethics which relate to librarianship. Es. Woodruff of the Lincoln city library gave a talk b professional reading of the librarian, in which she that all of the librarian's reading becomes profes - [ as it helps her to serve her patrons better. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">A.L.A 40 Miss Ingles of Omaha Technical High School library read her interesting paper, Glimpses of some Europeon libraries. She said that her first impression in visiting the European libraries concerned the greater reverence shown for books and the lesser attention given to ser - vice as compared with the libraries of our own country." Invitations for the 1929 meeting of the N. L. A. were extended by Beatrice, Grand Island, Kearney, Lincoln, and Omaha. Beatrice is the place selected. There was an invitation given by Mrs. Wilson, librarian of the Scottsbluff public library, to hold an A. L. A. Regional meeting there in 1930. The officers elect are president, Mrs. Johnson, Madi - son public library, first vice president, Miss Kramph. North Platte. second vice president, Miss Mallalieu. deputy state librarian, secretary. Miss Harris, Teachers College, University of Nebraska. From time to time through the text of this report re - ference is made to the American Library Association, of which the Nebraska Library Association is an affili - ated chapter. It is our desire that the close relation existing between our state and national organizations be continued. We wish to urge membership in the A. L. A. as well as in the N. L. A. It is also desirable for every librarian to become acquainted with the A L. A. publications. We feel that many of our libraries should place a stand - ing order for these. Made possible by the Carnegie Corporation, four li - brary institutes were held under the auspices of the American Library Association in the spring of 1927. Ne - braska was fortunate to come within range of the St. Louis meeting, May 31 to June 9. It Was our pleasure to have Miss Nesbit in attendance throughout the in - stitute. "It was a wise old Indian chief who first murmured the word 'Toronto', a place of meeting. And presently the Englishman, loving his play upon words, chuckled — 'A good city, To-run-to' ". So the good citv Toronto was the chosen meeting place of the A. L. A. in 1927, June 20 to June 25. This was the third A. L. A. con - ference to be held in Canada. Her literary and library capital proved so attractive that attendance was second only to that of the semi-centenary meeting of the pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p039">41 V X\J UQ j CmX • X rcoiUClit UW*. J^C E? XXtt^ yj \ III cH III CT LfUUXxX bated much to the success of the conference." Library E secretary of the Library Commission was invited I a paper on Book selection for hospital libraries, was not possible for her to attend the Toronto Miss Gates of the Omaha public library kindly sub - mits the following: "The American Library Association conference of 1928, was held at West Baden, Indiana, at the end of May. The setting of the roomy old West Baden Hotel, surrounded by golf links, bridle paths, woods and for - mal gardens, in the height of the peony season, was a refreshment in itself. One of the most timely papers wag given by Charles H. Compton, on the Outlook for Adult Education in the library. Mr. Compton had made a survey on the occupa - tional types who were taking reading courses in the St. Louis Public Library. He found that 'the readers of the Greek Classics include: printers, clerks, sales - men, a cabinet maker, a draftsman, stenographers, a musician at a vaudeville theater, a colored insurance agent, a hairdresser, a chauffer, a drug store clerk, a beauty specialist, a butcher, a telephone operator, a re - porter and a railroad brakeman's wife.' In his genial way Mr. Compton warned us against making propaganda of the Adult Education movement, suggesting rather the importance of personal service to the individual reader, offered with the least possible red tape. Ir. Bishop, Librarian of Michigan University, made a rt on the momentous work which is being done ugh the Committee on International Relations, men - ing his trip to the Vatican Library. In connection John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gift of two million dollars be League of Nations, for a library, it was decided eorganize and catalog the Vatican Library to serve international body of scholars who come to Rome, i task may take ten years but will make available for arch the valuable material of one of the greatest &gt;rical libraries in the world. Altogether the conference represented such varied ed - ucational interests as to be a thrilling experience. Kveral Nebraska librarians attended both the Toronto West Baden meetmffs. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">42 * jM—tiw\ttcofl * Education, Miss Harris, Miss Ingles; In - ■titational libraries, Miss Nesbit; Membership, Miss Bftomer; Junior membership, Mrs. C. A. Anderson, Pub - licity, Miss Tobitt. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">43 SUMMARY OF STATISTICS Volumes accessioned to December 1, 1926 37,850 Volumes in library December 1, 1926 30,631 Volumes added from December 1, 1926 to November 30, 1928 4,663 Volumes withdrawn to December 1, 1926 7,219 Volumes withdrawn from December 1, 1926 to November 30, 1928 597 Volumes accessioned to November 30, 1928 42,513 Volumes in library November 30, 1928 34,697 EXPENDITURES DEC. 1, 1926 to NOV. 30, 1928 From From Appropriation Appropriation 1925—1927 1927—1929 Books - $1,805.39 $4,199.24 Maintenance - 1,434.15 2,380.01 Binding 470.12 640.50 Intitntional libraries 2,216.30 2,884.10 Salaries and wages 3,686.92 10,295.00 $9,612.88 $20,398.85 9,612.88 Total $30,011.73 Appropriation July 1, 1927 to June 30, 1929....$31,800.00 Expended July 1, 1927 to November 30, 1928.. 20,398.85 Balance 11,401.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">44 j i — *. J ' &gt;&gt;s g- ? » Kfl e « fl 2 -c j: J I .5 gQ II eq o •*»&lt;■ « HO kft .-H T-l O IB erf o a: »O 1-1 I 2 f IONO O© C VC C O lO O gS OO 115 M O C Cl fl ps^w a h &lt;s ico oc ic io in III BONHNONWaONintDCCWWNC at od e li o e a o t- c x ci im x n a i^i-l&gt;-lOCi— t-CM &gt;— Cl C-: r- 00 iJliii! lii 1 1 liil MMvMm 1? J * * '^ * ° •- o o o •* ■* ° « » ooctrtsSiSc — — d; z k tc k J k ! J a i I ' !i </seg>
            <seg id="p043">45 S 05 ■" S .3 03(5 &lt;* .2 .15 a =3 g e8 T3 » £ J3 N 1 &lt;^ rt © S3 _, J3 * ~ B5 «S S ? « s *&gt; ® 2 O •£ J «S W . S .-a g § H -J OQ o t- c t ij O O O CO O o «o o co Tt&lt; cij co os r /OCOOi--o*05SOOOO J»qeDONNON9H«OB O «5l&gt;~»0-&lt;jr o^c&gt;f^H' r H" r^' r 4-o' C g L C&gt; CO rH r-( r-l § ii i i H a a a a &lt; ~o "o "3 "5 I j I j III] S-PIJJ ? 3 .2 -2 O &gt;-3 O, QQ OQ* I 02 I s § t | j 1 1 I !]]]] i I oill-S-s^llail-Ie o85.aj5s-3aasaa8 j « ta j o « o iS (S q q q tc t2 s* 1 1 1 ij ilji J IHMbHSSSN* O a^af eaB a g fl sod: £ o S !&gt;o a fl -g c c o a '-3 S I s 02 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">46 "3 ■§ "3 piilWlJi fill I UiimUUMtih I ! w&gt;:S!355S£ 0^ 0 S 0: **-t&gt;©»-'Ci©©©©«i J • • « a q e o o io e e e e w e io e e s IO ii U5 CD &lt;N © « N t- •«* oT i-7 «T Tf eT O IO" ► ihoi-i iHcaeorieo N liliiiill-i-i^^-iiB&amp;H-B I is* i iU^^I i ! I -111! i lfaliS!iIi3 j \ Ii|| iilJIlfSlJJJJlSJ MiJiJiJtJSZ^OOOCODQDCCOQpptx I </seg>
            <seg id="p045">47 ffl 3 | -g „ 1 ii^ii- a sii^ii «i , . . *H • • • ■ I* » J J j J J 00 CO CD 2 CO CO CO ID S EC DO K * , 03 CD notiupiMiQ oo?-«eoio*oon « o o_ia_ o'rjT-H'oo'i-ro'r-reo'ad'ad'oJ'oo «d~(M cT riHCO rHrHiH rHiH iH sanmjoA ■*" us" ci" co" co u^ co" i-T ei" *" ei" t» w" n qasM. J9d sjnog ioeeangoneo | fioSS Hn nhcqcoh co ca&gt;-iweoeoi-itH *"HO OOiON(-OioOc&lt;]NOHH : O5 »»U3«H!SiaHsilOH»« ;^l 72 I— I B(V0ipOU9j pus s^oog ooo^ooaoioter-joogo© t-»«noaii»(Nn2;2S2!S2 HHSNNIOH c^«®»°'*'C^eO sauBfeg OOOlOOOlM^oSOOOOOO OrH00'«|iTt&lt;0»e»OoOOOOeg&lt;0 io &gt;o &lt;:&gt;_« eje»^jtiH(oco«a»aorH'* ooo^oooioo^noeoob- b-OOOlOCMOCOoOOOOOOt- lH"co"rH" l-T W" r4" r-T N OI i-T" amoDnj paqsijqBjsa «3A Hoaoeosooo2N*«io» HOOHHWHHNONHOMH saoiaaaaaa9o»»o&gt;a rt'-li-li-liHi-li-li-lrH'-l'HiHrHrHrH 1 fi i$ fi » J" (sntraaa 0S6T) not^BpidOjj oaoooDOoisioNoonNso o^oaosoaiaiaooe^o t-7 t-T «" i-f iH iH rH rH* r4" cT C? cf M Ml I i MIHI II H N m*iooi»»oiorjeiim2 | o i-l r-t i-H i-&lt; l-H </seg>
            <seg id="p046">48 !flj!j|ililli,I h ....2 "3 £ ►&gt; » . J= . . aoijwpiojtQ 8»nniio^ e&gt;ii-it-ot~o«ot~m&gt;noi-ioa5ocaoci;» noxonoHONnonohoHioNTf » o_ n_ « t-^ n in © o s tji t&gt;_ s o n o n m*M. led BjnoH i- n n h j- n n«Hnn«*nH ,— •»1K) a t- n o n io h : h oo LO^fi--oo to • e t N n m h i-(t»iON * w r- n n r- »u»I»S' araoouj N S22 NOIOOOOe S l;lsoro N«: aDOaoocoouootcoOao^oooot-ic rf N H H pi r." I-T C-f r- r-T N* •*" i-l 9Sr "^SHoNo^iaoooo'-oier'insNK 01 d2« HHOrioio « i " r ' eoc ' iHHT - aasooaoaiaaoaoc-caociaoo: I (mmwo 0Z6X) 22J®22 o S tt&gt; oo©t^o»«^iooe »©o©go©«oooo»nQO-*r-ici©©'- &lt;Bt- ii (8n«!ni0SU3OW*ONTi&lt;l~(»00r' « m ri rt « h cf *eT i-T !-? cfirf i-7 th 0« i j | ■' 5 I i j : I I ! I I ] iilHIIilJIliJiJi!! II HHHH«iMN«cicin«NiMnnmnB </seg>
            <seg id="p047">49 — o fc •= » S3 q 'o "3 «'«aiii'i«ji&gt;i'J5w««ii»«'*^ • noi^BinaiiQ Nsoooonoi'NHiatoMnMiinri iomt-mo5r-(©'«}&lt;i-.i^eM-*0503osNNoc KS^C^t^t^Ct^lO^O CQ^O^t^r^iH &lt;D ■*_ © t&gt; t»- IO rt rt^lOiHSOi-liHlH r-t I saain|oA OCOCClM'tOi'Cl.'IOHOOODOOPlN co r-T »■ ef o" of pf t-T ■*" (-J csf pf pf ef eo" iH i-l i-( I 3J93M. jad sanojj ooo^naLioNooonooxon^n jaq^O ® :Ncot-io«iaoioeo&lt;)iannNO •*: co oj(Mo r -ie&lt;i'* to on ■** 3 siBoipouaj pats snoog co :tH^&lt;iHt» rt^n o^cch h nw fi co SaiJB[Bg oo :cocoiMOOoe«ino&lt;-toooo •*■* :t~Or-IOt^rH»-IO05OC0C'100'&gt;t»&lt;«' ion :NHHCoOwain*OH*^N« of J p* '- etnoouj i-- o :oooocoocooooaoioOoo -oo :»ioooccio'»'Oooi-ieoooo : s^cd oo oi^o sncj om« n v o ri of lo'i-Tpf t^'rn'rH'ef i-Ti-T of (ensnao 0S6I) noi^Bindoj a* OONnHNOianiOOOrtBMOONO l^OJOJ030000r-ti-l©^HOOi-(i-HO]iH xooiooaaQaoooaooaooo; i-liHiHi-lr-li-li-liHi-| I -li-li-lt-li-li-|t-lr-(i-l ooiioojo^-*oooer:o oo os © oi i-&lt; ■&amp; o&lt;)N«inioxooooeocoon(tir) ef i-7 of io" »c i-T «T r7 1-7 i-7 r-7 eo" i-T i-7 t-7 r-1 ■■« 2 A % s S H HI .&amp;-s I I | Jj3la"l2g||Eg.JjJgJJ ioes«o2SSn^2S N «2 OH^ </seg>
            <seg id="p048">50 aoi^Bjnojqj qiiislisllilillslSl saainio^ ss§sssss ISsgggssssi « (N W (N N 5O CO 1&gt;T „" N* rJ TIT © rH" TjT II ud sjnojj gssssssss^gsssg^ff^^ss C^W MB *N P) 00 ,- . O r-i «* HN : *^ 1-1 «qx) ■[vaipouaj pira sjjooy 2S Tt SS" 1 » loei -" no ' nolt "*t-t- o oOMMOnnHnoot- iM»n rt-S (N i-l OS «au«i»s •2 3SfcSSE2S lxl:300tDi n Ni nNooS o«TicnoHTi(CiHniEu:naiNHrio« n i-i r-T t»T amoooj *. N 1 » N . " o ° » o n ° § § m n S o t» N H t- N rTn T^r^ N tt cS "•A 3l5?l''!2t c ' 1 !;noce'. oioohhSh 855 H 2 o " c ' H c:c;rtOr-i-tjOHS Maeaooaocooocoaooaooaffio rlHHHHrlH'-HrirtrtriHHrtHrtH I as I (snsaaj 0Z6I) uoijBpidoj l.i 5 8 S g 5 S S&amp; S.S S3 S S g §§§ i-t HBHKHnOii cfoTi-ri-rrH"^ J I I I I I ! I ! ! i i i I i-l I ! I § •* | i ; ■ i ■ i ; i | ;■*'; ]ii]|]i)}1|ii{f,|H .•2 * ■si r- </seg>
            <seg id="p049">51 a 55 3 S| i.s e | 1 s B | liSllJljJSljIjilil . .as . . . . « . a . 2 2 S.gx &gt;. noijBinaiiQ I}13[I1JJ NlOONiiiOOH^ItONmNOOiao ** N Ol_lO 00 ri t~.»00 rtO_(r) H » « H 00 O o cfaTatf r-T'-H'rH'ort^sercrc^fafcrr-riCcrt^" i — i •— i i-Hi-i i-i i-i 1-irti «Oi-i©i-i 00 I saninio^ .til fiin ,_. OTfOm^OOtOOOOJCOCOr-IOOOOO [°A ocimtooo'-^omtvo^DiorHmot-mo » ■* » ro o&gt; »cc o) h in is &lt;o i oo &gt; '* o^cb os S io^'o'i^ TjTcs'c^rario'pfi-rorei'i-rco'r-rnfpf is oo nfiTT I j)39a Jdd sjno|j [10IJ 11 Sffln^iiNOOoaseionoNBoo' ocoi-i n « coHriH^nori^n III J3IJ totpois B S5{0( jaq;o tino iinHioioffis^NmnHioooo c-^-^co :mmu5t~«oot~c&lt;ii— &lt; to m cb i^ tr Ilr , OUJ13 ! i-l lONHriM^OOWOOOD CONOOldloOHHTHOBtllOBHCSO " CSffi-* r-IM COMHTfOOWOOTlinflr, CJ - fc 1 siBoipoiaaj pun sjfoog w — Oh S3UB[By S3UB[ amos &gt;-i©©c&gt;ioo»n50'j&lt;eo«oo©ooiraco©© ,_„ c;oooo©oO'*ro©r-iooc»5'l'©oo©Tf&lt;©Tt&lt; I B S o a t h t|i ia h * h •* co m n &lt;o o m * * oooooeioiitrtoNnonoooo ONOQOOHQO^lQOi&lt;P1NOOOOCO ouj o_ni3rtOHt&gt; cD_c^eqecao©^oo_(M o^©_ao - 1 -. ! &lt;: amoouj 21 5 paqstiqBjsg JB3 A JB OO-'MOr-iriOOaClOOHHl-rtM f8_j ooaoccc ooc. xocoosooooa T^i 1 1 (snsaaa 0 o6l) uoi;Bpidoj » 0c6 ii^Bpidi a o ■*- -I- "*- 31) o©oo«=©oo2 05 't (00m '^ tc ' OOOTt&lt; oo&lt;0"4&lt;©a:e&gt;[^o]ooioao(o©©©© lOj OOCC K C&lt;300 i C^0DC&lt;lt.O*OO^l0 &gt; NO&lt;0 f— I fH i-H i ! 1 ! S ! !.&amp; ! 1 g ! I j ! 1 ! i i O : I ! ri £ ::: ::: ::O:Ha:::: : c : : &lt;S : : J j2 i |1I-llil|lfI111!1P| nJ 0OOOOCOOOO«HIll0 IS it </seg>
            <seg id="p050">52 3 jljiiji S J niij Ooi}«(naii3 woo :n«o«HSU3«naen ;oo_ : otf^T ! t-T ■»!? &lt;£ oT oo" »■ aa ■*£&lt;£&lt;£ t- :o • CO H H j f* sannqo y ncoooo«oaooooooot&gt;-o&lt;3ooo aOasOOOCOCOtOOOOT^IMTttOiOOo tOdOOOOCOt^OOOfHiQOJOS O5 CO^ i^ im. ud sjnojj ion :h«io«*h lo^oaNon ; o i~ :*-^»HTffHOOs : Tf h 10 n h h o : w :eo w 10 n n : n t&gt; in «j&gt;toj r— I | 3 puB aqoog j»q;o snat-oeociH :c»t~&gt;nf-HOao-&lt;i&lt;o t h r- in m nn h teOr-'-ii-iNi''- 1^* 09ON«000O0Nceo00C &lt;Oi-i an m»(OH^«o(-HtiHe j 6dUB[Bg I r^ooiNooooooTfc-. oaowooo _; OMinNHoooNoeiNTfioio'COiooi i-T i-T r-T CO" iH" «h" — r-7 amojui a (•nsuao 0S61) not}B[ndoj * « — ONOOOOQC--.C-1^-I — H o W Jl O « -j S n HP ir-!i— (fHfHiHr-4i— !*-Hrtl— irH^Hf— Ii-H,—,; -S^ -i- +- +- 1-2 r-lr-I^OOOOOSi-Hu-JOr-liniOOgJmo o"^ 00QO Oo o §,£ rHtHrH'i-(r4'r4'i-?''«i''i- : 'r-H'NrH' i-I''-&lt;pr - g I ! { j | { • : } i i { I : ', : : iLl | i ! i u 1 \4 Si I - 11 'Jils ll-ilij.lIaili^ilHilll OoO^P-cfcCUOHliHWKWKWcoccccaD ?J^ OHfin^oeMtoieHNnJiogt. £ = 0««0980Oe00OO 0 3°0f H — H- HHHHrtrtrtH* t </seg>
            <seg id="p051">| as J ijliiiiiiiijiiij' noijBinoiiQ 10 n » o a w h i&gt; :t» o * :«o't~ei5'^''e &gt; i'o(r co r^ t-( : I saumiOA » 'I 00 . 'i" o .» omttisus^oomn a "N 1010^1 h H*n •* pT oT w" cif i-h" r-T tj!" qasji Jad sjnojj I El S[naipoi.ia { j pus s^oog aaq; 0 • sauBfBg x io os, f-. os, =&gt; o * w m, ■* o, io o « 5! S o if rl H h iHr^'cfl'of ,-? 1 aoioaaj s 22a t "2 H 2°'°J lxl '* llt| HS*N nHHrtrtHnHrtHHridHrtrtHH (snstwo 0S6T) uot^Bjndoj -&lt;_ J_ j_ e N o f s oOoDT-(aoo®oOoSNao O h" ff H CC ri ,-7 r^ 1-TcJi-T I M I j li ! I i II j M I! ! I S3 i i : i | i : s" i i jp i i : -8 i : !jii^l*i|iJil § !:i1 ifiiiiiiij|Iii£ii «ooHnn^iaot~3o5ortPin^iia 2 Ori S2 rlHrirlH !i ri N tlC ' NM M r-trH &gt; -|iHrH rtf _| rHrtr HT-l f H I _, I _ l rti-(r-l|H 0*1 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">54 &lt; I •S j* If * s J © g b a .s 1 b'JJIjb IJS 1 i S g*'^ uoijBinaaij o o t" o « n a ci t(i ci m : oo a a ojccwc^cscic^i-^eijasm : «jj tj o\\ cT r^ ' 'O &lt;m"~ ed n" t&gt;" c^f crT cT : in 1 o •*'l r-ii-H i-i Wi-li-l PIC^l I satnnjo_\ © e eo c i— '(Micoeoooom ao^oot^&gt;— ECoDNonaCr- cc aq^ oo b c h oo &lt;c m to (o w oo o_ oo_ r- TtT i-7 N 1 cc" »rf of irfirfafNi—'^*'^'^' i—i jad satmji -at~fiwfONT(iHOOoo«CT ~ci Din •— in n pa r-i m cot~ i U C&lt;5 l- : Tf Cl = 00 « OO N O C PI M g&lt;t : n H 4 1 3 « H i-! e« i— t siBoipouaj pirB sijooy SaiJBIEH sjBoipoued puB s^ooy aaqjo ■- c " f &gt;c n * a fi t» c (M it. o pi f| Cl " i- CI "— i— CO TH i— ■* &gt;1 ■X- : — OOMNOOOOOOKri SnNSn :°» n * n h h hwh M c io ! 5©co©irfct^'-occc = C". '^Ci-HTf^irtt-tOkftOOCC: J; o "■" ffi n « L " oo e. n io * w e ti in* riH r fi Ol ■* atnoju] _ (snsuaa 0S6l ) not^Bpidoj JB3 A SnrNccii'et-r-rieor-c. c a c c. cc^c. ccoacca SeSoHt S •* oo « oeosx oo h S co h r-__ c n c c L-rvo.in.rc r^ rn" ef i-? t^ f? e« i-T ei ih »-i « «5 I i : i :!: i :&amp;:::: i : i|I|i| li'hjjiif = S H P £ £ £ £ * £ £ fc £ 6?| .§••9 1} ONXOO^nrt^iOttSooc:© HSHl-Hrl^r-^nrtHHHiHl S F </seg>
            <seg id="p053">55 Liibrsnes in the following towns, financed other than by taxation, are under the auspices of Women's Clubs or other civic groups. A few of these are near the line of tax support. If other towns should be included in this list such information would be appreciated by the secre- Kof the Library Commission, s Klin Creek Elm Creek Orchard Oxford Page Alexandria Elmwood Eustis Ewing Palisade Palmyra Papillion Piker Exeter Fairmont Farnam Platte Center Polk Battle Creek Grant Beaver City Gresham Hardy Potter Beaver Crossing Hay Springs Republican City Ruskin Belgrade Hayes Center Big Springs Heartwell St. Paul Salem Boelus Herman Homer Shelby Bradshaw Hubbell Shickley Shubert Humphrey South Sioux Citv Stapleton Brownlee Imperial Bruning Inavale Carleton Jansen Steele City Strang Cedar Bluffs Keystone Chester Leigh Stratton Clarkson Lemoyne Sutherland Trenton Coleridgi! Liberty Crab Orchard Lushton Union Valentine Valley Crookston Mason City Culbertson Meadow Grove Davenport Deeatur Minatare Monroe Mullen Valparaiso Verdon Waco £2" Murray Nemaha Nora Wallace Waterloo Wauneta Western Wolbach Wynot Dorchester Dunning '£■ Oak Oakdale Ogallala </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>