<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00023">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00023</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BI-ENNIAL REPORT AND FINANCIAL EXHIBIT OF THE Nebraska State Board of Education To His Excellency GEORGE LAWSON SHELDON Governor</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">AND FINANCIAL EXHIBIT OF THf Nebraska State Board of Ed near ion To His Excellency GEORGE LAWSON SHELDON Governor COMPILED BY 1.1THER P. LUDDEN SKCRHTARV LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JANUARY 1, 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATE NORMAL SCHOOLS BOARD OF EDUCATION tPresidenl. C. H. Gregg, Kearney 19°6 Vice- President, H. M. Childs, York 191" Secretary, Luther P. Ludden, D. D., Lincoln ...1911 Bart L Sheilhom, Peru - 19" t Superintendent, James E. Delzell, Be. I). I.exington -..190K J. L. McBrien, Lincoln ex-Officio COMMITTEES Auditing— Brian. Child*, Shellhorn. Executive, Shellhorn, Ludden, Gregg Teachers and Employees — McBrien, Delzell, Gregg Text and Library Books — Course of Study and Rules — Delz^ll, Ludden, McBrien J. W. Crabtree, Be. D., Principal, IVru. A. O. Thomas, Ph. D.. Be. D., Principal. Kearney "Term expires Jan. 7th, 1909, succeeded by State Superintendent-elect K C. Bishop. Ltjanuary 2, 1909, President C. H. Gregg resigned as a member of the i\. On the same day Gov. Sheldon appointed Superintendent D \V Hayes, Alliance to fill out the rest of the term. JOn January 2, 1909, Gov, Sheldon appointed N. I*. McTkmald. of Kearney, Treasurer, L. G. Bri»n. Lincoln cx-Offici&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Lincoln, Nebraska, January 1st, 1909. His Excellency, (leorge Lawson Sheldon. Govr rnor of Nebraska: Sir: — On behalf of'the Nebraska State Board of Education and in Com - pliance with the law, creating said Board, herewith please find report and de - tailed statement of the expenditures of the several funds under our control, from the beginning of the present Biennium to December 31st, 1908. The original vouchers are regularly filed with the Auditor, while the duplicate properlyjfiled in the office of the Secretary. Very respectfully, d^a^^S^Ma^CcCt^d. Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION TO GOVERNOR GEORGE LAWSON SHELDON The history of our commonwealth in these two years is one of unique advancement, and you can ever look back with pride to your administra - tion. The State Normal schools have performed their part in this epoch - making period. Incorporated as a part of my report you will find the clear-cut statements of President J. W. Crabtree of Peru, and President A. O. Thomas of Kearney. We desire to call special attention to these statements from the men who are at the head of our Normal School work in Nebraska. THE ADVANCEMENT No biennium in the history of the Normal School work shows such marked advancement as that of the years 1907-1908. Two years ago we were able to say, "The growth is unparalleled in the history of any state in the Union." We still maintain the splendid pace then set, and the prospect before us is exceedingly bright. OUR GROWTH. Two years ago, using the rules generally employed in estimating attendances at similar institutions, we were called optimistic when for Peru we predicted an enrollment of 1,537, the previous biennium having enrolled 1,215, and yet we close the biennium with an enrollment of '1 543. During all the history of the Peru Normal 25,800 students have been enrolled, and during this last biennium one-tenth of the entire number has been in attendance, and the splendid showing made by Peru is also maintained at Kearney. We predicted two years ago in our re - port, using the same basis of calculation, that Kearney would show an enrollment of a thousand before the close of the biennium. The in - crease has exceeded our earnest expectations and the average for the three years of the Kearney Normal School history is over a thousand students enrolled for each year. Notwithstanding this unprecedented increase in student enrollment in both Normal Schools, we have been fairly successful in living within our income as given us by the Legis - lature in 1907. We have not been able to p&amp;y as large salaries as we </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BI-ENNIAL REPORT should for the talent at our command. We have been compelled to part with some of our good teachers because other schools could pay better wages than we. We are forced under present conditions, to work our teachers long hours. The first classes at Peru assemble at 7:45 a. in. and the last classes are dismissed at 6 p. m., and there isn't a school period during the day but what the class-rooms are occupied. Then some of the special classes have to assemble in the evening because we have no rooms and not enough teachers to do the work during the day. At Kearney we are confronted with the same conditions, only worse. We have fenced off the corridors to make extra class-rooms. Teachers are compelled to go from room to room to meet classes instead of having r finite place where special apparatus and proper school appliances equipment could best accommodate the work. NORMAL SCHOOLS EDUCATIONAL CENTERS. No one questions today but what our Normal Schools are rapidly becoming great educational centers in Nebraska. They are furnishing carefully prepared, well-trained teachers — teachers who go out and be - come a source of inspiration to other teachers with whom they come in contact. No one questions but what the educational advancement of Nebraska depends upon the efficiency of her school teachers. The ques - tion is often asked. "Will our Normal Schools continue to grow?" if we are given the larger and better equipment and sufficient funds to pay the salaries to maintain the standard we have already attained unto and to reach the ideal toward which we aspire. I-ast year at Peru fully three hundred more students came knocking at our doors and would have enrolled if we could have properly cared for them in the way of school rooms, equipment and teachers. At Kearney we were full to overflowing and simply had to stop tak - ing students for every room and corridor as fenced off was filled to its utmost capacity and teachers working from early morning until evening. This condition calls for very careful consideration and demands persis - tent attention on the part of every one interested in the proper develop - ment and solving of the great school problems in Nebraska. Our state should continue the good work so well begun and commit herself more fully to an enlarged Normal School policy. We have set a high ideal, and with the splendid teaching force at our command, if properly sus - tained, we can attain unto it for our Normal School instructors are among the very best in the land, ready to do thorough work in the graduate department, in the training department and in every line of pedagogical work. And while we are developing these specially strong school lines we are not neglecting, in the least the teaching of the great industrial subjects that today demand so much of the attention in school </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 OUR SUMMER SCHOOLS. Our Summer Normal School work shows a- very market increa^ the attendance; so much so that the Board now make the Summer Normal School a permanent policy of the State Normal work. We expect to con - tinue the very high grade of work in the Summer Normal, making it the equal of any institution in this country along the line of graduate, pro - fessional, academic or truly pedagogical work. The policy of the board is to bring to our Summer Normal Schools the very best instructors pos - sible for us to obtain, in addition to the regular faculty. Thus our Sum - mer Normal School work is growing in attendance year by year and increasing in popularity. The attendance last summer was simply lim - ited to the capacity of the buildings. Scores of teachers who want - take the work could not be accommodated. It is too bad that in a great commonwealth like Nebraska, when hundreds want to attend school, that we have to hang out the sign "No More Room." OUR STUDENTS. Those in very close touch with the Normal Schools note, as each bien - nium passes, the marked increase in the number of students that enrol for the full year's work. This is a very hopeful sign and augurs well for the years to come in school work in Nebraska. The raising of the stan - dard of education all over Nebraska has demanded better educated teach - ers — that means better pay — and better pay has been the means of bringing a large number of men again into the ranks of the teachers. This has been one of the pleasing incidents to our Board — the large number of men enrolled among our student body. Students as a class with us are orderly and devoted to their work; getting ready to deal with the great problem that is worth solving. A large number of them have raised the money for their education by their own personal ef - forts and this accounts in part for their devotion in preparing them - for their professicnal wcrk and helps them to realize the seriousness of the situation, and to feel their responsibilities to the great common - wealth of Nebraska for the educational advantages she is affording them. DO WE NEED NORMALS. The question is often asked. "Do we need State Normals"" If all the graduates from the State t'niversity. State Normals, Junior Normals and private Normals enterted the teaching ranks on graduation year they would constitute only a part of the teaching force required annually in our great state, they would hardly fill vacancies caused by resignations, withdrawals and deaths year by year. Quite a large per - centage of the entire body of teachei-s in Nebraska are untrained as </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BI-ENNIAL REPORT and the want of Nebraska in this direction is the want of every state in the Tnion. The only way we can meet it in this state is to maintain of Normal Schools that we may help supply the ever isinp demand of all our public schools for better teachers. The Normal S&gt; the only schools in which the history, the philosophy, the theory and the practice of education can be taught to any considerable number of young men and women, and they are the only schools in which the tsunjr nidied and expounded in the manner in which they ongfct to lx&gt; presented by the teacher in the school rooms. At the' name time they are the only schools in which the teachers, while being trained, actually practices teaching while being trained. There are other institutions devoting part of their courses to 'his specific work, are doing splendid work but still lack the particular application of the p vork under the eye of a master teucher. The Normal - its entire course to this especial work of furnishing thor - oughly educated and technically trained teachers — teachers who .alues received in instruction for the money expended. INDUSTRIAL EDUCATION. In this particular line of work our Nebraska Normals are way out in the forefront in the nation. It was in our Normal schools that tin - first attempts were made to teach industrial subjects. It was from our al Schools that the first petitions went to the Congress of this nation calling their attention to the needs in this particular direction. It was among our Nebraska Normal School forces that the bill now pending in Congress was formulated, asking for specific appropriation along these particular lines for the furthering of this work in the Normal it, of the United States. The ljttle seed sowing of the Nebraska al School people has taken a very firm rooting, and other states that at first opposed us are now rapidly coming in line, and the great statesmen of our nation are giving this particular subject very careful leration and seemingly are realizing that Nebraska's Normal School idea in the teaching of industrial subjects means the bettering of the rural schools. The members of Congress at Washington are be - ginning to vie with each other during this short session for the inaugura - tion of some scheme for government aid and encouragement for the improvement of the rural schools of the whole country- It is one of the greatest practical questions in the whole realm of their educational effort. Millions of dollars have been voted annually for universities, agricultural and technical colleges. Other millions have come from pri - vate benevolence and endowment, and these schools in their higher edu - cation have shown marked advancement. But there has been a n&lt; I the line of national aid for rural schools. Our idea is that it is Mi ■ r to work out a scheme of correlating the rural school with the al Schools than in any other way, for our graduates and under- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION graduates are both in very close touch with the rural school work, and that it would be money well expended if our government would thus contribute toward making this partcicular advancement — teaching of industrial subjects. It means a revolutionizing of present methods — it is one of the demands of the times — and our Nebraska Normal schools have striven to meet it. Just a little increase in our buildings, a little larger amount appropriated for salaries and maintenance, and we are ready for the work. It is coming. And it will mean a splendid vindication of the advanced policy and high ideals set by our Nebraska Normal Schools. This will not interfere in the least with the high ideals now attained in the great universities on these particular subjects, but it will give our rural schools technically trained teachers who will crowd forward these subjects along safe, sane, sound pedagogical lines. Ne - braska is an agricultural state, and imperatively demands for the rural communities today teachers trained along these specific lines, that old customs may be brushed aside and modern up-to-date methods put in their place on the farm, and thus continue the work of educating the boys and girls up to the very heart of nature and the soil. Soil is some - thing else besides dirt, and farm labor will then become something besides drudgery. This oldest vocation, this newest science will put a more attractive side of life into the farm and rural centers. Boys and girls will learn to love nature and to keep close to the soil. Yes, It will answer the oft repeated cry, "How to get them back to the farm." The coming has been slow, but Congress is moving and Nebraska Normal Schools having taken the initiative, are ready to do their part along these splendid lines. DOMESTIC SCIENCE. The Normal Schools of Nebraska are keeping abreast of the Normal Schools of the country in taking very advance steps in this particular line of teaching. We are increasing our equipment and now teaching teachers how to teach domestic science to the children in their schools. Thus we lead them to an intellectual appreciation of the affairs of the household and the relation existing between housekeeping and sound living. MANUAL TRAINING Another of the industrial problems is manual training, and the Normal Schools of Nebraska are hard at work along this line, knowing that a course in manual training will connect the children with, in a real way, the labor products of the world. It puts them in touch in a peculiar way with the great industrial activities of life. Possibly it will lead them to see the possibilities or the opportunities that are just before them in life. The ultimate object of all the industrial work in our Normal Schools </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 BI-ENNIAL RERORT Is to teach teachers how to teach the boys and girls of our public schools how to get the most out of life. RENTING OF TEXT BOOKS. The experiment started by our Board a few years ago of purchasing books at wholesale and renting to the student at a nominal fee each semester has now become an established custom. The results from the financial side are all that could be expected. At the same time we sell the books to the students, if they prefer to buy, at the actual cost to the school. At the beginning of the school year the student de - posits $3.00. At the end of the school year the deposit is returned less the rental fee. This department has been created and carried on with - out a dollar of expense or appropriation from the state. The rental teas enable ns to purchase new books as needed and to properly repair books and care for the department, and makes a great saving to every FEES. The Board has practically eliminated fees except the usual breakages In the different laboratories and these are charged up to students at actual cost REQUIREMENTS FOR ENTRANCE. The entrance requirements have been made just as rigid as the new law of the state demands. This works a little hardship on people living In the newer settled parts of the state where high school facilities are not as good as In the older portions of the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 DIRECT WORK OF THE BIENNIUM FOR EACH SCHOOL. PERU. The Legislature of 1907 gave us 125.000.00 for the building and equipping of a new heating plant at Peru. The cutting out of the $5 000.00 for an engine compelled us to make some changes in the heating plant proper for our old engine gave out entirely. The board therefore did away with the $2,000.00 for the coal storage addition, bought a new gasoline engine for the pumping plant out of funds derived from the sale of old material, and got along with one less boiler than we oug'it to have had in the heating plant. We also saved $l,2i)0.00 in architect fees. Our own engineer drew a pencil sketch of the plans and we paid $50.00 for the making of the blue prints and the secretary prepared tho necessary specifications, making a net saving of $1,200.00. The cut - ting out of these items and the saving on architect enabled us to pur - chase the engine dynamo and equipment therewith. We installed the entire plant with our own men, thus making another saving of nearly a thousand dollars. We have a heating and lighting plant all complete except the one boiler and coal storage room, and all within the appro - priation. Locating this building as we did against the bank, gives us ou the face side with campus at grade entrance, four excellent school rooms. The next story way down the bank gives us a much needed carpenter shop and store-room. Immediately under this and at grade entrance be - low bank is the blacksmith and steam-fitting department. Then a splen - did large dynamo and engine room, and adjoining this a boiler room with its battery of three boilers and room for the fourth boiler, together with quite a coal storing capacity. Here is installed also the hot water heat - ing plant for the gymnasium and all other buildings except the dormitory. Hot water for the dormitory is heated in a specially constructed hoi water boiler in the building, through which we pass coils of live steam, thus doing away with fire of every kind in the domitory except in the kitchen. ' With this appropriation of $25,000.00 we were able to com - plete this entire plant except the furnishing of the four large schoolrooms on the main floor of the plant. We need the school furniture very much for these rooms. We have borrowed a little furniture, but not sufficient to properly equip the rooms and the classes are so large that many of the students have to stand during the entire recitation. The entire plant was built and equipped as above outlined within the appropriation made by the Legislature in 1907, and we have 26 cents that will lapse back Into the treasury. We ought to have the coal storage shed addition, for it Is not good economy to store coal on the ground. We do need an - other boiler, for all the buildings on the campus are heated from the one </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 BI-ENNIAL REPORT plant and In extreme cold weather we should be greatly Inconvenienced If there should be a breakdown In any one of the battery of boilers. We must have the furniture for the schoolrooms for the borrowed furniture we will be compelled to return at the close of the school year In the matter of current expenses the particular items are herewith •et forth: ESTIMATE OF EXPENSES FOR THE COMING BIENNIUM. (c) Maintenance $ 23,000.00 (d) General repairs 6,000 . 00 Traveling expenses 800 . 00 (e) Unusual repairs 10,000.00 $40,700.00 Salary— principal, teachers 109,000 . 00 Salary— Employes 8,000.00 117,000.00 Building fund — .dniinistration building 40,000.00 Another story on library 10,000.00 50,000.00 $207,700.00 (c) This item is made of estimates as follows: Fuel, Lights, etc 12.000.00 Apparatus for laboratory 1,500.00 Printing and office supplies 3,000 . 00 Kage phone, telegraph, etc 1,500.00 ual training 800.00 Domestic science 800.00 Furniture and cases 1,500.00 Com— cement expenses 800.00 Agriculture 1,000.00 Pumping plant equipment 1.000.00 $23,900.00 (d) This item carries the general repairs. (e) This unusual repair carries the completion of the coal storage build- Ing. A general overhauling of the old building new roof, new floors in many places. An enlarging of the toilet rooms to keep pace with the growth of the school. The extending and enlarging of the sewer 8) stem. The entire 60 acres of campus must be refenced, we are at the mercy of the cattle of the neighborhood. There is a slight Increase in the amount for maintenance, but the school is much larger and the maintenance item necessarily must be greater. We ask just the same amount for general repairs as two years ago. but have another item of unusual repairs which is clearly explained in the Item of the foot-note. There is an increase in the salary schedule. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 \\ e must ha\ • more teachers if we car** for all the pupils who come to us. There is an increase in the amount of the emplo&gt; Two years ago the clerk of the Committee on Finance. Ways and Means made an error in not multiplying the salary of one year for the emp by two, and it was not discovered until it was too late to amend same. Hence during the biennium we had to get along with half the }u force needed; unable i many of the rooms more than on&gt; twice a week. This is not sanitary or conductive to cleanliness. But \w were up againsi a proposition of no funds to pay for the number of janitors needed. NEW BUILDINGS. We ask this year for $40,000.00 for a building to be termed Admin - istration building. Not that it is to be used solely for administrative pur - but a few rooms on the first floor, street entrance, would be de - \uted to administration department and the rest of the building d&lt; to classroom work. This building would be located against the side of the hill so that the administration rooms would be on a level with the street, while the first floor for school purposes would be on a grade yel with the campus, thus avoiding e.v ;air climbing, etc. We also ask for funds sufficient for adding another ttory to our nt library building. The remarkable growth of the school n tliis an Imperative demand. Day by day and evening by evening • available floor space is occupied by students, and still we are unal meet the demand in the way of reference library room. PAINTING AND FRESCOING. The urgent request is made of the board that our beautiful new pel and splendid library building ought on the interior to be paint - the walls tinted. We have made no formal request for the fun&lt;! doing this work other than to present the need and leave it to the wis - dom of the executive and the legislature to say whether this shall be dine. era] of the funds I have not touched upon because they are reg lar appropriations of the usual amounts for the specific work indi' KWe close the biennium with a deficiency only in the employes' ( the maintenance department. The first has been explained by the error in computing salary, and the second which it was not possible to avoid, is due to the very large increase of students, to care for all of them without exceeding tl.e amount i maintenance was im - ... </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 BI-ENNIAL REPORT KEARNEY. Herewith is the copy of the estimate for the needs of the new school : ia&gt; For maintenance $ 19.300.00 or general repairs 6,000.00 Traveling expenses 800.00 $26,100.00 Salary— employes 7,000.00 Salary — teachers 85,000 . 00 Salary— Summer School, extra 1.000.00 93,800 Building Fund — One wing and equipment 50.000.00 Chapel and gymnasium 50.000.00 100.n *219,!». rThis item is made of estimates as follow*: Printing and office supplies 1,600.00 Water, fuel aad lights 7,000.00 Telegraph, phone, freight, expn ... 1,500.00 Furniture aud equipment 7.000.00 Commencement 800 . 00 Manual training and domestic scienc 1,400.00 $ 19,300.00 (b) carried with it a new boiler For maintenance we ask the same amount as granted by the last Legislature. For general repairs an increase. We must have another boiler at Kearney. We are running the entire plant with one boiler and the break of a flue or any other slight accident compels us to shut down the entire heating plant and the school until the repairs can be made Again the dormitory is heated from the same plant and the break of a flue gives every occupant of that building cold rooms. With one boiler we are unable to rest it or to make minor repairs or properly the tame without shutting down from the time we start firing in the (all until we quit in the spring. SALARY AND WAGES. There is a slight increase over the amount appropriated two years ago, simply made necessary because of the very great increase in th&lt; number of students in attendance. The great need at Kearney is more teachers, more room, more equipment, or else compel us to say to the students that apply for admission, "It is simply impossible for us to take you now, because we have more than double the normal capacity of the present building and equipment in attendance." You will realize the taak that is before us in handling an enrollment that has averaged a </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 thousand different students each of the three years of the history of the school. The class work begins at 8 o'clock in the morning and continues uninterruptedly until evening. We ask you. in order that we may take care of the school work at Kearney properly, for an appropriation that will allow the building of the north wing of the present building, $ and the rear annex or chapel and gymnasium, $"&gt;0.0i&gt;' In the north wing, in addition to affording much needed school-room tilities, we could place our library where it ought to be, on the pi &gt;r. At present we have one small class-room for a library which is re than crowded to its shelving capacity with books, and insur' every way to accommodate the students. We do WK need a chapel an assembly room and gymnasium. The assembly room would ny purposes and no one questions but what attention in these days uld be paid to the physical nature as well as to the Intellectual. So ny of our students at Kearney come from the rural districts, accus - led to active physical life. It is not sane or sound reason to put them into the hard work of the school room without some relaxation or method of taking care of the pent-up energy. The gymnasium therefore km a necessity at Kearney. We h:ive a gord foundation for the intell - side, but nothing in the way of a gymnasium or ;i laying of a foundation for the physical training in connection therewith. To properly cai the work in both normals with the unexpectedly large increase in enroll- Ehas required the greatest of care and th. • of the conomy to come to the close of the biennium without deficits. The have been compelled to work the long hours with classes and with a shortage of equipment We have fOM to the of the funds given us then the Board stopped. EXPENSES OF THE BOARD. tThe large increase in the schorls also makes an Inci nount ork for the Board and the doing away of all railroad tran greatly increased the expenses of the Board. The legislature s ago reduced the amount we asked. $S 500.00. to fl.MO.00 for this We come down to January 1. IMS with ■ very small sum k treasury, and in order to care for the work up to March II, itW, w.- I ask for a small deficiency appropriation of $."&gt;uil.0i) We ask this for an appropriation for expense of the board of 92.590 Expense of the Board for the biennium </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 REPORT OR PRESIDENT J. W. CRABTREE. PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL. Peru. NVfir.. December 1, • rird of Fducation. biennium just ending n one of sp: for ihe Peru Stale Normal School. Of the ifi.MiO student - ? :, -his institution s: II or one-tenth fe In ar during this hiennium. Of the 1,111 who have graci . nizatic n of tl. han one -f. ibe ii during thi? niuni. NHH *li) I urged the pMM(a of th. .ire the lasi i .i 14 credit potatl I saw at the t 'Is that would be made on tin «rmal schools. It was thought by some that the attendance at uld dt • a result of the passage of this law and also ■ large number of students of tl. -oing to the new State : hi Kearney. !!■ &gt;ine rather interesting figures. The graduating class before th&lt; of the legislature of 1907 iin 1 "iT. That gives 145 gradual i ihe liieiinii.i.i. Th&gt; in the class of IM7, 14!» and in th&gt; during this biennium, just exactly twice as (hiring the previous biennium. It may be of further interest to know that between 170 and 17.". f duate next June. 1 i obably not anotli. normal h. ;it can ma! • I a showing in the in&lt; the finished product or in the number of graduates in proportion to the amount of the appropriation for the support of the institution. There are about Ml in the present junior i sainst 143 of year. Tl ■ during the past yeai&gt; hat of a &gt; o you. In 1H04 tl graduate - junior class, whereas in the Benior class of 190!l there are 17:: junior class . ly four times as many in highest claaaea now as at that time. why we have found 11 edingly difficult to live within our own estimates. Al each session of the leglslatun our t- on the number of students in the | the tin. Our estimate was too low for two reasons. First the "nd. the greater DMBfc inste; :iow in the hk &gt;ses. The </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 than the apparatus and appliances for the more elementary work. Classes are necessarily smaller in most of these college subjects. The per capita cost at Peru, estimated on the total annual attendance Is $46, which is considerably less than half the per capita cost at our State University, estimated In the same manner, though our junior and senior years correspond to the freshman and sopohomore years at the University. Our State University is said to have the lowest cost per student of any State University in the United States. It would not be out of proportion for ours to be $75 instead of $46 per student per year. Though we charge girls only fifty cents a week for rent of rooms in Mt. Vernon Hall, this fund has enabled us to provide good furniture for each room, to keep the building in good repair, to make and equip a good laundry room in tli nt, to enlarge dormitory kitchen and provide a fine new range for it, to make tunnel and connections with new build - ing plant and to beautify the campus about the dormitory. This dormi - tory therefore not only supports itself but provides funds for its enlarge - ment and betterment. Mr. Grinste;;d. a member of the board of regents of the Kentucky State Normal schools, who recently made a tour through the D States visiting state normal schools in order to get suggestions for com - pleting and operating their own plants i 1 interest and surprise at what we have to show for the appropriation of $25,000 by the last Leg - islature. He took nctes on every detail and borrowed the plans to present to his committee. It was quite impossible for him to see how we were able to construct that large building and equip it with such up-to-date heating apparatus and machinery besides extending the large tunnel sev - eral hundred feet and making heating connections. We take pleasure In showing the governor and members of the legislature or any interested ones the wise and economical use made of the allowance of 1907 for a heating plant. Owing to our limited salary allowance, we have not yet elected a teacher of drawing to fill the vacancy caused by Professor Caldwell's resignation a year and a half ago. For the same reason we employed no one to take Professor Frenchs' place in the department of agriculture last semester. We take pride In getting along on half the force of Janitory and engi - neers we should have had. But this is unwise economy. These laboring men have been overworked all the time and absolutely unable at times to keep the buildings heated, the rooms clean and the closets in proper condition. The slight increase in teachers' salaries fails to bring any one of them to $1,800. the mark we have been aiming to reach which 1b much less than we should have as our maximum. We would not be able to re - tain the members of our faculty who are in great demand for similar po - sitions where salaries are much better, were it not for their strong at- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 tacbment for Peru and also for the fact that the simple life at Peru makes a salary of $1,400 go about as far as a salary of $1,700 would in a large city. As you know we have lost some especially strong teachers of our faculty and will doubtless lose other unless we can in the near future gives them a slight increase in pay. As a rule professors are un - willing to leave Peru for less than an increase of seven or eight hun - lollars a year but eastern institutions have already begun paying this difference, and take some of our teachers. The present estimate will not permit of a general increase in pay for these people. The financial statement of the secretary shows the economical use made of all funds and also the present balance in each fund. These state - ments are in detail and in form to explain themselves. The state ac - countant expressed satisfaction on his visit at our method of keeping records and the care exercised in purchasing supplies. The cash funds are small in an institution of this kind and can be handled more conveniently without passing through the hands of the state treasurer, but believing that as a matter of precaution and to avoid any possible chance for criticism in past at least, on my suggestion a bill was introduced into the last legislature, requiring that these funds be deposited with the state treasurer. The bill became a law but was so amended as to apply only to funds from the sale of property which does not include the cash funds in this institution. It seems to me that it would be wise to ask the legislature to amend this law as our state treasurer has suggested or else request the state auditor and state treas - urer to arrange to have their records cover the cash funds from state normal schools. The additional inconvenience will amount to nothing as compared with the protection afforded to the schools. There has never been any criticism on the schools regarding the use of these funds and with this arrangement no suspicion of careless use of funds can ever tYou have on file In your office my report of the work of the schools detail and also the report made by each head of department These torts show that the progress made during this biennium has never in excelled in the history of the school. The friendly relations existing between the state Normal schools and the University has meant much to our schools and no doubt just as much to the University. There Is not another state In the Union where all Institutions, state universities, state normals, private and denominational schools and all public school articulate so well with each other and where there Is the degree of co-operation that exists In Nebraska. That is why our schools rank so high and a further reason why Nebraska boys and girls are forming the habit of continuing their education for the higher decrees. K Every effort should be made to secure an appropriation of $40,000 for administration building which would also contain a few class rooms. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 19 Our offices are now held In the cloak rooms of chapel. This not only hampers us in doing the work of the offices but it forces us to use rooms that are badly needed for other purposes. We need several more class rooms. In order to get rooms for classes we now begin at seven forty- five in the morning, and continue classes every period during the day to six o'clock. It Is even necessary to arrange for musical and other re- hearsals in the evening. ESTIMATE OF EXPENSES FOR THE COMING BIENNIUM. &lt;c\ Maintenance $ 23,900.00 (d) General repairs 6,000.00 Traveling expenses 800 . 00 (e) Unusual repairs 10,000.00 $40,000.00 Salary — Principal, teachers 109,000 . 00 Salary — Employees 8 000.00 117,000.00 Building fund — New administration building 40,000.00 Another story on library 10,000 . 00 50,000 . 00 $207,700.00 (c) This item is made of estimates as follows: Fuel, lights, etc 12,000.00 Aparatus for laboratory 1,500 . 00 Printing and office supplies 3,000 . 00 Postage, phone, telegraph, etc 1,500.00 Manual training 800.00 Domestic science 800. 00 Furniture and cases 1,500.00 Commencement expenses 800. 00 Agriculture 1,000.00 Pumping plant equipment 1,000.00 $23,900.00 (d) This item carries the general repairs. (e) This unusual repairs carries the completion of the coal storage build- ing. A general overhauling of the old building, new roof, new floors in many places. An enlarging of the toilet rooms to keep pace with the growth of the school. The extending and enlarging of the sewer system. The entire 60 acres of campus must be refenced. we are at the mercy of the cattle of the neighborhood. Very Cordially yours. J. W. CRABTREE. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 REPORT OF PRESIDENT A. O. THOMAS - KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL. Kearney, Nebr., December 1, 1908. To the Nebraska State Board of Education — Gentlemen: I am pleased to submit herewith a report of the pro - gress and condition of the State Normal School at Kearney, with a de - tailed account of its receipts and expenditures for the biennium now dosing. GROWTH OF THE SCHOOL, The school has had a remarkable growth. During the first ttTe years of its history twenty-one hundred (2100) students matriculated As bo student matriculates more than once, the matriculations do not show the enrollments. Many students who matriculated the first year of the school remained during the full three years, and are even yet in attend - ance. Counting the enrollment by years, over 3,000 students have en - rolled in the first three years. This makes an average of s.'vin hundred (700) students on matriculations and one thousand (1,000) student on en - rollment during each year of the school's history. I have studied some - what the condition of new schools in the United States, and have failed to find any school equaling the growth of the State Normal School at Kearney. The growth is accounted for largely by its central location. Its fine equipment, its strong work, and its splendid faculty. THE POLICY OF THE SCHOOL. The faculty realized at the outset that in order to build a school for the future and establish a reputation of credit to the state it must be careful of its products. It was a temptation many times to offer to graduate students with the minimum requirements, but it was the unani - mous opinion of our faculty that if we wished to succeed as a school and establish a reputation worthy of consideration we should be ex - ceedingly careful in regard to the teachers sent out from the school. We have even advised students who have not shown ability as teachers to enter some other calling, to go to some other kind of a school to pre - pare for some other line of duty. We have held to a high grade of work and have cut off students from certification and graduation who were . not fully up to the standard required. In many instances students have felt that they could secure grades from other institutions more quickly and more easily than from ours. For this reason we have lost some students who have been seeking for a short cut to preparation, but in most instancs the school was the gainer rather than the loser. We have endeavored to so regulate our course of study and our methods of Instruction that students who come under our tuition would come into </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 trough sympathy with our aims and ideals; that when they go out in - the schools of the state bearing the brand of our institution ild reflect credit upon the school. STRENGTH OF THE FACULTY. A.s principal of the schools I am indeed grateful to the Board of Kducation for placing in the school men and women of thorough scholar - ship and breadth of view added to successful experience in public school ce. it was no easy task to draw men and women who were in charge of institutions from all parts of the state before the school build - ing was completed, before course of study, programs and outlines were arranged, and form them into an effective faculty group, but the and women chosen by the Board of Kducation were men and women of real sympathy, of strong appreciation of the rights and privileges of oth - ers, and possessing strength of purpose and a zeal for the cause which made them invaluable in the work they were to undertake. Unity of purpose and narmonious action has marked this institution, and I point with just pride to each member of the faculty and to each helper; they have sought to improve themselves and to make themselves so valuable that the work of each special assistant and of each department could scarcely have been done better. Each deserves special mention. As prin - cipal of the school I have tried not to hamper but to give each depart - ment the fullest and freest opportunity. I have trusted the members of the faculty to investigate, to keep posted and fully abreast the times, to i •'&lt; onimend books and apparatus best calculated to make strong the of each department, but I have endeavored to guide the work so I would be the fullest sympathy and greatest unity of purpose between all ile part ments. STRONG DEMAND FOR TEACHERS I There is a great demand at the present time for teachers, and we entirely unable to supply it. Since early fall we have sent out into schools of the state nearly one hundred students. These students reluctant to leave their work in the middle of the year, but on account 3e strong inducements in the way of salary many have done so. The comes from county superintendents in the central and western por - 3 of Nebraska, and from many of the city schools in every part of state. In many instances the salaries offered are as high as ?• month. We hope in time to be able to supply the demand of m ers, and to be in such a position that when called upon at any le year to provide qualified teachers, we shall be able to do so. GRADUATES. Since the school year was organized three years ago, we have gradu - ated one hundred and forty-six students from the higher cource, fort&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 BI-ENNIAL REPORT four having been granted life certificates. One hundred ninety-five ele - mentary state certificates havi- been issued Eight diplomas have issued from the Department of Commerce, which represents a foui coarse beyond the tenth grade. BUILDINGS. The buildings belonging to the state are in splendid condition. W the Normal School building was erected many considered the ni;r from which it wag constructed an experiment, but time has demons the wisdom of the Board of Education in their choice of material from which to construct the buildings. It is the most comfortable, th' convenient, most attractive and most sanitary school building I have ever known. It is easily heated, substantial, and serviceable, and th* exterior walls have been pointed, cleaned and dressed, the building is perfectly dry. The dormitory is ideal for the purpose for which it is used. Five brick fire walls separate the building into sections and give it the greatest possible protection. It is so arranged that one par' be isolated from the n st. which renders ally convenient in of sickness. It required considerable outlay to set the equipment in the dormitory in first class condition. We have now demonstrated that being fully equii&gt;]&gt;ed the rental charges of 4n, 4"&gt; and M cents per will pay all running expenses and keep the property in good repair. During the past summer all the fixtures in the six bath rooms were replaced by the most sanitary kind, at a cost of nearly $r&gt;00. which was paid for from the dormitory fund. The heating plant, while serviceable, bears some errors in construction which might be overcome in a new plant. It is. however, effective, and furnishes heat for the various buildings at the minimum of cost EQUIPMENT I The school is equipped with the best of apparatus and materials In purchases we are careful to get the articles best suited to our I no makeshifts or substitute are permitted. Everything purchased •f a permanent nature. The laboratories are well supplies with con - lent and necessary aparatus. The furniture is in as good condition he day it was installed. We take just pride in the fact that no marks andulism or abuse occur upon the buildings or the furniture. In a x&gt;! for teachers the building should be a model of neatness and signs of abuse. Pencil marks, chalk marks, knife marks, etc., are nown to the property of this institution. PLANS FOR THE FUTURE The accompanying cut shows a diagram of a portion of the property at the State Normal School at Kearney. The Board of I Uon hired a competent landscape artist to lay out the ground iu d&gt; </seg>
           
            <seg id="p023">»C*~! &lt;—\ ■ '-••' STATE WOHMAL SCHOOL. KEARNEY NEB. 1Q \*S&gt; /HI "^&gt; "^ ® ■. I (I » /&amp; ■ • u p ■ «!^ — ** — »fet «. ■«( - vt — ■ a v " - V""* —— -\&gt;" -j, ~ t x ♦' *• m j « ■= — ™ TI — « — ■«,— i- ■». ■ ag to-, — y v — ".r — — — 6r- I I MOOfi. i- W 1 SCHOOL | \ I ! it*., '•■-~. m 4-~. \ • r L X^ * °i^ # mJ^ami I / (^ ; . LF 1^ I { % 3 U I I OtNGS, IP \ * I r^ V^h^^ ♦ ij r 1 J/i # r -« M0 &amp; B ♦ # » r' « / # &gt;%) *. m </seg>
           
            <seg id="p024">26 are marked on the diagram. Tbe central portion is the only part ?R-ing used. The plans provide for a north wing to contain the Art and Music departments, also Physiology. Botany and Zoology. The - wing provides for the Department of Education and the Physical Sci&gt; The buildings at the tear of the main building contain- the chapel and t&gt; M— ■Illlll Provisions are made for an Administration Building toward the southeast of the campus, while the Library Building will occupy the northeast portion. In the rear of the northwest is a model country school, while to the southwest is the model graded school. There are several parts of the property now being used whicl not show on the diagram. To the north is Green Terrace, the I dormitory. — a very tine structure, built at a cost of $4"&gt;.uou and div to the state by the citizens of Kearney. There is also a stone heating plant. To the west of the diagram is laid out a grove, just west of which is the athletic field, while still further beyond is the plat for agriculture The diagram shows the walks, drives, flower bed! tc At the present time all of the trees surrounding the campus and mm Those within are thriving, while nurs&lt; plete the parking. The ground - ])»■! ted with the lake, which is now ■water for irrigation. With one hundi en ordered to com - underlaid with four-inch pip. repaired and furnishing ab; portion of the normal campus can be sprinkled. Thei . ample fire prote The present building is practically fire proof. The Board 01 Um believes that the school grounds throughout the iould be beautiful, and that one way to encourage this is to shew what can be &lt;lone on their own grounds. When this pbuM If completed, it will offer one of tin most serviceable and beautiful plants in the United s The expensive portion of the parking is already completed. The campus will afford an aboretum in which will be found growi well in this country. FUNDS. As will be seen by the financial statement which follows, the fund - of tne institution are in good condition. It is our policy to live m our means and make every dollar count for its fullest value YV. have no deficiency in any fund, but may have small balances to ; to the state. We are gradually paying off all obligations from the purch texts. We have a sufficient number of books on hands to supply six hun - dred students. It was necessary at the oi&gt;ening of the present year to purchase books for many of the higher &lt; student working up in their course toward its completion Bv th 4 the nt year we shall have paid off the ei </seg>
            <seg id="p025">27 BI-ENNIAL REPORT ing text books with which the students are supplied at cost or for rent:&gt;.f- Our obligations for text books are now an follows American Book Company I :; Ginn ft Company ■■■ 328.0? Goodyear Marshall 180.00 1) ('. H^ath &amp; Company H Silver. Burdette * Co 139. 98 $1.3'.'. The text hook fund contains |M2 99 which will reduce the outstaml Iiik debts to f NEEDS OF THE INSTITUTION At the present time we are unable to put into operation with a full \ en ess the various departments of the school owing to the fact that these departments are not definitely located. It is necessary for the members of our faculty to hear their classes where-ver places can be found. They have no place to call headquarters, no place to estab- lish themselves and gather material and references for effective service In their departments, nor can this be done until the entire central por- tion of the plan is completed. The north and south wings are both necessary to the final establishing of all the departments of the institu- tion. ESTIMATE OF EXPENSES FOR THE COMING BIENNIUM. MAINTENANCE Printing and office supplies $ 1.600.00 Water, fuel and lights 7.000.00 Telegraph telephone, freight and drayage. . 1,500.00 Furniture and equipment 7,000.00 Commencement expenses 800.00 Manual training and domestic science 1.400.00 $ 19.300.00 C.eneral repairs $ 6,000.00 6,0i' Travelling expenses 800.00 800.00 SALARY AND WAGES Salary of engineers, janitors, etc 7.000.00 Salary of principal and teachers 86,800.00 93.800.00 BUILDING FIND: One wing and equipment $ 50,000.00 Chapel and gymnasium, with equipment.... 50.000.00 $100.i&lt; $219,900.00 Very cordially yours. A. O. THOMAS. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">28 PERU, NEBRASKA. SALARIES. Appropriation for the biennium, April 1, 1905- 1907 $71,400.00 Amount expended to Jan. 1, 1907 $ 59,724.28 Jan. 20, 1907 pay roll 3,817.03 Feb. 20, 1907 pay roll 3,664.43 Mar. 20. 1907 pay roll , 3,835.79 ••• May 10, 1907 pay roll 197.25 90.80 $ 71,329.66 $ 71.400.00 Amount lapsed at end of biennium 70.42 FUEL AND LIGHTS Appropriation for the biennium Apr 1, 1905-1907 $ 8,000.00 Amount expended to January 1, 1907 $ 5,927.06 1907 Jan. 4 C. B. Havens Co. coal 980.27 Commercial Elec. Co., supplies 54.00 John Wale, Jr., repairs, engine 19.00 Lyman Sand Co., sand 5.13 J. W. Crabtree, cash paid for freight 21.53 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 83 . 67 Phoenix Iron Works, engine repairs... 15.50 Mar. 29 Pittsburg Gage Co., supplies 26.25 Cling Surface Co., belt filler 8.50 Campbell Glass Co., glass, etc SI . 89 Western Glass Co., glass, etc 5.05 Crane &amp; Co., steam supplies 153.29 Crane &amp; Co., steam supplies 204.84 Hayes &amp; George, coal 108.15 Western Supply Co., supplies 10. 55 Burt W. Richards, boiler insurance.... 13.65 Standard Oil Co., oil and gasoline 64.89 Hardy Furniture Co., supplies 6. 00 Korsmeyer Co., electric supplies S3. 04 Apr. 30 C. B. Havens Co., coal 223.15 $ 7,990.41 $ 8,000.00 Amount lapsed at end of biennium 9.59 APPARATUS AND LABORATORIES. Appropriation for biennium Apr. 1, 1905-1907 $ 1,000.00 Amount expended to Jan. 1, 1907 S 725.97 1907 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">29 Bausch ft Lomb Co., supplies 40.21 Henry Hell Co., supplies 76.99 Central Scientific Co., supplies 61 . 82 Apr. SO Cambridge Bot. Co., supplies 19.86 Ward's Nat Science Co., supplies 23.00 $ 995.95 $ 1,000.00 Amount lapsed end of blennium 4.05 PRINTING AND OFFICE SUPPLIES Appropriation for the biennium Apr. 1, 1905-1907 f 1,600.00 Amount expended to Jan. 1, 1907 $ 1,594.09 1907 Jan. 4 J. W. Crab tree, cash advanced freight. 6.85 $ 1,599.94 $ 1,600.00 Amount lapsed at end of biennium .06 POSTAGE AND TELEGRAPH Appropriation for biennium Apr. 1, 1905-1907.. $ 900.00 Amount expended to Jan. 1, 1907 898.53 9 898.63 * 900.00 Amount lapsed at end of biennium 1 . 47 MANUAL TRAINING Appropriation for biennium, Apr. 1, 1905-1907 . . ? 1,000.00 Amount expended to Jan. 1, 1907 $ 212.72 1907 March 29 — Rudge Guenzel Co., supplies 159 . 13 Meek Lumber Co., supplies 356.86 April 10— Ray W. Weaverllng, supplies 140.65 M. E. Good, supplies 12.75 June 3 — Hardy Furniture Co., supplies 12.95 $ 895.06 $ 1,000.00 Amount lapsed end of biennium 104 . 94 FURNITURE AND CA8E8. Appropriation for biennium April 1, 1905-1907.. $ 800.00 Amount expended to January 1, 1907 $ 787.84 January 4, 1907, J. W. Crabtree, cash for freight 12.15 $ 799.99 $ 800.00 Amount lapsed end of biennium $ .01 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">30 COMMENCEMENT EXPENSES. Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 $ 800.00 Amount expended to January 1, 1907 $ 794.22 * 794.22 $ 800.00 Amount lapsed at end of biennium | 5.78 REPAIRS AND IMPROVEMENTS, Appropriation for biennium April 1, 1907-1907.. $ 5,000.00 Amount expended to January 1, 1907 $ 4,996.47 January 4, 1907, J. W. Crabtree, cash for freight 3.51 $ 4,999.98 $ 6,000.00 Amount lapsed end biennium .02 HEATING PLANT Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 $ 2,500.00 Amount expended to January 1, 1907 $ 2,499.48 $ 2,499.48 Amount lapsed end biennium .52 PHYSICAL TRAINING, Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 $ 1,000.00 Amount expended to January 1, 1907 $ 954 . 99 March 29, 1907, Midland Glass Co., supplies 27.66 April 30, J. W. Crabtree, for freight 7.15 9 989.80 9 1,000.00 Amount lapsed end biennium 10 . 20 PUMPING PLANT. Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 9 2.500.00 Amount expended to January 1, 1907 9 2,470.00 April 30, 1907, J. W. Crabtree, Pumping water SO. 00 $ 2,500.00 I 1600.00 AGRICULTURE. Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 1907 | 1,600.00 Amount expended to January 1 $ 1,427 . IS Jan. 4 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced 85.78 April 30 W. L. French, cash advanced S5.70 9 1,498.61 9 1,500.00 Amount lapsed end of biennium 1.39 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">31 BI-ENNIAL REPORT DEFICIENCY FUND. Deficiency fund appropriation vouchers on file 1907 $ 1,157.45 Estimated deficiency for February and March.. 325.00 $ 1.482.45 1907 April 17 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced $ 303.37 U. P. Uptegrove, printing sup 201.90 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. (freight) 214.62 State Journal Co., printing 189 . 25 Nebr. Sch. Supply House, supplies.. 122.16 W. Hacker, printing 126.15 Standard Oil Co., oil 82.42 L. R. Dillon, livery 6.50 Geo. D. Carring ton, advertising 2.00 C. C. Reed, oil 12.85 Hammond &amp; Stephens, printing 100.00 S. W. Hacker, printing 11.75 J. W. Crabtree, freight etc 74.93 Harry Porter, supplies 11.50 May 22 Nebr. Paper Bag Co., envelopes 20.00 $ 1,479.40 $ 1.482.45 Amount lapsed deficiency funds 3 . 05 KEARNEY, NEBRASKA 8ALARY TEACHER8 AND EMPLOYEES. Appropriation for the bienninm April 1, 1905-1907 $ 47,500.00 1907 Amount expended to January 1 $ 41,494.61 Jan. 20 Pay roll 2,441.70 Feb. 20 Pay roU 2,441.70 March 29 Payroll 1,121.99 $ 47,500.00 $ 47.500.00 DEFICIENCY APPROPRIATION. SALARY KEARNEY. Amount appropriated legislature 1907 for de- Mwcy $ 1,319.21 April 16 Pay roll balance March, 1907 $ 1,319.21 I 1,119.21 $ 1,319.21 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION ■JS HEATING PLANT. Appropriation for the biennium Apr. 1, 1905-1907 . $ 1" Amount expended to January 1, 1907 % 15,000.00 POSTAGE, TELEGRAPH, TELEPHONE, FREIGHT AND EXPENSES. Amount appropriated for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 I 900.00 •1907 Amount expended to January 1 $ 812.54 Jan. 4 A. O. Thomas, postage and freight 63.87 Kearney Phone Co., phone rent 12.90 April 30 A. O. Thomas, postage 10.00 891 31 $ Amount lapsed end biennium .69 FUEL, LIGHT3, WATER. Amount appropriated for biennium April 1, 1905 1907 $ 6.000.0* 1907 Amount expended to January 1 $ 3,308.11 Jan. 4 A. O. Thomas, painting smoke stack.. 13.00 J. M. Robinson, coal 1,229 . 68 Geo. H. Downing &amp; Son, coal 149.11 City Water Co., water 37 . 95 Midway Gas Co., gas and supplies.... 6.50 March 29 J. M. Robinson, coal 328.80 Geo. H. Downing &amp; Son, coal 123.43 W. K. Ayers, Pipe and supplies 64.10 April 30 City Water Co., water 45 . 90 Midway Gas Co., gas and supplies... 18.60 J. M. Robinson, coal 297.00 Knutzen &amp; Isdell, labor and supplies.. 58.37 I 5,680 46 * 6.000. ftO Amount lapsed end of biennium 319.45 PRINTING AND OFFICE SUPPLIES. Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 $ 1,500.0* 1907 Amount expended to January 1 1 1,232 . 94 Jan. 4 Kearney Hub, printing and supplies.. 28.75 H. A. Webbert, paper and supplies... 32.05 State Journal Co., printing 10.00 March 29 New Era Pub. Co., printing 8.25 A. B. Dick Co., printing and supplies 2.45 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">33 April 30 H. A. Webbert, printing and supplies 10S.19 Kearney Hub, printing and supplies 76.00 $ 1.499.13 $ Amount lapsed end of biennium ST EQUIPMENT, FURNITURE, ETC Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1905-1907 $ I,J Amount expended to January 1, 1907 $ 9,495.73 $ 9,495.73 $ Amount lapsed end of biennium 4 . 27 IMPROVEMENT OF GROUNDS. Appropriation for biennium April 1, 1905-1907 $ Amount expended to January 1. 1907 $ 4.998.26 $ 4.998. 26 t Amount lapsed end of biennium 1 .47 COMMENCEMENT. INCIDENTAL EXPENSES Amount appropriated for biennium April 1, $ 800.00 1907 Amount expended to January 1 ,t 1 Jan. 4 J. L. McBrien, advertising raska Teacher, advertising 16.00 % 798 . 59 $ Amount lapsed end of biennium... 1.41 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">EXPENSE, MEMBERS OF BOARD. Appropriation for the biennium April 1, 1M6-1M7 * 34 1907 Aniount expended to January 1 $ 1,1 Jan. 4 A. O. Thomas, expenses ]2 sl' T. J. Majors, expenses 8.80 Jas. E. Delzell, expenses M.li U P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses. . . . ('. H. Gregg, expenses 17. M J. W. Crabtree, expenses Rudge &amp; Guenzel, supplies... I.M Luther P. Ludden. expeMM Peter Mortensen 6.92 State Journal Co., printing March 29 C. H. Gregg, expenses 1S.SS Jas. E. Delzell 10. 1R L. P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses. . . 33.33 Luther P. Ludden. expenses Benton Bros., printing H. M. Childs, expenses 7.74 T. J. Majors, expenses April 30 T. J. Thorpe Co., rubber stamps Harry Porter, supplies 11.10 T. J. Majors, expenses Luther P. Ludden. expenses * i Amount lapsed at end of biennium I.M PERU, 1907-1909, SALARY. Appropriation for biennium April 1, 1M7-1M9 1907 I Apr. 20. Pay roll May 20. Pay roll June 11. Pay roll July 10. Pay roll July 22. Pay roll Aug. 23, Pay roll Oct. 3, Pay roll Nov. 1, Pay roll Nov. 23, Pay roll Dec. 18, Pay roll 1'4OS . . .1 3,70 3 448.13 2,777 .on 3.K" 3,fi!' 3.t;u </seg>
            <seg id="p033">35 BI-ENNIAL REPORT P&gt;b. 20 Pay roll 3,739.32 -&gt; Mar. 20. Pay roll 3,617 Apr. JO. Pay roll 3.721 si May JO. Pay roll S.«*3 00 June 2, Pay roll 95 00 AM 20, P«&gt; roll 3.300.00 July 21. Pay roll 3,267.00 Auk 20. Pay roll 791.67 8«pt. 10. Pay roll 1 -« ■ 3« Oct. 1. Pay roll 4.353.70 Nor. 1. Pay roll 4.342.00 De*. 8 Pay roll 4.795.80 D«c. 21. Pay roll 516.20 Balance on hand January 1. 1909 14.276.91 $ $ $ 88,000.00 H 4 000.00 196.35 Appropriation for biennlum, Apr. 1. 1907-1909 mo: May 10. Pay roll * 189 . 45 June 11. Pay roll 184.20 July 23. Pay roll 230.00 Aug. 23, Pay roll 175.00 3, Pay roll 230.00 Oct. 25, Pay roll 230. 00 20, Pay roll 258.45 Dae. 18. Pay roll 274.10 i Jan. 20, Pay roll 230.00 20, Pay roll OB M Mar. 20 Pay roll 235.00 Apr. 20, Pay roll 190.00 May 20, Pay roll 280. 00 June 21, Pay roll 235 . 00 July 21, Pay roll 235.00 Auk 20. Pay roll 230. 00 gept. 12, Pay roll 339.75 Oct. 1 , Pay roll 224 . 25 1 . Pay roll 286 . 00 Dae. i. Pay roll 78.00 $ 4.196.35 I 4 MAINTENANCE. Appropriation for biennium, Apr. 1. 1907-1909 $ 1!&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p034">36 Morton Printing Co., printing 130.00 Horace Partridge Co.. supplies 25.16 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 33.44 C. B. Havens Co., coal 513.72 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. for frt 30.45 May 10 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. postage 72'. 20 E. L. TTptegrove, office supplies 25.00 Bee Pub. Co., advertising 11.00 Ross P. Curtice Co., rent pianos 150.00 J. C. Chatelain, repairs on clocks 8.50 Bausch &amp; Lomb Co., miscellaneous.... 168.33 C. B. Havens &amp; Co., coal 809.12 Western Supply Co., supplies 25.09 June 3 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 6.00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 4.23 Gaylord Bros., supplies 6.75 ML C. Jack, ribbons, etc 19.00 Central Scientific Co 22.62 Remington Typewriter Co., writer 70.00 J. \V. Crabtree, cash, adv. pumping 35.10 Ray Weaverling, hardware 29.65 S. W. Hacker, printing 121.50 Lincoln Star, advertising 1 1 . 00 July 23 Xebr. School Sup. Co.. furniture 259.71 Oliver Typewriter Co., typewriter 62.50 Smith Premier Co., typewriter 90.00 Ross P. Curtis Co., rent, piano 10.00 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. H. B. Duncanson, cash for clocks 143.70 advanced for books, etc 60.50 H. B. Duncanson, cash advanced for Supplies, etc 19.45 H. B. Duncanson, cash advanced for stamps, etc 42. 68 H. B. Duncanson, cash advanced for freight, etc 43 . 33 M. E. Good, supplies 7.50 Montgomery-Ward Co., refrigerator 22.89 H. B. Duncan, cash advanced labor 48.75 Standard Oil Co.. oil, etc 82.34 Korsmeyer Co., fuse wire 1 . 63 C. B. Havens Co., coal 354.63 Hayes &amp; George, coal 28 . 30 J. S. Hemenway Co., supplies, lab 35.00 Cornell Eng. Co., supplies Lab 100.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">S4 H. B. Duneanson, cash advanced for •applies 18.06 Hammond ft Stephens, paper 12 . 00 Auburn Printing Co., paper 19.50 E. L. Uptegrove, supplies 5 . 40 Nebr. Teacher, advertising 15 . 00 Cornell Eng. Co., engravings 65 . 01 Miller ft Paine, toilet paper 10.50 8. W. Hacker ft Co., supplies 13.90 Nebr. School Supply, paper and supplies. 38.80 ■apt. IS Rudge ft Guenzel Co., supplies 11.86 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, supplies •tc 126.65 E. L. Uptegrove, supplies 55 . 45 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 42.26 Rudge * Guenzel Co., supplies 9.03 Nebr. Bag Co., envelopes 8 . 00 Nebr. Newspaper Union, printing 290.88 Oct. 24 Rudge ft Guenzel Co., supplies 13.77 New Century Co., printing 15.00 Ben ton Bros., printing 15.00 Bausch ft Lomb Co., Lab. supplies 84.75 John T. Maherr, supplies 7.80 Freeport Gas Co.. gas machine 410.38 C. B. Havens Co., coal 431.29 H. Hell Chemical Co., supplies Lab 15.95 Qoe— A Co., repairs and supplies 92.38 BurrU Drug Co., supplies Lab 80.35 Korsmeyer Co., electrical supplies 13.40 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, Forman. 32.50 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, labor 12.56 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, postage, •*« 71.61 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv, freight 59.61 1908 Jan. 4 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, postage, •tc 14S.80 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, labor.. 646.81 J. W. Orabtree, cash advanced, freight •t*. 114.01 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, lecture.. 4.11 J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced, Agricul- tural Department 18.01 Toledo Pipe Thread Co., supplies 4.60 8. W. Hacker, supplies 109.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 38 Her ft Co., supplies Lab 23.61 C. B. Havens &amp; Co., coal 677.67 Queen &amp; Co., supplies Lab 19.47 Standard Oil Co., oil. etc 82.32 Narragansett Machine Co., supplies... 425.40 W. ft L. E. Gurley, supplies Lab 6. 40 Ross P. Curtice Co., piano rental 60.00 Nebr. School Sup. Co., supplies 121.44 Griswold Seed Co., supplies Agr. Dep... 9.34 Frank Medley, repairs heating plant 16.65 Bausch &amp; Lomb Co., supplies Lab 360.05 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 76.08 Nebr. Electric Co., supplies 13 . 20 Benton iiros., offices upplies 14.00 Sunderland Bros. Co., repairs 121.15 Miller &amp; Paine, supplies Lab 17.37 Barnes Drug Co., office supplies 31.40 Harry Porter, office supplies 28 . 40 Ray W. Weaverling, hardware 35 . 79 B. C. Gilford labor and supplies 5.95 Nebr. School Sup. Co., supplies 40.00 Mar . 13 Korsmeyer Co., supplies 285 . 06 C. B. Havens Co., coal 1,399 . 15 H. P. Whitmore, supplies 21 . 00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 2R4.37 Freeport Gas Mch. Co., supplies 8.40 Sunderland Bro. Co., fire ciay 6.66 Cambridge Supply Co., supplies Lab 59.67 Xebr. School Supply Co., supplies 102.95 M. F. Good, supplies 10.56 Barnes Drug Co., supplies 13.93 Standard Oil Co., gasoline, etc 154.35 R. W. Weaverling Hardware, etc 96.90 Burrls Drug Co., supplies 137 . 20 Nebr. Sch. Sup. Co., stationery *» 17.60 Harry Porter, stationery, etc 46.10 N. A. Bengston, athletic supplies 25.00 S. W. Hacker, supplies 123.20 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv, labor, etc... 778.25 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. postage, etc.. 338.07 State Journal Co., office supplies S8.50 Alice Loomls, cash adv., supplies 17.63 Nebr. Newspaper Union, stationery 128.07 May 25 Western Supply Co., hardware 165.73 June 1 W. ft L. E. Gurley, supplies 8.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">39 BI-ENNIAL REPORT M. C. Ltlley £ Co., uniforms, etc 21.41 Nebi. Paper Bag Co., stationery, etc... 20.00 Korsmeyer Co.. electrical supplies 15.18 Kortroeyer Co., electrical supplies 2.54 Reese Printing Co., diplomas 67.50 C. B. Havens Co., coal 624.38 Burris Drug Co., supplies 41.50 Crane Co., supplies Lab 46 . 00 Rudge £ Guenzel Co., supplies 141.35 Alice Loomis, cash adv., supplies 18.45 Cusbman Power Co., supplies, etc J W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor, etc 330.40 J \V. Crabtree, cash adv. freight, etc.. Crane Co., hardware 74.75 Central Scien. Co., supplies Lab 21.65 Western Elec. Co.. electrical sup 67.13 Standard Oil Co., oil, etc 74.13 Rudge A Guenzel Co., supplies 19.35 S. W. Hacker, printing 141.85 Ray W. Weaverling, hardware 27 . 27 Meek Lumber Co., coal 4.00 July 23 Burris Drug Co., supplies 15 . 30 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor, etc 37 . 20 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. postage, etc.. 166.13 Alice Loomis, Sup. Dom. Science 18.85 8. W. Hacker, printing 17.50 ."underland Co., roof coating, etc 31.20 R. W. Weaverling, hardware 14.7: Standard Oil Co., gasoline, etc 87. 3S Frank Pettit labor 2C.00 C B. Havens Co., coal 309.79 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. Com. Ex. etc.. . 257.92 6 .enton -.ros., stationery 78 . 00 Korsmeyer Co., electric supplies 29.28 Nebr. Bag &amp; Paper Co., envelopes 12.00 Imperial Brush Co., brushes, etc 24.30 Sutherland Roofing Co., supplies 21.10 Nebr. Newspaper Union, bulletins 83.00 Rom P. Curtice Co., rental pianos 140.00 Korsmeyer Co., lamps 20.90 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv.. labor, etc 75.11 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv., postage, etc. 80.57 Auburn Ptg. Co., printing 23.25 Smith Premier Co., typewriter sup 14.76 H. B. Duncanson, cash adv. lab. sup 2S . SO </seg>
            <seg id="p038">40 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Burris Drug Co., supplies 36 H. O. Cole, labor and supplies State Journal Co., stationery, etc M . K. Good, groceries 1 1 . 05 Crane &amp; Co., supplies 33.43 S. \V. Hacker, printing ISO. 50 Standard Oil -oline 42. 05 Standard Oil Co., gasoline I W. Crabtree, cash adv. postage, c 28i.83 Standard Oil Co. Rasoline Standard Oil Co. gasoline John Hanna, supplies 82.50 John Hanna, supplies 82.50 Galvanic Bronze Co., tablet, etc Galvanic Bronze Co., tablet, etc Germo Mfg. Co., Carboline ft Germo... 30.00 Germo Mfg. Co., Carboline &amp; Germo... 30.00 B. C. Gifford, labor, wood, etc 34.00 B. C. Gifford, labor, wood, etc 34.00 Hardy Furniture Co., furniture Hardy Furniture Co., furniture 22.75 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal Whitebreaat Coal Co., coal S. C. Orr. lantern slides 18.90 S. C. Orr. lantern slides 18.90 Auburn Ptg. Co., exam, blanks Auburn Ptg. Co.. exam, blanks .1 W. ( rabtre... cash adv. labor, etc 103.90 .1 W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor, etc 103.90 .T. \V. Crabtree, cash adv. labor, etc.... 60.12 .T. W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor, etc 60.12 Ray W. Weaverling, hardware IS. 7* Ray W. Weaverling, hardware IB. 70 I .1 W. CrmMraa, cash adv. postage, etc.. 203.16 I .1. \V. Crabtree. cash adv. postage, etc.. 203.16 Mrs. M. C. Jack, ribbons 19.80 Mrs. M. C. Jack, ribbons 19.80 S. W. Hacker &amp; Co.. printing 26.35 S. W. Hacker &amp; Co.. printing 26. 35 Meek Lumber Co.. cement, etc 39.84 Meek Lumber Co., cement, etc 39.84 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal Whitebreast Coal Co., coal M. K. C.ood, groceries M. K. C.ood. groceries Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 Balance on hand Jan. 1. 190!t _ $ 19,950.00 $ 1!»." PERU— 1907-1908. PERU— 1907-1908. GENERAL REPAIRS. GENERAL REPAIRS. tpropriation for biennium, Apr. 1, 1907-1909.... r. 30 Meek Lumber Co.. lumber $ J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor 66.80 Appropriation for biennium, Apr. 1, 1907-1909 $ 6,1 1907 Apr. 30 Meek Lumber Co.. lumber $ &gt; J. \V. Crabtree, cash adv. labor 66.80 10 Meek Lumber Co., lumber 149.75 J. \V. Cmbtree, cash adv. labor etc H. O. Cole, repair supplies CM June 3 Meek Lumber Co., lumber 176. M J. \V. Crabtree, cash adv. repairs 649.53 C. W. Jones, tools and supplies Sunderland Roofing Co., supplies </seg>
            <seg id="p039">41 J. R. Lehmer, hardware 348.75 July 23 H. B. Duncan son, cash adv. labor 558.27 H. B. Dunranson, cash adv. supplies.... 228.21 Meek Lumber Co., lumber 223.34 Western Supply Co., supplies 22.92 Henderson, grass seed 14.00 J. Hanlon, labor 25 . 00 Nebr. City Iron Works, supplies 141.12 Table Rock Clay Co., brick 327.30 Table Rock Clay Co., brick 77.20 H. O. Cole, hardware 26.96 Lyman Sand Co.. sand 21.28 I. Wessel &amp; Sons, sheeting 10.19 Sept. 13 Sunderland Bros., sewer pipe 140.15 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor 198.18 Nebr. City Iron Works, supplies 44.86 Meek Lumber Co.. lumber, etc 360.92 .T \V. Kerns, crushed stone 24 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor 260.43 Meek Lumber Co., lumber 66.11 Jan. 4 Lincoln Sash &amp; Door Co., doors, etc... 53.50 Lumber Co., lumber 119. li Mar. IS Meek Lumber Co., lumber 271.66 Medley Bros., paper hanging, etc 36.30 July 23 Western Supply Co., sheet packing etc.. 22.07 Meek Lumber Co.. plaster, etc 22.56 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv.. labor 94.99 6 Meek Lumber Co., lumber, etc 359.07 J. W. Crabtree, cash adv. labor 93.75 Neb. City Iron Works, boiler crabs 3.00 .1 \V. Crabtree, cash adv. labor 84.25 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 .11 $ 6,000.00 5 6.H' PRINCIPAL'S TRAVELING EXPENSES Appropriation for biennium, Apr. 1, 1907-1909. $ 400.0 Apr. SO J. W. Crabtree, expense $ 10.36 June 3 J. W. Crabtree, expense 24.14 Sept. IS H. B. Duncanson. expense 6.88 Oct. 24 J. W. Crabtree, expense 52 . 83 Jan. 4 J. W. Crabtree, expense 19.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">42 Mar. 13 J. W. Crabtree, expense June 1 J. W. Crabtree, expense 49 . 2«&gt; July U .1. W. Crabtree. expense Nov. 6 J. \V. I'rabtree, expense Dec. 8 J. W. Crabtree, expense 20.52 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 83.82 $ 460.00 $ NEW HEATING PLANT Appropriation for biennium, Apr. 1, 1907-1909.... $ 25,000. •« 1907 July 23 Trade Review, advertising $ 2.00 Luther P. Ludden, cash adv. labor 9.60 H. B. Duncanson. cash adv. labor 12V ir, Joe Bunger, contractor 4,09 Sept. 13 J. W. Crabtree. cash adv. Labor 411.92 Lyman Sand Co.. sand 11.92 Table Rock Clay Co.. brick 171.30 Sunderland Bros., fire brick Allen, making plans 50.00 Sunderland Bros., Contract 5 .544 . M Joe Bunger, contractor 3,:: Oct. 24 Sunderland Bros., contract 1,1 Western Supply Co.. contract Allis Chalmers Co., contract J. W. Crabtree, cash for freight J. W Crabtree, cash for labor 541.01 Nov. 23 Joe Bunger, contractor 4.771.42 1908 Jan. 4 Allis Chalmers Co. bal. on contract.... Sunderland Roofing Co.. bal. con 771. no Western Supply Co.. supplies 172.06 J \V. Crabtree, cash adv. freifcli' 141.77 Western Supply Co., packing, etc Joseph Bunger 167. IS Meek Lumber Co.. lumber Neb. City Iron Works, iron bracket.... Sunderland Bros., fire clay 6.67 Table Rock Clay Co., brick 60.30 Mar. 13 Western Supply Co., supplies June 1 Western Supply Co.. supplies Meek Lumber Co., lumber 30.99 J. W. Crabtree. freight, etc 16.12 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 .26 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">43 BI-ENNIAL REPORT KEARNEY — 1907-1909 SALARY. "iK).OO * MAINTENANCE. ipriatlon for biennium, Apr. 1. 1907-1909.. $ 19.:&gt; . Apr. 30 Western Union Co.. clock rent $ 15.00 nc Co . supplies 6.70 Stoeling Co.. supplies 123.22 ing Clock Co clock for biennium. Apr. 1, 1907-1909.... I'ay roll $ IT Pay roll 2.995.60 2,987.10 3,031.65 16 Pay roll 3,090.95 roll i oil 488.30 3.038.45 3.149.65 3 156.20 Deo. B :.2.6» Jan. 4 Pay roll 11.85 Jan. 23 Pay roll roll 3,118.45 Mar. 13 Pay roll i.2O Pay roll 34.05 Pay roll 18.00 Mar. 20 Pay roll 3.118.45 - I'ay roll May 20 Pay roll 3,4 V 3.485.20 30.00 32.30 Pay roll 10.60 ... 3,532.08 Aug. I'ay roll I'ay roll 3,515.68 3.478.70 3,432.98 1 u Pay roll 7.80 20 Pay roll 3,461.10 D«c. roll Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 3.438.10 12.148.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">44 Harrison Nursery Co., trees 134.25 Mary Bailey, music supplies 21.08 May 10 Knutzen &amp; Isdell, tables, etc 213.74 Ward's Nat. Science Co., supplies 14.75 Nebr. Newspaper Union, printing 175.00 June 3 Kearney Hub, printing, etc 112.20 A. C. E verson, supplies 10.55 J. M. Robinson, coal 102.30 Midway Gas Co., gas 14.35 H. A. Webbert, paper and supplies 47.45 K. O. Holmes, supplies 15.49 Nebr. Educational Co., supplies 5.00 Midland Glass Co., glass 9.41 J. E. Tuttle, Commencement services... 35.00 A. O. Thomas, cash for postage, etc 108.95 Nebr. Newspaper Union, balance printing 73.00 Kearney Hub, printing 18.75 New Era Co., printing 8.75 City Water Co., water 73.35 Robt. Mclntyre, supplies 2.50 H. A. Webbert, supplies 27.80 P. H. Gilcrest, lumber 8.00 A. B. Dick Co., supplies S.50 K. O. Holmes, supplies 7.61 Ward"s Nat. Science Co 3.00 F. J. Saup. hall rent, commencement 40.00 Bausch &amp; Lomb Co., supplies 174.67 Nebr. School Supply Co., supplies 60.60 Patterson &amp; Wingard, grass seed 6.40 Marine Boil. Lab. Co., supplies 33.25 Geo. D. Barr, treas., printing, adv 10.00 State Journal Co., printing adv 34.00 W. D. Ross, supplies 20 . 00 Rand McNally Co., maps 80.50 Frank Holton Co.. musical inst 76.00 Sept. 13 A. O. Thomas, cash advanced 38.99 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. furniture, etc 102.65 Kearney Phone Co., telephone 26.10 Nebr. Phone Co., telephone 29.15 City Water Co., water 71.45 New Era Pub. Co., printing 14.63 Oct. 24 Switz Furniture Co., furniture 40.96 Binney &amp; Smith, crayola 3.00 Kny-Scheerer Co., lab. supplies 102 . 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">45 BI-ENNIAL REPORT Carpenter Paper Co.. paper 6. 40 Rand-McNally Co., globes 13.00 Prang Edu. Co., kindergarten sup 64.71 A. J. Lee, carbon paper 3.00 H. A. Small, supplies. Rudge &amp; Guenzel. furniture 54.50 Harry Porter, office supplies 32.20 Benton Bros., printing 15.00 A. B. Dick Co., supplies 10.95 Midway Gas Co., gas 5.60 H. A. Webbert, supplies 49.10 A. O. Thomas, freight and postage 55 . 86 Jan. 4 A. O. Thomas, cash adv., postage, etc.. 138.10 Rand, McNally Co., supplies 44.33 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 10.50 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 20 . 94 DeVoe &amp; Reynolds, paints 14.00 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., supplies 14.55 Xebr. School Sup. Co., supplies 226.18 i-rn Union Co., rent of cloc'i 15.00 Fred Medart, mats, etc 166.80 Spencer Lens Co., microscope, etc 63.89 Bairach &amp; Lomb Co., microscope, etc... 754.49 L. E. Knott Co., supplies lab 54.49 Atlas School Sup. Co., globe, etc 23.20 F. D. Barker, sup. bio. lab 13 . 75 Nebr. Tel. Co., phone rent and tolls 20.00 City Water Co., water 45.60 N. P. Matison, supplies 34.82 Kearney Tele Co., phone rent 8.75 Kearney Hub, printing and supplies 92.65 K. O. Holmes, supplies 7.90 H. A. Webbert, supplies 51.10 J. M. Robinson, coal 885.87 Mar. 13 Journal Co., steel lockers 200.00 Kearney Phone Co., phone rent, etc 9.35 Switz Furn. Co., matts, etc 5.95 Omaha Printing Co., cash books 8 . 50 Gilcrest Lumber Co., supplies 24 . 50 Newson ft Co., pictures 12. 00 Randolph-Jones Co., models, etc 25.00 Nebr. School Sup. Co., pencil sharpeners 7.00 ■nond Stephens Co.. reports 1 . 6o </seg>
            <seg id="p044">46 ■STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 5.. E. Knott, supplies lab 4" . 22 X. J. Lee, carbon paper J. II. Robinson, coal 741.13 Nebr. Phone Co., tolls and rentals 15.00 Kearney Hub Co., supplies 19.10 H. A. Webbert, toilet paper, etc 18.95 \. O. Thomas, cash adv.. stamps, etc.... 136.95 Harry Porter, stationery 7 .M Midway Gas Co., gas and mantles 29.90 BodinBon Hdw. Co., hardware 3.10 K. O. Holmes, kindergarten supplies Omaha School Sup. Co., furniture 86.50 Rockwell Barnes Co., office supplies.... 1.60 Ward Nat. Sci. Co., supplies Lab A. B. Dick Co., stencil paper 10.60 Vaughin Seed Co., raphia, etc 4 . 5fl Bausch &amp; Lomb Co., supplies Lab 165.69 Cambridge Sup. Co., ■supplies Lab 50.40 City Water Co., water May 26 Kearney Grocery Co., groceries 74 .92 A. O. Thomas, cash adv., express, etc. .. 165.6?. P. Henderson, seed K. O. Holmes, supplies 1 " . on Kearney Hub. stationery, etc 1 53 . 75 S. A. D. Henline, oil, etc J. M. Robinson, coal Midway Gas Co., gas, etc 8.45 Rees Printing Co., diplomas Lucien Smith, window shades F. S. Webster Co., supplies F. A. Newell. Bac. sermon Robcow James, supplies 1 25 . 00 Cambridge Supply Co., supplies Lab.... 1. 11 National Supply Co., clay Kny-Sheerer Co., barometer, etc 63.65 May 20 H. A. Webbert, bulletins, etc City Water Co.. water F. H. Gilchrist, lumber 7.45 L. E. Knott Co., supplies Lab Review Pub. Co., printing 8.35 Thomas Charles Co.. Sup. Kindergarten. Gaylord Bros., supplies Ward Sup. Co., Supplies Lab 2 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">47 BI-ENNrAL REPORT i Nebraska Teacher, advertising 25.00 Atlas Sch. Sup. Co., class reports 10.80 Western Union Tel. Clock rental 15. OO June I A. O. Thomas Cor.im. Address 85.00 T. J. Thorpe £ Co., steel stamp 1.0O July 23 Marion Smith, supplies art dept 84. Iff H. P. Whitmore. picture frames 200.00 Xebr. Phone Co., tolls and rentals.... 21.10 Kearney Phone Co. tolls and rentals.. 8.00 City Water Co., water 53.70 Midway Gas Co., gas, etc 17.45 N \V Electric Co., lights 8.24 J. S. Moore, saw dust 4.55 Hospe Piano Co., piano 130.00 B. H. Baldwin Co., piano 90.00 Lucien Smith, book-case 9.00 Thomas Charles Co., supplies :. 33.20 Harry Porter, supplies 30.45 Kearney Grocery Co 8 Review Pub. Co., printing : 8 . 00 State Journal Co., record sheets, etc... 7.00 J. F. Shaup. mgr. rent of hall 40 . 00 Lincoln Paint Co., paint 64.00 A. J. \jee, carbon paper 4.00 New Era Pub. Co., printing 8.50 H. A. Small plaster Paris, etc 12.60 S. A. D. Henline, supplies 3.35 H. A. Webbert, letter heads, etc 35.50 Kearney Hub. printing 25.50 Hammond &amp; Stephens, printing 68.00 r. F. Bodinson Co., hardware 9.30 L. E. Knott App. Co., supplies Lab 217.53 Kearney Hard. Co., hardware 81 . 75 A. O. Thomas, cash adv. freight, etc 60.28 Kewanee Boiler Co., repairs 50.30 Cambridge Botanical Co.. Lab. Sup 8.69 C. H. Stoeling Co., Lab. sup 38.14 Mclntosh Stereopticon Co.. I^ab. sup 90.50 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. furniture, etc.... 442.45 W. L. Hand, printing 4 25 J. M. Robinson coal 544.85 Bodinson Hdw. Co., hardware 6.65 Kearney Grocery Co., groceries 18.15 Kearney Phone Co., phone rent 9.95 Kearney Hub., stationery, etc 113.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">48 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION A. 0. Thomas, cash adv. postage, etc.. 346.53 Uty Water Co., water 75.45 J. D. Hawthorne, supplies 94.50 H. A. Small, floor brushes, etc 20.35 Kearney Steam Laundry, laundry 5.50 Western Union Tel. Co., time service etc 16.60 Midway Gas Co., gas 6.25 Harry Porter, supplies 50.63 Carpenter Paper Co., saw dust 3.50 Milton Darling, pictures 4.00 Fred Medart steel lockers, etc 304.00 Prang Edu. Co., supplies 76.44 Ward's Natural Science Sup. Lab 12.25 M. A. Webbert, supplies 95.00 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 38.01 Marine Biol Co., supplies Lab 9.00 L. E. Knott App. Co., supplies Lab 32.25 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Nebr. Telephone Co., toll • 22 . 25 State Journal Co., vault fixtures 1,000.00 Kearney Water Co., current, etc 28.37 Rees Wilkinson, writerpress, etc 138.50 F. H. Gilchrist Co., lumber, etc 75.00 Benton Bros., printing 28.50 Dec. 8 A. O. Thomas, cash adv. express, etc... 62.10 H. A. Webbert, stationery, etc 27 . 60 Scott Bros., fire clay 2.35 S. A. D. Henline, glass cabinet 33.00 A. H. Andrews Co., supplies 13.80 Kearney Daily Hub, bulletins, etc 66.00 City Water Co., water 26 . 10 Denver Fire Clay Co. Lab. Supplies 198.01 A. J. Lee, chemicals, etc 13.10 Kearney Water Co., supplies 331.99 Mclntosh Stereoptlcon Co., supplies... 1.25 J. M. Robinson, coal 175.30 K. O. Holmes, supplies 13 . 55 Kearney Water Co., supplies, etc 40.95 E. J. Thygesen, decorating chapel 75.00 Lucien Smith, shades 13. 65 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 3,998.63 $ 19,300.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">49 GENERAL REPAIRS. Appropriation for biennium, Apr. 1, 1907-1909 | 5,000 00 1907 May 10 Sam. W. Tool, labor $ 9.00 W. H. Arnold, trees 9.20 June 3 Knutzen ft Isdell, labor contract 727.79 A. Troxel, labor on grounds 67.75 C. A. Edwards, labor on groun Is 1 . 50 A. O. Thomas, cash adv., labor 9.00 Henry Leskey, labor on grounds 11 .00 July 2» W. L. Stickel Lumber Co., lumber 6.00 Sept. 13 E. J. Thygesen, decorating building 616.28 Oet 24 A. O. Thomas, cash adv., labor 36.25 E. J. Thygesen, dressing floor 18.74 Jan. 4 F. N. Gilcrest Co., lumber, etc 39.45 Knutzen ft Isdell, labor 185.15 Knutzen ft Isdell, labor 29 . 80 N. W. Electric Co., wiring, etc 23.50 Kearney Hardware Co., hardware 71 . 89 Mar. 13 A. O. Thomas, cash adv., labor 30.40 Knutzen ft Isdell, labor and supplies... 6.75 Lincoln Paint Co., paint 185.60 E. J. Thygeson, varnishing, etc 3.25 W. K. Ayers, gas piping 4.20 Knutzen ft Isdell, material and labor.. 126.47 May 26 A. O. Thomas, cash adv. labor 190.60 W. H. Arnold, trees 5.90 J H. Hadinson, labor 72.84 Switz Furn. Co., supplies 17 . 55 Midland Glass Co., glass 21.13 July 23 A. Troxel, labor 70.00 Swltz Furniture Co., paint 30.00 J. A. Allhands, labor 59.50 A. O. Thomas, labor 59.75 W. S. Freeman, supplies and labor 64.50 N. N. Hawley, labor 12.00 Balto ft Jacobson, supplies and labor... 346.42 E. J. Thygesen, painting 231 .00 Nov. 6 Hlbbard Brick Co., repairing boiler 20.00 Burgess Grandon Co., fixtures 341.00 Bolte ft Jacobson, cement walk 145.59 E- » Th nalntl m r fi Qf) </seg>
            <seg id="p048">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 50 Chas. P. Lucas, supplies and labor 19.55 Knutzen &amp; Isdell, labor and material... 165.97 Swltz Furn. Co., supplies 237 . 70 A. O. Thomas, labor 158 . 95 Gardner Governor Co., pump 60 . 00 X. P. Mat-son, supplies 190.29 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 203.89 % 5,000.00 $ 5,000.00 PRINCIPAL'S TRAVELING EXPEN8E. Appropriation for Biennium, Apr. 1, 1907-1909 $ 400.00 1907 Apr. 20 A. O. Thomas, expenses $ 20.80 May 10 A. O. Thomas, expenses 12.88 June 3 A. O. Thomas, expenses 9.43 July 23 A. O. Thomas, expenses 21.58 Sept. IS' A. O. Thomas, expenses 25.39 Oct. 24 A. O. Thomas, expenses 18.66 1908 Jan. 4 A. O. Thomas, expenses 45.84 Mar. 13 A. O. Thomas, expenses 36.62 May 26 A. O. Thomas, expenses 36.76 July 23 A. O. Thomas, expenses 31.21 Nov. 6 A. O. Thomas, expenses 70.24 Dec. 8 A. O. Thomas, expenses 32.07 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 38.52 f 400.00 $ 400.00 LIBRARY FUND. Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1907 $ 1,328.89 1907 Jan. 4 H. Holt &amp; Co., books $ 83.67 Macmillian Co., books 40.34 Prang Educational Co., books 12.80 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 6 . 68 Dr. Abbott, books 5.00 Columbia Col. Ex., books 59.10 De Bowers Elliott Co., books 61.50 A. J. Mercer, books 5.50 Maynard Merrill Co., books 25.97 Waldorf Bindery, binding books 136.95 , Wrtrtl, O_i (\\ </seg>
            <seg id="p049">51 BI-ENNIAL REPORT Deposited with State Treasurer. Mar. 29 Rand, McNally &amp; Co., books 41.88 Scribner &amp; Sons, books 12 . 88 University of Cha., books 9.26 Wm. G. Johnston &amp; Co., books 27 . 40 Gaylord Bros., books 8.20 World Publishing Co., books 2.40 Maynard Merrill Co., books 6.51 T. Y. Crowell &amp; Co., books 19.75 Scott Foresman Co., books 16. 00 The Macmillian Co., books 2.58 Houghton, Mifflin &amp; Co., books 15.30 Flanagan &amp; Co., books 18.45 Atkinson, Mentzer &amp; Co.. books 6.60 D. Appleton &amp; Co., books 60.09 H. H. Wilson Co., books 10.00 T. N. Hartzell, books 322.26 State Journal Co., paper 6 . 25 Hartzell Book Store, books 426 . 45 B. H. Sanborn &amp; Co., books 3.42 A. J. Barnes Co., books 21.37 Pub. School Co., books 3.14 Lincoln Star, paper 3 . 00 Apr. 30 T. N. Hartzell, books 100.31 Library Bureau, Library Sup 12.50 Carnegie Library Co., books 2 . 05 May 10 Bee Publishing Co., paper 4.00 June 3 K. O. Holmes, periodicals 154.65 June 8 Deposited with State Treasurer 650.00 July 23 Appleton Co., books 7 . 72 Macmillian Co., books 14.29 Educational Pub. Co., books 4.58 Western Pub. Co.. books 25.00 A. J. Barnes Pub Co 7 . 38 Atkinson, Mentzer &amp; Co., books 15.00 C. E. Merrill Co., books 3.56 T. N. Hartzell, books 261.39 Boston Book Co., books 135 . 00 Sept 13 Silver Burdett Co., books 174.46 Ginn tc Co., books 182.80 Oct 24 Atkinson, Mentzer Co., books 12. 00 Universal Pub. Co., books 44.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., book binding 160.80 Appleton * Co., books 6.84 W If Welfh Cn hnnki ♦ 1 A </seg>
            <seg id="p050">52 H. Holt &amp; Co., books.. Macmillian Co., books. 6.98 15.60 8.00 W. A. Clark, books. Oct. 10 Deposited with State Treasurer. 1908 Jan. 4 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books. 187.92 7.00 B. H. San born Co., books. Allyn &amp; Bacon, books. 27.60 American Book Co., books. 456.54 11.60 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding Per. Ginn &amp; Co., books. 103.48 Macmillian Co., books T. N. Hartzell, books. 2.78 354.53 Irwin Shepard, supplies. 47.75 K. O. Holmes, magazines. 167.30 500.00 Jan. 17 Deposited with State Treasurer. Mar. 13 Waldorf Bindery, binding books. 6.10 A. O. Thomas, cash adv. cards. 15.00 K. O. Holmes, subscriptions. Lincoln Star, subscriptions.. 8.65 3.75 5.85 State Journal, subscriptions A. ('. McClurg Co., books 80.64 May 26 K. O. Holmes, subscription. 3.')0 W. K. Fowler, books. 58.12 337. 2S McClurg &amp; Co., books McDevitt -Wilson, books 32.60 169. 34 Library Bureau, library supplies C. J. Platt, executor books 22.50 July 23 A O. Thomas, cash adv., labor, etc. 25.00 State Journal Co., subscription.... Waldorf Bindery Co., binding books 5.00 71.90 81.00 Jas. T. White &amp; Co., books Bee Publishing Co.. subscription 8.00 E. J. Dissette. treas. books 45.60 July 13 Deposited with state treasurer.. Nov. 6 Lincoln Dally Star, subscription. 1.300.00 3.00 6.00 World Pub. Co., subscription. Peru Normal School, books. . 23.50 A. O. Thomas, books 1.50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books. Longmans, Green Co., books. S68.50 2.90 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding books. 4.55 DeBower-Elliott Co., books. 54.72 Nov. 13 Deposited with state treasurer 6S5.00 $ 6.676.21 $ 1,427.68 7,103.89 $ 7,103.89 $ 7,103.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">53 BI-ENNIAL REPORT EXPENSE OF THE BOARD FUND. % 1,900.00 Appropriation for the biennlum April 1, 1907-1909 1907 Apr . 30 C. H. Gregg, expenses % 29 . 60 L P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses 16.67 J. L. McBrlen, expenses 7 . 04 Jas. L. Delzell, expenses 19.80 H. M. Childs, expenses 6.91 Luther P. Ludden, expenses 14.39 T. J. Majors, expenses 8 . 94 May 10 T. J. Majors, expenses 6.96 H. M. Childs, expenses 12.08 June 3 T. J. Majors, expenses 11.08 Jas. E. Delzell. expenses 12.82 C. H. Gregg, expenses 13.81 Luther P. Ludden, expenses 16. 0i L. P. Ludden sec'y office expenses 9 Q 39 L. P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses.... 16.66 July 23 H. B. Duncanson. expenses 15.00 Harry Porter, supplies 9.40 Benton Bros., printing L. G. Brian, expenses 4.97 B. L. Shellhorn, expenses 7.40 Jas. E. Delzell, expenses 19.66 &lt;\ H. Gregg, expenses 13.56 Luther P. Ludden. expenses 33.30 L. P. Ludden, sec'y services 50.00 Sept 13 C. H. Gregg, expenses 14.95 L. P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses.. .. 36.35 H. M. Childs, expenses 16.24 Jas. E. Delzell, expenses 37 .83 B. L. Shellhorn, expenses 17 .68 Oct 24 B. L. Shellhorn, expenses 6.96 Jas. E. Dalzell. expenses 20.53 L. P. Ludden, services 50 . 00 Luther P. Ludden. expenses 15.37 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, furniture 3.10 J. E. Ferris, reporting trial 72.00 1908 Jan. 4 Luther P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses 59.15 H. M. Childs, expenses 6.78 JaB. E. Delzell, expenses 42.80 J. L. McBrien, expenses 8. 80 J L Shellhorn pxmbim 7 Att </seg>
            <seg id="p052">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 54 L. R. Dillon, expenses 37.50 ( '. H. Gregg, expenses 30 . 24 L. G. Brian, expenses 10.70 Mar. 13 Benton Bros., printing 5.00 Jas. E. Delzell, expenses 10.80 H. M. Childs, expenses 11.76 (". H. Gregg, expenses Harry Porter, supplies 18.90 L. P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses 82.65 Bart L. Shellhorn, expenses 5.96 Luther P. Ludden, expenses 9.30 26 Jas. E. Delzell. ex; 8.16 Luther P. Ludden, expenses 20.46 Luther P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses 53.35 June 1 Luther P. Ludden, expenses 22.87 Bart L. Shellhorn, expenses 23 . 13 L. G. Brian, expenses 22 . 1 5 Jas. E. Delzell, expenses J. L. McBrien. expenses ('. H. Gregg, i 20.49 July 23 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 4.75 Luther P. Ludden, sec'y expenses and office supplies 132.36 Hammond &amp; Stephens, printing 10.00 L. R. Dillon, livery 12.25 C. H. Gregg, expenses 9.41 Bart L. Shellhorn, expenses H. M. Childs, expenses 5.24 Jas. E. Delzell, expenses 18.10 L. G. Brian, expenses 3.23 Nov. 6 Jas. Dalzell, expenses 14.06 Benton Bros., printing 14.75 Luther P. Ludden, sec'y office expenses 166.89 C. H. Gregg, expenses 22 . 42 Bart L. Shellhorn, expenses 8.30 H. M. Childs, expenses 6.08 Jas. E. Dalzell, expenses 17.94 Dec. 8 Bart L. Shellhorn, expenses 8.96 C. H. Gregg, expenses 19 . 04 H. M. Childs, expenses 8.28 Luther P. Ludden. sec'y office expenses 26.25 Jas. E. Delzell, expenses 25 . 06 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 112.16 * 1,900.00 * 1.900.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">55 CASH FUNDS AT PERU, NEBR. DORMITORY FUND8. Balance on hand at last report $ 897.35 Received for room rent, Winter term, 1907 418.35 Received for room rent, Spring term, 1907 528.80 Received for room rent. Summer term. 1907 226.40 Received for room rent, Fall term, 1907 447.96 m&gt;6 Dec. 3 R. B. Bedell, Not. salary, fireman $ 25.00 Dec. 10 Hattle V. Boyd, refund on room rent 1.80 Frank Medley, labor 6.00 Ezra Carey, freight and drayage 3.24 1907 Jan. 1 R. B. Bedell, salary fireman 25.00 Miller &amp; Paine, toilet paper 10.50 Jan. 5 E. G. Conkle. labor 8.70 Jan. 13 J. H. Adams, hauling coal 4.60 Jan. 19 J. S. Robinson, labor and material 9.60 Jan. 21 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., matts 1.02 Jan. 25 H. D. Jackman, labor 5.65 Jan. 30 Benton Bros., printing reports 60.00 B. C. Gifford. repairs 1.25 Feb. 4 R. B. Bedell, salary fireman 25.00 Lewis Adams, hauling coal 2.00 Feb. 7 C. Johnson, hauling coal 5.40 Feb. 19 R. J. Armstrong, hauling coal 7.50 Feb. 21 John Adams, hauling coal 13.15 O. J. Majors, hauling coal 1.25 C. W. Majors, hauling coal 2.50 E. L. Uptegrove, supplies ' 8.35 B. Van Wickle, hauling coal 5 . 00 W. Adams, hauling coal 2.50 O. Milstead, hauling coal 2.65 Mr. Haynes, hauling coal 2.65 23 H. D. Jackman, labor 12.45 Joe Cullem, wood 37.50 Lloyd &amp; Son, supplies ■ 1.20 Mar. 2 H. D. Jackman. pumping water 6.82 Mar. 5 J. W. Palmer, hauling coal 1.50 Mar. 17 H. D. Jackman, pumping water 13.57 Mar. 25 H. D. Jackman, pumping water 7.05 Mar. 31 R. B. Bedell, Feb. and Mar. salary, Fire. 50.00 H. W. Bedell, advanced for Ice 79.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 56 Mrs. M. C. Jack, supplies 6.70 H. D. Jackman, pumping water 16.42 E. L. Uptegrove. supplies .Myrtle Leach, refund room rent 3.20 Henrietta Martens, refund room rent.. .90 Apr. 29 Carpenter Paper Co., paper 16.50 May 2 R. B. Bedell. April salary fireman 25.00 May 10 Francis Blake, room rent refund 2.25 Benjamin Bedell, salary fireman 25.00 July 11 M. S. Jussel, labor 2.00 July 17 Margaret Fedde, refund room rent .90 illy 23 Fred Zink, labor 2.00 July 31 H. P. Whit more, pictures 12.50 B. E. Muniford, labor 6.00 16 H. D. Jackman. pumping water 17.25 Aug. 24 Milton Blankenship, cleaning walls 1.65 Ben Jones, cleaning walls 1 . 35 W. L. Miller, plastering 6.00 Fred Ebert, cleaning walls 2 . 60 Sept. 3 R. H. Medley, calcimining 3.75 10 C. E. Zink. Agt, freight, lawnmower 1.48 E. G. Conkle, carpenter work 11.20 E. L. Uptegrove, supplies 3.35 Harry Denning, labor 11.55 Charles G. Smith, labor 6.50 A. H. Madley, calcimining 38.40 &gt;t. 16 Chas. Smith, labor Oct. 5 Peter Henderson, lawn mower 10.00 Rudge &amp; Guonzel Co., supplies 105.60 Oct. 26 Burris Drug Co., supplies 59.45 H. W. Bedell, labor and supplies 54.05 10 R. B. Bedell, Oct. salary, fireman 25.00 Nov. 11 Western Supply Co., plumbing supplies 933.52 Nov. 12 Edna Frederick, refund room rent 2.80 Francis Fronner, refund room rent 3 . 40 Nov. 14 Nebr. Hardware Co., steel, iron, etc.... Nov. 16 Ne'ir. Hardware Co., steel, iron, etc.... Nov. 19 James Majors, wood 80.00 Nov. 22 Meddy Brush, refund room rent 1.60 Nov. 30 Rus-el Whitefield, labor 2.80 Nov. 30 P. E. Whitefield, labor 2.80 Pec. 1 Room rent Dec. 9 R. B. Bedell, salary 25.00 Dec. 12 If. 0. Jack, room supplies 28.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">57 BI-ENNIAL REPORT Barned Drug Co., supplies 24 . 42 Dec. 31 Glailys Baughman, refund .80 1908 Jan. Room rent and deposit Jan. 8 Ray Weaverling, supplies 16.25 Jan. 20 Harry M. Denning, painting 4.80 R. B. Bedell, salary Jan. 25 J. H. F. Scott, tools 3.15 Feb . Room rent Feb. 3 Ezra Carey, freight 1.19 Feb. 6 R. B. Bedell, fireman Nebr. Hardware Co., supplies 8.69 Feb. 8 P. M. Wilson, fireman 40.00 H. W. Culbertson. labor 33.60 Feb. 13 Will Vance, laundry .98 Feb. 14 W. N. Delzelll, expenses 20.25 Feb. 15 B. F. Hanlon, plastering 2.00 Feb. 20 Crane &amp; Co., supplies 104.98 Feb. 22 H. W. Bedell, labor 7.40 Mar . Room rent Mar. 4 Ezrr Carey, freight .40 Mar. 7 P. M. Wilson, fireman 40.00 Mar. 16 Frank Hayward, supplies lo.Vi Mar. 18 R. B. Bedell, fireman 25.00 Nebr. Hardware Co., supplies 2 .29 Miller &amp; Paine, supplies 7 . 50 Mar. 23 Burris Drug Co., supplies 50.41 Wm. Culbertson, labor 22.40 Refund room rent 2.25 Apr . Room rent Apr. 1 Ezra Carey, freight 7.00 Apr. 4 H. W. Bedell, ice 122.18 R. B. Bedell, fireman P. M. Wilson, fireman 40.00 Wm. Culbertson, labor 17.95 Apr. 16 Miller &amp; Paine, supplies 15.70 Western Glass Co., mirror 1 . 75 Apr. 18 Rudge &amp;. Guenzel Co., supplies 4.50 Apr. 18 F. W. Setser, labor 9.52 Thos. Comstock, labor 7 .00 Apr. 21 Otoe Lumber Co., lumber 1.80 Nebr. School Supply Co., supplies 19.50 Apr. 13 Hardy Furniture Co., range 217.80 Apr. IB J. W. Lunsford, labor 4 . 46 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Frank Allgood, labor 4 M May Room rent 58 May Refund room rept, Ruth Hogue 2.00 ilay Refund room rent, Besse Potter May 2 F. W. Setzer, labor 5.69 Refund room rent, A. Bright H. C. Ray, labor Thos. Comstock, labor May 6 B. C. Gifford, labor 8.70 May 19 H. C. Ray, labor 7.95 E. E. Mumford, labor 3 . 30 F. W. Setzer, labor 12.07 May 20 Hardy Furniture Co., hose May 25 P. M. Wilson, fireman June Deposits for rooms J une 3 Bennie Bedell, fireman H. W. BeJell. supplies June 4 P. M. Wilson, fireman 45.2". June 6 Ezra Carey, drayage 1.2") W. E. Marsh, labor 4 . M F. W. Setzer, labor 11 .M June 17 H. W. Culbertson. screens IK. i:&gt; June 20 B. C. Gifford, hauling coal 4.15 June 24 C. C. Reed, supplies July Deposit room rent July 7 P. M. Wilson, fireman July 8 Barnes Drug Co., paint, etc July 9 Lauretta / Corra f refund rent I.M July 9 ■uly 15 Miller &amp; toilet paper nlv. 1)11 A U Ui-icrVit -.win. ,»n) • im July 29 A. M. Bright, refund room rent Mary Anderson, refund room rent July 31 Minnie Sail, refund room rent 4 M Barbari Parli. refund room rent 1 .60 Fara Eidenmiller, refund room rent... 1.40 E. Christensen, refund room rent 1.40 A. Ketridge, refund room rent 1 .00 Lenore Lawrence, refund room rent. . . . Margaret Leese, refund room rent 2.00 Minnie Davis, refund room rent Aug. Deposit for room rent and breakage.. Aug. 1 P. M. Wilson, fireman Aug. 4 Ella Hill, refund room rent Blanche Pahl, refund room r«nt ... Aug. 8 Anieia Lucas, refund room rent </seg>
            <seg id="p057">59 BI-ENNIAL REPORT A up . 1 2 K nun 3 dc !h \ **"*! , r^f u'ld room rt*nt .... T U Sarah HerriiiBton. refund room rent... 2.00 Aug. 15.1 'wood, labor 15.75 R. B. Bedell, labor 12.25 A. Polston, labor 16.63 Jesse George, labor 8.75 G. M. Cole, labor 22 . 00 Aug. 29 James McMillen, labor 3.50 &lt;; M Cole, labor 16.00 R. B. Be.lell, labor 21 .00 labor 38.50 J. A. Eastwood, labor 21.00 P. M. Wilson, fireman 40.00 A. Polston, labor 21.00 for room rent 480.70 Sept. 4 E. P. Carey, freight, etc 5.72 10 J. A. Redliue, express 4.51 12 J. C. Woodies, labor 18.60 R. B. Bedell, labor 17.50 Jesse George. labor 35 . 00 G. H. Cole, labor 12.00 Jas. A. Eastwood, labor 12.25 R. J. Armstrong, labor 27.00 A Polston, lnbor 15.75 .eight, etc 2.78 De|K&gt;8it for room rent Oct. 10 William Boellstorff, labor 15.75 P. M. Wihson, fireman 40.00 Jesse George, labor 4 . 20 A. Polston, labor 19.25 G. M. Cole, labor 24 .00 J W. Able, labor 14.00 10 Elizabeth Moody, refund room rent 2.00 Elizabeth Oliver, refund room rent 2.00 Oct 13 E. L. Rouse, refund room rent Mrs. Alexander, refund room rent Oct. 22 Ellen Wahlstrom, refund room rent.... 2.00 Oct. 28 H. O. Cole, labor and supplies 63.74 II H W. Bedell, wiring Dorm 13.10 G. M. Cole, labor 12.00 Jesse George, labor 29 . 75 Woodie. labor 29.40 H \V Bedell, labor 41.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">60 R. J. Armstrong, labor 9.00 J. A. Redline, freight, etc 65.39 Not. Deposited for room rent. Not. 10 C. W. Joy, brooms 3.75 Not. 11 J. D. McMillen, laundry .65 Not. 13 Burris Drug Co., supplies 55.70 Not. 14 P. M. Wilson, salary fireman 40.00 Hardy Furniture Co., chairs 49.00 Western Supply Co., supplies 53 . 74 Hardy Furniture Co., hose 22 . 50 S. H. Atwood &amp; Co., concrete 40.25 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture 88.06 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., mirror*.. . 53.50 Sunderland Roofing Co., roof 36.00 Western Supply Co., pipe, etc 106.76 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 68.68 Not. 17 Omaha School Supply Co., supplies 9.65 Not. 19 Elsie Simmons, refund room rent 4.50 $ 4,843.40 $ 4,697.49 Overdraft. 145.91 $ 4,843.40 $ 4,843.40 LABORATORY FUNDS. I Balance on hand last report Laboratory fees, Botany Laboratory fees, Zoology Laboratory fees, EmBroyology Laboratory fees, Physiology Laboratory fees. Agriculture I-aboratory fees. Physics , Laboratory fees, Domestic Science. Laboratory fees, Geology $ 387.99 184.80 Laboratory fees, Chemistry. $ 1,266. 77 1906 Dec. 10 Mrs. E. M. Jack, supplies $ 13.85 Barnes Drug Co., supplies 4.37 J. W. Dennis, work in greenhouse 4.25 Ezra Carey, freight and drayage 8.50 Dec. 14 C. E. Zink, freight 2.73 R. D. S wisher Mfg. Co., supplies .60 H. B. Duncanson , supplies 15 . 50 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">61 BI-ENNIAL REPORT Jan. 10 Campbell Glass Co., supplies 21.65 Jan. 30 Bauscb £ Lomb Co., supplies 49.10 Bausch ft Lomb Co., supplies 171.75 Feb. 16 H. O. Cole, labor 42.70 Mar. 5 Central Scientific Co., supplies 14.70 Montgomery Ward Co., supplies 14.48 Mar. 12 Brooklyn Bio. Co., supplies 9.80 Mar. 16 M. E. Good Co., supplies 1.25 Mar. 17 Cornell Engraving Co., supplies 12.70 Mar. 31 B. H. Duncanson, supplies 27.95 Botany fees refunded 8 . 75 Agriculture fees refunded .50 Zoology fees i ef unded .75 May 31 Botany fees refunded 3.75 Physics fees refunded .75 June 13 H. Heil Chem. Co., supplies 15.50 Jane 24 Bauscb &amp; Lomb Co., supplies 161.08 Macintosh Stereopticon Co., supplies... 4.90 June 30 W. W. Mardis, supplies 2.40 Central Scientific Co., supplies .28 Griswold Seed Co., seeds and plants... 3.85 Page &amp; Gilbert, supplies .45 Catalogs and experiments, Prof. Brownell 1 .00 July 13 Capt. Edward Schultz, maps 6.55 July 15 Dept. Agriculture Bulletin No. 110 .10 July 2S' Refund Zoology fees .40 July 30 Henry Heil Co., supplies 12.45 July SI Wm. Gardam &amp; Son, supplies 6.50 C. C. Reed supplies 14.94 Sept 10 J. W. Crabtree. advanced on freight 23.80 E. G. Conkle, work of tables 46.90 ■apt. 16 H. B. Duncanson, cash adv. supplies 10.56 Oct. 4 Alice Loomls, supplies 2.50 Oct. 5 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies 8.40 Harry Porter, supplies 28.22 Oct. 8 Botany fees refunded 7 . 50 Zoology fees refunded 1 . 50 Physics fees refunded .75 Chemistry fees refunded .75 Oct 26 T. J. Thorpe &amp; Co., rubber stamp .21 Not. 1 N. A. Bengston, supplies 2.25 Zoology fees refunded .37 Not. 4 W. L. French, supplies and labor 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">62 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Glen Jenkins, Zoology fees refunded... .75 Nov. 7 Cornell Engraving Co., supplies 70.55 E. Jansen, laundry .40 E. E. Mumford. laundry .80 Dec . 1 Physics fees if Chemistry fees. . . Embroyology fees Agriculture fees. . Botany fees Zoology fees. Dec . 1 Fred Ebert, labor .45 Dec. 6 H. Cole, supplies 1.30 Dec. 23 H. B. Duncanson, supplies 18.65 Dec. 31 S. M. Dillow, refund .75 1908 Jan . Chemistry fees ii Zoology fees. Physics fees. Botany fees . Agriculture fees Jan. 9 F. D. Barker, supplies Lab 9.65 M. E. Good, supplies Lab 18.38 Jan. 10 W. W. Mardis, supplies Lab .70 Jan. 25 H. M. Eaton, field notes 7.00 Cornell Engraving Co., supplies 11.40 Frank A. Ward, supplies 175.00 Feb . Physiology fees Si Chemistry fees . . . Agriculture fees. . Domestic Science. Photography fees. Physics fees S £2 Zoology fees Botany fees. Refund , Botany, Lauretta Conn .75 Physics, Myrtle Gel wick .25 Feb. 3 Ezra Carey, freight 1 .96 Feb. 5 C. W. Smith, Asst. In Lab 15.00 Feb. 6 Geo. McGrew, Asst. in Lab 15.00 Russell Spafford, Asst. in Lab 15.00 Hilda Miller, Asst. In Lab 15.00 E. R. Burkey. Asst. in Lab 15.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">63 Bessie Zink, Asst. in Lab 45.00 Central Scientific Co., supplies 32.35 Tablet Ticket Co., supplies 3.62 Feb. SO Blodget Clock Co., supplies 1.52 F. D. Barker, supplies 2.95 Feb. 2» A. F. Heskett. freight 1-49 Mar. Apriculture fees Physiology fees. Botany fees S Zoology fees Physic* fees £ Photography fees Chemistry fees... Mar. 18 Henry Hell Co., supplies 65.93 IZ Apr. Photography fees Botany fees . . . Physics fees . . . Chemistry fees Zoology fees . . . 1 Agriculture fees. Physiology fees . . Apr. IS Bauscn &amp; Lomb Co., supplies 85.35 F. T. Jones, supplies .63 Apr. 16 W. W. Mardis, supplies 1.05 Apr. 21 American Book Co., books 2.00 Apr. 23 Harvard Appr. Co., supplies 38.38 May Laboratory fees May 19 L. E. Knott Co., supplies .84 Elmer &amp; Amend, supplies 1 . 53 May 26 S. W. Hacker, supplies 22.35 Jane Physics fees Chemistry fees Botany fees . . . Zoology fees Agriculture fees. Physiology fees.. Geology fees IZ Psychology fees Domestic Science fees June 8 C. W. Smith, Asst. in Lab 15.00 Oeo. McGrew, Asst. In Lab 18.00 June 4 E. R. Burkey, Asst. In Lab 18.00 Hilda Miller, Asst In Lab 18.00 June I H. B. Duncanaon, cash advanced SI. SO </seg>
            <seg id="p062">64 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION June 16 Bessie Zink, Asst. in Lab 45. 00 June 17 R. R. Spafford, Asst. in Lab 18.00 Bausch &amp; Lonib Co., supplies 4.30 June 19 Will Vance, laundry 2.99 June 20 Alma D. Eastman, Asst. in Lab 18.00 .Tune 30 J. G. Hesseltine, Asst. in Lab 36.00 Refund Phpsics fees 2.00 Refund Agriculture fees .75 Refund Physiology fees .50 Refund Botany fees 1 . 50 July Physics fees I Chemistry fees.. Botany fees Zoology fees Agriculture fees . Physiology fees.. Physicological, etc., fees. Domestic Science fees. . . July 1 C. W. Smith, Asst. in Lab 3.00 July 9 J. B. Dennis, Asst. in Lab 3.50 July 15 Bausch &amp; Lomfo Co., supplies 8.09 July 17 T. J. Thorpe &amp; Co., stamp 1.00 J uly 31 Refund Botany fees 8 . 15 Refund Zoology fees l . 4 . 50 Refund Physics fees 2.75 Refund Chemistry fees 1.00 Refund Agriculture fees 4 . 50 Refund Physiology fees 2 . 25 Refund Physiological, etc., fees 1.25 Refund Domestic Science fees .35 Refund Geology fees 13.00 Physics fees 6 Bessie Zink, Asst. in Lab 22.50 J. F. Hendricks, Asst. In Lab 16.00 Refund Botany fees .75 Refund Physics fees .25 Refund Agriculture fees .25 Physics fees I Chemistry fees. . Botany fees Zoology fees Physiology fees. . Agriculture fees. Domestic Science fees. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">65 Physiological, etc., fees. Plant Phpsiology fees . . . Embryology fees Sept. 30 Refunded Lab. Physiology .50 Oct. Physics fees Chemistry fees. Botany fees.... Zoology fees Physiology fees. Domestic Science fees ! . Physiological, etc., fees. Plant Physiology fees... Oct. 14 C. W. Bardeen, pamphlets 2.87 Franklin T. Jones, pamphlets .64 J. O. Hes«eltine, Asst. in Lab 5.25 W. L. French, supplies 4.88 Oct 31 Refund Physics 1 . 50 Refund Chemistry Refund Botany 3.75 Refund Zoology Refund Physiology .50 Refund Domestic Science 5.25 Not. Physics fees Chemistry fees . Botany fees Zoology fees Physiology fees. Embryology fees Plant Physiology fees.. Physiological, etc., fees Not. 14 F. M. Gregg, supplies 23.65 C. H. Stoelting Co., supplies 12.70 Alice Loomis, supplies 24.17 Central Scientific Co., supplies 25.67 Win. Gaertner &amp; Co., supplies 28.21 Chas. K. Reed, supplies 24 .00 St urges Bros., supplies 22.81 Cambridge Bot. Co., supplies 6 . 86 Cornell Engraving Co., engraving 27.18 Cornell Engraving Co., engraving 17.14 T. J. Thorpe &amp; Co., seal 1.21 Refund Chemistry .75 Refund Physics 1 . 50 Refund Botany 1 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">66 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Refund Zoology 1.13 Refund Physiology .25 Refund Domestic Science 1 .50 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 214.88 I 2,309.57 * TEXT BOOK RENTAL FUND Balance on hand last report .' . . $ 23.93 1906 Dec. Text Book rental first semester % 350.00 Text •Book sold first semester 100 . 00 1907 May 23 Text Book rental second semester 246.20 Text Book solj second semester 108.96 July 31 Text Book rental summer term 190.35 Text Book sold summer term 159.10 Oct. 26 Text Book rental firsi semester Text Book sold first semester 121.15 1.7" 1906 $ 1,799. 6» Dec. 1 Macmillian Co., text books 11.10 A. H. Andrews Co., text books H. W. Wilson Co., U. S. Cat. Supplement 12. M Dec. 8 Iowa Normal Monthl. subscription l.M Dec. 10 S. U Caldwell, supplies 1907 Jan. 14 Macmillian Co., text books 19 .20 Jan. 19 D. L. Musselman Pub. Co.. text books. . . Jan. 24 Houghton Mifflin Co., text book..s American Book Co., text books 16.20 Jan. 25 Aimsworth &amp; Co., text books Jan. 26 American Book Co.. text book..s C. N. Parker, text books T. Y. Crowell Co.. text books 4.00 J;;n. 30 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text books 6. On Ginn &amp; Co., text books 12.80 Jan. 31 Univ. Pub. Co., text books Columbia Col. Expression, text books... 22.70 Feb. 4 American Book Co., texo books 38.40 Ginn &amp; Co., text books 43 . 20 Nebr. School Sup. Co., text book's 12:: IS American Book Co., text books 11 .25 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">67 BI-ENNIAL REPORT Longman ft Green ft Co., text books 21.60 5 Ginn ft Co.. text books 12.80 Scribnerg ft Son, text books SI. 40 Appleton ft Co., text books 13.5* 8 Library of Cong. Cat. Cares 10. 10 16 C. Sower ft Co., text books 6.34 American Book Co., text books 3.82 1 9 Macmillian Co., text books 15 . 00 \V. E. Burrell, services In Library 1.20 C If, Penny, services in Library 3.30 J. T. Akers, services in Library 1 . 95 Mar. 5 D. C. Heath ft Co., text books 53.20 G E. Stechert, text books 2.82 Allyn ft Bacon, text books 24.00 American Book Co., text books 17 . 54 H. Holt ft Co.. text books 10.00 Longman Green Co., text books 5.46 Mar. 12 American Book Co., text books 16.00 Columbia Col. Expression 15.40 Mar. If C. E. Zink, freight and drayage 5.72 Mar. A. L. A. Pub. Board Sub. to A. L. B 1.00 C. R. Gates, service in Library 2.25 A. J. Wickland, service in Library 3.75 May 1 3 Ginn ft Co., text books 48 . 80 May 14 Manual Arts Press Sup. to paper 1.00 May .22 James Phillips, service in Library .60 Clyde Moore, service In Library 2 . 25 May 31 American Book Co., text books 1.16 June 8 Atkinson Mentze R. ft G. text books.. 12.00 June 24 Hinds Noble ft E., text books 36.17 American Book Co., text books 24.72 American Book Co.. text books 13.44 D. C. Heath ft Co.. text books 19.20 June :!&lt;i Ethel Sailors, GJerman Gram, rent 1.00 A. W. Haweg Sci. Co., chart 1.12 ■1Z Esther A. Clark, Horace 1 .65 Inly 17 Dennison Maf. Co.. labels 2.00 July 31 D. Parrott, text books 1.00 G. Harlow, text books 1 . 35 Ginn ft Co., text books 38 . 40 Aug. 16 Natl. Ry. Co., text boo'fs 8.00 W. K. Burrwell. Asst. In Lab 35.80 18 World Herald Sub 4.00 u. c Heatn it Co., text books 66.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p066">68 4 Ed. Review Pub. Co., subscription 00 221.14 Ginn &amp; Co.. text books o D. C. Heath A I books.. Jordan 1' tx&gt;oks Atkiirson Menier Co., text books Macmillian Co., text books.... D. C. Heath &amp; books 40.48 Jordan Bi i&gt;ooks 9-60 Atkinson Men; xt books 36.00 Macmillian (\&gt;., text books 10.00 10.00 American Book Co.. text books 40.00 American Book Co.. text books Holt &amp; Co., text books 40.00 Holt &amp; Co., text books 28.32 28.32 Appleton &amp; Co., text books 40.00 Appleton &amp; Co., text books 40.00 Ginn &amp; Co., text books... 5.40 2 Ginn &amp; Co., text books...' Allyn &amp; Bacon, text books 40.00 40.00 50.00 Nov. 12 Allyn &amp; Bacon, text books Xov. 15 J. L. McBrien, advertising .1. L. McBrien, advertising 50.00 Erwin Shc-ppard Mem. anl N. E. A. Vol. v Amelia F. Lucas, Adv. for express .95 ov. 30 Amelia F. Lucas, Adv. for express 1 Sale of Hamlet Sale of Hamlet S:2 Text book rental Text book sales. Text book rental Text book sales Sale Riverside Lit. series Sale Riverside Lit. series . 12 The Macmillian Co., books The Macmillian Co., books 13.32 Joy E. Morgan, labor 11.80 11.80 Dec. 20 Joy E. Morgan, labor Dec. 24 Luella Worick, labor Luella Worick, labor 20.00 20.00 1908 *S:S Jan. Transferred from Dep. Acct Transferred from Dep. Acct Text Book deposits Text Book deposits Houghton Milflin Co., books 6.84 7 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 6.S4 H. H. Ballard. supplies 2.10 2.10 H. H. Ballard. supplies Row Peterson &amp; Co.. A. Flanagan, bonk Row Peterson &amp; Co A. Flanagan, books 6.48 6.48 Jan. 10 Ezra Carey, freight, etc Ezra Carey, freight, etc 10.78 10.78 Jan. 17 Warren Burell, labor Warren Burell. labor Jan. 25 Gaylord Bros., books Gay lord Bros., books Refund, students 19.35 19.35 Ian. 31 Refund, students Ada Thompson 1.60 1.60 Ada Thompson Mamie Reed. . . Hessie Frost. . . Mamie Reed 2.20 2.20 Bessie Frost Text Book deposit 50. •• Text Book deposit Refund as follows: Maude Metcalf 2.10 2.10 Wilma Tawney 2.00 2.00 Boyd Findley 2.60 2.60 Ella Grimm -85 herine Petker 2.20 .85 Ella Grimm 2.20 1 fifl 1.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">69 BI-ENNIAL REPORT, ■ Gertrude Watson 1.50 Geo. Ebert 2.20 2.20 Z. C. Mickel 3.00 Lucy Keslar .33 Harold Humphrey 2.20 LJxiie Snyder .85 L. A. Hussong 1 . 00 A. G. Reed 1.55 Q. D. Reed 2.00 Odus Van Camp, refund 1 . 80 Feb. 3 Ezra Carey, freight 4.82 Feb. 5 Joy E. Morgan, labor 17.30 Feb. 6 Columbia College, books 15.40 Glnn ft Co.. books 16.00 Feb. 14 C. Ray Gates, labor 40.00 Feb. 18 Warren E. Burrell, labor 16.60 Feb. 20 Uni. Pub. Co., books 10.08 Feb. 20 Pearl Meyer, labor 1 .00 Feb. 20 Ginn ft Co., books 320.35 Mar. Deposit for books Refund for Ft. Journal Co. Mar. Refund as follows: John Juilfs 1 .80 Roy Davis 1 . 80 Herbert Falrchlld 1 .20 Zoe Hodkinson 1 . 80 Merl Sanders 1 . 50 Anna Purcell 1.10 June McMillen 1.55 Stephen Jensen 1.40 Mar. 3 Ginn ft Co., books 2.00 Mar. 7 J. E. Morgan, labor 15.60 Mar. 14 J. G. Henderson, labor 16.30 Mar. 16 D. Appleton ft Co., books 17.89 Mar. 18 Ainsworth &amp; Co., books 27 on Scribner ft Sons, books 6.70 Lenora Page, labor 3 . 40 Allyn ft Bacon, books S.22 Iowa School Pub. Co., books 6.75 Jordan Bros., books 4.80 D. C. Heath ft Co., books 10.02 Atkinson ft Co., books 46.&lt;M&gt; Warren E. Burelle, books 15.40 American Book Co., books 67.84 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">70 April Deposit for books Refund as follows: Lydia immerman .35 Gladys Lillibridge 1.46 Sophia Witwer 1.00 Harley Snowden 1 . 40 Ethel Smith 2.00 Aaron Lechliter 2 . 20 Sadie Jones 2.40 Plak Renfron 1.60 Alma Barber .65 Apr. 11 D. C. Cole, notary fees 1 . 50 Apr. 21 Silver-Bur Jett &amp; Co., books 3.38 Nebraska Teacher, paper 25.00 American Book Co., books 26.84 May Deposits Refund as per list 284 . 56 May 5 Edna BullocX, express .23 May 6 J. E. Richardson, pictures 3 . 50 May 39 W. E. Burrell, labor 8.50 May 22 Elmer R. Burkey, paper May 25 J. G. Henderson, labor 18.40 May 30 J. E. Morgan, labor 1 . 60 June Text book deposits 1,369.47 Exchange on check. Deposit for key, Everett . Fee for B. E. degree. . . . June 2 Nellie Folsom, Asst. in Eng 16.00 Anabel Joseph, Asst. In Eng 30.00 Sara Dunn, Asst. in Eng Myrtle Krebs. Asst. in Eng 17. M Lenora Page, Asst. in Eng 12 . 50 Tena M. Gunn, Asst. in Eng Virginia Byerly, Asst. in Eng 30.00 John A. Hanna, Asst. In Eng 22 . 50 June 16 Warren E. Burrelle, labor 29.70 June 17 C. M. Parker, course of study 10.60 June 18 L. R. Hill, advertising June 22 J. L. McBrien, address 25.00 June 30 Refund Text Book Dep 124. So Exchange on checks .55 July Text Book deposit </seg>
            <seg id="p069">71 BI-ENNIAL REPORT Merriam for list Seniors. Refund on &gt;al Co. Exchange on check ■i \nierican 115.9.") Henrj-.Holt &amp; Co.. books.. 46.08 A. C. MeClurg IL'7.44 •lnian Pub. Co., books 23.00 &gt;uks 9.01 Macmillian Co., books 18.00 hooks Ginn &amp; Co.. books !o Warren E. Burralle, labor 18 Lawrence Bryner. books 8.50 s.. . 1.00 ... school pins 34.90 Tena Gunn. Asst. in Ens l&gt;or 11.40 :id text books dep. SIB Exchange on checks .10 6 on u xt books 4 Jennie Tennant, pin Graf" R E. (I. 1 San: '-rk notai o 3 Draft, McHrier. .10 •&gt;. ;a F. Luc ... Aug. 11 \\ labor Hi fund on text books 440.48 Text book deposit 1,71 Due on oil acct Sept. 4 Ezra P. Carey, freight, etc 8.38 | lordon Beck, labor 1 . ",8 Allen Carmen, labor 1.75 14 Elmer Wilson, labor 13.40 19 Ezra Carey, freight, etc Refund on books 3.60 Text book deposit 0 Sale of pin : or exchanging Prog .inge o ncheck .10 ».15 mal for l.cnks </seg>
            <seg id="p070">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 72 Sale school pin *. 2.75 Text book deposit 30.16 Rent of lockers U.tt Nov. 14 Benj. H. Sanborn Co., books 8.05 Scribner &amp; Son, books 11.24 H. Holt &amp; Co., books 52.64 Ginn &amp; Co., books 123 . 84 Atkinson &amp; Co., books 98 . 40 American Book Co., books 45.14 D. Appleton &amp; Co., books 77.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 190 . 08 Macmillian &amp; Co., books 6.45 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 3.35 W. W. Deatrick, books 23.00 Hammond &amp; Stephens, diplomas 116.85 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 46.08 Not. 17 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding books 409.20 N'ot. 18 Bee Pub. Co., advertising 5.20 Not. 30 Refund on book deposit 11.30 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 583.74 | 6,370.66 $ 6,370. IC TYPEWRITING FUND I ialance on hand last report $ 124. 6* 1907 Jan . Sale of shorthand books 12.5* Sale of shorthand books 17. 5# May Rental on machines.... 112.5* July Rental on machines 23. M 1906 $ 290. •'■ 1 W. L. Musick, text books $ 15.00 Charles A. Foyer Co., typewriter ribbons 4.00 1 1 Harry Porter, supplies 9 . 80 190 Jan. 5 Smith Premier Typ. Co., supplies 20.75 Smith Premier typewriter 70 .00 19 W. L. Musick Co., shorthand books.. .. 12.60 Jacob North Co., supplies 40 . 17 Fnb. 19 Chas. A. Foyer Co., carbon paper 1.50 Smith Premier Co.. supplies 7.00 Mar. 5 Smith Premier Co., supplies 8.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">73 Feb. An error In account a year ago 1 .00 Mar. J. W. Crabtree, cash advanced 50.00 Mar. 18 Jenkins &amp; McGred, Eng 5.00 Apr. 13 Harry Porter, supplies 20.00 Apr. 16 C. A. Foyer, ribbons 4.30 Apr. 17 Nemataa Co. Teacher 5.00 Apr. 21 Nebr. School Sup. Co 25.26 If ar TvDewriter rent May Typewriter rent. May 20 Harry Porter 22 .60 June Typewriter rent 33.0 July Typewriter rent 3.00 July 15 Nebr. School Sup. Co 35.00 Refund typewriter 3.50 Aug. 7 J. W. Crabtree. expenses 10.00 Aug. 24 Myrtle Jones,! instruction 40.00 Sept. Typewriter rent 57 . 00 Sept. , 7 E. P. Carey, freight 5.30 Oct. Typewriter rent 21.00 Refund on rent 6.00 Not. 18 Harry Porter, stationery 26.20 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 32.72 481.50 $ 481.50 * MODEL SCHOOL FUND. Balance on hand at last report $ 4.11 1907 Tuition Winter term 73 . 05 Tuition Spring term 65 . 80 Tuition First semester 164 . 3 ) 1906 $ M7.M Dec. 10 S. W. Ha.cker ft Co., supplies 2.00 M. E. Good, supplies 1 .87 Barnes Drug Store, ink 1 . 25 Ezra Carey, freight, etc 2.3$ Dec. 17 S. B. Stewart, supplies . 2.00 C. E. Zing, freight 1.07 1907 Jan. 1 J. C. Curtis, moulding clay 2.00 Jan. 19 A. H. Abbott ft Co., supplies 2.90 Jan. 25 Thomas Charles, supplies 15.14 Feb. 16 D. Appleton Co.. books 6.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">74 Thomas Charles, supplies 4 . 30 Mar. 5 Rand McXally Co., supplies 20.25 Mar. 13 Thomas Charles, supplies 8.96 Mar. 31 Pearl S. Kelly, supplies 15.55 May 10 Gardiner City Education Co., suppli- 3.33 T. Y. Cry well, supplies 1.49 June 30 Miss Mutz, supplies 3.27 Miss Schlee, supplies 1 .00 Miss Hosmer, supplies 3.15 Miss Krebs, supplies .55 Titus Nursery Co., Xmas tree .50 July 31 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 8.59 Oct. 22 Sllver-Burdett Co., text books 2.96 Ginn &amp; Co., text books 36 . 00 Maynard Merrill Co.. text books 5.07 Harry Porter, supplies 13.86 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., text books 1 . 82 American Book Co.. text books 29.12 Nov. 16 Western Newspaper Union, supplies.... 11.76 Dec. Tuition paid I.M Sale of material Dec . 12 Harry Porter, supplies 8.65 Jan. Tuition for month 3.30 Jan. Tuition for month Jan. 7 A. C. McClurg Co.. books 10.89 American Book Co.. books 12.20 Garden City Ed. Co., supplies 18.17 Book Supply Co., supplies 4.55 Thomas Charles Co., error 1.41 Feb. Model School tuition 137.60 Feb. 6 Western Newspaper Union 2.45 Ginn &amp; Co., books 16.00 Feb. 12 J. C. Chatlain, supplies 2.60 Feb. 21 Nebr. School Sup. Co.. supplies 161.97 Mar. Model School tuition 9 . »•) Refund to Mrs. Dow .50 Mar. 18 McClurg &amp; Co., books II. U Riggs Pub. Co., supplies 3.75 Atkinson &amp; Co .52 Apr. Model School tuition 6.19 Apr. 16 Refund to Mrs. Dow, tuition Apr. 16 J. C. Curtis, clay 1.00 May From sale of material 21.81 June Tuition Summer term .9* June 20 Thomas Charles Co 38 . 51 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">75 BI-ENNIAL REPORT July 6 I.ou E. Hosmer, material sold 9 T"&gt; July IS E. L. Rouse. Xmas entertainment 5. it July 15 Thomas Charles Co 1495 Tuition First semester 106.20 Sept. Tuition First sen Oct. Tuition First semester 87.30 Tuition First semester 6.30 Lou E. Hosmei , sale material Nov. 9 K P Carey 28.68 14 A. McClurg &amp; Co 49. 68 Houghton Mefflin A Co 40.54 Refunded tuition .80 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 79.16 $ 719.89 $ 719.89 ELOCUTION FUND. balance on hand at last report $ 8. -14 1906 Dec. 5 Phoebe M. Roberts, entertainment 103.45 Dec. 19 .Wilma Cline. private lessons 8.00 Margaret Dunlap, private lessons 9.50 Gladys Majors, private lessons 3.00 1907 Jan. 8 Mae Jones, private lessons 4.00 Jan. 11 LeRoy Smith, private lessons 2.5&lt;» Feb. 20 Wilma Cline, sale of tickets 4.20 Mar. 15 Rena Haey. private lessons 1.00 May 1 Sale of tickets May 21 Margaret Dunlap, private lessons. 107.85 -May 27 Mae Jones, private lessons 9."0 May 31 Wilma Cline, private lessons 13.00 July 8 Wilma Cline, private lessons 10.00 Carrie Niedermyer, private lessons.... 2.00 July 22 Wilma Cline, private lessons 5.00 July 24 Mae Jones, private lessons 3.00 Nov. 22 Sale of tickets 87.50 1906 $ 397.44 6 Miss Roberts, entertainment $ 7."&gt;.00 Mrs. Nettleton, expenses 3.00 IM7 Jan. 10 Mrs. Nettleton, material for plays 5.25 Mar. 15 Mrs. Nettleton, programs, etc 3.SS </seg>
            <seg id="p074">76 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION K. E. Mumford, tacks .25 Robert Phelps, Asst. with curtain 1.20 June 3 Mary Moore, work on curtains 75.00 July 11 Mrs. Nettleton, Cert, for Dept 1 .00 July 15 Rudge &amp; Gueczel Co., curtains 50.00 Nov. 19 Mary A. Blood, entertainment 1U1.25 Dec. 1 Private lessons Dec. 2 S. W. Hacker, printing 4.00 Dec. 12 Amelia F. Lucas, supplies 2.44 1908 Jan. Private lessons 4.75 Feb . Private lessons 2.50 M ;i p . Private lessons 2 . 25 .Mar. 18 Columbia Sen. Expres., supplies 5.00 ('. M. Parker 6.75 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 20.64 Apr. Private lessons 13.75 Apr. 7 S. \V. Hacker, printing 4.50 Apr. 13 Emerson Col. of Oratory .60 Apr. 16 Ainsworth &amp; Co., books 7.20 M ay Private lessons S . 54 May 26 S. W. Hacker, printing 5.00 June Private lessons 49.00 June 17 C. M. Parker, books 2.00 J uly Private lessons 14 . 99 July 14 Nancy K. Meek, instruction 25.00 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 12.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 34.95 Burris Drug Co., supplies 2.00 July 29 Nancy E. Meek, instruction 21.50 Aug. Private lessons 5.60 Oct. Private lessons 9 . 00 Oct. 19 Dramatic Pub. Co., books 1.50 Daisy D. Nettleton, books 1 . 38 Balance on hand Jan. 1, 1909 25. 5o $ 519.69 $ 519.69 MUSIC FUND. Balance on hand at last report $ 72 . 55 1907 Feb. 22 Mr. Haushahn, private lessons 6.00 Mr. Haushahn, music 1.75 Mar. 4 Lillie Banks, music 14.50 Mar. 21 Sale of tickets 50.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">77 Mar. 22 Esther Wallace, music lessons. Apr. 3 Fern Ort, music lessons. Apr. 11 Sstlla Washburn, music lessons. May 17 Mary Ellenberger, lessons and piano rent May 31 Stella Nable, music lessons... .Tune 25 Lena Larimer, music lessons.. June 25 Henry Nielson. music lessons. July 5 Ethel Delzell, music lessons.. July 8 Ora Beck, mir&amp;ic lessons.. Carrine Porter, Ins. music. July 23 Marie Anderson, piano rent July 25 Sarah Ray, Ins. music ;: Not. 21 Blanche Collins, music lessons. 1907 * 209.93 Jan. 18 Geo. B. Jennings Co., music $ Mar. 14 Clayton F. Summy Co., music 63.44 May 31 Clayton F. Summy Co., music 3.93 8ilver-Burdett Co., music 4.38 C. F. Hinsley, moving piano 2.50 June 13 Clayton F. Summy Co, music 22.70 Charles .Otradovec, music 8.00 July 1 Clark Bruce, tuning piano 3.00 July 15 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., chapel curtains.. 50.00 July 31 Lyon ft Healy, Ins. Music 8.62 Aug. 16 Ginn ft Co., music 9.21 Nov. 18 Clayton F. Summy Co., music .64 Dec. 1 Private lessons. 1908 Jan. Private lessons. Jan . 7 Fillmore Bros., music 6.40 Lyon ft Healey, music 29 . 50 Feb. Private lessons. 14 75 Feb . 20 R. P. Curtice Co., music 1 . 90 r Private lessons. Piano rent Sale of tickets.. 16.50 49.25 Mar. 18 Silver Burdett Co., books 47.75 Oliver Ditson Co 2.20 Mar. 28 A. Loeb, supplies 30.35 r Private lessons. Rent of piano. . Apr. 1SS. W. Hacker, printing 5.25 Clark Bruce, piano tuning t. 50 May Private lessons. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 78 Glee Club concert... 12 Geo. H. Aller. music. May May May May June June 13 Mary G. Ellenberger, services 21 Edward Hodapp, music 23 Lyon &amp; Healey, music 6 E. P. Hodapp, music. 12 George Aller, concert proceeds For music lessons D. L. Carlson, cut Refund tuition. . . . June June July July 13 2:! Received music lessons Sidney Murphey, instruction Sidney Murphey. instruction Refund tuition i July .) uly s 14 Lola Lee Loce. instruction C. A. Jones, tuning piano. Lyon &amp; Healy, music... July lo Refund tuition. King .1 uly July July Refund tuition, Ellenberger Refund tuition, Kernen. . . . Lolo Lee Love, instruction. A. Loeb, instruction u 27 Aug. Aug. Sept. Oct. Sale of music book Sydney Murphey. . . For music lesson's. For piano rent I Oct. 6 Sidney Murphey, instruction For music lessons Nov. For piano rent Nov. Nov. Nov. 3 Sydney Murphey, instruction University Pub. Co., books.. Sidney Murphey, instruction 24 21 Balance on band Jan. 1, 1909 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">79 BI-ENNIAL REPORT CASH FUNDS AT KEARNEY. DORMITORY ACCOUNT. For Biennium Beginning December 1, 1906, and Closing December 1, '08 Items. Receipts 1906 Dec. 1 Balance in Dormitory fund $ 151.38 Room rent 129 . 95 Dec. 8 Anna V. Jennings, decorations $ 1.90 Dec . 9 Eva J. Case I Dec. 10 Patterson &amp; Wingard 3.50 Dec. 19 Anna Drury 8.00 Dec. 20 Lily Wallace 8.00 1907 Jan. 1 Room rent 43.63 Jan. 3 City Water Company 22.95 Feb. 1 Room rent 136.60 Mar. 1 Room rent Mar. 4 X. P. Matson 270.08 Mar. 22 Benton Bros 60\ 00 Mar. 23 X. W. Electric Company 47.88 Apr. 1 Room rent 110.10 May 1 Room rent 263 . 30 May 29 Piano rental 40.00 City Water Co 93.15 V W. Electric Company...-. 195.00 Doors and repairs 10.45 Kearney Telephone Co 6 .00 June 1 Room rent 71.40 June 13 Albert Lewis 16.00 July 1 Room rent 200 . 10 Aug. 1 Room rent 8.40 Mrs. M. L. Crowell 12.00 8ept. 1 Room rent 155 . 55 Sept. 16 U Smith 40.25 Sept. 16 L. Smith 40.25 Sept. 24 E. J. Thygesen 40 . 00 Sept. 24 E. J. Thygesen 40 . 00 Oct. 1 Room rent 107 . 25 Oct. 2 H. W. Electric Company 83 . 37 Not . 1 Room rent 37 . 60 Not. 6 Kearney Telephone Co 12.00 Not. 18 X. P. Matson 61.12 Nov . 26 L. Smith 5 . 00 Xov . 28 City Water Co 108 . 30 If. W. Electric Company 37 . 46 Dec. 1 Room rent 76.90 Room rent </seg>
            <seg id="p078">80 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Dec. 23 Kearney Telephone Company 6.00 Inez A. Ware 70.00 1908 .T:m . 1 Room rent Jan . 13 Gilcrest Lumber Co 6 . 65 Jan. 13 X. W. Electric Co 46.68 Jan. 20 Knutzen &amp; Isdell 93.65 Feb. 1 Room rent 356. SO A. C. Everson .60 Feb. 5 F. C. Scott 12.00 Switz Furniture Co 8.00 S. A. D. Henline 1.85 X. W. Electric Company 90.50 Feb. IT W. N. Delzell 20.25 Feb. 2H Pity Water Co 79.50 W. K. Ajres 36.00 J. II. Robinson 165.73 Mar. 1 Room rent Mar. 3 E. J. Thygesen 21.93 Mar. 12 Kearney Telephone Company 6.00 Apr. 1 Room rent Mav 1 Room rent K. &lt;\ Scott 11.00 May 9 Parker &amp; Hazlett 14.00 June 1 Room rent 205.10 June 11 J. Hazel White 11.25 June 12 City Water Co 47.25 X. W. Electric Company 1".7.41 June 26 W. K. Ayres 11.30 July 1 Room rent 108.55 July 10 Switz Furniture Co 37.00 Lucien Smith 37.80 July 11 X. P. Matson 35.00 (Xo August Report). Sept. 1 Room rent Sfpt. 4 Kearney Telephone Company 12.00 Sept. 15 Sophia Swanson 12.00 Ellen Swanson 12.00 Sept. 19 S. R. Wenzell IS. 78 Sept. 24 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co 61.63 Oct. 1 Room rent Oct. 3 J. I. Sinclair 2 . 75 X. P. Matson 484 . 25 Oct. Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Powers Co 17.45 Xov. 1 Room rent </seg>
            <seg id="p079">81 20 Kearney Water ft Elec. Powers Co Nov. 30 City Water Co. "45 Total refunds to students, not pre- viously reported Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1908 98. :&gt; Total $ 3,095 $ :.O9', CASH ACCOUNT— KEARNEY. For Biennium Beginning Dec. 1, 1906 and Closing Dec. 1, 1908. Items Receipts * I Dec . 1 Balance in Fund Typewriter fees 12. Dec. X A. C. Loshbaugh 1 65 Huntley ft Maguire Leonard Thompson Dec. 4 Helen Tolliff 5.00 Dec. 7 Western Union Telegraph Co 4.15 Dec. 8 Central Scientific Co 4.75 Dec. 11 Sam W. Tool 3.00 Dec. 14 Guy W. Pierce l.M Dec. 17 J. Wayne Chapman 5 . 00 Dec. 19 Marion C. Smith .95 Dec. 20 J. Wayne Chapman 5.00 Dec. 21 C. L. Hoppe 7.50 Dec. 27 C. B. A Q. Freight ft Drayage 4.68 Dec. 29 U. F. freight and drayage 1.24 1907 46.2 Jan . 1 Typewriter fees Jan. 3 Ina M. Parrish 15.00 Jan. 7 D. H. Baldwin ft Co 15.00 Jan. 8 Bruce Campbell 6.75 Jan-. 10 Pacific Express 5.18 Jan. 11 Marie Reasoner 2.50 Jan. 12 Western Union 12.00 Jan . 15 Adams Express 5 . 25 C. B. ft Q., freight .53 Jan . 17 Pacific Express .70 Jan. 18 Western Union 2.28 Jan . 21 Pacific Express 1 . 60 freight and drayage 4.68 Remington Typewriter Co 15. 00 Smith Premier Typewriting Co 15 . 00 Ray B. Rhodes .90 Gus8 Freiday .90 Jan . 23 Adams Express 1 . 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">82 Pacific Express 1.00 Jan. '24 Pacific Express l.M Adams Express 1.00 •Ian. 25 Pacific Bxpreat Adams Express 1 .M Jan. 28 Pacific BipieM Jan. tl r P. Freight 4 Western I'nion . . 4H Jan. M U. P. freight .... Jan. 31 Ad-.'ius ExpreM l.M A. J. .Mercer 8.35 1 Typewriter fees SI. M Ina M. Parrish I T. P. Freight C. L. Hoppe 11.64 4 Otto Moritz ft J. Wayne Chapman 10.00 8 Adams Express 1 1 Mary W. Bailey 11.70 Pacific Express 1 . I'm I 1 1 Pacific express 1 . 00 Feb . 14 Union Pacific freight 1 . H8 Feb. 18 Rothwell Allen l.M Feb. 19 Postage 19. M Feb . 22 Otto .Moritz .4". D. P. Freight 1 .S3 Feb . 23 Pacific Express Mar. 1 Typewriter fees Kearney Towel Supply Co Mar. Ina M. Parrish Mar. 5 Adams Express .30 Mar. 9 Adams Express 1 . 85 Kearney Livery &amp; Hack Line Mar. 11 Edward Shue 6.94 C. L. Hoppe J. Wayne Chapman 10.00 Mar. 22 Adams Express .35 Mar. 27 Postage 5.00 Mar. 28 Pacific express 1 . 00 Mar. 29 Adams Express .40 Mar. 30 Adams Express 1 . 50 Apr. 1 Typewriter fees 38.00 Apr. 2 Edward Shue Kearney Towel Supply Co 1 . 00 Apr. 8 Western Union Telegraph Co </seg>
            <seg id="p081">83 j. w 3 } n p v *n&lt;ipni3n ...•*•••••••••••••« i". \j\j - Apr. 10 Wm. Cockle 10.00 Apr. 15 L. P. Ludden 25.00 Apr. IT Bruce Campbell 3.00 Apr. 18 Polk-Avoy Directory Co 6.00 Apr. 19 X. P. Hanson F. H. Russell 4.25 Apr. 20 S. Drake 1 Apr. 30 Fred G. Keens .78 May 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc., O90&lt;; Typewrite fees 'S:S May 2 J. H. Mickey 10.00 D. H. Baldwin &amp; Co 1B.M May 6 Kearney Towel Supply Co 1 . 00 May 8 Richard Sindt 2.00 May 24 Orrie Marshall 8.15 May 28 Edward Shue 3.05 L. W. Robertson 12.25 May 29 A. Hospe &amp; Co 50.00 J. S. Moore 9 . 00 Nebraska Telephone Co Kearney Telephone Co 13.30 Knutzen &amp; Isdell 28.00 N. C. Abbott June 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc 438.2 Typewriter fees June 5 J. H. Lyon 1 . 00 June 10 I.emeul Tool 8.90 June 15 Black &amp; Kuhn Bros 1.00 June IT Smith Premier Typewriter Co 125.00 June 24 Marion C. Smith 3.10 June 20 Hammond &amp; Stephens 1 . 35 C. K. Dungan 11.00 June 2!» Goodyear-.Marshall Pub. Co 250.00 July 1 Typewriter fees 10.00 Richard Sindt 1.00 J uly 2 Robert Chambers 1 . 05 •&gt; July 3 O. J. Kern 10.00 W. G. Garrett 5.00 July 6 Remington Typewriter Co 125.00 July 10 Arthur Nichols 1.00 July 17 Margaret West 6.00 J. A. Williams 6.00 July 18 1. A. Downey 20.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">84 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION rl Text book r'nt'ls, fines, etc., (summer '07) Typewriter fees Aug. 2 D. H. Baldwin Co 15.00 Huntley &amp; Maguire 2.50 Aug. 3 Dan Ristael 15.00 Huntley &amp; Maguire 6 . 00 Aug. 14 A. Troxel 2.00 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc. Typewriter fees Sept. 19 Lemeul Tool 3.00 24 Remington Typewriter Co 150.00 Smith Premier Typewriter Co 125.00 Oct. 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc Typewriter fees Oct. 2 A'.bin Johnson 5.15 Oct. 7 Virginia Mercer 21.09 Kearney Steam Laundry 3 . 50 Oct. 9 Refunded to Bertha Ball, (typewriter).. 4.25 Refunded to W. Miller, (typewriter)... 4.50 14 Arthur Soderstrom .65 Oct. 29 Wm. H. Gregg 1 .00 31 S. C. Quick 4.00 Nov. 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc Typewriter fees. Earl Tool .45 5 Typewriter refund, A. Easterling 3.50 Nov. 6 Marion C. Smith 22.13 Etta Brown 1 . 00 Nov. 13 Hospe Piano Co 30.00 D. W. Hecox 5.00 Leonard Thompson 1.90 Nov. 14 Anna E. Caldvrell 11.16 Etta Brown 11.16 Nov. 25 Earl Tool 1.50 Xov. 26 L. Smith 30.00 Nov. 27 J. H. Hayward 2.00 Nov. 28 Smith Premier Typewriter Co 99.45 Active Hopson 5.40 Zelda Norris 12 . 00 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co American Book Co Dec. 1 Text book renials, fines, etc Dec. 3 Typewriter refund, Alice Dodge ITHifVi CniU Vic 1 1 flrt </seg>
            <seg id="p083">85 Dec. 13 Fred Bryant 5.00 Typewriter refund, Mabel Hotchkiss . . . 1 T."&gt; Dec. 20 Zelda Norris 12.00 Mable Coie I.M Dec. 23 Kearney Telephone Co 2.95 Jan. 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc Typewriter fees 5.00 Jan . 3 C. G. Henderson 1.25 Jan . 10 American Book Co 36 . 00 Jan. 16 Kearney Steam Laundry Jan. 28 Gregg Publishing Co 8.87 Allyn ft Bacon 6 . 62 Walter H. Baker &amp; Co 3.50 Haaae ft Son 5.05 D. H. Baldwin ft Co Feb. 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc 94.70 177. 5'i Typewriter fees Feb. 8 American Book Co 484 .09 11 Dr. H. C. Ward 15.00 17 J. K. Stableton 25.00 F%b. 21 Remington Typewriter Co F*b. 28 Typewriter refund, Henry Pearson o.50 Mar. 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc. Typewriter fees 42.4." ln. n.-. Mar. 9 Typewriter refund, Joy HayeB 3.75 Mar. 10 Arthur J. Barnes Pub. Co 55.28 Huntley ft Maguire 2 . 50 Mar. 17 Typewriter refund, C. McCray .25 Typewriter refund, J. Daugherty 2.50 Mar. 23 Typewriter refund. S. Eitelbuss 2.25 Apr. 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc Typewriter fees l.ii' D. H. Baldwin ft Co 15.00 Apr. 7 Kearney Steam laundry 3.00 Apr. 15 Remington Typewriter Co 50.05 May 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc 539.45 Atkinson, Mentzer ft Grover 3.32 Educational Pub. Co 1 . 00 May 4 Edward Shue .60 May 6 Thos. T. Crowell 7.21 May 18 Refund bookkeeping set 1.25 May 28 Bob Mclntyre 1.50 June 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc !&lt;♦&lt;* </seg>
            <seg id="p084">86 Jnne 26 Judge W. D. Oldham 5.00 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co Silver. Burdett &amp; Co The Macmillan Co C'has. Scribners Sons 1 1 . 63 July 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc 817.75 Typewriter fees John Borders 1 .M July 15 Supt. L. R. Willis John Jameson 4 . no July 22 Etta Rickanl 1 Typewriter fees .... Albert Gredler 13. M 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc Typewriter rentals Sept. 19 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co 1M.7I H ('. I. Swartwood Oct. 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc Typewriter fees Tyi&gt;ewriter refund. M. Faser Albert Gredler !•••• Oct. 20 A. J. Mercer Kearney Grocery Co 7 "•"&gt; 1 Text book rentals, fines, etc Typewriter fees Xot. 20 D. Appleton &amp; Co Atkinson, Mentzer &amp; Grover 6.60 Arthur J. Barnes Pub. Co 8 . 00 Bellevue College Educational Pub. Co A. Flanagan Co 5.40 Henry Holt &amp; Co 30 . 48 Houghton. Mifflin Co .55 Little, Brown &amp; Co .94 Chas. E. Merrill Co 6.91 The Macmillan Co 10.90 Newson &amp; Co 3.91 Prang Educational Co 18 . 84 Rand. McNally &amp; Co \V M. Welch Co Benj. H. Sanborn Co 10.28 University Pub. Co 30.60 Nov. 28 Remington Typewriter Company 6.00 Balance on hand Dec. 1, 1908 502.99 </seg>
            <seg id="p085">87 SALE OF PROPERTY ACCOUNT AT PERU, NEBR. 1908 Receipts Mar. 9 J. W. Crabrtree. water for Oak Glen to the close of summer term, 1908 J.~, "•• Jlar . 17 Edward Hodapp, stencil Bennie Rowan, broken window pane. . . . Mrs. Jones, broken window pane Beck, oil barrel Mar. 19 Gordon Beck, broken window pane .30 liar . 21 N. A. BengtBon, stencil . 1 1&gt; Apr. i Win. Culbertson, 14 chairs ft.M Wnj. Culbertson. one old rang* 3.5-&gt; Apr. 24 Maude Brims Ion. broken lamp cbinii: Apr. 27 J. B. Dennis, broken alcohol lamp Apr. 36 Fern Brown, broken thermometer May 4 Louis Magor. broken thermometer May 1 1 Rollo Fosnot, broker, flask . 1 ."&gt; May 22 Helva Nickel, breakage in laboratory... May 2S Harold Stephens, broken glass Mr. Lowe, old boilers, etc 450. 00 June 3 Received for stencils June 4 Prof. Brownell, lime June 16 C. O. Oline, stencils, senior class 13.60 Jane It John Hanna, typewriter ribbon .40 June 24 H. B. Duncanson. microscopes 8.00 Aug. 3 C. Hendricks. stencils .80 Aug. 21 J. M. Howie, cot 1.50 Aug. 29 Miss Lanphere, stencil .10 8«pt. « E. R. Burkey, rent of cots Mr». Glasgow, sale of cots Mrs. Glasgow, rent of cots .4^ Sept. 30 F. M. Ivers, lumb?r Mumford, sale of lamps June treasurer | 280.20 Balance on hand t 92S 65 SALE OF PROPERTY ACCOUNT AT KEARNEY, NEBR 1*&gt;7 Receipts June 8 Sale of alfalfa from campus j 15.00 r. 10 Sale of alfalfa from campus 15.00 Sale of cinders 9 . 50 </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>