<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00017.00003">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00017.00003</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska Public Library Commission</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">1 r 1 i im( i s </seg>
            <seg id="p004">i I ! ' </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Ini //. M: As required by law, I have the herewith the third hi port of the Nebraska Public Library Cuiim Very respectfully yours V L. HAI.J.KR, </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 SK( KKTAKVVS KKPOKT. The Nebraska Public Library Commission was created by a la » which we •i-ct June 28, 1901, ami active work was begun the following November The first five years of the life of the Commission has been a period of usual activity in library interests in the state. The number of public librarie has increased from 2h to 55. Interest has been aroused in manv comtnunitie •vhile it has not yet resulted in the establishing of libraries is sure to d so in time. Handsome library buildings have been built in Lincoln. Falls City Fremont. Beatrice, Kearney, Hastings. Grand Island and South Omaha. Th : administration in the older libraries have been improved. The Stat e ■11. which formerly consisted of a handful of people wh ther as an adjunct of the State Teacher ■Acfao now numbers in its meeting* from fifty to s« The number of trained librarians in Nebraska in re thirteen who have had regular course! in lib I ho have taken summer c&gt; i The first traveling librae &gt;ut in December 1901. m forty to fifty volumes each. A review of I if.' and th&lt; * the future most promising. a!tern" now numbers in its meetings from fi &gt; utv-five The number of trained librarians in Nebraska in 1901 was perhaf re thirteen who have had regular 1 ibrarv schools an taken summer The first traveling library was *ent out in December 1901. We now have :rom forty to fifty volumes each. A review of the past fiv .. ing and tlie outlook for the future most promisit I'uhlii- Library Commission. mlsaiim and tin n lepartnre of Mr. James 1. Wyer, who left ,ti Januarv reference librarian of the New York Stat ka in January, : ine reference librarian of tin director of the New York State Library Sell workers in establishing the Cotamiai tieo, anil always st&lt;xxl ready with his wide know! rv and vice-director of the New York State Library School. He w live workers in establishing the Commission, was president froii ■■&gt; further the library interests of the whole state. I&gt;r. Walter K. Jew Mr. Wver in Mav 1). Kullock resigned as secretary, her resi 12 effect th Miss Bullock had been secretary of t tary &gt;n With little assist*?, ry small appropriation she had yet br . of which the st.itr mav well be "ed the following "In acceptii Edna D. Bullock, who has been ka Public Library Commission since the inception of it ise, said commission cordially testifies tu the fidelity, ability, indus »nd success with which Miss Hullock has discharged the arduous dutief inciden founding and spread of the Commission work in the state Miss Char: laha, was elected secretary to succeed Mi-. Kullock ar. itj was nude assistant secretary he place &lt;A ir, resigned </seg>
            <seg id="p007">'lift* .mil llii|in-t Tbc reports of libraries show many ey from public spirited citi« I urnitureand lequest from the late Frank Murphy. L Omaha Public Library recer. le library; the library at Havelock h hr Omaha ruhlio Library received |io,uoo. Neligh's citueni have given I945 ■■ library; the library at Have luck bai Rhodes: the P. E. &lt;). sociev, the York I'ul &gt; the York Public Li &gt;rar\ ; the Beatrice Hi^h School has turned over to the Public Library ction of 550 volumes; tlie Teeumseh Library will f the lau- Mrs Brando*. There have been completed during the biennium f the late Mrs Ther mpleted during the biennium lie following public library buildings given by Andrew I 1 w \nilrew Carneitie: one ,tt ( ■land fi tings for J I f ae at S mh Oman; .,,,1 Holdn lie at S uth OmaV uildings from Mr Carnegie a* ac lively, which Mr Caroeeie ively, ill be read) 1 cy this winter, lid site and thi te and the -e being made fa Carnegie building. e Cam Appropriation*. The legislature of 1905 appro]. 1 the Public Library Coinmis- 'l ■ li. While this « inch as the Commission had asked tor and wa« 1 nli the extension planned, by the practice of stri. ■• this \v is not as much as the Commission hi By, it was sufficient to maintain the work already undertaken The work has ■ 11 to such proportions, however, that \ if the nt to in. iint. iin tht v tl ns, howi lation i&lt;- state. I'iiIiIh- I thill If I'iiIiIh l.ihniriis A number of lil hirinj; the biennium. At ity although a 1 \ am. At L \\ll tax w Rd has furnished twi free library. It is u every daj and evening. ■ of Dr. II. L. Smith turn over the H. L. Smith lil enient room e of the- lil : and will I ■Hi wi iblic Library on January I, H The library at Neligb stari- Januar !ir\ with a one mill tax levy in it* 5. Rooms in the city hall art- 1 mill tax levy ii K. ins ill the city hall are u River opened a public library in the s] ..6. The W.mmI y ii the spring of i9&lt;*. Tin El by a citizen and Ixioks were j;iveii by otli irary ordinance w ired and the librai lilinit dinance was • d and the libra I t XCU] At Norfolk. Minilen and J i V tl </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Travelintr Ukrarfe*. be Cotntnissioo in iq&gt; She •rn until at 1 K-l liffen t. They have tray an.l li in h A - of tht have circu u-rtnine ■in h I :iiv ere »re se neral intt children 1 tie !i w IVririHiit'iil Irax IhiL- Library Statinns. w Ci Laurel. Murr anr estun in&lt;l far aw \\ au </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Special Loan*. It is well to supply the demand for general reading with the traveling li - brary but there is another call made upon the Commission with more and more frequency which must be satisfied as far as we are able. This is the request of the student for material on a special subject. It comes from the club woman, the teacher, the high school dehator and the individual student and, thanks to the careful selection of our special loan collection and to the unfailing courtesy of the State Library and the Library of the State University, it is rare that we have nothing to send. We have circulated 1,230 volumes as individual loans during the bitnnium. This work is capable of indefinite extension and is of inestim - able value. School Libraries, A great deal of effort has been put forth by the Commission in behalf of school libraries. There is no law requiring school districts to purchase books other than text books, although the ruling has been made that school funds may be so spent. The popular way of raising money for school libraries is by enter - tainments and box socials. The money once raided, the question of sel. comes up, and it is here that the Commission is doing some of its best work. The graded list compiled by Miss Bullock, of 500 books suitable for school li - braries is distributed freely among the teachers. Many talks have been given by the Secretary at teacher's institutes and normal schools aud a great deal of correspondence on the subject of book selection has been carried on. Requests from teachers for assistance in this matter come in constantly, and frequently the jelection is left in the hands of the Secretary. "We have #25.00 for books for our rural school library. What shall we buy?' is the common demand. In a rural state like Nebraska where towns are small and a long way apart, the district school library must often lake the place of a public library and furnish reading not only for the children but also tor the young people who have left school and tor the fathers and mothers. Teachers and superintendents are very generally awakened to the great possibilities in a group of well selected books and the past two years has been a period of great activity in building up school libraries. Publication*. In February, 1906, the Commission issued its first number of the N&lt; Library Bulletin, a publication devoted to the interests of Nebraska libraries, to be published three or four times a year and sent free to every librarian and library trustee in the state. The first numbers have been most cordially re - ceived and we hope to make this a really helpful feature of our work. ■January the Commission published a Farm Circular giving a list of the in the special loan department on farm topics and domestic economy, 5 in which the library is particularly strong. The Commission subscribes for enough copies of the A. L. A. Booklist to send one to every library in the state. This list, published monthly by the American Library Association at a very small rost, consists of carefully selected titles with good notes. The books most desirable for first purchase in the small libraries are indM star. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Stale l.ilii-iirt Am«ria1i*a. No meeting of III. Library Association was held in 1904 l)ec« \. L. A. meeting in St. Louis. In December, 1905, the A ■ nth annual meeting in Lincoln with a large attendance. Mi nsin was the guest of the Association and w.is an inspi lea librarians. The officers chosen for 1906 were: President Thomas of McCook; first vice-president, Miss 1'annie Get Columbu iry K Ray of Kearney; secretary. Miss Neliit :&gt;urer, Mi»&gt; Margaret O'Brien ol ( Mnaha. l.onkiiiL' to the Future. 1.1 Wi r taxpayer! many foreigners, principally derm i j i&lt; 1 Swedes. Por th&lt;»e who do not read l-.nt;li&gt;li at ■rho do not use it readily umigli to find English tHxik?. ■ m who know the laagna|{e bui who wish to will ■! tin literature of their mother country ami foster a love ! !iil&lt;ln.-ti. we should provide foreign lx*&gt;W&gt; a^ hmhi aaonr funds oul.l In- loaned to the small lihrariea whoae limited ImhiU funil - the jmrcli igD l»Kik&gt;; they could Ik- &gt;i-m out in trav • and I know of several rural achoob where the Ixm &gt;k- could Ik.- cii lie ]&gt;u]&gt;iU ;lil with ]&gt;rofit make np a number of -tuily lil&gt;r;i lit baring H-w or no library facilities. These ahoul ual and ]&gt;!■ club work: American art. lonial hiator) . Shaki . and could Ik.- sent to I lae during the club ) i others who know he Ian tin he liililn-n. »c should provide fore 1 Ik mall librari limit* the purchase of foreign l«H&gt;ks; tin : I know of several rural schools when 1 could with profit make up a number of st .!&gt;s in towns having few i&lt; r club work: American art. Ai Shakt •I" st- durina the ilul In l d with the genera] ifi: iren's literature. There ihouM K of lecture! on the Mil IkhU anioiiL 1111 imprest ■en's literature. Then- si r with some instruction in the ill Mi </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 APPENDIX. Financial Report, Nov. 30, 1904 Nov. 30. 1906 Rkceipts Balance, Nov Appropriation, 1903-5, $1203 Appropriation, 1905 60c Travel 352-4O Printing Binding 53 Furniture Boxes 6. $55°5-4O 1697.S0 Balance $72o, the bienniv \u H I'ublisht ( Risers usly reported ■ssions Duplicates to replace lu-t or worn out -t and paid for by others 59 1'aid for bv Coniinission 16 Lost by others and paid for by Commission Not replaced *72O3 Krsements, Nov. 30, 1904, — Nov. 30, 1906 ilaries $336347 xjks 60 - 1 Total additi </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 STATIST1O OK NKURASKA TRAVELING LIBRARIES WHKRK KEPT brari TOWS corxTY -Mil *&lt;?*"» Store.... 4 68 55S Alliance Boxbutte Junior Normal ADoke Rovd Ansel: J ustcr Arcadia Valley Farm 34 Ashland ... Saunciers Public School School Farm Library Auburn N'emaha Aurora Hamilton Axtell Kearney v Bancroft ... v uming School School School c 4 69 Bega -Canton Bellwood . Butler Bennington _ Douglas M Bennington . D listrict Bertrand I'helps Bethany L.,- School School School Blair Washington Blair Washington iistrict Brainard Butler School Bank . School School Bridgeport Cheyenne Broken Bow Custer Bluff Post office 6 Callaway Custer Callawmy Custer Farm ridge Furnas hool Library Central Cit\ I lawes Cheney Lai • s office Merrick Private house Cherry Iiaper officf Store Cedar Lancaster School tack Custer ■ shops Coautock C uster CrawfoH Dawes School Iiarl&gt;er •Culbertson Hr hop Howard School ■li^trict Library Library I&gt;e\Vitt saline Killer .fferson I&gt;i\on Otoc Antelope Vi reek lohnsoo School I( (f 1 4a </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 STATISTICS OF NEBRASKA TRAVELING LIBRARIES— r&lt;&gt;»/&gt;«««/. bn Li Bemd - ers TOWN COUNTY WHERE KEF ■T Kxeter _ Fillmore Private house Fairfield Clav Jewelry store 6, tontanelle Washington Fontanelle Waahiagt Fort Crook . Sarpy . School Fort Crook . Sarpy 67 Friend ... . . Saline 100 Friend Saline Nance Friend Saline ding room ate house . 1 17 a Nance Gibbon Buffalo [School O.iblxm Buffal 'Gordon Sheridan . JTeleph O)nlon . Sheridan phone office ate house. 'Gothenburg Dawioa Gothenburg . Dawson ir 195 Grant Perkins Perkins 4.S Greenwood School rreenwood "Harvard . .. C!ay 1'uhlic I. me ■.-&gt;'■! Public Harvard Clav Library Library Havelock . . Lancast ■r Herman Washington Herman Washing i Hickman . Lancaster. School Hickman . Lancast r Holbrook ... .. Furnace- Hoi brook Furnace Holdregc _ Phe!ps . .... Junior Holdregc _ 1'help: Junii New or Norm spaper o Hooper Dodge Hooper . . . I Hoskini . W'avin 35 Hoskini Wayne re Huntle\ . Harl.m Huntlt- . Harlan ffice Ithica Saandcn School Saunder Ik Kearne Buffalo Watson Kearnt- Huffalo Wat: Post Schc Co. : k&gt;n's Rancl office . . Kenesaw .. \daius .. Post ofl Kenes .1 a \&lt;lams Kennard Washington School Kimball Kimball Co. Suj upt. office School h distric M •Laurel Cedar Printin Cedar Prin ing office Laurel Ccdu Cedar Laurel ■ ■■ \m Private Laurel I h Lawrence .. Nuckolls Schotil 3-' Lawrence Nuckoll h Lebanon Red Willow School Lebanon Red \V Sol w I-eij;h Colfax IveiK'h Colfax Sch Lewiston Pawnee Lewiston Pawn Lexington Dawson Lexington Dawn Lexington. Dawaon School Lexington Hawson Sch .1 Liberty Private Private house Lin wood Kulier •s Linwoixl . . ... Mutler I Long Pine ... . Browl I -■. ille C Luella -.llerician house L&gt;-ons Hurt ■x McCook . Ret) Wi Pub! Juni ScIk Sch&lt; Library Normal w 1 McCook Red Wi 1 Mead Saundc Mead lis 4 Mead Saunder Memphis Saunder Private hoi: M Milligan Fillmore re Scotts Hluff . Platte </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 STATISTH S OK NEBRASKA TRAVELING LIBRARIES- ( nt nun TOWN COUNTY WHERE KEPT Munlock Bank .. •Murray. I&gt;rug sto: D Drug store •.i iDakota Nehawka k , . . School ntelope . . . School 1 Sch&lt;x&gt;] . Nehawka Caaa Xehawka School School Neligh \ntelope ' Norfolk Madison Norfolk M Norma I UKMter School Norma! School Private house Private li 1 Filknore . . School I'illmort School Antelope Antelope Telephone oftce Telephone offer Vallev Valley I'olk ' Furniture &gt;tore Public Library. -•iinfn'&lt;l Final Pi iia - irpy Office Thurston Public Library Private hi Pleasant Dale . Sewarrl ■&gt;, !u«il Ponca Dixon ( Supt. office I'unlum vi;i .te house . Citi liutler . Farm . . Custer . . Luster ■ill di^trii't i &gt;] district 1 if jnrtii - ■! 1 district 74 »il district 7 ' &lt; &gt;fnce . Auburn Nemalia ' ■ School district 5 School district 50 Beatrice Creamery 1 Spal&lt;lin^ ' -reeley . Iteatrice Creamei Boyd &gt; tieUl Sarpy I &gt;ni l Harlau Si hool hurst Seward School :iK Public Librarj 1 . ;tat ■11 Boyd i- Office I Irut 49 llarlan 66 1 hurst ... ng JohMon Store . ., Snmmerneld. Kas Marshall I district 76 ■r ... Ni ■ house School rland Lincoln (Hoc Library S«4 Ot&lt;K 1'rivale house. I*rivate house Public Library Farm . . 1 'a wnet 6 I'rivste hou**&lt;" </seg>
            <seg id="p015">si U ls| |i s ok \ Kit It Vsk V I I! \\ KI.IM. I.IHKAK1KS ( \\ HERE K I row* ■or sty C TI h i '14 Yor \\ Schcx Ki \ nit- Custi i 1 M 4 WimhI ki II srMMAKV They have been to 177 places in 69 counties 4342 volumes have a reported circulation of ja Public lihrar '35 »9 ne library station ling libraries have made </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 S s. X 10 O&lt; X •*• / X x ™* X r^\C « w w \C « s * ■». V1OX w; X X X •&lt;. i - X I ac ir i ~ x ; z if. * W X »/} **5 M •- *^ "« }- X ■&lt;. /li r* — — i^ t^ tf. r XX rt tx CT*&lt;N i^X «-. — X Mai All "&gt;a * «J&lt; trice UJi M Ill Hi a '-I 5t 5t u s '-* '-/ "-&gt; • 5 = ~ x§ hIcB«35§Mp I 3|jj||]jj|jg |l|p||f1 — b ™ b "S s E p b *~" o c •— « "s.- xx u~, 5 tut-, &amp; — inx — &gt;c *r -r ~ t-— to m mo &amp;■ -*r *r&gt;t-* I ■ i! 3 • 8 8 3 8 -!? S^ 8 « — r-«. w — — it; m </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Y. f- f- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">-v y / I s I. V / /.-'?&gt; ' </seg>
            <seg id="p019">1 y s. r IO&gt; s s r /. 1 r. f x I </seg>
            <seg id="p020">) i </seg>
            <seg id="p021">; ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p022"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>