<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00030</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>ANNUAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1907</title>
               <date value="1907">1907</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001"/>
            <seg id="p002">OF THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION FOR THE YEAR 1907 PREPARED BY S. C. BA88KTT. Secretary Nebraska Dairymen's Association. </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">Ueorye I. mplianc the Nebrai a NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION. RETAREVS OFFICE. GIBBON, NEB,. FEB. I, 1906. nth the law in this ca*e made and provided, I hereby transmit iska Dairymen's Association for the year 1907. Respectfully yours. Sheldon, Horornor hi Set </seg>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">TABLE OF CONTENTS. « Members 9 it; Address of President. H. ('. Young 1! ( Treasurer -1 Secretary M nt of Committees 33 M ,Hon. W. A. Poynter 34 Dairy Statistics Hon. John J. Ryder 32 \ddress Andrew Elliott, Guelph, Canada .... 4o What Tends to Advancement J. R. Roberts .... 4H Work of the Dairy Commission J. W. Johnson .... 44 \dvantages and Disadvantages of Centralized Creameries A. E. Wilkinson.. .'.1 ng Machine Demonstration H4 Report of Auditing Committee Election of Officers ■lutions 66 Home Dairying and the Supplying of Private Customers. John Sneddon . . tions Necessary to Success in Establishing Local Creameries J. G. Winkjar. ... 71 Silo and Ensilage (Discuss ! on) 77 Remarks Hon. J. H. Williams. . . The Co-operative Dairy Cow Test E. M. Little. . . Address Prof. H. G. VanPelt . -7 What a Dairyman saw in Europe. . .Henry C. Glissman. . . . !»4 Cow Judging Contest !»0 Dairy Exhibits. lol Abortion in Cattle Dr. A. T. Peters . . . 102 A Comparison of Prices Paid for Milk and Cream . J A. Rush ton . . . . 10ft List of Creameries 101 Kry Herd Records for Ten Years, Cost of Butter Fat Production (Bulletin No. 101. University of Ne- </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">Officers 1908-1909 .John sneddon, Eagle s. c. Bassett. Gibbon Directors: Prof. a. i. Haecker. </seg>
            <seg id="p009"/>
            <seg id="p010">9 ( LIST OF MEMBERS. Honorary Life Members H. Monrad Minnetka, 111. L Gabrilson New Hampton, Iowa W. I). Hoard Fort Atkinson. Wis. I'uppe Osage, Iowa Omaha, Nebr. G. Lumbar Life Mtafeitl Gibbon. Nebr. Cor. Clark &amp; Water Sts.. Chicago. I1U A York. Nebr. \ Fort Dodge Iowa \ Fulnier F FurRason 7 Beaver Crossing. Nebr. Germantown Co-Operative Creamery Ass'n. man Henry C Germantown. Nebr. Station B. Omaha Nebr. Station B, Omaha, Nebr. man H. C. C.unther K. W Albion. Nebr Haecker Prof. A. I Hainer Hon. E. I Station A. Lincoln, Nebr Lincoln, Nebr Howe E. F Fairmont Cr'y. Co., Omaha, Nebr Lincoln, Nebr Honeywell J. K 2 Gibbon. N&gt;br. Omaha. Xebr. .Gibbon. Nebr. Sutton. Xebr. . .Gibbon. Nebr. Waterloo, Nebr. Gibbon. Nebr. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 NKHRASKA DAIRYMKXS ASSOCIATION Kirschbraum &amp; Sons King Morelle B. ... York. X King J. J. Merrill J. C Miller Dr. Geo. L I I.KI of \iiniiiil Miintu i- Bier Carl A well P. Callings .1. K n W. .1. D V A: -■11 A. .1. M. J.. . Thos. F. West I Diedrichsen J. • •1] .). H •I. A. { Honeywell &amp; Rt K email Ceo II iffer B. H. . . on Wni. . . . enson Cbas. w Vaughn F. H Whitmore W. Win K Prof. H Sony K T rt J. Walter troaf R \ O. K iwrd M. . ■ Oeo. II. ton W. P Kren J. . nan F. H Dan . . </seg>
            <seg id="p012">\ 11 1 1M N. .!;;. Lincoln . Havelock Waterloo iVor Salt Co.. New Vork City .Route Z. Havelock York .Station B. Omaha I 3d. Ave., Kearnev Omal -.a Arcadia 139 N. 14. Lincoln Kansas City. Omaha Route 4. Lincoln te Farm, Lincoln. Guile Rock. Gibbon. Lincoln Cozad. Orleans Huntley tate Farm. Lincoln. U:Ue Farm, Lincoln. Lincoln. Point Ohiowa X. 12, Lincoln. Pawnee City. Pawnee City. Staplehurst Dodge St.. Omaha. So. Omaha. \\\f :!. Heaver Crossing. Route 1. Columbus York. Route 1, I'nion. Wilsonville. Route 3, Dawson. oute 1. Auburn. 1 . Aurora. A Beatrice Cr'y. Co.. Lincoln. 1'eatrice Cr'y. Co.. Lincoln. J. A Ma Imperial. Tester li </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION n 1 Hanna T. G Oma'.s Hooper F. E 12 ft Jones, Omaha Harvey E. E 1ZSI Grace St.. Lincoln Hanson D. E Fremont Henry A. B Grand lslani Haller G. J Blair Howe H SSI B. 11. Lincoln Home Dairy Creamery Co Grand Island Hanzal J Hall E. J. Cretf Grand Islan Hammond H. F Hansen Martin . . Harsh J. \V . Aurora Gor r. Lir Aut Ks J. A. ley E. R a P. C. Line Omal Israel A. R N. 14. Lir A. C F Johnson H. C Johnson Andrew Johnson J. A. Jenkins S a Route 1. Qu Er Johnson E. K Bth H. H ka J. .. K Kcberger M K ffman II. A. th Adolph . Keen A. E. Kelley J. A. D43 Clinton St.. L Erty Hon. A. ■rack C. B. en A. A. . . Ast Beaver ( Eers August era L. G. &gt;n James Papil Papil Da Rfvertc Murkle O C«rr Morris L. E. Macken N I'Bfversfty Place </seg>
            <seg id="p014">T w XTY-TH1RD ANNUAL CONVENTION 13 I ndoff H. Route 4. Lincoln. State Farm. Lincoln. State Farm. Lincoln. H. A M. H Rockville. Route 3. Pender. ard State Farm. Lincoln. *k A. F Beatrice Cr'y. Co., Lincoln. Beatrice Cr'y. Co., Lincoln. M C. H 2203 Grant St.. Omaha. Morrasy A. ( 2544 O. Lincoln. .% h Herman i Route 1. Hooper. L. F 1210 L. Lincoln. iry John Grand Island. Bradish. O. ( Scandia, Kans. Route 3, Lexington. Nebr. Route 1. Pilger. ( Crete. A. E J. R. Stromsburg. Crete. M. D H. E. Crete. Route 2. Phillips, Tecumseh. Tecumseh. . A Rockville. Route 2. Farragut, Iowa l 1' Loup City. Nebr. Beatrice Cr'y. Co., Lincoln. Beatrice Cry. Co.. Lincoln. n F Route 2. Herman. Norden. n .1. I Inavale. Pearson C. Pierce S. r Genoa. Atlanta. E. K Smithfleld. W. K Lincoln, i Reid A. J State Farm, Lincoln. Rig? C. M Beatrice. Roberts J. R Normal. Ritchey Ge Rising City, Richards I. H .State Farm, Lincoln. Ravenna Creamery Co Ravenna. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Roche Leo Route 5, Wooi Ri Ruliffson M. S Route 4. Line Ryder J. J. State House. Lincoln Rector E. T. Fairmont Cry. Co.. Otuah Stelk Mrs. Wi.i. . . Miss Marie, Sneddon John . . bart Win. . ■ k W. 0 . . . . Grand Gran 1 Is E ■;i Wa son K. V ) ■never Art! never IT B. H A \ K St. Klv Sautter L. W San.l J. A. . Sanbourn Guv ley R. A. A Sjogren O. W Stewart R. . K O. A Sturgeon R. Tibege Ed. O Krnbur*: mas O. I. . Bplin A. U z E. E. . riniann C I hi Roy Kdeberg E Tine C. Van Skiver Jo', n Wulf W Williamson C. 1 Witt R Route Rou nbnt Webster C. A. A Warner W. \V Iniversityl' Weber J. W Friend Wilkinson A. E Beatrice Cry. Co.. Lincolr Wittenbach Chr Elm Cre Wiegert M. A Beem« </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 Lincoln. Route 4. Lincoln. . Fairbury. \ </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 rlMTY-THIRD ANNUAL MEETING OP THE NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Tuesday and Wednesday, January 21 and -_'-J, 11*0" Sessions held in Live Stock Pavilion, State Farm, Lincoln. I'm— cla&gt;. .liiiiiiHry -1 Report of Secretary and Treasur Appointment of Committ Rirtion in Cows and Barren ( at Tends to Our Advancemen 1 The Work of the Nebraska Dair\ .1. W. .1 ihnson. Deputy I) Centralized Crea "Advantages and Disadvantages A. K \V '•A Year's Experience with the Milking Machine". .Prof. A At 4 P. M. cows will be milked with a milkin presence of the audience and the working of the mac Wednesday, January A. M Report of Committees Election of Officers "Home Dairying and Supplying Private Customers ' John Sneild "Conditions Necessary for Success in Establishing Local Creameries' J. G. Winkjer. Dairy Division l\ S. Dept. of Agricultur 1:30 P. M "Feeding Dairy Cows" Prof. H. G. Van Pelt. Iowa Agricul tural College. "What a Dairyman Saw in Europe" Henry C. Clissmaii </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 Work of the Dairy Division I'. S. Department of Agriculture" Hon. Ed H. Webster. Chief of the Dairy Division K j-operative Test of Milk Cows at Nebraska Experiment Prof. A. L. Haecker t 110 P M Cow Judging Con COW JIDGING CONTEST Regulations Pro Rata Premium $ 1 Open to members of the association only. The pro rata premium will be divided among those scoring 75 or points out of a possible 100 points, in the proportion to the number of points scored above 75; provided that of the pro rata fund intestant shall receive to exceed the sum of $15.00. The judging will be done on Wednesday, January 22. at 3:00 P. SI. stock judging pavilion. Every member of the association is invited to take part in this HITTER, MILK AND CHEESE EXHIBIT January 21—24. 1908 K M. LITTLE. Superintendent. Experiment Station. Lincoln, Nebraska Regulations .lembers of the association only: any one may become a association by payment of annual membership fee of Rata Premium. Creamery Butter $ Pro Rata Premium, Dairy Butter t Rata Premium, whole Milk in 12-quart bottle cases i. Pro Rata Premium. Cream in 12-pint bottle cases % 1st Prem. id Prem. 3d Prem. 4th Prem Print Mutter I not less than 5 lib. prints I $5.00 $4.00 $3.00 $2.00 Ornamental Butter ."..OH 4.00 3.00 M 4.00 3.00 2.00 &lt; Creamery exhibits for pro rata premiums shall consist of not less than 2o-pound packages: dairy in .'-pound or 10-pound packages of any Of pro rata premiums no exhibit shall receive to exceed $5.00. Scale of points for butter: Flavor 45. grain 25, color 15. salting le of package and packing 5; total 100 Whole milk must be shown in cases containing twelve 1-quart bottles and cream in cases containing twelve 1-pint bottles. The milk and cream will be judged according to the government standard by a representative of the Dairy division. V. S. Department of Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">I it will pay i roportiot ibit 1 an Saturda ■nt n exhibition t li O 1 »• NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 1- This will give city and town dealers in milk and cream an to have their product scored by a competent judge, which any dealer well to take advantage of All pro rata premiums will be divided among entr petition scoring above the minimum of K"&gt; points in p the number of points scored above the minimum. All exl^ be forwarded by express-, charges prepaid, not later ths January 18th. and addressed to E. M. Little. Experim Lincoln. Nebraska All exhibits received will be placed propery cared for and at the close of the meeting return* The butter, milk and cheese exhibit will I building. Nebraska Experiment Station, during the week Agriculture at which time, Tuesday and Wednesday, .ianuar be held the annual i if the Nebraska Dairymen's A Remark Any person n ship fee $1.mi. atioi All session ot th at the Experiment Station. Ample street car facilitit Headquarters of the Da A hotel. For premium lit the butter, milk or cheese exhibit Experiment Station. Lincoln. Nebr For programs or other in ton ing address. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">p rroce mont 11 i t i edmgs of the Twenty-Third Annual Meeting of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association. I to order at »:S« A. M. by President H C. Young, nnual address as follows: PRESIDENTS ADDRESS Members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association. La mblei to hold our (twenty-third) Annual w Nebraska Dairymen's Association. To me it seems we met here one year ago. How many of us fited by tie many good things that were suggested in the xiation one year ago? I sincerely hope if your opportunities, and that the year's n a most profitable one. and that we are all here again knowledge aud to r'iscuss the best methods of terests — the greatest agricultural industry of are to be congratulated upon securing such a and well-postei speakers as are to address ;; and it is up to you, farmers and dairymen, who st, to catch on to the ideas of others and benefit your- ? experiences of those who have made a success in their And I want to impress upon each member of this associa- lake the best ot these meetings, that you must i\ icussion of the different papers that are to be read raid to ask questions, and what you learn in this way ikely to forget will not attempt to tell of the many good things the Nebraska nens Association has accomplished this year, nor will I attempt w the big increase of the dairy products of our state the past Notwithstanding the big business done by the creameries, the s and dairymen could have increased their business easily one - had they had more cows and the right kind of feed, to have a , for instance, full of ensilage to feed during the hot summer when the pastures were short, or any good succulent feed to sup- nt the pasture during July and August. What you want is a &gt;uneh of cows to give a good flow of milk the year around, reat credit should be given the officers of our Association, and allv the committee on Legislation. .Mr. Bassett and Prol. Haecker, </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 atur j un t n u mor I ■ • r ;i as it was surely through their special efforts that our last lesi created a Dairy, Food, and Drug Commission. And the man sumers and especially the producers of dairy products are sur many obligations to our Deputy Commissioner. Mr. Johnson great work he has accomplished in so short a time: and as dair let us always stand ready, to give him our heartiest support building our dairies and improving the conditions of our dairy barns and surroundings. The subject of sanitary milk, sanitary creamerie sanitary barns has received more attention and been commented on through the Press in the past six months than in years befor Dairy Commissioner was appointed. Let the consumers keep u good work, but at the same time bear in mind that the pri Etly first class article in the dairy line produced under tk« tary conditions, demands a better price: and I believe whi de get educated up to it. they will stand for it — a better price 1 good article. I mean Now, gentlemen, we are all in the dairy business to mak money out of it. As you all well know it is too strenuou juBt for our health, and, as successful dairymen, we niu on the lookout for something to improve our herds. We n better sires and better cows. We must buy better bi that they are from deep and rich milking cows. Again, we should congratulate ourselves that we r in our midst one of the best Experiment Stations in the w not make use of it by making year! ow supervision of our state Experiment Station. T we must keep up with the times. ;u w is to keep in close touch with the workin Station and not be afraid to copy after torn there at the "Fountain Head of Dairying." In conclusion. I would like to suggest to ou lutions that they present resoutions ask culture to appoint for our next State Fair a Superint Cattle, a dairyman. And I hope every member of this make it a point to ask his representative on the Board of Ag Kport such a resolution and impress apoa him tl: ■erintendent of dairy cattle. The dairy cattle an of the state are surely of enough importance to have a superintend* for this class. We ought to have a big exhibit State Fair, and we can have it with a good airy mar tendent. I wish to thank the members of our Association for the nor ferred upon me. in electing me president of the Associati tr, and trust that the coming year will be ;■ all. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">T 21 KY )RT OF SECRETARY AND TREASURER The President: — We will now listen to the report of our secretary C. Basse tt REPORT OF TREASURER nd Members of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association: nted the report of the financial transactions of the »• ition for the year 19 Respectfully submitted. S. C. BASSETT, Treasurer. RECEIPTS and $ 39.80 relle U. King, life membership fee 74 annual membership fe?s 174 m* State appropriation State appropriation 4SCM Life membership fees. J. K. Honeywell. J. A. Reedy. Total receipts .' * EXPENDITURES man. expenses attending directors ting A. Clark, expenses, directors meeting 8 and express I.M Frost, services at annuar meeting 1 ".'"&gt; P. F. I'aldwin. services at annual meeting 10.00 raine Follett. typewriting 5.0© Prof. O. Erf. expenses to deliver an address .... &gt;.00 Harris, expenses to deliver an address .... 1 H. G. Van Pelt, expenses to deliver an ■ rle Little, services at annual meeting E. Harnley. services at annual meeting 3.00 C. I). Perrin. services at annual meeting 8.20 C. Bassett, incidental expenses, annual meeting Shelton Clipper, printing programs •.!&amp; J. \V. Brewster. services as stenographer 37.00 Feb. 1 2 •' Whitehead &amp; Hoag Co.. badges 28.00 F. D. Reed, stationery and printing 8.30 Merle Little, services 2.30 1 R A. St. John P. M.. postage from July 25 to Feb. 25 28.1* </seg>
            <seg id="p023">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN ASSOCIATION Mar. 2 " C. A. Clark, expenses as member of eonir 4 A. L. Haecker. freight, telephone and telegra ::i ' S. C. Hassett. salary as .secretary from [ unit;, to March 31, 1907, 4 months at Jan. B. ( I isett, Telephoi \V. L Hunt* F. .In iki B. King R. Rober diet As \V E. Uiven In larr- \V. K Doul \ J. Straw M. A J. K. Anit-r C. A. Bro v Wni. Bre lei E. W. Baiiv Otto Bellows M. R. Bechoi V. B'.air E. Bro J .ek C. Carse Feb. t; Pd. A. \v. Alderman Premiun v.\ Newconib \ I'.rinton C. McXa L. Pra&gt; Culver v.\ A. CraMrm J. C. Coupland T. J. Collins </seg>
            <seg id="p024">V. F F. F H. ( K. F ( TY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION X </seg>
            <seg id="p025">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION 24 J. A. Reedy &gt; B. B. Rice " 1.30 S. Ransom J. C. Root it C. I'. Streitz A. J. Sackschevosky 1.1 (► Cyrus Strayner Roy Stephenson ■&gt; L. B. Sehallenberger Otto Schafer Roy Strawn &gt; Wiloslav Sovboda ('. F. Sjogren K O. \V. Sjogren Roy E. Til den T. Thompson John T. Thompson Thos. Thomps Fred llrirh K. VanderUerR Wni. Wulf Wm. Wulf A. Wayne Wilson A. Wayne Wi ('I. as. NVIing Wling V P. W. W V P. W Wood Rudolph Witt Rudolph Witt Harley Wilson Harlev Wi (Jeo. Tfl Ceo. Yost L. H. Young Mar. 4 " S. ('. Hassett. t»x|ieiis - 1 :i " S. ('. I'assett, ex|v I ' State Journal Co.. Buppltei 111 " Loraine Follett. Typewritir 28 " S. ('. Basset, exin : Express from Lincol Apr. 2o '" T. A. Burkey, mounting dairy ma May It • F. D. Reed, stationery and printir June 8 • Cornell Engraving Co.. halfton r Aug. "0 '• Cornell Engraving Co.. halttonc Phone to York Sep. 28 " Express to York Nov. 2(1 " Wm. Eicke. expenses directors rr Dec. 21 " Honeywell &amp; Reedy, expense co-operative con- . test 15 " R. A. St. John P. M., postage from April lt#7, to December 15, 190 JO 31 " Exchange Bank, exchange on drafts 31 " Express Lowell to York, halftones for report . . .30 Aug. 6 " S. C. Bassett, expense trip to Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p026">25 xpense directors meeting 8.90 tt, incidentals j 50 tt. salary as secretary from April 1 tier 31. 1907, 9 months at $25 and. to balance 67.77 J908.75 that ti itemized report be referred to the igether with the voucher: REPORT OF SKl'RKTARY f the Nebraska Dairyman's Assoeia- 1 an in rtant one to the fairy industry of e work of this association : You will recall .1 i the need of a state dairy com :&lt;&gt; prepare and pretest to the Ie?- na for tack ■ eommtaato* an 1 defiling its , I, as prepared by your committee as prepared by your committee ted into law except that in I of a dairy ■ Fool, Dairy and [tang Commi 1 into law except that in tl of a rtairv Food, Dairy and Drus Conn: l«i n in operation since last .July, a period ration sir.ee last July, a period 1 e commission was ■ new creation ani its officials &gt;n was a new creation and its offkia me h - I an .( llcient and useful work in the future. Mr. deputy commissioner, fa iinitel i airy portion of the law at ti V accomplished an i to ticn of the law at this 1,: '•mlments to the p &gt;n by to t ient ution by (ri-aiii Rate* ('ream Rat id intert-st in the same has not been confine! ta st in tie same has nut been confine! to limitory in that special ■erinUtorjr in that special &gt; certain localities and beeau h discrimi- and because or such discrimi- i irofitable (because ot unfair competition) to es- fitab!. .• ot unfair competition) to es: in August last, the state railway commissi in. August last, the state railway commission. e railway companies that cream rates were too low ilway companies that cream rates were too low si-ion to increase tho rates, gave a hearing to all which hearing a large amount of testimony was n to increase the rates, gave a hearing to all ted. at which hearing a large amount of testimony was the question of rates, cost of service, service ren- resented bearing on the question of rates, cost of service, service ren- atiens: the hearing lasted for several days. aring lasted for several days. he dairy industry of the state as well as of tn rates not only of this state, but of other states, and in this ection proper to state that the members of the Railway </seg>
            <seg id="p027">26 En are to te greatly conn lg manner in which tVis nio^t the eminently lair manscr ' n ce was finally adjusted: at th t&gt;n wl \ci rates established by the Railway Commit :n to meet conditions as the indications are that a number of local creamer will be in operation in the state in the near future and discrimination in the matter of rates a thing of the past </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Quality &lt; I our Dairy I'r. rim t to prevail, that under the cen ry butter, where the cream li | nake a fii article of an inferior grade, sells an inferior grade, sells • the centralized creameries noe the centralized creameries rathe iti\e open ■ 'iment le. Ii: sociaticm. .Mr. El. H. \V. t ■ that tl &gt;r ■ ■ B. lli to butter ' 1 ■ ! !insr with tin To in u that hut jorer utter, in one section of the t better, prices than secured by the te that Nebraska butter. ur cenraiized creameries, commands, in the top price' and is able to win its way in eom- in older dairy sections and under what have conditions of handling and manufacture. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">(ne of the burning questions has been and ! y the creamery companies for cream or more techni K butter fat: While not prepared to C\ dpoint of facts and statistics it tnts olten omit important fea and therefore it is diftic •me basis and therefore it is difficult to compare their - &gt;r conclusions. Mr. Webster, in the a red to. in imiiare nrire paid el i\eraee it aDDears nr hntfpr fat tl'fln far n« Whraskfl r*ai Dresident of the Fairmont Creann . i he has had a quarter of a eentu; c in the dairy i ri&lt;&lt;« Fair for Criiini lal and ttntral rre.i Kw * * I\ &gt; ' l - I \ i i i : &lt; -~ 'ii Kl"f I . Ill 1 ' 1 1 Hit" » *&gt;U . I I I h mor&gt; due • a Idltlonal la ■ and is therefor' Mr. Webster, in Xew Yo-k Prodn. pariM n as I I he i&gt;ii( ea paid creameries and the eo-operstlvi prices paid was made a part of the teatiBMm] lobaitt Railway Commission in the hearing in i cr.ain r of this testimony or comparison it I 1 to me I of the expense of delivery of the cream, on the part of U was not given the full consideration which its importanc with no intention other than a fair discussion of th prices paid for cream, I have herewith included a pared by Mr. J. H. Rushton bearing upon this subject; Mr. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">29 id intimate experience with all the details of and ments of much value in the con- ( . inpiiiriM n as li. Price* l'ai.l la* Mutt, r Fat lii&lt;lu&lt;liii K a iMti for termine the cost of this unit unit from the n. In this journey there tvit t. in the cream form, on his t t of production r, of taking this pound of e point of production to the assembling point? The nay not be the point of manufacture. In nibling point and paint ot manufacture are i the centralized plants the assembling point re are not the same. f a pound of butter fat at the point of A t of the pound of butter fat when all the anufacture have been charged up against it and it is icle we will follow the unit up to the point of manu- !er that in comparing prices paid in various localities, we ion a common ground. Any other system of comparing not on a common basis, will bring about wrong and fallacious the month of July the farmers received for nibling point, all grades and qualities alike. 20c. must Le added the cost of station labor, rent timate.l at 1.5c. per pound. The average cost Tom the assembling point to the point of manufac- Jund. The organization expense in looking after the distribution of cans, establishment of sta- will average .5c per pound. The sum of these items. lore, or L'::.2c. per pound. delivered at point of manufacture on an resents tlie cost, and you have the items of cost in detail attaching to the unit in its journey, delivered at centralir.ed factories in Nebraska in this connection that this estimate is based on deliveries of butter fat by the patron at the assembling point twice a week, which experience, extending over a long period of time, has shown to be above the average number of deliveries of cream made by farmers in the state of Nebraska during the time mentioned, as condi- tions now exist iirh &lt; i&gt;ni|iarri»iiii H. Kushton. f manufacture is a pound of butter 1 butter fat up d on the market? </seg>
            <seg id="p031">NEBRASKA DAIRY.MK.VS For the purpose of comparison «^ will as to wit: and l. r &gt;.:i2c. that his Iowa an 1 Mint at their respective points ol pro In perior conditions, so far as moneta Nebraska farmer over those of Ic basis. In both instances to farr delivery can be materially reduce:! but the extent to which tkta ago i per i&gt;»iin&lt; sota fainur at U r pelM The difference bi </seg>
            <seg id="p032">ONVENTION 31 n, other butterfat. »' a t n was 18 per cent., this would e price paid the farmers per pound butter fat nd that the general average price pail by Nebraska for the year 1908 was Dairy H— Iwrtij at t It;- Xebraaka Rxperimrat Station \ &gt;stion, the most valuable and important contribution ustry of the Mate and to c'airy literature, the past n issued !&gt;:■ 1 tat A. L. Haecker. entitled "Part 1 — Dairy Record for Ten Y Butter Fat Production I citing the pi and Middleton, Orangr larly n. New York, mis an 1 the Elgin an I </seg>
            <seg id="p033">32 This bulletin not only represents a great dt extending over a period of ten years but is iinalua record and history. To those of us who recall t ten years ago, with a few Jersey heifers, :md th development of the dairy herd as well a present proportion*, helpful a source of much pleasure that the utmost harmony and ac and the dairy fortunate tcr Nebr hail the efficient ;&lt;s Prof. A. L. 'tiou Join in ej It l- main 1 and bound with the nex; it 1 aiul bound with the nt seizing it as part of «mr red serving dairy inju&gt;- dairy lndu«tr&gt; that wl station shall be a tource station shall lit being designed to ihow the rrs being w tl tions. in and of thel tions. in and of then is never th&lt; ire to bra.^ka Experlmeat is never th&lt; charges for feed, care and nan state and in this statement as used in demonstrations and in Inatructioi Dairying Pnirv st utisli Complaint is often made tha any stat are not gathered and made public. The w have seemingly, no knowledge of how dim w it is to gather reliable statistics of this kind: when « number of farms in the state, ( r re than farms as well as in the towns ar milk cows, w -i'erei in the sum total, and how diff be to gather all this information, it is seen that am statist &lt;*airy industry are largely guess work, the only foundation wort being considered in the estimate, lor guess i . l&gt;eins the I us returns and the annual report Agriculture, showing the number of milk cows in is an estimate based somewhat on the last pi The growth and development of our dairy in iustry is approximau shown by the increase in the number of milk cows and the output our creameries, it being possible to secure quite accurately the numt of pounds of creamery butter made in the state each year. Herewith is given the number of milk cows in the state ani th number of pounds of creamery butter made for a term of years, thu </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Y t i ii I V a * k pa ii tvork for a The President appointed and I wi Auditing Comr Committee on \&lt;ll;in&lt; . lli&lt; HI T. Rector ady growth and development of the 19 -.."•44 purticularlize as to what measure originated •xiation had been of greatest benefit to the I should, without hesitation, mention the ishment of the department of Dairy Husbandry and the Dairy I'nhers ity, thus making it possible for larger num - the younger generation to take advantage of the &gt; dairying in all its various branches and which is grtat ttnefit to the dairy industry of the state: ht be mentioned that much time and effort were e regents of the university to establish the dairy al years resolutions, to that effect, were alopted tings of the association and on two different oc - apjiointed by the association, visited the dairy de- owa and Wisconsin agricultural colleges, and the mittees together with suggestions and reeommenda - i to the Hoard of Regents with the result that the Husbandry was finally established. Much of this re suitable for presentation two years hence when iportunity and pleasure of celebrating our silver of the organization of the association, a time and I forward to with fond anticipation to some of those who ?ption and who ha\e taken a more or less active part these \ .&gt;:irs. At this time there should be some committee« now announce those appointments. littee: E. M. Little and Wm. Eicke. Nominations: E. W. Frost; John Snedden and E. 0 ml (.!•&lt; will of the Itairyiui-n'- \"&lt;.&lt;iiUiun mid enjoy to and other owtfa in strength and ; this it I tb&lt; uteome (■! inch ■! I, an 1 at the flrst to ask the Improve] stock Bn 8 in session in this city, to tempomritjr aijourn i hall and the attendance of its members in order ■ ■&lt; tably i in point of numbers i number of to a !opt a constitution and by-laws and elect </seg>
            <seg id="p035">It ifR. BASSETT: A r. Presid^n r - 1 r IRK ,- ,. ,. 1 took for i about like :iK tie pe he was goin?. ai;d third. «ia will di\i J e my subject into thl problem by ellmlnatlofl. What Maid ol milk do w« propose to consil We know that from an ndiioint milk an in Committee on Resolutions: A K. Wilki J«»ett of Gibbon. Frof. A. L. Haeeker, of Lin would Ml . iVHEREAS. L. I) into three lieais. Fir^t: V third, how. In discussing the fir esting subject in all </seg>
            <seg id="p036">u 35 it has become a synonim for many f human kindness spoken of. But and men are so much »r. and inasmuch as that arge a flow This i l wa \ \v pro uctiun of milk like every i arm should be place;! upan fan and been a great beef r pearing and farms taking their placet, anl cheap lan^s have become able, farmers are be-inning to rea'.ize that beef production on this high priced land is not profitable. The cow that used to produce a i the range and thereby pay a good profit, does not pay when kept on land worth $75 to $100 per acre. She must do more than that. Her board under the range system cost very little, while now it has become a heavy expense to provide, and she must do nue. this paper will leav \vn by their a. ast ranges and tip low prire at which w that the ranges are so rapiily disap- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">36 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S A^ K'lATION something to pay it. The only thin and too many farmers expect can not When we com. ize tl produces but enough milk to mat readily know that ther capacity of the cow. \V] alent Idea that the row can 1 time, produce milk and n:a time, produce milk discussion! in farm in farn I want to • . ii prodi i far realms of d reali type. The &lt;'air&gt; t type. Tr COmbiMtlOBI of tl e t\&lt; Illty. Men coinl:ina dtsctMSiag other kinds of aninn -ine other k n hear a man who is bn standard bred* with CI3 great draft horse and at the great draft hoi Breeders don't waste time to Breeders don't waste tin French poodle. Hut when it French poodle. Hut when IW8 some how that is different, a some how that is different t some how turn all the feed , some how turn all th chance to have a heifer rail s have a male calf he will entir steer. The results of breeiing alont such lit destroy distinct types and produc but inferior in both. If a farm milk in paying quantities at proflta bred for that purpose. When the bi breed. The matter of breed is unimportant of taste and fancy. The Jersey, the Ho others are dairy type and dairy bred production. Make the choice and stick grow tired of the breed you have and wis get the change by crossing with another br and completely. The first element of succe in milk pr and the second of almost equal importance is r best bred cow of the finest dairy type may bt fault of her own but entirely the fault )W! care and intelligent feeding must go with intellie selection to give the greatest results in milk production. O every farmer and dairyman should keep in mind and that derived from dairy cows like the profits derived fror comes from the surplus feed which they consume bevond j n </seg>
            <seg id="p038">TWENTY-THIRD AXXl'AL CONVENTION 37 are expected to turn their surplus into be«f ced by careful breeding causes them to turn at profitable figures. The dairy cow with the- k production, changes her surplus into milk at u rd division of our subject: How shall we we have it? The president of our association ration of this subject than he has r consi with many other, by location have the matter milk producers do not ani can not live will consume their product in the whole how of my subject becomes important. To ation is unable to dispose of whole milk the er afforrts the best and most profitable mar- rnier whose wife or daughter knows how to make it will always find a profitable in farm. However, not e uce on lighter can make good butter as is shown gathered In almost every village store in tbt&gt; mi IV roduced on the farm into butter try store is neither profitable to i happinecs of the people in the their butter supply. It is not lady who may be otherwise a most make gilt eige butter. Th* and the lady who can niak. appreciate]. It is careful. uultiform duties in: 1&lt;;itional bur.ien of the making of ire. I to bear. In such cases the ich tault has been found with the without doubt has been just, but to the centralized creamerie made a market for cream at e hat unc'er the present system the ain at home his skim milk at its ago there was abroad in our state rom the results of his work had die3 and eans been forgotten. His monuments ry county in the older part of the state intled creamery and a whole lot of farmers dairying. This fellow was the co- ter. He retarded the growth of the dairy iron n our state at least ten years. He is occasionally appearing loubt upon the old theory that suckers are a perennial f harvest is now about ripe. We hope the farmers hi arned wisdom in Nebraska by former bitter experience and will </seg>
            <seg id="p039">38 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION gi\e the c o-cperath e promi favor of it, 6ut the or inui men who iper anytl ing aboi, ry bu operative i and (.ii-aiiiiointment. It community win MR. RYIil It is a roumioi the great institutions truth that our state is out and institution. You will mentioned that the dairy industry industry in this state; yet there now state of Nebraska, any figures or statistics that ran be railed a reliable. It is an old saying that "Fools rush in wr to tread," but your secretary has spoken of the almost impossibility of gathering such statistics. It is a big task, but we are taught that </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Y THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 39 iv 11 in to attempt it as part of the oratng to ask your n who sells cream if I ]&gt; ist e\ery creamery man and n ! am going to try to reach ill tackle the l have one. It what it do. Smith of the Bureau of Animal here, and wishes to say a few words n PROFKSSOR H. R. SMITH: Mr. President and Gentlemen: I that the Department of Animal Husbandry will have a ure bred swine in the pavilion at the noon hour, and that the han Uin?. I r&lt; lent an 1 Gentlemen </seg>
            <seg id="p041">M NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN : adies will serve luncheon and will send ii rom Agricultural Hall. Those who are interested &gt;wine wi vt tale. We will be glad to have all of you on hand at that time. Tli. ■rill only last during the noon hour and | nith a little souvenir. W C'oburn of Kum, and the wi I: i year to do tl is work with. We do not auur nionev in tl V are un aeainst in tl Ronnilv I better statist , m * mvel in every country? 1 think you may think there is only one — the man. farms you have everything that i iry to kind of a man will start a dairy on a f Bl under similar circumstances and ; bs. The right kind of a man will r irough the country and find a mai [ find that he is rather a scrub sort whv I like live stock and dairying i V e: &gt; ai ■ : MR. BASSKTT: I am in r hat Mr. Ryder pn a tremendous task to prepi Ml! Kl.l liner COM • , but they r;r uhhor county 1 on of them on that accoiii W! at is the ereati </seg>
            <seg id="p042">\VK\ Y-THIRD -YEXTIOS 41 i I a rt nor i A ot hMtv«a; men who have taken hold of better than other men have done, ike dairying is because the man who takes and by a wonderful evolution and skill cairy cattle and produces a pound of lie most finished productions that is tan. There are many wonderful things about have not time to talk to you and tell you all through a number of states of America and Dominion of Canada and you will pardon me portions of Canada were a bit better than \e Nebraska the second place. I Applause*, is country. I am compelled to say that condi- not so very much better than in other states. ing conditions to the best of their abiliy. But t 1 make is that when we are keeping dairy ring a product of those cows in the butter, an t takes no fertility from the farm. We talk ink it is better to divide the live stock ciuestion on the (arm and thus save the soil fertility. iners who never think of saving the soil fertility lity from any direction since the world came ■ of years ago. there has been no maintainance of nless it was from the soil. As long as there is there is no possibility of maintainance of that e soil. How very important it is then, to pay matter. More than any other people under the American people have been soil robbers from the Fathers first landed on Plymouth Rock up to the us empire has been expanding westward. The oil depletei behind them. There are abandoned nd states. Hut 1 don't take much stock in that tate of Maine. 1 find they are paying toring the fertility of the soil and they are re - n it. Hut what 1 want to impress upon every man le soil all that is necessary to feed mankind; we i for all that is necessary to clothe and feed our them with the luxuries of life. If there is any erve luxuries, it is the farmer, but how can we e the fertility of the soil intact? Go back to een cultivated for thousands of years. It was. Co back to the British Isl rs that the average grain was a hundred years ago k a word in tavor of statistics. We lag. I pl&lt; itly for the dairy farmer W&gt;- have incr- s of land in the Province </seg>
            <seg id="p043">42 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION i ;e of Ontario more than one hundredfold. How has Simply by intensified farming. I would rather ha under my own supervision than 1 would to have a leased out; rented land becomes more and nior can we keep up the fertility of that soil? We cai crops which seems to be the natural way. an iin thoroughly well-filled with v able mold, win restoring the &gt;oi\, which does it art in sen in natural fertility, and make it n able, am to produce. 1 saw a pi did it by selling turnips ;it in their work in the cornfield las' to have kf;&gt;t the w not w A w liners \V1 I ]&gt; year in tl corn balance away. They will give then a crop and throw the r 1 could get a man at two di one inch of the ground and ; it seven inches from thi man two dollars a day for the ext seven inches of corn-stalk 1 would than the cost of the cutting. Looking over the program I realize that t n in store than what I may have to say and I will therefore t it by saying that when I am in Canada I seldom attend a meeting o this kind where the emblem of our country is not displayed upon th wall. If this meeting were being held in Canada, for instance, am one single American was invited — I am not saying anything becaus textile. In alfalfa bl bicta said t! '.'men that nl </seg>
            <seg id="p044">X 43 aid have the British flag and we would American flag. And is not that the way the With those two flags there is nothing not accomplish. They stand for higher id t'hat war should cease and that the uld prevail. But gentlemen, I am very rishman. You know, an englishman, a talking about their various nation- to the Scotchman. "What would you be ■ Well. " the Scotchman repliei. 'I d I would like to be in all things a Scotchman, be - itcbmaa -&lt; of Mftk; but if 1 could not be i like to be in all things a Scotchman, be- arth: but if 1 could not be t won Kimlishmaii. " So the Scotchman in turn an. It you verc not an Knglishnian, what would n Englishman." So the Scotchman in turn lot an Knglishnian. what would ell," the Englishman said, "I would not be anything aid. "I would not be anything in in the world. If I was not an Englishman I would be i. tin niii "Pat, if you were not If I was not an Knglishman I would be I. "Fat. if you were not An -1 faith." Sail Pat. "If I were And faith." Sail Pat. "If I n. 1 would be ashamed of ro; i Laughter and ap- Laughter and ap- Sl DENT: Tl • a niir prof ir program r Advancement?" by Mr. J. R. \cl\an Mr. J. R vill BO' AIIAT IKMIS TO (Hit \l&gt;\ ■AXCK.MKM Mr. I. R. Rol la an •■plesaaal (■■ iry |)roducts will ■ an tin products will alw.i ■ u ill subiuit thi-ii submit tin • ral jr&lt; vhcn I undertook to ''airy ;. ea«, I ■ doing business in an ofti&lt; e up tOWB. i with book shelv. mighty papers, a largo office chair on wbl up town. I who came in to do business. I to accept a on I and that was ever built. I began in through cracks in the siding. With my ciiat collar turned ap. I would milk n get up and dance to get my feet warm. In the 1 thawed out it was hard to keep my rubber ff when I waded through it. In the hot days of r stench came up from the mire under the floor. I a stron in that old barn than in the house I lived in. nt more hou an unpleasant business under the conditions I have The dairy i fou have all seen enough of it. Here at the State Just described, y Farm the dairy ] produces much more than the most of our herds. </seg>
            <seg id="p045">44 Their product is more acceptable to those wh. To r such a business would be far more pleas-ant. Dairymen would w make such a change. The questi n is: how to g needed improvements. It east* a great deal to keep bar We do not run state institution;: T rnnient wi We must look elsewhere lor the appropriations. If v class dairy we can proem more and it wi If we produce more, the eclw \\ 111 be appropriate we produce better, let the buyer pay. Ha to a creamery ?t the price of strong, pa could have been paid for a number one product n urn, perhaps : RThtn lor the Mk&lt; he ri?iryman of the dairyman's fans consume your product! consume your produc grading qaeatios. Develop ; the only road to a:l\an the only road to a No dairy such No dairy such at tain a dean dairy Tli. tain a clean dl teaching farmer* at the dair teaching farmer thej are to prodw they are to produ careful, intelligent effoi for improvement At Lincol for Improvement. At Lii milk. No matter win that dairy is in. the Bill that dairy is in. the milk who buy that milk at retail, who buy that milk discriminate. There would discriminate. Ther. spectors would grade tl spectors would grade the i grade and worse, there wo grade and worse, there \v&lt; Inspection, if we set enough Inspection, if we get enough troubles. Let inspection re troubles. Let inspection re see through their see through tlu-ir eyes, and mi dition improve. dition improve A PTi \l TKIiNOON SSI \ s THE PRKS1DKXT: W THE PRKSIDENT: W would be more appropriate ; would be more appropriate and listened to have a report from our I) to have a report from our Deputj Da to announce that he is witl on the subject of ■The Wo Mr. .1. W. Johnson THK WOBK OF THi; I».\II{V (OMMISSK .1. W. Johnson, Deputy Food. Dairy and Drue Con \ The Dairy Department about six month! During these few months I information as would </seg>
            <seg id="p046">w v THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 45 ;iiniences. where the cows are 1 this situation nd nn farmers butter is being te. not I ror'essional dairymen, not re centered iu the business, but by farmers oduction of be' lot considered pork and grain products. first, not seconi and not i tie Nebraska farms. The big money for the big corn field, the big grain stacks ittle. The daily contributions of unch of cows is con i small consequence not get the consideration and refoi r. making 1: is I •orn and cattle naniial plans, says to himself. money is the foundation on t build my fortune. The small money from the milk and Jinen folkl &gt;oeries anj household ex- «n ka pc&lt;i. I ixby. tells that the Nebraska farmer can at night Dairymen, of cow fanciers, milk and butter h all tie fire sentiment that gees with an in - ng of the dairy industry, can hardly blame the his broad fields and dreams of his tting to some extent at least the rustling cow. i wl •■!■" a man's treasure is. there will his in and &lt;r.tt!e state the dairy interest is up ition that it is for the present in the rough hands sker and the pork producer and so long as this condition r ry interests will fail to reach that high standard attained Wisconsin and other states where the farmer thinks n field and never "hears the corn growing at night." i nean that the dairy interest in Nebraska is languishing. i i It is nun ing forward right along with the procession. but not in the lead as in some staes, and will never get that fine ninatin attention that it deserves until it drifts, as it ultimately finto the hands of professional dairymen whose interests are ered in that particular busln- There is a demand calling louder and louder for more care. more clean ;md more common honesty in the production of milk and cream. This demand comes from the towns' people who are more an i more sensitive as to the cleanliness of milk and from the butter factories of the state on whom there is a steady pressure for r gxaie butter. Higher grade butter demands higher grade cream and higher grade cream means more care and Quicker Jelivery from •earn producer </seg>
            <seg id="p047">6 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIA 'his demand tor more are In the proc fill, as it seems to me be Bas It i me be answered in due time by the are going out from our State Agricultural College P volve and there is now eve, K a te in the hands of experts In •online here to this State Fan rment of the Pure Food 1 r H«' ha pp*n in «» which the nuhli milk from her rk the butter nrint and him and that holds 1 im subject to criniinl prosec production of milk or cr man who milks tki cares for the milk and w B rami}y. this • ) u re Food lot a wcr*. Bat t I milk anl cream, foul wit! ?s him on the shoulder an for use. That cream has too lone, is unlawful, an o Let me illustrat One of our dair&gt; comine into York with a rai "Let me see your cream" ■ fuots. From e\»&gt;ry farm communl farms tl ej take with tl will trow into hetttT fin enacted bv the I.eeislatim to give them the advanta I ahlfflt] r&gt;run m \ ;i I n . ■ This F»ure K flu' linp all 1 lu- ■■&lt; ndt»r This law ] would feel tl:a people If I could somi in t li n mtmti Tie Nebraska farmer i ntilated stable. Ha ma sanitarv wav. So lone as I </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Y THIRD AXXl'AL COXVEXT1OX 47 anded th farmer 'and what right ha\ .■ in r the Pure Food Law," was the ream wherever I find it m pro\ i to be thoroughly ba 1 &gt;r. and you have no right t t it ame. " said the farmer, "and that nlawful to sell it," reiterated the Inspector, "ani if you prosecution and to a fine of $lo.t»o 1 the farmer, who admitted that his cream was bad, venteen days old. "1 lave not sold it yet offer it for sale." said the inspector. ave net eicn offered it for sale" said the farmer, who at there was a law i the inspector. "It is unlawful for you to have " yoni iin with the intent to sell it. and rest mid prosecution now. even before you have with your rotten cream." threw away the unfit cream, and. commending not before fully understood, promised to take and to not hold it on the farm until ■reafter with unclean hanr's, in a filthy cow to market with rotten cream is a violator of as the druggist who has Hirney's Catarrh Cure butcher who has an attractive looking loaf of in which is mixed unwholesome and unlawful us not yet sold a pound of it roduce for sale, or to sell, or to have for gale mie milk or cream or butter in this state. a time in the history of this Pure Food Law, if it is I hope it will be. when the milk dealer will be t because there is formaldehyde in the milk, not &lt;\ at short measure and not because it is deficient butter tat. but because the cows that produced It kept in a filthy stable and because the man who milkei the cows milk was unclean and unsanitary in his work. )«. if 1 have sufficiently emphasized the commands of the law 'Stablish cleanliness in the production of milk on the farm, let me remind the 17oo cream receiving agents in this state, that B unlawful also for them to be unclean or unsanitary in their hand - of the product as it passes through their hands on its way to the butter factory Any one of th&lt; ream receiving agents is liable to prose- na •ows </seg>
            <seg id="p049">48 ror unfair test that cheats eithf If the banker makM ■ ta or unfair test thai • ither the b&gt;iyi If the banker n:;ihc&gt; a Mae &lt;n try in his ited and cmdMUM riniinal. is prosecuted and ci be as high a standard tor honesty in tl , in the banking liusiness ' \V!;\ sliouhi not the c in the banking business? \\'\ a false test or who enters 01 i ! of tie butter l;it ounti ir Team, why should he i: I anker who I :ti i. s in tatement of tl h but miker who n-a farmer's deposit in the l.ai.k '.' \Vh\ should ;v in tl . Me by t! w jus of tl'i harmful i ■ in col o i li an milk, to \&gt; .it koi k ■ tliat pal life. HODOt] in food or drink, for man Hen to me • ry patii it an 1 hsl • •ry milk and butti until uncleanliin- ration ai driven from our si Now to Ket back to I it re&lt;-ei\ins itatiOBI &lt; n its »ai to the but ■ an' \V1 at about tie count!*] from on Now to Ket back in rwei\ ins ftatit r that houses it in an un\en onions and dried fish ? The tlons at many of these cream r it fair to hold up the farmer on v. the law while the cream buyer counter good cream and then hoi*- w I am talking now for tr right to contaminate this delicat w little expense would provide a clean place where it w Is it honest for the cream recehins; asent who repr factory to lower the value of the commodity by mistreatment while in his possession after he has purchased it with his The creamery managers complain of this Lad treatment ani they havt a right to complain. The odors from cabb;: w cream to the butter factory, on into the butter to lower its value in the market. Who wants to eat butter Hat ore 1 with keresene an fish? They don't allow it in Wisconsin lerate It here in Nebraska" </seg>
            <seg id="p050">THIRD ANNTAL CONVENTION \ 1 49 A \ W. T method i nd at t il&lt;l t u am from the receiving agent to the w again ra the question as to cleanliness lean." Is it sanitary in its construction. employed by this department as inspectors are teAgricultural College. They are experts in the now their business. They ha.e examined the gtaly, reported the facts, and these reports show ith two or three exceptions are constructed rmity to the most approved system of sanitation Uirning out clean butter, honest butter,, honest in st in weight, with the label on each package show- are tt:ere short weight larniers' butter in packages in ughout tre state, where the law has nor but the integrity which the law seeks to ea- ackage is coming and the tricks of adulteration oing out of business. jnlawfullness in the use of the old testing machinery. mil stubborn resistance on the part of many of the their delay in complying with the law which com- r, the weighed sample and the nine inch bottle. accredited experts among the butter makers have by which they undertake to prove that this re - aw as to these approved testing appliances is un- ablish integrity in cream testing. But notwithstanding the law remains, with its commands and it must be ven if it is found necessary to prosecute every cream- Team tester in the state. The old testing methods new methods, the definite and statutory provision must w t a new law into effect. There must be some nee mixed with the force that is applied. While we law we must take time to educate the people as to uires. 1 believe this Pure Food Law should be pushed W lied always with one purpose, to get it into effect with the sible good and the least possible harm to every business interest )uches. I might suggest in this connection that patience with &gt;ut of date methods and the old machinery is on its last legs bout ready to give place to the county prosecutors and the tie six inch bottle and the pipette system may be just as ac - iut the law does not believe it. The law condemns the old and commands the new method and the new appliances and the ies of the State who are demanding cleanliness on the farms he receiving stations, as they have a right to under the law, how themselves lawful and not wait for prosecution to force iting equipments into use. a word about short weight butter packages. The short </seg>
            <seg id="p051">EBRASKA DAIRYM! eight butter package without a label is unlawful and dishone? jod nianv farmers throughout the state have been putting u el awiui randed 14 ounce butter packages and these haw been retailed rocerv store and charged for as pound*. It is unlawful. Th ood Law commands the butter i ) show its net weisht bv the lab Eiow its net weight by the label. This law m ell as creanierv butter. "Make the butter pack me ?r where it conies from. ' That i i .* ne*.. .... nlawfulnt' \ 1 , * • ». „ — 1 i f t U- II III' 1 ., n# * Vi II i mi i « a.' mm , I. .. * „ N'ebras! feel as I do, that \ * imtiHoitv 1 1\ nit [1 be not considered first in ini uver wrongs ■ * HlHlIUlu one thought must be kept in mind ri dairy business and that is that the various departments of the bu ■ must stand together and co-operate with each other for the p «»ral good of the common CMM which is aniard of da x&gt;d many farmers throughout the state ■anded 14 ounce butter packages and the* II do not charge that this ers Careful investieatioi 1 1 1 ■ 1 1 ..»- 11-1. mi.t ani I. .&gt;..., «,, 1... I, »-., i , , ] . ,, I n i i I until u-*a ran triifbfllll in the hearts of ou an1 cream production out on the be in testing crfani at the receiv ing there may be. if any. on the hntter nnrl whatever laws may I wrongs, and whate\er friction nun i laws and from the natural com petit exist between the nrodueers of crea </seg>
            <seg id="p052">NTY THIRD AXXTAL CONVENTION 51 \I&gt;VA\ I.U.I t of Xel rasl- by reason of a f been able to fore No doubt thi t. accurate and definite system by which the uet is measured. and the butter factory are yoked together me team. They may pull apart, as in ;iay be jealous of the other as to which is ion of the load, but they cannot break away ng each other out of bu&gt;- ed with applause, and the motion was made iriiitiou tender Mr. Johnson its pleige and ping him to carry out the law a\e just issued a bulletin. Number One i in due time, which was publishei la be printed on heavy cardboard to be place i in ation in the state. It contains the rule under sting must be done. I have consulted with il other experts that I have been able to talk with 'tin. and tl.e dairy inspectors, and all who are k will be expected to observe it in all cream-testing ng to make the people religious in establishing a n ition all over the state and we believe it So being advise 1 by these experts I have and regulations an 1 they will be sent out to i posted up so that every tarmer can figure uhl he teste;! AMI IISA1&gt;V.\NTA(;KS OF CKXTKAI.IZM» CKKAMKItlKS. A. E. Wilkinson the question of co-operative ani centralized r t &gt;il. Men who are recognized author- work, have been driven into the discu- The drift of all this would indicate a desire on the lace the centralized creamery system in bai repute er and the public in general. Claims are made that Nebraska and Kansas where the centralized creamery vail, the cream producer has suffered in consequence r&lt;rn ira J e to use the dairy and creamery industry nresota as an example, claiming that the farmers ire lar-ely patrons of local co-operative creameries. tter price for their butter fat than have the tarniers aie patrcnizing the centralized creameries. laimei that the centralized creameries pf Nebraska, avorable transportation rate on cream shipments, have e the local co-operative creamery out of business, is agitation prompted t e officials of the Nebraska State </seg>
            <seg id="p053">52 NEBRASKA DAIRYMKVS r lit from i-braska lackin ality of Dairy Association in requesting this paper on th&gt; vantages of co-operative and centralize:! cream. honor and opportunity affor ntins th I will endeavor to show th conditions have been ami still are the conditions in \ and braska who are patronizint - higher a\eraee price for their cr* p origin of this agitation in Nebraska - how they c&lt; Minn, centralizers receive w sota — that we have hal boi operati-e crt I due to the a.herse natural con people towarJ fair? tot that th tariii' irgel) cattle specially bred for lairyin in Nebraska that y en account of a lack he axerape bn • i am rat N I voluntarily encouraging the in initry whl to the lai I I H'OUld t &gt;r industry th agitation is unwarrante 1 and n id if cont work a hardship an.i gi - thereby directly injurinj. creainery work. r w About a began a campaign to alxanc t would amount to forty or fifty in effect and had beea for nior .:airy agents for th- in their behalf, public men who are c creamery work, and secured t before railway commissions ask in claiming that the centralized systen t and dairy industry and unless a !\ar would mean practically the annihilation system. It is not my desire to speak disparagingly o this move. 1 am satisfied, however, the avera whenever a question arises affecting the public and the rai railroads are usually aiming to take care of their own int we very seldom find public officials, either state or national. VI ing assistance in favor of the railroads, against the public, an or an industry. I regret that I am unable to secure official dairy and ci statistics covering the industry in the early days of our state, b investigation and observation we find the first dairying in X was in making butter on the farm. Having no facilities and knowledge of the art, our farmers produced a very poor (|u butter. This butter was taken to the stores an 1 a chandise. the price averaging from six to twelve r^n: le ( eniran; ■ . e as ream than is Ml 1 the |&gt;atr ■ ns an I the cisinclicat </seg>
            <seg id="p054">\VKNTY-TH1RI&gt; ANNIAL CONVENTION 53 IV I A nd, w \ r ■ went into various communities in the state and induced i business men to subscribe for a sufficient amount of al co-operative creamery. I know of no better way • or not this was a wise move on the part of those • money in these local co-operative creameries, state of Nebraska i the natural advantages for the support and maintenance of these [uote Henry Wallace of Des Moines. Iowa, a man will agree has always been a true friend to the is of all of our states and a very valuable tatirn is taken from a speech ma-'e by him before nen's Association at Fremont. Nebraska, in De - ubject was. "Mistakes of Iowa Dairymen": a mistake ten or fifteen years ago in pushing our ahance of tame pasture. Profitable dairying re - - season possible and the greatest variety of ■It many of these creameries brought into existance became sickly, weak, unprofitable and perished, leav- in the mind of the farmer that dairying was an un- I ence rendering it more difficult to establish the conditions for profitable dairying appeared. a mistake in organizing creameries in advance mery farmers. Few men who are not trained to milk are young, will learn after they are full grown. They Jt have to and they will not until driven to it by financial made the mistake of paying too much for our cream - were Davis and Rankined; slick fellows these. They telling the truth as to the possible and actual yield of ted cows, but telling it in such a way as to make it an by assuming that these were average, instead of any good farmer could secure these yields, and 'ured with any kind of feed and care. They did ey left it to be inferred. They deceived the found a rough steer or two among the farmers heir pen. They induced the management of means of large advertising contracts, to put th of the editor, as I happen to know from exper tor of the then great agricultural newspaper of lese promoters and their imitators carried on t a path of creamery desolation: "Sick-Sisters" Davis &amp; Rankined creameries in Iowa. We suspect isters in Nebraska also. In every business the promoter ur h before the same convention, on page 151 of the following to say in part: )ur friend. Professor H;.&lt; a. has told us what loremor Hoard </seg>
            <seg id="p055">arity only to cot rvice to M corn to speak of up there. It is little, thin corn. I corn state but they can grow marvelous fields of gra an atmosphere that is a luxury to breathe, and wat I clear as crystal, with bri you cannot make butte i's earth. Not being ab butter making, and pet m. 3k trc ing dov tl ann in this mat for the tFMDorta pared with otl i product, also the la Ie: it also seems that th licable to all parts of the i blishment of creameries i ht so desire. This would to all parties interestei your commission has no :i D i. In deter right, power or author connection therewith whether the proposed rate w establishment of local creameries or be prejudicial to the inters centralized creameries, and that you have the authority only to con- •ider and determine as to what is a reasonable rate for tt Fe here he would tell us what wonderful things dairying ha- that state. The problem up there was altogether a different matte rom what you have in Nebraska. Why.' Hecausp they cannot ero </seg>
            <seg id="p056">iVV •:.\TV-THIRD ANNUAL CO.VVEXTIO.V 55 i ng. In otr airyiug and on al creamery a re extensively considerably reduc less remunerative t i of this question through the press many need which are hardly warranted by the facts industry and possibly a brief statement of the state at this time might be of benefit in arriving ig of the matter. While the dairy industry i - ir most valuable resources, it is carried on at ;ie on our farms: that is. on the principal source of revenue or looked upon as the nsidered in the farm management us returns, on only mis out of a trifle over 2 per cent., was dairy I revenue. In Iowa the per cent of like han three t '■',), in Minnesota six (•), and in • Nebraska farm contains 246 air*' "ill, with an average of four (4i milch co.&gt; a table of figures showing the average in Nebraska as compared with Av. No. Acres per Cow SI with a sufficient number it the dairymen or pal .iiid often twice each day. the whol* thus insuring the butter comma' Bcient number of dairy cows to i ( d to a creamery from a much ;i whole milk, yet past conditions have ins in that respect are not much ■w localities in this state where there is ng distance for teams, to make the »pw» - )fitable. It is claimed that an increa the establishment of local creameries. This, work; conditions in a dairy way must very before we can have many local creameries, strictly ?r words, a larger per cent of farmers must engage a more extensive scale than at present, to make such success. Nebraska farmers are not likely to engage in dairying until the average size of our farms is red or until the prices for grain and live stock are than at present. f Minnesota and Iowa a it is hardly possible to ■ 'd pro. in </seg>
            <seg id="p057">CKHRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION n reply to the question, 'Are present conditio i 'an be said that considering the condition of the daii id itate at this time; that our dairies are small and very much hat we have more than 30,000 hand separators whic i lairymen to produce a very condensed quality of cream shipped long distances to a factory, and that iairying is ssue on our farms ■in* i ait K ■ ate tan In rrpa mprioi In comi.arinj »vell to consider varying \V k; uses a hand n u station the cream is hauled home. Tl of milk I the proi reivine station and 1 that the one whi labor and is to mud ("onsiderabl time we had about 146 acliiiK many persona to infei is measured by the number a marked shrinkage in our dairy industr in the method of nianufaci if at anv time there van of the number were all ii &gt;1 year, and of those in operation not 80 per ce mem - of creamery ■iii system of promotion, at points where th for creameii. there was not a sufficient nu cows to insure their sui &gt;&gt;1 such plants can be fovind in scons ol busini state — a complete financial 1 i While dairying is not ;i states less favored in fertilit it can be tillei and abundant a ■tended bv the inc Birds tn dairyman »h &gt; a dav :it 1 honif Thp forn has been and still is ■ srowi </seg>
            <seg id="p058">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 57 t illustrated by comparison for a term of 1900 't.'i 512. .144 669,334 11,726,180 21,646,279 aska's past and present condition perfectly. es in Nebraska failed and it was not the fault act their failure was completed before the creamery system of our state. However, the erative creameries furnished some valuable ex - lizers in teaching them that owing to the disin- toward dairying, the general breed of cows nstead of dairying, also owing to the short ■ would never be a large volume of milk pro - munities, especially not a sufficient volume to &gt;r the manufacture of butter i? Nebraska suffered seriously from drought and Many people left the state believing that it wu em to remain here, build up home and prosper. The ng that unless dairying or some other means was our farmers could get some profit from their land more would leave thereby causing as great a loss »s to any other interest in the state, and they therefore me movers in the inauguration of what is known as the kimming station plan, voluntarily putting cream rates industry, and no favoritism whatever was an central creameries were erected at points where l »re favorable with lines reaching out through and skimming stations were erected in communities where favorable for the production of milk. These tations were inexpensive as compared with the local creamery fully nanufacture of butter. The object was to furnish a market to the tarmers for their butter fat without the expense of man muring the butter in each community, the saving of which enable the creamerymen to operate on a less volume and to wouh pay the producer a higher price. By bringing the cream from these stations to one central plant the whole butter making process vario under the supervision of an expert buttermaker, thereby making came it possible to produce a more uniform quality of butter which could be marketed much more advantageously. In 1900 and 1901 we found some of the conditions that had favored dairying under this plan, changed. The farmers were raising better crops and realizing higher prices for their grain, hogs and cattle. 890 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">iTION n n ur tion m u k ii NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIA More of their time was naturally taken up with ffork. They then began to complain, claiming »as consumed in hauling milk to the skimming st£ hat the skim milk when returned to the farm wi to their calves successfully, and that the calv&lt; valuable to be injured in this manner. The profits luring the past three or four years from their c other additional profits trom their farn crop conditions, made them more independent lit. and n of milking cows if they could possibly avoid it. tl tinue furnishing milk unless these nhjertional In fact a large number did quit. Many maintenance, found their shrinkage in U ate the station longer would mean a loss. This condit ter and financial ruin sta the industry from the fate farmers would overcome V onment ot the skimming loss on the investment in had laid the stem. in their purpose. Ther of their patrons and tl the introduction and sweet, which furnish a ■at stimulus to the da It not only kept th at were milkini into the fold practically all of the back new converts. In addition to this it enabled t! men to go into communities that had producing sufficient product t fact today, on this plan, the cen' a market to communities that c of butter fat in one yea From the standpoin Of gel in this way than by buildint particular places and leavins our state without a market. This is whv the crean N wonderful growth since the ad The volume is drawn fro creanierymen can treat eve heretofore had received a sufficient volum Krai that the creanierymen who ha:i in oney in erertins plants and in labor 1 i tlat the h By this plan the farn fired to deliver his cream to I week in warm weather and t« This proved a great stimulus </seg>
            <seg id="p060">WENTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 59 it i t -nier. though the only one in the neighborhood sel - enent of the competition of all centralizers within high a price for his cream as if he lived each of them. The plan must certainly have been farmers, otherwise we would not continue to en.io*- It can well be called the system that does most people, which certainly makes it more than a system that would benefit only a f"\v ave had in the past ten years dea'in&lt; uers of Nebraska who are producing milk, I am it le induced to go back to the whole milk syst«n:. - the tanners of Nebraska consider that with the ■boat by delivering the cream but twice to three t in volume to one-tenth of the whole milk, toget. er that derive from having warm, sweet milk to feer on are realizing a greater average net profit for their but*°r armers of any other state in the Union .and further inclusively shown by the following figures: e reports received by the Minnesota State Department of ■d that there were I I pounds of creamery butter imount paid to the patrons was $13,774,422. Allowing ;e overrun was 18 per cent., this would show that the paid the farmers per pound butter fat was .181c. I neral average price paid by the centralized creamerymen ear 1906 was ,194c. per pound butter fat. When rtion that at least r, o per cent, of Nebraska's vol- iroduced from May Itth to August loth, a period when ire at the lowest point, it makes this a wonderful i see where it gives an opportunity for anyone who rhe prices that the centralize! creamerymen i Nebraska or to make the claim that the farni - ct-iving a better average price for their cream ners of Nebraska. It may be true that in some particular Minnesota where an extremely large volume of milk is i co-operafive creamery in that community is un.-kr nt, a higher price is paid than these averages show, ; to arrive at the general results and determine Nebraska in general, we cannot take for a basU at isions some particular community in either state vored mprecedented prosperity that our farmers they have not only maintained our volume o e increased it, which is further proof that we are that are profitable and satisfactory to ;he </seg>
            <seg id="p061">60 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCIATION braska State Dairy Association report for 1898, wherein I fin of the Leaders" taken from "Cow Culture" by the Honorable F. D Coburn, secretary of the Kansas State Board of Agricultur whi reads as follows It is desider by its author to present in this report t modern thought of the men who are now and have been for n giving closest study, combined with practice, to all mat connected with {"airyin? and dairy stock hi t ore. managers, cr proprietors. Forty-two ciuestinns were carefu formulated with a view to ha\ing them cover th which general information sec inn l ie ! or importan I will whifh. in but opini r)priate in i The first question is WITH A GOOD i R&lt; WITH A GOOD I ROHAHILITY OF THKIR HAV FICir.NT NUMBER OF COWS. Udil.I) YOI RECO! FK'lr.NT NT.MHKR OF FARMERS OF A GIVEN COMMUNITY TO ORGANIZE A FARMERS OF A GIVEN CO NITY TO ORGANIZE AN •"OR HITTKR OR CHEES A CO-OPERATIVE FACTORY FOR HITTER OR I A CO-OPKRAT1VK FACTORY OF ENCOURAGING PARTIES WHO WOULD BUT Tl OF ENCOURAGING PART WHO WOCU) MIY T CREAM OR WHO EXPECTED TO MANUFACTURE FO EX-QOVERKOR hoards answer "That w altogether a question &lt;&gt;f men. Any coininunii CREAM OR WHO EXPECTE EX-GOVERNOR HOARD AMF 'That will depend alti It is altogether a &lt;r they will they will.' HKNRY WAI. LACK S replj "When the co-oper»tlvi HENRY WAl.l.Ai I "When the co-operative aged in a business-like way. it i^ ry JAMES WILSON, protVssnr of agricultui • aged in a business-like \\a JAMES WILSON, prc periment Station. r«&lt; operation elucates in business and itair on the kind of peoi H. D. GIRLER. of Illin Dairying, answers the queatloi in "The essential point is t matter much whether it is &lt; r know of individual creameries that tak * Ing butter and then net their patr the same qualit yof milk, than co-operative competitors that make tl butter for cost. There is no business in which inexperience mak« x greater losses than in the creamery and m of trained and reliable men for this work is short. Mil and cheese are perishable products: hence, constant vigilan sary to success." H. M. BANDT, creamery operator and president Kat at Dairy Association, states: I have yet to see the first successful purely cooper run by farmers. Co-operation must exist on either plan .1 would be obtained." </seg>
            <seg id="p062">TWENTY-THIRD ANNIAL CONVENTION 61 GEORGE MORGAN, dairyman, and ex-president Kansas State Association, rep In nine cases out of ten it has resulted in failure. Exper ■oved that it is always best to put the business into the hands cal manager who is financially interested in the enterpri NISSLEY. ex-eecretary Kansas State Dairy- Association, re- low mend proprietary ownership." (1 EYETH, factory operator and ex-prestdent Kansas State ation. states: amery business is carried on on business prin- \VI nd indhidual ownership preferable; however, sonu co- successful and satisfactory." the opinions of men in the successful eastern as well as Kansas, and from their unbiasei lapMfi mast conclusion that the success of the co-operative system In nd Kansas is at least \ery questionable. ET question propounded is as follows: your observation are factories conducted on the co-operative profitable and more satisfactory to patrons than those under lependent ownership which either buy milk or cream out- it on the customer's account? Hoard's reply is a community is intelligent enough to know whether tr«d or not. there is no better method than the proprle- When they take charge of their own business they must judgment on t'.ieir part Wilson well but if co-operative 'it. whole- much of his time for nothin Kansas, replies &gt;ri\ate ownership is paying the farmers from 1 more for butter in Kansas. A conservative an make the farmers most money AN, dairyman and ex-presi'ent Kansas Dairy is to say of his observation in Kansas: unagement is necessary under either system. As rftier has not given dairying much attention and nnot run the business successfully. Purely co - -1 ul. involves a better knowledge of the tails than will be found in tl ■» average community in Kansas Another question propounded: X^'hat is the smallest number of aily milk supply tjj/at will justify the building and »s or a tion of a creamer EX-GOVKRNOR HOARD state will take SM cows supplying I«M to 6000 pounds of milk, to expenses and leave any profit on the investment." </seg>
            <seg id="p063">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION- 62 A r n nt met r »■ I he dairy ir would 1 will sav tha JAMES H. WILSON states "There should be 10,0(10 pounds of milk daily tt creamery outfit." JOHN MATHIESON. ex-president Minnesota Da .states Hoard's Dairyman has placed the number at small enough. I think GEORGE MORGAN, of Kan^ "Five hundred to Son co Thus we have the unbiased opinion of most men in Wisconsin. Minnesota. Iowa and Kansas. Th eastern states where they have special dairy c&lt;&gt; pasturage which enables them to keep up a good volun the greater portion of the year, it requires trom furnish a sufficient volume of milk creamery, how many of our cows in Nebraska, that for beef purposes instead of dairying, would necessary volume of milk to suoc co-operative creamery throug t agement is at hand? .Mr. ,\ ii Having five to ten cow or cream four, five or six than attempt working it at me w EX-GOVERNOR HOARD "I would think not: he had better ini cow "Yes, but carry cream rather than m the more expensive and disadvantage JOHN GOULD, of Ohio, dairyman ar "No. It takes him all the tin along the road." In my estimation this last question w apply to the conditions of Nebraska; not only ter the present time, and the opinions given by ; em conclusively that it is impossible to operate local co-ope eries successfully to any extent in Nebraska, especial consider that the average number of cows in our dairies w four or five, and owing to the sparsely settled condition portion of our state, it would not only require the haulin distance of 5 or 6 miles, but in the western parts where etry has proven of the greatest value to our farmers, it aul of from S to 15 mil' In summing ud this Question from iuv ooint of view I each system has its place, its advantages an 1 disai\anta centainly conservative The next question i HENRY K. ALVORD. Washlngt. viBion, V. S. Dept. of Agriculture. rej </seg>
            <seg id="p064">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 63 jperative creamery system, so far as th* state has been developed, has proven Yet I don't think their wonderful growth or the system as it is to the inclination of the thI the natural advantages they possess. Its fortune lie In the uncertainty of contluel ir patrons, proper management, and thtfr retailer thereby dealing as close also the possible future economic demand of whole milk system in favor of the hand ystem in Nebraska has been a success wonderful growth of the industry in our stale because it meets the requirements of our untry. Its disadvantages lie solely in the ition is liable to work and the fact that the business in the various communities will no radical creameryman to deal directly with the a on as high a degree of educational work with would lik I have nothing but praise to extend to our friends ta and Wisconsin. I congratulate them on the success attained. I am sure if they thoroughly understood the con- ska, as they exist, they would reciprocate to the extent f congratulating us on our success under entirely aiverse and different would advise our people to stand by the centralizers east until such time as they can honestly find that the proprietary amerymen have not treated them fairly or that they an do no better for themsehes. Then when we meet in a national con- mi to one another the glad hand of fellowship, feel- ngaged in a work that carries with it the highest eat industry and one that is contributing largely to the states: we shall then spend the valuable time conventions discussing means of building to greater ather than in controversy that only tears down. Nebraska State Dairy Association and the dairy :1 interest, we can congratulate ourselves on the progress we have made Some very valuable features have appeared. ar Through the efforts of this association, combined with the creamerymen and dairy interests of our state, our last legislature recognized the value of the dairy industry in enacting dairy laws that provide the necessary regulation and the creation of a Deputy Food ft Dairy Com- nee missioner with inspectors. While the deputy commissioner and his in- spectors have been engaged in the work only a few months, they are to be congratulated on the success they have attained. It is the duty of every creameryman and dairyman of Nebraska to as- sist our state deputy dairy commissioner and his inspectors In every way possible to carry on this good work. Mistakes, no doubt. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">64 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION men to en t met amerymar in n ilking them. ' animal. In norning will have crept into our work, caused largely by the fierce competition that we are experiencing, but with the present dairy laws to regulate any abuses that may exist, and with careful and conscientious force them, we are justified in expecting a great improvement during t year 1908. I While Nebraska at present may not have the distinction of beir greatest dairy state in the I'nion. I feel that we stand second i in our school and experimental station of dairy husbandry, whe the young men of our farms can come and learn corre&lt; dairying and creamery work, and it is the duty of every crt our state to encourage this branch of education in our it means the sowing of seed that some day will We failed so far to find cows that we cannot milk. \V cows good milkers. We have very little trouble in r They have well-balanced udders and they are a very gentl • this respect Jerseys seem to be better than Holstein State Farm. Lincoln. Nebraska. January THE PRESIDENT: The first order of exercise this ban. THE PRKSIPKNT: According to our program, the hour of 4 o'clock having arrived we will now have a demonstration of the milking machine with the workings of the machine explained by Mr. Hawker. At this time two dairy cows were brought into the pavilion and the milking machine attached and milking done in the p if the convention. During the demonstration I lowing qu&lt; Q. Don't you think that another year you m resul- A. Yes. and I think alon« that line we ran d&lt; and educate them to the use of the machine. We had ■ jroi last year milked by the machine and she BM producing in all something like three humored pounds of t&gt;«1 calved at a year and ten not We took the call away and at once milked with the mac! Understand we are doing this milkll Bevum re. The sound that you hear is the pi tQ. How can you tell when you are through milking with this hine? A. In the first place you can &lt;• no milk in the udder. In the second plao that then milk flowing into the can. It does not hurt for i&gt; milking. Q. Suppose you have a kicking cow A. Of course, the machine does not stand in the stall. Y milk a kicking cow with the machine easier than you can with the bands; should it become unjointed, it can be hooked up again. general rule, however, cows do not kick with the milking machine. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 65 MR. I \ v ainoun for the last two years r this A toward uni Auditing Committee M. LITTLE: Mr. President: Your committee appointed nts of the treasurer, beg leave to submit the following r committee, find the accounts of the treasurer to be correct nditures in every instance made for the greatest good of E. M. Little. \VM. EICKE. Committee. report of Auditing Committee was adopted and the nks to you all. I would say at this time also that ry man. I feel that the best interests of the cream - &gt;rved to the best interests of the dairy industry. Whatever work 1 can do in filling the office of president I will do for the dairy industry. I feel that this association baa a t* is in a position to do the dairy industry a great nee an this state. I think the creamery men of the state ood ir ars have been so busy trying to get cream that per- otten the influence and the benefits and the value of ave for ation. but the influence of the Association has been great ving all those in the business pt here a year ago and asked this Association to take some tee discharged. tet IE PRESIDENT: The report of the committee on nominations in order. R. FROST: Mr. President and Gentlemen: We. the under- comniittee beg lea\e to report the following nominations for of our association: • A. E. Wilkinson. Lincoln. (('-[resident. .John Sneddon, Eagl&gt; ■cretary-Treasurer. S. C. Bassett. Gibbon. jr Direuors. H. C. Young, A. L. Haecker. E. T. Rector, E. \V Hanna. h E. W. FROST. JOHN SNEDDON. K. T. RECTOR. Committee. R. LITTLE: .Mr. President: 1 move that the report of the on nominations be accepted and that the persons named declared the duly elected officers of the Association for the g year and the committee discharged. he motion can; R. WILKINSON (president elect I : Mr. President and Gen- i: 1 am certainly very grateful for this honor you have shown : that the Association has very much need of strong men, iBCneace would le of greater value to it than mine; but ! am not before you to dictate, but will say that I accept </seg>
            <seg id="p067">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 66 e t&gt;n in regard to the passage of a dairy law by the legislature and as through the influence of this Association largely that we secured law, which I believe is going to be of great benefit to the industry, paper that was presented here yesterday by our Dairy Conimis - err, Mr. Johnson, is certainly a fine one. We reel that we can go now and have a law, administered by a fair and conscientious Dairy imissioner, to back us up and to enforce the rules and regulations are needed. As far as I am concerned, it will be my aim to work ork as closely as possible with this Commissioner and for the greatest good of the Association and the industry plause.) in general. 1 thank A ■ THE PRESIDENT: The next Committee on Resoluti* jn our program is tt KMR. ItASSETT: Mr. President leave to submit the followin Your Committee on Rt RESOLVED: The dairymen - ;i congrat I he state upon the marked progn past year, and we heartily end&lt; •nactiiiK the Pure Food law. pas H-tion thereunder of an energe ler, Hon. J. \V. Johnson, and I anoe in enforcing wise and effic urork an improvement of the qu the development of that most lorse the educational work he rageously carrying on. made in the dairy in action of tT i by that bo:!y: we a ■ Food, Dairy and D t ps and regu Nebraska d; rtant indus RESOLVED: We congratulate n r"ess and development. WHEREAS: Realizing th ■ agriculture in our public schools arm of the state, RESOLVED: That we note with interest a E. J. Burkett has introduced in the Senate of the I'nited providing for recognition and asistance by the gen the teaching of agriculture in state normal sci endorse and approve the same RESOLVED: That we commend the action of the memt the State Railway Commission in their investigation •am and final adjustment of the same, and feel that considering the d interests involved, the rates established are for the best interest dairy industry of the state as a whole RESOLVED: ' We deprecate the uncalled for attempt and unwar ranted attacks being made upon our industry in the attempt to array he excellent work it is doing in the education of Nebri tot alone in the art of dairy husbandry, lint in the ■&lt; iisseminated throughout the state by its professors, by &lt; nd by institute work, and we hereby pledge to cordia rith the University in the work of the future makii&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p068">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL, CONVENTION 67 &lt; meries against centralized creameries, and declare our iple that there shall be given equal opportunity li and encouragement to each, with special privileges to none. Our motto iiild up and not tear down v ESOLVKD: We are unalterably opposed to any increase in rates •ream and dairy products by common carriers. re. recognizing that in the end every increase tn he producer of cream and invitably tend to the ig or destroying of the dairy industry industry. OLVED: That the refusal of transportation companies to 1»- am cans is a discrimination against the dairy in- ind injurious to its effects. E OLVED: We trongly favor the passagee of the bill pending i by Senator Fulton of Oregon, providing that no e transportation of products be changed without being first given and opportunity for all parties in interest to nd we respectfully ask our Senators and Members of )ill their support KRKAS: For long years past in live stock parade at the state breeds has been given prominence and distinction by &gt;osition at the head of the cattle portion of live stock LVED: That we respectfully request of the Board of Mana- ming state fair, to the recognized dairy breeds be id distinction LVED: That we recommend to the Board of Managers of Agriculture, Mr. B. If. Little as Superintendent of ? next state fair were read by the secretary and on motion duly pted as read PRESIDENT: We will now proceed with the regular pro- xt paper will treat of "Home Dairying and Supplying Private Customers." by Mr. John Sneddon. NEDDO \ lent and Gentlemen of the Convention: I have been so ilding and other work heretofore mapped out, I have repare a very elaborate paper. My first experience in dairying was when I was a boy. As the began to realize what there was to be gained by milk- *■ cow and 1 stuck right to it. and I'm happy to say that today &gt; uld not have chosen a better occupation, that is, that would be suitable to me. nor one that would bring better returns for the and labor expended on it. In regard to the kind of stock I 1 out with common cows and afterward we thought to improve our herd by purchasing a short-horn bull. We continued to cross with the short-horn until 1892 — I started in 1882. Afterwards I secured Holstein bull and from the half-blood secured some very good cattle. I doubt not but what some good strains can be obtained with half- </seg>
            <seg id="p069">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION- 68 ins and the anie. unt ing the pu xperier not t to pick ou r 1 xten :ill n by , fls. But we continued to use and improve tbe Holste ? Holstein blood we got into the herd, the better they b&lt; lecided to use tbe thoroughbred. So we have been usi stock for about ten years now. From my limited t Id recommend to any one starting in the dairy busi to start with any common stock or half-breeds, but strain that you like and stick to it. There is notliin; ting with one kind and then switching off to something In the subject assigned me I cannot give vei perience becaue I did not have the advantage of a dairy schoo was nothing of that kind that 1 could avail myself of. Ic school a person can gain in the short time of three nioiitl what it took me years to learn. 1 think the prospects and the dairy business are greatly benefited by attendant school. I would say however, that in looking for ■CM I would try hard to please my customers to the best ot I believe that it is a good thing to cater to your eustoii you can get a higher class of patronage. If somt of tl ■ have a little more salt than others, and still others would 1 their butter not .-■ usual. And in many ways ] i K &lt; tomers can be catered to. much to your profit. If you i Q. You aay you make butter. What kind of a LA. We have a one-hundred-gallon churn and run ne. We also run our separator with this same powt Q. How do you keep the cream cool in summer tin LA. We have a galvanized iron tank off in a littlf h water running around the tank. Q. Do you use ice? A. Yes, sir; we put up our own ice right kind of butter you can secure tt;e t-xira p£ gentlemen, that 1 cannot say \er&gt; much along new or useful to the mon i h&lt;1 men there are any question would lit to try and answer them. IQ. What do you t- A. We feed alfalfa while it luU. 1 bu and I erected a silo. 1 beliew it will be a grt We feed alfalfa and ground corn and oai IQ. What kind of silo ciid you build? A. Well, it was a home-made affair and extent. I had the lumber man send for In grooved and tongued. It is 2n teet in t!i;t IQ. How many cows do you k&lt; • A. We have 20 now. I erecte.l a barn f Q. Do you keep a record? A. I have just commenced this fall to do Q. Do you test the milk? A. Yes, 8ir. </seg>
            <seg id="p070">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 69 Wt I ou do for hot water? W put in hot water plants yet but intend to do so r nee any difficulty with the smell of the gasoline x k and butter? .V No. we have not had any difficulty yet. The gasoline engine and it is boxed up pretty tight with plenty of air ou put the butter up in for market anrl wrap it up in paper. an your utensils? hum we first take luke warm water and wash in we take and icald the churn. Then we cool steam end to put in a steam boiler soon l like your po» engine I think is pretty good power. We have ny trouble with the engine getting out of repair n a room off by itst-lf ferable to have it in a room by itself. at do vou consider the best feed? calves, some corn and alfalfa hay; some bran. To ei with alfalfa, ground corn, a little bran and oil unds of butter a week do you average? to the first of January, our average was 98 ■;r number of cows including heifers we milked a mar mnier was is. We milked all summer and the everage num- milking machine? nilk by hand. We feed a good many of the You don't keep any record of the amount of butter churned lp does it require to handle your business? w M myself and one hired man last summer and we ran A ■it a four-hundred- acre farm and milked that number of cows. jurs a day did you work? Q H w man the summer time I generally worked about twenty. (Laugh- A Ir arse, a part of that time I was busy with another branch Of rk not connected with the dairy businei of w Have you any boys? Q A Do vou pxiiept to k£€p ttios^* bovs oil the? fsrm 1 Q A </seg>
            <seg id="p071">70 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCI ATION a Q. Well, do you expect them to work twentv hour A. No, sir, nor my hired man either. Q. Do you use a starter for your cream? A. Xo, sir, I have never tried to use any start Q. Do you churn every L'4 or 4 s hour: A. Forty-eight hours. Q. How do you ripen your cream A. That part of the business is left to my w butter-maker on the farm and she attends to the crea separating is done. I have not paid very much attention of the business ■ Q. Does your wif A. She puts the c work. p do the churning': ream in the churn and the Q. Do you use a butter worker A We have Ju Q. DO you salt the butU A. Yes, sir. Q. How much salt d A- W quar n Q. How many dairy cows lk A. I think from twelve to fifteen ei man could profitably hand Q Well. 1 mean how many cows could he har whole time A. I never Rave that question ver n part of his time, I think he can handle f n right. I don't say that that number will take Q. What is your average pi A. We secure 25c. a pound I of Lincoln, and it is imp' Q. Do you use coloring? A. Yes. but very little coloring in their butter and we don Q. Do you have any complair A. Yes, a little. Q. What is the complaint" A. Some people want a great de 8o much. We have one customer in -alty. He uses about two pounds a week. O any coloring and want a good deal of in I have found that it has paid me because it did not take much extra tim Q. What means have you to det ne when enough to churn? c A. I have not paid much atten </seg>
            <seg id="p072">w NTY-THIRD AXXIAL CONVENTION 71 A i A 1 Tt n't k a r Local ( \ .VINKJF CONDITION'S VK&lt; i e I a The success gives the produc consideral I way of determining the amount of moisture t tried anything in that way. but my wife works r it is washed and salted in the churn it is I I don't think there has been any complaint of moisture in it. the butter once or twice anger of over-working the butter? &gt;elieve by over-working the butter you spoil the ny much attention to the moisture in the butter? iod deal. ■arator do you consider the best? had experience with two, the American and the American was a continual source of expense. It a year for expens you tell when you have washed butter enough? now exactly how you would tell but my wife is par - butter and could tell. q. What do yarn pay out for repairs on your United States sep- aid out a cent so far. and have used it a little PRESIDENT: We have another number on our program it treats of Conditions Necessary for Success in Es- reameries " by J. O. Winkjer. of the Dairy Division, ulture. and .Mr. Winkjer will now address you. •:i{ Ladies and Gentlemen KSSAKY FDIC SUCCESS IN KSTA HUSHING LOCAL CKKAMKKIKS .Mr. J. G. Winkjer le subject of organizing a local creamery, I want ation the local co-operative creamery, for the re»- established it serves the interest of the dairyman letter than any other system we have at the present of any system is measured by the net return it rs of the raw material. From this fact radiate all rding the development of the dairy industry. In cost of transforming the raw material into umption must be deducted from the proceeds. In operative creamery when the cost of production Is </seg>
            <seg id="p073">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 72 deducted, the remainder forms the net returns to the dairymar any other method he receives only part of this remainder, for the ott part must go as profit to the owners. In the case of the co-opt Lit creamery, the dairyman gets the biggest stimulus for producin raw material. Furthermore this stimulus is intensified by the fac that if he, with his fellow producers, increases the suppl material to the factory by producing more himself and nrtucin neighbors to produce more, or in any other way reduc tl transforming the law material into butter, he knows that returns will be increase 1 accordingly. Then also, if I ai management, he can Improve the quality so as t&gt; for the butter, he knows too that the returns to him w Thus it is thaf he gets Interested in his neighbor and in him. and an interest anil enthusiasm in the w the cooperative creamery at the head of the list. The creamery in order to niak as near as possible to the plan rake the &gt;:■ ablisliiim a eo-epet carefully taken into ■ the organization. When a few fan to raise sufficient niont solicits shares and when the cream actual interest in it. and tin ing together that is given tl the company The ad Woe of the outfit should be carefully sifted. Or laws of the state, sell all tl hand, go to work in a busin. a hard task sometimes to sell all tt work, but this part has to be do: time, and if it right time, it gives a vim to the bu right results. It is generally ct rged promoter that he takes too much for what he gives in retur is only a small matter compared with the set back if not entirt ture given the dairy business in that and other localities that hear o conditions. Get your information from a state creamery inspector dairy professor or dairy commissioner, or from the national dairj Kision at Washington, or if you have access to several real sue. perative creameries, get information as to what course they have followed to attain their success. It would also be well to see conditions where a creamery has not been a success and avoid the things that have made it unsuccessful. The state and federal employees in the dairy work have seen all these conditions and are able to guide you to </seg>
            <seg id="p074">TWENTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 73 e information in a paper, short or long, that in organizing a local creamery. Each lo- Take. for instance, the question of how urting a co-operative creamery. Suppose an average record of 300tb of butterfat take G &lt; • &lt; &gt; cows if they averaged only 1001b the chances are that they would not do as &gt; the 200. It is quite safe, however, to start long to share holders. Then again it depends on mers are that take part. There are cases where inn cows and made a success and on the other r.iHi cows and made a failure. There must be ncy in every community where a co-opera- rted. I have not yet seen a co-operative creamery id a shorter or longer period of difficulty of opera- nd it is imperative for each community to have ie necessity of staying by the organization and *!&gt; the benefits which are sure to come. tion of officers is an important part of the organization. the confidence of the community. Se- wl 3d presiding officer and has a keen who is a Get a man for secretary who is straight in rrect account and is amiable and accomodating atrons. The secretary is next in importance aking a creamery successful. The directors ■et at regular meetings and dutifully perform retary and treasurer, not as a mark of dis- nianagenient that will give the Every substantial business con- busint eral men interestel. always have their officers industry is too important to deviate from good ake any chances on results. There are instances on account of a dishonest official anding vacant to that community alone but as far as the fail - etinies ignorantly and sometimes maliciously inted out as an example that the farmers cannot run their own business. It is much easier to work &gt;rmtiT« creamery in a locality where nothing has there has been a failure: but even in a case where a failure, the scatters i forces can be gathered and a suc- built up the organization of a local cream - roduce the same result. If poor poor or an entire failure, and If used, there can be no other than are used, the results are E substantial results that will build up a good dairy industry, the dation for all agricultural pursuits. There are no uncertainties wiU the same rause will always | ood, substantial, tried methods ar </seg>
            <seg id="p075">DISCl'SSH Ee question coining n I &gt; as to tl amery. Mr. Klliott gal hundred cows making butter fat per MR. W INKJET in the nort into hut that product upon and when this Ian farmers shall have as man binatinn miuine tin- lam whole liusii work for their own siki MR ROBKRT.S: Wher produre the average mention \ here in this neighborhood and pounds ot butter a year. 1 have a herd that is doing it. A can do it. The main thinn is t right kind of care, and it is not local or centralized creameries. I thir the cream in good condition. If it is What I was KettiiiK at was . row s tn stui ' ■ ry « Ill tl &gt;■ ll Another poll a price tlmt would bring tatiim. Hut when w </seg>
            <seg id="p076">RD ANNUAL CONVENTION «&lt;t what his cream is worth, ave the best quality of cream price. r, after many ye;t: owth of the private dairies as thirty-five years, is, I think the centralized creamery is in a -&gt;Iieve w an be main- w ta of our &gt;n. In nt will and or fifteen You would fall down tin:- n we look carefully to it. of the bu- in and price an i five it a (tin will so ws what they n men or experienc i aniery will be in ago up in Minnesota, but that the farmers cannot agree. I Mr. Ashburn, how long since K \SIURX: About fifteen years &gt;ns in as n"od shape fifteen years ago as now \ emember in what respect they were different from rhaps it would be wrong to say that they were in the now. The situation up there is. or was, that the larger plant was trying to get hold of the whole territory and the uny Inisi- teratlve creaniery in a iirnatf creamery an:l put Mr. Smith one another anil the s nuiniim at ;i Now t: t; and tirin - I it. an 1 not fail. As Mr. ;anize with men having contilenre in lize with a sooj management. nient is coDceraei, it might tiusinf </seg>
            <seg id="p077">76 I small plant or co-operative creamery « tartir cause of the success of the co-operative creamer r man. It was due to one man who was there on t got them on the right track. If you want any the place to have them is where they can b&gt; Mlilil no question in my mind but what the co-op* ati system that builds up the dairy industry better than at There is no system that tends to unite the farmei tends to unify and drive away jealousy inste; each other and where you have these condit dairy industry Q. What do. to man u fact u r co-operative creamt n A. I think a pound by t) Q. About how i ruiery man u fan t A Ahout :;in Q. Docs youi A l! 11 I in Mm patron ti i &gt; to be slii|i|i»- 1 1 10 in t whicl l(j(al an ( r— IB is not t lie 1. K knoi .ition tl'ii-. and i they ( (iiild si |p ii We us.' 1 a little ( of cr&lt; l.a|ie from (,i aroun.l hei I tl ink that deliver tl'e (ream t the cream was weighed and reamery. All the cream can it was into the creamery by shipping on the cars. And is it not ■ r Plied by rail, it is hauled a long d A. Yes; and there is alvantai: generally want their cans returned poor. In this way. the farmer d&lt; reek and usually has only a short distant Q. You are ipeaklmg about the hand A. Yes. the hand separator system. Q. Are you speaking about the 1 ami years ago? A. No. I am speaking of tl years ago. as it was then It is thr*t </seg>
            <seg id="p078">NTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 77 I R WIN r id wood with w h about I £7, tern there at the present time with great J ai in ing to preserve the cream :ny mind that the best thing for the dairy - centralized system, that it would make w aper and I tried the shipment of cream in a id a creamery. We started out with the shipping found out that the shipment of cream was a detri- of good dairy butter. as good cream here as you would there? i start a co-operative creamery in this state and run it am satisfied that you will have as good cream here ma there I Minnesota I. K.IKR: In a refrigerator car it would be just as good i a long distance or over night, as if it were hauled by nary distance. The cans that we put the cream in are with a piece of ice in them. I have not seen it done nk cream shipped in refrigerator cars for three hun - ;i be equal to the usual hauling it over the country cream by wagon. NT: If there are any further questions now to be i Inns the line of the feeding of dairy cows, we now tr partition his silo so as to use one-half of the the other half at another time? Is it a round silo? proper size for a practical silo? OTT: 1 would recommend that the dimensions of the rteen feet. The deeper you have the silo I ■. all things considered. At all vents, it must always be han large. I think fourteen feet is about the a\&gt; rdinary farmer. On account of shrinkage. I would rec - en hoops instead of iron ones, and that the silo be built MM iron expands and the wooden hoops would shrink with the staves and there would be less d.in«?er of the silo falling to ooden hoops. I vould therefore recommend v.-ooien Hjxfi inches, and each stave nailed to each hoop. deep would you go down w as you wish. I have seen silos go down so that they </seg>
            <seg id="p079">7- Bvater in them. I think it a better plan not t" go dim n lk you can go higher better. With the facilities thai days, you can raise the silage up and then it Is ■ it off the silo. Five or six feet down is all right. Q. How da A. i Voice ) How do you climb down to throw the silage up? ■Q. If the silci was built too deep, would there be any d orming as it sometimes does in deep v. ■ -. that prieip in this silo busines: A. I don't think that holds good in Q. ! storms A. MR. ; K'S'oti i- silo must bi think it shrink cm MR. WILKINSON: Mr. Prc si '. nt: Williams. 1 am pleased to such an interest In our work. 1 would move you nvited to speak to us. There being loud calls [or Mr. Will! ■ Mr. President and Gentlemen: I Id !&gt;.• instructive to yen. The onlj thil it wit ■. to ii a sun;: </seg>
            <seg id="p080">79 If the other m- iiitn sure they would express the *• nothing about the dairy business *o cows and milked them &gt;n me after awhile that very great tiding about the business of dairying. farmers did not pay them thought that this -an to find out that book business r that nun should study in connection i to take up the study ot book I might say that I was prac- 'iish to pay innection with farming: that not try to put any of my foolishness i "Let Na- 1 followed their advice. I would . ■ pt to I ii this Railroad Com- be matter of at e'lual jus- it tli. We si all do all w« ■n ricultur- aii to make ■men. tt- with Xa- 1 and ttu f r. a sit thi Hut if the sreat mas mins about the reign ng that my work will « in our agricultural college. It inak te trying to fit themselve ii iid farming instead of run- is nothing nicer to me </seg>
            <seg id="p081">80 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION than to see these young men here learning how to take care of the far and run it upon a more intelligent basis. They arc nir things that will contribute to the wellfare of the w world. (Applause i Adjourned till l:St Afternoon BeMtMh ( \Ve&lt;lne&gt;«la.v. ) THE PRESIDENT: This afternoon we will ti THE PRESIDENT: This afternoon we » "Co-operative Test of Milk Cows at Nebraska Expel Co-operative Test of Milk Cows at Nebraska Kx iner ft. E. M. Little. Mr. President. Ladies and (ientlenien : This e co-operative dairy cow contest that ha^ Mr. E. If. Little Mr. President. Ladies and Gentlemen: This is a report the co-operative dairy cow contest n ing the past year. During the meeting at the pavilior ing the past year. During the meeting at the year ago. we had seven cows that entere 1 ii year ago. we had seven cows that eiit test for one year at a time. These cows w&lt; test for one year at a time. Thes. were pla&lt; Erf at that time and were given a place in the conte Erf at that time and were given a place in the contest by th&lt; of the Dairyni' .iation according to their r; of the Dairymen V ion according to their rank with Professor Erb's placement. That placement settled with Professor Erbs placement. That placement I and the cows were let t here for one year, that and the cows were lett here for one year, that is. i ago. or until their lactation period closed We kei ago. or until their lactation period closed. We k of these animals. not only as to milk produced, but of these animals. not only as to milk produced, but w milk at each milking and ascertained the butterfat coi milk at each milking and ascertained the butterfat contained in the and from that record we lia\e prepared an exhibit of t and from that record we have prepared an exhibit ductlon; and their feeding record has been kept t ductlon; and their feeding record has been kept tra&lt; possible. On account of hav possible. On account of having to feed our alfalfa i ni lot, we were unable to keep a record of it but w*&lt; lot. we were unable to ke proximation of it. We have during the winter. fe&lt; proximation of it. We I for each pound of live weight, a for each pound of live weight, and have figured in ration according to that. I have placed the entire record on cl ration according to that. 1 have placed tli. front of you. The history of Mteh cow is on one we take up the chart part ol animate completed theii one became sick. She had a other was a short-horn cow that did t so she was returned to her own formulated until a month befo last Association meeting herf best cows from over the state: neither d chance to send their best animals, but tn&lt; herd that had freshened since tt freshen at that time. The Co-operative Dairy Cow Test. B. M. Littlf DurlD* the first two week! of January, 1907, seven milk cows w assembled at the Nebraska Experiment Station as entrees in the dair cow tost conducted jrirtly by the Nebraska Dairymei. tatlon and the Rxperiment Station. A committee appointed by the dairymen's association drew up a </seg>
            <seg id="p082">w N.TY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 81 ,v bra Kx r 1 t ■ copy of which is appended. This bject of the test and the value that is to be i collected to those interested in dairying. ed there were four Jerseys, two Holsteins and rt-horn. Their names and history are as follows: Holstein, seven years, one month .-suian. Omaha, contributor. Holstein, six years, 1 month and twenty days, ributor Quincetta 171839. Jersey, five years, six months and ten well &amp; ReeJy. Lincoln, contributor. Ann Kinlock 196444. Jersey, five years, five months and Woodlawn. contributor. Fern Pogi- four years, ten months and seven Young. Lincoln, contributor. 3 of Londondale 36th Shorthorn, three years, ten days, iraf. contributor. Lincoln, 199890, Jersey, one year, ten months and seven Nebraska, contributor At the time of the dairymen's association meetings in January. Oscar Erf, of Kansas, passed upon these cows and judging from tandpoint of the work they could be made to do in the year d them in this order: First, Matina; second, Julia; third, Pedras; i. Marguarite; fifth. Fern Pogis; sixth, Liddie Lincoln; seventh. The plan of the test was not formulated until a month before the opened. January l. 190 7, and consequently no special selecting or the test could be done. The contributors sent ani- ■nls that would come the nearest to satisfying the ah in the governing rules without regard to the make in the class the co-operative dairy cow test conducted In e Nebraska Dairymen's Association and the Station h reliable data to breeders and dairymen of the ■ raetical application of the milking machine on ms of the state and all unaccustomed to such a Iking; also to furin - of cows that can be used in t and at the end of the year to compare the of this class; to show in a practical way the ivell bred dairy animals in the dairy, and also such information p brought out by the test. Rule I. — The test to be conducted under the auspices of the Ne - ka Dairymen's Association and the dairy department of the t-rlnu'nt Station and under the direct supervision of the committee in named, sui-ti committee being authorized to provide all needed and regulations governing the test and to solicit cows for the •st from breeders. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">82 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Rule II. — That seven cows be assenil four Jerseys, two Holsteins. and one milki - be loaiiHj by tlie different lir. . for one year, when the rims with their cal Rule III. - That th. six weeks w ny effe&lt; « i !■»&gt; U at U as follows: &gt;h the br&lt; KRule IV. Tha ughout tl .1 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">HIRD ANXIAL CONVENTION 83 i. the rows were gradually put onto me manner Dec. U'. Ian. 11, Julia and Marguar- </seg>
            <seg id="p085">.4 x'EBRASKA DAIRTMKI CIA1 »ith the exception of alfalfa hay. was w t i ,-lind an 1 ■ :hese weights entered on the herd records. Alfalfa wi he mangers and yard racks lal could not be determine!. A reasonabl upon the Experiment Station upuu me experiment Station 1107-8 leeding trials was ma- Fhese trials show that, on an average, everv cow in the he srage. every cow in tl besides other roughage, one and on-fourth p Hundred pounds liveweight during tl V the amount of hay charged to each anim following table shows Hi nt of each foodstuff with the number of months on pas &gt;i.v«; Kij-dkip VAMK — » H, M. ('♦■ The second while the roughage and i ii)i columns. I'edro fresl tively more of the ex Iri crowded during an a milking period Name First Weight Last W*i*h ■tie 114( ro Ml Mariruarite 115c ■»i; Each weight given here is the average of two di ifferent made a week apart. The difference between the firs iuaue it ween apart. i nc difference between the first weight and last weight represents the gain made during the milking period. the case of all five cows this weight was quite uniforn bran. corn, oatfeed. lion in the class. .lulij Pedro is not charged wl Kflow and their individual d hts of the cows at the beginni Liddia 68" juii» m </seg>
            <seg id="p086">TY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION M e money value of the food stuffs consumed lnlform schedule of prices. It is impossible representing the markets all over the state ai &gt;rs that influence food values in different com- i as taken which considers, as nearly a: tuffs at Lincoln. Nebr.. during the time ol Ton ie value of products, i. e. butter and soli.is not mate is more representative than the Uersity. tor during the winter the pro irice. Tl:e following table shows the by tlie different cow \ Veil Me •&gt;.« t ■ mjm 0- ' Ci his table the total cost of food is shown. st producer, also consumed the greatest amount of &gt;6.«8. Li Idia, the smallest cow In nting to north of feed which is but little more than half ict the cost of total concentrates shows that \\s show a food ranging between these extremes. tes is the main item however in every case, being of pasture and roughage together. The r the class was $4L'.4",. Cnier western conditions ils as this class contained, the cost of food may when the time of freshening i sconsidered together KHistuffs contained in the ration., the cost appeals The cows were charged with food only during the •Mey were in lactation and not for a calendar year. &gt;' Louis Exposition are employed as a basi itter at ISe. pr pound and soli Is not uriiiK the summer it was retailed as ticallr three times as much as Liddias. The </seg>
            <seg id="p087">■ RASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION it with : IIIlll harges we ha\ ■ llullt IB t tl it 1-I\l\t\'i1 It , vfiutii' stiwL* _» kai .. • animals « i the 1 I without delav to show in tl * rows shows a nroilucticn ( the coHt of food amounting truly a pood performuni e ami He w\ . In determining the pro ■ply deducted from 1 » -j 1 1 . . tii \ 'i 1 ii •■ t \&lt; i ■ luhnr nr Hire-Ill- a profit of on I \*f.) vi i :i r»&gt; so ne:i r !s would 1 a\ e mate! Tl.is is Ih siniiilH bil Of the N' results arp not i » 1 tnoimn under eood rare and jnaiu butter and 639.4 pound- </seg>
            <seg id="p088">VENT'S THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION -: jws honest care can duplicate it. imber on our program is an ad- r of Iowa Agricultural College I'r nt iiiul Gentlemen of the Conven - uare to address you today. One ir and found you to be appreciative tan !- -bowel intelli- ■ion tl -'xi brought on ■ it' mint!. I will hurri lly that I brongl i.o were not b&lt; t tim» - remember ol speaking; of tht&gt; • -us. that is. turning the co» mind. 1 will hurridly it that tini . it'll I &gt;mber ot speaking of th t Is, turn ins tl e the time for her to freshen. This her to freshes. llll she should :i bran an I mi bran an I &lt;■ apparatus in proper eonditi apparatus in r conditioi ome Mesh and itreDStk an! &gt;n and Letter heart an.l naturally ih&lt; i larger Mow of milk, and ■ if her milk will bi -t six or eight - its greatest growth, anr] t!u iw of milk, and her milk will be tl st six or eiglit rt lid the ■ tall tin- best start in life. We must ill tile be tart in life. We must t it be used by the cow for the pro - ill he gi\en up to the proilur- Then in regard to the time when the cow for the pn ut should 1 ven up to the produc- n in arl to the time when t say during three or tour days prior to that iring three or tour days prior to that the cow should recelTe small houl I small &gt;\v ran mash is better than any other. with two pounds of grounl o tter than any other iran of ground oats and up with warn water makes a very lax ttive in its mi si cooling and b should be taken into consideration at this re and management which the after she freshens, depends \ con neglected, as far as feed and care are con- a ng the first thirty days can never be brought up to the termines what her record will be. )(&gt;W motherhood is greater during the t tion than during any other period. I think rcibly on the charts of the cow contest by n in w that had freshened here on the ground her surrounding and had care at the time, while some I two or thr&gt; before coming here. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">.EBRASKA DAIRYMKN : am satisfied that has some bearing. (i ;ix weeks before the cow freshens and to in this i he period when she does fresh&lt; i and thirty he first thirty days of lactation le digestiv s during the remainder of the la hirty days in different w «s ha\e been fed so that the: »ere increased rapidly, putting them on iow one that was nut on li after having given the brai Thpn inp lit production am Uv tl'n wav Tti:lt H T tit t-jLn it fur i , Tl'.- Ho. Ki i ft t-i i ii in ■\ fi.^ * M t nf Iho 1 full How of mi!l. von a fart to tali in tie statin:- ration will nrnili would five pounds; Din &lt;T**:». The first reason i&gt; milk with a gradual increai duction. I think a rapid lac change whether an increa: of the feed is always the best. The second reason is tha need thirty days instead of tei t and the third reason is that &gt;u a her feed. During the first thirt off her feed you cannot get her bac ment until her next period of lactation, a get a cow to the limit of her ability she al mm satisfied that has some bearing. So tl at in iroduction of milk, I am satisfied that the best ti is during the remainder of the lactation period. Foi tf &gt;ther reasons, we should be very careful regarding the nia »e supply the teed. I have exprimented personally du ler ralvine. Never have I know] nine to produc oats a riav. weiuhini durtion tl . is not tMioimh to niaV </seg>
            <seg id="p090">89 as two limits. One is the limit of her ability, the ability which w as to produce milk, and the other is the limit of her capacity. There is a difference between the two. If you feed a cow up to the limit of her ability, she ia giving you ail the milk she can. will affect the digestive apparatus and this will isefullness. There comes a time when the cow la he can. If you increase it. she fails to respond. So king a at the best possible way is to increase the feed slowly am sat radually, and in small amounts. Over-feeJing will take away ijlitv in milk production. ■us in a weak and emaciated condition when she calves. ly you must give a feed that will give some fat. such as silage and so forth, so that she can take on enough flesh and na to work with, so that she can work persistently; and remember a certain amount of flesh upon the cow's body is absolutely She must have strength and power or else she cannot make w of milk. Take it in your own experience with a cow of Iry type. If she freshens in good fleshy condition, she will nt and an excellent milk-producer during her whole period tation. Professor Little just gave you an example of that kind. ' does not freshen in good condition, she has not the power or keep up her flow of milk during the year, and consequently f her time is taken up in idleness. nk this covers, in a general way, that which I spoke to you ir. I want now to talk to you a little farther on the feeding giving more attention to the economy of feeding. There lifferent classes of feeders. The first class belong in a greater the breeders of pure-bred cattle, who feed for large records l the records add value to the offspring. This class of breeders 'or results. They furnish feed to their animals that they know oduce the greatest amount of milk and butter fat. They do it es at great expense, not caring so much for the expense as they the making a record, because the record itself without a consid- eration of the cost stands for results. There is one objection besides se to this method of feeding; in many cases a cow coming out with e record, unless the feeder has been very careful in his operations, ured to a great extent and her ability both as to milk pro- duction and producing offspring. We have a second class of feeders that go to the other extreme. In their effort to secure large profits, they do not provide the feed that the cow should receive. In too many cases we find feeders attempting to produce milk and butter with dairy cows with only the feed which is raised on the farm. In our state the results would be worse than here because we raise largely corn, so that over there we have for feed largely corn and timothy hay. This class of feeders neither produce milk nor do business at a profit, because they do not take into con- sideration the commercial end of their business. To be successful in feeding dairy cattle, there are three points </seg>
            <seg id="p091">90 h, wi t x :l who. u i r Elch absolutely must be considered, either two of wt third will not bring the greatest success. They are pra I business methods. We have the practical man who ce has learned to feed cows. As a rule he makes qui Fhe does not if he does not incorporat iness principles. And then we have takes into consideration the best of some science and the scientific mat practical methods f l We have known bankers to go into the dairy cow business and many instances they have founj banking ni we have the man who is absolutely srientifi. methods. He has two of the thr He takes into consideration large This is the kind of busing lect a ration for cows one should roods are available and what tht he has upon his own farm to I the alfalfa hay tl raise it. It is al hardly know how alfalfa hay ami ■ Ks at your &lt;i roduce milk M to these, th know that alfalfa and silage contain products in conjunction deal of nutriment which tl and butter fat. It is then rations. In alfalfa you hydrates. In alfalfa you ha culent feed, and all that protein and some carlx foods. In selecting foods, tl He should know feed stuffs as know their composition and th&lt; we have marked upon tl in that sack or box. so tha stuff is composed of. He should practically a waste of your own Knowing the composition' .nri tibility of foods and the pric« to know or figure out what the which of the foods is the most economical. Take cottonseed mea which Is a source of protein, it contain r cent, d If we were looking for protein it would be better for us to use cotton seed meal at the same or slightly greater cost per ton than to buv brai «t per ton than to buy bra with a digestible composition of KM' ] per cent, protein. We will look immunity. It is not diffic which food is indigestible. Wha </seg>
            <seg id="p092">91 w ■D milk att amount of protein that we would get out of one nl. Further, in buying bran at $25 a ton, we 5 for the same amount of protein that we would cotton seed meal at the present cost of $30.00 a conditions that must be taken into account tical effects of these foods upon an animal. ?rous to feed in any greater amount than two and in using that feed in larger amounts we had we find certain kinds of feeds laxative in their are directly opposite. Oil meal and bran are Kestive appartus, while the cotton seed meal is who has alfalfa hay and no corn silage. In that •blem. He has nearly all the pretein he de - 3. cow at the rate of 2 0 pounds of alfalfa hay ng a large supply of protein. It would be foolish he market to buy more protein for that cow. f us do because a certain feed that we can buy am sure there is a mistake. If we have all the protein we need and should go on the market and buy cotton tein. oil meal, rich in protein, we would be doing come a long ways from balancing up our rations What we want is carbo-hydrate to balance that pro- ?orn meal and hominy chops, a food rich in car - ther hand, if we have silage and no alfalfa. If we ther food rich in carbo-hydrates simply be - ce the cow begins to get fat and our results lilure. In the dairy business people have dlf - and no man can stand up and say what they awing what feeds are available and what they ry simple thing to learn how to select feeds. food which you think is cheapest, determine otein there is in it and divide the cost by the e got the cost of one pound. Take every food M to, divide the cost by the digestible pro - r pound of protein in every feed you have matter. There is not a child in the fifth figure it out. For carbo-hydrates divide the •bo-hydrates in the same manner and you have his nutrient. In this manner you can ftnd out ? the cheapest carbo-hydrates are: where the cheapest proteins are hen combine them from their cheapest source and you have a ra - hat is economical and one which will produce the best results in and butter fat production. Gentlemen, I thank you for your kind ntion. (Applause Q. What do you think of alfalfa hay and corn ground In the cob DISCUSSION </seg>
            <seg id="p093">92 as a ration? A. You have a very good ration in that combination, and prot one of the best rations. Personally. I would make some exceptions t it for the reason that when we buy a cow we look for a big body an lots of capacity. We want them because we know that sixt of the capacity of the cow is used up in maintaining her body when we get capacity and utilize it with corn ground up with in tible corn cobs, the space we have tried so hard to get is no to best advantage. I do not know but what I can as feed for steers, a pound of corn cob meal with corn meal. F months the steer has corn and grass and goes to the shan dairy cow a loager period of usefullnt Q. Should the corn lie shelled and dry ground ? A. Yes. under one condition and that is pro thing else to take the place ot the corn cob A. Yes. Ifj plan in feeding :tt St. Louis w for large resul&gt; place chopped alfalfa hay in with n . the w to cool: Then we inix.-&lt; same result as though w ment and nutriment satisfied that t make the ration lot mix it with ground f( 1 will tell vou why wt Whatever I - of digestion - cate her food, but when st her cud which is nothing mot viously swallowed. If you £i her stomach in a heavy mass and w never regurgitates and she has no chanc U the digestive juice that chang n regurgitates food that proces never Q. Would you consider it tat each milking? A. Yes, sir; certainly Q. And would you weigh her food and milk A. Yes. especially for the first thirty days w statement broader than that, I am satisfi a •ry cow's feed every day in the year. Then you ar In the position of a business man. How long would I arry on his business without business methods? Where would he be insid of thirty days If he allowed his clerks to do as they wanted t Suppose he did not check up his deposits every d;, ivould nat urally be out of business in less than a month. It pays to work with buslnes methods. It costs you more, If you knew milk those old cows that you have than it pays. You exi &lt; worth </seg>
            <seg id="p094">NTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 93 0 worth of return. If you would do ing of each cow's milk each time you would find nding around that are .not doing much for you. so each time to weigh this milk, but you wtll try time. It will not take very much time to would not take two minutes per cow per day to d: and if you had a pair of spring balance scales take but a minute to weigh each individual cow's business, to know what each cow eats and what You would soon find out that you have several of those ng around not paying for themsel feeding alfalta hay would you feed bran? not. If 1 had a cutter. 1 would cut up the alfalfa on was if you were feeding alfalfa hay and corn cob ?d bran? ion't believe I would, but instead of buying bran I er and run hay through and mix with the feed to rtion would you feed cut up alfalfa »-o to three pounds at every feeding. The best way ad it out on the barn floor and pour warm water on and you will flnd a sweet aroma coming from in bran u people want more than anything else in hen you have succulent feed and material for With the silo and alfalfa in conjunction you t cow feeds in the country. I know of dairymen Iowa and buying alfalfa at good price and taking ik with their silage. You have all the feed nec- rn stov and digestible matter. While corn irotein in conjunction with corn silage and alfalfa t think for a minute of using it as a substitute for either. Vhat about feeding ear corn? A for you to grind that corn than for the cow to You must Lear in mind the fact that the cow makes her milk e digests her food when she is resting, and for that reason we )uld give the cow all the rest we can; and her feed should be ground in the finest possible shape and then she gets along better ani her di- •' apparatus does not have a lot of matter it cannot handle. (Ap- ■ 1 THE PRKSIDEXT. Last but not least on our program is a trip by ex-presiclent, Henry C. Glissman, and we will now hear </seg>
            <seg id="p095">94 } i i. I" ban to I got dered from bim as to "What a Dairyman saw in Europe." (Stenograi port.) MR. GLISSMAN: Mr. President and Gentlemen. Som fall I promised our secretary that I would prepare him an it under the heading "What I saw in Europe," and I started tw times but found it considerable of an effort. I will try it way to tell you some things I not interest me and it is rather It had been my desire for started out one morning and t Did my father that I was going York and if I felt inclined. I would continue my journ v It was in the spring of the ye which is a very pleas ,1 abroad. When I landed in N€ York 1 tound no roon A response to my telegram for room. When I land* ;i I realized for the first time that I did not know where I tu looked big to me — people going ry direction on the elevated cars and diving jwn into holes. I will admit that a little lost. I got a policeman i Hudson River. This w;i- k a ten. At half past nine' someone cancelled \ If of the opportunity. The Ireland. It was satisfaction ti at Plymouth. As we near sights it was ever my pi A or forty rods of the coast. T and sizes. There were no quart more of a triangle. Their crazy-quilt work and was real saw We did not stay only long enc other smaller vessel and then we K we arrived at the river that lea pier of Hremen Steamship Line, t j&gt; land for some time as the tide was gont the ship, the servants and almost al an.! carried grips. I wondered wt me or anybody else, but I soon learn. landing waiting for a conveyance to tak ;il first vision of a German railro long, loaded with coal. 1 could hardly every car there and switch is with men by main force. But of experience with the German railroads before I wa journey. The next morning I boarded a train to go to r r many. Most all the farms there are owned by barons and are estates. That is where I wanted to go to see my peo| how dairying was carried on there. So 1 started out. 1 had to ( ears at Hamburg and I asked the porter if such a train would the place I wanted to go and he said "Yes, this one here In that train and we started out. I rode and rode until I won saw. What might intere difficult to present a papt a long time to take a trip abroa </seg>
            <seg id="p096">95 » *n I w i for »• ad rid a r if or m for r (o get to my destination. When you understand much larger than the state of Nebraska, you can rode for three or four hours but as the porter train, 1 took his word for it, but I nevertheless the end of the road instead of finding myself ;o to. I was in a great big railroad shed in a f. 1 still had my ticket. Instead of taking the ticket way they do in this country, you ride to any place you end of the destination they take up your ticket and e right or not. This was my case. I showed my e place I wanted to go to. He looked at the ticket t me and sized me up I thought kind of fiercely. in officer and marched me away. I did not know and didn't know what I had done. I found out later he train and ridden to the end of the road. (Laugh - n clear across the northern peninsula of Germany. I some high-sounding magistrate whose name I will leak and he questioned me and thought that I was he man as 1 should an1 the reason for it is because I bad given him two and a half cents he would ight. You cannot get anything out of a German ser- when I learned that. American-like. I tipped My uncle told me that the reason I did not get bet- I did not tip the servant two and a half cents, and instead of tipping two and a half cents, I Veil, the first night, being single, I thought I would look for They told me there was a dance of some kind going as well as cattle. I attended the dance ly cousin induced me to dance, but after it was i dancing for me in Germany. A few days later i what they called a "stock show." It was a kind of cattle t was held once a year for one day and the cattle are brought at country and the males are supposed to be for bree ling nd are bred up and selected by the government, and the i to those that have been selected. He can use any or his own use. but cannot stand them for public use unless by the government. This is the case in both cattle and horses. aw perhaps 300 cattle and 150 horses at this place, the thing that im- pressed me most in the cattle was such a conglomeration of bree Is. They have no ideals The cattle were kind of a cross between a native cow and a short-horn. All of them were dual purpose cows. The boat tig to beat my way through. I also found out later that I was ect to a fine. I used what little German 1 could speak to good intage. I told who I was and that I did not mean to do any harm. is permitted to pay my fare and return. After riding two or three rs I finally arrived at my destination. I found out afterwards the on that I had gone to the end of the road. I did not get as much </seg>
            <seg id="p097">96 exhibited on the ground was producing eight thousand pout * per year that averaged 3 hi per cent, butter fat. Thi r better than third cow in this contest that we have here. Th ow wa fed for record and kept under test conditions. My first im iressior cattle in northern Germany was not very good. In fact you migt my impression ot cattle in northern Germany was not very good. 1 country has its own ideals. One county county for black and another county for one for beef and another for milk. Th another trip to this town, which seems to twe or three times a year, where they off for red an red and white an .n y don't specialize n be the onlv markt r horses and It is a good deal like a street fair bi cattle. The horses and cattle were lin&lt; i confined t&lt; in the publii all kinds of cattle were shown, inclu r k )»S HI again I saw evidence of mixed blood. Y a could not find tie of the same blood. I found perhaps the best. They were mur on the order of the German Danes which are something likf amusing thing to me was the wa sell cattle by weight or auction* with the owner. A asks the owner of it what Iih » owner "What will you gi\ of buying I will pa shoulders. That is a fa&gt; they agree, then the owner ght and the deal is maie. Here w&gt; dollars worth of horses and cattl just that way. They have no cattle. I ma !e another trip Lack t&lt; railroad trip anJ attended the Nation a good deal about the German navy deed worth anyone's time. Most ■! or forty there in the harbor. We tot to them and from a scientific staii:!] that I caw In Germany. R S Another thing that was specially e sale of milk for infants. I and 1 went in. I told them I was an into their way of handling that kind r A busir w ii courteously and found that it was a place where mothers eouli get milk for their infants from a certain cow child and said she wanted milk she wa n a number ai would go out to the dairyman and the dairyman would nuin accordingly. The milk was pure and every day the milk fron. differently numbered cows was sent to this station and moth t </seg>
            <seg id="p098">97 * A it my ur it r i a o'clock at tw ur mi tl.is country. cow every day. I don't know what the population t probably 50.000 inhabitants. And since this iU- itilisl.ed the number of deaths among infants in a •s had decreased twenty per cent. The milk was sold t about three cents a quart. It is one of the things mi in Uermany that with all their high-price i feed 1 they can make and sell many things at a lower this country. Of course labor haa something to Mgh-priced man there doe* not get much over a r and a woman who does a marts work gets from We would be lucky if we had some of them over get the real inside view of these much-talkel-of ler to do this I had to go away from the railroad •nt out about twenty miles, and in order to cover it guide who knew the country and with two bicycles Most of the Herman roa Is are macadamized, and on id is a loot path which might also be used by bicycles. i.e and approached this estate owned by some baron, r four large estates and in going through it, we rode and we ro.Ie through forests that had never been ; the road. We saw not less than fifteen or twenty We finally lan.ied at the farm wl.ich wax made up of ned-roofed buildings. Above the door there was an There we found 135 cows, mostly Holstein im - n.l. but they had dairy cattle as a foundation. Their got at a co-operative creamery averaged six thous- er row. These cows were in a pasture at the time ,• were all tethered in a row with ten-foot chains. they couli approach each other. Two men were ater for the cows. 11&gt;ey were taken out in the nd they stayed there nntil the fall, tethered, and ittle bit and in that way the whole field was kept arm building, on the same estate, there were 160 kept more on the American plan and the cows were the pasture. He had an average production of nine milk at a test of three and four-tenths per cent n the year round. visit where they were growing wheat and as I could •■plie miles of it by rail we started out to walk. I e. 1 asked him how far it was and he said it was vralk. We walked a couple of hours and got to a ttle opening and after we lad rested a while I asked him how much said "An hour or so:" We finally got there about night and 1 found 1 had walked three German miles. les. I would like to see myself walk that distance in y uncle was fifty-five years old and kept up a pretty </seg>
            <seg id="p099">98 good gait all the way, aa that distance was nothing to hi Dot go with me. But I must hurry on. I spent a good deal of my time Kburg at retail milk depots and with farmers and th i milk. And, summing it all up, the average Herman fa not thrifty as the Nebraska farmer. The German farmer will not tak on anything new. The son works the same as his father and his grat father and his grandfather's father. After leaving Germany 1 w over into Holland, where 1 might say I found conditions alt different. Holland is an up-to-date country. You can it. In Germany nobody cares wt •ther you go or come. E railroads in Germany, if you ha baggage you must get it ar i Holland your baggage is and the people are a great people rile. In Holland i you. That is one of the I it. but as soon as you get over int r you. You can get it at the deput of the American style; there th civilized and bring your baggage t I noticed after I landed in north rn Holland. When 1 arr wanted to see lotni I met an American. I told him cattle and he was acquainted with some of tt me how to reach them, and he went with me. We took a k tramway, a little car. small engine, the car holding eig sons. The surface of the country in Holland beir along at a pretty good gait. \V ■ tie and grazing" country and at one place, being could count 12IKI cows. They all work togettu goodlier number of good cattle in Holland than disappointed in their beef. I high in Hollar of an animal is worth more f( of Holstein cattle of some of tl • '.ported heifer that would bring on the mark* ject for him to develop milking qualities, (iermar eighteen and twenty cents per Dunn, live w traffic it upon canals, and along thf Kng vegetables and things for a country of lots of good c Sht say perfect dairy cattle. ing the Holstein breed ahead good Holstein cows here than j ale. Hollan sttle. Still not a I think the Aniei Hollan I. V can Holstein cattle in Hollar From Holland my trip m largely oi ing. I visited Rot terdani and Amsterdam and 1 took a trip to Hague, and saw whet the International Peace Conference was held; then back into Germar again and then a trip to the Rhine. The Rhine is the ri t eryone who travels ought to see. I found it worth my while. I saw some cathedrals and looked over other points of interest. I traveled down the Rhine for a day. The banks are lined wfth vineyard 'V are on the side of the mountain so steep that you have to walk zigz to them, sometimes two or three hundred feet above the river. Oc rationally you will find a patch of alfalfa, and see women carrying wa </seg>
            <seg id="p100">99 F * 1 r 8 scor money m t u k 1 r 4.', per heads, and so I traveled down until I reached made up my mind that I had seen enough of the )ut doubt grand. I have seen our grand Yosemite mountains in this country do not inspire you uw feeling that these mountains along the Rhine do with old castles. I traveled through southern Germany during har- Methods are poorer than in northern Germany. I saw most of larvested by hand. Men. women and children were cradling linding it by hand and carting it by oxen, the wagon bein* their horns, the rope between them. m there I went over into France and for the first time I realized was to be a green-horn. I could speak ordinary German, but. came into France — And to tell you of my travels in France ake all the afternoon and evening. I will say this much — that ression of France was very good. Every piece of ground that cultivated is used to its full capacity. I did not tarry long in on account of my being unable to speak the language, especially went to the restaurant for meals. I spent a few days in Paris k in the American Legation and the American District, where- he Americans live, and from there took the steamer for Am - i after a very rough voyage, during which time I did not get arrived in this country safely. ou for your kind attention. (Applause.) COW Judging Conli-st most interesting features of the program at the the Nebraska Dairymen's Association was the cow ntest. In this contest ten I 1 0 I milk cows were used repre - s Holstein. Jersey and Shorthorn breeds: the cows were offie- red or placed as regards each one's merits as a dairy cow, by H. Pelt. Professor of Dairy Husbandry at the Iowa agricultural ach cow was placed a placard giving her age. breed also a letter to designate each one: the cows were enclosure adjoining the dairy building, giving abun 'ant mrtunity for contestants but excluding the general public: nsisted in placing the cows in the order, 1st place, 2d place. ar as possible as they were placed by the official score: only if the association could compete and a cash premium of $150. rated among those scoring 75 or more points out of a possible ■mnting only the points scored above and including 75, a contestant scoring 75 points had one (1) point to his &gt; two points, etc.: to correctly place a cow counted ten paints total score: 126 members took part in the contest: two (2) rrors (omissions) such that their scores could not be allowei: i below 75 points and could not participate in the premium 86, or 68 per cent, scored 75 or more and the value of points and including 75 was 30 cts. each: of the whole number part ti."&gt;. or M per cent, correctly placed the best cow and 59, or cent, the poorest cow: Of the winners, 49. or 60 per cent, were </seg>
            <seg id="p101">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 100 students now in attendance at the Dairy school: also c 69, or 81 per cent are now or luivi- l&gt;i&lt;n students in th and the higest score made in judging. 92 points, was mac of the Dairy school. &gt;f the m e Dairy t J Names and scores of those taking part K strong, K. A . \V. R Armstrong, K. A K&gt; Uriftis, .1 I 4 Ate n. W. H s4 Graham, F. W Applt'^at.'. (). E Anthony. Edgar Hriiitun, W.P .. Bushier. Carl A Deiggreo, John. ( 'kiaNscn, A. J . . w, Morel ftppifUltr (). E 72 Hansen, Martin 72 Hansen, Martin 84 Hector, Lows . W Hanson, Donald 7* Harvey, Earl. . . 7t&gt; Hammond, H. F Hurtt, C. H . .. Anthony. Edgar... 84 Hector, Lows 98 Hrinton, W.P 78 Hanson, Donald ... Buehler. Carl A . . 7" Harvey, Karl .... H«Ttrjjren, John 78 Hammond, H. F 82 -sen, A. .1 68 Hurtt. C. H i, Mnrel .72 Hammond. Roy 7» Dal&gt;elstifii. M 77 Harris, J. A ■lstien, Chas. 88 Borah, .1. W Dabelstien. M Dabelstien, ("has Doubt. W. H Doubt. \V. H. .88 How... H H Doubt. F. M 96 Hoffnieiv Doubt, F. M DeJanette, C K 7&lt;i Johnson, H. ( Eanette, C. E Iricbsen, .) U-.v.F. L... Diedrichsen, J . 86 Johnson, Andrew ley, P. L, 7 Johnston, Elmer K •rton, .). 76 Johnson, .) A Edmonaoa, .1. K. . rbrook, OH nuiach, Henry. Predrichaoa, &lt;&gt; F iner, \i. H . . . FV&gt;rberger, John . Fowler, Cleve Kdmonson, J. K 76 Knutli. Adulpli Ai .)« H bterbrook, &lt;). H 74 Kusk^i. Joseph K ■ch, Henry 7ti Knutli. H K Frvdrichson, O. P 76 Kelley, .1 -&gt; iner, \i. H 7- Kauffman, B. V K. Porberyer, John B2 Kraxl A I. Ki I P\)wler, I'h'Vf 7t Leaders, Angus! 74 Lead&lt; Francis, R. .1 Gerkintf, J. R, Francis, R. .1 80 Larson. James 81 Gerking, J. R SI Luttin. A. A 81 I.ut Kssnichlaus, E. E 82 Leaders, Louis •■ by. Mary 11 78 LaYerack, C E Gabby, (has. K Marshall, Roy K. i, Looiae C 84 Marsh, L.F 7- Gibb. John 84 McNmv, H . t (iramlich, J. H 78 Mullin, C. H Graoake, B. F 80 Meyer, M. H. Kssnichlaus, E. E by, -Mary B.. .. rack. ('. i Gabby, (has. E Geis. I»uise (' 98 Marshall, Roy E, «4 Marsh, L. F &gt; Gibb, John *4 McNare, H. &lt; Gramlich, J. H 7- Mullin. ('. H Graunke, B. F RO Meyer, M. H. Gieta, E. E 78 Molgaard, () Gi.-tz, E. E 76 Molgaard, ( ) Garrison. F. F 71 Mullenhoff. H. (i.. </seg>
            <seg id="p102">TWENTY-THIRD ANNl'AL CONVENTION 101 Sneddon, John SO Sautter, Louie W Schildmeyer, W. W 76 To Schildmdyer, Arthur... Swim, B. H ■ 74 Nelson, Clarence Nore, her Sand, Justus no sr « *4 Schoenbeck, W.O Swanson, E.V I Nelson, A. E Nelson, i &gt; C Sjogren.O. W 68 Studley, Russell Sturgeon, R. M Sahn, A.C 7fi Geo. S Saul, Ralph son, Alfred - Vandenberg, E. D Vanshiver, John Vantine, C. L ~- 66 Wiegert, MA (no score) Wulf. William Weber, J. W 7* Witt, Rudolph da, .1 1 -Ml Williamson, C. L 74 -d Wagner, William 74 7^ Webster, C. A. A 70 Richmond, Guy Robb, E. E Young, Carl 82 0 ffson, M. S Yeakle, 0. R 76 Dairy Exhibit e dairy exhibit, in charge of E. M. Little as Superintendent, decided advance over like exhibits of recent years but not what uld be at an annual meeting: There were 21 entries of butter, one of cheese, two of whole milk id two of cream: the Dairy department of the University also made fine exhibit of dairy products which did not compete for premiums: The judging of the butter and cheese was by Mr. J. G. Winkjer of Dairy Division D. S. Dept. of Agriculture, and the awards were as follows DAIRY (PACKAGES) 1st premium Mrs. Wm. Stelk, Grand Island, Score 90i Morris, L. I Moritz. Herbert Morrasy, A. C. Miller, A. &lt;i Meyer, H. I Noble, G. C. I.S... ( trteeren, H l'hege, Edward O Ht Thomas, Geo H 78 Uhl, Roy 91 v, E. P vin, L . Sidney . . Har\- s, Omer D Joseph. . . A. J . . e. &lt;;. e </seg>
            <seg id="p103">Ipremitm Honeywell &amp; Reedy. Lincoln, premium August Lead* ■■ Fapillior premium L. G. Leaders. Papillion Papillion 5th premium M. Mechen. University Pla 5th premium M. Mechen, ♦»th premium Miss Marie Sfcelk. Grand Island. t premium Miss Marie Sfcelk. Grand I premium .lames Larson, Davey. ind 7tli premium .lames Larson, Davey. Davey DAIRY (PRINTS) DAIRY (PRIN Is premium &lt;ieo. S. Phillips, Tecumaeh, Is premiam Geo. S. Phillips. Tecamseh, 8 Id premium Mrs. Wm. Stelk. Grand Island. Id premiom Honeywell A Reedy, Lincoln. 4th premium Miss Marie Stelk, Grand Island. f&gt;th premium John Bneddon, Ku^le. 5th premium John Sneddon, Kan &lt;&gt;th premium M. Ifachen, .University Pla 7th premium .1. C. Doubt A Sons, Havelock. 7th premium .1. C. Doubt &amp; Sons, H iUTTKKIlKKA.MKKVI 1st premium Mr. Pardue, Beatrice ( 'reamery • Lincoln. 8d premium Home Dairy Cn ery &lt; lo, .'id premium Ravenna Creamery Co, Ravei 4th premium Thos. 1' Weal Point. \ r&gt;tli premium ( &gt;. Muckle, Riverton. Bth premium Guy Sanborn, Arcl prints (creamery) premium Beatrice Creamery Co, Lincoln CHEESE 1st premium Clir Wittenbach, Eln Mll.K 1st premium H. C. Yoang, Line ,'2d premium -I K. I{(ihei-t&gt;. Normal. CREA.\ CREAM 1st premium H. C. Your 1st premium H. C Young, Lincoln. AHORTIOX IN CATTLE Dr. A. T. Peters ABORTION IN CAT Causes of \oii&lt;'ont;ii;i(iii&gt; Alxirtion • "As abortion most frequently occurs at those three-week ♦interva w at which the cow would have been in heat if non-pregnant, we ma assume a predisposition at such times due to a periodicity in the nervou system and functions. Poor condition, weakness, and a too watery state of the blood is often a predisposing cause. This in its turn may result </seg>
            <seg id="p104">XTY THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 103 it n r iv I is last nam ated temperature c the foetu t food, from the excessive drain upon the udder rora the use of food deficient in certain essential rogenous constituents or albuminoids, from from roundworms or tapeworms in the ■ I flukes, trematodes) in the liver, from worms ark, damp, unhealthy buildings, etc. In some nent is so deficient that the "fetus dies in the consequence. Excessive loss of blood, attended . becomes a direct cause of abortion. is of important organs are notorious causes of mtagious fevers (lung plague, rinderpest, foot- is a common result. Affections of the chest ation of the blood induce contractions of the Dentally by Brown-Sequard. Pregnant women ted in many cu- he abdominal organs are fertile sources of that cause bloating (tympany of the first r the diseases of the ovaries, kidneys or bladder. . or stone, in the kidneys, bladder, or urinary iredisposing or even an exciting cause in mag- stricts and in winter. The presence of tubercles in aments of the womb, and even on the womb 1 as efficient caus n of the heart, a common disease in old cows -sens the circulation in t^e placenta (and ltrition. may cause abortion. kinds are especially dangerous, as they are us- Tiiistention of the first stomach f paunch &gt; with lirectly beneath and to the left side of the above all an excessive distention of that ts the womb and its contents dangerously. It is of the womb by preventing aeration of the that tends to indigestion is to be carefully guarded water, which hinders rumination and digestion: isea the womb to contraction and the calf reen, succulent grass, to which the cow has . which has just been wet with a slight shower; apples, pumpkins that are or have been [)ly covered with hoar frost; food that has been r that has been badly harvested; growing corn, ll is unused to them; a too dry food or a too at bran, pease, maize, and cotton seed) fed too of them, induce abortion. The dry and stimu - ■d being on constipation and straining, and also of the body, which in itself, endangers the life </seg>
            <seg id="p105">'•oar of Contagious Abortion Vhile any one of the above conditions t &gt;nly by reason of the contagium that the disease can &gt;erpetuated and transferred from herd to herd. Whe •ow is placed in a herd that has hitherto been healthy, ; l healthy i that rear after year, in spite of the facl he otr n that herd remain tl ii 8 due to contagion. When a bull, living in a heal illoweri to serve an ahn • a cow from an fc'hen the nienib*- ,n ltl in considerable numbers, contagion may be safely inferred. reiy mi Ing in the same uastun brought into the aborting In the full till! IV: had the infection con hv thpir nun 11 lact with wall foil the infected uniri rnniniittee found or npnr ahnrtin lodeeri for twen wards inserted in lint till .'.I with cow Rhnrtion nrevailed ahortions in the sow. M animals it will affect also I Cows that are about to abo is considerable swelling of the udde and if it is her first calf t udde fore a normal birth, and there ii dish color and an offensive o&lt; three to five days after these symptoms have been notio tagious abortion is usuallv due t such as blows, falls, straii and violei Treafmen Whenever abortion c ■curs in a it is caused by germs which gain entrance into the animal : - therefore it is no&gt; essnrv that the afterbirth be removed and burned t the afterbirth be removed and bur soon after partaitlon le. Thoroughly scald the stall whl&lt; ontagious principle in precipitating an epizoot erwards miscarriage becomes iir* these invariably a t ttn la rL'i- s;t n lil Mi in the other. C.altier find has been intensified I sick animal from the well ones, for whei it is caused by germs wliich gain entrs </seg>
            <seg id="p106">:i li or i n antiseptic solution. When the iject the cow with an antiseptic otash. a tablespoonful to three n be injected either with an ordinary 1 'ted into the vagina, or by the id of the hose that is inserted i week for six weeks. The tail and hind :horoughly sponged with the same solution lays. The cow that has ■harge from the vagina The writer would rt aborted should not has entirely &lt;•&gt; commend that irobably the carrier n weeks. The bull is ull should be tin oughly disinfected lution, as a table- with some antiseptic potash to a pailful of water. A rubber nough to slip into the er end and when elevat sheath of the bull, a &gt;d will force the solu - md the operator ran sheath. The limbs of eptic solution. and with the right h hly in all parts of the &gt;nged with a good antii appear as describe i. ■d or one-half-ounce kept perfectly quiet. ■btillc acid internally. the feed every few The animal should b stockmen u car mice dos in &gt;nt of Contaj ;ious Abortion om the treatment of sporadic abortion, it ?ldes or disinfectants. &gt;d building, yards, and use of germ I &gt;ws in isolal have acces eiing ewes, goats * even to their manure sows, rabbits, or mares &gt;m the isolated to the noninfected premis ensils are desirable. l back part of the stall and gutter anc mnces sulphate of copper (bulestonei ii arising and watering at leas' « applied to every stall when adjacent. To treat the whole In the it is impossible to say how man: the more needful as that in om in ! kept on. she becomes insuscepitabli i full time. A cow may therefore be infectini elf no longer aborts. •rosive sublimate, 1 ounce each of alcoho tter plenty of slaked lime on the ihieh a funnel has been attached jiled. This vaginal irrigation shoulii be when the symptom k haw may be us </seg>
            <seg id="p107">ip in a wash I root of the tail. Being ven poisono Dltnala . with this liquid, and this li pent, solution of carl I I When an niusr h. it-ii hv tin mil and wmtererd freelv w be washed ont with injected through with a funnel in for a week In injection ion d:i]l\ ■ a spi'iuatt after »*;ir OlltSli; kmrilu mi lilacinu 1A COMPARISON :. FOR u HOLE I "ERENT STATES YORK. BELLI N( t'ONSIX. MAKING CHI •O.VSIN. EASTERN \ I MILK TO fACTORl RASKA AND KANSAS By Mr. .1. H. Rn In the fiKiires hei We have assumed an a terfat for the year 19( We have assumed that ski farm is worth 30c. per cwt.; skii worth i5c. : and skim milk from t ■893 worth 10c. per cwt. Also that to deliver milk o each trip, going and coming, takim Btrip. going and coming, takir and I le to make the delivery. W« li.-i . •• a»umed here the persona &gt;a tnd glycerine, and shake thii njection into the vagina and )arrel out of the wav rulva. anus, back of the hii ;i farmer livint point of the cream, having year, testing ::.7 per cent, butte </seg>
            <seg id="p108">1IRD XNTAL CONVE.VFJoN 107 neiples would apply in the 'club' i ten ing we have assumed an equality of onsin: In Wisconsin. Minnesota and ir NVbr Wisconsin, Minnesota and ka ami Kansa groM at his lilk and butter fat tea 878 trips of i&lt; $7tU.25 lours time at 25c. per hour 02.50 at and skim milk milk at 30 cents E91.7I 114.50 cents on farm $387.25 fat List of Creameries I) CKKAMKRIKS County Omaha arv Dairv ( IHniylas Alliance Box Butte Lancaster Lancaster 1'latte Lincoln Lincoln Columbus Omaha IKniL'las Merrick Douglas Saline Central City &lt; 'rnaha Crete York Douglas Fontanellt Washington Dodge Fremont Fairbury i Jefferuon Dodge Hooper Kearney Buffalo Douglas Madison Douglas Gage K ( lmih&gt; Norfolk .ratre ( &lt; ty Cry.C Beatrice ::::; RateDna Buffalo Sherman Valley Loup City Havenna Ord York jpply to. &lt; &gt;maha &lt; &gt;maha Waterloo Cream Co </seg>
            <seg id="p109">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION- 108 y v c ton « X Mi il.OO IH.00 315.00 'tl."&gt; (hi LOCAL CREAMERIES Count Euan, A. W la Cry. Co r " " Deweese Arcadia Archer Bancroft Burton Clay Valle; Merri C limit Bancroft Burton Creamery Bechter, William Fierce Plato Hall Cairo Co-Op. Cry. Ass'n Carlton Cry. Co. Cairo Thaye Custer Hamil Carltor ■toed Co &lt;)p. Cry. Co Coz, Joshua &lt; omstock Hampton Bancroft Fletcher. S. R. &lt;v Sons Cur Germantown Co-Op Cry. C Home Dairy (iermantown Sewar Grand Island Hall Lewis A: Goldsworthy Lyons Cry. Co. Norfolk Mad Ljroni Burt Kp Valley Co.( )p. Cry Am iinnis Cry. Co. Dannebrog Howa Amelia Ho Meadow Grove Cry. Co. Medow Grove Madiso No. Loup Co-Op. Cry. Ass'n. No. Ixmp Vi O'neill Creamery Km Red Cloud Cry. &lt; &lt;&gt; Riverton " " Riverton Frar Wett Point Butter .v Cry. co. Weil 1 Cox Bros. Cheese Factory .1 The Wisconsin farmer selling his milk to the (he- Receives fjross at factory 45,00(1 lbs. milk at 10 lbs. of cheese to the 100 lbs. 36.000 lbs. Whey at 10c per 100 lb Total rceived for milk and butter at factory !-«•• 4.600 lbs. cheese at lie for makin-r He makes 270 trips at 7"&gt;c each to deliver his milk from farm to factory- Net for Butter Fat and Whey on farti alue of the Whey Net for Butter Fat on the farm Therefor* 1665 lbs. of Butter Fat equals 1 lb would equal Neligh &lt;ry. &lt; (&gt;. Nelifjh An Newman Grove Cry. Co. Newman drove Ma Imyler " " Bchuyler Colf»j grist. Geo. \V Humbolt Rii-ha ■ing Creek Cry. Co. l reston Plane Libory " " St. Liborj Howa </seg>
            <seg id="p110">109 SK •he conditions heretofore named, taking his milk U factory and receiving 1 cent less than New York for his butter fat would equal +4K.V&gt; have 3*3on lb of skim milk akinjf... 57.38 * I 'roceeds at the point of assembling would then be. . .I504.93 . iiiling, 173 trips at 75c per trip 129.78 av ing net for butter fat and skim milk on the farm 377.13 acting the value of the skim milk from this we have alue of the butter fat on the farm '. • 57. 3« at leaves net for butter fat on the farm S31U.77 efore if 1WW) lbs. of butterfat on the farm equals 319.77 will equal .« 1820 ease of the Kansas-Nebraska farmer, delivering butter fat to the point of assembling under the t ■ system now in operation in the states named and 4 cents less than New York for this butter fat would equal $3«9.tiO ie would also have 38,250 lbs. of skim milk on his farm for feeding calves and pigs, worth for the purposes hundred 114.75 akinff the gross proceeds from both milk and cream at point of assembling S514.35 is estimated that he would make 70 trips to haul am from his farm to the point of assembly, at 75c 52.50 ng him net for his butterfat and skim milk on Ml. 85 acting $114.75, the value of his skim milk, and rve for his butter fat on the farm 347. 10 Therefore in*", lbs. butter fat on the farm equals Ml. Mi r 1 lb. equals * 2085 ■V RKCAPITILATION therefore it appears from the above and foregoing that the iork farmer at the point of delivery recieved for his butter fat and skim milk, gross 704.25 The Wisconsin cheese patron at the point of delivery for itterfat and skim milk, gross 821.00 The Wisconsin, eastern Minnesota and eastern Iowa farmer at the point of delivery for his butterfat and skim milk, </seg>
            <seg id="p111">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN S ASSOCU 110 ATION J re f it f. +.U a BKansa*-Nebraska farmer at the point of de ved for his butterfat and skim milk, jrross Further, it appears from the above ar ■ York farmer received for his butterfat skira milk on his farm net The Wiaeonaia ehMM patron received for butter fat and skim milk on bis farm, net The Wisconsin, eastern Minnesota and • Iowa farmer received for his butter fat and tikim mUk on his farm, net K Kansas-Nebraska farmer received for his butt nd skim milk on his farm, net New York farmer at his farm rt ■ &gt;n«in cheese patron at his far fat. net onsin, eastern Minnesota and eas &gt;ei for his butterfat at his farm n&lt; Kas-Nebraska farmer at his far * t Continuing further it appears that York farmer receives per cow from b n the farm Wisconsin cheese patron receives per can on his fa from his butterfat and whey. Wisconsin, eastern Minnesota and eastern Iowa fan receives per cow on his farm for hi* milk and butt'i- Kas-Nebraska farmer receives per cow on his far iilk and butterfat It also further appears that th New York fanner on the farm receives for From the tbore and foregoing it appears tha Vork farmer on his farm received net for sonata cheese patron received net on farm &lt;&gt;n&gt;in. eastern Minnesota ami eastern Iowa farn f»nii net for liis liutterfat Kansas-Nebraska farm ed on his farm butterfat It also apiM-ars th.r </seg>
            <seg id="p112">XTY-THIRD ANNUAL CONVENTION 111 patron on the farm receives for his w M nnesota and a&gt;!-rn Iowa farmer at per cow aer on his far a a M-a- live* for his rther appears on I 'a je t&gt;4 of the Statistic airy complied from (be I'nited States census for 1!*M&gt; hief of the Dairy Division of the Dept. at the number of cows per square mile in the state of hat the number of cows per square mile in the state hat the number of cows pet square mile in the state was i of cows per square mile in the state number of cows per square mile in the state the nun number of cows per her cows per square mile in the state tran was i&gt; number of cows per •juare mile in the state a* s number of cows per liiare mile in the state it the number of cows per square mile in the state That the number of cows per square mile in the state Nebraska was - Now it also further appears that the population per ■ quare mile in th€ state of New York is 1 \V .'oils a. Iowa Minnesota lllino Illinois yg j Michigan , .» i , MK'tugan 4° 16 Missouri &lt;•• Indiana Indiana Kansas i«° Kansas I* Nebraska 11 HIT Wil </seg>
            <seg id="p113">be &gt;ear re i inw an arm w« " We happen to have a record of our operations for t ind a comparison of that year with IWH shows as follows: ■ The difference in the New York price for butter i i« Vssumine the same basis »&lt; in our table for IW1 lavine ten cows, producing 4- r &gt;.i*N&gt; lb of milk, averagini l-»:V)lb of butterfat. The average jv.ce paid the patro: 1*93 was 15. 6« cents per pound. so that the returns on the i. r &gt;.66c I23SH. Hutterfat at tti.nonn. Skim m; it K&gt;c per cwt.la fair val ifferent condition*) considering th Total returns on Kutterfat farm from 1»&gt; co« th it llet in N. Y r table Rftu r 1 ■. Gain in va (nst of deli » * i A ill 4 yea 1. The better means employed to secure i 1. The better grade of Skim Milk: tThe decreased cost of assembling. »ip»- r&gt;f the results shown above, ret «f tv&gt;» cnws in Nebraska, furnishing cream to t wonder that the growth of the busine-»&gt; since L900 ha it anv wonder that since IDO&amp;tbe growth has b&lt; Gain in value of 1 Total Gain in !!«• &lt;iain imt OOW ployed in ths dairy busir three Doints: </seg>
         
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>