<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00018.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00018.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  EXPERIMENTS WITH CORN.</title>
               <date value="1905">1905</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">i- Nebraska BULLETIN AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION NEBRASKA. K II. EXPERIMENTS WITH CORN. ARl i ARM. Yield. rn bi on of Plants. II M.ITV MI1KR 5. 19U9. I ARM. \SKA A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">STATION NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD . THE STATION OFFICERS THE WORKING STAT - </seg>
            <seg id="p003">\ iii experiments which . ■ this Station duri ng I he |&gt;:isi three ii carried r&gt;« ill v;iri. h fjeneral in &lt;1 be published N" argument to prove ill, aiiv in - and nature &lt;&gt;f the com plant which Kirinv of handle the crop ' ill III. III! COOPERATIVE TESTS OF VARIETIES. • I iilVivnt climal ic and soil com] ml in or&lt; under Diul it ions, the cooperation of fnrun - gccnn*d in experiments t" &lt;I&lt;m ill |&lt;&gt;iulii)!! Varieties of turn under i ■'■]&gt;( r;ii ii r was f ii in i - Kirh variety to h bo plan( h rcfcrciiic to climatic ■! wen- given the lies in Hie accompanying the map. i : Ms of i he 10(1 1 testf in tlic following table. 1 fourteen different var \ in. art. ii. xmndarios n( tin- divisions, wliidi are </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 ■-.ments with Corn. . of the Noi Tlic viehl [kt aci ■ the tests is given in treated bj itself: * Where corn of the sam&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 r- - ! r - «r ._ &lt;2 BaOO 35 ■ssasssss • * ft - RSS85«3^5S -*■ t- 3 S . . T ...... ■ i - 3) r. St- r- t- !"• t- t- ? i </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">7 -*» t- 1-4 3-! — Lz &gt;-, ■3 •*; : '0 '■ o 5 5 75 ' flfiljij SS ■*• -^ -f -'5 8 .-&gt; . . </seg>
            <seg id="p008">I iixpfrxwiffits tvtth C oth. JS 5P »O 00 &lt;C S: r- . - t- ■» . s ■ f — -,; t_ «- - - </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Experiments with Ctm. " ri-:iS»iS ■ o o i- oo iq - i M 2 5 — — £=£&lt; = ■ -r — 'x #n». s;;.s P S5« 5 l-M Sri o ?i - • Jim Si^^S 6s is . « 8 Z a 2 l; S « a •ji • ■ F°33 &lt; O M -5 * "Osiris g « I a V I &amp; M M •o D 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Proa the results of fn&lt;- tli following coiii I For Sort imi 1 . KcnI's Yellow I &gt; late ii Nortli is earlier i linn I Iriala when- lx&gt;ainin; Ell. Imi in il ripened in nearly lico is probablv the b in Section ('., t\u •lection r&gt;. Calico and I \ ariclieSi fU'iii provori i«- moth I M.'iiniiiiitli v rilioo ■ lid nut in S faihtl </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 I TY TESTS ON THE EXPERIMENT STATION FARM. n farm before ' ih taken &lt;m each net v luit o iiuic the effe* of those vaiiet ics w liidi these varieties in years m. 1»HJ'_. 1904. 51.0 77.2 74.0 8-2.1 72.8 83.1 : : fil.5 84.9 ■s yii s in llit' aiding ilif i g of the niil in nearly the sa i 1 1 ■ lative standing. ietiea for the th ree yean rapre- </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 nt at kin.l. RELATION OF SIZE OF EAR TO YIELD It is frequently nf W&gt;| I ill I ll«' &gt; taken The runt i onlv a I' - aril \;i: 1 J </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 &gt;• marked difference* in tlr are not justified in uld alwi I the data '•urn for w« liould I- Her cared type than THICKNESS OF PLANTING CORN. M in 1904, experiments were made at the of different rales of planting • of car. qualitj of the lumber of barren stalks and sinkers, and upon the 11 -i nunihcr of plants d( the c\|icrimcni the plantings were K i line extra kermis were planted in the hill. rn was aim nehes high, it was tbim ed number of plants per bill. In L903 idc t&lt;&gt; vary from one to four kernels per !MM the niaxiniiiiii was increased to t'w were placed forty-fonr inches apart ilts in their various phases in; I table showing Hie average results THE V1KI.II OK GRAIN. rower the all-important quo how to in eld. This point is therefore tli iu connection with a study of the rate per 100 plants. No. of cr y; 68 55 174 119 98 82 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 llli- ' kIkiuIi ■ iu;l(l&lt; plan similar in botJi j i quality, 1 1 It might liiivc h ice the liiiili'-si | Bumbor of tiller* Two nlai of planti he hill | t&lt;&gt; the hill and ' bihI 1904 llill 1 II v &lt;&gt;lll til' nil ili&gt; 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 than nn.v liill. This would seem to in nil. ;i rather tliin vinmm yield tin- rate should ! gave l,.i\)'2 pounds P mhIs per acre with hill. Tin 1 [»i '\cr w:is lies! proportion of i lover would Bint true lnc;l use harmi i illcrs on the thinner plant - r ii 1 iMTiir in the thicker Illinois Siiiiiuii rcjior - siinil;ir taking the inosl stover, K;ii!il lowest |M'rccntage of tit'hes :i[&gt;art of plant in™. Thus in 1904 six lanted ;ii the rate of one to the hill ile the i lied as high as twenty-seven t the rale of five stalks j»«&gt;r hill. lo result in a degree of barrenneM ier than wo ,- natural. - &gt;v«»r wove made only in _ i l;nl v with ! !fnv«&gt; (.::;(•_' iKMimls II. w li it-li \\;is 1 1 i &lt; • rate tliat 1 1 would !'&lt;■ r pro|M&gt;rtion of loin tin 1 (lilt'i •ri'iicc in rules i:i ii-i-ii gtalk </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 TILLER5, OR "SUCKERS." In order to understand 1 1 thai have been n uent ami value or la« in this connect ion brandies and FiK 1 fr. ' 3 stalks. Bj this form of been gradually red branches still app •'suck The development of injj to the variety of con flint corns. To take the den variety &lt;&gt;( U the young plant is np, em •pniftniln the 1 &gt;&gt;]*•&lt; porn pint i mlouhtfHi a much bran </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 a i bv careful examina- If inmliiicpiis are favorable, ii id develop into tillers hij»li. Ct i) of these buds are ; 1 1 1 Favorable conditions ;is l&lt;.|ic&lt;l tillers, rsiiiilly all tillers ile I heir start bv i lie I ime The young tillers are ;it lirst attached to the main plan! and draw tMeir suh - sistcncc from it i hence the name Riieker), but they Boon develop their own iiiul Hntilly become v i i- 1 ii ;i I 1 v independent plilllts. Siimel illies enlife k«'|ki ration lakes j» 1 a c e uh the pushing away , tiller by the rapid Ii i»f I,,. ili itself and lain plant. Figure :*&gt; liliintin^R. The results .is for two yean of tl ions are as folloi ;iy niiikc tillers. In I III 111 I i rat ion, in tins pamte&lt;l. Figure il which favor Hie irs of plant- mI&lt;- of the iniinltcr «&gt;f </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 i lull, 8 tillers developed. i hill, 25 tillers developed. 11 t hill, 7&lt;&gt; tillers developed. i hill, l'.ts tillers developed. i. n which this experiment was cob nt three stalks per hill was a one tiller developed to every four ■ lie or two stalks per hill were left. ■ I to make up the difference. The will also vary from year to year, just as ils which constitute a maximum stand will year, depending on soil, moisture, climatic I'm- example, i n &lt;&gt;f 1903 was very Nperimeiits showed that about four plants xitnuin yield, while in 1904, a drier •r hill gave besl yield. The following thai in 1!M&gt;3 the tendency of the tillers was tand io four st;ilks per hill and in 1904 to "rr hill. 1903 1904. i.-2 4.9 4.1 ■1.4 q qo o no 1 mother influence in determining ii this, plantings were made rodiici ion on adjacent plats, one of which had been in grass for several Table X. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 \ mil. i i \ i — devi lopm ol of tillers the produced K&gt;4 tillers identical conditions ex- l bur til tillers per hundred. ile in I'.hi."! when seed grown from w;is planted «&gt;n plats differing as in •suit was the xame as before as will be mi of figures •"&gt; and &lt;&gt; showing photo - of the two pla I'I.ANTi:|i COBN. corn lias fewer find's than sur- llv due to the slower start ii on. .Must uf the tillers start, dnr - rowth. Listed corn usually lias !tidiii"hs for growth during the first and therefore develops they are more &lt;&gt;r In careful counts made for two planted corn, where l»itli d had almos there was very little difference in the fninid to jilav a part in tho ii olmerred in the differ - • ■ produced under similar Figure 7 illustr </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 tins probable, in fact, that the te licrciit in ;ill porn and that is decree liy different c;irs ami &lt;lii' ■ i ■ 1 1 (I i* n difl Not* thm difffivii ■ .ij i - planted fill 1 1 1 I « Ml &gt; SIH'll ■rn with a tendei nditions tJiat prevent the forn been planted under mure favorable vp prmluood i ill We have found in prai when the pi. lopmcnt &lt;&gt;f i bis tendei </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 9 tillering must therefore eaehed. ■w experimental date are yet at hand on which to an idea of the value of till- \ They have a value in that ~/ they thicken op a deficient nl of corn and when well developed produce ear*. In the experiments on the of planting it was found rate that for each 100 plants at the of one ]mt hill there were produced 171 ears of corn. \&gt; I nlv alioiit two per cent of the lanis produced more than one it is evident that a large ir ■ illers produced ears, same conclusion has been past two years we have fully removed the tillers froi other row in a por - tion of the corn-field. The Id of these rows, as com T red with those on which the \' m were left, was as follows per acre Tillers left on. Bushels. SS 74 81 i .\a:iis. reached in another way. For </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Removing ■ w lici than bo of Wl.il* - INCRi 111 t! in tli' ■ t \v&lt; i ■' ' the nitclx and m have praotio&lt; &gt;! tion. p;tcli -MOW till' panic soil, and I </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 'xtnents u each pla 81.(5 I in si I i 1 1 1: nml pluitl i :iili in n ii he noticed !»■ • iiihI taller than iliflVivw : t III' I \n t'pl in a mills, ;i- i HI* hi'- all of wliii-li "01. Tl .mil the sni i \ icltl of </seg>
            <seg id="p026"/>
            <seg id="p027">27 t; of corn of the \\ which hud yielded only 62 bushels per SHlt Of OIK" \ iijj this method of selection may be greatly inn NG CORN FOR HIGH OIL CONTENT. d &lt;&gt;f selection ;is that followed i8c the oil and pi (intent of different ears of i per cent. It is easy to pick out are high in oil by chemical analysis, but there - will transmit this high oil to increase the oil and protein dill a question, but at any rate it i- in he accomplished in this line. lining any marked incres of coin during the short time inducted, bul there has b Following is a summary of tit fit t. •r ■ Hi. ■ p oil in the ears |&gt;1 -. parately ami analyze its - in i 1904. 11)06. i § -S s I J 3 o c o • ft ■ .' /Vr rent I ■ 5 68 +.16 6.503 i of 1902 the oil content ! in tlic cars planted, </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 o Tvpd in that the oil nd 1004 exceeded ,vould seem from this &gt;! itent independently A NEW LOCALITY. mtrv for a nnm ion where soil and cli - inderj»oes more or less becomes i Mine, was obtained •an. In the was als These wen it ion. A experiment be- nit tin nti-al Nebraska lliiiost two i lia.l an i Iowa, but the icclimated corn. f plains grown in a urn the variety I bulletin, of the L'L' va - irniers in various orn plant Snow-linke Whiti n height, tli. • ml tu be heavier 200 square inches lie home- </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 parts of T 2 from Iowa, 1 from Indian periments the ~- i l: 1 1 i t Hlf f;l side tin ng. ii ■ u ii. the right w»» from -■-■■! whi.-h had U frown in N&gt;brm»k . fapf* I'CSU 1 1 S f ( T 1 the varieties from the &lt;&gt; own. Their Ion it first adapted o ... </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 r A d nod from this is that to get the best ieed must be home-grown, and it in the same locality. t seed (frown in will not do iis well in western Nebraska ■ jo. There should be careful county of the suite. A CROSS-BRED VARIETY. t w;i relop ;i new type of corn is ihlislied varieties. Crossing induces Bometi sible to combine in the qualities &lt;&gt;f the two varieties. corn for Nebraska has probably not yet ■il. In tin search for improvement we have ad ing varieties and will now attempt to develop .if the state, new strains of corn from n the hope of getting a variety that shall be her and which shall be adapted to the different being crown. KEEPING SEED-CORN. having good, vigorous seed corn i- d, bui the importance of saving the nditions is not so well understood. Seed by being frozen while it still con as it usually does when first field. Ordinarily to prevent damage to the gather the seed corn early or hang it up in some dry, well ventilated i ermine the value of drying seed-corn care /.ini:. the corn from one field was divided , part being put in an ordinary crib and part room. In a field test the next spring, that from germinated 90 per cent and that from the crib </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 h 70 per cent. Furthermo up of the (TJlilx-il seed, tuaiiv ing that they had l«vn injured tip EL ween them. Th&lt; f» or two feet deep. Mi ler. A iniii ! ijiiivd ■ \ fariiu-r sliou after it dry before freezing mule l&gt;.\ ordinnrv &lt; r </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 JEPfH OF PLANTING, &gt;ne. two, three, and four f niif and two indies came &lt; n as quite cold and wet 1 a larger per cent of l\, It is generally thought thai deep planting will the roots to develop p, bat tliis is not the Figure 11 is from a photograph of four plants, ~.ed of which was ii depths of one, w\ and four uch below the surface. conditions, but plant- re fur tin THOIStl ■&lt; it a greater depth than 1112: torn in fact, it is a positive illation than this. Listing permits the ith soil, although the seed when w P- oct of depth of planting on nt. v iil out in L904. .(ami, while only a sniiill per '■ame and a still less It will be . mil tins that, no matter what the depth of plant- in which develops at (he base </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 THE SEED FIELD. v farmer should attempt a pin &lt;m en fur his own ii will nnju i !!«■ will ;ilw;ivs be able I then dai nved t&lt;» pla i MARY v of tl Corn On f although thi- thinn / larger number. The proportion of 1 bv the- nite of plain ii._ per acre. Suckers ;irc more abnndai of corn, and more abundant which is less productive. Tlir I more Bt rough inhon and thi, Ilittli in and nld ho p •ther &lt;&gt;n a small fieli ir from event mixing </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 - thinner than the soil and moisture ifticient rainfall it would not - ble to remove the tillers in the hope of improT' ts n&lt; le to the which it is to be planted. There should be careful ery county of tli' n a dry seed room in the fall {rare t nd in the field than seed-corn from the - left in the crib over winter. ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. it liis indcliicdiios to Mr. E. ( ! ice he has rendered in ilie • • liinents here reported, and for helpful Bug- pretation &lt;&gt;f results. obtained through il«» 4 K! In- 1 &gt;epartmenl of &lt; "hi ler the ■ </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>