<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>FOURTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA Branch Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Milford, Seward County, Nebraska BEING FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">FOURTH BIENNIAL REPORT -OP THE- NEBRASKA Branch Soldiers' and Sailors' Home Milford, Seward County, Nebraska BEING FOR THE BIENNIAL PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1902 Thb Fbimowt Trtbuke Fkbmont, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Milford, Neb., November 30, 1902. To His Excellency, the Governor of Nebraska, and to the Hon- orable Board of Public Lands and Buildings : Gentlemen: — I would most respectfully submit the following report for the biennial period commencing February 1, 1901, when I took charge of the Milford Soldiers' and Sailors' Home, to November 30, 1902. I desire to call your attention to the necessity of increasing the appropriations for the Home very materially. The legislature of 1901 appropriated $20,880, which has been insufficient to meet the demands of the Home. I desire to call your attention to the wonderful per cent of in- crease of members in the last two years, which increase has been nearly double. There have been so many expenses to meet in the way of smoke-stack, sinking well, removing and repairing cow-barn, re-shingling roof of main building, plastering, paint- ing and plumbing upper story of main building, repairing the ice-house; also repairing laundry and putting in new washing machine; also water-heater for kitchen. When I took charge of the Home it was very much run down, and repairs were needed in every department; and while I have supplied in a measure these needs, there still exists a great need of repairs and furnishings for the comfort of the Home. I would recom- mend the following appropriations: For employes' wages $ 5,000.00 For maintenance and clothing 20 000.00 Fuel and light 3,000.00 Drugs and surgical instruments 600 00 Stock food and farm 500 00 Furniture and bedding 1,000 00 Telegraph, telephone, express and postage 300.00 Laundry repairs 250.00 Library 75-OO Visiting and examining board 800.00 General repairs on building, and building coal shed . . 2,500.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Branch Soldiers' and Sailors' Home. 351 Note. — The Home is in need of the following : One set of harness, one wagon, one two-seated top buggy, one mower, one hay rake, one corn cultivator. The estimated cost of same will be about two hundred and eighty-five dollars ($285.00). PERMANENT IMPROVEMENTS. The Home requires in the way of permanent improvements a hospital that will accommodate from sixty to seventy-five patients, with kitchen, dining-room and doctor's office adjoining. This building should be separate and apart from the main build - ing. Many of the members are from seventy-five to ninety years of age, and should be kept by themselves, apart from noise and confusion. Their food should be of different charac - ter from that of the others, and suitable for old and feeble per - sons. This would reserve the main building for the members of the Home who are able to care for themselves and do away with restraint. The estimated cost of building would be ubout fifteen thous - and dollars ($15,000.00). COMMANDANT'S RESIDENCE. The commandant should be furnished a residence apart from the Home proper. It would be conducive to discipline. As the main building is now constructed there is no adequate room for the commandant and his family. Estimated cost of residence building about twenty-five hun - dred dollars ($2,500). WATER SYSTEM The Home has neither a system of water-works nor proper or suitable fire protection. At present the only fire protection consists of a small tank in the garret of the main building that holds about thirty barrels of water. I would recommend the erection of a stand-pipe at an estimated cost of about three thousand dollars. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">352 ELECTRIC LIGHT PLANT. There is at present no system of light except kerosene lamps, which are dangerous in the extreme, especially when handled by old and feeble men. A suitable plant is estimated to cost about three thousand dollars. AN ENLARGED BOILER HOUSE If there should be erected an electric light plant, it would necessitate the enlargement of the boiler house, and a new boiler would become necessary for increased service. Estima - ted cost of same about two thousand dollars. GROUNDS AND ORCHARD The Home has very beautiful grounds surrounding the build - ing. If an appropriation was made to beautify the same and to plant an orchard thereon, it would be a great benefit as well as a lasting improvement. In a few years the orchard would be self-sustaining. To make these improvements it would cost about five hun dred dollars ($500.00). DEFICIENCY CLAIMS. The last legislature failed to provide for deficiency claims to the amount of one thousand six hundred and seventy-six dollars and sixty cents. These deficiencies should be provided for. OFFICERS' SALARIES. I would recommend the officers' salaries as follows Commandant, per year $1,200.00 Surgeons, per year 800.00 Engineers, per year 400.00 and that the legislature create the office of Adjutant for the Home at a salary of six hundred dollars per year. We have on roll at this date 124 members and seven applica- tions approved, making a total of one hundred and thirty mem- bers'. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">D RANCH oOLDIKRS AND oAILORS HOME. 353 Members present last report 66 Gained by admission 94 Returned from furlougli 823 Total 983 Loss by discharge 40 By death 14 Furlough 828 Total 882 Total members present 101 Average members present during the twenty-one months ... 77 Per capita for the 21 months that I have had charge is. ... 297.94 Average cost per capita per year 170.24 Average per capita per quarter 4 2 - 2 4 I would recommend a burial fund of six hundred dollars ($60000) as the average death rate would be about twelve per annum. I would recommend an appropriation of two hundred dollars ($200.00) for maintenance of religious service preaching at least twice per month by a resident pastor, and services to sick, and burying the dead. The Visiting and Examining Board and Geo. W. Brandon, M. D., Home physician, have made a report of the Home which is attached to and made a part of this report. Mr. J. Brooks, the commissary sargeant, has performed his duties in a most effectual . and satisfactory manner. I am also pleased to be able to say the same of G. W. Brandon, surgeon, and Mrs. Laura Penn, the matron. I trust that there may be an influence brought to bear in behalf of our comrades, for no people in the nation can lay claim to being more generous and patriotic than the citizens of Nebraska. Our people want her soldiers to have as good care as can be given them. The people stand ready to vote any amount of money neces- 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">354 sary to render the remnant remaining of the Grand Army com - fortable and happy the few days left them. It has been pro - claimed in every campaign and is the sentiment of the people, they stand by the men who stood by the country in times of war. All that the men who have been born since those perilous times want to know is, what do these men now need to make the rem - nant of their lives peaceful and as far as possible happy, and they are more than willing they should have it. No constituency will ever call in question an act of a single member of the legislature who votes money to be used in smooth - ing the pathway of a veteran of any war. I also desire to express my thanks to the Governor, Board of Public Lands and Buildings, and Visiting and Examining Board, for courteous treatment during the many questions that are constantly demanding conference for their settlement in an institution of this kind. Yours most respectfully, Chas. Penn, Commandant. Brokkn Bow, Nbbr., December 4, 1902. To His Excellency, the Governor, and the Board of Public Lands and Buildings. Gentlemen: — In accordance with the laws of the state of Nebraska governing soldiers and sailors homes, the Visiting and Examining Board beg leave to make the following report of the Home at Milford, showing the condition of the same dur - ing the biennial period beginning December 1, 1900, and clos - ing November 30, 1902. The Board has exercised the same jurisdiction over this Home in conjunction with the commandant, as over the Home at Grand Island. The membership of this Home has increased in like manner as at Grand Island. At the close of the biennial period begin - ning December 1, 1900, the total membership on the rolls was sixty-eight members, and now there are 100. The appropriation of 1901 was made on the basis of a mem- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Branch Soldiers' and Sailors' Home. 355 Eip of sixty-eight, and with the increase of members it has simply impossible to keep within the amount appropriated, i a deficiency. The location of this home is beautiful, and is a popular resort and will grow in importance. No more desirable location can be found in ihe state. Built upon an eminence that commands a magnificent view of the surrounding country, the Blue river circles in crescent form around it, while along its borders a dense growth of natural timber abounds, furnishing shade and a most delightful resort for our aged defenders of our country. The Visiting and Examining Board take pleasure in report - ing that the best of feeling prevails among the officers, em - ployes and members. The officers and employes are faithful, and are using every means at their command to make it com - fortable and pleasant for the inmates of the Home. I 'he addition built a few years ago for the purpose of a hos - 1 is not suited for such, but will answer for members that not sick. A new hospital building separate and apart from main building, large enough to accommodate say seventy - people, is an absolute necessity. This would give the room le main building to those who are able to wait upon them - selves. With both Homes crowded at the present time to their full capacity, it necessitates more room, and this hospital building would help to give the needed room. We also strongly endorse the recommendation of the com - mandant for the building of a cottage for the use of the com - mandant. Justice demands that there should be a cottage away from the main building for the commandant and his family. This will release for members the space that the com - mandant and his family now occupy. We also would recommend that the statute which was passed for the control of this Home when there were only about thirty members, should be amended and enlarged to meet the present needs of the institution. We fully endorse the recommendations of the commandant </seg>
            <seg id="p008">356 I the amounts asked for by him. We believe in some inces the amount is too small to meet the demands of the ae. Respectfully submitted, John Rkesk, President. Sarah C. Swert, Secretary. R. S. Wilcox, C. E. HlBBRRT, Bri.le C. Bolshaw. Milford, Neb. Kr : I herewith submit the report of the department of Physi - and Surgeon for the period, commencing March 22nd, 1901 e present date. I obtained charge of this department March 22nd, 1901, imme - diately following the reign of my predecessor, Dr. J. M. Muir. Although I had frequently had charge of the department, during the temporary absence of the attending physicians, I had never before had the opportunity of a close observance of the general workings of the institution, and as I became more acquainted with the management of the same, 1 was more favorably impressed with the efficient way it was managed. The surround - ings could hardly be improved upon by nature, and with the ingenuity practiced by the controlling powers, it has become as near an ideal resort, and sanitary home as would be possible for the amount of funds invested, sewerage being about perfect, water good, location of the best, being far enough from the vil - lage for protection and convenience and not too far to become a burden and overstrain on the inmates and attendants. The cul - inary department is in excellent condition, the commissary of good quality and well prepared, and not overburdened with indi - gesiibles, very little complaint being offered by the inmates, and that of a trivial nature. Ee action of the governing powers meet the approbation of mates, to the entire satisfaction of all so far as I can observe, :, harmony and good-will being the watchword of the insti- 1 have written about 1,000 prescriptions, besides refilling nearly </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Branch Soldiers' and Sailors' Home. 357 all of them from two to twenty times, a large majority of them being for chronic ailments, and conditions that ars incurable, and can be relieved only, and made more comfortable. I have had very little surgery. Removed one eyeball and a number of small tumors, polypuses, etc. There is no severe sickness existing now, except such chronic ailments as we expect among a lot of broken down men, and conditions caused by age. There has been no epidemics of a severe nature except short epidemics of so called grip and a few cases of inflammatory dia - rrhoea during the hot weather, and nearly all of those can.be traced directly to carelessness or indiscretions. The institution is nearly all the time crowded beyond its capacity, it being fre - quently necessary to fill the hallways with cots. The hospital is not what it should be, not large enough, and poorly located. If the commandant could be provided with accommodations in another structure, easy of access, it would leave a goodly num - ber of rooms for the convenience of inmates. We have had sev - eral deaths since I became attending physician, namely : John Truax, age 62, died Oct. 5th, 1901, chronic bowel and liver trouble; Joseph Estep, 61, died Oct. 13th, 1901, general catarrh and senility; Dennis Murphy, 59, died Oct. 27, 1901, corrhosis of liver from drink; Isaac N. Smock, 59, died Nov. 8, 1 901, geiieral paralysis; Beela H. Flusky, 63, died Dec. 24, 1931, chronic cystitis; Robt. McCrossen, 77, died Feb. 9, 1902, nerve and heart failure; Alexander W. Alloway, 59, died March 8, 1902, heart failure; Joseph Householder, 62, died April 2, 1902, chronic eczema, asthma and heart failure; David Alle - baugh, 58, died June 2, 1902, paralysis, general — chronic; Fred - rick Holdren, 59, died June 23, 1902 — died suddenly while away on furlough; Joseph Davison, 56, died July 24, 1902, acute alco - holism; Joseph Gallagher, 61, died August 13, 1902, paralysis; Robert N. Dryden, 61, died Nov. 3, 1902, paralysis. Hoping the prosperous condition of Nebraska may continue, and the integrity and honor of its citizens, especially the govern - ing element, be blessed with the reward they deserve, I have the honor of submitting the above. Gko. W. Brandon, M. D. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">• </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>