<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH BULLETIN</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH C. T. BURCHARD, M. D., President, Falls City E. ARTHUR CARR, M. D., Vice-President, Lincoln L. STARK, M. D., Treasurer, Hartington. H. B. CUMMINS, M. D., Secretary, Seward BOARD OF HEALTH JOHN H. MOREHEAD, Governor WILLIS E. REED, Attorney General A. O. THOMAS, Supt. Public Instr J. D. CASE, M. D., State Health Inspector, Lincoln WM. F. WILD, M 1 . D., Director Bacteriological Laboratory, Lincoln I have often thought it was a pity that all infectious diseases of the human race were not transmitable to the lower animals, because it is a well known fact that from eight to ten times the amount of money may be secured from the Legis - lators and those in charge of the funds, for the protection of the lower animals than can be secured for the protection of the human race. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 3 CONFERENCE OF STATE AND LOCAL BOARDS OF HEALTH The Fourth Annual Conference of State and Local Boards of Health will be held in Omaha, January 25th and 26th, 1916. Headquarters will be at the Rome Hotel where all sessions of the meeting will be held as they have a fine Assembly Hall and rooms for Committee meetings. Special rates have been made as follows : Rooms without bath but with the privilege of de- tached bath, $1.50 for one person of $ .75 each for two. Rooms with private bath $2.50 for one person or $1.25 each for two. Prospects are good for a very entertaining and instructive meeting as we have the promise of papers from men of note and authority on the different subjects to be considered. Address of Welcome by Hon. James C. Dahlman, Mayor of Omaha. Response by his Excellency, Governor John H. More - head. Dr. Hugo Erichsen of Detroit, Michigan, President of the Cremation Association of America, will deliver an address on the evening of January the 25th. Dr* Erichsen is a strong exponent of Sanitation and is a mem - ber of a large number of foreign societies on Hygene and Sanitation. He is a well known lecturer on this subject and his address will be of great benefit to those in attendance. Dr. Paquin, Health Commissioner of Kansas City, Missouri, has promised to be present and address the meeting on the subject of "The Broad Powers of Hygiene Physically, Mentally and Morally." Dr. Ralph W. Connell, Health Commissioner of Omaha, will address us. His subject being "The Res - ponsibility and Duties of a Health Officer." </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska State Board of Health Dr. Robert Retzer of Omaha, Nebr., Dean of Creigh - ton University, will have a paper. His subject being, "Fatigue." Dr. Irving S. Cutter of Omaha, Nebr., Dean of the University of Nebraska, will have a paper on "The Pres - ent Status of Ophthalmia Neonatorium in Nebraska." Dr. F. L. Wilmeth of Lincoln, Nebr., Dean of Cotner University, will prepare a paper on "Proposed Legisla - tion." Dr. Charles F. Crowley of Omaha, Nebr., Consult - ing and Analytical Chemist and Cemical Engineer, will have a paper. Subject, "Septic Tanks." Dr. W. S. Fast of Beatrice, Nebr., Superintendent of the Hospital for the Feeble Minded, will prepare a paper on "Vaccination as a Preventive Against Typhoid Fever." Dr. W. D. Guttery, Superintendent of the Norfolk Hospital, will have a paper. Subject not yet announced. Dr. F. P. Fall of Beatrice, Nebr., ex-President of the Nebraska State Board of Health, will prepare a paper on either "State Sanitary Survey," or "Our Much Needed New State Constitution." Dr. P. F. Dodson of Wilbur, Nebr., ex-President of the Nebraska State Board of Health, will prepare a paper or take part in the discussion. Dr. A. L. Muirhead of Omaha, Nebr., ex-President of the Nebraska State Board of Health, has not yet deter - mined whether he will prepare a paper or lead in discus - sion. Dr. W. H. Wilson, ex-State Health Inspector, and also Dr. S. R. Towne of Omaha, Nebr., ex-State Health In - spector, will both prepare papers or lead in discussions. Dr. Wm. Edmonds, Health Officer of Nebraska City, has been asked to take part on the program as has also Dr. D. T. Quigley of Omaha, Nebr. Dr. George Shidler of York, Nebr., will prepare a paper on "My Experience With Boards of Health." </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 5 Dr. E. B. Hanna of York, Nebr., will talk on the sub - ject of "Whooping Cough." Dr. Chauncey F. Chapman, Superintendent of Health Lincoln, Nebr., will speak on "Methods of Vaccination in Public Schools." We have the assurance of such men as Dr. E. S. Ragan, Health Officer of Seward, Nebr. Dr. H. A. Schultz of Sutton, Nebr. Dr. Arthur Wade, Lexington, Nebr. Dr. J. N. Campbell, Stanford, Nebr. Dr. S. J. Stewart, Hastings, Nebr. Dr. J. J. Workman, Milford, Nebr. Dr. E. J. Latta, Lincoln, Nebr. Dr. C. W. Jester, Bethany, Nebr. Dr. J. F. Spealman, Lincoln, Nebr., ex-health officer. Dr. Benj. R. McCrath, Grand Island, Nebr. Dr. P. C. Kelly, Grand Island, Nebr. Dr. Harry H. Thompson, David City, Nebr. and others who will take part in the discussions of the different papers. Aside from the medical profession, we will have a number of distinguished men and women on the program who will address the meeting. Willis E. Reed, Attorney General, Lincoln, Nebr. Subject to be announced. A. 0. Thomas, Superintendent Public Instruction, Lincoln, Nebr. Subject, "School Inspection." Judge Kennedy of the State Board of Control, who favored us with such a splendid paper last year, has con - sented to prepare another for this meeting. George E. Johnson, State Engineer. "Relations of the Engineer to the State Board of Health." Mrs. K. R. J. Edholm of Omaha, Nebr., Executive Secretary Nebraska Association for the Study and Pre - vention of Tuberculosis, will have a paper on "The Fun of Being a Health Officer." She will also give a report of the National Tuberculosis Association held at In - dianapolis, Ind., and will be discussed by Dr. C. A. Lutzen. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska State Board of Health We wish to acknowledge our indebtedness to the physi - cians of Omaha and to the Commercial Club for the interest they are taking in this meeting, and we feel that with their co-operation and the large attendance at our previous meet - ings, that we will have a large representation from over the state, and but few local Boards of Health will fail to send a representative. Although our program will be somewhat ex - tensive we feel, by excluding all forms of entertainment and conforming ourselves strictly to business, we can cover the entire program satisfactorily and that all who desire will have an opportuniyt to present their views on the different subjects. We urgently request that representatives from local Boards of Health express their views on the different topics presented. We are also anxious to impress on the representa - tives the fact that although it is necessary to prepare a pro - gram, we realize that this is their meeting, and the greatest benefit that we will derive will be from the discussions and the opinions of those in the field. We have recently adopted a new sanitary code for this State which we feel is abreast of any in the Union. If pos - sible it will be issued and in the hands of the physicians and health officers of the State before our meeting. The laws and rules therein will be explained, their necessity given and means of putting them in effect. Quarantine rules and regulations will be thoroughly dis - cussed and means for the prevention of the spread of diseases will be presented by men of experience and who are qualified to handle the subject. The question of water pollution and the prevention of water borne diseases will be thoroughly discussed. We would earnestly request that the physicians in every town in the State urge the necessity of sending a representa- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 7 tive to these meetings that they may familarize themselves with the laws and rules governing sanitation and disease pre - vention. Certificates of Attendance will be issued by the secretary to those who attend both days, in order that the local author - ities will be assured of their attendance, that they may receive their expenses. H. B. CUMMINS, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska State Board of Health THE LAW RELATING TO MATTERS AFFECTING OR TOUCHING PUBLIC HEALTH AND VITAL STATISTICS and REGULAIONS ADOPTED BY THE NEBRASKA STATE BOARD OF HEALTH Rule 1. The Board of Secretaries are directed and au - thorized to organize by electing from their membership, a president, vice president, secretary and treasurer. RULE 2. The Secretary of the Board of Secretaries shall keep a record of all proceedings, receipts, expenditures and of every matter presented to the Board of Secretaries, and shall present any and all matters to the State Board of Health at the request of the State Board of Health. Rule 3. Complaints with reference to unsanitary condi - tions within the jurisdiction of the State Board of Health shall be referred to the Secretary of the State Board of Health who will order such inspection or investigation as is deemed neces - sary. The State Health Inspector or any member of the Board acting as such inspector shall file with the Secretary of the Board a copy of the complaint, his finding and recommenda - tions. Rule 4. The State Health Inspector, under the authority of the Board shall proceed according to the law to abate any unhealthy conditions which he may find through investigation or inspection. Rule 5. The several county health officers and the health officers of all incorporated cities and villages in the state shall make quarterly reports as to the general sanitary conditions of their counties, city and village ; such reports bearing espe - cially upon matters relating to communicable diseases. Rule 6. The several county health officers and health officers of each incorporated city or village shall keep close watch over apparent epidemic or endemic diseases existing </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 9 within their respective jurisdiction and if a question arises as to the proper care of such diseases, they shall notify the State Board of Health in order that an investigation may be had. RULE 7. If county health officer or health officer of any incorporated city or village has knowledge or a reasonable belief that the return of births and deaths for his county, city or village is not being made as required by law, he shall im - mediately report such fact or suspicion to the State Board of Health. Rule 8. If any county, city or village health officer has knowledge or reason to believe that death certificates, burial permits or permits for removal of dead bodies are not being filed, or issued in accordance to law, he shall immediately report such fact or suspicion to the State Board of Health. Rule 9. The several county health officers shall note and investigate conditions of slaughter houses, rendering estab - lishments, factories, creameries, mills, railroad stock yards, private pens or stock yards within city or village limits, livery barns, city or village water supply and sources, city or village sewerage management and disposal, public buildings or any matter touching or affecting the public health and sanitation within their respective jurisdiction and shall report such con - dition to the State Board of Health from time to time as pro - vided by rule one of this section. Rule 10. County, city or village boards of health shall at all times bring to the attention of the State Board of Health any or all conditions which they may deem in need of sanitary inspection or investigation by the State Board of Health. Rule 11. The county, city or village health officers shall assemble at least once a year and as often as is deemed neces - sary, or on call of the State Board of Health to discuss gen - eral sanitary problems and to present at such conferences the special sanitary needs of their individual districts. Rule 12. County, city or village health officer shall make such investigation and reports and obey such directions relat- </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska State Board of Health ing to sanitary conditions and problems, as shall be prescribed from time to time by the State Board of Health. Rule 13. No person, co-partnership, corporation, or any officer, agent, servant or employee thereof shall knowingly sell, furnish or give away, for drinking or potable purposes to any person, co-partnership, or corporation, water which has been condemned or which is obtained from a source of supply that has been condemned by the State Board of Health or its lawfully authorized officers, agents or employees, until and unless such water has been purified by some method approved by the State Board of Health, or until and unless the condem - nation placed upon said water, or its said source of supply has been removed or set aside by said Board. The word corporation as used in this section of the rules and regulations of the State Board of Health shall include municipal corporations, as well as private corporations. Aside from the above special rules there has been adopted a Sanitary Code, governing quarantine and the prevention of the spread of contagious diseases, which will be published in book form and sent to physicians, superintendents of public instruction and county clerks. The above are simply general rules governing sanitation and are published for the purpose of giving the public an insite into the duties of the local Boards of Health and health officers. As this is the time of the year that contagious diseases are most prevelant, and, when precautions could be taken to prevent their spread, I publish a part of the rules that have been adopted by the Board. These rules take effect January 1, 1916, when they will become a law and all persons should familiarize themselves with them to avoid trouble. One of the things that we must impress on health officers and also upon parents and guardians is the fact that they are held equally responsible and will be prosecuted for their neglect. I am sorry to say that there are people who will permit their chil - dren to enter school when they have knowledge or a suspicion that their children have a mild case of Scarlet Fever, Whoop - ing Cough, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 11 Rule 1. Exclusion from Schools and Public Gatherings, Etc. No person suffering from Asiatic cholera (cholerine), smallpox, typhus fever, bubonic plague, diphtheria (mem - branous croup), scarlet fever ( scar let ina), measles, including rotheln, whooping cough, cerebrospinal meningitis or po - liomyelitis shall be admitted into any public, parochial, or priv - ate school, college or Sunday school, or shall enter any assem - blage, or railway car, street car, vessel, or steamer, or other public conveyance. Rule 2. Exclusion from Schools and Public Gatherings, Etc., of the Well Members of the Family. No person shall be admitted to any public, parochial, or private school, or col - lege, or Sunday school, from any family in which Asiatic chol - era (cholerine), smallpox, typhus fever, bubonic plague, diph - theria (membranous croup), scarlet fever (scarlatina), meas - les, including rotheln, cerebrospinal meningitis, poliomyelitis or whooping cough exists. Rule 3. Responsibility of Parents, Guardians, Etc. No parent, guardian or other person having charge or control of any child or children shall allow or permit such child or chil - dren to go from any family in which a case of Asiatic cholera (cholerine), smallpox, typhus fever, bubonic plague, diph - theria (membranous crop), scarlet fever (scarlatina), meas - les, including rotheln, cerebrospinal meningitis, poliomyelitis, or whooping cough has recently occurred, without a permit from the Board of Health or its proper officer. Rule 4. Reporting Cases of Disease by Physician. It shall be the duty of every physician called to attend a person sick, or supposed to be sick, with any of the diseases declared to be dangerous and contagious diseases by the State Board of Health, within twenty-four hours thereafter to report, in writ - ing, the name and residence of such person to the Board of Health, or its proper officer, within whose jurisdiction such person is found, and where a person is taken sick with any of the aforesaid named diseases as are declared dangerous and contagious by the State Board of Health, and a physician is i </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska State Board of Health 12 not called, it shall in like manner be the duty of the owner or agent of the building in which such person resides, lives, or is staying, or of the head of the family in which such disease occurs, to report, in writing, the name and residence of the patient to the local Board of Health or its proper officer. RULE 9. Reporting Cases of Disease Presumably Com - municable in Schools. When no physician is in attendance, it shall be the duty of every teacher to report forthwith to the principal or person in charge of the school all facts relating to the illness and physical condition of any child in such school who appears to be affected with a disease presumably com - municable. It shall be the duty of the principal or person in charge of every school to report forthwith to the local health officer all facts relating to the illness and physical condition of any child attending such school, who appears to be affected with any disease presumably communicable, together with the name, age and address of such child. Such child shall at once be sent home or isolated. Rule 10. Reporting Cases of Disease Presumably Com - municable in Hotels, Private Households, Boarding and Lodg - ing Houses. When no physician is in attendance, it shall be the duty of the head of a private household or the proprietor or keeper of any hotel, boarding house, or lodging house, to report forthwith to the local health officer all facts relating to the illness and physical condition of any person in any private household, hotel, boarding house or lodging house under his charge, who appears to be affected with any disease presum - ably communicable, together with the name of such person. Rule 11. Reporting Cases of Disease Presumably com - municable by Nurses and Persons in Charge of Camps. It shall be the duty of every visiting nurse and public health nurse and of the person in charge of any labor or other camp, having knowledge of any person affected with any disease presumably communicable, who by reason of the danger to others seems to require the attention of the public health au - thorities, to report at once to the local officer, within whose </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 13 jurisdiction such case occurs, all facts relating to the illness and physical condition of such affected person. Rule 12. Reporting Cases of Communicable Disease on Dairy Farms by Physicians. When a case of Asiatic cholera, diphtheria, amoebic or bacillary dysentery, epidemic cerebro - spinal meningitis, epidemic or septic sore throat, measles, scar - let fever, smallpox, or typhoid fever exists on any farm or dairy producing milk, cream, butter, or other dairy products for sale, it shall be the duty of the physician in attendance to report immediately to the local health officer the existence on such farm or dairy of such case. It shall be the duty of the health officer to report imme - diately to the secretary of the State Board of Health by tele - phone or telegram, the existence on such farm or dairy of such case, and giving the names of the localities to which such dairy products are delivered. Rule 13. Reporting Cases of Disease Presumably Com - municable on Dairy Farms by Oivner or Person in Charge. When no physician is in attendance, it shall be the duty of the owner or person in charge of any farm or dairy producing milk, cream, butter, cheese, or other food products likely to be consumed raw, to report forthwith to the local health officer the name and address and all facts relating to the illness and physical condition of any person, who is affected with any disease presumably communicable, and who is employed or resides on or in such farm or dairy or comes in contact in any way therewith or with its products. RULE 16. Removal of Cases of Communicable Disease. After isolation by the local Board of Health no person, without permission from the local Board of Health shall carry, remove, or cause or permit to be carried or removed from any room, building or vessel, any person affected with diphtheria, scarlet fever, smallpox, of typhus fever. Without permission from the local Board of Health no person shall carry, remove or cause or permit to be carried or removed from any hotel, boarding house, lodging house, or other dwelling, any person affected with chickenpox, diph- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska State Board ok Health theria, epidemic cerebrospinal meningitis, epidemic or septic sore throat, measles, mumps, polimyelitis infantile paraly - sis), scarlet fever, smallpox, typhus fever, or whooping cough. Rule 17. Removal of Articles Contaminated with Infec - tive Material. Without permission from the local health of - ficer no person shall carry, remove, or cause or permit to be carried or removed from any room, building, or vessel, any article which has been subject to contamination with infective material through contact with any person or with the secre - tions of any persons affected with Asiatic cholera, diphtheria, scarlet fever, smallpox, typhoid fever, or typhus fever, until each article has been disinfected according to the special rules and regulations of the state department of health. Rule 18. Right of Entrance and Inspection. No person shall interfere with or obstruct the entrance to any house, building, by an inspector or officer of the state or local health authorities, in the discharge of his official duties, nor shall any person interfere with or obstruct the inspection or exam - ination of any occupant of any such house or building, by any inspector or officer of the state or local health authorities, in the discharge of his official duties. Any persons violating these rules are subject to a fine or imprisonment or both at the discretion of the Court. Our Laws, Rules and Regulations governing all matters pertaining to Public Health and Sanitation will be in the hands of the authorities in a very short time. Anyone wishing fur - ther information concerning these laws, rules and regulations may obtain same by consulting the health authorities. The proposed rules and regulations pertaining to tuber - culosis that were published in the last issue of the Bulletin have been adopted by the Board and will take effect January 1. 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 15 RULES FOR SCHOOLS— SANITARY REGULATION OF Rule 1. All sites upon which schoolhouses are erected or maintained should be dry, and such drainage as may be necessary to secure and maintain dry grounds and dry build - ings should be selected and supplied. Rule 2. Each pupil in each school building should be sup - plied with not less than 200 cubic feet of free air space. Rule 3. The interior walls and ceiling of all rooms and school buildings that are occupied for study or recitation should be either tinted or painted with some neutral color, such as gray, slate, buff, or green. RULE 4. All school rooms where pupils are seated for study should be lighted from one side only where possible, and the glass area should not be less than one-sixth of the floor space. Rule 5. The windows in each such school room should be provided with roller or adjustable shades of neutral color, such as blue, slate, buff or green. Rule 6. Desks and desk seats should preferably be ad - justable, and at least 20 per cent of all desks and desk seats in each room should be adjustable and should be placed that the light shall fall over the left shoulder of the pupil. Rule 7. Blackboards should be of a dead black without gloss and in no instance should such blackboards be placed on any walls in which there is an opening through which light is permitted to enter the room. RULE 8. All schoolhouses should be supplied with pure and unpolluted drinking water, and no water for drinking purposes be supplied unless such supply and the source thereof should, after a thorough investigation, be approved by the Board of Health. Rule 9. All schoolhouse wells or pumps should be sup - plied with efficient drains to take away waste water, and under </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska State Board of Health no condition should pools or sodden places or small or large mudholes be allowed to exist within 50 feet of such well. Rule 10. Wherever it is practicable sanitary drinking fountains which do not require drinking cups should be pro - vided, and in no case shall a drinking cup for common use be permitted. Rule 11. When water is not supplied from faucets or sanitary drinking fountains, then covered tanks or coolers, supplied with spring or self-closing faucets should be provided. Where such coolers or tanks are supplied, each such tank or cooler should be thoroughly cleansed and scalded once during each week that it is so used, and such tanks should be emptied and refilled with fresh water each day they are so used. Rule 12. Heaters of all kinds used in schools should be capable of maintaining a temperature of 70 degrees F. in freez - ing weather within said schools. Rule 13. Schoolrooms should be provided with such means of ventilation that will withdraw the air from the room and replace the same at least four times every hour. Rule 14. Every schoolhouse that is situated on or near a line of improved public sewer and water main should be pro - vided with properly installed flush closets for the use of each sex. RULE. 15 Every schoolhouse should be kept in a clean and sanitary condition at all times. The grounds, halls, passage - ways, study rooms, cloak rooms, water-closets, lavatories, and outbuildings should be kept free from accumulations of dust, dirt, trash, rubbish, filth, and refuse of all sorts whatsoever at all times. Rule 16. Wherever the floors of any school building or part thereof are constructed of wood and not covered with any covering, such floors should be oiled at least four times in each school year. All such floors should be thoroughly swept at the end of each day such building are in use, and all furniture </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 17 and fixtures should be freed from dust each day in some such manner, that said dust should be taken up in the process and should not be distributed through the atmosphere in the room. Rule 17. The windows in all schoolhouses shall be kept clean at all times, and all schoolhouses, together with their out - buildings, should be effectively closed and barred from in - truders at all times when not in actual use. We are pleased to note the interest that is being taken in our bulletins by the schools of our State. It is always our purpose to make the bulletins both interesting and instructive to those who will take the time to read them. Following is one of the many letters that have been received by the depart - ment requesting us to mail out copies of the bulletin : Dr. H. B. Cumins, Seward, Nebr. My dear Sir: I am just in receipt of the October copy of bulletin No. 4, issued by the Nebraska State Board of Health. I should like very much to have you mail a copy of this bulletin to each of the teachers of this county and am, therefore, enclosing here - with a list of the teachers of Dodge county with the request that you kindly mail them direct any bulletins that your board may issue from time to time. Thanking you for this favor, I am, Very truly yours, J. M. MATZEN, County Supt. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska State Board of Health VITAL STATISTICS To the Honorable State Board of Health, Dear Sirs : I wish to submit the following report. Dur - ing the last half of the present year the inspector visited the following places once, and some of them twice to investigate insanitary conditions and settle disputes in regard to diag - nosis, quarantine and sanitation. The towns .visited are Uni - versity Place, Wahoo, Giltner, Benkelman, Indianola, Stanton, Linwood, Grand Island, Lexington, Thurston, Wayne, Eagle, Fairbury, Omaha, Ravenna, Seneca, McCool Junction, Brad - shaw, Central City, Prosser, Beatrice, Exeter, Nebraska City, Valparaiso, Holdrege and Falls City. During this period there has been more smallpox than in the corresponding period of time last year, owing to the cold damp weather which has been particularly condusive to that disease which is shown by the prevalence and spread during the summer months of this year. Other contagious diseases have averaged about the same. In all places visited, without a single exception, the department received the hearty co-op - eration of the local health officers which resulted in obtaining a higher degree of sanitation and in checking epidemics. The statutes of the state having given the Board of Health the superivision of collecting and compiling vital statistics, the returns are made from every city and village in the state by the local registrars who are appointed by this department. These records which cover a period of eleven years are exceed - ingly valuable. This department has found the late reports to be better than those heretofore, which no doubt is due to the fact that the local registrars and physicians are realizing the importance and value of complete records. Respectfully submitted, J. D. CASE,, M. D. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 19 DEATHS BY COUNTIES FOR 1915 Adams Adams 335 335 Grant 11 Grant 11 Antelope 89 Antelope 89 Greeley 28 Greeley 28 Arthur 2 Arthur 2 Hall 247 Hall 247 Blaine 7 Blaine 7 Hamilton 114 Hamilton 114 Boone 84 Boone 84 Harlan 68 Harlan 68 Box Butte ! 94 Box Butte \ 94 Hayes 15 Hayes 15 Boyd 32 Boyd 32 Hitchcock 37 Hitchcock 37 Brown 47 Brown 47 Holt 131 Holt 131 Buffalo 228 Buffalo 228 Hooker n Hooker 11 Burt 146 Burt 146 Howard 68 Howard 68 Butler 122 Butler 122 Jefferson 121 Jefferson 121 Cass 156 Cass 156 Johnson 92 Johnson 92 Cedar 104 Cedar 104 Kearney 62 Kearney 62 Chase 17 Chase 17 Keith 16 Keith 16 Cherry 72 Cherry 72 Keya Paha 10 Keya Paha 10 Cheyenne 40 Cheyenne 40 Knox 92 Knox 92 Clay 120 Clay 120 Lancaster 1020 Lancaster 1020 Colfax 78 Colfax 78 Lincoln ~ 114 Lincoln ~ 114 Cuming '.. 102 Cuming [. 102 Logan 15 Logan 15 Custer 136 Custer 136 Loup 8 Loup 8 Dakota 47 Dakota 47 McPherson 1 McPherson 1 Dawes 50 Dawes 50 Madison 242 Madison 242 Dawson 110 Dawson 110 Merrick 72 Merrick 72 Deuel 7 Deuel Morrill 20 Morrill 20 7 Dixon 67 Dixon 67 Nance 37 Nance 37 Dodge 205 Dodge 205 Nemaha 76 Nemaha 76 Douglas 2480 Douglas 2480 Nuckolls ., 100 Nuckolls ., 100 Dundy 35 Dundy 35 Otoe 154 Otoe 154 Fillmore 123 Fillmore 123 Pawnee 77 Pawnee 77 Franklin 87 Franklin 87 Perkins 13 Perkins 13 Frontier 42 Frontier 42 Phelps 94 Phelps 94 Furnas 76 Furnas 76 Pierce 84 Pierce 84 Gage 299 Gage 299 Platte 170 Platte 170 Garden 18 Garden 18 Polk 58 Polk 58 Garfield 32 Garfield Gosper Red Willow 71 32 Red Willow. Richardson 71 Gosper 22 22 Richardson 156 156 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska State Board ok Health Seward 135 Sheridan 56 Sherman 45 Wheeler 8 Sioux : 8 York 121 Stanton 54 10831 CAUSE OF DEATH From Dec. 1, 1914 to Dec. 1, 1915 Typhoid Fever 86 Measles 43 Scarlet Fever 36 Whooping Cough 55 Diphtheria 79 Influenza 69 Dysentery 27 Erysipelas 26 Purulent Infection and Septicemia 104 Tetanus ■. 13 Tuberculosis of the Lungs 378 Tuberculosis Meningitis 20 Pott's Disease ....: 4 Tuberculosis of other organs 80 Syphilis 17 Cancer of the Liver, Stomach 261 Cancer of Peritonaeum, Intestines, Rectum 45 Cancer of Female Genital organs 47 Cancer of the Breast 41 Cancer of other parts 212 Other Tumors 13 Acute Rheumatism 16 Rock 14 Thayer 96 Saline 140 Thomas 4 Sarpy 72 Thurston 105 Saunders 146 Valley 66 Scotts Bluff 99 Washington 91 Wayne 64 Webster 91 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 21 Chronic Rheumatism .-. 18 Diabetis 176 Exophthalmic Goitre ...'. 15 Leuchaemia 26 Anaemia, Chlorosis 90 Alcoholism 23 Meningitis 1 17 Locomotor Ataxia 17 Other Diseases of the Spinal Cord 24 Cerebral Haemorrhage, Apoplexy 601 Softening of the Brain 21 Paralysis without specified cause 184 General Paralysis of the Insane 60 Other forms of Mental Alienation 22 Convulsions 72 Epilepsy 48 Pericarditis 21 Acute Endocarditis 88 Organic Diseases of the Heart 1163 Angina Pectoris 60 Diseases of the Arteries 184 Embolism and Thrombosis 82 Diseases of the Veins, etc 8 Haemorrhage, other Diseases of the Cir. System 28 Diseases of the Pharynx 6 Diseases of the Larynx 7 Diseases of the Lympathic System 1 Diseases of Nose and Throat 5 Bronchitis, acute 53 Bronchitis, chronic 46 Broncho, Pneumonia 212 Pneumonia 815 Pleurisy 19 Pulmonary Congestion 67 Asthma 39 Pulmonary Emphysema 35 Diseases of the Oesophagus 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska State Board of Health 22 Ulcer of the Stomach 37 Other diseases of the Stomach, Cancer excepted 78 Diarrhoea and Enteritis (under two years) 121 Diarrhoea and Enteritis (two years and over) 53 Appendicitis and Typhilitis 88 Hernia, intestinal obstruction 114 Other diseases of the Intestines 85 Cirrhosis of the Liver 86 Biliary Calculi 32 Other diseases of the Liver 47 Simple Peritonitis 153 Other diseases of the Digestive System 7 Acute Nephritis 364 Bright's Disease 288 Chyluria 1 Other diseases of the Kidney and Annexa 18 Diseases of the Bladder 39 Diseases of the Prostate 39 Cysts and other Tumors of the Ovary 3 Salpingitis and other diseases of the Female Genital Organs 2 Accidents of Pregnancy 20 Puerperal Haemorrhage. 23 Other accidents of labor 9 Puerperal Septicemia 32 Puerperal Albuminuria and Convulsions 30 Gangrene 36 Acute Abcess 2 Diseases of the Bones, Tuberculosis excepted 5 Congenital Debility, Icterus, Sclerema, etc 893 Senility 559 Suicide by poison 48 Suicide by hanging 27 Suicide by firearms .' 50 Suicide by other means 49 Accidental Poisoning 19 Accidental Drowning 49 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 23 Burns 56 Traumatism by firearms 40 Traumatism by machines 30 Traumatism by railway, vehicles, etc 68 Injuries by animals. 13 Starvation •&gt; .5 Excessive Cold.. 1 Excessive Heat •&gt;. Lightning 12 Homicides 22 Other external violence. 181 No cause 97 Cause of death not specified or ill defined. 49 111 defined organic diseases 55 Other diseases of the Respiratory System .. i Other general diseases 9 Neuralgia and Neuritis 7 Poisoning by food 6 Other diseases of the skin and annexa 3 in ex Hodgkin's Disease 6 Other diseases of the Nervous System o Absorption of Deleterious Gases, Conflagration etc 20 Chorea 1 Diseases of the Thyroid Body 3 Encephalitis 13 Calcuid of the Urinary Passage 1 Anthrax 1 Diseases of the Joints 2 Mastoiditis 2 Rickets 2 Mycosis 1 Sudden Death 4 Rabies 1 Pellagra 1 Electricity (lightning excepted) 4 White Swellings 1 Furuncle 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska State Board of Health Graves' Disease 1 Intestinal Parasites 2 Addison's Disease 1 Other Acute Poisonings 1 Still Births 458 Total 10831 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">CLASSIFICATION OF BIRTHS FROM DECEMBER 1, 1914, TO DECEMBER 1, 1915 County T. u. i C &lt; X Adams ; 273 245 518 Adams ; 273 245 518 452 35 28 2 ! 1 452 35 28 2 i 1 Antelope 153 129 282 Antelope 153 129 282 Arthur 6 3 9 Banner 3 14 Blaine 13 19 32 259 9 6 2 6 259 9 6 2 6 Arthur 6 3 9 8 1 8 1 ... Banner 3 14 4 4 Blaine 13 19 32 31 i „„ 31 1 Boone 205 203 408 Boone 205 203 408 374 13 15 2 374 13 15 2 Box Butte 100 95 195 Box Butte 100 95 195 179 10 3 2 1 179 10 3 2 1 Colfax 145 127 271 1 228 8 ll 1 26 8 .. 297 13 4 3 7 2 Cuming 169 157 326 Custer 301 293 594 Dakota 76 58 134 568 11 5 2 4 4 124 5 2 3 Dawes 67 71 138 134 1 2 1 Dawson 216 168 384 374 4 3 1 1 1 Deuel 30 29 59 54 2 2 1 Furnas 107 109 216 Furnas 107 109 216 209 4 2 ; 1 209 4 2 1 Gage 255 258 511 Gage 255 258 511 2 488 18 II 1 4 1 2 488 18 11 4 1 Garden 48 39 87 Garden 48 39 87 84 1 1 . 1 84 1 1 1 Garfield 80 86 166 Garfield 80 86 166 157 3 12 3 157 3 12 3 Gosper 35 44 79 Gosper 35 44 79 77 1 _... 1 77, 1 ........ 1 Grant 20 17 36 Grant 20 17 36 1 34 1 1 1 1 34 1 1 1 Greeley 97 68 165 Greeley 97 68 165 151 4 4 3 1 2 452 20 1 3 1 5 151 4 4 3 1 t Hall 245 237 482 Hall 245 237 482 452 20 1 3 1 5 Hamilton .... 99 81 180 Hamilton .... 99 81 180 174 2 3 1 174 2 3 1 Harlan 117 91 208 Harlan 117 91 208 ... 201 3 3 1 201 3 3 1 ... j 58 1 Hayes 32 27 59 Hayes 32 27 59 58 I 1 Hitchcock .... 53 43 96 Hitchcock .... 53 43 96 91 2 2 1 91 2 2 ! 1 Holt 198 176 374 Holt 198 176 374 359 9 3 S 27 359 9 3 I S Hooker 11 16 27 Hooker 11 16 27 27 Howard 110 108 218 Howard 110 108 218 191 3 18 1 4 1 191 3 18 1 4 1 Jefferson 191 1 187 378 Jefferson 191! 187 378 353 20 12 2 353 20 12 2 Johnson 131 I 120 251 224 21 2 2 11 Johnson 131 I 120 251 2241 21 2 2 1 1 Boyd 90 88 178 170 4 2 1 1 Brown 79 87 166 165 1 Buffalo 276 211 487 470 4 2 5 J 5 Burt 189 173 361 1 339 6 16 1 Butler 176 155 331 289 5 1 18 18 Cass 176 153 328 1 304 12 7 1 2 3 Cedar 195 202 397 356 20 13 3 2! S Chase 28 45 73 72 1 Cherry 100 84 182 2 178 3 3 Cheyenne 70 38 108 98 6 2 2 Clay 162 172 334 307 8 15 2 2 Dodge 302 373 675 644 9 6 9 7 Douglas 1970 1850 3773 47 2630 158 257 66 187 522 Dundy 52 45 97 92 4 1 Fillmore 150 112 262 241 4 8 1 6 2 Franklin 145 131 276 254 8 7 5 2 Frontier 90 70 160 149 9 1 ! 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">CLASSIFICATION OF BIRTHS FROM DECEMBER 1, 1915, TO DECEMBER 1, 1915— (Continued) I — 9 1 x I c c County a I 5 •2 1 1 1 I £ I :S « n I J Kearney 107 90 i 197 181 5 11 Keith _... 32 33 ! 65 64 1 Keya Paha... 33 25 58 57 1 _.. Kimball 5 7 12 11 1 . I Knox 224 200 423 1 387 19 9 2 5 2 Lancaster .... 917 927 1 1837 7 1507 202 87 23 3 22 ... 801 5 4 1 t Lincoln 156 1571 313 Logan 10 20 30 29 1 Loup 30 28 58 67 1 I | McPherson.... 7 7 7 Madison 248 230 478 437 17 15 2 2 5 Merrick 118 116 233 1 222 7 3 2 j Morrill ; 63 50 112 1 107 2 3 1 Nance 117 112 229 209 7 4 _ t Nemaha 135 128 263 260 2 1 Nuckolls 148 127 275 254 3 14 4 Otoe 193 192 385 363 17 3 1 1 Pawnee l 117 98 215 211 3 i 1 Perkins 17 9 36 35 1 Phelps 89 100 189 183 5 ; 1 ! Pierce 175 138 313 286 18 7 1 1 Platte 273 233 504 2 , 441 27 3 7 1 27 228 1 16 1 Polk 125 121 246 Red Willow.. 115 105 220 Richardson.... 245 206 451 198 7 13 1 1 441 3 1 111 5 Rock ■ 39 44 83 79 2 1 ' 1 Saline 207 162 369 335 10 1 2 18 3 Sarpy 137 113 250 231 14 2 3 Saunders 210 210 420 Scotts Bluff.. 149 120 265 374 10 19 3 7 7 4 222 21 20 1 I • Seward 198 161 359 333 10 9 3 4 1 1M: 8 l! 1 1 Sheridan 96 108 203 Sherman 135 115 250 222 10 7 2 1 8 12 1 1 Sioux i 8 6 14 Stanton 121 84 195 170 12 3 8 2 Thayer 134 139 273 Thomas 16 9 25 257 8 6 2 16 9 25 25 Thurston 153 153 257 49 281 9 13 1 2 Valley 142 102 244 211 3 9 2 8 5 Washington... 156 109 265 242: 8 12 3 Wayne 130 115 245 198 31 16 1 Webster 158 147 305 296 61 1 11 29 1 Wheeler 16 14 30 York 201 1 165 366 343 8 ! 10 3 2 Total i 14139 13047 27065 ! 121 I 24109 i 1002 794 '• 182 ' 342 757 Twins: M. 171; F. 125; W. 296; Amer. 258; For. 38. 148 pairs twins. Tripletts: M. 1; F. 2; W. 3; Amer. 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 27 REPORT OF MARRIAGES BY COUNTIES FOR 1914 Adams 259 Hayes 16 Antelope 150 Hitchcock M Blaine 20 Holt 141 Boone 98 Hooker 2! Box Butte 143 Howard 77 Boyd Jefferson 71 187 Buffalo . Johnson 239 78 Burt 6.', Kearney 4:; Butler 111 Keith 58 Cass ]22 Keya Paha 17 Cedar 116 Kimball 62 Chase 22 Knox 135 Cheyenne 161 Lancaster 929 Clay Lincoln 104 173 Coif ax Logan 88 83 Cuming Loup 102 3 J , Custer 170 McPherson 11 Dakota 241 Madison 131 Dawes 108 Merrick 92 Dawson 113 Morrill 78 Dixon 87 Nance 80 Dodge Nemaha 301 114 Douglas Nuckolls 2421 87 Dundy Otoe 196 6&lt;&gt; Fillmore 102 Pawnee 8-, Franklin 71 Perkins 21 Frontier 42 Phelps 8&gt; Furnas 6.", Pierce 101 Gage 226 Platte 18' 1 Garfield Polk 51 62 Gosper Red Willow 113 38 Grant 20 Richardson 159 Greeley 48 Rock 39 Hall 343 Saline 111 Hamilton- 9.°, Sarpy 168 Harlan 85 Saunders 147 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 - Nebraska State Nebraska State Board of Health 28 Scotts Bluff 154 Scotts Bluff 154 Valley 89 Valley 89 Seward 134 Seward 134 Washington 120 Washington 120 Sheridan 63 Sheridan 63 Wayne 95 Wayne 95 Sherman 63 Sherman 63 Webster 92 Webster 92 Sioux 38 Sioux 38 Wheeler 7 Wheeler 7 Stanton 59 Stanton 59 York 157 York 157 Thayer 118 Thayer 118 Thomas 19 Thomas 19 Total 11934 Total 11934 Thurston 84 Thurston 84 DIVORCE REPORTS, 1914 Adams 42 Adams 42 Dixon 4 Dixon 4 Antelope 23 Antelope 23 Dodge 63 Dodge 63 Arthur 1 Arthur 1 Douglas 649 Douglas 649 Banner 1 Banner 1 Dundy 4 Dundy 4 Blaine 2 Blaine 2 Fillmore 9 Fillmore 9 Boone 9 Boone 9 Franklin _ 10 Franklin 10 Box Butte 33 Box Butte 33 Frontier 8 Frontier 8 Boyd 6 Boyd 6 Furnas 16 Furnas 16 Brown 16 Brown 16 Gage 46 Gage 46 Buffalo 36 Buffalo 36 Garden 10 Garden 10 Burt 14 Burt 14 Garfield 6 Garfield 6 Butler 13 Butler 13 Gosper 3 Gosper 3 Cass 26 Cass 26 Greeley 5 Greeley 5 Cedar 4 Cedar 4 Hall 49 Hall 49 Chase 2 Chase 2 Hamilton 7 Hamilton 7 Cherry 21 Cherry 21 Harlan 9 Harlan 9 Cheyenne 16 Cheyenne 16 Hayes 2 Hayes 2 Clay 3 Clay 3 Holt 24 Holt 24 Colfax 5 Colfax 5 Howard 6 Howard 6 Cuming 13 Cuming 13 Jefferson 26 Jefferson 26 Custer 21 Custer 21 Johnson * 6 Johnson * 6 Dakota 5 Dakota 5 Kearney 6 Kearney 6 Dawes 17 Dawes 17 Keith 6 Keith 6 Dawson 14 Dawson 14 Keya Paha 2 Keya Paha 2 v </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Third Annual Bulletin No. 1 29 Knox Knox 19 19 Rock 5 Rock 5 Lancaster 243 Lancaster 243 Saline 13 Saline 13 Lincoln 21 Lincoln 21 Sarpy 17 Sarpy 17 Loup 4 Loup 4 Saunders 11 Saunders 11 McPherson 3 McPherson Scotts Bluff 16 •7 Scotts Bluff 16 ,) Madison 42 Madison 42 Seward 11 Seward 11 Merrick 9 Merrick 9 Sheridan 12 Sheridan 12 Morrill 10 Morrill 10 Sherman 1 Sherman 1 Nance 5 Nance 5 Sioux 2 Sioux 2 Nemaha 14 Nemaha 14 Stanton 2 Stanton 2 Nuckolls 8 Nuckolls 8 Thayer 4 Thayer „ 4 Otoe 19 Otoe 19 Thomas , 4 Thomas , 4 Pawnee 3 Pawnee 3 Thurston 32 Thurston 32 Perkins 1 Perkins 1 Valley 10 Valley 10 Washington 4 Phelps 12 Phelps 12 Washington 4 Pierce 11 Pierce 11 Wayne 5 Wayne 5 Platte 6 Platte 6 Webster 15 Webster 15 Polk 7 Polk 7 York 3 York 3 Red Willow 22 Red Willow 22 Richardson 19 Richardson 19 Total 1964 Total 1964 </seg>
            <seg id="p030">a 1 JSuipuaj y x f. 5 paiu«jo y. — s o a I S3 I t&gt; ™ •*&lt;-'•-'«■♦ :rt :n : :«■* : ec 11 : 10 0» I s 1 5 T M ! SI E ? : &gt; U I ' v ■ • : : ! : • § IliiiigiiiiiilJls^lEEilfi Suipuaj — ;** ; i I- 1 * I passiuisiQ r*- 1 i*-* 10 ■ rr^ :H«c&gt;H«eeMNO&gt;«NHO&gt;«&gt;aiSH&gt;et-n«t-a« pSJUBJQ Nw: N HHrtHH 9 N H« MO I * j LLU_ 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 1 j j 1 1. j - ■ ■a k Mrtrt ; :rt ; :^ : : : : : :^i : : i^ec : : ; : n « : 5 I ! rt - q\ ' ___ . » to an : ;« e-i c. ?i - :::::«:: s*4 !H«« C a [ El &lt;m »i : : : rt r-i :hhnio : :«H :isn : : .-&lt; : e&gt;) : e- o 3 1 01 ! i I !&gt; l~ ! I i I i i ! I ! I- ! i ! ;- 15 i &lt; £ MUM jJJ i I M I | | I j | | S ►: MM Mil" 5 u rt *• : : : : : : — i X &gt; ! w S 10 °° : i i |*H(ooi- ;oo : ■.■+^t-&lt;i-i : is CJ cc : :S»N ■X N i i • i ;;■■;; | ;; ;n ;; :n :n :; : eo &lt;-i : 3 I I I I ! M 1 i i I j i I &gt; ! : I ! Mil k \o&gt;»t: </seg>
            <seg id="p031">1 Suip ISSIU. U3d «!Q I rt i ! : I " {[ li I T ill _J : : : : ! : : ; : : i i i i ■ ■ : : 1-1 iHian ! i i I I !**!**!**!** I i :*««»• I IM ; t 1 _J i : : : M : i ! ! ■ ■ : j ill &gt;»}U' «0 oooo^OrHOioMioxici»Ne«rt»^ieioN&lt;e*io&lt;in-&lt;aoio — I I "* i i 1 i"* i : i I** i I ':"•** i i i"* I '•••9 : :eomHi-4 j ; ; j : i : i : ! • ! : ! : ! : I i -hN : ;eo ; : : : ; ; : : eg :.h : ; ;« :«« jH IM*4«4*4 : ! i : : : : I ! ! I ! : I I j ■ 9 K ' B O t I g 9 : : O] 1-1 01 co &lt;-i C4 o&gt; m &lt;h i^i«4C-«4 :&lt;h : :«ia&lt;HiiniOHM : : i "- 1 i : : M : 1 a a 1 = 1 |rt j in I j 1 ; \v* 1 : j ;ihm ;ih : : ; j^x ; juswrH : 5 3 op I &lt;M j Hdrtioe :04 :&lt;H^4e4 : :««&gt;SM ; :^c ; :«&lt;h : jieMMn 2 m 0 u A ■Jl I Q V4 ; : ; jf : |M ;i- ;h :« : :ei ;m : :«w» ;:«;;: 3 i * ! j ** " 2 r •3 « :(M ; ;-»;::::::•» j : i :e &gt;i-&lt; :.-«::: 3 a i ; i i ; ; : ■ ; i ; • • • ; ; ; ; • ■ ; ; ; ; S|« ; i [ s i • i • ; : ;■;■;■•■:: ; ; i j 5 8 &gt; i : ::: i {:!!::!!!!:!: i !** I ! I ! i 1 ! ! u ::::::::::::::::::::: : : : : 1 : « &gt;h ; • i i i ; ; ; ; : 1 ; ; ; ; : ; ; ; : ; ;;;;;;■; : ; :m Eft :: :!H :: :ih ::::::: :^i : : :V&gt; : : \ o £_ II 1 1 IN III M II I I I j III III :ei :eoioeo :^ :&lt;«n :m-i««H : ri :eot-iHii : ■» n :-. — _ *&lt; : : : i i I I n i g x i ! I i i i_j s I — J | I £3 s i 2 &gt;&lt; I '_ M M I 1 M I i ; ' NNih :«::: :o&gt; :::::: :C4C4 : :W«w : :•* : !ih *■* i* i i : ! : i 10 &gt;&lt; ; i : ; i i ! ; i I i • I i i I '■ \ I OJ &gt;. I 9 : :■&gt;» :w : : : :&lt;-■ ; : :e&gt;I : &lt;i :::::: &lt;h :: :N : :.h £) ! : : ; : : i i i I i ! ; i ; ! i ! ! : </seg>
            <seg id="p032">X corn CM *rir. ti ~- c; auipuaj on : icorn : :^t M ?i cm : I co passiuisiQ 5 P^ubjo 2 r" s a * 3 1 C-. 3 b iSNN ■N ■M ■*" ; ;■• ; 9 i « •r 71 rtN g I ti «h» : ih :c-Nrtcooo •*« :iinn M s &gt; jr. * s ■ i 5 I (NCM rr Z L we: »-. K UL * t- C. t- * "N h C E 3 U 9} N&gt;-iea 71 o £ O t .1 io : c3 &lt; &lt;N"»N : : :nn IN IN iHrHN^JMN c |hh«h :mco : :isa cot- : :rtN Hl»^HM [~ i ■vn"O : „ en &lt;o h eo co co n&gt; «c » co so ri KKrHNON 5 ■ 3 I I leoonHteioMt-Boiiot-NoieooNrtNNH^iooTiiiooco ce §• j* °? .° 3 ■^« cc &lt;x = 11 i I i ! ! Wii i i MI M i ! ! ! ! MJ i M lllllllllilllllllillillllJlll </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>