<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00049.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00049.00030</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>How to Select Good Layers</title>
               <date value="1920-07">1920-07</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">July, 1920 ircular 12 1 How to Select Good Layers FRANK E. MISSKHL A GOOD LAYING HEN. TRAPXEST RECORD, 231 EliCiS IN ONE YEAR AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN </seg>
            <seg id="p002">GOOD LAYERS 1. Mature early for the breed ~2. Are vigorous .'i. Have good capacitv 4. Moult late 5. Moult quickly ('). Have faded shanks (yellow shanked varieties) POOR LAYERS 1. Mature slowly 2. Moult early 3. Moult slowlv 4. Shanks hold color 5. Have thick pelvic bonee — poor capacity </seg>
            <seg id="p003">HOW TO SELECT THE GOOD LAYERS KRANK K. MISSKIII A typical farm Hock of ninety-four hens was culled by a poultry specialist last July and a few suggestions made as to improved methods of feeding. The report which the owner of the flock submits indicates the advantages of culling and the promptness with which results are secured if this work is care - fully done. The report on culling this Fillmore county Hock is as follows: The results in this instance cannot all l»e accredited to culling but is partly due to the improved opportunity which the U'tter birds had to secure feed and care, but this does not minimize the necessity of culling but rather places additional einphasi - on it. Certain standard methods of selecting good laying hens have l&gt;een developed as a result of observations made at the laving contests and at other places where trapnesting is being done. The first quality which is definitely established as being necessary in high egg production is body capacity and vigor. BODY CAPACITY AND VIGOR Heavy layers are hearty eaters and must necessarily convert a relatively large amount of feed into eggs. A 5-pound hen that produces 2(H) eggs in a year must convert about !&gt;0 pounds of raw material in the form of grains and by-products over into the finished product — eggs. Plenty of room for a large fully developed digestive and reproductive system is. therefore, very important, and the term used to denote this quality is capacity. Comparative length and breadth of the body cavity is usually measured by finger widths, the two measurements which are ob - served iM'ing the distance between the pelvic or lay bones, and the distance from the end of the breast bone to the pelvic bones. Body width is indicated by the distance between the two pelvic bones, depth and length by the distance from the breast bone to the pelvic bones. Before cnllin&lt;r (!»4 hens) After cullinjr &lt;:&gt;o lit-iis) Dale K£K S l»i'l July -2.") II July 26 s July 1" 10 July 31 J."» Auji. 1 15 Aujr. -1 -Ji» 29 f.l </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Xkkraska Exphument Station Circular 12 4 MEASURING THE CAPACITY FOR EGG PRODUCTION The laying capacity of hens may he estimated hv noting the distance (1) between the lay bones; and (2) the distance from the end of the breast bone to the lay bones. The best layers in a typical Hock will indicate a body depth of four or more fingers when in laying condition while the poorest hens may not indicate more than "two-finger" capacity. The distant* :&gt; between the pelvic bones may also vary from one to three fingers in width in birds of the same variety. —^ t — — — —^ - Emphasis should heiv be placed on the fact that capacity measurements will vary with the breeds so that the same standard should not be used, for instance, for both Leghorn^ and Orping - tons. A Leghorn with three-finger body depth capacity will represent an expected high producer while Orpingtons with three- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">.) THE SKELETAL STRUCTURE OF A HEX The bone marked A is the breast bone and the bones marked B are the pelvic or lay bones. An estimate of the laying capacity of a hen may be made by noting ihe distances between these bones. How to Select the (jood Layers </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Circular 12 6 S. (. W. LKCHOKN HEN. TRAPXKST RKCOKIl, .'49 KCCS IN ONE VKAK Vigor and activity are characteristics 1 good layer finger capacity are much more common. The greatest value is to be attached to the capacity tests when birds of the same general type or breed are compared. Good egg production is absolutely dependant on vigor, but not all vigorous hens are good layers, the breeding of the bird having a great influence. The general condition of the bird, symmetry and balance, strength of head and beak, are the best indicators of vigor and vitality. Great activity of the bird at feeding time, promptness to get off the roost in the morning and a reluctance to go to roost at night, are characteristics of the most vigorous birds. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">How t&lt;&gt; Sfxect tiik (toon Layers i C. RHODE ISLAND RED HEN. TRAPNEST RECORD, 215 EGGS IN ONE YEA! LAYING CONDITION An observation of the laying condition of the hen will very naturally be made at the same time that her capacity is noted. The abdomen of the good layer is soft and pliable when she i; - in good condition and laying heavily. Poor layers and birds - that use feed material for storing up fat rather than egg pro - duction will have a hard lumpy abdomen. PIGMENTATION TESTS FOR HIGH LAYERS A method of selecting good layers in a nock of naturally yellow-shanked and yellow-skinned birds is known as the pigmen - tation test. Pullets which have been naturally raised usually </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nkkkaska Kxpkkimknt Station Cum ti.ar 12 8 have a conHiderable amoiinl of piginented IkxIv fat stored in the skin, shanks and other sections of the body, fhiring a period of heavy laying there is a tendency to draw on this reserve fat supply for egg-making material. The color pigment is removed with the fat and the shank and skin becomes much lighter in color. In a yellow shanked flock in which all birds are given the same feed and can, the better layers may be selected after several months of heavy laying by means of the light colored shank characteristic. Poor layers will always have a considerable amount of the yellow pigment in the shanks and skin. LATE MOULTING TEST A study of trapnest records shows that hens which lay over a comparatively long period make the l&gt;est annual egg records. It has also lieen observed that certain hens will lay persistently and then moult quickly while others will insist on a four-mouths vacation for the moulting job. Those hens which moult early and slowly are poor layers while the persistent layers that moult late alwavs have l&gt;etter records. EARLY MATURITY It has also been observed that of a group of birds hatched at the same time and given the same care, the best layers arc those that mature earliest. Pullets that begin to lay in October. November and December and lay consistently until the following November always have better records than those that do not begin laying until January. February or March and probablv stop laying before October. With good care and management Leghorns should l&gt;e matured in 200 days, Rhode Island Reds. Wyandottes and Plymouth Rocks in 225 days and Orpingtons in 240 days from date of hatching. USE OF TRAPNEST While flocks can be very efficiently culled l»v means of the physical characteristics mentioned above, the evidence which is so secured is circumstantial and is recommended for use especially because of its convenience. Even in flocks of carefully culled birds there will still be great variation in egg production and the use of the trapnest is the only way to get positive evidence of egg-laying ability or lack of it. Though the trapnesting of the great majority of farm flocks is not practical, the securing of breeding stock, especially pedigreed cockerels, from stock that has been trapnested is practical and is, therefore, suggested, (ireatest returns will be secured from the farm flock when proper attention is paid not only to culling and selection but to breeding and to feeding as well. (5M) </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>