<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00017">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00017</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>American History January 1, 1900--December 31, 1901</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-06</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">• American History January 1, 1900— December 31, 1901 By I ) . \V. CALDWELL Professor of Anu'ricnn Ilistorv I'niversity of Nebraska Published by the STATK OK NEBRASKA DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION LINCOLN 1902 ALLKIGHTS KESBKVkl) I I AIR. NRBR Danish Lulh. Publ. Hi&gt;u» KM </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">tthe teachers ol American history in Nebraska into whose hands this little work may fall: It asks to be judged leniently, as it has come into being through and tribulations., jostled and crowded aside by class prepara - and examination papers; laid aside and picked up again with little regard^for its tender youth. However, it is here at last, lopes it may help to give to Nebraska boys and girls a little bet - ipportunity to know the life of their well-loved country. It its teachers to use it wisely, and not force its readers to commit hronological table to memory, or recite verbatim the list of ;s or amount of imports. It wishes to be discussed and under- I, but not to be memorized. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">A HISTORY 190J OUTLINE OF AMERICAN January I, 1900— December 3», DOMESTIC AFFAIRS POLITICAL. I. Conditions —January I, lyoo. subsidy. The Tariff. apportionment. I 5. American commerce. 6. Strikes. 7. Exposition 8. Oklahoma. 9. Oil fields. Ill RELIGIOUS AND MORAL. I. Church conventions. 2. Heresy — church trials 3. Lawlessness. 4. Corruption. IV 1. Polar expeditions. 2. Electrical development. 3. Science and disease. EDUCATIONAL. 1. Endowments. 2. Freedom teac.iing. 3. National universities. 4. Traveling libraries. VI. REFORM MOVEMENTS. 1. Direct primaries. 2. Election of Senators. 3. Municipal reform. 4. Temperance movements. II. MILITARY. 1. Army and Navy. 2. Schley Court of Inquiry. 2. Steamship subsidy. 3. Elections. 4. The Neprro Question 6. Census — re INDUSTRIAL 1. Monetary. 2. Trusts. 3. Railroads. 4. Prosperity. SCIENTIFIC. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 VIII. NECROLOGY. 1. Sherman. 2. Harrison. 3. McKinley B COLONiES AND DEPENDENCIES. I. IN PACIFIC 1. Alaska. 2. Guam. 3. Samoa. 4. Hawaii. 5. Philippines. II. IN ATLANTIC. 1. Porto Rico. 2. Cuba. 3. Danish West Indies. C FOREIGN A p PAIRS. I. The Hague Conference. II. The Boers, American attitude III. Isthmian Canal. IV. The East, and America. V. The Monroe Doctrine. VI. Pan-American Congress. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DATES AND EVENTS. December 6. 1899— Gold standard bill introduced. December 18. 1899 — Gold standard bill passes House, 190—150. K anuary 2. 1900— Goebel contest in Kentucky begun. ' Secretary secures "Open Door" policy in China. January 4, 1900— Senate begins discussion of gold standard bill. Ban:ary 6. 1900.— Testimony begun on case of Senator Clark ana. Bamiary o. 1900 — Senator Beveridge's (Ind.) speech for reti.11 - of Philippines, anuary 10, 1900— Secretary Gage on sale of New York Custom Ianuary 11, 1900— Senator Pettigrew attacks President's Philip - policy, anuary 16, 1900— Senate ratines treaty for division of Samoa. annary 18. 1900 — Morgan reports favorably to Nicaragua canal. anuary 20, 1900— Report against Polygamist Roberts, anuary 23. 1900— Report against right of Quay to seat in Senate, anuary 24. 1900— Senator Pettigrew attacks treaty with Sultan of Sulu. January 30. 1930 — General Wood announces his Cuban cabinet. January 30. 1000 — Governor Goebel (of Kentucky) shot. February 3. 1900— Hague Conference treaty ratified. Bebruary 16. 1900 — House deDate begins on bill for government iwaii. B r ebruary 19. 1900— Senate debate begins on bill fur government awaii. 'ebruary 19. 1900 — Army bill introduced, ■"ebruary 23. 1900— Anti-Imperial Conference (Phil.) condemns Philippine policy February 28. 1900 — Porto Rican tariff bill passes Ho;ise, 171-162. March 1, 1900— Hawaiian bill passes Senate. Karch 9, 1900 — Eugene Debs nominated for President by Social crats. -March 14, 1900 — Gold standard bill signed. March 20, 1900 — Debate on Loud postal bill begun. March 24, 1900. — New Carnegie company organized. Capital $161,000,000. March 26, 1900 — Davis (Rep. Minn.) advocates free trade with Poito Rico. March — 1900. — Forakor (Rep. Ohio) advocates 15 per cent duty with Porto Rico. EFarch 29, 1900 — Vote to impose the 15 per cent duty — Senate pril 2. 1900.— Porto Rican tariff and government bill passes the e 40-31- April 10, 1900 — Hawaiian bill in cenferenre. April 10, 1900— Senator Clark's seat in Senate declared vacant. April is, 1900 — Porto Rican bill signed. April 12, iqoo — Senate refuses to consider Nicaragua bill, 33-15. April 13, 1900 — House votes to submit amendment, people elect lenators, 240-15. February 5. 1900— Hay-Pauncefote treaty signed </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 April 17, 1900 — Senator Hoar (Rep, Mass.) criticises Philippine p° licv - . _ . „ April 24, 1900 — Quay refused seat in Senate, 33-32. May 2, 1900— Nicaragua canal bill passes House, 225-35. May 10, 1900 — Populists nominate Bryan and Towne. May 21, 1900 — Senate refuses to consider Nicaragua canal bill, May 21, 1900 — Neely-Rathbone postal scandal — Cuba. ■May 31, 1900 — United States Supreme Court no jurisdiction in itucky election case. , une 5, 1900 — Anti-trust bill before judiciary committee. une 17, 1900— Bombardment of Taku, China. une 18, 1900 — United States troops ordered to China. , une 19, 1900 — Attack by Boxers on foreign legations, Peking. une 23, 1900 — Methodist church abolishes time limit on pastors. une 23, 1900 — Presbyterian church refers revision of creed to committee. June 30, 1900 — Surplus treasury revenue for year, $80,000,000. July 6, 1900 — Bryan and Stevenson nominated by Democrats. July 10, 1900 — Allies in China. 21,304 soldiers. July 14, 1900— Allies capture Tientsin, China. August 8. 1900 — Bryan notified of nomination — Indianapolis. August 16, 1900 — Liberty Congress declares for Bryan. August 28, 1900 — Allies enter forbidden part of city of Peking. September 4. 1900 — Peace commission appointed by China. Sentember 15, 1900— Election for Cuban Constitutional Conven- tion. Nationalists win. September 17, 1900 — Coal miners strike. B October '. 1900 — v^cal miners' strike settled; advance of 10 per in wages. ■October T2, 1900 — Judge Gray appointed on International Arbi - on Board. November 2. 1900 — Roosevelt delivered 673 speeches, traveled 21. - 209 miles during campaign. November 5. iqoo — Cuban Constitutional convention organizes. November 6. 1900 — Election — McKinley 292 votes, Bryan 155. K November 7, 1900— Treaty for two additional islands, Philippines, .000. November 15. 1900 — Censorship on messages from Manila ends. December 3. i9oo — Congress meets. December 3. 1900 — Army reorganization bill introduced. December 4, 1900 — Isthmian canal commission reports for Nic - f..a. December 4. 1900 — Ship subsidy bill taken up in Senate. December 5, 1900— Hay-Pauncefote treaty considered in Senate. 1 December 6. 1900 — Army reorganization bill passes House; vote he "canteen clause," 159-51. December II, 1900 — Debate begins on reduction of war tax. December 13, 1900 — Davis amendment to Hay-Pauncefote treaty. 65-17. ■ December 17, 1900 — Argument on Porto Rican and Philippine tar - begun before t^e Supreme Court. ■ December 18, 1900— Investigation of hazing at West Point begun Congress. December 20, 1900 — Hay-Pauncefote treaty, as amended, ratified L December 22, 1900 — "Ident'-al" note signed by powers. China. January 7, 1901 — Reapportionment bill before congress. January 8, 1901 — Senate debates army "canteen." </seg>
            <seg id="p009">WILLIAM McKINLEY </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 Banuary 8, 190 1 — Reapportionment bill pastes: pro. ides for 386 bers in house. January 18, 1901 — Army reorganization bill passes senate, 43-28. Kanuary 18, 1901 — Amended "canteen" clause stricken out; goes nference committee. January 22, 1901 — Resolutions on death of Queen Victoria. January 23, 1901 — Ship subsidy bill debate. January 25, 1901 — Taft commission reports on Philippines. January 28, 1901 — Towne speaks in Senate for Filipino self-gov - ernment. January 31, 1901 — Army bill goes to President: "canteen" forbid- February 2, 1901 — Army bill signed. February 5, 1901 — Mrs. Carrie Nation wrecks saloon K February 12, 1901 — Michigan supreme court decides public fran - .•s taxable. K February 16, 1901 — Russian retaliatory tariff against the United es. ■February 25, 1901 — Platt provisions in regard to Cuban relations Jnited States adopted, 43-20. K February 27, 1901. — Spooner amendment regarding Philippines &gt;ted, 45-27. March 1, 1901 — Spooner amendment regarding Philippines adopt - ed in House, 159-134- March 4. 1901 — River and harbor bill failed in Senate. Senator er talked it to death. K March 11, 1901 — Great Britain refuses to accept modified Hay - ticefote treaty. ■March 13, 1901 — Carnegie offers New York City $5,200,000 for ries. March 23, 1901 — Aguinaldo captured by Funston. April 12, 1901 — Cuban Constitutional Convention refuses to ac - cept Platt resolutions, 18-10. K April 12, 1901 — United States proposes to nations to reduce the lese indemnity by one-half. April 27, 1901 — Cuban committee's final interview with President Cinley. May 3, 1901. — Jacksonville fire — 148 blocks burned; $10,000,000 May 7, 1901 — Strike on Albany street railroad. May 9. 1901 — Great excitement in Wall Street over Northern Pacific railroad. May 20, 1901 — Pan-American exposition opens. May 20, 1901 — Machinists strike. May 22, 1901 — Alabama constitutional convention meets. May 23, Virginia constitutional convention elected. May 25, 1901 — South Carolina senators resign. Later withdraw resignations KMay 27, 1901 — United States Supreme Court decides on Insular s. June 7, 1901 — Governor Stone, of Pennsylvania, signs rapid tran - sit bills. June 7. 1901 — Carnegie offers $10,000,000 to Scotch Universities. June 11, 1901 — President McKinley announces no third term. B'une 12. 1901 — Cuban Constitutional Convention accepts Platt itions, 16-11, four absent. June 21, 1901 — Civil government ordered in Philippines. June 21, 1901 — William H. Taft appointed first governor. June 22, 1901 — Chaffee appointed military governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 July 4, igoi — Taft inaugurated civil governor in Philippine!. July 24, 1901 — Schley court of inquiry granted. July 25. 1901 — Free trade between United States and Porto Rico. July 26, 1901 — China to pay indemnity of 450,000,000 taels. August 20, 1901 — Alabama Constitution finished. August 2O, 1901 — China receives final terms of powers. September 2, 1901 — Vice-President Roosevelt's Labor Day speech at Minneapolis. September 5, 1901— President McKinley's address at Buffalo. September 6, 1901 — President McKinley assassinated. September 12, iqoi — Schley court sits. September 14, 1901— President McKinley dies. September 15-19, 1901 — President McKinley's funeral services. September 20, 1901 — President Roosevelt's fijst cabinet meeting. September 24, 1901 — Czolgosz trial — sentenced 26; prison 27. October 2, 1901 — San Francisco strike settled. October 22, 1901. — Pan-American Conference meets at City of Mexico. October 24, 1901— Illinois Supreme Court decides franchises sub- ject to taxation. November 7, 1901— Alabama c nstitution ratified by 25,000 maj. November 7, 1901 — Closing argument in Schley case. I November 13. 1901 — Northern Securities Company formed; cap - $400,000,000. November 18, 1901— New Isthmian canal treaty signed. November 19, 1901 — National reciprocity convention meets at Washington. ■November 22. 1001 — Convention at San Francisco for Chinese usion. B November 30. 1001— Report of Isthmian canai commission goes to ident. B December 2, 1901 — Supreme Court gives decision on status of ippines. December 2, 1901 — South Carolina and West Indian exposition at Charleston opens gates. December 2, 1001— Fifty-seventh congress holds first session. December 3, 1001— President Roosevelt's first message. December 4, 1001— Hay-Pauncefote treaty sent to Senate. December 9, 1901 — Shio subsidy bill reintroduced. December 10. 1901 — Carnegie offers $10,000,000 for national uni- December 13, 1901 — Schlev Court of Inquiry reports. December 14. 1901— Wireless telegraphy — Marconi. December 16, 1901— Hay-Pauncefote treaty ratified; vote, 72-6 December 17, 1901— Postmaster General Smith resigns; H. C. Payne his successor. December 18. 1901 — House passes Philippine tariff bill, 163-128. December 19. 1901— Both houses adjourn for the holidays. December 31. 1901— Cuban election. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">I PRELIMINARY.— January I, 1900, found the Republican party ontrol of every department of government, and just beginning to ie its policy on the new questions which were rising into public at - ion. A period of great general prosperity was destroying the mem - of the hard .times of 1893-1897, and the issues which those times made prominent were rapidly disappearing. With the advent of er times, following so closely upon the change in parties, there in to appear among the people a disposition more favorable tqw - the party in power in its treatment of the new problems arising 1 changed domestic and foreign conditions. With this general mary before us, we may now turn to consider briefly the more &gt;rtant questions of human interest that have come before the :rican oeople during the two years of our study. THE SHIP SUBSIDY BILL.— One of tne first measures to come prominently before the people was that intended for the en - couragement of our merchant marine. American ships, which had in 1800 carried 91 per cent, and as late as i860 at least 66 per cent of American foreign commerce, in 1898, carried less than 10 per cent of that trade. Several remedies had been already proposed, but in 1900 attention became centered on a bill championed especially by Sena - tors Frye of Maine and Hanna of Ohio, providing for a bounty to American ship owners. As introduced it proposed that $9,000,000 each year for 20 years should be paid to the builders and owners of American ships, the amount to be paid depending on the speed of the vessel, its carrying capacity, etc. The chief arguments for the bill are: that it is disgraceful for a great nation to have so few vessels to float its flag n the high seas; that it is wasteful, as we pay $150,000 - 000 or more annually to foreign countries for carrying our imports and exports; and that, owing to lesser cost in building vessels and lower wages for seamen in other countries, we cannot compete; hence the government must aid our merchantmen. The opponents of the measure reply that to tax the whole people to aid a few great firms, or at best a single industry — ship building — is unjust. Furth - er they urge that our ship-building supremacy ended only when iron and steel vessels replaced wooden ones, and now that we can make steel at less cost than other nations can, we may hope soon to re - gain our lost position without resorting to subsidy — a claim they be - lieve justified bv the fact that our shipyards now have more work than they can do. some of it coming even from Europe itself. The measure was not pressed in 1900 for fear of its effect on the national election, as manv western republicans, especially of the rank and file of the party, were either lukewarm for, or even adverse to, its pas - sage. After the election it was set aside because other measures were more pressing and its terms were not entirely satisfactoiv to all ele - ments of the party. Senator Frye has just introduced, December. 1901. a new bill which it is claimed obviates the objection urged by western republicans against the former one, but as it has not yet been discussed, no predictions can be made in regard to its fate. THE ELECTION OF 1900— A single question— the free coinage of silver — had dominated in the election of 1896. But since then new problems, arising largely from the Spanish-American and Filipino </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 wars, had thrust themselves upon the attention of the people. That Mr. McKinley and Mr. Bryan would again be the opposing candi - dates was eaily recognized, but whether the new o. ihe old issues would be made prominent in the party platforms was less certain. The Re - publicans preferred to conduct the political contest on the old issues. .iemocrats tended to choose the new ones. The Republican party was more harmonious than for many years; although there was, in its membership, a strong anti-imperialistic sentiment which circumstances might develop into dangerous proportions. Yet when «.ii June 19th. the convention met at Philadelphia there was no oppo - sition to Mr. McKinley, and no contest over the platform — a docu - ment which recounted the accomplishments of the party rather than formulated a program for positive action. For a moment the vice - presidency threatened this unity of action, as the leading men — Sec - retary Root, Senator Allison and Governor Roosevelt — had all em - phatically refused the use of their names. Two elements, however, entered to force Governor Roosevelt to reconsider: the first, the strong demand from the west for his nomination; the other, the pressure of the Pennsylvania and New York "political machines." The charge was made at the time that those who controlled the "ma - chines" wished to force him into the vice-presidency in order to get rid of him in New York politics. To accomplish this end they raised the cry that he would be a weak candidate for governor but a strong one for vice-president. His nomination was made unanimous en - thusiastically. I The Populists held their convention May 9, at Sioux Falls, South ota, and nominated Mr. Bryan and Mr. Towne. The Populist y, essentially a radical party, leaning decidedly toward socialistic ciples, emphasized in its platform the idea of increased functions [overnment, greater governmental control over the money of the ltry; and public ownership of railroads as the best means to con - corporations and trusts. It also approved bi-metallism, opposed ailed imperialism and militarism, stood for direct election of sen - s by the people, and for labor as against capital. The Democratic convention met at Kansas City, July 4. The party had been divided in sentiment over the money question since 1896, and possessed a conservative as well as a more radical wing or element. An effort made early in the spring to stampede the party to Commodore Dewey having failed, Mr. Bryan's nomination be - came a foregone conclusion. Two serious questions, however, re - mained; one relating to the platform, the other to the vice-presidency. One element of the party wished to ignore the money question, ex - cept in a rather meaningless generalization, thus placing the entire emphasis on trusts and imperialism. But the bi-metallists, under the leadership of Mr. Bryan, demanded the re-affirmation of the "free sil - ver" plank of the platform of 1896. The conservative section of the party apparently yielded on this question, but would not consent to the nomination of Mr. Towne; so Mr. A. E. Stevenson, of Illinois, was made the party's candidate. Later Mr. Towne withdrew from the Populist ticket, and that party endorsed Mr. Stevenson. I The campaign was marked by a better moral tone, but less en - iasm, than was manifested in 1896. The most prominent issues 5 the Philippine and Insular policy of the administration, the mili - and trust questions, and, to a less degree, the money issue. The :ome of the campaign was easily foreseen some weeks before the tion, as it became evident that the conservative democrats who Id vote for Mr. McKinley were much more numerous than the i-Imperial republicans who would come to Mr. Bryan's support 1 fact, when coupled with some dissatisfaction on the part of the </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 well enough alone," secured a great majority for Mr. McKinley. In a total vote of about 14,000,000, he received 7,217,000 votes and Mr. Bryan 6,357,000; while 207,000 votes were cast for the Prohibition ticket, 33,000 for the Social Labor, 50.000 for the Straight Populists, and 94,000 for the Social Democrats. The electoral vote for Mr. Mc- Kinley was 292, and for Mr. Bryan, 155. THE NEGRO PROBLEM.— The fifteenth amendment conferred on the negroes the right to vote. For a few years after its passage (1870) the privilege was exercised but under the leadership of cor - rupt men it was abused. Then the whites of the south justified them - selves, on the ground of self-preservation, in driving the negroes from the polls. Later fraud was substituted for force. During the last few years the same result has been secured by the adoption of new con - stitutions which limit the right to vote to those who can read or who have a stated amount of property. In some states, however, there exists both the so-called "grandfather" clause, and a provision which allows the judges of election to determine who can understand the con - stitution when read to them. In this way many ignorant whites con - tinue to possess the suffrage, while the negroes are denied it. Mis - sissippi and South Carolina limited the suffrage some years ago, but during the last two years conventions have been held in N. Carolina, Alabama and Virginia, with the -vowed intention of making constitu - tions that would disfranchise thr larger, the ignorant, port. on of th&gt;. ne - groes. In Maryland, a ballot law was passed (iqoi) with the same general motive. The people of the north have seemed remarkably in - different about the matter. In part no doubt because they have come to believe that the people of each state must settle this question for themselves without interference from those who have less knowledge and are less directly concerned. It has also been suggested that since several million people in the Philippines are, by the consent, if not by the actual will, of the northern people, deprived of a voice in their own government, the North cannot consistently take notice of a sim - ilar condition in the South. The census returns (1900) show that the negroes increased, during the last ten years. 18 per cent, the whites 21 per cent, indicating that the negroes are becoming a gradually de - creasing factor in our political and social life. Yet the problem re - mains a dangerous one. Booker T. Washington. Mr. DiiBois, and other negro leaders, are advising their people to become industrially necessary, and economically self-supporting, leaving the political problem to solve itself gradually as the intelligence of the Blacks in - creases. In the meantime these leaders and other friends of the ne - gro insist that education, especially industrial education, is the final need of the colored people. I TARIFF AND RECIPROCITY— From 1893 until very recent - ic tariff question has played a very small part in our political his - . Now, however, largely under the influence of the trust problem. :gins to come to the surface again. Opponents of protection urge it aids combination and makes it possible to raise prices, or at I to keep them from falling, thus injuring the consumer. Some : also pointed out that as American manufacturers can and do prsell their European competitor!", protection, being unnecessary, ht to cease. The surprising part of the movement, however, is ■owing sentiment in the South in favor of the tariff, while the de - for protection is decreasing in the North. Both President Mc - ley in his last speech at Buffalo and President Roosevelt in his &gt;r day address at Minneapolis urged a more liberal policy and </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Knitted themselves to the support of reciprocity— an indirect od of attacking protection. Several reciprocity treaties are now ing in the Senate. Their fate will probably indicate that of pro - &gt;n as well. I CENSUS AND REAPPORTIONMENT.— The constitution re - es that a census shall be taken every ten years, in order that esentatives may be apportioned among the states in proportion heir population. Since 1850, in addition to numbering the peo - statistics pertaining to agriculture, manufactures, wealth and al life have been gathered. The census returns of 1000 show 76, - 520 people in the United States (excluding our island possessions). fhom 33 per cent live in cities of over 8,000 population. Previous 860 population doubled in about 25 years; at the resent rate of ease nearly 50 years will oass before the population will be twice t it is now. The three most populous states are New York, with $,009 people; Pennsylvania, with 6.301,365; and Illinois, with 4, - 550. The three largest cities are in these states: New York, with 7.202 inhabitants; Philadelphia, with 1.293,607; and Chicago, with '•575- There are in all 160 cities in the United States whose pop - ion numbers over 25,000 each. In reapportioning the members of the House among the states two principal questions arose: (1) Shall the States that have disfran - chised part of their voters (see Negro Problem) have their represen - tation reduced proportionately; and (2) Shall the number of mem - bers of the House be changed? The decision was to increase the number of members in the House from 357 to 386. By this increase no state lost a member, while New York, Illinois and Texas gained three each; Pennsylvania, New Jersey and Minnesota, two each; and Arkansas. California, Colorado, Connecticut, Florida, Louisiana, Mis - sissippi. Massachusetts, Missouri, North Carolina, North Dakota, Washington. West Virginia and Wisconsin, one each. The difficul - ties in finding an adequate answer to the first question were so great that no action was taken. However, within the last month (Decem - ber. 1901,) s eral bills have been introduced in congress whose object is to reduce the representation of those states that have adopt - ed educational or property qualifications for suffrage. « « INDUSTRIAL LIFE. I MONEY PROBLEMS. — Having noticed a few of the most im - ant phases of the political, let us now turn for a brief study of the strial, history of our period. As money is the basis of all modern stry, and much discussed, we will begin with it. A bill to establish gold standard, introduced December 6, 1899, after discussion and ndmerit, became a law March 14, 1900. It provided that the pub - lebt be paid in gold; that $150,000,000 in gold be kept in the treas - to preserve gold payments; that the public debt be refunded into ear two per cent bonds, these bonds to be used by the national cs as a basis upon which to issue bank paper money. We should also notice the rapid increase in the volume of money in th« United States. April I, 1900, the treasurer estimated that </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 Ewere in the United States 2,021,246,506 dollars, or $26.12 for person; November 1, 1901, this amount had increased to 2,246, - 2 dollars, or $28.72 per capita. The following table shows how rapidly the gold production of the world is increasing: 1 896 — $202, 25 1 ,000. 1 897 — $238,8 1 2,000. 1899— $315,000,000. 1898— $287,428,000. 1900 — $307,000,000. (without South Africa.) ■These facts are not unlikely to produce great political and social lges in the not distant future. Other very important monetary topics will soon confront the American people. The question of retiring the "greenbacks" (na - tional paper money) and issuing bank money in its stead finds advo - cates. Others favor demonetizing silver, making gold the sole legal tender. Secretary Gage has just propounded his central bank theory. He would have the 4.000 or more banks, with their billion dollar cap - ital, confederate, forming a central bank of $50,000,000 capital, with the right to establish branches. This central bank would then be - come the depository of all United States funds. When this system was once established he would do away entirely with the Independent or Sub-Treasury system which has existed since 1846. In fact, the question is rapidly reducing itself to this: shall the United States or shall private corporations control the issue of the paper money of the nation, and handle its revenue? I RAILROAD BUILDING AND CONSOLIDATION. — The s' 1900 and 1901 have been 1 among the most prosperous of any in history of the railroads of the country. They have added nearly x&gt; miles of road in this period, having on July I, 1900, 193,345 miles, a total trackage (including double tracks and sidings) of 258.000 s. In June, 1900, the railroads empjoyed 1,017,652 men, and had »s receipts from passengers and freight of $1,487,000,000: after icting running expenses they had $557,000,000 left with which to interest, taxes, and dividends. These two years have been marked rery rapid and extensive consolidations by either purchase or the lation of new corporations. Six companies, on January I, 1901, rolled 98.015 miles of road. These six companies were domi - d by the Vanderbilt interest with 19,455 miles of road; the Penn - auia interest with 13,772 miles; the Morgan roads with 11.735 s; the Morgan-Hill interests with 20,458 miles: the Harriman dicate with 18,800 miles; and the Goulds with 13.795 miles. In all n thirteen other roads joined these six interests, 140,831 miles, ■4.40 per cent of all the roads in the country were included. i Rates for passenger service, for the year ending June 30, 1900. just a trifle higher than during the preceding year, averaging above two cents per mile; freight rates also were slightly high - veraging 0.729 cents per ton per mile, as against 0.724 the year re. Railroad stocks have advanced very rapidly during the last years, and are now at nearly twice the price they were bringing years ago. During the struggle for the control of the Northern fie its stock sold for a part of one day at $1,000 for a share whose value was only $100. I Hie testimony gathered by the Inter-State Commerce Commis - proves that discriminations in rates in regard to both persons places still continue; and testimony just taken (November. 1901I rs that through rates on wheat intended for exportation ire h lower than advertised, thus violating the law. This commissioa </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 t;ry urgent in its demands that congress shall give it more power rder that it may control such actions. Since December I, 1901, Northern Securities Company has been organized in New Jersey a capital of $400,000,000 for the purpose, it is supposed, of com - ig the Great Northern, the Northern Pacific and the Burlington s into one great whole. Governor Van Sant, of Minnesota, is such a consolidation is contrary to public welfare and law and invited the aid of State and United States law in an attempt to it the plan, having brought suit in the United States Supreme ■t, as well as in the State court, to test the issues involved. I TRUSTS AND CORPORATIONS —The question of trusts begun to attract attention before January I, 1900. but the great rest in the subject has been aroused by the events that have taken e since that date. "Trusts," as the word is now used, are only ntic corporations. They may be organized under the laws of any he States, but can secure the best terms in New Jersey, conse - itly that state has become the home of nearly all the great com - tions formed during the last two years. Many great companies large capitals were organized during the year 1899, and early 900, but the era in which the most record-breaking corporations : chartered began in the fall of 1900. and has continued with little nution. The United States Steel Company, with a capital of it $1,100,000,000, chartered February 25, 1901, leads all organi - &gt;ns in size. The Anthracite Coal Company, the various railroad binations. the Sugar Trust, the Standard Oil Company, the uit Trust, the Cotton Seed Oil Trust, comprise a very incomplete of the great companies of this class, each so extensive that it tically has a monopoly of the traHe or manufacture concerned, total capitalization of the companies organized during the last years amounts to several billion dollars, and plans are under way will vastly increase this amount. Recent ficrures give the "in - rials" as capitalized at $6,500,000,000. Various views are held in regard to these great companies. One class of men, perhaps confined to those interested, consider the trust a public good, and believe they ought to be allowed to develop with - out restraint, claiming the tendency is not dangerous and that the result will be cheaper production, lower prices, better wages, and more stability. Another, and very large section of the people accept the trust as a permanent institution, but insist that it ought to be con - trolled by law. Men of this group ask that the affairs of these giant organizations be made public; that their annual reports, stating assets and debts, profits and losses, and rates of profit be published. Pres. Roosevelt in his recent message seems to commit himselt to this theory. It is also urged that the inter-state commerce commission be given greater power over railroads in order that it may prevent the destruction of competition and business rivalry. Still others would find a remedy in a lower tariff on trust-made articles, in order to in - crease competition and thus lessen the danger of excessive prices and unjust charges. A third section of the American people, believ - ing these trusts to be a menace to liberty and public welfare, are not for regulation, but for destruction. They hold that when compe - tition is destroyed, human nature constituted as it is, will be unable to resist the inducement to raise prices, lower wages, ignore the B"z welfare, buy legislators and destroy civic virtue; hence the remedy is to destroy them altogether. The profits of some of corporations seem to some to justify this view. The Standard Company, capitalized at $110,000,000, is worth on the market about </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 $47,800,000; and for the four preceding years its dividends had aver - aged over $32,000,000 per year. Various plans have been suggested to secure greater control over corporations. March 15, 1900, an amendment to the constitution was introduced in the House. Its intent was to give congress power to regulate and repress monop - olies, ami to charter and dissolve combinations. As its terms were not satisfactory to two-thirds of the members, it failed. Both of the great political parties, in their platforms of 1900, pronounced against combinations in restaint of trade, the Democrats taking the more radical stand. To the minds of many people public ownership of the railroads, and perhaps even of other natural monopolies, begins to present itself as the true and only solution of this great question. PROSPERITY. — Periods of depression, prosperity, and specu - lation seem to follow each other at rather regular intervals. A se - vere depression extending all over the civilized world began in Aus - tralia and Argentine Confederation in 1800 and reached the United States in 1893. Recovery began in 1806 and by 1809 the nation had reached a very high plane of industrial activity, which still exists, as may be seen in the regular employment of nearly all who care to labor, in the rise of wages, and in the enormous increase of exports. The resulting vast balance of trade tends to bring our bonds home from Europe, to entice some of its gold and silver to our shores, and lastly to change the money centre of the world from London to New York. A further illustration of the rapid increase of wealth is found in the large bank accumulations, in the loans made at New York to foreign nations, in the rapidly fallim rate of interest, in the specula - tion in industrial stocks, and in the ledger of the United States, which shows the revenue of the government in excess of expenditures and increasing from month to month. I INVASION OF THE WORLD'S MARKETS BY THE UNIT - STATES. — The industrial development of the United States dur - the last two years has produced a marked commotion through - the world. A few statistics will indicate the reason. I For many years European agriculturalists have felt the compe - n of the American farmer, and in England, France and Germany cially, much has been written in regard to the decay of their is. and the remedy. Now the manufacturers also begin to fear they are to be destroyed by the cheaper goods of the United es. Its people and workingmen are so intelligent, its manufac - rs so enterprising and ingenious in securing better machinery and per methods, and its natural resources in iron, coal, lead, copper, other raw materials so abundant, that it seems destined to lead world in manufactures as well as in agriculture. Already the :ed States is selling locomotives in England, Russia and India; ting iron bridges in Egypt, building war ships even in a few in- Total foreig-n trade 1900 1901 (est.i " exnorts 1 C "00 l'Kll (est.i Total exports of manufactured articles: United States 1860 1900 Great Britain 1860 - i9tX) $2,244,193,543 2,400,000000 1,394.479,214 l.S'M).' (X).(l (i W0,000,000 432.0O0.0O0 6'3.00'»,(&gt;0&lt;i 936,000,000 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 Kces for European nations. The export of manufactured goods increased about $100,000,000 worth each year during the last two tThe effect of this sudden invasion of the foreign markets of the apean nations, and even of their home markets, has carried dis - ; and dire predictions of lower waees. hard times and revolutions been made. Various remedies have been proposed, the most mon being high tariff duties on our products seeking their mar- The formation of an European Union, somewhat like our own, been suggested, but historic rivalries, differences in race, lan - ;e and interests, will make this a difficult measure to realize. The •e only can solve the problem. I Already the future effect of these conditions on our own country ns to attract attention. Some hold that we cannot continue to more than we buy indefinitely; hence they urge that it is for our •est to lower duties, even going to the extent of free trade, if ssary, that prosperity may continue in the whole world, for these believe that the greatest prosperity will come to us with the cor - onding highest prosperity among the nations that buy from us. I STRIKES AND LOCKOUTS— Labor, discontented with its e in the better times, strikes to force employers to grant better ss, or shorter hours, or some coveted privilege. Employers, dis - fied with the demands of labor, use the lockout to bring their to terms. Thus an industrial war has prevailed for much of the during the last two years. Recognizing the evil results of such •ndition, about the middle of December, 1901, representatives of r and capital met at New York City, and attempted to formulate t plan by which the two interests might work in harmony in the re, or at least settle their disputes by peaceful rather than war - methods. Provision was made for a committee of arbitration of teen men, six selected from corporation interests, six from ng labor leaders, and six from disinterested citizens. The com - ce chosen includes in the 1st class, Messrs. Hanna. Schwab Rocke - r; in the second group. Mr. Gompers, Mr. Mitchell and Mr. Shaf - while ex-President Cleveland, Bishop Potter, and Archbishop md. have been named for the third section. The committee or - zed with Senator Hanna as chairman, and Mr. Gompers as sec- IAs examples of the conditions this commission hopes to avoid he future we may cite the following cases: A lockout by the em - ers of machinists and carpenters, at Chicago. February, 1900; r a strike by the mechanics: the "strike" and "lockout" stopped ly all building in Chicago for many months; about 75,000 men : unemployed, and building to the value of $100,000,000 remained mplete. The matter was finally adjusted, February, 1901, when ly of eight hours with a Saturday half-holiday was agreed upon nen and employers. The strike of the street car men in St. Louis, 8 to August, 1000: riots and bloodshed; for weeks scarcely a moved. The anthracite coal miners strike: threatened in March, ffect September 17. when over 100.000 men quit work: eight days the matter was compromised, the men gaining the right to buy of r than "truck" (mine-owners') stores. The southwestern teleg- Iers were "out." December 8. 1900, to January, 1901. Six thous - granite cutters quit work March I. 1000. for an eight hour day teamsters and dock-workers of San Francisco struck, July », and for months business of many kinds was nearly at a stand- A street car strike in Albany, May 6, 1901, resulted in riots and </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 I militia was called out before the trouble was adjusted. The strike :h caused the greatest sensation, however, was that of the steel kers in, the shops of the United States Steel Company. Thous - i of men were called out by President Shaffer of the Union, main - o secure a recognition by the company of the right of its em - ees to join labor unions, although other causes of complaint were Dunced. The trouble was compromised September 14, 1901, but in main to the disadvantage of the laborers. It is difficult to draw general conclusions, as to results; on the whole, wages have 1 increased and hours shortened, but the other demands of the ring men have generally been successfully resisted. R EXPOSITIONS— The Paris exposition, 1000, noted for its art and stic display, was visited by many Americans. The Pan-»American osition, Buffalo, May 15 — November 2, 1901, was celebrated for color scheme, its electrical display and the lessons it taught the world in regard to the future of electricity. The South Carolina In - ter-State and West Indian Exposition began December 2, 1901, and has to do primarily with southern interests. Already congress has appropriated $5,000,000 for the Exposition at St. Louis in 1003, to commemorate the purchase of the Louisiana territory. St. Louis, and the state of Missouri, have raised large sums also; hence the out - look for one of the greatest of the world's expositions is good. i OKLAHOMA.— The opening of the "Cherokee strip" to home - d in the summer of 1901 taught anew the lesson that free land in United States is almost exhausted. Many applicants for each "ter section of land appeared. Choice by lot was finally resorted avoiding the rush and riot that would otherwise have prevailed. rns of several thousands of people grew up in a month's time, and uninhabited region became populous in a few weeks. The whole •ement illustrates how different are the conditions of settlement from those that prevailed a century or less ago. t OIL-WELLS. — The California oil discoveries, and the Beaumont, as, "oil-spouters" promise to revolutionize many interests, and rhange the direction of industrial development of the southwest, roads are already using oil as a fuel instead of coal. Perhaps the le fuel problem may be simplified, and dependence for refined oil the Standard Oil company broken; although it is yet too soon oresee the final outcome. « « REFORM MOVEMENTS. DIRECT PRIMARIES.— This system which seeks to give every voter an equal voice in selecting candidates for office, and to protect »in this right by law, antagonizes the old convention system. Its ids claim that it is more democratic, that it will lessen corrup - and trading, and destroy the political machines which exist in many places under the control of selfish and self-seeking bosses. Wisconsin in 1900, the governor and legislature were elected pledged to this reform. The legislature, untrue to its pledge, but anxious to appear to satisfy public sentiment, passed an act of little </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 Ie, which Governor La Follette vetoed, appealing again to the &gt;le and the next legislature, who will doubtless sustain him. In nesota a law was first passed applying only to the city of Min - &gt;olis. Its success led the legislature of 1900 to extenfl its prin - •s to the whole state. Other states, as Nebraska, Massachusetts, ' York, Kentucky, etc., are moving in the same di ectipn. Doubt - within a few years every state will control the nomination of lidates — more important even than the election- -by law in such anner that the whole people will not merely ratify the choice of few, but will actually determine who shall hold office. I POPULAR ELECTION OF SENATORS— Closel akin to the movement comes another — the demand for the election of ted States Senators by the direct vote of the people. The cor - use of money by men who sought to buy their way into the ite, in Delaware, in Montana, in Pennsylvania, and perhaps in t states has intensified this dema.i^. Several times in recent s it has happened that one or more states would have only a le Senator, and at the present moment Delaware has no senators nise a deadlock exists in the legislature. Also if Senators were ted directly by the people, state legislatures might be chosen on :ly state issues. In order to secure this c' ange an amendment he constitution must be made. The House has adopted the ndment, but the self-interest of senators causes them to refuse r assent, thus blocking all action to secure this reform. I MUNICIPAL REFORM— Three questions a.e prominent and ; been much discussed, especially during the last two years: (1) II cities govern them: elves, or shall they be governed largely by e legislatures; (2) Shall cities own and control their waterworks, ting plants, etc., and (3) shall they be governed honestly? The must be settled first; for upon its answer hinges tl;e decision in other questions. Great gains have beeu made in the last two •s in nearly every city. The election, November. 1901, u4 Mr. Seth v as mayor of Greater New York marks an epoch. It means hon - and efficiency; it means that New York will be governed fpr the d of all, not for the interest of the few. Reform barely fiileo in ladelphia. and succceeded in Toledo. Cleveland and Columbus, O., r° reform mayors t ere elected. In these ci ies the election led on the question of city ownership of water, gas and electrical its. lower fares on street cars, and city government for the good ill its people. I TEMPERANCE MOVEMENTS.— Three important movements aining to the liquor traffic have been much discussed during the year or two. Mrs. Carrie Nation, claiming that she had done ■ything possible to prevent the illegal sale of liquor, led a crusade )hysical force against the saloon, hoping in that way to arouse lie sentiment to the enforcement of the law. Arrested for the de - ction of nropertv. she was freed only to renew her attack. Rear - ed, she wrote from her prison and continued the agitation. Peo - differ greatly in opinion regarding the effect cf her course. BThc apparent success in South Carolina of the dispensary system e State itself selling by its officers all the liquor disposed of legal - 1 the state, same not to be drunk on the premises — has caused a rspread discussion of the system, and its adoption by the people iouth Dakot ; although, as no appropriation was mad&gt;. to put the into operation, nothing so far has been done in that State. The </seg>
            <seg id="p022">21 AVoman s Christian Temperanc Union and its friends have also se - cured the passage of a law by congress abolishing the "canteen" (a place where liquors, refreshments and reading matter were kept) from all army "posts." Much discussion in regard to the workings of the law has taken place. Some condemn the law, claiming that drunkenness has increased in the army; others deny this statement. The discussion continues with both army officers and civilians divided in regard to the wisdom of the policy. « « EDUCATIONAL PROGRESS. {TRAVELING LIBRARIES— In various ways in recent years tnpts have been made to widen the field of education. Public iries have been established in towns and cities. Colleges and uni - ities have planned "extension courses," where lectures were given own and village when asked for. The mot,t recent and perhaps most effective agency in carrying education to the people's door been found in the traveling library. Books are arranged in sets 5 to 50 volumes and sent to any place i.hat will make provision for r care, to be kept a few weeks, then replaced by a new set. Laws such libraries now exist in Iowa, Wisconsin and Minnesota. The raska legislature of 1901 passed a law establishing traveling li - ies, and appropriating money to make a start. Miss Edna Bul - has been appointed librarian, and may be reached at Lincoln. I ENDOWMENTS FOR LIBRARIES AND UNIVERSITIES — bably never in the history of the world have as large sums been n by private individuals to found and aid educational interests luring the last two years. Mr. Andrew Carnegie has given many ions of dollars to erect library buildings — the largest amount, $5. - x», going to New York Citv to construct branch library build - , scattered through various sections of the city. Besides his gift iio.ooo.ooo to Scotch universities, Mr. Carnegie has endowed a 'technic School at Pittsburg, and has just offered $10,000,000 to blish a graduate school or National University at Washington. . Stanford has increased the endown nt of Stanford University ome $30,000,000, and Mr. Rockefeller has increased his gifts to aaro University by several millions. Estimates have been made over $100,000,000 were given to education during 1901, and per - i half as much durinsr the preceding year. The effect of these ; remains uncertain; if it results in establishing schools where thought is hindered in the least, or if it causes the people to re - their own endeavors (even sacrifices, if necessary) and to rely on men to support higher education, the outcome may be harmful, er than helpful. FREEDOM OF TEACHING.— The question of the right of teachers to express freely their views on controverted topics has se - cured thorough discussion during the last two years. The issue was precipitated at Stanford university, where several of its most distin - guished professors resitmed because they felt that the right of free - dom of teaching was at stake in the enforced resignation of Professor </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 is. While public sentiment was somewhat divided in regard to merits in this particular case, it seems that the great majority of ated men everywhere felt that true education would be destroyed achers were forced to suppress their opinions, or to warp their :eption of the truth in order to retain their places. The unselfish ude of Professor Howard and those who acted with him has cer - y made the future freedom of teaching much more secure. I\ NATIONAL UNIVERSITY.— Washington suggested, Jeffer - advocated. and J. Q. Adams revived, the idea of a National Uni - ty to be located at the Capital. Discussed for over a century, ealization may now be at band. Yet even now there is much dif - ice of opinion in regard to its nature. Some would make it only ger and more richly endowed state university; others propose a ol for graduates of State Universities and the various colleges; : still others would establish a school for research only. A com - ;e of the National Teachers' Association reported against the plan; the other two ideas are still open to discussion. Mr. Car - :'s offer of $10,000,000 to endow a National University will prob - precipitate further discussion, and cause action along some line. I PRESIDENT GI^MAN.— The retirement of Mr. Gilman, Febru - 22, 1901, from the presidency of Johns Hopkins University, after ears of servicce, calls to mind that graduate study in this coun - reaches back little beyond 1876, when Johns Hopkins began its t work. President Gilman has now been placed at the head of movement to found a National University, so perhaps his great inizing power may yet begin a greater work than the ne he has passed on to his successor, Dr. Remsen. « « RELIGIOUS OUTLOOK. I CHURCH MOVEMENTS.— The religious world also seems to ! felt the quickening effects of the new century, and to have marked for itself vast changes in the near future. In the Methodist church rules which govern the length of pastoral service, and determine right of women to vote in conference and assembly have been ussed and amended. The Presbyterian church, June 3, 1901, ap - ited a committee to draft a revised confession of faith to be sub - ed to the assembly in 1902 for consideration. Meanwhile the &gt;copal church discussed the question of its attitude toward the arriage of divorced persons. All the religious bodies were deeply ught up over foreign missions, especially those in China, so rude - isturbed by the Boxer uprising. A number of heresy trials have 1 taken place, the most noteworthy being those of Rev. Mr. Mc - ert and Professor Mivart. In general the cause of this apparent ;st finds its basis in the so-called higher criticism — an attempt to y the ordinary rules of historical criticism to the Bible. ■MORAL UNREST.— This spirit of unrest has also manifested f in many forms throughout the country. Hazing at West Point me so disgusting that an investigation was held, and strong </seg>
            <seg id="p024">23 i mres taken to bring it to a speedy end. Mob violence has ap - ed in all sections of the country, but especially in the south where ings and ly.chings of negroes have not been uncommon. A re - n seems to have begun, accompanied by a feeling that law must :rmitted to take its regular course. Perhaps even the same rather :ss temper may account for the election of the confessed believer alygamy, Mr. Roberts, of Utah, and the use of bribery in sena - 1 elections. Yet it should be noted on the other hand that Mr. :rts was refused his seat, Mr. Clark was unseated by the Senate, Mr. Addicks, of Delaware, failed in his attempt to buy his Way the Senate. « « SCIENTIFIC RESEARCHES. (SEEKING THE NORTH POLE.— Two American expeditions, under the command of Mr. Peary, the other under the direction dr. Baldwin— the money furnished by Mr. Ziegler— have spent the two years in the land of the midnight sun, seeking an opportunity lenetrate to the North Pole. In the summer of 1901, Mr. Peary eeded in exploring the northern coast of Greenland, while Mr. Iwin established his camps and made preparations for a dash to North at the first favorable moment. Both are experienced in r expeditions, and well equipped for their work. Each hopes the summer of 1902 may reward him for his sacrifices by a sight he North Pole. Questions of electrical phenomena, as well as eography are to be solved by these explorations. i SCIENTIFIC DISCOVERIES.— The greatest discoveries have 1 ma:!e in the field of electricity, and among the most noted may named printing without ink — a discovery possibly destined to itly modify that industry. We must also keep in mind the wireless graphy of Marconi, by which he has been able to signal across Atlantic ocean. Multiplex telegraphy and the sending of pic - s by telegraph indicate the new fields into which the electrician rioving. Long distance telephoning has been made a commercial ress, and Edison's storage battery system may in time result in acing steam with electricity on our railroads. Color photog - ly also should be mentioned. I SCIENCE AND DISEASE.— The relation of certain species of •quito to malaria and yellow fever has been established. Pro - ion from its sting or bite, which may be secured by means of net - ;, or destruction of its larvae (young), which may be accomplished pouring crude oetroleum over swamps and other of its breeding :es, enables men to live in regions hitherto considered almost un - ibitable. Great advancement has been m de in our knowledge of sumption, and a great tuberculosis conference was held in Berlin he summer of 1901. Sunlight, pure air and electricitv are held to destructive to its germs. Its communicabilitv seems also to be iblishcd, hence isolation hospitals are needed to keep it from ;ading. Just as this is written a claim comes from the University Michigan that a remedy against typhoid fever has been discovered. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">24 Knew century is thus ushered in with the hope that some of the : diseases may be, if not eliminated, at least greatly mitigated sir extent and severity. « « MILITARY AFFAIRS. KARMY. — December 3, 1900, a bill for reorganizing the army luced, and after a long and exciting debate became a law 2, 1901. During the debate many amendments, relating to ■ny, and its use in the Philippines, were introduced, but de - lie bill as passed provides for a regular army of 58,000, sub - rease to 100,000 men, at the pleasure of the president. Two ts of importance were adopted — the first prohibiting the and the second stating the terms the Cuban constitu - vention must adopt before the troops of the United States withdrawn. I THE NAVY.— At the beginning of 1000 the United States had battleships and two armored cruisers in commission. Since then ral additional vessels have been launched, the Illinois, the Mis - ■i an:! the Wisconsin. The average displacement oi the first eight: — the Kearsage, the Kentucky, the Indiana, the Iowa, the Massachu - setts, the Oregon, the New York and the Brooklyn — is 10.000 tons. The six now under way or completed — the Alabama, the Maine, the Illinois, the Missouri, the Ohio and the Wisconsin — average 12,000 tons. The eleven contracted for as early as 1900 — the Pennsylvania, the New Jersey, the Georgia, the Virginia, the Rhode Island, the West Virginia, the Nebraska, the California, the Maryland, the Colo - rado, and the South Dakota — will average 14,000 tons, while con - tracts were let in 1901 for five more that will average 15,000 tons. These thirty great iron monsters — costing from $3,000,000 to $5,000, - 000 each — wilL form the chief strength of the American navy. In ad - dition to these vessels, one monitor was launched, November 10, 1900. and three more are under construction. Secretary Long in his report of December 1001, recommends that congress appropriate $100,000, - 000 more for the completion of our navv. It is urged against his sug - gestion that this means a tax of six dollars for each family in the United States — an amount that is both unwise and unnecessary. Sec - retary Long states in favor of his recommendation that our increas - ing importance as a nation justifies the expenditure, and he also claims that it may save in war, or in preventing war, vastly more than it costs. He insists that our flag floating in every country and on every sea will increase our trade enough to justify the expense. I THE SCHLEY COURT OF INQUIRY.— Mr. McClay, one of historians of the American navy, in his third volume, which treated he Spanish-American war. charged Admiral Schley with coward - md insubordination. Alter some little discussion, Admiral Schley ■d that a court of inquiry be summoned to decide in regard to his : or innocence. Secretary Long granted the request July 24, . and on September 12. the court began its sessions. For many ks the court was engaged in taking the testimony of officers and </seg>
            <seg id="p026">THEODORE KOOSEVELT </seg>
            <seg id="p027">25 CBgiaim of the Santiago fleet. November 7, the closing arguments were made. After, some weeks spent in reviewing the evidence, the court handed down its decision. December 13, 1901. divided in opinion. Admirals Benhani an! Ramsey found Admiral Schlev guilty of all the charges except cowardice. hi!e Admiral Dewey dissented in part, i&gt;rai^ing A 'miral Schley in "eneral. giving him the credit of winning the great victory at Santiago. The Secretary of the Navy anproved the findings of the majority of the court, held that A'miral Dewey's 1 in regard to who was in command at the battle of Sai was not before the court, dismisse . Mr. McClay from his position in the naval service, and announced the whole matter closed. The peo - ple arc yet discussing it. Kx-SECRETARY OF WAR ALGER— During the summer of Mr. Alger published a history of his administration of the war tment. defending his nianagmcnt and replying to the charges &gt;se methods, "spoiled meat." and inefficiency. The work new material for a study of the Spanish-American war. « « NECROLOGY. JOHN Sll KR..1AN. one of America's greatest financiers, rank - ing with Hamilton and Gallatin, died at Washington, October 22, 1900. Born in Ohio, in 1823, he entered into politics soon after reaching his majority, and nassed the greater portion of his life in the public ser - ted to Congress in 1854, he soon became one of its most note 1 members, was a prominent candidate for speaker in 1859. and would have been chosen two years later, had not the choice of Chase as Secretary of the Treasury left a vacancy in the senate to which he w*a advanced. In 1877 he became Secretary of the Treasury 1111 kr President Hayes, an 1 through his efforts specie payments were re - sumed two years later. Again he returned to the senate, which tion he resigned to enter President McKinley's cabinet as Secretary of State. His health failing he resigned a year later, 1898, to spend the rest of his days in dignified retirement, respected as one of Amer - ica** greatest and most honest statesmen. I BENJAMIN HARRiSON— Ex-President Harrison was one of few men who grew in oublic estimation after leaving the idential chair. At the time of his death, his hold on the public greater than at any previous moment in his career, although he not in full harmony with the tendency of the times. As a lawyer. :sman and orator he took a high rank. Although not a popular in the usual meaning of the word, as he was almost cold in ner, he held the most important offices within the gift ot the peo - -those of senator and president. Born in 18,33. graduating at nine - . he early entered upon the practice of the law which he laid aside nter the army during the civil war. and, with reluctance, to serve enator and president even. Resuming his law practice in 1893, at close of his presidential term, he won honor as well as wealth in mrsuit. Defending Venezuela in its boundary dispute with Great </seg>
            <seg id="p028">26 Britain, he was U the height of his fame when he died, March 13, 1901, at his Indianapolis home, at the age of 67. WILLIAM McKINLEY. — No event in recent American history has caused such universal sorrow as the death* of President McKinley. September 14, 1901. A man who had few or no personal enemies, ami who was respected by his political opponents for his high character, pure morals, noble manhood, gentle and humane spirit, it seemed be - yond belief that any one could be found base enough to take his life. Yet at the moment he was extending a friendly greeting to the Amer - ican citizens who gathered to welcome him to Buffalo, an anarchist. whose name no one cares to remember, aimed not only at his. but at the nation's, heart as well. The sorrow of the American people over his death, was only equalled bv their horror at the deed. All stood appalled. In a land of freedom, self-government, and majority rule, there seemed no place for such an attack upon the "plain man's" friend, and the people's legal representative. Perhaps Mr. McKinley had at the moment of h s death fewer enemies, and more devoted friends "than anv other man who has ever been in American public life." As a voung man in Ohio, his personality began to show that gen - ial goo'l nature, and thoughtfulness for others that marked so pre - eminently the closing days of his life. He entered the army a youth of eighteen, and at the age of twenty-one held a captain's commission. He was elected to Congress, term after term, from a district that had a normal democratic majority. Twice governor of the great state of Ohio, he then acquired the experience which helped to fit him for the duties of the presidency, to which he was twice chosen by large majori - ties. As a statesman he was cautious, conservative, and inclined to accept rather than lead public opinion. A strong protectionist, he yet advocated reciprocity, and advised widening the markets for our goods. "His management of our foreign relations had been so tactful and conservative as to inspire confidence throughout the world in the peaceful intentions and amicable snirit of the United States, and he had lived to see our relations with all sovereign nations, great and small, more entirely harmonious than they had ever been at any time in the history of the American government." But after all his devo - tion to his wife, his patience and thoughtful care for those around him. his simplicity and kindly forgiving spirit, mark the elements in his career that will be most important, and longest remembered by the American nation. The last words, taken down at his bedside, breathe the spirit of the man. He said: "Good-bye all; good-bye. It is God's way. His will be done." « « COLONIES AND DEPENDENCIES. ALASKA. — In Alaska great excitement has prevailed over the development of the gold discoveries of 1897-99 at Nome. Thousands of peoole are now living in comfortable homes whep only a few months ago nothing was visible but a frozen, ice-bound waste. What threat - ened for a time to become a rather serious conflict of jurisdiction between Canada and the United States was at least temporarily settled by an agreement, late in 1899, upon a provisional boundary line. But no adequate government hat vet been established in Alaska by the </seg>
            <seg id="p029">27 United States, and it is consequently a scene of much confusion and disorder. GUAM. — As one of the results of the Spanish-American war the United States came into possession of the island of Guam, situated in the far Pacific, with an area of about 150 square miles, and a popula - tion of about 9,000 persons. The people accepted American rule in a friendly spirit, and government began under favorable conditions. A system of public instruction was provided for in January. 1900, and a requirement made that every adult citizen learn to write his or her name by July I, 1900. Slavery, existing in the island at the time of its acquisition, was abolished February 22, 1900, by the first governor. Captain Leary. SAMOA. — The Samoan islands, situated about half way between Hawaii and Australia, had for several years been under the joint con - trol of Germany, England and the United States. This arrangement caused much international friction, which was ended by a treaty, signed December 2, 1899, and ratified January 16, 1900. providing for the division of the group betwec Germany and the United States. England withdrawing entirely from the islands. By this arrangement the United States acquires the island of Tutuila, with the harbor of Pago Pago, the best in the southern section of the Pacific ocean. The area of Tutuila is about 54 square miles, and its population ap - proximately 4,000. Its harbor is larfe. land-locked, and situated in the main course of trade, and will be one of great advantage as a naval and coaling station. HAWAII. — The American flag was raised over Hawaii August 12, 1898, but at the time our study begins no provision had yet been made for its permanent government. February 16. 1900. a bill was in - troduced into the House providing for its government, and three Hays later Senator Cullom, of Illinois, introduced a similar bill in the Sen - ate. The general purpose of both bills was to make Hawaii at once an organizH territory, similar to New Mexico or Arizona, with powers of local self-government, and the privilege of sending a dele - gate to Congress; the rights of citizenship and trade to be the same as those existing between the older states and territories. April 6. the House passed a substitute bill, prohibiting the immigration of Chinese from Hawaii into the United States, which was accepted by the Senate after a conference with the House, and signed bv the president. April 30. Sanford B. Dole, former president of Hawaii, was made its first governor. Parties were soon formed, adopting the names alreadv in use in the United States. In the first election the Hemocrats were victorious, their candidate for delegate to Congress. Robert Wilcox, securing a majority of 316. and the territorial legis - lature falling under their control. The legislature, on meeting, quar - reled with the governor, who adjourned it in anger. The reason as - signed for the ill-feeling, and for the . democratic supremacy, was the corruption conn cted with the payment of losses incurred from the burning of the Chinese quarter of Honolulu in the work of eradicat - ing the bubonic plague. THE PHILIPPINES.— During the entire year 1900 the war in the Philippines continued, with the American troops gradually cap - ti'ring the Filipino strongholds, thus forcing the natives into a guer - rilla warfare. By the summer of 1901 the insurrection was confined to small bands in rather isolated" regions, and provision becran to be made for replacing military with civil government. The Taft com - mission report, submitted to congress January 35, 1901, announced </seg>
            <seg id="p030">28 that in many provinces civil government had been inaugurated, or con - ditions were favorable for so doing. June 21, 1901, civil government was instituted in the Philippines, and Judge W. H. Taft appointed as the first governor. His inaugural oath was taken July 4, and procla - mation was made that the military authority was to become subordi - nate to the civil, although the military governor was to retain author - ity in those districts where order had not been restored. Twenty - seven provinces were declared ready for civil government, while twen - ty-five others were to be left for a time under military control. June 15 a supreme court of seven members — four Americans and three Filipinos — was constituted. An attorney general, and other civil of - ficers, including departments of Commerce and Police, Justice and Finance, and Public Instruction were appointed. The public school system was place! under the control of Mr. F. W. Atkinson, who was empowered to employ teachers from the states an-1 to organize the school system. About 1,000 teachers have gone to the Philippines to enter on this educational crusade, it is the intention, so said, to have English introduced to such an extent that public business may be conducted in that language by 1906. !he United States supreme court decided in the "fourteen dia - i rinc, cases." Deer iqoi. that after signing the treaty Spain the territory therein acquired belonged to the United s. and could therefore be no longer subject to the tariff restric - laH upon foreign countries; although it declared congress could w fix such duties as it saw fit upon exports and imports between Jnite ! States and its dependencies. The House has sent to the e a bill imposing the Dingley duties on all imports from the Phil - ;s; and though the question has been made more or less u party the recommendation of the Taft government that the duties be e;! &gt;o tit cent may cause a change in the present party policy e the bill is finally maHe a law. In the meantime trade has been isintf and prosperity seems to be returning to certain portions i islands. PORTO RICO. — The first Porto Rican question of importance in 1900 was the matter of revenue. The president's message had rec - ommended free trade with Porto Rico; but Congress, after a long and bitter debate, concluded to lay IJ per cent of the Dingley tariff duty ■bob all goods passing between Porto Rico and the United Slates. 'v.tv was to en 1. however, by July 1. IQ02, or as much sooner as the people of Porto Rico provided some other means of raising a domestic revenue. As such provision was soon made, free trade be - tween Porto Rico and the United States began July 25, 1001. The above act also provided for Porto Rico a form of government, con - sisting of a governor, appointed by the president for a term of four vears; an executive council or cabinet of eleven members, appointed by the president and the senate, and constituting the upper house of the legislature; and a lower legislative house, elected by the people for a term of two years; all legislation to be subject to congres - sional anm'H'Tient. This bill did not receive the full reoublican sup - port, bat becan.e a law by a vote of 161-153 in the House and 40-31 in the Senate. A public school system has been organized; and indus - trial recovery from the destructive hurricane of August, 1899. and the changes incident to war. may be easily noted. Mr. C. H. Allen, the first governor, resigned September 3, 1890. Mr. W. H. Hunt assuming the duties of the office in his place. The area of Porto Rico is 3,600 square miles, and it has a population of 953,243. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">29 CUBA. — Affairs in Cuba have been, and still are, .n rather an un - settled condition; yet measures looking to the organization of an independent republic are slowly taking shape. September 15, 1900, the Cuban people elected a constitutional convention, in which the Nationalists (Pro-American) 1 ad a majority. It organized Novem ber 5, and early in 1901, had formed a constitution very similar to our own. The principal question before the convention was the acceptance or rejection of the Platt amendment which required the Cuban convention to incorporate stated provisions giving the Unit - ed States certain privileges in Cuoa. At first the onvention re - fused; but after a committee had visited Washington the demand was agreed to by a vote of 16 to 11, with 4 absent. The struggle for president was^ becoming exciting, when on.; of them — Maso — withdrew on the ground that all election officials were controlled by his opponent. Thomaso Palnia was elected December 31, 1901, by a majority much increased — and yet a light vote — through the non-at - tendance at the polls of many of his opponents. iTHE DANISH WEST INDIES.— A treaty has been signed by :h the Danish West India islands, including St. Croix, St. Thom- St. John and some islets, are transferred to the United States $4,500,000. But just at the moment of writing much dissatisfac - over the proposed transfer seems to have arisen in Denmark; some opposition in the islands themselves. What the final out - e will be must remain for the new year to decide, although there been some talk of submitting the question of sale to a vote of islanders themsel es. These islands, located just east of Porto &gt;, contain only some n8 square miles, wi'h a population of ib; but as they lie in the direct line of trad:, and as one of the harbors in the Caribbean sea is found on St. Thomas, they be - e of considerable importance in commerce. « « FOREIGN RELATIONS. (THE HAGUE CONFERENCE— Called at the suggestion of Czar of Russia the Hague Peace Conference recommended to the ons the establishment of a permanent arbitration „ tribunal to :h they might bring their d'sputes for settlement. February 5, , the Senate unanimously approved the treaty which provides the president shall appoint four distinguished citizens of the ted States, who, when joined by representatives chosen by the t civilized nations of the world, shall constitute the arbitration unal. No cases, thus far have come before the tribunal for ar - ition. THE BOER WAR.— On the whole the sympathy of the Amer - ican people has been with the Bqeij in their struggle with Great Britain. Although the long established po icy of neutrality and non - intervention in foreign affairs has been adopted and followed by the government, there ire many who would like to see the president of - fer his services to bring the war to an end. The large number of </seg>
            <seg id="p032">30 deaths of children in the Boer concentration camps, during the last few months, has greatly intensified this feeling. I [HE CLAYTON-BULWER TREATY.— February 5, 1900, :tary Hay and the British ambassador, Sir Julian Pauncefote, d an agreement by which those provisions of the dayton-Bul - treaty of 1850 which provided for the neutrality of any isthmian by the ,oint action of Great Britain and tl United States, were fated. The senate, however, before ratifying, added three im - int amendments. The refusal of the British government to ac - the amendments necessitated the renewal of negotiations which, y, December 4, 1901, led to a new agreement entirely abrogating Jayton-Bulwer treaty. This action permits the United States to ;ruct, own, and control the trans-isthmian canal, subject only jual use by all nations. The sentiment of the country strongly s the view that the United States itself — not private individuals &gt;uld own and construct the canal, and at present the Nicaragua : possesses the greater popular favor. A bil» is now pending in ress which provides for its construction under the direction of Secretary of War. I THE MONROE DOCTRINE.— The United States has taken ision on several occasions in recent years to renew its allegiance ;he Monroe Doctrine, and President Roosevelt in his first mes - : reasserted its binding force in strong terms. Its reaffirmation his moment when we are entering more largely into the world's tics brings some sharp criticisms from other nations, including charge that we are not consistent; that we demand that other ons shall keep hands off this continent while we assert the right nterfere elsewhere. Yet both England and Germany have just :tically admitted that it affords a rule of conduct to which they conform. I THE PAN- -MERICAN cONGREbi.— The Pan-American con - is of 1889-90, held at Washington, under the guidance of Mr. ne failed to accomplish all that he hoped. The Congress, which October 22, 1901, at the city of Mexico, assembles under favor - circumstances. It aims to unite the Americas more closely, to oye obstructions to commerce, and ' bove all to advance the ciple of arbitration. The danger of failure on the last topic lies wo differences of opinion: shall arbitration be compulsory or vol - ary; shall it apply to existing or only to future disputes? The ted States is ably represented, and plays no unimportant part in leliberations. RELATIONS WITH TURKEY.— The delay u the payment of losses sustained by American citizens during the Armenian outrages led to some ill-feeling, but after a hint that force might be employed, settlement was made. For some weeks now the country has been ex - cited over the capture of Miss Stone, an American missionary, by Bulgarian brigands, who hold her for a ransom. ICHINA. — The last two years have been years of the most intense tement in our relations with the Orient. The Boxer uprising cost lives of many American missionaries. The United States united the nations of Europe, and Japan in sending 1 joint army to ing to reiie.ve the besieged ambassadors who, for many weeks, ng the summer of 1900, were in the greatest danger. After the ure of the city, and the suppression of the uprising, the United </seg>
            <seg id="p033">31 States advocated moderate, rather than excessive, punishment of the leaders, and bv its judicious course has gained greatly in Chinese es - teem. When the question of the partition of the Empire was sug - gested, the united States opposed, and was largely instrumental in securing the "open door" policy (the same rates of dutv for all na - tions in Chinese commerce). Un the whole the course of the United States, in opposing excessive punishments, and an exorbitant indem - nity — fixed at 450.000.000 taels — has produced a better feeling in China; whether the continued exclusion of Chinese laborers from our shores will counteract it only time can determine. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>