<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00006">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Feeding Tests and Carcass Studies with Early Spring Lambs and Aged Western Ewes</title>
               <date value="1932-12">1932-12</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 276 December, 1932 Feeding Tests and Carcass Studies with Early Spring Lambs and Aged Western Ewes A. D. WEBER AND WM. J. LOEFFEL Department of Animal Husbandry '■--' '__ ■■" ' '_titr__ m^_ f '. ' *■**" ~i "*' .sw^^^isssal H^J fUS [jU^H '' F f i n-J—i———————ulVB—r^———-'^ ' V—-WB_\ W_W——————————i——————' —j'sW H|i*t,V _t\_^_______\ \S_\_____\ '' *^^ * — ' * '.^tW jUsa^^ 1 * ' - ..^ .. '. £____t r . - _______\\ * fc] Bfls Sa^lBl jj* ____W_____\ B BgH ' j^Jl* z^jz-]^.:™**' -~ -^^^^^^^^^P^^^^^^^^'B»BBBM» .. Hr . I Lambs at marketing time — Lot 1 above, Lot 2 in the middle, and Lot 3 below. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OP AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. Burr, Director </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Page Summary 3 Introduction 5 Objects of the Experiment.. 5 Experimental Procedure 6 Experimental Feeding Data 6 Results before lambing 7 Lambing records g Data on ewes after lambing g Data on lambs 10 Results after weaning. 12 Total feed consumed and total gain per head 15 Market data on all ewes : 15 Market data on all lambs 17 Carcass Studies of Lambs _ 17 Carcass grading 20 Chemical studies '_ 22 Cooking tests 22 Palatability studies _ . 24 Carcass Studies of Ewes 26 Physical and chemical analysis 28 Cooking tests 29 Palatability studies 31 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY ■ ■ • • ■ . ■ ■ ■ - </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studies with Early Spring Lambs and Aged Western Ewes A. D. WEBER AND WM. J. LOEFFEL In a previous study made at the Nebraska Station 1 , aged western ewes were purchased in the fall, fed a heavy grain ration before and after lambing, and marketed the following spring. It was found that early spring lambs can be pro - duced at a profit by this method if sheep and lamb prices are favorable and if fat ewes sell for as much per pound in the spring as breeding ewes cost the preceding fall. Many aged western ewes have been fed grain liberally be - fore and after lambing during the past decade because profits depended very largely upon whether the ewes were fat or thin when marketed. The spread between the prices of fat ewes and cull ewes frequently has been more than five cents per pound. Another reason for feeding a heavy grain ration was that during the years 1921 to 1930 fat ewe prices dropped practically fifty cents per hundredweight each week for seven weeks beginning May 1. This meant that a fat ewe brought but little more per pound June 15 than a cull ewe sold for on May 1. Hence, from every standpoint it appeared justifiable to feed the ewes so that they would attain a reasonably high degree of finish by May 1, at which time they were marketed and the lambs were either sold or else weaned and continued on full feed. j During a time of falling sheep prices profits are uncertain. Therefore, if the production of early spring lambs from aged western ewes is to be profitable under such conditions, pro - duction costs must be kept at a lower figure than was formerly thought necessary. The experiment reported in this bulletin represents an attempt to find such a method. OBJECTS OF THE EXPERIMENT In order to determine, if possible, the minimum amount of grain that may be fed to aged western ewes and produce choice early Jambs, three lots of fifty ewes each were fed as follows: The feeds used were ground ear corn, corn silage, cottonseed meal, and alfalfa meal. Approximately the same amounts of cottonseed meal and alfalfa meal were fed all lots. The ground ear corn was fed at the levels indicated. Each lot received all the corn silage it would clean up. "Reported in Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 250. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 1 Lot 1 — Fed a heavy grain ration before and after lambing Lot 2 — Fed no grain before and a liberal grain ration after lambing. Lot 3— Fed no grain before or after lambing. The second object was to study the quality and palatability of carcasses of ewes fed liberally on grain before and after lambing and to determine the effects of weaning upon the quality and palatability of spring-lamb carcasses. experimental procedure Sheep used. — Aged white-faced Wyoming ewes were purchased on the Omaha market August 27, 1930 Al - though thrifty and in good flesh, these ewes were classed at the market as "broken-mouthed" or "one-year" breeding ewes. They were bred to six purebred Hampshire rams raised in the University flock. Representative ewes and lambs were selected from Lot 1 for the carcass studies and the data collected therefrom were averaged with those obtained in similar studies made in con - junction with the experiment reported in Nebraska ExDeri - ment Station Bulletin 250. Method of feeding. — The ewes grazed in a cornfield and on blue grass pasture during the breeding season from August 28 to October 23. No grain was fed during this period. They were fed in dry lots during the remainder of the experiment. The ewes had access to open sheds, and a closed lambing room was available during cold weather. They were fed grain and roughage in bunks in the open and the lambs were fed m creeps under the sheds. All rations were hand-fed twice daily. Weighing and marketing — Individual weights of each ewe and lamb were taken on three consecutive days at the beginning and conclusion of each phase of the experiment The averages of these three weights were considered as the initial and final weights respectively. The ewes and lambs were snipped on the evening of the day the last experi - mental weight was taken. Shrinkage in shipment was cal - culated from the average of the three final experimental weights. All shipments were by rail. experimental feeding data All of the ewes ran together during the time they were on pasture. The six rams were marked and breeding dates were recorded every three days. This information was used in allotting the ewes, for it was believed that unless the various </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studdss lots lambed at about the same time the results would not answer the question as to the amount of grain that should be fed before and after lambing. Type, weight, and condition were also considered when the ewes were divided. Results before lambing. — Table 1 gives the gains and feed requirements of the ewes from the time they were divided October 23, 1930, until about 30 days before lamb - ing, or January 15, 1931. Lots 2 and 3 were fed together before lambing, since the plan of the experiment specified that these lots should be fed the same during this period. The gains and feed requirements of Lot 1 are typical of the results obtained by many sheepmen in Nebraska and are quite similar to the results reported in Nebraska Bulle - tin 250. The ewes in Lot 1 were fat at lambing time, while those in Lots 2 and 3 were only in medium flesh. The ex - ceptional gain made by each group is misleading unless it is remembered that a considerable part of it is accounted for by the unborn lambs and foetal membranes. Hence the amount of feed required for 100 pounds of gain has no significance, although it does indicate that on the basis of actual increase in body weight, ewes do not make as efficient gains as lambs do. Table 1. — Gains and feed requirements of ewes before lamb - ing, October 23, 1930, to January 15, 1931 — 84. days. Lot 1 Lots 2 and 8 Ground ear corn Cottonseed meal Cottonseed meal Alfalfa meal Alfalfa meal Corn silage Corn silage Number of ewes 50 100 i Pounds Pounds', Average final weight „ 152 126 Average initial weight— „ — 105 104 Average gain ... 47 22 Average daily gain 0.553 0.261 Average daily ration: Ground ear corn 2.25 Cottonseed meal — 0.12 0.13 Alfalfa meal I _ 1.00 1.14 i Corn silage 2.11 4.78 j Peed required for 100 pounds gain: Ground ear corn '. 407 Cottonseed meal 22 48 Alfalfa meal 181 436 Corn silage 381 1828 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 The results secured before lambing indicate definitely, however, that a liberal grain ration must be fed if it is de - sired to have the ewes fat when they lamb. But in order to determine the final effect, if any, of condition at time of lambing, it is necessary to study carefully the data col - lected in subsequent phases of the experiment. Lambing records. — It will be seen by referring to Table 2 that there was little difference among the lots in aver - age date of lambing. There were five barren ewes in Lot 1, two in Lot 2, and three in Lot 3. The rations fed had nothing to do with failures to breed, for experimental feed - ing did not begin until the close of the breeding season. Table 2.— Lambing records. Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot S GO ewes EO ewes GO ewes Average date of lambing. Feb. 12 Feb. 12 Feb. 16 Number of ewes that lambed 45 48 47 Number of lambs dropped: Singles . 34 38 38 Pairs of twins 11 9 9 Total lambs dropped,. 56 56 66 Average wt. at birth (pounds) — 9.9 10.4 10.6 ■ Number of lambs dead at birth.... 5 2 3 From careful observations during the lambing season, it is the authors' opinion that the lower average weight of the lambs at birth and the greater number of lambs dead at birth in Lot 1 than in either of the other lots were due to the condition of the ewes at lambing time. There were more cases of difficult lambing in Lot 1 than in the other lots. It is interesting to note that the heavy silage ration fed to Lots 2 and 3 did not result in weak or "watery" lambs, as is often supposed to be the case. Data on ewes after lambing. — It was not advisable to take individual weights immediately prior to lambing be - cause of the danger of crowding the ewes ; hence the data given in Table 3 cover a period of 115 days, or from approxi - mately 30 days before lambing to May 10, 1931, when the lambs were weaned. Despite the fact that the ewes in Lot 1 received an average daily ration of 1.98 pounds of ground ear corn, 0.18 pound cottonseed meal, 1.00 pound alfalfa meal, and 2.10 pounds corn silage, each ewe lost 14 pounds. Similarly, the ewes in Lot 2 lost in weight even though they received a liberal grain ration after </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studies lambing. As would be expected, Lot 3 showed the greatest loss per head, or 19 pounds. Figured for the entire test, Lot 1 showed a net gain of 33 pounds per head, while Lot 2 made a net gain of 13 pounds per head. Lot 3, on the other hand, gained only three pounds per head during the entire experiment and the wool growth per ewe more than accounted for this amount. This indicates that a heavy silage ration supple - mented with cottonseed meal and alfalfa meal will not fatten an aged western ewe that suckles a lamb. The shrinkage in transit was least in the lots making the larger gains. The dressing percentages indicate the Table 3. — Gains and feed requirements of ewes from approxi - mately SO days before lambing until their lambs were weaned, January 15, 1931, to May 10, 1931 — 115 days. Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Ground ear corn Ground ear corn Cottonseed meal Cottonseed meal Cottonseed meal Alfalfa meal Alfalfa meal Alfalfa meal Corn silage Corn silage Corn silage Number of ewes 50 50 50 j Pounds Pounds Pounds Average initial weight 162 125 127 Average final weight 138 116 108 Average loss in weight 14 9 19 Fleece weight per ewe 7.8 6.4 7^2 Average daily ration: Ground ear corn 1.98 1.01 '. Cottonseed meal .18 .18 ZH Alfalfa meal 1.00 1.19 153 Corn silage 2.10 5.12 6.05 P.ct. P.ct. P.ct.', Shrink In transit 7.25 8.06 9.52 Dressing percentage 50.2 46.4 42.O; Carcass grades 1 P.ct. P.ct. p.ct. Regular. 6.3 25.6 2.4 Good 40.6 32.6 2.4 Fair 43.8 „ Extra heavy 3.1 L Medium 3.1 16.3 33.3 Culls 3.1 6.9 19.0 Cutters 18.6 35.7 Condemned 7.1 Selling price per ewt* $2.75 $2.00 $1.00 'Regular Is Swift's top grade. Carcasses weighing from 60 to 65 pounds were traded strong; those welshing from 66 to 80 pounds were graded fair, and carcasses 80 pounds and up were graded extra heavy. All carcasses In these three grades showed good finish. This ia the price received for the ewes marketed May 12. Complete marketing data on all ewes are given in Table 6. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 differences in finish: Lot 1 yielded 50.2 per cent, Lot 2 yielded 46.4 per cent, while the low yield of 42.0 per cent for Lot 3 reflects a decided lack of finish. The carcass grades, furnished through the courtesy of Swift and Company, are additional proof of the differences in finish. The Lot 1 carcasses were very attractive and exceptionally well covered. This is indicated by the fact that 93.8 per cent of them graded good to choice. While only 68.2 per cent of the carcasses in Lot 2 were good to choice in finish, they were far superior, on the average, to those from Lot 3, of which only 4.8 per cent were good to choice carcasses. The high percentage of cull and cutter carcasses as well as condemned carcasses from Lot 3 sug - gests that they had little value and justifies the low price at which they sold. In this instance, however, selling price does not adequately portray the differences in the carcasses resulting from the three methods of feeding. The differ - ence would have been shown much better had the level of sheep prices been higher. When prices are extremely low, it is questionable whether it pays to fatten the ewes, assum - ing, of course, that the added return from the sales of the ewes is the only justification for doing so. But the re - turns from the ewes are only a part of the total revenue from an undertaking of this kind. The effect of the condition of the ewes at the time of lambing on the lamb crop must also be considered. Data on lambs. — The lambs were fed a grain mixture composed of ground shelled corn 12 parts, bran 2 parts and old-process linseed meal 3 parts by weight in creeps where the ewes could not enter. The results are given in Table 4. Because of the high mortality among the lambs in Lot 1, only 40 were started on feed in this lot, as compared to 51 in Lot 2 and 50 in Lot 3. Most of the lambs that died were weak at birth or out of ewes that gave little or no milk. Whether the heavy loss sustained in Lot 1 was due to the condition of the ewes is difficult to say, especially in view of the fact that the remainder of the lambs in this lot were stronger and took to grain more readily than the lambs m the other two lots. This trouble was not expe - rienced in a test conducted during the winter of 1929-30 •IIS be / &lt; i? e creeps were provided, the lambs began to nibble at the feeds given the ewes. They were creep-fed 66 days before weaning and continued on full feed 28 days after the ewes were marketed. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Table 4. — Comparison of the gains and feed requirements of lambs before and after weaning. Phase 1 — Before weaning Phase 2 — After weaning 66 days 28 days Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Number of lambs 40 51 50 39 50 49 hrj Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds Pounds E Average final weight 63 57 56 76 69 68 g Average initial weight , 25 24 24 63 67 56 § Average gain _ 38 33 32 13 12 12 Average daily gain— 0.567 0.494 0.476 0.443 0A32 0.447 H Average daily ration: w Ground shelled corn - : — 0.54 0.46 0.47 1.57 1.07 1.10 H Bran 0.09 0.08 0.08 0.26 0.18 0.18 Linseed meal . _ 0.14 0.11 0.12 0.39 0.27 0.28 &gt; Alfalfa hay -„ - - 0.64 0.50 0.51 L15 0.95 0.98 Q Feed required per ewt. gain : ,-, Ground shelled corn 96 93 98 353 247 246 s, J Bran -..- 16 16 16 59 41 41 W Linseed meal 24 23 25 88 62 62 £ Alfalfa hay 112 102 108 260 220 220 to ~~ T P. ct. P. ct. pTct. W Shrink in transit - - 6JS9 JMS4 7.21 CO Dressing percentage 51.0 48^6 48.4 g Carcass grades: P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. t) Choice 35.5 10.6 17.4 §j Good -- ~ 32.3 42.6 39.1 Medium, — 19.4 34.0 ~ Cull „ 12.8 2.1 19.6 Canner cull __ J:;;:;;;;;;: _ 10.6 8.7 SelHng_prlce per ewt — —■■■» __■-____: _ZZ ____-_-__ ■■ ?8.00 $7.50 $7.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 By referring to Table 4 it will be seen that the lambs in Lot 1 consumed more grain and made larger gains than those in either Lot 2 or Lot 3. Part of this difference is explained by the fact that the Lot 1 lambs were more robust, doubtless because the heavy grain ration fed their mothers stimulated the flow of milk. The ewes in Lots 2 and 3 received a heavy silage ration and required more time to clean up their feed than was taken by Lot 1. It was very noticeable that the lambs in Lots 2 and 3 spent more time eating from their mothers' bunks than did the Lot 1 lambs. As a result, the lambs in Lots 2 and 3 ate less grain in the creeps. The silage and ground ear corn which they ate were bulky and hence satisfied their ap - petites but probably contributed little to their body weight. The Lot 2 lambs were more uniform when weaned than the Lot 3 lambs. It was evident that the milk flow of the ewes fed no grain was lower than it was in the other lots. All of the ewes in Lot 3 were thin and several became emaciated and unthrifty. It appears justifiable to con - clude, therefore, that lambs out of aged western ewes do not make maximum gains in a dry lot when their mothers receive no grain during the suckling period. However, feeding no grain affected the ewes much more than it did' the lambs. In this test, as in the previous one, the lambs made re - markably economical gains during the suckling period. Here again the figures are misleading unless it is remem - bered that a considerable portion of the feed consumed by the ewes should be charged to the lambs, since milk un - questionably was responsible for much of their increase in weight. It will also be recalled that all of the ewes lost in weight during the suckling period ; consequently the in - crease in weight made by the lambs was the only return from the feed eaten by the ewes. Results after weaning. — The lambs were weaned May 10 and the ewes were marketed May 12. In the test reported in Bulletin 250 it was observed that lambs continued to make satisfactory gains when weaned at about three months of age. This practice makes it possible to market the ewes when prices average considerably higher and also results in a saving of the feed required by the ewes. Top prices are paid for lambs averaging 60 pounds for only a short time during the Easter season. As the season progresses more weight is demanded. The lambs in this experiment were not heavy enough May 10 to sell well for slaughter and there is little demand for feeders, especially </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studies Ms '■_____ ■■-.': '"■"-.' ■ T' : BasssssssssHsssassL - ________________ H | ' I lj 7:: ' EH 7?:' "■"■■ g - .-'~B?B.7 1 - »3SS!2 j JHH3H " : ' ' 1 3 I . ■# 81, 9^s^^^__i*&lt;y3ks_-fj. v.^/^Ss^HJ i a siM. jflBssae . , «C slsa«ats&amp;^^^..^XXii ■H NnKBan^ftt/^S^&amp;'fa''; " .* %g''ift^ -^ sstSijIp^f £ 'ffijptff ! assB^sss^ *asaTiBs f^-^*^ V'*) M^ - : ? 1 ~i : I Fig. 1. — The ewes when the lambs were weaned — Lot 1 above, I. Lot 2 in the middle, Lot 3 below. - natives, at that time of year. While prices of spring lambs usually decline during May, the drop in price is usually not great enough to make it unprofitable to continue feeding lambs until they attain the most desirable market weight and finish. Bat unless the lambs are marketed prior to June 15 there is no justification for the expense and trouble of hav - ing them arrive in January and February. The principal reason for this is that the season for genuine spring Iambs </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 closes the first market day in June. Prices tend to drop sharply after that date because of increased receipts of Comtek the range Stat6S ' as WeI1 as from the The average daily gain for each of the lots was some - what less during the 28 days after weaning than for the suckling period. It will be noted by referring to Table 4 that there were no significant differences in gains during this final period. There was a marked difference in the amount of feed consumed and in the economy of gains. All of the lota were virtually self-fed. The Lot /lambs Appeared mor? vigorous and demonstrated this by consuming almost 50 per cent more gram than was consumed by either of the S 5Sr.%-- Se 7^ 1 i 8inal Vi l atheT unthrift y lambs in Lots ?o£ d 3 *. amed fairly wel1 but tended to »row instead of fatten and it was apparent that they did not consume as ISmbs Kram aS WaS eateD ' ° n the avera * e ' b y the other Although the Lot 1 lambs consumed more feed than to ?SffZ+ B _ h % 3 '} hey U - Sed , % less effi «ently. As a mat - ter of fact, the feed required for 100 pounds of gain by Lot 1 was almost as large in amount as is ordinarily re - wh^sta^e^n Hf *"* '** *""*■ 6 ° P ° UndS Three Lot 1 lambs died during the period following weaning. Each one of these was fat and thrifty and showed no evide f sickness . Post . mortem Txlmfna - tions revealed that eating too much grain was responsible for the deaths. No trouble of this kind was experienced in the test reported in Bulletin 250, although theTmount ?h/!!i COnS w e i?- P ? r £ ea l da - ily in that test averaged about the same as m this test. But in this, as in the previous test, the economy of gains was sufficient justification for feed - ing the lambs 28 days after they were weaned The lambs were marketed June 9. The dressing per - centages and carcass grades were again furnished through the courtesy of Swift and Company and are given in Table ilofftJ-* had a mark e d advantage over the other lots in yield and carcass grades and this superiority was reflected ancf f in the S - ellin *. Pnce ' AWhougn Lots! and 3 sold at the same price, yielded approximately the same and averaged about the same in carcass grading, thi Lot 3 carcasses showed more variation, particularly in grades, than either of the other lots. On a discriminating market and with a fairly high spread between high-gVad! </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studdss and low-grade lambs, Lot 3 would have been the low-selling lot by a considerable margin. From a study of the data on the lambs, the feeding of grain to the ewes, at least after lambing, appears justifiable even in a period of depressed prices. Furthermore, a care - ful analysis of the data on both ewes and lambs leads to the conclusion that if the ewes are thin at the end of the breeding season, they should be fed grain before lambing, since it is practically impossible to fatten a ewe suckling a lamb. It is questionable whether as much grain should be fed prior to lambing as was fed in this trial. In view of the difficulty experienced with Lot 1 at lambing time, it would seem that a liberal grain ration would be preferable to an exceedingly heavy grain ration before lambing. This question, however, can only be answered by further experi - mentation. Total feed consumed and total gain per head.- — In the test reported in Bulletin 250 ewes fed a heavy grain ration for 178 days consumed 5.6 bushels of ground ear corn; per head. In this test, ewes handled in a similar manner over a period of 199 days averaged 5.48 bushels of ground; ear corn. j The total feed consumed and the total gain per head by lots are summarized in Table 5. The figures are based on the number of ewes purchased and the number of lambs marketed rather than on the number of ewes marketed and the number of lambs dropped. This method is used because it is the fairest way to account for the feed con - sumed by the animals that died. This table, then, • will probably be of more interest and value to the farmer who wishes to use one of the methods followed in this study than it will be to the investigator who wants to make a critical analysis of the results. Marketing data on all ewes. — Pertinent data relative to the marketing of the ewes from each lot are given in Table 6. Two points deserve special consideration in con - nection with these data. In the first place, it is evident that the price of fat ewes declines rapidly as the season advances. This makes it imperative that the, ewes be fat and ready for market as early as possible. method of feeding used in Lot 1 fulfills this requirement. In the second place, nine dry ewes, five of which failed to lamb, were marketed from Lot 1 on March 25 at $2.25 per hundredweight more than was received for the -bulk of the ewes marketed from Lot 1 May 12. As has already been explained, the number of barren ewes was not due </seg>
            <seg id="p016">3f g Table 5. — Total feed consumed and total gain per head during entire experiment. a Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 r Ewes | Lambs Ewes Lambs Ewes Lambs S* Number of days fed 199 94 199 94 3 Total gain per head (pounds) 33 51 13 ~^ 3 g Feed consumed per animal 1 : S Ground ear corn (bushels). 5.48 I.57 H Ground shelled corn (bushels) _.. 1.52 ...._ 1 13 1 13 m Cottonseed meal (pounds) 27.74 29 75 1_ 28 i 46 H Linseed meal (pounds) _ — ... 21.29 ......'.... 16.80 ...1 15 82 _\ Bran (pounds) 14 . 19 1054 10 ; 55 g Corn silage (pounds) 384.10 959.02 . 1066 40 § Cut alfalfa (pounds) ., — 182.68 225.90 __ 264 08 Alfalfa hay (pounds) __ 30.34 62.91 .......... ~GZM W 'Based on ewes purchased and lambs marketed. P r— t to Oi </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studdss to the method of feeding. Such ewes are likely to, be found in any flock, since failure to breed is often the rea - son why range ewes are marketed in the fall and it is not always possible to detect all of them at the time they 'are purchased. It is desirable that such ewes be marketed as soon as possible after it is determined that they will; not lamb. If they have been fed grain, as the Lot 1 ewep in this test were, they will be fat and can be sold immediately at a good price. Marketing data on all lambs. — The marketing data on the lambs from each lot are presented in Table 7. It is interesting to note that the three lambs slaughtered May 13 for carcass studies at Lincoln were appraised at $1.50 j per hundredweight more than the other lambs in Lot 1 sold for on June 9. This merely illustrates again that the pro - duction of early spring lambs is a specialized business, since success depends very largely upon price trends. The Easter lamb market should be the goal of those engaging in this business; but if it is impossible to get the lambs ready at such an early date they should be continued on full feed until they grade at least medium to good and'pre - ferably good to choice on foot. Finally, we can conclude that the method followed in Lot 1, or a modification of it, is entirely satisfactory where the object is to produce early spring lambs from aged western ewes that are marketed after raising one lamb crop. CARCASS STUDIES OF LAMBS Carcass studies were undertaken to determine whether there is any deterioration in carcass quality after weaning. Some maintain that after weaning the lambs grow rapidly, lose their "milk fat," and thus lower their carcass quality. During the two-year period, eighteen lambs were slaugh - tered from Lot 1, which had been full fed. Nine were slaughtered at weaning time and an equal number j four weeks later. The lambs selected for slaughter were average for their respective lots. Ewe lambs only were used, for the sake of uniformity. Gramlich and Thalman 2 conclude that heifers fatten more rapidly than steers. Whether this difference holds true in sheep is unknown, but it was thought that a more accurate comparison might be made if the sex factor were eliminated. All slaughtering was done in the Experi - ment Station meat laboratory. The tentative method of =Sex and Age as Factors in Cattle Feeding, Nebr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 252. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Table 6. — Marketing data on all ewes — average weights calculated from market weights. = = ph,. Lotl jfjj I Lot 3 Date per Number Average Number Average Number Average _t&gt; marketed ewt marketed weight marketed weight marketed weight a Dollars Pounds Pounds Pounds £ March 25 6.00 9 132 2 120 3 107 a. March 25 2.50 1 120 3 103 2 105 g May 12 2.75 32 120 "Z ~ M May 12 2.00 .... ...... 43 100 _ &amp; May 12 1.00 „ _ 42 92 S3 May 12 .... i» " May 20 , 2.00 3» 128 . g •One canner cripple sold for 50 cents. , 2 Three ewes slaughtered at Lincoln for carcass studies. t. CO TABLE 7. — Marketing data on all lambs — average weights calculated from market weights. jlj I PH,» j*j I Lot2 I Lot3 === § Date per Number Average Number Average Number Average __ marketed ewt. marketed weight marketed weight marketed weight g Dollars Pounds Pounds pounds C May 13 9.50 3 1 67 „ S ■ , M June 9 8.00 31' 70 .... .... 2 June 9 7.50 .... .... 47 65 48» 64 to June 12 7.75 3* 78 __ _. .... .... °* 'Slaughtered at Lincoln for carcass studies. 'One cripple not included. •One Iamb died in transit ; not Included. 'Slaughtered at Lincoln for carcass studies. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studdss slaughtering and cutting approved by the co-operators in the National Quality in Meats project was used. The slaughter and cutting data are presented in Table 8. TABLE 8. — Slaughter and cutting data — average of two years. 28 days At weaning after weaning Average weight per lamb (pounds) 67.56 80.56 Hot carcass weight less 2%% (pounds) 33.89 40.70 Dressing yield (per cent) 50.16 50.52 Caul and ruffle fat (pounds) „ 1.94 2.57 Caul and ruffle fat (percentage of live.wt.) 2.87 3.19 Average weight of pelt (pounds) 7.23 9.40 Average cold weight of carcass (pounds) 32.58 38.85 Average weight 7-rib rack (pounds). 3.14 3.97 Rack (percentage of carcass) 9.64 10.22 Average weight of legs (pounds) 10.71 12.65 Legs (percentage of carcass) 32.87 32 56 j Average weight of rough loin (pounds) 5.61 6.75 Rough loin (percentage of carcass) 17.22 17.37; Average weight of kidney fat (pounds) 1.10 1.17 Kidney fat (percentage of carcass) 3.38 3.01; The average weight of the lambs slaughtered at wean - ing time was 68 pounds. Those slaughtered 28 days after weaning averaged 81 pounds, or 13 pounds more. The carcasses of the weanling lambs averaged 34 pounds, while those from lambs continued on full feed for 28 days after weaning averaged almost 41 pounds. The carcass weight was computed by deducting 2y_ per cent from the hot car - cass weight. This method appeared preferable for calcu - lating dressing yields because of variations in the humidity of the cooler. Dressing yields in both instances were in excess of 50 per cent. The high dressing yield was probably caused in part by the overnight shrinking prior to killing. The higher dressing percentage of the lambs 28 days after weaning might be considered as an indication of greater finish. Internal fat is considered by many as an indication of finish. The weanling lambs had 1.94 pounds of caul and ruffle fat, while those slaughtered 28 days after weaning averaged 2.57 pounds. Not only did the internal fat in - crease in weight, but it increased more rapidly than body weight, as evidenced by the fact that these fats made up 2.87 per cent of the live weight of the weanling lambs and 3.19 per cent of the weight of similar lambs slaughtered 28 days later. The pelts of the weanling lambs weighed 7.23 pounds each and those of the lambs slaughtered later weighed 9.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 d J$ e A 8rov $\_ ot pelts was more than the increase of body weight, probably because of the growth of staple and the mcrease in yolk occasioned by the warmer weather. ™SP , cuttin g me thod employed was a modification of com - mercial Practice. A seven-rib rack was made in order that tbis cut might be comparable to the rib cut of beef. While ?£tT™i? 0m ? nsed H 4 per cent of the carcass of wean - ling lamb, this percentage was 10.22 per cent in the lambs Mteed four weeks later. This was due principaUyto the thickening of the flesh and the fat covering of this cut «4+t t a U I i 0in - was made ' coasting of the loin with the attached flank pieces and including the kidneys and kid - ney fat. This accounts for the larger percentage of loin SiSi * ene rally given in cutting teste. During the 28 days M%?frl7W lB *^ Ml i percenta * e £ loin increased froS 17.22 to 17.37. This increase can hardly be ascribed to Sf 0 * Mdn f? fat ' The increase in kfdney IhiJfE f ° Und to be very l light &gt; ta fact relatively less rapid than the increase in weight of the carcass. The kidney fat comprised 3.38 per cent of the carcasses of the lambs at weaning time and only 3.01 per cent of the carcasse?from lambs slaughtered 28 days later. It is interesting that fS Z e he d Jt^ S f g t yi f d i, lll^ r ? al fat ' and some SS changL to be noted later indicated greater finish in the second SStS^C^t E* th6re Was no increase in the amount of kidney fat. Packing house men who handle lambs ex tensively are inclined to consider the kidney fat as one 5 the most reliable indexes of finish. Probably due to the increased percentage of loin and rack, the percentage of legs declined from 32.87 to 32.56. True, the percentage changes were not great in any instance and might be re  - &amp;£* -ttSg. 6 aS t0 fadlVidUal Variations ' or va «a - •E arca^JI radin8r -~' The ca rcasses were graded by a com- S5„ e ;i th l ee&gt; 'ri 8 descriptive grading chart This method was based on the suggestion of Spencer*, who pro- S f d 0 fi ™ grades as follows: choice, good, medium, com - 2S2L? k ° •* Nu .™ e rical values were assigned to these S^f J 6 f nm^ lg Wlth one for choice « The average grades assigned by the committee are given in Table 9. „t £L?? eTfi g e nume rical grade of the lambs slaughtered at weanmg time was 1.59 and of those slaughtered four </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studdss Table 9. — Lamb carcass grades — average of two years. 28 days At weaning after weaning Average carcass grade 1.59 1.55 Average carcass grade High-good High-good Length of leg (cm.) 23.78 • 24.39 Circumference of leg (cm.) 27.89 29.31 Relation of length to circumference 1.17 1.20 weeks later, 1.55. Both of these grades are within the upper limits of grade " good." So far as could be deter - mined by the graders, no deterioration in quality occurred in the four weeks following weaning. There is an uncon - scious trend on the part of graders to be more lenient with the carcasses of young lambs and to "tighten up" as the animals get older. The fact that the graders found no lowering of grade then appears to be doubly significant. Spencer 5 has reported that in better-quality lambs the cir - cumference of the legs is proportionately greater than the length. The method of Spencer was applied to all lambs slaughtered and the average results included in Table 9. In the carcasses of the lambs slaughtered at weaning time, the circumference of the leg was found to be 1.17 times the length of the leg from the aitch bone to the point of the hock. When similar measurements were made on the lambs slaughtered 28 days later, the circumference of the leg was found to be 1.20 times the length. This further strengthens the assertion that no lowering of carcass quality resulted because of weaning. Table 10. — Physical analysis of lamb short racks — average of two years. 28 days At weaning after weaning Average weight of short rack (pounds) 1.57 1.98 Average weight of edible portion (pounds).... 1.33 1.70 Percentage edible material (per cent) 84.71 85.86 Average weight of hone (pounds) .24 .27 Percentage of bone (per cent) 15.29 13.64 The seven-rib short racks were center-split and one-half was separated into edible and inedible material. ] The edible material was comprised of fat and lean. The! bone, cartilage, and neck ligament were classed as bone. The results of this physical analysis are shown in Table 10. During the 28 days of full feeding following weaning, the percentage of edible material increased one per cent. •A Method of Determining Quality in the Wool and Meat of Market Lambs. Proc. Am. Soc. An. Prod., pp. 168-167. 1927. - I </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 Chemical studies — The edible material from the DrecpH a ng sa 8 usaLTill W i C ifH g r nd thr&lt; T h a */lHnch,Sat?„f Sffi taSMSIS ChemiSt ' The aVGrage -suite e ar S e U Sre: TABl fells7 &lt;JhemiCal StUdi6S 7mde With tomb— average of two At weaning ~~28 days afte~r weaning _ Average^ Range Average Ra^ Analysis of rack flesh: " ~ - Crude protein ' (p.ct.) __f. itSlltS __U _tS' l»l\ Ether extract (p.ct.) 41.26 34.25-49.go _lf_ ffigrgg Analysis of kidney fat: " Water f per cent; ...... 7.04 5 04-11.97 7 or roi. m nn Crude protein (p.ct) 1.51 0.81-244 183 i'u Ether extract (p.ct.) 91.42 85.55-93 66 91 ?I agio",!™ Refractive index' .... | 1.4560 1.4555-1.4567 14562 iSSl-JJfc 'Based on three samples only. ~~ The kidney fat was removed and finely choDDed hv hand and sampled for analysis. No great cLnges Fn com position were noted in either the rack flesh or the kidn^v fat. No loss of fat was observed following weaning where the lambs were continued on full feed. In fact there was some evidence of increasing fatness. To determine Zth! 1^ of the kidney fat was kffected'by^eantog r£ frachve indexes were determined in the first trial I ?in£ practically no differences were found, this proTedure was dispensed with the second year. proceaure was Cooking tests. — All cooking teste were made „ ni i a . «,« supervision of Miss Matilda Peters roi "th Horn E?ono m £s Department. The official method of roasting Tamo le J? as approved by the co-operators in the Quality Ind Palatobfl Srealte* Th? l g « ati0n^ WaS foIlow?d in roSsttngWeft 527° P tw i eg "S?* 8 w ? re seared for 20 minutes at 9fi?o I' OT J h i? y re then P lac ed in an oven heated to 257 F. and kept there until the temperature at the centS of the roast reached 167° P C7R° r \ o«;7Ji * j v center </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studdss PJ . .tfcAjG&gt;-- . f ?\ __\w' r \_\\. F - \ __A\*s-K?^k 6 B ' I I I I Isssssl ssssff 1 ssssf ' HS BaBBff 'jtssstosftsav ' ■'■ ■ atpssssssSaWwl /SsIssssssssbW- saiSf^sT^ria^ .^bs^ssk^^bp IsssW ', I- , ff f « m -ll ' 'issslsf \ -'■ /'A' 'asl BaV ssssssalkm I'^l ' '^flGsBMBSsBHs ir ' , *•&gt; S SB— | BBBBBHi|*M&gt;n - &gt;. 3\_ -el-: TH •:- •■■ ■- --_\\ I :■"■• , __;_! -5 2 3&gt;; ; l 7777'-.:'' j •*•■- 7_ _ f j ! 3 i _ -■ '"" ! '-''■■ -vi ir 'aaW . ' ;~*%kH j ' _wR fcja^^*aasssV ■ Juv^rs—, c^H Fig. 2. — Representative carcasses and cuts from weanling Iambs in Lot 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 be prepared, the cooking studies were confined to only one year's work. The comparison is doubtless based on too limited numbers, yet where the data on nine lambs are available, they coincide closely with the average data based on only three. During the roasting process, the roasts from the wean - ling lambs lost 11.89 per cent by evaporation, while those from similar lambs full-fed for 28 days after weaning shrank only 10.19 per cent. The reverse was true of the loss by drippings, being 3.82 per cent from the roasts of weanlmg lambs and 7.09 per cent from the other group. No explanation can be offered for the longer time required to cook the legs of the weanling lambs. The results were consistent m all three samples, but do not agree with the results secured the preceding year when six legs from weanling lambs were cooked. The average of the six legs cooked durmg the first year's work was 36 minutes per pound. These data are not summarized in Table 12, since no cooking teste were conducted with the roasts from com - parable lambs slaughtered 28 days after weaning. Table 12. — Cooking data with lamb. Lambs slaughtered Lambs slaughtered £* a, a 28 d «™ _ . weaning time after weaning Weight of leg roasts (grams) 1494 ____ Loss by evaporation (grams) 178 192 Loss by evaporation (per cent) 11.89 10 19 Weight of drippings (grams) 57 133' Drippings (per cent) 3 -82 7 0 g Roasting time (minutes per pound) 55' 33' Palatability studies. — The committee which passed upon the cooked roasts varied from six to eight persons, all of °i m mv d considerable experience in this kind of work. The official cooked-meat grading chart was used. mi average £r adln Ks are given in Table 13. The roasts taken from the lambs 28 days after weaning showed more intensity of aroma, flavor of fat, and flavor of lean. In aroma, the increase in intensity amounted to seven-tenths of a grade and in flavor of fat the increase was three-tenths of a grade, while in the intensity of lean Z°l_. 1 mc rease was four-tenths of a grade. The aroma and the flavor of the lean were slightly less desirable in the roasts taken from the older lambs. The differences here were slight, only one-tenth and two-tenths of a grade re - spectively. The flavor of the fat appeared to increase two - tenths of a grade as a result of 28 days of full feeding after </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 Table 13. — Palatability studies with lamb. Average of roasts from Iambs Average of roasts from lambs H slaughtered at weaning time slaughtered 28 days after weaning W Average Average O grade Descriptive term grade Descriptive term £j Aroma: Intensity 4.71 Slightly pronounced 5.39 Moderately pronounced 13 Desirability . 5.71 Moderately desirable 5.61 Moderately desirable 2 Texture . 5.39 Moderately fine 5.11 Moderately fine Flavor of fat: 2 Intensity 4.67 Slightly pronounced 4.98 Slightly pronounced Desirability 5.67 Moderately desirable 5.84 Moderately desirable O Flavor of lean: 5 Intensity 4.83 Slightly pronounced 5.22 Moderately pronounced &gt; Desirability 6.42 Moderately desirable 5.22 Moderately desirable [g Tenderness 6.42 Tender 5.17 Moderately tender OT JuiciiLGSS * ___ Quality . 4.67 Slightly rich 4.07 Slightly rich 2 Quantity „.. ' 4.59 Slightly dry , 4.00 Slightly dry gj </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 S e q a uiSonab r ie ether SUCh Sma " diff^ences are significant The difference in texture was verv slie-ht ir™™ +1.^ «£«KS .^^_£t_7___&gt;3_3s^ days later graded 5.17 or moderately tender In Si ness, the roastefrom the weanling lambs graded luSdS In e rhl han P? r ° aS ? from lambs fu » fe d 28 da/s linger fro^ J? 6 opm Y? n8 ° f the .grading committee, the rof ste rXTrs% e wean . lm * lam bs contained more and richer JuicV the difference m each instance being six-tenths of t *£££ CARCASS STUDIES OF EWES It has been shown that the price received fnr- +»,« « m » an important factor in deternSg whether 'the il^f tion of early lambs shall be profitabfe^r not Because of hP^? 110^ 6 ? f ? e eWes from a financia" standponS and because of the lack of information concerning the IS and palatability of the carcasses of fat a£d Iwes a toS of nine ewes were slaughtered and detailed Ses were 1981 T&gt;!f, eWeS w £ e /Stored in 1930 and threTln 1931. The same methods were emoloved a* fn~ i a „ko j It should be recalled that the ewes were all aeed anH designated as "broken-mouthed." TheJ were 5! from aftr'^Sng^n^f 'ff * «?t MX^S »Ater lamDing. All of the ewes used had suckled In™*™ Based on the lot average, the ewes had gained 33 P oSi ds each during the course of the exDerimpnt *«««.,?«. slandered were average Tn wefgTt^nd ha^ma'de* S? age gains, they may be considered as typical of Lot 1 Th* slaughter and cutting data are reported^ Tabled rnmrf„Hr e \ aVe^ aged . 13 ° P ° UndS after a 12-hour shrink leiri v lV hG leasing yield on the hot carcass weight less 2V 2 per cent the average yield was 50.3 per cent All accosted for h tht 8horn prior to a«£bteTwhfch accounted for the low average weight of the Delt ioko S 7 S W fi T n h6 in * ernal |at (the caul pf U8 the ruff^fat) aver- Ss g ed d a 7 s 5 fo r P ?Xe1 ai Sh r s __HfL Th % Same CUttin * method was usea as lor the lambs and it was found that the short rack </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studqis ■ ■ ■ ■■»■■ ■■■Issf W ' M A m. I m m mm mm Ml m __\ - 9 111 sl mS by . _■_. ■ ■ ,_ x. ' fir stsssssssssssssssssssl__- -.sssssssssasssssL-. T / BBBBBBsW at SaBBSM ssssssssM &lt;LJf I ■ nK r '.* r - \\____w\wi (____m ■« *l? f *§*^r_W _\\^^__ _Wj&amp;9^^__ rtPl_9^^_i ____W__ "^."^^ l^ss^^^^^^^^sT . J» ■ *« *■* «»&gt;.'*•• wlB__ ■slt.sst^aiar ■&lt;•. .._. ______ •__*&amp;____-*. Jt^— '^i«is«sssssss»»s^»ssssssssssssss«lJssss»«m»&gt;^.TMafc^fc^«M^ t ,,^ M | K^a^a^a^a^a^a^a^a^,,3 M | p s^ B-^^^jl : jj-^lfLJ MB feo2-j| fe . Fig. 3. — Carcasses and cuts from lambs slaughtered 28 days after weaning from Lot 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 TABU! 14.— Average slaughter and cutting data— average of two years. y ' Average weight per ewe (pounds) "*" ,,.,,- Average hot carcass weight (pounds) ZZ" _ _ mil &lt;ES% w 3^£Sti^ ; less w * r^- « Pelt rpo«nd«; - y ~ 7.56 Weight of 7-rib rack fpound*; "" 1 °°° Rack (percentage of carcass) _ ._-\_-__t Weight of legs (pounds)_.__. | *MJ Legs (percentage of carcass) _ ,tli Weight of rough loin (pounds) ZZZ toii Rough loin (percentage of carcass) " loa. Weight of kidney fat (pounds) """"" ,?? Kidney fat (percentage of carcass) !"~""!ZZ! 535 comprised 10 per cent of the carcass, the legs 31 per cent, and the rough loin 19.82 per cent. Each carcass carried mv P ° Un i S of kldne y fat &gt; or 5.35 per cent of the carcass. The mutton carcasses were graded by the same commit - r T r e v, as ,f ra J d . ed the lamb carca sses. As will be noted in SSSL li, he . carcass grade was 1.90, or good, al - though the individual carcasses ranged from choice to medium. Without exception, they were very well covered Table 15.— Mutton carcass grades— average of two years. Average carcass grade : t oft Length of leg (cm.) ZZZZZ &lt;&gt;b?q Circumference of leg (cm.) " ____ "" 2*2 Relation of circumference to length "" .." ~Z_ _ ig with good heavy kidneys. The carcasses, however, lacked the shapelmess of lamb carcasses. In beef terms, the car - casses were "cowy,;" that is, they were noticeably promi - nent in the hips, bulging in the ribs, and flat in the loin. While quite well covered, several carcasses showed con - siderable unevenness of covering, being rather patchy or gobby. By applying Spencer's suggestion with regard to leg plumpness, it was found that the circumference of the leg was 1.18 times as great as the leg length. This is about tne same relationship as was found with the lambs pro - duced by these ewes. 1..EWS? 1 and ch .? mical analysis.— As with lambs, one - • * °i-vi e seven-rib rack was boned out, being separated into edible material consisting of fat and lean and inedible material consisting of the bone, cartilage, and neck tendon. In this separation, 86 per cent was classed as edible and </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studies 13 per cent as inedible. These are approximately the sartie percentages as were found in the lambs full-fed 28 days after weaning. The edible material was thoroughly ground, mixed, and analyzed. The rack flesh contained 39 per cent water, 0.61 per cent ash, IIY2 P er cent crude protein, and 48 per cent ether extract. Compared with the rack flesh of the lambs which had been full-fed 28 days after weaning, the flesh of the ewes was definitely fatter as indicated by a lower I percentage of water, ash, and protein, and the higher fat content. Table 16. — Physical and chemical analyses of mutton — aver - age of two years. Weight of rack (pounds) 3.£4 Weight of fat and lean (pounds) „ 2 80 Fat and lean (per cent) . 86 42 Weight of bone (pounds) _ 1J43 Bone (per cent) _ 13 r 7 Chemical analysis of edible portion (fat and lean) : Water (per cent) J- — 39 49 Ash (per cent) - _ — 61 Crude protein (per cent) 11 55 Ether extract (per cent) 48 31 Chemical analysis of kidney fat: Water (per cent) _ ~ 4.78 Crude protein (per cent) _ .84 Ether extract (per cent)..... — 94.40 Refractive Index 1 14548 1 Refractlve index based on three samples only. The same might be said about the composition of the kidney fat. During the second year's work, refractive in - dices were determined on three kidney-fat samples. [The average refractive index was found to be 1.4548. This in - dicates that the fat of the ewes was somewhat firmer than that of the lambs that sucked them. Cooking tests. — In co-operation with Miss Matilda Peters of the Home Economics Department, three leg roasts Jyere I prepared each year. These cute were roasted by the official method for roasting lamb as agreed upon by the co-opera - tors in the National Quality in Meat project. The average weight of the roasts was 2,835 grams. Each roast lost, on the average, 12 per cent through evapo - ration and 8 per cent by drippings. The time required for the roasts to reach a uniform degree of " donenjess " averaged 38 minutes to the pound with a range of 30 to 44 minutes. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 276 ■ »•'• m ■ ■"'!«•'' ' -P ■' X all' fek ad •'■.'• afi "''•». H BBBBBBBBBBBB&amp;~ SaEaFrc^SH Tt?*-* &amp;."- a\_wt__\__.tif%r^__\ __________ Tat ' 1 * *^Ja»" ■ f M ___t__t_\ BBBBBW .^SBBBBBBBBBBBBbJ ssssssssl ssaisaBBssV *. : ESB[«afeiia£lsE^ Pig. 4. — Representative carcasses and cuts from ewes in Lot 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Feeding Tests and Carcass Studies Table 17. — Cooking data on mutton roasts — average of bvo years. J Weight of leg roasts (grams) ; ,.,, ■ „ 2834.83 Loss by evaporation (grams) , 336 00 Loss by evaporation (per cent) " 11.85 Weight of drippings (grams) 234 67 Drippings (per cent) _ g°2g Roasting. time (minutes per pound) „ „." 3s!27 . . , . *i Palatability studies. — A committee of nine passed judg - ment upon samples of the cooked mutton, recording their impressions on the official cooked-meat grading chart. The average grades are presented in Table 18. It is particu - larly interesting to compare the palatability grades with those for lamb as given in Table 13. In the judgment' of the committee, the aroma of the mutton was more pro - nounced, although not materially less desirable than that of lamb. The texture of the meat was more coarse in the mutton carcasses. The flavor of the fat and of the lean was slightly more pronounced and somewhat less desiraible in the roasts from the ewe carcasses. Table 18. — Palatability studies with mutton — average of two years. Average grade Descriptive term Aroma: ! : Intensity _.. 5.56 Moderately pronounced Desirability - 4.69 Slightly desirable j Texture 4.88 Slightly coarse ' Flavor of fat: Intensity 5.04 Moderately pronounced Desirability _ 4.58 Slightly desirable Flavor of lean: ~ Intensity 5.52 Moderately pronounced DeslrabUity 4.68 Slightly desirable Tenderness 4.39 Slightly tough Juice : Quality — _ 3.88 Perceptible Quantity 4.00 Slightly dry In comparing the roasts from the ewe carcasses with those from the lambs, the greatest difference noted was in the tenderness. The lamb roasts ranged from moderately tender to tender, while the mutton roasts were graded slightly tough. In the opinion of the committee, the lamb roasts had a richer juice, although not a great deal more juice than those from the ewes. tiMJ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>