<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>History of Farm Land Prices in Eleven Nebraska Counties 1873-1933</title>
               <date value="1934-06">1934-06</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE , UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 72 History of Farm Land Prices in Eleven Nebraska Counties 1873-1933 ELEANOR H. HINMAN Department of Rural Economics Location of the Counties Studied LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JUNE, 1934 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Pago Introduction 5 True Sales by Warranty Deed 11 Volume of farm land sales, 1873-1933 11 Total value of farm land sold, 1873-1933 17 Sales price per acre sold, 1873-1933 21 Distribution of farm land sales by price groups, 1910-33.. 28 Distribution and price of farm land sales, by size of tract sold, 1910-33 29 Farm land turnover, 1874-1933 33 Relation of True Sales to Other Types of Transfer, 1920-33 36 Types of land transfers.... 36 Foreclosures as related to various other items 41 Land transferred to credit corporations, 1920-33 44 Various Factors Affecting Farm Land Price 46 Farm income 46 Commodity prices 48 Mortgage interest rate _ - 61 Transportation costs .- 52 Soil types - 63 Other factors affecting farm land price.: 60 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY A record of all the true sales of farm land by warranty deed m 11 Nebraska counties from 1873 to 1933 is presented by years and studied m connection with several economic factors affecting land price. A record of all land transfers other than true sales m the same counties during the years 1920-33 is also presented. The counties from which data were obtained are grouped m four principal type-of -farmintr areas. Allowing the average price per acre of the farm land sold m 1910-14 to equal 100, the average price per acre of the land sold annually m the nine eastern counties rose from about 8 m 1873 to 178 m 1920, and declined to 77 m 1933. The price m the two western counties was much lower than that of the eastern-Nebraska land m all years; but the land price relative had risen by 1921 to 2C4 m a sand-hill county and to 287 m a high-plains county. The rate of turnover of farm land by decades tended to decrease from the period 1884-93 m the nine eastern counties and from the period 1894-1903 m the two western counties up to the period 1924-33. The rate of turnover was usually higher m the two western counties than m the eastern counties. A special study of the velocity of sales of farm land m York and Box Butte counties m 1917-20 indicates that there was little land speculation m these counties during the years mentioned. True sales of farm land declined from 81 per cent of all transfers conveying full title to farm land m the nine eastern counties m 1920 to 30 per cent during the first eight months of 1933; and from 81 to 21 per cent m the two western counties during the same years. Fore - closures (sales by sheriffs and receivers) increased from 0.3 to 14 per cent of all transfers conveying full title m the eastern counties and from 0.5 to 26 per cent of all such transfers m the western counties. Other types of forced sales also increased greatly. In the period 1920-33 the foreclosure rate ranged from two foreclosures per 100 farms m Saline county to 53 foreclosures per 100 farms m Logan county. It varied approximately with the rate of farm land turnover m 1918-20 and inversely to the value of farm land m the several coun - ties studied. Farm land price m .the 11 counties followed the trend of Nebraska net farm income from 1914 to 1933; but changes m land price were much less extreme than those m net farm income and lagged one or two years behind the latter. The same was .true of the relation be - tween the index of the Nebraska farm price of agricultural commodities and the index of farm land price m the 11 counties from 1910 to 1933. From 1873 to 1894 the general commodity index and the Nebraska farm land price index moved m opposite directions; from 1899 to 1910 both rose but at different rates; from 1914 to 1933 they cor - responded rather closely. One of the several factors producing this divergence before 1910 was a decline m the mortgage interest rate, which m 11 sample townships m southeastern Nebraska decreased from nearly 11 per cent m 1874 to about 5% per cent m 1905, and, except m 1917-22, remained approximately stationary thereafter. Rough, rolling, sandy, and clayey land had a somewhat more rapid turnover than better land during the years of peak prices (1918-20) m most of the counties studied. Foreclosures and other forced sales were most numerous m each county on the same types of soil which sold most rapidly m 1918-20. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">History of Farm Land Prices m Eleven Nebraska Counties 1873-1933 ELEANOR H. HINMAN » ™?wif ÜbJeCt ° f - farm land price is intimately intertwined entire life of a farm purchaser, bringing failurp and Hi&lt;f couragement to the farmer and Serious hardshfp to hfs" family. Similar mistakes on the part of creditors financing farm purchases may result m failing or embarrassed bankf and loan companies, to a degree which may cripple the economic life not only of the rural areas, but also of the A detailed, year-by-year record of farm land sales anrt prices from several typical Nebraska farming areas over a 61-year period may throw light on the behavior of land values m the counties studied and m similar farming areas and may help towards supplying a better iSSHS land pSe analysis and forecasting than now exists. This bulletin £2 X £/"♦* S Te T Td f ° r H Nebras ka counties. It "s based on 76,544 true sales of farm land by warranty deed which occurred m these counties during the years 187i1933 and also presents data on 14,418 other transfers of farm ' land J*^ " the ? ame coun «es during the years 1920- S;,- J P f}■ 1^ 818 1S Placed on the last 24 years of the period studied Some causal factors affecting land price! iSh * T dlCa i ed m the dißc " 88 ion, but a detailed analysis of such factors does not fall within the province of this bufletin data— All data for the years 1910-33 were for Box BuS y T fr ° m the /«? n^ deed re^rds, and tLdZt IZ- io,n te ' Lx^ an &gt; and Y °rk counties m the years pre - ceding 1910 were from the same source". Data for the other counties m years preceding 1910 were obtained chiefly from thereports of land transactions published m the locafnew^ wi;h Th the 8 D i d vi»ir" SfXrUuHurS- nSS'" T V? "Si" » a K reement Aaricultunil Economic. US Denartment of A ""!? Economicß of the Bureau of 1873-1909 are Uken from" Pro? RanW™, f ÜbifuSoSi % A ' "*""' .'" the years from Box Butt.. Lean. Sa.ine. ' ,T^ S22S2F&amp; ""* </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 6 papers, which m turn had obtained them from the county records. Years m which the newspaper reports were obviously incomplete or defective were supplied directly from the county records. Data from the newspaper reports are more easily obtained than those from the county records, but are unfortunately somewhat less accurate. This is partly because of omissions and misprints, but more especially be - cause the newspapers rarely give the date of the instrument. Tabulations based on them are therefore according to the date of filing the deeds instead of according to the actual date of sale. Since filing was frequently postponed until months and occasionally until years after the signing of the deed, this defect somewhat obscures the sharpness of the land price changes m the years preceding 1910. The newspaper reports, however, probably furnish a sufficiently correct idea of the general tendencies of land sales and prices m these counties up to 1910. The most serious problem encountered m the tabulations made directly from the county records, was the occasional difficulty m drawing a distinction between true or bona fide sales and other transfers. A true sale of farm land may be defined as a transfer of full title for a consideration which expresses the sales value of the land so transferred, at the time of the transaction. In doubtful cases, the tract was located on a soil survey map of the county and its considera - tion studied m connection with the sales price of tracts of similar soil type and topography at the same period. If the consideration still appeared too low, the transaction was omitted from the class of true sales. Another troublesome problem was afforded by the mortgages, for the language of the deed did not always specify whether the value of the mortgage was included m the consideration named, or whether it was m addition thereto. For those years when a federal revenue tax on land sales was m force, this point could be determined definitely from the amount of the tax; but m other years doubtful cases had to be estimated according to the probabilities by reference to the soil map. All sales of tracts less than five acres m size, and sales of tracts of what - ever size located within one mile of incorporated towns, were omitted because of the possibility that they might include nonagricultural land. Sales between persons bearing the same surnames were included among true sales if the price per acre closely approximated the average for that county and year ; but otherwise they were omitted as doubtful. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Farm Land Prices m Nebraska 7 Counties studied.— The 11 counties from which data were obtained have been classified m four principal type-oftfarm- SfhSflT- T ?- 6 firS^ gr ° Up COnsists of se ™ n soStheasW half nr n ?^ *?"* accordin * to the census of 1980, J f n f , more of th f farm acreage was m farms deriving 40 per cent or more of their income for the year 1929 from the cash sale of gra nor other crop specialties This group com! prises Clay Fillmore, Otoe, Polk, Seward, Saline and Yoric counties. Unquestionably the proportion of Scrop f Sms ? *? e ? c aunties varied greatly during the 61-year Sd studied; but a relatively high proportion of such farms is characteristic of that part of Nebraska south of the Pllttl * T ? t he ,f econd type-of-farming area, represented m this study by Merrick and Platte counties, half or more of the farm acreage was occupied by livestock farms m 1929 "LhJstock farms ' include farms indicated by the Fifteenth Census as fnTtoir^ dairy, or poultry Sm S accord! ing to their principal source of income m 1929. Most of the livestock farms m these two counties were animal specialty farms. The Fifteenth Census distingufshes between stock-ranches and animal-specialty farms as follows- "A ffSfr n ° h «. B tyP !. Of &lt;*»«*■«*« m which chLfTmphasS is placed on the production of livestock (usually beef cattte sheep, or goats) by grazing; while an animaUspecTa'tv farm of Son^^S 1 ? ?° re e ™? hasis Placed on the production or SSS^ f V t^i ° f Uve f. tOck i UBually h0 « s ' beef cattle, or sheep) ■ A high proportion of animal-specialty farms is SfSfS 11 *^ ° f th , 6 Nebraska corn-belt countiefnS of Kfnc^ 9m rather than kindrthe t4 .rSi 6 Sa ". d ?n U C ° U " ty ' Logan ' is includ ed as a sample of the great sand-hill grazing area covering about one-sixth of the 25^' p P ro »™ a *?ly two-thirds of Logan county is sandy • «? T, ed f° r grazing and one -third of the soil sur - face is "hard land", much of which is capable of tilWe ea ? 2 Vr,- fiftl : S t f G f arm land m this couSty was occipfed m 1929 by livestock farms, mostly stock ranches. The mean annual rainfall is about 20 inches. One high-plains county, Box Butte, represents the Nebras - ka panhandle. Box Butte county was predominantly a i anch - mg county from the time of its organization until about 1914; • Fifteenth Census of thn U. S.. 1930, Vol. 111, Pt. 1, p. s. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 8 TABLE 1.-Census summery of the agncmtural history of 11 Nebraska counties, 1880-1980\ Value per acre ffifffr- Proportion crop land In' Livestock per farm I Year A ff' «™nof" No. of *?£ P^T linden I Other Hay Swine Cattle Ho™« w Lea f« n m. n «3Ste l"g» du'te' "ror-' Wheat I grain. crop. _ ! •and* P ,et. p.et. P*t. P.ct. No. No. No. P.et. ofacret P.ot. NEBRASKA 1880 49.157 19 63.887 150 $11 - * « &lt;* S7 51 13 |0 1| * ss skb 7 8 °s as? s .= 1 B ? is s s - i^ iS'lB 6 ? 0 8 ? Jllrltl S S iS TO S IT 57 19 36 24 7 47 SEVEN SOUTHEASTERN NEBRASKA CASH-CROP COUNTIES TWO EAST-CENTRAL NEBRASKA LIVESTOCK COUNTIES as- s b as •! ? s j a s a sss s a aa p } » = a », s s </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Farm Land Prices m Nebraska 9 Table 1.— Summary of agricultural history.— (Continued) Approx- Propor- Acres Value per acre tS?j|f" Proportion crop land in' Livestock per farm iraate tionof No. of per farm ' ° faerea PCt - *•*■ ** P.ct. P.ct. No. No. No. P.ct. ONE SAND-HILL COUNTY ONE HIGH-PLAINS COUNTY "" 689 79 688 981 IS 1 12 m \\ fS 2 62 » " J»2O 689 94 641 1.009 82 3 ~ 18 22 w sfi ,5 41 " " 1025 ■ 689 85 715 816 23 ft ~ it ,1 2 2 2 6 17 44 IB 81 'Tenth Census of the U. S., Vol. 111. pp. 70. 72; 125-6. 162-3. 197-8. 233, and 294-7 ~ ~ Eleventh Census of the U. S.. Vol. X. pp. 162. 218-9. 297-8. 837-8. 375-6. and 441-2 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 but during the war and post-war years the growing of grain and potatoes increased until the cash-crop farms outnum - bered the livestock farms in 1929. Box Butte county is fringed by sand hills on its eastern and southern borders, and by a strip of rough, broken land along the Niobrara river on the north; but the rest of the county is a fairly level plain composed chiefly of soils of the Rosebud, Dunlap, and Valen - tine series. These soils vary considerably in productivity but much of them is suitable for tillage. The mean annual rainfall is about 16 inches. Census summary of the 11 counties. — A brief summary of the agricultural history of the 11 counties studied, as revealed in successive United States censuses from 1880 to 1930, is presented in Table 1 to serve as an introduction to the data on land sales and prices and to indicate the character of the sample used. The data in this table are assembled here for reference and will be discussed in connection with later tables. The following points about the agricultural history of these counties may be noted here by way of introduction: (1) Only one of these 11 counties — Otoe — was extensively settled before the Civil War. The settlement of the other eight eastern counties occurred chiefly between 1866 and 1880, or during the fifteen years immediately following the Civil War. Some new land continued to be taken up during the 1880's and early 1890's. The two western counties did not have many settlers until the years from 1885 to 1890. (2) The type of agriculture, as indicated by the proportion of farm land in crops and the proportion of crop land in wheat, other grains, and hay crops, was fairly stable in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties from about 1910 to 1930, and in the two east-central livestock counties from about 1900 to 1930. Logan was prevailingly a stock-ranch county in all census years studied. Box Butte county was mainly a stock-ranch county up to and including the census year 1910, as indicated by Table 1; but subsequently the growing of wheat, other grains, and potatoes (not shown in Table 1) increased so greatly as to transfer this county into the cash - crop class by 1929. (3) The estimated value of farm land (including build - ings) increased greatly in all counties up to the census year 1920, and decreased greatly thereafter. The estimated value of farm buildings per acre increased up to 1920 in all coun - ties, and, in all counties except Clay and Logan, showed further increases in the subsequent census years when land values were falling. The terms "land values" and "land prices , as </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska used in this study, include the value of buildings and improve - ments upon the land, unless otherwise specified. (4) Gross farm income per acre was much greater in 1929 than in 1899 and earlier census years, but it increased less than land values. Gross farm income was not listed by the censuses of 1910, 1920, and 1925. TRUE SALES BY WARRANTY DEED VOLUME OF FARM LAND SALES, 1873-1933 Number of sales.— The greatest activity in farm land sales in the seven southeastern-Nebraska counties occurred m the years 1882-93, 1901-02, and 1917-19. More sales occurred an 3882-84 and in 1892-93 than in any subsequent years. The large number of sales in what may be called the developmental period (about 1880 to about 1893) may be ascribed to the following causes: (1) After the best land had been homesteaded, new settlers often preferred to buy land from the railroads (which had received large grants in these counties) or from private owners, rather than file on the less desirable land which still remained free. (2) Home - steaders frequently bought additional land. (3) Some home - steaders were moved more by a love of adventure than by the desire for a permanent home; this type usually sold their allotments soon after they had proved up on them. (4) Speculators bought land to hold for an anticipated rise in price. This class doubtless accounted for a much smaller proportion of the sales than the home-seekers, but they appear to have been more active during these years than at any sub - sequent period. Increasing land sales usually accompanied the periods of general business prosperity, but with diminishing vigor as the early period of development receded. The land boom of 1917-20 arose from the high price of farm commodities, which resulted from war-time and reconstruction conditions in Europe. Many farmers and many business men convinced themselves that these high prices would continue indefinitely. Farm tenants seized what appeared to be a golden opportun - ity to become land owners. Farm owners bought additional farms or acreages. Another spur to purchasers of farm land was the circumstance that recent inventions of farm machin - ery had increased the size of the holdings which could be efficiently farmed by one family. The combination of high commodity prices and intense competition among purchasers bid up the price of farm land to disastrous heights. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">TABLE 2.-True sales of farm land by warranty deed in 11 Nebraska counties, 1878-1988} Number of sale. Numb " ° f acrea "» _ . 1 high- ZJ o .. _..„i l sand-hill 1 high-plains 7 southeastern 2 east-central 1 sand-hill plains W Year 7 southeastern g^w'' *££■$ cclV counties' counties' county* county^ « coun_es _ — lggg2 £ 1878 816 12J 6 , m 19&gt;6 2 9 CQ 1874 431 \f ..__ 70.804 20.564 W 1876 428 12B 74 214 25,786 &gt; 1876 «00 }85 ~~ g „, 2 8, 9 j 9 1877 645 1" — 106025 84,872 H 1878 669 228 769g7 1B&gt;882 M 1879 ,666 2?J 'Z — 108.777 28.789 ? 1880 1-000 229 •— n9 ,840 20.294 1881 1-076 163 191.188 44,489 CO 882 1.634 889 ••••- = »' Jg 69 , 2 4 6 1.119 g 1883 1.558 480 3 ••- 206 926 4B, 8 84 480 -~ ► 884 1.678 875 9 "l 149 768 88.043 .199 320 • 1885 1.360 311 9 9g4 24 fl89 4,520 1.440 JrJ 188 6 J-242 190 , 4 g 43 126.988 21,167 18.889 6.564 g 1887 1.208 189 J; 171 133 039 81.139 5,159 26.874 m 1888 1265 217 85 171 133.039 ai 1 » 8984 g | 1889 1.194 231 91 2 130.001 80 r 1890 1.387 282 «» - 4 140,667 37,916 6.720 27,117 fo 1891 1.222 379 39 "« »"•"?' 64 012 9 680 34,687 Q 1892 1679 685 61 211 W.lii mu 43 43g w 1893 1584 278 62 f" ill 642 22.605 9 820 33.032 I8 9 ' 1.08B 194 f JJ 2 j « g^g 4.320 30 229 W 1895 832 168 « u480 5,400 26.348 C 1896 696 99 33 J 27 „„„ 8.720 22.507 £ 1897 784 210 145 u9 93S 24.491 4.440 26.600 £ 1898 1.015 2 0 26 H5 1 299 3 8 , 4 0 H 1899 971 215 84 3g 403 g 949 69.453 „ 1900 896 296 49 0 29 003 6798 64.008 2 1901 1.363 216 40 286 b u 1 3 , 4 1902 1.230 231 61 »« 49 715 7 , 280 86.093 -3 1903 1.058 323 41 75 »$• ,„,, ,,„. 35.564 N&gt; 1904 879 286 JJ .,- i9i 90G 48.374 6,720 S-J.8J0 1006 1.089 . 354 83 136 MM9G. 48.374 1906 1.020 883 ig 844 92.615 36,941 7.760 81,763 1907 821 804 48 »« » s6 UB u , 168 51,602 1908 767 298 89 "» 91372 47.648 8.040 53.737 1909 823 829 2» . </seg>
            <seg id="p013">TABL fo?r:^. e sa % s °l far^ land b y warranty deed in 11 Nebraska counties, 1873-1933. — (Continued) Number of sales Number of acres sold Ye " r "' B0 £unTes' rn 'SattTrf^ l8and ; h i 11 1 high-plains 7 southeastern 2 east-central 1 sand-hiU plifn." gggS counties' county* county* counties' counties' county* county« SS ?g' B 2?2 i. 2 i l , ll2MS 49 ' 873 10 '880 60.887 M 1912 787 §56 fo ,?J 89 ' 354 S4 - 470 14 -704 27.128 £? 1918 628 ins il l h 80 ' 948 82 - 200 ".240 29.624 g 1914 Ik! Jor if J? 73.366 22,757 17,840 25,044 2 Igi5 «1 }? R f? 71 59.655 26,673 11,678 15 905 « 1916 656 194 n .1! 63 ' 027 20,484 26.374 24,280 __s 1917 1246 291 i? 2 J?S 71 ' 116 22 .84S 28,214 30.659 f 1918 1225 *?? i« J1S 144 - 19B 87 ' 398 51 -603 76 600 &gt; 1919 }'Q9i ,57, 12 J 832 146,904 50.516 49,751 89.112 Z i926 997 4 34 9 ?? 8 ? S 160.255 46,031 36.087 110 957 O 1921 i85 ,.« 90 23 f 118 - 217 62 - 230 33 '473 68.669 M 1922 ill Jon ?? 48 65 ' 338 16 .637 10,479 12.081 2? 1923 til 15? ? n 88 41.946 11,279 6.037 10.216 2 1924 m Jnl JS il 44 - 190 16.696 3,160 10.335 Q 1925 489 JJb Jn ™ 4B ' 859 12 - 470 4 .» 9 ".853 W 1926 459 J 4 4 n ?2 4 2 54.686 16,823 9.640 10 120 CO 1927 i98 Ji? J? ll 48 ' 493 14 .5« 6.440 21,232 _, 1928 I?8 l» J 4 , 9 ? 43,444 13.128 5.480 26.984 8 1929 Mi J™ J2 "J 57.059 17,703 5,516 27.458 * 1930 466 1J4 '2 22 68,917 ,fi . 537 ".440 22.743 W 1931 3I6 J, 4 , ? 67 61.885 14,632 2,000 18,939 £ 1932 !ao U 8 i ,1 H J9.157 13.972 9,880 14.088 | 1933' l|o li '? f n 32 ' 258 I 0 ' 827 12,480 8.219 S ■ — -3° 4 10 15,633 4^205 W20 9,778 &gt; ment la,^K^^^^^Tof^",?,? bX^__f_____ m L_l $£_ th " C0Unty 2S" record8 8nd the date is «** when the in.tru- S from 1873 to 1889; data from Scwarf county, from 1873 to 1892 indicatcd in the U " S - ccn8us of "30. Data from Otoe county are missing • Box Butte county. • First eight months only. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 Years with comparatively few sales in these counties were 1873-79, 1894-97, 1913-15, and 1921-33. These periods were coincident with serious depressions, except for the last-men - tioned, which extended over thirteen years and included two serious depressions and intervening recovery. Agriculture, however, had small share in this recovery; and, as will be shown, the price of farm land continued to fall throughout this period. Fewer sales of farm land occurred in 1932 than in any previous year studied, back to and including 1873. Doubtless papers for a few 1932 sales had not yet been filed at the time when the data were gathered, in the autumn of 1933 ; but such late filings can hardly have been numerous enough to change the conclusions just stated. Of the southeastern cash-crop counties studied, Clay, Fill - more, and York counties had the greatest sales activity dur - ing the 1882-84 land boom and the 1892 boom, and Clay, Saline, and York counties during the 1917-20 boom. Otoe, Polk, and Seward counties appeared less affected by extreme variations in sales activity during the years for which data were obtained; but in Otoe county data obtained commenced with the year 1890 and in Seward county with 1893. The pre-war peak year of sales activity was 1882 in Saline and York counties, 1883 in Fillmore county, 1884 in Clay county, and 1892 in Polk county. The post-war peak year was 1917 in Saline and York counties, 1918 in Fillmore and Seward counties, 1919 in Clay county, and 1920 in Otoe and Polk counties. Saline and York counties, where the farmers bought much land early in the boom years before land prices rose so high, suffered less financial embarrassment in 1921-33 than counties where more purchases occurred in later years of the boom. Otoe and Polk counties, however, did not have much of a land boom in any post-war year. The trend of land sales in the two east-central livestock counties agreed closely with that in the seven cash-crop coun - ties, except that the pre-war peak year of sales was 1883 instead of 1884 ; and the post-war peak year was 1920 instead of 1919. The fact that during the post-war land boom the peak year of sales coincided with the peak year of prices should be kept in mind in studying the subsequent foreclosure history of these two counties. The relatively large number of transactions occurring when prices were at their highest re - sulted in a relatively large number of embarrassed owners, as compared with the cash-crop counties. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska The trend of sales activity in the sand-hill county was quite different from that in the nine eastern counties The number of sales in Logan county in 1917-19 was higher than in any previous or subsequent year. The number of farms appears to have declined slightly between 1910 and 1920 be - cause the ranchers had bought the small holdings of many farmers, 3 but the livestock industry was prosperous in 1916 - 20 and land sales were numerous. A few sales of very laree ranches in 1931 and 1932 kept the number of acres sold dur - ing these years from declining as it did in the other counties studied. S S e *. iV^.ty in the high-plains county, Box Butte, re - sembled that in Logan in a general way. Box Butte county differed from any of the other ten counties studied in having enjoyed a considerable revival in farm land sales durinjr the years 1926-29. This revival was characteristic of the semi - arid wheat lands of western Nebraska and eastern Wyoming. Acres sold and size of parcels.— The trend of sales activ - ity as measured by the number of acres sold corresponded closely to the trend as measured by the number of sales, especially in the nine eastern counties. The average size of the tracts sold in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties subsequent to 1880 varied only from 106 to 134 acres, and showed no regular tendency to increase or decrease. In the same years the average size of the tracts sold in the two east - central livestock counties varied from 100 to 149 acres Variation in the 1870's was a trifle greater. The average size of the tracts sold was considerably smaller than the aver - age size of the farms in these counties,' indicating probably tnat farms were frequently acquired piecemeal. The average size of the tracts sold in the two western counties in the years immediately following their organiza - tion was approximately a quarter section, because most of these sales were made by homesteaders selling off their home - steads. Later on, however, the average size of the tracts sold increased considerably. In Logan county subsequent to 1910 cons&amp;,e&amp;o„£n^^^^^ b ] mp^« </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 ii I a I I i i i i i n _[,___. I \ T».t MUrt.csaK-caos COUNTIES I I . . I I _ *C.CtMT«*LMtiat«lST0CKeOONTKSj o I i l\ I 100 ZT~$- M Ts A7_\ 1 ZL / N A\Hl^\l\ LA I i I j i 1 I rM 8 ftn is™ iiil mi unr &gt;»oi . km ttu ntt tm. itJ» * _ H 3 _ ' _ ■ % _ _ I _ J s .1 _ . a s§ I's^i 3 Etf I 3 it. i MIS M iS &amp; Fig. 1.— Relative number of acres of farm land sold annually by war - ranty deed in two type-of-farming areas &gt; eastern Nebraska com - pared with prevailing business conditions in the United States, 187d - 1933. (Average number of acres sold annually in 1910-14 =1UU, data computed from Table 2.) The prevailing business conditions are from W. D. Thorp, Business Annals, pp. J81-MB» National Bureau of Economic Research, Monograph 8, New York, 1926. JJata for 1927-32 were added from Thorp, The Depression as Depicted by Business Annals, News Bui. 43, p. 1, National Bureau of Economic Research, Sept. 19, 1932. Abbreviations used: dep = depression, pan =panic; pro = prosperity; rec= recession; rev=revival; sl=slignt. it ranged in different years from 222 to 1,976 acres; and in Box Butte county from 224 to 978 acres. This extreme varia - tion is due partly to the small number of true sales in these counties in certain years, and partly to the circumstance that part of the sales were of very large stock-ranches and part were small grain farms or specialty farms. Relatives of the number of farm acres sold. — The five - year period 1910-14 has been widely used by statisticians as a base period when conditions in agriculture are believed to have been more nearly normal than in most other years. If we allow the yearly average for the number of farm acres sold in 1910-14 in each of the four groups of counties studied to equal 100, we find that the relative number of acres sold in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties in the pre-war peak year 1884, was 357; but the relative number of acres sold in the two east-central livestock counties in the pre-war peak year 1883, was considerably lower, being 210. Land sales were not very numerous in the two western counties during these years. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska w 400 l 1 r , 1 I | |, lj — n — 1 — | I I SANO HILL COUNTY- LOGAN I |\:: |» M 'HIGH runs COUNTY- BOX BUITC / jj; ■* ~~ r i i 1 — — w g A //IT 5aoo . /j _ j- j o : \ / •. : g.oo — in&amp;y v., .z .z^a .-La/ J ZZVe^Zl^^ SHl? ! ? ■*"* - ditions in the United States l88Siq^ .Prevailing business con - sold annually in 1910-14-100 nlL'^ n . umber of «»■ are repeated I from Figure 1 he P revall,n &amp; business conditions During the post-war boom, on the contrary the sales 9 pHv lL W f tern lan^ Was * reater than tKastorn countier In the seven southeastern cash-crop counties T the Sf™ Sag ~ r •-- «a =srf3S TOTAL VALUE OF FARM LAND SOLD. 1873-1933 In general, the total value or consideration nf +1,,. * £ ?Qi7 - G P ! a r year for the total val »e of thTland sold came in 1917 in Saline county, in 1919 in Clav i„„ v T and Box Butte counties, and in 1920 fe^Si S 1^1° fV Y ° rk ' counties studied. The factors" jffig^dSSflS'tffi of'acreTsow' SaleS price * er "^ "dSJSSnbS </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Table S.-Total consideration of farm land sold by warranty deed in 11 Nebraska counties, 1878-1988 1 , and consideration relative to a 1910-14 base. ToUl consideration consideration (1910.14-100) ~ . . ~ 1 nlgn- m — : . _ tin i itrA. n i.in&gt; 7 southeastern 2 east-central 1 sand-hill plains __ Year 7 ■■mtt.ffn, . »^gg^ ]___\s * "!&amp;&amp;"" ' 'SSSrf eounto' | c^ung co^_ g 1878 T^M76 * J08.891 8 4 3 UM 448258 125.809 : 9 4 g 1OTK 618,819 11M67 g 6 ** }??« 468803 1«,420 ' !0 B W 187? ««« B }.IS? 0 ZZZ 12 « &amp; JStJ 700,866 186,619 10 4 gj Un 666 198 105.060 }g 7 1* {IU 916,780 198,898 —^ 20 6 m liiY 1,127,142 149,892 . — — — ffT 12 "J }|qJ 2 122 800 866.069 ~~- J 2 ' 20 4 g }gSi 2 888 435 607,229 $ 6,600 -— - « 18 1 &gt; J2S7 2,856.862 627,249 800 ~~ 18 3 0.2 1896 2,514,636 282.465 «.»&lt;« 115,668 80 }9 }• ?2 £ 1897 MS-IS «2*496 ii:lio 84302 38 6 M 18 fa 1898 8.118,854 ISS'l?? SiSoB 117,792 40 15 « JS « 1899 8.318,182 469,617 83.285 »M g4 22 19 28 g 1900 2,807.861 654,815 29.196 j« J B9 21 24 28 Z 1 1 I I 11 1 ! 8 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">T^8^w l n^Zy i0 V f f a ™\ a ' n i 5oW by warranty deed in 11 Nebraska counties, 1878-1983 , and consideration relative to a 1910-U base.— (Continued) Total consideration Relative consideration (1910-14-100) 191i 8,605,385 2,943,003 167 416 ill «i« 7^ : Z — 1912 8.405.129 2 985.506 1?S 404 «8'432 Jo, 1ft? }?i 94 HH 1918 7,761.170 2267,745 218 629 $43590 M ,"* 100 3 1914 6,644,970 2.561,040 101,820 197507 79 Jr 7B £ mB 6,610,899 2.061,854 218 670 271816 ll ll 68 &lt; s 2 1916 7,743.419 2.293 808 2sl.947 «0828 9 6 f £ J 88 B9 * 1917 17,208,480 4.234,628 882 247 • 1895 647 20? ,31 "J 94 1918 18.829.010 6,656.096 662 084 2 074 121 227 i«? ?oS 80B £ 1919 24,296.469 6.124,887 585 764 _______ ml III 427 45 3 &gt; 1920 21.242.808 10248761 778795 2983805 1*1 III 8&lt;B 741 _* 1921 9.146.339 2 223.276 805.000 614.766 11°0 M , B »° 2 JH ° 1922 5.705.954 1.661.688 100 630 864.384 69 ll '« l ll krt 1928 5.692.290 1.988,721 74 495 302 648 69 R? ll ll ZS 1924 6.797.449 1.687.790 47 020 297.676 70 AL il 66 3 1926 6.870.102 2.226.860 148 048 275 625 83 n .1 ll O 1926 6.036,638 1,848.992 122.897 495659 ?s » ll 60 W 1927 5.255.746 1606597 85 400 684 807 « ?? J? 108 » 1928 7.081.575 2088046 86 810 863.087 85 70 ll III *•» I- 9 ? 5 /' 94 1,835,888 115597 828 808 86 62 % UI S 1930 5.956,476 1,669.788 43.220 684.190 72 KR li ill 1931 3,867,686 1,468,886 51160 448 664 J? I. ll " 8 'T' 1932 2.829.712 844 106 95 425 191991 is il 8S 97 5 1988 ' UHM 810.205 "oMq 5 igl.jgl \\ | 6 fi 42 g 1 Box Butte county, •First eight months only. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 T — I — 1 — 1 — 1 | | I M I 3 rs.t. him. casM-eaop cowrms l\ • . C.CCNTHAL NCSA. LIVESTOCK COUNTICS • • S 1 SANO MILL COUNTY i i i eoo 1 HWH PLAINS COUNTY i— ; &lt; I I I "1 f~ O : »- : ! Bjoc f— t » I I M 5- — ■■ ■ m 3 § \\ |joo : n* a l__._____J.__ A i \ I \ f&amp;fsk 9 iiri" "7m iu* ii* iw i™ •»" "» •«" ™" "■ F IG . 3, Relative consideration of farm land sold annually by warranty deed in four type-of-farming areas in Nebraska, 1873-1933. (Con - sideration of all farm land sold annually in 1910-14 = 100.) Total consideration, relative to a 1910-14 base.— To facilitate comparison of the four farming areas studied, the total consideration of the farm land sold has been computed relative to the yearly average for the base period, 1910-14, by the same methods described in connection with the relative number of farm acres sold. The height of this relative con - sideration in the peak year, 1919 or 1920, appeared to in - crease toward the westward. In the seven southeastern cash-crop counties, the relative consideration stood at 293 in the peak year; in the two east-central livestock counties, it stood at 345; in the sand-hill county (Logan), at 502; and in the high-plains county (Box Butte), at 741. Of the seven southeastern cash-crop counties, Clay, the westernmost, had the highest relative consideration in the peak year, the figure being 451. Of the two east-central livestock counties, Mer - rick, the more westerly, had the higher relative considera - tion in the peak year, the figure being 452. In other words, the less the annual rainfall, and the greater the distance from the principal grain and livestock markets, the bigger the land boom of 1917-20 in the Nebraska counties studied. Several reasons may be found for this. In the nrst place marginal and near-marginal land is apt to be more affected by changes in the economic cycle than other land. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska In depression periods such land often produces no income or virtually none, so that the market for it practical? &gt; S£ appears and it can scarcely be sold at any price. In periods of increasing prosperity, such land suddenly commences to return an income ; and because of the low value of the land during the preceding years of depression, the returns for a ™™/. earS - ™ aj , - be 8 »nJriBingly high in proportion to the owner s original investment. In the second place, in the semi - arid regions because of the low land value per acre, farms large enough for extensive stock raising or for hijrhlv £ 6 iT ed M a u ming re ? uir t a much smaller investment than 1920 thrL N ff r 8ka - • In .i h f.* hird P lace ' be^een 1915 and 1920 three factors coincided to encourage the demand for western wheat lands represented in this study by Box Butte county. They were: the increasing use of strains of wheat suitable for semiarid lands, the development of machTnery especially, adapted to large-scale farming on dry lands and the large foreign demand for wheat arising from war-time and reconstruction conditions in Europe. SALES PRICE PER ACRE SOLD, 1873-1933 General trends.— The sales price per acre of farm land sold in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties rose from $6 in 1876 to $180 in 1920 and then declined to $77 durinf the first eight months of 1933, this being about its 1909 level The ? nJ y interruptions t0 the u Pward march before 1920 occurred in 1874-76 1887, 1895-97, 1900, and 1915; and were Sowed by prompt recovery in each case. Since 1920 it has been a different story. In 1920 Polk county land at $207 per acre was the highest-priced in these seven counties, and Clav county land at $142 was the lowest-priced. Clay county land prices were usually the cheapest among these seven counties - but the other six counties did not by any means always stand in the same relation to each other. Prices in the two east - ?SSn i lvest °&lt;* counties rose from $5 in 1878 to $165 in 1920 and declined to $74 in 1933. Logan county prices rose from $2 in 1884 to $29 in 1921 and declined to $6 in 1933 but the price decline was highly irregular, owing chiefly to the extremely small number of true sales in this county sub - sequent to 1921. Box Butte county land sold even more cheaply than Logan county land up to about 1906; but after this it increased rapidly in price to $43 in 1920 and 1921, and e&amp;mont^^M933 he """ *£ ~ °** ?16 * the first A feature of the price history of the two western counties was the conspicuous decline in land values between 1910 and </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 'lOOl I I 1 I 1 I I 1 1 o TStNtSaCASH-CKOPCOONTItJ A Q I E.CINT1UL MB*. UVISTOCK COUNTIES l\ . *|« I SANDHILL COUNTY -i+\ V g I MICH PLAINS COUNTY lj V - H — i — r — i — r~^ / W|00 — — /v*~ ' X — ! ,r gg 3b itMa»T~ 36^^ . m isr — thi mrr — Ha* FlO. 4. — Average price per acre of the farm land sold annually by war - ranty deed in four type-of-farming areas in Nebraska, compared with prevailing business conditions in the United States, 1873-1933. Land price data from Table 4; prevailing business conditions repeated from Figure 1. 1915, not experienced by the eastern counties. Following the passage of the Kinkaid Act in 1904, these two counties had filled up with settlers homesteading grants of 640 acres each, in accordance with the act. Since many of these Kinkaiders had not sufficient capital for stock-ranching, they attempted grain farming, even on the sandy soils of Logan county, where the acreage in cereal crops rose from 9,651 in 1904 to 25,219 in 1911. These ambitious attempts met with disaster similar to that which had overtaken the settlers of the nineties; the crops blew out, and little was harvested. The Kinkaiders vanished even more suddenly than they had appeared. The number of farms in Logan county dropped from 377 in 1913 to 144 in 1914, as reported by precinct assessors. The simultaneous drop in land prices was produced mainly by disillusioned settlers attempting to dispose of their holdings. A somewhat similar history occurred in Box Butte county, except that the chief trouble there was not wind erosion but drought. Precipitation at Alliance in the years 1910, 1911, 1913, and 1914 was 11.6, 13.5, 13.8, and 12.2 inches respec - tively, or from three to five inches below normal. 8 As a result of this succession of dry years many new settlers left the county, so that the number of farms reported by precinct •Climatic Summary of the United States. Sec. SR: Western Nebraska. V. t. U. S. Dept. of Aa-r., Weather Bureau. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska assessors dropped from 587 in 1910 to 367 in 1914 while tho fSVVJ 1 " 118 dr ° PPed fr ° m 547 ' 177 J" WW » to 260 &gt;280 in 1913.« Recovery was prompt in this county. A special feature of the Box Butte county land orice his •° r ? Q on S 1 ** from $23 per acre in 1926 to sS one'chfef S^S^ ° f the W^J^S ™ doubtSs £?s^^^ in P !l C „ e la «*— L J?nd prices respond rather slowly to econom- MoK? a ,? g f- , Depressions sufficiently serious to affert N /^« a Q S Q ka I and Pr - ices began in the au tomn of 1873 the serin* not decline » iff In other words, there was a lag of one or • tWo veaS fbSnr* ft farm land prices studied responded to Ihe £wa?d pull ot %tr dep, £ a l lon \ except in i929 wh^n the land prices ?n the C ° ntinued «F^^ Se - ward trend. The lag in periods of revival was as lnno- n  - sometimes longer. General business recovery from the de pressions mentioned above commenced in 1878 irqt iqi!" and 1922; but the Nebraska fam land prices studied I did a n nd r i? 2 ToiSr. 1879 " to ' 1898 « *£TmS®ig land™ Mn a sr°M f K r ¥ 8 l ag is , the cus tomary manner of selling £ wlk ° St Ne^aska farm land which is sold changes hands in February or March, just before the spring planting season But the sale is often contracted for, at a specified orice dnr" mg the preceding summer or autumn. lEffiS a contract, for sale, or by signing the deed for the S ak and Placing it m escrow with a third party, to be delivered when certain conditions are fulfilled. The transacti^S dates cu^ent^the 6 time wffi^ the Prke is baS « p °* «S current at the time when the agreement was made Anothpr reason for the lag is that high farm land prices usuluv re - sult from high agricultural commodity prices, which must be maintained for more than a year before land purchaSrabe come convinced that the change is going to £ ? nSmlnent" £l S f;»r Ce '"FEW the chief Purchasers of farm "and several years of high farm income are necessary before many • Thirteenth Census of the IT. S.. 1910. Vol VII t&gt; &lt;n State Board of Asricuiture. Sui. V.%22-43. Lincoin. Neh,. Jan.. se.«h. V92 T 6 h0rP • Bu8ine » Annals, pp. 181 . 14B . National Bureau of Economic Re- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 purchasers can accumulate savings to make a first payment. Other reasons may be the unorganized condition of the farm land market, and the fact that other industries have some - times recovered more promptly than agriculture, notably in 1878 and 1922. Sales price and census estimates of value. — The sales price per acre of the farm land sold in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties was a little lower than the census estimates for the average value of all farm land, quoted in Table 1, in every census year. The same was true for the two east - central livestock counties except in 1925 ; and also in each of these nine counties rspectively, with a few exceptions. 8 This suggests that possibly, in these counties, the less productive Table 4. — Price per acre of farm land sold by warranty deed in 11 Nebraska counties, 1878-1988 1 , and price relative to a 1910-14 base. | Price per acre Price relative (1910-14=100) 7 south- 2 east- 1 sand- 1 high- 7 south- 2 east- 1 sand- 1 high- Year eastern central hill plains eastern central hill plains counties' counties' county' county* counties' counties' county* county 8 1878 T $8 $8 _ — 8 7 — — 1874 7 6 _ — I 1 - — 1875 -7 6 _ ~ 7 7 _ 1876 66_— % I — — 1877 76__ 2I — ~ 1878 7 5 _ _ 7 5 _ 1879 7 1 — — I a ■■•■""" 1880 8 7 — — I a " ~ ££ 11 8 =■ Z 11 I Z Z iH| JJ 9 IB 18 10 45 hu 14 11 2 14 12 18 — ills 18 10 4 $ 2 18 11 36 13 1888 19 12 7 4 19 18 64 27 1887 18 17 7 7 18 18 64 47 Ills • 20 18 9 5 20 14 82 88 1889 22 16 8 5 22 17 78 83 ilio 22 14 8 6 22 15 78 40 lSfll 24 15 7 6,. 24 16 64 40 .1892 28 19 7 6 28 21 64 40 ilia 81 19 10 6 81 21 91 40 1894 81 28 10 7 81 26 91 47 1895 80 18 8 5 80 20 73 83 ill! IS 20 9 5 28 22 82 83 Jill II ? 9 ° I I ll li 4 5 5 li l5S lo 15 I 8 . 80 16 45 20 1900 26 17 4 2 26 18 86 18 1901 80 21 5 2 SO 28 45 1 "°2 86 28 5 3 86 80 46 .20 1908 40 40 4 8 40 43 36 20 SSS ii S'S 3 SS 55 Si li SSI 66 68 7 7 55 63 64 47 882 To Io i5 2 : ■■ tt n .% ll 1909 78 65 11 16 77 71 100 100 Join 91 82 12 17 90 89 10D 113 111? 96 11 11 16 95 92 100 107 • Exceptions were as follows: In 1910. sales prices were higher than census estimates in Otoe and Merrick counties. In 1926, sales prices were lower than census estimates in Fillmo-e and Merrick counties. In 1930. sales prices were higher than census estimates in Polk and Saline counties. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska TABLE A.— Price per acre of farm land sold by warranty deed L Price per acre Price relative (1910-14=100) Year lES£_ *,%__ * __f- SE ' 8 °. u0 - 2 eagt - * »"»• 1 &gt;W- counts codes' co^ *&amp; rSB. a^M i5« 'iSS $ ,S8 _ •}• Is? til m — isr 1914 llS JoO J | " 105 109 109 93 1916 106 101 8 5? Ill 109 82 80 1916 109 103 8 il III 109 73 78 1917 119 lis ? U }? 8 "2 73 98 1918 128 110 IS w J" }24 64 120 1919 162 188 16 ll Ml 12 ° "8 IBS 1920 180 186 23 !s III UB 136 207 "21 16B 184 29 JI III i 79 209 2 87 1922 136 138 17 il IU 14B 264 287 1923 . 129 l!i ll ll HI "0 155 240 1924 126 131 n 2K III \ 2 l 218 193 1926 126 182 Ii ll III U2 »00 167 1926 124 127 19 ll III 14S "« "0 1927 ill ?22 IB ll III 1S8 "3 163 1928 124 ill \l ll \H 183 145 167 1» 29 120 hi Jo Is III III US i» 3 1930 116 JJ" 22 28 11? Ill 91 24 ° 1931 99 ill 8 If "J } 24 200 187 1932 88 78 8 _\ ll H 4 - 45 207 1933* 77 74 I ll II 8S 73 1B3 - — 6 IS 76 80 55 107 =PP S|S?»S£«!S»StH IKS 'Logan county. •Box Butte county. •First eight months only. land may have changed hands a little more rapidly than the best land, except perhaps in a period of rapidly fallinjr land values. In Box Butte county, on the other hand, the sales price iQ™ eq i U Q a 90 M alue ln 1890 and 1900 ' and hi^ her in laio, 1920, and 1925, thus suggesting a contrary situation ion^°^« county * he l?ales P rice was ab °ve the census price in 1890, 1910, and 1930, and below it in all other census year! Price relatives, of farm land.— On reducing the yearly sales price per acre of farm land to price relatives on a 1910 - 14 base as shown in Table 4, one finds that prices in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties rose and fell at approximately the same rate as those in the two east-central livestock* coun- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 ties, from about 1903 to date. In the earlier years the seven counties south of the Platte were priced a little higher relative to the 1910-14 base than the two north of that river. Polk and Platte counties, where land prices in 1920 were just twice those for the base period, enjoyed the greatest post - war price increase in these nine eastern counties. Clay county, with a price relative of only 137 in 1920, had the smallest increase. It also suffered the greatest decrease from the base period to 1933, for its land price relative in the first eight months of 1933 stood at only 56. The two western counties showed a slower rate of land price increase from the settlement of the county up to the base period, 1910-14, than the two eastern groups of counties. From the base period to the peak year (1921 in these two counties) the increase was greater, so that the relative stood at 264 in Logan and 287 in Box Butte. Logan county land prices suffered a greater decrease from 1921 to 1933, relative to the base period, than any other county; but Box Butte prices were better sustained during the depression of 1930-33 than those of any other county studied. Highest-priced sales, 1910-32. — The average price per acre for the ten highest-priced sales in each of the seven cash-crop counties subsequent to 1910 rose from a low of $140 in 1911 to $303 in 1920 and then declined to $118 m 1932. "Highest-priced sales" figures for the first eight months of 1933 are omitted from Table 5 because seven of the 11 coun - ties studied recorded less than 20 sales occurring in those months; the ten highest and the ten lowest sales overlap. Using 1910-14 for a base period, the price relative of these ten highest sales rose to 202 by 1920, and sank to 79 by 1932. Accordingly, highest land prices in these counties rose more up to 1920 than the average land prices shown in Table 4; and sank further from 1920 to 1932. Some of these high-priced sales represent rather small tracts with valuable buildings on them. In the sand-hill county (Logan) , the ten highest - priced sales attained $85 per acre in 1920; in Box Butte county, $110. In nine of the counties (all except Saline and Seward) the rise from the pre-war base period (1910-14) to 1920 was greater for the price of the ten highest-priced sales than for the average price of all sales. The collapse from 1920 to 1932 was more drastic for the highest-priced sales than for the average of all sales in all ten counties for which figures were obtainable. Logan county figures were omitted in 1928-24 and 1925-33 because of the very small number of true sales in each of those years. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 Table 5. — Price per acre of the ten highest-priced and ten lowest-priced sales in 11 Nebraska counties, and range between them, 1910-82 1 . 1 Highest-priced sales Lowest-priccd sales """^ bctw 7 0 n ,ggg° **» hi * h «* «" d Year 7 south- 2 east- 1 sand- 1 high- 7 south- 2 cast- 1 sand- 1 high- 7 south- 2 east- 1 sand- 1 high- *__ eastern central hill plains eastern central hill plains eastern central hill plains _. counties' counties' county* county' counties' counties' county' county' counties' counties' county 1 county 5 M 1910 $143 $147 $ 29 $42 $40 $24 $ 3 $ 4 $103 $123 $ 26 $ 38 S 1911 140 184 27 42 45 28 3 4 95 106 24 88 _. J 9 } 2 }5S 149 31 45 53 23 2 4 100 126 29 41 F ill's ll 2 16B 24 44 54 43 5 4 108 112 19 40 &gt; 1914 160 150 23 26 65 81 4 5 85 119 19 21 Z llll ill 14S 20 29 61 87 3 S 91 108 17 26 O loll III III ll 41 62 38 2 6 97 127 81 35 .. 1917 198 187 81 56 64 47 2 4 144 140 29 62 1918 229 218 60 61 59 42 3 6 170 176 57 67 W J 9 ! 9 266 253 79 89 64 47 2 7 202 206 77 82 S 1920 803 294 85 110 87 70 6 11 216 224 80 99 S 1921 267 296 78 76 90 71 9 22 167 226 69 54 K llll 208 201 36 67 88 77 7 17 120 124 29 60 1923 195 194 ..__ 60 75 61 ... 15 120 143 _ 45 S }924 188 184 50 76 58 — 16 112 126 34 Z 1926 184 190 39 62 74 69 8 IS 110 121 ' 31 49 *-* llll 177 202 -- 49 72 65 „ 8 105 137 ..... 41 2 1927 169 176 69 76 70 _ 8 93 105 61 S llll " 5 19S -- 69 73 4B - 9 1° 2 "8 — 60 3 1929 186 166 86 67 50 - 8 119 115 78 £ 1930 165 197 62 65 66 -_ 10 100 141 62 TO 1981 162 166 57 57 56 ... IS 105 110 44 W 1932 118 122 88 52 88 __- ? 66 84 20 £ •True sales by warranty deed. Thc average Is weighted according to the number of acres in each of the sales included. ' Clay, Fillmore, Otoe, Polk, Seward and York counties. Average price per acre for the ten highest-priced sales in each of the seven counties— 70 sales each year. Same for lowest-priced Bales. ' Merrick and Platte counties. Average price per acre for the ten highest-priced sales in each of two counties. Same for lowest-priced sales • Logan county, • Box Butte county. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 Lowest-priced sales. — Tlie peak year for the lowest - priced sales was 1921 instead of 1920, in each of the four farm - ing areas shown in Table 5, and in each of the 11 counties ex - cept Polk and York. The price of the ten lowest-priced sales rose less rapidly by 1920, in relation to the pre-war base period, than the average price of all land sold, in eight counties out of the 11, the exceptions being Polk, Saline, and York coun - ties. The price of the ten lowest-priced sales stood higher in 1932, in relation to the pre-war base, than the average price of all land sold in all counties except Otoe. In other words, there was a market for inferior land during boom years like 1917-20 ; but in depression years like 1921 and 1932 the poor land could scarcely be sold at all, and only the better land found a market. Price range, 1910-32. — The range between the price of the ten highest and the ten lowest sales in each county was greatest in 1918-20, in each of the four farming areas shown in Table 5, and least in 1932. The smaller number of sales in 1932 had something to do with the narrowing-in of the range, but a more important factor was the market differen - tial mentioned above. During prosperous years, both good and poor land sold readily ; during depression years, as a rule, only good land could be sold. DISTRIBUTION OF FARM LAND SALES BY PRICE GROUPS, 1910-33 Nine eastern-Nebraska counties. — Figure 5 illustrates the percentage distribution of farm land sales according to the price per acre, in the "uimiiiiiiiiuwii T° zssmm &lt; "° - nine eastern-Nebraska g «^^M^^^^^^^^Sl|i|^^w of the sales in the seven Jf, « the two livestock count- __ Wm ies were for less than """""V t %._Htm. cmh-cmp cqqwtks *pou per acre, except in _. ///&gt;uii 1 1 nj uu llinnnnTs sn 1910-12 also. The modal s^^^^^^M^^^^WMm/A^m taining more sales than *»«• i li SSc9?^^ any other — in the seven cash-crop counties was ?"&gt;• *&gt;.— Percentage distribution of the true «A«iq -iq-iA and saIes of farm land according to the !$ou-$»y in lHiu ana saleg price per acre in two ty pe-of - j»fT8in m 1931-3d; $100- farming areas in eastern Nebraska, $149 in 1911-19 and 1910-33. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska 1921-30; and $150-$199 in one year, 1920. Sales were more closely concentrated about the modal price group at the be - ginning and end of the 24-year period studied and more scat - tered during the intervening years, especially during the peak year, 1920. V The distribution of sales in the two livestock counties closely resembled that in the seven cash-crop counties but in most years the livestock counties had a slightly more scattered price distribution. These two counties border on the Platte river and therefore have a wider variety of soil conditions than some of the cash-crop counties; this fact probablv accounts for the difference. Two western count - • tsr a. t •. ____ __\ w» ts*. ,.. n ies. — Most Logan and _ J^^BS______l^^^^^^^^____l Box Butte county sales uj5« '"[.fe^^^^i^^B^^s^, were for less than $50 " M B^^^^^^f^^^^^ : - j per acre in all 24 years. &lt;M However, in both these __ I I counties in 1920-21, '"-** J^^^S^^j^wRP^" and Box Butte i n &lt;raaaaaaa_______________mma»Wtrh-« ■ I lOOQ Ol 1 XI. H»MO MILL COUNTY 1928-31 also, there was m _______________^e^83^_m^ZG&amp;g_l a considerable percent- • D »°«i^^^|^^^^fBijp^-§^J age of $50-$99 sales. "*" --^fw^M^CTMHte^' 1 A very few sales for t f ''j^__^^SS____af-_____\^' ' I $100 or more occurred I -I^^^S^^^^K^^^^ ' I in Logan county in «mF-Z&lt; I /Ww^'^lff*^,' - 1919-23, a n d i n B o x J^-*aWKk\aa_m________________M Butte county in 1920 imcNuaiwcoumY and Several subsequent FlG - 6 - — Percentage distribution of the true years, as shown in Fie- sal - es of farm land according to the sales Ilrp fi • P«ce per acre, in two western-Nebraska ure °- counties, 1910-33. DISTRIBUTION AND PRICE OF FARM LAND SALES. BY SIZE OF TRACT SOLD 1910-33 ' Seven southeastern cash-crop counties. — From 11 to 18 per cent of the farm land sales in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties were of tracts of from 5 to 49 acres in size, in years commencing with 1910. From 37 to 47 ner cent were in 50-to-99-acre tracts; from 33 to 43 per cent were in 100-to-199-acre tracts; and from 5 to 8 per cent were in tracts of 200 acres or more in size. There was a marked tendency to sell in multiples of 40 acres— 80 and 160 acres being the commonest sizes. No regular tendency to change in the distribution of sales according to size was observable during these years. The 5-to-49-acre tracts were the highest - priced group in 22 years out of the 24; the 200-acres-and-more </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 Table 6. — Percentage distribution of the true sales 1 of farm land in nine eastern Nebraska counties, according to the size of the tract sold, 1910-33, and average price per acre of tracts of the specified sizes. Percentage distribution by size of tract Price per acre by size of tract 200 j j 200 Year 6-49 60-99 100- acres 6-49 I 60-99 I 100- acres Total acres* acres* 199 and acres* 1 acres* I 199 and acres more I | acres more P.ct. P.et. P.et. P.et. P.et. SEVEN SOUTHEASTERN-NEBRASKA CASH-CROP COUNTIES' 1910 100 12.8 42.6 89.6 6.1 $98 $ 90 $ 89 $ 97 1911 100 12.8 44.6 87.1 6.6 104 96 97 96 1912 100 16.8 41.2 88.1 6.8 122 103 101 110 1918 100 11.0 48.1 88.4 7.6 111 107 106 101 1914 100 17.8 41.1 84.2 6.8 126 107 106 120 1916 100 16.4 44.1 84.7 6.8 118 108 106 98 1918 100 16.2 41.9 86.7 8.2 126 110 109 98 1917 100 14.8 39.6 88.4 7.2 187 120 119 116 1918 100 11.3 40.9 89.3 8.4 142 184 129 114 1919 100 11.2 37.7 43.1 8.1 170 163 160 160 1920 100 12.8 88.7 40.1 8.8 213 187 176 174 1921 100 17.1 36.7 37.7 8.5 167 165 170 168 1922 100 18.1 89.6 85.7 6.6 171 144 184 116 MU 100 18.2 40.6 88.8 7.4 161 128 181 119 1924 100 14.8 40.9 88.4 6.4 146 127 128 112 1925 -. 100 16.0 40.8 36.6 7.1 148 128 126 111 1926 100 17.4 42.6 36.8 4.8 188 128 128 117 1927 100 14.8 46.5 88.4 6.8 148 125 120 108 1928 100 14.6 42.6 86.8 6.6 182 129 124 112 1929 100 15.4 46.7 88.8 6.1 185 124 123 96 1980 100 18.9 44.6 34.8 6.7 149 117 119 90 198] 100 12.1 47.1 82.7 8.1 107 102 100 88 1982 100 11.1 48.2 89.6 6.1 78 98 85 91 1983" 100 12.1 42.1 40.7 5.0 88 84 72 81 TWO EAST-CENTRAL. NEBRASKA LIVESTOCK COUNTIES 4 1910 100 18.3 34.6 89.7 12.8 I 100 86 85 71 1911 100 16.3 82.0 40.4 12.8 97 95 86 77 1912 100 16.0 82.8 40.2 10.9 100 100 92 88 1918 100 20.6 29.2 40.6 9.7 118 109 100 89 1914_ ; 100 16.8 84.7 86.2 13.8 116 108 ■ 108 84 1915 " 100 17.6 84.7 89.8 7.9 128 104 97 100 1916 100 20.6 84.5 86.6 8.2 114 111 101 96 1917 100 10.6 86.2 40.8 13.0 121 116 115 107 1918 100 9.2 33.9 46.9 10.9 150 118 114 95 1919 100 11.2 81.2 46.0 12.6 142 156 180 128 1920 100 12.5 24.9 48.1 14.6 225 174 162 160 1921 100 16.4 25.9 44.8 12.9 228 193 186 102 1922 100 22.0 28.0 40.0 10.0 145 118 143 146 1928 100 18.4 86.9 82.6 12.1 167 128 121 101 1924 100 21.2. 27.9 44.2 6.7 201 154 182 94 1925 100 17.9 29.0 43.4 9.7 167 136 186 110 1926 100 27.9 28.6 87.1 6.4 149 116 125 186 1927 100 18 9 82.2 47.0 , 6.9 188 124 122 115 1928 100 16.8 85.9 89.9 7.8 140 127 122 86 1929 100 21.6 80.9 89.6 7.9 181 126 114 104 1980 100 27.1 27.8 89.6 6.6 1S8 128 112 85 1981 100 17.9 81.2 88.4 12.5 120 117 US 82 1982 100 17.9 82.1 86.9 18.1 122 84 87 68 1988* 100 15.8 86.8 42.1 6.3 126 71 73 64 1 True sales by warranty deed. ■ ■■■ 'Sales of tracts under five acres In size are not Included in this study. The 5-to-99 - acre Interval group has been split as indicated to show the rarity of sales below 60 acres in size and the higher value per acre of these small tracts in certain years. •Clay, Fillmore. Otoe, Polk. Saline. Seward, and York counties. 'Merrick and Platte counties. 1 First eight months only. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska tracts were the lowest-priced in 19 out of 24 years and tipri 25 00^ 199 ?^ gr ° U ? f0r Iowe8t P^n yet another »frl ?•? Cheap l and rarely sold in ver y small parcels, although it was not uncommon for the valuable land to sel e Parcels. The smaller farms usually had a larger in - vestment per acre in buildings and improvements than the larger farms, which is one reason for the tendency of nrice to decrease as size of tract increased. ooiT W&lt;? e * st - centr f l livestock counties.— The distribution of sales in two east-central livestock counties resembled the £TSS2? i b on there was a sm aller percentage of the sales m the 50-to-99-acre group and a larger percentage, as a rule, m every other group. Most of the sales of small tracts occurred In Platte county, but about as many 200-acre-and - more tracts were sold in Merrick county as in Platte. For this reason, the tendency for price to decrease as acreage in - creased was even more marked than in the cash-crop counties. A sand-hill county.— In Logan and Box Butte counties there were so few tracts of under 100 acres and so many large ranches sold, that a grouping different from that in the east - ern counties has been used, as shown in Table 7. In Lotran county, the small farms were selling faster than the bie ranches in 1910-12 and 1923-30, while the big ranches weri selling faster than the small farms in 1915-20. Of the verv few true sales in 1932-33, most were large ranches. All this agrees with what has previously been related of Logan county history during these years. The price per acre of the 400 - acre-and-more tracts was much lower than that of the smaller tracts, in every year studied except 1915 and 1929. A high-plains county.— The proportion of sales in small ii v ( L. to *?? acres) in Box Butt e county varied irreg - ularly between 41 and 76 per cent of all sales, and the pro - portion of large tracts (400 acres and more) from 8 to 30 S?£ ui but the Proportions were so fluctuating that it is difficult to draw conclusions from them. The price per acre of sales in the 400-acres-and-more group was lower than that iL onn f o Q o W ° grOUps in „ 21 years out of 24 » and tied with the 200-to-399-acre group for lowest place in two of the re - maining years. Price relatives. — In the seven cash-crop and two live- 7 K °? ™ unties shown in Table 6, the price of the small tracts (5 to 49 acres) rose higher by 1920 in proportion to the 1910 - 14 hase period than the price of tracts of any other size. In Logan county, also, the price of the small tracts (5 to 199 acres) rose faster by 1920 than any other type. In Box Butte </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 Table 7. — Percentage distribution of the true sales' of farm land in two western Nebraska counties, according to the size of the tract sold, 1910-83, and average price per acre of tracts of the specified sizes. , ... I Price per acre by size Percentage distribution by size of tract 1 of tract v«.r T *00 I 1 *°° lear 5.I99 200-399 I acres I 5-199 I 200-899 acres Total acres* acres and acres* acres and I more | I more "pZAt. . pZct. Prct. P-ct. ONE SAND-HILL COUNTY (LOGAN) 1910_ 100 78.2 21.9 4.9 $13 $20 $ 6 \l\l~ loo 68.6 14.8 16.7 12 15 8 ill? 100 51.0 20.4 28.6 16 17 8 I9li 100 40.0 16.6 44.4 14 14 11 19„ 100 36.4 24.2 89.4 16 18 6 1916 100 87.3 18.7 49.0 8 9 8 1915 100 g&lt; 22Z 4&lt;6 17 jj 6 1917" 100 86.5 18.0 60.4 16 8 6 iglff 100 28.1 28.9 48.0 22 27 8 1919_ZZZ 100 36.6 25.8 38.7 27 20 U \l\l 100 29.3 17.8 63.8 45 40 17 1921 ZZ 100 48.3 17.2 84.6 68 60 19 1921 iuo 429 § ¥___ 100 60.0 20.0 80.0 52 62 o 1928 100 600 g8 9 \lji 100 50.0 20.0 80.0 29 48 9 1.2-ZZZZ 100 52.9 17.6 29.4 26 44 11 tm 100 50.0 7.1 42.9 33 8 12 \l?l 100 88.6 23.1 88.4 44 24 8 1929 100 47.0 11.8 41.2 89 6 7 \.lo~ZZZZ 100 66.6 33.8 11.1 28 27 8 1981 100 20.0 40.0 40.0 88 6 5 \ll\ too 20.0 10.0 70.0 9 17 7 ..It-ZZZZ 100 25.0 25.0 50.0 4 27 2 ONE HIGH-PLAINS COUNTY (BOX BUTTE) ,„,„ 100 76.8 13.8 9.9 18 18 14 fc 1 ISS I?:? 5S it:? S S ™= S ?S: 7 o *S « U i !== ISS » 11:1 ??:°o j 1917ZZZZ 100 71.9 18.4 9.7 19 22 14 g== = S S:S Si S2 IS lE^ S S:S a i 8 ? :5 s tg,, 100 60.6 81.6 7.9 86 41 SO t?" 156 634 26.8 9.8 85 34 17 \.UZZZZ loo 42.8 84.6 28.1 34 86 19 1925 100 65.0 37.5 7.6 28 26 28 ,o9« 100 54.7 25.3 20.0 26 81 17 )l„ ISS 598 27.2 18.0 80 82 17 IMS 100 68.3 17.8 18.9 38 31 20 J9W 100 64.6 27.3 8.1 87 86 86 }980 100 65.7 26.8 7.5 86 34 17 t931 100 67.4 21.8 21.8 85 42 25 1982 100 40.7 48.1 11.1 22 26 liisS*: Z 100 70.0 80.0 88 - 18 * True sales by warranty deed. '____, . «.,. .»„j„ * Sales of tracts less than Ave acres in size are not Included in this stany. ' First eight months only. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska county the large tracts (400 acres and more) showed nearly as great price increases by 1920 as the smaller tracts. FARM LAND TURNOVER, 1874-1933 Sales per 100 farms.— As shown in Table 8, there was a general tendency for the" turnover of farm land to grow pro - gressively slower, from the decade 1884-93 to date, in the seven southeastern-Nebraska cash-crop counties. In 1884-93 TA ™d!^%lZ% 19 V arm M in n Nebraska counties &gt; Sales per 100 farms | Acres sold, per 100 acres in farms Decade 7 «2 uth - 2 east- 1 sand- 1 high- 7 south- 2^st^ 1 sand- 1 hiri, eastern central hill plains eastern central Ml" Jain," "unties* counties' county' county' counties' counties' county 1 rounfa' No. No. No. No. No l\Tn xr~ ». 1874-1888— 95 97 — s&gt;% VT - No - 1884-1893— 186 106 186 ill gi li V^ "S3 1894-1908- 66 68 208 424 i. tl H .11 1904-1918— 60 89 186 299 in il ll 10 ° 1914-1928- 66 68 III III 3 ? ° 4 l " * 2 1924-1933'.. 80 33 42 M 18 jj 22 _\ f-™. T il C '%!'* V C £? e * aIes by „ wurrant y deed. The number of farms and the acres in farms are those for the years 1880. 1890. 1900. 1910 1920 and 19X0 inHmwSlX f in successive United Stetes cen,u,es. except "tn Logan comrt* in 1920 ?Se1 TaWe? *w" note 1 for page references.) The 1920 census datafor Wn~umy appear to be in^" ?^ t n, : n theref °^ e 7 porU of thc Pree'nct assessors for th? ye^r. giving 246 farJ? anrf" 861.030 acres In farms, were substituted for census figures! (Ag?lcu"turalStatS?e»^f Nebraska for the Year 1920 State Dept. of Agr. Bui. 107 pp. 12 and 16 ) Statistica of JSr'" y 'i? i " m S r |;,? toe - PoIk - Sallne - Seward, and York countl™ ■ Merrick and Platte counties. 4 Logan county. * Box Butte county. « Incomplete, since data were obtained only for the first eight months of 1933. there were more sales than there were farms in these coun - ties in 1890—136 sales for every 100 farms. Reasons for the large number of sales in 1884-93 have been presented in the discussion of Table 2. In the following decade, 1894-1903 the rate of turnover was only about half as rapid, being 66 sales for every 100 farms. It continued to decrease slowly &amp;irl* ? subse Q u ent decades, and then dropped sharply in £ 24 ,"f 3 i! *? only 80 sales per 100 farms. Especial notice should be taken that the land boom of 1917-20, in spite of its soaring prices, did not comprise sufficient sales in these coun - ties to reverse the prevailing downward trend of turnover in the decade 1914-23, as compared with preceding decades. The two east-central livestock counties had a history very similar to the preceding, but they had a more rapid rate of turnover in every decade except 1884-93 and 1894-1903 than the seven cash-crop counties. The two western counties had a very much more rapid rate i£&lt;T?^l OV^i. thail x the e ? stern counties in every decade except 1884-93. The extremely variable number of farms in these </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 counties should be remembered in connection with these figures on turnover. The very rapid turnover in 1894-1903 was due, wholly in Logan county and partly in Box Butte county, to fewer farms rather than to more sales. Sales per 100 farms compared with value per acre. — As shown in Figure 7, J00 _ , , , the number of sales \ in 1914-23 per 100 \.. farms in 1920 tended \ | + lmotb cqunths | to decrease in pass- » \ ing from the counties z-~ - V with a low land value | \ to those with a high _ m _ \ land value, among . \. the counties shown 2 N. in this study. It is g « - -^v* possible that, in 4 counties with 1 a n d s M _ •' .^n^^ values very much J higher thanany shown here, the 'S « k_ _z no do trend shown above «.oo Lt „»u«c or ,«-««, m.-ym was reversed For Pio. 7. — Farm land turnover during .the example, a central- ten-year period 1914-23 compared with y * ' *__ -J.V the average value of farm land per acre lowa county Wltn in 1920; and fitted curve estimating the farm land values most probable rate of turnover for averaging $310 per counties having average land values in - acre had 86 sales in teryening between those of the counties i di a oo -^ _. -.. ti\f\ studied. Turnover is measured by the iyi4-^d p ei 1UU number of sales during the period 1914 - farms existing in 23 per IOO farms extant in 1920, as in 1920, 9 or a more Table 8. The average value of farm rapid turnover than land per acre is from the Fourteenth Occurred in any of Census, Vol. VI, Pt. 1, pp 690-8. The rr . r xt regression curve is computed from the the nine eastern JNe- observed data by the method of least braska counties dur- squares. Key to counties: ing the same years. 1— Clay 5— Saline 9— Platte Acres sold, per 2 — Fillmore 6 — Seward 10— Logan IOO »^n&gt;. U, f-,Jwr&gt;_ 3— Otoe 7— York 11— Box Butte 100 acres m farms. 4_ Polk 8-Merrick | R! ! I \\ '• f| ) — Since the tracts sold averaged smaller in size than the farms in each of the four farming areas, it follows that the number of acres sold per 100 acres in farms was considerably less in every area and decade than the number of sales per 100 farms. Measured • W. G. Murray, An Economic Analysis of Farm Mortgages in Story County, Iowa, 1854-1931. Ia. Agr. Exp. Sta., Research Bui. 166, p. 420. Jan., 193S. (Computed.) </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska in this way, the turnover in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties decreased from 98 acres sold in 1884-93 per 100 acres in farms, to only 18 acres sold in 1924-33 per 100 acres in farms; while the livestock counties showed a fairly similar history. The very numerous sales in Logan and Box Butte counties were of comparatively small tracts, so that the turn - over rate in these counties was not so extraordinary if meas - ured in acres sold per 100 acres in farms. It was, however, usually somewhat higher than that in the eastern counties. Velocity of sales in two counties, 1917-20. — Because of the relation of the land boom of 1917-20 to farm credit diffi - culties in 1921-33, a special scrutiny has been made of sales in two of the 11 counties during these years, in an attempt to find out what part of the farm land boom during these years was speculative in nature. In York county, a south - eastern-Nebraska cash-crop county, it was found that three - fourths of the tracts and acres sold changed hands only once during the four years 1917-20, and one-fifth of the tracts and acres sold changed hands only twice. Only four per cent of Table 9. — Velocity of sale of farm land in York and Box Butte counties, 1917-20. Tracts' Acres Times sold ~~ " — ■ York Box Butte York Box Butte county county county county NUMBER SOLD DURING 1917-20 Once 473 542 60,265 163.799 Twice ._ 124 216 12,872 54.142 Three times. . 24 83 2.657 18.437 More than three times 6 32 760 6,176 PERCENTAGE OF ALL TRUE SALES DURING 1917-20 SOLD: Once 75.6 62.1 75.6 67.6 Twice 19.8 24.7 19.4 22 3 Three times 8.8 9.6 3.8 7.6 More than three times 0.8 3.7 1.1 2.5 1 If a certain tract was sold once in its entirety and part of it a second time, it was counted as two tracts, one of which was sold once and the other twice. the tracts and acres sold changed hands three times ; and only one per cent, four times or more. Accordingly there cannot have been very much land speculation in 1917-20 in this county, for if there had been a larger proportion of the acreages sold would have changed hands several times. The Nebraska farm land boom of 1917-20 was a boom by farm - ers who wanted more land to hold and to farm; speculators had only a very minor share in it in this county. There is every reason to believe that the situation shown in York county was characteristic of the other six southeastern cash- </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 crop counties and perhaps to a slightly less degree of the two east-central livestock counties. In Box Butte county, at the western end of the state, there were more tracts and acres changing hands two, three, and more times in 1917-20; so it is probable that land speculation played a somewhat larger role in this county than it did in the southeastern part of the state. However, even here about three-fifths of the tracts and two-thirds of the acres sold in 1917-20 changed hands only once, while one-fourth of the tracts and. one-fifth of the acres sold changed hands only twice. In the figures given above, if any tract was sold in its entirety once and part of it was sold a second time, it was counted as two tracts, one of which was sold once and the other twice. RELATION OF TRUE SALES TO OTHER TYPES OF LAND TRANSFER, 1920-33 TYPES OF LAND TRANSFERS All transfers conveying full title. — Transfers conveying full title, as shown in Table 10, include all land transfers ex - cept those of quit-claim and part-interest rights. Such trans - fers, in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties, decreased from 1,330 in 1920 to 773 in 1923, increased to 1,028 in 1929, and decreased again to 907 in 1932. Apparently this de - crease was continued into 1933, although a complete record was not obtained for that year. Somewhat similar trends were observed in the other three farming areas studied. True sales. — The true sales shown in Table 10 include those by referees', trustees', and administrators' deeds as well as those by warranty deed. The latter constituted the bulk of the class as may be seen by comparing this table with Table 2. True sales in the seven southeastern cash-crop coun - ties decreased from 80 per cent of all transfers conveying full title in 1920 to 30 per cent during the first eight months of 1933. A high ratio of true sales to all transfers conveying full title is characteristic of prosperous years. The decrease in the percentage of true sales in 1920-33 in the two east - central livestock counties closely resembled that in the cash - crop counties, except that it commenced earlier, being sharper in 1921-22 and in 1931-32. True sales in Logan county de - creased from 73 per cent of all transfers conveying full title in 1920 to 15 per cent in the first eight months of 1933 ; true sales in Box Butte county, from 85 to 23 per cent. Foreclosures Foreclosures, as shown in Table 10, in - clude all foreclosure sales by sheriffs, receivers, and special masters in chancery; also tax lien foreclosures by county </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska commissioners. Only a very few of the last-named type were found in the 11 counties studied. The number of foreclosures in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties increased from only three in 1920 to 74 during the first eight months of 1933, or from 0.2 to 14 per cent of all land transfers conveying full title. In the two east-central livestock counties the percent - age ratio of foreclosures to* all land transfers in 1920 and 1933 was almost identical with the above, but it began to in - crease earlier. In these counties, this ratio was higher in 1922-32 than it was in the seven cash-crop counties. Two waves of foreclosures may be observed, one occurring about 1922-26 and resulting from the depression of 1921 ; the other mounting in 1930-33 and resulting from the great depression commencing in 1929. It should be noted in connection with the depression of 1921 that the crest of the foreclosure wave did not come until two or three years after the depression was over. A study of the farm mortgage history of 11 southeast - ern-Nebraska townships indicates that the crest of the fore - closures resulting from the depression of 1893-96 also did not come until 1897-98 in those townships, or during the early years of recovery immediately following the depression. 10 This development was partly due to the delay necessitated by law before a foreclosed farm may be disposed of, but partly also to the circumstance that many creditors did not care to institute foreclosure proceedings until they saw a prospect of being able to sell the farm for something approaching the amount of the debt resting upon it. In the two western counties shown in Table 10, foreclosures were very frequent in 1924-28, amounting to 29 per cent of the Logan county transfers conveying full title in 1926 and 25 per cent of the Box Butte county transfers conveying full title in 1925. Apparently this severe storm of liquidations cleared the air for a while, because foreclosures in 1931-33 were less numerous in these counties than during the preced - ing foreclosure period. Further discussion of foreclosures in relation to various other items is reserved for a later sec - tion. Token transfers. — Token transfers, as shown in Table 10, include all transfers of full title to farm land for which the monetary consideration mentioned in the deed was from $1 to $100, with or without "other consideration". This is a decidedly mixed class including gifts, trades, and assign - ments of title to avoid foreclosure proceedings, but without "Eleanor Hinman and J. O. Rankin. Farm Mortgage History of Eleven South - eastern Nebraska Townships, 1870-1932. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. -Research Bui. 67, p. 63, August, 1933. ! </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 ioHN«c^«oo^;i&gt;H«!oweo os co »-j oo oq oo t&gt; os oo © ca *■&lt; to *o o S « to ci © i&gt; ci ©3 od --* os t© &lt;o 06 to io ci od us •-« oi to i&gt; oo od o to to cd t-^ 2 5 °" • . - o 5 t. _ ™ S u ** ccoN^WNO«ifWh;H(flnn n q in oo tj ih q o o -j t- w t- ta ?* s-*m H wddd«5iot^cJwcicit&gt;dd W^td tot^ea ed tdoi edo*-«0) °? 8 5 © „ : — S I -, &gt;S c A £ ■" wtnnwweooHHcoHiMcitM ■•onowionovwoohoio a o 3 _• oocded*v^69^ededisiai&gt;^i ©©^^©'wiocicd-^t^cieJed ef a £§ -*• •«» o S3 ** iS 3 — ~S ** "C 2J5 o* o ci to cd to r-J © io •-« © oa ci to ed ei os •** cd io cd cd cd »- ci »c t^cd ■^ "*"* pH 3 CO « IO iS 13 O &lt;0 iO W « « ft N CO O io r 1 L3 C u'. u- l- C f Ol n 1 f— J 1 cv\ o =3 8 P oooooooooooooo *z. oeooooeo&amp;ooooo *•* J* 71 q o©oo©oo©oo©oo© fi ocsoooooooooooo fe; £ " «■ S •?-—---; g — — - - s * — E ft, u S -iE-a-S£ rf V O (y. Vu " A? d CO MMNNNNMOIMMNNCIH u 2 -5 a S 2" • S S» C © n OHHQNOtoiov«-&lt;r-t-o H toe-iocitooc)cir-os©^&gt;ooo C4 *» Z H OO tO 00 IO OS C4 fc- OS OS 55 to to 10 OO &lt; mieoniMNMC'liMNMHNH g 3 • g ~ g 1 — t g 1 *"** — v£ o ? HCOot-nuNEc^ini-coOH CO oa io us to os ■* t- o «-* cj oo frl 00 to Za J£ m &gt; O b.usva»H-«^vvoiSMia« &lt; t-ttoo c-««o 00 cie&gt; o-, to,© C — B ■ ' 5 _&gt; ** B 2 c % i **^ *r i £ . m Moootottifliotsniflisoieo O gj ba eeio&lt;eia«t.««oac.e9ei^ »,nn^^, MHMMMn &gt; .og z NNW^NWcoeo^vt-e. 00 c ■* § e I I el i gS5SSSS33SS3§aS 5§3§S2SSSSSSSSgg © H ' " " lH I n — q ooiaeetNt-t*oi3oooNt-o "SSSlSSiStSSzJl^iSSS 7^* &lt;J &lt;J eOOOt^OOOOtOOOOOtOCAOOOaiO IOC4CMClC1CMCIC100CieOC4C4r4 11 1 1 i III MM' ! ! i 1 ! i I i II I s j I j I I i ! ; j j j I&gt;* e^e4tn^iotoi&gt;obcno^cico o^icacQ^totoc-ooedo&lt;-iciM NNNNNNNNNNncJWW CJ M CI M C4 N M JJ CJ CJ 00 W CO M OOCSOOOGOOQOOOQ C» OS » C» C&gt; Oi Oi C» » 0* CO « CO Ol </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Table 10.— (Continued) . ONE SAND-HILL COUNTY' }J2y 107 78 1 12 16 8 100 72.9 0.9 11.2 16.0 !2o£ f2 30 1 14 17 100 57.7 1.9 26.9 13.5 llll 5S 23 6 17 7 12 100 43.4 11.3 32.1 13.2 1923 39 11 4 19 5 13 100 28.2 10.3 48.7 12.8 llli 2 7 13 10 9 5 10 100 35.1 27.0 24.3 18.5 llll 74 21 21 25 7 18 100 28.4 28.4 33.8 9.4 ll 2 l 56 18 16 19 8 14 100 82.1 28.6 83.9 6.4 llll ll ll 1S 26 8 U 100 24.2 21.0 41.9 12.9 &gt;i_ 1928 51 14 13 24 0 14 100 27.5 26.6 47.0 0.0 _T llll 49 19 6 22 2 14 100 38.8 12.2 44.9 4.1 _. 1930 39 9 18 10 2 86 100 23.1 46.2 26.6 6.1 5 llll 43 5 6 28 4 11 100 11.6 14.0 66.1 9.8 R }032- 38 10 10 14 4 8 100 26.3 26.3 86.8 10.5 M 19S8» 26 4 6 13 8 7 100 15.4 .23.1 60.0 11.5 ONE HIGH-PLAINS COUNTY" g 1920 280 237 1 81 11 71 100 84.6 0.4 11.1 3.9 w llll ll ff I 21 7 38 10° « 2 - 8 I- 8 27.8 9.1 2? 1922 91 40 3 36 12 25 100 43.9 3.8 89.6 13.2 g 1023 . 89 48 11 26 9 42 100 48.3 12.4 29.2 10.1 Q 1924 83 26 20 24 IS 36 100 Sl.S 24.1 28.9 15.7 W 1925 114 42 29 84 9 47 100 86.8 25.4 29.8 7.9 M llll J 6B . 76 34 40 B 48 100 49.6 21.9 26.8 8.2 t-t llll III ! 00 31 29 7 34 100 59.9 18.6 17.8 4.2 _*, nil JJ2 J? 6 1B 42 9 4S 10° 61- 8 9-2 24.3 6.2 llll ll 2 . U1 6 80 6 39 100 73.0 8.3 19.7 8.9 __ 1980 124 77 3 41 3 28 100 62.1 2.4 88.1 2.4 3 llll ll 49 7 87 4 47 100 50.6 7.2 38.1 4.1 68 llll. ll ? 8 15 48 2 I 5 100 83.7 15.3 49.0 2.0 W 193S« 47 11 13 23 0 21 100 23.4 27.7 48.9 0.0 &gt; ■ ■ — tn 'Includes both true sales by warranty deed and other true sales. Sj 1 Sheriffs' and bankruptcy sales and tax lien foreclosures. &gt; 'Sales for from Sl to $100 "and other consideration". The class Includes gifts, trndes, and assignments of title to mortgage-holders to avoid foreclosure proceedings. 4 Clay, Fillmore, Otoe, Polk, Seward, Saline, and York counties. The "cash-crop" counties are those In which farms obtaining 40 per cent or more of their Income for 1929 from sales of grain or crop specialties were more numerous than farms which obtained 40 per cent or more of their income from sales of livestock or livestock products, as indicated In the U. S. census of 1930. * Includes only deeds signed In 1983 and filed during the first eight months of that year. Merrick and Platte counties. In these counties the livestock farms outnumbered the cash-crop farms in 1929. "Livestock farms" comprise those classified In the 1930 census as dairy, animal-specialty, stock-ranch, and poultry farms. ' Logan county. 'Box Butte county. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 detailed study of the mortgage history of each tract thus transferred it was impossible to distinguish the three classes with any degree of certainty. The number of unencumbered gifts (clearly indicated as such) in the counties studied showed no marked tendency to increase or decrease during the years under consideration. They constituted a little less than one-third of all the token transfers in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties, the two east-central livestock counties, and Box Butte county, and about one-eighth of the token transfers in Logan county for the 14-year period 1920-33. Transfers definitely stated to have been in consideration of assuming or releasing the mortgage indebtedness on the tract, plus from $1 to $100, included about one-sixth of the token transfers for the 14-year period 1920-33 in the seven south - eastern cash-crop counties, about one-eighth in Logan county, and about one-fourth in the two east-central livestock counties and in Box Butte county. This group increased greatly in all 11 counties between 1920 and 1932-33. Token transfers for from $1 to $100 "and other consideration" (without specifying the nature of such "other consideration") com - prised about two-fifths of all token transfers for the same period in the two east-central livestock counties, one-half in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties and in Box Butte county, and three-fourths in Logan county. Probably a very considerable part of this group, especially in more recent years, consisted of assignments to avoid foreclosure proceed - ings. Token transfers increased from 13 per cent of all land transfers conveying full title in the seven southeastern cash - crop counties in 1920 to 50 per cent during the first eight months of 1933 ; and practically in the same proportion in the other three farming areas studied. It is believed that most of this increase was due to assignments for debt. The fore - closure figures in the preceding column by no means do jus - tice to the severity of the farm mortgage situation during this 14-year period. For every farmer who was sold out by the sheriff or receiver, there were apparently one or two others who surrendered their farms for debt without court proceedings. Some of these men have contracts which permit them to repurchase their farms for the amount of the debt within a specified period if they are able to do so. Others remain as tenants on the land they formerly owned; still others have been rendered homeless as well as dispossessed. "All other" transfers conveying full title. — "All other" transfers conveying full title include transfers for more than $100 but less than seems reasonable for a true sale, transfers </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska where an annuity forms part or all of the consideration re - ceived, and transfers conditional upon payments to follow someone's death. These varied irregularly, but in general seemed tb decrease at about the same rate as all transfers conveying full title. Quit-claim and part-interest transfers. — Quit-claim and part-interest transfers arose chiefly from four sources, as fol - lows: (1) Settlement of estates consequent upon the death, retirement, or divorce of the owner. The death rate among farm owners probably did not vary enough to affect these figures during the 14-year period studied; retirements prob - ably and divorces certainly declined during the depression. (2) Clearance of title preparatory to sales or to execution of mortgages. (3) Assignments of title to mortgage-holders, some of which were made by quit-claim deed. (4) Sales of farms held in partnership. These various elements seem to have offset one another so that the number of quit-claim and part-interest transactions showed no very regular tendency to alter conformably to changes in the economic situation. Because of this and be - cause of the large number of such transfers often simulta - neously affecting the same tract, quit-claim and part-interest transfers are omitted from the percentages shown in the last five columns of Table 10. FORECLOSURES AS RELATED TO VARIOUS OTHER ITEMS Foreclosures per 100 farms. — The number of foreclosures in 1920-33 per 100 farms existing in 1920 varied from four in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties, to 53 in Logan county. The variation in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties was from two foreclosures per 100 farms in Saline county to six such foreclosures in Clay county. The extremely low foreclosure ratio in Saline county may be explained on the following grounds: (1) The farmers in Saline county did their land-buying early, 1917 being the peak year. Land prices were lower in this year than later, and the purchasers had one or two more years of high commodity prices in which to reduce their debts than those who bought in 1918 or 1919. (2) Mortgage interest rates were low in Saline county. The ratio of debt service charges on owner-operated farms in 1929 to indebtedness on the same farms was 5.2 per cent in this county, which was lower than the average for the seven cash - crop counties (5.5 per cent) and for the state as a whole (5.7 per cent). The very high foreclosure rate in Logan county may be explained on the following grounds: (1) Marginal and near-marginal land usually suffers sharper de- </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Table 11.— Foreclosure sales per 100 farms m 11 Nebraska counties compared with various more or less correlated items. Types of transfers per 100 farms g^ lee per &#132;,„, goM Va) Ratio ttonof" ■" 1920 ' farm J*t turn g ' [ — " real service acreage S J^. ' Pxt. P.et. Pxt. P.eU P SEVEN SOUTHEASTERN NEBRASKA CASH-CROP COUNTIES H ill .iTTTiii Hi is Yo"k JZZ t 25 26 96 197 77 105 61 120 6.2 88 g, TWO EAST-CENTRAL NEBRASKA LIVESTOCK COUNTIES " gj fe| i s its S S I. S I 2 .S I 1 ONE SAND-HILL COUNTY . W Lojan | S3 102 117 1 12 23 6 92 74 | 17 6.5 79 g ONE HIGH-PLAINS COUNTY H Box Butte-I 86 72 150 | 17 48 16 153 63 | 30 6.8 89 | i Th . _ umber O f farms m 1920 was obtained from the Fourteenth Census. Vol. VI. Pt I, pp. 690-98; «tcept for Logan county. The num - iS^^SSrST^^t!^ 1^ - -,ue of the Il^uTes^afrrXa^clat- jK2a &lt; iSRJ^^ &gt; (JS!^ VoL HI. Pt i. PP. 925-981.) </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska clines in earning power during a depression than land of aver - age value. (2) The farm land turnover was very high in Logan county, especially in 1918-20. (3) The farm mortgage interest rate was higher than in any other of the 11 counties studied, except Polk. The average number of acres per fore - closure in Logan county in 1920-33 was 692, indicating that the foreclosed tracts were a little smaller than the average Logan county farm according to Table 1. In some cases the same tract underwent foreclosure twice during the fourteen - year period. Token transfers as related to foreclosures. — The number of token transfers in 1920-33 per 100 farms in 1920 varied from 27 in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties to 102 in Logan county. It was usually low in the same farming areas where the number of foreclosures per 100 farms was low, and high in the same areas where the number of fore - closures per 100 farms was high. The most variable element in the token transfers was assignments of title to avoid fore - closure proceedings, which explains this correspondence. In a few counties, however, such a correspondence did not occur. In Polk county, for example, the number of token transfers per 100 farms was 20, or less than in any other of the 11 counties; but the number of foreclosures per 100 farms was five, or more than in any other of the seven southeastern cash - crop counties except Clay. True sales, 1918-20, as related to foreclosures, 1920-33. As indicated in Table 11, the number of foreclosures in 1920 - 33 per 100 farms in 1920 was highest in the counties which had the highest rate of farm land turnover during the pre - ceding years of high prices, 1918-20. Logan county, however, had a much higher foreclosure rate than might have been an - ticipated from the rate of turnover in 1918-20, Saline county a somewhat lower foreclosure rate. In the other nine coun - ties the foreclosure rate was approximately proportional to rate of turnover in 1918-20. Coefficients of the correlation between the foreclosure rate in 1920-33 and the turnover in 1918-20 were not computed because of the small number of counties observed. Land values and foreclosures. — Estimated land values in the counties studied bore a fairly definite relation to the fore - closure rate, especially when the estimate chosen is that for the census year 1930, as shown in Table 11 and Figure 8. In general in the counties studied, the foreclosure rate was high- </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 est in the counties hav- i — rr _ 1 1 1 1 1 1 — ing the lowest land *- V" - values, and lowest in i V ISSSSSUI!^ the counties where land «« - \ r- ' - was valued at from I \ about $100 to about !„- »\ $120 in 1930. In coun- I \ ties having still more \ K _ \ valuable land, the fore- £ \^ closure rate tended to §„_ t rise slightly. A some- g &gt;s^_ __~£^ what similar correspon- * , i ■ t ■ *T* n^ i dence between land s*'*Sjic.nocl_*s.oftiMmStnmr&amp;scm.rfLs ■*• values and foreclosure Fl(J 8 ._ Farm mortgage foreclosure rate rate is shown if the f or the 14-year period 1920-33 compared 1920 census estimates with the average value of farm real Of value are used, ex- estate per acre in 1930; and fitted curve i • j »~ nn „„,,„+„ estimating the probable foreclosure rate n ,^? an COa _V- for counties having land values inter- But the 1920 census ng- vening between those of the counties ures on the number and studied. The observed data are from value Of farms in Logan Table 11. The foreclosure rate is meas - „„„-!,, __„ „.„i,oWTr in wred by the number of foreclosures in county are probably in- 192WJ8 * per 100 farms extant in 1920. complete, as nas Deen j.^ e fitted curve is a regression curve observed (page 15, computed from the observed data by the footnote 3). The live- method of least squares. stock counties had a Ke y t0 counties: 3lightly higher foreclos- 1— Clay 5— -Saline 9— Platte urn rfttP than cash-croo 2— Fillmore 6— Seward 10— Logan ure rate tnan casn crop 3 _o toe 7 _ Yo rk ll— Box Butte counties having the 4_ Po i k 8— Merrick same land value. . . The percentage of increase in the sales price of farm land from 1910 to 1920, and of decrease from 1920 to the first eight months of 1933, appears to have borne very little relation to the foreclosure rate. LAND TRANSFERRED TO CREDIT CORPORATIONS, 1920-33 Significance. — Transfers of farm land to banks, loan companies, life insurance companies, and other credit corpora - tions during the 14-year period 1920-33 were practically always either foreclosures or assignments for debt. In 1920 a few loan companies and country banks may have been to a small degree in the real estate business from choice, but the appearance of the credit corporations in this field in later years resulted solely from the necessity of realizing upon their loans. Accordingly, in this particular instance it is readily possible to show the relation of the assignments to the foreclosures. Since much of the land transferred to the </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Table 12. — Transfers of farms to banks, loan companies, insurance companies, and other credit corporations in 11 Nebraska counties, 1920-38. Transfers transferred Method of transfer T.. m i.. T~.*.t_r- Acres to credit to credit •£. * £S-tu transferred corporations corporations »£? «££!fU.. to credit 1920-88. 1920-33, county 192™S3 ""ESS?" , perl0 ,° pcrl °° _ , , T ° k ™ Quitclaim /, Bouniy UM1 1920-83 farms In acres in Foreclosure 1 transfer" deed or Other **- 1920 1 farms In part interest &gt; 1920' }S — — . K No. Acres No. Acres SEVEN SOUTH-EASTERN CASH-CROP COUNTIES ► ____ All 530 87,795 8.8 8.6 163 181 93 os S Clay 138 22.265 7.7 6.8 42 49 \\ Is Fillmore 50 8.417 2.5 2.4 17 17 ?0 « Otoe 64 10.988 2.8 2.9 27 16 11 w W £ ok 74 14.371 5.0 6.4 . 24 26 16 o « Sa»ne 85 4.046 1.7 1.1 6 . 12 " 12 9 Seward 77 11.890 3.6 8.4 28 24 9 lfi K York 02 15,818 4.6 4.6 19 37 10 26 „ TWO EAST-CENTRAL LIVESTOCK COUNTIES " All 323 56,736 9.2 8.2 83 130 56 al Merrick 152 30.331 11.1 11.0 42 63 19 ia S Platte 171 26.402 8.0 6.4 41 67 37 26 3 ONE SAND-HILL COUNTY gj Lo«an 83 66,834 33.7 18.2 28 33 12 10 ONE HICH-PLAINS COUNTY Box Butte 88 35.181 13.7 5.4 20 25 16 27 * Farms and acres In farms in 1920 for all counties except Logan were obtained from the Fourteenth Census, 1920. Vol VI Pt 1 dp 690 9 For Logan county, they were obtained from Agricultural Statistics of Nebraska for the Year 1920, State Dept. Agr. Bui 107 no 12 and 16 - ■ Includes foreclosures by sheriffs' apd receivers' sales and special masters in chancery ; also tax lien foreclosures ■Includes all transfers for from .«|1 to $100 and "other consideration". </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 credit corporations still remains in their hands to be sold at low prices, a study of these transfers also indicates the ex - tent of an important factor depressing the price of farm land. Rate of transfer. — The number of transfers to credit corporations in 1920-33 for every 100 farms existing in 1920 varied from four in the seven southeastern cash-crop coun - ties to 34 in Logan county, as shown in Table 12. The three counties having the highest rate of such transfers were Logan, Box Butte, and Merrick, which also had the highest foreclosure rates; and the three counties having the lowest rate of such transfer were Saline, Fillmore, and Otoe. Farms transferred to credit corporations were about the same size as the average for the county in all of the counties studied except Logan and Box Butte, where the farms so transferred were much smaller than the average in size. Evidently the credit corporations took over more of the small-sized grain and crop-specialty farms than of the large stock ranches in these counties. Method of transfer. — Assignment by token transfer was the commonest way of conveying farm land to credit corpora - tions in every county except Otoe and Seward, where fore - closure was commonest, and Box Butte, where assignment for the value of the debt plus more than $100 was commonest. Token transfers accounted for about one-third of all trans - fers to credit corporations in the seven southeastern cash-crop counties, two-fifths in the two eastrcentral livestock counties and in Logan county, and one-fourth in Box Butte county. Foreclosures comprised about one-third of the transfers to credit corporations in the seven southeastern cash-crop coun - ties and in Logan county, and about one-fourth in the two east-central livestock counties and in Box Butte county. As - signment by quit-claim deed or by transfers of part-interest comprised from about one-seventh to about one-sixth of the transfers to credit corporations in the four farming areas studied. "Other" methods of transfer — usually assignment for the amount of the debt plus more than $100 — included from one-eighth to one-third of the transfers in the four respective farming areas. VARIOUS FACTORS AFFECTING FARM LAND PRICE FARM INCOME Land price and farm income, 1914-20. — Farm land price is determined by a more or less conscious capitalization of farm income, at the current rate of interest. In theory, </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska future income is capitalized. But since purchasers tend to be optimistic about the future during periods of high farm in - come and pessimistic during periods of low farm income, in practice current income tends to be capitalized, with some allowance for extremes of inflation or deflation, and with a lag of one or two years before purchasers become convinced of the permanence of trend changes. This relation between farm income and land prices is illustrated in Figure 9, which compares land price for the 11 counties relative to a 1914 base with the average net income per farm relative to the same base, for the Nebraska farms keeping complete accounts in co-operation with the Department of Rural Economics of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. The num - ber of such farms was highly variable in different years, rang - ing from 17 in 1920 to 230 in 1930; and only a small pro - portion of them were located in the counties where land price was studied. However, the income figures are believed to be „0 /\ 1 1 / \ ltW» MO r_ n \ nm UhNo race in ii NCM.cauNTca f" | \ ACflES SOLD IN 1 1 NEBR. COUNTIES I / ' NET INCOME PER TARU- NEBR. / / i i NtTiNcoue rcMioo or capital value // \\\ ZZ J 100 — t&amp;a.. — rx~ — _A\ \ v^^ lOOS^U-r^ i,-V_l +f__^-_ ... ■-•_ &gt; \\ N \\ \ \ •A 0 1 -*J I | I I HU IMO H2J ItlO Fig. 9. — Relatives of farm land prices and of acres sold compared with relatives of net income per farm and per $100 of capital value in Nebraska farms reporting these items, 1914-32. The price relatives for each of the 11 counties were computed and then averaged. Acres sold computed from Table 2. Net incomes from H. C. Filley, Effects of Inflation and Deflation on Nebraska Agriculture, 1914 to 1932, Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 71. 1934. (Computed.) </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 reasonably representative of general conditions on Nebraska farms. The land price relative used in Figure 9 was obtained by computing a price relative for each county and averaging them. In this way price changes due solely to the variable proportion of cheap western land sold were avoided. The low farm incomes in 1921-23 explain not only the de - creasing farm land prices in 1921-24 but also the increase in the number of mortgage foreclosures from 1923 to 1925. It often takes two years after a default, and sometimes longer, before foreclosure proceedings culminate in a sheriff's sale. The plunge of farm incomes into the red in 1931-32 sufficiently explains both the land price decreases and the increasing num - ber of foreclosures in these years. Sales activity and farm income. — The number of acres of farm land sold in the 11 counties relative to a 1914 base showed an extremely close correspondence with the relative net farm income from 1914 to 1930. Sales activity recovered less than farm income in 1924-29 and declined less than in - come in 1930-32. Doubtless many of the sales in 1931 and 1932 were sales for very little more than the value of the indebtedness on the property, and some of them were sales of repossessed farms. The close correspondence between sales activity and net income in 1914-30 results from the circum - stance that farmers are the principal purchasers of farm land, and that they quite promptly invest income surpluses in land purchases. COMMODITY PRICES Agricultural commodity prices and land price. — The price of agricultural commodities is an important factor in determining net farm income and therefore in determining farm land price. From 1910 to 1933 it was probably the most significant factor because it fluctuated more than the other determining factors. As indicated in Figure 10, the farm land price relative in the 11 counties followed the index of the Nebraska farm price of agricultural commodities from 1910 to 1933 in a general way and after a lag of from one to three years. Agricultural commodity prices rise more steeply than land prices in periods of prosperity and decline more sharply in periods of depression. This principle is illus - trated in Figure 10 with especial clarity for the years 1910 - 33. Agricultural commodity prices rose less steeply and declined less sharply than the net farm income shown in the preceding table, for the reason of course that expendi - tures, especially fixed charges, consumed a larger proportion of gross receipts in depressed years than in prosperous ones. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska /. . I i*to-i4.mo , I / A JOO PARU LANO PRICE INII NEIR.COUNTIES 1 / / ■ I WHOLESALE PRICE OT ALL CSUUOOITIES* \- S X NCSA. TARM PRICE OP ACRI.COMUQQITIES' // / l\ roRccLosuRCSPCRKiooorARiuiNiicouNnes* // /':'\ / / i 1^^^ 100 -^.g^^X '.V A I I I — • is** Sou 1*10 imo nio —~^ FlG. 10. — Price relative of farm land compared with the index of the wholesale price of all commodities, 1892-1933, and with that of the Nebraska farm price of agricultural commodities, 1910-33. 'The land price relative for the 11 counties was obtained by computing a land price relative for each county, adding the figures for each year and dividing by 11. In this way, changes in the price index due to vajrying proportions of the cheap western land were obtained. 3 Bureau of Labor Statistics index. For the years 1910-33, this was obtained from The Agricultural Situation, Vol. 18, No. 8, p. 20. U. S. Department of Agriculture. For 1890-1009, it was as given in Farm Economics No. 72, pp. 1586-7, N. Y. State College of Agriculture. Ithaca, N. Y., 1931. * Prepared by Harold Hedges, University of Nebraska, Dept. of Rural Economics. 'Per 10,000 farms reported by the census in 1920. General commodity prices and land price. — An index for Nebraska agricultural commodities has been constructed only back to 1910. Wholesale prices in general — including the prices of agricultural commodities — followed a downward trend from 1873 to 1894, at a time when Nebraska farm land prices were rising. Wholesale prices rose from 1897 to 1910 but not so fast as Nebraska farm land price. However the latter did not begin to rise until 1900 and, except in the two western counties, continued rising until 1914. Preceding 1914, other factors affecting farm land prices were active; these reversed the influence of declining commodity prices in 1873-94 and reinforced the influence of rising commodity prices in 1900-10. Some of these factors have been indicated previously and others will be discussed later. From 1914 to 1932 the course of land price bore a fairly close resemblance to that of wholesale commodity prices. Agricultural commodity prices and mortgage fore - closures. — As shown in Figure 10, low Nebraska agricul - tural commodity prices in 1921-23 were accompanied by </seg>
            <seg id="p050">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 an increase in mortgage foreclosures which continued until 1925. The partial price recovery in 1925-29 was accompanied after a year's lag by decreasing foreclosures in 1926-29. The commodity price collapse in 1930-32 was accompanied by mounting foreclosures. Foreclosure figures for 1933 are incomplete, but it is believed that government action in refinancing mortgages has prevented a further increase over 1932 in foreclosures. Without such action, fore - closures might have gone on increasing in number for a year or two after commodity prices began to recover, as they did in 1924-25 and also in 1897-98. 1 7 S.C. NEBRASKA Z _. I ANTRAL NEI RASKA ,»"", CASH-CIOP LIVE ITOCK COUN' ItS I COUNT IES .-\ MO \ — \ »» I00 V »-*-^ 'X/ - ' 00 FORECLOSU IE3 \ FORI rLOSURBsA. A / \ PER 10.000 riRUS -j NcT" ptR 0.000/ N ~-. / V \ * imp nzs I93Q \___ !•*£ IM0 ______ *o°i — i 1 1 1 i — i n LOCAN :OUNTY /IPOJATOES* B0XB1ITTE , \sr-- &gt; COUNT If loo /V ir—^ lA\ ' ,oc row closures/ N_ /\ 1 T wheat" \\ PER .OOOWRUS' \ / \ a rolttCLOSURES "WMifc^X / V V \ PERIJOOO a/' \ *• • 5f^ iSH NM WIS 1920 192* MM Fig. 11. — Farm mortgage foreclosure rates compared with price rela - tives of principal products in four Nebraska farming areas. 1 Wheat: Price relatives (1910-14=100) of the average price received by pro - ducers. H. C. Filley, and A. M. Hauke. Local Prices of Farm Products in Nebraska. 1896-1982. Nebr. Atcr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 284, p. 24, Lincoln, Nebr., 1988. 'Hoes: Price relatives (1910-14=100) of the average price received by producers. Same source as preceding;, p. 80. •Feeder steers: Price relatives (1910-14=100) of top Prices paid at Omaha. Omaha Daily Journal-Stockman, Vol. 46. No. 172, p. 8, Omaha, Nebr.. Jan. 1, 1984. ♦Potatoes: Price relatives (1910-14=100) of the averasre price received by pro - ducers. H. C Filley and A. M. Hauke, op. cit., p. 37. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska Prices of principal products and foreclosure rates in four farming areas. — Some differences in the land price history and especially in .the foreclosure history of the four differ - ent farming areas studied may be partially accounted for by the price history of their various principal products. As indicated in Figure 11, the fact that hog prices sank lower in 1921-24 than wheat prices, relative to a 1910-14 base, may be one reason why the two east-central livestock coun - ties had more foreclosures than the seven southeastern cash-crop counties, especially in 1922-25. High prices of feeder steers in 1928-30 may be one reason why the fore - closure rate in the two western counties was lower in 1931 - 32 than in some earlier years. MORTGAGE INTEREST RATE Land price and interest rates.— Decreases in the farm mortgage interest rate current in any locality, if they per - sist for several years, result eventually in increases in the farm land price. This is because purchasers are willing to pay more for land if they can give a mortgage on easy terms as part of the purchase price. Figure 12 indicates that the interest rate per farm mortgage filed in the south - eastern cash-crop area decreased from nearly 11 per cent in 1874 to about 5^ per cent in 1905, and, except in 1917 - 1921, varied little thereafter. Sharp declines in interest rate in 1879-82 and 1898-1902 were followed after a lag tOOi I i 1 ■ | FAHULAJD /\ pwce . / \ , i0 ; _za — i p * J i _ y i __&gt; 100 ==-* -f- | 0 i _ s »„ UOKTUGCINTCItUTIUIE-. / \ . _ ..* x / : X I ■ST&gt; Wi IMO ItU IMO ° Fig. 12. — Average interest per mortgage in 11 southeastern-Nebraska townships 1 compared with the price relative of farm land per acre in seven southeasten-Nebraska counties 2 , 1873-1933. „ J E - H. Hinman and J. O. Rankin, Farm Mortgage History of Eleven Southeastern Nebraska Townships. 1870-1932. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bui. 67, p. 25. Lincoln, Nebr., 1938. The townships included nine in York, one in Saline, and one in Saunders counties. 'Clay. Fillmore, Otoe (mls-ing in 1878-89), Polk. Saline, Seward (missing In 1873 - 92), and York counties. Price relative based on the years 1910-14. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 of a year or two by gradual but enduring increases in land price. The generally declining trend of the mortgage in - terest rate from 1874 to 1905 is one reason why the be - havior of land prices sometimes differed from that of wholesale commodity prices in general. High interest rates in 1920-22 contributed to the land price deflation during these years, but the price deflation of 1930-33 occurred at a time when interest rates were' practically stationary. Data on the behavior of interest rates over a prolonged period are not available for the other four areas studied, but such rates did not decrease so soon nor so much in the western part of the state as in the eastern part. Foreclosures and mortgage interest rates. — Relatively high interest rates (6.3 and 6.5 per cent respectively on owner-operated farms in 1930) in Box Butte and Logan counties were doubtless a contributing factor to the high foreclosure rate in these counties in 1920-33. But the effect of the high interest rates in precipitating foreclosures was less than that of some other factors previously dis - cussed. Polk county with an interest rate of 6.5 per cent in 1929, had only five foreclosures in 1920-33 per 100 farms in 1920; but Logan county, with exactly the same rate, suffered 53 foreclosures per 100 farms. 11 Some of these foreclosures were on fractions of farms, and some tracts underwent foreclosure twice during the 14 years. TRANSPORTATION COSTS Freight rates. — Transportation costs in general declined from the commencement of the period studied (1873) until about 1907. The nine eastern-Nebraska counties were already served with railroads in 1873, but the extension of branch lines continued for some years after that date. Freight charges were very high during the early periods of settlement and development but were later gradually reduced. Freight rates from typical shipping points in the 11 counties tb Omaha and Chicago remained low from 1907 throughout the war and the early post-war period, but about 1919 or 1920 they increased very sharply. In 1921 rates on wheat shipped from Alliance, Geneva, or Columbus to Omaha and Chicago ranged in different in - stances from 155 to 172 per cent of the pre-war rates (1910-14=100), and rates on cattle and hogs from 141 to 181 per cent of the pre-war rates. This sudden increase ,x "Interest rates" quoted above are the rat'os of debt service charges on owner - operated farms in 1929 to the mortgage indebtedness on the fame farms in 1930. Fifteenth Census of the U. S., 1980, Vol. II, PL 1, pp. 1274-8. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska co-operated with the factors previously discussed to reduce farm incomes in 1921 and compel land price deflation. Freight rates remained rather high, especially on short hauls, throughout the 13 years of deflation (1921-33). In 1934 freight rates on cattle and hogs shipped from Alliance, Geneva, or Columbus to Omaha were about one and one-half times the pre-war rate, while grain shipments were about one and one-third times the pre-war rate. Charges on shipments to distant points such as Chicago, Minneapolis, or Kansas City were also above the pre-war rates, although the increase was less than that on short hauls. 12 These high freight rates co-operated with the general commodity price deflation to keep land prices low in 1921-33. Other transportation factors. — Road and highway im - provements from the early period of settlement up to about 1910-14 reinforced the effect of decreasing freight rates to encourage land price increases. Such improve - ments since 1910-14 probably constitute some offset against the higher freight rates mentioned above. The develop - ment of motor transport has probably had a similar effect. Charges for transportation by truck have not been especially studied in connection with this bulletin, but it is common knowledge that the amount of farm produce transported by truck has increased greatly in recent years, especially on short hauls. SOIL TYPES Principal soil types. — A study of the location and soil types of the farms sold during 1918-20, the post-war boom years having the highest prices, throws light upon some of the characteristics of this boom and also upon the mort - gage distress of 1921-33. In Figure 14 a map of the prin - cipal soil types in the counties studied has been prepared through the co-operation of the Nebraska Soil Survey, and the farms sold have subsequently been entered upon it in black, according to their legal descriptions. Because of the small scale of the map, it has been necessary to combine related soil series and greatly to simplify the complexity of the soil configuration, even at the risk of omitting im - portant distinctions. The upland soils here labeled as "superior loess soils" include principally soils of the Butler, •* Data obtained from the following schedules filed with the State Railway Com - mission : Local. Joint, and Proportional Freight Tar'ff: Grain. Grain Products. Flaxseed: Carloads, Series No. 1800 and 5400, Chicago. Burlington, and Quincy Railroad. Local and Joint Freight Tariff on Livestock: Carloads. Series No. 6200 and 15025, Chicago, Burlington, and Qulncy Railroad. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 /r i _._..- "~ z 3 &gt;&gt; HP 7T HBy^'^n Q&gt; r 9 °* *° ** S "** |1| » « fe « ■ » - » —- ■• ■ i ; * iljl </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska Crete, Hastings, Fillmore, Knox, and Marshall series, and also some related series of minor extent. These soils vary greatly among themselves, and even within the same series, in respect to productivity and value, but in general they may be regarded as "superior" to the "medium" Holdrege and Nuckolls loess soils of southeastern Clay and south - eastern Logan counties. The Carrington soil is a glacial drift soil, likely to be somewhat rolling in topography, and rather more subject to erosion than the loess soils. The Scott soils are claypan patches occupying basins with poor drainage, and are relatively unproductive. The Rosebud soils of Box Butte county range in texture from a rather porous silt loam to a loamy fine sand. The Rosebud silt loam, which includes nearly half the area covered by the series, is regarded as a good dry-farming soil. The Dun - lap soil is a leavier silt loam which is regarded as one of the most productive soils in the county. The silty terrace soils include the Waukesha and Hall series principally. The sandy terrace soils are, in general, less pro - ductive than the silty soils. The bottom soils are highly com - plex in configuration and vary extremely in value, and the good and poor strips are so intermingled that they cannot be indicated in a map of this size. 18 j True sales by warranty deed, 1918-20, and soil types/. — Figure 13 shows that, while all soil types participated! to some degree in the land sales of 1918-20, in at least seven of the ten counties mapped the sandy, rolling, clayey, J or otherwise inferior land sold noticeably faster than the better land in the same county. 14 The farmer who owned a good farm was likely to believe that the land was worth as much to him as it could be to anyone buying it. j The competition among purchasers was so intense that men! paid top prices for inferior acreages. " For a more complete discussion of soil types, see the surveys of these &lt; ounties by the Bureau of Chemistry and Soils, United States Department of Agriculture. 14 To particularize, sales were thickly clustered in the following localities: Clay: In T 5 N, R 7 and 8 W, where the topography is uneven and some of the soil is poor. Fillmore: In T 8 N, R 1 and 2 W. on and around the clavpsn patches (Scott silt loam). 1 Otoe: In T 7 N, R 9 and 10 E (very rolling) : and on the Missouri rivtr bluffs, especially those dissected by deep gulleys. f Saline: Legal descriptions of the land sold in 1918 were not obtained, but in 1919 and 1920 the Carrington glacial drift soils sold faster than the better laid. Seward: In the drift hills &lt;T 9-12 N. II 1 E) and along the breaks between the upland and the valley bottoms of the Big and Little Blue rivers. York: On the breaks between upland and valley bottoms. Merrick: Along the strip of sandy terrace between the S'lver Creek alnd Platte river valleys, known locally so "Poverty Ridge" : ahd along thc sandy riveir bottoms between Central City and Clarks. A </seg>
            <seg id="p056">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 5 I . « f C ~Z. _ _ a a = s '. • •'"•.••* 1-1 , |*&gt; = iu </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska The most conspicuous exception to this tendency was Box Butte county, where the better farming land in the central part of the county sold faster in 1918-20 than the sandy or rough strips around the edges. The development of the dry-farming enterprise in this county undoubtedly accounts for this peculiarity. In Platte and Polk counties, all types of farm land seem to have participated in the 1918-20 boom without noticeable differences in degree. Sales in Logan county were not mapped, but it has already been made evident in Table 7 that the sand-hill grazing land is this county sold more rapidly in 1915-20 than the farming land. Soil types and foreclosures. — In Figure 14 the farms undergoing foreclosure in 1920-33 in the 11 counties studied have been located on a simplified soil map. It is evident that, except in Box Butte county, farms located on in - ferior soil underwent foreclosures more commonly than those on good soil. In comparing Figure 14 with Figure 13 it will be seen that the foreclosures in 1920-33 were most conspicuous in the same areas where sales in 1918-20 had been most numerous; and indeed, often affected the same tracts. However, even in Platte and Polk counties, where 1918-20 sales were quite evenly distributed over all soil types, foreclosures were concentrated on the bluffs bordering the Platte and Elkhorn valleys. In other words, a man who bought good land in 1918-20 stood a somewhat better chance of weathering the 14 years of agricultural depression commencing in 1921 than a man who bought rough, rolling, sandy, or clayey land in these counties. In Box Butte county, on the other hand, foreclosures were most numerous on the better land in the central part of the county. This was the land which figured most in the ex - tensive land boom of 1918-20 in this county. Also, because "of the development of the wheat and potato enterprises, and the resultant increase in the number of farms, farmers invested substantial sums in improvements upon such land, which added to the burden of indebtedness upon it. Soil types and token transfers. — As has been stated, the foreclosures shown in the preceding figure represent only a part of the forced liquidation of farm mortgage debt subsequent to 1920. Besides the foreclosures, there were the assignments of title for debt. Their location is suggested in Figure 15, which shows the location of all token transfers </seg>
            <seg id="p058">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 g% s • t _t - _. HBr^BSS^V'^ — O Ct &lt;0 •"- ? ''"" — &lt; "**T U </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Farm Land Prices in Nebraska C"* gj to ' ■ - **" ft"~TB^^^3 5? — © • • **" 5 |S e a t- . _ -s. _ _ - s •'"'*' •" " i.| 5 J " ' " * 8 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 72 except unencumbered gifts. The figure includes, along with the assignments for debt, many gifts of encumbered property and many trades, which could not be separated from the assignments on the basis of the data in the deed records. If Figures 13, 14, and 15 are compared, it becomes evi - dent that a very considerable part of the land sold in 1918 - 20 subsequently figured in some form of forced liquidation. Detailed comparison also reveals numerous cases where a farmer attempted to increase his holdings in 1918-20 and subsequently lost both his new purchase and his original farm. But foreclosures and token transfers were by no means confined to the land sold during the 1918-20 sales boom. They also occurred on other land. It was not un - common for the same tract to be transferred for debt twice or more during the 14-year period. Double foreclosures also occurred. Transfers to credit corporations, and soil types. — As shown in Figure 16, the farms transferred to banks, loan companies, insurance companies, and other credit corpora - tions during 1920-33, except in Box Butte county, were most frequently those on rough, rolling, sandy, or clayey land. Figures 14-16, taken together, suggest that the poor land was overvalued at the time loans were placed upon it, even more seriously than the good land. OTHER FACTORS AFFECTING FARM LAND PRICE Several other factors influenced Nebraska farm land prices during the period studied. The most important of these may be summarized as follows: (1) Changes in agricultural technique tended to raise farm land prices, because they tended to increase net farm income and because they increased the number of acres which could be farmed by one man. (2) Increases in population tend to raise the value of farm and. (3) The rate of taxation increased during the period rtudied, especially between 1910 and 1930. This increase was a factor, although undoubtedly a very minor one, in the land price decline from 1921 to 1933. (Mfi </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>