<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00016.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00016.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Girls' Industrial School FOR JUVENILE DELINQUENTS AT GENEVA, NEBR. FOR THE BIENNIUM ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1906</title>
               <date value="1906">1906</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EIGHTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Girls' Industrial School FOR JUVENILE DELINQUENTS AT GENEVA, NEBR. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Hon. John H. Mickey Governor BOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BUILDINGS Hon. H. M. Eaton President Hon. A. Galusha Secretary Hon. Peter Mortensen Treasurer Hon. Xorris Brown Attorney General OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES i .1. Mr.Mahnii Superintendent B Ward Matron Lena E. Ward Manager Family M Evelyn Meyer Manager Family "B" Edward Sammis Housekeeper Mrs. Emma Beard Cooking Teacher Martha A. Melntyre Si wing Teacher Oliva C. Owens Laundry Teacher Chester E. Coleman Engineer Fred Johnson Engineer </seg>
            <seg id="p003">REPORT. Geneva, Nebr., Nov. 30, 1906. To His Excellency, John H. Mickey, and Members of the State Board of Public Lands and Buildings: E:h pleasure I submit for your consideration the eighth bi - 1 report of the "Girls' Industrial School," period ending 30, 1906. I heartily thank you for the confidence reposed in me and the support you have given individually and collectively. The harmony which has prevailed all through the biennial has ma - terially assisted me in my management of this work; a work well calculated to tax the strength and test the endurance of any one. On Feb. 15, 1905, the active charge of the institution devolved upon the present management, being the first lady appointed to this position in the state. I felt the grave responsibility E* upon me, and that the strong arm of an all-loving Provi - was necessary to sustain me in the undertaking. I feel duty in this report to acquaint you with the conditions existed then, and the changes that have taken place not in a spirit of censorious criticism, however, but as * facts so you may better understand our condition. IMPROVEMENTS. - all severe measures must meet with more or less discour - irs was no exception, the dilapidated and pov&gt; stricken appearance of the "Home" rendered our laborion forts difficult and discouraging as we tried to "clean up" and lish a home-like appearance ltial to the "girl heart" — faded wall paper, shabby Moor coverings, eurtainless windows, out furniture, and many other things too numerous to mention about the Home interior, while laundry, boiler room. barn and yards correspondingly exhibited si&lt;rns of nt-L The two years past became unquestionably the busiest in the life of the institution. A thorough renovating of the entire building was instigated, and owinpr to our limited appropria - tions for extra labor and improvements, much of the work de - volved upon the inmates. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">I Walls which had been kalsomined for years appealed to me the poorest means of economy in making repairs; a perma - nt and pleasing effect could not be obtained. The artists were ith to undertake the preparation of the walls for enameling, t the "love for the beautiful." so surely planted in the heart every woman, asserted itself in the minds of my "little flock" d they were soon at work washing, scouring, and sandpaper - b;, until every trace of kalsomine was removed, and the walls condition to be permanently repaired, made clean, sanitary Floors received similar attention — paint was removed by much scrubbing and patient labor, the hard wood restored to its original beauty, then waxed and polished, the little iron beds enameled, white draperies hung from the windows, a few beau - tiful pictures to adorn the walls — and the effect was most E'he old hospital was transformed from a bare, comfortless m to a neat, sanitary and comfortable apartment ; the walls ered with sanitos, floor padded and canvas covered, wood •k enameled in white, new beds and bedding furnished. wing room fitted out with shelves, closets and individual stalls for inmates' clothing collecting there for repair. Echoolrooms next received attention — steel ceilings, new elec - al fixtures were put up. walls enameled and appropriate pie - * hung in the different rooms. Girls' dining rooms were next in order — steel ceilings put up. the wooden partition that divided the rooms was removed and iron columns put in place of wooden jrirders. giving the much needed support to the building, and by throwing both rooms we have a spacious, better lighted, and more cheer - ful looking room for a refectory. Kitchen was entirely remodeled, partitions torn down to re - lieve the crowded condition, windows cut in that would admit air and sunlight, a door leading into the yard has proved the greatest convenience, and a large refrigerating room built off of kitchen to accommodate a stationary ice-box. 7x3 ft. — this was no doubt the most necessary and beneficial improvement made about the interior of the Home. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">303 Among the most noticeable improvements on the grounds wh the placing of flower beds at different points, giving a pleasing appearance and being of much help in developing in the girls a love for the beautiful in nature. ffer 1,200 feet of cement walks were laid, leading to laundry. ;room, cellar, barn and boiler room. The old brick walk in t of main building was replaced by 5-foot walk of cement carriage step. The chicken house moved to a better location and the yard 'tidied up" in general. The storeroom has been painted and put in good repair. Eaundry has been fitted out with new cement floor, a window in north wall, ventilator placed in ceiling, new ■team dr ldry stove, window awnings and other necessary furnishing ed to this department. Eew coal house built convenient to kitchen that will accom - ate a car of range coal. ( &gt;ur heating plant was in the poorest possible condition. At times during the winter the building could not be warmed tensive repairs were necessary, and the task seemed a terrible undertaking with limited means at my disposal. By exercising the greatest economy I was able to extend the boiler roon put in place one new 60" dia. 14 ft. long boiler, furnish eld boiler with full set of new tubes, connect both to brick stack with steel breeching, put dampers in each boiler so they can be used independently or together, new steam coil in heater, a new high grade hot water pump to supply boiler and laundry. r steam mains with asbestos, repair steam radiators through - out the building and put a new tin roof on storeroom, boiler roon and laundry. The many other improvements made during the biennial period would be a difficult matter to mention. It has taken a great deal of money to make the necessary repairs that were forced upon me, but the interior of the building is no longer unsightly — instead we have a neat, comfortable and attractive looking home. DISCIPLINE. The discipline of the school has been uniformly good : not :&gt;e has been attempted and this is a matter of jrreat congrat - ulation T have endeavored as f;: to remove all feel- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">LANDOOMMISS1 304 Eof restraint, to add to the comfort and privileges of the i and I find contentment, interest and happiness generally ifested among them. RELIGION. Iigious services are held each Sunday; Sunday school con - ducted in turn by the family managers, and chapel services by pastors of the various churches in Geneva. To those gen - ••n I feel personally indebted; the amount of food they have each life which has come under their influence will never be told, but will assuredly leave its impress and stimulate them II that is good and true. Without it the stimulus for better life, better ideals, and noble living, would to a remarkable ex - be removed. In this institution sectarian training is i. for that would be to violate the very principles of the eoiwrtitution, but distinct religious instruction at stated times liiay be held by any of the ministers. It has ever been m.\ c'eavor to have pure, Christian influence constantly and con - felt. EDUCATION. The educational work in the schoolrooms could not be passed, the thorough interest shown by the girls in their school ■;. the wholesome discipline during the biennial period and zealous efforts of the teachers have placed our educational ..rtnient upon a high basis. For convenience the school is di - 1 into 1 railed "A" and "B" Families. The "B" family, or smaller girls, attend school in the mornings and taught in the industrial departments during the afternoon. ' family consists of larger girls, who receive their train - ta domestic duties in the forenoon and attend school in the afternoon. Four and on.- half hours are devoted to their in - ry day except Saturday The branches taught are as follows: Arithmetic, oral and written; geography, readinur. history, orthography, pi .. penmanship, grammar. Eng - lion. algebra and language. OCCUPATION. der this head I would briefly state that the girls are en- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">305 baking, waiting table, washing, ironing, chamber work, dress - making in fact everything that comes under the head of house - hold duties. KITCHEN. The cooking department is one of the leading features of the ■1. It is most excellently managed by our kind-hearted, rous and never-tiring teacher; the greatest pains have been exhibited by her to instruct each girl in this most necessary and practical science. I record with pride the work accomplished under her supervision : 24,288 loaves of bread, 7,330 rolls or buns, 500 fancy and plain cakes, 9,560 cookies, 4.120 pies, 180 gallons pickles, 2.530 glasses various kinds of jell, 90 quarts rhubarb, 89 quarts pears. To quarts peach. quarts plum 0 quarts canned plums, 50 quarts blackberries, 500 quarts cherries, 57 gallons catsup, 100 quarts chili sauce, 996 ouarts mixed butter uarts tomatoes, 1,718 pounds dairy allons sauer kraut. SEWING ROOM. This department is superintended by a young woman who has grows up and received her education in the Home. Recognizing her ability, her expertness with the needle, and above all absolute worthiness for promotion, I placed her in this posi - tion, paying her a small salary, and am more than gratified with the creditable amount of work accomplished during her time of - In addition to the industry required to bring about satisfactory results. I must credit the patient labor in- t lived in the daily making, mending and darning of the cloth - g for our large family. The number of garments made are as follows: til) Sunday uniforms, consisting of a black skirt and white waist; 50 Sunday undergarments, 40 extra white waists, 160 grey dr&gt; • blue 1 1 24 large I aprons, 200 small kitchen apt petticoats. 4"&gt;0 undergarments, 140 night - 4 sunbonnets, 50 carpet slippers, 60 ironing pads, 500 ironing holders. Mended and repaired -unday uniforms, 4,060 petti 1.104 undergarments, 5,820 hose, 1 gowns, 500 aprons. 2,500 towels and tea-towels hommed, 8,624 miscellaneous articles. LATNDRY. r laundry is also in charge of one of our girls. It is care - economically and well managed ; the work done .in this ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p008">306 departii/ i much credit. The washings are heavy, including oft d employees' clothing, table linen, bedding, and inmates' garment*. The work has solicited great praise from people i ; the institution: besides being one important industries, it is deemed one of the plinary departments of the school, training the girls in habits of care and and fitting them for a a\ t out to set- HOUSEKEEPING. This department is in charge of a lady whose duties ai • net the girls in th&lt; the home, to cultivate in them Ifor neatness, cleanliness and They are t, amber work, to wait table, and make and mend all household During the biennial they have made 120 iheeta, BO pil - r cas&gt; 16 table cloths, 6 dozen hem - tched napkins. 12 f.v I pillows. 6 embroidered pi Mount Mellick. 8 eyelet doilies, 24 small drawn work p rds miscellaneous hemstitching, 5 dr&lt; &lt;rfs. f&gt; table i, 8 wash stand e let, 3 in iwnwork, 1 in color FARM. Our forty acres of lai Eight a ■rn, four in alfalfa, eleven in pasture, six in garden, four in playgrounds, one in orchard, six Home and other buildings. We have increased our small herd of cows so butter-making has be - come an important industry and we are able to make enough butter to supply our table The girls do the milking, make the butter, raise the chickens and help with the gardening. Following is a list of farm and •■n product* for the past two calves, 1,700 270 bu. corn. WO cabbages. 15 bu. onions. 12 bn. car - 100 bu. beets. 110 bu. turnips. 675 bu. potatoes, 15 bu. pars - nips, 56 tons alfalfa, 20 bu. peaches. 150 bu. cherries, 20 bu. grapes. 1,718 ll.s. butter. 10.248 gals. milk. RECREATION AND AMUSEMENTS Egular hours for recreation ar -ide and out-door games ged in as much as possible. Basket ball was something new iris, and this summer pach family was supplied with a let* outfit. On July 4th. 1905, the first piano in possession </seg>
            <seg id="p009">307 to hasten to the general assembly room, and when they reached the door, strains of "The Star Spangled Banner" greeted them. Intense surprise and happiness shone on their faces, and over sixty voices immediately took up the chorus. It was, indeed, a glorious Fourth for the girls, and their piano has helped i 1" pass many a happy hour and pleasant winter evening. K'rof. X. C. Abbott irave us ■ 'icon entertainment - of the Philippine Islands; it » &gt;nly interesting but educational and highly appreciated. On the evening of Decoration Da.\ innate of the scl nvited to hear Nebraska's University boys, at the large tab - ernacle, and it was an event in the lives of the girls that will r be forgotten. During Fair time the same kindness and consideration was .shown by the members of Fillmore County Fair association. privi led so the girls partook of every pleasure on the grounds. It would be hard to find on either occasion better be- I or happier girls. Never in the 1 ihool have as many privileges been extended ; indeed, every liberty consistent with order discipline is permitted the girls, and it has been conduciv the v&lt; i results. Occasionally I am disappointed in - girl, but these disappointments are few and far betw. the privi anted and the confidences reposed are highlv prizt While the strug trs has been a stren I am not discouraged at the result obtained. I firm!; have the brightest, the most intelligent, the heah pnd happiest girls of any institution of a similar kind. DONATIONS. Many donations have been made in the way of reading matter. One that deserves special mention was a library of thirty-six nmes given by the members of the Christian church. To friends who have so generously contributed to our happiness I d thanks and appreciation, not only for the gift itself, but for the kindly interest in the school which prompted the £ri' </seg>
            <seg id="p010">308 In setting forth the needs of the institution, I do so after a careful investigation of the conditions confronting us. For some reasons our school has been long neglected and there are there - fore many conveniences and some absolute necessities which should be supplied. Fn building of a small cottage on the grounds for the farmer, his work is such that he is constant- I required about the place and the wages paid offer little or inducement. Owing to this unfortunate feature I was obliged make six changes in my farm-help in less than a year and a i. ••rn is much needed. Ereenhouse is one of our greatest necessities, having no e to care for our plants from season to season it would in ort time not only pay for itself but would add an important ure to the educational pursuits of our girls. fhe question of di&gt; of the institution be met. The ire constantly overflowing and ( ile aim plaints art- made frequently, ist say the g has been shown by our orth of the school grounds is a ravine or draw and Kthis the sewerage from the school could easily be drained future trouble from this source avoided. Another matter which I trust this legislature will serious - ier is the question of salaries paid ill s in this tution. Very few are qualified or fitted for this line of work and those who Ml ; unity for pleasant and mot be secured nnl able remuneration i- lor such The FAITHFUL TEACHEB in this work must be untiring in her efforts for the nncnt of those girls. Not a moment of the day or night und free from the responsibility resting upon her; the iterate habits contracted either by heredity or environment. that could not be eradicated at home or elsewhere, have fallen &lt;r lot to grapple with. It becomes her duty to find the watnn to overcome them. Her life itself is a close, confining, ntary ex I might add a strenuous one With the O **^ 'HJ-FtlClJIItrlll "1 III" £ lllS I II &lt;1 I v"Jll" I ll&gt;, til' j </seg>
            <seg id="p011">- 309 ©r&amp;Dimctflncc ox cncr^v, impulsive, tnon^iitipss, wiiii ihooqs &amp;nci dispositions that vary with alm&lt;&gt; waking hour, tenai ly adhering to former habits, makes the question of handling. training and educating them a very difficult one. I would respectfully call your attention to the monthl pend offered by the State for their invaluai ices. Another piano oughi to be placed in the school, the trirls have bhown more than ordinary talent for music, and have manifested deep interest in acquiring such knowledge of it as we were 8ble to give them. Our limited opportunities are to be ref ted as I believe music should have a prominent place in this home, not only for the entertainment it furnishes, but for the wholesome influence it e: in the culture and refinement of the mind of the girl. Following is what I believe to be a fair estimate of the a needs of the school for the coming term Salary of superintendent. 2 yean $3,000.00 Salary of matron, 2 years 1.440.00 Salary two family managers, "_' years Employes' w ra 5^40.00 Incidental funds as follows Medical attendance Medicine 300.00 Placing children in homes "&gt;00.00 Music and amusements Telephone rent and toll 200.00 Live stock, carriage and harness Chaplain fees, telegrams. et&lt;- 250.00 Incidental extraordinary 250.00 fuel and lights 4,500.00 Water supply 1.000.00 Board and clothing 8.500.00 Kepair and improvements 5,000.00 Furniture, kitchen ware, dishes, et&lt;- 750.00 Total amount $36,010.00 PER CAPITA. This is a matter of vital importance and I have sndes </seg>
            <seg id="p012">310 - KKPOItT the distribution of funds so you may understand the effort put h to reduce our per capita to the lowest possible minimum. Eighty-six girls have been cared for during the past two years, and though our number is smaller than many other of the state the expenditure per inmate is greater. The amount required for a girl is much more than that of the ■fc boy, the amount of labor to keep a girl's wardrobe in a neat, clean, healthy condition is much greater and results harder to get. Only by careful, conscientious, efficient and pains - taking work on the part of qualified officials and teachers plished. Then on the other hand we cannot employ them on the farm, in the garden only in a very light manner, nor utilize them immon laborers, consequently it resolves itself into a q tion simply of expenditure of money in educating, training, and g them to meet physically and morally the conditions that will greet them when they leave the school. I am sure it is the desire of the board that they be required to do only that which is conducive to the making of good women. I have con - r'dered this proposition from every side, and have used the labor of the girls wherever it was possible to do so, — by placing them in charge of some of the domestic departments and compensat - ing them with smaller wages, I was able to use the balance of this money to make necessary and permanent repairs. It was only by the most careful economy and constant watch - fulness that the necessitous work was carried out in every depart - ment as the present high standard of the school will testify. There will be no deficiencies before the legislature for the past </seg>
            <seg id="p013">311 TABLE NO. 3 — DEFICIENCIES OF FORMER ADMINISTRATIONS. Medicine and incidentals ...$71.16 Fuel and lights 431.78 Repair and improvements 146.58 $649.52 rLE NO. 4 — COST PER CAPITA FOR TOTAL EXPENDITURE AND CURRENT SUPPORT DURING THE BIENNIUM. Salaries and wages -.$9,922.63 Board and clothing . 8,779.69 Fuel and lights 4,026.52 Tahlk ii. 1 Al'PKOPRIATi &gt;R THK UlKNNIUM Available arces 1 s - .J. I 1 — a s. &gt;! $ q i" Officers salaries.. Employees wages 00 •5733.40 1233.61 5MO.00 ;i73.lil Fuel and light Board and cloth- ing 713.W 4.VHJ.0O 5213. M ■1500.00 10999.62 1419.93 Furniture fund School and library Water supply Medicine and med. at'nd., placing cbild'n in homes, etc. etc 750.00 1- 134.31 400.00 ",:i4.31 «K) 1000.(K) 12 1000.00 33.04 13 8080.00 2342.13 2025.31 316.68 .14 Tab; Uepa AND p iii 1 g j P 2 o ! .80|« 400.000$ 115.000$ 5150. 80|t U4S.1W </seg>
            <seg id="p014">312 Furnitur ''n and dim 1 l. v ol and library 3l- r medical attendance, placing children in homes nmsi «k, carriage. harn&lt; 2,025.31 i 1 1 1 is; t rnti* &gt;n ' ' IVr capita $344.15 TABLE NO. 5 — CASH STATEMENT RECEIVED. i. on hand $119.53 Dec. 1, '04, 1900 ft I, L4c $ 76.00 Jan. 24, '05, Stover &amp; Co., 1 cow 26.20 Jan. i 1 calf 5.40 Jan. 2 1050 It) hoys (5 4.40 46.20 May 1. '05. old iron 1.70 May 1. IK, old furniture 22.50 178.00 June 1, 'On, 7 hops 1390 tti 4.70 | 65.33 June i hogs. 430 11-2 19.35 3010 11, f&amp; 4.20 126.42 211.10 Dec. - 15 hogs. 3430 tb (a .04 1-2 $154.35 Jan. 22, '06, 8 hogs. 2070 ft (a 4.90 101.43 Jan. 22, '06, 18 hogs, 2630 It) &lt;g 4.6:. 122.29 Jan. 22, '06, 1 male hog 7.75 Feb. 17. '06. 1 cow. 1240 ft Sri .03 37.20 Aug. 1. '06. 2 hogs, 640 It, u, 5.40 $ 34.56 Aug. 1, '06, 27 1-2 bu. cherries (u 41. 25 .»ug. 1. '06. 5 loads cinders, (n .50 2.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">313 PAID OUT FOR INCIDENTAL EXPENSES. From Not. 30. '04. to June 1. 06 1294.3] From June 1. 'of), to Dec. 1. '05 1 From Dec. 1. "OS, to JmM 1. '06 From June 1. "06, t&lt;&gt; Not. 80, fit Total amount of cash paid out 30, "06, total amount of cash on hand TABLE NO. 6 — MOVEMENT OF POPULATION SINCE OPENING OF SCHOOL JULY 15, 1891. Admitted op to Nov. 30, 1906 Discharged 421 Died 2 Sent to Feeble Minded Institution 1 Sent to Institution at Milford to insane hospital Remaining in school. Not. 30," 1906 TABLE NO. 7 — BY WHAT AUTHORITY COMMITTED itv Court 424 District court Juvenile court Not recorded 14 Total TABLE NO. 8 — CAUSE OF COMMITMENT Larceny Assault '1 Assault 3 Larceny _"• Attempt at murder 1 Attempt at murder 1 Mendicant .Mendicancy Disorderly conduct I Disorderly conduct 49 Xot recorded 1 N'ot recorded 1 Forgery 2 Forgery 2 Prostitution 72 Prostitution ding Incest 2 Stealing :! Incorrigibility Incorrigibility 236 Vagrancy Total * Vagrancy 41 Immorality 5 Immorality 5 Total TABLE NO. 9 — AGE TABLE NO. 9 — AGE WHEN COMMITTED WHEN COMMITTED. Nine years Ten years 11 Six years ... 3 Six years I Xine years Seven years ... Seven years 12 Ten years Eight years 8 121.75 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">314 • i years q years ... recorded 2 in een year. 1 Total LTA.BLK — FROM WHAT COUNTY ADMITTED 12 Kearney 2 Lancaster 1 5 Lonp ;l Lincoln Not recorded 3 .492 Total TABLE NO. 11 — COLOR OF INMATES Colored t Kearney Lancaster Loup Lincoln Knox Madison Merriek Mcl'hersoo N'ance Xemaha Nuckolls Otoe Pierce Polk Pawnee Phelps Platte — Richardson Red Willow Seward Sarpy - Saundere 1 Stanton Sheridan Thayer Valley ...'._ I Washington I Wayne 1 Webster I York 3 ■ .!IL' Dawson ' Dodcc Douplas I Fillmore Frontier Furnss Franklin 4 1 10 2 2 27 12 8 33 14 3 4 10 2 2 27 . 8 33 Greeley Howard Hamilton Johnson ! 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">315 STATISTICAL FORM FOB STATE INSTITUT1 Prepared in accordance with a resolution of the National Con- ference of Charities and Correction, adopted May 15, 1906. Name of Institution — Girls' Industrial School,. POPULATION. M. F. Tl. Number of inmates present at beginning of fiscal year 63 63 Number received during the year ... 16 16 Number discharged or died during the year 16 16 Number at end of the fiscal year 63 63 Daily average attendance (i. e. number of inmates actually present) during the year 60 60 Average number of officers and employes during the year 2 8 10 EXPENDITURES. Current Expenses: — 1. Salaries and wages $2,443.50 2. Clothing 2,000.00 3. Subsistence ... — 1,755.15 4. Ordinary repairs _. 0.00 5. Office, domestic and outdoor expenses 549.52 Total $6,748.17 EXTRAORDINARY EXPENSES 1. New buildings, land, etc. $ 0.00 2. Permanent improvements to existing buildings 4,047.79 Total 4,047.79 Grand total $10,795.96 Notes on Current Expenses : — 1. Salaries and wages should include salaries of trustees or directors, if any. 2. Clothing includes shoes and also materials for clothing and shoes if they are manufactured in the institution. 4. Ordinary repairs include all of those which simply main- tain the buildings in condition without adding to them. Any repairs which are of the nature of additions should be classed with "permanent improvements." </seg>
            <seg id="p018">316 LAN' Kh.POI\i 5. This item includes everything not otherwise provide g. furniture, bedding, laundry suppl -ngineer's supp age. freight, library, etc ■utive head (Superintendent, Warden or other title) — LYDA J. 1CMAH0N, Supt. REPORT OF FIRE. Every tr. ir late misfortune by fire is entirely obliter- ated: practically pairs made were 1 by tli nd the building what work 1 never in its history been in -ondition, and this fact will materially lessen the appropriations asked for during the coming biennial REPAIRS MADE ARE AS FOLLOWS In summing up my work of the past two years I ean recall much that was unpleasant, difficult and disappointing. But from you. rnor, and members of the board. I h r drawn couragement by your intelligent appreciation of the work sought Best of all has been the knowledge that the 8 tided a board whos. i has for its sole ol improvement of the school ; that the purpose for which it wu blished might be better and more fully accomplished. I would also state in this connection, that there never was kindly, a more appreciative feeling toward the state offi - cials than at present exists on the part of the girls. They fully rppreciate the attitude of the governor and board toward them. and we are indeed grateful for all that has been done for their education, training and many privileges accorded. To the teach - ers in the different departments for aiding so nobly to carry out my plans to train the erirls into habits of usefulness and right living is due a large me; ss the school has attained iew roof including tin » &gt;n deck ■ing. including labor, lime and sand 264.-M furniture, etc 1,317.01 'aintinp roof, paperiag, tod painting interior 1 ;!ass 45« lewiriner building for litrhts. 261.6( Total </seg>
            <seg id="p019">317 To Miss Lena Ward, I would especially extend sincere thanks 8nd gratitude for the encouragement and sympathy ever receiv - ed during trying and strenuous periods of my work in this in- The girls too deserve a word of appreciation, with very few ptions they have manifested an interest in the institution and according to their ability co-operated with the officers in their work. I The genial, pleasant spirit of our worthy matron has pervaded e atmosphere of the home interior so universally that no e ve been allowed to gather, no unpleasantries recorded and thing but harmony and good will, will mingle in our memor - &gt; of the past two years. That this condition may continue to ist is my earnest desire. I Trusting that the legislature in its judgment will aid to finan - illy better the conditions mentioned in this report, I remain. With great re rvant, LYI&gt;.\ .1 MeMAHON, Superintendent GENEVA, NEBR., OCT. 28, 1906. tia •]. MeMab eva. Nebraska : KDear Madam: — I submit this my report as phj t' the rls' Industrial School, during your administration. Iation with you. tin- - been 1 and I appn shown by all. durin nnection with the school. The conveniences and sanitary tions of the buildings, have been much improved under -ion. adding greatly to the health and welfare of the Then m but little - and that of a mild adily yieldii Fortunately, tli i malignant di contend with during tl at admin - ration and am glad to be able here ha no deaths, itiy of the inmir E. elusion -will say. I the faithful mance of the matron. .Miss Sude Ward, in her kindly &lt;• tion in my work as physician. 'iirs, </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>