<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00002.00011">
	  <teiHeader>
		    <fileDesc>
			      <titleStmt>
				        <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
				        <author/>
			      </titleStmt>
			      <publicationStmt>
				        <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
				        <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
				        <idno>00002.00011</idno>
				        <availability>
					          <p/>
				        </availability>
				        <date>2007</date>
			      </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE WARDEN OF THE NEBRASKA STATE PENITENTIARY WITH THE REPORTS OF THE OTHER OFFICERS OF THE INSTITUTION. FOR TWO YEARS ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1890. OMAHA, NEB.: HENRY GIBSON, STATE PRINTER 1890.</title>
               <date value="1890">1890</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>

		    </fileDesc>
		    <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-05-29</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item> 
         </change>
			      <change>
				        <date>2007-03-20</date>
				        <respStmt>
					          <name>Thomas J. Wattenbarger</name>
				        </respStmt>
				        <item>Enrichment</item>
			      </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date> 
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name> 
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item> 
         </change>
		    </revisionDesc>
	  </teiHeader>
	  <text>
		    <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">
WARDEN 

i u 

Nebraska State Penitentiary 

» I I II I Ml 

TS OF THE OTHER OFFICERS OF THE 

For Two Years Ending November 30, 1890. 

i M \ 1 1 \ . \ i I : 

\ 1:1 i;lll*OV -I VI I. IIM\ I II," 

IXSTITl'TION. </seg>

            <seg id="p003">
« 

0FFICER8 OF PRISON. 

1"IKINS 


...Physician. 

\HIKK 

W. H.,u 

Chaplain. </seg>

            <seg id="p005">
KEEPERS AND (ilARDS. 

Principal Keeper. 

. ..Day Turnkey. 

Night Turnkey. 

Day Keeper of Cell-House. 

Night Keeper of Cell-House. 

Night Watch. 

Night Watch. 

Keeper of Kitchen. 

. Keeper of Laundry. 

Keeper of Harness Simp. 

Keeper of Cooper Shop A. 

K 

m kki: ... ...... Keeper of Cooper Shop B. 

Keeper of Cooper Shop C. 

Kin 

Keeper of Wood Shop. 

Keeper of Broom Shop. 

M El i ROOT Keeper of Foundry. 

Williams Keeper of East Gate. 

D\\\ SON 

Keeper of East ( late. 

Shotwell Yard Guard 
Iawsom .... Yard ( iuard 

Yard Guard 

\i 

Wall Guard 

\NK 

Wall Guard 

ANODE 

V^. Wall Guard 

w 

Wall (iuard 

\ 

I ) w\ -i &gt;\ 

K \ i ffm \ n , Wall Guard 
Bi 88Et Wall (iuard. 

W Hopkins Usher 

1'KISoN CONTRACT. 

\V. H. Dobgan Manager for Lessee 

DOBGAN 

Clerk 

\ 

Hark. 

Steward 

H 

H. Prcscott. 

Engineer </seg>

            <seg id="p007">
i 

WARDEN'S REPORT. 

Warden's Office, 

Nebraska State Penitentiary. 

Lancaster, Nebraska, November 30, 1890. 
• rable Board of Public Lands and Buildings: 
mkn: — 1 herewith submit to your honorable board 

i 

KN VIA 

t report as warden of the State Penitentiary from 
. 1888. to and including November 30, 1890, accomtlie 
reports of the physician and chaplain, and 
ables of the prisoners confined in this institution 

lima 

i 1 

i 

v 

i 

encement, February, 18C9 

IMPROVEMENTS. 

lave been some very much needed improvements 
n^ which is an extension of the sewer system so 

I 

idequate to the wants of the institution. 

aokestack has been built of sufficient capacity 
tecessary in running the different shops and 

lings properly. 

lilding and cell-house have received a new 
hen and cell house have been ceiled, painted 

¦ lit ion. The main building has been 
. which adds greatly to its appearance 

KXEK \l. REMARKS. 

dthy moral feeling among the prisoners, as 
chaplains report, and a disposition among agreat 

:eml to their religious duties. Mr. Howe, the 
is devoted his time to the moral welfare of the 

i 

I 

men. and t 

o his indefatigable services and kindly words and 
the unfortunate inmates may be attributed a great 
successful discipline we have been enabled to main- 

manner 



i 

1 

.1 

r </seg>

            <seg id="p008">
The health of the convicts lias been excej 

and there has been hut one death among the inmatt 

ease. Dr. J. (). Carter, the physician in char 

amined the men daily, and. as his report will Bhow 

eeodod in keeping the sick list at a lower figure than ei 

fore, and through his untiring watchfulness and prom] 

lias been able to place the penitentiary in the besi 

¦ition that it is possible to have Buch an institute 
trough the liberality of Mr. C. W. Mosher, tfa 

the library lias been increased by 500 choice and readable b 

k 

donated by that gentleman. This makes the presen 

the library 3.000 volumes, which has been rearrang 

catalogue made and one placed in each cell. The library 

great factor in moulding the morals of the inmates and mal 

for the week, while others are compelled t&gt;&gt; remain in d 

i- 

ness, as the light from the lamps jn the cell-house is total! 
inadequate to allow them to either read or eat by it. Such 
system would add greatly to the comfort and convenience ( 
all connected with the institution. 

K would also recommend that the capacity &lt;&gt;f the hospit; 
ubled. This can onlv be done by the addition of anothe 

244 

I hem contented with tln-ir surroundings, and a di 
as Mr. Mosher'fi is of incalculable value. \ 
'he food furnished by the lessees is of &lt;¦ 

and of abundant quantity, well prepared and i 

ent kinds to protect tin- sanitary condition "f tin 

l.'Ki &lt;&gt;MMKM&gt; A I |i &gt;N- 

I would respectfully recommei 

that a complete system of electric 
tution. so that all rooms of each bui] 

be properly lighted. We have i. 
side of the cells but coal-oil. This 

light at any time, and more &gt;.. now b :tricity 

made to furnish a better one. The convii 

use candles in their cells to read with, and on wint« 

ings they must use them to dress ami eai their breakfast 1 

Some convicts are able to make their allowance "f candles</seg> 

            <seg id="p009">
245

IK I'KMTEMIAin . 

the present structure. This would 

n between the beds and add greatly to the 
¦ irk. and would provide for the separation and 

[unts suffering from contagious diseases, 
¦ead of such diseases among the other 

your attention to the unfortunate condition of 
\ icte. 1 am of the opinion that the legislature 

al 

le a remedy for this class of convicts by the pasper 
law allowing of their removal from the peni- 

t 

o the insane asylum. The officers and assistants 
appointed with reference to their qualifications to 

ad '-are for sane criminals and cannot give that 
ttention to the insane that humanity suggests. 

now confined here three men who should be in an 
ler proper treatment. It is not only a wrong to these 

it* creatures to be continually confined in separate 
n i&gt; a wrong to .the sane convicts who are compelled 

r ravin 

parity lias about reached its limit, and before 

ir expires we will be crowded for room. The plan 
wo men in one cell is a pernicious one: the cells 

he- accommodation of one prisoner only; they 
small for two persons. It is an impossibility 

together so that they would be congenial to 
nsequently it creates discord among them 

I would urge upon you the absolute necessity for 
building .&gt;f another cell-house on the east of the 

f sufficient capacity to allow us to place but 
. This will provide ample accommodations for 

dd greatly to the health and comfort of the convicts, 
pectfully recommend that the following amounts be 
ated tor permanent improvements, general repairs 
he maintenance of the penitentiary for the two year3 
• ing April 1. 1891, and ending March 3J. 1893. 

I 

ippropn 
Ukd for t 

Cotninen 

y 

lymenl i &gt;f lessees for the maintenance of prisoners in </seg>

            <seg id="p010">
i 

accordance with an act approved February 26. 1K7V. and 
approved March 2, 1887, as follows: 

Biom April 1. ls91. to March 81, 189-2, ai 4&lt;i cents 
¦ach per diem I 59,861 
rom April 1. 18W, to March SI, 1898. at 40 cents 

each per diem . .... 83,050 &lt; 

Total. 

i-2i.au 

(JBXERAI. REPAIRS. IMPROVEMENTS, ET&lt; 

KO th&lt;&gt; ladies of the Wo 
i I return my heartfelt tl 

B shown at all time;- to the unfortunat 
ution, and their kind remembrano 

and isolated life from the outside world by the don 
flowers and excellent reading matter. 

¦'o Dr. Carter and the Bev. Mr. Howe 1 return thanks f&lt; 
hie assistance thi^y ha\ e rendered me in the manag 

and care of the inmates, and to their help in their difl 

246 
Repairing &amp;nu maintaining electric l»!l system 
Telephonic and speaking lube lines 

Telephone in warden's oflRce 

'« 

Delivering prisoners on court i»rd 

Stationery and printing 

Approprial ion i &gt;r f&lt; ¦ 
Photographing &lt;¦ &gt;w\ icts 

General repairs 

Total. 

Before closing n 

to tli«' ( lhautauqua 1 

for the noble work 1 ' 

my charge. It is as ton is 

tion h.is awakened among 

ment their work li.i- ai 

better tone and compo ;it 

have been under their instrm </seg>

            <seg id="p011">
247 

VTATE PEXITEXTIARY 

I 

in greatly indebted for the present high sanitary 
the iirison. 

i 

ntlemen associated with me in the capacity of 
keepers have at all times perrormed their duties 
satisfactory manner, and it gives me great pleas- 

.» 

hlv 

thus publicly to thank them for their efficient 

it 

rnor.lnliii If. Thayer I am under many obligaausel 
and advice in the discharge of my duties 

V 

rdfii 

ntlemen, in closing allow me to thank you for 
assistance rendered me at all times. 

And. ec 


Respectfully, 

Dan Hopkins, Warden. </seg>

            <seg id="p012">
248 

LAND COMMISSIONER 

KKI'OIM 

Hun. Dan Hopkins, Warden Nebraska State Penitenti 

I IV 

I Sir: — I have the honor t&lt;&gt; herewith submit my n 
sick and wounded of the Nebraska State Penitent 
two years ending November .SO. 18W. 

por 

ir 

I 


3 

I Permit me to render my sincere thanks for the i 
tment I have universally received at the bands 
and subordinate officers. 

in 

f v 

n 

PHYSICIANS BIENNIAL REl'oKT 

Respectfully 

.1. O. CABTBR, Prison Pliv 

From December 1. 1888, to November SO, 1889, we 

deaths: from December 1, 1889, to November 30, 18! 

wrere four deaths, only one of which was from sick 

tabulated statement below will show, 

* 

Remittent fever . 

Intermittent fever. 

Typho-malarial fever 
Rheumatism. 

tills 
ipelas. 

Pneumonia 

Diarrho-a and dysenten . 

Lacerated and cunt us.-, t wounds ] 

tumption. . 
t disease . . 

Softening of brain 

Gonorrhtea 

Insanity.... 

»"Ppe 
dental deatli from burning 

Total 


i 

t 

h 

t 

'P 

i </seg>

            <seg id="p013">
IAPLAIN'8 REPORT. 

km-. Warden Nebraska State Penitentiary: 
Limit y with my duty as chaplain of the Ne- 

t 

ate Penitentiary I hereby submit to you my biennial 

condition and advancement of convicts 

barge for the last two years ending November 30, 

ilso append some suggestions, having in view the best 

society as well as the convicts (as seen from my 
if observation), the giving expression of which I 
.vill no! deem me presumptuous, as 1 am conscious 

sympathy with and full acquiescence in all moves and 
•s the objed of which is reform. 

irell known, the conditions under which we labor are 
he m 1-1 favorable and yet the improvement (morally) is 

perceptible, in proof of which I draw your attention 
mber who have joined the several classes of moral 

The ('huutauqua Literary and Scientific Circle, 
fifty members, evince a more than ordinary in- 

heir work, and the Christian Brotherhood, which has 
rship of fifty, whose sincerity is beyond question. I 

in my personal intercourse with the convicts diamistakable 
evidence of the awakening of moral 

unl religious thought 

mdition, I believe, is largely due to the different 

mployed to direct the mind of the convict 

moral agen 

&gt;in Ins present unenviable situation, inspiring him with 

!»¦ by bringing him to realize that the future isin possession 

happiness and Buccess which will be delivered to him 

on proper and well-directed effort: and, sir. we arenotoblivi- 

f The fact that to you we owe much for the support you 

lave given to all efforts tending to the amelioration of the 

nvicfs condition. We are greatly indebted to the many 

side ladies and gentlemen who have given voluntary aid 

,'f a high order. Especially are we under obligations to mem- 

249 </seg>

            <seg id="p014">
bers of the Chautauqua. Literary and Scientific ( 
Woman's Christian Temperance Union, who ha\» 

1 

n 

rend 

service which are of inestimable value to the conv 

KM 

prison. 

We make no attempt at praise or laudation in - 

1 

Mrs. Angie F. Newman and Miss Frances M. KHiilc 

11 

have so often spoken words of comfort ami advi&lt; 

deeds of kindness to the convicts of this prison 

alone in the objects of their solicitude and car 

their seal and untiring efforts in In-half of the fa 

their zeal and untiring efforts in behalf of the fal 

stricken they have gained a place among the w 

stricken they have gained a place among tli 

Wl 

reformers second to none. Their influi ni 

reformer! second to none. Their influi nee and \ 
stimated by human measurement. 
It is with feelings of sadness and regrei tha 

Btimated by human measurement. 
t is witli feelings of sadness and regret i 

the death 'it' the late 1 &gt;r. Turner. His life was dei 

the deatli of the late I &gt;r. Turner. His life v. 

cause of his fellow-men, especially the com i 

cause of his fellow-men, especiallv the con a i 

labored most successfully, tidings 

many an anguish-bound sou ned within , 

In the removal of Dr. Turner tin 

In the removal of l&gt;r. Turner the pri* 
i teacher, a counselor and .1 friend. 
Services ba&gt; e been regu 
'I by a prison choir thai 

lose a teacher, a 
Services ha\ 

listed by a prison ch 

preeiative character. 
Permit me to agai 

which is entirely inadeq 

which is entirely inadeq 

t 

? specially as to room. We - 

? specially as to room. W 

chapel well furnished and I 

chapel well furnished an 

us that surroundings have p 

us that surroundings ha\ 

and thoughts 

and thoughts. 
If there is a place on earl b 
ich as to produce a bappj and contented t'r; 

If there is a place on 

that place is the one in wind) we assemb 

the author of our beiim, the 1 

hoMer .it our uestinv. 1 \v 

also like to call your attention to an 

matter wl 

mature consideration I find to be of vital importan 

'•class distinction among the convicts'" I will not 

at 

a lengthy explanation a* to what is meant by "cIj 

t 

tion among convicts." as it i- a subject well und&lt; 

i 

250 </seg>

            <seg id="p015">
r 

i Mi the outside parents and guardians em- 

I 

means to prevent and guard against evil 
gnixing the tact that association moulds, 
tines the character, so here the same cause 
effect. 

linary comprehension can well understand 
the young man who has commited his first 

i 

t 

ant association with the hardened and aban¦ill 
inevitably lead to the worst possible result. 
it. we should, if possible, turn out a better 

limiai w 

rstand 

\ 

L'nder our present system we are al 

k 

¦ at a worse man. 

&lt; of society demand a change of our present 
fur' recommend that this important matter 

i 

r 

the proper authorities, that they may devise 
i\ which this crying evil may he regulated 

i 

lied 

n~ should be reformatory the best inter 
demonstrate. 

v 

a very prevalent opinion among a certain 
ivicted man or woman is beyond the pale of 
u they are incapable of reform, that they 

or sentiments in harmony with the rest of 
\ are monsters in human form, and that 

discovered through the agency of the courts. 
I class let me say I stand ready to refute 

ical, wicked in conception and most 

tl 

ct 

when it was conceived to be the proper and 

A 

i 

ealing with criminals to heap upon them all 
ad tortures known to depraved men, thereby 

ir 

he indi^niti 

¦elling them 
committed i 

. as was believed, to make reparation for the 
ind also deter them from the commission of 

oother offenst 
f the system 

Time and experience has proven the fallacy 
All IV^ll II 11 Id C I , UllvtT \^ \J LA 11 1/ X Iv* 

251 </seg>

            <seg id="p016">
where severity lias been the practice crime ha 

daring and frequent 

We may punish and torture the poor crime- b 

in 

until his cries and lamentation-* cause angels 

devils t-&gt; cringe, arid what is the result:- You ha\ 

to madness, you have destroyed every good an 

1 11 

pulse he may hare possessed, you have &lt; 1 r i • • &gt; 1 

fountain of his soul, his whole being Ims becon 

t 

with but one thought, one desire- revenge. 

Tins 

consequence -the legitimate offspring of fa 

h 

We an- must happv 

practiced in prison discipline and the manag 

ire in the best regulated rommunitii 

monuments of disgrace and mis ion i 

if a cruel and unenlightened 

i Mic of the c 1 1 i • • t' agem 

greatly in need rs a prisoi 

many south are in \\i\&gt; respi 

;i Dumber of convi&lt; 

ignorance and \ ice are insep 

duty of the state aa a pi 

duty of the state as 

.i&gt; will place within the 

.is will place within tin' 

in it- limits the opportunii 

in its limits the opportui 

mentary education ;it leasi . 
I would like to suggest the propi ¦ 

I 

prison entirely separate from the male. \ 

prison entirely separate from the ma 

ated a female prisoner i- confined in a 

ated a female prisoner 

tiri'-d in 

limits, there \&lt;&gt; remain subjeci to all tl 

limits, there to remain subii 

&lt; 

the want of exercise and sunshine wi 

the want of exercise and Bunshine will eng 
In conclusion, permit me t&lt;&gt; tender tnj sinci 

In conclusion, permit me to tinder tnj sinci nks t 

k- foi 

the courteous treat men 1 1 have received at 

the courteous treatment 1 have received ai your ham 

RespeetfuJl} . 
I , \\ t i i ( ) \\ |-' ( 1 1 1 ) I 

252 </seg>

            <seg id="p017">
TABLE A. 

iriHoners received into and discharged and 
¦ntiary in each year from its establishment. 

mil including November :». 1S90: 

Z- v. 


•i i 

r / 








1 

I I 

I 

I 

253 


*= 

- ----- 1 X / . £ - s </seg>

            <seg id="p018">
SCHEDULE A 

Showing Prison. ts Confined, etc., from H 

tentiary to November 30. 1888 

TABI.K N&lt;&gt;. l 

COUXTIE 

A HF.KK 

• NV 

ED VNI) M MIU 


A.dd ins. 

Antelope.. 
Box Butt.- 
Brown.. 


E 

Clieyomif. 
Cass. . . . 

B 

Cuming. 
Custer.. 

Cherry. 

Daw son. 



Dixon. . . 
Dakota. 

1 

Fillmore. 
Franklin. 
Furnas. . 
Frontier 

ie 

a 

254 </seg>

            <seg id="p019">
&gt;TATE PENITENTIARY. 

255 


Ha 

1 

1 

43 

182 

12 

10 

IT 

7 

64 

1 

18 

!5 

5 

3 

47 

' 

S 


5 

18 

24 

N 

S 

s 

Si 

M. 

otanton 
•oheridai 

•&gt; 


»*Vallej 

.' JVashimrton </seg>

            <seg id="p020">
Wayne. 
Webster 
Wheeler 

Total 

TABLE Ni &gt;. J 

I'IKKKKKN I I HIMES \ ' 

M 


R, attem 
inn 

'«• 


Highway robbery 

Kig burglar tools in | 
1 voting 

Biling a mare 
reenv . 

i 


I^arceny from jierson 


Obtaining money under false pretens 


256 




my 
Burglary.. 
Jan and 
Bribery. 
Burglary and 

Eng h;i\ 
prfeii nil; 
ig and -t 
lililii; hoi 
-stealing 

E roving timbei 
ezzlement.. 
&gt; personation. 
©I* V 

Grainl larceny. 
Gran 1 larceny, accessor} 

Horse-stealing 


I..M1KMIAKV.</seg>
 
            <seg id="p021">
257 

meter false pretense 
.... 
• ¦ 

•&gt; 

:; 

i 


¦ _ m &gt;erty. 
rty 

\ 

m 

1 rument. 
¦ 

t:l Ml - \&gt; \ 1 Ns I PKKSOX. 

(RIMES \t MNs l PEBS 
nier 
¦ ¦ . rapt? 

: 

r 

with intent to roll 
•¦"iiiiniT tVliiiM . 
•ii&lt; I. 

8 

3 

6 

1 

¦&gt; 

. 

•5 

•&gt; 

1 

i 

E 

M 

\ 

5 

-'7 

¦i- 

' i nj( 


_ to kill 

15 

booting to wound 

7 

(eduction, 
hem. 

1 

1 </seg>

            <seg id="p022">
TABLE X(&gt; 
PERIOD &lt;&gt;K SENT 

i IK 

SEN IKMK 

Iy days 
lMlltllS 
t month 
months 
vear 

• hie year, one month 

¦ year, two months 
vear. three month 

&lt; hie year, four minitli- 

Kear. five inont 
ear. six montl 

&lt; hie vear 

¦year, ten 
\ . ars 

Two vear 

Three years 
Three j &gt;;n&gt; 
Four \ far- 

¦ yea rh, si x 
vears 

, Ten yean 
Eleven years 
Twelve years 
Thirteen years 
Fifteen years. 
Twenty years 
Twenty-one years 
Twentv-foiir vears 

258 </seg>

            <seg id="p023">
&lt; &gt;iif dav 

¦ years, si \ m&lt; ml 
ears 

Seven yean 
Kitflit years 
Nine voar&gt; 


i 

1 



M'.l.K X&lt; i 1 

A I h i\ BEKc &gt;KK i u\\ n TK)N 

•2 

- 

x 

1 

¦3 

1 

1 

1 

I 

6 

8 

8 

l 

7 

2 

: 

1 

¦2 

1 

1 

3 

u 

1 

9 

B 


: 

i n 

&gt;k 


259 

V 



¦ dealer, 
rainer. . 
ist 

¦-&gt; </seg>

            <seg id="p024">
C'andymaker. 
( 'alsominer 

Collector. 

Ketmakct 
;ist. 

K'htsmai 
st 

B maker 
tive. 

Engineer 
Fireman. 

Kdrymai 
er 

Florist 

Gardner 
Horseman 

Ressmakeji 
er. 

Harter 

rsekeeper 
tier 

Hotel- keeper. 

Implement dealer 
Inm puddler. 

Jeweler. 

Junkman. 
Lather.. 

Laundryman 
Laborer 

Lawver 

260 </seg>

            <seg id="p025">
1 

4 

i 

11 

4 

• 

\ 

8 

: 

¦V 

1 

1 

1 

m 

: 

h 

•2 

49 

6 

8 

1-2 

8 

•&gt; 

1 


I 

k- 

I 


261 



II 

Kc moulder 
m-keeper 
ol-teacher </seg>

            <seg id="p026">
Sheetiron- makei 

Krsmith 
t 

Teamster. 
Teacher 
Tinsmith 
graph 

VV'a^onmakei 
Woodturner. 

Total 

\l:i.K \i &gt; 

41 . K \ I II MK 

Fourteen years 
Fifteen years 
Sixteen yen is 
Seventeen yean 
Eighteen years 
Nineteen years 
Twenty years 

262 </seg>

            <seg id="p027">
St«&gt;ne&lt;-utter. 

Kn&lt;i machine a^cnl 
ulator. 
ler . 

¦e driver 
in titter.. 

tjraph i 
ilsterei 
inarv 
.er 

er. 


w 

in- veai 

ntv-twu \t j ;ir^ 

Im-c \ 

ii- vi -a 


ve vea 


\ \ ears 

ren \ ears 

i^clii \ ears 

• Illllf \i\trs 


i 

wo year 

ree year* 

r year 

vears 

ven vears 

\ ears 

\ eai 

ir 

.11 


¦ ears 
» ears 

Kour 3 
ive yean 

IV 

t \ Illlli x t;ii 


•&gt; 

: 

n 

; 

5 

;¦: 

0 

:: 

1 

263 </seg>

            <seg id="p028">
264 

I. ANIi COMMISSIONER'S KKPmI 

Sixty years 

I -one years 
t wo years 
¦five years 
-six \ ears 
-seven vea 

Louisiana. 
•uri 
Mississippi. 
Maryland 

Massachusetts 

Michigan. 
Minnesota. 
New York 

K Hampshire 
iska. 

Indian Ten 
Kentucky 
K.m-as. 


ta 


us 
100 


Ifi 

1 

is 

8 

•21 

4 

31 

•) 

I ' IKKK.NK KS. 

¦ 

1 


8 

1 

33 

8 

74 

* 


¦&gt; 

i 

\ 

: 

: 

•&gt; 


i </seg>

            <seg id="p029">
265 </seg>

            <seg id="p030">
266 



s 


1 

¦ zerland 
land. . . 

Sweden 

Total 

i 

FABLE X&lt; 

IAI. KKI.A I II 1X8 \ 1 COXVICTIi 

t 

Ibcr wlio can read and wr 
ber who can read only 
ber who can neither read 

t. 

or write 

Total 

li 

I'ABI.K \&lt; ». 9 
EDUCATH iN 

Number of convicts, single 

Number &lt;&gt;f com i«t&gt;. married 

Total. . 

Number of convicts having fathei 

Number of convicts having mothe 

Number of convicts having both. 

Number of com irt^ having n&lt; 

Total 

Number of colored convicts 

Number of Indians 

Number of females 

fABLl 

Temperate 

Intemperate 

Moderate 

Total </seg>

            <seg id="p031">
VBLE \&lt;&gt;. in 

KLKill «\ 

1 

•« 

1 

iiii 

i 

&gt; 

¦) 

N 

j 

6 

78 


1 

1 

4.) 

i 

¦&gt; 

9 </seg>

            <seg id="p032">
TABLK N&lt; 

11 

hlM'OSITIOX c^ 

N\ HI 

Convicts received to November :«&gt; 


harged on good time 

Discharged on full tim. 

ur 

Discharged on habeas corpus 

Pardoned. 

Sentence reduced by supreme ( 

Died natural deat hs 


Committed suicidt 

Reoapturt-d 

Remanded for new t 

Sentence comm 

Convicts in penitent ia n I &gt;ei i 

Total 

268 


Discharged by order of suprenu 

Escaped </seg>

            <seg id="p033">
269 

\IK PENITENTIARY. 

S&lt; HHDILH B, 

onfined, etc., from December, 1888. to 
November 30, 1890. 

TABLE NO. 1. 

KS UMKKK ioNVHTKH AND M.MBKK. 

1K-C. 1, IXM- I. 

IMS, to INK*, to 
Nov.Jl, Vmiii. 
1SHH. MM. 

5 1 

3 

1 

2 2 


5 3 

a 4 

i 

i 

i 

6 3 

1 1 

4 

2 1 

1 1 

8 4 

6 

1 


35 43 


1 

z 

7 5 


5 


2 7 

6 S 

E 

: 


270 

i.wn roMMisHiovKK's rri&gt;oi 


Ku I'llUS. . 

m </seg>

            <seg id="p034">
Howard.. 
Hamilton 
Harlan 

Hitchcock 
Jefferson 
Johnson 

Kearney 
Keith. 

L i ,' i ¦ i 

Lincoln 

M 

¦ 

H: :: 

Eanlson 
Willow 

Sheridan 
Sherman. 
Beward 

sr 

Stanton 



!i 

200 194</seg>
 
            <seg id="p035">
IAHLK NO. 2. 

MES \NI' NTMHKR OK EACH Al 

\ 

AIXST 

PROPERTY. 

Dec. I, Dec. 1, 

I**, to iw», to 

Nov.30,Nov.», 

18H9. 1HHH. 

2 4 

54 34 

- 

anil larceny i 

e-stealing . 2 

&gt;ezzlement 1 

20 SI 

h 

iling 2 

42 4a 

u 

¦in person 8 8 

lilroad 2 

none} under false pretense 3 6 

ropertj under false pretense 

1 

11 6 

\ ing stolen g I-. 1 2 

Selling mortgaged property 5 8- 

Train robber} 2 

Uttering forged instrument 1 1 

Having burglars* tools in possession 2 

Horse-stealing 17 2J&gt; 

Highway robbery 2 

CRIMES A'.AINST PERSON. 

AMault with intent to murder 6 7 

Assault with intent to rape 2 2 

271 </seg>

            <seg id="p036">
Kult vrith intent t&lt;&gt; rob... 
ult with intent to wound 
ult.... 

Bigamy 
Incest 

M i in I &lt; t 

4 

i 

Total 

\Hl.k X&lt; 

i i 

-ENTEXi I 

One year 
year 

I year, three month 
year, foui nionth&gt; 
year, six months 
year eight month 
years 

¦years, six months 
years, eleven mont I 
! years . 

Thn-o years, --ix months 
Three years, nine montl 
Four years 

Five years 
Six years 
Beven year 
Eitflit year; 
Nine vears 

272 


Slaughter 
it. second ilejjjn 

1 1 1 • &gt; 1 1 T 1 
Six rnooths 
Eleven moi 


8 1 

1 

¦1 

1 

¦2 1 

I 

1 

1 

.t 

¦200 194 </seg>

            <seg id="p037">
TABLK NO. 4. 

X I TIME OF SENTENCE. 

Uac. i. ix 

!*&lt;8, to IS9B, to 
Not .30, Not »», 

W. raw. 

:h l 

:: a 

. . s t", 

irs . 8 9 

s 9 

7 10 

7 10 

6 11 

6 11 

ears . 13 10 

13 10 

ir- 13 10 

13 10 

ii 

10 12 

10 12 

ir- . . . 12 12 

12 12 

F8 12 11 

12 11 

re. . 16 8 

16 8 

• 7 7 

a 

i 

,u - .14 6 

14 6 

nty-nine years 6 7 

6 7 

1 1 

; 

6 9 

6 9 

ii &gt;. 8 4 

S 4 

Thirl 5 -1 wi ¦ j ears. 10 4 

10 4 

,\ 

Thirty tlm-c \ car- 4 6 

4 6 

Thirty-four years 2 8 

2 S 

i 

% e 

/Thirty-five j ears 3 2 

3 2 

Thirty-six years 2 4 


¦ 

Thirtv-seven veara 6 4 

273 </seg>

            <seg id="p038">
Ky eight years 
y nine years 
years 

Forty -one yeara 
Forty-two years 
Forty-three years 
Forty -four years. 
Forty-five years 
Forty-eight \ t-ar&gt; 
Forty-nine years 
Fifty vears 

Fit'ty-t wo yearn 
Fifty-three \ eiirs 
Fift \ ton r years 
FiH \ -five year* 
Kift) -seven yea i - 
Fifty-eight years 
8ixty-two years 
Sixty-rive years 
Six t\ -six years 

Total 

\r.i 

OC( I PA1 I"N KKI 

Bit, insurance 
ioneer 


1 

Blacksmith 

Barber 

5 4 

Kimaker. 
ender . . 
her . 

1 

8 

274 </seg>

            <seg id="p039">
I ATK PENITENTIARY 

275 

i i 

! 

: 

: ; 

4 S 

&gt; 

!i 

i 

i 

i 

i 


: ; 

:&gt;. ¦&gt; 

i '1 

A •&gt; 

4 1 

\ 



i 


. . 


Merchant 

i 

ttachini 

2 8 </seg>

            <seg id="p040">
Musician 

No occupation 
Physician 

Painter 
Plasterer 
Print,,'. 

Plumber 
Peddler. 
Polisher 

Railroader 
S ilesinan. 

S naker 

Sailor 

Stonecutter. 

School teacher 
Stayedrivi'i . . 

Stewnfitter. 
Servant 

Shoe varnisher 
Teamster 

Telegraph operator 
Tailor.. 

Safemaker 
Upholsterer 

Watchman 

Total 

•JIM i l'.U 

276 </seg>

            <seg id="p041">
TABLE No. 6. 

II. A' ¦ OF BIRTH OK (( 

\&lt; E &lt;&gt;K BIRTH OK CONVICTS. 

IMSsi to 188W, to 
Nov. no. Sot. 3D, 

IM 1990. 

1 

.... 

;• 

. 

rnia 
lumbia 

Columbia 

; : 

na 

20 17 
19 iO 

.... 

kan- 

•&gt; 


6 8 

K 

.... 

1 

ma 

ana 
.I. 

13 10 
2 

ssippi .... 

: : 
2 

liassachussettfl 

Ma. 

i 

5 6 

Mini. 

3 5 

9 9 

7 7 

... 

N\w Jersey, 
urolina 

N\w 

1 4 

1 I 

\'-\ ada 

N. 

1 

17 17 

&gt; 

Pennsylvania. ¦ 

Pennsylvania 
Rhode Island 

Rhode Island. 

&gt;(iiith ( ';irnlin:i 

i : 

Eennessee 
exas. 

Vermont 

a i 

irifiina 


277 </seg>

            <seg id="p042">
278 

LAND COMMISSION!?!- 

REPOR'I 

Wisconsin. 

West Virginia. . 
Indian Territory 

FOKKIONE1 

Bavaria.. 
Bohemia. 
Brazil 

Ocean-born 
Prussia 

Polan.l 

Switzerland. 
Scotland.. 

Sweden 
Wales.. 


TABLE S'( 

SOCIAL RBI.A I 

\ I 

December 1, 1888. t&lt;i N. 

"Number of convicts, single 
Number of convicts, manic 


Canada 
Denmark. 
Fraii' 

&lt; Jermaiiv 
M </seg>

            <seg id="p043">
ts having father only 28 

Ts having mother only 39 

iving both 82 

having neither 56 

f colored convicts 21 

f In&lt;lian&gt; 

1 

females 8 

&gt;ecember 1. 1889, to November 80, 1890. 

I 

nvicts, Kingle 149 

&gt;nvicts, married 45 

194 

ii 

sonvicta having father only '37 

«-r of convicts having mother only 33 

F 

r of convicts having both ' »*8 

r of convicts having neither 56 

f colored convicts ... .... . . 7 

Indians 0 

r 

females . ... 8 

TABLE NO. 8. 

HABITS. 

?ecember 1. Ihss. to November 30. 1889. 

101 

W 

i 

1 

(ecember 1, 1«h«.(. to November 30, 1890. 

I 

rat 


[ntemperat 
rate </seg>

            <seg id="p044">
279 

TABLE NO. 9 

K December 1, 1888, to November 30, 188! 
vv who can read ami write 

¦ber who «-a 1 1 read onh 
ber wild can neither r 

¦ber who cai 
ber win • cai 

M'.l 


1 1. -.-, mbei 1 

Number win i ack 

NimiluT wh&lt; 

[)« 

i 


Number v 

I" A 1 : 1 

\dventist 
Baptist 

Catholic 

Christian 

an! 

Episcopal 

Bum Reform* 
cran . 

llethoilist 

280 </seg>

            <seg id="p045">
KIM i \ I |(&gt;N 

¦ t)eceinl»er 1. 1889. to N 
ber vvlin can read and « 


; : 

; 

i 

i 

88 T'.t 
'.'(HI 194 

fABLE Mi. 12 

lll'iS OF CONVICTS. 
December 1. 1888.. 


inber 1. 1888. to November 30 


1887 

; 

ml returned 

n 

138 

9 

supreme court 

1 

a 

ii \ November 30. 1889 ... 379 

540 540 

iiv December 1, 1889 879 

ember 1, 1SS9 to November 30, 

194 

Vi 

in 1S88) 1 

i time . 158 

Remanded for new trial ... ... 8 

Dtence commuted 14 

Pardoned. - 8 

Died . . 4 

Convicts in penitentiary November 30, 1890. 887 

lota] 674 674 

281 </seg>

            <seg id="p046">
SCHEIMLE C, 

Showing Number of Convict*, Where Fran, e 

tc., i 

Penitentiarv November 80. 1890 

TABLE X&lt;». 1 

COl'NTIES WHERE 

&gt;NVICTEP Wl&gt; NTMKKR 

KRi IX 

Z2. 

Box Butte 
Brown 

B 

Blaine 

Cheyenne 

Cumin«. 

sr 

sr 

Dou-las. 
Dixon . 

Daw son 
Dodge. . . 

8 

&gt; 

l 

&gt; 

282 </seg>

            <seg id="p047">
3 

1 


udet 


Sheridai 


283 </seg>

            <seg id="p048">
Scott's Bluffs. 
Sherman 

Thajer 
Webster 

Kington 
ler.. 


Total 

TABLK No. 

&gt; 

RIMES AGAINST 1' 

i;i ii'KH i i 


Burglary 

Burglary and larceny 
&lt; 'iittle-stealing 

Embezzlement 
Forgery 

¦d larceny 
way rubl&gt;cr\ 
e-stealiiiK 

Hog-stealing 
Larceny 

Obstructing highway 
&lt; obstructing railroad 

Kning money under false pi 
¦rv 

Receiving stolen goods 

Selling mortgaged property 
Train robbery 

I'ttering forged instrument 

284 </seg>

            <seg id="p049">
MES AGAINST THE PERSON. 

\ 


\ 

H 

\ 

v harm 

\! 

leeree 


I 

;: 

th intent to kill 

\v 

ta 


FABLE NO 8. 

I'KKIoI) OK SENTENCE. 

• 

wo im nith-i 

inontlis 

tonths 

•&gt; 


\ 

tl 

lonth- 

&gt;v 

1 

\ ni.iiitl 

1 

I! 

1 

: 

\ II 

1 

i\ yeai 

285 </seg>

            <seg id="p050">
Seven years 
Eight years 
Nine years 
Ten years 
Eleven yean 
Twelve years 
Thirteen years 
Fourteen year: 
Kit teen years 
Twentv years 

Bty-four &gt; ean 
ty-five \ ear 
\ vears 

Kcrty-niiK 

Tola 

lAt: 

AT ION A 

¦ ioneer 
r 

Blacksmith 
Bookkeeper 
Baker 

Bartender 
Butcher 
Brewer 

I 

Bricklayer 
Brickmak'T 
Busdriver 
Broommaker 

Builder and contractor 

286 </seg>

            <seg id="p051">
287 </seg>

            <seg id="p052">
Merchant 
Machinist 
Musician 
Moulder 
None. . . . 

Plumber 
Painter 

Paper-hanger 
Peddler 

Printer 

Plasterer. 
Railroader 
Shoemakei 


Stonecuti 

Sheet iron worki 
Shoevarnisl 

Total. 

288 
Safemaker 
Teamstei 
Telegraph i &gt;pei 
Tinsmith 

E:o roller 
man. </seg>

            <seg id="p053">
289 </seg>

            <seg id="p054">
West Virginia. 
Wisconsin . 

Washington, I). C 
TVxas 

KOKKIGN Hi 

£T 

H.,,,.,,,, 
Havana 
Canada 

Denmark 

&lt; iennaiiy 

s 

( &gt;cian born 
Poland.... 

Russia 

Sweeden 

Switzerland 
Scotlaud • • 


Total 

290 </seg>

            <seg id="p055">
W'.I.K N&lt; &gt;. 6. 

I CONVICTION 

0 

•&gt; 

! 

: 

28 

I 

17 

\: 

&lt; 

¦¦&gt; 

3 

; 

4 

•i 

H 

•' 

i 

vear 

ii 

\ vears 

291 </seg>

            <seg id="p056">
Forty-eight years 
Forty-nine years 
Fifty years 

) 

Fifty-two years 
Fifty-three years 
Fifty-four years 
Fifty-five years 
Fifty-seven years 
Fifty-eight years 
Fifty-nine years 
Sixty yean 

E-five years 
-six years 
ity-two vea i 

Total 

r A HI 

\ 

Number of convict 

Number of convicts married 

Total 

Number of convicts having; fat S 

Number of convicts having in 

.tli. 

Number of convicts having both 
Number of convicts having neitl 

n 

Total 

Number of colored convict 
Number of females . 

Number of Indians. 

292 </seg>

            <seg id="p057">
IAHLK NO. 8. 

H.UMTn. 

s 

59 

I 


TABLE No. 9. 

EDUCATION. 

t who can n-a'l and write 365 

an read only 

99 

neither read or write 

¦1-1 

TAP.LK NO. 10. 

KKLIGION. 

¦1 

IT 


•' 

s 

1 

•&gt; 

: 



Moi 


Presb\ teriai 

16 

; 

vat 


293 </seg>

            <seg id="p058">
Kersalist 
irian 

given 

j&gt; 

Tot 

¦ berof 
ber of 

294 </seg>
         </p>

		    </body>
	  </text>
</TEI.2>