<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00071.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska Tractor Tests</title>
               <date value="1929-01">1929-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-11</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 233 T „ „,&gt;„„ January, 1929 Nebraska Tractor Tests 1920-1928 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">BOARD OF TRACTOR TEST ENGINEERS Oscar W. Siogren, E. E. Brnckctt, C. W. Smith ENGINEER IN CHARGE OF TESTS H. L. Wallace ASSISTANT IN TRACTOR TESTS F. N. Laub </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Nebraska Tractor Tests - This bulletin summarizes all reports of Nebraska official tractor tests conducted since this work began in 1920 under the provisions of the Nebraska Tractor Law (5531-5543 The Compiled Statutes of Nebraska, 1922). During the 9 years that this work has been in effect, tests have been conducted on 154 different models and types of tractors. During the first 4 seasons of testing there were several tractors the claims of which had to be revised before they could complete the test. During the last 5 years, however, every tractor tested has been able to go thru the test and meet all original claims made for it. All tractors used in these tests are certified by their manufacturers as being stock-model machines. It should be remembered that during the tests the tractors are in the care of skilled operators and the results are, therefore, prob - ably somewhat better than would be secured by the average operator. Tractors are credited only with the power delivered to the measuring apparatus, no allowance or corrections being made for atmospheric conditions, drive wheel slippage, belt losses, or other losses. Fuels used are of ordinary kinds regularly supplied to the trade, no special or high-test grades being used. Regular operating settings of the carburetor, spark, air heater, and governor are not considered as adjustments in the report. Copies of the original reports contain 3 pages each and may be secured at 5 cents for each report of any tractor, from the Department of Agricultural Engineering, College of Agricul - ture, University of Nebraska, Lincoln, Nebraska. The de - scription of each test contained herein is taken from the official report and from the specifications submitted with the application for test. A summary of the data contained in the reports is given in the table accompanying this bulletin and made a part of it. In this table the tests are grouped in 5 divisions, 3 of these falling under the belt test and 2 under the drawbar test. In all the tests an effort is made to keep the engine speed as near the rated figure as possible, excepting in the variable load test where the engine speed is allowed to vary within the limits of the governor without any adjustments being made during this part of the test. Under this variable speed - test are shown the highest and the lowest engine speeds, which give a direct indication of the governor control of the engine. The fuel readings for each part of the test are given in gallons per hour, horsepower hours per gallon, and pounds per horsepower hour. The water consumption is given in </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 gallons per hour. The temperature is given for both the air and the cooling fluid in order to show whether or not the engine tends to run hot. In the maximum drawbar test the drawbar horsepower, drawbar pull in pounds, and speed in miles per hour only are given. It should be kept in mind that this test is taken over 4OO-ft. runs and that the tractor should not be expected to maintain this pull except for very short periods. Thruout the entire test an accurate record is kept of all repairs and adjustments necessary on the tractor and the same is incorporated in the official reports. OPERATION OF THE "ONE CARBURETOR SETTING " PLAN ON THE NEBRASKA TRACTOR TESTS DURING 1928 At the beginning of the tractor-testing season of 1928 a new procedure was incorporated in the method of testing tractors. This plan is as follows : After the limber-up run of 12 hours is completed, the tractor is given a series of brake horsepower tests, the first being a two-hour test with the engine developing maximum horsepower at rated engine speed. This maximum horsepower test is carried out accord - ing to the provisions of the tractor-rating code developed by the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers. The purpose of this test is to check the manufacturer's rating of the tractor and in case this rating is higher than the code rating, attention is called to this fact in the official report! This two-hour maxi - mum test is not included in the report of the official test be - cause duplication of the results attained would scarcely be possible outside of the laboratory. Upon completion of the two-hour maximum test, a series of experimental runs of 20 minutes' duration is made. Start - ing with the 100 per cent maximum, all adjustments are made to bring about maximum horsepower at the rated engine speed. The load on the dynamometer is then changed to give rated horsepower at rated engine speed and a run of 20 minutes is made. After completing this rated-load run at maximum carburetor settings; the adjustments are all changed back to the 100 per cent maximum test and former readings verified. The load on the dynamometer scales is next reduced 1 per cent and the carburetor adjusted to a leaner mixture until this load is carried at rated engine speed. A run is then made at rated load with the above - mentioned carburetor setting. The same procedure is carried out for 98, 97, 96 per cent, and so on, of the ultimate maxi - mum. Charts I and II present in curves the data from 2 such preliminary tests on 2 different tractors that have appeared here for test this year. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Nebraska Tractor Tests After the completion of the preliminary run and the plotting of the data in curves, the manufacturer is asked to select the particular carburetor setting that he desires to be used in the official tests. All official tests are then made on the setting chosen by him. Referring to Charts I and II, it is to be observed that 97 per cent of the ultimate maximum is the most economical setting in both cases; however, experience has shown that this point is usually too lean to give satisfactory performance on the drawbar tests and particularly so if the weather is cool. While pulling a maximum drawbar load an engine operating at or near the most economical fuel mixture is rather sensitive to temperature changes of either the cooling fluid, fuel, or air. The drawbar load also fluctuates to a much greater extent than the brake loads. On the maximum drawbar tests it is necessary to stop at the end of each run to take certain read - ings and also to calculate the data to determine the necessary changes in load for the next trial. The following procedure in obtaining the maximum drawbar pull is used. All runs are made with the "butterfly or throttle valve wide open over a 400-foot course. Therefore, the controlling factor of the speed is the load carried. To arrive at the maximum horse - power at rated engine speed is of necessity a cut-and-try process. That is, if at the end of a trial, the engine speed is found to be high, another trial is made with a greater load. Hence, due to such stops, the temperature of the cooling fluid and of the motor as a whole drops. If the fuel-air mixture is at or very near the critical mixture, the above-mentioned cooling of the engine changes the gasifying point of the fuel to the extent that the actual mixture is too lean to support maximum or full load of the engine. Experience shows that, if stable operation is to be attained, it is safer to select some point on the richer side of the most economical point of the curve as shown in Charts I and II. Charts III and IV give the fuel consumption at varying loads. All tests were made on a one-carburetor-setting basis. Particular attention is called to. Chart III. It is to be observed that the load carries well beyond the half load and almost to the one-fourth load before an excessive increase in fuel con - sumption takes place. This curve shows quite clearly the possibilities and advantages of a carburetor designed to operate economically over a wide range of loads without changing its adjustment. A tractor equipped with this car - buretor would show good economy under field conditions where the load varies through quite a wide range. Results of tests indicate that the manifolding must be very carefully worked out and should be verified by actual tests </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 before final adoption. The beneficial results of a good car - buretor may be almost lost if it is used in conjunction with a poor manifold. Some manufacturers are fully aware of this problem and are giving it due consideration. • i ■■.■'■ OBSOLETE TRACTORS Several tractors tested during the earlier seasons are no longer being manufactured or have been superseded by later models as indicated in the following list: Test No. 1. WATERLOO BOY 12-25. Manufacture dis - continued. Replaced by John Deere 15-27 (Test No. 146) . Test No. 3. CASE 10-18. See Test No. 91. Test No. 4. CASE 15-27. See Test No. 109. Test No. 5. CASE 22-44. See Test No. 110. Test No. 6. CASE 10-20. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 7. CASE 20-40. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 8. OIL PULL "E" 30-60. See Test No. 103. Test No. 9. OIL PULL " H " 16-30. See Test No. 111. Test No. 10. OIL PULL " K " 12-20. See Test No. 112. Test No. 11. OIL PULL "G" 20-40. See Test No. 116. Test No. 18. FORDSON. See Test No. 124. Test No. 19. TWIN CITY 12-20. See Test No. 121. Test No. 20. EMERSON-BRANTINGHAM 12-20. Man - ufacture discontinued. Test No. 23. TITAN 10-20. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 24. INTERNATIONAL 15-30. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 25. INTERNATIONAL 8-16. Manufacture dis - continued. Test No. 26. HART-PARR " 30." Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 30. AULT.MAN-TAYLOR 30-60. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 31. AULTMAN-TAYLOR 15-30. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 32. AULTMAN-TAYLOR 22-45. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 33. MOLINE ." D " 9-18. Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 35. COLEMAN 16-30. Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 37. PARRETT 15-30. Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 39. AVERY SIX CYLINDER MODEL " C." Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 40. AVERY SIX CYLINDER MODEL " C." Manufacture discontinued. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Nebraska Tractor Tests S es £ S 0 ' ii' 4-^S RY 12 - 20 ' Manufacture discontinued. "%*% S O&lt; !!• RY 14 " 28 - Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 46. FRICK " C " 15-28. Manufacture discon - tmued. , .Test No. 47. FRICK "A" 12-20. Manufacture discon - tmued. Test No. 48. TWIN CITY 40-65. Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 49. WALLIS " K " 15-25. See Test No. 92. Test No. 51. LAUSON 15-30. See Test No 132 Test. No. 54. ALLIS CHALMERS 6-12. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 55. ALLIS CHALMERS 18-30. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 56. MONARCH 18-30. Manufacture discon - tmued. in Tes ' No - 57. AVERY SINGLE ROW CULTIVATOR 5 - 10. Manufacture discontinued. Srt N? 59* HOLT^TU 3 »- 2^0 nU M CtUr | *™M*u*L xest jno. t&gt;y. ttUi/I Til 25-40. Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 60. BATES STEEL MULE. Manufacture dis - continued. Test No. 61. HOLT " T16 " 40-60. Manufacture discon - tmued. Test No. 63. TOWNSEND 15-30. Manufacture discon - tmued. Test No. 64. UNCLE SAM 20-30. Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 66. SQUARE TURN 18-35. Manufacture dis - continued. Test No. 67. TWIN CITY 20-35. See Test No 122 Test No. 69. PORT HURON 12-25. Manufacture discon - tmued. £ 6S £ S a Z?" MINNEAPOLIS 17-30. See Test No. 118. Test No. 71. AVERY 12-25. Manufacture discontinued as ss a ssss^ssa^isS Test No. 76. BEST "A" 60. See Test No. 105 Test No. 77. BEST "S" 30. See Test No. 104. No 115 A "" SHAWNEE p OWER PATROL. See Test tintld* 79 " HART - PARR " 20 " Manufacture discon- Test No. 80. EAGLE 16-30. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 81. EAGLE 12-22. Manufacture discontinued. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Test No. 83. ALLIS CHALMERS 18-30. See Test No. 151. Test No. 85. CLETRAC " F " 9-16. Manufacture discon - tinued. Test No. 87. INTERNATIONAL HARVESTER COM - PANY 15-30. See Test No. 130. Test No. 88. CASE 12-20. See Test No. 91. Test No. 89. AVERY TRACK RUNNER 15-25. Manu - facture discontinued. Test No. 90. CASE 40-72. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 92. WALLIS 15-27. See Test No. 134. Test No. 95. McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20. See Test No. 142. Test No. 96. AVERY 20-35. Manufacture discontinued. Test No. 97. HART-PARR " 40." See Test No. 140, Test No. 98. BEST " 60 " 40-60. See Test No. 105. Test No. 99. BEST " 30 " 20-30. See Test No. 104. Test No. 100. BEAR 25-35. See Test No. 101. Test No. 102. JOHN DEERE " D " 15-27. See Test No. 146. Test No. 106. HART-PARR 16-30. See Test No. 128. Test No. 107. HART-PARR 12-20. " See Test No. 129. Test No. 108. MONARCH " D " 40-60. Manufacture dis - continued. Test No. 111. OIL PULL " M." See Test No. 143. . Test No. 112. OIL PULL " L." See Test No. 141. Test No. 113. MONARCH " C " 25-35. Manufacture dis - continued. Test No. 116. OIL PULL " R." See Test No. 145. Test No. 127. TWIN CITY 21-32. See Test No. 152. Test No. 131. LAUSON 16-32. See Test No. 148. SUMMARY OF SPECIFICATIONS AND COMMENTS The following pages contain extracts from the reports and specifications of tractors which have been tested and which according to our best information are now being manufac - tured and sold: Test No. 12. HUBER LIGHT FOUR 12-25. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. Kingston magneto. Kingston " L " carburetor. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L head. Mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley : Diameter 13", width 7", rated speed 1000 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, expand - ing shoe clutch. Rated Speed: Low, 2.70 miles per hour; high, 4.15 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.09 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Nebraska Tractor Tests Comments: Magneto timing adjusted 3 times. Valves ground on third cylinder. All valves ground. New carbu - retor put on but made no difference in performance of ma - chine. Fan belt relaced. New water tank put on to replace leaky one. Pin in butterfly valve sheared off. Test No. 13. MINNEAPOLIS 12-25. Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. Mav 17 to June 3, 1920. K-W " H " magneto. Kingston " E " carburetor. No air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. S^,?" 11^ Diam eter 15", width 61//', rated speed 750 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch expanding shoe. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.21 miles per hour; high, 2.98 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.21 miles per hour. Comments: Throttle lever and control for water feed to carburetor broken. Valve tappets adjusted twice. Fan belt relaced once and tightened once. First tractor submitted was considered defective. Test was run on a second tractor sub - mitted. Test No. 14. MINNEAPOLIS 22-44. Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. Mav 18 to June 3, 1920. K-W " HT " magneto. Kingston " E " carburetor. No air cleaner. Own, fly-ball governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18i/&gt;", width 10i/&gt;" rated speed 700 R.P.M. " Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, clutch contracting own make. Rated Speed : Forward, 2.7 miles per hour ; reverse, 3 1 miles per hour. Comments : Some difficulty with leaky joints in fuel line Valve push rods adjusted. Oil pipe leading to left bearing of rear jack shaft was broken. Test No. 15. MINNEAPOLIS 35-70. Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Minnesota. May 21 to June 4, 1920. K-W " HT " magneto. Kingston " E " carburetor. No air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 24", width 101/4", rated Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, clutch contracting band, own make. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Rated Speeds: Forward, 1.9 miles per hour; reverse, 2.8 miles per hour. Comments: Center crankshaft bearing adjusted. Exhaust valve stems ground down. Filed extra notches for governor control lever. . Two new spark plugs. The morning after the brake test had been completed the engine was started in the usual way, gained speed rapidly and after only a few revolu - tions the clutch and belt wheel broke into many pieces which were thrown in various directions. The cause for the break - age could not be determined. The wrecking of this clutch and belt wheel would indicate a serious defect in this tractor if it were certain the accident was due to weakness of these parts. It is probable, however, that the breaking of these parts was due to some other cause and not to the fault of the tractor. The report holds that the tractor should not be dis - qualified because of the accident. Test No. 16. HEIDER 12-20. Rock Island Plow Com - pany, Rock Island, Illinois. May 28 to June 8, 1920. Dixie " 46 " magneto. Kingston " L3 " carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Waukesha, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter. 14", width 7", rated speed 720 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, open friction drive, fric - tion clutch. Rated Speeds: First, 2.25 miles per hour; second, 2.50 miles per hour; third, 2.75 miles per hour; fourth, 3.00 miles per hour; fifth, 3.25 miles per hour; sixth, 3.5 miles per hour; seventh, 3.75 miles per hour; eighth, 4.00 miles per hour; re - verse, the same as above. Comments: Set screw in butterfly valve worked loose. Test No. 17. HEIDER 9-16. Rock Island Plow Com - pany, Rock Island, Illinois. June 1 to June 9, 1920. Dixie " 46 " magneto. Kingston " L3 " carburetor. Ben - nett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 12", width 6", rated speed 750 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, open friction drive, fric - tion clutch. Own make. Rated Speeds: First, 2.25 miles per hour; second, 2.50 miles per hour; third, 3.00 miles per hour; fourth, 3.25 miles per hour ; fifth, 3.5 miles per hour ; sixth, 3.75 miles per hour ; seventh, 4.00 miles per hour; reverse, the same as above. Comments: Some difficulty with the oil indicator. The oil tube to the left of master gear was cut off by wearing against the fenders and the oil tube to right of master gear was clogged. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Nebraska Tractor Tests tJ?* ?* 21 * o WI , S 9.9 NSIN 16 - 30 - Wisconsin Farm Tractor Company, Sauk City, Wisconsin. June 9 to 18 1920 Eisemann " G4 " magneto. Schebler " A " carburetor! Koss, Wortham dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly - ball type governor. J Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 8", rated speed 615 R.P.M dr di SS1 B &amp; 1 " wheeIs&gt; 2 drivers &gt; enclosed gear drive, clutch Rated Speeds: Low, 2.53 miles per hour; high, 3.66 miles per hour. Gears may be changed to give the following rated speeds: Low, 1.83 miles per hour; high, 2.57 miles per hour. Comments: Replaced fan belt. Test No. 22 GRAY 18-36. The Gray Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. June 11 to July 3, 1920 Bosch " DU4 " magneto. Stromberg " M3 " carburetor Bennett, dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Waukesha flv-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise RPM 5 Diameter 113 /8"&gt; width 8 "&gt; rated speed 950 Chassis: Wide drive drum in rear, 2 guide wheels in front. Clutch, own, cone type. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: Ground valves and adjusted tappets. Tractor would not develop rated load. Manufacturer was permitted to put on new cylinders and pistons and tractor was given additional limbering up. Put on Stromberg carburetor in place of Bennett. Carburetor float valve ground. At the end of the test there were slight leaks around plugs above valves and around spark plug porcelains. A good deal of lost motion in the steering gear. Test No 28. BEEMAN MODEL G 2-4. Beeman Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. June 22 to July 2, 1920 Heinze " AX1 " magneto. Kingston "J" carburetor' Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. No governor Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 4i/ 2 ", width 33,4", rotates at engine speed. Chassis : Two drive wheels in front, 2 castor wheels in rear. Clutch own make both external and internal expanding Rated Speeds : 0.75 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Replaced carburetor. £ Test No. 29. LA CROSSE 12-24. La Crosse Tractor Company, La Crosse, Wisconsin. August 2 to 5, 1920. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Atwater-Kent " K3 " magneto and dry batteries. Strom - berg " MB3 " carburetor. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11", width iy%", rated speed 900 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, own clutch contracting band type. Open gear drive. Rated Speeds: 2.50 miles per hour. Comments : Line drive attachment was used. Operator had reasonably good control of tractor with 4 lines. Replaced fan belt, changed 2 spark plugs. Replaced governor springs, changed ignition timing, ground valves. Test No. 43. AVERY 25-50. Avery Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to 30, 1920. K-W "HK" magneto. Kingston "Dual" carburetor. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, yalve-in-head,. mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 22", width 8Vs&gt;"» rated speed 700 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers. Open gear drive, expand - ing shoe clutch, own make. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: Clutch adjusted twice. New governor spring put in to replace old one which was too weak. In the test the cab needed additional bracing to hold it rigidly to the engine frame. Test No. 44. AVERY 45-65. Avery Company, Peoria, Illinois. July 26 to August 3, 1920. K-W "HK" magneto. Kingston "Dual" carburetor. Bennett dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley : Diameter 26", width 10", rated speed 600 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, own make expanding shoe clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: The rating of this tractor was changed from 40-80 to 45-65. Test No. 45. CLETRAC 12-20. Cleveland Tractor Com - pany, Cleveland, Ohio. July 29 to August 9, 1920. Teagle " 665 " magneto. Kingston " L " carburetor. Own make air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Nebraska Tractor Tests Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head. Mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 8", width 6" rated speed 1265 R.P.M. . Chassis: Crawler track, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive. B &amp; B disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Normal, 3.5 miles per hour. Variable from 1 to 4 miles per hour. Comments : Fuel pipe broken. Oil gauge did not register. Test No. 50. FLOUR CITY 18-35. Kinnard &amp; Sons Manufacturing Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. August 9 to 25, 1920. K-W " TK " magneto. Schebler " A " carburetor. No air cleaner. Pickering, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 26", width 7V 2 ", rated speed 353 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, own make expanding shoe clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 3.0 miles per hour. Comments: Five new spark plugs added. Replaced fan belt. Ground valves once. Counter shaft bearing was cut at end of drawbar test due to. lack of oil. Bearing was oiled by grease cup and altho oil cup was screwed down during test the rear side of bearing was not lubricated. Test No. 52. FLOUR CITY 40-70. Kinnard &amp; Sons Manufacturing Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. August 13 to 24, 1920. K-W " HK " magneto. Kingston " L " carburetor. No air cleaner. Pickering, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 34", width 10", rated speed 334 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, clutch shoe type own make. Rated Speeds: 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: Repaired fuel tank. Replaced 5 spark plugs Test No. 53. ALL WORK 14-28. Electric Wheel Com - pany, Quincy, Illinois. August 16 to September 14, 1920 Kingston " L " magneto. Kingston " E " carburetor. Dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 133,4", width 7y 2 ", rate dspeed 900 Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, open gear drive, disc clutch, 8" extension rims. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Rated Speeds: Low, 1.75 miles per hour; high, 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: Clutch pin lost out. All valves ground once. Valves on cylinder No. 4 ground twice. Larger carburetor put on and hot air line altered. Test No. 62. INDIANA 5-10. Indiana Silo Company, Anderson, Indiana. September 13 to 17, 1920. t Atwater-Kent " K3 " battery ignition system. Kingston L carburetor. Bennett, dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Le Roi fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise, gelt pulley: Diameter 7", width 6i/ 2 ", rated speed 1000 Chassis: Two drivers with truck in rear. Open chain drive, clutch contracting band own make. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.48 miles per hour ; second, 2.59 miles per hour; third, 2.90 miles per hour; fourth, 3.86 miles per hour. Reverse, same as above. Comments : Small sprocket on final drive showed consider - able wear. Test No. 65. TORO 6-12. The Toro Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. September 23 to 29, 1920 Eisemann " GS4 " magneto. Kingston "L" carburetor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Le Roi fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Beft pulley: Diameter 8", width 41,4", rated speed 1200 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch double band, own make. Three-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.6 miles per hour ; high, 3.7 miles per hour ; reverse, 3 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments necessary during lGSL. Test No. 68. BATES STEEL MULE 15-22. Bates Ma - cnme &amp; Tractor Company, Joliet, Illinois. October 12 to 18, 1920. Dixie Aero magneto. Bennett " J " carburetor. Bennett water type air cleaner. Simplex fly-ball type governor i in - e: y, e f ticaI ' valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 8i/ 2 ", rated speed 853 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, clutch a &amp; is dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 3 miles per hour; high, 4.5 miles per hour. ■ . Comments: Minor adjustment on oil line. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Nebraska Tractor Tests Test No. 73. WETMORE 12-25. H. A. Wetmore, Sioux City, Iowa. April 6 to 12, 1921. Splitdorf Aero magneto. Schebler " ATX47 " 114-inch carburetor. No air cleaner. Weidely fly-ball type governor Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 63,4", rated Sp66u X088 Iv.P.IM. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, Fuller disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3Ut miles per hour; high, 5.9 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Hand operation ol throttle was necessary to control engine speed within safe limits of loads three-fourths rating and under, when carbu - retor was set for best fuel economy. Heavy grade oil was found necessary for the engine. Test No. 75. LAUSON " S" 12-25. The John Lauson Manufacturing Company, New Holstein, Wisconsin. April 20 to May 6, 1921. Dixie "46 " magneto. Kingston " L " 1^-inch carburetor. Taco No. 2 water type air cleaner. Taco fly-ball type govern - or. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft y™^ Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7", rated speed boO JR. P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; expanding shoe clutch. Kated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; high, 3 miles oer hour. r^*! 0 ™™ 611^ A11 spark plugs Clutch tightened. Clutch throw-out shoe broke. Test No. 78. RUSSELL GIANT "A" 30-60. The Russell &amp; Company, Massillon, Ohio. June 6 to 25, 1921 Bosch " DU4 " magneto. Kingston " E " 2-inch dual car - buretor. Bennett 2i/ 2 -inch dry centrifugal air cleaner. Pick - ering fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise Madison-Kipp mechanical lubricator. Belt pullev: Diameter 24", width 10", rated speed 525 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; shoe clutches. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.9 miles per hour; high, 3.2 miles per hour. ~ * Comments : New fan belt. Fan belt tightened. Lagging came off belt pulley. On account of overheating, original radi - ator was replaced by larger one which was made standard equipment. All valves ground. Clutch tightened. One ex - haust valve spring broke. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Test No. 82. ALLIS-CHALMERS 12-20. Rated 14-27. Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wis - consin. September 13 to 24, 1921. Dixie "46C" magneto. Kingston "L" H/i-inch carbu - retor. Taco No. 2 water type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 12i/&gt;", width 6i/&gt;", rated speed 817 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; own make shoe clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; high, 3.1 miles per hour. Comments: Gasoline feed pipe broke at tank connection. Carburetor disassembled and cleaned. All valves ground. Magneto timing retarded. Two new spark plugs. All spark plug gaps adjusted. Cylinder blocks removed and top rings on 2 pistons found sticking from, too close fit. Oil pipe broke at connection at front of engine. Test No. 84. ROGERS FOUR WHEEL DRIVE. Not rated. Rogers Tractor and Trailer Company, Albion, Penn - sylvania. April 1 to May 1, 1922. Berling " FL41 " magneto. Zenith " L8 " 2-inch carbu - retor. Bennett 2-inch dry centrifugal air cleaner. Buffalo fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 16", width 10", rated speed 800 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels same size, all drivers; own make multiple disc clutch; hydraulic steering control. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.6 miles per hour; high, 3.6 miles per hour. Comments: Shortened fan belt. Eight new spark plugs. Adjusted valve tappet. Installed . larger vacuum tank. New governor spring. Removed belt pulley clutch throw-out arm and tightened spring. Pulley clutch not used in test. Re - paired broken fan bracket. Welded water manifold. En - larged suction line to oil pump. Fan belt lacing broke 3 times. Test No. 86. HOLT CATERPILLAR " T-35 " 15-25. The Holt Manufacturing Company, Stockton, California, and Peoria, Illinois. July 19 to 26, 1922. Eisemann " G4 " magneto, Kingston " L " 1^4-inch carbu - retor. Dailey oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical; valve-in-head, overhead camshaft, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11%", width 6i/ 2 ", rated speed 1000 R.P.M. Chassis : Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers ; own make multiple disc clutch. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">• Nebraska Tractor Tests ndS? p d er S So e u d r S ; : hir5 2 J SSS pfr S? intermediate ' *** TeS s rn m S^dTn1°ef?taV reSSed - °" e neW SP3rk «** Test No. 91. CASE 12-20. J. I. Case Threshing Machine Company Racine, Wisconsin. April 6 to 17, 1923 MaChme Bosch AT4 magneto. Kingston " L3V " 1%-inch car Ey Pe SEX* Clean - °™ ™ ke «" eter 14^", width 6%", rated speed 1050 R P.M clutJh 8818 ' WheelS&gt; 2 drivers ' twin di sc 10-inch disc ho?r ated Speeds: Low ' 2 - 2 miles P er our : h^h, 3.0 miles per Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. i&gt; ,*, «. N^- 93 ' RUSSELL " LITTLE BOSS " 15-30 Russell &amp; Company, Massillon, Ohio. May 16 to 23 1923 Sphtdorf Aero "448" magneto. Kingston "L"'lV,-inch SfS^npS 0 "^ 1166 !?'^ 2 d T ivers : °wn make shoe clutch, hour P : ' 2A miles per hour; hi^ h ' 3 - 7 mil es per Comments: Fan belt tightened. Clutch adjusted t&gt; Tes n o**Z- 94 ' RUSSELL " BIG BOSS C " 20 3O Russell &amp; Company, Massillon, Ohio. May 16 to 25 1923 carburet? 0 - Kingston " L " '«8b* li^^e^^ »?5 Rated lUed^ T^ elS 9A d -, iVer "'* r n make shoe clut &lt;*. hour Speeds ' 2 ' 4 miles P er hour; high, 3.7 miles per </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Engine: Vertical, valye-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Dow metal pistons. Lynite (aluminum alloy) connecting rods. Belt pulley: Diameter 12", width 9", rated speed 1290 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers; multiple dry disc clutches. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.35 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3.80 miles per hour; high, 6.15 miles per hour. Comments : Slot in governor plunger lengthened 3/32 inch. Points of one spark plug readjusted. Test No. 103. OIL PULL " S " 30-60. Advance Rumely Thresher Company, Inc., La Porte, Indiana. September 6 to 13, 1924. American Bosch " DU4 " magneto. Secor-Higgins 2%-inch carburetor. Own 2-stage air cleaner; centrifugal first stage; oil fibre second stage. Own fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 25", width 11", rated speed 470 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; own disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.5 miles per hour ; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 104. BEST " S30 " 25-30. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 22, 1924. American Bosch " ZR4 " magneto. Stromberg " MP3 " lV^-inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 12", width 7", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks both drivers; multiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.75 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.63 miles per hour; high, 3.63 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 105. BEST " A60 " 50-60. C. L. Best Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. September 15 to 29, 1924. American Bosch " ZR4Edl8 " magneto. Stromberg " M4 " Special 1%-inch carburetor. Pomona oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make centrifugal type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 10", rated speed 650 R.P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Nebraska Tractor Tests Chassis: Tracklayer type, 2 tracks, both drivers; multiple dry disc clutch; enclosed gear drive. Rated Speeds: Low, 1% miles per hour; intermediate, 2% miles per hour; high; 3% miles per hour. Comments: At the end of the test the vacuum tank leaked at the bottom seam. Exhaust valve on No. 1 cylinder would not hold compression. Test No. 109. CASE 18-32. J. I. Case Threshing Ma - chine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 27 to November 4, i924. Bosch "AT4.IVC3" magneto. Kingston "L" 13/ 8 -inch carburetor. Donaldson Simplex oil fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7 1 /)", rated speed 1000 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.46 miles per hour; high, 3.28 miles per hour. . Comments: During the maximum drawbar test the clutch was adjusted once. Test No. 110. CASE 25-45. J. I. Case Threshing Ma - chine Company, Racine, Wisconsin. October 28 to November 9, 1924. Bosch " ZR4 " magneto. Kingston " L " 2-inch carburetor. Own make water type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine :' Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter. 16V£", width 8V£", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; ex - panding shoe type clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; high, 3.2 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test the right cyl - inder head gasket burned out and both gaskets were then re - placed. Test No. 114. HEIDER 15-27. Rock Island Plow Com - pany, Rock Island, Illinois. May 7 to 13, 1925. Dixie " 46 " magneto. Kingston " L " li/£-inch carburetor. United, whirling vane type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, head not removable, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley : Diameter 14", width 7", rated speed 725 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; friction drive. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Rated Speeds: One to 4 miles per hour. Comments: During the belt run before any data were taken, the right pulley shaft bearing heated excessively. It was removed and balls found to be chipped, ball retainer bent and broken, and inner race broken. It appeared that the trouble was caused by a defective inner race. A new bearing was installed. The friction drive ring was found slightly burned (probably due to excessive slip when bearing failed) and was replaced by new ring. Test No. 115. SHAWNEE THIRTY (Road Maintainer). Shaw-Enochs Tractor Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 16 to 28, 1925. Eisemann " GS4 " magneto. Zenith 1-inch carburetor. United, whirling vane type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head (Ricardo) removable, mounted lengthwise. Chassis: Two drive wheels (by which machine is steered) in front carry engine and transmission. Two non-drivers in rear carry road working equipment and operator. Enclosed worm gear drive. Disc clutch. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.5 miles per hour; high, 3 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 117. McCORMICK-DEERING " FARMALL." International Harvester Company of America, Chicago, Illinois. September 14 to 19, 1925. Splitdorf " Aero " 937950 magneto. Ensign " 3DA600F " 1-inch carburetor. Pomona Model 118 oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable cylinder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diam - eter 14", width 6y 2 '"» rated speed 693 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers; enclosed gear drive; multiple dry disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3 miles per hour ; high, 4 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 118. THE MINNEAPOLIS TYPE B 17-30. The Minneapolis Threshing Machine Company, Hopkins, Min - nesota. October 21 to November 12, 1925. American Bosch " ED21TC " magneto. Wheeler-Schebler " A " lVk-inch carburetor. Donaldson " Simplex " oiled fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Detroit lubricator. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15V&amp;", width 7V£", rated speed 825 R.P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Nebraska Tractor Tests clfi^ 31 F ° Ur wheels&gt; 2 drivers ! enclosed gear drive; disc pe?h^fr SpeedS: Um ' 2 ' 23 mil6S Per h ° Ur; Wgh ' 2 ' 84 ""k* Comments: It was necessary to drill 8 holes before the left extension rim could be attached. . After the limbering-up run ~m^r e 5 &gt;r H. IUly °^ C1&amp; } dat&amp; , WCTe teken the en « lne hea d WES removed, the carbon cleaned out, and all valves ground. Dur - ing the limbering-up run and the rated drawbar test, the fuel line clogged up, requiring stops for cleaning out Test No. 119. CLETRAC "K" 15-25. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 22 to May 5 192G Eisemann « GS4 » magneto. Tillotson " R2 » cYrbureto?: Pomona, oil fiber type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type feo'TpM P y: D ' ameter 12 "' width 6 ". rated sS len^thwile Vertica1 ' valv e-in-head, mounted crankshaft disc^luteh. Track " layer ' 2 tracks ' enclosed gear drive, single Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4 50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comments : During the half load brake test the oil pressure line sprung a leak. During the rated and low gear maximum ,WH ar t te l tS th 1£ eaT Shi^ lever . h «d to be fattened in S m order to keep the gears m mesh. The advertised miles per hour as given should be corrected to: Low, 2.13 miles 5er atTaV^P M 23 yS?" P er &gt; ur ; rever^ 1-66 miles^er h5ur at la to K.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 120. GLETRAC "K" 15-25. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. April 30 to Mav 5 1926 Pomonr "^ " ma^? to - Ti »oteon " R2°» cYrbuS: loSSr. type ar cleaner - Own ' fly - ba11 ty p e i % in - e: -y^ ica ,l' valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft 860RRM: P Diameter 12 "' ™ dth G "&gt; rated speed disc^utch. TrackJayer ' 2 tracks ' enclosed gear drive, single Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 4 50 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. W wL 6 ?? : Durin l ?-i he rated and Iow « ear maximum draw - «rH te ? te , the fi^ar shift lever had to be fastened in place in W^ - eeP if 8 in mesh - The advertised miles per honr- £Jw n o! h °", ld be c e rrected to: Low ' 2 - 13 m«es ?er ari^RyM^S e P ngiSe 0Ur; reVGrSe ' L66 mileS h ™ </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Test No. 121. TWIN CITY " TY " 17-28. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 17 to 21, 1926. American Bosch " ZR4Ed26 " magneto. Bennett, dry cen - trifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Holley " 257 " carburetor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves; mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 6", rated speed 650 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, disc clutch, 6" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour; reverse, 1.75 miles per hour. Comments : During the drawbar tests it was necessary to place two small bolts in the gear shift lock to keep gears in mesh. It was necessary to adjust the governor several times on drawbar test to maintain proper engine speed. Test No. 122. TWIN CITY "AT" 27-44. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. May 20 to 27, 1926. American Bosch " ZR4Ed26 " magneto. Wheeler Schebler " A " carburetor. Donaldson Duplex oil fiber type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, removable head and cyl - inder sleeves, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 21", width 8V 2 "» rated speed 466 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, twin disc clutch, 7" extension rims. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 2.9 miles per hour; reverse, 1.87 miles per hour. Comments : During both the rated load brake test and the rated load drawbar test the fan belt tension had to be read - justed. Test No. 123. HUBER NEW SUPER FOUR 18-36. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. June 7 to 12, 1926. Eisemann " GS4 " magneto. Kingston " L3 " 1 11/16-inch throttle opening, manifold type A cold bore, 2 3/16-inch Pomona " Vortox " oil fiber type air cleaner. Kingston, fly - ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15V&amp;", width 8", rated speed 695 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, twin disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.2 miles per hour ; high, 3.8 miles per hour. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Nebraska Tractor Tests Comments: After the limber-up run and before the brake tests were made, the fan belt was replaced with a new one. Before the drawbar tests were run the fan belt broke and was again replaced with a new belt. During the limber-up run 3 cap screws sheared off the steering post and clutch lever sup - port. Before the brake tests were run a ball and socket con - nection was put on the governor throttle rod. During the maximum test the fuel line broke at the carburetor connection and was replaced with a new fuel pipe. Test No. 124. FORDSON. Ford Motor Company, De - troit, Michigan. June 21 to 28, 1926. Fordson magneto. Holley " 235 " carburetor. Own, water type air cleaner. No governor. Engine : Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise, high compression head. Belt pulley: Diameter 9V&amp;", width 6", rated speed 1000 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Multiple disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 1.58 miles per hour ; intermediate, 2.24 miles per hour ; high, 7.05 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.14 miles per hour. Comments : At the end of the limber-up run and before the official brake tests were made the spark gap in the spark plugs was adjusted to 0.020 inches at the same time a spark plug gasket was replaced in one spark plug. Test No. 125. CLETRAC "A" 30-45. Cleveland Tractor Company, Cleveland, Ohio. August 27 to September 7, 1926. Eisemann " GS6 " magneto. Tillotson " ST3A " carburetor. Pomona " Vortbx " oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly - ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15", width 8i/&gt;", rated speed 690 R.P.M. Chassis : Two tracks, enclosed gear drive, single disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.4 miles per Tiour ; high, 4.75 miles per hour; reverse, 1.8 miles per hour. Comments : During the low gear drawbar tests the gear shift lever had to be tied in place in order to keep the gears in mesh. In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engi - neers and the Society of Automotive Engineers, the belt horsepower rating of this tractor should not exceed 44 horse - power. Test No. 126. HUBER 20-40. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. September 7 to 16, 1926. </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Eisemann " GS4 " magneto. Kingston " L3 " carburetor. Pomona " Vortox " oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly - ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15i/ 2 ", width 8", rated speed 666 R.P.M. . - Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Twin disc clutch. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.47 miles per hour ; high, 3.48 miles per hour; reverse, 1.94 miles per hour. Comments : During the rated brake test the fan belt broke and was replaced with a new belt. Test No. 128. HART-PARR 18-36. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. October 18 to 25, 1926. Robert Bosch " ZU42 " magneto. Stromberg " MB3 " car - buretor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Donaldson dry centrif - ugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 9", rated speed 800 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Dry plate clutch. Seven-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 miles per hour; high, 3.00 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. Comments: Before the half load brake test was run the spark gap in the spark plugs was adjusted to 0.020" gap. During the maximum drawbar test one spark plug was re - placed. Two small screws were lost out of the carburetor air connection during the test. The crankshaft speed of the rated load and first maximum drawbar tests were low due to an error in calculations made by observer during test which was not discovered until too late for correction. Test No. 129. HART-PARR 12-24. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. October 18 to 28, 1926. Robert Bosch " ZU42 " magneto. Stromberg " MB3 " car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley : Diameter 13", width 8", rated speed 850 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, dry plate clutch. Six-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.66 miles per hour; high, 3.33 miles per hour; reverse, 2.25 miles per hour. Comment: During the varying load brake test both spark plugs were replaced with new spark plugs ; one had a cracked porcelain and the other a defective gasket. During the low </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Nebraska Tractor Tests gear maximum drawbar tests the gears slipped out of mesh It was necessary to improvise a method of holding gear shift ,^ e £., ln P lace - The low K ea r train of gears was burred slightly due to the gears slipping out of mesh. Test No. 130. McCORMICK-DEERING 15-30. Inter - national Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 26 to November 2, 1926. f Own, " E4 " magneto. Ensign " RW " carburetor. Pomona Vortox oil spray type air cleaner. Own, fly-ball type governor. Jy Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft s eed624 e R P^M^ PUlley: Diameter 16 %". wi dth 9", rated Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive Multiple dry disc clutch. Six-inch extension rims. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles ner hour. Comments : No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 132. LAUSON 20-40. The John Lauson Manu - facturing Company, New Holstein, Wisconsin. March 28 to April 22, 1927. American Bosch " ZR4Ed26 " magneto. Kingston " L3 " carburetor. Taco, water type air cleaner. Taco, fly-ball tvDe governor. * y Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise Belt pulley: Diameter 17i/ 2 ". width 8", rated speed 600 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive clutch own make twin dry disc. . ' Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 to 2.50 miles per hour; high, 3.25 to 3.50 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.00 miles per hour Comments: The belt rating of this tractor should not ex - ceed 37 horsepower in order to conform to the provisions of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the So - ciety of Automotive Engineers tractor rating code Test No. 133. HART-PARR 28-50. Withdrawn from tGSti. • Test No. 134. WALLIS 20-30. J. I. Case Plow Works, Racine, Wisconsin. April 29 to May 10, 1927 American Bosch "ZR4Ed26" magneto. Kingston "L3" carburetor Wallis dry " cloth screen type" air cleaner Pickering fly-ball type governor. i a w^ n - e: Y&gt; e £ ica1 ,', va^n-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18i/ 2 ", width 7", rated speed 476 It. P.M. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch dry plate with disc. Rated Speeds : Low, 2.75 miles per hour ; high, 3.33 1/3 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments : The rate of travel of this tractor is : Low, 2.88 miles per hour ; high, 3.49 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.88 miles per hour. The above speeds are calculated at the rim of the drive wheels and at 1050 R.P.M. of the engine. Test No. 135. HUBER SUPER FOUR 40-62. Huber Manufacturing Company, Marion, Ohio. May 17 to June 24, 1927. Eisemann " G4 " magneto. Ensign " A " carburetor. Pomona oil spray type air cleaner. Kingston fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15 W, width 9%", rated speed 733 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.00 to 2.50 miles per hour; high, 3.00 to 3.50 miles per hour; reverse, 1.75 to 2.25 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test and after ap - proximately 25 hours running ignition trouble developed due to spark plugs. Two of the plugs were replaced with new ones of the same make but did not remedy the trouble. The Stitt spark plugs, which were standard equipment, were then replaced with A-C plugs and no further ignition trouble was experienced. The left spindle arm sheared off causing the front axle to bend somewhat; the axle and spindle arm were replaced with new parts. The packing gland nuts on the water pump were tightened several times during the test. The flexible oil tube leading to the clutch throw-out collar was leaking at the end of the test. Test No. 136. SHAW MODEL " T25." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 22, 1927. Own make magneto. Tillotson " MS6A " carburetor. No air cleaner, No governor. Engine: Vertical, F-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 51/2". width 1W, rated speed 275 R.P.M. Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open chain and gear drive, clutch own make expanding band. Rated Speeds: Low, 0.50 to 1.50 miles per hour; high, 1.25 to 2.50 miles per hour. Comments: During the brake tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The, exhaust valve stem was found to be sticking. It was removed, polished and the valve </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Nebraska Tractor Tests ground. The exhaust valve push rod was adjusted to give more clearance and the guide reamed out. The inlet valve spring was found to be somewhat weaker than a standard spring. The inlet valve, spring and cage were replaced with a new assembly. Before the official brake tests were run both piston rings stuck in their grooves. The lower ring was broken in removing and was replaced with a new ring- both rings were given slightly more end clearance than they had previously. During the drawbar tests the following repairs and adjustments were made: The caster wheel arm was broken and replaced with a new one. The clutch shift lever broke and was repaired. The fuel line broke off at the carbu - retor and was repaired. During the limber-up run a stop clip on the cultivator beam control broke. In the advertising literature submitted with the specifica - tions for test of this tractor we find the following claims which are not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit " B " page 15 ENGINE SPECIFICATIONS. " POWER RATED CONSERVATIVELY AT 1 H. P. On tests develops about ly 2 horse power." Exhibit " B " page 8. " Figure 18 show ing SHAW DU ALL Model T25 running in low gear pulling a road drag with scales indicating 450 pounds direct pull on the drawbar, which is sufficient to pull a ton load on a cart or light wagon." Test No. 137. SHAW MODEL " T45." Shaw Manufac - turing Company, Galesburg, Kansas. June 7 to 23 1927 Own make magneto. Tillotson " MS7A " carburetor No air cleaner. Own make pneumatic type governor. Engine: Vertical, air cooled, L-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 3", width 2i/&gt;", operates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Two wheels, both drivers, open gear and chain drive, clutch own make expanding band. JXated Speeds: Low, 1.00 mile per hour; high, 1.43 miles Comments: In the advertising literature submitted with the specifications for test of this tractor we find the following SrL™u-. W u £ h ,1F™ not substantiated by the results of this test: Exhibit " B ' " T45 ": " DRAWBAR PULL 650 lbs. On low gear, this pulls a iy 2 ton load on a light cart or waeon " .. Test No 138 CONTINENTAL CULTOR No. 32. Con- Vq.vt 1 Cultor Company, Springfield, Ohio. August 6 to 17, Ford Model " T " ignition system. Holley " Ford " carbu - retor. No air cleaner. No governor. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise No belt pulley. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Chassis: Two wheels, both drivers, open chain final drive, multiple disc clutch. Rated Speed: 3.00 miles per hour. Comments: During the rated drawbar test the left main drive chain broke. The broken link was replaced with a new link. During the same test two teeth were broken on the main drive sprocket; the test was completed without repair. Test No. 139. MONARCH 10 TON MODEL F. Monarch Tractors Corporation, Springfield, Illinois. August 15 to 26, 1927. American Bosch " ZR4Ed26 " magneto. . Zenith " L7T " carburetor. United 1%" twin, dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Le Roi, fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. No belt pulley. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, partly enclosed final drive, enclosed gear transmission, chain and sprocket final drive. Clutch own make disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.5 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.6 miles per hour; high, 3.3 miles per hour; reverse, 2.5 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 140. HART-PARR 28-50. Hart-Parr Com - pany, Charles City, Iowa. August 17 to 31, 1927. Robert Bosch " ZU4 " magneto. Schebler " D " carburetor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly - ball type governor. Madison-Kipp lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 14", width 9", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive clutch own make dry plate. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.25 miles per hour; high, 3.25 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: After all tests were completed and during the final inspection number 4 cylinder was found to have little or no compression. The piston was removed and the top ring was found to be stuck in its groove, also a small hole thru the wall of the piston in the top groove at the lap of the ring. The ring was released and the hole plugged up. The water passage . between the cylinder- head and engine block on this tractor had been enlarged to permit freer circula - tion. It is understood that this change is to be made standard on all tractors of this model. Test No. 141. OIL PULL 20-30. MODEL "W." Ad - vance-Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. September 15 to 24, 1927. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Nebraska Tractor Tests American Bosch " DU4/2Ed26 " magneto. Own make car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 7 Y&gt;", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make double disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.2 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.7 miles per hour. Comments: After the limber-up run and before the official belt tests were made, the lubricator could not be regulated properly. It was disassembled and cleaned out thoroly. Dur - ing the drawbar tests the compression on number 1 cylinder was found to be somewhat less than number 2 cylinder and there was considerable leakage by the rings on the compres - sion stroke. The piston on number 1 cylinder was removed, the carbon cleaned out from around the rings and) all valves ground. Both spark plugs were replaced with new plugs ; the porcelains were found to be defective. The fuel valve and water valve required frequent adjustment during the drawbar tests. Test No. 142. McCORMICK-DEERING 10-20. Inter - national Harvester Company, Chicago, Illinois. October 3 to 8, 1927. Own make " E4A " magneto. Ensign " R " carburetor. Pomona " Vortox " Model 118 oil spray type air cleaner. Own make fly-ball governor. Engine: Vertical, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 15^", width 7", rated speed 661 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive clutch own make multiple dry disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2 miles per hour; intermediate, 3 miles per hour; high, 4 miles per hour; reverse, 2.75 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 143. OIL PULL 25-40. MODEL " X." Ad - vance Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 6 to 13, 1927. American Bosch " DU4/2Ed26 " magneto. Own make car - buretor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 183,4", width 8V 2 ", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.8 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 144. ROCK ISLAND 18-35. Rock Island Plow Company, Rock Island, Illinois. October 12 to 19, 1927. Dixie "46C" magneto. Stromberg " M3 " carburetor. Buda fly-ball type governor. United dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Engine: Vertical, L-head, mounted crankshaft lengthwise. Belt pulley: Diameter 18", width 71/2", rated speed 660 R.P.M. Chassis : Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin dry disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 3 miles per hour; high, 4.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments : In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor rating code of the American Society of Agricultural Engineers and the Society of Automotive Engineers, the belt horsepower rating of this tractor should not exceed 32 horse - power. Test No. 145. OIL PULL 30-50. MODEL " Y." Ad - vance Rumely Company, La Porte, Indiana. October 13 to 24, 1927. American Bosch " DU4/Ed26 " magneto. Own make car - buretor. Donaldson dry centrifugal type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. Manzel lubricator. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 211,4", width 10", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make twin disc. Rated Speeds: Low, 2.3 miles per hour; intermediate, 2.9 miles per hour; high, 3.5 miles per hour; reverse, 2.9 miles per hour. Comments : On the rated drawbar test the water pump lost prime for short intervals. At the end of the test and during the inspection of the tractor both intake valve springs were found broken. Test No. 146. JOHN DEERE 15-27. MODEL " D." John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 24 to 29, 1927. Splitdorf " 246C " magneto. Schebler " DLT " carburetor. Own make fly-ball type governor. Donaldson Simplex oiled fiber type air cleaner. Engine: Horizontal, valve-in-head, mounted crankshaft crosswise. Belt pulley: Diameter 1514", width 7%", rotates at crankshaft speed. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Nebraska Tractor Tests ow^mlke d£? Ur WhCelS ' 2 driV?rS ' encl0sed gear drive ' clutch Rated Speeds: Low, 2.5 miles per hour; high, 3 25 miles per hour; reverse, 2 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 147 MONARCH 6 TON. Monarch Tractors Sfgie SXST type * over "° r - ™- WLSE lentfE. No r be?tpu]iey™"" 1 " headl m ° Unted CrankSlmtt Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, partly enclosed final drive SSS&amp;XZ&amp;SgTZ chaln and sprocket fim " dJI ™ : Rated Speeds: Low, 1.86 miles per hour: intermediate 9 89 £?LS; ; high&gt; 4 - 07 miles p * r hour; "SSSTSe^iS£ Comments: It was necessary to adjust the water pumn packing glands several times during the test. It was 3 leaking some at the end of the test In order to conform to the provisions of the tractor ratine mer . 1Can^ 0C^ ty of Agricultural Engineers aSd American Bosch " ZR4 " magneto. Tillotson " R2 " car cleaned: Taco fly - ba11 : Taco wJter type^L' Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length- STrPM P y: Diameter 16 "' wid *h 8", rated speed CMch? i T : win°disc,trSatf driV6rS ' end ° Sed * ear dri - tn?i a / ted -? PeedS V, L0W&gt; 21/t to 21/ 2 miles Per hour; high 3U to 31/2 miles per hour ; reverse, 2 miles per hour. /4 iM^ &gt; n IP?. 1 " 1 ! p l ug gaps were adjusted to 0.025" £M£ Vv^v^were^n? aK^eVo^ The^rburetor^oat grjutaljjj, the^ o f g Tractor Company, ClevelanJTohio. April Sio May io^S Delco-Remy battery ignition system. Wheeler-Scheoler fly A £ll SSSSJ ° m ° na Oil SPray tyPe air Ch S </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Experiment Station, Bulletin 233 Engine : Vertical, " I " head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley : Diameter 15", width 13", rated speed 851 R.P.M. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks,. enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Borg &amp; Beck, single plate type. Rated Speeds : Low, 2 miles per hour ; intermediate, 3.5 miles per hour; high, 5.5 miles per hour; reverse, 3 miles per hour. Comment: The battery cable insulation became defective on the rated drawbar test, causing the ignition to become shorted. The insulation was repaired with tape. Two grease cups on the clutch throw-out collar sheared off during the limber-up run. Oil was leaking from the clutch shaft in front of the transmission and also from the crankcase where the front drawbar is connected, at the end of the test. Test i No. 150. CATERPILLAR " 20 " 20-25. Cater - pillar Tractor Company, San Leandro, California. May 17 to 29, 1928. Eisemann " G4 " magneto. Ensign " AE " carburetor. Pomona oil-spray type air cleaner. Governor own make, fly - ball type. Engine : Vertical, " I " head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 11%", width 61,4", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Tracklayer, 2 tracks, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make, single-plate type. Rated Speeds: Low, 1.79 miles per hour; intermediate, 3.07 . miles per hour ; high, 4.67 miles per hour ; reverse, 2.35 miles per hour. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 151. ALLIS CHALMERS 20-35. Allis Chalm - ers Manufacturing Company, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. June 18 to 26, 1928. Eisemann " GS4 " magneto. Kingston " L " carburetor. Donaldson and Allis Chalmers centrifugal and oil-fiber type air cleaner. Own fly-ball type governor. Engine : Vertical, " I " head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 8.5", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive, clutch own make expanding shoe type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2V£ ; high, 3% ; reverse, 31/4. Comments: No repairs nor adjustments. Test No. 152. TWIN CITY " FT " 21-32. Minneapolis Steel &amp; Machinery Company, Minneapolis, Minnesota. Octo - ber 1 to 8, 1928. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Nebraska Tractor Tests Robert Bosch " FU4 " magneto. Stromberg "M3" car - buretor. Donaldson and own make, centrifugal and cypress - moss type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Vertical, "I" head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 16", width 1V^", rated speed 651 R.P.M. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speeds, miles per hour: Low, 2.36; intermediate, 3.17; high, 4.45; reverse, 1.74. Comments: Before the maximum belt tests were run, the packing gland nut on the water pump was tightened. During the maximum low gear drawbar test, the clutch was adjusted. Test No. 153. JOHN DEERE " GENERAL PURPOSE " 10-20. John Deere Tractor Company, Waterloo, Iowa. October 22 to 29, 1928. Fairbanks-Morse ■" John Deere" magneto. Ensign " BJ " carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil - fiber type air cleaner. Governor, own make, fly-ball type. Engine: Horizontal, " L " head, mounted crankshaft cross - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 13", width 6Vfe", rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear and chain drive. Clutch: Own make, disc type. Rated speeds, miles per hour : Low, 2 1/3 ; intermediate, 3V6 ; high, 4 1/3 ; reverse, 2. Comments: Before the operating maximum belt test, oil was found to be leaking from around the flywheel end of the crankshaft. This was repaired by readjusting the gasket and tightening gasket cover plate. Test No. 154. ADVANCE RUMELY " DO ALL." Ad - vance Rumely Thresher Company, La Porte, Indiana. Octo - ber 29 to November 24, 1928. Eisemann " GV4 " magneto. Stromberg " Ml " carburetor. Donaldson-Simplex auxiliary twister and oil-fiber type air cleaner. Waukesha fly-ball type governor. Engine: Vertical, " L " head, mounted crankshaft length - wise. Belt pulley: Diameter 10", width 51/2". rotates at crankshaft speed. Chassis: Four wheels, 2 drivers, enclosed gear drive. Clutch: Twin disc, dry-plate type. Rated speed, miles per hour: Low, 2.625; high, 3.75; re - verse, 2.875. Comments : On the rated and maximum load drawbar tests, it was necessary to improvise a method of locking the gear - shift lever in place to prevent the gears from slipping out of mesh under load. [10W </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>