<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00012</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA, PRESENTED TO THE GOVERNOR FEBRUARY 1, 1904.</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA SEVENTEENTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THB Agricultural Experiment Station or NEBRASKA Presented to the Governor Febki akv 1, \W4. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">U. S. Agricultural Experiment Station, The University of Nebraska. To B ■/, •/. //. Mickey, ■ tratka: Sir: — In accordance with the act of Congress approved March 2, 1887, and the act of the general assembly of the State of Nebraska approved March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment stations, I have the honor here - with to submit the Seventeenth Annual Report of the U. S. Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. E. A. Burnett, Divrrto The University of Nebraska, February 1, 1004. GOVERNOR'S CERTIFICATE. State of Nebraska, Executive Department, Lincoln, February 1, 1904 I: — i. hereby acknowledge receipt of the Seventeenth Annual Report of the U. S. Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska. John H. Mickey, </seg>
            <seg id="p003">1 till* v-lx* P lv_ 1AJ-* KUo 1 Ej±\ \Ji? L xl£i olAl It./ IN . THE GOVERNING BOARD (THE REGENTS OF THE UNIVERSITY) •John L. Teeters, Lincoln, President . .Term expires 1908 bm P. Rich. Omaha . .Term expires 1906 Kli&gt;ha C. Calkins. Kearney . .Term expires 1MB Carl J. Ernst, Omaha . .Term expires 1906 Charles S. Allkn, Lincoln . .Term expires 1910 William G. Whitmore, Valley Term expires 1910 .1 8. Dales. Lincoln. Financial Secretary.* THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE John L. Teeters E. Benjamin Andrew-; E. A. Bl KKETT THE VISITING COMMITTEE W K. Mellok, Loup City ( K. W. Flkxas, Brownville S B, V Stephens, Crete. The State Board of Agriculture The State Horticultural Society THE STATION OFFICERS. BBlknett, B. Sc I, Ph. D r and Anim i. . Associate Director and Agriculturist \ MARSHALL Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF H. R. Smith, B. Sc -mal Husbaudmmm A T. Peters, D. V. M tnimal PukolcgUt Charles E. Bessey, Ph D. . Botanist S. Avekv. Ph. D Clumut A. L. HaECKEK. B. Sc. A '.iry Huhandman LAWRENCE BkINER, B. B Entomologist E H. Barbour, Ph. D. 3 O. V. P. Stout. C. E &lt;;. D Swkzev. M. A J H. Gain, M D. C nimal PathoUgist SNTDER, M S na: Husbandman S W. Pekin r « Foreman *By an act of the Legislature of the State of Nebraska approved and in effect February 15, 18M, the State Treasurer became ex offido custodian of the Experiment Station fund on and after July 1, 1899. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">i ERTIFICATE. Official Roster of the Station Director's Review— I Experimental work Station staff. . Improvers North Plane Substation Farmers" Institute- Publicatio: Acknowledgment - U FINANCIAL STATEMENT A Frxors Disease of Corn eld investiga- o Summary . A Corn Mold Ihty is Bean Hybrid: ant habit td qua'. ' &gt;d color . . . ower color ed color. . . M A Soft Rot of the Sugar- Beet— General bacteriology of the sugar-beet currence and general character of the disease Observations i: Observations in 1902. Inoculation experiments on sugar-beets Whole beets Pieces of beet. Beets in the ground Mother beeta Voaag beet* Surface inoculations Relation to water supply Quantity of inoouiatio: - ".ion of inoculation Saprophytic decav of beet* Secondary organisms completing decay Color and appearance of disease^ Chemical changes in diseased beets Inoculation experiments upon other The organism — &gt;rphological and general characte Form . . . Size kmsmgaUom Motihty and flagella Sporulation Involution forms Staining reaction Wall reactions Pigment </seg>
            <seg id="p005">V sugar-Dee* Red garden beet . . 87 Sugar-beet petiole 87 Sugar-beet leaf. . 91 t»to n Carrot . . White turnip ■ iadish .... Parsnip ... &lt;• Salsif Sweet pota- I • Coooanut . ana Orange. . . M rar-agar a^'ar on inr and cane ■» . . M - g . ane - \ _■ i ia— M ) M and Viioc-h - irmperatur- era hire rstnra I &gt; a Re d- mal tber bacteria on beet an at ■: </seg>
            <seg id="p006"/>
            <seg id="p007">EXPERIMENTAL WORK. The work of the^Experiment Station for the current year has been confined to the following lines, namely : Improvement of corn (1) by selection of varieties in variety tests and (2) by selection of individual plants of de - sirable qualities; tests of varieties of forage crops and mix - tures of grasses and clovers ; tests of varieties of cowpeas and soy beans; cultivation of soil for small grain; effect of manure and grass in crop rotation ; tillage experiments, in - cluding effect of soil aeration, soluble salts, moisture supply and temperature on crop production ; effect of several years' growth of alfalfa upon the productiveness of soil. A study of different amounts of grain with alfalfa pasture in economic pork production ; a study of the effect of ground bone added to a corn ration in pork production; a study of wintering calves on roughness and on roughness with different grain rations; a comparison of corn meal with corn meal and ten per cent oil meal in fattening steers on pas - ture ; a study of rations in fattening steers, in which corn and corn with ten per cent oil meal are fed with prairie hay, alfalfa hay, corn stover, and sorghum. A study of prairie dog and gopher extinction with Pintach gas by-products; a study of contagious abortion; laboratory experiments with hog cholera virus: dipping cattle for mange. A study of diseases of cultivated plants in Nebraska : a study of the grasses and of the poisonous plants in Nebras- A study of the poisonous properties in sorghum and Kafir corn ; a study of the potassium nitrate theory in cornstalk disease; analyses of poisonous weeds in hay and grass; in- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ./ / WFW. ff J.TC-V/ Ofl vestigation of rape for possible poisons injurious to hogs; investigation of methods which may be applied in creameries for the more accurate determination of butter fat in cream ; a study of the chemical composition of various commercial stock foods; a study of the chemical composition of seepage waters from irrigation and of the relation of ex - cessive irrigation to alkali in irrigated soils. K study of various substitutes for butter fat to use with -milk in rearing calves. A study of rations for dairy i; experiments in beef production, using beef bred sires »iry cows. A study of cover crops for orchards, of mulching garden vegetables, pruning and spraying fruit trees, and breeding hardy fruits. Cooperative experiments have been carried on with farmers in extending the winter wheat growing area, in the distribution of Kherson oats, and in testing the leading varieties of corn in different sections of the State; also co - operative experiments with nurserymen in hybridizing fruit Eaperation with the United States Department of Agri - re with macaroni wheats and some grasses and forage ;, and in the distribution of 136,000 doses of blackleg ne. STATION STAFF. I here have been no changes in the Station staff during last year, other than the addition to the staff of Mr. W. Jnyder as Assistant in Animal Husbandry and Assistant erintendent of Farmers' Institutes. IMPROVEMENTS. Iiring the current year numerous additions have been i to the buildings and equipment of the School of Agri - ire by which the Experiment Station will largely benefit. ,iry barn, silo, and judging pavilion, costing $11,000, has constructed. A machinery building costing $11,000 has constructed for instruction in carpenter work and fsmith work and the study of farm machinery. A icultural laboratory and greenhouse has been con - ;ted at a cost of $7,000, for instruction in lines of horti- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 culture and gardening and including laboratories for ex - perimental work. Plans are completed for a School of Agriculture building which will be constructed next summer at a cost of 160,000 with its equipment. In all, (100,000, appropriated by the State Legislature of 1903, will be expended for improvements during the biennium which closes April, 1905. A street railway now runs directly to the Experiment Station, connecting us with the City. NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION. The Legislature of 1903 appropriated $15,000 for the es - tablishment of a substation west of the 100th meridian in Nebraska, the purpose of said station, according to the bill passed,- being "to determine the adaptability of the arid and semiarid portions of Nebraksa to agriculture, horticulture, and forest tree growing, such as the production of grain, grasses, root crops and fruits of kinds commonly grown in the same latitude in other States; also the most economical methods of producing such crops without irrigation." I ing under the authority granted by this act, the Regents of the University, after careful consideration and examination of a number of sites in different localities of the State, accepted a proposition from the Citizens' Committee of North Platte by which a tract of 1920 acres of land three miles south of North Platte was purchased for an experi - mental substation, the people in the vicinity of North Platte donating a considerable part of the purchase price. The North Platte station is admirably adapted to the purposes for which it is intended. It contains about 270 acres of bench land under an irrigation ditch, about 150 acres of level table-land with an elevation of nearly 3,000 feet, and 1,500 acres of rough pasture land covered with buffalo and other grasses, suitable for experiments in the maintenance and improvement of grazing lands. It is hoped that this experiment station will be able to assist in solving impor - tant problems relative to the agriculture of the central and western part of the State. Through the generosity of the people of North Platte in subscribing liberally toward the </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 purchase of this tract of land, enough money was retained by the Regents to operate this experimental farm for the year 1904; but the continuance of experimental -work at the North Platte station will depend upon State appropriations. The importance of this work demands that liberal appropri - ations should be granted for the maintenance of this station. FARMERS' INSTITUTES. Nine members of the Station staff have assisted in Farmers' Institutes during the past winter. The addresses at these meetings have furnished a means of disseminating the results of experimental work among the people and an opportunity for the Station men to , become acquainted with the needs of the farmer. The State Legislature appropria - ted $12,000 of the University funds to carry on the Farmers' Institute work in the State for the biennium closing April, Various state agricultural societies meet with the Uni - versity each year, including the State Board of Agriculture, State Horticultural Society, State Dairymen's Association, State Live Stock Breeders' Association, State Swine Breeders' Association, State Veterinary Medical Associ - ation, State Poultry Association, and the Duroc- Jersey Swine Breeders' Association. All of these have endorsed the work of the Experiment Station. PUBLICATIONS. t accommodate the increased mailing list, the bulletins ow published in editions of 22,000 or upwards. The lal Report, containing the financial statement and some le more technical experimental work of the depart - s, is published in an addition of 2,500 copies. ■be publications of the Station since those named in last Annual Report are as follows : Sixteenth Annual Report. Presented to the Governor January 81, 1903. Bulletin No. 78 (Vol. XV, Art. IV). Macaroni Wheats By T. L. Lyon. Distributed March 11, 1903. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Bulletin No. 79 (Vol. XV, Art. V). Experiments in Orchard Culture. By R. A. Emerson. Distributed idarch 30, 1903. Elletin No. 80 (Vol. XVI, hing Garden Vegetables, ted July 15, 1903. Art. I). Experiments in By R. A. Emerson. Dis- Eilletin No. 81 (Vol. XVI, Art. II). (Sugar Beet Series XII. ) Experiments in the Culture of the Sugar Beet in raska. By T. L. Lyon and A. T. Wiancko. Distributed iember 1. 1903. Press Bulletin No. 18. Pig Feeding Experiment at the Nebraska Experiment Station. By E. A. Burnett and H. R. Smith. Distributed March 16. 1903. ACKNOWLEDGMl Ee various railroads of the State have furnished con - able transportation to assist in carrying on experimen - ork located outside of Lincoln. The agricultural press, especially those papers located within the State, have shown their appreciation of the work of the Experiment Station by [giving a liberal amount of space to the experimental work reported, and in every way facilitating and extending the usefulness of the Experi - ment Station. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 '€ttt OlQflOtl oj rE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA OFFICE OF FINANCIAL SECRETARY rnancial statement for the year ended June 30, 1903. RECE11T9 K received by the State Treasurer from the Treas - r of the United States: installment appropriated the fiscal year ended June 30. 1903, as per act Jongress approved March 2, 1887 $15,000 00 KSEMESTS For salaries ... t 8,774 69 I&gt;abor 1,300 00 Publications 1,229 87 Postage and stationery Freight and •xprei 606 60 83 16 Chemi al supplies 206 05 Seeds, plants and sundry supplies. . . . 500 49 Feeding stuffs 674 69 Library .... 4 77 Tools, implements and machinery 426 78 Furniture and fixture- 53 75 Scientific apparatus 560 06 Live stock 58 00 Traveling expenses 36 55 Contingent expense&gt; 15 00 Buildings and repaii 610 54 S15.000 00 115,000 00 SUPPLEMENTARY STATEMENT Funds from other sources than the United States for the year ended July 81, 1903. Total receipts by the state treasurer Paid, temporary services .... $ 382 78 Postage and stationery . . 71 66 Freight and express .... 110 08 110 08 Chemical supplies. Seeds, plant* and sundry sop| Feeding stuffs PS Library. Tools, implements and ma&lt;hii Furniture and fixtures rv Scientific apparatus Live stock Contingent expenses. Buildings and repairs Balance July 31. 1903 J. S. Da </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 A FUNGUS DISEASE IN CORN. A. T. PETEKS, DEPARTMENT OF ANIMAL PATHOLexa. In 1899 we received a letter from Mr. W. H. of Lynch, describing a very peculiar disease among the domestic animals of Boyd County. From the description given in the letter it was first thought that the disease was due to ergotized grain, but upon investigation no ergot could be found. The general belief of the residents of the infected district was that it was due to an alkali in the water or soil. They gave this affection the name of alkali disease and when an animal became affected it was said that it was "alkalied." This correspondence led to an investigation in July of 1900. The Botanical Department sent a represent - ative, Mr. A. A. Hunter. Mr. Hunter and myself visited a number of farms that had sustained losses from this peculiar disease. We made a thorough investigation of the fields in which these animals were pastured and also of the food that was fed, and found that wherever this disease existed there was a dry rot on the corn. This dry rot was of a pinkish color. On the farms that had never had any trouble of this kind we did not find any diseased corn. This led us to sus - pect that it must be the fungus on the corn that was pro - ducing the disease. As previously mentioned, the disease is similar to that caused by cattle eating ergotized grain. In horses it usually affects the hoofs and there is a slough - ing off of the hoofs at the coronet band. The same effect is seen upon cattle. Fig. 1 shows a horse where the hoof has sloughed. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Ki... 1 ■number of chickens were seen on these infected farms •e there was a great loss of feathers. On all farms :e this trouble existed the eggs were not fertile. Suspecting the grain, a quantity of corn from farms where this trouble existed was shipped to the University farm, where it was fed to some hogs. In a short time it produced the symptoms observed Qn the farms in Boyd County. Pig. 2 shows a hog at the University farm that was fed on this corn. It will be noticed that the bristles have been shed and that the hoofs are sloughing. While in this condition the animals suffer greatly, especially when compelled to move about. The animals become gaunt very rapidly and where this kind of infected feed is con - tinued a large per cent of them finally die. As mentioned, the owners of the infected stock did not at - tribute this trouble to the grain but to the drinking water or to the soil. Samples of water were therefore taken from each farm that was visited, and the Chemical Department made examination to determine whether there was an ex - cessive amount of alkali in the water. It was found that this water was good and that it did not contain an excessive </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 amount of alkali. The trouble could not therefore be due to alkali in the water. Furthermore, alkali could not pro - duce the symptoms that were present. Chemical analyses were also made of the corn but it was found not to contain any abnormality. The fungus found on the corn was not analyzed at that time on account of other work pressing. This fungus will be studied at some future time. As stated, the corn that was sent to the Station and fed to hogs produced the identical disease in them. Another exDeriment was then conducted. The dry mold that was found on the corn was cultivated on crackers and com meal mush, and this was fed to shoats and again the disease was produced, showing once more that this fungus km caused the disease. Again, the facts that peculiar corn having the dry rot on it was found on every farm on which there were diseased animals, and that it was absent on the farms that had never had any trouble, go to show that the disease must be due to the fungus 1 FIELD INVESTIGATE July 17, 19&lt;&gt;0. Mr. A.'A. Hunter and myself investigated the farm of Mr. J. W. H., 3i miles east and 1£ miles north </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 of Lynch. The investigation consisted of examining bis com and oats and the live stock. We found many samples of corn affected on his place. We took samples of water and brought them with us to be analyzed on our return to the laboratory. Mr. H. had some hogs affected at the time of our visit. They were just beginning to recover from the effects of the disease. Mr. H. has had this disease on his farm ever since he came on the place, in 1891. The first seed that he sowed on the farm was some that he brought with him from Knox County. He first noticed the disease on his farm in the fall of 1891, when he began to feed his first crop, corn, to hogs. Seven hogs became affected, 'and all died. The symptoms were : falling out of hair, losing of flesh, and finally losing the hoofs ; then show - ing convulsions. The same fall*he fed cattle on the pasture and hay, and [symptoms similar to those described in the hogs appeared about February, 1892. He has had more or less trouble with this disease ever since. He has had about 100 head of cattle'affected since then, with a loss of two per cent and a damage of 65 per cent. He has had during that time about 300 hogs. 90 per cent became affected, with a loss by death of 80 per cent and a loss finally of 99 per cent. Horses, three affected, with a death of one. Chickens can - not be raised successfully on account of the eggs not being fertile. All of these animals have been fed corn and oats, and pastured, but the disease appeared in each place, with a heavier loss when fed corn. For a long time Mr. H. as well as his neighbors firmly believed that it was due to the water and soil. Mr.'H. however used the'same water for house - hold purposes that^was used for the stock without ill effect to the family. July 17, 1900. Mr. A. R. has been^ on his farm of 160 acres northwest of Mr. H.'s since 1891. He commenced losing cattle in 1892 with^this disease. He brought his first seed from Knox County. The number of cattle affected was 25; loss, 5. Mr. R. claims that these cattle contracted the disease in the pasture for they were not fed grain, so he states. Horses affected,' 10, with a loss of 4. These horses were fed grain and pastured. Hogs affected, 200, with a </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 R. has been of the opinion that the trouble was duo to the July 17, 1900. Mr. M. P. of Lynch lived west of Mr. .1. W. H.'s place for about four months. His brother liv*'d there before him, and had this disease on the place more or less for the last number of years and bad about 50 hogs affected, with a recovery of about une-third. He had some mulos affected. We also found diseased corn on this farm. July 17, 1900. Mr. F. H. has lost animals for the las - years and had about the same success as his brothers. We Pimined some oats which he had left in the granary and ich were 3 years old. and took some of the same with us the laboratory for a final examination. He claimed that of these oats produced the disease in Knox Count . arm where he took some of these oats with him to feed. July 17, 1900. Mr. J. M. has had the disease on his place for a number of years. He has been on the farm since He lost quite a good deal of stock. He believes that the dis - ease is in the water more or less. We found a great quar tity of diseased corn on his place. July 18, 1900. Called at Mr. B.'s farm which has al been affected with this fungus, though he bad no corn on his place at this time. On account of the seriousness of the trouble for a number of years past, he was going to sell his farm at a sacrifice. July 19, ISoO. Mr. J. M. M. had this trouble for five .v only in horses. They took this disease chiefly when on pasture, in fact he claimed only on pasture. Since livincr on the farm he has had about 10 head affected. All horses affected drank the same water that the rest of the stock had with the exception of the last two affected. They were watered out of Ponca creek. July 19, 1900. Mr. C. E. B. lived on his farm for e! years and had the trouble more in horses than in any other animals. He has had about 10 animals affected. Mr. B. claimed that all these animals received no grain, and that they were only fed on'pasture. He admitted that a number </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 of horses have been in the pasture for many years without becoming affected. Mr. B. claims that in his neighborhood it is only in the pasture. Illy 20, 1900. Called at Mr. J. K. 's place but he was not ome. We examined his corn and found that it was quite y affected. We took a sample of his corn with us. He lost hogs and cattle. fly 20, 1900. Called at Mr. A. M. 's farm and found that »rn was quite badly affected. He lost cattle and hogs, aid that he thought it was in the pasture. He has lived le place about six years and has had the trouble more or during that time. July 20. 1900. Called and examined Mr. S. W.'s farm and his corn. There was not very much left of his old crop and we could not find any diseased corn. He claimed that he never had any trouble on his farm with any of his stock. Ily 20, 1900. Called and examined Mr. P. S.'s farm and but could not find any diseased corn. He never had trouble with his stock. We examined a horse that had i disease and found a lacerated tongue. No other dis - d stock on the place. July 17, 1900. Mr. C. M. had the disease brought on his place by buying diseased corn from infected farms. The corn that Mr. M. raised on his own farm was free from dis - ease but the corn he bought was heavily infected. Ily 19, 1900. Mr. J. M. McG. lives at the edge of town. le winter of 1898-1899 he bought some corn from a sus - jd farm owned by Mr. S. and fed it to hogs, cattle, and bs, with the result that the hogs and cattle soon became ted alike. Hogs soon lost their hair and hoofs. Cows n losing their hair and tails. He then began feeding i freely on bran and soon checked the disease. It also ted the chickens so that they lost their feathers and the would not hatch that season. As soon as new feed administered the trouble stopped. July 20, 1900. Mr. W. C. lives two miles south and one mile west of town. Mr. C. had trouble when he bought corn from Messrs. H. in the year I'iW. He fed this corn to hogs and horses. The corn was fed to </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 I lead of hogs and all but 26 became affected. One horse me affected. The next year he bought 300 bushels from G. and raised 26 pigs out of 174. He claimed that little pigs would be perfectly healthy but soon would n to lose their hoofs and from the excruciating pain vary soon. The 26 pigs that Mr. C. raised were from 5 that were not fed any of Mr. G. 'scorn, or, in other words, diseased corn. July 20, 1900. Mr. F. H. of Lynch never had any trouble when he fed the corn that he raised on his own farm. He had trouble about six years ago on his farm, but has had no trouble sicce, which he thinks is on account of changing the seed each year. We found no diseased corn on his place. Kily 20, 1900. Examined Mr. L. K. 'a corn but could not any diseased ears on it He bought corn some years from Mr. H. and had the disease, but he has changed corn almost every year and has had no trouble since. Illy 17, 190O. Called on Mr. J. H. and found his corn much affected with this characteristic fungus. He has lost horses, cattle, hogs, and chickens with this dis - for a number of years. His farm adjoins that of his her, J. W. H. J. H. has been on this farm since 1891 and used corn of his own raising for seed ever since r the year 1900 did the disease seem somewhat milder fr. J H.'s place, and he attributes this to the fact that lad bought some new seed corn that spring and also ed over all of the diseased ears, which he thought ed the trouble. Mr. H. lost some cows and hogs some e years ago. This spring Mr. H.'s cows lost their es through abortion. Iily 17, 1900. Mr. J. P. had lived on his place, half a from J. W. H.'s farm, since 1891. He had been bled with this disease ever since he fed his first crop. :hiefly lost cattle, hogs, and chickens. He said the only ■ that he had no trouble since he has been on the farm in 1 H 94, during the dry year, when he received help on unt of not having any crop on his place, but the next • it was as bad as ever. This is the first year that Mr. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Kicked over his corn, and it is the first litter of pigs that las been able tm raise since being on the place. He it some of the diseased corn for fuel. Ily 17, 19»K&gt;. Mr. J. S. of Lynch has had the disease on arm for eight years with a very heavy loss. The stock fed chiefly on corn, We found a great quantity of dis - i corn on his place. The last six months he has had ;r success than at any other time while on the place, ttributed this success to the picking over of hisdist and burning the same, only feeding the best ears to his Illy 17, 1900. Mr. N. P. had trouble on his place for :s. He lives three miles east and one mile north of ch. He lost a number of hogs, cattle, and horses. We id diseased corn on his place. He has been picking over same for some time. He supposed that it was his soil was affected with this disease. The first two years they were on the place they boiled all their feed and no trouble. They boiled the feed on account of scar - of food; not as a preventive measure. They also com - ned that all of their eggs are unfertile and will not Illy 18. 1900. Called on Mr. A. Z. and found that he had i on his place for the last nine years and has heen more ess troubled all that time. Last year he loaned two ses to a neighbor who had infected corn and the hi ,me affected, but when returned soon made a recoverv. ; years ago he had some trouble in raising chickei unt of the eggs not hatching. Mr. Z. has picked over corn and has quite a quantity of worm-eaten corn, as iJaimed it to be, on his place, but at this time had no July 18. 19001 Mr. S. C. lives eight miles from Lynch and has lived on his farm nine years this fall. Ever since his first crop he has had more or less trouble with his pig*. The last two years he has had some trouble with his horses. The first five years he soaked the corn and he h'ad no trouble with the stock to which soaked corn was fed. Since discontinuing the same he has had trouble with his horses. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 I links it can be avoided by soaking or by picking over orn. He also fed diseased and wormy corn to his hogs soaked the best clean ears and fed them to his horses. He that when following this practice he had no trouble with iorses but did have with his hogs. Ily SO, 19*30. Mr. E. A. C. said that ever since he picked his corn he has had no trouble with his stock but ys had trouble if he neglected to do this one important c of picking over all the corn. KJuly 24, 190t&gt;. samples of water were received from County and submitted to the chemist for examination. s thought that the loss of stock might be due to e:&lt;&gt; ■quantities of alkali in ber of grains of matter r was as follows: their drinking water. The in solution in each gallon of Samples J. H., Lynch, Nebr llo.T A Z., •' • ■ " 1 33.75 .. B., " '• 21.00 J. W. O., " - B" 1 e amounts are rather high compared with the amounts Blids in water found in most parts of the State. Mineral rs, however, of high reputation for medicinal pur] i contain far greater quantities. They are about the same as the waters from many wells in the arid regions. Of more interest, however, is a consideration of the nature of the solids in solution. It was found that they consist almost entirely of calcium and magnesium sulphates and car - bonates. This is the same solution that we would get by Iving gypsum, Epsom salt, and chalk in water contain - ing carbonic acid. Evidently such a solution would repre - sent very '"hard" water_but could not possibly produce the symptoms previously described in this paper. No trace of </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 A sample of apparently healthy corn from Boyd County, used as a check, gave no evidence of ergot. A sample of apparently infected corn, which had produced in pigs a dis - ease having all the appearance of ergotism, was submitted to a chemical examination. Hofmann's test showed the presence of ergot. SUMMARY. K Affected corn from farms where the trouble ex uced the same disease when shipped to the Experiment on and fed on un infected ground. Investigations showed that the mold was identical on all diseased corn examined. IThe dry mold found on the corn was cultivated on ers and corn meal mush, which when fed produced the se. KThe corn having this peculiar dry rot was on every 1 where the disease existed and was absent where the ble did not exist. ■ When the affected corn was soaked it did not produce disease. 6. Where the use of this corn was discontinued, the dis - ease disappeared. »It could not have been alkali in the water, for the r did not contain an excessive amount of alkali ; ler could alkali have produced the disease. 8. It could not have been due to ergot, for none was found in the grain and gelds. ■ Chemical examination of the corn showed no abnor - condition. Chemical investigations of the fungus are now in progress. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 A CORN MOLD. ( Fusarium mon iliform JOHN L. SHELDON.* !In the winter of 1900-01, when there was so much being *id about the damage done to cattle from eating moldy orn. I became interested in the mold, that is, interested to now what one mold among several thousand it might be nat was reported to cause the damage, and how it affected tie cattle. Mr. Hunter, who was assisting Dr. Peters In tie investigation of the moldy corn disease, showed me ome of the moldy ears, and also gave me a few kernels. 7hile I had frequently seen corn with a reddish mold on it, specially immature ears of sugar corn that had been husked and allowed to lie in a warm, damp place, and thought little about it, still, the stories that were current of horses, cows, and hogs losing their hair and hoofs, and of hens losing their feathers and toe-nails, were sufficient to excite some incredulity and curiosity on my part, as well as make me rather cautious about handling the stuff. Cultures of the mold were made on crackers that had been placed in a hot oven for a few minutes in order to kill any other molds or bacteria that might happen to be on them. The crackers were then placed in covered glass dishes and slightly moistened with distilled water. Small pieces of the mold were picked out of the kernels of corn with a needle and planted, as one plants seeds, on the moistened •John Lewis Sheldon, Ph. L)., now Plant Pathologist of the Virginia Experiment Station and Professor of Bacteriology in the Wen Virginia University. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 crackers. The dish was kept eovered and in a warm room. The next day small white tufts of the mold began to show a the plantings had been made ; they increased in size rapidly until the mold completely covered the crackers likf a mass of down. But instead of tne mold remaining white was at first, it began to show a pink color, finally changing to a rich salmon, with here and there a spot of blue and black. The blue and black spots were due to the presence of blue and black molds which are common every - where on pastry, fruits and vegetables. The blue and black molds were "weeded out'" where they were not abundant, and new cultures started from the salmon-colored I bout this time Dr. Peters sent me ten samples of corn a as many different farms, each sample consisting of q one to three ears, with the request that I examine n. All of the samples showed large spots of a pink d, and several other spots in small amounts. Evidently 7 had been selected for the one mold. The kernels ire the pink mold was present were considerably broken tie ends and crumbly, so that when shaken or struck on table, the inside would fall out in the form of a coarse Portions of the moldy kernels from each ear were ex - amined with a microscope, and found to consist principally arch grains, branched thread-like pieces of the mold and an enormous number of somewhat elongated, egg - shaped and sickle-shaped bodies, the fruit or spores of the mold. The sickle-shaped spores were for the most part divided crosswise by one or more partitions (septa), usually three (fig. 1), and recognized as belonging to a group of molds called Fusarium, The other molds present were also examined and found to be an Aapt rgiUut, a Penidttium, and a black mold the name of which was not determined. One ear which was pink was also gummy, instead of crumbly like the others, and became slimv when wet; it contained besides the Fumrtum a large number of exceedingly small, rod -shaped objects, bacteria. The effect of the Fun alone on the corn is similar to the dry rot of the potato, </seg>
            <seg id="p025">25 which is caused by a mold of the same name; and, when the bacteria are present to any considerable extent, to the wet rot of the potato. Moldy corn from several localities besides those from which the samples referred to were collected, has been ex - amined, a number from corn that was being fed to some horses and hogs at the Experiment Station. The mold or fungus may generally be recognized by the pink color and the broken, crumbly ends of the kernels. When it grows between the kernels and on the husks, it may be nearly white or with only a shade of pink, a mass of very fine tangled threads. The only sure way to distin - guish it from some other pink fungi is to examine it with a microscope. The peculiar sickle-shaped and septate spores are characteristic of a Fuaarbtm. It attacks the end of the kernel first, gradually working its way toward the cob. How the fungus gets on to the corn in the first place is a difficult question to answer, but it is probable that it does so after the corn is husked, or when the ears become ex - posed or fall on the ground in the field. The practice of allowing the corn to remain on the ground after it is husked is a bad one, especially when it is exposed to the rain and snow. If the fungus is already on a few of the ears, it will spread through the entire pile in a short time if the happens to be somewhat green or moist. In handling the moldy corn, the spores and pieces of the fungus threads or filaments which are in the ends of the kernels are shaken out and scattered through the pile. If the corn which the spores fall upon is slightly moist, they germinate almost immediately and begin to feed upon the corn. Corn that is not thoroughly dry and mature when put into a pile is liable to "•heat" and "sweat." 'Heating" and "sweating" are among the best possible conditions for the growth of the fungus. The spores of the fungus are probably able to live in the soil for some time, or the fungus itself in the pieces of corn and husks at the bottom of the pile. When the corn is re - moved from the pile the spores are scattered about. The spores are so small, the largest being only about one five- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 tedth of an inch long, that they are easily washed &gt;ne place to another by the rain and blown about by nd. In order to find out what the fungus would do soil, some moldy kernels were planted in a flowerpot piece of glass placed over the top of the pot to keep il from drying out. In a few days the delicate white ats of the fungus began to grow out of the kernels and er the pieces of dead leaves and stems in the soil, all appearanees the fungus seemed to grow as well on ad material in the soil as it did on corn and crackers. In order to watch the development and growth of the fungus more closely than can be done when it is growing on corn, or any other substance which is not more or less transparent, and to separate it from other fungi and bacteria which are usually found growing with it, pure cultures were made. All the apparatus and media on which it was grown were repeatedly sterilized before an attempt was made to obtain a pure culture. The pure cultures were obtained by placing a few spores from the corn into a test-tube of liquefied bouillon-agar, and after shaking it well, the contents of the tuba was carefully poured into a Petri dish, making what is known as a poured plate. By this process the spores became scattered through the plate, so that when they germinated they could either be transferred to another plate by cutting out small pieces of the agar, or the other fungi and bacteria could be removed. In this way it was possible to study the fungus obtained from a single spore, but on account of its small size it was rather difficult. By making what is termed a drop culture, it was possible by the aid of the microscope to watch it from the time a spore was placed in a drop of nutrient medium until after it had fruited and the new spores had dropped off, and they in turn had germinated and produced spores. A drop culture was made by putting a drop of some medium like bouillon-agar on a thin piece of glass (cover-glass), putting one or more spores in the drop and then inverting the cover-glass over the hollow in a glass slide. The cover-glass was held in place by putting vaseline around the edges. In about twenty-four hours after the spores were placed in the drop. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">27 they had germinated and new rapidly growing filaments. spores were produced on the </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Iutline drawings of the fungus were made by means of microscope and camera lucida, and while they are not stic. they may serve to give a better idea of what the rus is than can be done with words alone. All the out - s are drawn to the same scale and are about 4uo times natural size. I he spores vary considerably in shape and size both in cultures and when taken from the corn. Those in fig. :e taken from a kernel of corn. It will be noticed that T are from one to five celled and from egg-shaped to ewhat curved, sickle-shaped, and spindle-shaped. The spores increase in size during germination, a filament growing from either end, and, in case of the several-celled spores, may grow from the side, but usually only the end cells germinate (figs. 2-9). As the filaments increase in length and become older, septa are formed in them. The age and size at which the filaments begin to fruit varies. Sometimes a considerable growth occurs before any spores are formed, and then the new spores form soon after the old spore germinates, a very short filament being produced (tigs 2, 3, 5-7). The spores are formed for the most part on the ends of branches from the principal filaments, the direction which the branches take depending upon where the fungus grows, but they generally grow upward the same as the branches on other plants. The filaments would grow upward in the medium until they touched the under surface of the cover-glass, when th.?y would turn to one side and grow close up against it. This afforded an opportunity to see how the spores formed. A small knob appears on the end of the branch ; it grows longer and larger around, a septum is formed separating it from the remainder of the branch from which it finally drops off. The time which it required for a spore to form before it dropped off varied with the amount of food present, the temperature and moisture, being under favorable conditions about ten to fifteen minutes, about as long as it requires to describe in detail what takes place. Other spores are pro - duced in the same way. The spores after falling off may germinate at once or continue to grow in the medium and be- </seg>
            <seg id="p029">29 come septate (figs. 10-12, 13a). There is usually one septum formed across the middle of the spores and sometimes two, so that the spores are either two (fig. I* 1 ) or three (fig. 11) celled, other septa forming later (fig. 12). There occurred repeatedly in the cultures single celled spores which were in chains (figs. 13b, 14, 15). These spores were not borne on the older portions of the filaments but on the younger ones where the branches, instead of re - maining in or on the surface of the medium, extended out into the air. The spores in chains could not be accounted for for a long time. It was first thought that there were two fungi instead of one, although every precaution seemed to have been taken to obtain pure cultures from single spores, and that in spite of the care that was taken, in some way another fungus had gotten into the cultures. An en - tire day was spent in watching the spores form on a single filament (fig. 13) and the changes which they underwent. It was found that those that were formed in the medium either germinated after they fell off from the branches or continued to grow in the medium and became septate (fig. 13a), while those that formed in the air were either in bunches (figs. 13b, 14a, 16) or in chains, and that I stages might occur on the same filament as shown in tig. 13a, b. The chain of spores shown in fig. 13b extended out into the air, while the remainder of the filament was in the medium, which will account for the loose spores scat about the ends and sides of some of the branches. As the branches grow and the spores are produced one after an - other, the spores are pushed to one side (fig. 10) or remain packed together (fig. 7). The single-celled spores are produced during the active growth of the fungus. The number of spores that might be produced by a plant originating from a single spore under favorable conditions in even one day is probably in the thousands and possibly in the millions. Each spore under favorable conditions will produce a separate fungus, so that it will be readily seen with what rapidity a large £of moist corn mav become moldy during a few warm in autumn, if spores of the fungus become scat 1 ugh it. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 The sickle- shaped septate spores seem to be the ones that retain their vitality during unfavorable conditions. The kernels previously referred to contained very few septate spores when planted, and those that were septate had but one septum. The kernels were examined a few days after they were planted and most of the spores were then of the septate kind. Whether the conditions were unfavorable in the soil, or whether the septate spores are the ones that carry the fungus over from one year to the next, will require further investigation. Several other species of Fuaarium which are the cause of plant diseases have been grown in connection with the one on the corn, and comparisons made between them. None of them, with the exception of one found on the beat, produced spores in chains. A search auions the available literature fails to throw any light on the subject, no Fusarimn being described which produces spores in chains, although there are several which it resembles in other ways and it may be only a form of one of them. Until it is ascertained that this particular Futarhm has been described it may be known as ium iHuiiHifiH-mr. The color of the mass of filaments and the size of the three septate spores are characteristic of a number of species which have been reported as occur - ring on corn, but the one-celled spores borne in chains are very characteristic of this particular one on corn. It may be briefly described as follows: Kporoilochiutn, subeffuse, salmon-pink; sporophores, simple or usually opposite; microconidia, continuous, oblong-ovoid, iiforni, 6-10u Ion;;; macroconidia, falcate, acute, for the most part Late. 23-40u long. |»e mold has the ability to grow on a number of things ies those mentioned. To see what effect different foods [d have upon it, and whether it was confined to starchy s like corn and crackers, it was tried on several. It i fairly well on the following, better of course on some on others: rice-starch, corn-starch, sago, tapioca, wroot, bouillon-gelatin, bouillon-agar, asparagus-agar, to, glycerin-agar, asparagin-agar, galactose-agar, ocol-agar, grape-sugar, peptone-agar, and one per cent erin water. When this fungus and some other species </seg>
            <seg id="p031">31 of Ftuotivm were grown on media containing glycerin, the medium wai 'colored various shades of red, the shade of color depending to some extent on the species, approach - ing violet in some instances. Cultures made in a Liborius tube filled with glycerin-nutrient solution-agar would indi - cate that it can grow without air. The spores germinated in the agar near the bottom of the tube and the filaments gradually pushed their way through the agar to the top, where they covered the agar. A pink layer appeared on the top of the agar due to the action of the fungus on the glycerin, and gradually extended downward in the tube. Per it had been determined that it could grow on some e animal products, such as bouillon, gelatin, and rin, it was tried on pieces of sterilized fresh pork, i it grew as well as it did on corn. Whether it will on a living animal or not is a problem for some one to work out. N&lt; irgaard* describes an epidemic skin disease among the horses on the Umatilla Indian Reservation, Pendleton, Oregon, in which "the disease manifests itself through severe itching and loss of hair over almost the entire body. The animals remain around the rubbing posts all day, and a number of them die from starvation." An examination of Rmples of the skin demonstrated the presence of an itch iptra "/"')• but he did not think them present in fficient numbers to account for the almost complete loss of hair. Microscopic examination of sections of the skin showed the presence of spindle- or si«kle-shaped bodies in the hair sacs and sebaceous glands. When pure cultures were made by pulling out some of the hairs and placing th»&gt; roots in agar, in the course of a few days a fungus appeared which grew rapidly and assumed a salmon-pink color. When the fungus was examined with the microscope, '"numerous sickle-shaped -segmented spores, char of Fumrium" were found. Mayo+ attributes a disease called "staggers" to the feed - ing of moldy corn, the mold being an . uther .raard, Victor A. Science 14 S Bali. Mi Kansas Agr. Kxp Sta. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 tltltl'Hl I Ka Fuaarmm. He seems to think that the funeus enters :irculation in some way and finally becomes lodged in kidneys and liver, his conclusion being based on some iriments made by him on a guinea-pig and a colt. Bitting* made an investigation of the loss from cerebro - spinal meningitis which is attributed in some parts of the country to feeding moldy corn. He separated two molds and a bacterium from the corn, and fed cultures of them. One of the molds and the bacterium gave no results, but the other mold, a Ftuarium, produced a redness of the gums, insalivation, and an intestinal disturbance. tis well known that bacteria and other fungi are the s of diseases in domestic animals, but investigations of kind belong to the veterinarian rather than to the 1st. At the request of Dr. Peters, I examined some bristles and scabs from a pig that was being fed moldy corn. Lace were present to some extent. On the outside of the scabs I found starch erains and the sDores of some fungus, in all probability those of the Fusarium which was growing on the corn being fed. There were no spores nor starch grains found on the under side of the scabs next tu the skin. The finding of the starch grains and spores on the outside of the scabs can be readily accounted for, from the possibility that the pig may have been lying on the pieces of moldy corn scattered about in the pen, or the other pig in the pen with him may have given him a gentle root in the side when they were eating, or he may have rubbed his itching sides with his own nose. At a post-mortem examination of a horse that had been fed on moldy corn, I made a rather superficial examination of the blood, kidneys, and liver, but nothing was observed which indicated the presence of fungus fila - ments or spores. It would be strange if one did not, find tungus spores or bacteria on almost any part of an animal that had been dissected and which had been previously fed on moldy corn, unless extreme care were taken. I was obliged to discontinue the investigation at this t on account of other duties. The most important re - i have been given in this report. •Bitting. A. W. Bull. Indiana Agr. Ex, </seg>
            <seg id="p033">33 HEREDITY IN BEAN HYBRIDS BY K. A. EMEK Two years ago the writer published an account of a pre - liminary study of bean hybrids.* The paper dealt exclu - sively with the kinds of combinations of parent characters found in hybrids, without any attempt to show the numerical relation existing between the types. In fact, the numbers of individuals of the various hybrids which had been grown up to that time were so few that accurate statis - tical treatment was impossible. Since then, much larger numbers of individuals have been grown. Still larger numbers would undoubtedly have given the results more value, but at the present time, when problems of heredity are receiving so much attention from plant and animal breeders, as well as from biologists, any evidence, however meager, is of value. Mendel's experiments in hybridization opened a new line of inquiry. His principles of heredity are now well understood, but of the exact range of their application comparatively little is as yet known. The pres - ent paper is a discussion of the writer's work with bean hybrids in the light of Mendel's discoveries. The methods of work employed recently have been prac - tically the same as described in the former paper. The only important difference is that to protect the hybrid plants from insects that might cross-pollinate them they have been grown under one large frame enclosed in wire cloth, instead *Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Rpt. 15 (1902), pp. 30-48. (Ph&lt;i </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 I oder small individual screens as formerly. While it ot be positively asserted that no cross-pollination has i place between the hybrids grown in this way, it is ,in that the possibility of crossing, which is com par a - y small even in open culture, has been reduced to a min - i. Plants of the parent races of all hybrids have been n in the enclosure with the hybrids and no evidence of »ing between these races has been apparent. In all work oss-pollination, the flowers have first been emasculated, writer has never been able to use the method employed sehermak*, of pollinating the stigmas made to protude unopened flower buds by manipulation of the wing The characters discussed in this paper relate to habit of plants, strineriness of pods, toughness of pods, color of pods, color of flowers, and color of seeds. Records have also been kept of the shape of seeds, but since the work is being carried on in cooperation with Professor Haven Met - calf, of Clemson College. South Carolina, and since the work is not yet complete, publication is deferred until later. The characters studied are not so sharply defined as Mendel found similar characters in peas or even in beans. While this makes it more difficult to group the individual plants in the study of any character, and therefore more difficult to interpret results, the work has an added interest, since characters of a "more or less" nature have been avoided (perhaps wisely) in much of the work done by other experi - menters. PLANT HABIT. Itans are often classed according to habit, as either pole iush. Pole beans are commonly long, twining vines, tically prostrate except where provided with poles or r devices for support. Bush beans are usually short, i, non-twining plants. At one time these two forms i regarded as distinct species, F%tutahu tntiffaris and In Mendel's experiments with beans, these two ies were crossed. The only characters in regard to ■•Tschermak, E. "Weitere Beitrage Qber Verschiedenwerthigkeit Merkmal bei Kreutzung von Erbsen und Bonen." Berichte der ichen botaaischen Gesellschaft, Jahrgang 19 (1901), pp. 35-57. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">35 habit mentioned by Mendel as distinguishing the two species ard, a dwarf axis for / and a long axis (10 to 12 feet) for P. vulgari*. At present the two forms are re - garded as belonging to one species. Certain races like Marrow and Navy which for purposes of culture are classed with the bush beans are really intermediate between the true bush and pole types and may be better termed runner )eans. In some ways they resemble pole beans much more han they do bush beans. In length of axis they are usually ntermediate. They do not commonly twine sufficiently to climb a support like pole beans, nor are they erect like bush beans, but have runners two to four feet long. The difference between runner beans and pole beans is largely one of length of axis and of the degree of development of the power of twining about objects. Circumnutation is best developed in pole beans but not infrequently seen in runner races and not entirely wanting in some races of bush beans, as evidenced by the twisting of the stems, especially where the conditions encourage a rather tall growth. Moreover, as is well known by gardeners, runner beans and pole beans are not always easily distinguished. Runner beans grown in very rich soil and supplied with an abundance of moisture, often acquire the power of climbing supports like pole beans. Lessening the intensity of the sunlight has somewhat the same effect. In hybrids between bush and runner races, pole beans are very frequent; likewise runner beans often appear in hybrids between pole and bush races. In fact, the gradation between the pole and runner forms in hybrids is so complete that one is very frequently puzzled in attempt - ing to separate a number of individuals into the two groups. The difference between bush beans and the other two types, however, is quite distinct. While in general the pole and runner forms in a lot of hybrids have much longer axes than the bush forms, this difference cannot always be relied upon. It is not uncommon to find bush plants with longer axes than other plants that are classed as runner beans. The one difference that is characteristic in all cases which have come under the writer's observation is that runner </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 and Dole beans continue the elongation of their axes some - what indefinitely, pod clusters continuing to develop axially as long as the plant continues to grow, while bush beans produce many pods or pod clusters at about the same time on all of the usually numerous and short branches, after which the axes cease to elongate, making the pods appear as if borne terminally. During the past year I have found an occasional plant which produced several clusters of pods close together and later sent out a short runner bearing axillary pods. Such plants, while possibly intermediate be - tween the true bush and runner forms, have been classed as runners. From the progeny of these plants, next gener - ation, it should be easy to determine whether this classifi - cation is correct. Iom the foregoing it is obvious that the types of plant t in beans cannot be regarded as intft-etoracfera. There at least three distinct characters concerned, namely: th of plant axis, long or short, with numerous inter - iate lengths; twining habit, developed in various de - s or not at all; and position of pods, axial or terminal, le writer's experiments, the two characters first named s been neglected except in some of the most recent £; the latter alone will receive attention in this paper. Ii the records following, the parent races with axial pods e and runner beans) are marked ".I." and those with linal pods (bush beans) are indicated by " </seg>
            <seg id="p037">&gt;d Ht-ijort 37 Table l.—PlattikabH mtw»—Jhrt Number of plants of 1st generation. Pods F( ** a axial. _T*1, ■ I Numl 2 plant! z _ srener - Parentage. Parentage. 1 Pods minal Navy .1. X Challenge Black T 236 Navy .1. X Challenge Black T i 3 297 •• •• X Warwick T I 297 " "X Warwick T 370 Warwii k T X Navy .1 370 Warwii k T X Navy .1 Navy .IX Paris 7'. . ivy A. X Paris T 2 I" " &gt; ■■ - &gt; •' •■ X " - ... 528 " -X ""... 1 501 Paris T. X Navy .1 501 Paris 7'. X Navy .1 607 " " X " " 607 " "X •' " 434 Ultra T. X 434 Ultra T. X 538 " " X " ■ MM " " X " " 540 " "X " ■ 4 540 I " "X " " .I....4 401 Navy A. X 30^« 1' .. .. X •• •• 4 401 Navy A. X 2«'« 2' .. .. X •• •• 4 :m 2o;o T. x J«iy -l ; :m 2o;o r. x J«iy -l (ilO Davis T. X " (ilO Davis T. X " ■' ■■•■ H39 July .I.X Davi- :«9 July .IX L&gt;avi «11 '• '• X Warwick T till '• '• X Warwick T 44i; Marrow .1. x 2070 T. :: :: ; :: :: £ i'aris r 44li Marrow A. X 2070 T. JEO '*')&lt;' * ' 458 "X " '• I •• x Ultra T 511 •■ "X '■ 515 ■ X '• ...1 442 Ultra T. x Marrow .1 4 461 " " X " " 2 •■ X " ■ •• "X " '.... I Total | 109 ! 4 Disposition of the pods along the axis is. here clearly dominant, 109 first-generation plants having exhibited this character and only four the opposite allelomorph,* terminal *The terminology adopted in this paper is after Bateaou and Saunders, "Experimental Studies in the Physiology of Heredity," Re- ports to the Evolution Committee of the Royal Society, I, (1901), p. 196. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 arrangement of pods. The four plants with pods arranged terminally are almost without question not hybrids at all, but are merely individuals of the race used as maternal parent, Ultra. The second- generation plants which will be grown from seeds of these plants next year will prove whether this belief is correct. It is not uncommon to secure occasional seeds, even when great care is used in emasculating the flower buds before they open. The evidence in favor of the belief that the four plants referred to are pure Ultra individuals instead of hybrids,' should be noted. In hybrid No. 488. Ultra x Marrow, the two plants that have pods arranged terminally, failed to show the in - fluence of Marrow pollen in any character, while the other two plants, with pods axially disposed, show this influence in almost every character, just as do the other hybrids of the same parentage. The seeds of the two first-named plants are yellow-brown and the pods long and slender like the seeds and pods of Ultra, while the two last-named plants have pods that show plainly something of the broad char - acter of the Marrow pods, and seeds spotted, yellow-brown, red-brown, and white, characteristics of Ultra-Marrow hy - brids. In case of hybrid No. 538, the two plants with terminal pods are like all true Ultra plants, as noted in case of the plants of hybrid No. 488. The one individual of hybrid No. 538 that has axial pods has seeds plainly inter - mediate in size and shape between the small, round Navy seeds and the larger, longer seeds of Ultra. Moreover the color of the seeds of this one plant is typical of the Ultra- Navy hybrids, being mottled, black, and dull grayish Bie behavior of second-generation hybrids with respect :ial and terminal arrangement of pods is recorded in the wing table: Kl is interesting to note, incidentally, the difference in seed color of enermtion individuals of Ultra-Marrow and Ultra-Navy hybrids, the seed* of both Navy and Marrow are entirely white. A case r to that of the Ultra-Navy hybrids here noted was reported by •mak. who crossed a white-seeded race with one having light seeds. Ber deutsch bot. Gesellsch. Jahrg. 19 (1901); p 61. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">39 1 ABLE II. — / /" "*n — 9COOYld~Qtni6T€tf i ' First Number of plants genera- 1 of second gener i tion. tion. Parentage. Z Pod Pod* Pods ;iO8 _ i " axial, terminal. j 101 Keeney.l x G..ld™ Wax T. ... 102 " '• X Davis 7 Navy .1 &lt; Challenge Black T 1 t'minl 1 5 •■ " x •• ■ •• ... I ■ ■ Warwick T 1 " 11 I 370 Warwick T. X Navy .1 1 BNavy A. X Paris t i - 5 - - x - - I 501 Paris T. X Nary A ...2 I'ltra T. X •' :: :: i : ■ x Marrow .t. 511 Marrow A X Ultra T ' • x Paris T 445 B Davis T. x July .1 1 July A. X Davit T. I t" " X Warwick T 1 " .^_. - 3 Tota -• .118 Ihe recessive allelomorph, terminal pods, occurs in the md generation together with the dominant allelomorph, ,1 pods, there being 324 plants with the latter and 118 l the former habit, or a ratio of 2.75 : 1, very close to Mendelian ratio of 3 : 1. Kly a single hybrid of the few carried to the third gener - has given results of statistical value. The record of ihavior is presented in the following table. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Table lll. — PUint habit— pa —third-g\ hybrid — .V Number of plants of third gen - eration. Second generation. Pods Pods axial, termina Pod position l I H 3 HA B1 II- 1 32 4 88 From Table III it is seen that the recessive allelomorph, terminal position of pods, which occurred in the second generation bred true in the third generation, the nine second-generation plants having produced 130 plants in the third generation (Group 1). Of the 19 plants exhibiting the dominant allelomorph, axial position of pods, in the second generation, nine plants (Group 2) produced, in the third generation, 225 plants, all of which had axially-disposed pods. The 10 plants (Group 3), however, that showed the domi- &gt;. T.) Terminal 1-4 ...14 1-7 :: i - 4-3 4-10 ** » '»J7 II 8-3 4 4-1 Y...AU 4-4 28 10 4-13 .'.'.'.'. ..9 TouLTerminal ' \m Axial </seg>
            <seg id="p041">41 nant character in the second generation produced, in the third generation, both dominants and recessives, 270 of the former and 75 of the latter, or a ratio of 3.6 : 1, the dominants be - ing somewhat in excess of the Mendelian exnectatior. With respect to the allelomorphs in question, therefore, the individuals in Groups 1 and 2, Table III, are to be regarded as homozvgotes, and those in Group 3 as heterozygotes. The relative number of heterozygous and homozygous forms among the dominants of the second generation, as shown by the behavior in the third generation, is not in close con - formity with the expected ratio of two to one, the actual ratio being 1.1 : 1. The purity of the recessive form is further shown by the behavior of hybrid No. 102 (Keeney A. x Davis 7"). In the second generation (Table II), seven individuals with terminal pods were produced. One of these was selected for further trial and has bred true to the seventh generation. As illustrating the change in our ideas regarding hybrids that has come with the conception of unU-ckaractert, the following records of multiple hybrids are interesting. Some of the primary hybrids of the races Marrow, Navy, Paris, and Ultra/recorded in Table I were again crossed in such a way that the original parentage of the multiple crosses consisted of all the four races above named. Be - fore Mendel had taught us the necessity of considering the units concerned in heredity to be the separate characters of an individual rather than the individual or the race as a whole, we should likely have regarded the following hy - brids as practically identical, namely : (Paris x Ultra) x (Navy x Marrow) (Paris x Navy) x (Ultra x Marrow). (Ultra x Navy) x (Marrow x Paris). We should doubtless have regarded each of the hybrids as one fourth Marrow, one fourth Navy, one fourth Paris, and one fourth Ultra. As a matter of fact the ultimate progeny of these hybrids may be much the same but their behaviors in the early generations are very dissimilar, as seen by the following table. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Table IV — /■ —multipL Number of plants. * n Parentage 1 1 Tot'l T. x A. and .1 i -, I .... ..17 A. X .4 In regard to position of pods, the individuals of Group 1 behaved exactly like, rii hybrids, the dominant character, axial position of pods, alone appearing in all of the K plants, while the individuals of Group 2 behaved like 'generation hybrids, there being 58 plants with the dominant character and 17 with the recessive character, a ratio of 3.4 : 1. As a matter of fact, the individuals of Group 1 are first-generation hybrids and those of Group 2 are second -generation hybrids with respect to the position 2&amp;W- ; sl'aris'/'. x Ultra 7' ) T. X(Navy,l. x Marrow.l.) .1 5 ■ .ivy. I. x Marrow. I | , Paris T. x Ultra 2'.) T. ... .5 '.'.'.'.'.'. Marrow. 1). I. .'.'.'. ■ 561 • -J .. .. •■a 7 ■ M.irn. Paris'/'. xNavy .1 ...1 ■ (Ultra Tx Navy .1 ,.| ...A Harrow A X Paris T. )A 1 1 ■ i </seg>
            <seg id="p043">43 of the pods on the plants, though the plants of both groups may be, and in fact are, second-generation hybrids with re - spect to othsr characters, such as seed color, size, and shape, pod size and shape, etc. Why a plant with terminal pods (Paris x Ultra), crossed by a plant with axial pods (Navy x Marrow), should yield nothing but plants with axial pods, while in another case two 'plants, both with axial pods (Paris x Navy and Ultra X Marrow), when crossed together should yield both axial- and terminal-podded plants, would Iiexplicable except by Mendelism. Paris * Ultra is not rid at all in respect to the position of its pods, since i parent races like itself have terminal pods. Likewise, Marrow is not hybrid with respect to pod position, i its parents, like itself, having axial pods. Naturally, i, when Paris x Ultra is crossed by Navy x Marrow, the Its are the same, so far as pod position is concerned, as single terminal-podded race were crossed with a single axial- podded one. Paris x Navy, on the other hand, is hybrid as to pod position, one parent, Paris, having ter - minal, and the other, Navy, having axial pods; and similarly, Ultra x Marrow is hybrid as to pod position. Moreover, so far as this one character is concerned, one of these hybrids is t-xactly like the ether, so that the results of crossing them is the same as would follow from crossing two indi - viduals of one of the hybrids or from inbreeding a single in - dividual. When gametes are pure with respect to unit - characters, the individual plant arising from the union of the two gametes may be pure bred in regard to the par - ticular characters, even though it was produced by crossing distinct races; or it may be hybrid with respect to these eicters even though it was produced by inbreeding a 8 individual plant. POD QUALITY. The only characters relating to the quality of pods that have been studied are "toughness" and " strincriness. " Bean pods are either stringy or at . tough or U A stringy pod has strongly developed fibers along both Kres, while in a stringless pod these "strings" are lly or almost wholly wanting. Tough pods have strong </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 fibers in their walls, the fibers running obliquely across the pod from suture to suture. Tender pods are practically without these fibers, the pod walls usually being more or less fleshy. These cross- fibers are concerned in the dehis - cence of the pods on drying, accompanied by the forceful discharge of the seeds so common in wild legumes. In races of beans which have had the cross-fibers "bred out" of their pod walls, the pods are indehiscent, merely shrivel - ing up on drying. Different races of stringy- and tough - podded beans vary in regard to the strength of the suture and cross-fibers. Young pods of even the most stringy- and tough-podded races are practically stringless and tender, the fibers developing as the pods grow. In hybrids between stringy- and stringless-podded races, the pods of the first generation of plants are sometimes in - termediate between the parent races in stringiness, while in other cases the pods of the first-generation forms are so nearly stringless that the difference between them and the pods of the stringless parent is scarcely discernible. It should be noted, further, that in case of intermediates there is sometimes a strong tendency towards dominance of stringlessness, the majority of the pods resembling the stringless parent much more closely than the stringy one. In other cases, however, this tendency is not so noticeable. The behavior of several hybrids in the first generation with respect to stringiness is shown in the following table. In the column headed "Parentage," "&amp;." is an abbreviation for "Stringless'' and "%." for "Stringy." </seg>
            <seg id="p045">45 Table V. -firs' No. of plants of first generation 7. Parentage III 111!! The writer is ready to offer no explanation of the fact that in some cases stringlessness is dominant while in others true intermediates occur in the first generation. In the majority of cases stringlessness has been dominant where the pistillate parent is stringless and intermediates have occurred where the pistillate parent is stringy. But this has not held in all cases. Unfortunately no true reciprocal hybrids have been observed in this connection. In the second generation of hybrids where stringles - is dominant, the recessive character, strong suture fibers, occurs together with the dominant form. Where inter - mediates are found in the first generation, three types occur in the second generation, namely, intermediates and the two extremes. The intermediates, however, vary more in strength of fibers in the second than in the first gener - ation. This was s&gt;o pronounced in some cases that it was difficult to classify the individuals correctly. On the whole, the intermediates approximated the stringless forms some - what more nearly than the stringy ones. The records are shown in the table below, the various hybrids being arranged in two groups, according to the stringiness of pods in the first generation. ■-p s* r* Golden V Mohawk UM Keeney 8$ X Davis - Stringless &lt;ir«*en .■&gt;'.•&lt;. X Warwick &gt;, .240 " " '• X .258 Wardwell S$. X Navy - .351 Davis Sy. X Challenge Black &gt;.- &lt; Jones 8a .3*4 " "X " " Savy &gt;.v X Challenge Bla ■.'41 Curfie Sy. X Golden Wax St 874 Red Valentiue 8y. X Stringless Green 8* .375 X .378 X I ■- 1 Total _ — </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Table VI. — Pod stringine*»—mcon First No. of plants of % ea ' second generation. . c Parentage Golden Wax H». X Mohawk Hy 1 S* 4 Stringles.- Warwick Sj 19 " •' X " '• 1 14 1 i)avis •&gt; :s ■1 4 u ■• :v »....! •_&gt;■ 1 ...9 .10 . Total Group 1 j . . .s* . . . «n 0 Total Group 2 - It is interesting to note that in all cases where stringless - ness was dominant in the first generation, only two forms, dominants and recessives, occurred in the second gener - ation. The ratio, however, of dominant 65 to recessive 33, is not in accordance with the Mendelian expectation, but, instead, is practically 2 : 1. Furthermore, in all but one case where the first generation was intermediate between the parents, intermediates occurred together with the two parent forms in the second generation. Here, also, the numerical relation between the three forms, 114 stringless, 80 intermediate, 78 stringy, is not according to expectation. This may Derhaps be accounted for in part at least by the considerable variation in ihe intermediate forms leading to error in classification. Behavior in the third generation ill! ilnl X Davii S;/ 1 ■ \ ardwell S». x Navy 8) ...4 ... ■ Challenge Black 8t I ...11 ....1 Challenge Black N* 4 :ed Valentine .S&gt;/ x Stri unless Green &gt; . 1? ...11 ... </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 ought to clear up the doubt, but unfortunately only two hy - brids were carried to the third generation. One of these represents the group in which stringlessness was dominant and the other the group in which intermediates occurred. Records of the former are given in the following table. The individuals with stringy pods (the recessive character) bred true in respect to stringiness in the third generation. Some of the stringless-podded individuals of the second generation (pure dominants) also bred true in the third generation, while others (heterozygotes) produced both types in the second generation. In the table below, the records are arranged in three groups, one containing the heterozygotes and the other two the two type - homozygotes. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Tablk VII.— Pod stritu/im**— third-yen x Warwick &gt;'//.) Number of plants 5 Second generation. of third gener- " T! ation. 2* "C Pods Pods | | Pod character. string- s f r^. Pod character W7 1- 9 Stringy 13 :.... ;;;.« « 1-15 •• 9 1-18 •• ....80 1-24 : •' 1 287 1-36 •• 14 140 IS •• l-n ; 11-15 .... 14 240 1 21 " .U '.- -' Stringless • i- 5 8 240 1 21 " . .a 1- 6 14 1- 8 " ' "10 1-13 " 10 227 1-14 ...."."" 1-16 '• 1-17 " 7 1-20 " 9 240 1- 4 240 1- ? 240 1-12 240 1 13 240 1 14 240 1-19 ' "(j 240 I 120 1-28 •■ ia ; 6 -.? " 5| 9 -10 s 1 -W ! " .14 i 7 : :.:...io s a H \ wn l-w i : •• 1-25 •• :;■;;. ::::: .:::: 9 240 1 2 '• 12 So i-ei ::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::.::::::::• i«ii m .:::::::::■••::•: ■•£■ 1- 9 ■' ...4 a 240 i-io io ;:.. M 1-16 ■ ISSSSL: • H0 ... Stringless.. </seg>
            <seg id="p049">'r/f'/f *1 /{/''&lt;"' / 1 Cg-^L^f v 49 The ten stringy-podded plants of the second generation produced, in the third generation, 140 plants, all with stringy pods. Of the 33 stringless-podded plants of the second generation, 18 produced 201 plants in the third generation, all of which had stringless pods, and the re - maining 15 produced 195 plants, 56 with stringy and 139 with stringless pods. The ratio of stringless to stringy, approximately 2.5 : 1, is very much nearer the expectation than was the case with the various hybrids of the second generation as recorded in Table VI. In case of the second generation plants of the one hybrid included in Table VII, the number of stringless- and stringy-podded plants, 10 and 33 respectively, give a very close approxi - mation to the Mendelian ratio, considering the very small numbers dealt with. Of the 33 plants of the second gener - ation which exhibited the dominant character of string - lessness, the number of apparently pure dominants, 16, as against 15 hybrid forms, is far in excess of the expected re - sults. On inspecting the individual entries in Group 2 (Table VII), it is noticed that in several cases very small numbers of plants were grown in the third generation. It is quite possible that if larger numbers of plants had been grown, some of them might have had stringy pods and would therefore have been classed in Group 3. In Group 3, one plant. No. 240-1-2, produced 13plantsin the third gener - ation, only one of which had stringy pods. It is there - fore perfectly reasonable to suppose that some of the plants included in Group 2 are really heterozygotes and should have been included in Group 3. If some of the plants of Group 2 could be put in Group 3, the ratio of dominants to recessives in the third generation would be made nearer 3 : 1 and the numerical relation between pure dominants and heterozygotes of the second generation would also have been brought more nearly into conformity with the theo - retical relation. Taking up now the third-generation forms of the hybrids that yielded intermediates in the first generation and inter - mediatas together with the two original parent forms in the second generation, we find results that are decidedly sug- </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 gestive. It should be noted here that the records of these plants are not so reliable as those presented in the pre - ceding tables, on account of the conditions under which the work was carried on. The seed was planted late, the season was unusually wet and cold, prolonging the growth of the plants, and killing frosts occurred early so that some plants never thoroughly matured. Furthermore, continued wet weather after frost caused many pods to decay some - what; before they were harvested. The records are given, however, in the belief that they are true in general, not - withstanding the possible errors in particular cases. The following table presents these records arranged in five groups. </seg>
            <seg id="p051">51 Number of plants of third Second generation. generation. x. Pl»nt I P»di P ° dS Pod« v" Pod character. -ing- inter- „._:„__ No less mediate. 9lna « r Pod character f 1- 5 Stringy 8-1 hi 10 36 1 y I|4-i2 ■• ■&gt; -tringte 8- 5 i .a .a in H- 9 4- » 3- 4 Intermediat . 3- 6 ' 4- 1 .4-4 4- 7 4-10 i I 4-13 . -.'1 8 3 1- 1 Stringless 1 4 1- 8 ; ■ i 4-14 " ... ...6 f 1- 4 Stringy I 3 I ■i : 4- 9 '4-11 B ..88 4 •&gt; 1 Total Stringy 2 " Stringless Intermediate. H II .. .18 -tringless . U . . .16 Stringy i Hi : 1 54 Of the 3" plants of the second generation of this hybrid, only 28 produced offspring in the third generation. Of these 28, 7 (Group 1) with stringy pods gave rise to 177 plants in the third generation, all with stringy pods. Like- wise 5 second generation plants (Group 2) with stringless pods bred true, producing 35 plants, all with stringless pods. The remaining 16 plants (Groups 3, 4, 5) produced in the third generation various forms, from stringy to - </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 ' tOH (&gt;J .^ stringless, 243 plants in all. The ratio of pure stringless forms to hybrid forms to pure stringy forms in the second generation was, therefore, apparently 5 : 16 : 7 instead of 11 : 7 : 12 as indicated in Table VI. This probably means simply that it was difficult to distinguish between inter - mediates and stringless pods on the one hand and between intermediates and stringy pods on the other, and that con - sequently errors were made in classification; otherwise it is difficult to account for the fact that stringy plants of the second generation (Group 5, Table VIII) produced more than one form in the third generation. Stringiness, a re - cessive character, has always bred true heretofore. The fact that the intermediates varied considerably was noted in discussing the records of the second generation, given in Table VI. No attempt, however, was made to divide these intermediates into subgroups. Indeed, an accurate classifi - cation based on the strength of suture fibers was impracti cable. Partial immaturity of the pods, exposure to unfavor able weather after maturing, and possibly other conditions, combined to make the results less definite than might have desired. It is possible, however, to make three groups of the heterozygotes of the second generation (Groups 3. 4, 5, Table VIII), one consisting of the forms that were discernably intermediate, and the other two of the forms that were not distinguished from the true string - forms on the one hand and the true stringy ones on the other but which were evidently heterozygotes as shown by their behavior in the third generation. Examining these three groups (Groups 3, 4, 5, Table VIII). we note relatively small numbers of intermediates, only 16 in a total of 101 for Group 3, 9 in 67 for Group 4, and 1 in 75 for Group 5. It is possible that this may in part be due to incorrect classification owing to immature or partly decayed 'pods, the presence of which has already been mentioned. A further noticeable feature is the approximately equal numbers of stringless and stringy in - dividuals in Group 3 and the unequal numbers in Groups 4 and 5. In Group 3. from intermediates of the second gener - ation, the numbers of stringless and stringy individuals are </seg>
            <seg id="p053">* 53 47 and 38 respectively, or a ratio of 1.24 : 1. A similar group of second-generation forms (Table VI) contained 114 stringless- to 7^ stringy -podded plants, a ratio of 1.46 : 1. In Group 4 (Table VIII), from stringless parents there ar&gt; stringless to 16 stringy individuals, while in Group 5 from stringy parents there are 54 stringy to 20 stringless plai ratios of 2.63 : 1 and 0.37 : 1 respectively, or, if the latter be reversed, 2.7 : 1. From this it appears probable that if, from heterozygotes of the second generation, individuals that approximate closely the stringless extreme be select' the results in the third generation are much the same as they are where striglessness is a dominant character from the start (see Table VII). That is, the two extreme forms, homozygotes, commonly the dominant and recessive char - acters, will occur in about equal numbers, and thf heterozygotes will be like those of the preceding generation and therefore closely resemble the original dominant form, making the numerical relation of dominant and recessive forms approximate the theoretical ratio of 3 : 1. Li wise, if second-generation heterozygotes be selected that are plainly intermediate between the two extremes, there re - sults, as in the previous case, about equal numbers of the two extremes, homozygotes, together with variable heterozygotes like those of the preceding generation, some of which resemble, and are classified with, one extreme, and some which resemble and are classified with the other. And again, in an exactly similar way, if the selected second - generation heterozygotes resemble the stringy extreme closely, the third generation will, as before, be composed of the two extremes, homozygotes, and the heterozygotes which on account of resembling their immediate parents are practically indistinguishable from the stringy extreme, making the ratio of stringy to stringless individuals ap - proximately 3:1, as if stringiness had been a dominant Srharacter all the time. Whether other cases of apparent rsal of dominance are to be explained in this way can be suggested here. In the study of pod toughness, comparatively little has been accomplished. Degree of stringiness of pods is not </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 |,ys easily estimated, but toughness is even more difficult itermine accurately. Moreover, the wall fibers of pods more seriously injured by unfavorable weather after jrity than are the suture fibers. In hybrids between ;h-podded and tender-podded races, there is a strong ency toward dominance of tenderness, the pods of first - ;ration hybrids being almost as tender as the tender - led parent. A number of observations on first-gener - a hybrids is given in the following table. ''Ten.'' and h." after names of races indicate the races are "tender" "tough" respectively. Table IX brick. as S5 "5. 5 Parentage I nnglew Green \ arwick Tgh 1 X " " 1 ardwell Ten x Navy Jiih HI Uavis Tgh x Challenge Black 3 1 858' '' " X Jonc- In the second generation the two parent.types occurred, to- gether with intermediates of varying fiber strength. The rs are given in the following table: Table X. — ]'&lt;xl \n. ,,i hybrid*. First Number of plants of gen. second generation i 1: -5 ¥ ingless Green Ten. x Warwick Tgh. 1 Ten] 3 11 . ■24rt " " s/ '■ 1 ii a\ ii .j X '■ 1 " 6 .....I 6 9 ■'ardwell Ten x Navy Tgh - 1 " | 4I A avy Tgh. x Challenge Black I . . .2 5 4 1 2; 5 " X 6 » 8 X 4 Total. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">55 Although tenderness was dominant in the first generation, intermediates occurred, together with dominants and re - cessives, in the second generation. The dominants, inter - mediates, and recessives, 17, 38, 22, respectively, have the ratio 1 : 2.2 : 1.3, approximating the theoretical ratios of pure dominants to hybrid forms to pure recessives namely, : 1. Records for the third generation were not secured : hence it is impossible to test the accuracy of the classification made in the second generation. POD COLOR Bean pods when immature are usually either green or . The latter are known as "wax" beans. They vary from yellowish white to almost pure white. The pods of practically all races are green when very young, and lose their color, becoming yellow as they ripen. Only those races, however, whose pods lose their chlorophyll while still comparatively young are called yellow podded. Yellow - podded races vary considerably in regard to the age at which their pods lose their green color. Some races which are commonly classed as wax beans have pods which never become perfectly yellow. When such forms occur in hybrids, they are classed as yellow if they are as nearly yellow as the yellow-podded parent of the hybrid grown under the same conditions. In a preliminary paper,* the writer termed such forms greenish yellow, and considered them intermediate between the green and yellow parents. In most of these cases, however, no careful comparison was made between the hybrids with greenish-yellow pods and the yellow-podded parent. I am now of the opinion that this interpretation was incorrect, and that intermediates rarely if ever occur in hybrids between green- and yellow - podded races. In the few cases studied, green color of pod is dominant in the first generation. In the table below, under the heading "Parentage," "','." indicates that the parent was green -podded, and " 1*. " that ii had yellow pods. ♦ •Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Rpt. 15 (1903). pp. 30-43. tHybrids often have purple markings on the green or yellow ground color (see pages 58, 59). In the present discussion the ground colors alone </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Table XI -Pod color ration hybrids. Number of plants of first gen - eration. Pods Pods green. yellow. loliawk (I. X Scarlet Flageolet )' 4 .olden Wax 1*. x Mohawk G 285 Navy &lt;l. x Challenge Black )'. BJulv'r? x Davis )• Davis r. x July O 1 Total In the second generation, the recessive character, yellow pod color, occurs, together with the dominant color, green, as shown in the following table. Table XII. — Pti color- lion hybrid*. Fi «t lube r of plants generation. of second gen- K eration Parentage s. ■- P. 0 * 1 Pods Pods £ color greem yellow 55Mohauk 0 x Scarlet Flageolet )' I Green 1 1 8 " •&gt; 55 " ■' X rlden )' x Mohawk G X 1 s 0. I S •&gt; 3 Challenge Wax )' 7 4 ...11 I •» July O. X Davis )'. 1 '• 4 88B " •• x ■' .V. -&gt;2 tilO Davis )'. x July '.' 1 Total. 128 49 The results here, 123 green and 49 yellow, or a ratio of 2.51 : 1, are fairly near the Mendelian expectation, allowing for the fact of the small numbers. In the third generation, the behavior of the one hybrid that was fully tested was, with one or two exceptions, about what might be expected from dominant and recessive characters. The records I Parentage. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">57 Table XIII. — I'od &amp;i(i,,-—th hybrid — No. Blade V. Number of plants of third generation. Second generation. ■'■ p N r Pods Pods green. yellow Pod color. II- 1 Yellow 1-8 8-7 4-11 13 R 1 *8 1-4 " 1-5 A A % ■ 4-4 A K. r i-i ; 8-8 4--8 ,4-7 I 4 " 12 V 4-14 3 9 4-14 •■ ... ■ Total Yellow ... .28 Green 3 The second -generation plants with yellow pods, re - cessive character, produced 31 plants in the third gener - ation, 28 of which were 1 yellow and 3 green (Group 1). There is no question as to the correctness of the observation that the three plants bore green pods in the third gener - ation. If an error was made in the records it must have occurred in the second generation. If no error was made, the writer can offer no explanation of the peculiar behavior of the yellow-podded second-gener- *Se« text. 1- 8 Green .31 '• •• 4- 8 4-10 ' .M 4-18 1- I </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 ation plant in producing three green-podded plants in the third generation. (For further evidence of purity of the recessive character, yellow pods, in hybrids, see the following paragraph.) Thirteen of the second-generation green-podded plants (Group 2) produced nothing but green - podded plants in the third generation, 146 in all, while nine of them (Group 3) produced two sorts of plants, 158 g] podded and 56 yellow- podded ones. The ratio of dominants to recessives here is 2.82 : 1, a very close approximation to the demands of theory. Of the second-generation domi - nants, however, the ratio of heterozygotes to homozygotes, parated by their behavior in the third generation (Table XIII, Groups 2 and 3) is far from expected results. Instead of two hybrid forms to one pure dominant, there are actually more of the latter than of the former. In several cases the third-generation individuals in Group 2 are so few that it is possible that they are not homozygotes. In cases of only three or four individuals, the heterozygotes might often be mistaken for homozygotes, owing to the chance absence of the recessive form. After making allow - ance for this possibility, however, there are still too few hybrid forms for the number of pure dominai That the recessive pod color, yellow, commonly breeds true is shown by the record of another hybrid. No. 57. As shown in Table XII. the first-generation plant 57 - 1 pro - duced, in the second generation, eight green-podded and two yellow-podded plants. The two latter were selected for further trial but produced only a few individuals in the third and fourth generations, all of which, however, had yellow pods. From these, 96 plants were grown in the fifth gener - ation, about 300 in the sixth, and about 3000 in the seventh, all of which had yellow pods. Furthermore, from a second - generation plant with green pods (heterozygote) two yellow - podded plants were produced in the third generation. These gave rise to 40 plants in the fourth generation, all with yellow pods. E sides the two more common pod colors discussed ), bean races may have blue-green pods, accompanied ue-green color of the stems and leaves, and purplish- </seg>
            <seg id="p059">59 colored pods. In the latter case the purple color usually appears as spots and splashes on a ground color of green or yeilow. A single hybrid one parent of which has blue - green pods has been grown. The records are not complete enough to have statistical value. They indicate, however, that blue-green color of stems and leaves is practically dominant over green, and that blue-green color of the pods is practically dominant over yellow pod color. No hybrid between a blue-green- podded race and a green - podded one has been grown. In later generations the yellow pod color and the green color of leaves and stems have bred true. In the case of leaves and stems a few ex - amples of undoubted intermediates have occurred in the second generation. No hybrid including in its parentage a race having pods marked with purple has been grown by the writer. In several cases, however, hybrids have had their pods strongly colored with purple, and this has occurred in hybrids between two yellow-podded races, between two green - podded races, and between a yellow-podded race and a green-podded one neither of which is marked in this way though all of them may occasionally have a few specks of purple near the tip end of the pods.* Though this peculiar coloration of hybrids has not been given the attention in a statistical way that it should have received, the writer is of the opinion that it is to be regarded as heterozygous. In cases where the coloration is very pronounced in the first generation, many individuals of the second generation show no trace of it, while others are marked as in the first generation. Second -generation plants'that show the colors of the parent races only, have bred true with respect to the absence of purple coloration. In one case such forms have bred true to the sixth generation. Furthermore, the purple spotted forms of no generation have bred true. FLOWER COLOR. Pew records of flower color have been kept. White color of flowers is correlated with white seed color and usually the darker the seed color the deeper the flowers are colored. *Nebr Agr. Exp Sta. Rpt 1 pp. 41, 42 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 E&gt; seeds are white with but a small amount of color the eye, the flowers are also sometimes white. Prac - the same results can therefore be secured by a study 1 color as from a study of flower color. Colored bean flowers are usually violet- purple. The color of even the darkest flowers, however, is plainly diluted with white. Among bean races, many degrees of intermediates occur between the deepest colored and the white flowers. Since even the dark -colored flowers contain some white, it is often difficult in case of hybrids to distinguish accurately between the dark-colored flowers, and some of the inter - mediates. But between white flowers and intermediates, on the other hand, it is rarely difficult to draw the line. In the records presented here, therefore, the plants are separated into two groups only, one with white flowers and the other with flowers that show some color without regard to the intensity of coloration. In hybrids between plants with deeply colored flowers and white-flowered plants, the dark color is usually dominant. When a white-flowered plant is crossed with a plant whose flowers are merely tinted with color, or when both parents have tinted flowers, it is not uncommon for the first-gener - ation individuals of the hybrid to have flowers much more strongly colored than those of either parent. In the second generation, both parent types occur, together with inter - mediates,* which, for reasons noted before are here classed with the dark-colored individuals. The records of a few second -generation hybrids are given below. Parent races with white flowers are marked "ir." and those with colored flnwpra " C " 'These intermediates appear to be blends. Whether or not they may simply be mosaics of very fine pattern has not been determined. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">61 ■£* JZXJ1S2&amp;. X ■ 5-8 Ji = II — Ie ratio of colored- to white-flowered forms in the id generation, 75 and 30 respectively, is 2.5 : 1. In the generation it was observed that the white flowered id-generation plants had bred true in respect to flower and that of the second-generation plants with colored rs some had bred true while others had again produced classes of flowers. The actual number of plants with a and with colored flowers was not determined. SEED COLOR. Ijan seeds vary greatly in color. The immediate results rossing two races having different seed colors cannot be told from any other hybrid between races with similarly red seeds. A case illustrating this point was noted in ntally in discussing plant habit (see page 38). While seed color of many hybrids has been studied, only two rids that have been carried to the third generation e been grown in sufficient numbers to give results of istical value. A single hybrid individual of Stringless Green, a race with dark brown seeds, crossed by Giant Stringless, with yellow-brown seeds, in the first generation yielded seeds that were at the time judged to be intermediate between the two parents, though my notes state that they resembled the dark brown seeds of Stringless Green much more closely Parentage s I \ ardwell 1 ■ ..1. 235Navy W. M 7. x Challenge Black &lt; .lured X Golden Wax W. 1 X - X Challenge Black C 1 X X ! -] Total I.. I.. .... </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Ethe yellow- brown seeds of Giant Stringless. There no indication of a mosaic of the two colors. The seeds led to be a blend between the parent colors but were in - iced little by the lighter colored race. In the second generation the two parent colors, yellow - brown and dark brown, occurred together with forms like the first generation. The latter varied somewhat in shade of brown, none of them resembling the yellow- brown parent at all closely but some of them approaching the dark brown parent color so nearly that it was found difficult to separate the two forms. My notes, in fact, contain memoranda like "Medium dark brown, almost dork brown." Out of 36 plants, 15 had yellow- brown seeds and 6 were classed as having dark brown and 15 medium dark brown seeds, not very smooth numerical results The behavior of the progeny of the three groups is shown in the following table. By mistake a complete record of the numbers of plants was kept in only a few cases. On account of this, the total number of seeds is given in the table along with the incom - plete records of numbers of plants. I see no reason why the numbers of seeds produced cannot be employed in this way as well as the numbers of plants, provided that it is as - sumed that on the average the various groups of plants are about equally productive. No attempt was made to distin - guish between dark brown and medium dark brown seeds in the third generation, the two sorts being grouped together and all termed dark brown. This was done because the slight discoloration resulting from protracted rainy weather at harvest time made almost impossible any classification — a difficult enough undertaking with the more perfectly pre- </seg>
            <seg id="p063">63 Table XV.— Heed color— th Third generation Third generation . I Second genermtion. _ „ . Second generation. &lt; Seeds Seeds Seeds y. f dark brown. yellow-brown. dark brown. yellow-brown. Plant 5 Na S66d COl ° r Number Number Number I Nu Seed color. No Seed color. Number | Number Number | Number plants. seeds. plants, i seeds. plants. | seeds. plants. ' seeds Vellow-brown 1-4 1-5 30 8S3 1-6 U 84 I 1-10 l-ie 1 17 1-18 i ...W ! i-2i ............. I 1-2.1 ...it wo 1-31 t 1 ■■ •' - i f 1- 7 Dark brown 301 E- 7 Dark brown '.... .801 -13 ' •' 1 10 ....456 1 1-13 •' " 10 ...(V -&gt;0 " " 8 7-21 1 1-35 " " 7 374 1-35 " " 7 374 L l-8t&gt; Med. dark brown 7 251 Med. dark brown 7 | 251 I Dark brown 23 .... - ..66 Med. dark brown _. • ....«,.. - Med. dark brown 22 236 6 51 I 1 » 17 .... 17 ... --&lt;■ Ill 8 IIS 1 11 8 IIS En • » 11.) -15 ■• : M H l 15 : 368 : 6 127 I I n 6 127 ... 1 M ' ..6»8 ... ...698 I " &lt;, 1-24 - 434 1W 1-24 B 434 I 164 ; l« M ; 164 I i 1-28 ■• 129 ■ Mi ...143 1 29 ■ ...6 485 1 143 i 1-32 4 64 1-33 • 29 549 14 29 549 ! U 1-37 ' 6 1«5 ;.: ..122 1 TotaliYellow-brown 0 0 Dark brown (1 me- dium dark brown). 64 .. 2103 0 Med. dark browu (1 d ark bfcwn) 178 .4170 68 1 1«W 3 plants that bad yellow-brown seeds in the second All the plants that bad yellow-brown seeds in the second generation (Group 1 of the above table) bred true in the tbird generation, producing a total of 4728 yellow-brown </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 seeds and none of other colors. The second-generation plants with dark brown seeds (Group 2) also bred true with a single exception, the orogeny of one dark brown seeded Dlant having produced both dark brown and yellow-brown seeded individuals. The second -generation plants with medium dark brown seeds (Group 3) produced the two forms dark brown and yellow-brown seeded individuals in the third generation with the exception of one plant, all the progeny of which had dark brown seeds. These two excep - tions simply indicate something of the very close resem - blance between the dark brown and some of the medium dark brown seeds and the consequent difficulty of separat - ing them. In Table XV the individuals are grouped, not according to the colors assigned them in the second gener - ation, but rather in accordance with their behavior in the third generation, the homozygous forms being put in Group 2 and the heterozygous ones in Group 3. The plants of &gt;up 2 produced 2103 dark brown seeds and no others. The heterozygotes (Group 3) produced a total of 5466 seeds, 4170 of which were dark brown and 1296 yellow- brown, or a ratio of 3.22 : 1. It is interesting to note, also, that the incomplete record of numbers of plants, 179 with dark brown and 53 with yellow- brown seeds, affords nearly the same ratio, namely 3 3* : 1, a substantial agreement in both cases with the 3 - 1 ratio. In hybrid No. 235, Navy with white seeds crossed by Challenge Black with black seeds, the three first-generation plants had seeds that v\ere mottled black and dark brownish gray, the black covering the greater part of the seeds. In the second generation, both parent colors, black and white, occurred in separate individuals together with individuals having mottled seeds. In case of the latter there was con siderable variation in the relative areas covered by the black and by the gray, and in some cases the gray spots were brownish as in the first generation, while in others they were distinctly blue-gray. It should be noted here that the seeds of the first-generation hybrids and some of the second - generation ones were not properly matured, which may account in part for the brown-gray color. Black seeds that </seg>
            <seg id="p065">65 are not properly matured often show a considerable admix - ture of brown. The blue-gray color seen in second-gener - ation forms is probably simply a mixture of the black and white parent colors. In reality, black color in bean seeds is commonly blue-black. An unripe seed of the black seeded race is always blue, and only becomes black on dry - ing. It is probable that when diluted with white the blue is still seen in the dry seeds : hence the blue-gray color of some hybrids. The gray spots are in some cases, in part at least, made up of blue and whitish spots arranged in a very fine mosaic. Whether this is true in all cases or whether there may be true blends of black and white, has not been determined. To the unaided eye most of the spots appear to be blends. Iie number of individuals of the second generation that ied white, mottled, and black seeds were 10, 7, and 13 •ectively, or a ratio of .77 : .54 : 1, a small number of in - lediates in proportion to the numbers showing the mt colors, the expected ratio being 1 : 2 : 1. From r behavior in the third generation, it is seen that not all black-seeded individuals can be regarded as pure black is. ihe mottled seeds of the third generation like those of second varied considerably in the relative amounts of k and gray and in the particular tint associated with gray. In the records all were classed as mottled black gray. The records for the third generation are given ,he following table, the individuals being arranged in • groups. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 hybrid— No. Challenge /Hark I;. Number of plants of third Second generation. generation Seeds „ . mottled seea » black * white gray- Seeds black. Plant No. Seed color 3- 2 1- "J Whit. » 11 4 1 n ■ S 15 HI tlottled. black and dark blue-gray blue-gray . . . 4 dark brown-gray | 2 - •• v&gt; ; 9 ....) •&gt; 8 3 1- 3 : 4 i i i j i , i 4 *"» " » ! 1 " 11 4 4-H '• •) 1 Total White ...u ... Mottled, black and gray I • Black ! BO 0 4 ■• I " 1 9 The second-generation plants with white seeds bred true in the third generation, the nine second -generation individ - uals having produced 2&lt;&gt;9 third-generation plants, all with white seeds (Group 1). The second -generation plants with mottled seeds (Group 2) produced, in the third generation, some black seeded, some mottled seeded, a«d some white seeded plants, just as seeds of first-generation plants did 11 1 1 4 ■) t5 Black J = </seg>
            <seg id="p067">67 Be second generation. The numbers of black, mottled, white seeded individuals in the third generation up 2) were 30, '.'A, and 9 respectively, or a ratio of 3.33 : 3. 78 : 1, instead of 1 : 2 : 1, which might have been ■ted. Of the second-generation plants with black i, some (Group 3) bred true in the third generation, bfl the white seeded forms did, four individuals having produced 80 third-generation plants, all with black seeds. The remaining nine black-seeded second-generation individ - (Group 4), however, did not breed true, but instead produced both black- and white-seeded forms. Of the 29 second -generation plants recorded in Table XVI it is evident, then, that not more than 13 individuals (Groups 1 and 3) can be regarded as homozygous, the remaining 1H ■•Iniups 2 and 4) being heterozygous. At tirst it was thought that a mistake must have been made in classifying the second -generation plants, many of the mottled i showed so little of the gray color, and that of so dark a shade, that it was often difficult to distinguish them from pure black seeds except by the most careful examination. From a glance at the table, however, it is evident that the black-seeded forms .of iGroup 4 are not exactly lik mottled -seeded forms (Group 2), since plants of Group 2 produced black-, mottled, and white-seeded individuals, while the 'black-seeded plants produced only black-seeded and white-seeded forms. The numbers of black-seeded and white-seeded plants is noteworthy, K) black to 29 white, a ratio of 2.76 : 1, almost as might have been expected if black seed color had been dominant and white recessive. I should be remembered in this connection that this is the only case of a difference in the appearance and be - ior of heterozygous forms, though the differentiation is e clearly seen here owing to the fact that more sharply led characters are being dealt with. In the case of pod lginess, the very hybrid here considered, No. 23." ted similar peculiarities in third-generation forms ale VIII). The se,cond-generation intermediates produced rmediates and the two extremes in the third generation. le forms that were classed as stringless were found in </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 reality heterozygous with a tendency toward the ratio 3 stringless to 1 stringy, and likewise some second-generation plants that were called stringy-podded failed to breed true, showing a tendency toward the ratio of 3 stringy to 1 string lew. In case of pod stringiness, tne difficulty of determin - ing accurately the degree of devlopment of the fibers led to somewhat indefinite results. An important difference be - tween pod stringiness and seed color in respect to the be - havior of heterozygous forms in the third generation is that only one of the parent seed colors, black, was exhibited by heterozygous forms, while in case of pod stringiness some individuals of both parent types failed to breed true. It may be significant to note in this connection that in case of pod stringiness the intermediates varied greatly, some of them approaching closely the stringless parent and some the stringy one. while in the case of seed color the inter - mediates (mottled seeds) varied less, some resembling closely the black parent type but none approaching the white parent form. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">69 A SOFT ROT OF THE SUGAR-BEET. • BY HAVES MET' The work embodied in the following pages is the oat - growth of joint work with Mr. G. G. Hedgcock of the U. S. Department of Agriculture on the general 'pathology of the sugar-beet. Our joint investigations on this particular or - ganism and disease have already been published (Hedgcock and Metcalf, 1903), as has also the original designation of the species (Metcalf, 1904). GENERAL BACTERIOLOGY OF THE SUGAR BEET The healthy, living sugar-beet contains no bacteria. Up - on the surface of the beet many organisms are found; not different in quantity or kind, according to my observation, from what are present in cultivated soil generally. Of these the most commonly observed have been /&gt;'&lt;■ idmosw Frankland, Bacillus mycoides Klilgge, the omnipres - ent Bmctihu $ubtUu (Ehrenberg) Cohn, !&gt;■ wiDe Bary, Bacillus rmigatu* (Fltigge) Mig., and a form closely re - lated to, if not identical with An Chester (Chester, 1899). To these should be added three undescribed forms, -a small yellow pseudomonas, which is inhibited by temperature above 36° C. ; a white yeast, capable of pro - ducing alcoholic fermentation ; and a very large (5-6 microns) slime-producing bacillus. Brhese studies were practically completed in December, r.H).'. whan itted as a thesis for the Doctorate of Philosophy. Certain matter led in the thesis as presented (histology and enzyms) is. for lack of . omitted in the present article, and will be published later else - ?. For the same reason tables and detailed experiments have been y omitted and only conclusions given. ■tHaven Metcalf, Ph. D., Botanist and Bacteriologist, South Carolina cultural College and Experiment Station. (Bacterium teutlhim Metcalf. ) </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Three organisms occurring: in rotting beets and adjacent soil are of special interest, in that they all appear at times, and under certain conditions, to be able to attack living beet tissue. The first, a bacterium, appears to produce much the same effect upon beets as lUu-t. teutlium, but differs in its cultural and physical characters. The second is a small bacillus, which produces a brown pigment on beet tubes, but no geu &lt;&gt;r slime. Herein it differs from Kramer's organ - ism (Kramer, 1891) with which it was at first confused. Its biochemical relations and cultural characters seem to ally it with BaaUhu earotovonu (Cf. Jones, 1901, I, p. 312), but it does not grow parasitically on either carrot or tomato. The third is similar to the H. beta* of Busse (1807), and may prove to be identical. Iie disease first described by Arthur and Golden I attributed by them to bacteria (since designated as "curly " Townsend, 1902), is fairly common in Nebraska, at t in dry seasons: also another disease, in which the ited beets appear upon section to be full of brown or k spots instead of rings. Neither of these is a soft KREXCE AND (1ENERAL CHARACTER OK THE DISEASE tiotu in nx/J.—On September 25, 1901, Mr. Hedg - cock received from Grand Island, Nebr., five beets samples of a rot occurring there. These beets were affected with a soft rot which had rotted away the lower half of each beet ; the crown was normal, and the leaves unaffected. cept in two cases where the outer leaves had died. No fungi were present; and cultures on bouillon agar showed only BenicUlium and Aspergillug. No cultural examination for bacteria was made at this time. On October 2 Mr. Hedgcock found the same rot at Hershey, Nebr. A considerable number of beets, growing in an irrigated field below the irrigation ditch, were found affected. Six of these beets were brought to the laboratory. The following description is from notes made at the time : "Lower half of beets decayed, and nearly consumed by mites; rotten portion honeycombed, with 'pockets' of a </seg>
            <seg id="p071">71 viscid fluid, colorless or translucent, sour smelling, exuding under the slightest pressure. Vascular tissue not rotted: ends of bundles project out beyond where parenchyma has been consumed. Rotted tissue and tissue for 5 — 20 mm. be - yond the part actually decayed discolored yellowish-gray; the color darkens on continued exposure to air. Sound tissue seems perfectly normal ; near rotted and discolored tissue a band 10 — 30 mm. wide becomes reddish on exposure to air, and then black (tyrosinase?).* No black rin:.' spots; leaves normal, not wilted or curled; outer larger m dead in soni' Mites present in oldest rotten part in great numbers; also some nematodes. " Pabsequent examination of the viscid exudate showed it to pure culture of a bacterial organism. Cultures from lower part of the beet where the mit&gt; present and the tissue most completely disorganized, revealed the white K mentioned on page 69, and a number of common soil ria. Specimens of the mites sent to Dr. L. O. Howard i Department of Agriculture were identified as belong - tto an undescribed species of the genus Tyrogtyp n it became evident that the disease was of some im - inue. one of the beets of this iot was photographed 1). The leaves had been removed at the time the ograph was taken, otherwise the photograph is repre - itive. About November 1, a lot of beets were received from various points along the Gila River valley, through the Itesy of Prof. Thorn ber of the University of Arizona, le were quite dry when received, and had been topped re being sent. Three of the beets appeared as if the r half had been eaten off. One of these upon section red cavities still filled with viscid fluid, apparently quite lar to what had been obseryed in the beet from Hershey. a being placed in a damp chamber, the decay continued . the beet was nearly consumed, developing the unmis - ble characters of the rot as it has been described, r Hurt, tfiit/imu was isolated from the other two be&lt; *Cf. Bertram], Sur une nouvelle oxydase d'origine vegetale. Bui. de la Soc. China. 3, XV. 793 (1896). </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 On November 24 six bushels of beets were pulled from a field in the creek bottoms north of Lincoln, Nebr., and stored in a cellar. In any ordinary season the field would have been very wet. No beets were found which were dis - tinctly affected with this rot. The field as a whole was badly affected with curly top and the similar "spot" disease already mentioned. On December 21 a few of these beets, supposed to be sound, were brought to the laboratory for inoculation purposes. Upon close observation the tips of these beets were found to be covered with a viscid substance which had partially dried; upon squeezing the tips, small drops of a clear viscid fluid exuded. Upon section, the tips for about 3 cm. were found to be honeycombed with small passages and cavities filled with the clear exudate. The tissue was not in the least discolored ; there was no sour smell, although the exudate was strongly acid to litmus. Microscopical examination showed that the exudate was full of small motionless rods. Cultural characters proved thf organism to be the same as that found in the later stages of rot of the beets previously described ; and the subsequent decay of these beets showed conclusively that this was an early stage of the same rot. Later other beets of the same lot rotted in the same way. On December 3, in examining some beets which had been sent from Grand Junction. Col., in October and kept in a refrigerator, one was found decaying with a soft rot; and plates from this beet showed the characteristic organism. At different times during the autumn other beets were received from various parts of Nebraska and from Tucson. Ariz., which were found to be affected with the disease. 1902. — Inoculations conducted in the green - house during the winter and spring of 1901-1902 indicated that lkvt. t&lt; ■utlium would not attack any but a relatively mature beet. Nevertheless during the spring and early summer a careful lookout was kept for the disease in any form in which it might occur. A number of cases of "damping'off'^were investigated, but the organism was not isolated from'any of the affected specimens. Specimens of earth from several localities where beets had been grown </seg>
            <seg id="p073">*3t C^Cr / ' 1 / 1 /i '/( / v &amp;\%jKJ\JF * 73 in 1901 were examined for traces of the organism, with a view to ascertaining how it lives over the winter. Twenty - six plates of beet juice agar were made from earth from a number of different fields where beets were growing or had grown ; and the resulting colonies were carefully scrutinized for cultural resemblances to this bacterium. From 23 plates only negative results were obtained. The remaining 3 plates were all from different parts of the Held in the creek bottoms north of Lincoln. The rot had not been actually found in this field, but beets from there had rotted in the characteristic way after being stored (see page 72). These plates showed a number of colonies of an organism morpho - logically indistinguishable from Bart, teut/imn. When grown upon various other media it was found to be culturally the same organism ; but no successful inoculations of live beets could be made with it, although repeated attempts by various methods were made. The first occurrence of the rot in the field was noted by Mr. Hedgcock, July 21, at Grand Island, Nebr. He re - ported that over one half of the beets in several adjacent fields having an area of over 300 acres were rotting from various causes. A considerable number were affected with the Hlnzoct'inid surface rot (Duggar and Stewart, 1901) ; but by far the larger portion were rotting from the tip upward with a soft bacterial rot From samples of these beets teutlhtm was isolated without difficulty. The appearance of the affected beets was in general the same as that of the beets found rotting the previous year ; but in some cases secondary organisms had followed the primary rot much more closely, giving the whole beet a different external ap - pearance, and internally limiting the charactr "pockets" of translucent colorless exudate to a very narrow area. This condition appeared to be due to the fact that the fields in which these beets were growing were not only very wet, but had been a few weeks before actually under water ; in every case more wet than any of the fields in which the rot was observed in 1901. Itart. teutlium was isolated only from fairly large beets ; the younger or smaller beets with - stood the wet weather much more readily ; and very few * </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 E beets were found decayed from any cause except in low situations where they had remained under water me time. On August 6, I visited the fields of the Standard Cattle Co., at Ames, Nebr. Here a considerable tract of land had been partly under water earlier in the season, and was still more than normally wet. So badly rutted were the beets in this field that it seemed at that time that they would not pay for harvesting. At least 90 per cent were more or less affected. A portion of these beets appeared like those found in the fall of 1901; the majority showed more the ap - pearance of those found earlier in the season at Grand Island. Many had started to rot not only at the tip, but also at one or more places on the side. About one third of all the beets in the field had this form of rot unmistakably. (See fig. 2.) A considerable number, which, from their ap - pearance were supposed to be rotting with Bact. teuUium, turned out to be infected with a culturally different or - ganism (see page 70). Many others were affected with the i on in surface rot. Another characteristic form of rot appeared to be associated with the brown pigment-forming organism, mentioned on page 7o. In the wettest places it was evident that some beets had been killed and rotted saprophytically. But a striking feature of such places was the frequent occurrence of perfectly healthy, large, vigorous beets, unaffected by the wet soil and untouched by any parasitic rot. Kr. Hedgcock further reported the rot as present at Ames Grand Island on August 30, and still very serious. At is he reported this rot and Rhizoctonia as in a few cases ting the same beets. On August 14 several characteristic specimens of the rot were secured from a low place in a beet field near Union College, Lincoln, Nebr. Also 20 or more from the field north of Lincoln, from which the beets described on page 72 had been obtained the previous year. These resembled those obtained in 1901. No field observations were made after this time. There can be no doubt that, had such been made, the rot would have been found in many other places. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">75 INOCULATION EXPERIMENTS ON 8UGAR BEETS \\'/,n!f licet*.— The very first attempts at producing the dis - ease artificially in sound beets, by pricking in the exudate from affected beets, were successful. But the first attempts to isolate the organism by poured plates failed. Bouillon agar and bouillon gelatin of the composition given on pages 91 and 95 were used, and although the exudate from both the diseased and the inoculated beets was dense with small bacteria of apparently one kind, no bacteria of this kind appeared on the plates. After some experimenting it was found that pure and unattenuated cultures could be obtained by using cane-sugar agar, or beet- juice gelatin or agar pre - pared according to the formula on page 93. It was r sary to take great care that the agar was not too hot in pour - ing. Inoculations with such cultures gave the same results as inoculations with the exudate. At first it was deemed necessary to sterilize the surface of beets and checks with mercuric chlorid, by soaking in a 0.01 per cent solution. This killed and blackened the 1 for 1 — 2 cm. in from the surface, forming a layer which, though sterile at first, did not remain so, but invariably be - came slowly overgrown with Penicillium. Later beets were soaked in tap water for twelve hours before being sterilized. These did not absorb the poison, and consequently only a thin superficial layer was killed. The following notes taken on the beet and check shown in fig. 3 are typical. Both beets had been topped when harvested, about une month be - fore inoculation. They were washed, soaked in tap water for fourteen hours, soaked in a 0.01 per cent cent solution of mercuric chlorid for one hour; one beet was then stabbed at the tip with a needle which had been dipped in a colony of Jkict. teutlium in a beet-juice-agar plate; the other beet was similarly stabbed with a sterile needJe. Both were then placed under small bell jars with no additional moisture. 8th day. — Both free from fungi. 15th day.— Sticky exudate at tip; culture shows organism to be identical with that used for inoculation. Check un - changed. </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 b day. — Cut off 2 cm. of tip; typical exudate and pockets around line of inoculation. Bth day. — Exudate forming pockets under epidermis 10 from tip. Plates made from this place show one and one organism. No visible change in check. Kih day. — No further external evidence of decay; no th on beet tubes inoculated from the tip; strong growth bes inoculated from side. Ith day. — No further external evidence of decay; beet check cut open longitudinally and photographed. Beet pletely honeycombed from end to end with typical ;kets" of exudate. Odor strongly acid. Inoculations of tubes from middle parts failed: from crown successful; one organism present. Check beet sound at tip, but id at crown with a dry, fibrous, brown, alkaline rot ma Mae Rostr. ). One hall of inoculated beet returned to without sterile precautions; other half cut up for tubes Petri dishes. Halves of check beet returned to jar. ii day. — No change in half beet. No other organism growing. Check beet dried and covered with PenidUium. ■i day. — Small spot of white yeast on cut surface of half beet. "1st day.— Yeast spread over entire surface of half beet and growing rapidly. Check beet completely disorganized. Bth day. — Half beet completely overrun by yeast, and nken to less than one-fourth original size. Later, as the type of rot produced by this organism proved so unmistakable, the preliminary sterilization of the surface was omitted. It was found that when healthy beets were placed in even a moderately damp chamber, new would rapidly form over all wounded places; rootlets would put out; and, if not kept in darkness, chlorophyll would be formed in the regenerated tissue, and later, leaves be formed at tne crown. As beets in this condition readily ed the attacks of I'eiticil/ixm and indeed of all saprophy tic organisms, it was clearly not only not necessary but even not desirable to sterilize the surface. The fact that iiiitihim penetrated such obviously living beets, break - ing down tissue and forming the characteristic ''pockets'' </seg>
            <seg id="p077">77 and exudate throughout their whole interior, is the best proof of its parasitism. (Cf. Jones, /&lt;*•. ctL, pp. 305-306.) Pig. 4 shows a cross-section of a beet inoculated under these conditions. The section is cut just above the thickest part of the beet. The photograph was taken on the 26th day after inoculation, when every part of the beet was dead and the decay induced by the parasite apparently complete. a of Beet. — About 50 pieces of raw beet have been in - oculated, with the same essential results as in whole beets. Cubes of beet, even if not more than 3 cm. square, if placed in a damp chamber before getting dry, form a rough, irregular growth of new tissue over the surface, in the cells of which chlorophyll is readily formed. Such pieces re - main alive for from 6 to 10 weeks. Beets in the Ground. — Inoculations of such beets were made both in the greenhouse and out-of-doors. The beet shown in fig. 5 was started in the greenhouse, and set out in the open ground in June. It grew normally, but was of course more mature than beets planted out-of-doors in the spring. It was inoculated in the usual way and watered Ii inoculated beets which were allowed to decay in a damp nber the rot involved the entire beet. But no case has i observed in the field or as the result of inoculation of • in the ground, where the beet has rotted much above surface of the ground. Mather lirrts. — Several attempts were made to inoculate mother beets well along in their second year's growth. While the parasite obtained some slight foothold in such beets, its growth was weak and of short duration. This is probably to be attributed to the fact that in such beets the sugar upon which the bacterium largely depends is con - sumed in the production of stalk and leaves. Tubes made from such beets supported only a weak growth of the bac- Ynunij Jieets. — A few attempts were made to inoculate young beets, but all such inoculations failed. Tubes made from such beets did not support a good growth of the bac </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Bun: tubes from beets less than 3 cm. in maximum leter supported no growth at all. This was also buted to low sugar content. Attempts were also made to inoculate seedling beets with rot; results were negative. The roots and stems of seedlings just out of the ground were scarified, and watered with water containing a large quantity of exudate from a rotting beet. Some of the seedlings were in open pots in the greenhouse: others in a special apparatus for studying damping off (Metcalf and Hedgcock, 1903); still others in under bell jars. Some of the latter damped off with hi and /. ". lions. — Repeated attempts have been made to produce the rot by merely placing a loopful of a culture on the uninjured epidermis of a beet, or on the surface of a piece of beet after it had become completely covered with new tissue. Such attempts have been uniformly unsu&lt; ful, although care has been taken to keep such beet^&gt; in saturated air, in order to prevent the bacteria from dry - ing. There is no evidence so far either from field obser - vations or from inoculation experiments that infection ever takes place except through wounds. The rot was found to id rapidly through piles of beets in cellar and silo; but such beets are usually covered with wounds which have not (1, giving ready access to infecting organisms. I have described elsewhere (Metcalf, 1903) how beets pre - viously wounded on the surface may be inoculated by fr&lt; •»&gt; - living nematodes which have been grown in cultures of f/inui. I tn Water Supply. — As field observations indicated excessive moisture was favorable to the rot, a rather orate series of inoculations were made under varying litions of moisture. Results indicated that moisture Ted the disease at all stages, but especially at the out- Beets were inoculated by placing a loopful of exudate he freshly cut surface, which was then allowed to dry, beets being covered with a paper cone to keep off dust, o case did such beets decay. Other beets inoculated by sep puncture and kept dry in the same way, rotted in </seg>
            <seg id="p079">79 Iracteristic fashion, but only through the center : a shell ound tissue one eighth to one fifth of the diameter of the t surrounded the decayed portion. Beets not supplied h excess of moisture, but prevented from drying by be - placed under a bell jar showed the condition represented Bg. 4. Beets placed partly in water in closed vessels and julated, exhibited no shell of sound tissue; but the ex te formed in large pockets immediately under the lermis, as in the field. The results of these experiments icated what later results confirmed : that the bacterium ensitive to drynr Iantitp of Inoculation*, — Decay ensues more rapidly at if a considerable quantity of inoculating material is Many beets have been inoculated by inserting into sh in the surface an entire colony from a plate, or as h of a pure culture and its substratum as could be ed up with a 2 mm. loop. itiom &lt;&gt;/ Inoculation. — While the rot spreads most readily from the tip upwards, it is not impossible, as early results indicated that it might be, to inoculate a beet on the side. Apparently a beet may be successfully inoculated at any point except in the woody crown, if the point of inoculation is sufficiently moist. ropkytic Decay o —The behavior of check beets indicated that beets are not readily attacked by saprophytic organisms nor unfavorably affected by remaining in a damp chamber for many days. The two following experiments were made with especial reference to this question. I Twelve sound beets were freshly cut at the tip, and ed each in a closed jar with enough tap water to cover bottom of the vessel one centimeter deep. On thf all the beets but one (No. 12) were putting out roots and )ts and showed no signs of decay. On the '2vth day No. ras half covered with At\ . the shoots on the other :s had for the most part stopped growing. On the the water in most of the jars was turbid; No. 12 was pletely covered with In/ ; the roots and shoots of . 1, 2, 4, S, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, were partly dead; &gt; 10 were covered with slime at the tip, and appeared to </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 be rotting. On the 50th day Nos. 6, 7, 10 were half rotten with a brown, odorless, fibrous rot; Nos. 1, 2, 4, were beginning to rot. On the 70th day Nos. 3 and 5 were sound; Noa. 1, 2, 4, 8, 9, 11 were at least half rotten with the brown rot, and Penicillium, Aspergiilus and other fungi were com - pleting the decay. On the 80th day No. 5 was still sound, but roots and shoots dead; No. 3 was covered with fungi. On the wth day Fuxarium was growing on No. 5 and on the 90th day completely covered its surface. The brown rot is bacterial and seems to be caused by one of the bacteria referred to on page 7u. El check beet placed in a damp chamber with water in )ttom April 8, 1902, was still alive and free from decay ugust 21, when last observed, and had made con - kble growth. This is the longest time of resistance to noted — 136 days. Cultures of each of the nine saprophytic bacteria mentioned on page 69 were grown on beet tubes; ten beets were inoculated, one with each of these, and one with the brown-pigment-forming bacillus. All soon rendered the water rather turbid, B. vulgatnu rendering it decidedly viscid. On the 10th day all the beets were growing and showing no signs of decay. On the 25th day the beet inoculated with the brown bacillus was beginning to rot at the tip in a characteristic fashion. The tip of the beet inoculated with B. myoiiiiis was soft. On the 40th day the roots and the new growth on the surface of all the beets appeared dead ; the brown rot organism was slowly but steadily rotting its beet; the tip of the beet inoculated with B. myootfea was rotten a little way above the water. Spots of undetermined species of Fcnicillium, Aspergillus, Muoor, and Fiixurhim were growing in all but one. This beet which had been inoculated with rium remained sound until the 82dday, when molds appeared on its surface and it rotted rapidly. Superficially at least, the rottiner appeared to be caused by fungi, although there were plenty of bacteria in the last stages. Poured plates showed that no one organism took part in this decay. The brown rot and possibly B. mycuules may have been primary causes in the decay of their beets. No sub- </seg>
            <seg id="p081">81 Kent experiments were made on It. mycoiden, but this single rvation is of interest in connection with JLinharf s re - on the bacteria that are found associated with damping henomena. (Linhart, 1899). ndary Organisms Completing Decay. — These organisms may be widely different, and as a result the appearance and odor of beets affected with the rot varies widely in the field. In 1901 hardly a beet was found in which the tissue already decayed was not infested with mites of the genus In 1902 the mites werw observed in only a few cases. The mites do not follow up the rot very closely, so that the characteristic pockets and exudate occupy a con - siderable space in the beet, and the rot is thus easily dis - tinguishable A small nematode ( Ithaixi / (Claus) Biitschliy) is of frequent occurrence, and probably is an im - portant agent in disseminating the disease (Metcalf, 1!&gt;&lt;&gt;3). Several yeasts of undetermined identity regularly follow the rot. All these organisms are particularly luxuriant when the decaying beet is in wet soil; and as they follow the primary rot very closely, the appearance of the beet is rendered quite different from that of one affected with the parasitic rot alone (Cf. figs. 2. 5 and 4) or from one infested with mites. I the laboratory, experiments were made to ascertain t organism could grow on old beet tubes and on sli( ulated beet kept moist in Petri dishes. The ordinary ophytic organisms of the laboratory utterly failed to v on such pieces. Only and a white y- Mibly the same as that occurring in the field, made any wth. Specimens of Tt/nxjly pints placed in tubes or Petri es with pieces of decayed beet, multiplied and produced same changes as in the field. By placing earth in the es of decayed beet and keeping it wet or putting the tyed beet in the ground, decomposition took place iugh the agency of various bacteria as in the field. Kis, however, singular that pieces of the decayed beet wholly unattacked by such common and omnivorous :i as FenicilliuiH, Fuxarium, A </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Etmiiii. Botrytia, and Mucor. What there is in the de - beet that inhibits the growth of these must remain a ;t for future investigation. / a ml .1 The appearance and color of diseased beets vary greatly, even when unaffected by secondary organisms. The color of the beet represented in fig. 3 was thus described in notes taken when the beet was cut. The color symbols are those of Prang's system. "When first cut, general color Y6, or a trifle lighter, with darker streaks in no definite position; woody parts of crown slate color to black. General color darkens gradually upon exposure to air to 3Y5 or 3Y6; streaks to OYO 3 . Woody parts of crown quite black. No color changes after the first six hours except those incident Ii beets newly inoculated and in early stages observed in fields, there is no discoloration of the tissue. The first age is toward yellow, spreading into a clay color or y; then these colors gradually darken. But several ;s have been cut open which were half rotten and yet e scarcely altered in color; while others have been jrved which were very dark in color in the earliest ;es. ideal Cltange* in Diseased Beets. — The chemical changes in the beet resulting from this rot are quite distinct so long as no other organisms are present to complicate the process. The cellulose walls of the parenchyma cells are broken down into a viscid gummy substance which fills the spaces made by the dissolved and collapsed cells, forming the characteristic pockets. The surrounding tissue which is not dissolved is killed, discolored, and fails to respond to Russow's cellulose test. The cane sugar is nearly all, if not all. inverted. Acetic acid is formed inconsiderable quantity as a by-product ; formic and succinic acid and alcohol are present in appreciable amounts. The extreme acidity of these beets affords one very prominent diagnostic feature of this rot. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">83 INOCULATION EXPERIMENTS UPON OTHER VEGETABLES I inoculating vegetables other than the sugar-beet, a iderable quantity of the pure culture on a piece of it* tratum was inserted, and at least the place of inocu - n kept wet. The results are so uniform that details will be given. Only ripe vegetables and fruits were used. Upon red garden beet the bacterium made slow but pro - longed growth. In half long orange carrots the tissue be - came involved for 3 cm. about the place of inoculation in two out of five carrots, but did not spread further. In sweet potatoes growth ensued immediately around the place of in - oculation, but did not spread. In ripe bananas growth started with apparent vigor, but the bananas rotted with some rot of their own too soon to make extensive obser - vations. Onions, hyacinth bulbs, and parsnips were un - affected when inoculated in December, 1901 : but when the experiment was repeated in April, 1902, the rot spread a varying distance — never more than 2 cm. from the place of inoculation. On potato, white turnip, radish, tomato, and apple, bo growth occurred. THE ORGANISM. I. MORPHOLOGICAL AND GENERAL CHARACTERS. Form. — A short rod with rounded ends, about half as thick as long . — Average 1.5 microns in length, by 0.8 microns in diameter. Maximum, 2.2 microns in length by 1 micron in thickness. Minimum. 0.8 microns in length, by 0.5 microns in thickness. Rods ready to divide, measuring 3 microns in length, are so common in certain preparations aa to give a very deceptive idea of the proper size. These observations were made on sugar bouillon cultures 48 hours old, the bouillon being of the formula and titre given on pag&gt; Measures taken on all other media used, solid or fluid, in - cluding the exudate from decaying beets, show no essential deviation from the above. Within these limits the organism is remarkably uniform in all media. Measurements of hanging drop preparations do not differ from those of stained preparations. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 —The degree of aggregation varies greatly on different media. In the decaying beets, on vegetable tubes, and on liquid media, single rods and diplo-rods are much more common than chains; and where chains occur, the; are rarely of over ten elements. In sugar gelatin, long chains of fifty or more elements are formed, which, how - ever, break apart very readily, and consequently are not easily observed. In sugar agar long chains are formed at the beginning of growth, but as soon as the agar begins to liquify, these chains are broken up, and the subsequent growth shows only single rods, diplo-rods, and short chains. In some fluid media which have been rendered alkaline with chalk, a thick floccose or cumuloid — not viscid — precipitate settles to the bottom of the tube. This precipitate exhibit* chains of considerable length, sometimes of over 50 elements. No zoogloea or surface-film or rim-film of any sort is formed upon any medium. Iitilitij and /Vr/r/W/a.— Motility has not been observed on medium, in young or old cultures. In media that are rendered viscid by its growth, this organism exhibits vnian motion, but no true progressive motion has been rved. All attempts to demonstrate flagella have failed. . — No capsule has been observed upon any medium. None is demonstrated by any capsule stain. ulation. — Spore formation has not been observed. In very old cultures vacuolated forms have been seen which when stained -mith anilin stains might be mistaken for stages of sporulation. Spore staining (Abbot's method) reveals the real nature of these appearances. olutkm Form*. — In old cultures upon which the bac - terium has made vigorous growth, vacuolated forms some what larger than the normal size of the organism are occasionally found. No mycobacteria or other strikingly abnormal forms have been seen. ning /traction*. — The bacterium stains readily and quickly with all the common aqueous anilin stains. It is stained by Gram's stain. While no exact comparativr studies were made on the relative staining facility of young and old cultures, no striking difference has been observed. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">• 85 Wwl Reactions, — Bacteria from inoculated beets, beet tubes, and cane sugar agar were employed in determining the wall reactions. The bacteria were stained yellow by a solution of iodine in potassic iodide, but this is not followed by a blue color upon the addition of sulphuric acid. There is thus no evidence of cellulose in the wall. (Cf. E. F. Pigment. — No pigment is produced upon any medium. (hlnr. — The bacterium develops an acid odor of varying intensity upon different media. There is no offensive odor at any time. No odor of indol, skatol, methyl-amine, butyric acid, mercaptan, sulphuretted hydrogen, or ammonia reduced under any conditions. II. CULTURAL CHARACI vk«;etabi.e i i The medium was prepared by placing slant cylinders of raw beet in test-tubes, with enough distilled water to cover the lower third of the slant. The tubes promptly sterilized in an Arnold sterilizer for 20 minutes on three successive days. Later in the work I found that steril - izing for 20 minutes on two successive days was enough, pro vided the tubes had been prepared in a cleanly way. Be - fore being used, all such tubes were kept at laboratory tem - p.-rature i for at least three days, and the few that spoiled were rejected. This method has proved more efficient than incubating the tubes at ;:■ C, since one of the undescribed bacteria (see page 69) which occurs as y frequent contamination is inhibited but not killed by the higher temperature. I have also sterilized beet tubes in an autoclave, keeping them for 10 minutes at a temperature of Hit C. No cultural difference could b^ detected bet such tubes and those sterilized in an Arnold sterilizer. Ereak cultures on this medium result in a viscid, clear, use growth, strongly and increasingly acid, which ads rapidly and evenly from the line of inoculation; and, Kin this work, the methods so fully and accurately worked out lith l'.MJl have :herwise specified, with this ition. that t :it glass 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 if the culture is not weakened in any way, covers the whole surface of the beet and fills the water in from 12 to 24 hours C. At first the growth is as clear as water, but gradual - ly it becomes translucent — like ground glass. It is not at any time nacreous; /. e., it does not reflect rainbow col- The growth in the water is so solid that the tube can be inverted. It is viscid, but cannot be drawn out into threads: a portion lifted out from the rest breaks away readily, leaving a cone about 5 mm. high which may remain elevated above the general surface for from 10 to 30 seconds. Its thickness and vigor varies with the particular piece cf beet; it may be as thick as 1 cm. on some, or less than one tenth of that thickness on others. Viscidity and color do not appear to vary. Sometimes the growth is smooth and even, and conse - quently appears wet and shining; at other times the surface is irregular, the growth consisting of large drops more or less isolated; or again, the drops may be so small as to give the surface an irregular, shagreened appearance. This appears to be wholly due to the way in which the surface of the beet cylinder is cut. The organism does not grow on the vascular tissue; consequently, there is thin growth or no growth where this tissue is exposed and a heavy growth where a thick and uninterrupted parenchyma layer lies on the surface. The bacteria penetrate the tissue, dissolving the paren - chyma and forming "pockets." as in the raw beet. As timt - goes on. the half cylinder of beet shrivels, until little is left but the vascular tissue. This fragment sticks to the side of the glass, and the viscid bacterial mass remains in the bottom of the tube, hardening gradually, but not shrinking greatly from its original volume. Drier tubes were also used, in which only the curved bottom of the test tube was filled with water. Upon such tubes the organism begins to grow normally, but seldom continues long enough to cover the eutire surface of the beet, although growth may take place inside the beet tissue. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 lucent only in the thickest places. Such cultures soon lose their vitality. Fully mature beets were used for making these tubes. Upon those made from young beets, the organism makes no growth. This difference appears to be due to differenct - in sugar content. Upon tubes made from beets stunted by the "curly top" disease, the organism made no growth, or only the feeblest. Even upon different parts of the same the bacterium may show difference in vieor;». &lt;j., tubes from the crown of the beet support less vigorous growth than those from lower down. § general the bacterium is short-lived upon beet tubes, noculation limit varying from 5 to 18 days. Its life is est in the tubes where it grows wjth greatest luxuriance. El &lt; in, ilen IU'*-t. — Upon this medium, growth en - ar to that on the sugar beet, only less vigorous, and nued for a somewhat longer time. The tubes were pre - 1 in the same way as the preceding. Petiole. — Pieces of large petioles were cut 4 cm. long, split, and each half placed in a test-tube with a small Quantity of distilled water and sterilized for 15 minutes on 8 successive days. No growth, or at least no visible growth, ensued upon this medium, either on the solid substratum or in the water. The water did not become in the least thick or turbid. But beet tubes were successfully inoculated from petiole tubes 2* days old; showing at least that the bacteria used in inoculation live in this medium for that length of time. This I believe to be the correct explanation : for not only was there no growth in these tubes visible to the naked eye or the lens, but cover-glass preparations made from the water and surface of che petiole showed hardly any organ - isms; and poured plates made from four tubes showed that in these tubes no more organisms were present on the fourteenth day than on the second. E far-beet Leaf. — Pieces of green healthy leaves d in tubes with distilled water and sterilized for 15 tes on 3 successive days. The results were essentially ame as with the petioles. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 sugar-beet tubes, except that they were sterilized for 15 minutes oh 4 successive days. The first tubes used were early in December, 1901 : inoculations of these tubes 'ed in no visible growth. Beet tubes inoculated from these gave no uniform results — tubes from a culture 4 days old remaining sterile, while in one case a fairly vigorous culture -•■cured from a tube 16 days old. In April, 1902. I again inoculated some potato tubes. The bacterium grew in the water at the bottom of the tubes, making a clear viscid growth similar to that in the water of the beet tubes but not growing so rapidly. There was no visible growth on the surface of the potato. About a month later this experiment epeated with the same positive result. (rrot — Carrot tubes were prepared in the same w;i tubes. In the water of these tubes the organism grew. ; slowly than in the water of the beet tubes. In 17 out ie 40 carrot tubes upon which the bacterium was grown. ) growth was- also made on the slant surface of the table. This growth was clear and viscid, and in all re - ts resembled that in the beet tubes, except that it vigorous, longer lived, and slightly more acid. Ii e carrots showed the same variation with the season ih characterized the potato. Of the 15 tubes inoculated inuary, only 3 showed growth on the vegetable; while &gt; tubes inoculated late in April, 14 showed such growth greater or less extent. In 5 of these the growth pene - id the tissue for a short distance. Kboth trials check tubes of R. aarotovonu made copious and al growth, and did not show any noteworthy difference the two occasion*. White Turnip. — Tubes prepared in the same way as beet No growth ensued. Eight tubes were inoculated in December, 1901, and 10 in April, 1902. Two check tui rntonn us made typical growth. Itdish. — Short red radishes were used: tubes prepared beet tubes. Results negative. Ten tubes were t one time, in May, 1902. Two check tubes of H. can made good growth, but not so copious as on turnip or ot. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 I snip. — Tubes prepared like beet tubes. The bacterium readily in the water, rendering it viscid; and in 4 of ) tubes inoculated, some slight growth occurred on the surface, but did not penetrate the tissue. The inocu i limit was 17 to 25 days. E Tubes prepared like beet tubes. The bacterium in the water enough to feebly cloud it, but did not r it viscid. There was no growth on the vegetable. K'&lt;t Potato. — Tubes prepared like potato tubes. The rium grew vigorously in the water, rendering it v. im 36 to 48 hours, but no growth was observed on the Rtonut. — Tubes prepared like beet tubes. Eiglr were inoculated at 8 different time&gt;. No visible h resulted. Tomato. — Red ripe tomato&lt; cut in | md each solid piece, together with a quantity of juice and pulp, was placed in a tube. No water was added. The tubes were sterilized in an Arnold sterilizer for 25 minutes on 2 suc - cessive days. No visible growth ensued in any case. The inoculation limit of these tomato tubes was extraordinarily loiiirione successful inoculation of a beet tube was made from a tomato tube 56 days old. Twenty tubes of this medium were used. Two check tubes of /&gt;'. a i showed fair growth. Banana. — Tubes were made from ripe yellow banan tme manner as beet tubes. Sterilization considerably darkens the banana tissue, making it of a grayish salmon color. Upon this medium the bacterium makes more vigorous growth than upon any other vegetable tissu - cept beots. The water in the bottom of the tube is rerr I, and the surface of the banana covered in from 24 to :56 hours. The character of the growth is the same as that on the sugar beet. The bacterium does not, however, pene - the tissue. The inoculation limit of these tut slightly longer than that of sugar-beet tubes. Kte. — Tubes were prepared in the sam beet from large ripe winesaps. No growth Three 'able. </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 check tubes of O'Gara's apple rotting bacillus* made a copious growth. The inoculation limit was quite long, varying from 15 to 29 days. -Tubes prepared like tomato tubes. Only 6 tubes re inoculated and none exhibited growth. illon Agar, — The agar was made in the following way: 740 grams of finely minced round steak was placed in a large beaker with 1500 cc. of distilled water, and stirred with a glass rod. After being kept in the refrigerator for 20 hours, the mixture was squeezed through cheese cloth, leav - ing about 1550 cc. of red turbid fluid. This was steamed in an Arnold sterilizer fur 30 minutes and filtered through paper: the result was 1510 cc. of very light colored clear bouillon which titrated +2.8. To this was added 15 grams of Witte's peptonum siccum and 7..") grams of sodium chlorid. To 500 cc. of this bouillon 5 grams of thread agar was added; this was dissolved, the mixture filtered through cotton, and the titre adjusted to +1.5 of Puller's scale by the standard method. The fluid was then cleared with the white of an egg, filtered through paper, tubed, and steril - ized for 20 minutes on the 2 following days. In plates of this agar colonies did not appear for at least 4* hours, and then made slow and limited growth. The submerged colonies were fusiform, of sharp outline and porcelaneous, /. e., translucent, white or remotely bluish — appearing like a bit of fine porcelain or finely ground glass. Under the lens the colonies appear more granular, and mor e refractive than to the naked eye. The colonies are of various sizes, in no case exceeding 1 mm. in length, and sel - dom exceeding 0.5 mm. The surface colonies are round or nearly so, thin, not viscid, porcelaneous to transparent, with entire margin, very slightly thicker and consequently less translucent in the center than at the edge. The margin appears under the lens to be minutely granular. Growth is slow, and the colonies are seldom over 0.5 mm. in diameter. •O'Gara, P J Preliminary notice of a bacterium a with apple rot. Read before the Nebraska Academy of Sciences, February, AI.AK-A&lt;.AK </seg>
            <seg id="p091">91 Streak cultures in agar tubes are equally slow or even slower in development. Growth begins in the water of con - densation at the bottom of the slant. In some tubes which were not fresh, i. e. t in which the slant surface had become somewhat dry, growth was confined to the water; although check tubes of H. coU and H. amtyUwnrui developed over the sur - face without noticeable retardation. In perfectly fresh tubes individual colonies begin to appear along the line of inoculation which are in no respect different from surface colonies on the plates. If these colonies are numerous enough to fuse, the margin of the streak thus produced is irregularly undulate. This surface growth tends to pene - trate the agar, but not so noticeably as the growth in the water, which may erow down into the agar 5 mm. or more. When this occurs, the water is rendered slightly viscid. Eib cultures in agar tubes result in the development in I i* hours of a line of growth which is at first filiform gradually becomes minutely beaded. Individual ies are usually ellipsoid. Growth is slow, but of equal at bottom and top; the whole line does not attain a i of overt i. 5 mm. in any case. The surface growth is the surface colony of a plate, if the agar is sufficiently The inoculation limit of stab cultures is rather loni: Kdays; while the extreme limit observed in a streak re was Hi days. This appears to be due to the fact the slant tubes dry out sooner than the stab cult ximents in making inoculations from the diflV parts of streak cultures confirm this view. It must be confessed that there is very little in the appearance of this bacterium on the conventional meat Kagar to distinguish it from many others, ar was also used of the following formula: Distilled water Liebig's meat extract 1.5 grams Sodium chloric! 8.5 grams *\ij(l I*- cl£Ttir . . • '• JJFiilllS Witte's peptonum su cum . .'.. grains </seg>   
	           <seg id="p092">92 This mixture was boiled for 10 minutes, cleared with the white of one egg, and filtered through paper. As upon titration it was found to be -i 1.8, no alkali was added. Upon this agar the bacterium makes no growth. illon .If/"/ 1 and Vane Sugar, — Two hundred and fifty cubic centimeters of the agar last described were melted, and 12.5 grams (5 per cent) of commercial beet sugar were i. Upon this medium the bacterium produced a growth profoundly different from that on meat-peptone agar. In stab cultures a delicate filiform line of growth appeared in about 8 hours from the time of inoculation. During the 18 hours the line trebled in size, attaining a general thickness of 1 to 8 mm. ; while several wing-like outgrowths had begun to grow rapidly from near the bottom of the line id the exterior of the tube. In radial view these out - growths appeared lenticular: in longitudinal view, nearly circular. Their actual form appears to be roughly that of a double-convex lens. The surface of these outgrowth - of the line is irregular, with many fiame-like prolongations. \q end of 48 hours two of these outgrowths had reached the wall of the tube: the line in the center had still further thickened, excapt within 1 cm. of the top of the agar. The surface growth at the top of the stab, on the surface of the medium, appeared like a small drop of viscid fluid, hemispherical in shape. This drop did not increase in size after the first 12 to 1h hours; in later cultures in which the agar was not so moist this drop did not form at all, but the growth was entirely below the surface. The surface growth and that in the agar is like the growth inside inocu - beets and on vegetable tubes— fluid, viscid, vitrei lucent, strongly acid to litmus, always without color. :i agar is used which is dark in color, the contrast be - tween it and this colorless portion through which the rium has grown is very striking. By the end of the fith day the tube could not be inverted, since the agar was fluid in the center. By the end of the 10th day the bacte - rium had grown practically all through the agar, except on the top, and the agar was reduced to a viscid, colorless, translucent fluid, slightly thicker in consistency than </seg>
            <seg id="p093">93 glycerin. The tube then slowly dried out, the unliquefied ■tions at the top and elsewhere sticking to the side of the a; the liquefied portion finally drying to about one fifth of original bulk and darkening slightly in color. (Fig. 6.) While such a liquefaction of agar has never been rep&lt; before, so far as I am aware, it may be not uncommon. Stab cultures in agar are not commonly used, and this phe - nomenon would be observed only with difficulty in slant cultures. Whether or not the liquefaction is physiologic ally comparable with the liquefaction of gelatin must be settled by further investigation. Kon this medium the organism is very long-lived, ul inoculations having been made (in cold weather) tubes 65 days old. Ereak cultures in slant tubes of this medium begin fa p in the water of condensation at the bottom of the and unless the tube is quite fresh, no growth U Ke on the slant surface. When it does occur, the gro droplets, like the growth on the surface in a stab cul - . The growth in the water appears whiter than on ium yet described, but soon begins to liquefy the ■ at the bottom of the water, when it assumes the chara istic appearance of the submerged growth in the stab cul - ture. This liquefaction may continue downward for 1 cm. ; but in no case have I seen it extend farther. Tubes of the same agar containing 10, 12|, 15, and B It of sugar were also studied. In the first three, growth lightly retarded at the outset, but is then more vigorous, liquefaction more complete. In the last, growth was v and feeble, and only a small cylinder liquefied. Ten cent appears to be about the optimum amount of sugar this medium. U/ar. — Two large beets were ground up and the juice pressed out with a screw press. The juice was black and very acid, titrating +6.2. This was filtered through cotton, and without further clarifying, and without addition of alkali, 1 per cent of agar was added. The agar thus obtained was black and perfectly opaque. In stab cultures the bacterium grew luxuriantly, following the same </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 mode of growth as on sugar agar. As fast as liquefaction took place, the agar was decolorized. Agar tubes were also prepared from beet juice extracted in the following way: A large beet was chopped up fine, covered with twice its bulk of distilled water, and allowed to stand for 24 hours. The whole was then boiled until the beet fragments were soft, and the liquid drawn off by squeezing the beet pulp in cheese-cloth. The juice obtained in this way was colorless, and the agar fairly clear in con - sequence, though less clear than bouillon agar. It was found exceedingly difficult to filter any beet juice agar through paper : accordingly it was filtered through cotton, which gives as clear an agar as one needs for most purposes. Growth on this agar is not optically different from that on a 5 per cent sugar agar ; but of all the media used for making poured plates of the bacterium, this was the best, since the bacterium did not become attenuated upon it for some time. Kfew slant tubes of both beet juice agars were inoculated, same types of growth followed that have been de - led for slant tubes of sugar agar. The inoculation time limit of these tubes cannot be given in days, as it varies greatly. In general, the culture is alive until liquefaction is complete, and the tube begins to dry out. In making media from beet juice, no alkali has been added in any case. Consequently the titre of the beet juice media has varied greatly. GELATIN Iive hundred cubic centimeters of the bouillon described page 90 was stiffened with 50 gram's of gelatin and isted to -rl.y by the addition of caustic soda. Poured plates were made with this medium at the same time and by the same method as the agar plates described on page 9&lt;&gt;. In about 48 hours growth became evident. The submerged colonies were mostly fusiform, but some ellipsoid,- sharp in outline, porcelaneous to dirty white in color — noticeably more opaque than the submerged colonies of the agar plates. In 72 hours the most of these fusiform colonies had become spherical and attained a maximum </seg>
            <seg id="p095">95 diameter of 0.5 mm. Surface colonies did not differ essen - tially in size or appearance from the surface colonies on agar, except that they were somewhat more opaque. On 3 plates poured a few weeks later, when the gelatin had be - come somewhat drier, no surface colonies appeared. The gelatin did not become liquefied. Stab cultures in tubes of this medium resulted in a thin, beaded, dirty white line appearing in about 48 hours. The line and some of the individual colonies attained a maximum diameter of about 1 mm. The surface growth was limited, and quite like a surfaee colony of a plate. The gelatin did not show the slightest signs of liquefaction. Shaken tubes resulted in scattered colonies, from 0.5 to 1 mm. in diameter, in appearance like the spherical sub - merged colonies of the plates. There was no liquefaction. No streak cultures were made. Gelatin was also made by the formula on page 91, substituting 50 grams of gelatin for ," grams of agar. No growth took place upon this medium, though check tubes of ft. pyocyanea grew normally. Bouillon Gelatin and Cane Sugar. — Two hundred fifty cubic - centimeters of the gelatin last described was melted, and 12.5 grams (5 per cent) of commercial beet sugar was added. Upon this medium the bacterium makes one of its most characteristic growths, strikingly different from that on any other medium. In stab cultures a delicate beaded line de velops in from 12 to 18 hours, consisting of tiny colonies more or less distinct, and quite translucent. This line steadily increases in size for from 3 to 5 days, and by the end of this time may nearly fill the tube. This bacterial mass, now perhaps a centimeter or more in thickness, I margin like that of a cumulus cloud — it appears as if con - sisting of a mass of semi plastic spheres rolled together. In appearance it is porcelaneous to translucent. The gelatin is not liquefied (nor would liquefaction be expected in the presence of cane sugar). If the gelatin is liquefied by heat and poured out, the bacterial growth remains coherent. It is not viscid, like the growth in sugar agar, but feels crisp when crushed between the fingers. Microscopical examina - tion shows it to consist of rods set very close together and </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 arranged in radial order in each constituent colony. The longest chains occur in this growth that this bacterium forms upon any medium. The inoculation limit of such tubes is long, but variable; the determining factor is apparently the drying of the medium, as it is in the case of sugar agar. Ielatin tubes containing 10, 121, 15, and 2o per cent of ir were also studied. Growth ensued in all, but was rded in the 15 per cent gelatin three days, and in the 20 cent five to eight days. In the latter, growth was not »rous. The growth in the 12£ per cent tubes was some - t more vigorous than in the 10 per cent tubes; 12£ per i appears to be near the optimum amount of sugar in tin for the best growth of the organism. &lt;icl&lt;ititt. — Upon this medium, from beet juice made by the method given on page 94, the bacterium made essentially the same growth as on 5 per cent cane sugar gelatin. OTHKK MEDIA In slant tubes of Loffler's blood serum, very slight, dirty white, viscid growth occurred in the water of con - densation, but not on the surface; nor did the growth pen - etrate or liquefy the medium at any point. On egg albumen no growth occurred; nor on Smith's nutrient starch jelly Bouillon. — The bouillon used (see page 90) contained a considerable amount of muscle sugar. A fermen - tation tube of it inoculated with H. ruli gave 2.6 cc. of gas. In this medium, adjusted to +1.5, the bacterium made a poor growth. Forty-eight hours after inoculation the lower part of the tube appeared slightly clouded; within the next 36 hours the remainder of the liquid became clouded in the same way. After the fourth day a very thin precipitate settled to the bottom — in some tubes none at all. The clouding is not enough to produce opacity. No pellicle appears at any time. The medium never clears, nor is there any breaking into strata beyond the slight sedimentation already referred to. The growth renders the medium ac»d ; five tubes at the end of 4 days titrating +2.4, +2.4, +2.7, </seg>
            <seg id="p097">97 ■+■*•• o, -\- &amp;t, Op rcsDtJC'ti vciy . idr dou 11 ion docs not become in the least viscid. Bouillon was also used which was made from Liebig's extract. This bouillon was free from muscle sugar; at least 3 fermentation tubes of it inoculated with5.ro/ishowed no growth in the closed arm and formed no gas. This I have found since to hold true in every case with bouillon made from Liebig's extract. But the titre of this bouillon has been observed to vary considerably, the extremes being Kand -f-2.9. Upon this bouillon the bacterium makes no le growth. t500 cc. flask of bouillon made from meat was freed from :le sugar by inoculation with B. eoH in the usual way. titre was adjusted to +1.5 Two fermentation tubes of bouillon, inoculated with B. ooU showed growth only in open end. The bacterium made no growth in this um. iilmi and Cam 8ugar. — Both the bouillon prepared from steak and freed from muscle sugar, and bouillon prepared from Liebig's extract, were used as a basis for this medium. No difference could be detected in the growth in the two bouillons when sugar was added ; so for the test work the bouillon from Liebig's extract was used, with the addition of 5 per cent of commercial beet sugar. This proved an ex - cellent medium for this bacterium; the bouillon began to be clouded in about 10 hours after inoculation, and the clouding gradually increased until the end of the third day, when the medium became nearly opaque. No pellicle was formed, but a slight sediment was evident on the 2d day, which slowly increased until the 5th day. This sediment appears to be due to the settling of the bacteria to the bottom of the tube, and to consist wholly of bacteria; as no sharp line separates it from the fluid above (which is more dense toward the bottom than at the top), it is difficult to exactly define its thickness. The bouillon, originally adjusted to -(-1.5, becomes more acid day by dajr. The maximum degree of acidity observed was +5.2. ■bout 8 per cent of cane sugar in bouillon appears to be optimum amount. Tubes containing 10, 12, 14, 16, and </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 Ijr cent were tried. Growth in the 10 per cent solution retarded slightly, no clouding of the tubes being evident ,t least 60 hours. In the 12 per cent solution no growth lared for 6o hours in any tubes and 6 out of the 10 tubes lined sterile. In 14, lti, and 18 per cent tubes no growth ed. The optimum and maximum percentages of sugar lar to be lower in bouillon cultures than in agar or bin made with the same bouillon. The inoculation time limit of 5 per cent sugar bouillon tubes appears to be from 6 to 10 days; of 8 per cent tubes, 5 to 8 days. table Juicca. — Beet juice was prepared by the method given on page 94. The bacterium grew readily in this medium, and without retardation. The juice became clouded in about 12 hours, and the clouding gradually increased for the next 2 days. Growth was apparently much the same as that on 5 per cent cane sugar bouillon ; the same gradual clouding, slight sedimentation, absence of ring or pellicle, slight viscidity, and increase in acidity was observed. Three lots of this beet juice were prepared, which titrated +3.2 and +2.1 respectively. In spite of the difference in the titre no difference in the crowth of the organism could be detected. Ilroths were also prepared by the same method from beet res. white potatoes, carrots, white turnips, and tomatoes, growth was apparent in the beet leaf, tomato, or turnip :e. In the potato broth growth took place which was iter than that in beet juice, and no sediment was de - ited. The growth in carrot broth was similar in all re - cts to that in the beet juice. These broths were all acid itmus. Milk. — Separator milk was used, free from cream, and am - photeric in reaction. Tubes of it were sterilized in an Arnold sterilizer for 20 minutes on 3 successive days. Many inoculations were made on this medium, but in no case was there acy evidence of growth. The milk did not undergo any change in appearance or consistency; tubes 5, 10, and 15 days old did not coagulate upon being boiled in a water - bath. </seg>
            <seg id="p099">99 II ami &lt; /'/•.— Chemically pure saccharose was used. No change in the appearance or consistency of nilk was apparent at any time; but the milk coagulated irmly in tubes 6 days old, upon being boiled for 3 tea in a water-bath. This was the only optical evidence owth; there was no separation of curd at any time, nor the milk acid to taste or smell. That some acid was uced was shown by the next experiments. Litmus Milk. — In this medium no growth occurred. Litmut Milk- and Ocme 8ugar. — On the 3d day, inoculated tubes showed a slight lightening of the blue color as com - pared with check tubes which had not been inoculated. A distinct reddish tint was apparent by the 5th day, but did not generally increase subsequently. Boiling coagulates the milk without changing the color. In all experiments with milk, check tubes of li. ooH were employed. SYNTHETIC MEDIA t'achinsky'* Solution. — Upon this medium no growth occurred, though check tubes of / - made good growth. Five per cent of c. p. saccharose was added tu a portion; in tubes of this a very faint milky clouding became visible at the bottom by the 3d day. Inoculations made with a 2 mm. loop from this elouded portion to beet tubes resulted in an unmistakable growth of the bacterium. In spite of the fact that no development took place in tubes of pure Uschinsky"s solution the bacterium lived in such tubes for a long time, if protected from the light. Vigorous growth on beet tubes has been obtained upon inoculation from a perfectly transparent tube of Uschinsky's solution 58 days old. The inoculation limit in tubes with cane sugar appears to be much shorter — not over 14 days. No growth appeared on this medium; check tubes of li. Solution. — This was made by the following formula : Distilled water 200 cc. I Magnesium sulphate « »• 04 gram Acid potassium phosphate 0.2 gram Ammonium phosphate 2. grams Glycerin 9. grams </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 Kion of 5 per cent of sugar the same sort of growth — a clouding near the bottom of the tube — that appeared e last described medium, appeared here, but with con- Kable retardation, not being visible until the 5th day itenr's Solution : Tap water : . 200 cc. 95 per cent alcohol 6 cc Ammonium phosphate 0.1 gram Calcium chlorid 0.02 eram No growth appeared in this medium; nor with the ad- dition of 5 per cent of cane sugar. Frcu dilution: Distilled water 500 cc. Sodium chlorid 2.5 grams Di-potassium phosphate 1. gram Ammonium lactate 3. grams Sodium asparaginate 2. grams No growth occurred in this medium; but upon the addition of 5 per cent of cane sugar a clouding so slight as to b&gt; - scarcely perceptible appeared quite uniformly throughout the tube, beginning at the bottom on the 4th day. No growth appeared, although check tubes of li. &lt;-oli grew normally. Upon the same solution without the sodium chlorid no growth was made. This fact —that the bacterium will not grow on peptone solutions has added great difficulties to the task of working out its biochemical relations. Solutions were also made consisting of 1 per cent peptone Iater plus 1 per cent of each of the following substances: ;rose, Merck's anhydrous grape sugar, saccharose, &gt;se, maltose, dextrin, mannite, laevulose, galactose, and erin. These solutions were used in fermentation tubes, growth occurred in any tubes except those containing harose and dextrose. In the former a very faint cloud - _ appeared on the 3d day in the open arm ; on the 4th day the lower third of the closed arm was clouded ; on the 5th day, the entire tube. No gas was formed. This clouding was very slight indeed, far less than that in corresponding tubes of sugar bouillon. Inoculations from this tube to beet </seg>
            <seg id="p101">101 tubes resulted in a very feeble but characteristic growth. In the dextrose tube a similar clouding appeared during the 3d day in the open arm : and on the 7th day had spread through the tube. No gas was formed. Inoculations on the 8th day from this tube to beet tubes resulted in no growth. The experiments with saccharose and dextrose tubes were repeated ; as the results were not uniform, and often no growth took place in the tubes, these media were abandoned. The following solution was tried with reference to nitrate All synthetic media were sterliized in an Arnold sterilizer. Ill PHYSICAL AND BI(K HF.MICAL RELATIONS RELATION TO TEMPERATURE. Death-point — Beet juice prepared according to the method described on page 94, and titrating +2.3, was used as a medium in determining temperature relations. Thin walled test tubes about 15 mm. in diameter were used; these plunged to the bottom of thenlugs into the water-bath, and kept there 10 minutes. Check tubes were employed in every case. As nearly as possible the methods employed were those of E. F. Smith (1901, pp. i. A water-bath provided with a mechanical agitator and a Novy-Reichert thermo-regulator was employed. The tubes were inoculated from beet tubes with a 2 mm. loop, from one to three hours before being heated in the water-bath. After heating they allowed to cool at room temperature. From all tubes in which clouding ensued, poured plates were made and the colonies isolated and studied in order to make certain that the clouding was not due to contaminations. The results of the careful testing of 52 tubes by these methods indicate that the thermal death-point is very near 45° C. This point varies as much as 2 degrees (44° — 46°) on different media; but not enough experiments were made to demonstrate con - clusively what is the factor of variation. Maximum Teiuperatwrt. — Experiments to determine the uction, but upon it the bacterium made no growth. Distilled water 500 cc. Peptone ."». grams Sodium nitrate. ... . '.01 gram </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 maximum temperature at which growth would take place were made by placing fresh beet tubes, newly inoculated from other beet tubes, in a large Lautenschlager incubator, controlled by a gas pressure regulator and a Novy-Keiclitrt thermo-regulator. Irty-six tubes were used at various temperatures from C. The results indicated that no growth takes sabove 32° C. upon this medium. Three days' exposure is temperature invariably resulted in death, and one day noticeable loss of vigor. It has proved impossible to cultures through the summer without unusual pre - ons against heat : from this cause cultures have been itedly lost. Minimum Temperature. — Twenty beet tubes were placed in different compartments of an ice-chest at various temper - atures for 3 days. The range of temperature was dt-t&lt; i - mined in each case by using a maximum and minimum ther - mometer. Temperature in an ice-chest is not under as accu - rate control as temperature in an incubator; but the results seem to indicate that no growth takes place below 3° ( there is distinct though slow growth. E i ve beet tubes were inoculated and left at about 20° C. for urs, then placed in a freezing mixture and kept nearly ■eezing-point for 3 days. After removal from the freez - mixture at the end of this time, the cultures developed nally and without retardation. imum Temperature. — Since slight changes in manner of growth are more apparent upon beet tubes than upon any other medium, beet tubes were used in determining opti - mum as well as maximum and minimum temperatures. K)out 17° C. appears to be the optimum temperature on medium. But very little difference can be detected in growth of beet tubes at any temperatures from 15 to Kis thus evident that the whole temperature range of bacterium lies rather low; which is perhaps to be ex - id of a form living at some depth in the soil. RELATION TO LIGHT. — Three freshly poured plates of beet </seg>
            <seg id="p103">103 I! agar, in Petri dishes with polished tops, were placed i Stender dishes filled with ice; one half of each plate covered with black paper, and the whole apparatus was sd in the direct sunlight for 10 minutes. This was at ison College, S. C, October :, at 11 :30&gt;. m. The It of such exposure was to destroy 50 per cent of the ised bacteria, as shown by the subsequent development e plates. Exposure of 2 plates under the same condi - i for 18 minutes on November 6th resulted in the death 1 the exposed bacteria. The exact time limit for fatal isure was not determined. I&gt;i(1'u,sril Liijht. — No accurate experiments have been made to determine whether Ilwt. tetUlium is sensitive to diffused light or not. The most of the cultures were grown in the diffused north light of the laboratory, and no difference was noticed in the vigor of those and the few tubes that were grown in the dark. I is not impossible, however, that diffused light may have iderable influence upon the pathogenic power of the nism. While no exhaustive comparisons were made, it ted that inoculated beets decayed more readily in the dark in the light, at least in the early stages of decay. It noted that while the organism made no growth in tubes schinsky's solution, it remained alive for some time: for » 30 days if the tubes were in the light, but for 40 to 58 in tubes kept in a dark closet. It must be remembered lis connection that Uschinsky's solution is a perfectly sparent medium. RELATION TO MOISTURE. Iiat this bacterium is favored by an ample water supply is sensitive to dryness has been clearly shown at every e of the inoculation and cultural experiments. The ral occurrence of the rot in soil more than normally wet ;ests the same thing. I determine accurately the degree of sensitiveness to cation, 40 pieces of sterile silk thread were dipped in a juice tube in which the organism was growing vigor - r ; then dried at room temperature (abou for </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 I ing lengths of time, and placed in fresh sterile beet i to develop. All tubes inoculated with threads that been dried for more than 35 minutes failed to show r th. A similar experiment in which the threads were n through the viscid growth in a beet tube, resulted in r th after longer periods of drying, 28 hours being the observed. This was undoubtedly due to the fact that •iscid culture from a beet tube dries very slowly, and on &gt;utside first, forming a layer that protects the bacteria in ; whereas the beet juice medium used in the first case i nearly as quickly as water. ttum t&lt;&gt; Fr&gt; a. — The growth of this organism deep in the tissues of the sugar-beet, and its tendency to penetrate cooked beet in test-tubes, suggests at once that it is not an obligative aerobe. Its growth in stab cultures along the whole line of puncture, and the rapid and normal devel - opment of colonies in shaken tubes, points to the same con - clusion. Tubes of steamed beet, beet juice agar, 5 per cent cane sugar agar, and ii per cent cane sugar gelatin (3 of each kind) were inoculated directly from a diseased beet, and placed im - mediately in an atmosphere of hydrogen in Novy jars. The hydrogen was prepared and the apparatus arranged accord - &gt; the directions of F. G. Novy (Laboratory Work in Bacteriology, p. 312). Growth in the beet tubes was distinct - ly retarded; but in the other tubes, which were stab cul - tures, growth was indistinguishable from that in check tubes in air. But inoculations of live sugar-beets from tubes kept for 4 days in hydrogen totally failed. Beets inoculated from the check tubes rotted normally. In the heet tubes attenuation was further shown by a watery growth, not viscid as it normally is. Cultures grown in vacuum, with oxygen exhausted, and those grown in carbon dioxide, gave contradictory results; and the work was not continued long enough to warrant tenable conclusions. Ebes of 5 per cent cane sugar gelatin inoculated by 's method showed exactly the same growth as check i without the layer of paraffin over the medium. Since the bacterium does not grow in pure peptone </seg>
            <seg id="p105">105 solutions, a 1 per cent peptone solution with .25 per cent of Liebig's beef extract was used in fermentation tubes, and to this fluid was added 1 per cent of each of the substances mentioned on page 100. Six fermentation tubes of each kind were inoculated. Results were as follows: In check tubes of sugar free bouillon no visible growth ensued ; but poured plates made from the bouillon in the open end of one of these tubes indicated that some slight growth did take place. Growth in bouillon with saccharose was vigorous and characteristic. The open end clouded uniformly in about 12 hours; in 18 hours the connecting tube was clouded, and the closed tube for about 1 cm. The top of the clouded portion was very sharp and distinct, and slowly advanced up the closed end of the tube, reaching half way to the top in 48 hours, and usually completely clouding the tube by the end of the 3d day. In tubes of bouillon with dextrose a very slight growth ensued, barely dimming the fluid. The tube was entirely clouded by the end of the 3d day; as th^ growth was slight, the limit of clouded and unclouded parts was not so distinct as in the saccharose tubes. It should bt noted, that the earlier statement that this organism does not grow on dextrose media, should be modified by this result. In tubes containing maltose a similar growth ensued None of these tubes ever cleared. In none of the other tubes was any growth visible. No gas was formed in any tube. This bacterium has not been observed to produce gas under any conditions. ition to Arid* and Alkalies. — In general the bacterium is indifferent to the reaction of its medium ; or rather, has a wide range of adaptability in this respect. This may be correlated with the fact that the reaction of its host plant, the sugar - beet, varies widely. Though normally acid (fresh samples of pure beet juice have titrated +6.8), when grown in alkali soil the cut surface will often blue litmus. K portions of saccharose bouillon of the formula used in entation tubes hydrochloric acid was added until the rent samDles titrated +1.3. +1.5, +2.0, +8.0, +5.", KO respectively. Five tubes of each sample were tubed, Lized in an autoclave, and inoculated from a fresh beet </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 tube. The experiment was later repeated with two tubes of each sample. Results indicated that at +3.0 growth was not noticeably retarded; at +5.0 growth was retarded 4 days and very feeble. At +12.0 there was no growth, but the inoculation limit of one of these tubes was 32 days, showing that the bacterium remains alive in the acid medium. Cf. results with tomato tubes (page 89). I similar experiment with acetic in place of hydrochloric indicated that the bacterium was even less sensitive to acid. At +5.0 growth was only slightly retarded, growth was hardly perceptible. At +12.0 there no growth. Inoculation limits were not determined. Portions of the same medium were adjusted to the follow - ing degrees of alkalinity by the addition of caustic soda: . —2.0. —5.0, — H.0, —12.0, -15.0, —20.0, —24.0. In tubes reacting — 1.0, — 2.0, — 5.0, growth was normal in ap - pearance, quantity, and rate. Growth was retarded in tubes reacting — 8.0 for 4 to 7 days, but was copious and prolonged when once under way. No growth ever appeared in the remaining tubes. The experiment was made of placing a quantity of pow - dered chalk in the bottom of tubes of the same medium, and of beet juice, and determining the effect upon the growth of the bacterium. The results were quite striking. Growth began normally, but continued for from 20 [to 30 days. The appearance of the liquid was at first the same as of that in check tubes without chalk: after the 5th day, the bacterial growth began to settle to the bottom of the tube, ultimately forming a floccose mass one centimeter or more deep in tubes containing 10 to 12 cc. of liquid. The bacteria form - ing this mass were aggregated into chains of 5&lt;&gt; or more elements. Not all of the bacteria settled to the bottom ; the fluid remained turbid until it dried out. B i Km Animals. — Since the maximum temperature at h growth takes place is 32° C, it was deemed unneces - to make any inoculations upon animals. Kperiments were made, however, of feeding beets de- I with pure cultures to chickens and rabbits. The ens refused to eat the beet even when kept without </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 I food. Rabbits at first refused it but finally ate it in quantities. After several days the rabbits became ed with diarrhoea, not seriously enough, however, to t in death in any case. Two rabbits were killed, and limentary tract carefully examined. The beet seemed ; simply as an irritant, so far as could be noted. No nee of abnormal gas formation in the intestines was ved at any stage. OTHER BACTERIA ON BEET AND BEET JUICE The diseases and organisms described by Kramer (loc. alsoE. F. Smith (1896), Busse(l*97), and Stift (190o) are quite distinct from this disease and organism; as also are the diseases described at various times by Sorauer i 1894, 1*97). A considerable number of writers have described bacteria that produce a slimy growth in beet juice or on beet tissue ;». &lt;j., Glazier (l^'Ju), Van Tieghem ( : Miss Cunningham (1899), Koch and Hosaei. I, St. Epstein (1902), R. G. Smith (1902), and Weiss (1899). Such organisms aDpear to be very various: and while none of them are to be confused with BaeL U utltum, some of them may belong in the same group. ECONOMIC CONSIDERATIONS. Not enough field work has been done to demonstrate how widespread this rot may be. That it may be serious in restricted localities, and that it occurs in widely distant places, has been demonstrated. But it is of more interest as being to a certain extent a type of a number of soft rots, which, collectively at least, are a source of tremendous annual loss to beet growers. ihis rot, and others that affect the living beet, must not confounded with the common saprophytic rotting of ts which have been drowned out in wet places and sons. But the preventive method for all is the same, purely agricultural, via., to grow beets on relatively dry und, so far as possible. There are other crops that are :er adapted to bottom lands and similar situations, mple, corn is unaffected by the same desrree of moisture </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 that is favorable to the soft rots of the beet. It is difficult to see how any practical scheme of special treatment could be devised for preventing or curing the rot in wet land, where the bacterium is already present. Apparently this rot has caused most serious loss late in the season and in lo: and other soft rots have contributed to the loss. This could be to a great extent avoided by not storing beets from wet land at all; or ff necessary to store them, keeping them separated from the beets from high ground, which keep well if not contaminated. The experiments on pages show conclusively that the sugar-beet, if properly handled, should not rot in storage. Cold storage, even if financially practicable, would not be so efficient in this case as in many others, on account of slow growth of the bacterium at low temperature. Beets even from contam - inated ground, if sunned and dried thoroughly, according to thejnethod recommended by Jones for carrots (/&lt;«.&lt;•//.), would undi&gt;ubtedly keep much better, on account of the sensitive - ness of this bacterium to dryness, heat, and light. Such treatment would of course lower tonnage, and on that ac - count would scarcely be employed by farmers selling by weight ; but could be used by sugar companies growing their . beets. The fact that this is an acid rot has led to the suggestion that liming wet soils might be a practicable preventive measure. In the light of the culture studies which show the indifference of the organism to alkali, and the observations indicating the common occurrence of the rot on alkali soils, the efficiency of such a method is to be doubted. But if it be desirable or necessary to grow the sugar-beet on wet ground, it is probable that a strain could be bred by careful selection for a few years, which would be adapted to ■oil and resistant in great measure to the soft rots. The sugar-beet has already demonstrated its extreme adapt iveness to various other soil conditions. I have seen no fields so wet or so badly affected with rot but that here and there could be seen a few vigorous, luxuriant plants, un - touched by the rot, and apparently unaffected by their almost hydrophytic condition. Continuous selection from such beets </seg>
            <seg id="p109">109 Eterm of years could not fail to yield interesting results. ly mind this is the most hopeful line of investigation in ection with the soft rot diseases of the beet; not only a practical but also from a scientific standpoint. FL'RTHKK PROBLEMS WITH BACT. TBVTUVM One of the most interesting problems connected with this organism is the causes of its easy attenuation. A quantitative study of the cultural and physical agents which injure or destroy its pathogenic power might shed light on the whole question of pathogenesis. These agents are not invariably the same as those that shorten its life, or reduce the apparent vigor of its growth on culture media. I has been demonstrated that inoculations cannot take :e through the uninjured epidermis. How then do»&gt;s :ulation occur naturally? If through wounds, what cause.-, wounds? Does the same agent ('. r/., an insect) that e. wound, also transmit the bacterium, or is this done by latodes (Metcalf, 1903) or other saprophile animals, that lot themselves make the inoculation wound? Iow does the organism live in the soil, and over winter.' at is its relation to the culturally similar form isolatt-d a the soil of a beet field (page 73), and the slightly dis - ilar form that is associated with a similar rot (pag&lt; Hurt, text/iiun a special "strain" of a soil organism not inarily pathogenic? Or is it a highly differentiated bac - um, as its special avidity for cane sugar would indicate? i clearly not an isolated form, but one of a group. (tquefaction of agar-agar has not hitherto been reported, his liquefaction only apparent, and produced by slime eted by the organism?* Or is it a digestive phe - enon, physiologically comparable with the liquefa jelatin? A few experiments indicate that the latter is case; but the entire phenomenon should be investigated ACKNOWLEDGMENTS. I am under obligation to Mr. G. G. Hedgcock, who first *For ttiU criticism and suggestion I am indebted to Dr. i </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 called my attention to this disease, and has supplied me with most of my material ; to Mr. E. A. Bessey, for valuable suggestions as to inoculation methods; to Dr. Erwin F. Smith and Prof. L. R. Jones, for pure cultures used as checks; but most especially to Dr. C. E. Bessey, in whose laboratories and under whose direction this work was done, and whose keen and kindly criticism and oversight at every have been of the utmost value. BIBLIOGKAPHV Arthur, J. C, and Golden, K. E. 1892. Diseases of the sugar beet. Bui. 39, Vol. 3, Purdue Univ. Agric. Exp. Sta. 1^97. Bakteriologische Studien liber die Gummosis der Zuckerriiben. Ztschr. f. Pflanzenk. VII, p?i and 149. ter, F. C. 1899. Studies in systematic bacteriology. 11th Annual Report. Delaware Coll. Exp. Sta. Cunningham, C. A. 18 ( .i9. A bacterial disease of the sugar beet. Bot. Gaz. 28, 177. 1901. The sterile fungus Rhizoctonia as a cause of plant diseases in America. N. Y. State Exp. Sta. Bui. 18 -tein, St. 1902. Ueber die siiuere Gabrung von Riibenschnitzen Centbl. Bakt. u. Par., 2 Abt, Bd. VIII, 25. Glazier, F. 1895. Zur Gallertausscheidung im Riibensaften. Centbl. Bakt. u. Par., 2 Abt., I, 879. Hedgcock, G. G. , and Metcalf, Haven. 1903. Eine durch Bakterien verursachte Zucker - riibenkrankheit. Ztschr. f. Ptlanzenk. XII. , 6 Heft, p. 321. Jones, L. R. Duggar, B. M., and Stewart, F. C. </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 13th Annual Report (1900), Vermont Exp. Sta.. p. )9 1901. II. Bacillus carotovorus n. sp., die Ursache finer weichen Fiiuinis der Mohre. Centbl. Bakt. u. Par., 2 Abt., Bd. VII , 1 and 2. Koch, A., und Hosaeus, H. l*-94. Ueber einen neuen Froschlaich der Zuckerfab - riken. Centbl. Bakt. u. Par. XVI, -225. Kramer. Ernst 1891. Die Bacteriosis der Runkelriibe (1: L. ), eine neue Krankheit derselben. Oesterreich - isches Landwirtschaftliches Centralblatt, Jahrgang 1 (1891), Heft 2. pp. 30-36, and Heft 3, pp. 40 -41. Linhart, G. I. Krankheiten des Riibensamens. Oesterreich Ungariscb Zeitschrift fiir Zuckerindustrie, 1 - (Abstract in Ztschr. f. Ptlanzenk. X, No. 2, lid M'tcalf, Haven 1903. Cultural studies of a nematode associated with plant decay. Trans. Am. Mic. Soc. XXIV Metcalf, Haven 1904. Bacterium teutlium, sp. nov. Centbl. Bakt. u. Par., 2 Abt. Metcalf, Haven, and Hedgcock, G. G ;. New apparatus for pbytopathological work. Jour. App. Mic. VI, Wt;. The bacterial diseases of plants; a critical re - view of the present state of our knowledge. Am. Nat. 30:357, p. 716, and 30:358, p. 798. Smith, E. F. ?. Occurrence of Kramer's bacterial disease on sugar beets in the United States. Am. Nat. 32 p. 99. Smith, E. F. 1901. The cultural characters of Pseudomonas hya - cinthi, etc. Bui. 28, U. S. Dept. Agric, Div. of </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 Smith, R. G. 1902. Die Gummigahrung von Zuckerrohrsaft. Centbl. Bakt. u. Par., 2 Abt., Bd. VIII, 18-19 iuer, P. 2. Die Gummikrankheit bei Runkelrtiben. Ztschr. f. Pflanzenk. II, p. 280. Sorauer, P. 1h;*4. Eine mit der "Sereh" des Zuckerrobrs ver - wandte Krankheiterscheinung der Zuckerriiben. Export, No. 30, 18M. Sorauer, P. 1*97. Peldversuche rait Ruben, welche an der bakto riosen Gummosis leiden. Ztschr. f. Pflanzenk., VII, p. 77. Sorauer, P. 1891. Ztschr. f. Pflanzenk., I, 360. Stift, A. 1900. Einige Mitteilungen iiber die Bakteriose der Zuckerrtlben. Ztschr. f. Pflanzenk., X, d. S. Townsend, C. O. 1902. Some diseases of the sugar beet. Rept. 72, U. S. Dept. Agric, p. 90. Van Tieghem, Ph. 1878. Sur la gomme de sucrerie. Annales sciences naturelles. Se&gt;ie 6, Tome 7, 180. Weiss, E. 1*99. Ueber drei in gestiuerten Rtlbenschnitzeln neu aufgefundene Milchsauerebakterien. Journal fur Landwirtschaft, 141. </seg>
            <seg id="p113"/>
            <seg id="p114"/>
            <seg id="p115"/>
            <seg id="p116"/>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>