<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00088.00001">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>npd.0088.0001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2009</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Message of R.L. Cochran Govenor Delivered to the Fifty-Third Session of the Legislature of Nebraska</title>
               <date value="18??">January 5, 1939</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Laura Weakly</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <seg id="p001">MESSAGE ..OF.. R. L. COCHRAN GOVERNOR Delivered to the Fifty-Third Session of the Legislature of Nebraska January sth, 1939 </seg>
         <seg id="p002">Governor Cochran's Message DELIVERED TO THE FIFTY-THIRD SESSION OF THE LEGISLATURE OF NEBRASKA January 5, 1939 j MR/CHAIRMAN AND MEMBERS OF THE NEBRASKA LEGISLATURE: .. i¦¦ In again accepting the office of Governor and in carrying out my constitutional duty in calling attention to the conditions and needs of the state, I do so with a feeling of. deep responsibility, a responsibility toward supplying revenue for needed governmental services and at the same time, a responsibility for those defraying :the cost of these services. Under our state constitution, members of the legislature are elected on a non-political ballot. While there is no such provision as to the office of Governor, I assure you I shall be equally non-political, in view of which, we can approach these problems with an open mind without partisan prejudice, with but one desire and that is to do what is best for the people. of Nebrasfta. You and I appreciate the confi - dence they have placed in us! In appraising the needs of the state, we must take into account the condition of the people of the state as a whole. We must think in terms of what is best for all of Nebraska. We must think in terms of majority instead of minority interests. We must think of ability to supply these needs. We must think of a thirty-six per cent reduction in valuation of property during the past ten years and a much greater reduction in the average income of our people. We are forced to admit we cannot maintain the standards for any of the functions of govern - ment equal to the standards of ten years ago, when the physical value of property and the total income of our people were very much above that of today. I call your attention to the fact that the value of all property for taxation purposes is $2,033,302,482.00 today compared With $3,167,489,300.00 in 1929. This reduction in valuation and reduction in income have made it necessary for us to reduce the costs of the' long established governmental services. During the past four years the. total property tax paid for governmental services in all divisions of govern - ment, including the state, county, municipality and school district, was ten per cent less as ah average than during! the period of four years immediately preceding. I cite this as evidence of the retrenchment that has been accomplished in the long established governmental services. </seg>
         <seg id="p003">During recent years, however, we have added new governmental services. In the main these services have consisted of those activities related to relief in some form, the social security law embracing old age assistance, aid to dependent and crippled children, and to the blind. This trend toward increasing the services rendered by government ex - tends to our local subdivisions and includes such activities as direct re - lief on the part of the counties and relief on the part of municipalities as well. Call it by whatever name you may, all of these activities per - formed by all units of government constitute in the end relief to those in distress. A recent report of your Legislative Council discloses that almost three million dollars per month is spent by the state, local and federal governments for relief in various forms in Nebraska. This means, that while we have been reducing our expenditures, for the long established governmental services, both local and state, the state has been adding new governmental services with a net result that despite these reduc - tions, state appropriations and expenditures have increased and, of course, state taxes as a whole have increased. Note well that this increase in expenditures has come about as our capacity to pay has decreased. Does not this situation dictate to us our duty to carry out a program of at least halting any further increases in public expendi - tures and even accomplishing reductions wherever possible to do so? I feel sure that such a program will have the whole-hearted support of the great majority of Nebraska citizens. SOCIAL SECURITY Three years ago, Nebraska adopted a social security program pro - viding for old age assistance, aid to crippled and dependent children, and to the blind. The first appropriation was for 53,036,054.13 per year. The second appropriation was for $3,750,000.00 per year. The total number on June Ist, 1936, receiving old age assistance was 20, - --600. The total number on June Ist, 1937, was 26,839. The total num - ber as of June Ist, 1938, was 26,357. The total number today is 26,808. At the time this honorable body was in session two years ago, when appropriations were made for this governmental service, the number on old age assistance was constantly increasing and it was recognized by the legislature that a closer supervision was needed to the end that the ineligibles be eliminated and that those most deserving of assist - ance would receive more equitable benefits. As a result, the legisla - ture directed the transfer of the administration of old age assistance and related activities to the State Board of Control with provision for the appointment of a director of Assistance by the Governor to be confirmed by the legislature. Within a very short, time after the new administration of social security became effective, reductions 2 </seg>
         <seg id="p004">were effected in the old age assistance rolls. Had not this closer super - vision been effected, it is my opinion that more than 30,000 would be receiving old age assistance at the present time instead of 26,808. I say 'this because during that period, 4,808 new cases have been added to the rolls and 4,839 have been subtracted from the rolls. To a small extent the elimination of those on the rolls was due to removal from the state and some reductions were effected through death. However, large re - ductions were accomplished through closer scrutiny resulting in dis - covery and elimination of ineligible cases. . - While there have been recent increases in the rolls at the rate of about 150 per month, it is felt from the experience thus far had that the upward trend can be broken and perhaps actual reductions accom - plished by an extension of trained personnel selected on the basis of a merit system by which only persons of demonstrated ability and knowledge of the program may be employed on this program. Legislation should be passed which will provide the necessary au - thority for the State Asistance Director to install a merit system in the Assistance Program covering both state and county personnel, re - taining, however, the maximum of local control possible. I wish to advise you that such legislation will be necessary in order to insure a continuation of federal participation. As you know, the allocation of funds for social security is now made among the various counties of the state on the basis of population. During the past two years, we have had difficulty in securing approval of this plan by the Federal Social Security Board. We have been un - able to secure approval of our plan, but we have been able to receive federal funds on the promise that I recommend to this legislature that our law be corrected so as to provide that all allocations to counties be made on the basis of need instead of on the basis of population. In passing such legislation, it is recommended that a provision be inserted stating that the Director of Assistance may use the assistance needs as shown by the records on June Ist, 1938, to determine the allotments to be made to the various counties. - ' . . .: ¦ ¦ ¦ ¦ -." .¦¦¦¦-¦ ¦ ¦ ¦¦ . / ' . - House Roll No. 17 of the Special Session of 1935, which provides for old age assistance payments of ?30 per month less income, should be amended to conform with the federal law and the determination of payments.on a need basis. We see a growing tendency by which persons plan ahead for the time when they will be 65 years of age, when they feel there will be a grant for them. Some dispose of their property. In some cases, relatives who have supported indigent old people up to the time they are sixty-five years of age, refuse to do so any longer. In short, we see a tendency for the people to plan for an impoverished old age so 3 </seg>
         <seg id="p005">that they can receive public assistance. We see a constantly reduced feeling of responsibility upon the part of relatives. We see an absence of thrift and an increased tendency to disregard moral and legal re - sponsibilities toward relatives in distress. The administration of assistance can be helped immeasurably by a proper interest on the part of our citizens generally, as well as by those in public office, by calling attention to any cases where fam - ily responsibility is being neglected or the law evaded. The carrying out of such a program will rebound to greater benefits for those in actual need without other means of support, family or otherwise. I recommend the passage, by your honorable body, of legislation which will make the laws with reference to family responsibility more effec - tive. Many of the troubles that I have described arise from a quite general misconception of our present program. What we have today is an assistance or relief program based on need, not a pension pro - gram based on inherent right. It is felt that if first liens could be placed against property belong - ing to old age assistance recipients, considerable refunds would be collected and it might possibly keep some ineligible persons from ap - plying for assistance. Attention is called to the legislative error made at the close of the 1937 session by which one-tenth of one cent of gasoline tax, intended for social security, was in fact not appropriated for any purpose. It cannot be expended for any purpose until it has been appropriated by the legislature. It is recommended that an emergency appropriation be made by your honorable body at as early a date as possible cor - recting the legislative error made in 1937 and making available the proceeds from the one tenth of one cent of gasoline tax to which I have just referred. I emphasize this matter for the reason that this appropriation will be necessary in order to make payments to the counties on January 15th. This does not contemplate any increase over the seven and one-half million dollars appropriated by the legislature of 1937 for social security, but would make available the seven and one - half million dollars as the legislature and the governor intended. Re - allocation of accumulated totals in counties where the needs are less than the present allotments also will be necessary. This will likewise require emergency legislation. It is recommended that revenue be appropriated in order to main - tain at least the present standards of old age assistance, aid to depen - dent and crippled children, and to the blind. As a suggestion and rec - ommendation the following estimates may serve as a guide as to amounts and sources of revenue: 4 </seg>
         <seg id="p006">Beef and liquor taxes.. . $1,500,000.00 Perl Head Tax........;............ 1,000,000.00 Gas Tax from % of 1c.'...;. , 1,650,000.00 Estate Tax ............................ 50,000.00 \ T0ta1..................... ..... .$4,200,000.00 In addition to the above, it is estimated that $125,000 per year ad - ditional may be obtained in federal funds for aid to dependent children and the blind by matching same with county funds raised by levies for mother's pensions and for the blind. The present state appropriation per year for these activities is $3,750,000,001 It is recognized that the above sources and estimated amounts yield an amount somewhat in excess of the present three and three-quarter millions of dollars expended annually. However, it is possible, if not probable, that the per head tax collections may be less thanj the estimated amount shown, but it is believed that legis - lation can He passed to make the per head tax collections more effec - tive. | | TAXATION The assessed valuation of all physical property in the state was $3,167,489,300.00 in 1929. The assessed valuation in 1938 was $2,033, - --302,482.00. This means that in order to raise the same amount of state appropriations from property taxes today, it will require .1.55 mills as compared with one mill in 1929. In other words, it requires a 55 per cent greater levy to raise the same amount of money than it did in 1929. This means that we cannot expect to maintain the same standards of governmental service, both local and state; as were main - tained a decade ago when we were possessed'of greater wealth and a correspondingly greater income. . There are two general problems to taxation: First, a wise deter - mination of public funds to be expended; and second, provisslon for equalization to the end that each citizen pay his just proportion. In 1921 the intangible tax law was passed, a measure designed to tax property in accordance' with its valuation at fixed rates, very considerably below the average mill levy for the state. It is a well known fact that this law has not been effective and that millions and millions of dollars of intangible property have escaped taxation with a result that real estate and other property have had to carry a heav - ier burden to compensate for intangible property which has escaped taxation. The law has generally been a failure, despite the fact that the mill levy was placed low as an inducement to holders of intangible property to declare same for taxation purposes. To the end that a greater equality in taxation may be accomplished with a reduction in 5 </seg>
         <seg id="p007">taxation of other property, it is recommended that legislation be passed along- the following lines: First, require all stock brokerage houses in the state to furnish a list of all common stock purchases made by their clients during the year, these to be filed in the assessor's office. This would be easier to accomplish than to demand that all national corporations furnish a list of their stockholders within the state. Second, require state ownership certificates on all corporation bonds held by residents within the state. The national government now re - quires ownership certificates for income tax purposes and a sinrlar form can be designed. Our state inheritance tax is lower than almost any other state in the union. It is recommended that the rate of inheritance tax be raised For many years it has been recognized that an inequality exists in the distribution of the tax burden as between personal and real property. A report of the State Tax Commissioner for the year 1937 shows for example that there are more electric washing machines as - sessed in a certain county than in another county with ten times its population. This example applies likewise to other items of personal porperty in the same proportion. It is recommended that a study be made to determine and enact a method to place personal property on the tax rolls on a basis of equality with real property, to the end that property of all kinds may be taxed on a more equitable basis. The facilities of the Tax Com - missioner's office or any other state agency will be made available for this study. Suggestions made with reference to taxation of intan - gibles and personal property are in no way to be considered as an at - tempt to raise more public money as a whole, but rather to obtain greater equalization among the taxpaying- public. There are two different types of legislative action which may af - fect the taxpayers adversely. One is increased appropriations for state purposes. The other is legislative action granting to officials of local subdivisions of the state the power to increase tax levies. It is neces - sary to avoid one as much as the other. At the present time it is quite natural for some people to suggest new forms of taxes as a means of relieving the taxpayer. There is, however, but one way to relieve the taxpayer and that is to spend less of public funds both as to the state and its subdivisions. Any discussion of public finances in Nebraska would not be com - plete without calling attention to the two fundamental reasons for Ne - braska's splendid position from the standpoint of fiscal policy. 6 </seg>
         <seg id="p008">First, constant adherence by the state to the pay-as-we-go policy with a consequent freedom from bonded indebtedness. Second, maintenance of local self government. ' The great degree of local responsibility that exists has made it possible for the state to avoid new forms of taxes. The first of these fundamental reasons springs from the state constitution. The second can be maintained by diligent watchfulness on the part of the people and their representatives. .... As required by the state constitution, I shall later submit my budget of estimated expenditures necessary for the various agencies of state government. My ideas are in harmony with the report of the Legislative Coun - cil which recommends that sufficient reductions be made in appropria - tions for the next biennium to absorb any delinquencies in the general fund during this biennium to the end that the state levy for the next two years may not exceed the levy for this two-year period. Legisla - tion may be necessary to accomplish this. '.- . ; ;¦'¦¦¦.: ; STATE FAIR •¦ ¦'/.; ¦¦¦'.' Two years ago, I recommended that the State Board of Agricul - ture be authorized to issue debentures for the purpose of refinancing the bonds now outstanding upon the grandstand on the state fair grounds and that the State Board of Educational Lands and Funds be authorized to invest school funds in these bonds. The legislation did not pass. The average rate of interest being received on school fund investments at the present time is less than three per cent, but if this legislation had passed, and an investment in these bonds had been made at the rate of three per cent, $14,720.85 would have been saved to apply on indebtedness against the grandstand during a two-yea.' period, without impairment of our school fund. The state fair is recognized as one of Nebraska's state institutions. Appropriations are made every two years in order to defray the cost of the fair and for the maintenance of* buildings on the fair grounds; hence the taxpayers of "Nebraska have a continuing financial inter - est in the property, they have an interest in any savings that might be effected. . . : ¦... . It is again recommended that the - legislation outlined above be passed at this session. .¦ ; ; ¦;¦.. .;;./¦. ELIMINATION AND CURTAILMENT OF BOARDS AND BUREAUS New responsibilities of government, both state and national, have been responsible for the creation of new bureaus, created mainly for furnishing relief in some form. Demands for more regulation have </seg>
         <seg id="p009">likewise been responsible for some additions in governmental agencies. I invite your study and I pledge my cooperation to the end that we refrain from adopting any new agencies and that we abolish or curtail the activities of any bureau of government, if possible. Certainly we should halt any tendency in the direction of further increases either in the number of bureaus or in the activities of existing bureaus. CONSTITUTIONAL AMENDMENT Nebraska has five institutions of higher learning, the State Uni - versity and four State Normal Schools, the State University being ad - ministered under the Board of Regents, the Normal Schools under the Board of Education for State Normal Schools. In my judgment, there is no more excuse for two state boards of education than there is for two boards of education in any local school district. It is my opinion that the cause of education can be advanced and a sav - ing in taxpayers' money made by having one board of education "n charge of all state institutions of higher learning. It is respectfully recommended that this session of the legislature submit a constitutional amendment that the people may have an opportunity to effect tlrs saving. INSURANCE The business of insurance is affected by a very high degree of public interest and the state has an active duty in connection with that business for the protection of the widow and the orphan where life insurance is involved and the lawful beneficiary of any kind of in - surance policy. In the discharge of this duty the state should set up and enforce two requirements: First, every new company entering the Nebraska field should have a financial structure so adequate as to meet every foreseeable condition; second, the state through proper officers should exercise a rigid supervision over all companies and have power to con - trol, liquidate, or rehabilitate before actual insolvency develops, and thus timely safeguard the interests of the policyholders. Experience abundantly has demonstrated that our present require - ments as to financial resources of those entering the field, whether on a mutual or stock plan, are too low. These should be increased. At least one judicial decision has interpreted our present statutes as requiring proof of insolvency before the state may take charge of a mismanaged company. This is providing for a lock after the horse is gone. I recommend such statutory changes as will enable the state to act before ruin has become an accomplished fact. 8 </seg>
         <seg id="p010">BANKING By their votes the people of Nebraska have eliminated the require - ment of double liability on bank stock. This is a mandate. I recom - mend revision of pur statutes in conformity therewith, with due care that rights accrued under the old system be.not invaded. I ¦¦. '¦':':' ..'•••'¦ ¦"¦¦¦:• ¦ ¦ ¦•¦¦•..' HIGHWAYS The condition of the state and federal highway system when work now under contract is.completed will be as follows: . . •: Paving 2925 miles '¦¦.' ' ¦" ,' Gravel 5450 miles : Earth ..;.......... ......... 358 miles Total .;........................ 8733 miles There appears to be a strong sentiment for continuing a road building program. This is reflected in many ways. Successive legis - latures have passed bills providing for extension of the state highway system. These bills have had almost unanimous support. In fact, I felt it necessary to veto a bill two years ago in order to halt the extension of the state highway system,, which had already been extended beyond our ability to finance with respect to construction and maintenance. It will take many years at the present rate of building to construct the system already designated. This sentiment is reflected further by nu - merous delegations many of them headed by members of the legis - lature who have called upon the State Engineer and myself to urge, construction in their respective districts. These delegations reflect the attitude-oil the farming and business interests of the state.' Oftentimes argument made for a project is based on the fact that it will provide labor for ifural areas. •" . . ¦ ¦ The paving of the original highway system has been greatly re - tarded because of continual additions made by the legislature to the state highway system requiring improvement'and maintenance on a con - stantly increasing mileage. Even moderate progress such as has been made can be maintained only in the event that the present rate of gaso - line tax is continued and that an unreasonable amount not be taken therefrom -for purposes other than highway use. I do not insist that the present rate of progress be continued in highway construction, but I submit that the public does insist on a rate of progress in the future at least equal to that of the past. • Available federal funds will be matched during the present bien - nium with the exception of approximately $1,175,000.00. Had the pro - gram suggested two years ago been adopted by the legislature, this loss would have been avoided. This program contemplated using a 9 </seg>
         <seg id="p011">small percentage of county gasoline tax funds to match federal feeder road allotments to Nebraska. In other words, failure to adopt this program in the 1937 session cost more than one million dollars to the state in federal funds during this biennium which we were unable to match otherwise. I again recommend that provision by law be made for the counties to match federal feeder road funds, with revenue which goes to them, under existing laws, from the gasoline tax, to the end that we do not suffer another similar los 3 during the next biennium. This is entirely logical for the reason that the federal feeder road funds are expended generally on roads now under county supervision and county mainte - nance. By following this plan of having the counties match federal feeder funds from their share of the gasoline tax, the combined capacity to match federal highway funds will not be reduced even though we use one-fourth of a cent more of gasoline tax for social security. A study of highway use is being made at the present time by the State Department of Roads and Irrigation with the idea of determining the equitable allocation of costs of highway improvement and main - tenance among various classes of highway users and methods of col - lection. The idea behind the study is to determine who uses the roads and to determine further an equitable distribution of the cost of the various uses. This data will be made available to the legislature and it is hoped that the legislature will make a study of it. HIGHWAY SAFETY The 1937 session of the legislature passed a law providing for a safety patrol, motor vehicle driver's license, and for mechanical in - spection of motor vehicles. For the first time the upward trend of highway fatalities has been broken. The total loss of life in highway fatalities in 1937 was 322. The total loss of life for 1938 was 223. This represents a saving of 99 lives and a reduction of 31'/: in fatalities un - der 1937. In my opinion this was accomplished because of the activi - ties of the State Safety Patrol in cooperation with local law enforcing agencies, supported by the press, radio, civic groups and the public generally. While complete statistics for the year are not now avail - able, it is believed a proportionate reduction has been made in non-fatal accidents on the highways with attendant reductions in personal in - juries and property Joss. The part of this law providing for mechanical inspection of motor vehicles has not been satisfactory. It is recommended that this pro - vision of the act be repealed and that the function of mechanical in - spection of motor vehicles be reserved to the local subdivisions of the state and left optional with them. 10 </seg>
         <seg id="p012">LABOR O The unemployment compensation act passed by the 1937 session of the legislature has been in effect for a year and a half. Experience with this law, together with changes made in the federal law, neces - sitate certain amendments. The amendments which appear necessary have to do with the railroad unemployment insurance law, provision for merit rating of employers beginning- in 1940 and provision for dis - position of the $l,3oo,ooenind collected from Nebraska employers prior to the enactment of our law. ; • . . PLANNING BOARD REPORT ¦ ¦ As provided in Chapter 207, Session Laws of Nebraska, 1937, the Planning Board has submitted a report to the Governor and in accord - ance with said law, I am transmitting the Board's report to your honor - able body. I am impressed with the great amount of work that has been performed by the members of this Board without compensation. The entire membership of the Board has been motivated by a high sense of devotion to public service. ; . CONCLUSION I submit these recommendations and comments for your earnest consideration, recognizing our mutual desire to work together for the best interests of our state and the perpetuation of democratic govern - ment. I shall be glad to consult with you in solving the problems which confront the people of our state. I assure you that you will have my co - operation at all times. '¦'¦'¦'¦". .... ¦'' .¦'.•'.: Respectfully submitted, .¦;'¦ • : R. L&gt;. COCHRAN, ; - . : Governor. 11 </seg>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>