<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00041">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Tuber Development in Triumph Potatoes as Influenced by Time by Planting on Dry Land in Northwestern Nebraska</title>
               <date value="1932-05">1932-05</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 61 Tuber Development in Triumph Potatoes as Influenced by Time of Planting on Dry Land in Northwestern Nebraska H. 0. WERNER Department of Horticulture LINCOLN, NEBRASKA MAY, 1932 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">CONTENTS Summary :. : 3 Experimental Methods and Climatic Conditions .............: 5 Location of trial plats and soil type used , 5 Size and arrangement of plats ....'. '. 5 Soil preparation ..^ 5 Seed stocks ; 5 Planting dates 6 Harvesting methods '. 6 Climatic conditions :. .. 8 Results of the Experiments . &#132;11 Plant development _ 11 Plant emergence .....11l Final stand 11 Height of plants. .— &#132; '.;. 11 Occurrence of disease.... :.....„.. 12 Vine maturity at harvest time .13 Stems per seed piece ...14 Tuber development :....:.' .14 Tubers per hill.. : '. ..'.. .....;. 14 Weight of tubers ! 16 Shape of tubers ; 22 . Knobby or growth-cracked tubers 25 Color of tubers...; :....... : 28 Tuber cracking and cutting at harvesting time J 28 • Common scab prevalence and severity 29 Yield of potatoes :;. 39 Total yields.. '. 39 Distribution of production according to tuber size and scab 43 Yield of marketable potatoes 43 Storage '. 44 Conclusions and Recommendations : 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY 1. Triumph potatoes were planted on dry land in Box Butte county on four dates from mid-May to late June or early July, during six consecutive seasons. Data are presented concerning many phases in the development of the crop. During four years tubers of various planting dates were harvested on semi-monthly dates toward the end of the growing season. Weather data are summarized for the last five seasons. ' ■ 2. ■ Plants emerged more quickly and the final stand of plants was greater with the earlier plantings (May and early June) than with the later plantings (mid- and late June). The former were practically mature by 1 September 15, when the later-planted lots were hardly over 20 per cent mature. 3. Early blight caused serious damage to the May and early-June plantings when rainfall was high in the early part of the summer. Fiisarium eumartii and F. oxysporum. were most prevalent in the early plantings. In several seasons, Rhizoctonia caused damage to late plant - ings by late-season stem and stolon girdling. .; . 4. The number of stems and tubers per hill generally increased as planting was delayed. Cool, moist weather at tuber-enlargement time increased the number of tubers. 5. The heaviest tubers and highest percentage of heavy tubers were generally produced by early plantings when conditions were favorable in the early part of the summer and by late plantings when conditions were favorable either throughout the season or late in the summer. During late-summer dry weather, tubers from early plantings lost weight while still attached to the plants. 6. The W/L and T/L ratios were consistently high for tubers from late plantings and low for those from early plantings. High soil tem - perature, compact soils, periods of rapid growth following those of slow growth, and increase in tuber size all tended to decrease the W/L ratio. .7. The highest percentage of growth cracks generally occurred with mid-June plantings. They were produced by good growing conditions following fairly short periods of unfavorable weather, while knobby tubers generally resulted from alternation of extreme conditions. 8. Cracking at harvest time was generally most severe with the late - planted tubers, - but frequently conditions altering turgor pressure caused mature tubers to be subject to cracking. 9. Common scab decreased in prevalence and severity as planting was delayed. This was apparently due to the effect of low temperatures in late August and September. Pitted scab was most prevalent in the early plantings. 10. On a perfect-stand basis, early plantings were generally most productive unless killing frosts were very late or late-season growing conditions were very favorable. On a field basis the yields .were always highest with the earliest plantings because of the superior stands. 11. The highest yields of scab-free, marketable-size tubers were pro - duced by the late plantings in four out of six seasons. 12. Tubers from late plantings lost more weight than those from early plantings. Scab infection accelerated the rate of weight loss. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">Tuber Development in Triumph Potatoes as Influenced by Time of Planting on Dry Land in Northwestern Nebraska H. O. WERNER Triumph potatoes were planted on four different dates during six years in order to determine the best planting date on dry land in northwestern Nebraska, where this, variety is grown primarily for seed. Features considered in comparing the merits of these planting dates were: stand of plants; vine growth; disease prevalence; time of plant maturity; number, size, and shape of tubers; crack - ing at harvest time; prevalence and severity of common scab; total yields and yields of various grades of potatoes from various harvesting dates; weight loss in storage;- and duration of the dormant period. The experimental aspects dealing with the seed value of the potatoes grown in these plats will be reported in later publications. EXPERIMENTAL METHODS AND CLIMATIC CONDITIONS Location of plats and soil types used. — All plantings were made in Box Butte county at an altitude of about 4,000 to 4,100 feet. The 1925 to 1929 trials |were located on Rosebud silt loam and those of 1930 on Rosebud very fine sandy loam. These soils are typical of those upon which potatoes are extensively grown in northwestern Nebraska. Size and arrangement of plats. — ln 1925 the plantings consisted of five adjacent rows of 100 hills each. In 1926 five adjacent rows of 200 hills each were planted. In 1927 and 1928 four plats distributed by a Latin square system, each plat consisting of 5 rows 4 rods long, were planted on oach given date. In 1929 and 1930, 6to 12 adjacent rows, ■ each 17 rods long, were planted on each date. Soil preparation.-r— Each year (except 1930) all the soil was plowed just prior to the first planting. Consequently, by the time the later plantings were made it was sometimes packed by heavy June rains to a greater extent than was desirable. This condition could not be entirely rectified even though a deep blind cultivation was given immediately after each plantingj In 1930 the soil for the first two plantings was plowed on May 19, for the third on June 13, and for the fourth on June 20. Seed stocks. — A commercial lot of certified seed, prac - tically free of virus diseases, was used in all plantings from 1925 to 1929. Plants from this lot varied with regard to season of maturity. Some ripened very early, whereas </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 others were still green when killed by frost or when har - vested in late September or early October. In 1930 a very uniform medium-early line of tuber-indexed seed stock was used. Throughout the entire six-year period the virus disease in these plantings (according to field observa - tions and greenhouse readings of sample tubers indexed during the winter or planted in the South) never exceeded one per cent and was generally less than 0.3 per cent. No spindle tuber or mosaic (in any form except super-mild) was found in 1929 or 1930. The seed potatoes were stored in commercial farm potato cellars. During the various seasons the tubers were just beginning to sprout by the middle of May, by early June the sprouts were Vs to Vi i ncn long, by mid-June from % inch to 3 inches long, and by late June or early July from Vi inch to 4 inches long. Sprouts were always rubbed off all tubers as they were cut for planting. The 1925-to-1927 lots of seed were treated with mercuric bichloride at plant - ing time, the 1928 and 1929 stocks were treated with hot formaldehyde during March, and the 1930 stock was not treated at all because of the very extensive sprouting of the potatoes. ! Planting dates. — Potatoes were planted on four dates. The first planting each year was made in May and is desig - nated as A. Very few potatoes are planted at this time in commercial practice. The second planting, B- — early June, was made at the time when commercial planting generally is beginning, the third planting, C — mid-June, about the middle of the planting season, and the fourth, D — late June or jearly July, at the very end of the planting season. Exact planting dates for each year are given in Table 1. Table !1. — Date of planting dviring each of the six years , . . ! . . . . B — Early . j D — Late June Year A — May . June C — Mid-June I or early July I 1925 May 25 June 5 June 15 | July 3 1926 May 11 June 5 June 17 July 6 . 1927 May 14 June 1 ' June 16 July 1 1928 May 10 June 5 June 22 . July 3 1929 May 27 June 7 June 17 June 29 1930 May 20 June 1 June 17 I June 27 Harvesting methods. — In order to obtain detailed infor - mation concerning tuber production and development, in - dividual plants were harvested on different dates from each planting-date group in 1926, 1928, 1929, and 1930. On each date four sets of thesame number of plants were dug </seg>
            <seg id="p007">. Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes • ■ • ■ ■■/ ■ ■ I ■ ■ i in different parts of the block planted on each date, 30 as to equalize soil variation. Only those plants were dug that were apparently heajthy and adjacent to other hills in the row — that is, not adjacent to a vacant space.! Yields from such plants represent a field having a perfect stand. Notes were taken on each frill concerning the degree of maturity, | the number of stems* the weight of each tuber, the severity of any scab on each! tuber, and growth cracks and knob - biness. With some |lots, the length, width, and thickness of each tuber was measured. Additional details on the method of securing information on scab, maturity, and other characteristics ! are given under those headings. Not all of these phases \jvere studied every year; this accounts for some gaps in tables. , Each year potatoes were also harvested from the plats I by commercial methods. Stands were irregular in these plats and yields were lower than from individual plants, but were typical of commercial conditions. In determining the duration of the dormant period of the harvested tuberk, greenhouse plantings of 30 to 100 representative seed pieces were made at intervals from October to April. The results from some of these tests have been reported I by the author in Nebraska Research Bulletin 57, The Effect of Maturity and the Ethylene Chlor- Table 2.- — Precipitation and mean temperature at Alliance Year May June | July Auk:. Sept. Oct. Season June 1- I Sept. SO Total precipitation (inches) 1925 2.52 4.07 1.84 1.42 0.33 | 3.24 13.42 7.66 1926 3.86 3.37 2.80 1.60 0.19 1.15 13.47 8.46 1927 3.29 3.40 0.91 3.30 1.26 j 0.64 12.80 8.87 i 1928 3.95 3.70 1 3.77 1.06 1.11 ! 1.08 14.67 9.64 1929 2.10 2.20 1.57 1.15 3.23 j 1.79 12.04 8.15 : 1930" 5.62 0.89 2.23 3.21 1.96 | 2.29 16.20 8.29 33-yr. av. ~2.79 |~2.82 1.71 | 1.70 | 1.06 j 1.06 | 11.14 | 7.29 Mean minthly temperature (degrees P.) 1925 59/7" 67.4 1 j 73.5* 69^5 .61.6 3JU 6TI 681 1926 61.0 66.3 1 | 72.0 71.9 55.4 52.6' 63.1 66.5 1927 54.8 62.8 j 70.4 66.4 59.5 51.0 61.0 65.1 ' 1928 '■ 58.8 60.4 1 j 70.7 69.2 57.7 47.5 60.9 64.4 1929 ' 52.6 64.4 ! 73.6 74.0 54.4 48.5 61.3 66.7 193Q | 52.6 65.2 | 75.6 71.6 59.0 45.8 61.7 68.1 28-yr. av. 54.a 65.7 j 71.7 70.7 60.2 47.1 61.6 67.3 ■Alliance data not available. Those recorded are from Seottsbluff records. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 hydrtn Seed Treatment on the Dormancy of Triumph Pota - »?5f Ul J? atic condit &gt;?»«— The daily temperatures and pre - cipitation as reported from Alliance by the U S Weather Bureau for the period from May 1 to October 31 in the years 1926 to 1930 inclusive are shown in Figure 1 anda monthly summary together with the average precipitation and mean temperature for 33 years, is presented in Table 2 (including 1925. data). When the data from Alliance were missing for occasional short periods, those from Scotts- J-+7-j-7-il t I miniiriyf} _P_i| W .'-Ijune", ."".""juxI l_i«UusT_L".SB?rJ.J'! oct" v" "» MAY- — ! IUNE - -' - JULY-- &gt; -AUGUST- L--SERT " OCT X .l—^NE^LjUlij^^UGus^ J ■ "sbLi OCT. I -J&amp;ij-Ti--^fr--^-v l | r^fj|^-»d MAY * 3«€ * 'JULY" T A&amp;uffr * &amp;pf. + OCT^ * Fig. 1.— Daily temperature and rainfall at Alliance between May 1 and October 31 for each year from 1926 to 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes bluff, which is about 45 miles west and south, were sub - stituted. Most of these substitutions were for temperature. Temperatures tend to be a trifle higher and rainfall lower at Scottsbluff than at Alliance. Much climatic variation occurred during the six years of this test. No two years were very similar, i The most important facts about each season are discussed briefly and comparisons are made of the weather occurring each year with the long-time aver - ages for each month. A 33-year average on rainfall and a 28-year average on : temperature are available from Alli - ance. In 1925 there was an. abundance of moisture during June (44 per cent above average) and in early July. The rainfall in August and September was 84 and 69 per cent below average. The temperature was high in May and about 2.5 per cent above average in each month until October, except August, which was 0.7 per cent below the average. The temperature was relatively low when one considers the low precipitation at the end of the summer. In 1926 the precipitation during May, June, and July was 28, 20, and 64| per cent respectively above the long - time average, but in August and September it was 6 and 82 per cent respectively below. For the entire period from June 1 to September 30 it was 16 per cent above the aver - age. The rainfall occurred in four principal periods and then in heavy showers in early May, mid-June, early July, and mid-August. Planting conditions were good, but drouth conditions prevailed most of the time from about July 10 to the end of the season. The temperature was above normal from May 1 to September 1. September was 8 per cent cooler than normal, thus reducing the June 1-to- September 30 temperature 1.2 per cent below normal. A hail storm on August 16, which destroyed 99 per cent of the tops, and a freeze on September 24 rendered this a most unusual season. In 1027 the growing-season rainfall was 21.7 per cenii above average — 18; 21, 94, and 19 per cent above average m May, June, August, and September respectively, while in July it was 47 per cent below average. Rainfall was fairly well distributed, but from about July 10 to August 20, although the plants did not suffer severely, moisture was inadequate for good tuber development. During planting time there was frequently an excessive amount of rain. The soil was very hard, dry, and cloddy at digging time as a result of a driving rain on August 20 and 21, which was followed by three weeks of hot, dry weather. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 The temperature was 3.3 per cent below average from June 1 to September 30 and during each month it was also below average. The coolest and wettest August during the six years occurred in 1927. The first killing frost occurred September 20. A rain and snow storm at the end of September improved soil conditions for late digging. In 1928 the growing-season rainfall was the heaviest of any of the six seasons, having been 32.2 ■ per cent above average. The numerous heavy rains during June made planting difficult and were responsible for many poor stands because they packed the soil and prevented proper soil aeration. June and July were very rainy but about August 1 a severe drouth period began and continued until September 18. The soil -was again hard, dry, and cloddy at digging time. The temperature was the lowest for the six years. During June it was 8 per cent below average. In 1929 the rainfall was from 8 to 32 per cent below average every month until September, when it was 205 per cent above average because of a period of rainy, snowy, cold weather between September 2 and 8. Decidedly drouthy conditions prevailed through most of June and continued till September 2, with only slight periods of relief when rains of slight effectiveness occurred on July 8 and August 6. Soil conditions were satisfactory through - out the season for all except very late plantings and were very good at digging time. The temperature was below average in May and June (4 and 2 per cent) but rose to 2.6 and 5.7 per cent above average in July and August. The 1929 September was the coldest one in the six years — 54.4° F., or 9.6 per cent' below average. The first half of the month averaged about 2.5 degrees lower than the last half. In 1930 the monthly rainfall was from 30 to 116 per cent above the average throughout the entire period ex - cept in June, which was 68 per cent below average. The light June rainfall was effectively distributed in two showers so that the only plantings that suffered because of dry soil were those made during the last 10 days of the month. The rainfall occurred at fairly regular intervals throughout the season. The temperature was above aver - age in July and August. July was the warmest of any month during the entire six years. The warmest period occurred from July 1 to 10. Hot weather was beginning to be serious when the situation was relieved by two rains, both of which reduced the temperature slightly. The most </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Time of. Planting Triumph Potatoes serious period of stress occurred during the end of July and early part of August and was definitely broken by rains occurring at frequent intervals after August 10. RESULTS OF THE EXPERIMENTS PLANT DEVELOPMENT Plant emergence. — The early plantings emerged most slowly (Table 3) because of lower temperatures (Table 2) and more dormant conditions of the seed tubers. Slightly over three weeks were required for half of the seed pieces of the- May plantings, and about two and one-half weeks for the early and mid-June, plantings, and generally two weeks for the late-June or early-July plantings. (The time ] required for emergence of half of the plants is considered a good measure of vigor and speed of growth.) Tn each year there was considerable variation in the time of emergence because of weather conditions. The final stand of plants was almost invariably best with the May plantings, averaging 93 per cent for the five-year period, compared with 79.5 per cent with the late plantings (Table 3). Table 3. — Five-year means (1926-1930) for days for emer - gence, final stand, number of stems, and estimated matur - ity at end of growing season Days for ■ cmerjrence of Mean final stemi oer Mean or Plantinc time plants from 50 stand of .IfJP „££ estimated per cent of plants !Ced pleCe maturity by si-f ! nieces mid-September Mean Mean . ■ .. number P.ct. number P.ct. A— Mid-May | 23.8 93.0 2.97 93 B— Early June j 17.4 92.7 3.37 76 C— Mid-June ! 17.8 l 88.2 3.27' 36 D— Late June \ 15.8 | 79.5 | 3.86 1G 1 The mean data for this date are out of line, principally because the 1928 planting was ma.de when the soil was too wet. - Height of plants. — In 1927 the height of 100 plants of each planting date was recorded at about 10-day intervals from time of emergence until the plants ceased to increase in height (Fig. 2). The shape of the growth curves is practically the same for all planting dates. The period of increase in height, as measured from the time half the plants had emerged until height growth practically ceased, t varied from 34 to 43 days. The maximum height increased as planting was delayed. The low July rainfall and high temperatures were detrimental to the growth of the May </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 1 : ~ 1 ~\ ' ■ . __L Z f / / A PLANTED MAY 14 2 / / /• 8 PLANTED JUNE I _ jf. t __ _ ~—^S — — ] C PLANTED JUNE IS j | yY i ./ V^ D PLANTED JULY I NUMBER OT DAYS TROM PLANTING Fig. 2. — Growth rate of potato plants when planted on various dates in 1927. plantings, causing early termination. The ample August rainfall and declining temperature favored the continued vegetative growth of the later plantings. In 1928 the May planting produced the largest vines and the July planting the smallest, because of the effect of the abundant June and July rainfall upon the former and the injurious effect of the low August and September rainfall, upon the latter. In 1929 and 1930 the vines of the early plantings were relatively small because of unfavorably high July and August temperatures both seasons and, in 1929, the occurrence of a prolonged summer drouth. Favorable moisture and temperature, especially during September in both years, caused heavy vine growth with the late plantings, but was too late for the early plantings, which were too mature to profit by these favorable con - ditions. Occurrence of disease. — The common early blight ' was prevalent to a serious extent in 1927; vines of all plantings, but especially the earlier ones, were severely injured. In 1928 the vines of the May and earlyrJune plantings were seriously damaged by the disease during late July and early August, but during the dry weather in August and September the disease was not serious with the late plant - 1 AUernaria solani (E and M) Jones and Grout. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes ings. In 1930, a season especially favorable for early blight during July and August, much damage was done during' August to the early plantings, causing the early death of the vines. However, the low temperatures during late August and September were unfavorable to the early blight organism and very favorable for the growth of potato plants; consequently the late plantings were dam - aged very little. Fusarium wilt, both F. eumartii Carp, and F. oxysporwm Schlecht, frequently were serious in the early plantings but never in the late plantings. The amount of infection varied from year to year. Vine maturity at harvest time.: — During most seasons the vines from May plantings were practically ripe by the middle of September (Table 3). In fact most of the vines from early plantings (A and B) were dead before Sep - tember 1. The vines of the early-June plantings (B) matured almost as quickly. The mid-June plantings (C) were generally quite immature by mid-September, at which time the late-June or early-July plantings (D) showed but few indications of maturity. Maturity of the early plant - ings was frequently, hastened by early blight, which was seldom serious with late plantings. , r . /// ' - - h\ \ A Fl- * f CCI UAT 20 *~" "" * / If \\ \ a Pi&gt;» ixo junc i — i ii ■■! - v) ( /// ya \ . , C h-A* co junc n — — -— . z i HW • I \ W \ n rxAt rtD juhc 27 — —■ ■ 1 . i ■ ■ ■ 1 . r^s~--^£^ • •■ ' i ' t ' . NUMBER Or SUMS PtR PLANT Fig. 3. — Percentage of plants with various given numbers of stems when planted on four dates in 1930. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 The maturity of the tubers, from the commercial stand - point, was closely correlated with the maturity of vines. The tubers from the first two plantings were always quite mature and were not damaged much by handling, whereas the tubers of late plantings were immature and easily dam - aged in harvesting. Stems per seed piece. — With each delay in planting there was generally an increase in the number of stems per seed piece (Table 3). Favorable conditions in some seasons caused an increase in the number of stems. This increase was largely the result of a decline in apical dominance during the prolonged storage period, as indicated by the general increase in these later plantings in the number of plants having three, four, or more stems per seed piece (Fig. 3). Within any one lot of seed potatoes, there was an increase in the number of stems and a correlated in - crease in the number of tubers per hill and in the total weight of tubers per hill, such as was apparent in the case of the June 17, 1930, planting as shown in Table 4. TUBER DEVELOPMENT Tubers per hill. — With delay in planting there was com - monly an increase in the mean total number of tubers per hill in years when there was an abundant moisture supply at the end of the growing season, as in 1929 and 1930 (Table 5). When moisture was abundant early in the season but deficient at the end, as in 1928, the number of tubers was greatest with the earliest plantings and lowest with the late plantings. In 1929 the early-June (B) plant - ing produced the lowest number of tubers per plant* prob - ably because the growth was stimulated very early in the season (1.2 inches of rainfall on June 1, Fig. 1), and during TABLE 4. — Mean number of tubers and weight per hill pro - duced by 100 hills from June 17 planting harvested Octo - ber 1, 1930 Ste Tfll Per SiS 8 nS£er Tubers per hill ™°™ weight of hlU of stems tubers per hill Number Number- Mean number Grams 1 8 2.75 413 2 43 3.83 700 3 25 5.28 780 4 11 6.09 782 5 6 8.17 1,166 6 5 9.20 1,280 7 1 15.00 1,600 8 1 I 9^00 I .1,500 . . </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes the hot, dry weather the plants were too large to be able to build up food reserves for tuber formation. Then before the cool weather of September arrived the plants were too mature to respond (Table 5) . With the two later plantings Table 5.— Mean number. of tubers per hill from each plant - ing date during three years (all lots harvested in early October) I • • ' . I Total number of tubers Tubers weighing' more than Planting | 75 grams time' I 1928 | 1929 | 1930 | 1928 | 1929 I 1930 A 6.42 4.01 5.11 2.79 1.84 | 3.13 B 6.94 3.09 5.11 1.77 1.16 3.08 C ...; 5.23 4.11 5.19 0.91 1.11 3.66 D 5.54 4.96 | 8.39 1.00 1.67 ! 4.95 1 A represents May ; B, early June : C, mid-June ; and D, late June. the tops were smaller and more able to store up a reserve so as to produce more tubers even by August 16. In the June 27 planting in 1929 and 1930 an invasion of Rhizoctonia - girdled the stems and caused the production of an abnormally large number of small tubers. High temperatures were commonly associated with low rainfall and low temperatures with high rainfall; consequently some of these differences with regard to the number of tubers per plant were probably due to temperature as well as to moisture. The number of marketable-size tubers (over 75 grams) tended to decline as planting was delayed. Important ex - ceptions occurred in the case of some late plantings as a result of favorable weather at the end of the season. The number of tubers per plant was much greater in some seasons than in others. During 1928, when moisture conditions were favorable early in the season, and in 1930 when they were reasonably favorable throughout the sea - son, the number of tubers per plant was greater than in 1929, when there was a serious moisture deficiency until the very last month. The number of marketable-size tubers was greatest in 1930. The favorable weather in September, 1929, caused the production of appreciably more marketable-size tubers per plant from the last two planting dates harvested on October 1 than were produced By comparable lots in 1928. The mean total number of tubers per hill was almost always as great at the time of the first harvesting (between * Bhixocttmia eolani Kuhn. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 60 and 90 days after planting) as at the end of the season and frequently the mean total number of tubers waffess di£ ™ ° f t] ? 6 SeaSO " than at some earlier harvesting date The maximum number of tubers per hill was "en vfnI^ P t r ° d -f Ced^ USt Prior to the attainment of compile vme maturity Consequently with the early planKs the There generally was a distinct tendency toward an in - crease m the number per hill of tubers weighing 75 grams or more with each later harvesting date In ? 930 how ever, the maximum number of marketable-size tubers was" bel 16 wfthihT itf * r th / T Sy 2 ° P lantin^&gt; and SJt™ ber 16 with the June 1 and June 17 plantings, while only ™ J u , ne 27 Planting continued to increase the number of marketable tubers until the last harvesting date October 2 This indicates, as do other data, that in this favorabte sea " son crop increases were secured by increases in the sfze of the largest tubers, that these ma/have absorbed some of &amp;h-f m^ at ft nal8 0U A °S the SmaIler tubers or may have in - hibited the growth of such tubers, and that while the latter SEE Hr atUrin A O1 ? th \V nes they lost moisture and some of them dropped below 75 grams in weight. The distribution v«i % PlSntS Wlth u re ?ard to the number of tubers produced S V t a e m e S d pe V r er p y iant UCh Same &amp;S regarding the^X^of Mean weight per tuber.— The tubers from the eirlier S SS 88 W f e + r nerally eavier than those from thl la Ir &amp;^P"f the " nus " all y favorable season of 1930 the l5i««? £ gS PJ oduc ed heavier tubers than the earlier w? S 8 ' th ? ° rd^ °/ the bantings harvested October 1 havmg been June 17, June 27, June 7, and May 20 (Fig 4) A.2^% mean . we^ht per tuber harvested a given number of £ a , fte , r Planting was greater with late- than with early - planted stocks m years which had favorable tuber-develop- Srm,^ tVr S at the e^ d of the season , as in 1929 or throughout the season, as in 1930 (Fig. 4) . When climatic conditions were favorable early and unfavorable tag™ fa 1!«S ! H early-planted stocks (A and B) produced the heaviest tubers in any given number of days. In six veara the heaviest tubers were produced during the velr whfch was favorable throughout the greatest period of time </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes T ! ~~ T~TT~ ■ i . yS ■ I; _ ____ j _*___ _^_*_ :____:. __._._ __ 1 / _^«* ix_*T - _7 &gt;^ ' _____ / tiCZ^^jr Q__1_S_ KAWyTSrrp I VT&gt;*_&gt;^* nii-*r ■ q_,__9__£q___ j _o ?_-J _,— ftfr ■ • _______l . ° •» » H__S_c ran _,?_. im «.TOHJS8_t « ' i0 '» "" Fig. 4. — Relation between length of time plants were in field when planted on various dates during three different seasons and mean weight per tuber. Lot A was planted in late May, B in early June, C in mid-June, and D in late June or early July. Lot 1 was har - vested in mid-August, Lot 2 in early September, Lot 3 in mid-Sep - tember, and Lot 4 in late September or early October. For exact dates, see Figure 5. (1930). The mean weight per tuber was greater on each harvesting date than on any prior harvesting date, except in 1928 when there was a decrease in mean tuber weight, during late August and early September in the May-planted (A) stock which matured very early that year. Distribution according to weight of tubers. — The earlieu plantings at any given harvest date commonly produced the highest percentage of tubers weighing over 75 grams (Fig. 5). In 1930, however, by September 1 the later plant - ings had produced the higher percentage of marketable - size tubers. As the growing season advanced, the percent - age of seed-size tubers (51 to 225 grams) harvested from any one planting date increased with but few exceptions. In 1928 and possibly also 1930 (differences being slight that year) the maximum percentage of large tubers, was </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 PERCENTAGE OF TUBERS OF VARIOUS SIZES PRODUCED FROM LOTS PLANTED ON DIFFERENT DATES BASIS OF TOTAL WEIGHT DATE HARVESTED *» AUC3 AUG. 16 SEPT I I SEPT. is I 0C T I DATE PLANTED "*» M *» '■—" m» |t«u|u,D uat buu| uo lure w&gt; t/uuluiDLArc u* LgulLoluai — ££S ££££&gt;£ JIM JLW J«T JUWJIJCAMC &lt;UNC KM JUNC mr nwcer Aoo aoTbo a, | b, |c, a ? |Bg |c z |b7 A 3 |aV|c 3 " ~ i7 c7 qT a. J oa I I I BC L— J . u - C3fl * 1 r -■ 1 '( ■ 1 b3 E?99 pT33 hB mm [ i [' ' I *u ■ Fig. 5. — Occurrence of tubers of various sizes, classified by percentage of total weight, when planted and harvested on different dates during three, seasons. The figures adjacent to the legend indicate weight in grams. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes Table 6. — Relation of time of planting to the distribution of __, sizes of tubers Planting 1925 1926 1927 . "'" 1928 1929 . 1980 Five-year time 1 — . 1 1 mean 3 P.et. P.ct. P.et. P.et. P.et. P.et. Seed size — 51-225 grams A 87^8 9T77 79.8 SsiTo 83^ 7T8 81.6 B 83.4 88.0 81.5 71.4 83.6 61.8 76.3 C 80.8 97.4 76.6 47.0 74.7 50.3 65.9 D 87.8 88.6 90.6 72.8 84.7 53.4 77.9 U. S. No. 1 size — over 75 grams A 76.7 7&lt;U) 89^8 i 60A 73^4 86^9 77.4 B --- 81.5 53.7 83.6 49.1 64.3 88.2 73.3 C 83.3 68.6 88.4 29.6 52.8 93.3 69.5 D 83.4 4.3 61.5 35.4 58.6 89.4 65.7 Small whole seed — 26-50 grains A iol 2^3 2H 13~4 M 4! 7.9 B . 8.5 8.7 5.3 21.2 12.0 4.0 10.2 C 4.7 2.6 2.7 31.6 18.5 2.0 11.9 D •--• 5.7 11.4 8.7 22.8 11.3 4.5 10.6 Oversized tubers — over 225 grams A 2.0 ~0 12/7 0~ JU5 22JJ 9.1 B 6.9 3.3 13.2 2.9 0.9 32.7 11.3 C 14.0 0 18.6 0 1.8 46.6 16.2 D 7-9 0 0.7 0 0 40.5 9.8 'A represents May: B'. early June: C. mid-June; and D. late June. =Data for 1926 not included in five-year mean. harvested from May plantings before the end of the season, that is, at about the date when the vines were maturing rapidly. The highest percentage of tubers of U. S. No. 1 size (over 75 grams) was produced in 1930, followed by 1927, 1925, 1929, 1928, and 1926 (Table 6). Drouth in 1928 and hail in 1926 prevented the development of a high percentage of large tubers. Individual weights of all tubers from the various planting dates at the several harvest dates were determined and the percentages falling within certain weight limits have been calculated. The weight classes used were (1) seed size, 51-225 grams; (2) U. S. No. 1 size, 75 grams or more; (3) small seed size, 25-50 grams; (4) oversize, 225 grams or more; (5) culls, less than 25 grams. Detailed data are given in Table 6 and Figure 5. Barring the effects of un - usual seasonal conditions such- as hail in 1926 and drouth </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 I l y ■■' / / i ■■'•.■ -^ , — . — IS V"i7^" ! i AA/' i __/__ •Ff . : , . i *° Nuuecn or o»« fbom plantm; to mar.cst -nut Fig. 6. — Tubers weighing between 51 and 225 grama reported as per - centage of total yield harvested a given number of days after plant - ing from lots planted on different dates during three years. Plant - ing dates for A, B, C, and D were respectively May, early June, mid-June, and late June, while harvesting dates for-1, 2, 3, and 4 respectively were mid- August, early September, mid-September, and late September or early October. in 1928 and disease such as Rhizoctonia in 1930, the gen - eral conclusions to be drawn are' as follows. The highest percentage of seed-size tubers (51-225 grams) was generally produced by the earliest planting, followed by the latest planting, with the mid-June planting producing the lowest percentage (Table 6). Of the tubers harvested a given number of days after planting, the later - planted lots always produced the highest percentage of tubers of seed size if climatic conditions were favorable for potato production during the latter part of the season, as in 1929. When midsummer conditions were unfavorable the early plantings' gave the highest percentage (1928). As the growing season advanced the percentage of seed - size tubers generally increased! with each succeeding harvest date (Fig. 6) '. The decreases in 1930 were due to the production of oversize potatoes that season. The percentage of U. S. No. 1 size tubers (over 75 grams) was consistently high with the! earlier plantings. With later plantings it varied considerably, being high in seasons having favorable growing conditions late in the season, and low if conditions were unfavorable (Fig. 5, Table 6). </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes • The percentage of small whole-seed tubers (25-50 grams) was lowest in the earliest plantings and increased with later plantings. It varied greatly from season to sea - son, being especially high in the hot, dry seasons and low in the seasons of higher moisture. Oversize tubers (over 225 grams) varied greatly from season to season. The mid-June and early-June plantings generally produced the highest percentages and except in unusual seasons the late- June planting produced the lowest. Tubers of this size are undesirable because of greater susceptibility to cracking and mechanical injury at harvest time. When harvested late there was little difference in the percentage of culls — but with early harvesting they became an important factor. In point of tuber size only, the early and late planting dates appear to have been more desirable than the customary mid-season dates. Table l.—Mean W/L, T/L and W/T percentage ratios for all tubers of given weight ranges harvested from lots planted on four different planting dates in 1929. Four hundred • random-selected tubers from each planting date were calibrated. Date of planting Range A— May 27 B— June 7 . of : L weight W/L T/L I W/T 1 | W/L j T/L I W/T Gnuns | P. it. I'.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. 1- 25 ! 108.9±2.0 97.9±1.7 111.2 103.4±1.5 89.7±1.6 115.3 26- 50 102.1±1.2 ! 91.3±1.2 111.8 98.9±1.] 86.9±1.0 113.8 51- 75 ' 91.0±0.9 ' 82.8±1.0 109.9 96.4±1.] 8e.7±1.0 111.2 76-100 91.6±1.6 81.1±1.4 112.9 90.7±l.l 80.6±0.9 112.5 101-125 80.7it2.1 ' 70.8±1.9 114.0 88.8±1.6 80.6±1.6 110.2 126-150 75.4:1:2.7 ' 69.0±2.5 109.3 88.9±2.2 76.7±1.7 115.9 151-176 63.9 62.8 101.8 80.4±2.4 70.3±1.9 114.4 176-200 78.2 70.7 110.6 107.0 84.5 126.6 201-225 80.5±9.7 , 70.8±9.1 113.7 80.0 74.1 108.0 Date of planting Ran£e C— June 17 I D— June 29 of J . weight W/L T/L j W/T W/L | T/L | W/T Gnnns I P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. .P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. 1- 25 i 109.2±1.6 102.8±1.7 106.2 111.3±1.6 97.8±2.0 113.8 26-50 108.7±1.0 96.2±1.0 113.0 114.1±0.8 '98.6±0.7 115.7 51- 75 111.2±:1.0 97.3±1.0 114.3 111.6±0.8 95.9±0.9 116.4 76-100 : 107.7±l.l 91.0±1.0 118.4 108.0±1.0 91.3±1.0 118.3 101-125 105.7±1.2 93.0±l.l 113.7 103.2±1.4 86.5±1.2 119.3 126-150 105.8=t2.6 92.6±2.4 114.3 100.4±l.l 84.0±1.3 119.5 151-175 . 103.9±1.3 90.2±1.9 115.2 100.1±2.6 85.0=2.9 117.8 176-200 , 102.6±4.4 87.2±2.9 117.7 109.0 91.0 119.8 201-225 I 94.1±2.8 73.5±2.8 128.0 'W/T calculated an mean W/L divided by nun T/L. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 Shape of tubers. — Each year the length and width of a number of potatoes harvested on the last planting date were measured as the potatoes were weighed individually. The ratio of the width to the length was then calculated for each tuber by the formula, W/L x 100, to express the relationship as a percentage ratio. Thickness and length were calculated on the same basis, that is T/L. With Triumph potatoes a short, blocky shape is considered the best. Hence, a high percentage ratio of width to length (W/L) is desirable. A value of 100 indicates a round tuber, over 100 a wide, good-type tuber, and less than 100 an elongated, poor type. Preliminary tuber calibrations revealed a correlation be - tween increased tuber weight and a decreased W/L ratio. The mean W/L, T/L, and W/T percentage ratios for all tubers of each 25-gram weight group harvested from the four planting dates in 1929 are shown in Table 7. As tuber size increased, the W/L and T/L percentage ratios decreased, indicating elongation. This condition occurred in all of the planting-date lots. Means based on all tubers of a lot may lead to erroneous conclusions if the tuber-size distribution is not quite similar. The fairest method of judging environmental influence on tuber shape is to com - pare ratios from tubers of similar size. There appears to be a slight tendency for the W/T per - centage ratio to increase with the larger tubers. This in- TABLE 8. — Average of W/L percentage means of tubers of various weights from the four planting dates of each of five seasons — average based on five annual means — all lots harvested in early October ' Time of planting Range of ------- 1 b— Early j j ' tuber weight A— May [ June | C— Mid-June I D— Late Juno H : i i : " — Percent Percent Percent Percent 1- 25 105.2 108.2 111.9 115.3 26-50 101.7 100.4 108.7- 110 2 51- 75 99.5 99.0 107.4 109.1 76-100 97.3 95.9 104.7 106.3 101-125 94.9 94.9 126-150 90.4 . 92.6 151-175 89.1 90.9 176-200 87.9 ...... ! 201-225 86.8 j ...".'.'.. "".""• Weighted j : | j j '^^ mean 97.3 | 101.1 | [ 103.7 1 107.5 1 Seasons of 1925 to 1930, except 1926. which was omitted because of hail damaee. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes dicates that as tubers became larger and longer they also became slightly flatter. The W/L and T/L tendencies having appeared to be very similar, it was considered un - necessary to use more than one ratio as a tuber-shape index and the W/L ratio was chosen as being most desirable. (See also Tables 8 and 9.) With each successively later planting date the W/L per - centage ratio for each 25-gram group increased in almost every instance. The annual means for each size from the various planting dates are quite fairly represented by the. five-year averages given in Table 8. According to these data the highest W/L of the May planting, 105.2 per cent with the 1-25-gram group, was lower than the lowest for the tubers from late-June planting, 106.3 per cent with the 76 - 100-gram size. The mean W/L for all sizes is 10.5 per cent greater for the late-June planting than for the May plant - ing. ; Table 9. — Classification of tubers of various sizes from two 1927 planting dates according to whether W/L percentage is less or greater than 100 per cent Range of June 1 planting July 1 planting tuber weight w/L less I W/L more W/L less W/L more •than 100 I than 100 than 100 than 100 . , ■ Grams . Percent Percent Percent I Percent Over 301 100.0 0.0 I 226-300 87.9 12.1 100.0 | 0.0 151-225 " 79.6 20.4 36.8 63.2 76-150 60.9 39.1 45.2 54.8 1- 75 52.8 4T2 34^0 66.0 When tubers are grouped by sizes into groups of greater range (75 grams), the shape differences due to planting time are shown to be very pronounced (Table 9). Com - parison of two representative lots grown in 1927 shows a very much higher percentage of tubers with a W/L ratio of less than 100 in the case of June 1 plantings than with July 1 plantings with every size. The deviations from the tendency for increased W/L ratio from later planting (Table 10) can be accounted for by the weather conditions. For example, good growing conditions in 1926 stimulated early development of good - type tubers. The mid-August hail storm terminated the growth of these tubers by killing the plants completely. The plants of later plantings resumed growth and this re - sulted in decided elongation of the tubers. The annual </seg>
            <seg id="p024">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 TABLE 10. — Mean W/L percentages of tubers of all sizes from four -planting dates in six successive groioing seasons A— May B— Early June C— Mi.l-Junc D-Late June i m^of i all dates ins fo ig^g a sfAj a !&amp;&amp;., &amp; 10^0.0^8^ loin inn n-'Kn"'? Sf'lilH 40 ° 108 - 5 ± 0 - 5 400 109.9+0.4 ! 1600 1 107.9 1930 400 9o.4±0.o 430 95.1±0.5 399 92.2±0.1 397 104.6±0.5 ■ 162:.! »6.i| Fiv L - ~ : ■ i : - year 97.3 I 101.1 103.7 j 107.5 'Data for 1926 omitUnl in calculatinK mean because of hail-storm damaire. mean W/L percentage ratios show that great variations in tuber shape occurred from year to year (Table 10). The influence upon tuber shape of weather condition? prevailing during relatively short periods of time is shown by the data from tubers harvested on different dates in 1928 (Table 11). With the early plantings the potatoes became more elongated as. they continued to increase in size, but with the late plantings they became relatively wider. In 1930 with June 17 plantings, the very rapid growth period in late August appeared to cause "greater increase in length than width of tubers. However, on Sep - tember 2 the W/L ratio of tubers of any given size averaged higher than those of the same size on August 16, but be - cause the larger tubers constituted a higher percentage of the crop on September 2, the mean W/L ratio for the date was lower. The mean W/L ratio of tubers harvested Sep - tember 17 was higher because of lower temperatures and slightly reduced growth rate. During the last two weeks of September there was no rain and the soil became very TABLE 11. — Mean W/L percentage of tubers torvested on different dates from different planting date lots in 1028 I Date planted^ Date | ■ harvested \ A— May | B— June C— June D-- .Tune Percent Percent Pet' cent Percent July 16 118.5 ± 0.6 | August 3 107.2 ± 0.6 100.1 ± 0.6 August 16 107.6 ±0.6 105.4 ± 0.8 111.9 it 6.7 September 16 \ 103.2 ± O.fi 114.0 ± 1.0' [ ] 1*0.6 "± 6.6 1 Means based on 79 tubers, means of all other means on 200 tubers. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes Table 12. — Sfiape of tubers harvested on different dates in 1930 — all lots planted June 17 V : Date harvested | Tubers Mean W/L ratio Number Per cent August 16 299 91.8 ± 0.6 . September 2 300 90.1 ± 0.4 September 17 342 94.3 + 0.5 October 1 : 399 92.2 ± 0.4 hard. This may have been responsible for the decrease in the W/L ratio of tubers harvested October 1 (Table 12). Knobby or growth-cracked tubers. — When tubers were harvested about October 1 the highest percentage of rough tubers was most frequently produced by the mid-June Table 13. — Occurrence of tubers with growth cracks and knobs when planted and harvested on various dates dur - ing four seasons Percentage of growth-cracked or knobby tubers harvested on various dates — on weight basis jj at( . Growth-cracked j Knobby planted ! ■ ' Season of 1926 7/19; 8/9~~^8/16 j 9/6 9/28 |[ 7/19 8/9 8/16 9/6 9/28 . ; I . A— May 11 1.01 0.10 0.56 0 0 .0 0.46 0 0 2.74 C— June 17 . 0 .... .... — .... 4.18 D— July 6 . .._ .... .... .... 0.50 , .— ... .... — 4.07 Season of 1928 7/16 I 8/3 8/16 0/1 9/16 ]| 7/16 j 8/3 | 8/16 I 9/1 j 9/16 ■ ' ' ji A— May 10 0 1.03 3.21 ..- .._ I 0 0 0 _ _ B--June .'&gt; .... 4.-14 3.27 3.94 7.90 ' 0 .0 0 0 0 C— June 21 .... , .._ 0.35 1.26 0 ...0000 D— July 3 ■■■■ I 0 2.14 || 0 0 Season of 1929 i 8/16 9/1 . 9/16 10/1 | 8/16 . 9/1 9/16 10/1 A— May 27 . 0 0 0.81 .0 0 0 0 5.72 B— June 7 0.86 0 0.34 0.64 0 0 0 10.56 C-— June 17 0.29 0.86 0 0.32 0 0 0 9.88 D— June 29 0 0.22 0 0 0 0 5.76 Season of 1930 i 8/16 ~o7l 9./16 10/1 l| 8/16 9/1 9/16 I 10/1 A— May 20 1.06 0.42 0 0.07 | 0.09 3.93 4.83 3.87 B— June 1 I 1.27 1.90 2.22 2.52 0.59 3.14 4.23 3.20 C — June 17 1.19 9.63- 5.88 5.96 0.02 3.67 3.60 4.66 D— June 27 . 0.59 0.9S 0.57 7.01 4.90 5.35 Total percentages of cracked and knobby tubers in 1927 were as follows: May 27, 2.74 : June 1, 2.55 : June 16, 4.92 ; July 1. 1.67. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 planting (Table 13), followed, by the early-June, late-June, and May plantings in the order named. The tubers of the early plantings were too mature or rigid to respond to favorable growing conditions at the time of their recurrence in late August or early September, when tubers of the late plantings were generally just beginning to develop rapidly without having suffered any serious growth check. The early- and mid-June-planted lots either suffered a check in growth or endured a period of stress during which carbo - hydrate reserves could not be built up but during which the vines remained sufficiently vigorous to respond to subse - quent favorable weather conditions. Consequently con - siderable injury was done to the shape of the young tubers whose growth was thus suddenly accelerated. When har - vested earlier in the season the results were very much the same. A striking condition occurred in 1930. After a period of hot, dry weather, cool weather began about August 10 and continued the remainder of the season. This was accom - panied by a light rain between August 7 and 11 and a one - inch rain on August 15 (Fig. 1). At this time the lot planted June 17 was just ready to begin to enlarge its tubers. These favorable conditions caused such a rush of food reserves into the young tubers (which then averaged only 36.4 grams each) that a large percentage were split with from one to four growth cracks. These cracks some - times extended the full length and were frequently from 0.5 to 1 cm. deep, but only a few of the tubers produced knobs. These cracked and knobby tubers constituted a total of only 1.21 per cent of the crop harvested August 16 in contrast with 13.30 per cent on September 1. During this interval the mean yield per hill had increased from 165 to 598 grams, or an increase of 262 per cent, and the mean weight per tuber increased from 36.4 to 108.6 grams, or a gain of 199.5 per cent, indicating that the expansion of the tubers was very rapid. During September the increase in weight took place at a reduced rate. As the tubers de - veloped some of the cracks were smoothed out by the ex - pansion of interior cells, leaving only a broad, smooth scar on the surface by the end of the season. This, together with the development of additional tubers (as shown by Fig. 5), accounts for the lower percentage of cracked pota - toes in October. . The data in Table 13 were secured from plants adjacent to plants instead of to missing spaces, in other words' a 100 per cent stand condition. In 1930 data were secured on </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Time op Planting Triumph Potatoes field-run lots of more than 1,100 pounds of each planting ™ e ' were sorted by commercial methods (Table 14). These potatoes were dug on October 7. A week of cool weather with about 2.3 inches of rain had occurred since the harvesting of the individual hills, the data from which appear in Table 13. With these commercial quan - tities the total percentage of rough, knobby, and growth- T able U.— Distribution of crop produced by planting on vartous dates in 1930— according to percentage of each grade classification Classification of tubers Date of Panting — May 20 | June 1 | June 17 | June 27 U. S. No. 1 size P - CU PcU ' P - cU P-&lt;* - f" m es , : 24.22 34.05 30.36 32 87 £g E 1 1 Cut ;•••" •- 5.61 1.63 3J19 fi.'sn J° tal 1 90-30 | 91.90 | 95.14 | 94.34~' U. b. No. 2 size ;...| 5 . 52 | 484 | 3 Q7 -j j^— Cul1 slze - • • I 4.18 I 3.26 I 1.79 | 2 27 "" Total weight sorted [ | | \ *™&gt; cracked tubers from the first to the fourth plantings ?T*h£ te i d^ t0 it 8 ' 13^' 50 - 9 '. and 9 ' 7 P er cent respectivefy i™/^; , The g°° d growing conditions during this first week of October and the imperfect stand are the only factors which can be held accountable for this great increase in rough Growth cracks were produced when the development of relatively immature tubers was retarded and then T very suddenly accelerated, as in the case of the June 17 plan£ ings m mid-August of 1930. Knobs were produced when the growth of immature tubers was severely retarded or even terminated and then renewed by very favorable e « - r^T^ ndi v!°5 S ? r when * row th of tubers was re - sumed after they had already become quite mature, as in all lots in 1926 and 1929. Apparently cracking oSurs when the peripheral tissues can no longer restrain the P«m,cK J ncrea f sl " g f ° rC u e •, But when these tissues are strong enough to restrain such forces the meristematic tissues, ad - jacent to the eyes, are forced to renew their growth and </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 bulging eyes. and knobs are produced. Whenever growth is severely checked while the tubers are very small, growth renewal frequently causes the development of elongated and later of "bottle neck" tubers because growth occurs only at the apical eyes of the new tubers, the basal portion remaining dormant. This is the most common cause of the poor type of potatoes from early plantings. Color of tubers. — Skin color of the Triumph potato is very much affected by environment. While the color of different lots of potatoes was, not measured by any of the accepted methods, the differences were apparent upon casual observation. The skin color of tubers from the early plantings was invariably much lighter than that of the later plantings. These differences were most pronounced in 1929 and 1930, when the tubers from the early plantings made most of their growth at relatively high temperatures, while those from the late plantings developed in the low September temperatures. Tuber cracking and cutting at harvest time. — The cracks, bruises, and cuts resulting from the harvesting operations varied to some extent in accordance with the condition of the tubers. In 1930 the percentage cracked in harvesting (digging, picking, and placing in cellar) was greatest, 30.8 per cent, with the tubers from the last plant - ings and least, 1.84 per cent, with those from the first (Table 14). Probably the lower percentage of harvest - cracked tubers from the June 17 as compared with June 1 plantings may be accounted for by the very high percent - age (50.8 per cent) of knobby and second-growth potatoes. This new growth in the knobs relieved the turgor tension and hence reduced the number of cracks from mechanical shocks. In another series of plantings made on May 20 and June 27, from each of 30 selected tuber lines, of which about 5 bushels of each were sorted, the average percent - age of cracked tubers was 4.5 per cent from May planting? and 21.6 per cent from the late-June planting. ("bracking at harvest time in October with late-planted stocks was materially reduced when vines were cut off at the, surface of the soil oh September 8 and still more when they were cut off August 15 (Table 15). However, when the vines were cut off at a height of 6 inches (the damage thus done being comparable to that from a hail storm, a light frost, or an attack of early blight) and the plant con - tinued to grow, the percentage of cracked tubers was not affected. With early planting the vines and tubers were more mature and vine cutting did not appreciably alter the </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes Table 15.— Effect of cutting vines upon the cracking of Triumph potatoes at harvesting time on October 7, 1930, at Alliance ■ ■ I Percentage of total weight Vines cut | cracked in harvesting .'■ . ■ ■'■ 1 j ■ . '• June 1 planting i June 27 planting Percent Percent August 15 At soil surface .'. 3.92 8.22 At six inches | 9.68 29.(51 September 8 ...!-.■' At soil surface..... ..I 7.42 14.00 At six inches | 7.46 30.10 Not cut i | 6.30 | 30.78 percentage of tubers cracked in harvesting. In a recent publication a are data on tubers harvested from plants of different planting dates and subjected to a set of standard shock tests. The tubers from late plantings cracked much more easily than those from early plantings. Many of the latter did not crack with even the most severe tests. In 1927 the percentages of potatoes cut in digging were 6,2, 2.5, 9.7, and 9.8 per cent respectively for the first to the last planting dates. The data for 1930, in Table 14, show a similar trend. With 30 tuber-line strains the aver - age percentages of potatoes cut in digging were 1.1 from the May and 3.5 from the late-June planting. Generally more potatoes were cut with late plantings than with early. When more were cut with early than later plantings (as in May, 1930, plantings) it was generally because the soil in the early-planted blocks was hard and 'dry, thus making deep digging more difficult or impossible. The high per - centage of cutting with later plantings was apparently due to the tubers being set more deeply and many of them on longer stolons. Common scab ' prevalence and severity. — Each year be - tween 200 and 1,000 tubers from each planting date were examined individually and classified with regard to the occurrence and degree of severity of scab. The various scab classes were established by the following system: 3 Werner, H. O. The Cause and l^rcveniion of Mechanical Injuries to Potatoes Nebr. Art. Exp. Sta. Ilul. 260, Auk., 1931. * AciintrmitcvjA acahira (Thaxter) Gussow. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 Class 0 — Clean tubers; no scab spots visible Class 1— Less than 5 lesions y 8 inch in diameter or 1 lesion y 4 inch in diameter. Class 2— More scab than Class 1 but less than V. of the surface scabby. Class 3— From % to ,% of the surface scabbv. Class 4 — More than % of the surface scabby." For most practical purposes the potatoes of Classes 0 and 1 may be considered as being marketable as No. 1 grade potatoes. Class 2 potatoes would generally be considered marketable but as a No. 2 grade product. Potatoes of Classes 3 or 4 would be too scabby for the general market but could be used for seed purposes (as is frequently done) after being disinfected by the hot formaldehyde method. I his more general classification is used in several of the tables and charts in this bulletin. Notes were taken as a means of distinguishing between those tubers having pitted scab and those having common or superficial scab. Each year all notes were taken by the same person, although those of the different years were not always taken by the same individual. As' the classi - fication used depends on observation rather than math - ematical measurements, some errors undoubtedly occurred but with the large number of tubers used, these tend to balance one another. These errors probably were most serious in distinguishing between clean and very slightlv scabby tubers. The amount of dirt on the potatoes varied on the different harvesting dates and interfered with some of the readings. These errors probably account for some of the minor inconsistencies. A scab coefficient or index number, based both on the percentage of scabby tubers and the severity of the scab, was calculated for "each lot as follows : 2fv Scab coefficient = . 4 v = severity of scab with Class 1 given a value of 1 Class 2 of 2, 3 of 3, and 4 of 4. f = percentage of total weight of tubers in each scab grade. The occurrence and severity of scab on any lot of pota - toes are dependent upon : the presence of the organism, the environmental or soil conditions prevailing when the tubers are susceptible to infection (through unsuberized stomata or lenticels) , whether temperature and other con - ditions are favorable for the growth of the organism, and </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes Table 16. — Tubers classified according to scab prevalence on basis of percentage of total weight produced in. each of six years at Alliance— harvested in late September or early October ! ' Five-yr. Class No. 1 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 mean' ■■"•.■•• . A — May planting P. ct. I P. ct. P. ct. P.ct. P.ct. P.ct. 0 58.18 18.72 10.73 57.70 3.53 29.77 1 12.36 16.44 16.65 20.20 5.41 14.21 2 8.18 28.11 37.31 14.20 49.69 27.50 3 7.77 21.10 32.05 5.80 39.14 21.17 4 13.51 15.63 3.25 2.00 2.23 7.32 Marketable 70.54 :■; 35.16 27.38 77.90 8.94 43.98 Unmarket - able 29.46 64.84 72.62 22.00 91.06 55.99 B — Early June planting* 0. : I 19.84 8~63 j 66.50 iiii 34.02 1 ! 17.15 25.89 21.10 5.19 15.67 2 41.48 37.19 10.20 | 61.21 31.31 3 14.74 21.58 2.20 28.61 14.51 4 6.79 6.71 0 0.35 4.49 Marketable 36.99 , 34.52 87.60 9.83 49.69 Unmarket - ::'.;. able ........ | 63.01 65.48 12.40 90.17 50.31 C — Mid-June planting 0~~^ 82.72 27.88 84.50 ~~25!&lt;J5 45.06 1 4.42 18.64 9.54 12.90 33.45 15.79 2 3.98 37.40 30.82 1.30 39.68 22.64 3 2.26 10.36 29.13 0.80 1.82 8.87 4 6.61 5.72 25.35 0.50 0 7.64 Marketable 87.14 46.52 14.71 97.40 58.50 60.85 Unmarket - able 12.86 53.48 85.29 2.60 41.50 39.15 D — Late June planting ~0 96.62 35.99 21.14 76.50 43.05 54.66 1 1.52 31.18 28.84 20.10 38.73 24.07 2 1.21 22.25 30.25 2.50 17.90 14.82 - 3 0.17 6.28 13.92 1.00 0.32 4.34 4 0.48 4.29 6.20 0 0 2.19 Marketable 98.14 67.17 49.98 96.60 81.78 78.73 Unmarket - able 1.86 32.83 50.02 3.40 18.22 21.27 'Class 0=no scab; Class 1— wry slight; Class 2=slight ; Class 3=medium ; Class 4= severe. =Data for 1925 omitted. 'Four year average— detail data not obtained in 1926. ' . </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 ' finally whether the infected tubers continue to grow, thus providing the growing plant with tissues which are con - sidered essential for the development of the disease. Time of planting has a relationship to all of these factors. The exact nature of this relationship will, of course, vary as seasonal conditions fluctuate from year to year, and a cor - responding variation in the prevalence and severity of scab will occur. Therefore time of planting, like any other group of variable factors, will not affect scab occurrence the same each year but certain general relationships will exist which apply over a period of years. Seasonal variation in scab prevalence. — The amount of scab varied very much with the different seasons. The five-year average percentage of scabby tubers from mid- June plantings (C) harvested late was 54.94 per cent (sum of all scab class percentages, Table 16). The lowest per - centage in any. one year was 15.5 in 1929. and the highest was 94.8 on the same farm in 1928. The low percentage in 1929 was evidently the result of the very good tuber - development weather during September, when most tuber growth occurred at temperatures too low (53° F.) for scab development. There were similar annual variations from all the other planting dates. A better idea of the seriousness of the infection on any lot in any year can be gained from the scab coefficients in Table 17 and from Figure 7. These show that during the last five years scab was most serious in 1928, with 1930 and 1927 not far behind, while in 1929 it was the least serious. Effect of time of planting on scab prevalence and sever - ity. — Potatoes from the earlier plantings generally con - tained a higher percentage of scabby potatoes and had higher scab coefficients, when harvested on any given date, than did those from the later plantings (Fig. 7 and Tables 17 and 18). The five-year means (1926-1930) of percent - ages of entirely clean potatoes, as based on total weight harvested on the last harvesting period, were, for plant - ings made during May, 29.8 per cent, for early June, 34. Q per cent, for mid-June, 45.1 per cent, and for late June or early July, 54.7 per cent (Table 16). When the mean of percentages of clean tubers was calculated on the basis of total number instead of weight, the percentages were some - what higher, having been 34.1, 38.9, 50.2, and 60.5 per cent respectively. The mean scab coefficients for the three - year period were lower for each succeedingly later plant- </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes PERCENTAGE TUBERS OF VARIOUS SCAB CLASSES PRODUCED FROM LOTS PLANTED ON DIFFERENT DATES BASIS OF TOTAL WEIGHT '. date harvested *£ r AUG3 AUG. 16 SEPT, I ~ SEPT. I5~ OCT. I ~ DATE PLANTED «■» m»t jy^ mm Mlll MHt uat &gt;[||t |WI w mat w &gt;jmc „, M»r c LOT NUMBER *oo _*o_ B o A, B, C, A, Bj C 2 D, A, B, C, D, A 4 B4 C 4 'ET ,22 ' ' . . : . ca ■ r-i LCO "' D IQ2 Fig. 7. — Occurrence of scab of different grades of severity during three seasons when potatoes were planted and harvested on various dates. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 TABLE 17. — £cab coefficients for lots of potatoes harvested on various dates from the different planting dates during five years .■ Date 1926 1927 1928' 1929 1930 year^ Planted' ■ I __ mean Harvested August 15 to 18 A 53.5 13.5 53 ! 400 5 - — 43.5 12.4 49.4 35.1 C -_. .._ .._.. 33.8 1.8 23.4 19.7 Harvested September 1 to 2 A . — : 39^6 16\5 51.8 . I JmTo B . — 56.6 14.2 48.0 39.6 C 73.3 6.0 23.9 34.4 D 43.5 4.1 15.5 21.0 Harvested September 16 to 18 A .._ ..._ 50.1 19.2 56.6 42l) B i — ...... 48.0 . 19.0 65.5 44.2 C _ 64.5 10.5 28.2 34,4 D • 39.0 8.8 11.5. j 19.8 Harvested October 1 to 3 A 26l 49.5 5o7l lfTi 57V7 42.1" B ..- _ ...... 42.6 48.0 11.8 53.7 I 37.8 C „. 14.6 37.0 64.5 5.0 29.1 32.9 D 1.6 27.1 ' 39.0 7.0 18.9 21.6 »A represents May ; B. early June : C. mid-June ; and D. late June. 'Coefficient lor July 16 harvesting from May planting in 1928 was 4.3. of Auirust 3 harvesting from May planting 46.6. and from early June 1.9. ing date, having been 42.1, 37.8, 32.9, and 21.6 respectively for the four planting dates when harvested late (Table 17). The five years', data, while not complete, followed the same trend, having coefficients of 40.5, 39. 0, s 30.1, and 23.4 respectively. These results are partly accounted for by the fact that with late plantings most tuber development occurred during the period of cooler weather in late August and September, whereas with early plantings the period of greatest tuber growth occurred during the warmer time of the year, in August, with little or no growth in September. In very un - usual seasons, such as 1928, tuber development was earlier than usual because of very favorable early-summer mois - ture conditions, but was terminated rather abruptly in early * The mean for early-June planting was calculated only on four years' data. If that for 1926 had been available the. mean would undoubtedly have been lower. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Time op Planting Triumph Potatoes August by hot, dry weather. The tubers of early plantings had less scab even when harvested late in the season than did some of the later plantings. In the case of the earlier plantings not only were more of the tubers scabby than with later plantings, but a greater area of the tuber surface of infected tubers was covered with scab, as is indicated by the higher percentage of tubers in the scab classifications Numbers 2, 3, and 4 in Table 16 and Figure 7 and the higher scab coefficients shown in Table 1 7. During the five-year period 1926-1930, when tubers were harvested at the end of the season, the mean percentage of the total weight of the tubers too scabby to sell (grades 3 and 4) was 28.5 per cent in case of May planting and only 6.5 per cent in case of late-June or early-July plantings (Table 16). The early-June and mid-June, plantings produced inter - mediate percentages, having averaged 19.0 per cent and 16.5 per cent respectively, of unmarketable scabby pota - toes. Effect of time of harvesting on scab prevalence and severity. — When potatoes of any planting date used were, harvested early, the percentage of clean potatoes was gen - erally greater (Fig. 7) than when harvested later, but the scab coefficient was not much different (Table 17). When the weather toward the end of the period of tuber growth was cool, as was strikingly the case in 1929, the percentage of clean potatoes sometimes increased at the end of the season, having been at the lowest point in lots harvested during the middle of September (Fig. 7). The percentage of tubers showing the more extensive amounts of scab infection and the higher scab coefficients frequently increased between the first and second harvest - ing dates from lots planted on the same date, but at later harvesting dates these percentages of severe scab some - times showed a decrease. This latter condition occurred in periods especially favorable for tuber growth and un - favorable for scab development, as in September, 1929. A small tuber infected early might have been classified in Class 3 or 4 early in the season, but with weather condi - tions favorable for tuber growth and unfavorable for the scab organism this tuber, after increasing in size, might have been placed in Class 2. . Many tubers were found in which the stem end was quite scabhy and the apical portion entirely clean. Espec - ially was this the case where the shape indicated two periods of growth. The new-growth portion had developed under conditions unfavorable for the scab organism. </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 Table 18. — Percentage of weight of tubers of each scab class that consisted of tubers of a given size, when seed was planted on May 20 or June 27 and harvested October 1 1930 (Lots AU and DJj.) ' Scab classes anil time of plant injt Ra 3 B0 Cll?a " Very slight Slight Medium Severe 8ii " M 2 y J g-r c ; M 2 a o y J "-r , M 2 a 0 y J ™ c • M / O y j^\ %™ Grams P.ct. P. it. P. ct, P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct. P. ct I P ct P ct Over 451 7.9 3.9 •&gt; 7 ' . 376-450 8.2 ' 3.9 41 301-375 9.1 9.0 6.8 mo 10.2 100 226-300 10.8 21.1 14.0 31.0 ! 20 0 0 151-225 29.2 24.1 19.8 30.4 30.0 27.7 ! 39^1 0 46 : ' (i "" 76-150 39.0 19.9 38.8 26.5 35.9 16.4 I 24 1 0 40^ 0 51-75 9.3 7.5 14.1 2.8 8.3 2.0 ' 4.4 0 50 0 26- 50 14.7 9.2 15.6 1.4 4.2 0 \ 1.9 0 8.6 0 !■ 25 7.8 3.4 11.7 0.2 0.8 0 0.3 0- 0 0 Percent - age of total wt. 3.5 43.1 5.4 38.7 49.7 17.9 39.1 0.3 2:2 0 Relation of length of time plants or tubers were in the field to scab. — The percentage of marketable clean tubers was generally greater from the later than from the earlier plantings. The percentage of severe scab (Classes 3 and 4) also was greater with the early than with later plantings that had been in the field the same number of days. As could be expected,- the coefficients of the latest planting dates tended to be the lowest. During the season of 1928 which was unusual because of the prolonged late summer drouth, the percentage of clean tubers was sometimes less from the later than from the earlier plantings. (Scab in the June 22 plantings is believed to have been abnormally high because of bad soil conditions throughout most of the season, a result of planting when the soil was too wet.) From these data it appears that the temperature prevailing during the period of most rapid tuber growth was a very important factor in determining the amount and severity of scab and that the number of days the plants or tubers were in the field was a less important factor. Tuber size and scab prevalence. — The scab on the large tubers was commonly of a more serious nature than on the smaller tubers. The data in Table 18 show that the clean potatoes were mostly the medium-sized and small tubers, while the scabbiest tubers were of the larger sizes. This condition may have been due to several factors. The large </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes potatoes probably were susceptible to infection over a longer period than were the small tubers and they also provided more growing tissue in which the scab organism could thrive. Occurrence of pitted scab. — Throughout most seasons much of the scab from earlier plantings was of the pitted type (Table 19). When planting was delayed the per - centage of pitted scab dropped off rapidly. Generally the pitted scab constituted a smaller percentage of the total scab when the potatoes were harvested early than when harvested at the end of the season. The percentage of the pitted type was highest in the years when scab was most prevalent, such as 1927 and 1930. Although scab was present to a serious .extent in 1928, pitted scab was serious only in the May and early-June plantings. There was very little relation between type of scab and the extent of the scabby area on any one tuber. Generally pitted scab was slightly less prevalent when a small area of scab occurred on a tuber than when a large area was found. Yields for various seasons were determined by two methods. By one method a number of normal hills ad - jacent to other normal hills were harvested individually from each planting date at intervals of about two weeks. This method was used during the last three years. The number harvested varied during the years from 50 to 200 Table 19. — Occurrence of pitted scab in potatoes harvested on several dates from various planting dates during four seasons Time of Pitted scabby tubers as percentage of all scabby tubers planting ~ 1927 1 ■ 1928 | 1929 | 1930 Lots harvested August 16 May 77.4 3.9 iil Early June 12.0 3.7 91.3 Mid-June 3.9 Lots harvested September 1 or 2 May 78.0 19.1 57^ Early June ...... 23.7 2.5 55.1 Mid-June ...... ...... 1.4 13.9 Late June 3.4 Harvested October 1 May ; 84.1 85^3 ' JTl 5873 Early June • 70.5 18.0 . 2.7 56.5 Mid-June 50.8 1.2 0 33.3 Late June „ ■. 24.0 2.7 0 23.9 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 Table 20. — Production data based on hills representing per- feet stands , Date harvested July 16 | August 3 | August 16-17 | September 1 Ycar Date planted ii " ii ' ; May Early May Early Mid- May ' Early Mid- Late .-._ : June I Juna Juno 1 June Juno June A. Mean total weight (grams per hill) 1 1928 267 !! 454 135 47(1 365 100~TT~ 395 I 214 1929 i: 141 73 59 '186 118 112 138 1930 — ii 410 309 165 j 621 529 | 598 382 B. Percentage of total weight of practically scab-free tubers over 50 grams' 1928 I 64.4 25.0 29.0 i 16.8 i£i 10.2 I 35.8 1O6 36 212 192 9 I - — I 41.6 20.1 9.1 56.0 45.6 28.3 16.5 1930 I ij — : 1 2.3 7.3 40.0 6.5 11.4 68.6 70.2 C. Mean weight (grams per hill) 1 scab-free tubers over 50 grams 3 1928 172 114 39 i 80 82 10 | . . 42 8 ~W 1929 ■' . 59 15 5 104 54 32 23 j*930 Ii = ?__??_ 66 41 59 411 269 Date harvested September 16 October 1-7 Year ' Date planted May Early Mid- Late June June June A. Mean total weight (grams per hill) 1 1926 283 ■ ogo . 1927 _. 1928 388 242 290 1929 243 150 163 142 . 320 211 236 319 1930 612 664 774 761 569 605 788 1048 B. Percentage of total weight of practically scab-free tubergj&gt;ver 50 grams ! 1925 I 28.0 5{f4 7X8 95.6 1926 57.2 37.1 47.0 1927 33.7 33.7 44. 8 60 .3 1928 20.3 22.5 7.3 30.3 . 1929 58.6 53.4 61.4 54.1 f 66.2 73.2 73.8 81.7 1930 13.8 19.5 ; 66.3 86.8 |j 7.7 8.2 56.9 75.7 C. Mean weight (grams per hill) 1 scab-free tubers over 50 grams 1 ~1926 ~ ~ ~. 1! 162 ~ 98 104 1928 87 18 88 1929 143 81 100 77 I 212 154 174 260 1930 84 116 494 661 [ 44 50 449 806 ■To secure bushels per acre multiply grams per plant by factor 0.40591. -Glean tubers and scab class 1. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes per lot, but the number from each lot was nearly the same in any one year. This method quite accurately depicts the yielding capacity of normal plants. It represents yields when stands are perfect. Of somewhat more practical use were the yield records secured by harvesting entire plots, where field conditions prevailed with imperfect stands ofi plants more or less irregular in size. • " . YIELDS OF POTATOES Total yields. — When yields were figured on the basis of perfect stands, the highest were generally from the early plantings (Table 20). The early plantings were always most productive when potatoes were harvested before the middle of September. When the frost-free period was de - layed until October, as in 1929 and 1930, the highest total yields were secured from the late-planted lots. In 1928 and 1930 when weather conditions were favor - able for growth early in the season, very satisfactory yields were secured during August and early September. During these two years very little increase in yield occurred in the early-planted blocks after September 1 (Table 21). Table 21.— Daily average increase in total yield of potatoes from midsummer to October 1 during three crop seasons (perfect-stand basis) Increases in grams per hill per day 2 during intervals Planting .July 16 Aug. 3 Aug. 16 Sept. 1 Sept. 16" time ' to to to to to Aug. 3 Aug. 16 Sept. 1 Sept. 16 Oct. 1 Season of 1928 A 13.30 T69 ~. ~ i ~ B 17.70 2.47 -0.44 C 7.10 1.75 D 4^10 Season of 1929 A Z7 i ~ 2.65 O7 532 B 2.65 2.28 4.07 C ; 3.12 3.64 4.86 D 0.19 I 11.80 Season of 1930 A ~ ZZT~ 1331 -2.87 ' B ...... 14.30 9.00 -3.98 C 27.05 11.75 0.90 D „_ 25.70 23.68 19.12 'A represents May: B. early June; C. mid-June; and D. late June. * Convert grams per hill to bushels per acre by multiplying with factor 0.40591. &gt; Lots for 1930. harvested October 1. suffered some weight loss before being weighed. They were put in cold storage One week after being dug and were weighed several weeks later. Shrinkage during this time might have amounted to 6 per cent. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 In 1929, when growing conditions were unsatisfactory in mid-season and very good in September, yields of alllots increased rapidly in September, with the greatest increases in late-June-planted blocks. With early plantings the* weather conditions during late July and August were more important than with late plantings. Unfavorable weather in August damaged plants of early plantings so that they were not able to profit as extensively by the favorable* weather in late August and September as were those of later plantings. However, when conditions did not improve in September, the highest yields were secured from the early plantings. Among the plats where variable stands prevailed, the highest average yields were secured from the first plant - ings and the lowest from the last plantings (Table 22). In four of six years the early plantings were most pro - ductive and in the other two they were the least. Con - sidering the six-year average from the May plantings as 100 per cent, the average yields from the three later plant - ings were 91, 89, and 71 per cent respectively. The poorer stands with the late planting dates account for lower yields when field yields are considered than when average vields per hill are used. TABLE 22. — Total production and yield of marketable-size clean tubers from field plats of each planting date during six years Time of • Six-year planting' 1925 1926 1927 1928 1929 1930 mc'ans Total bushela per acre— based on total yield from field plots A _™_ 1 192.8 12fU 3041 I62T 88.6 j 266.9 I 190.2 £ •- "70 77.4 305.6 85.5 90.4 301.8 ' 173.0 | £ T "9-3 23.6 284.0 42.0 107.7' 372.8 169.6 D 1*5-8 35.7 18Q.0 56 0 891 | 2!)7 8 . 13il Percentages of marketable tubers' weighing over 50 grams £ 2^0 5^2 33.7 20.3 66.2 Tl ~1ET B 55.4 45.0 33.7 22.5 73.2 8.2 39.6 £ — HI 37.1 44.8 7.3 73.8 56.9 48.6 D 95.6 47.0 60.3 30.3 81.7 75.7 65.1 Bushels per acre of marketable tubers- weighing over 50 grams A 54.0 72.3 102.6 32.8 58.7 20.6 56.8 B 98.1 34.9 103.1 22.5 66:2 24.7 58.3 C 135.9 8.9 127.2 3.1 79.5 212.2 94.5 D 139.4 16.8 108.5 16.9 72.8 ' 225.5 96.7 ■»«= June o r ear, y July . </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Time op Planting Triumph Potatoes 1928 CROP TOTAL YIELD BY VARIOUS TUBER SIZES AND SCAB CLASSES ]*TE HABVESTE JUUM6 AUG. 3 AUG. ie SEPT. I SEPT. 16 DATE PLANTED «g» ■ MAT | JUNE* MAY j JUNE | JUNE MAY I JUNE I JUNE I JULY UAT I JUNE I JUNE I JUUT &lt; ;■ i rFi Fig. 8. — Yield per acre of potatoes of various sizes (shown by height of column) and with various degrees of scab freedom (shown by width of column) when planted and harvested on specified dates in 1928. 1929 CROP TOTAL YIELD BY VARIOUS TUBER SIZES AND SCAB CLASSES MTE HARVESTED AUG. n SEPT. a SEPT. IS OCT. I EATEFLANTO MAY | JUNE | J^T" MA, | | JUNE | JUNE "Sy | JUNE | JUy [ JUNE | jy j JUSE | JgjE fc 'fflTe vtiitltL IF 1 '-'" I r"i . I .' r~^ij -7— '■4 ' r j\ ' ■ 1 1 i -I Fig. 9. — Yield per acre of potatoes of various sizes (shown by height of column) and with various degrees of scab freedom (shown by width of column) when planted and harvested on specified dates in 1929. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 1930 CROP TOTAL YIELD BY VARIOUS TUBER SIZES AND SCAB CLASSES OOtHMItsni MM.,, I 1IJT . , | M , T .|. I pt-,; FlG ; n 1 i &gt; '~&gt;l eld P " aC j e Of various slze s (shown by height of column) rMnJ£\ arxo " s ¥ freed «»n (shown by width of column) when planted and harvested on specified dates in 1930 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes i Distribution of production according to tuber size and scab. — The total production of all potatoes of each 75-gram tuber weight group (25-gram groups for tubers weighing 75 grams or less) and the production of clean, salably scabby and unmarketably scabby tubers in each of these size groups are shown graphically for potatoes planted and harvested on various . dates during each of the last three seasons in Figures 8, 9, and 10. The height of each divi - sion of a histograph indicates the total production of pota - toes of any given size. The width of the subdivisions shows the potatoes of each scab class of that particular tuber size. From these data it is apparent that generally scab was most prevalent and most severe in the larger tubers and when potatoes were planted early. The maximum pro - duction of clean potatoes of the most desirable sizes was secured with the later plantings. Yield of marketable potatoes. — The total yield of pota - toes is of less practical significance than the yield of pota - toes which can be sold advantageously. Since Triumph seed buyers prefer medium and small tnbers, the author has considered as marketable for the seed trade all tubers weighing 50 grams or more that were free or nearly so from scab (Classes 0 and 1). The percentage of such tubers for each lot is reported in Table 20, Section B. Tha percentages for tuber weight distribution are reported in Table 6 and Figure 5 and for distribution according to scab grades in Figure 7. According to these data the percent - age of salable potatoes increased quite consistently from the early to the late plantings. When harvested before the end of the season the early plantings had the highest per - centage of salable tubers, except in 1930 when the latest plantings were superior during the whole season. When these percentages were applied to the actual total amount of potatoes produced by the end of the season, the very late plantings were again generally found to have produced the greatest quantity of salable potatoes (when yields were calculated on a perfect stand basis, Table 20, Section C). When harvested early in the season the small size rendered unsalable many potatoes produced by the latest plantings. When the percentages of salable potatoes are applied to the total yields produced by the end of the season from plantings under field conditions, the produc - tion of salable potatoes is found to have been decidedly higher from the latest plantings (Table 22). If the aver - age total yield of salable potatoes for six years (Table 22) from the May plantings is figured at 100 per cent, then the </seg>
            <seg id="p044">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 HH^ISTt? 6 threC l ater P la " tin 2 s w ould have been 103, 166, and 172 per cent respectively. These figures do not take into consideration the greater percentage of potatoes that would be thrown out of grade in the late-planted lots S s ! ? cr *g m *- , The . P ercen *age of potatoes cracked might reduce the production of salable potatoes from late plantings below that of the early plantings. Likew°™ the percentage of rough potatoes; which will vary from'season to season, might cause many tubers to be discarded When the percentages as reported in Table 14 for the 1930 crop are applied to the total yields reported in Table 22 the production of primes is 64.6, 102.8, 112.4, and 97.9 bushels respectively for the first to last plantings. The production of scabby potatoes was 113, 103, 12, and 7 bushels respec - tively and of knobby and growth-cracked tubers 40, 40, 190, and 29 bushels respectively. Tubers cracked in har - vesting amounted to 5, 19, 17, and 92 bushels respectively. The high yield of krobby tubers in the June 17 planting was due to the season. Except for that feature, the market - able yield of potatoes from this planting would have been far ahead of the other dates. Where the scab hazard is considered serious, planting during the last ten davs of June may be most desirable; where scab is not much of a menace, earlier plantings, but not' much earlier than June 10, will be most desirable. STORAGE When held in commercial potato cellar storage the most rapid weight loss occurred with the tubers from the earliest plantings and the least from the latest plantings — unless other factors intervened (Fig. 11). The more rapid shrink, age of the tubers from May plantings than that of the early and mid-June plantings of 1930 is believed to be due to the large amount of scab, especially pitted- scab, in the tubers from the May plantings. The weight loss by January 1 (12 weeks after digging) when many potatoes are being shipped, was 5.5 per cent for mature and 10 per cent for immature tubers. Almost exactly one-half of this weight loss occurred during the first two weeks. The weight loss of each lot continued at a fairly constant rate from about November 15 until about May 19, the sixth to thirteenth weeks of storage. During this time the total loss was about 6 per cent of the original weight and the weekly loss was about 14 of 1 per cent kprouts began to develop by the end of this period, ially m the tubers from early plantings, and weight loss </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Time of Planting Triumph Potatoes aii' p u I ] I i I ■ I i i I I 1 I M jii&lt; i i i I i ;; tMjJJ = : " I ■ ~~" i"ttt_Htl _:,-TN3 s" 1 . 1 . _ s s; ■ __ZZiIl_ . Nj ' :||||||^=|e|||e|§| ■Ijiii. ti -M" i 1 I'll 'J|t~P : isliesi I :i -i- 1 . r~T_7T i 1 1 f l \ 3 ■ Fig. 11. — Weight-loss curves derived from periodic weighing in 1930-31 of eight crates of potatoes from each of the four planting dates specified. Potatoes were harvested October 7 and were stored in a farm cpllar at Alliance. was accelerated in proportion to the development of the sprouts. By the average western Nebraska planting date (June 10 to 16), the mature tubers had lost 13 to 14 per cent and the immature tubers 19 to 20 per cent. By July 2, when weighing was discontinued, these lots had lost 16.2 and 24.4 per cent respectively. The very heavy shrinkage at the end of the storage period was largely due to the de - velopment of rots, which was most serious in the most im - mature lots. The tubers from. the very late plantings were not in the best condition for storage, as is indicated by their very rapid initial weight losses and their constantly greater rate of loss, when compared with the tubers of the early-planted stocks. CONCLUSIONS AND RECOMMENDATIONS In deciding upon the best planting date for any specified area in northwestern Nebraska, the advantages and dis - advantages of planting at various times must be balanced against each other. Briefly stated, early plantings (late May and early June) will generally produce larger yields, larger tubers, and tubers less likely to crack in harvesting, but the tubers will have poorer color, will be more elongr ated, and will contain more scab than will tubers from late </seg>
            <seg id="p046">Nebraska Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 61 plantings (mid-June to early July). With the later plant - ings the tuber type and color will generally be best and scab will be less prevalent, but the total yield will be less the tubers, being more tender, will be damaged more at harvest time, the frost risk will be increased, and the shrinkage m storage will be greater. For the purpose of securing maximum yields of scab - tree and marketable-size potatoes, the most desirable planting time appears to be between June 15 and 20 If common scab is not likely to be serious, the best time is prob - ably between June 5 and 15. If severe scab is almost certain to occur, planting after June 20 would be best. In the regions of northwestern Nebraska which are cool and high in alti - tude, plantings should be made toward the beginning of the specified date ranges. Thorough seedbed preparation and the best storage conditions are especially essential for pro curing good stands with late plantings. j . ■ .• I3M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>