<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00045">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00045</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  FEEDING ALFALFA TO HORSES.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 28. The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. FEEDING ALFALFA TO HORSES. Ky H. J. Grami.ii m. Distributed August 27, 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">of Expert UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD Ithi iiocsii or tmi uaiimiTTl HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. IIONOftA'BLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE, Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS SAMUEL AVERY, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancellor. E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Dean, College of Agriculture, Director ment Station. J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary. EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF C. W. Pugsley, B. Sc, Director. H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc., Assistant Director. A. E. Anderson, A. B., Farm Demonstration Work. Mabel Daniels, B. Sc, Home Economics. Huldab Peterson, Boys' and Girls' Clubs. Emma Reed Davisson, Women's Clubs. Frank C. Dean, A. B., Agricultural Editor. THE EXTENSION COUNCIL. (hCADS OF DIFADTMCNTl) E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Agricultural Botany. F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry. L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering. *R. K. Bliss, B. S. A., Anim.t! Husbandry. J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Animal Pathology. J. H. Frandsln, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry. Lawrence Brunei, B. Sc, Entomology. T. A. Kiesselbach, A. M., Experimental Agronomy. H. C. Filley. A. M., Farm Management. W. J. Morriu., M. For.. Forestry. Alice Looms, A. M., Home Economics. *H. A. Emerson, D. Sc. Horticulture. P. B. Barker, A. M., Instructional Agronomy. G. A. Loveland, A. M., Meteorology. H. E. Bradford, A. B., Principal, School of Agriculture. Kesigmrt. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Feeding Alfalfa to Horses 3 FEEDING ALFALFA TO HORSES. II. J. GRAMLKII. fhere has been much diversity of opinion among horsemen as to feeding value of alfalfa hay for horses. There are some who laim it as the best known roughage for horses, while their hbors declare that the feeding of it spells ruination to any good e. Instances may be cited where men have fed alfalfa exclu - ly for the past ten years with no apparent ill effect. Likewise, does not need to travel far to meet the man who has tried it ral times and given it up as a bad practice. With a view of at least comparing the effect of alfalfa versus wild hay, a little experiment was started at the University Farm during the winter of 1912-13. Owing to the constant inquiry for information relative to the feeding of alfalfa to horses, it lias been deemed best to prepare a publication upon this subject and devote a portion of the space to the results obtained from this preliminary experiment. Before going further it is but fair to say that an experiment with so few animals as were used in this case is not to be taken as absolutely reliable. In fact, it is hard to get defi - nite experimental data on horses because of the small number generally available. Another factor which tends to make an experi - ment with horses unreliable is the difference in the temperament and disposition of individual horses. I or this particular test two teams of mules and one team of draft lings were used. The four mules each received the same amount rain. Supplementing this, one mule in each team received alfalfa , whereas the other received a like amount of prairie hay. Like - t, each of the horses received the same amount of grain with receiving alfalfa and the other prairie hay. These three teams e chosen because they were to be worked regularly at heavy ling and because the same animals were always worked together, i insuring a like amount of work for both animals in each team. All hay and grain used in the test was weighed for each animal. The grain was a mixture of coarse ground corn and oats of equal parts. The hay was shipped from Lincoln County. The alfalfa was of a good grade with the exception that it contained some Russian thistles. The prairie hay was also of a good grade and of </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 average composition. The feeding was done regularly at 6 a. m.. 12 m., and 6 p. m. Only two-thirds as much grain was fed on Sun - days as on week days. Initial and final weights represent the aver - age of weighings taken on three consecutive days in each case. All six animals were in the harness every day, when the weather was fit. Most of the time was horses averaged 8 hours' work test, while the mules averaged the mules was due to a lack of spent hauling coal and feed. The for every working day during the 7 hours. This lesser amount for work for them at times. By com- paring figures of the table attached it will be noticed that the mules consumed much less feed than the horses. tall of the animals were being fed prairie hay prior to the ex - ent, it was deemed best to start the three on alfalfa gradually, was accomplished by feeding them alfalfa stems from the Fig. L — Jewell, fed prairie hay, corn, and oats. I tie racks for a month. Twenty pounds of hay per day was used starting. The mules would not consume this much, however, i it was soon found that they were satisfied with half that amount. slight tendency to scour by the three fed alfalfa was noticeable first, but by the end of the first week this trouble had ceased and de from the color of the droppings there were no external indi - ions of the rations being fed. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Feeding Alfalfa to Horses 5 iwill be noticed by the table appended that the six animals i rather large. As stated before, their work was heavy, and were driven at a walk all of the time. Results would possibly have shown so favorably for alfalfa with driving horses, espe - y in hot weather, as many horsemen think for driving horses is a washy effect. Fig. 2. — Jeff, fed alfalfa, corn, and oats. Alfalfa versus prairie hay -for work animals in a test lasting from Januari'l, 1913, to^April 1, 1913. W1.lt Sail tnt.it Cut it KM tar iraia ' Mfin- Wt. at tifk (••&lt; KME IF MWM. 1ft It «ar Hf •» itr •» | &gt;n! clau Litt lHa Hi aa; Lbt. Lb: Lbi. I.bt. Urn. Hrt. CO. 15 1.720 1.760 +40 8 24 Ifc Nig (horse) 10 alfalfa | 20 George (horee) 11 pr. hay 20 IS 1,690 1,670 —20 8 24&gt;_. Jeff (mule) 5 alfalfa 10 12 1,350 1,330 —20 7 16».j Jewell (mule) 6 pr. hay 10 Dlna (mule) 10 alfalfa 10 Queen (mule) 10 pr. hay 10 12 1,340 1,300 — 10 7 16H&gt; 12 1,240 1,260 +20 7 16 Vj 18 1,200 1,210 +10 7 16% </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Prices of feeds used in foregoing test — From the table we see that the mules held their own on half the amount of hay consumed by the horses and four-fifths the amount of grain. Loads of 2 tons each were hauled by the three teams, and when we consider that the mules worked nearly as much as the horses on considerably less feed there is a point made for the economy of the mule in this particular test. This is substantiated by common practice upon the farms of Nebraska where horses and mules are worked and fed together. The horses in this experiment had been eating 30 pounds of No. Irairie hay per day prior to the test. As Nig seemed to be sat - id with 20 pounds of alfalfa, George was cut down to 20 pounds prairie hay, and by referring to his weights in the table it will seen that he practically held his flesh. Likewise, the mules were ind to hold their weight on 10 pounds of hay, whereas prior to experiment they had been allowed practically 20 pounds of prairie hay. It will be seen that the horses consumed 5 pounds each meal, Iile the mules ate a little less. With corn at 45 cents and oats 33 1 /-) cents, bran at $1 per hundredweight is not practicable work horses as a regular feed. In this test the alfalfa-f«d ses were fed a balanced ration without bran. Furthermore, it 5 desired to use only such feeds as were grown and always avail - e on the farm. Oats and corn are two entirely different kinds feed, and both should be fed to horses, — -the proportion of corn ng greatly reduced in hot weather because of its heating and tening tendencies. While this test was not to compare oats with n as a horse feed, previous tests have shown that they are about lal pound for pound. If oats can be secured for less per pound n corn, then they are the cheaper feed for horses. For the stal - l, brood mare, and growing colts, the corn had best be eliminated. at least during warm weather. A criticism may be raised that this experiment would not have §:n the same results in hot weather even with the same animals, experimental data are at hand regarding the effect of alfalfa in weather, altho late in March just before closing the experiment! had a warm spell and on several of the hottest days two of the .orn, per bu. $0.45 )ats, per bu. .33}^ ilfalfa, per tori 10.50 'rairie hay, per ton • • ■ • • 10.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p007">l : ceding Alfalfa to Horses 7 I-'ig. 3. — Rack suitable for feeding alfalfa to horses. alfalfa-fed animals were hitched to a plow and worked 10 hours breaking up alfalfa sod. They stood the work fully as well as their mates, all four animals sweating (;uite profusely as would naturally be expected. IFlie last column in the table is of especial interest to those inter - ed in the economy of horse power. All feeds were charged at ist they cost delivered at the University Farm. Everything was aght in carload lots. Freight and an extra switching charge hac be paid at Lincoln, besides a reasonable amount allowed for un - ding the car and hauling to the stables. E'his feed cost would have been considerably less on the farm, :re it was produced. On the other hand, prices given are all er than those prevailing at the present time but about the aver - for a series of years. Ehe animals were never given access to feed of any kind other i that fed them in their stalls. Once a week they were turned a small paddock to roll. At 24J4 cents each per day the feed alone per year for each horse would amount to $90 and to $60 for each mule. If one were to add depreciation, veterinary attendance, shoeing, interest on valuation, </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Ir, and other items, the amount would be increased considerably, the other hand, under average farm conditions, a horse can be ; thruout the year for considerably less than the above cost, stalk fields, straw stacks, and pasture lots lessen cost percept - . Also, grain and hay fed on the farm where grown would be led considerably less than that which was used in this test, be - se of transportation charges. ALFALFA AS A HORSE PASTURE. Ilfalfa has been used extensively as a pasture grass for horses lany sections of the state. It has proved especially valuable for purpose during drier seasons such as the past several have i. Instances of horses bloating on alfalfa pasture have yet to ecorded. Where one does not expect to cut hay from the lots, other grasses may be seeded with the alfalfa. At the L ni - ity Farm we have several pastures of a brome grass, timothy. &lt;&gt;]&gt;. and alfalfa mixture. This gives a most excellent feed for les. The alfalfa and brome grass insure early spring and late pasture. Fig. 4.— Yearling draft filly on alfalfa pasture. Eo obtain the best results from pasturing work horses on alfalfa, should be turned out regularly every night. Turning out one it and keeping in the next is bound to derange the digestive </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 tract much quicker than pasture every night. The writer closely watched six work horses which were turned out on alfalfa every night from the middle of May to the first of October during the summer of 1913. Oats and corn were fed to each three times a day, and alfalfa hay was fed at noon. They were in the harness every day the weather was fit and were used for all kinds of heavy farm work. Even during the hottest weather when the thermometer registered up to 110° F. these horses seemed to stand the work equally well with dry-fed horses on adjoining farms. If the season b not too wet and the alfalfa extremely washy, it is advantageous to begin turning horses out early. This gets their systems adapted to the plant before the hot weather sets in. Colts and young horses are generally permitted to run on the alfalfa during the entire grow - ing season with the best of results. The alfalfa plant contains a relatively large percentage of bone and muscle making elements, and hence its value for young stock either as a grass or cured hay. Where the hst crop of hay is not cut in the fall, we have a most excellent winter pasture for horses of all kinds. There is but little danger of the plants being injured from this pasturing in an ordinary Nebraska winter unless the horses get to pawing the ground too closely. , IK. mixture of 8 pounds of alfalfa and 12 pounds of brome grass kes splendid horse pasture, in fact a pasture which is reasonably e for any kind of stock. The seeding should be done early in spring, April preferred. The most satisfactory way to seed ime grass is by hand. The seed bed should be well firmed down, i a harrow should precede and follow the seeder. The alfalfa i be put in with a broadcast seeder or drill. The first year the ime grass will grow rather tall. However, the alfalfa will hold own and come on vigorously in a year or so. Blue grass will ■ work in. and the three grasses give an ideal pasture for horses all kinds. ALFALFA FOR FATTENING HORSES. Elsewhere in this bulletin are statements from several horse feeders regarding their experience with alfalfa for fattening horses. During numerous trips to the barns of the large feeders in this state the writer has heard nothing but praise for alfalfa. Most of these men consider that alfalfa is largely responsible for their success in feeding. One feeder reports a gain of 4 pounds per day on 150 head fed two months. These consumed 21 pounds of coarse </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 ground corn and 14 pounds of alfalfa daily. The average breeder looks upon such a ration as destructive to a horse's system. Sev - eral even consider that it should be made a penitentiary offense^ to "burn a horse out," as they say, with so much corn. The feeder admits that this fattening does a horse no good from a practical working standpoint. However, the buying element at the public Fig. 5. — Drove of horses fattening on alfalfa hay, corn, and molasses meal auction ring demands fleshy horses and pays well for them. Hence, it is purely a dollars-and-cents proposition with the feeder, and so long as buyers insist on fat there will be someone endeavoring to fulfill their demands. In one feed yard visited, a drove of 200 horses was being finished on the following daily ration : 5 pounds of oats, 18 pounds of coarse ground corn. 3 pounds of cut alfalfa, and 10 pounds of sugar beet sirup. This was fed mixed in troughs twice a day and in addition the horses had access to alfalfa hay in racks. These were large horses, many of them exceeding 1,800 pounds. The heaviest horse was a sound dapple gray of good age. He sold out of the yard for $350 and tipped the scale at 2,100 pounds. Ten cars of these horses went thru the Chicago Stock Yards, and much newspaper comment was created by their splendid appearance. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Fig. 6. — Finished on grain and alfalfa hay. ALFALFA MEAL. Alfalfa meal is being used as a partial substitute for oats in the grain ration of many horses, especially in city stables. Oats are often proportionately high priced as compared with other available horse feeds. Furthermore, in many seasons oats tend to be light and of poor quality. Oats are undoubtedly a natural horse feed. However, when we remember that oat hulls have practically the same composition as oat straw and that ordinary oats contain about S3 per cent by weight of hulls and light oats a much higher per cent, we can readily see wherein oats may be a costly feed, espe - cially in years when the berries are small and shriveled. I a eliminating oats from the feed, something must be fed to add c to the corn ration. Corn alone has a tendency to be too heat - and is apt to become a soggy mass in the stomach and cause :stive troubles. Alfalfa meal adds bulk to this corn, balances the ration, and forms a cheaper feed, as a rule, than bran or :r commercial by-products. A charge of about $3 per ton for ing and grinding alfalfa hay covers most of the expense over above the hay cost. Some feeders buy the alfalfa meal with v Orleans molasses added to it, some mix the two themselves, le others prefer the dry meal. Molasses is relished by most ses and seems to tone up the system and improve the condition erially. LETTERS FROM HORSEMEN. Below are a few statements from horsemen of wide experience </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 relative to their results with alfalfa in the horse ration. These men handle horses on a large scale and their remarks carry considerable weight. Among the number are farmers, breeders, importers, deal - ers, and feeders. §. J. McLaughlin, Hall County. — I am a great friend of fa for all stock. For horses I want it fed with good oats plenty of common sense. Beed to brood mares before and after foaling but with modera - , say one good feed a day. Overfeeding may cause abortion. i)ne good feed a day to work horses will save grain and keep n in better condition. I feed it to my stallions once a day with best of results. I might add that alfalfa fed to brood mares, •k horses, and stallions should be cut after the bloom has faded the seed pod is forming. And it should be carefully cured and free from dust. For growing colts, I like the softer hay and plenty of it, but well cured and free from dust. I also feed all my horses cut alfalfa mixed with oats and a little bran. I feed no corn to any of my horses except when at hard work, and then it is mixed with oats, bran, and cut alfalfa hay. I have used alfalfa pasture for growing horses for the past five years with the best of results. Do not like it for brood mares and work horses until late in the summer when it is a little harder. April 4, 1914. E. R. Watt, Kearney County. — I am a firm believer that fa is the proper feed for horses of all ages — for growing , for work horses, and for fattening horses. Khave never had any bad results from overfeeding but am care - not to feed wet alfalfa hay. For growing colts, I think it to feed some straw or cornstalks with the alfalfa. For developing horse and mule colts from one to three years old. I find 10 pounds of alfalfa hay per head per day in dry lots with a little corn fodder or wheat straw makes a splendid feed. They will grow well and actually get fat. They even do better than when fed prairie hay and 10 pounds of corn or oats. Five pounds of alfalfa per head per day to the same class of stock when running in field or cornstalks will make a better growth than as many pounds of grain. I fed 50 head of three- and four-year old colts one winter in a dry lot on alfalfa and wheat straw, at an average cost of 12 cents per head per day. They did fine — were fat and ready to break in the spring. They were sold to farmers who realized a good sum- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Ii\-diiu/ Alfalfa to Horses 13 mer's work, as the colts were in splendid condition. I have fed the same class of colts on alfalfa alone and find that they eat too much, get paunchy, their legs swell, their hair becomes rough, they become lazy, and will not exercise enough. Further - more, the cost of alfalfa fed alone is too great. For the work horses, I feed a liberal amount of alfalfa, but do not allow them to stand to a manger full all the time. I work my horses hard (using hired help) and they keep up well. They also stand the heat and have good wind. But I am always careful not to let them gorge themselves on alfalfa (or any other feed) when they are not at work, as on Sundays and rest days. Eor fattening horses, I always feed all the dry alfalfa hay the &gt;e will eat, together with ground alfalfa meal mixed with coarse ind corn — using a self-feeder. t prefer coarse alfalfa hay, first or second cutting, and want the If a rather ripe or in full bloom when cut. Horses do not care alfalfa leaves. The leaves should be taken out of the horse igers and fed to the cattle, as cattle will clean up exactly what horse does not want, and likewise the horse will eat the stems of lfa hay after the cattle have left them. thave never had anything but good results from the feeding of lfa to horses, and have fed it in all forms to thousands of them ng the last ten years. January 19, 1914. {'. B. Bowman &amp; Sons, Boone County. — My experience with ing alfalfa commenced 22 years ago, and I now have over r hundred acres seeded to it. I feed it the year round to work horses, stallions, brood mares, and colts. I consider it best feed known for brood mares producing milk, as well as for colts. As a horse pasture I consider it has no equal both summer and winter. When working the mares hard, we always turn them in alfalfa pastures at night with their colts. If the feed is short in the pasture, we have open feed racks with alfalfa hay in them. Iluch has been said as to alfalfa producing heaves. I think al - a as well as any other hay should be fed either in down mangers, the ground, or outside in open feed racks as much as possible, [ consider this reduces the danger of heaves to a great extent. Ell of our mares, colts, and young stallions run in yards or pas - s with open sheds all winter and have free access to feed racks lfalfa. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Theories have been advanced that feeding alfalfa to brood mares lessens the per cent of foals and their vitality. My observations and experience do not justify this theory. We breed from 18 to 35 mares of our own each season, and always have raised a large per cent of foals. One year every mare which we bred settled and carried her foal until the normal time. I)ur county has over thirty-four thousand acres of alfalfa, and 5 generally conceded here to be the greatest horse feed known, to developing bone and producing growth in colts there can be question as to its superiority. I feed very light grain rations secure good weights by the time colts are mature. I consider ilfa one of the important factors that make it possible for us to ;e just as good and just as big draft horses as they do in the World.— T. B. Bowman. April 1, 1914. Frank Howard, Pawnee County. — In regard to alfalfa hay, I will say that I have fed it a great deal and find it one of the most valuable hays that we have. It keeps the stock in a healthy condition and acts quicker in the way of making fat than any other hay. Ehen feeding it to fatten horses I let them have all they wish of it in the same yard I keep other hay, either timothy or wild as I think a horse keeps better balanced on his feed by letting have both kinds. However, I have never had any bad results tting horses have full feed on alfalfa alone. R think a work horse should be limited as to the amount of alfalfa, should have other kinds at the same time, either timothy or wild as horses love alfalfa and if they have a chance will eat more i is necessary for them to work on, and possibly their wind lit be shortened a little by it. I consider it one of the best paying crops raised and any country that cannot Taise it is certainly handicapped in growing draft horses. October 18. 1913. fOLF Brothers. Boone County. — We hear it mentioned that cannot turn horses out on alfalfa pasture because they will e themselves and bloat. There is absolutely nothing to this, have never had a sick horse on alfalfa pasture. We used to buy up many thin geldings and fatten them for market, often shipping them to market right off alfalfa pasture. Of course, shipping horses fed in this manner will shrink them somewhat and they will not ship as good as if they had had grain with it, but nevertheless, they will hold their flesh. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 For 14 years we fed alfalfa and corn to fatten our shipping horses and topped the market in Chicago several times with horses fed in this manner. We always considered that we saved a great deal of grain by feeding alfalfa hay. These horses were fed in the open and had free access to all of the alfalfa they wanted. ietding alfalfa in the barn makes the stalls pretty wet, as it ks on horses' kidneys. The kind of hay that we are feeding to stallions in our stables is timothy and alfalfa mixed, and this in opinion is the best horse hay. It keeps their bowels in fine je. and they seem to like it very much. But, as said before, if were feeding horses out in the yard, we would feed them pure We have also fed our work horses on alfalfa hay, and they seem to keep fat and do their work all right. It makes, however, a dif - ference which cutting one feeds to his work horses. First and sec - ond cuttings are the best ; the third cutting is too washy. We think a good deal of alfalfa, and it would be mighty hard for us to get along without it. October 22. 1913. J. M. Gates, Sakpy County. — I have never experienced any bad results from feeding alfalfa. I keep about 50 head of horses and feed alfalfa the year round. I find that by feeding it the horses keep in good flesh on considerably less grain than where other hay is fed. Last year we bred 10 mares and now have 8 live colts. The year before we bred 10 and had 8 live colts and one dead one. Last winter none of our young horses received grain except the weanling colts, yet all were in splendid condition this spring. timothy and prairie hay, but after horses and cattle have me accustomed to alfalfa they do not care for the other. I also pasture alfalfa with both horses and cattle. I have had some trouble with bloat in cattle but never with horses. Give me alfalfa every time. June 15, 1914. ALFALFA POINTERS tlfalfa is a splendid horse feed but must be fed with judgment care. Because of its palatability, mature horses are likely to eat too much alfalfa, if permitted to have free access to it. E average farm horse at hard work is allowed to eat much alfalfa and other roughage than he really needs to maintain ■ight. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Feeding Alfalfa to Horses &lt; 'lie pound of alfalfa or other hay and about 1 : -4 pounds of grain per day for each 100 pounds of the hone's wcifht make a good ration for the working horse. Horses like alfalfa stems. Refuse from the cattle racks is very acceptable to horses. Keed mature horses first and second cutting alfalfa which is free n mold and dust. Ko make the best horse hay. alfalfa should l&gt;e allowed to stand 1 well out in bloom. Pi curing horse hay it is well to keep in mind that the dust which resent in so much alfalfa is largely a result of the presence of ign moisture such as rain or dew at making time, rather than presence of a little moisture within the plant. N'ever feed wet alfalfa hay to horses. A sudden change of feed deranges the horse's digestive system Horses accustcmed to alfalfa as a regular part of their ration are seldom troubled from its use. E alfalfa hay is stored in the barn for horses, it is well to sprinkle nerously, while mowing it away, with a mixture of salt and air - •d lime, equal parts. trowing draft colts have seldom, if ever, been injured by eatinf much alfalfa and oats. ( lood. well-colored alfalfa is of practically the same composition as wheat bran and is of equal value to it in the horse ration. Eature horses of a greedy disposition, if allowed to run to al - racks at will, may eat too much and suffer attacks of impac- Draft mares heavy in foal, and taking but little exercise, not ■quently suffer attacks of this nature. An alfalfa pasture is a splendid place to develop draft colts with a maximum of bone and muscle. Some complaint comes from the humid regions to the effect that mares on alfalfa pasture during the breeding season are hard to get in foal. This trouble seems to be more or less local and can be avoided by temporarily keeping the mares in other pastures. An alfalfa patch forms a splendid night pasture for work horses, providing they are used to it and turned out regularly. E cause of the comparative ease with which alfalfa may be n in practically all parts of this state, it should form a portion ist of every horse s ration. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>