<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00039">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00039</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  SWEET CLOVER IN NEBRASKA.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">EXTENSION BULLETIN NO. 22 The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. SWEET CLOVER IN NEBRASKA By T. A. Kieksklbach. Disthihvted Aritn. 1, 1914. SWEFT CLOVER FIELD. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. THE GOVERNING BOARD. (the mocnts of the university) EABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON, Crete. ABLE GEORGE COUPLAND, Elgin. ABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN, President. Lim oln. ABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE. Valley. HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Falls City. THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMtKI. AVERY, Ph. 1)., I.I.. I)., Chancellor, ex offi&lt; io. E. A. BiRNETT, B. Be.. Director. J. S. DALES, M. Ph.. h'utnni ml Secretary. FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., Bulletin Editor. THE WORKING STAFF. ■\d Wu.cox. Ph. D., Aprieultural Botany. I &gt;s&lt;&gt;\, Pn. D., Agricultural Chemistry. ("mask. B. Sc M. E., Agri&lt; ulturnl Engirt' Bliss, B. S. A., Animal II usbnnilry. VJajw, If. I&gt;. C, Animal Pathology. Fi,AMist\, M. S. A., Dmirt Husbandry. OKI Bki'NER. B. Sc. Entomology. If II— ■&gt;! II. A. M., E -pi rim &lt; n tc.l Agronomy. ■ Pnisi kv. B. S&lt; .. Farm ilnntiijemi nt and Agricultural Ertension. Mohiiii.i. M. Foi:.. t'(,n s'iii. ■nm H. Haiiikh r. Ph. D., Geology. ■ CiiATiiiKN. A. M., Higliirnii Engineering. Emekson. D. Sc. Horticulture. ■ P. Stoit. C. E., Irrigation Engineering. IXMTMLAlm, A. M., Met: uinlogy. W. P. Sxyder, M. S., Superintendent of Experimental Substation, North Plattp. W. W. Burr. B. Sc, Associate in Soils and Crops, North Platte; Assist - ant Afiriciiltiirist, Offitc Dry Land Agriculture, U. 8. Department of Aarii -ult lire. ■ Lee, A. M., Associate in Animal Husbandry. Swk\k. A. ML, Associate in Entomology. II K. K. Lixk. A. M.. Assistant in Agricultural Botany. Calvin. B. Sc, Assistant in Agricultural Chemistry. Darker. A. M., Assistant in Agronomy (Soils). s Hon. B. Sc. Assistant in Agronomy (Crops). Ratclikf, A. B., Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. ko .1. GiiAMi.iiH. £i. Sc. Assistant in Animal Husbandry (Horses). Sti-rhexant. A. M., M. U., Assistant in Animal Pathology. Woodward, A. M., Assistant in Dairy Husbandry. J. R. Cooper, B. S( ., Assistant in Horticulture. C. A. Helm. B. S( .. Assistant in Experimental Agronomy. Jambs Cowan. M. B., Superintendent Experimental Substation. Valentine. Fbitz Kxorr, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation, Mitchell. S. W. 1'ERiN. Farm Superintendent. H. L. Nvb, Foreman Demonstration Farm. Culbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SWEET CLOVER IN NEBRASKA. BY T. A. KIKSSEI.BACII. If object of this bulletin is to rapplj the often requested Mtkra concerning sweet clover culture. This crop is Ix'iiiji ('■ cussed as especially suitable for pasture and meadow Hitics where the rainfall is relatively low and also for ini - g the fertility and physical condition of impoverished SPECIES TO PLANT. Kltho there are a great Banker "f species of sweet clover, three are at all common in this country. These are. Int. iennial white sweet clover (MelilotiU albtn : second, the yellow 1&gt;ienni:il sweet clovn- i MtWottu &lt;&gt;/fi&lt; iusttt) : and the small yellow annual sweet clover \ Melilotut iinlirti). I ire should lie taken to avoid planting the small annual i'S in this State, as it is very inferior. Unfortunately much i- seed sold in Nebraska as sv eet clover has l&gt;een of this st worthless sjiecies. It will not 1k&gt; considered further in ollowiny: discussion. In jieneral. the white sweet clover is recommended for planting, nowever. the lar;;e yellow is fairly well adapted and is held ill favor by some growers, seed of this sj&gt;ecie8 is scarcely to be found on the market. HABITS OF GROWTH. The younir sweet clover plant closely resembles alfalfa, but can lw readily distinguished by a bitter taste. It grows into an erect, branching, steininy plant and is biennial. Growth is slow tin- tirsi year, and usually no seed is develo|&gt;ed. It should be cut for hay the tirst year, when it has made its maximum growth in the fall. The second year a hay crop and seed crop may l&gt;e produced. The plant ordinarily dies when it has matured a seed crop, and if it is desired to continue the field of sweet clover it is necessary either to replant or to permit the crop to reseed itself. EXTENSION BULL. NO. 22, AGB. EXP. STATION OF NKBR. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Street Clover in Xcbragka The second year it may attain a height of from five to seven feet under favorable conditions, but the first year it seldom rcaclMi over thirty inches. If sown in the fall, either two hay crops or both a hay crop and a seed crop are produced the following year, and then the plant dies. ADAPTATION OP SWEET CLOVER. Sweet clover will thrive upon any nonacid soil suitable for other cultivated crops. It will do especially well on a fertile soil with an abundance of rainfall. However, when a stand is once obtained, it will make a comparatively vigorous growth on thin, clayey, or sandy soils containing but little humus. Satisfactory stands and yields are often obtained in central and western Nebraska where the rainfall is light. Its production lias l&gt;een too limited in western Nebraska to permit a definite statement regarding the likelihood of success in regions \vln're alfalfa is a failure because of deficient rainfall. On account of the limited experience with this crop in Nebraska, it is advisable to plant i»nly a few acres until results have shown it to be a suitable and well-adapted crop for one's own conditions. Thruout eastern Nebraska it grows luxuriantly in a wild state and especially along the roadsides. In central Nebraska it is very common in the river valleys and all low land where the ground water is only a few feet below the surface. On the heavy table-lands in the west central portion of the State, sweet clover has shown no natural tendency to gain a foothold, even where it ■;rows profusely in adjoining valleys. However, there have been many reports of success on the sandy land. Thus far it has been impossible to secure a growth of sweet clover which would stand thru the winter at the Experimental Substation at Valentine ui&gt;on any of the higher ground. It will, however, grow on the low ground where moisture is not so limited. There, it apjtears no easier to secure a stand of sweet clover than of alfalfa. In the extreme western part of the State, sweet clover is again found native only where there is easy access to water — either irrigation, river, or subsurface moisture. te marketability of the hay grown in many native hay &gt;ws in the Platte valley in central Nebraska has lieen y interfered with by the presence of sweet clover. The clover becomes coarse and woody by the time the native is ready to be cut for hay. However, some of these meadows in by sweet clover have returned considerable profit by &lt;ting and threshing for seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 §a rule sweet clover should not be grown for a general crop where alfalfa or red clover yields well. The per - character, the greater yield, and the higher market value hay make alfalfa more desirable. PREPARATION OP THE SEED BED. In general, the same preparation of the seed bed should be &lt;riven for sweet clover as for alfalfa. Early plowing followed hy occasional disking and harrowing is desirable on heavy to medium heavy soils. In case the plowing is done shortly before seeding, the soil should be repacked either with a roller or by disking several times with the disk set rather straight. A firm, tine, moist seed bed is very important. Under these conditions a stand is quite certain, but there is much danger of losing the seed when sown on a poorly prepared seed l&gt;ed. It may also be sown on cornstalk land by simply disking in preparation. Upon loose, sandy soil which is inclined to blow, it may be desirable first to seed the land to a small grain erop and then, instead of plowing, merely disk the stubble before sowing. The stubble will tend to hold the soil. Upon sandy, prairie sod. where the stand of grass is light, sweet clover may be sown directly upon the sod without first breaking it. The seed may be covered bv a shallow disking. SEEDING SWEET CLOVER. Both hulled and unhulled seed may be obtained on the mar - ket. Twenty to twenty-five pounds of the hulled seed should be sown on an acre, while at least five pounds more of the unhulled seed should be used. Frequently 50 per cent or more of the seed is hard, which will not germinate readily. For this reason more seed is necessary than would otherwise be the case. Altho this r.ite makes seeding expensive, the general experience has Iteen that it is not too much under average conditions. The seed may be sown broadcast and covered with a smoothing har - row set rather slanting or else with a grain drill with grass seed attachment. In either case the seed should not be covered more than about three-fourths of an inch deep. Etreet clover is sometimes sown with a nurse crop such as t, oats, or barley, but this is likely to result in a loss of the because the nurse crop dries out the soil to the disadvantage e clover. Where such a nurse crop is used it should not be d thicker than about half the normal rate for a grain crop, often desirable in dry seasons to mow such a nurse crop for </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Kwcet Cltioor in Nebraska tafly before reaching maturity. This may prevent top complete drying out of the soil, with a subsequent loss of the clover. Sweet clover may be sown any time in the spring after the ground is fit to work, until the first of June. If sown in the fall it should be done early, preferably by the early part of August. The early fall seeding will permit sufficient growth to prevent winterkilling. Tn the western portion of the State spring seed - ing is probably to be preferred. INOCULATION Sweet clover is a legume similar to alfalfa, and for successful LTowth depends upon the presence of the proper bacteria in the soil. It happens that the same bacteria which form tubercles on alfalfa roots are the proper bacteria for sweet clover; eoaar i|iicntly where alfalfa lias ben found to thrive without special inoculation, the same may be expected to be true of sweet clover. If iliere is any doubt i-egardinir tin* incsence of tile proper bac - teria in the soil, it is a wise precaution to intrcduce them arti- Irially either directly to the mil or on the seed. Several methods of inoculation may be employed. I access is to he had to an old. healthy sweet clover or alfalfa soil from this field may he scattered at the rate of :S00 or minds an acre over the land to )&gt;e seeded. The land should lie immediately harrowed in order to prevent the drying f the applied soil. This method is most likely to give re- Ihere the seed is inoculated directly, this may be done either liHteria In aiing soil as descrilwd above or with artificial lafion culture. When soil is used, the seed is first dampened then mixed with an equal amount of the soil. The seed d then In- sjiread nut and dried in the shade and seeded as as sufficiently dry. In adjusting the seeder, allowance must lie made for the increased bulk caused by the mixture of the ind seed. The [Hire culture method consists of moistening the seed with prepared culture-solvtion and then drying before seeding. These cultures may be purchased from dealers and can also be obtained in limited nuantities free of charge from the United States De - partment of Agriculture. Washington. D. C. A field which has been seeded, but later upon careful exam - ination is found to be lacking the necessary bacteria, as indi - cated bv the absence of the small ffrarte-like clusters of tubercles ■ \ </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Pthe routs, may be inoculated by scattering bacteria-bearing il upon it, followed by a harrowing. SWEET CLOVER HAY. Chemical analyses indicate that a good quality of sweet clover h:iy contains about the same food value as alfalfa or red clover, bat in ordinary practice sweet clover hay contains such a large percentage of hard, woody stems that there is more waste than in the case of alfalfa or red clover. It is rich in proteia and is readily eaten by stock when accustomed to it. Opinions differ widely regarding the best time to cut for hay. Boat advocate waiting until the seed is fairly well formed; others advise cutting Ix-fore the first bloom appears. Taking everything into consideration, the early cutting seems preferable, the chief reason being that the hay is less woody. The hay is. however, more easily cured if cut somewhat later. In general, sweet clover hay cures more slowly than docs alfalfa. Care must be taken in handling not to shatter the leaves, as they are the most valuable part of the hay. SWEET CLOVER PASTURE The general experience of farmers is that stock must acquire a taste for sweet Hover before eating it readily. Very little difficulty is experienced, however, in getting stock to eat it, and when they have once acquired the taste it affords excellent pas - ture. While sweet clover may Ih&gt; pastured with less danger of bloating the stock than either clover or alfalfa, some cases of bloat have been noted, and it is well to exercise the same pre - cautions against it as with clover and alfalfa. This consists chiefly in keeping the stock off when the sweet clover is wet with rain or dew. To make good pasture, the plant should be grazed sufficiently close to prevent a coarse growth. At the same time care must l&gt;e taken not to graze the plants so closely that an insufficient quantity of seed will be formed to reseed for the fol- HARVESTING SWEET CLOVER SEED. Usually the second cutting of the second year is left for seed. The first cutting often makes the larger seed crop, but the total value returned is usually greater where the seed crop is pre - ceded by a hay crop. The plant dies after the seed crop is produced, and the tieh: must be reseeded. unless sufficient seed </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Xweet Vlovti in Nebraska the same time and for this reason harvesting must be done at the time that the maximum amount is mature. The same precaution against shattering of the seed should Ik? taken as with clover and ;il fa I fa. Two hundred to five hundred pounds of seed per acre may be expected. EFFECT OF SWEET CLOVER ON THE SOIL. t properly inoculated, sweet clover has a very beneficial upon the soil. Similar to other legumes it has the power lizing nitrogen — one of the most important elements of nutrition — directly from the air because of the bacteria live on its roots. Tn addition to increasing the amount of ble nitrogen, sweet clover has an abundant root develop - which greatly increases the organic matter in the soil. Bis a well-known fact that the productivity of the soil is sed by the growth of sweet clover even when the entire r removed. On very thin or worn-out soils an entire crop ■et clover can profitably be plowed under for green manure. Eng shallower rooted, sweet clover does not dry out the to as great a depth as does alfalfa, and for this reason ling crops in the rotation are not so likely to suffer from ' moisture. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>