<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00027</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Studies of the Etiology and Control of Blister Canker on Apple Trees</title>
               <date value="1917-12-15">1917-12-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">RUE ARCH BULLETIN NO. II THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN or the AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION or NEBRASKA STUDIES OP THE ETIOLOGY AND CONTROL OP BLISTER CANKER ON APPLE TREES Hy I Km in ClNlfM Hi -HMIMI 1M1 OfcCKMNKN l'i, H»I7 HWMI Mlltm t*HI»¥k MMMI*, IKFMM^h^*' 1 A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">2 nnmm station or mum tMl MVINMtMt MANN IMI&gt; WfMM lit HH fNf»M*Mf 1 1 111 II Mfe ww n rfliiroirwwM fMI WIMJNf Iflff f i^kffl'W ,P .T Jill"" 'I"'* ftiiihiwliiH 'Will IL WVt.WvJ 9 F « I lMWl'*xJ1iLl]hlili&gt; «/ I W I »W ft W ' '""" ""' /■ 1 L*r/5;"n.T i. 'M'"'"'/ '» ■iHt'iiliiiiHi &gt; In until / t 'k7i Jl' lilAL'lL U I""'/"," /" I/'"'/ nj/lwlw mill 1'linhilnnt 1/ Rtl/fc fiWr'Jw v '.UiiiiWn In lliiiiliiilliiii \l'+l»iiiin l\ m hfi'iijni in ■\iii&gt;iii&gt;'it\i Ui 'A W'"' ■Uv tl Jl"' I 11 ilWMIlHIti U i* fe\\ »l i ■lolmiinii Pirn* ihtimilt* &amp;ii\i\ \*'fi '*wMnni """^ •'»"" """"" </seg>
            <seg id="p003">HMtMW hi n Ul'lllUllltnl, ft HMHIt * mtUum hM hmmi wmihhh 1 HumwiHH m Hi* Pimm htHttilHi *IHIth A»hWHHIt» MUM Mmiiiim IK II if I tomm* ImiilHtiHHi Hinmin immmim iHlniiM HiiiiH hwi-iihiimti I'M* huHltW IlllilillHtlltli, Iliilil limmlHliiiii* *i II iMxiliilliHlliill hiiH trii mini ilium lit Illinium HlittHi ill Hmtlillii III Hi* Haul HlllhlllHtlllU IH WHIM HI imniMII 4| iHiniiiHinm in miiiw Imiiiihtiim in I in* in MHhiMI ♦# mm nnihiiiHiiim Hmiml Hiimviiliiliii k&gt;. (Wfirt nl Hull ¥nituiih mi mimmiiiiiin 11 I* IK hi m m M HkIhimh m hnihlilH hiinihiim in mwMHliiHii VMMti »ll»mlll)IIIH HhlllHtt* III hlllllllll Hulling hi Vmmim mimiHH UmlHium H*»Hiunmti*nntt» HlMlWHWlu l»ll..lf ( ,MfHl. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">•TUDIEI OF THE ETIOLOGY AND CONTROL Of ILIfTER CANKER ON APPLE TREEI l»r I' »*4ini » '^ic« I* IIMIIIII Ilil* Th« Mi»U«r iiitnk*&gt;r «NU«ttd Wy Sumwulurtu iinmf«t§ Ttfli if i&lt;y fw&lt; Hi" 11111*1 «Wniiliv« difttf*** of MpuM t^tNMt fmjn4 M Mi UniUtfl himUk. Hhi'imud dftmag* dMt« to lhi» 4i»#»## wm Am rujwrUI in Illinuu j» |«0'2. Hintw that tlm# Mm* diMMt mm li»«!ii H!|iurUf»J Ui t-'HUHf imirli &lt;i(inut|/t&gt;-- in til! uin&gt;\u-\innUtfUw mtciiimn «Mt ut Dtu Horky Mmwum*. In Nuhr»*k» th« 4»» - s»n« u ho |)iuvttUiiil llmL it jh iirtu'lunWy \minm»\h\u Ui find »D ovchuri (ntf from it, wiuj in in«tiiy Uminwuu wiutlu mchnrin h«va buuri duHlrnymi tin u iU tttlwks. BecHUMo of thu nipid divtwrniniition ami Uw 4u»trnuiivn n»tura of \A\hIuv ijiiikur, tlu* writer in the ftill of IMJ2 Jimgin u tutrio* of uxpoi imunU in »n atuniwtt to find Hom« rnawu of controlling it. It wa« soon found that little program could be made in this direction without u thoro knowledge of the etiology of the disease, Accordingly this phase of the work wm taken up in 1914 and both phases continued to date. MtfTltinUTION Our present knowledge of Nummularia diaereta indicates that it causes a serious disease only of various species of Malus. However, it has been reported to cause cankers on Amelanchier, GlediUia, SorbuH, Cercis, Ulmus, and Mag - nolia. The writer has succeeded in inoculating artificially both Pyrus communis and Amygdalus persica. Altho no characteristic cankers have appeared on either of these, micro - scopic examination has shown an abundance of invading hyphae thru the discolored area of the wood. Since 1902, when it was reported as a destructive disease in orchards in Illinois, it has been reported in every apple - growing section east of the Rocky Mountains. It is especially The writer la under creat obligation* to Dr. E. Mead Wllcox and Prof. R. IT. Howard for valuable ■UKirratlona and •ncouragement, to Dr. Florence A. McCormlck fur advice and ainlitance in hi»tolojry and microtechnique, to (irovp M. l'urter and Knimctt I :. &lt;'utter»on for mmlmanri- In making In - iK'iilut H'liH, and to Minn Kdna ISi-nty for inunmancr In udmrnbllnK and check- Ins data. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 destructive in the region known as the Middle West, — Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Iowa, Missouri, Kansas, and Nebraska. Practically every orchard in the State has more or less infection. The extent of infection and amount of damage varies, as will be shown later, with the varieties of apples, soil conditions, amount of precipitation, and general weather con - ditions. Owing to the fact that the fungus is a wound parasite and since the disease may exist in a tree for several seasons before becoming conspicuous or even noticeable, the distribution of infections appears very irregular and scattered in an orchard. Even when trees become infected at the same time, the dis - ease shows externally on some trees long before it can be detected on others. After a time the disease becomes notice - able on all the infected trees, and finally they are killed. It is a common sight in Nebraska to see dead trees here and there thruout an orchard, and especially in neglected orchards to see whole blocks of dead trees, with here and there a tree which still has a few limbs bearing foliage and small apples. HISTORY The causal fungus was first described in America by Schweinitz 17 in 1834 under the name Sphaeria discreta. At that time it was considered to be a saprophyte and conse - quently of no economic importance. In 1863 the Tulasne brothers 18 gave an excellent descrip - tion of the fungus illustrated by numerous drawings. They re - named it Nummularia discreta by which name it is known at the present time. That they found it to be a parasite is shown by their statement : "It grows with us during the autumn and winter on Sorbus hybrida L. on the thick bark which has re - cently died." However, they attached no importance to the fungus as the causal organism of the disease. It remained for Hasselbring 11 to observe the destructive - ness of the disease caused by this fungus. In 1902 he noted a cankerous disease very prevalent and doing a great deal of damage to orchards in Illinois, which he called Illinois canker. He found the disease was caused by the fungus Nummularia discreta. In his report he gave a very comprehensive account of the symptoms and general appearance of the disease, but aside from this added little to the knowledge already furnished by Tulasne. "These reference* are to the bibliography, page 68. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Blister Canker 7 In 1912 Gloyer 10 of Ohio published a circular on "Blister Canker" caused by Nummularia discrete, but added little of any importance to the facts already published. The disease was first noted in Nebraska about 1903 but it received no attention and no report was made except to men - tion its presence in the State. SYMPTOMS AND GENERAL. APPEARANCE It is impossible to describe the symptoms of blister canker so that the casual observer will be able to identify the disease in all cases. Under certain conditions the symptoms are very marked and characteristic, as indicated by Hasselbring 11 , but under other conditions these characteristic symptoms are wanting. The injury often resembles very closely that caused by other agencies such as winter injury, sun scald, blight, collar rot, and the so-called arsenical poisoning. The writer is of the opinion that a large share of the damage attributed to other causes is in reality caused by Nummularia discrete. The symptoms vary with the variety of trees, point of inoculation, soil conditions, amount of precipitation, general weather con - ditions, and treatment of the orchard. On the more resistant varieties sharply denned cankers usually appear. In the ear - liest stage the bark takes on a darker brown color and soon becomes slightly shrunken, and depressed below the adjoining healthy bark. The canker usually does not begin at one small point and spread, but a considerable area of affected bark will appear rather suddenly and continue to grow in size, spread - ing most rapidly in the direction of the long axis of the limb. The initial spots vary in size, being anywhere from two to eighteen or more inches long and one-half to six inches wide. The inner bark in these spots and at the edges of old cankers has a mottled appearance due to intermingling of dead areas within the living tissues. The size of the original cankered spot and the mottled appearance of recently affected areas are due to the fact that the fungus invades the older xylem tissues of the tree first and then works gradually toward the surface, killing the tissues as it advances. The advance is naturally more rapid in certain portions of the affected area than in others. Consequently the bark is not attacked evenly, but in spots wherever the fungus has approached near enough to the surface to kill the cambium. The bark is never attacked until the underlying tissues are killed. During the months of July, August, and September small round blister-like protuberances one-eighth to one-quarter </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 inch in diameter appear all over the affected surface, or in the case of large spots where the center has become hard and dry, only along the margin of the cankered area. These "blisters" are caused by the formation of stromata (masses of spore - bearing mycelium) beneath the surface of the bark. Spores (conidia) are produced during the latter part of the same sea - son or early the next spring. The blisters are ruptured by the pressure from beneath, disclosing a pale grayish-tan colored mass of mycelium and spores. The cankered area increases in size each season as long as the branch remains alive. The bark of the older portions becomes blackened and rough. The stromata become flat or concave on the surface. Continued growth at the edges causes them to assume very irregular outlines. Often several blend into one, covering an area of nearly an inch in diameter. The surfaces of the stromata often appear light gray in color dur - ing the early spring, due to the growth of mycelium and the production of spores (conidia). Later, especially after the bark has been thoroly wetted by rains, the surface of these same stromata may appear coal-black due to the presence of ascospores which have been formed on the interior and forced to the surface. With age the cankered bark begins to crack in all direc - tions and fall off, leaving irregular patches of dead wood exposed. The stromata, however, usually remain firmly at - tached to the wood by means of a ring of fungous tissue for a considerable period of time after the bark has fallen away. If these stromata are removed, irregular dark brown to black rings, showing the points of attachment, may be seen in the lighter colored wood. The point of inoculation often greatly influences the symp - toms of the disease. Where entrance is gained thru a large wound, cankers are usually formed first at the point of initial infection, but if thru a small wound or thru a frost crack in the trunk or any of the main branches, the wound usually closes and the first cankers may appear in some of the branches which have been weakened or wounded. In cases of this kind one or more whole limbs often die in one season and usually few, if any, stromata are formed on their dead sur - faces. When stromata are found in such cases, they are at the base of the limb where the fungus can still draw on the living tree for food. Where the inoculation takes place near the extremity of a branch, the branch is as a rule gradually can - kered its entire length and stromata usually dot the whole sur - face. In all cases stromata are formed more abundantly </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Blister Canker 9 where the cankers are protected from direct sunlight, but on the other hand light does not affect the location of cankers. Inoculation very often occurs thru wounds at the base of the tree made by rodents or by machinery in cultivation. In such instances, where the wounds are too large to heal over at once, the cankered margins advance and the bark falls away, but stromata are rarely found except on young trees or where new branches arise near enough to the wounds to be affected. Inoculation often occurs in roots near the surface of the ground thru wounds made in cultivation or otherwise. In such cases that portion of the root is usually killed and the dis - ease first becomes manifest as a canker at the crown. Some - times the whole root system is affected but the fungus grows from one root to another with much more difficulty than from one branch to another, so that, as a rule, even tho a part of the roots may be killed, the others will remain intact until after the whole tree has become infected. On the more susceptible varieties the symptoms are some - what different. Whole trees often appear to be killed in a single season and no Iruiting bodies appear, or one main limb after another may succumb in a single season and produce stromata only at the base near portions of the tree which are still alive. In many instances stromata form on the limbs dur - ing the same season that the disease first appears in the form of visible canker, but many of them never produce spores. Many more never rupture the epidermis, and practically no ascospores are ever produced. The perfect stage of the fungus is rarely found abundantly on the most susceptible varieties except when the cankers occur on the trunk or very large limbs, and even then it is often wanting owing to thick, corky bark which hinders the formation of stromata. However, enough immature or sterile stromata may usually be found upon a minute examination of the tree to identify the disease. The disease makes rapid progress in trees suffering from drouth. The effects of drouth will be discussed later. Here again the symptoms are often somewhat modified. Whole limbs or even whole trees often die in a single season, or the bark may die only in long strips, sometimes reaching from the tip to the base of the limb, while the remaining bark will remain alive sometimes for several months. Infected trees suffering from drouth often put forth foliage and set an abundant crop of fruit only to have both leaves and fruit wither and die. In case the limb or tree does not die outright the leaves turn yellow and the fruit, while it reaches a certain </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 10 state of maturity, seldom attains sufficient size to be worth harvesting. Stromata are rarely formed in large numbers. These symptoms, while most commonly found associated with drouth conditions, are by no means confined to trees under such conditions. Badly affected roots or trunk may induce the same symptoms. DESCRIPTION OF THE FUNGUS CON1DIAL STAGE As before stated, blisters appear during the late summer months upon the surface of the newly cankered areas. These blisters are caused by the formation of circular interwoven masses of mycelium just beneath the surface of the bark. Conidiophores arise from the surface of these stromata. They are short and usually more or less branched. Several conidia may be borne on the tip of each branch. Both conidiophores and conidia are nearly hyaline. Gloyer 10 not inaptly uses the term "honey colored" in describing them. The conidia are oval, rather sharply pointed at the attached end, and measure about 5 by 8 microns, altho they are often smaller. The spores are set free by the layer of bark which covers the stromata being ruptured by the pressure of the conidiophores and spores beneath. Conidia may be produced during the latter part of the sea - son on one-year-old cankers. The same stromata may produce conidia the next spring and for several seasons thereafter. These subsequent crops of spores occur, however, only on cankers protected from direct sunlight. In many instances spores are not produced until the spring following the appear - ance of the canker. As before stated the stromata in many instances never produce spores at all, due to the death of the limb or tree cutting off the food and water supply of the fungus. During favorable seasons conidia are produced thru - out the growing season but as a rule under Nebraska condi - tions they occur most abundantly in the early spring during the months of April, May, and June, and to a less extent in September and October. Hasselbring 11 stated that he was unable to germinate the conidia, but Gloyer 10 found them to be quite viable and that they germinated readily in distilled and well water, prune de - coction, and a 4 per cent sugar solution even after having been kept in the laboratory for three months. The writer found no difficulty in germinating conidia, when taken as soon as they matured, in water, and synthetic </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Blister Canker 11 liquid and solid media, but found their viability to decrease rapidly with age. In tests made soon after maturity of the spores an average of 82.2 per cent germination was secured, using semi-solid and liquid synthetic media, and water cul - tures which contained one per cent each of cane sugar and peptone. There was little difference in the amount of ger - mination in any of these media. Spores which were placed in a moist chamber for a few hours and then desiccated did not germinate at all. Spores which had been kept in the labora - tory for six weeks gave a germination test of only 8.5 per cent. No satisfactory results were obtained from the use of solid media. Upon germination the endospore gradually draws away from the exospore except near the points where the germ tubes emerge. Later the exospore is entirely broken up. The perfect or perithecial stage of the fungus appears one or more years after the conidial stage. Under favorable conditions it appears the following season tho in many cases it does not appear at all. The perfect stage is rarely found except in cankers on the trunk and large branches. During the early spring and summer perithecia are formed in the stromata which have previously borne conidia on their sur - faces. These perithecia are arranged more or less in layers beneath the surface of the stroma, and are 0.2 to 0.4 mm. wide by 0.3 to 1.8 mm. long. The older and larger perithecia lie near the center of the stroma and are connected with the surface by means of long narrow necks. New perithecia are formed both above and below the first layer and around the edges of the stroma gradually increasing its size. Two or more stromata may fuse at the edges forming one very large irregular stroma. The asci which are about 12 to 15 by 160 to 180 microns arise from all parts of the interior of the perithecia with their free ends extending diagonally toward the center and the neck. Asci of all stages of development may be found in the same perithecium. Interspersed among the asci are numerous long sterile mycelial threads. The asci contain eight oblong brownish-black spores each. These spores measure about 10 to 12 by 13 to 16 microns when dry, but upon absorbing moisture become almost spherical. During wet weather the stromata absorb water readily and the spores are expelled in great quantities. Some remain clinging to the surface but many are thrown entirely free. Glass slides smeared with vaseline and suspended 1%, inches ASCOGEN'OUS STAGE </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 above a group of stromata placed on moist blotting paper in a covered vessel caught and held large numbers of spores. Tulasne 18 stated that the spores are expelled in March or April. The writer has found spores being expelled during every part of the growing season depending upon weather con r ditions. Stromata kept in the laboratory for over three years expelled spores in large quantities within a few hours after being placed in contact with wet blotting paper. It is very common to find ascospores being expelled thru masses of conidiophores and conidia on the surface of the stroma. The spores are hyaline until they attain full size when they assume a dark brown or black color with a lighter line ex - tending along one side. Hasselbring 11 gave a very accurate description of their germination. He stated : "In germination the exospore cracks along the lines previously described. Two germ tubes originate from the endospore. These turn away from each other and remain at first closely appressed to the spore. Then they grow out in opposite directions." Hasselbring found that oxygen is necessary to spore ger - mination. The writer also found this to be true. Spores deeply embedded in poured plates did not germinate at all while the percentage of germination was high at or near the surface. Ascospores retain their vitality for a long period of time. A large number of stromata were secured in the spring of 1914 and the spores tested for germination at intervals of three months. After three months the per cent of germina - tion was 91.8. This was nearly 20 per cent higher than when the spores were first taken. This was probably due to the presence of a large number of immature spores when the stromata were gathered. After three years the per cent of germination was 31.9. It was found, however, that a great number of these spores were so reduced in vitality that the germ tubes grew to be only a few mm. in length and died. As was the case with conidia, few spores germinated when they were exposed in a moist atmosphere for several hours and then allowed to dry before the test was made. MYCELIUM Mycelial growth in artificial media is relatively slow from both conidia and ascospores. For this reason it was very dif - ficult to secure pure cultures from conidia unless the spores were taken from those first matured on the stroma before the bark became ruptured. Later, spores of Macrosporiwn and Fusarium were often found intermingled with the conidia. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Blister Canker 13 At first the hyphae from conidia are rather heavy and be - cause of numerous large vacuoles appear abundantly septate. The hyhae produced after the cultures were a few days old could not be distinguished in any way from hyphae in asco - spore cultures. It was a simple matter to secure pure cultures from asco - spores. The stromata were placed on moist blotting or filter paper in the bottom of deep petri dishes which had been ster - ilized. When the spores were expelled they adhered to the cover in large quantities. The spores were then transferred to poured plates. These cultures were usually free from con - tamination except for the presence of bacteria. Bacterial growth was prevented by acidifying the media with lactic acid. Ordinarily the mycelium branches very little when young and the hyphae maintain a relatively direct course. Several mm. behind the growing tip the older part of the mycelium branches profusely. Many hyphae often arise at the same point on one or both sides of the main trunk and spread in a fan-shaped area over the media. These hyphae are usually much smaller than the parent stock. In the older cultures, compact masses of mycelium are formed at these points of division on which in many instances the writer has found conidiophores and conidia. Conidia were first noted in cul - tures which were sealed with paraffin and left for several months. An attempt made to germinate these spores met with failure. It was later found comparatively easy to induce cultures to produce conidia by checking growth suddenly or by allowing the culture to dry slightly. It was also found that the conidia would germinate readily. Gloyer 10 indicates that the rate of growth of mycelium in apple wood was very rapid where the wood had lost a portion of its water content, but that no growth was made where the wood was sterilized with steam at 15 pounds pressure. He attributes this failure of growth to an excess of water caused by sterilizing with steam. In the dry wood he secured the phenomenal growth of 8 inches thru heartwood tissues in seven days, a feat which the author tried in vain to duplicate. Wood cylinders 1 inch in diameter were sterilized in mercuric chloride for 30 minutes and then washed in distilled water. The ends were next trimmed away with a sterilized knife to remove any mercuric chloride which remained, dipped in alcohol and the alcohol burned away. Others were sterilized by steam under 15 pounds pressure. Five sections sterilized each way were inoculated at one end and placed in cotton - plugged cylinders which permitted rapid evaporation of water. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 g 8 § 1 ■" « "S oo ft ■ -~ 3 » 3 o « 8 oo v S u SI II I i *&gt; si S— OOOOt^ HDCtflflOO O 00 QO »u ** c ; c ! t *! lom-vinoo o o S *•£ ooooto touigonde o oo us . «e M-*ioootnoooo5 t- gu OOOOQO OSBOBK oo rt ri 3C »M*MMM U5 ia "S^ HHHCOM OCCIAMCON U3 IO IO V N ! M I I I I I 1 I i i a «ds^ J J J J J J j j E |siii iiiiii i i £ sssss sgggii i 1 i I I &lt;«« &lt;««_&lt;_ \ % i i i i I i iiiiii i c : \\s\\ !|! . ;- i i i S : 5 i a : s a £ = 65 i « 5* i I is S = -.2ii.2.2 ®* i'5 f, = ! s » — c "&gt;»"&gt;»"&gt;» 1 &gt;* b N i a ~ it I i iS^o^^xX^o^ ZC i S M - g T3 T3 -C -O T5 ~ 0) * N «^^is|iiiiiif« I I I I I I • i ! ! I i : I II •2 § I mi oil : : Q a 2 - : y •' i« ;ts i o o 0 loan La _ljjjj_. g !§§S£5 lllllS ' o t||S|S gggggg 8 o c : J I H Z » </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Blister Canker 15 Five others were inoculated and placed in cylinders with ground glass stoppers which prevented evaporation. One sec - tion of each was examined each week. The first examination showed little growth in either case. The second week the sections from the cotton-plugged cylinder showed the most vigorous growth. The third week the hyphae had advanced in one of the sections sterilized with mercuric chloride in the cotton-stoppered cylinder 1% inches and in the one sterilized by steam 214 inches. In the sections where no evaporation was permitted the one sterilized with steam showed an ad - vance of li/i inches in three weeks and the one sterilized with mercuric chloride 1 inch. After this time practically no growth was made in sections sterilized with mercuric chloride and allowed to dry. A growth of 3*4 inches was found the fifth week in the steamed section which was allowed to dry. Of the sections not allowed to dry out the one steamed, exam - ined the fifth week, showed a growth of 2% inches while the one sterilized with mercuric chloride showed only 11/2 inches. In the sections sterilized with mercuric chloride only the heartwood was invaded, but in those sterilized with steam even the bark was invaded. In all cases, but more noticeably where the wood was steamed, a dark brown slimy liquid exuded from the wood. This remained in the bottom of the tightly closed cylinders but soon dried up in those plugged with cotton. Sections of branches were then dried by heat until 10 and 20 per cent of water respectively had been lost, and enclosed in cylinders as above. Growth was noted in only one case where the cylinders were plugged with cotton and only slight growth was secured where the cylinders were tightly closed. Twelve branches one-half inch in diameter and bearing leaves were inoculated in one-year-old wood and placed with the cut ends in water. At the end of the sixth day the myce - lium had grown above the inoculation an average of 4^4 inches. Branches which were inoculated and not placed in water showed practically no growth. KXPERIMENTAL INFECTION In 1914 a series of inoculations were planned in order to secure definite data on the manner in which the disease is most readily disseminated, how infection occurs, the rate of prog - ress of the disease after infection occurs, varietal resistance and control measures. Actual work in the field was begun in May of 1915, altho inoculations had been made on trees in the </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui, It .a, oooom ootewtAHN ca « — : X "X t 1* i-(- cc {£ HH W WMW in (D &lt;fci i. « © O O O rH HVVHI-H * J* t- B-5 *" %«. v. 1 § — a* s •"S-S » S2I2H2 SS^S''? "° "5 S* ** "" coooo ooo so S S g^ OOOUC UUOUUU u 5 § 8 « s 1 t 5f 1 oo *i &gt;-S i J [3 I ! I I fl « .1 ■c a: 25SSS|^ V°B s .s Me •" * C: &gt;J © -s 1 s ■% % mi : u i. e « ■ ■ -c S8 Sc«; c iiiiii ? 1 5ss« 3 i5 nun i r- laiowo© khmsonoi so ,- t~ = .£ o „ x x x x x o J o* »&gt;&lt;s«22222 S^ 01 Q) m t- r: &gt;- ■_ c in cc sc w 03 e c "5 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Blister Canker 17 greenhouse before that. Over 2,000 field inoculations were made in trees of several varieties, ranging from 1 to 16 years old. Inoculations were made in every manner in which it was thought possible that infections could occur under field condi - tions. Ascospores, conidia, infected wood tissues, and pure cultures of the fungus were used as inocula. In making the inoculations with pure culture and infected wood the surface to be inoculated was first washed with 95 per cent alcohol. The wound was then made with a sterilized knife, chisel or auger as the case might be. The inoculum was placed in position and the wound covered with a sterile cotton patch. This was in turn covered with a square of cloth coated with paraffin and the whole then wrapped with several layers of cloth saturated with grafting wax. The inoculations with other inocula were covered in the same way but the surface to be inoculated and the tools were not sterilized except in a por - tion of the operations. Care was exercised to use trees free from previous infection. To determine whether or not a tree was infected one or more large branches were sawed off close to the trunk, or borings were made with an auger, and trees which showed discolored wood were rejected. The spores were secured by cutting away the disc from a stroma and exposing the perithecia, then drawing out the spores by means of a pipette partly filled with water, or by causing the spores to be expelled and collecting them from the petri dish covers as has already been explained. The spores were placed in water in a bottle and inserted in the incisions by means of a bulb pipette. Inoculations were made by spraying spores upon the unin - jured surface of the bark of limbs and current growth,* and in like places after the bark had been bruised but not broken open. Others were made where the surface had been cut away but the cambium left uninjured. Inoculations were also made on current growth in the region of the cambium, by lifting the bark with a knife and inserting the spores, and in the xylem by making a slanting cut or by removing a portion of the wood. The same method of procedure was followed in making inoculations on older limbs except that a greater amount of wood was removed. The cuts were made to extend thru a definite number of annual rings from one to five below the *By current growth is meant growth which occurred during the season In which the inoculations were made. Wood which matured the previous jrear in called one-year-old wood. ASCOSPORE INOCUIJVTIONS </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui 12 8 onnoi-e e o&gt; « * o n c u) e © ej te OO NQOOlOOtC © i-I ' N rt *« ** i-n *&lt; •« oo t- w « v s.8 11 OO «tAlAC4 00O *f Ol •*«- M c-. 8| ■*- &amp;* ■ o %&gt; 7. OS Nl-ltOXU) O — w NI* WQQCU3 o f* 9) Cl zl -»- If _,^,^_ «««««« « &lt;B sssss mm § § 55555 055555 5 1 8 it it if ****** s * 77'5'9 I 9 I 5 I 9'9'9'9'9 "5 •? j 5 s s 5 5J5555 5 5 it e X inn niiis i i •* s 8 8*'"* "" ££5l5 £5£55£ "° 3. -5 t ■?! ? c « a t Si i I 1 -«-. v. -- - r - - "1 al 3&amp;=^22222 2 ii^ II detggfsgggggJgs* s^ g oaeouuu -M«iiir. a. ii U ii , r i iius linn i i « Sill 1 ■°- o - OJS -°o e -3 - S BB8&amp;S&amp; mill I </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Blister Canker 19 surface in order to note the region in which the most active growth occurred. Branches were cut off leaving stubs 10 to 12 inches long and the cut surface evenly inoculated all over. Branches were also removed according to the most approved methods of pruning and the whole cut surface inoculated. As indicated in table 1 no infection occurred from sprayed inoculations even when the bark was bruised or shaved. Neither did any infection result from inoculations in the region of the cambium on current wood. Twenty-six per cent of the inoculations made in the xylem of current growth were effective. It was noted, however, that infection occurred only in twigs where the deepest cuts had been made. It is evident that the wound reduced the resistance of the branch, since it was noted that this also occurred to some extent on larger limbs. Infection took place more readily where the wounded surface was comparatively large. As shown in the same table the percentage of infections increased with the age of the tissue inoculated from the cam - bium to four-year-old xylem but there was little difference in susceptibility of four and five-year-old xylem. In fact the stub and pruning wound inoculations showed that from the age of four years on, there was little difference in the sus - ceptibility of the wood to infection since infection usually started on stubs and pruning wounds quite evenly on all of the wood four years old and over, while on the younger wood there was a gradual reduction in the number of infections in each successive ring of newer tissue. No infection occurred in the cambium or outside of it except in very thick bark. In a few cases slight indications of infection were found toward the outer portion of the bark where inoculations were made in the trunk and large limbs, but in all cases the progress of the mycelium was so slow that injury from such infections is negligible. In no case was the cambium found to be injured. A number of different varieties were used in the series represented in tables 1, 2, 3, and 4, but the same proportions of inoculations with the four inocula and the different tissues inoculated were maintained in all cases. CONIDIA INOCULATIONS A series of inoculations were made with conidia dupli - cating every feature of the series made with ascospores. Co - nidia recently matured were secured from stromata still pro - tected wholly or in part by the covering of bark. None were taken from stromata bearing ascospores. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. u as J_ oooot- -Hiaiat-oouj &lt;e s&gt; t- 2 u t e ! c ! c : c ? u ; »N»*f;&lt;» n ?. S ■-C, oooow ri^ia'wt^oo oi oo ia kJB COCO* n h la (a rsJ m a *£ k a. ooooce NHuia^a oj nw»Nt*t- oo t- uj 4 „ i. &lt;fei « « « K £O OOOON OOt-WrHO M te V -w «NNN»IP5 V C4 N ,-t | 9 « «1 « a ■*- |^ % | ? I* § « Z- © « i.3 O i- iniaiooo M-i-rt-wt-oo t- « «s 53 g t; i—^^MM OICTIONM ■* CO © ■* OS §S ■«• -r It I iiiii iiiiii i i £££££2; £ £ si S g •"3^ S 3 = 33*3 's'H's's'b's "3 3 '■""s 2 *££u" g « » « « » « a, S* "** *" ,= P P = = 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 3 S -e a. a. cu cup. o.a.o,o.a«a&lt; cu cu i i| IIIIII Nil I I J ! S C 0*8 0. 5 * 8 a. X. !J *J M is if NJJJds \»i oo *» s -S «| B s i asa ads !-3 c X i £ £ - 5 I c "° 5 b N S a •S * ?S : =-2 o B x x x x x o t; o- _- ■ — •* •" •* s-, _g I ammuou -.mw^^w ft, (I g iJifil ill MI I i! &lt; I § it5=^£ lllIll « J a 3 &gt;- j: 5 oooooo u £; .; CO a^BAlie^! ■S'3'3'3'55 £ • h sssiis Him i </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Blister Canker 21 The results tabulated in table 2 substantiate those in table 1 in regard to susceptibility of the various ages of tissue inoc - ulated. The much lower percentage of infections indicates that the conidia are much less virile than the ascospores or that they are more easily inhibited. However, this was to be expected from the results of germination tests made in the laboratory. INFECTED WOOD INOCULATIONS The infected wood was secured by sawing out a section of a limb two to three feet above the external boundary of a well-defined canker. The bark was removed after which the wood was sterilized by being immersed in 95 per cent alcohol and flamed over a Bunsen burner. A sterilized coarse - toothed saw was used to reduce the wood to sawdust which was placed in wide-mouthed bottles and slightly moistened. The results given in table 3 show a slightly higher percent - age of infection than was obtained by conidia. In the case of inoculations in the older tissues the percentage was decidedly higher. This might be due in part to the larger wounds which it was necessary to make in order to insert the sawdust, and in part to the fact that the fungus was already well established in the sawdust. Here again the older wood was found to be much more susceptible than the younger tissues. This infec - tion by means of diseased wood clearly shows the futility of attempting to control canker by cutting away the canker itself, as long as any of the mycelium is left in the tree. PURE CULTURE INOCULATIONS The fungus was transferred from initial cultures to petri dishes containing a layer of media several mm. thick in order to prevent drying out quickly, and allowed to grow until the mycelium covered the surface of the medium in a heavy mat Inoculations were then made by cutting out squares of the medium and inserting them in the incisions made in the tree. The percentage of effective inoculations was considerably higher than when either conidia or infected wood was used but not so high as when ascospores were used. As in the three pre - viously mentioned series, the older tissues proved much more susceptible than those nearer the cambium. No infections occurred in current growth except where the xylem was deeply cut. In no case did the mycelium penetrate uninjured bark even tho the inoculum was placed in direct contact with the bark and covered. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">!2 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 ■ ■a I r- Li ? &lt;' o Sooiaoiaoia Q D . ; c tc r. - h w c: 3 On^nwncqm s - 5 1 JU rj &lt;-4 s bM X ZtflOUSOiAOOOO WNHr-MHOOlMOO « l-t « i-H W N W s. tfOQ 2 iwO * 1^ • V' X 3 S ~ s ooiaoto 'udteMcocdu CH .-t • 1 X . "; - — 4 • 1 1 z--. : h : J ',-ir-j *«^Hp ; ; % j : o ] 4 hi 3 c"5 {seiouious ' — z £ m ■* m &lt;o c* e» w - - — B ciooiflocifloceois C r« ICt « M r&lt; f ifl tC » r. V t* \£} U3 C4 IO t^ r* C~- C4 V U3 04 O O O 00 O 00 9 S — — _^ — — s £OOlOOOiaOlOOIOlflOU3U90U}OU30C jjjiaooooiataoou ri 3 c~ o s = o * "?"?"?*" ® °. ® c </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Blister Canker 23 • ?? •♦i I EC "»NHMH U •«• N rtCJ rH Cl ft d B I 5-5 *3 SiJ» U3 U5 O U5 O •-J •* j:- C»U9N»N ■&lt;C Lg«« N «rH Cl •^ £ * U-a o's§ js ia . e '.' a . i0 . 0 . &lt;=&gt; . iO . u '. 1.1 U»00OHNHC5H •5 4) 1 0) O*j n 5 HHHiHrt "I • ! \ r : : ; : 1-H C- I Mi f ; , I i a, a n I &gt;3 c £©©us©usus©us . M a © s US g i i ! o &gt; OOkOOUJkOC =&gt;«» Mi ■?- •5- HteooH^coe o»t^ ; i I j L i -— ; — e - &gt; 1 x fc. &lt; **&gt; z s^ O "3 . - q 3 c ziaoiooou3u)Oiaou:oiau30 &gt;™c VotaoiAOtookOOOiooiaoiA 2 w — *S co « co o oo o&gt; ia eo m eo c&lt;i co cfl " us g 00 1 t © % 1 - - [ J _. ll &gt; * oo 5 *3 C £ o O O U5 O US O IO O O © © US US O I i i « &gt;3 C JE©C|IO©©©©©US«U5U5©U51OI IS : u-: ° &lt;^ I f i 00 ®^^OU5OUSO»0OOOOU3lrtOl0OOlrtOU3OOO us it - L£ - OQ HOOWOOOOOlflOiOWOifliOiOiOlfiOOlOOOlfl U^W^NeCOJHHCONNMMMNHM^eONHONW us e -^-J. _ _ : - •J III Be ogo IS I 09 j « ,-t ,-1 ri rHrt 1-1 W j TTmT" ■ S I I lilt 1 ' Si i i i i i i i • Ml 2 j I t I i t I i •&lt; 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 The foregoing data clearly indicate that the fungus is a wound parasite and that the older the tissues exposed by wounding the greater is the danger of infection. All wounds are liable to infection, and since wood older than five years is the most susceptible it is especially dangerous to leave large pruning wounds unprotected. It is evident that the disease may be disseminated by means of ascospores and conidia, and by infected particles of wood which may cling to the pruning tools. On account of their greater virility ascospores are perhaps the greatest menace, altho even with the short period of time during which they are viable, conidia offer a great source of infection due to the fact that they are formed in such large quantities over a long period of the growing season. ROOT INOCULATIONS Inoculations were made with ascospores in roots of Jona - than and Ben Davis trees, with the same general results. It was impossible to infect roots near their rapidly growing tips, and one-year-old wood was found to be very resistant. Shal - low roots were always more susceptible than those 12 or more inches below the surface of the soil. However, this was mani - fest by the slow progress of mycelium in deep roots as com - pared with the rate of growth in roots near the surface more than by the number of effective inoculations. The percentage of effective inoculations was much lower in all roots than in the portion of the tree above ground. In the roots 39.4 per cent were effective as compared with 75.27 per cent in the trunk and branches. DETERMINATION AND IDENTIFICATION OF INFECTION In order to determine the number of inoculations which produced infection it was necessary to section and stain the wood and examine it under the microscope. At first the fungus-bearing tissues were killed by the use of formalin and alcohol, corrosive sublimate, and picric acid and corrosive sublimate. The formalin alcohol solution proved the most sat - isfactory since no washing or clearing was necessary before sectioning. An attempt was made to conserve time and labor still more, since there were so many inoculations to be exam - ined, by sectioning the wood without killing. This proved so satisfactory that with the exception of a few which were run thru the celloidin process all the remaining specimens were treated in this way. The sections were cut with a sliding microtome using a very heavy blade. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">Blister Canker 25 The greatest difficulty lay in obtaining a desirable stain. Several were tried with unsatisfactory results. The Pianese stain used by Vaughan 21 was promising but required a long time to stain the hyphae and when this was accomplished the staining of the cells was so dense that the hyphae were ob - scured. At the suggestion of Doctor McCormick the formula was changed as well as the subsequent treatment of the sec - tions with very gratifying results. The modified formula was : The sections were cleared in carbolturpentine, washed in 95 per cent and absolute alcohol and stored in xylol. Mount - ings were in balsam. By this method the cells were stained green and the hyphae a deep pink. Staining required only two to five minutes. By comparing the discoloration of inoculations where mi- croscopic examination revealed the hyphae invading the tis - sues with that made by incisions where no inoculum was in - serted, it was found extremely easy in the majority of cases to recognize infections. Therefore, after more than 200 inocula - tions had been examined to the extreme limits of the invaded tissues, the presence of the characteristic discoloration was taken as an indication of the presence of infection, except in doubtful cases when the microscope was employed. No inoculations were made from these artificial infec- tions.* The fact that characteristic stromata and conidia were produced from infections caused by each of the inocula used was considered ample proof as to the identity of the infec - tions. No ascospores have yet been produced on any of the cankers from artificial infection. While examining inoculations for infection, it was ob- served that in a number of cases the infection extended to all parts of the tree. This aroused a suspicion that the tree might have been infected at some previous time in spite of the pre - cautions taken to select sound trees, especially as several places were found where infection might have occurred, such as frost cracks in the trunk and old pruning wounds. This led to the examination of a large number of trees which showed no visible signs of canker. The results were discour- •Since preparing this manuscript the author haa isolated the causal fungus from some of these artificial infections and made new inoculation* which have produced typical cankers. Malachite green Acid fuchsin- Martius gelb Water (distilled) _ _ Alcohol (95 per cent) _ 0.50 gin. 0.50 gm. 0.02 gm. 150.00 cc. _ 50.00 cc. </seg>
            <seg id="p026">el ika Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. II I | I I I I I 1 I I I II I I I I -1 1 IlMll llllilill 5 bS i : i ! i ! i i i i ! ! i i ; - £°c 8 I I I II i II II I i I 0 Soii« j g u&gt; i i I M I j ! ! MM LLL illlj i_jLiii i i ill! xs «••••• • »i ,. J ■Je =&gt; « I i •8 s I * S^onnNnHNMMioinMnJi j $ a! O £ S3 r-r-f-i -~ •§••••• • . : 0 P I &gt; i • * ••••• • * . . » 3 O C S«OHHOOOOMH»MOM*HHOn 0 i "i 5 g i5 Mil B if Is 3 Z I 5 " SS -lie i ■ i • .. t» L ! • ■ — ~~ ■§••*•• • • I tc C gooOHriOHHMO»»ne»rt ; ea "&gt; i i i i SO r* i i i i "S 1 S 5 E CO £ f 1 = IB ■ B o Z Is - i 1 •*■ a, » i "&amp; — Cl S " ■ C u - SI I r o* * **••* • • • • * M ■ 2 1 2 a 1-t Hi y"5 I :&lt; C O * a s *-■=»• ., . .! 0 C OOOOOrtrH O O O O t-l rH tH C4 i-H « O I n U5 ' E I! O fc. • -t- i </seg>
            <seg id="p027">Blister Canker 27 o » o Oh*i* °« s s° 1 1 ■C o c C u a: a: « iS 0&gt; 5 »i fl O M •+ X ta i t£ a S c o o CiAiAuuiooaoiNine 1 X C 1 ii s o d * C l g 2 |! | e e "5" g SI i5 UO s o C 5 ? ■o*" 5 O*«»o*oioionn»i-r&lt;xf| o « C 1-1 _j &amp; "&amp; " ic ~ »« «J 1° a J9 « io X B S u F o 3 ja w * * # « * ] to ! « CMHMOOiHHVMM«hinT!£! OO -C to 1 « _ ! e c -- -f • 1 si aj - 31 s 1° I" "S ♦• • w I £ G CHHf)OrtlOONNNNiaOlfl&lt;C C4 * C I n i if — rH f &amp;&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 aging in that of 42 apparently sound trees examined, which were from 12 to 16 years old, only 3 were free from the fungus. In a number of cases infection was traced to cracks and other wounds in the trunk, several to pruning and other wounds in the limbs and a smaller number to injury to the roots near the surface of the ground. This led to omitting from the data any infection which could not be followed from the inoculation to the end of infec - tions except in a few cases specifically mentioned later, such as stub inoculations and inoculations in four trees which had been root pruned. (ilM)WTH OK MYCUMUM IN THK WOOD INOCULATION IN TISSUES OK DIFFERENT AGES The growth of the mycelium within the tree varies with the age and condition of the wood. In tissues which are still active the hyphae are confined largely to the tracheal vessels and the medullary ray cells, altho the adjacent sclerenchyma cells are slowly invaded as the tissue dies. The hyphae ad - vance rapidly along the tracheae passing from one to the other and to adjacent cells thru the pits in the cell walls. This ex - plains why recent infections appear as long brownish-black threads in the wood. The tracheae offer little resistance to progress of the fungus lengthwise of the branch, but lateral progress thru the medullary ray cells and the adjacent scle - renchyma is very slow. The most rapid progress occurs in that part of the annual growth made early in the spring when the tracheal vessels are relatively large and abundant. Here many of the parallel tracheae communicate thru pits so that the progress laterally is also relatively rapid. The annual ring of growth on either side is protected from invasion to some extent by the barrier of small, thick-walled, nonpitted wood cells which form late in the season's growth. Tracheae in this region are fewer and somewhat smaller. However, the regions of the different an - nual growths communicate by means of the medullary rays and thru these are finally invaded. As the fungus goes deeper into the branch each succeeding year's growth up to four-year - old wood is found more susceptible. However, from here on there is practically no difference in the susceptibility of the tissue of different ages altho there is the same relative rate of progress in the different cells. This difference in suscepti - bility of tissues of different ages which varies in different varieties and individual trees of the same variety is no doubt </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Blister Canker 29 due to the presence of protoplasm in the still active tissues. This is shown by the fact that in the laboratory the one-year - old xylem of wood cylinders in which the protoplasm had been killed was invaded as readily as the old heartwood, but was not invaded in cylinders where the protoplasm was not killed. As shown by the data in table 5, while infection occurs in xylem of all ages the rate of growth is very slow in the outer annual rings of growth, as compared with the older tissues. Infections also took place from the inoculations in the region of the cambium, but examination showed that the infection was in the xylem lying just beneath. Where the strands were found just beneath the cambium an extra number of small wood cells were found between the infection and the cambium. In many cases where the infection was in small limbs this caused a distinct ridge in the bark which extended as far as the end of the diseased streak. These inoculations were made in May, 1915, and exam - ined in November, 1916. The time which had elapsed was equal to almost two growing seasons. In determining the amount of growth made by the myce - lium, microscopic examinations were made as in the case of identifying infections. In fact many of the inoculations served the same purpose. At first sections were made and examined every inch above and below the inoculation until no discolored strands showed in the tissues. It was soon found that the hyphae could be found easily until the region within two to three inches of the end of the brown strands was reached where they became very few and were found only in the tracheae. In the majority of cases, however, on close ex - amination hyphae were found within a few mm. of the end of the discolored areas. Accordingly in measuring the distance covered by the hyphae the end of the discoloration was taken as the limit of infection. Radially hyphae were nearly always found to extend to within at least one or two cells of the mar - gin of the discolored area except in the case of the medullary rays where the distance was sometimes greater. In the long axis of the branches the active tissues are killed one to three or even more inches ahead of the invading hyphae. The whitish dry spots may often be seen in cross section with the naked eye. The killed area is readily determined by stain - ing and by plasmolysis tests. In using the Pianese stain it was found that the dead cells stained much less readily than those which were still active. For this reason the cells of the infected sections were much lighter in color or were only </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui, lyeurusKa Agricultural tJxp. Station, Research Bw 12 II ! i Oo5 Jjjinus i o out j m ise ! cl . ais sss j 5 s- I - *s I s t L I I H « « B -fc_ jg 1 . = | 1|I I-M -| 12 OUJ | S ? fc.. § . &amp;U OSS ! 5 - » W- : • ? ■a w. 8 L [ L 1 1 M 111 Jo» I s .. s o- j s z * &gt;• I r — | — 1 I " i|! loo i s I S 4fl^| a i ~| - 53 3 5 Ig !§£ 5 : ooo! SS ooo 5 t- § \&lt; I ■ 0=^ a" m " " j •■•* •» «•-'» * S« ■&lt;■ s &gt; * 111 Jjo^u, 5 ooo § oo* S | 5 - .= * * ' c • =s ? e .« « _ ° »- oc © 5s- a 100 " o o«oo rt j;3 2*x«i, «i ;«» -• o i oioo ih oeu ■-T ••lorn ■*' | oo ooo « . «a i £ ? = &gt; = 5 B «- O M Dip « • !r o t- :« _giooio ie eieo io ©oo ec t- I oux B»«u tc oioo in I ©oo g _ _C i in in — i i Ml 5a 111 '&gt; I ! ! 1 :i\ I i I I !l 1 I &lt; h h &lt; 2 5, </seg>
            <seg id="p031">Blister Canker 31 c t- g^-t-to lo eioi-i »l « «' n I I t- lo in o o ei ci i-i ei Lc®® Si5 I - | u E- &lt; (•I! i i i*= X © © 10 os° £ "2 in i o loin ; © ©in ; eg s . SIS s^" i - «• • ii\ » &amp; s i_l_ l 2 [ "e *S-5ScS « =&gt; © « 3 = — ,2"^°. i °1 lo . l °. i "*. u&gt; . ia . i ©. § !1l l l _ ! ° 035 i "*. t= &gt;. ta . ' *\ m© i t-; 5§ . SIS S-^ i S" 5 ! S S" i 8 « -^ ! L l_! L * I* ! : | i •§ 00 " J«C g i © US g W JigJ god-* ; w ei« ; «5 ! oi QJ I m *^S 8 9 I « "" " 1 * r- g N **C g P5 « t- P o 3 — -5 ® °, *"? co ® "^ ° °° ©©© «© rw :;i Joioo oo oicio w i in in to • - i| j! a i be J5 m i O !• g &gt; . 5- </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 lightly stained while the adjoining cells always took on a deep stain. By employing this stain it was found that unstained or lightly stained spots appeared in sections made beyond the actual discoloration in the branches and that these spots cor - responded in position with the area occupied by the fungus in infected sections. The cells in such spots did not respond when treated suc - cessively with 20 per cent cane sugar and distilled water. However, the surrounding cells did not always respond sat - isfactorily but there was sufficient response to show the pres - ence of living protoplasm in the majority of cases. It was noted that in general the mycelium grows more rapidly in a downward than in an upward direction. This is especially true in inoculations on the smaller limbs, and on the larger limbs where a great deal of growth has been made. In the larger limbs where the hyphae have proceeded only a short distance the average growth is as great in one direction as another. The difference in growth in smaller limbs is per - haps due to the fact that the ascending hyphae are constantly encountering younger wood while the descending hyphae en - counter older wood. This theory is upheld by the fact that in the roots the greatest growth is toward the trunk. INOCULATIONS IN STUBS In the stub inoculations (those which were made by cutting off a branch 10 to 12 inches above its base and placing the in - oculum over the entire cut surface), the relative amount of growth in tissues of different ages as indicated in table 6 cor - responds very closely with the data given in table 5. In stub inoculations, however, the growth is much more rapid owing to the death of the tissues, caused by removing the foliage. Almost as rapid growth was secured by keeping the foliage removed from branches which had been inoculated. In table 6 the number of rings of annual growth free from infection is given. This shows the radial distribution of the mycelium 5 and 10 inches from the point of inoculation. It was impossi - ble to show the longitudinal distribution owing to the fact that the mycelium had entered the trunk of the trees. Very few conspicuous cankers were produced by inocula - tions where the limbs were not injured in some way. In the stub inoculations, the first infection usually occurred close to the center of the wound and the mycelium proceeded rapidly toward the trunk. The newer wood and finally the bark was invaded beginning at the end of the stub and extending toward </seg>
            <seg id="p033">Blister Canker 33 the trunk. When the cankered area reached the trunk there was no further external evidence of growth until the mycelium had invaded the outer rings of wood in the trunk when the cankered area was again enlarged. INOCULATIONS IN TREKS OF DIFFERENT AGES A number of inoculations were made in young trees of dif - ferent ages to ascertain if susceptibility to attack by blister canker was in any way associated with the age of the trees. Trees of several varieties ranging from one to four years of age at the time of inoculation were used. The data in table 7 indicate that, as in the case of inoculations in limbs of mature trees, the age of the wood inoculated is a more important fac - tor than the age of the tree. ROOT INOCUI.ATIONS Inoculations with nscospores were made in the roots of Ben Davis and Jonathan trees. The roots were uncovered, and inoculated in the manner already described. Wires were attached which would reach above the surface of the ground and zinc labels attached. The soil was then replaced. The data in table 8 show the results of these inoculations. The mycelium travels much slower thru the roots than thru the upper portion of the tree. That this is not alto - gether due to the cellular structure is shown by the fact that in a number of the roots examined the tracheae are much more numerous and are larger than in the trunk and limbs. How - ever, pits in the cell walls of the roots examined were not so numerous as in the cell walls of tissues in the branches. That cellular structure does modify the rate of growth to some ex - tent is shown by the fact that the mycelium passes very slowly and with difficulty thru the region of the crown of the tree where the cells are greatly distorted and compressed. It was noted that this was true whether the infection came from the branches or the roots. No doubt the growth in the roots is retarded to some extent on account of lack of oxygen. That this must be true is shown by the slower growth of mycelium made in roots situated rather deep in the soil, while in those at or near the surface the growth was found to be almost as rapid as in the trunk and branches. Growth may also be re - tarded by the abundance of sap in the roots. The severing of a root at or just beyond the inoculation caused the growth of mycelium to be much more rapid, and as will be shown later the checking of absorption of water by increasing the osmotic </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 pressure of the solution surrounding the roots rendered them very susceptible indeed. Table 8 shows that the older tissues are the most suscep- tible to infection. A number of inoculations were also made in roots of young trees in jars. It was found that one-year-old roots became infected with difficulty and then only when near the surface of the soil. In such infections the growth of the mycelium was very slow. Mycelial growth in the region of the crown of the tree progressed more rapidly in young than TABLE 8 — Rate of growth of mycelium above and below inoculations in roots Inoculated in Xyleni Inoculated at Cambium VAIUKTY Helow Above low Inches Inches Inches Inches 24.0 22.0 31.5 26.0 21.5 20.0 18.5 24.5 37.0 25.5 14.0 12.5 48.5 51.0 8.0 11.0 15.5 37.5 46.5 17.0 42.0 31.5 7.5 6.5 Ben Davis _ I 58.5 29.0 12.5 10.0 3.0 11.0 1.5 2.0 3.0 I.I 2.0 2.0 I.I 3.0 2.0 2.5 4.0 1.5 1.5 1.0 14.0 13.5 11.5 16.0 21.0 20.5 14.0 10.5 11.0 15.0 I _ Average | 23.39 21.62 10.15 10.77 f 2.0 2.5 2.0 3.0 3.0 3.0 2.0 3.5 :t.5 6.5 3.0 I.I 1.1 5.0 1.5 1.5 18.0 26.5 I.I 5.0 21.0 16.0 1.0 1.5 42.5 36.0 3.5 2.0 Jonathan ._ _ 2.0 4.0 3.0 3.0 10.5 11.5 2.5 2 5 ti.o 7.0 2.;, 1.0 x.5 12.0 1.5 1.0 3.0 1.5 I I 5.5 4.5 I 10.0 6.5 | _ 14.0 7.5 i I _ Average I 10.20 10.00 2.36 2.50 .\b&lt;&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Blister Canker 35 in old trees. In young trees the cells in this region are not so distorted and compressed as in mature trees. SKASOXAI, SISCKITHHMTY An attempt was made to determine at what season of the year trees are most susceptible to infection. Inoculations were made in two-year-old trees and in branches of mature trees, the branches ranging from one-half to one inch in diameter. The inoculations were made at about the same date in May, June, July, and August, respectively. All were examined at the same time the following winter. The data secured (table 9) are rather contradictory in that inoculations made in May in young trees made slightly less total growth than similar inocu- Table 9 — Comparison of rate of growth of mycelium from inoculations made at different seasons of the year DATE 1NOCULATKD Two- Year-Old Trees Above Below one- Inch Wood of Mature Trees Above Below May 20-25 Inches , Inches 4.0 12.5 2.0 8.5 5.0 11.5 3.0 | 7.5 3.0 7.5 1.5 3.5 2.5 4.0 2.5 7.0 2.0 | 4.5 2.5 7.5 _. j Inches Inches 8.5 19.0 8.0 20.5 3.0 7.0 12.0 13.5 7.0 11.0 5.5 9.5 11.0 21.5 16.0 14.0 10.5 23.5 5.0 9.5 18.0 41.0 Average 2.80 7.40 9.50 17.27 June 22-28 12.0 15.0 12.0 12.5 6.5 8.5 2.0 | 6.5 2.5 | 5.5 1.5 5.0 2.5 4.0 2.0 6.5 2.0 2.5 2.5 5.0 1.5 2.5 10.0 15.0 10.0 20.0 23.5 28.0 12.0 18.0 21.0 19.0 12.0 14.0 7.0 8.5 13.0 15.0 10.0 10.0 10.0 ! 12.0 8.0 6.0 6.0 14.0 I Average - - 4.27 6.68 11.87 14.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 Table 9 — (Continued) — Comparison of rate of growth of mycelium from inoculations made at different seasons of the year Two- Year-Old Tree. W ,° e ° d ,, "' PATK INOCUI-ATEP Above lN-lnw Above Below Inches Inches Inches Inches 1.5 1.5 9.0 14.0 9.0 4.5 7.0 7.5 11.0 1.0 9.0 3.0 2.5 3.5 6.0 1.5 3.(1 4.5 14.0 19.5 1.0 4.5 12.5 15.0 Au«. 23-28 7.(1 8.(1 12.0 18.0 2.5 fi.O 12.0 14.0 4.(1 6.0 6.0 18.0 3.5 5.5 5.(1 10.0 4.(1 7.0 4.5 12.0 1.5 2.(1 12.0 14.0 30.0 i 1.0 1.5 12.0 Average I 4.25 5.08 8.79 14.42 lations made in June. The average growth of June inocula - tions in branches of mature trees was no greater than that of July inoculations. The July inoculations in young trees aver - aged less growth than the August inoculations. Ben Davis trees of equal size and vigor were used in both series. The writer is unable to explain the much more rapid growth from inoculations made in late summer. It could not have been be - cause the spores were more virile late in the summer since half of the inoculations in each case were made with pure culture. Hence the trees must have been more susceptible at that time. However, if this is true, it does not explain why the late inocu - lations made such a phenomenal growth compared to the infec - tions which had the whole season in which to grow. uly 15-20. i . .) 1.5 1.0 2.11 4.5 2.0 4.0 1.0 6.5 2.0 1.0 2.5 12.0 3.0 6.0 4.0 8.0 3.5 8.0 6.5 2.5 9.0 14.0 5.5 16.0 14.0 5.5 14.0 11.0 4.0 ] 24.5 18.0 11.U 6.5 30.0 13. 0 24.0 25.0 6.0 16.0 6.5 7.5 31.0 21.0 I ! average _ 3.09 5.23 12.04 16.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Blister Canker 37 During the winter of 1916-1917 a number of two-year-old trees were planted in large jars in the greenhouse. A group of 10 were inoculated just as soon as set, 10 more four weeks later just as the buds were swelling, and an equal number as soon as the trees were in full leaf, which was about five weeks after the second series. They were examined fourteen weeks after the first inoculations were made. The average growth in the first series was 18.75 inches above and 20.75 inches below the inoculations, or a total of 49.5 inches. This was an average of slightly over 3.5 inches per week. The sec - ond series made an average growth of 8.2 inches above and 9.5 inches below, or a total average of 17.7 inches. This was an average of 1.77 inches per week. The third series made when the trees were in full leaf showed an average growth of 1.37 inches above and 1.45 inches below, or a total average of 2.82 inches. This was an average of 0.56 inch per week. The data thus far indicate that the mycelium makes its most rapid progress during the season when the tree is making little growth. Whether the slow growth is due to the retarding influence of an abundance of water and a lack of air or whether rapid growth is due to the presence in the tissues of stored food materials, the writer has been unable to deter - mine. EFFECT OF SOU, MOISTURE ON HUSt'EPTIBIIJTY An effort was made to ascertain the relation of the amount of moisture in the soil to susceptibility to blister canker. Oil barrels were secured and sawed thru half way between the heads. Each end made a large tub. The oil was burned out and the tubs set in the ground so that only about three inches of the top remained above the surface. The trees were planted in soil in these tubs which were covered with a flat cone of rubberoid roofing to exclude rain. Water was prevented from running in at the hole around the tree trunk by a shield of potter's clay. In one series the soil was kept saturated, in another the water content of the soil was kept at the optimum for normal growth, while in the third only enough water was supplied to keep the trees from dying. In the saturated series all of the trees soon died so that no data could be secured. The data from the other series are given in table 10. There was considerable variation in the individual trees of the same series, and in several cases trees with an optimum </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 | ft •*! - '-■ ° ■- ; jgiooio o ouso 1-1 •7 "S ■♦oem «e x '■ "3S 2 c-t e ooo ooioie i-t rH O O c. .- Cl l\i"&gt;.°. " ? 5|fc 8 to t- 3 oeu « cjO« «IO^ ■» gnn 2 w I = ;u» e oooS i ooo - I c !f I 82S C-? ct a ;U3 o t- I- t- m m I OIOU 1C UIISU) H ■* t- d ■* NIOiH « &lt; 5 a i- c NNH N i-i «* r-i JM i- OOHOi si WOO ifl LAOOr-t m B m SB," 0) « r - i«8 g 0 . - t- usiaiA to in t^ « in J .T- ? ? ?^ — — \\ — 0) o o 9) «■ S 0 V V S ¥ i Si iS S •ss « 5 3 a c c .- = ZZ | S &lt; f- fc is - &gt; - I h~ &lt; • ls_ _ «* &gt; » o © © n &lt; s I? ;|l I |«-»-§ Big g pNMWM s|° 2a. v « r- •«8 £ S*®"? « H l&lt; &lt; TJ </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Blister Canker 39 | OJj- | ■««»* « «©«• wmW „•! n^n „• r- ■o"o * IS ® " § g alt I S* 0000 " "S" S* " ""- - • U.R ■o II i III H fii.i SK 3 1 3 - !&gt; c 3 -5 © .— " ■Z ill » jH^"? « O . O . U &gt; S OOB So 0.0.0 § to t Jvi "-I S ' OQ u o^ - « a 3o&lt;— oj « o o t- | « JSo," S!5^"?^ ® "»*"» ® »«»&lt;=&gt; « 0100 « •w. n go ; "S -«S S = ®^ "» Ol °« &lt;=&gt; iOO : O OU5O fe3 ! J : i si I I 9 i u ■" T &gt; Z. &gt; &gt;&gt;■" . S H___&lt;j_A_JL&lt;.j H &lt;i w l_4 1 | 5*. ■=■ I 1 SI III a n s i If -- L ac X &gt; VOiA ! ill I |o««» o o te us t- rH 00 W t- eo j -^ eo j o jo o n i ■* ei i ; o in in o o coon | ei t~ IDIOO mom ei ih *-i inm o — -^ n o o m CO CO CO r- M CO n in _ : IO om ; t- ■♦&gt;-&lt;; e« O lain j o « r* \ *i o o o m ■: « 1H •» ffi o mom o </seg>
            <seg id="p040">brasi igrtcul \ural Exp. Stati on, Research Bui. . 2 s H ill as? IK •«S 1 "Sooood a co ta ■ uo t- oe ■• io W OUO i- O O O uieo ■* ej co co | &gt; o 3 "S ■* oo ■* 1 r •r •* ci co cocom CO 00 | ! - ■2 ■ 'O'o • Sao - i. - - c y U5 00 00 = — — - n laoo oo t' d CO CO W ri coco n icon - o o CO H-4— - § &gt; BHHrl pi e co ie i oiau) co CO NNM ci r4 e us ci s II ii o f e O OOlfl U3 IO WOO 03 I I I I 111 i i i |_ i "5- ft 5 t- c o o n t^ io a H CO ooo co uioa CO -*-. £ -»*. «. 33 v | VU3OU3 0 « o CO "^^"^ O «'«» to co ousifl co oiao ■w CO ci CO W M CO o CO £ 1 i 1 5 o i ■ sotao x — , — I « © so oo ia CO OOO CO U2 O O 00 SO 00 t^ NNN — — 04 c &gt; 0) 4O US kA ~ *— r-» » o 00 U51O ; O ■* CO C« : CO P4 :__ o ooo ie loo o aoteio &lt;e hnn Hrtri i^ — CO 00 P4 M a 2 I I 1 M 1 9 i | 1-1 : S u &gt; &lt;■ a &lt; I </seg>
            <seg id="p041">Blister Canker 41 so K H h if! «a.- ««S Q3£ 1 1®-?® m ! n 00 "^OO 00 I I I i i i i i i i i i i 9 ■ -&lt; 5 M | ill!! : ! I ! I Mill II I ' Mill 1 i a ill i « «&gt; as£ i i i OS i ! % i !&lt;=» ; • « I « p I O » O OlfiO 00 » a i ol o in o o i-j d i-Jciei in' •- 1 1 ! ■, m o n | iioeo us c?^"? °o •j y co eo ■*• eo eo^i-i n « 5 | g ! a a x .•o'o 2a,- - : : — : "I I I a, k e « us i rs &gt; tiooe us U^ &lt; S9 06 mow ; us go ■§ c-s m ■» to hmio! n iHusteici m | c 3 &amp; i»5 I i : i I I i I mi! e 1 • It ■ • ■ ; ■ • ■ I : I i : «. « &gt; o ! * S ° n l| U3U3O 0 -** i ® •* j lOOt-ION O jo'vt^mi U9 MNM M o&gt; C&gt; 00 00 "«■ «■&gt; I = ■3 il •- a i! Li ! : j 1 ! I M I 1 e&lt; ' -&lt;i &lt;: a &lt; ■ r , 5 * a O o &gt; n I I </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 supply of water proved more susceptible than those with too little water. In the majority of instances, however, there was less fungous growth in the trees which received the proper supply of moisture. The average of all the inoculations in the two series shows a greater growth in the trees lacking water. When the inoculations were examined the amount of terminal growth made by the trees was measured. The average growth was 16.5 inches per tree for the optimum series and 4.35 inches for the dry series. This would indicate that conditions which contribute to the vigor of the tree tend to inhibit fungous growth. A number of water sprouts which had made a growth of over three feet in one season were removed and sections 12 inches long inoculated and placed in closed cylinders. An equal number of one-year-old branches of terminal growth which had made a growth of only 12 to 14 inches were inocu - lated in a like manner. Fungous growth was much more rapid in the water sprouts than in the terminal growth. This may have been because the tracheae in the former were very large and numerous. KKLATIOX OF A\ All, A I ILK MTKIKXTS TO SISCKITIBILITY To determine the effect of different concentrations of min - eral nutrients and of depriving the trees of certain elements, trees were planted in pure river sand and supplied with a nu - trient solution. The complete nutrient solution was used at a concentration of 0.1 per cent, 0.2 per cent, 0.4 per cent and 0.6 per cent, respectively. Other groups of trees were sup - plied with the complete nutrient solution minus nitrogen, po - tassium, phosphorus, magnesium, and calcium. These solu - tions with one element lacking were used at a concentration of 0.2 per cent. The solution was administered at the bottom of the jars thru a rubber tube attached to a smaller jar. The bottoms of the feeding jar and the one containing the tree were on the same plane so that the height of the liquid in the feeding jar would indicate the height of the water table in the other jar. A fine screen was placed over the opening on the inside of the large jar to keep the hose from being clogged. Two inches of coarse gravel was first placed in the bottom of the jar which was then filled to within two inches of the top with river sand. The tree was put in place as the jar was filled. Two inches of clean gravel was placed over the sand and the whole cov- </seg>
            <seg id="p043">Blister Canker 43 ered with rubberoid roofing as in the case of the tubs already mentioned, to prevent evaporation and a consequent concen - tration of the nutrient solution. A record was kept of the amount of solution used by each tree and the amount of growth made. Table 11 shows the relative amount of fungous growth for trees in each solution compared with the amount in trees which were inoculated at the same time and set in soil. The least infection was found in trees set in soil. These trees made a much more satisfactory growth than any of the trees supplied with nutrient solutions. Of the trees supplied with nutrient solutions those receiving a 0.2 per cent complete solution made the most satisfactory growth and showed the least infection. Trees grown in solutions of higher concentra - tion (0.4 per cent and 0.6 per cent) were badly infected and made little growth. The osmotic pressure of the 0.6 per cent solution was so great that it was impossible for the trees to obtain sufficient water to maintain growth. All but one of the trees lost their leaves and were practically dead above and below inocula - tions. The same conditions obtained, but to a lesser degree, for the trees in 0.4 per cent solution. The trees in 0.1 per cent solution made little growth but, except for a stunted appear - ance, remained apparently healthy. They were more heavily infected than the trees in soil or those receiving the 0.2 per cent solution. There was so much variation in the amount of infection and such a difference in the amount of growth made by the individual trees that no reliable conclusions can be drawn. All of the trees made some but in no case a satisfactory growth. Even the trees with no nitrogen made considerable leaf growth altho there was practically no root growth. The only definite statement which can be made is that the greatest infection was always found in trees which had made the least growth. The supply hose in one of the jars became clogged. This was not noticed until several days later when the feeding jars were being replenished. It was noticed that none of the solu - tion in this jar had been used, and that the leaves of the tree were wilting. The obstruction was removed but the tree did not recover. The hose in three other jars were then stopped for five days with like results. All of these trees (indicated in table 11 by *) were as badly infected as those grown in the solutions of high concentration. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">m Agricuh !^ttra/ i Sfahi :, Researc) i Bwi. 1 so S I 1 o a 1 o 00 U-S 00 M o to j i j uj'w e I •&amp; s s" • _ 5 i i ~i ■ ! ia in m o oo ■» I L&lt; in oo I • I j iiai-in o «rH | c* HH ri| I MM M i ■ • ta \ m • • oui |m ota I n | : oo to L_l L_L" I j ; uus o i uj« o |HN N i i o o o ; low co : n« e* I t i to to N j oo i «■» ■■r. I ; &gt; o &lt; i 5 :«« w eo n 5" |J — gj. M ooool eeuri B &gt; o&lt;Oi-i ci| osood ai ""5 MHHbI HHrt rt «Z ■l mm c = pa it • CO t- Z - ooo eo otaOiH h*o ooot^od •* ait^ o 5 Zx s n i o I m ■• I r- « • oiooh o oo to ooom yiHtecici t- W M w hohV BjfH H'rl TIM iH nnNN 4- I i I I a In i i- II • 0) o oo m oooto oooo gWfHri 00 OS 00 OS 00 (DON te © 0 i g a 2 ! j : i ! i i i a I « i ■ I d 1 • i « i &amp; I I i a I I o 1 "5. I 6 | I IV &gt; I I I I o I I O I j | ! I m o - I I I I i &gt; k - i i "a ! . i li a » a 1° o ill i li \ »i \ li. 1? J Us 5 I </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Blister Canker 45 g c HO .8 4 Jj as V to C I* !l i i HO 1 i-H a J | O 2 a *" ♦* m a* ; &gt; :OO O &lt; S \ \ eoioo i-i ■«— ■a •h &gt; «OOU3 i-c c M x Z « 2 S I * 3 - i % * a i z 2 g i I H I 3« J I* ? o k ■a M M e I s ; ® * irt OS t- • o 109 10 i 00 r^ ei i : ] ■-. ; r — T Gi **&gt; Ci - - - - 00 Ci rH cj si « n o e« ! E i I i I I 1 El IS £ u &lt; I e r-^ &lt;e j e \iataia - i s - o : IOU3 ul IhIO » i o o o &lt;o t-INN CQ o o o » 03 i-H ai oi rH C^ 5 i s ; II i s i II ! J; i o &lt; i o 000 i OS t-^ 00 j • O IAU3 IO -r = t-^ CO &lt;-l I 00 is 00 ■* i-i O i-&lt; 1-1 N M W O OOOO i-ci &lt;c ■«■ MClr-l N TT I I s ! I I h IJ \ £i j - - M !• : O i t-^ : ui i -- WO ; Cl «^« ! « » : a&lt;^t i SS o . ■■ JZrl $u in c 10 «s c J 1" OS CJ !oo ~ 0 - £ z A? .- a CSOO^H o^ I °C HN ' , i&amp; ! 11 I fl i He 2 i ! s:= ° j 1$ I ? T -w 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 Later, trees were planted in jars of soil and watered from the top. Four grams of nitrogen, potassium, phosphorus, cal - cium and magnesium, respectively, were added in a 0.2 per cent solution weekly to a series of four jars each. The trees were inoculated as soon as they were in full leaf. They were examined ten weeks later but no appreciable difference could be found in the amount of infection. The trees which received nitrogen made a slightly faster growth, but there was no dif - ference in amount of growth made by the others. In the spring of 1915 two fourteen-year-old Ben Davis and two Jonathan trees of the same age were inoculated. A trench four feet deep was dug around each tree, close enough to re - move approximately one-third of the feeding roots. The inner wall was lined with tar paper to prevent a rapid growth of roots out into the soft wet soil with which the ditches were filled. The trees made very little growth but each bore a crop of undersized fruit. The leaves turned yellow and fell long before the surrounding trees shed their leaves. In 1916 both Jonathan trees bore a light crop but made little growth. One of the Ben Davis trees did not bear any fruit and the other only a few small apples. The leaves appeared yellow tmd wilted thruout the season. Several characteristic cankers were formed. When the inoculations were examined it was found that all of the heartwood and all of the sapwood except the two outer rings in the Ben Davis trees was infected, and in many instances all of the wood was infected, so that no data could be secured on the amount of fungous growth except to note the amount of wood still intact. The Jonathan trees were likewise found to be so badly infected that few reliable data could be secured. However, the fungus had made much slower lateral progress than in the Ben Davis trees as shown by sectioning the wood of the trunk and limbs. The comparative amount of infection is shown in plates XIV and XV. VARIOTAL SUSCEPTIBILITY A great deal of variation is shown in the susceptibility of different varieties of apples to blister canker. There is also considerable variation within each variety. The data given in table 12 while not conclusive give a fairly reliable indica - tion of the comparative susceptibility of the different varieties. These data do not agree in all cases with field observations. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">Blister Canker 47 Field observations indicate that varieties such as Missouri, Janet, and Maiden Blush are comparatively less susceptible than conclusions drawn from table 12 would indicate. In the main, however, field observations and inoculation data corre - spond quite closely. The inoculations in this series were all made in the heartwood during the same week and were exam - ined at the same time. It was noted in examining young trees which had been inoculated that when the varieties were on their own roots the susceptibility of the roots corresponded to that of the tops, but in budded trees where all of the roots had come from the seedling stock the roots showed all degrees of susceptibility ranging from great resistance to great susceptibility. There wa^ less difference in the percentage of inoculations which proved effective in the different varieties than in the comparative amount of growth made by the effective inocula - tions. The difference was most noticeable where inoculations were made in active xylem. The percentage of effective inocu - lations was high in all varieties where the inoculations were made in the heartwood. On account of having a very limited number of trees of many of the different varieties it was im - possible to make enough inoculations to furnish satisfactory data on this phase of the subject. According to the data given above and field observations the varieties are tentatively grouped as follows : Susceptibility may and no doubt does vary in different localities and under different conditions as does susceptibility to apple scab and apple blotch (Cooper 5 ) . Variation in suscep- Very Resistant Moderately Moderately Resistant Susceptible Very Susceptible Oldenburg Wealthy Jonathan York Winesap Willow Twig Arkansas Rome Beauty Arkansas Black Maiden Blush Janet Champion Minkler Grimes Fameuse (Snow) Missouri Stayman Winesap Northern Spy Virginia Beauty Chicago Wolf River Yates Northwest King David Greening Walbridge Delicious Ben Davis Gano Yellow Transparent </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 I INS* © £ h c2S22 I I i El 5S9H 10 o m o m N XNNH c — wj uw W* w •O MMMM ro c^ *&gt;•? *fe \ r, * I a. n o « O » 0) IO *£ 5-S •S"&amp; 5 II S2^idSiS2g|j: "^^-'cid^w* j» si • s ; :M OOCJOOlfiOOOO jo * 5 a "* "* ™ °* " * * °* "" i" inoooort^^ nonis i !te — - «iw tat . . yj w'j CJ « II II s M U3 OlO OOOlOO OOOO 00 U«M«HONC1 00 WMNMBNNNNMO^ ~ i-H rH *1 n CO c t -1 x I | &lt; r- I -- &lt; » *•&gt; &amp; s ** « &lt; &gt; i^_ p 8 . * s_ ! I II Mo " I I | I i i ir ~ ■&gt;■•■■ , I I I I I I I I I** "g « „ • Nil TTTTTTT" I OD IS *"»»«"» P OOUSO I ! S V.V A g«on»M Li teodr-ioi- . BO '• * 33 : t» '• tn o j3&lt;=&gt; «woowoioia i «© o o o w 10 o io o o o j tS •a £ 2 t- i^_ &lt;J O r-t Hri&lt;H ■o i S e O Z j-OOOOiaoOOU3O«c OOO U 3 § N '*'-&lt;Ni-ir-! 1 H N "MO&lt;Jci •«•••■ 5 •« • </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Blister Canker 49 :Js . m £ «• "5 •• t- | *5 &gt; ~ ~ ~ ! tr- * £ o =&gt; i "» © "O c U3 USOIfl O OU3U3OOO O10 i N -k&gt; .5? &gt; ! m O ■* » n i « io us *■ us »n«t«« ■«• » I •» e -S * I . ih ' . : "«~,'C • 5 t- o o jo ® 8 — &gt; si °, ® "°, 'I °. "^ "? "? ® ® "? * °. *~ •• In g,^ N n "&gt;* « ■«■««■*«« «^;n hS iS o i&gt;o !o m C fl I ) o o us !t» usotoe ! us o us o oo S"*fci 0 1 Uri«ri«gi «Oi-iloO rHOOioioit^ Bt^pi B fc"-^ &gt; CQM^»fHrHiHr-( CflWSN IAC4HH ! M H«|H iH *&gt; I 1| ~ l , |_ . ■ | S O J l« ! t- io io r- ° £&gt;_^ooirtooo iouj | 1a oiAoia : us uoto to S&gt;"S si u»«'ooui «' ooo M t-^-»««J : h t-ineaio " .Dnn r&lt; h eqe«|») mhih ;ih hmh h -H 3 "^ co *"? "^ "^ "^ ua o o ia o -w oiaio o £. Z — - FH M«H C4 r-t M r-» r^ i-i C4fH *-t 3| | bt 1 ; z " — , ' N OU3 0 ! IO OOlfliQia t- OiaOrH -a A u to oo io io -j&gt; (ieuici » ■«■ io &lt;o oo oi » oo io oi 5 5 &lt; ° i-ICOr-Mi-H-l r&lt; O " : ! "a."^ « * £ • • i « ° §• J I IO OO I IO IOOIOIO ; &lt;O IO1O US OS o 1 e«ria io usoo I t-i o»»io ; ■-! mm m ~* I s is l« I- l» * ■"S ji .coooomir^ ■«•«!« oeoioio;.-! «eo co e» r p — I r K S . &gt; S il« i«»i MO r» I© j^oooiw oio;c»! ooooio oo«h e : «,5 ! ~~ I" ; J3 — • &gt; S S " * 2? ta it- i- S'-S " 5 JOOO i;O IO © ! W ( ©OlOOiiQO USOO H Y-fe. i i ! 'i ' I a b i « \ \ \i\ I §j . § &amp; </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 1% § 111 * i ij 1 1 : i-« ! * 2 I * §1 ! I'l 1 «i « ■ ii | S.K g 11 - a &amp; w - CQ &gt; it 3 £ : £« ! us o o o • S i o o &gt; ; o oo e i S» i«i uses «' •&lt; S** | N »« « i 5 le o J3 j- O ] O OO O • gN i« t-^rH oi B a** ; i- nn n '_ [_ • S I o o : j-o ■ o oo is &lt; £ *" ; &gt;-i n» n ; £ © o _£ us o© o • g«»* oooo oe s s » © J,a©©'a o o in 5 a " ■* '' V t^ in ■t % o L 1 e J3© © »"»*-: 5 g m' mi i-t o ©' fBTfi L.s" * gii [« »=&lt;i^ • 8 © S £ © © IS " - °&lt;i i - 1,- ~~ rnir i ! 1 1 si b U * •» x m j o us© t- © j 5 r" i-c i-l H j L* IS o ©lO t- © o N«d * » ■1 1-1 « II tn mo lOOt- ©US t- o© O *n © : o ©USt- U5W o ©©!© m**w us'-* jus ©oojos "5 O i © US© « USU3©©O O© j US -^^^ej MN'vr^v tote \ ■ ! i( I "&gt; us © ©US N ©©USU9 t- ©O us n»m *«ii«L rite •* l_ i i| te SOS « co n oe » CO ©e© n NHfl ») - - 1 TT^ : TT~~©" w " Irli "Ml ~ i .i I r^ ■3 ■ II : I - o i P a I £ § * 8 5 2 £ 2 o 2 - - = * a I £ «il 3 IS I I II </seg>
            <seg id="p051">Blister Canker 51 I M :_J ° ■§ o jjj©©io 5h ooo .2 8 ° • »!«»*« «•« ss«5 - «"° " *■ « M \ tr. C 2 S 8 n « © B J" - J= °. °. °. •?, in in in s» N .o JjNin'eq &lt;e d© d i •§ § S K _ i £ t- m a.** ' 5 «*** * "?* 1 ~&lt;fc» 3 « ceinn ei &lt;edoo |^ « a n « « ■«&gt; § m &lt; £ «io »! 1.S S 'I 1 e.S *g I it S 8 S5S Ss 1 1 1 1 ••is ■g C i5 ' nn H if 1 I ill ~* 1 7s I !• I J \ 2. a &lt;=;* « 1| I I J s| * \&lt; 8 t "* N o s i. , , I &gt;z^: — I 1 ! ■ i i i !■ &gt;&lt; § s ■ s H a &lt; i &lt; . o ia e-. in ri o » d a _- « o o o ooo o o o o « 1H « •• ■* » o o i © in in in © o o e oooo n fi ci &lt;e ! &lt;e Hrt N M CO I M i i , o o mo n ■«• » lO»-i 00 o e o e o© io i- i-i nod © •&lt; •&gt; MM C4 o © m oe ia ia ta o m m in m m oo od «i-« © © © in so© © © lie f © © © © © o© © •&lt; tj ri ,ri S&gt; TH in M — © © e © © o © oo © M e* &lt;-i i-i n\o en © o o I O © © T IT &amp; 2 &lt;a s ' ► S co £ be " I S * g 5 t « &lt; &lt;&lt; X &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 12 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. I in : : =Lf 0 ' s .a 0 ."? *■: "? o . u ? 1^ °? °.°.°. * ° &lt;=&gt; ■25 5 3 a °° ~ i °&gt; UHieieoi h*sn ri h h h mm «m tete c.» I r ■ 1 h I t, * " « loo S-2 1 5 5 a t^iowio us «&lt;e U e-i n |-e « S «« I n « « B* 1 Is" » loo j^^j £ ga oioomt- ooiousus T5 _ * S «»«•♦•♦ -^ ON mU "°S ■&lt; 5 |j . HH,r« N M 0.5 jjfOotaoo 1000 in o I e °.o "S^ &gt; 5n e " o ' a ' 1^ ocjeiius -r » oo 00 B S S « ! l«- I !O O •S8 j» * Omiomo xnm j* eoii" •«"'•»■ !•■: 1 s |o ! § ~... 2 o^ § « j. — — ! i L_ 3^ S &gt;Io!i§ coin ..'S .g I * Ip- I I" --• |- I I I |; "|- -*• s •= * s ! |io I Mo 1 i i; * 'gill l In 11^ [I J| M Ml |! -.-\\r- - 1 i-i I 1 5 I « I ? s * IS a s I I I I 1 si : ~1 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Blister Canker 53 tibility of apple trees to blister canker must be due to several factors. It is evident that structural differences influence to a great extent susceptibility to and amount of infection. That the degree of immunity is due in part to physiological factors can not be disputed and we may no doubt explain immunity in part by means of chemical differences. Norton 14 designated anatomical or structural differences as the chief determiner of immunity of asparagus to rust. Ward 1 ' in a study of rust resistance in Bromes states he has con - cluded "that the mr.*ter has nothing to do with anatomy but depends entirely upon physiological reactions of the proto - plasm of the fungus a..d of the cells of the host." Jones, 12 Gid - dings and Lutman do not believe that in the case of potato late blight, immunity is determined by either chemical or ana - tomical factors. Cobb 3 asserted that in the case of wheat rust anatomical hindrance plays an important part, but this is denied by Eriksson. 8 Cook and Taubenhaus 4 suggest that the presence of tannin in the cell sap influences to considerable extent susceptibility of trees to fungous diseases. That immunity of apple trees to Nummularia discrete does depend to a large extent upon cellular structure or mechanical resistance is indicated by the fact that certain varieties which have been found very resistant were found on examination to have a cellular structure different from that of other varieties which are decidedly susceptible. Table 13 gives a comparison of the number, size, and thickness of cell walls, of tracheae, wood cells, and medullary ray cells in different varieties. By referring to table 12 it will be seen that varieties such as Delicious and Ben Davis are very susceptible, Winesap and Jonathan moderately resistant, and Oldenburg and Wealthy practically resistant. The table shows no constant difference in the number of tracheae present in a given area but the walls of the tracheae were found on an average to be thicker than in susceptible varieties. The wood cells which surround the tracheae were found to be considerably larger and thinner walled in susceptible varieties such as Delicious and Ben Davis than in resistant varieties such as Oldenburg and Duchess. A greater proportion of the cells were also found to have pitted walls and, since the hyphae must depend upon utilizing the pits as a means of passing from one cell to another, it fol - lows that these varieties would be more susceptible. Perhaps the greatest difference in cell structure of the different vari - eties is in the number and size of the medullary ray cells. While there is no great difference in the shortest diameter of the cells they are considerably longer in Delicious and Ben </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 &gt; * hioviohu) *i C" jHOOOMU »-&lt; r-t C* r-t C* « 2" i sg oaooooo© C , H 2*: oooooo ooo o o * m ~ t~ *r ia la us * MNi-H^H i-k £ 2 X X X X x W £ © o o o i&amp; o IOWW j * l»CO O 00 t- t- I 2 V. 5 § g s e tauSHnto "ftMMMM 00 t- 00 M t - : y. /. f- x r f -* &lt;c -v^ t- MMN« I I *» ,~ £a ~« •his 2 ® X o ~ co co ■«■ 10 ia 10 g J - w =000000 s s - £- 000000 » £ - -:•»■•»■ te &lt;e ,-, to J; s a Si-n-iooo© •S_g g oooooo 5 .a S u seooooo -. » - c o o o o o § K f" e I O IO i-t t- »-h t- O&gt; £* cc ec m eo « co 5 =qSS£-=.S </seg>
            <seg id="p055">Blister Canker 55 Davis than in the other varieties mentioned and have much thinner walls. There is also decided difference in the relative size and number of cells in the tissues formed early in the season and those formed rather late in the fall. The earliest and most abundant infection is almost always found in the region of the larger cells, formed in the early spring growth. TW com - parative number of late thick-walled cells is much giwater in the before mentioned resistant varieties. In making cell measurements and counting cells the area covered under a high power objective was taken as standard. This measured 0.36 mm. in diameter. The tissues formed early in the spring and late in the fall of each annual ring formed during the last five seasons were examined in each variety. Five specimens of each variety were examined in each region, making a total of 50 examinations for each variety. The data shown in table 13 represent an average for all these measure - ments. The number of medullary ray cells was determined from tangential wood sections. The different dimensions of the cells were determined by using both cross and tangential sections. These data while of a preliminary nature show clearly that structural differences play no small part in influencing im - munity of apple trees to Nummukiria discreta. It is also quite evident that immunity is influenced to some extent by physiological factors. The fungus progresses much more slowly in tissues where the protoplasm is still active. In fact the regions of the cambium and phloem are rarely if ever invaded until the tissues have been killed. As soon as the tissues are killed they are readily invaded as shown by both laboratory and field inoculations. This in itself does not account for the difference in degree of immunity of differ - ent varieties unless the age at which the cell content becomes inactive varies. There is a great variation in the age at which xylem tissues remain active in different species of trees but how much difference there may be in different species or sub - species and varieties of Malus has not been determined but is being studied by the writer at the present time. By comparing the rate of growth of mycelium in tissues which were known to be active and those known to contain no protoplasm some interesting results were obtained. In secur - ing these data 20 inoculations in one-year-old xylem of Ben Davis, Delicious, Jonathan, Winesap, Oldenburg, and Wealthy were examined. Ben Davis and Delicious were grouped to- </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 gether as susceptible, Jonathan and Winesap as moderately susceptible, and Oldenburg and Wealthy as resistant. A like number of inoculations in the heartwood of each variety were examined at the same time and grouped in the same way. Total growth above and below the inoculation was considered. There was a great deal of variation in the amount of growth made by the fungus in each variety, as shown by the data in table 14. In order to reduce the experimental error to a min - imum much larger numbers should be employed than those used in securing the above data. However, considering the probable error the results clearly indicate that some factor or factors in addition to anatomical differences operate to influ - ence immunity. TABLE 14 — Relation of active and inactive tissues to varietal susceptibility Range of Range of oSffn V " iatlon A G7o r 4fh e V " iatlon One- Year- , in Heart- ~ . GROUP Old Xylem Mini- Maxi- wood I Mini- Maxi- mum mum mum mum Inches I In. I In. I Inches I In. | In. If no factors other than anatomical differences operate to influence the rate of growth, the fungus should make relatively as much growth in one tissue as another. Therefore, con - sidering the rate of growth in inactive tissues of groups 1 and 2 as standard it would be expected, assuming 28.03 to be cor - rect amount of growth in active tissue for group 1, that the amount of growth in group 2 would be 19.4 inches, but instead it is 9.8 inches. Considering groups 2 and 3 in the same way, the amount of growth in active tissue in group 3 should be 17.2 instead of 3.1 inches. Branches of the different varieties sterilized by steam under pressure and then inoculated showed practically the same amount of growth in all xylem tissues. There was ap - proximately the same difference between woods of different varieties as was shown in field inoculations in heartwood. . Susceptible | I I 13 I 4.5 I I. Moderately sus- ceptible ~ ! I i ! I.I 2.5 I I 36.5 65.2 51.0 I II. I I. Resistant 3.1 i 0.5 | 7.5 11.5 4.5 31. </seg>
            <seg id="p057">Blister Canker 57 Branches were also notched deeply below the point of in - oculation. In such cases the fungous growth was always more rapid than where the limbs were left intact. The effect of cutting off the water and food supply of trees has already been discussed. The foregoing data all indicate that both anatomical and physiological factors are concerned in modifying immunity to blister canker. METHODH OF CONTROL. During the fall of 1912 a series of experiments was insti - tuted to discover some means of controlling blister canker. One method was to cut out the canker. In doing this the cankered surface was removed and the discolored wood cut away until sound wood one inch deep surrounded the wound. Another was to remove the branch on which the canker was located. When it was found impracticable to remove the branch the canker was cut out. In cutting out a canker where too little sound wood surrounded the wound, the branch was removed. A number of different disinfectants and covers were used on both kinds of wounds. They were so arranged that each cover would be used with every disinfectant in about the same number of treatments. Some wounds were left without covers and some without disinfectants. A number of trees were pruned heavily at the time the cankers were treated while the remainder were left unpruned. All treatments were numbered and records were made of the location, size, depth of cut (where the canker was cut out) , and amount of sound wood between the discolored area and the surface of the bark. At the end of the first season as indicated in table 15, it seemed that a high percentage of the treatments would prove effective since the wounds were healing nicely in the majority of cases and both trees and foliage appeared healthy. At the end of the second season, however, it was apparent that treat - ing cankers according to any of the methods used would not prove satisfactory. In many instances the disease was visible in the bark at one or more points at the margin of the old treatment. On examining these treatments it was found that the disease appeared in the bark at points in the margin where the discolored wood was nearest to the surface at the time the treatment was given, or where for some reason the tissues </seg>
            <seg id="p058">\x Vebraska Agricultural Exp, Station, Research BuL It n t^ oj t- -- — I- -. 2 c C j NHMO»»OMlfl^ O O 00 © © 00 &lt;C © 00 ' £ NHHH 00 — — ; «■ £ " E 10 CO 90 ' y: I- iG 00 SC [- 1 «•♦ i 00 ■&gt;. xnisoouM* 3C 3 • ; us noom t- oo oo t-oooooooo oo « u i. lAOniondteod re o oo » u: d m c c cc - C9ONIA Nionoiod 00 CCIAOVN n i-i n M C4NONNOIC r u) oo ea t- ci m mnonooo *Ot-«C» r- © oo co to © t~ 10 © I- © t- ce COVOlO^O AOt^wceoxo I oo 00 00 00 © 00 00 © f a: ,-- © *«• »-• oe Z CON i C4 © Cl » © 00 C0« 5t Z :.-i CON^Hr-^ M A ■J OC CO CO -^ KNp u I I. J ■J &gt; a ijiiiliij iPPupii - « s r j HNCO^IAWt^O •— ff) CO «U3(0h&gt;o ; «• CO WNVt^O 10 i- l: c. c x it. c ; Z Ti kO V &lt;h N N O &lt; c r- us t- &lt;c ce oo &lt; XOMOMOO^- ; U5 in n N^MNMUJW^ 1 ; M M m •* :i :: i* :: n - *£. S N © C* © r* © *« t- i = : n 5 o^SS'i22"'J 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">Blister Canker 59 * - fe -*~ £* ~ G e* © co © w © co © © oo ' w m k f i n f i m oo 5 &gt; .* »-*©co©co©co©© n 01 oo co &lt;e &lt;c t*- t-« © © 7* &lt;e © co © eo © co ©* ©* oo « *-« co* -^ -^ irt co © ©' oo 5 oo r ~ oo oo oo © oo © oo © © oo oo oo oo oo oo oo es © © oo g X Tl «OM oo r I I ooqooooqoooo co © t- oo oo © e&lt; \a oo co oo t- t- CO CO b- 00 © Cl oo co in © w m Tl ci - ci - n :: ci «- CO W NtOncOMNM M VN^U^ 1 A -1 Cl 1 3oeoesi©5COi^« oo oo co co ej A CO N ) C-i —*■* c. X i iii I * 1 S S g 3 * - - a x — H 1-H iiSM "o s « « s'3'3 s J SiP^ w O S O 1) •s;a £ £ n 9B r- &lt; h n x tc l: h x « u 00 CO &lt;D CO t- t- © © C* i* 5 i« 2 ".ESS- i J U %*v«-o KJ J t&lt; U £ &gt; O ihC4 " ti.:*i-/. 5 «s 1 B •9 si 1 c &gt; u ■= H | "c is J H»lflrtOOlOC5V •M £ 00 hOMOhOO t Q0O«O«CO«COC fc, wdcodccdwoc i rH N ri t-1 rH y » o co oi eo o w o o I ceiaoocecooeDoo 1 'X t- O0 t- M X CC © O — — — C C4 *-H f-H tH *-H M I- us IS I eo I* OS I n w 09 zr, i— 0J t- 00 00 00 Irt «WMNNOO «iflio«"tcdd — — — CCNNOHOO t- n eo « &lt;C t© N t-I O O O ■x x tc m t- r. r. n h oi » N c: c: eo «l c - a) - 1 £ SIS I I *J IS &lt;t eo „ C O". - « s </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 had not been sufficiently nourished. Where the cut was made straight across the top or bottom of the wound instead of being made pointed or where insufficient foliage was left on a branch to insure the proper amount of elaborated food materials to heal the wounds, cankers appeared almost invariably. The unsatisfactory results led to the institution of the more fundamental experiments which have already been described, together with more minute observations of the treatments already made. New treatments were made each season as cankers appeared. The same methods were followed except that an effort was made to eliminate all discolored wood. In all cases the amount of wood free from discoloration was measured and the number of annual rings of growth repre - sented was noted. In all 115 trees were treated. The total number of original treatments was 341. Of these 22 were re - treated three times, 105 were re-treated twice, and 214 were re-treated once. This totaled 831 treatments. In so far as the beneficial effects of the various covers and disinfectants used are concerned table 15 may be taken as representative of the treatments made after 1912. Whether or not canker hyphae were left in the tissues at the time of treatment was found by close observation and microscopic ex - aminations to be the determining factor. The effect of either covers or disinfectants was practically negligible where in - fected wood was left. A number of artificial infections in young trees in the greenhouse were treated but not covered. In some the dis - colored strands were all removed while in others a small amount of the discolored wood was left. In all cases fungous growth continued from the remaining discolored wood while no evidence of the disease could be found in the trees where the discolored wood had all been removed. It was found that the fungous growth was more rapid near the treatments than in similarly cankered limbs where no wounds were made. This was no doubt due to the fungus being able to secure oxygen more readily. A number of wounds were made in pairs in branches which contained myce - lium close to the surface. One of each pair was disinfected and covered in the same way that canker wounds were treated while the other was tightly wrapped and waxed over to exclude air. In practically every case characteristic cankers formed about the wound which was not tightly wrapped. A few of the wrapped wounds also developed cankers, but such cankered </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Blister Canker 61 areas were much smaller than those which appeared at the unwrapped wounds. Heavy pruning was found to be injurious rather than bene - ficial where the trees were heavily infected. While it induced more vigorous growth of the tree, it also exposed the mycelium of the fungus to the air wherever large wounds were made. Cankers almost invariably appeared at these pruning wounds within one or two seasons. Radial growth of the fungus in badly infected trees was observed by cutting off large limbs at the trunk and noting both the amount of wood in inches and the number of annual rings free from the disease. It was noted that the fungus occupied about the same relative position in the trunk and larger limbs when the number of annual rings from the sur - face was considered. There was considerable variation in the amount of wood free from disease when measured in inches, due to the fact that some branches were much larger than others of the same age. The fungus is not always confined to tissues of the same age. Most limbs grow faster and have a much thicker annual growth on one side than on the other. Hence the fungus is usually much nearer the surface on one side of the branch than on the other, even when confined to tissues of the same age. It was found that if the growth of a branch was ma - terially checked, the fungus grew thru the greatest number of annual rings of tissue on the side where these rings were the thinnest. Usually the least deposit of tissues is made on or near the upper surface of the branches. Here also, as a rule, the largest number of injuries occur. Often a very shal - low wound extends entirely thru one year's growth of wood. This permits a more rapid advance of the fungus. These tissues are also much less active than on the lower side of the branch where the heaviest deposit of tissues usually occurs. There are actually fewer cell walls to penetrate on the side where the annual rings are the thinnest, since lack of growth consists of a fewer number of cells rather than lack of size of individual cells. It was noted that the proportion of cells pro - duced late in the season and having relatively thick walls was much less in the regions of least growth than on the opposite side of the branch. In the most susceptible varieties of trees under normal con - ditions the fungus was found to grow very rapidly in the heartwood. When active tissues were encountered the growth of the fungus was checked, but it still advanced slightly faster </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 62 than new tissues were being added on the outside. When the growth of the trees was materially checked the fungus gained very rapidly often killing the tree. This explains why so many Ben Davis trees died during and soon after the severe drouth of 1913. The trees were already infected and were checked by the drouth to such an extent that the fungus was able to invade the tissues very rapidly. Jonathan, Winesap, and many other varieties suffered to a much less extent. In these varieties the fungus was found to progress little if any faster after active tissues were encountered than new tissues were added when the trees were in a normal condition. Hence even when checked by the drouth these varieties still offered a great deal of resistance to its advance. MUTHODS OK PKKVKXT1XG INKKCTIOX All accumulated data and observations indicate that methods of control for blister canker must be preventive rather than curative. The importance of avoiding wounds of all kinds to any parts of the tree has already been emphasized, as well as the necessity of keeping the tree in a moderately vigorous state of growth. The protection of all wounds from infection is of the utmost importance. This may be done by eliminating the source of infection by preventing the formation of spores, or inhibiting them in some manner, and by using disinfectants and adhesive dressings for the wounds. It was noticed in the laboratory that the stromata absorb water very readily, and that a considerable amount was taken up before the spores were expelled. Copper sulphate and lime sulphur were then used to ascertain if such materials would inhibit spore germination. The different materials in solution were absorbed readily and the beneficial results were found to be twofold. The quantities of spores expelled were noticeably less when either copper sulphate or lime sulphur was used than when water was used. It was also found that a high per - centage of the spores did not germinate. The difference was most striking when copper sulphate was employed. When lime sulphur was used about 3 per cent to 5 per cent of the spores germinated and a few produced normal mycelium. When copper sulphate was used 1 per cent to 3 per cent ger - minated but in no case was normal growth obtained. The hyphae rarely reached the branching stage but after they at - tained a length of about 1 mm. remained stationary for a time and then disintegrated. </seg>
            <seg id="p063">Blister Canker 63 A number of inoculations were made with ascospores on pruning wounds 1 to 2 inches in diameter. These wounds had been covered six months before the inoculations were made. Similar wounds were made and thoroly disinfected three weeks before being inoculated. The results are given in table 16. It was not noticed until too late to remedy the omission that no check was left for the sc .ies of disinfectants. Table 16 — Efficiency of various coverings and disinfectants used for pruning wounds in preventing infection* Total Num- I Number Total Num- Number of „ „ . TREATMENT OK WOUNDS ber of In- Effective pwlinv. The evidence indicates that suitable dressings and disin - fectants aid very materially in preventing infection. Liquid asphaltum, and white lead and oil appear to be of about equal value. Where either was used there was very little cambium injury and no checking of the wood beneath. In a few cases the covering raised in blisters which later broke and per - mitted infection. This difficulty was overcome by making a thin application of the paint and later putting on a heavier coat. Both pine tar and coal tar were readily absorbed and much checking of the wood occurred. There was also consid - erable cambium injury. ■or in- i-.neeiive Effective lullona Inoculations £.nective LUY K*n Asphaltum (in gasoline) _| 39 7 17.95 White lead._ | 35 5 14.29 Venetian red _ _ _ | 31 13 41.94 Pine tar | 16 5 31.36 Coal tar | 11 4 36.36 White lead and copper sul- [ phate _ _| 35 4 11.43 No cover | 51 j 49 j 96.08 i i i DISINFECTANT Phenol _ | 15 11 73.06 Mercuric chloride 1-500 _| 16 4 25.00 Copper sulphate saturated solution _ _ _ _ _j 15 3 20.00 Formalin 20 r /r - - - _| 12 8 66.67 Lime sulphur 32° Baume I 14 6 42.86 Iron sulphate saturated so- lution ._ _ _ _ j 11 I 5 j 45.45 •Covers were applied six months before inoculation, disinfectant* thre weeks before inoculation. M ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 Of the disinfectants used copper sulphate proved the most satisfactory. The efficiency of copper sulphate is no doubt due to the fact that the tissues for a short distance beneath the surface of the wound retain the copper for a long time. Tests made over a year after several applications of copper sulphate to the surface of pruning wounds showed the pres - ence of copper in considerable quantities. Practically no in - jury resulted from the use of copper in this way. CONCLUSIONS 1 Blister canker is very generally distributed. It occurs in all fruit growing regions of the United States east of the Rocky Mountains and is the most destructive disease of apple trees known. 2 The symptoms of the disease vary with varieties, age of trees, available water and soil nutrients and general weather conditions. Under certain conditions the injury is very similar to that caused by other agencies, such as sun scald, winter injury, collar rot, and the so-called arsenical poisoning. 3 Nummularia discreta Tul., is strictly a wound para - site. Infections may occur thru wounds in both roots and branches. 4 Infection may be present in a tree for several seasons before the disease becomes visible on the outside. 5 The disease is disseminated by means of ascospores, conidia, and infected wood. 6 Both conidia and ascospores are produced thruout the growing season if weather conditions are favorable. Co - nidia are usually produced during the same season in which the canker first appears and on the surfaces of the same stro - mata for many seasons thereafter. Ascospores are produced one or more seasons after the conidia first appear. One stroma may produce ascospores for several seasons. 7 Ascospores are much more viable than conidia and for this reason offer a better means of disseminating the disease. However, conidia also play an important role in spreading the disease. 8 Infection rarely occurs in rapidly growing tissues, but takes place readily in inactive xylem tissues. 9 The fungus does not destroy the cellular structure but advances thru the pits in the cell walls. The most rapid prog- </seg>
            <seg id="p065">Blister Canker 65 ress is made longitudinally thru the tracheae. Radial progress is comparatively slow and is most rapid in the medul - lary rays. 10 Hyphae are always found closely associated with the characteristic brown discoloration of the wood. The wood cells are often killed several cm. in advance of the invading hyphae. 11 The fungous growth is usually slightly faster below than above the inoculation in parts of the tree above ground. In the roots, the reverse is true. 12 There is a great deal of difference in the susceptibility of different varieties of apple trees to blister canker. Of the common varieties Ben Davis, Gano, and Delicious appear to be the most susceptible while Oldenburg and Wealthy appear to be the most resistant. 13 Susceptibility is greatly influenced by the general vigor of the tree, by the supply of water and soil nutrients, and by the season of the year in which the inoculation occurs. Trees are rendered more susceptible when too little water is available, or when they are under-nourished. The greatest amount of infection is found in trees making less than normal growth. Trees appear to be least susceptible to infection dur - ing the period in early spring and summer when they are mak - ing the most rapid growth. The addition of fertilizers to the soil not deficient in any element has been of little or no benefit. 14 Both anatomical and physiological factors contribute to cause a variation in resistance of apple trees to blister canker. It is possible that chemical factors may also play an important role. 15 Control measures must be preventive rather than curative. A diseased tree can be cured only by removing all infection. This is obviously impracticable except in a very few cases. 16 The heavy pruning of infected trees aggravates the disease. 17 Both ascospores and conidia may be inhibited by spraying or painting the cankers with either copper sulphate or lime sulphur. 18 Infection may be prevented to a great extent by dis - infecting and covering all pruning wounds. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 RECOMMENDATIONS PLANT RESISTANT VARIETIES One of the greatest factors in controlling blister canker is to avoid planting trees which are known to be very suscepti - ble. It is inadvisable to plant susceptible varieties such as Ben Davis and Gano. These varieties will not prove resistant even under the most favorable conditions and are of poor quality. The Delicious is also a very susceptible variety but is of ex - cellent quality. Varieties such as Jonathan, Winesap, and Stayman will under average conditions live and produce heavily for a long time even after the heartwood has become infected. AVOID WOUNDS It is of the greatest importance to avoid making large wounds of any kind. This may be accomplished to some degree by training the trees while young. Small wounds in young trees are not nearly so easily infected as wounds in old trees which expose wood several years old. If a tree is properly pruned and trained while young little pruning will be necessary after the tree reaches bearing age. PRUNE AT THE PROPER SEASON OF THE YEAR A little pruning will always be necessary even in well trained trees, but by doing this work at a time when there is the least liability to infection a great deal of the trouble may be avoided. It certainly is not advisable to prune dur - ing warm, wet weather. Summer pruning at any time is questionable where wood more than one year old is removed. DISINFECT AND COVER ALL WOUNDS Pruning wounds, even if made during the winter, may become infected unless protected by covers. All wounds which expose wood more than one year old should be covered. Suitable dressings and disinfectants aid very materially in preventing infection. Liquid asphaltum, and white lead and oil appear to be of about equal value. A tendency to blister may be overcome by making an application with the paint quite thin and later putting on a heavier coat. Both pine tar and coal tar are readily absorbed by the wood and allow the wood to check or crack. Considerable cambium injury may also occur. Copper sulphate has proved the most satisfactory disin - fectant owing to the fact that the tissues for a short distance </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Blister Canker 67 beneath the surface of the wound retain the copper for a long time. PREVENT DISSEMINATION OF SPORES By scraping away and burning all cankered bark from infected trees or by covering all cankered surfaces with a coating of heavy paint or liquid asphaltum a great deal of infection may be avoided. In the first case the spores are destroyed and in the second they are prevented to some extent from escaping. Unless treated in this way all cankers should be thoroly painted or sprayed with copper sulphate at the rate of 1 pound to 2 gallons of water, early in the spring before the dissemination of spores begins. This should also prevent to some extent the formation of new spores. It would also be well when applying the regular orchard sprays to cover thoroly all parts of the tree. This would offer some protection from canker infection. When a cankered limb ceases to bear profitably it should be cut off and burned. As soon as a tree becomes so badly dis - eased that it is no longer profitable it should be removed from the orchard and burned. New trees may be planted to fill vacancies. There is little danger of their becoming infected thru the roots if one or two - year-old trees are used and the roots are not cut back severely. (ll-3- - 17— 5M.) </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 BIBLIOGRAPHY 1 BROOKS, C. Blister Canker. N. H. Agr. Ezp. Sta. Bui. 144; 129-130, f. 27. (1909). 2 Blister Canker. N. H. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 157; 23-24, f. 28. (1912). ■i COBB. Agr. Gaz. N. S. Wales, Vol. Ill, p. 1. (1892). 4 COOK, M. T. and TAUBENHAUS, J. J. The Relation of Para - sitic Fungi to the Contents of the Cells of the Host Plants (1. The Toxicity of Tannin). Del. Exp. Sta. Bui. 91. (1911). 5 COOPER, J. R. Spraying Experiments in Nebraska. Exp. Sta. Research Bui. 10. (1917). 6 The Control of Canker in the Orchard. Neb. Hort., Vol. 3. (1913). DUGGAR, B. M. Blister Canker of Apples, Fungous Diseases of Plants; 282-284, 125-126. (1909). 7 8 9 ERIKSSON, JACOB. Die Getreideroste 73; 351. (1896) FAUROT, F. M. Apple Tree Canker. Bui. Mo. Fruit Sta. 6:11-12, f. 4. (1903). 10 GLOYER, W. O. Apple Blister Canker and Methods of Treat - ment. Ohio Exp. Sta. Clr. 125; f. 1-7. (1912). 11 HASSELBRING, H. Canker of Apple Trees. 111. Exp. Sta. Bui. 70, pi. 1-4. (1902). 12 JONES, L. R., GIDDINGS, N. J., and LUTMAN, B. F. Investiga - tions of Potato Fungus, Phytophthora Infestans, U. S. D. A. Bui. 245. (1912). 13 LAMSON, H. H. Apple Tree Canker. N. H. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 87:130. (1901). 14 NORTON, J. B. Methods Used in Breeding Asparagus for Rust Resistance, U. S. D. A. Bui. 263. (1913). 15 O'NEAL, CLAUDE E. Some Species of Nummularia in Indiana in Proceedings of the Indiana Academy of Science; pp. 235-250. (1914). PADDOCK, W. The New York Apple Tree Canker. N. Y. Agr. Exp. Sta. Bui. 163 (1899) and 185. (1900). 16 17 SCHWEINITZ. In Trans, of the Am. Philos. Soc., 4:195 No. 1249. (1834). TULASNE. Sel. Fung. Carp. 2:45. (1863). IS 19 WARD, H. M. The Relation Between Host and Parasite in the Bromes and Their Brown Rust, Puccmia Dispersa (Erikss.) Annals of Botany, Vol. 16; 233-315. (1902). 10 Recent Researches on the Parasitism of Fungi. Annals of Botany, Vol. 19; p. 21. (1905). 21 VAUGHAN, R. E. Ann. Mo. Bot. Gar., 1:241, 242. (1914). </seg>
            <seg id="p069"/>
            <seg id="p070">70 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DES( U11TIOX OF PLATE I Ben Davis tree showing typical cankers at 1. Such a tree will produce little fruit, and is a menace to the whole orchard. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">Blister Canker 71 Plate I </seg>
            <seg id="p072">Vohr/w,te» A.yrutiwni ft..vp. Vatinn. Resfnvh But. r*:** Ktr-vvr* f&amp; rt. %tr fi w!i«»n irtiL May V mJa. was «. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Blister Canker 73 </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DESCRIPTION OF PLATK III Grimes Golden tree with large canker on a main branch at 1, and a large canker extending more than half way around the trunk at 2. Cankers like the one at 2 are very common on this variety. </seg>
            <seg id="p075">Blister Canker 75 Plate III </seg>
            <seg id="p076">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 76 DESCRIPTION' OK PLATE IV A. Canker measuring 1% x 7 inches which developed within a single week. Stromata appeared on the surface during the same season. B. Portion of an older canker. No ascospores have yet been produced. C. Portion of a canker more than four years old. Much of the bark has fallen away but the stromata are still firmly attached. The black color is due to the presence of ascospores which have recently matured and been forced to the surface. D. Portion of an old canker with the stromata covered with conidia. E. Portion of a cankered limb from which the diseased bark has been cut away revealing the light colored spots with black edges where the stromata had been attached. </seg>
            <seg id="p077">Blister Canker 77 Plate IV </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSrilIITION OK PLATK V A. Camera lucida drawing of germinating conidia. B. Camera lucida drawing 36 hours after germination of conidia. C. Camera lucida drawing 60 hours after germination of conidia D. Camera lucida drawing of section of stroma producing asco spores within, and conidia on the surface. E. Camera lucida drawing of section of mycelium grown in cul ture, producing conidia. </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Blister Canker 79 Plate V </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSCIUITIOX OK PLATE VI A. Microphotograph of cross section of a stroma. The spores had been expelled from several of the pel ithecia. B. Microphotograph (much enlarged) of two of the perithecia shown in A. Asoi and ascospores of all degrees of maturity are shown. The light colored spores are still immature. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">Blister Canker 81 Plate VI </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSt'ItllTlOX OF PLATE VII A. Camera lucida drawing of ascus and ascospores, when first removed from the stroma and the same after germination or the asco - spores. B. Camera lucida drawing of ascospores 36 hours after germina- tion. C. Camera lucida drawing of ascospores 60 hours after germina- tion. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">Blister Canker 83 LATE A # - xJ 2 // f I? *J^ ' • H u u \ /I ■ i J o^ ~a u ~a na •L^ s\ *4&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSrHIITION OF I'LATK VIII A. Microphotograph of a single hypha in pure culture showing the manner of branching. B. Microphotograph of a hypha several days older than the one shown at A. C. Microphotograph of ascospores 60 hours after germination. D. Microphotograph of germinating ascospores. </seg>
            <seg id="p085">Blister Canker 85 Plate VIII I 4 gfff ( - —^"iV.r^' ! 1 t i ■ &gt;/ \ r ' •■T ; \ ■ f,&lt; A ! 1 I • . B / .7 jj it r^ J.i ' ♦ ' \ Si: 9 .• •r- 1- -Lti vacn/. « ■*- . T : / X . \ ' ■ \ [ ) " V » • • »* * • * </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research, Bui. 12 DKSCKIITIOX OK 1M.ATK IX A, B, C, and D. Microphotographs of longitudinal sections of apple wood showing invading hyphae. In A, the hyphae are shown in the medullary ray cells as well as in the tracheae. In C, the hyphae are shown passing thru the pitted walls of two adjoining tracheae. </seg>
            <seg id="p087">Blister Canker 87 Plate IX </seg>
            <seg id="p088">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 88 DKSt'ltllTION OF PIjATK X A and B. Microphotographs of cross sections of apple wood show - ing invading hyphae. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">89 Blister Canker Plate X </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DESCRIPTION OF PLATE XI A. Camera lucida drawing of longitudinal section of apple wood showing invading hyphae. The wood cells are not broken down but the hyphae pass from one to the other thru the pitted walls. B. Camera lucida drawing of cross section of apple wood and invading hyphae. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">Blister Canker 91 Plate XI </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 moscmiTio.N ok platk xii Arrangement of trees which were supplied with nutrient solutions, showing where water supply was controlled. Trees in three rows at the right and those in the foreground on the left are growing in nutrient solution. The jars were buried in soil to prevent injury to roots by heat. Solutions supplied thru small jars at 1. Trees in the left background grown in covered half-barrels. Water was added thru holes in the covers, in which corks were fitted. </seg>
            <seg id="p093">Blister Canker 93 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 94 ( DESCRIPTION OK PLATE XIII A. Making cut in which to insert inoculum. In this instance a half-inch wood chisel was used. B. Inserting inoculum in wound. C. Covering inoculation with sterilized cotton, and covering this in turn with a square of paraffined cloth. D. Putting on the protective covering of cloth which has been saturated with grafting wax. In the upper right-hand corner of C is a finished inoculation showing wrapping and zinc label. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">Blister Canker 95 Plate XIII " mm </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSCIUITIOX OF PI.ATK XIV Cross sections of trunk and branches of Ben Davis tree, which was starved by having a portion of the root system removed, and inoculated. The tree cut off just above the ground. Cross sections 2 inches thick were removed at approximately 16-inch intervals. These blocks were planed and photographed. The crown and roots were also dug up and examined. A. Crown of tree. As shown in the photograph little of the infection extended into the roots. One root, however, wnlch was close to the surface of the ground was infected for several feet. Infection emerged below the crown of the tree. B. Two sections of trunk and two sections of main limb. C and D. Branches attached to the lower right-hand block in B. E. Branch attached to opposite lower left-hand block in B. Infection was close to the surface over the entire tree. One char - acteristic canker was formed on branch D. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">Blister Canker 97 Plate XIV </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSC'IUITION OK PLATE XV Cross sections of trunk and branches of Jonathan tree treated as described in plate XIV for Ben Davis. A. Crown of tree. As in the case of the starved Ben Davis, the canker infection emerged at the bottom. However, none of the roots were infected. B. One section of trunk and eight sections of main limb. C. Eight sections of main limb attached opposite limb shown in B. The last section was not infected. Infection did not extend as far longitudinally or laterally as in the case of the Ben Davis trees treated in the same way. </seg>
            <seg id="p099">Blister Canker 99 Plate XV </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 thru in 2 in and DKSCIUITIOX OK I'LATH XVI Ben Davis tree inoculated but not starved. A. Crown of tree. The infection here was slight but emerged a crack below. B. One section of trunk and eight sections of main limb. C. Lower series, five sections of limb attached just above section B. Upper series six sections of limb attached opposite section B. The last section in all cases was free from infection. The amount of infection was considerably less both longitudinally laterally than in the case of the starved Ben Davis. No cankers were formed. </seg>
            <seg id="p101">Blister Canker 101 Plate XVI </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 Ben DESCUIITIOX OF PLATE XVU Jonathan tree inoculated but not starved. A. Crown of tree. No infection extended below the crown. B. One section of trunk and six sections of one main limb. C. Five sections of main limb attached opposite limb in B. The amount of infection was less than in the case of the unstarved Davis or the starved Jonathan. No cankers were formed. </seg>
            <seg id="p103">Blister Canker 103 Plate XVII </seg>
            <seg id="p104">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 104 DKSC1UIT1OX OK PLATE .Will Jonathan tree infected by wild inoculation thru frost crack in trunk. A. Crown of tree. Infection did not extend into the crown. B. Two cross sections of trunk, one longitudinal section between the two cross sections and one between lower cross section and crown. Longitudinal sections show the depth of the frost cracit and accom - panying infection. C. Sections of two main branches showing a slight amount of infection. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">Blister Canker 105 Plate XVIII i 3k «r Jm Kb 1 t^ 'b ■ . . ■ t ' X C </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSO'IUITION' OK IM,ATK XIX A. Cankers resulting from pure culture inoculations on stubs. B. Canker resulting from pure culture inoculation in xylem. C. Cankers resulting from ascospore inoculation on stubs. D. Canker resulting from ascospore inoculation in heartwood. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">107 Blister Canker Plate XIX i ■ A B D ■ \ c » '■V </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DESCRIPTION OK PLATE XX The P1 ctiire tells its own story. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">Blister Canker 109 Plate XX </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKscniraox of plate xxi Another Nebraska orchard. The trees are all Ben Davis. Nearly all are dead. All will be dead in another year or two. </seg>
            <seg id="p111">Blister Canker 111 Plate XXI </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DESCRIPTION OK PLATK XXII Injuries which permit ready infection. A. Tree split by frost. B. A poor job of pruning. C. Combination of sun scald and borer injury. D. Tree injured at the base by mice. </seg>
            <seg id="p113">Blister Canker 113 Plate XXII </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKSCKirTION OF PLATE XXIII Ben Davis tree infected with canker. All the wood more than two years old and in many places all but the one-year-old wood was infected. This shows the futility of attempting to control canker by cutting it out. </seg>
            <seg id="p115">115 Blister Canker Plate XXIII </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 12 DKStltllTlOX OK IM.ATK XXIV Methods of treating canker. A. Cankered limbs were removed but, as shown at points 1 and 2, all the wood except that formed during the last year was infected. The next year cankers appeared on the remaining limbs. B. Cankered limb removed but the canker is spreading up and down the trunk. C. Nearly half of the bark and a portion of the wood was removed for a distance of nearly six feet, and the wound covered. This is a useless expenditure of time and money. D. A cankered limb was removed and an attempt made to re - move all infected wood. It was found impossible to remove all of the diseased wood. Two years after treating canker appeared at 1 and 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p117">Blister Canker 117 Plate XXIV </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>