<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00038.00013">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00038.00013</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>BIENNIAL REPORT of the FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION to the GOVERNOR of the STATE OF NEBRASKA for the period from DECEMBER 1, 1914 to NOVEMBER 30, 1916</title>
               <date value="1916">1916</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BIENNIAL REPORT of the Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission to the GOVERNOR of the STATE OF NEBRASKA for the period from DECEMBER 1, 1914 to NOVEMBER 30, 1916 by CLARENCE E. HARMON Deputy Commiuioncr </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION John H. Morehead, Governor Commissioner Clarence E. liar man Deputy Commissioner W. S. Frisbie State Chemist G. C. Turnipseed Secretary Miss Grace A. Trott Clerk Miss Agnes Russell Stenographer INSPECTORS E. C. Kemble V. E. Stahl A. J. Tusa Frank Maloney D. W. Heeox Geo. S. Mayo C. C. Holm Sophus Neble, Jr. P. J. Biglin J. P. Turner Martin R. Bloom W. S. Austin A. L. "Wagoner J. W. McKissii-k Weights and Measures Inspectors F. W. Schaupp E. H. Holms George Keenan Seed Inspector and Analyst Louise M. Allen Mell A. Sehmied, Special </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005"/>
            <seg id="p006">To His Excellency JOHN H. MOREHEAD, Governor of Nebraska Dear Sir: I have the honor to submit herewith a report of the Nebraska Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission, for the period beginning December 1st, 1914, and ending November 30th, 1916. CLARENCE E. HARMAN, Deputy Commissioner. Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, December 1st, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 7 REPORT To cover all matters pertaining to the operation of the Pood, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission for the past biennium and the laws this Department has for enforcement, would serve no good purpose, therefore, this report will treat with the most important matters only and in a general way. The past two years have been very productive of results in every direction. The results obtained are not all the result of prosecutions, but are the result of constant, individual and col - lective efforts on the part of those connected with the Depart - ment and the co-operation of those engaged in business in every section of the state. New Legislation During the last session of the Legislature, several sugges - tions were made by this Department recommending changes in some of the laws then in force and in every instance these sug - gestions were incorporated into law. Changes were made in the Dairy Laws whereby this Department can make rules and regu - lations for the purchase of cream on a quality basis, but condi - tions up to this time have not seemed to warrant that such a step be taken, yet it is an assured fact that this is the proper plan to pursue in the very near future. A standard type of cream scale was fixed in the law, also the sensitiveness of the scale. This insures the accurate weighing of samples of the farmers' cream where heretofore the plan of operation was inaccurate and not on a proper basis. The Pure Seed Law was rewritten and made a separate law and now it is effectively enforced to the advantage of every farmer in the state. The Feeding Stuffs Law, which was formerly part of the Pure Seed Law, was rewritten and is known as the model Feed - ing Stuffs Law of the country. Heretofore, live stock remedies were touched on in the Feeding Stuffs Law, but a new law was passed, which requires the filing of the name of each live stock remedy and the in - gredients contained therein with this Department. A large number of concerns refused to make the filing and have with - drawn their products from this market. It is generally under - stood that these remedies that are not now on sale in Nebraska, are the ones which have brought nothing but discredit to live stock remedy manufacturers in the past. The law relating to the pay of inspectors for the Depart - ment was changed and placed on a semi-merit basis. The In- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE speetors formerly received $4.00 per day, but under the new provision they receive $4.00 per day for the first two years and $4.50 per day thereafter. A new provision in the law was made requiring that the net weight, measure or numerical count be placed on the main label of all food in package form. Heretofore this requirement was made on but a few kinds of package food — now it covers all food in package form. A new provision was made covering the branding of drugs in relation to the curative and therapeutic effect. Under this provision no false claims can appear on the label of any patent or proprietary remedy of any nature. Nebraska is the first state in the union to take this long step in the interest of the purchasing public. A few changes were made in the standards of the weights and measures law, which cover the matter of Departmental jurisdiction under the law. This was occasioned by the failure of a law enforcing officer to file a complaint against a dealer, and this Department, under the then existing statute, was powerless to proceed. Now this obstacle is entirely removed. Several other changes were made of minor importance which are not necessary to enumerate here, but the net result of the new lgislation passed by the last legislature is more than gratifying as the public in general has been benefited con - siderably thereby and the laws we have for enforcement have been placed on a plane second to no other state in the union. A law was passed making it a penitentiary offense to sell meat for food purposes from an animal that had died otherwise than by slaughter. The enforcement of this law was not placed under the jurisdiction of this Commission, but was made a part of the criminal code, but if it becomes necessary a prosecution could be filed just the same as if it were a part of the food laws. The reason that we suggested the passage of such a law was that the penalty under the food law for the sale of meat of animals that had died otherwise than by slaughter, was insuffi - cient. Pure Pood Week By proclamation of Governor Morehead under date of March 11, 1916, the week of April 3rd was designated as Pure Food Week. This is a new departure and one which has since been followed by several other states. It was very generally observed by food dealers in all sections of the state and should be carried forward in the interest of pure foods and Nebraska produced foods. A copy of the proclamation issued by Gov. John H. Morehead and a copy of the notice sent out by the Department, calling attention to Pure Food Week, is incorpo - rated in this report and will be found on another page. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISS ON 9 INTERIOR VIEW OF LABORATORY </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Departmental Needs Not many changes are necessary in the laws under the juris - diction of the Department for the protection of the public, but it might be well to mention several changes that should be made. The constitutionality of the inspection fees for inspecting coal oil and gasoline is now in question in the Supreme Court. It is not known what the result of this litigation will be, but the fact that the Department is collecting a large sum in excess of its cost of operation, should be taken into consideration. The Department should be enlarged to cover matters not now covered, to be of service to food manufacturers and producers through the use of our Laboratory and the establishment of civil service or merit system for the inspection force in the field. Inspectors should be paid according to their term of service and their ability to render service. Six dairy inspectors should be employed the year around in place of six for the summer period as now provided for in the law. An addition of three inspectors in the weights and measures field should be made, making the total number in this work six. As matters now stand, three men are in the field and are unable to cover the entire state oftener than once in three years. With the increasing amount of work coming to our Labora - tory, two additional Chemists should be employed. This will give an opportunity to do some research work, which has been very difficult in the past on account of such a large volume of business handled. A further suggestion might be that a new law be enacted covering the sale of patent medicine in Nebraska, which would require all concerns selling their products in this market to register the same with this Department before being offered for sale in this state. Some states have taken this step and it has proved to be of great advantage as well as a protection to the public. Department Bulletins Previous to this biennium, it has been customary for this Department to publish a pamphlet containing all the laws and the rules and regulations pertaining thereto, but this was found to be an expensive as well as a bad plan. Many people write the Department for a copy of the law pertaining to a certain subject and the rulings by the Department on this subject. Under the former plan it was necessary to send out all the laws where only one was asked for. Under the present plan a bulle - tin covering each law has been issued, also bulletins covering the rules and regulations under each law. In this way when a copy of the law is asked for, the person is given full information in </seg>
            <seg id="p011">POOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 11 VIEW OF GENERAL OFFICE </seg>
            <seg id="p012">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 12 ever}- way and the cost of mailing and printing is considerably reduced. Several bulletins are in the course of preparation which will be published soon. The list of bulletins now in print is as f 0II0W8 : 1 — Food Law 2 — Bottlers 11 — List of Creameries 3 — Dairy Rules and Regulations and Dairy Law 50 — Drug Standards 51 — Rules and Regulations governing Food Products 52 — Food Standards 75— Meats, Meat Markets, Slaughter Houses 100 — Weights and Measures 101— Imitation Butter 102— Cold Storage 103— Paints and Oils 104 — Commission Merchants 114 — Sanitary Food Law 119 — Testers and Samplers 122 — Grading of Cream 123— Eggs 123— Live Stock Remedies 124— Pure Seed 125 — Feeding Stuffs 126— Clean Milk 150 — Creameries 200 — Live Stock Remedy Registrations 201 — Oil and Gasoline 222 — Temporary Refreshment Stands 301 — Rules and Regulations on Paints and Oils Rules and Regulations governing inspectors. Patent Medicines With the incorporation of what is known as the Sherley Amendment into our Food and Drug Laws, at the last session of the legislature, this Department was placed in position to be of great service to the public in driving out of the State all the fake cure-alls and misbranded patent medicines being sold. Two courses were open to accomplish the desired result. One was to immediately inspect all the drug stores in the state and file complaints against all druggists who had on hand misbranded patent or proprietary medicines. The other course was to go slowly and to gradually eliminate these cure-alls by working in co-operatoin with the retail druggist. The latter plan was adopted and it can be said that while some were inclined to place obstacles in the way, the greater portion of the druggists </seg>
            <seg id="p013">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 13 in the State have been active in support of the law and are giving their earnest effort to assist the Department in placing the patent medicine business on a legitimate basis. Several prosecutions have been filed and some of the largest manufacturers in the United States have been forced to change, not only the name of their Company, but the name of their medicine from a cure-all to a remedy. This is the first state in the union to make such a clean sweep in the matter and with the results that we have had, it is very gratifying. Prosecutions It has not been the policy of the present administration to file prosecutions promiscuously or for technical violations of the law, but a policy of co-operation has been pursued all along the line and, where it has been found necessary to file prosecutions, they were filed. The record for the biennium shows that 325 cases have been filed. In all but eleven cases, the defendants were found guilty by the Court, or pleas of guilty were entered by the defendants and the fines and costs paid. Three cases were dismissed on account of insufficient evidence and in two cases the Court officer was unable to locate the defendant*. In five cases the Court decided against the State and one case is still pending. This record of successful prosecutions is without question the best record ever made by any Department of like nature in the United States and the Department also holds a good record for the size of fines levied in the larger cases. In one instance at DeWitt, Nebraska, where the town had been voted dry, a man who had been engaged in the saloon busi - ness saw his way clear to go into business and sell a so-called temperance beverage of which he bought a car load. The Depart - ment received information in regard to the matter and an in - spector was immediately sent to DeWitt to secure lawful samples of the article being sold. The State Chemist made an analysis and found the beverage contained more than 4 per cent alcohol, which proved that the article being offered was not a temper - ance beverage, or a so-called near beer, but was in fact genuine beer and was misbranded to evade the law. On a complaint filed with the County Court, the entire shipment of the beverage was seized, the Defendant fined $200 and the beverage destroyed. Some 12,000 bottles were in the shipment. The brewery located at St. Paul, Minnesota, and which maintained an office in Om - aha, was also prosecuted and pleaded guilty, paying a fine of $200 and costs. A complaint was filed against a Cold Storage concern in Omaha for having in their possession in cold storage, foods unfit for food. The Company pleaded guilty, paid a fine of $250 and costs. . » . </seg>
            <seg id="p014">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 14 Several concerns engaged in the wholesale coal oil and gaso - line business in Nebraska, asked the District Court at Omaha for a restraining order covering the matter of the collection of in - spection fees fixed in the law for the inspection of coal oil and gasoline. The Attorney General, acting for this Department, then asked the Supreme Court for an injunction against every oil company doing business in the State enjoining them from interfering in any way with the operation of the law. The in - junction was granted and this Department directed to proceed under the law to pay all the expenses of operating. The Depart - ment was instructed to turn the balance of the oil inspection fees into the Court, which has been done, pending the final adjudication of the matter. The State Fair For several years past, this Department has had a force of inspectors on the State Pair Grounds during the Fair. These inspectors have had charge of the handling and sale of food and refreshments on the grounds. Each year the matter has been handled to good advantage, but during the present year the greatest good was accomplished. The State Fair Board acting in co-operation with this De - partment, condemned several buildings which had been used heretofore as restaurants and stands. These buildings were torn down and a large modern restaurant building was built. The building was divided into five compartments and equipped to carry on the business properly. As an endorsement of the action of the Board in building the building and a further endorse - ment of the proper handling of foods by those who secured the concessions in this building, the public patronized these places to the extent that more than 30,000 meals were served in the five restaurants during the Fair. Several new departures from former methods of handling foods at the Fair grounds were placed in the rules and regula - tions by this Department. One of these was the ruling made prohibiting the sale of hamburgers on the Fair grounds. This ruling was popular with the public in general and met with very little opposition on the part of the concessioners. Those in position to know were immediately convinced that this was a good procedure and one of protection to Fair visitors. Ham - burgers are made of meats which usually cannot be used for other purposes and must of necessity be properly kept to be fit for food. On account of business at the Fair Grounds being only of a temporary nature, it is almost impossible to serve hamburger properly, therefore, it was thought the wisest plaii would be to eliminate hamburger on the Fair Grounds, which was done and which has since been adopted by several other Food Departments. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">FOOD, DRUG, DAIR YAND OIL COMMISSION 15 GRACE A. TROTT Lincoln Clerk 1913-1916 TILLIE C. EPPENS C. TURNIPSEED Lincoln Lincoln Stenographer and Secretary (Re»lgned) Secretary 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Another new plan placed in operation by this Department was the inspection of each food and refreshment establishment on the grounds twice daily and the placing of a large sign on each of these places, showing that the place had been inspected by the Pood Inspector on that date. On the first day's inspec - tion of the establishments, not many cards were tacked up, but as soon as those engaged in the business knew that the inspectors meant business, very few places were denied the cards as they all made a big effort to comply with the law. A bulletin was issued covering the requirements of the Department for temporary food and refreshment stands and very little trouble was experienced enforcing the law. Without question, Nebraska State Fair in 1916 ranks high - est of any State in the union for the cleanliness and purity of the foods and refreshments sold on the Fair Grounds. Department Exhibit at State Fair As has been the custom during the past four years this Department placed an exhibit on the Fair Grounds showing some of the most important matters handled in the enforcement of law and the distribution of bulletins relating to the provisions of the law and other information. A special effort was made this year and a larger exhibit than usual was installed. The exhibit attracted thousands of interested visitors and it is thought that the results accomplished were worth the effort put forth in gath - ering together and installing the exhibit each year. The inter - est in pure foods seems to grow and a larger number of people visit our exhibit each year. Pure Seed Exhibit A pure seed exhibit was installed in Agricultural Hall and was in charge of Miss Louise Allen, State seed analyst. While visitors are fewer in number at this kind of an exhibit it can not be said that the effort and expense put into the exhibit were not worth while. Hundreds of interested farmers visited the booth and were given detailed information in regard to the analysis of seeds as to purity and germination. They were also given information as to the identification of foreign weed seeds and the weeds themselves, as many kinds of different weeds had been grown from the seed by Miss Allen expressly for this exhibit. A cut showing the seed exhibit will be found elsewhere in this report, and also cuts showing the Pure Food, Drug, and Dairy exhibit. State Laboratory During the biennium the total number of chemical analyses made by the State Chemist was 2,718. This number is above the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND FOOD COMMISSION 17 W. S. AUSTIN Central City J. W. MOORE GEO. S. MAYO North Loup I nspector Lincoln Inspector (Resigned) Inspector 1913-1916 1913-1916 1913-1916 FRANK MALONEY P. J. BIGLIN D. W. HECOX Kearney Omaha O'Neill Inspector Inspector Inspector 1913-1916 1913-1916 1913-1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 18 average for a biennial period and represents chemical analyses of every nature. It is a departmental rule that the Laboratory be thrown open to the public and every analysis made that can be made. The original intent of the law was that the State Chemist should make only such analyses as came to the Depart - ment through the regular order of business, but there must be some place where citizens of the state can get information with - out finding it necessary to send to some chemist in Kansas City or Chicago and at the same time be required to pay an un - reasonable fee to secure the information they want, when it can and should be given them at the hands of the State, free of charge. Complaints That Pure Food Law enforcement is popular goes without saying, but the best evidence that the public believes that it should be protected under the Food Laws is th&lt;&gt; number of complaints that come to the office from every section of the State, notifying the Department of minor offenses and asking assistance or information. Quite a number of prosecutions have been the result of complaints. Just recently a housewife called the writer to the phone at his residence, and stated that she had purchased two kinds of meat at a local meat market, both of which were unfit for food. She asked what could be done to protect her in the matter. She was told that her complaint would be given immediate attention, and a visit was made to her residence at once, the meat examined, and found to be in bad condition. Complaint was filed the next morning against the meat market, the dealer entered a plea of guilty and paid a fine and costs. In another recent instance the writer was called to the phone on Sunday morning and told by a housewife that meat had been purchased the previous evening for Sunday dinner and when it arrived at the house on Saturday night, was spoiled. The dealer had been notified, but had failed to give the matter his attention. An inspector was sent to the residence, made an examination of the meat, and Monday morning a complaint was filed against the dealer, to which he entered a plea of guilty and paid a fine and costs. These are only two instances wherein the Department has been of service in small matters to housewives out of a large number of just such complaints. While all complaints do not result in prosecutions, the general effect is that the public know that this Department is here for their protection and feel that their complaints will receive immediate attention. Office Records and Blanks The records of the office for handling the business coming to the Department is now handled on a systematic basis and is </seg>
            <seg id="p019">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 19 SOPHUS NEBLE, JR. A. H. HELD J. W. McKISSICK Holdrege Inspector (Resigned) Omaha Beatrice Inspector Inspector 1915-1916 1914-1916 1915-1916 J. P. TURNER C. C. HOLEM E. A. BORLAND Hastings (Resigned) Fairbury Inspector Minden Dairy Inspector Inspector 1915-1916 1916 1916 C. C. MORSE R. D. NELSON Norfolk (Resigned) Dairy Inspector Lincoln Fremont Inspector (Resigned) 1916 1916 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE divided in subheads, so that each employee has a certain branch of the work. All permits issued under the law are issued in duplicate and in numerical order. For fees received for all items covering inspections and matters other than permits, re - ceipts are issued in duplicate and numerically. The records con - taining all permits and receipts for fees are complete in every detail. A record is also kept of the daily cash receipts and another reeord contains all the expenditures in detail. Another record shows the receipts and expenditures under the several subheads. The Department has been audited regularly during the past four years by the State Auditor's office as often as twice yearly and at each time the Auditor's report has shown the records of the office are complete and correct. Inspection Blanks and Inspections To make reports of business establishments effective, it is necessary that the matter be handled on a business basis and in a way that will attract the confidence of those engaged in bus - iness. One of the important features necessary to accomplish this, is to cover the matter of inspection intelligently and it has been found that the best plan to pursue is to have a well drawn inspection blank covering in detail all the items usually found in a place of business. From time to time changes have been made in the inspection blanks used by the Department and at this time a blank is being used which covers each estab - lishment fully. A copy of the inspection is left with the person in charge of the business, which is a new departure and one that is very productive of results. Heretofore the plan had been to make the inspection blank out in duplicate, sending one to the office and the inspector retaining one. Under this plan the business man was not given full information. Under the new plan he knows in regard to all items that meet with the approval of the Department and in what degree, and he also knows in regard to the items that meet with the disapproval of the Department. Each place of business stands for itself and it is the rule rather than the exception, that under our present plan of in - spection it is much easier to secure the co-operation of the dealers than under the old plan. For the year from December 1, 1914, to November 30, 1915. the total number of inspections made by the Department was 23,707 and for the year beginning December 1, 1915 and ending November 30, 1916, the total number of inspections of all kinds made was 28.743. making a grand total for the biennium of 52,450 inspections. This is the largest number ever made dur - ing any biennium by the Department. A table showing the </seg>
            <seg id="p021">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 21 NELL A. SCHMIED F. W. SCHAUPP Lincoln Weights and Measures Inspector 1913-1916 E. H. HOLMS GEO. F. KEENAN Kearney Lincoln Weights and Measures Inspector Weights and Measures Inspector 1(15-1916 1916 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE number of inspections of each kind for each year is published elsewhere in this report. Sanitary Orders When unsanitary conditions are found to exist in places of business where foods are produced, manufactured, distributed or sold, two courses are always open to the Department. One is to file a prosecution covering such conditions as found, the other course is to furnish what is known as a Sanitary Order and which is provided for in the law. Changes have been made from time to time in regard to the form of the sanitary order and within the last year a new blank form has been adopted. In the years gone by some trouble has been experienced in securing the compliance with sanitary orders after being issued. Many reasons might be assigned as the cause of this trouble, but the main reason was that, it seemed to be impossible to impress those on whom the order was written, that the order must be complied with in accordance with the law and within the time fixed in the order. Heretofore, the order was made out, a copy left with the dealer and a copy sent to the office. Under the new plan a sanitary order is served on the dealer, his signature required in receipt of the order and a copy sent to the office. Now it is the rule rather than the exception that these orders are being complied with promptly. During the past two years this Department has issued 2,555 sanitary orders and practically everyone of them is complied with at this time. Inspectors The law provides for sixteen regular inspectors to enforce the Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Laws. Provision is also made for three inspectors to inspect scales, weights and measures. A further provision is made for six Dairy Inspectors for five months of each year, beginning May 1. The present force in the field is well organized and well equipped to handle the duties devolving upon them. The greater portion of the inspectors now in the field have been with the Department some time and thoroughly understand their duties. As suggested in another part of this report, greater results could be accomplished if the dairy inspectors were kept the entire year and the number not decreased. In this way the regular inspectors could give all their attention to food, oil and other matters and the dairy industry would be given all possible assistance as it is one of the largest industries in Nebraska and entitled to every consideration. Under the present plan, we have an insufficient number of weights and measures inspectors and the number should be increased to at least six to give the public all the protection they are entitled to have. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 23 It is a well known fact that good inspectors, who handle their work properly, cannot be hired today and discharged to - morrow, for the reason that there is no line of business that educates ?&gt;n inspector to take up this work, as inspection under our laws is peculiar in itself, and the only training that can be secured for this work is in the work itself under proper guidance. Frequently inspectors of this Department, after be - coming well acquainted with their duties, have attractive offers from business concerns at an increased compensation and it is not infrequent that these offers are accepted. The work of an inspector is attractive and interesting, not because of the compensation he receives, but because of the results he obtains. The compensation is on a per diem basis and is the only Department under state government operating under this plan. For a beginner, the pay an inspector receives is sufficient, but as the inspector becomes more proficient in his duties, he should be given additional compensation so that fre - quent changes would not be necessary and the inspector would have something to work for and look forward to. The field work of this Department is good training and it is very gratifying to the writer to be able to make the state - ment that many of those who have left the service, are now occuping positions of importance and responsibility. One former inspector is now Deputy State Auditor, another is State Insur - ance Examiner, another is manager of a large creamery; one is Deputy Internal Revenue Collector; one is field manager for a large insurance company and another is field man for a large creamery. One is now employed in the service of the railroad company, and one is operating an up-to-date retail food estab - lishment. Finance On another page of this report will be found tables showing receipts and expenditures for the past biennium for each month under the separate subheads and a recapitulation for the year. The tables will show a large increase in the receipts of the office which is the result of constant effort in every dierction to enforce the provisions of the law for the collection of fees. Up to and including August 31, 1915, the expenses of the Department were paid by the State Treasurer on warrants issued by the State Auditor. On account of the ruling of the State Treasurer that the last legislature had not appropriated the fees of this office for the expenses incurred in enforcing the law, the Department was confronted with a serious condition of affairs. Two courses were open. One was to discontinue the work in the field and in the office, or to assume unprecedented responsibilities in the interset of the whole state and carry the work forward as heretofore. Governor Morehead directed the </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Deputy Commissioner to proceed with the duties of his office and pay all expenses from the receipts of the office. This was done until an effort was made to restrain the Department from collecting fees for oil inspections. The matter was carried to the Supreme Court who ordered this Department to go ahead, pay all expenses and turn the balance of the oil fees into the Court, which has been done and in the neighborhood of $80,000 has been deposited with the Clerk of the Court from January, 1916, to date. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 25 LAWS FOR ENFORCEMENT It is not generally understood that the laws we have for enforcement are separate and distinct in themselves, but placed under the jurisdiction of this Department and, while all the laws relate to each other in some respect, they do not cover the same subject matter. The laws that require the greatest amount of attention and effort are the ones that pertain to Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil products. Hundreds of matters might be touched on in this report that pertain to each of these laws, but space forbids going into these matters in detail. It is thought best to touch on matters in general pertaining to each law separately. The Food Law Nebraska was one of the pioneer pure food states and as the years have gone by, our Pure Food Department has gradual - ly grown in importance and the laws have been gradually brought to a higher plane at each session of the legislature until now no state in the union has a more complete and compre - hensive Pure Food Law than has Nebraska and at the same time must be noted that these laws are popular with the general public. Wholesale and retail food dealers as well as those engaged in other branches of the food business, are all found to be in favor of pure food laws and their enforcement and it would be an injustice to our food people in Nebraska if they were not given this recognition and endorsement in this report. There was a time when people engaged in the food business failed to recognize that food laws were as much to their ad - vantage as to the advantage of the consumer. As the matter stands now, all food establishments are on the same basis under the law and none have an advantage over another. Standards are fixed for cleanliness, purity and branding, so that it is up to each individual to comply with the law thereby receiving the approval of the public with their patronage. Drags There is no line of business coming under the jurisdiction of this Commission which is being handled to better advantage in the state than is the drug business. There is a reason for this. Every druggist is fully equipped to handle his business intelligently for the reason that he has educated himself to do so and we feel that he is entitled to every consideration and assistance that the Department can give him, because he is usually found to be active in the support of the laws requiring the sale of drugs in compliance with the law. There are a few exceptions to this rule, but they are very few. Due acknowl- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE edgment must be made to those engaged in the drug business in Nebraska for their assistance, advice and co-operation during the present administration. In the enforcement of that part of the drug law relating to the proper branding of drugs and proprietary medicines, we have been active to the extent, that during the past two years we have removed from sale in the state more than 50,000 pack - ages of misbranded patent fake and cure-all medicines. We have had the hearty support of practically every druggist we have come in contact with in this successful effort, as was also the case in our campaign to eliminate the sale of fake aspirin tablets. More than 250,000 of these tablets were seized and several prosecutions were filed against wholesale concerns who had "bilked" half the druggists of the state by false represen - tation. These tablets were found to be an entirely different product from what they were branded and sold for and con - tained ingredients of a harmful nature. The Dairy Industry This state is one of the few states in the union that has a large and growing dairy industry. In the neighborhood of 45,000,000 pounds of butter is manufactured by the Creameries each year of which the greater portion is shipped outside the state. No better creameries can be found anywhere and this state can be justly proud of the fact that we not only have the largest creamery in the world, but also the largest butter manufacturing center in the world. The latest and most up-to - date methods are employed in the manufacture of butter by every creamery in the business and no better butter can be found as our butter sells on every market. It is estimated that the dairy industry in all its branches in Nebraska produces more than $40,000,000 worth of products each year. All of this has come to pass through constant effort and energy on the part of those engaged in the business and also on the part of the state for the encouragement and protection found in our dairy laws and the assistance of the Dairy Depart - ment of the State Farm. Many years ago a state Dairymen's Association was organized, which has been a potent factor at all times in the encouragement of those engaged in the dairy business and for their co-operation with those engaged in the educational branch of the work as well as that of law en - forcement. All Nebraska citizens can feel justly proud of this big industry and those engaged in the business as there is no asset that we have that is more important to the growth of the state than this big industry. They deserve all consideration and every assistance at the hands of our people. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSION 27 City Milk Supply During the past biennium several surveys have been made by inspectors of this Department and State Chemist of the milk supply of the cities and larger towns in the state. To make a complete report of all the surveys at the different times would be impossible in a report of this kind, but the public should have the information that it is our opinion that the milk supply in Omaha, Lincoln, Beatrice, Nebraska City, Fremont, Grand Island, Kearney, Hastings and Norfolk is above the average found in the country over. In Omaha the matter of city milk supply is in the hands of the Health Department, and it is giving its best effort to keep the milk sold to the people there up to a proper standard and quality. We have no criticism whatever to offer on the method employed in handling this important item of public consumption in Omaha, but on the other hand, we are frank to say that no city in the country of like size has a better milk supply than has Omaha. Credit is largely due to the City Milk Inspector, who gives all his time and attention to the duties of his office. Were this Department to offer a suggestion, it would be that he be given additional assistance, but under present conditions the best results are being obtained. In the city of Lincoln, the milk supply is under the City Health officer and the people of Lincoln are being protected fully. While the field that is covered is not as large in Lincoln as it is in Omaha, a milk Inspector is employed and his work has been of advantage to the people of the city of Lincoln and a credit to his Department. The milk supply in Lincoln is greatly improved over two years ago. It should be remembered that milk is a part of the daily consumption of every citizen of the state and, therefore, it is important that this product be given the strictest attention as to its cleanliness and purity. Our Department has supple - mented the work of the city officials to the extent of its ability and feels very much gratified over the results obtained. While numerous prosecutions have been filed from time to time to cor - rect conditions, the greater part of the work has been educa - tional and co-operative to the' end that all concerned can congratulate themselves on the conditions as they exist at this time. Petroleum Products The use of petroleum products is increasing each year to a greater extent than any other product sold in the state. This is easily shown by a comparison of the fees collected for in - spection. In 1911 and 1912 the total fees collected amounted to $113,000. For 1913 and 1914, $143,000, and for 1915 and 1916, $221,657. This shows an increase for the past two years of </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE $78,657 for fees collected over the previous two years. Fees for the year 1916 alone amount to $129,107, which is $53,000 more than were collected in 1914. Inspection of petroleum products is now well in hand and every barrel coming into the state is inspected according to law. While the quality of the gasoline will not compare favorably with the quality of four years ago, it is true that with a fixed standard requiring a certain gravity test, the users of gasoline would be compelled to pay a much higher price than now. With the change in the law made four years ago removing the fixed standard of 62 degrees gravity test and permitting the sale of gasoline with the requirement that the correct test be stated on the container, a large saving was made to even- user of this product in the state. The greater portion of gasoline being sold in Nebraska at this time shows a test of 58 degrees gravity, which is of sufficient quality for use for power purposes. As a better protection to purchasers of gasoline, this De - partment ruled that gasoline below 54 degrees could not be sold in the state of Nebraska for the reason that, if it was below 54, it would not be gasoline. This effectively stopped the shipping into the state of inferior gas distillates. Linseed Oil The campaign waged during the previous biennium against the sale of adulterated linseed oil has proved to be effective and Nebraska today is absolutely free from adulterated linseed oil. Not a single barrel has been found by any inspector during the past biennium where formerly the users of linseed oil were robbed of at least $100,000 a year through this agency. Now they are getting pure linseed oil and just what they pay for. Sanitary Law The state has on its statutes the best Sanitary Food Law in existence. Its operation is in the interest of the general pub - lic for pure and clean foods and the greatest effort put forth in any direction is in the enforcement of this law. It covers every matter completely and meets with popular approval by all who are conversant with its provisions and operation. The best pos - sible evidence exists in all places in Nebraska where foods are produced, manufactured and sold, when taken into comparison with conditions that existed in the state not many years since. You will now find confectionery displayed in glass cases, meats fully protected, wrapped bread, and in fact, every article of food, no matter whether being transported or displayed for sale, to be absolutely protected from flies, dust, and dirt at all times. This is in full compliance of the law and observing persons will quickly note the difference in conditions as they exist in Ne - braska and in other states they visit. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 29 Weights and Measures The legislature of 1913 passed a law known as the Stand- ards of Weights and Measures and gave its enforcement to this Commission. An effort was made to secure a sufficient number of inspectors to properly enforce this law at the last session of the legislature, but provision was only made for three inspectors, who find it impossible to cover the entire state as often as neces- sary. After working for three years with three inspectors, it has been impossible to cover the whole state more than once, so it can be readily seen that additional inspectors are absolutely necessary. The law is effective and covers all matters necessary with the exception of inspection. At first the law was unpopular, but after being in operation some time, it has become very popular among those who buy and sell commodities in trade. A summary of the inspections made and fees collected during the biennium is as follows: Summary of inspections made by the Weights and Measure Department from December 1, 1914, to November 30th, 1915: Sealed Condemned Adjusted Hopper scales 190 4 1 Weights 2,867 50 161 Counter scales 1.756 74 81 Pumps 587 25 126 Platform scales 1.433 85 38 Wagon scales 767 41 85 Stock scales 225 38 10 Measures 1.601 126 11 Automatic scales 70 7 6 7 Dormant scales 52 1 1 Track scales 1 Total 9,549* 451t 520$ Summary of inspections made by the Weights and Measures Department from December 1, 1915, to November 30th, 1916: Sealed Condemned Adjusted Hopper scales 169 11 7 Weights 2,767 52 116 Counter Scales 2,653 120 60 Pumps 1.077 63 120 Platform scales 1,948 124 136 Wagon scales 951 66 91 Stock scales 322 47 11 Measures 1.715 313 19 Automatic scales 117 1 2 Dormant scales 96 4 C Slot machines 9 5 1 Total 11,824* 806t 569* * Total number of scales, weights and measures sealed. t Total number of scales, weights and measures condemned. t Total number of scales, weights and measures adjusted. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Weights and Measures fees to November 30th, 1915: received from December 1 1914, Total for the year $3,699.75 Weights and measures fees received from December 1 1915, to November 30th, 1916: Cold Storage Foods Our Cold Storage Food Law has been a model for other states in enacting legislation on this subject. It meets all con - ditions in a proper manner and is being effectively enforced by this Department and observed by those engaged in this class of business. As years pass the storing of food products in cold storage in seasons of plenty for use in seasons of scarcity, is constantly on the increase. Our law cannot be said to be a conservative law as some of its provisions and penalties are drastic as it is intended that the sale of cold storage food shall be made without misrepresentation. December $ 206.00 .January 209.60 February 220.40 March 251.95 April 264.15 May 234.90 June 269.70 July 350.20 August 342.75 September 389.55 October 424.20 November 536.35 :' *' December $ 416.35 Fanuary 571.25 February 651.20 tfarch 525.40 484.75 *ay 593.75 Fune 385.40 ruly 400.10 August 302.45 September 370.84 )ctober 610.65 November 479.35 Total for the year $5,789.49 'otal weights and measures fees received from Decem- ber 1, 1914, to November 30th, 1916 $9,489.2' </seg>
            <seg id="p031">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 31 There is a natural prejudice in the mind of the public against cold storage food. It is acknowledged by all that cold storage food is not as good as strictly fresh food of the same kind, but it is a well settled fact that in times of scarcity when production is light, the price would be much higher on fresh foods than it is under present conditions, as cold storage food tends to reduce the price in times of scarcity and on the other hand, increase the price to the producer in times of plenty. In this way both consumer and producer receive a benefit. The law requires that cold storage warehouses shall be in- spected by the Department each quarter and that a report shall be made by each concern operating a cold storage showing the food in cold storage at a temperature of 40 degrees or less for a period of sixty days or longer. "We have twenty-two cold storage warehouses in Nebraska in which an immense quantity of food products is in storage. A report furnished the Depart- ment on the 25th of November, 1916, from all the warehouses in the state has been compiled and is herewith given, which gives full information as to the amount and kinds of food in storage Cold Storage Report, November 25th, 1916 Butter (pounds) 1,560,926 Eggs (cases) 63,589 Frozen Eggs (pounds) 333,146 Poultry (pounds) 324,241 Poultry (barrels) 113 Poultry (boxes) 284 284 Fish (pounds) 68,254 Beef Carcasses (pounds) 2,265,362 Cuts (pounds) 347,611 Trimmings (pounds) 347,846 Pork Cuts (pounds) 545,249 Trimmings (pounds) 228,180 Mutton Carcasses (pounds) 59,178 Cuts (pounds) 1,277 Trimmings (pounds) 59,033 Veal Cuts (pounds) 359 Trimmings (pounds) 9,774 Apples (Boxes) 16,581 (Barrels) 11,738 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Other fruit (Barrels) 15 (Boxes) 9,809 Cider (kegs) 13 Fanners Meat (pounds) 2,195 Dried Fruit (boxes) 11,331 Cheese (pounds) 34,713 Vegetables (crates) 157 Cured Meats (pounds) 2,884,100 Wild Game (number) 364 Meat (boxes) 143 Beer (kegs) 213 Miscellaneous Packages 1,255 Miscellaneous Pounds 11,241 </seg>
            <seg id="p033">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 33 A BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION In harmony with the program of Governor Morehead, every effort has been put forth to place the Pood, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission on an efficient business basis. Business methods have been installed in conducting the affairs of the Department and many practices that have heretofore been in vogue have been eliminated and while it can not be said that no mistakes have been made, an honest effort has been put forth at all times to give the people of Nebraska a fearless and practical and, at the same time, fair enforcement of the laws under the jurisdic - tion of this Department. The results that have been obtained were not secured in a day, a week, a month, nor a year, but secured by constant effort on the part of every person connected with the Department at all times. Under the law those connected with the Department in field work are not paid on a monthly basis, but are paid for each day of service rendered and for this reason each employee in the field has given full value for the money he has received during the past four years. Not a single inspector has been given a vacation at any time, but has put in his full time and energy in the service of the state. Until recently it was the practice to purchase mileage for all inspectors, but under a recent ruling no mileage is now used by any of our inspectors. Elsewhere in this report is reproduced a bulletin which was issued by the commission relating to rules and regulations gov - erning inspectors. In submitting this report, I take some pardonable pride in the showing we have been able to make during the period I have occupied the position of Deputy Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Com - missioner. I have given my full time and attention to the duties of the office and my heart and soul have been in the work. There is no position under state government in which there is more grief, or where a greater measure of successful results can be accomplished and the record that has been made stands for itself, no matter whether it be successful in greater or less degree. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 BIENXIAL REPORT OF THE ENCOURAGEMENT Occupying a position as active head of such a Department with a large field of activities, naturally brings criticism as well as encouragement from those who come in contact with the de - partment. On the one hand there are always a few who take advantage of the political faith of the one in charge of the work and make every effort to dishearten him and destroy his usefulness and the fruits of his labors. On the other hand there are many who stand ready to encourage and co-operate in any movement for the benefit of the people of the state regardless of political affiliation. It has been my purpose to pay as little attention as possible to those engaged in political warfare and give every energy to the enforcement of laws during my entire term, and I feel that while I may not have accomplished all that I have set out to do, that I have done my utmost and feel a deep sense of gratitude to those who have seen their way clear to join hands with me in the biggest and most beneficial work under state government, "the making of Nebraska the best pure and clean food state in the Union.'' </seg>
            <seg id="p035">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 35 Q t S. h la E S S 5 5! i*l «:s ps (O -5S - c a S I5 i«c </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE PROCLAMATION We, as citizens of this stale have many things to be thankful for and have many things that we can point to with the greatest of pride. Nebraska is one of the largest food producing states in the union and these foods are sold the world around, a fact that should be brought home to every citizen of the state. "Stand up for Nebraska" is a eood slogan, but in food nutters the world "Nebraska Foods First" should be the slogan, and every effort should be made to keep this slogan in the foreground to the extent that all the people of this state be brought to realize that the foods produced and manufactured here are second to none. In justice to our producers and manufacturers and in justice to ourselves as consumers, we should all join hands in advertising in every way possible every article of food produced or manufactured within the state, and show that our foods are superior in quality and that our supply is abundant. To accomplish the best results we must hang our banners where they can be seen and not only attract the attention of our own people but the people in other states who buy from us, as it is shown that our production is far beyond our consumption inasmuch as we produce nearly a halt billion dollars of food products each year. It would seem proper that a certain time be fixed wherein all con - cerned can take part in furthering the general welfare of the state and also of the producers and consumers of food products, therefore the week of April 3rd is hereby designated as the Pure Food Week. All organizations of commercial endeavor, all societies of public wel - fare, all business concerns engaged in selling, distributing and manufac - turing foods, and all persons engaged in the production of foods, are hereby requested to co-operate in this movement and lend every effort for its success. Believing that our citizens will agree with me in this matter and will cc-operate to help carry out the Intent of this proclamation, I hereby set apart the week of April 3rd for the purpose mentioned. Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, March 11th, 1916 JOHN H. MOREHEAD, Governor. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DEPUTY FOOD COMMISSION 37 DISC3 SHOWING 8EDIMENT IN ONE QUART OF MILK </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE PUKE FOOD WEEK In harmony with the proclamation of Governor Morehead that the week of April 3rd be designated and set apart as Pure Food Week in Nebraska, it is suggested by this department that all persons and con - cerns dealing in food products make a special effort during che time mentioned to display and advertise such foods as they have tor sale, and to so arrange their places of business that the best possible state of clean - liness and attractiveness will prevail. The slogan "Nebraska Foods First" should be adopted by all and such foods as are produced or manufactured in this state should be given the preference in displays and advertising. As this in the land of peace and plenty it is suggested that the United States flag be used in decorations. On the one hand "Our Flag" will rtpresent peace and the foods will stand for plenty. "i our co-operation is very necessary to make the Pure Food Week a buccess and this department will lend every effort to assist in every way possible. NEBRASKA FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION By CLARENCE E. HARMAN, Deputy Commissioner Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska, March 17th, 1916. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 39 FOOD, DRUG, DAISY ft OIL COMMISSION Financial Report RECEIPTS From December 1st, 1914, to August 31st, 1915. Under this heading appear the receipts from all sources tor each month. December- Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 66.00 Retail Imitation Butter 76.83 Creamery 2.92 Feeding Stuffs tax tags sold 179.50 Seed analysis fees received 3.00 Oil inspection fees received 7,497.69 Weights and measures fees received 206.00 Copy of oil report sold 5.00 Hydrometer sold 4.50 Total I 8,040.34 January — Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 60.00 Retail Imitation Butter 36.00 Creamery 2.50 Retail Ice Cream 3.00 Commission Merchants 420.00 Cold Storage Licenses 96.00 Feeding Stuffs tax tags sold 282.10 Seed analysis fees received 11.00 Oil inspection fees received 6,805.08 Weights and measures fees received 209.60 Copies of oil report sold 10.00 Feed analysis fees received 2.00 Total $ 7,935.28 February — Testers and samplers' permits issued f 78.00 Retail Imitation Butter 12.61 Commission Merchants 400.00 Cold Storage Licenses 5.00 Feeding Stuff tax tags sold 168.00 Seed analysis fees received 12.50 Oil inspection fees received 5,554.85 Weights and measures fees received 220.40 Copy of oil report sold 5.00 Feed analysis fees received 4.00 Total 6,460.26 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE March— Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 124.00 Retail Imitation Butter 3.35 Creamery 5.08 Bottlers 168 Commission Merchants 10.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 220.00 Seed analysis fees received 22.00 Oil Inspection fees received 4,363.10 Weights and Measures fees received 251.95 Copies of oil reports 15.00 Total $ 5,016.16 April- Testers and samplers' permits issued % 132.00 Retail Imitation Butter 21.67 Wholesale Ice Cream 4.16 Retail Ice Cream 4.00 Commission Merchants 10.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 185 00 Seed analysis fees received 19.50 Feed analysis fees received 1.00 Oil inspection fees received 4,134.88 Weights and measures fees received 264.15 Copies of oil reports 10.00 Mileage redeemed 15.78 Total I 4,802.14 May- Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 111.00 Retail Imitation Butter 5.00 Wholesale Ice Cream 8.40 Retail Ice Cream 1.00 Bottlers 1.66 Commission Merchants 10 00 Live stock remedy registration fees received 210.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 102.38 Seed analysis fees received 4.50 Oil inspection fees received 6.281.34 Weights and measures fees received 234.90 Copies of oil reports sold 10.00 Mileage redeemed 12.78 Total $ 6.992.% June — Testers and samplers' permits issued f 3.00 Retail Imitation Butter .83 Live Stock Remedy Registration fees received 410.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 115.73 Seed analysis fees received 1.50 Oil inspection fees received 9,498.76 Weights and measures fees received 269.70 Copies of oil reports 10.00 ToUl $ 10,309.52 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 41 July- Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 3,683.00 Imitation Butter 1,55500 Creamery i i »i nn 1,134.00 Wholesale Ice Cream 355.00 Retail Ice Cream 97 oo netail Ice Cream 97 00 Bottlers oRft'nn 280.00 Commission merchants 10.00 Cold Storage inspection fees 62o!oo Live Stock remedy registration fees received 9o!oo Seed analysis fees received ., '50 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 52^00 Oil inspection fees received 8,07&lt;!74 Weights and measures fees received 350 20 Weights and measures fees received 350.20 Copies of oil reports iq^O Miscellaneous 2 83 Total % 16,314.27 August- Testers and samplers' permits issued 272.00 Imitation Butter 9750 Creamery 18200 Wholesale Ice Cream \\ g 0 00 Retail Ice Cream 6 'qq 5°!" e " : • • . 15^00 Cold Storage inspection fees ' ' 50 00 Live Stock Remedy Registration fees 30 00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 5500 p eeaing stuns tax tags sold 55 00 Seed analysis fees received Vno 3.00 Oil inspection fees received " 799469 Weights and measures fees received ...!!!! 342 75 Copies of oil reports sold 10 00 10.00 Total $ 9,117.94 DISBURSEMENTS From December 1st, 1914, to August 31tt, 1915 Under this heading appears a statement of fees paid into the State Treasurer's office showing the date on which the payment was made. number of the Treasurer's receipt and the amount December 31st. State Treasurer's receipt No. 97154 $ 8 689 10 January 15th, State Treasurer's receipt No. 97661 1709 65 January 15th, State Treasurer's receipt No. 97660 7 834 34 February 16th. State Treasurer's receipt No. 98682 ....... 7^935 28 March 16th, State Treasurer's receipt No. 99580 6460 26 April 15th, State Treasurer's receipt No. 100822 5 016 16 May 14th, State Treasurer's receipt No. 102088 .... 480'' 14 4.802.14 June 14th, State Treasurer's receipt No. 103385 ...] 6!992'96 July 15th, State Treasurer's receipt No. 104642. July lbtn, state Treasurer s receipt No. 104642 10 309 52 September 7, State Treasurer's receipt No. 106145 16 814 27 September 7. State Treasurer's receipt No. 106147 9117 94 9,117.94 ToU1 ■•• $ 86,681.62 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 42 VOUCHERS DRAWN FOR EXPENSES Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commission from December 1st, 1914, to August Slat, 1915, by Months December — Salary to Deputy Commissioner $ 187.50 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 22.78 Salary for November and December of State Chemist 300.04 Expenses of State Chemist 11.52 Salary of Secretary 90.00 Salary of Stenographer 70.00 Salary of Clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,188.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 456.11 Telephone and Telegraph 15.40 Mileage for inspectors. State Chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 360.00 Express and Drayage 1.21 Office expenses S3.42 Furniture and repairs 83.03 Postage 100.00 Salary of seed analyst 48.00 Expenses of seed analyst 25.75 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 290.10 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 120.11 Total $ 3,522.03 January, 1915 — Salary of Deputy Commissioner % 187.50 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 19.35 Expenses of State Chemist 30.00 Salary of Secretary 90.00 Salary of Stenographer 70.00 Salary of Clerk 70.09 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,316.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 641.12 Laboratory Supplies and equipment 10.36 Telephone and Telegraph 12.95 Mileage for Inspectors, state chemist fend deputy com - missioner 240.00 Printing 121.32 Office expenses 19.54 Furniture and Repairs 106.35 Postage = 55.00 Salary of seed analyst 60.00 Expenses of seed analyst 21.50 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 295.85 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 131.89 Total $ 3,498.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 43 February — Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 187.50 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 4.50 Salary of State Chemist 150.00 Salary of Secretary 30.00 Salary of Stenographer 70.00 Salary of Clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,160.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 509.51 Laboratory Supplies and equipment 7.43 Telephone and Telegraph .' 14.06 Mileage for Inspectors, State Chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 240.00 Printing 148.75 Express and Drayage 1.S8 Office Expenses 33.04 Furniture and Repairs 55.60 Postage bO.OO Salary of seed analyst 10.00 Expenses of seed analyst 33.96 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 250.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 152.85 Total $ 3,235.58 March- Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 187.50 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 4.20 Salary of State Chemist 150.00 Expenses of State Chemist 5.60 Salary of Secretary 90.00 Salary of Stenographer 70.00 Salary of Clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,128.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 500.20 Laboratory Supplies and equipment 48.95 Telephone and Telegraph 18.28 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 240.00 Printing 58.50 Express and Drayage 6.74 Office Expenses 34.75 Furniture and Repairs . Postage 50.00 Salary of Seed analyst 24.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 250.00 Expenses of weights and measures Inspectors 114.30 Total $ 3,051.08 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE April- Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 187.50 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 9 00 Salary of Secretary 90.00 Salary of Stenographer 70.00 Salary of Clerk 70.00 Salary of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1.352.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 558.37 Laboratory Supplies and Equipment 43.60 Telephone and Telegraph 12.85 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 240.00 Printing 13.50 Express and Drayage 6.27 Office Expenses 12.96 Furniture and Repairs 66.86 Postage 100.00 Salary of Seed analyst 32.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 250.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 126.91 Total .$ 3,491.82 May- Salary of deputy commissioner % 197.16 Expenses of deputy commissioner .45 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 1.50 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,364.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 553. '!3 Telephone and Telegraph 14.40 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and deputy com - missioner 240.00 Express and Drayage 2.26 Office expenses 77.93 Postage 100.00 Salary of seed analyst 82.50 Expenses of seed analyst 13.35 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 250.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 128.11 Total $ 3,404 89 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 45 June — Salary of deputy commissioner $ 208.33 Expenses of deputy commissioner 4.50 Salary of State chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 6.95 Salary of secretary .- 90.00 Salary of Stenographer 70.00 Salary of Clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug. Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,822.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 834.25 Laboratory supplies and equipment 79.38 Telephone and Telegraph 18.04 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 240.00 Printing 120.90 Extra help 40.00 Express and Drayage 4.73 Office Expenses 10.30 Postage 85.00 Salary of seed analyst 100.00 Expenses of seed analyst 68.1b' Salary of weights and measures inspectors 250.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 116.55 Total $ 4,389.59 July- Salary of deputy commissioner $ 208.33 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 30.77 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,394.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,158.47 Laboratory supplies and equipment 23.44 Telephone and Telegraph 23.79 240.00 86.25 9335 10.00 20.75 100.00 100.00 40.04 250.00 150.62 f 5,310.31 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and Deputy Com- missioner Printing Extra help Express and Drayage Office expenses Postage Salary of seed analyst Expenses of seed analyst Salary of weights and measures inspectors Expenses of weights and measures inspectors ToUl </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE August — Salary of deputy commissioner t 208.33 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 100 Salary for July and 13 days of August of Secretary 129.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2.381.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,261.48 Telephone and Telegraph 17.65 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 720.00 Pringting 204.75 Extra help 160.00 Express and Drayage 4.40 Office Expenses 30.05 Postage 100.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 251.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 279.14 Total * 6.038.30 August- Salary of deputy commissioner $ 208.33 Expenses of deputy commissioner 24.01 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 30.42 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil inspectors 1,450.50 Expensesof Food Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 601 85 Extra help 70.00 Salary of seed analyst 96.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 261.00 Total % 3,032.11 RECAPITULATION December 1st, 1914, to August 31st, 1915 Balance on hand with State Treasurer December 1st, 1914...$ 71,948.40 Paid to State Treasurer 85,681.62 Total \ $167,630.02 Total amout of vouchers drawn for expenses 38,974.44 Balance on hand with State Treasurer August 31st, 1915 $118,655.58 Cash on hand December 1st. 1914 $ 10,692.75 Total amount of fees collected 74,988.87 Total $ 85,681.62 Total amount paid to State Treasurer $ 85.6S1.62 Cash on hand August 31st. 1915 ' none </seg>
            <seg id="p047">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 47 Receipts from September 1st, 1915, to November 30th, 1915 September, 1915 — Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 126.00 Imitation Butter 191.65 Creamery 20.00 Wholesale Ice Cream 10.00 Live Stock Remedy registration fees 30.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 157.10 Oil inspection fees received ! 9,888.58 Weights and measures fees received 389.55 Copies of oil reports sold 5.00 Hydrometers Bold -9.00 Mileage redeemed 44 72 Total $ 10,871.60 October- Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 122.00 Imitation Butter 438.41 Retail Ice Cream 1 .00 Bottlers 5.00 Live stock remedy registration fees 40.00 Feeding stuff tax tags sold 105.00 Oil inspection fees received 11,373.56 Weights and measures fees received 424.20 Copies of oil reports sold 15.00 Hydrometers sold ; 7.00 Total 1 12,531 17 November — Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 102.00 Imitation Butter 417.86 Creamery 20.00 Retail Ice Cream ; . . . ; 2.00 Bottlers 5.00 Live Stock remedy registration fees 5.00 Oil inspection fees received 11,088.12 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 159.00 Weights and measures fees received 536.35 Copies of oil reports old 30.00 Total $ 12.360.13 Disbursements from September 1st, 1915 to November 30th, 1915 September — Salary of deputy commissioner % 208.33 Expenses of deputy commissioner 6.25 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 9.00 Salary of secretary 90.00 Extra help 42.00 Salary of weights and measures inspector 117.00 Expenses of weights and measures Inspector 20.15 Salary of clerk 70.00 Total $ 712.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE October — Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 778.50 Expenses of Food, Drug Dairy and Oil Inspectors 321.13 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 355.50 Expenses of weights and measurers inspectors 280.96 Paid to State Treasurere Receipt No. 107432 10,158.87 Total $ 12,263.29 November — Salary of state chemist $ 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 34,35 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,374.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 534.39 Printing 56.80 Postage 100.00 Salary of weights and measurers inspectors 346.50 Expenses of weights and measurers inspecotrs 207.26 Total... $ 2,803.30 RECAPITULATION September 1st, 1915, to November 30, 1915 Balance on hand with State Treasurer August :!lst. 1S15 $118,655.58 Paid to State Treasurer ■ 10,158.87 Balance on hand with State Treasur ir November 30th, 1915. . . .$128,814.45 Cash on hand September 1st. 1915 noue Total amount of fees collected ) .55,782.90 TotalPaid to State Treasurer $ 10,158.87 Paid out for expenses on voucher assigned to Deputy Com- as missioner 5.620.45 Total $ 15,779.32 Cash on hand November 30th, 1915 $ 19 983.58 Receipts from December 1st, 1915, to November 30th, 1916 December — Testers and samplers' permits issued 84.C0 Imitation Butter 237.65 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 145.09 Seed analysis fees received .50 Oil inspection fees received 2,076.14 Weights and measures fees received 416.35 Copies of oil reports sold 15.00 Total $ 2,974.u4 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 49 'eeding stuffs tax tags sold 308.61 teed analysis fees received 17.61 )il inspection fees receiyed 6,690.81 heights and measures fees received 525.41 !opy of oil report 5.01 iileage redeemed 30.9^ Total I 7,»09.4! January, 1916 — Testers and samplers' permits issued 78.00 Imitation Butter 36.81 Commission Merchants 80.00 Cold storage licenses 35.00 Seed analysis fees received 1.30 Oil inspection fees received 15,753.65 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 222.50 Weights and measures fees received 571.25 Copies of oil reports 10.00 Total $ 16,787.21 February — Testers and samplers' permits issued 110.00 Imitation Butter 54.25 Retail Ice Cream 2.00 Commission merchants 440.00 Cold storage licenses 75.00 Cold storage inspection fees 10.00 Live stock remedy registration fees 5.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 181.33 Seed analysis fees received 19.50 Oil inspection fees received 14,722.91 Weights and measures fees received 651.20 Copies of oil reports sold 16.00 Total $ 16,286.19 March- Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 186.00 Imitation Butter 17.53 Creamery 6.66 Wholesale Ice Cream 5.00 Retail Ice Cream 1.00 Commission merchants 100.00 Cold storage licenses 5.00 Cold storage inspection fees 5.00 Live stock remedy registration fees ■ 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE April- Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 166.00 Imitation Butter 22.51 Wholesale Ice Cream 10.00 Retail Ice Cream 2.00 Commission merchants 20.00 Live stock remedy registration fees 5.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 298.95 Seed analysis fees received 22.50 Oil inspection fees received 10,441.05 Weights and measures fees received 482.75 Copies of oil reports sold 15.00 Interest on cash department fund 366.90 Total $ 11,852.66 May- Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 160.00 Imitation Butter 8.35 Creamery 4.17 Wholesale Ice Cream 9.16 Retail Ice Cream 2.00 Bottlers 6.25 Commission merchants 10.00 Live stock remedy registration fees 10.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 246.26 Seed analysis fees received 9.00 Oil inspection fees received 9,123.00 Weights and measures fees received 593.75 Copies of oil reports sold 10.00 Intrest on cash department fund 26.12 Feed analysis fees received 1.00 Total $ 10,218.05 June — Testers and samplers' permits issued 20.00 Retail Ice Cream 2.00 Live stock remedy registration fees 15.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 198.60 Seed analysis fees received 2.00 Oil inspection fees received 10 794.30 10,794.30 Weights and measures fees received 385.40 Copies of oil reports sold io.OO Interest on cash department fund 83.14 Imitation Butter .84 Total 1 ii.5ii.28 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 51 July— Testers and samplers' permits issued | 3,136.00 Manufacturer of Imitation Butter 100.00 Wholesale Imitation Butter 22b!oo Retail Imitation Butter i 630 00 1,630.00 Creamery ]'/\ l[282!oo Wholesale Ice Cream 37s!oo Retail Ice Cream 79'on Retail ice Cream 79 00 Bottlers 2 6r'oo 265.00 Commission merchants loloo Cold storage inspection fees 665 00 Feeding Btuffs tax tags sold 189 00 189.00 Seed analysis fees received i^oo Feed analysis fees received , i^oo Oil Inspection fees received 11,603^05 Weights and measures fees received 40o!lO Copies on oil reports sold io!oo Interest on cash department fund 46^92 Total * 20.018.07 August — Testers and samplers' permits issued 308.00 Retail imitation butter 3&amp;M Creamery , 124 ; 0 o Wholesale Ice Cream , . . 40^00 Retail Ice Cream 11M Bottlers 85 ; 00 Commission merchants io!oo Feeding stuffs tax tags sold &amp;7.50 Seed analysis fees received Oil inspection fees received 12.144!lO Weights and measures fees received 302145 Copies of oil reports sold lo!oo Interest on cash department fund ] 34 48 Hydrometers sold \\\ 35Q TotaI * 13,148.87 September — Testers and samplers' permits sold ) 152 00 Retail imitation butter 216 8 1 ; 216.85 Creamery \ \ 1833 Wholesale Ice Cream : , won Retail Ice Cream B ' oo Ketaii ice Cream 5 00 Bottlers o n nn 20.00 Live stock remedy registration fees \ 20I00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold , 292 50 Seed analysis fees received \ \ " 4^00 Feed analysis fees received \\ j'qq Oil inspection fees received " 10,346!l0 Weights and measures fees received '.'.'.'.'. 370^84 Copy of oil report sold " 5' 00 Hydrometers sold nmc Interest on cash department fund , 26 72 ToM * 11.495.09 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE October — Testers and samplers' permits issued 136.00 Wholesale imitation butter 18.75 Retell imitation butter 1,434.17 Creamery 7.50 Cold storage licenses 5.00 Cold storage inspection fees 10.00 Live stock remedy registration fees 10.00 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 310.50 Seed analysis fees received 1.00 Oil inspection fees received 13,009.15 Weights and measures fees received 610.65 Copies of oil reports sold 10.00 Interest on cash department fund 17.29 Total $ 15,580.01 November — Testers and samplers' permits issued $ 100.00 Bottlers 10.00 Retail Imitation Butter 1,055.52 Feeding stuffs tax tags sold 382.00 Seed analysis fees received 1.00 Oil inspection fees received 12,402.80 Weights and measures fees received 479.35 Copies of oil reports sold 10.00 Interest on cash department fund 24.58 Total % 14,465.25 Disbursements from December 1st, 1915, to November 30th, 1916 December — Salary of deputy commissioner $ 208.33 Expenses of deputy commissioner 9. SO Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 31.88 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,338.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 536.35 Printing 33.00 Weights and measures and supplies 21.10 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 346.50 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 183.89 Total I 3,019.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 53 January — Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208 33 Expenses of deputy commissioner 11.20 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 64.01 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,356.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 500.21 Postage 100.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 337.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 191.24 Other services 273.90 Total $ 3.358.S9 February — Salary for January and February of deputy commissioner. . .% 416.66 Salary for January and February of state chemist 300.00 Expenses of state chemist 8.15 Salary for January and February of secretary 180.00 Salary for January and February of clerk 140.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,576.00 Expenses of Food. Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 535.19 Telephone and Telegraph 112.01 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 1,720.00 Printing 179.50 Extra help 76.40 Express and Drayage 17.20 Office Expenses 127.45 Furniture and Repairs 123.33 Weights and measures supplies 57.95 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 346.50 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 122.36 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 111946 35.00 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 111945 80.00 Paid to Clerk of the Supreme Court 1,644.50 Other services 60.00 Total f 7,858.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE March- Salary of deputy commissioner 208.33 Salary of secretary 30.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,652.50 Expenses of Food Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 634.22 Telephone and Telegraph 24.89 Mileage for inspectors , state chemist and Deputy Com - missioner 480.00 Printing 302.25 Express and Drayage 2.16 Office Expenses 50.64 Furniture and Repairs 81.03 Weights and measures supplies 10.35 Postage 100.00 Salary of seed analyst 28.35 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 337.50 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 142.35 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 112486 140.00 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 112487 75.00 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 112484 150.00 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 112485 150.00 Paid to Clerk of the Supreme Court 14,722.91 Total % 19,382.48 April- Salary of deputy commissioner % 208.33 Salary for March and April of state chemist 300.00 Expenses of state chemist 19.60 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 83.02 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,704.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 659.23 Telephone and Telegraph 15.95 Printing 120.00 Extra help 210.00 Express and Drayage 3.92 Office Expenses 261.67 Furniture and repair* 88.40 Postage 100.00 Salary of seed analyst 223.42 Expenses of seed analyst 15.14 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 346.50 Expenses of weiyhts and measures inspectors 156.44 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 114513 5.00 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 114514 100.00 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 113796 366.90 Paid to the clerk of the Supreme Court 6,690.80 Total f 11,838.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 55 May- Salary of deputy commissioner $ 208.33 Expenses of deputy commissioner 22.70 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 15.26 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,627.00 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 674.81 Telephone and Telegraph 19.39 Printing 126.63 Extra help 6.82 Express and drayage 6.47 Office expenses 293.05 Postage 100.00 Salary of seed analyst 121.50 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 333.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 198.64 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 115340 20.00 Paid to clerk of Supreme Court 10,441.05 Other services 250.00 Total $ 14,863.20 June — Salary of deputy commissioner $ 208.33 Expensse of deputy commissioner 22.70 Salary of state chemist 150.M Expenses of state chemist 20.64 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,973.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,090.94 1,090.94 Telephone and Telegraph 26.15 Mileage for inspectors, state chemist and Deputy Com- Corn- missioner 45.00 Printing 155.65 Extra help 237.34 Express and drayage 402 Office expenses 34.10 Furniture and repairs 39^00 Postage i5 0 00 Salary of seed analyst 117.00 Expenses of seed analyst 3 [$$ Salary of weights and measures inspectors 355^50 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 222.81 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 116808 26!o6 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 116809 10 00 Paid to clerk of the Supreme Court 9 123 00 9,123.00 Other services '286^80 ToU1 * 14,532.14 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE July- Salary of deputy commissioner $ 208.33 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,329.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,431.77 Printing 195.75 Extra help 94.74 Express and drayage 1.32 Office expenses 9.90 Postage 75.00 Salary of weights and measures Inspectors 306.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 226.18 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 117917 83.14 Paid to Clerk of the Supreme Court 10.794.30 Other services 250.00 Total * 16,385.93 August — Salary of Deputy Commissioner % 208.33 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 10.81 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of clerk 35.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,470.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,344.91 Telephone and Telegraph 44.50 Printing 281.00 Extra help 108.00 Express and drayage 1.19 Office expenses 116.41 Furniture and repairs 25.00 Postage 100.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 310.50 Expenses of weights and measures Inspectors 275.54 Paid to Clerk of the Supreme Court 6.603.05 Total $ 12,243.74 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 57 September — Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 9.70 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 80.95 Salary of secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 2,343.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Inspectors 1,511.68 Telephone and Telegraph 25.40 Printing 153.00 Extra help 67.60 Express and drayage 6.01 Office expenses 245.52 Postage 100.00 Salary of seed analyst 99.00 Expenses of seed analyst 45.82 Salary of weights and measures clerk 80.00 Weights and measures supplies 21.20 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 301.50 Expenses of weights and measures Inspectors 261.21 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 118999 46.92 Paid to State Treasurer, receipt No. 119581 34.48 Paid to Clerk of the Supreme Court 5,613.41 Total $ 11.465.23 October — Salary of Deputy Commissioner $ 208.33 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 18.15 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Salary of Secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy * Oil Inspectors 2,602.25 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy ft Oil Inspectors 1,668.15 Telephone &amp; Telegraph 33.32 Printing 5.50 Extra help 8.73 Express &amp; drayage 4.76 Office expenses 154.30 Postage 100.00 Salary of weights and measures clerk 80.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 279.00 Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 263.72 Paid to Clerk of the Supreme Court 5,476.56 Total $ 11,012.77 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 BIENNIAL REPORT. OF THE November — Salary of Deputy Commissioner 208.33 Expenses of Deputy Commissioner 28.95 Salary of state chemist 150.00 Expenses of state chemist 27.25 Salary of Secretary 90.00 Salary of stenographer 70.00 Salary of Food, Drug, Dairy &amp; Oil Inspectors 1,939.50 Expenses of Food, Drug, Dairy &amp; Oil Inspectors 1,168.70 Laboratory supplies 5.60 Telephone &amp; Telegraph 18.20 Printing 884.45 Extra help 30.00 Express &amp; drayage 2.50 Furniture &amp; repairs 161.53 Postage 100.00 Salary of seed analyst 9.00 Salary of weights and measurers clerk 80.00 Salary of weights and measures inspectors 351. CO Expenses of weights and measures inspectors 281.43 Paid to State Treasurer receipt No. 121374 25.00 Paid to State Treasurer receipt No. 121375 43.01 Paid to clerk of the Supreme Court 7,472.94 Total % 13,147.39 RECAPITULATION December 1st, 1915, to November 30th, 1916 Balance on hand with State Treasurer December 1st 1915 $128,814.45 Paid to State Treasurer 1,390.51 Balance on hand with State Treasurer November 30th, 1916... 132.204.96 Cash on hand December 1st. 1915 19,983.58 Total amount of fees collected 152,246.80 Total 172,230.38 Paid out for expenses on vouchers assigned to Deputy Commissioner $59,229.11 Paid to State Treasurer 1,390.51 Paid to Clerk of the Supreme Court 78,482.52 139,102.14 Balance on hand November 30th, 1916 $ 33,128.24 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 59 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE 60 NEBRASKA filMCAMirttTEB Herewith is given the name, location, and number of pounds of butter manufactured by each of the Nebraska creameries. We have 64 cream- eries in the state which secure permits from this Department on the basis of the number of pounds of butter manufactured each year. The total number of pounds of butter manufactured by all creameries in Nebraska for the year ending June 30th, 1916, is 45,198,880 pounds. This is an increase of over4,000,000 pounds in comparison with the year previous. Name year previous. Name Location Lbs. Mfg. Location Lbs. Mfg. Golden Rod Creamery Co Alamito Sanitary Dairy Farmers Co-op. Creamery Co. Hartington Creamery Co Golden Rod Creamery Co Fremont 787,000 Fremont 787,000 Alamlto Sanitary Dairy Omaha 100,000 Omaha 100,000 Fanners Co-op. Creamery Co Wolbach 150,000 Hartington 100,000 Wolbach 160,000 Hart ington Creamery Co. Hartington 100,000 100,000 Verdigre Creamery Co. Beatrice Creamery Co. Fairbury Creamery Co. Verdigre Creamery Co Verdigre 100,000 Verdigre 100,000 Beatrice Creamery Co Lincoln 7,300,000 Lincoln 7,300,000 Fairbury Creamery Co Pairbury 100,000 Fairbury 100,000 Alliance Creamery ft Produce Co., Alliance Creamery ft Produce Co. Holdrege Creamery Co Alliance 423,000 Alliance 423,000 Holdrege Creamery Co Holdrege 100,000 Holdrege 100,000 Fairmont Creamery Co Omaha 8,176,000 Fairmont Creamery Co.. Fairmont Creamery Co.. Fairmont Creamery Co.. Henningsen Produce Co. McGinnis Creamery Co.. Harding Creamery Co. . . Kirschbraun ft Sons Ravenna Creamery Co. . . Fred Carpenter Omaha 8,176,000 Fairmont Creamery Co Crete 3,124,000 Crete 3,124,000 Fairmont Creamery Co Grand Island 1,907,000 Grand Island 1,907,000 Henningsen Produce Co Superior 222,132 Superior 222,132 McGinnis Creamery Co. . .' O'Neill 400,000 O'Neill 400,000 Harding Creamery Co Omaha 3,800,000 Omaha 3,800,000 Kirschbraun ft Sons Omaha 3,000,000 Omaha 3,000,000 Ravenna Creamery Co Ravenna 500,000 Ravenna 500,000 Deshler 100,000 Fred Carpenter Deshler 100,000 Beatrice Cold Storage Co. Omaha Cold Storage Co. F. Johnson Beatrice Cold Storage Co Beatrice 240,000 Beatrice 240,000 Omaha Cold Storage Co Omaha 3,000,000 Omaha 3,000,000 F. Johnson Louisville 100,000 Louisville 100,000 Neligh 100,000 Neligh Creamery Co Neligh Creamery Co... Riverton Creamery Co. The Home Dairy Neligh 100,000 Riverton Creamery Co Riverton 100,000 Riverton 100,000 The Home Dairy Grand Island 100,000 Grand Island 100,000 Adams Center Creamery Adams Center Creamery- Archer 100,000 Archer 100,000 Fontanelle Separator Creamery Co.. Fontanelle Separator Creamery Co.. Crounse Creamery Co Fontanelle 200,000 Fontanelle 200,000 Crounse Creamery Co Malcolm 100,000 Malcolm 100,000 Farmers Co-op. Creamery Co Farmers Co-op. Creamery Co. Keystone Creamery Co Fullerton 100,000 Fullerton 100,000 Keystone Creamery Co York 100,000 York 100,000 Soren Sorenson Soren Sorenson Kimball 100,000 Kimball 100,000 Humboldt Creamery Webb ft Co Humboldt Creamery Hnmboldt 100,000 Humboldt 100,000 Webb ft Co Valentine 100,000 Valentine 100,000 Lincoln Pure Batter Co. Wm. Betcher Lincoln Pure Batter Co Lincoln 900,000 Lincoln 900,000 Pierce 100,000 Pierce 100,000 Wm. Betcher Columbus Cream Co. P. H. Hermes Columbus Cream Co Columbus 100,000 Columbus 100,000 P. H. Hermes Falls City 100,000 Falls City 100,000 Clarks Creamery Co Ravenna Creamery Co Switzer Creamery Co Blue Valley Creamery Co. Geneva Mfg. ft Supply Co. Alex Bisel Clarks Creamery Co Albion 100,000 Albion 100,000 Loup City 300,000 Loup City 300,000 Ravenna Creamery Co Switzer Creamery Co Norfolk 100,000 Norfolk 100,000 Blue Valley Creamery Co Hastings 869,748 Hastings 869,748 Geneva Mfg. ft Supply Co Geneva 100,000 Geneva 100,000 Albion 100,000 Albion 100,000 Alex Bisel Lancaster Milk Prod. Aas'n North Platte Creamery Co.. Swift ft Co Lancaster Milk Prod. Ass'n Lincoln 100,000 Lincoln 100,000 North Platte Creamery Co North Platte 100,000 North Platte 100,000 Swift ft Co Lincoln 1,000,000 Lincoln 1,000,000 Buffalo Creamery Co. Kearney 100,000 Kearney 100,000 Buffalo Creamery Co , </seg>
            <seg id="p061">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 61 St. Paul Co-op. Creamery Co. St. Paul 100,000 Uermantown Co-op. Creamery Co. Germantown 200,000 Seward Creamery Co. Seward 200,000 Loup Valley Creamery Co. . . Erickson Butter &amp; Eggs Co Dannebrog 100,000 Newman Grove 100,000 Waterloo Creamery Co. Omaha 100,000 David Cole Creamery Co. Omaha 4,300,000 Freitag Ice Cream Co. Norfolk 100,000 Fred Schneider West Point 100,000 Cedar Valley Creamery Co. Spalding 100,000 Alfalfa Butter Co. Omaha 100,000 Boulder Creamery Co. Fairbury 100,000 Scottsbluff Creamery Co. Scottsbluff 100,000 Farmers Union Co-op. Creamery Co. Fremont 100,000 Farmers Co-op Association. Bridgeport 100,000 Hemingford Co-op Creamery Co Hemingford 100.000 Burwell Butter Factory.. Reed's Ice Cream Factory Burwell 100,000 Randolph 100,000 45,198,880 Total </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUMMARY OF INSPECTIONS For the previous biennium the total number of inspections made were 24,596, but during the present biennium we are able to show more than 100% increase, with a total of 52,457. This does not show the total amount of work done by the inspectors, as frequently they are called upon to make investigations, re-inspection, and attend to matters per- taining to prosecutions. The last two years have been the best in the history of the Department. Summary of Inspections from December 1, 1914, to November 30, 1915 Bakeries 631 Bottlers 30 Cars oil and gasoline 6,519 Cold storage 439 Confectioneries 728 Cream stations 1,953 Creameries 53 Dairies and milk plants '. 177 Drug stores and soda fountains 555 Pish markets 20 Food factories 98 Groceries 3,814 Hotels 1,820 Meat markets . . 2,324 Mills and feed stores 30 Packing houses 9 Paints and oi's 120, Restaurants (included with hotels). Saloons 398 Scales, weights and measures 2,905 Seed 707 Slaughter houses 179 Wholesale fruit stores and grocers 17 Miscellaneous 120 Produce 16 Milk condensing 3 Breweries 14 Jobbers 15 Commission merchants 13 Total inspections 23,707 Total number of chemical analyses 1,739 Total number of prosecutions 142 Total number of sanitary orders issued 1,433 Summary of Inspections from December 1, 1915, to November 30, 1916 Bakeries 631 Bottlers 48 Cars oil and gasoline 8,356 Cold storages 360 Confectioneries 794 Cream stations 2,016 Creameries 99 Dairies and milk plants 488 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 63 Drug stores and soda fountains 422 Fish markets 1 Pood factories 96 Groceries 3,563 Hotels 1.160 Meat markets 2,387 Mills and feed stores 446 Packing houses 65 Paints and oils 221 Restaurants 620 Retail fruit stores 2 Saloons 121 Scales, weights and measures 4,103 Seed 610 Slaughter houses 165 State institutions 16 Wholesale fruit stores : 23 Wholesale grocers 203 Produce 98 Miscellaneous Ill Breweries 14 Fair grounds, circus and parks 1,631 Total inspections 28,750 Total number of chemical analyses 979 Total number of prosecutions 180 Total number of sanitary orders issued 1,122 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE RULES AND REGULATIONS GOVERNING INSPECTORS Term of Service All inspectors with this Department are employed on a per diem basis, and paid for time actually employed. Inspectors for the first two years service receive not to exceed $4 per day and $4.50 per day after the first two years. Weights and measures inspectors receive $4.50 per day for time actually employed. General Rules General rules govern all inspectors. Special rates are made to govern each branch of the service. Mileage The use of mileage has been discontinued and regular railroad tickets must be purchased and receipts obtained therefor in each and every instance. Receipts and Expenses Receipts for expenses must be on blanks furnished for that purpose. Under the law all actual and necessary traveling expenses are allowed, but a separate receipt must be secured for each item of expense. Lodg - ing and meals at hotels may be paid and receipted for as one item, but the date of each item must be set forth on the receipt, viz.: Lodging 50 cents, breakfast 50 cents, dinner 50 cents, supper 50 cents, 10/25. Lodging 50 cents, breakfast 50 cents, 10/26. Bus fares, telephones, telegraph or other services must not be in - cluded with other items, but must be on separate receipts and show in detail what the same are for. Expense Limited The following rule must be observed as to meal and hotel accom - modations: Meals and lodging must not exceed $3 per day. This does not mean that this amount will apply to each day, but as a maximum, and only as occasion demands. Lodging must not exceed $1.50 per day, and this is allowed only in the larger towns. Meals on dining cars must not exceed 75 cents for breakfast, and $1 for dinner or supper. Tips can not be included in receipts. Meals for other persons can not be included as expense items, and not more than three meals can be charged for on one day. No allowance will be made for Pullman car service other than berths. No expense is permitted at headquarters other than postage supplies, telephone and telegraph. Daily Reports Reports must be mailed to the Department for each day actually em - ployed, showing expense for the day and inspections or other kind of service rendered. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 65 &lt; UJ to I- K I X UJ o a o z &lt; o o o u. li. o l - rr a </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Monthly Expense Account On the last day of each month a monthly expense account must be made out and each item of the same must be represented by a receipt showing the expenditure and what for. All expense accounts must be made out and forwarded in duplicate. Auto or Livery Hire In extreme cases only is the use of automobiles or livery permitted. The Department prefers that inspectors do not hurry matters and give sufficient time at each town to complete the work. Special instruction will be given for any other procedure, and in the absence of such In - struction, all Inspectors are to be governed by the first statement in this paragraph. Telephone and Telegraph It must be explicitly understood that telegrams or telephone calls to this Department must not be sent collect, but always paid for at the point of origin. Collection of Money Under the law each person must forward fees direct to the Depart - ment unless It is specifically stated otherwise in the law. Inspectors are instructed not to receive fees for permits or licenses. Inspection fees may be collected by Inspectors unless Instructions are given to the con - trary. Supplies Requisition blanks are furnished for supplies, and in ordering sup - plies these blanks must always be used. Special Blanks Special blanks are furnished for each branch of the service, and all such blanks must be used and completed in detail. All information must be complete, in every instance. Inspection Reports A report of each Inspection made during the day must be forwarded to the Department. Such reports must cover all places Inspected during the day, and be forwarded immediately at the close of the day. This Is a never ending and imperative rule and no exceptions are made whatever, and no inspector will receive instructions to do otherwise, nor will he be permitted to do so. Monthly Vouchers Blank vouchers are furnished by the State, and the total number of days worked at the per diem rate, must be listed on the voucher as well as the total expense incurred as shown on the expense account and receipt All Touchers must be signed and sworn to before forward- Ing. Vouchers must be forwarded with expense accounts at the close of the last day of each month. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 67 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Sample* of Product* Follow the law closely in the purchase of products for the purpose of analysis or investigation. Get the proper receipt and seal each pack - age with Department seals. A letter of explanation must accompany each lot of samples purchased when forwarded to the Department, and all packages of samples may be forwarded express charges collect. In sending to this Department for analysis samples of any manu - factured product, the following Information must be given on each sample: Name and location of manufacturer. If bought of jobber, the firm name and location. Be particular as to this, and write names plainly. Brand or name of article, any representation by seller as to quality or character of goods. Inspectors are instructed to give preference to original packages. In no case should the contents of a package be tampered with or a portion of the sample removed. The inspector's label should never cover an important part of the label covering the sample. If there is no place on which to attach the inspector's label, use a tag attached by means of wire or cord. When samples are sent in bulk, as spices or buckwheat flour, the inspector's label should be attached so as to seal the package. In case of samples sold in amount smaller than those required for analysis, as extracts or olive oils, it will be necessary to send double or triple samples. When samples are taken in this manner, the bottles or other containers should be wrapped or tied together so as to form one package. Perishable samples, i. e., samples showing signs of fermentation or spoiling, should be marked "Perishable," in order that they may re - ceive proper immediate attention ou arrival. Cheese and fresh meats should not be forwarded in ordinary paper wrappers or in tin boxes. Use paraffined paper or other covering that will neither absorb fat nor permit formation of mold or must. Milk and cream samples requiring preservation should not be so treated as to render valueless the results of analysis, 1. e., the amount of preservative should not be more than is necessary for keeping the sample a few days. One-quarter of the common corrosive sublimate tablet is ample for one pint of milk, and ten drops of formalin solution in the same amount of samples will be sufficient. In order to be acceptable for analysis, each sample must bear the official department label. A sample cannot be accepted: (1) If the label shows discrepancies as to number, date or de - scription of sample. (2) If the inspector's handwriting is illegible or careless. It is important in all cases to give correctly the names aud ad - dresses of retailers, manufacturers and Jobbers on cards accompany - ing samples. Whenever the name of the manufacturer cannot be given, then, if possible, give the name of the Jobber. </seg>
            <seg id="p069">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 69 1O LU K I X UJ &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Inspectors will be expected to observe strictly the above regu- lations. Sanitary Order* Sanitary orders take the place of prosecutions, and when sanitary orders are issued, the conditions to be corrected must be set forth on the order and such orders must be addressed to the owner of the business, and not to the owner of the building, unless they happen to be one and the same person, firm or corporation. The signature of the person to whom the order Is addressed must be secured in every in - stance. Always read the sanitary order to the person to whom it is addressed, and leave a copy of the sanitary law. TEMPORARY REFRESHMENT 8TAND8 August 1, 1916 At this season of the year when street fairs, county fairs, carni - vals and other celebrations are the gathering places of people seeking entertainment and recreation, the temporary refreshment stand is always found in evidence. Some of these stands serve the public well, but the greater portion of them do not. Some think that a tem - porary stand that sells either food or drink, can be handled "any old way," and also think those that patronise these places should not expect to receive their money's worth, but take what is handed to them without a murmur. There is no good reason why the public should be required to buy hamburger and other similar products which are of doubtful origin and composition, and are cooked out in the open and exposed to every form of contamination, flies, dust and dirt. Uncleanliness, in the handling of foods or drinks, Is a violation of the law, and there can be no possible excuse for such violation. It is a well known fact that the requirements of the law can not be met as easily in a temporary place of business as in a permanent place, and for this reason the following rules and regulations are offered to govern temporary refreshment stands: Rules and Regulations No. 1. Stands should be entirely screened, but must have that part screened In which cooking is done and food is kept. No. 2. Stands should not be located In the street but should be located back of the lot line. No. 3. All persons employed in such places must wear clean cloth - ing and keep said clothing clean by frequent change it necessary. Clean water and towels must be provided for the use of such persons. Provi - sion must be made for waste disposal and garbage, which must be removed at least twice daily. Waste and garbage must never be thrown on the ground near the stand. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 71 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE No. 4. All utensils used for preparing or serving foods or drink must be kept clean and a sufficient quantity of water must always be provided for this purpose. ? » No. 5. Food or drinks can not be displayed on counters or elsewhere unless the containers are covered by tight covers of wood, glass or metal. Cloth or mosquito bar will not serve the purpose. No. 6. Drinks should be served in individual cups of paper, but if glasses are used they must be thoroughly washed in fresh clean water immediately after being used by each patron. Glass or metal containers should be used and wooden tubs should not be used for the keeping of drinks in bulk. If dippers are used for filling cups or glasses they must be kept in the Jars or containers when not in use. The use of containers with a faucet, or spigot, near the bottom, is recommended. No. 7. Ice cream cones and lemonade straws must be kept in a well covered container until used. They must not be displayed on a counter uncovered. No. 8. Candy, popcorn, and other confections may be sold only in package form, and when such confections are prepared in outdoor stands, that part of the stand must be enclosed, so that said confection will be securely protected from flies, dust and dirt. Screening alone will not accomplish this. N. 9. Hamburger deteriorates quickly and is always of doubtful origin, and should never be permitted to be sold in temporary stands. If a supply of meat is to be kept on hand, a refrigerator with a sufficient amount of ice in it, must be installed and the meat kept in the refrig - erator. The same rule will apply to all perishable foods. No. 10. A tight metal or glass cover must be provided for griddles on which weiner wurct or other meat is cooked. The cover on the griddle may be open on the side next to the operator only. Griddles should be cleaned thoroughly and frequently. No. 11. All imitation drinks must be plainly labeled to show that they are imitation. If artificially colored, this statement must also appear. No. 12. Foods not in containers must be securely protected from flies, dust and dirt at all times. • SPECIAL NOTICE It must be understood that the foregoing rules and regulations cover all matters pertaining to the handling and sale of foods and other refresh - ments. In making inspections, inspectors will be governed by the State law in all matters. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">POOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 73 » tr u. ui &lt; I x ui a D a. Q Q z &lt; Q O O U. O h cr a. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE Please Hang This Up SPECIAL NOTICE Bulletin No. 117 No. 1. No. 2. No. 3. All article* of Food must at all times be securely protected from Flies, Dust, Dirt and all other contamination. The term "Food" means and includes all articles for food, drink, confection, or condiment, whether simple, mixed or compound. The clothing and person of those who come in contact with^ or handle food, must be clean at all times, and such persons must wash their hands thoroughly before beginning work each day, and after handling any article which is unclean. No person who is afflicted with a contagious or Infectious dis - ease shall be allowed to work in any establishment where food is cooked, served, prepared, produced or distributed. Neither shall any person or persons be allowed to sleep In any such place. No. 4. No. 5. Spitting on floors, walls, or utensils is positively prohibited. Cuspidors must be provided and the same shall be emptied and cleansed daily. No. 6. Every food producing or distributing establishment during the fly season shall have all doors, windows and other openings properly screened. The floors, walls and ceiling of every such place, must at all times be kept in a clean and sanitary condition. No. 7. All utensils, implements, machinery and equipment used in handling, cutting, mixing, canning and preparing food products, must be kept clean at all times. No. &amp; Every toilet and wash room must be properly ventilated and kept clean. All wash rooms must be supplied with soap, running water and clean towels, in order that all employees can properly observe the provisions of this law. Refuse, dirt, and all other waste and unwholesome products must be removed dally. No. 9. No. 10. Unsanitary conditions will be deemed to exist in any food estao - lishment, where proper precautions are not taken for the exter - mination of rats, and mice, cockroaches or vermin. No. 11 The presence of cats or dogs is positively prohibited in any kitchen, dining room, bakery, meat market or other place where food is produced or prepared. No. 12. Unwholesome conditions will be deemed to exist in any kitchen, bakery, meat market or other food producing establishment where the smoking of cigars, pipes or cigarettes is permitted, and the same is positively prohibited. THE 8ANITARY FOOD LAW FIXE8 A PENALTY FOR VIOLATION OF THE 8AME NEBRA8KA FOOD, DRUQ, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska By CLARENCE E. HARMAN April 1, 1916 Deputy Commissioner Do Not Deface or Destroy </seg>
            <seg id="p075">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 75 Please Hang This Up CLEAN FOOD Bulletin No. 118 The Nebraska Food Law prohibits the sale of eggs unfit for food. A penalty of $10 to $100 is fixed In the law for violation of Mm*. EGGS MUST BE CANDLED Dealers must candle all eggs purchased to avoid the penalty fixed In the law. PROTECT YOURSELF Market your eggs when they are fresh as they spoil quickly and must not be aold when spoiled. Always keep out of the sun. Never allow them to be near anything with a strong smell, as they become tainted and are unfit for food. CAREFUL HANDLING An egg is the most delicate of products and will spoil quickly unless kept properly and handled carefully. Market your eggs often and avoid loss. THE NEBRA8KA EGG CROP The egg crop of this state each year amounts to more than $15,000,000. The loss from spoiled eggs amounts to over $2,000,000. Careful handling and frequent marketing will stop this enormous loss. TO EGG DEALER8 Keep your eggs In a cool dry place and in shipping them insist that they be shipped in Refrigerator Cars only. Never allow any shipment to be left on the station platform in the hot sun. It ruins them. Never hold eggs in hot weather. Ship them. All inspectors of this department are instructed to pay strict atten - tion to the enforcement of the Spoiled Food Law. Bulletins covering the matter of care and handling of eggs will be mailed upon application. NEBRASKA FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION Dated at Lincoln, Nebraska By CLARENCE E. HARMAN April 1st, 1916 Deputy Commissioner </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE OF NEBRASKA FOOD, DRUG. DAIRY AND OIL. COMMISSION LINCOLN LEGAL SANITARY ORDER STATE OF NEBRASKA V8. For Street At NOTICE — Contrary to the form of the statutes in such case made and provided, and against the peace and dignity of the people of the State of Nebraska, the following unsanitary conditions have been found to exist in your place of business : Under the requirements of the law the above conditions must be abated within days from this the day of , 191 , or give reason before the Deputy Food, Drug, Dairy and Oil Commissioner why such order should not be obeyed. A Copy of this order will be fled with the Food, Drug, Dairy and OH Commission and you are required to NOTIFY said Commission within the above mentioned period that said order has been complied with. Signed Inspector. The receipt of the above order is hereby acknowledged, Signed </seg>
            <seg id="p077">POOD, DRUG, DAIEY AND OIL COMMISSION 77 tuMI 5°5" O 5 lalljil fens 3 ; - t Kg fjl i OSi. =tso _ lillifl i i§|f.II&amp; 11-^ lisSI II cqh &gt;t&gt; o—^--fccn £ v ■&gt; X&gt;&lt; : : : : : : : : ! '• '• '• till !!!! 1 1 i I till : ! 1 : : £ ■ ; ; ; I | | | I II 1 I I I I I 1. 1 I I I I | I i I I I I I I s 1 1 1 1 1 1 I I i i I ! ! ! :::::::: Mill j I ! j j j j j Mill ! ! i I ! i f I I I ! i ! i i { [ ' i I i i I I ! 1 1 I I 1 ! I t I I I 1 | I j I j I j j ! ; I ! I \ j i i i j I j j j i j I j j I I I j j lilii M i : : : : : 1 I ! I I I I I : : : : : : : : : : : :::::::::::::::: • ; ; • • : ; lill! : : i I I 1 I I I I | I I I I I I \ E S ~m$ 3-3 s | s iS iiillSjiilifiiiJililli! i d if! &amp; o El e S l H 0 8 ! : ! : i : i { | I I I I I I I I i 1 1 1 ! M ; ! ; i i i ; ;' I j I j { i j j j {I j j j | :::::: I j ! ! M i I 1 1 I I I | I j {j : : : _4j iijiii&amp;yliii O^feW U«BfcH&gt;JW QtfuJSo^ BOS I. s ■ 5! - </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE I it E (C ( Id 0 ; I I i ■ \&gt; P I I i &lt; 5 M &gt; M X P o 3 o o I &lt;s n I u x I I u a f -&gt; Hi c I I I 4 ; I j I I i K W X I u c &lt; -I 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">FOOD, DRUG, DAIRY AND OIL COMMISSION 79 'A n s 3 ri j j o c a 1 s ! i o .3 I i 3 i 5 5 Mm rj Z 3 — o 5. M a s* a : H H OS i a B9 6S • i i M •!? w 3 iiH 2 1 1 1 6 S 6* fe &lt;*. l — 2 i ! ■ — j O B &gt;&lt; h -e 5 1 * s &gt;•&gt; c .- v5 *4) *" 1 I &gt; i k ii j « fe H * </seg>
            </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>