<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00050.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00050.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Annual Report of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association for the Year 1919</title>
               <date value="1920-02-01">1920-02-01</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-14</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">JACOB SASS, PRESIDENT Nebraska Dairymen's Association t </seg>
            <seg id="p002">ANNUAL REPORT OP THE Nebraska Dairymen's Association FOR THE Year 1919 &lt; \ Prepared by J. E. PALM, Secretary Nebraska Dairymen's Association </seg>
            <seg id="p003"/>
            <seg id="p004">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 5 - Nebraska Dairymen's Association. Secretary's Office, Lincoln, Neb., Feb. 1, 1920. His Excellency, S. R. McKelvie, Governor of Nebraska: Sir: In compliance with the law in this case made and provided, I hereby transmit the annual report of the Nebraska Dairymen's Asso - ciation for the year 1919. Yours respectfully, J. E. PALM, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">• </seg>
            <seg id="p006">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 7 OFFICERS OF THE ASSOCIATION FOR YEAR 1920 DR. HARVEY A. MORRISON, President College View C. E. MORSE, Vice-President Lincoln J. E. PALM, Secretary-Treasurer Lincoln BOARD OF DIRECTORS C. H. GUSTAFSON Lincoln JOHN FRAZEUR Bellevue J. H. FRANDSEN State Farm, Lincoln JACOB SASS Chalco CHAS. GRAU. . . Bennington </seg>
            <seg id="p007"/>
            <seg id="p008">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 9 TABLE OF CONTENTS Page President's Photo Frontispiece Letter of Transmissal 5 Officers of the Association 8 Board of Directors 8 Honorary Life Members 10 Life Members 11-12 Annual Members 13-14 List of County Agents 15-16 County Superintendents 17-18-19 Program of 1920 Meeting , 22 President's Report 26 Secretary's Report 41 Dr. Van Ess' Address 28 Report Committee on Constitution and By-Laws 38 Mr. Guf-taf son's Address 43 Prof. Hendrickson's Address 48 Hon. Dan V. Stephens' Address 51 Mrs. Ryan's Address 60 Prof. Frandsen's Address 66 Mr. Barney's Address 73 Committee on Resolutions Report 81 Election of Officers 83 Banquet Proceedings 85 Mr. Bixby's Address 89 Mr. Sass' Address '. 93 Mr. Morrison's Address? 96 Mr. Stuhr's Address 102 Mr. Barney's Address 107 List of Contestants Cow Judging Contest 1920 115 List of Presidents and Secretaries 117 Mr. Frazeur's Address 118 Nebraska's Champion Cow 119 Dairy Exhibits State Fair 121 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">10 HONORARY LIFE MEMBERS Name Address •J. Dixon Avery Philadelphia, Pa. S. C. Bassett .- Gibbon, Neb. •Hon. C. L. Gabrielson New Hampton, Iowa Prof. T. L. Haecker St. Paul, Minn. Prof. W. A. Henry MadisoiH Wis. •Hon. W. D. Hoard Ft. Atkinson, Wis. W. W. Marsh Waterloo, Wis. J. H. Rus-hton Omaha, Neb. Hon. A. C. Tupper Osage, Iowa Hon. Dan V. Stephens Fremont, Neb. • Deceased. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">11 LIFE MEMBERS Name Address Alamito Sanitary Dairy Co Omaha, Neb Andreas, H. C Beatrice, Neb. Ashbarn, D. P Gibbon, Neb. Babcock, L. J Gibbon, Neb. Bayley, J. M Gibbon, Neb. Bingham, R., &amp; Son Omaha, Neb. Coffin, L. S Port Dodge, Iowa Davis, Dr. B. B Omaha, Neb. Eiche, Wm Sta. B, Omaha, Neb. Flint, H. P Gibbon, Neb. Prazeur, J Bellevue, Neb. Fulmer, P. S Gibbon, Neb. Glissman, H. C Sta. B, Omaha, Neb. Guernsey Dairy Farm Stromsburg, Neb. Gunther, E. W Albion, Neb. Haecker, A. L Lincoln, Neb. Hatner, Hon. E. J Lincoln, Neb. Holcomb, M. H Clay Center, Neb. Honeywell, J. K Lincoln, Neb. Her, P. E Omaha, Neb. Jones, A Madison, Neb. King, Morelle B York. Neb. Kirschbaum &amp; Son Omaha, Neb. Krumhaur, Henry Lincoln, Neb. Lessentin, F. W Omaha, Neb. Liebers, O. H Lincoln, Neb. Little, E. M Clarks, Neb. Magenau, Otto Fremont, Neb. Merrill, J. C Pierre. S. D. Meyer, H. W Route 3, Lincoln, Neb. Miller, Joseph La Platte, Neb. McGinnis, R. W 845 Nye Ave., Fremont, Neb. Olson, E. A Stromsburg, Neb. Palm, J. E. Lindell Hotel, Lincoln, Neb. Pfeiffer, Otto Elkhorn, Neb. Rector, E. T Omaha, Neb. Reedy, J. A Wildhorse, Colo. Roberts, J. R Lincoln, Neb. Stewart, Wm Lincoln, Neb. Stouffer, Hon. R. B Bellevue, Neb. Stubbe, Henry Omaha, Neb. Sutton, Hon. W. M Table Rock, Neb. Scnwager, Chas. F Omaha, Neb. Tagge &amp; Boldt Cairo. Neb. Templin, A. M Omaha, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">12 M&amp;U16 Address Thompson, F. M Fairmont, Neb. Treltschke, Julius Omaha, Neb. Vaughn, F. H Cheyenne, Wyo. Whitmore, Hon. W. A VaUey, Neb. Wing, H. H Ithaca, New York Witt, Reinold Scribner, Neb. Woods, W. Righter Station B, Omaha, Neb. Young, Hal. C Lincoln, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 13 ANNUAL MEMBERS Name Address Abts, M. C Columbus, Neb. Adams, J. C Marquette, Neb Anderson. Arthur : Springfield, Neb Avery, H. R Station B, Omaha, Neb. Bakor, W. R Route 1, Box 223, Lincoln, Neb. Barth, Chas. E R. F. D. 5, Lincoln, Neb. Branson, J. B Lincoln, Neb. Butler, Wm Lincoln, Neb, Barton, C. R Gehring, Neb, Boehr, John W Hastings, Neb Cornell, H. L Lincoln, Neb Crandall, H. C North Loupe, Neb. Crowell, Cecil Red Cloud, Neb Davidson, W. H Springfield, Neb. Doll, Augustus Station B, Omaha, Neb. Doubt, W.. A Kearney, Neb. Fithian, Glenn Lincoln, Neb. Frandsen, Prof. J. H State Farm, Lincoln, Neb, Frost. E. W Woodlawn, Lincoln, Neb Gustalson, C. H Lincoln, Neb, Grass, Chas Bennington, Neb Grau, Chas Bennington, Neb Gray, Lewis Central City, Neb. Gray, Wayne Central City, Neb. Hanson, Peter Station B, Omaha, Neb. Harris, J. R Emerald, Neb. Hendrickson, Prof. J. W State Farm, Lincoln, Neb. Hogue, R Crete, Neb. Holling, E Station B, Omaha, Neb. Hunter, Paul Lincoln, Neb. Jenkins, S Lincoln, Neb. Jenssen, Wm Station B, Omaha, Neb. Jerauld, W. T Auburn, Neb. Jones, C. W Lincoln, Neb. Johnson, A. F Route 5, Lincoln, Neb. Kilgore, R. R Ulysses, Neb. King, Lee Central City, Neb. Kohler, Roy State Farm, Lincoln, Neb. Kromke, Homer Jansen, Neb. Lively &amp; Son, L. D Route 3, Omaha, Neb. Loose, Oscar Lincoln, Neb. Marshall, R. C Lincoln, Neb. Martin, 0. M Lincoln, Neb. Morrison, H. A College View, Neb. Morse, C. B Lincoln, Neb. I </seg>
            <seg id="p013">14 NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Nelson, J. A. E Geneva, Neb, Olmsted, C. E Rokeby, Neb, Osterhaut, M. D Crete, Neb. Parmenter, B. F Route 4, Lincoln, Neb, Pearson, J. A Malcolm, Neb. Pierson, S. M ". Lincoln, Neb Prime &amp; Son, G. A Arapahoe, Neb. Rice, William G Ft. Crook, Neb Rohever, George Station B, Omaha, Neb. Rosacker, Chas. N Station B, Omaha, Neb, Ryan, Thomas G. Rydberg, Carl Sass, Jacob . Severe, O. A. Shroyer, J. O Starke. Chas. H S wanson, E. C Stromsburg, Neb. Swanson, F. A Stromsburg, Neb, Thompson, Prof. B. H State Farm, Lincoln, Neb Thompson, S. D. Voss, William Walker, D. G Wallis, H. C. Woodruff, W. B. Youngreen, Elmer Valley, Neb, S Route 3, Lincoln, Neb Wood River, Neb Chalco, Neb, Palmyra, Neb Humboldt, Neb [ Red Cloud, Neb D Lincoln, Nel Millard, Nel : Hastings, Nel Station B. Omaha, Nel </seg>
            <seg id="p014">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 15 NEBRASKA EXTENSION SERVICE W. H. Brokaw, Director COUNTY AGENT SECTION Administration and Supervision R. E. Holland, County Agent Leader University Farm, Lincoln H. J. Young, Assistant County Agent Leader J. F. Lawrence, Assistant County Agent Leader N. W. Gaines, Assistant County Agent Leader County or District Agricultural Agent Address Antelope County Neligh Box Butte County Alliance Buffalo County J. E. Ludden Kearney Butler County E. T. Winter David City (Boys' and Girls' Club Leader) Cass 1 County L. R. Snipes Weeping Water Cheyenne County H. G. Gould Sidney Clay County J. H. Claybaugh Clay Center Colfax County H. L. Nye Schuyler Cuming County K. C. Fouts West Point Custer County H. J. Kleihege Broken Bow Dakota County C. R. Young Dakota City Dawes County Fred L. Taylor Chadron Dawson County Alvah R. Hecht Lexington Dodge County R. N. Houser Fremont Douglas County E. G. Maxwell, 412 P. O. Bldg Omaha Fillmore County J. L. Thomas Geneva Frontier County W. H. Campbell Stockville Furnas County W. R. Wicks Beaver City Gage County L. Boyd Rist Beatrice Garden County Oshkosh Hall County James R. White Grand Island Hamilton County 0. E. Quinn Aurora Holt County F. H. Lancaster O'Neill Howard County George E. Davis St. Paul Johnson County J. F. Purbaugh Tecumseh Keith County George H. Kellogg Ogallala Kimball County C. L. Dietz Kimball Knox County Center Lancaster County B. L. Montgomery, Court House . . . .Lincoln Madison County R. A. Stewart Battle Creek Morrill County H. A. McComb Bridgeport Nance County Fullerton Otoe County A. H. DeLong Syracuse Phelps County J. L. GUmore Holdrege </seg>
            <seg id="p015">16 Agricultural Agent Address County or District Platte County W. G. McRuer Platte Center Polk County. Lynn Sheldon Osceola Red Willow County. Richardson County.. Saline County H. H. demons McCook Joseph L. Worrell Falls City W. C. Calvert Friend Saunders County. . . Scotts Bluff County. Seward County R. H. Watson Wahoo Phil Sheldon Scottsbluff L,. C. Christie Seward Sheridan County . Thurston County . Valley County Webster County. . C. O. Sawyer Rush ville W. E. Lyness Walthill C. C. Dale Ord Henry R. Fausch Red Cloud </seg>
            <seg id="p016">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 17 DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC INSTRUCTION STATE OF NEBRASKA LINCOLN Executive Division John M. Matzen State Superintendent John Speedie Deputy State Superintendent Cora A. Thompson; Assistant Superintendent I. N. Clark Rural School Inspector Archer L. Burnham Normal Training Inspector Frank R. Beers Assistant Normal Training Inspector Lulu S. Wolford Head Certification Department Assistants Cecile Snapp Secretary Ruth E. Wheeler, Secretary of Normal Training Department. Bookkeeper Maud Davis Stenographer Emma A. Todd Stenographer Verdena Whitney Clerk and Statistician Caroline C. Cooper Clerk of Examinations Mrs. C. D. Wheeler Clerk of Examinations Etta Brown Clerk of Examinations County Superintendent Address Adams Mary Dungan Hastings Antelope C. A. Mohrman Neligh Arthur Mrs. D. G. Williams Arthur Banner Fred L. Johnson Harrlsburg Blaine A. L. Shamblin Brewster Boone Bertha M. Sheckler Albion Box Butte Opal Russell Alliance Boyd Nellie May Edwards Butte Brown Mrs. Lenna Morris Ainsworth Buffalo Katheryn Laughlin Kearney Burt W. T. Poucher Tekamah Butler Oma L. Cady David City Cass 1 Alpha Peterson Plattsmouth Cedar Emma Schwerin Hartington Chase Addie P. Spangler Imperial Cherry Edith Adamson Valentine Cheyenne Anna McFadden Sidney Clay L. J. Gilkeson Clay Center Colfax F. J. Vogltance Schuyler Cuming Emma R. Miller West Point Custer T. C. Grimes Broken Bow Dakota W. E. Vow Dakota </seg>
            <seg id="p017">18 County Superintendent Address Dawes Edna Rincker Chadron Dawson W c. Bloom Lexington Deuel Retta P. Brown Chappell Dizon W. F. Richardson Ponca Dodge j. E. Marsh Fremont Douglas Mabel Johnson Omaha Dundy Una Richards Benkelman Fillmore Margaret Haughawaut Geneva Franklin Pearl O'Neal Bloomington Frontier Goldie P. Stark Stockville Furnas G. W. Fletcher Beaver City Gage Bertha Foster Beatrice Garden Esther Johnson Oshkosh Garfield Florence Alderman Burwell Gosfcer F. W. Montgomery Elwood Grant Winnifred D. Moran Hyannis Greeley Margaret L. Tracy Greeley Hall W. A. Julian Grand Island Hamilton Arthur S. Nelson Aurora Harlan Frances E. White Alma Hayes Edgiththa Grant Hayes Center Hitchcock Evelyn Besack Trenton Holt Anna Donohoe O'Neill Hooker j. H. Garrett Mullen Howard W. G. Baker St. Paul Jefferson Henry Abrams Fairbury Johnson Helen Wright Tecumseh Kearney Minnie Norlin Minden Keith Katherine Feather Ogallala Keya Paha Abbie Pelletier Springview Kimball Rachel McElroy Kimball Knox Allen S. Stinson Center Lancaster Jeanette C. Nelson Lincoln Lincoln Aileen G. Cochran North Platte Logan A. C. Loshbaugh Gandy Loup Marcia Smith Taylor Madison N. A. Housel Madison McPherson O. A. Johnson Tryon Merrick Margaret McCutcheon Central City Morrill E. F. Kelley Bridgeport Nance Chloe C. Baldridge Fullerton Nemaha Bess E. Anderson Auburn Nuckolls Mildred Mauck Nelson Otoe Charles Speedie Nebraska City Pawnee Bertha Kuhlmann Pawnee City Perkins Mrs. Margaret Bailar Grant Phelps 1 Alice A. Swanson ,,,,,,,,.. Holdreg«j </seg>
            <seg id="p018">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 19 County Superintendent Address Pierce Marjorie Parminter Pierce Platte Fred S. Lecron Columbus Polk Amelia Rasmussen Osceola Red Willow Helen Cousce McCoofc Richardson D. H. Weber Falls City Rock Evlyn W. Towle Bassett Saline L. J. Bouchal Wilber Sarpy Bertha Bishop Papillion Saunders F. E. Alder Wahoo Scotts Bluff Ada M. Haldeman Gering Seward J. C. Greenwood Seward Sheridan Pearle E. Summers Rushville Sherman L. H. Currier Loup City Sioux Vinnie Newell Harrison Stanton S. E. Eddy Stanton Thayer H. E. Barbee Hebron Thomas Inez L. Oakes Thedford Thurston Ellen M. Brown Pender Valley Lelia Mooreman Ord Washington N. T. Lund Blair Wayne Pearl Sewell Wayne Webster Estelle Ducker Red Cloud Wheeler Edith Bowler .\. . . .Bartlett York Tslfer C. Lord York </seg>
            <seg id="p019"/>
            <seg id="p020">Proceedings of the THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL MEETING of the NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION Held at the Dairy Building, University Farm Lincoln, Nebraska, January 21-22, 1920 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">22 WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON SESSION January 21, 1920 The Thirty-Fifth Annual Convention of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association met in the Dairy Building at the University Farm, Lincoln, and was called to order by the President, Mr. Jacob Sass, of Chalco, at 1:30 P. M., January 21. THE PRESIDENT: The Address of Welcome will be delivered by a man who put in his 1 boyhood days on the farm; who knows what it is to get up early in the morning to go out and milk the cows. They did not have those modern barns nor the conveniences they have now; but the old, cold barns; and it was rather hard for a boy to get up early in the morning. I have the pleasure of introducing to you Hon. J. E. Miller, the Mayor of Lincoln. (Applause.) ADDRESS OF WELCOME Hon. J. E. Miller, Mayor, Lincoln, Neb. Mr. Chairman and Gentlemen of the Convention: I come here in a double capacity — not only as Mayor of the city, but as a representa - tive of the Board of Regents; but in neither position am I qualified to speak to you in an expert way upon the work you call yours. So that I am not going to bother you with any views about how things should be done. Your Chairman very kindly told you that I had had some experience. I think he got that from a little story I told him just before we came up here. I remember when I was ready to start to school one morning, when I had fifteen minutes to make the mile and a half through the snow, mother said, "John, have you fed the calves?" John hadn't. As there were two or three, you know what it meant — get the milk; warm it; take it into the barn; divide it into portions, and try to get the unwilling calves to take their breakfast. You know the results. I tried to force their heads into the can, and finally I got astride of the calf's neck and tried it that way. Before I got to school I had to put on my Sunday clothes because the others were not fit. (Laughter.) Your President made reference to the barns. We had better barns then than you have here now except on the good dairy farms. I was raised in Pennsylvania, and we had the bank barns: there. It is told as a joke the Pennsylvania Dutchman had a fine barn for his cows and not much of a house to live in. That is told by people from New York or Illinois where they have neither a fine barn nor house. In fact, we had both. I do not think you would have called our barns the best place to keep stock, because we kept them too warm, but they were comfortable for the boys who had to milk. I was thinking of what progress has been made in your calling in the forty-one years I have lived here. When I came here, most of the cows wore Texas horns. Very, few looked as though they were ready </seg>
            <seg id="p022">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 23 to be milked or had any inclination to be milked; and not very many of them would. I remember the kind of churn the average farmer used — the up - and-down dasher. When you compare that with the modern way of caring for the cattle and taking care of the milk and cream, and churning it, I think you will agree about as much progress has been made in the business of the dairy farm as in that of any other thing that we have to do with. There has been a great change from the old farm wagon in which you drove to town forty-one years ago, to the automobile you drive now. But I believe the change in butter - making has been just as great, if you will consider the difference in the quality of the cattle and the manner of handling and the price you get for it. I remember the price of butter varied from six to twenty-five cents in winter, and it wasn't good butter, then. The great problem the city people have now — we are having committees appointed in every town, and we have one big State Committee to solve the problem of how to give the farmers about seventy cents a pound for butter fat and sell butter at twenty-five cents a pound, without putting too much salt and water in it. I expect neither party will be fully satisfied with the decision. It amuses me when I hear Nebraska people complain about high prices, because I presume we come as nearly getting our share of that big price as any other people in these United States. We have had a pretty fair price for our wheat and corn. I believe we figure out there is no money in raising corn; but I cannot help but have a suspicion if you raise forty bushels per acre and get $1.25 a bushel for it, it must pay pretty well. I remember when it went up to twenty cents the farmers were pretty glad to haul it to town. The merchandise we sell is high. I cannot understand it. We do not know why it is so, but it is. I do not know when we are going to get over it. I had hoped the change would come gradually, but I would not wonder if we keep on until we strike the ceiling and go down with a crash. It looks to me as though if anyone had a sure thing for the future, it is the man who gets good agricultural land in a state like Nebraska. I know more about Nebraska than I did four or five years ago. Although I have lived here forty-one years, I think I have learned more in the last five years than ever before. That is because of the act you elected me to the Board of Regents, and one of our duties las been to go over the state and visit the various experiment stations and schools; and by driving over in an automobile I have become better acquainted with it. You cannot see a state from the railroad. Anyone who passes through Nebraska in a dry summer will have a bad mpressrion of it. But if he would get out in an automobile and travel where people live and crops are raised, he would think very differently of it I • " ' - ~ "Wl I think your industry is Just in Its beginning. Think of the place </seg>
            <seg id="p023">24 dairy products have in the market of the world today as compared witn a generation ago. The change has been marvelous. I remember visiting Cuba after our Spanish war — about 1900 — and the only butter we got was made in Venezuela. We were not exporting butter to our nearest neighbors. Now we are sending butter pretty nearly all over the world — to Europe — England, France, and other countries that do not raise sufficient themselves. Our dairy products are going every - where. We used to think you could not get good cheese outside of Europe. Then our neighbors in Canada began to make it. Nebraska has not taken her place among the cheese-making states as yet. I do not know why, exactly. Maybe there is so much money in butter we have not gotten to making cheese yet. We had two or three factories, but I think they have discontinued doing business. But the time will come when we will do our part in that work. I suspect today we are making more butter and cheese than any other one country in the world, and I would not be surprised if we are making more than all of Europe right now — butter, at least. I am .. pretty sure we are eating more. Professor Frandsen tells me Omaha makes more butter than any other city in the world. I was here when we first began to ship butter out of the state. I remember how it was done. A man by the name of Osborne came and started a renovating factory in which he bought the poorest butter that our town people would not buy, and put it through a washing machine and repacked it and shipped it east. That was the beginning of the commercial dairy business in the State of Nebraska, so far as I know. That was thirty-eight years ago. Previous to that time, when we accumulated too much butter, there wasn't a thing we could do with it. We threw a good deal of it away, and some of it did not deserve any better fate. The farmers did not have facilities for making it, and did not know how to use the ones they had. So when I say in no other line of Industry has there been greater progress made than in dairy products, I think I am within the truth. If we pay more, we get more for our money. We can afford to use less and have it good, rather than to have quantity without quality. Gentlemen, I hope your sessions will be profitable to you. I am sure they will be. There Isn't anything more gratifying to me — because I have always taken an interest in things agricultural — than to find out that in these last few years the practical man on the farm has learned to know that the man who has made a study of that same business from a scientific standpoint has something in common with him, and they can learn from each other. In our business we have hardly discovered that yet. It is the hardest thing to get a young man to believe there Is anything he can get from the schools that will do him good in his business. He is mistaken, and after a while he will waken up to the fact that even the schoolmaster has something of value for him. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 25 I congratulate you upon the fact that you have had wisdom enough, through the legislature, to put up such buildings, and enable the state to hire men who have been trained from a practical and scientific standpoint to help you in your work. As a regent here, I am a little prejudiced. We try to get all the money we can for this institution. We try to persuade the legislature to give us all the money we can to promote the interest of agriculture on this campus. Looking back over it, I believe we waste about as little money here as any place else I know. The man who thinks you can do anything without wasting some money is mistaken. If he. will look into his own business, he will admit at the end of a long career he has made mistakes; so that your Board of Regents, even with the expert help and advice we are ready to follow, will make mistakes 1 . But I think the few hundred thousand dollars per year the State of Nebraska spends on this campus is one of the best investments it makes. If you believe it, too, I hope that at the various sessions of the legislature you will see to it those members who come up here — some of them very skeptical — are told that the institutions on this campus are of assistance to you; and if they can get that into their heads thoroughly, there is none of them so ignorant or narrow or stingy he would not furnish us money enough to do this business on the greatest scale. I want to say this is the greatest agricultural school and college in the United States. We have one of the best equipped dairy buildings and best arrangements here of a group of buildings in the United States, or associated with any college in the United States. I have the same ambition for every other department. I hope you will go through the mechanical engineering building and see what we are going to try to do to teach the young men something about farm mechanics. I do not believe I would learn about it if I would stay for a great many years; but the young men I have talked with agree they get a great deal of knowledge that is of real value to them in their work. It is the ambition of the regents to do practical things on this campus. Yet we do not overlook the cultural side of it. We think here are other things to get besides learning how to do his work. He wants to be taught the nicer things of life. But we want this to &gt;e practical; and with your assistance and advice and co-operation, I am sure it will be the constant endeavor of the board to make it so. (Applause.) JACOB SASS' RESPONSE TO ADDRESS OF WELCOME In response to the address of Mayor Miller, we are glad to come to Lincoln and to this great institution. We like to come to the University Farm. We like to meet the regents, the dairy professors and instructors. UFor many years I have known the boys and girls who have been ling to this school. These same boys And girls have returned to </seg>
            <seg id="p025">■•« the*fanns with new ideas that have changed many of the old farm practices. Years ago some farmers scoffed at the idea of sending boys to school to learn to farm. They said these things should be learned at home. However, most of the farmers today have gotten past that notion and are realizing more of the worth of this institution. The boys too have a better opinion of the work of the University Farm. Once in a while a boy may come here only for a good time, but nine out of ten of them consider the time they put in here well spent. In this time of high prices when the salaries of common laborer has increased from $35 to $110, and where the wages to farm hands has increased any where up to 200 per cent, I have been wondering if the salaries of our professors and instructors in this great institution have been taken care of. These men have been putting in the best part of their lives in getting an education, and now they are here in this great institution teaching our children to be better farmers and better home-makers. We know that food and clothing have doubled and trebled. These men must live and are anxious to lay aside a little money for a rainy day and for the time when old age will deprive them of their present working power. In some way, I sympathize witn these men because they are giving us the best time of their lives, and I am sure that their salaries should be taken care of so that they may have a chance with the rest of us. The farmer — the agriculturist — is ready and willing to pay for those things which mean greater service to him. He is willing to pay taxes for the erection of splendid buildings, for experiments and for salaries of our professors, when the money has been spent wisely and gets results such as have been accomplished here. I thank you. (Applause.) THE DAIRY INDUSTRY President Jacob Sass, of Chalco The history of the development of agriculture in the most pro - gressive nations of the world has been one of gradual change from grain growing to livestock farming. As cultivation of the fields has become more intense, fertility of the soil has become more and nnre an important factor. The most practical means of keeping up thi3 fertility of the soil has been largely by the us« of the dairy cow. The dairy cow has proven that she has a place also in converting Cughage into palatable human food. It is a pleasure to know that e dairy industry has been making rapid progress during the past few years. As an industry, it has grown from many angles. The progressive dairyman is no longer satisfied with the scrub cow. poor equipment, and careless methods of feeding and managing the herd. The scrub cow is gradually giving up her place to the high grade and the pure bred. The modern dairy farm now has the latest and the best machinery and equipment for saving labor. The herdsman must be skilled in the care and management of the herd, and must </seg>
            <seg id="p026">27 know how to put together a ration that will cause each cow to produce the greatest amount of milk for a given amount of feed. A number of agencies have made valuable contributions to ihe dairy industry. Among these could be mentioned the work of the University and the Experiment Station. They have, through the station work and the extension service, given valuable help in selecting better animals for the farms, and in planning suitable rations 1 that would at the same time save the farmer the greatest amount on his feed bills. In addition to this, the University Dairy Department has served as a common meeting place, and a place where the best interests of all phases 1 of the dairy industry might be considered. The different organizations and co-operative associations have helped the dairy farmer to realize the importance of his business. They have helped him to market his product to a better advantage than could be done as individuals. Co-operative buying of material, as well as co-operative cow testing and co-operative bull associations', have each had a place in bringing about better cattle, better methods, and in general, better conditions for the dairyman. The dairy farmer has perhaps been a little slow in realizing that it costs him real money and real labor to produce real milk, and that he is entitled to a just return for these. It is only within the past few years that any attention has been given by the dairymen to cost accounting, whereby it becomes possible for them to arrive at a fair and uniform price for a uniform product. It is not possible to mention all the agencies that have contributed to the benefit of the dairy industry. However, some of the more recent ones are included in the late dairy legislation, which provides for tuberculin testing and a closer inspection of dairy products. These facts, together with the present knowledge of the importance of dairy products rs a part of our food, give the dairyman a right to be proud of the industry of which he is a part. (Applause.) The dairymen of Nebraska have also a right to be proud because rf the fact that Nebraska is now producing more than seven million acros of corn, and more than a million of alfalfa. With these feeds as a foundation, a balanced ration may be had for the dairy cow, and It 's produced as cheaply in Nebraska as elsewhere. This in turn will mean greater production of human food; will build soil fertility, and will mean larger yields per acre for our grain crops, thereby paying bet^r interest on the investment on this high-priced land. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: Ladies and Gentlemen, our Dean is not here; so we will take up "Tubercular Demonstration" — something that will be very valuable to us farmers; something a good many of us do not know anything about. It is going to be interesting and going to teach us something in the future; and we are also going to take this back home and tell our neighbors. I have the pleasure of introducing to you Dr. Van Es. (Applause.) </seg>
            <seg id="p027">28 TUBERCULAR DEMONSTRATION Dr. L. Van Es Mr. Chairman and Gentlemen of the Nebraska Dairymen's Associa - tion: Professor Frandsen asked me to come here and show you something about tuberculosis. We may sum up some of the things that are perhaps of interest to those who are confronted with this as a practical problem. Looking at the subject of tuberculosis from a historical point of view, I would say there have been several stages in the mind of the public at large towards this disease; and we might begin with the stage of profound ignorance, which lasted thousands of years, possibly. Then we took tuberculosis as a thing for granted. When people would die of tuberculosis, we thought it was something that had to be. When the herds of cattle, especially some of the better type of animals and the dairy cow would, as they called it, just "peter out and die," they did not suspect the cause, or realize the extent of these gradual losses, because they did not keep books. Patrons would call our attention to what they called "grapes," or what not. That was the day of ignorance. This day of profound ignorance made way for semi-ignorance, when we knew, and we did not know. People began to suspect that after all this disease might be something that is transmissible. There had been suspicion aroused, and when things commenced to narrow down and people had to be more careful about their business, it commenced to dawn on some folks that this "pearl" disease might be transmitted from animal to animal. When you may say modern medicine was born, experiments were made showing it was possible to transmit the disease of man to other animals, and it was found to be true this disease could be transmitted — that the animal inoculated would develop the same disease as the man from whom it was taken. The manner in which that was brought about was not known. Where those observations were going on, there arose another thing. It was discovered that at least in some of the diseases that were com - municated from man to man or animal to animal, or vice versa, they were due to living organisms — to small living plants or animals which were inhabiting the animal as parasites, and capable of producing changes and upsetting the animal organism in such a way as to produce a definite disease. It has been shown in the case of the silk worm dis - ease in France. It was then that the germ theory came on. It set many investigators at work. It showed the road upon which the dis - ease problem had to be attacked eventually. In 1883 the Government Physician announced he had discovered the germ that could be held to be responsible for the disease known as Kerculosis in men and cattle and other animals. I think with that ;overy the period of ignorance came to an end, because there was </seg>
            <seg id="p028">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 29 light thrown on the path ot the investigator; and although we had to be careful not to stumble, there was light ahead, and we could work out a system by which eventually we might hope to conquer this in - cubus. However, the period when the densest ignorance about the sub - ject came to an end doesn't mean the goal was reached. We had to go through some other remarkable periods which followed one another quite rapidly. The first period that followed the discovery of the tuberculosis germ was the period I call hysteria. People became hysterical about the thing and commenced to work on peculiar schemes and doctrines. They proposed just simply to kill the animals that had the disease, and that would be the last of them. But it did not work out that way, because for every animal that would show disease, there were ten they did not find it on. There are various stages of this disease. It does not come on like a case of pneumonia. You cannot tell with tubercu - losis. However, they became encouraged by the discovery of a specific method of diagnosis. They said, "We will pick out the tubercular animals and put the disease under the ground." They failed because they began five hundred years too late to do it. In many countries to - day, to kill every tubercular animal would so reduce the number of breeding animals it would cripple the animal industry the world over. It was obnoxious to say to a man about his herd, "This animal must be killed." It resulted in failure. They tried it thoroughly in Belgium and in our State of Massachusetts. There was not money enough the taxpayers could throw into the hole to cover it up. Other methods must necessarily be followed. Then we came gradually into the last stage of our knowledge, which perhaps will be followed by still another one or two. The stage we find ourselves in today is practically the same, but in two particulars: First of all, we have learned by theoretical knowledge and practical application that the disease can be conquered and pushed out of the couotry; and the other thing is that it can only be done when the man who owns the cattle says it shall be done. The whole question of tuberculosis rests with the man on the farm. The doctors may devise the most ingenious ways it can be done; but as long as the man who has the cattle in charge is not in sympathy or familiar with what is wanted, there is no hope of ever curing tuberculosis or any other animal disease we have. We have gradually reached this stage: The men re - sponsible for the management of our herds have come to the conclusion tuberculosis is too expensive a proposition to let grow. That aspect of mind is coming about when many of the breeders' associations give evidence of a hearty good will to conquer this disease. Animals are becoming more and more valuable. That is an especially fortunate position. It is fortunate that it is verified by a definite knowledge on the part of dairymen. As a matter of fact, I run across both dairymen and breeders who. as far as tuberculosis is concerned, are pretty thoroughly familiar with </seg>
            <seg id="p029">30 the essentials of the thing, and will keep the herd clean. Yet there are some who have not thought very deeply on the subject; who have not had their attention called to it in a very forcible way — which is to have it in their own cattle. For the benefit of those, I may be permitted to sum up what the essentials are concerning the question of tuberculosis in our cattle, and the prevention of the disease. There have developed in the course of our evolution of knowledge certain definite pieces of knowledge that are applicable to almost any transmissible disease, and notably so in tuberculosis. In the first place, the disease has only one cause, and that is the specific parasite which can only produce this characteristic disturbance of the animal body we know as tubercular lesions. That cause may be facilitated in its operation. Unsanitary premises will en - courage the development of tuberculosis; under-feeding, bad housing, over-crowding and over-work will facilitate it; but they cannot cause tuberculosis per se. The germ has to be there. Give me a herd of cattle free of tuberculosis, and you will find the disease can only be caused by the germ, just as typhoid fever can only be caused by the typhoid organism. They are for a great part absolutely specific. Keep that in mind. The second piece of information that has gradually crystallized out of all those investigations of the last fifty years is that when those specific organisms are produced, they only grow and multiply in the animal body that is susceptible. We do not find the tubercular germ running around our pastures and multiplying, or in the milk. We do not find it multiplying in the empty stables. Take the cattle out and leave the tubercular germs behind, and they will die. The animal body is the breeding place of those particular germs, which applies not only to tuberculosis, but to most of the specific diseases. You will find tuberc - ular bacillus in the laboratory; but you may ask, "What cow or man or hog did you come from?" If it is intelligent it can tell you. So in our herds, in fighting disease in cattle, we have often in the past been induced to look at the wrong places. We think a soap factory causes us to have scarlet fever! It is impossible. They can turn your stomach, but they can't give you a communicable disease. Nor will a filthy manure pile cause disease of a specific nature. It may breed flies which carry disease, but per se it will not cause disease. So we must find the fountain head of tuberculosis, which is the living animal. There is the only place where the germ of the disease can multiply, and it is the multiplication of the germs that is responsible for the spread of disease. If they did not multiply, the disease would die out. There is the key to the whole situation. If you have a clean herd of cattle and allow no tubercular animal to come in contact with the herd, you need not fear tuberculosis. Now how is it transmitted? If we understand that, we have the great secret of preventing tuberculosis in your herd. How does a germ from one animal get to the other? Because we might put a fence up </seg>
            <seg id="p030">THIRT Y-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 31 before he goes through. The art of disease prevention is to put up barriers that the germs cannot get through, without getting knocked on the head. If a typhoid organism comes to the door, we knock it down. Through what holes in the fence did those germs from the unhealthy animal become transmitted to his healthy neighbor? We have first direct contact. That means rather an intimate asso - ciation of one animal with another. Before we can understand that, we should inquire by what channels does the tubercular germ leave the body of this diseased animal? How does it get out? Because we com - mence to look at some of those specimens and you would wonder how it gets out, since nature &amp;s a rule is a pretty fair disease preventive by making an attempt to keep disease confined in its own locality. it gets out on account of a breaking up of the infected tissues and the escape of the germ on the surface of some of the organs connect - ing with the outside. There is an example of tuberculosis of the lungs. When you find it is greatly changed, softens, breaks down, then some of the broken-down lung tissue will discharge into some of the air tubes and be thrown out. With many cows you have no trouble picking up some of the germs you can gather from the windpipe or the nose. What happens to those? Perhaps in cattle it is more dfflicult than in man. In man the germ can be spit out. Man is the only animal that has acquired a good many peculiar attributes, and one of these is, he has learned how to expectorate. He is the only animal who can do a good job of it. He spreads out millions of germs which are ground into dust, and away she goes! The cow has not learned to spit. When she gets anything in her throat, she swallows it. When she swallows secre - tion from the disease germs, the germ passes into the digestive organs and passes out of the body with the bowel excreta, in the majority of cases being alive, because the tubercular germ is so constituted that not many of the chemicals it meets in the digestive apparatus of the animal will kill it. It does not propagate itself there, but the manure of fhe tubercular cow is perhaps one of the most potent factors which bring about the distribution of the disease, because stable manure will eventually dry up, be ground into dust, and It will settle on the food or into the drinking water which the cattle come in contact with. Another way is the discharge of the nose. Very often you find in the case of contaminated drinking water in cow stables, with each cow standing in her own stall, the disease goes from one to the other and follows the row like a row of dominos. This animal delivers a certain amount of bacteria in the drinking water, and the others take it up, and by and by, away she goes! Other means are produced by indirect contact. This includes all which is brought about by intermediary things, and the milk plays a part. The udder is one of the mechanisms by which the disease germ can escape from the body. Animals which have a healthy udder, but tuberc - ulosis in other parts of the body, have bacilli in the milk. It is looked upon as one of the principal factors responsible for the spread of dis - ease. It may be fed to calves. </seg>
            <seg id="p031">32 It is perhaps the truth, although we have no way of checking it up, that tuberculosis is usually contracted very early in life. Our greatest authorities think all tuberculosis is contracted before a person is five years old. I do not like to say to what extent that is true. So it is said calves getting tuberculous milk furnish the largest number of tubercular cows for the future. There was a time when we had our skimming station where we used to cake our milk every day, and we would take the skim milk back to feel our cattle and hogs. It was one of the great clearing houses. Everybody brought milk — perhaps from thirty farms. It went through the separator and the skim milk came out and was hauled away to other farms. If there was one of those contributing herds which had tuberculosis, sooner or later the germs found their way to the skimming station, and the rest of the fellows got their share and took it home. Perhaps much disease can be traced to those old skimming stations. In my travels in Denmark, I visited one of the celebrated tubercu - losis workers at Copenhagen. We were sitting in his laboratory and visiting away when one of his assistants came in and told him of cer - tain packages that had come in for examination. It proved to be horse material. I said, "Have you tuberculosis in horses here?" "Yes; our farmers are in the habit of feeding the skim milk to their horses, and we get every year great numbers of cases of horse tubercu - losis on that account." While Denmark is a thoroughly organized country, and can boast of the best method of dealing with tuberculosis, yet the dairy cattle of Denmark become very heavily loaded with tuberculosis. Now perhaps we would like to know a little bit as to what the dis - ease is, and I would call attention to some of the specimens which I have brought. The essential tuberculous process is the formation of a small nodule in which the germ grows, causing tissue death and the formation of new tissue. Then little nodules are formed that break down and become soft and cheesy. You will find it in all the organisms, al - though in cattle the lungs are the worst involved. You find it in the mem - brane that lines the inside of the chest and outside of the lungs, in the cavity of the belly, in the liver and spleen. The losses occasioned by this disease are terrific, although we do not seem to feel it because it is insidious. It works slowly. It is not a spectacular disease like anthritis, or blackleg. There you get a little action for your money. You go to the stable and there are several animals lying dead. It works accompanied by a brass band which will let you know it is there. Tuberculosis will work insidiously. After a few years animals commence to die, but you do not feel that very much until the whole herd is practically gone. There are, however, terrific losses. I consider it is the heaviest incubus that rests on the cattle in - dustry of every civilized country today. If we consider our own coun - try, a man told about the figures of the animals condemned for tubercu - losis, and summed it up by saying: "In 1916 there were condemned at </seg>
            <seg id="p032">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 33 the United States inspected slaughter houses, which involve half the meat slaughtered in this country, enough tuberculous material to fill fifty trains of forty freight cars each!" That was at a time when the beefsteak and the pork chops were getting pretty small, yet they were condemned. Perhaps what would be more interesting to you at this time is the means of prevention we have on hand that we can employ. The cow with the disease is the fountain head of the infection. At one time we could not find all of those. Now we can, practically. The ones we do not catch are a negligible quantity — that is by means of a tubercular est which most of you have seen used, and will not be described unless somebody particularly desires it. It is the, principal factor upon which tuberculosis prevention hangs today. We can remove the animal that is diseased. It is an extremely effi - cient test, but it will not say how much tuberculosis the animal has. twill tell you it has the infection, but it does not say how much. Yet, portant as that seems, it does not really matter very much. Many observations have shown a reactive animal is always a dangerous animal. We have seen where the animal which has an open tubercu - losis is to be eliminated, and the ones with the closed tuberculosis can be kept in the herd. I have seen it worked "out where in spite of large appropriations of money, they never accomplished their purpose. The closed tubercular animal of today is the open one of tomorrow. Such animals are responsible for Introducing tuberculosis into the herds. It is necessary to keep the reactive animal from infecting others, even if it is not necessary to slaughter the animal. Let us start out with the infected heed. At the present time this is' an easy question to answer. Under stress of disease, ways and means have been devised to make it easy for anybody to know what to do. The State of Nebraska has entered into different agreements with the United States Department of Agriculture by which herds can be tested, the reacting animals eliminated, and the ones that have to be killed paid for partially, so that the owner does not have to carry the whole loss. The State carries one-third; the United States, one-third, and the owner the rest. Now I am not enthusiastic about slaughter in all cases. I do not like to slaughter animals for breeding purposes. I would kill the tuberculosis animal of no particular breed or value; but take animals of good blood and you can segregate them in such a way you can raise a healthy calf from that infected cow. The cow should be segregated, and the minute the calf is born it must be taken away from her. It is surprising how short an exposure will infect this calf. With the ordi - nary herd that does not boast of high-blooded cows, of course this is not necessary. The next step in the eradication of the disease is 1 to keep animals free of the disease; to prevent any reactive animal to be introduced into this particular herd. If you have a clean herd you can keep it </seg>
            <seg id="p033">34 clean until Gabriel blows bis horn If you do not let any tuberculous animal In, or feed products which are infected. You have to buy stock once in a while, and tills Is where most of us allow the disease to break through. It Is extremely difficult to go to a sale and buy milk cows such as you would buy in great numbers without running the risk of tuberculosis. The great secret ol tuberculosis prevention among dairymen is to breed as much as possible your own female stock. That is one of the keys to the situation of saving our herds from tuberculosis. I think with these remarks I have touched upon the essence of the subject. I win snow you these specimens. No. 1 represents the lining of the chest, No. 2 is an infected liver. No. 3 is a piece of the ribs. No. 4 is a piece of a tuberculous lung. I remember this 1 cow. Any ol you would be willing to pay a good price for her. She was a family cow and giving good milk. We gave her the tuberculosis test and she reacted. There was nothing to do but kill the cow, and it was sur - prising how badly she was affected. She might just as well have had wooden lungs as far as respiration was concerned. No. 5 are some of the generative organs. No. 6 are the spleens of three tuberculous hogs No. 7 is the liver of a hog. No. 8 shows tuberculosis of the bone of a hog. Hogs show this form ot tuberculosis more often than any animal except man. Hog tuberculosis is always cow tuberculosis transferred. He follows the cattle in the yards, and there is where he gets his tuberculosis. When you think your cattle are all right and ship your hogs and hear some are affected with tuberculosis, go home to your herd and Bee where it is, because you will find it. At one time I found myself in charge of the veterinary service of the State. I made arrangements that all hogs going from that State with tuberculosis should be reported to me. When I got the reports from the government experts they were found to be tubercular, I would advise the owner of the hogs. Between twenty and thirty asked me what to do. I advised them to have their cattle tested and see if they would not give the answer. In every case it was found in their cattle. Whenever they found it in their hogs, they would get all the way from 5 to 95 per cent of reaction in their cattle. No. 9 shows tuberculosis of chickens and turkey. They had a habit of keeping their poultry indoors, which was responsible for a great deal or their tuberculosis. We could figure three days before Thanksgiving El Christmas we had a time examining the turkey livers. The woman uld see the bumps on the livers and want to know what was the tter with the turkey. We can separate the two kinds fairly well. It is not possible the tuberculosis of the poultry has anything to do with the tuberculosis of </seg>
            <seg id="p034">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 35 attle or hogs. Once in a while we can produce a positive infection. t is possible the reverse is the case. My opinion Is as far as the pre - ention of bovine tuberculosis is concerned, you need not worry much bout the chickens, either as a source or a result of the animal disease. We made some experiments in which we took some chickens and in - ectt&gt;d them with bovine and human bacilli, and they became very poor nd looked like they were tubercular; but when they died I could not nd anything that looked like tuberculosis. I took a little bit of the iver and injected the guinea pigs, and it was found their livers were warming with disease. A chicken might go to the slaughter house nd feed up on those lungs and carry the disease to a cow stable, lthough I think it does not happen very often. I believe I have given you the most essential parts. If I can illus - trate further, I will be glad to answer questions, if the Chairman will permit it. I want to thank you for your patience. (Applause.) QUESTIONAIRE Q. I would like to ask how long after you injected this into a critter that that will last— that is, how long does she have to be left before you inject again? A. I think, to make it reasonably safe, sixty days. Many of them will react in a week, but there is danger. Q. Would you consider an animal properly tested if she had been tested, and in 65 or 70 days she reacted badly so that she had to go to the Omaha market? could that be possible? She had been tested and got by, and the second test she was found to be diseased. A. I would like to see the age of the lesions of the cow before I could answer "Yes" or "No." Q. You think it would be possible for it to lie dormant? A. She may have contracted the disease after the first test. We can distinguish whether the lesion is old or young. You cut through a tuberculous lesion and it is like cutting through a sack of sand. Q, After killing them you know whether they have it or not? a. You always know that; yes, sir. Q. What precaution has a person to take in order to keep a valu - able animal on the premises and not infect the rest of the herd? a. Keep them so there is no contact. You can put a partition in the stable. Make the partition pretty tight. One time a breeder of Shorthorns wakened up to the fact they had tuberculosis, and they were very valuable. He tried to segregate the diseased cattle. It did well for a year and he made the second test. We found in the so-called healthy herd two or three reactors. We could not tell where it came from. There had never been any contact. I at first thought these </seg>
            <seg id="p035">36 animals had not reacted the first time. Then I thought it might he possible to find out where the leak was. Finally I said, "Let's go to the pastures." He had two pastures side by side. He had put two wire fences between. A little ways off I saw a windmill. "Is that the place where they get their water?" I asked. Yes.' That was the whole thing. There was a round tank and they could both reach it. It is the easiest thing in the world to make mistakes about. After you think you have the thing cinched, examine every day. Q. Did I understand you to say most of the cattle took it when young? Would there be a possibility for that germ to lie dormant and not react if tested? A. Not likely. Q. If there was the least bit, it would react? A. Yes, sir. Q. In segregating animals that have reacted, do you think it neces - sary to remove all the manure from the animals you have segregated? A. The manure of reacting animals is always a source of danger, and the disposal of it should be made with that thought in mind. If you take it out and scatter it over a field, the organisms will die. But do not scatter it over the pasture where the cattle are. Wait several months. You can pack the manure and let it get hot. Q. Would it be possible for an animal to react and not find any lesions in a microscopic test? A. The tubercular test is so much more delicate than our eyes there is no comparison. You may have a tubercular lesion the size of a grain of wheat, but you will never find it. The reaction tells the in - fection is present somewhere. We used to be very much disappointed. We would get into arguments about the tubercular tests. Some fellow would sue us for damages because he did not find lesions; but the veterinary doctors have shown there is nothing to that. It was like a man who was a typhoid carrier. He has the germs all the while, and once in a while he scatters them. By blood tests we can pick up that. If you examined his body you might not find any lesion. So with the reacting tubercular animal. You do find lesions in perhaps 80 per cent of the cases. The more recent the infection, the more powerfully does it react. If an animal has had it for ten days, is dumpy, and stands shivering, they are the very animals where you won't find a lesion. Q. Do you take the position the tubercular bovine is likely to give the disease to the human family? A. Yes, it can do so. Q. Do you take the position the human tuberculosis is given to the bovine? </seg>
            <seg id="p036">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 37 ** A. Yes. If you take monkeys and inject one group with bovine and one with human, you will find the bovine organism proves the more Virulent. Fight It because the disease la disastrous to your own in - dustry. We used to preach the disease must be fought because it was a menace to humanity. I am positive the great bulk of tubercular people get their disease from human infection. I think it is wrong in a public health measure to induce people to bark up the wrong tree. If we have to fight human tuberculosis, make the man sate (or his surrounding, and do not make the milk supply to blame for it. I think we must be truthful to the facts. I have done a fairly good share of tuberculosis work, and I find bacilli that look like the typical bovine type, and they look like human cultures. I cannot tell. I do not like to make myself responsible. I maintain a certain amount of human tuberculosis — especially of the glands, like scrofula and bone tubercu - losis — is due to bovine origin; but I think the great bulk of the infec - tion of the human comes from the humans. I brought these specimens here because I have often thought you would like to know what the disease is like, although it must be said most of the animals that react do not show lesions like that. Most ot thesre specimens are old lesions. I thank you, gentlemen. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: In behalf of the Association, I want to thank Dr. Van Es for his splendid lecture. I am only sorry every dairyman and cattle raiser in the State of Nebraska was not here to hear him. Professor Frandsen tells me that Dean Burnett has another engage - ment and cannot get here until tomorrow morning. We would like to hear from some of those in the audience, and I will first call upon Mr, Gustafson. MR. GTISTAFSON: Mr. Chairman: I was wondering since Dean Burnett's address has been put off until tomorrow, if it would not be advisable to have the report of the Committee on the Revision 'of the Constitution and By- Laws this afternoon? If it is agreeable and ac - ceptable and proper, would like to make a motion to the effect that we call for this report at this time. The motion was seconded and carried. </seg>
            <seg id="p037">38 REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE ON REVISION OF THE CONSTITU - TION AND BY-LAWS Constitution and By-Laws of the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association (1) This Association shall be known as the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association. (2) The principal place of transacting the business of this association shall be where the Secretary has his residence in this State. (3) The general nature of tbe business shall be tbe promotion of the dairy interests in the State of Nebraska. (4) This association shall contract no indebtedness and incur no liabili - ties whatever except by approval of its directors and in no case for an amount exceeding funds available for the fiscal year. (5) Section l. The officers ot the Association shall consist of a Presi - dent, Vice-President, Secretary, Treasurer and Five Directors. Section 2. The officers of the Association shall be chosen annually from the members of the Association, at the regular annual meeting and shall hold their offices tor the year following their election and until their successors shall be chosen. (6) The President, Secretary and Directors shall constitute a Board of Managers who shall manage the affairs and control the business of the Association during the time that the Association is not in session. A majority of the Board, at a regular called meeting, shall constitute a quorum to transact business. (T) The Secretary shall audit and pay all the bills against this Asso - ciation where the amount is for a less sum than Five Dollars ($5). In the incurring of expense all payment of bills against the Association of an amount greater than the sum of Five Dollars (?5), the Secretary shall obtain the written consent of the President and Directors of the Association. All of said transactions to be laid before the Association at its next annual meeting for inspection and approval. (8) tThe Treasurer shall give bond in the sum of Two Thousand Dollars ,000), the same to be approved by the Board of Directors, and to be tne custody of the President (9) The annual meeting of the members of the Association for the elec - tion of officers shall be held at Lincoln. Nebraska, during the week of Organized Agriculture. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">THIRTY"!^ IFTxi A pi W UAL LUN V X!*W 1 HJ*N 39 By-Laws (1) Each member shall pay an annual assessment of One Dollar into the treasury of the Association. (2) The payment of Five Dollars at any one time shall exempt the member from the payment of annual dues. (3) Public notice of all regular meetings of the Association shall be given by the Secretary at least twenty -days before the meetings and a written or printed notice shall be given to each of the members thereof at least five days before the meeting. (4) All meetings of the Board of Managers shall be called by the Presi - dent or Secretary, or any three of the Board of Managers, notice of which shall be given to the members thereof, at least five days before the meeting. (5) Any vacancy that may occur in the Board of Managers may be filled by appointment by the Board tor the unexpired term for which such officer was chosen. (6) Section 1. Any person who is a resident of the State of Nebraska and who is a producer, or who directly represents producers, may be - come an active member of this Association, by paying in advance, a membership fee of $1.00 per year and subscribing to the Constitution and By-Laws. Section 2. Any person distinguished by his service to the dairy in - dustry may be elected an Honorary Member by a majority vote at any regular business meeting of the Association. Such membership shall expire at the end of two years unless re-elected. (7) The Board of Managers shall fix the salaries of the Secretary and Treasurer, and may authorize the paying actual expenses of the officers and directors incurred while transacting the business of the Association. (8) Section 1. This 1 Constitution and By-Laws shall become effective immediately upon adoption. Section 2. This Constitution or By-Laws may be amended or changed by a two-thirds vote of all the members present at any annual meeting. MEMBER: Are these to supersede our old Constitution? THE SECRETARY: It is a revision of the one made thirty-live </seg>
            <seg id="p039">40 years ago, which has been butchered so that we have practically no Constitution and By-Laws. Now we have something to work on. H. C. YOUNG: I move the adoption of the Constitution and Laws. The motion was seconded by Mr. Templin, and carried by a rising </seg>
            <seg id="p040">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL, CONVENTION- 41 REPORT OF THE SECRETARY-TREASURER Mr. J. E. Palm, Lincoln, Nebraska January 21, 1920. Mr. President and Members of the Dairymen's Association The report of the Secretary given you today will be a short synopsis of what the Association has accomplished the past year. The detailed reports and other interesting items will be given at length in the year book. On February 26th of last year, when the dairymen assumed control of the Dairymen's Association, to whom it rightfully belonged (th.j pro - ducer), we felt that we had made a start towards making this Associa - ttun what it was intended for, a Dairymen's Association, and not a manufacturers' association. The Legislature was in and we had had no time to prepare for any legislative bills, your officers and directors were on the watch to see that no bills were passed that would be of great detriment to the milk producer. We are pleased to say that what we went after we obtained very satisfactory results on. We decided that we would like to see the con - sumer and the producer getting closer together and we had made up two sets of display fixtures that gave very interesting information, both as to the value of milk as a food product; also information as to feed - ing and caring tor the dairy cow at the lowest possible cost, and at the same time obtain the best results. These exhibits In connection with other milk information, was shown at eight county fairs 1 in various parts of the state with an experienced dairyman in charge; explaining the value of milk as a food product and answering the questions on the various points of dairying that the public may desire. We find that the results were very gratifying. At the State Pair at Lincoln we had a very nice exhibit and also had on display the variour - forms that milk could be used in, and we had experienced demonstrat - ors there educating the public the various ways in which to prepare this food. The State Fair Board kindly gave us, or set aside, Wednes - day of that week and called it "Dairy Day," the first time that it had ever been done. Mr. D. D. Aitken of Flint, Michigan, a speaker of na - tional fame, gave a very interesting lecture that day, and it was ad - judged by the crowd that attended that day that it was a day long to be remembered. Your officers and directors had a thousand posters made, like the ones you see hanging in this room; these were displayed at all our various exhibits, and one was sent to every County Superin - tendent of Schools in the State. Also one was mailed to most of the banks in the State, with a request that they be posted so the public might get more information on milk as a food value. We also had 20,000 colored postcards printed, a facsimile of the largo posters, and they have been given a liberal distribution through - out the state. The more publicity we can give as to the Importance of using milk and butter and the various products made from milk, as </seg>
            <seg id="p041">42 to their food value, in place of using so-called substitutes, as we all know there are no substitutes discovered as yet that can take the place of milk and the products made from milk as a food value, the more milk will be consumed and a greater demand will be created for same. With the demand increasing means increased revenue for the milk pro- ducer. The Dairy Association has lent assistance in every way that it could to straighten out the griefs and tribulations of the milk pro- ducer. We also encourage the Boys and Girls' Clubs to learn the art of Judging. We gave a prize of $15.00 to the Boys' and Girls' Club judging team of Scottsbluff. For this coming year we see great possibilities for the Dairy Associa- tion, and I hope that at this meeting you will all stand together and and give every assistance you can to continue this as 1 a Dairymen's Association, i would suggest that we put on a "Better Bull" campaign, for I believe tMat the success of the dairymen will be quickened by the introduction of pure bred stock into their herds. Would also like to state that great credit is due Prof. J. H. Frandsen for the wonderful as- sistance that he has given the Association this year in furnishing facts and figures to the milk producers, assisting them in ascertaining the cost Of production, as well as 1 many other educational features. I herewith submit my financial report and as you will see we have finished the year with a surplus on hand sufficient to care for all the expenses of this annual meeting. On February 26th, 1919, we took over the Association with a deficit and there have several bills appeared during the year that were left unpaid by the former administration. I thank you. » General Summary of Receipts and Expenses for 1919 Lincoln, Nebraska, January 1st, 1920. Receipts Cash received from R. W. McGinnis $ 47.79 Rec3lved from memberships 78.00 Received from state appropriation 1,500.00 Received from state appropriation 1,000.00 Total $2,625.79 Expenditures Salaries, officers, etc S 500.00 Other services, etc 11.25 Books and printing 385.18 Telegrams 3.94 Postage and parcel post 37.00 Mileage and travel expenses, officers, delegates, etc 276.04 Office supplies 4.10 State Fair exhibit 327.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 43 County Fair exhibits 283.49 Fixtures , 111.44 Boad for treasurer 5.00 Total $1,944.44 Cash on hand January 1st, 1920 681.35 Total $2,625.79 J. E. PALM, Sec.-Tres. PROFESSOR FRANDSEN: I move you the report of the Treasurer be referred to the Auditing Committee. The motion was seconded and carried. THE PRESIDENT: I will appoint the following as an AUDITING COMMITTEE H. C. Grau T. E. Snodgrass H. C. Young MR. C. E. MORSE: I would like to hear some of these farmers ex - press their opinion as to what they think the organization has done and ought to do, and whether they feel it has been of any benefit to them financially, morally, physically, religiously, or any other way in the last year; and any suggestions for its improvement. I would like to have them all take a hand. THE PRESIDENT: We hare with us the President of the Farmers' Union and would like to hear from him. MR. C. H. GUSTAFSON: I should think they would be sick and tired of listening to me! I want to say I feel good to think the dairy interests of Nebraska have come into the hands of the dairy producers. I feel pleased to think we have adopted a Constitution and By-Laws that will keep them in the hands of the farmers and producers. I of course am advocating very strongly organization among producers, for the reason that by observing what the other fellow has done, we have found that about the only thing we can do to save ourselves is to organize. I have taken a keen interest in the welfare of the dairy business for a number of years, for several reasons. One reason is I think it is one of the hardest parts of the work of the farmer — the most unpleasant. It is all the time. It is every day — Sunday, Christmas, Fourth of July, and every day. It is one of the Jobs most of the farm children do not like very well, because it is hanging on all the time. I think any kind of a Job of that kind ought to be paid for well. I do not think any - one should be asked to perform a duty to his fellow man of that kind at a loss. There are some things' we would not mind so much doing </seg>
            <seg id="p043">44 at cost, but 1 think the dairy business should be well paid for. Any - one who has tried it will agree it does not pay very well. * I have milked cows for forty-seven years, practically. I started to milk when I was six years old, and quit milking cows about two years ago; so I have a good idea about what it is. If anything can be done to create interest in the dairy business and make it better and more pleasant, that is exactly what we want. Milk and its products are the most healthful and necessary products we produce. Milk is necessary for the welfare of human beings. I came to Nebraska in 1869, and we broke the virgin soil, and found it fertile, and there was no trouble raising a crop. We raised Wheat and corn until we have come to the place where we must do something else. You people who have traveled in the south and have observed what has happened down there will realize what is going to happen to Nebraska sooner or later. It is a beautiful garden spot, but it won't produce forever without putting something back into it. For keeping tbe Eoil fertile, if anyone has devised a better plan than the raising of live stock and the dairy industry, I do not know what it is. For that reason I think everyone who has the welfare of the State of Nebraska at heart should be very much interested in the dairy business and live stock production. I repeat, how can you expect the farmer to be in - terested in it unless he can at least make both ends meet? Now, then, we know what the trouble is. What is the remedy? It is for us to get together and work out our own salvation, because nobody is going to do it for us. Whether we be dairymen, poultry raisers, corn and hog producers or wheat producers makes no differ - ence. We must work out our own salvation, and it can only be done through organization. An organization of this kind is valuable, but I am sorry It is im - possible for the farmers to be present in large numbers. I would like to see several hundred ot the fanners who milk cows present at these meetings and arrive at the best possible solution. None of us can give you a 100 per cent cure for these things. We do not do that in farmers' organizations; but we get together to work out plans the majority can agree on, and get busy and push them to successful completion. There is no question the dairymen need to be organized as well as anyone else. $ Right down in my heart I do not like organization. I wish we were all so good and pure we did not need organization; but we cannot have what we wish, so we must meet the thing just as it is. Now we have the forces organized against us, and what is up to us to do? Nothing but to organize, too. And for goodness' sake get out Of the idea Some - body is going to come around and give you a good start. He won't do it. YOU must do these things for yourselves. Every other way has been tried time and again, and they all worked OUt the Other Way. We have been told for years how this thifag could be done if we would lust let them do it for us. We tried that. Let's quit our kicking and com- </seg>
            <seg id="p044">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 45 plaining and use all our energy and a few of our dollars to make the changes we need. That's what we need, and that's what we are doing, and doing successfully — co-operation, il you please. That's the greatest word in the American dictionary today. The more we co-operate the more we will succeed. The more we support co-operation, the more it will do for us. That's the whole thing. The dairyman ought to be interested in present legislation pending at Washington, especially the legislation affecting the packing in - dustries. The "Big Five" are not satisfied with selling hogs and sheep and cattle. They have gone into six hundred different kinds of busi - ness, and are now manufacturing buttons for our coats, combs to comb our hair, and goodness knows what they have overlooked! They have reached the point where they practically control food products — not only meat, but dairy. The American people could not stand it any longer, so they started legislation. After we got them on the hip, they went to the Attorney General. I hope it does not fool anybody. It isn't what they promised tbe Attorney General, but what is interesting us is, what the Attorney General promised them. Don't lie down on this important legislation at Washington, and don't be scared of the fellow who hollers about "injustice," because • we are not trying to do an injustice. We are just trying to make them be good Just like we have to be. We are not asking them to do anything we are not going to do. We are not ask - ing for any law to be enforced on them we are not willing to have en - forced on us. All we ask for is justice and to prevent special privilege. We are asking that the terminal points be made a terminal body on equal terms. Why not make your little stock yard at your station a privately owned stock yard. The transportation system, whether owned by the railroad company or the government, includes these stock yards and loading stations along the line. But at the end of the road there is a private bunch that owns and controls It. It is not right and has not worked out right. We are not going to take it away, but pay every dollar it is worth and put it into the transportation system where it belongs. They have special privileges of shipping, and their private meat cars have the right-of-way over the stuff you and I ship. Why give them belter service than anyone else gets? The records are their cars make 20 per cent better service than any other class of cars, because it is possible for them to keep control of them. Some of us have an idea we are going to have co-operative packing plants of our own. How can we compete as long as the other fellow has the privilege? The third point Is we would like to have the same advantages when we bring our meats to the different distributing centers as they have — rons that can handle fresh meats. We want the transportation com - es to own all that belongs to the transportation system, and Hot &amp; little chunk here and there to private invaders. That's the legislation </seg>
            <seg id="p045">46 we are asking (or. Somebody said in Omaha when we started to ad - vocate this legislation, "What's the use of monkeying? They are beat - ing the government already." If they are, I say It is time we are trying to do something. I hope each and every one of you interested in that matter will sit down and write to your congressman and senators your ideas, and what you want them to do on that. It is my privilege to go to Washington from time to time on legislation, meeting boards and some Of our officials on matters of various kinds; and if there is any one thing the congressmen and senators want more than anything else, it is the opinion of the majority they represent. That is what they are looking for. I have two letters from Nebraska congressmen asking for the opinion of the farmers of Nebraska on certain points. One says, "i understand there is a large bunch of you farmers advocating a cer - tain thing, but I have had letters from individuals advocating the oppo - site. Which do you want me to do?" We must get together and try to sing the same kind of a song at the same time. Otherwise we will bewilder our congressmen and senators and they won't know what we want. I am not advocating the farmers should go into partisan politics. I do not believe in it myself. But I do believe these farmers in Ne - braska should take an active interest in the welfare of our government and the welfare of our business and the welfare of our children to see we get laws that are just and fair to us. That is all we ask. I have never asked for a special privilege. I am absolutely opposed to any farmer getting any special privilege of any kind, and I am Just as much opposed to anybody else getting that special privilege. It would not get us anywhere excepting into trouble. Fair play to everybody is what we Stand for. What we need more than anything else is true co-opera - tion and more ot it among us farmers. I thank you. (Applause.) (Calls for Mr. Templin.) MR. TEMPLIN: I am not a speaker. I will say this, however, that I have been attending these conventions for fifteen or twenty years. During all that time, this is one thing I have discovered: There is a great proposition in the way this organization was run to buy a COW and make 300 to 500 pounds of butter. The parties who put up that kind of an argument were not putting up any money. According to the best information I can get, the average cow in the State of Nebraska makes about 130 pounds a year. So we have been beaten for the last fifteen years, according to Wisconsin and Iowa, by not co-operating and organ!2l!l2 and manufacturing our own products. Now the situation is this: Those communities made $9 a head from the average cow. They naturally would want you and I and every other man to put in a cow that would make twice that much. Then they would make $18 instead of $9. That was the kind of argument for rm. We eat there and took it all in and did not have stamina enough say, "Get out, and let us attend to that ourselves," </seg>
            <seg id="p046">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 47 Last year when I read in the paper the farmers had hold of this institution, I said, "Amen!" I am out of the business, but I want to tell you that you are starting now right where you should have started twenty years ago. You have them on the run, and you can keep them there as long as 1 you attend these meetings and attend to business. While I have retired, I expect to be here when I can. I enjoy these meetings. None of you has enjoyed the ousting last year as much as I have. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: I will appoint the following members as COMMITTEE ON RESOLUTIONS H. A. Morrison John Frazeur O. A. Severe. MR. JOHN FRAZEUR: I move we adjourn until 9:30 Thursday morning. The motion was seconded and carried. Adjournment </seg>
            <seg id="p047">48 THURSDAY MORNING SESSION January 22, 1920 The Convention was called to order in the Dairy Building by Presi - dent Sass at 10:30. IMPORTANCE OF THE SIRE Prof. j. w. Hendrickscn Mr. Chairman and Members of the Nebraska Dairy Association: The subject of the sire has perhaps been one of the old-time sub - jects. It has been discussed for a good many years and yet we find that people are hesitating in some localities about giving UP the scrub sire. I thought in taking up this subject we often talk upon the theoretical Standpoint, and say, "We have heard New York — or some other state — Is making an attempt to get rid Of the Scrub Sire and in its place they are potting the pure bred." I have not data of that kind to bring to you; but a little more than a year ago there were three of us in the College who became Interested in knowing What OUr herd bad been doing, and in making an investigation, the report centers around three Sires that we have found in the herd of the Dairy Department; and it is the result of those i will tell you a lew things about this morning. These sires were selected with the ordinary precautions of getting the best we could tor the money invested, with a view of bettering our herd conditions. They were sires that had come to the herd at different times, representing two different breeds. The first is that of a jersey sire purchased for the University herd about 1908. He re - mained in the herd for a good long time, and we had as a result twelve daughters from this sire coming from nine different dams. The pure bred sire is valued largely by the Influence he can make and the influence that would be felt through the next generation. The summary of each case is simply the results we have taken from ft period going back to about 1910-11 when the records of these daughters became known. These records were made in the first and second lacta - tion period, and we have made comparison in each case by taking the first lactation period of the dam and the first of the daughter; the same Of the Second, and on through. There were only twelve that had com - pleted from one to two lactation periods. It is possible that some one five years from now could take up this same subject and give more Information than we can give today. We find there was an increase of production in one generation of 42 per cent or more. The first HOlStein Sire Of importance was that of Prince Ormsby Mercedes Dekoi — a sire who remained only one year. Because of an unruly disposition, they got rid of him. We have only three daughters from this Sire, and they are from three of the best cow? we have ever had in the herd, one ot those cows has held the record for milk pro- </seg>
            <seg id="p048">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 49 auction in Nebraska until the last few months. Another cow is Kittle Gerben, the famous dairy cow of Nebraska. Her daughter in the first lactation period made an increase of 38 per cent in milk and of 73 per cent in butter during that same period, comparing the first lactation period of each one; and of 16 per cent in butter during the second lactation period. Going to the cow with the record for Nebraska, her daughter made an increase of 53 per cent in milk and 85 per cent in butter in the first period. In the second, she had an increase of 42 per cent in butter. This principal daughter of LaMay is still continuing her production. Within the last few weeks she has made a seven-day record of 723 pounds of milk and 34.42 pounds of butter. So even as a mature cow she is making approximately 54 per cent more than the dam. We hare taken only the average of the different animals we have taken here. The second Holstein sire following Prince Ormsby Mercedes Dekol was King Segis Hengerveld Vale. He remained in the herd for a longer period, but we have only six of his daughters. Of these we have a number of striking results. In one case the milk production was 106 per cent more than that of the dam. The butter production was 109 per cent more than the dam's in the first place. In making these com - parisons, we have not taken the poorest cows, but the best cows we have. In no case do they average extremely low. The production in the twelve Jerseys was above 250 pounds of fat. I think you heard the average cow was producing less than 130 pounds. If we compare with cows producing a greater amount of butter fat, it is possible with poorer cows to give an influence that would be greater. Of these six, four of them made a material increase in the produc - tion. In two cases for one period the- production was slightly under that of the dam. This will happen in any herd. We have compared twenty-one different daughters coming from sixteen different dams. It is possible to find an animal occasionally will decrease, even with the best care and ancestry. You cannot take any kind of a cow and get the best In the first generation. But we have made an average increase through the three sires of approximately 42 per cent in two generations. I have given in Circular 8 a little summary of the financial gains we might hope to get. These three sires cost the University a net sum of $420. Considering the amount we paid for them and the return we got in selling th'em left us $420. Using the 1918 price for butter fat during the two years, they brought a return of $1,246.14 over and above the value of the product of their dama. The sale of whole milk would have returned $2,137 over and above the value of the whole milk of their dams. During the same time the three daughters of Prince Ormsby Mercedes Dekol would have given a return of $1,169 in the price of whole milk. The butter fat sold from the six daughters of rig Segis would have given a gain of $759, and from the whole milk. $1,298, as a total. So we have approximately $4,000 increase from </seg>
            <seg id="p049">50 the sale of whole milk of these daughters over and above the produc - tion of their dam for a period of two years. Each daughter had in - creased the yalue of her product approximately $100 per year for the whole milk. You may say the 1918 price was higher than the average farmer re - ceived for his milk. I will grant it from 1910 up to the present time; but I am going to say we will cut that price in two, and even then we will find these daughters have given a production to equal $50 in money above that their dams would have produced. This 1 $2,000 that we got could also be considered a purchase price, and we could set that aside and still find we have a handsome return from the money we had invested. We have invested only $.420 in these three sires, and for two years' time, granting we took half the price, they have given us more than $2,000 pront for that $420 invested. These conditions are such that we do not have to go to New York State to get them. They are not conditions we framed up and got ready for you people, because they are conditions going on, and we took no account until all three sires were practically gone. It is im - possible to recall them. The most we received for any of those sires was $280 at the close of their term of service in the herd here. If we had known of their importance in the herd and the influence they were having, it would probably have taken $2,000 to be any inducement to sell them. We are following the influence of these two important sires with the present herd bull, for which the University has refused an offer of $10,000. We are hoping that our herd will be built up to something greater than it has been in the past. There is still one other point. This would not be complete or a fair consideration if you could not take the other side. If you care to read Bulletin 993, it describes conditions on a good many farms, and espe - cially the scrub sire. In one particular instance where a survey was made, the scrub sire decreased the production of the daughters, and in the second generation there was another Increase amounting to 45 per cent less than the dam. We have issued this report in the form of a circular which is for distribution, and the title is "Pure Bred Sires." It is known as Circular 8. We have also given a review of the publi - cation out to the newspapers so that results may be had more gen - erally. These results are from a practical breeder's standpoint. We can - not tell you everything about breeding or the influences that will affect your herds. The breeding problem is practically in its infancy. They are experimenting. Our herd is simply one of the stations in which the breeding problem is being carried on. The results of these experi - ments are yours. I believe if we have made for ourselves, as I think you will agree we have, several hundred dollars in increased produc - tion, you can do the same thing. In addition to that, these same animals are In our herd and will continue, some of them, for five or </seg>
            <seg id="p050">\ THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL, CONVENTION 51 six years. They have proven they are increasing their production, and we are able to put forward a better type of animal in the daughters than in the dams; so that you are increasing your herd from year to year. The pure bred sire is probably one of the greatest factors, because it is the moat economical. You cannot pay $1,500 apiece — or at least the average farmer is not inclined to pay it — for pure bred cows to get a good foundation. But you can take your scrub cows, and from the best statements you can get, in less than four generations you can double your production with any kind of cows if you are careful in selecting the sire. It has been proven this is true in the breeding proposition — milk characteristics are transmitted alternately. That is, the sire will have a greater influence than the dam. His offspring will receive the characteristics' to produce milk If he comes from a line of ancestry that possesses those characteristics. Jrrobably one of the difficult questions to settle is: How are we going to tell whether the sire will influence our herd for good, or whether he will have the reverse effect? There are probably three important phases to be considered in the selection of the sire. The first is what the sire can do — his record. If he is old enough so you can get the records of his daughters to compare with their dams' you have the best record that it is possible to get. You have to take your chances on a younger animal. The next point will be his pedigree. How many high-producing sisters has he? What are the records of his dams? How do they average? If there are many low producers mixed here and there, you are not sure you are going to get an animal that will give high pro - duction. If all the ancestors are relatively ranking high, it stands to reason he has inherited those characteristics. The third point is the individuality. If you can get the record of production of his ancestry and then the individuality, you may be reasonably certain he will influence your herd for good. I thank you. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: Our next speaker hardly needs an introduction. He has been at all times a friend to the farmer, ready to take up our voice in Congress, and always has worked for the interest of the agri - culturist. I take pleasure in introducing to you Congressman Dan V. Stephens. (Applause.) LOANS FOR DAIRYMEN Hon. Dan V. Stephens, Fremont, Nebraska Mr. Chairman and Gentlemen: I assure you that I am always glad to participate in these agricultural meetings. Sometimes my friends give me the laugh when I say I am a farmer. I don't know Just why. I do not know whether they think of me as a kid-glove farmer, a proxy farmer or a political farmer. But as a matter of fact, I am deeply </seg>
            <seg id="p051">52 interested in farming, because practically all the money I have is in - vested in that industry. I am frank to say to you that I have a little money invested in other lines of business. When I make the compari - son between my investments in agriculture and those in other indus - tries, I am astonished at the difference. The profits are so much greater in other industries. There is a cause for that which the organ - ization can remove. Their main reason for this is the isolation of the individual farmers and the lack of close organization. Every industry in the country is closely organized excepting that of agriculture. We have barely touched upon it. We have done some things, but until we tie our farm organizations together for the purpose of crediting and marketing, they serve no particular purpose in increasing the price of your product. I am interested in the manufacture of refrigerators. We take the raw material that goes into that refrigerator and the labor cost that goes into it, and the overhead cost, and add them together. The total is what the refrigerator costs to produce before it is marketed. Then we add the selling cost to that; then our profit to the selling cost; and when we get the grand total, we get the price at which that re - frigerator must be sold to make our profit. We either have to sell that refrigerator at that price or "go broke." When you go into a store to buy one of our refrigerators, just keep in mind who fixed the price on it But when you take your butter to market, do you fix the price on it? No. When you take your cattle to market, do you fix the price? No. Your hogs? You did not last season, anyhow, did you, when they dropped from $20 to $10 a hundred? (Laughter.) If you had had any control over the price of hogs, you would not have permitted the tremendous loss in that product. This question of organizing agriculture so that it can have something to say about the price of the stuff it has to sell is vital to its welfare and prosperity, and I marvel that we still have to be told about it. The very isolation of the farmer makes it difficult to get complete and perfect co-ordination and co-operation of all the different angles in this mighty industry. Do you know agriculture as a whole represents approximately sixty billion dollars of capital? Just think of that — a most staggering sum! It is 25 per cent of all the wealth in the country. It is so big the very size of it in a measure makes it difficult to control its own product. Is it not remarkable when we stop to think about it, that only seven years ago, notwithstanding the fact we had at that time around 180 billions of wealth in this country, we should find ourselves at the drop of a hat in the midst of a panic, when nobody could get any money upon all that vast wealth. Most of you passed through that panic in 1907. Not a single penny had been taken off our assets. A month, a day, or a week before that panic, no one would have questioned our ability to pay our obligations; and yet the day that panic fell upon us, </seg>
            <seg id="p052">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 53 • could not have paid a cent. That was a perfectly stupid position be found in. The remedy was so simple, I marvel an intelligent people could have gone on for a hundred years without discovering it. We had at that time 8,000 national banks in the United States, or - ganized under the authority of the government. Bach one stood on its own bottom. If one of them were weak or had been mismanaged, when one of these stringencies came upon the country, that bank would be closed because of its inability to meet its obligations and pay its checks. The minute it closed, fear would be thrown into the hearts of the de - positors of every other bank in that neighborhood. Bankers merely assemble in their vaults the credit of different individuals. Tom, Dick and Harry put their surplus money into the banks. This gives the banks loaning power. The man who hasn't money can get it if he has credit. That's all a bank is. It is an assembly of our credits. At that time we assembled them in units, and none of these wer.e tied together. The banks did not stand shoulder to shoulder. They would often criticise one another. One would say, "Now, that bank over there is pretty weak"; another would throw out the suggestion that another had a lot of bad loans and before long the whole neighborhood would be in a state of doubt about the stability of their financial institutions; as a result they would take their money out, and the banks would be so weakened many could not stand the strain. In 1907 I do not know how many banks failed, but in 1893 we lost count of the number that failed — all because of our own stupidity and lack of courage. We finally got to the point where we had enough backbone to say, "These national banks are going to be tied together. We are going to make them put up a deposit in the Association; sub - scribe to the stock of it. We are going to make them Jointly loan money to each other through a central bank." How they disliked it! At one time the American Bankers' Associa - tion voted almost unanimously against the adoption of the Federal Re - serve system. I was in Congress and received their letters by the thousands protesting against the passage of that Act! Now they would not do without it. They have no worry now, because each has had to contribute to a common fund to be used in time of need. It wasn't a voluntary matter. They had to subscribe to the stock. Each may draw support from it. When a bank gets a little short of funds, it just picks up a lot of your notes and bunches them together and sends them to the Federal Reserve Bank. This branch at Omaha or the Federal Reserve at Kansas City will give them the money on them. You naturally wonder where they get the money for this purpose. What is money? It is only a representation of credit. It is a medium of exchange. When we organized this Federal Reserve Bank we gave it the power to issue notes. You will find your money is all composed of Federal Reserve notes. (Shows one.) That is an issue of the Fed - eral Reserve Bank. It is issued upon your notes and the capital stock of those banks. That is the guarantee back of that paper. The law </seg>
            <seg id="p053">54 says there must be 40 per cent in gold. Those gold certificates we used to have — and we used to have silver certificates, and greenbacks' — all those certificates are in the Federal Reserve Banks — billions there. They constitute the gold basis for rediscounting your notes. They make up the 40 per cent and your notes make up the other 60 per cent. What does this money mean? It means we have taken your credit — 60 per cent of it — and turned it into money so you can circulate it and pay debts with it. We have done it through the Federal Reserve sys - tem for the financing of short-time credits. Men who want to borrow money for three months or thirty days go into these national banks. They call this class of notes "liquid -paper" because it can be turned into money in a very short time. Our ability to do this carried us through the greatest war the world has ever known without a ripple in finance. Do you know what happened during the Civil War without this Federal Reserve system? These greenbacks that are now cherished and held as gold reserve were the only money we had in circulation. They were worth thirty-five cents on the dollar. That money went down to that figure. You have to have security back of money — a guar - antee back of it that somebody is going to redeem it. This had no such guarantee at that time. When you get this Federal Reserve money, why don't you doubt? You never heard anybody casting suspicion on this money; yet it is a credit money issued on commercial paper. Yet nobody doubts it. Why? Because back of it is the biggest volume of gold in all the world, and the biggest volume of credit of farmers, busi - ness men, shipbuilders and manufacturers ever assembled in all time. It is the only kind of money worth while because the supply of it goes up and down with the needs of the country. Farmer Smith wants to borrow $10,000 to feed cattle. He goes into a national bank and borrows it for six months. He gives a chattel mortgage on his cattle. The banker can take that note to the Federal Reserve Bank at Omaha and get $10,000 in this Federal Reserve money on that note. His note constitutes a new credit. Suppose they did not have the money? The minute this note comes in for $10,000, they have added $10,000 of assets to tbe bank. They issue $10,000 of new money on that asset. In the course of six months the cattle are fat and Smith sells them. He pays off the $10,000 note. When he pays it off, they take that amount of money out of circulation. Practically speaking, they do not destroy the money; but it is taken out of circulation. Until Mr. Smith or some one else wants another $10,000, they keep it out. If two billions are loaned out for agricultural and commercial purposes and a billion is paid in in the course of three months, it means the net circu - lation has been increased a billion dollars during those three months; and as fast as the notes are paid the circulation is reduced. SO this is a circulation medium that rises and falls with the need of the people. We never had that system before. When vast sums of money were wanted for agriculture and manufacturing purposes there was not enough to go around, so there was a constant clamor for more credit. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 55 In 1890 when some of us were nutty on the free silver question — and I was one of them — (Laughter) there was only about fifteen Elars per capita in circulation. We declared then if we could double supply of money we could double the price of wheat. It was God's th. too, and you know it. We know if we had doubled the standard money we would have doubled the price of products, because money measured in products. When you have too many cows they are sap, and when you have too few they are high-priced, so it is with Now we have about fifty-five dollars per capita. Just see what a difference that makes. We have money enough to do the business. That is what we have done for commerce. Now I am coming to a thing in which you men are vitally interested. That is the credit system for the agricultural interests of the country — the basic industry upon which everything rests. If it does not thrive, the rest of the industries cannot, because it serves them all with raw materials and foods. Now what, sort of a credit system have we for the farmer? He uses the Federal Reserve for his short-time loans. But he cannot afford to go to the bank and pay commercial rates on short time loans for money to buy a farm, such a loan will run for many years. What the farmer needs is a credit system that will enable him to secure the largest amount of credit upon the security he has to offer, on terms that will enable him to get the lowest possible rate of interest with the principal amortized over a long period. That's the thing he wants. How can we get it? At the present moment we have on the statute books of the land the CU credit system known as the Federal Farm Loan Act. It was sed as a result of us farmers in Congress fighting for it. We are all farmers in this part of the country. There is no other industry out here that is worth considering. Whatever industry there is here lives upon the land. And if we have any sense, we know our interests are as completely wrapped up in the interests of the farmer as if we were actively engaged in that industry ourselves. So the representa - tives in Congress from this western country never stopped clamoring for this rural credit system for the farmers after we got the Federal Reserve Act. We said, "Here is what has been done for the business interests. Let us do this for the agricultural interests." We got it through. If we undertook to pass it today we could not do it, for the reason the old mortgage banker crowd was asleep when we passed it. They think it will injure their business, but it won't. An honest man doing an honest business is not going to be injured by this Federal Farm Loan Act. Only those seeking to take an undue advantage who will suffer. Just before we organized our Federal Joint Stock Land Bank at Fre - rt last spring, a man asked for a loan of $15,000, and said he could it from an old line insurance company, but they wanted $1,500 com- </seg>
            <seg id="p055">56 mission. Now think of that! The regular rate of Interest I think was around 7 per cent. In addition thereto, he was being required to pay $1,500 commission. Now It is extortions of that character that the Rural Credit System makes difficult. As a result the mortgage bank - ers have created a paid propaganda for the repeal of the Farm Loan Act. They have kept a propanganda going constantly through ali their representatives in Washington and their spokesmen who speak at every bankers' convention. They have mailed out literature until they have everybody thinking there is something wrong with it. I even noticed the other day the Farmers' Union meeting at Omaha had been duped into passing a resolution favoring a law subjecting their own securities to tax. They passed a resolution advocating that their own farm bond on their own land be subjected to tax! The lands had already been taxed. They asked to have the same lands taxed again by taxing the bond against them. Now coming back to the working out of this system, wa take the assets of the farmer in the form of first mortgages on the land for the purpose of establishing credit; and the only way to give these assets character so that the public will buy them, in the form of bonds they had to be safeguarded by some kind of a governmental organization that would supervise every step in the way. So the system was organ - ized with two arms. One was the co-operative arm, the Federal Land Bank, and the other was the arm supplied by private capital, the Joint Stock Land Bank. The co-operative arm has its unit of organization in the National Farm Loan Association — a most excellent method of com - bining the resources of a neighborhood. Many small farmers who have not adequate security at the bank for borrowing can unite and pledge each other their securities and secure the best of credit. It is a splendid thing and it has enabled tens of thousands of farmers to secure the credit they require, and at the same time have a steadying influ - ence, as the law contemplates, upon the interest rates in the neighbor - hood. This man who wanted $1,500 commission on a loan can't get that commission in a neighborhood where there is a Joint Stock or Federal Land Bank, because they will say, "We can get that loan and won't have to pay that commission." So the old mortgage banker must get down to our level in interest rates or he can't do business. I venture to say the farmers of America have been saved hundreds of millions up to this time through the operation of this system. This is how the system operates: The Co-operative Bank serves that class of borrowers who desire a co-operative loan. The Joint Stock Land Banks serve that other class of borrowers who never have been favorable to a co-operative system. Many of them like to do as they please and borrow their own money in their own way. They have that service through these Joint Stock Land Banks. For example the appli - cations pending in our bank today amount to seven million dollars, and it is Just seven months old. It means there is a tremendous demand </seg>
            <seg id="p056">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 57 for money among the farmers. The average size loan we have made so far has amounted to $13,000, and every dollar was loaned to a farmer for agricultural purposes, contrary to the charges these mortgage bank - ers make that these banks are loaning to speculators. We are com - pelled to loan for agricultural purposes only by the Board at Washing - ton who inspect every loan we make. So there are seven million dollars in applications pending averaging $13,000 each, waiting to be closed — ($3,000 above the amount the Federal Land Banks loan, and they have loaned all they can handle with the limit of $10,000 they have). So you can see what a tremendous demand there is in the country for financing the farmers. The truth is the system now is inadequate to finance the farmers. The Federal Land Bank at Omaha is asking to increase the loan limit to $25,000. Notwithstanding the fact we have the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Land Banks which are serving the people to their full capacity, and the old insurance companies which are loaning every dollar they have, there is not enough money in the country to supply this great agricultural industry. We can't begin to furnish the money these people need. Then isn't it an amazing spec - tacle to have somebody rise up somewhere in some public meeting and insult the farmers of this country by telling them they have too many banks in this country from which to borrow money, and recommend that borne of them be put out of business? Can you witness a spectacle more remarkable than the duping of a whole body of farmers them - selves, as was done in Omaha recently in the passage of a resolution advocating the liquidation of one arm of the Farm Loan System? It is the most absurd situation I ever heard of. I tell it to you not for the purpose of criticism, but for the purpose of warning you against the propaganda that meets you at every turn of the road. It is worth while to know how and where and why you are going to be approached, and then you can decide upon the merit of the question intelligently. In this State the dairyman perhaps requires credit in a larger degree than the average farmer, because his Improvements run into money much faster than on an average farm. So here we have a farmer who desires to erect a dairy on his farm as we did a few weeks ago. A man wanted to borrow $10,000 to equip his farm for a dairy. It was worth $300 an acre. He could take that $10,000 from us, and all he had to figure on was raising $700 a year. If he could raise $700 a year the debt would pay itself. It would be paid in full at the end of a period of thirty-three years. He could pay more at any time he wanted to after five years. If he wanted to pay a little penalty, he could pay all of it before five years. The point is, all he has to figure on is the pay - ment of $700 each year. If this dairyman does not pay off his debt sooner, and pays $700 a year, and uses all his surplus earnings for im - proving his stock or going into outside business if he desires to do so, at the end of thirty-three years the whole debt is wiped out. Suppose he had borrowed it from an old line insurance company for the same period of time and paid only S'.i per cent interest semi- </seg>
            <seg id="p057">56 mission. Now think of that! The regular rate of interest I think was around 7 per cent. In addition thereto, he was being required to pay $1,500 commission. Now it is extortions of that character that the Rural Credit System makes difficult. As a result the mortgage bank - ers have created a paid propaganda for the repeal of the Farm Loan Act. They have kept a propanganda going constantly through all their representatives in Washington and their spokesmen who speak at every bankers' convention. They have mailed out literature until they have everybody thinking there is something wrong with it. I even noticed the other day the Farmers' Union meeting at Omaha had been duped into passing a resolution favoring a law subjecting their own securities to tax. They passed a resolution advocating that their own farm bond on their own land be subjected to tax! The lands had already been taxed. They asked to have the same lands taxed again by taxing the bond against them. Now coming back to the working out of this system, we take the assets of the farmer in the form of first mortgages on the land for the purpose of establishing credit; and the only way to give these assets character so that the public will buy them, in the form of bonds they had to be safeguarded by some kind of a governmental organization that would supervise every step in the way. So the system was organ - ized with two arms. One was the co-operative arm, the Federal Land Bank, and the other was the arm supplied by private capital, the Joint Stock Land Bank. The co-operative arm has its unit of organization in the National Farm Loan Association — a most excellent method of com - bining the resources of a neighborhood. Many small farmers who have not adequate security at the bank for borrowing can unite and pledge each other their securities and secure the best of credit. It is a splendid thing and it has enabled tens of thousands of farmers to secure the credit they require, and at the same time have a steadying influ - ence, as the law contemplates, upon the Interest rates in the neighbor - hood. This man who wanted $1,500 commission on a loan can't get that commission in a neighborhood where there is a Joint Stock or Federal Land Bank, because they will say, "We can get that loan and won't have to pay that commission." So the old mortgage banker must get down to our level in interest rates or he can't do business. I venture to say the fanners of America have been saved hundreds of millions up to this time through the operation of this system. This is how the system operates: The Co-operative Bank serves that class of borrowers who desire a co-operative loan. The Joint Stock Land Banks serve that other class of borrowers who never have been favorable to a co-operative system. Many of them like to do as they please and borrow their own money in their own way. They have that service through these Joint Stock Land Banks. For example the appli - cations pending in our bank today amount to seven million dollars, and it is Just seven months old. It means there is a tremendous demand </seg>
            <seg id="p058">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 57 for money among the farmers. The average size loan we have made so far has amounted to $13,000, and every dollar was loaned to a farmer for agricultural purposes, contrary to the charges these mortgage bank - ers make that these banks are loaning to speculators. We are com - pelled to loan for agricultural purposes only by the Board at Washing - iwho inspect every loan we make. So there are seven million dollars .pplications pending averaging $13,000 each, waiting to be closed — 000 above the amount the Federal Land Banks loan, and they have led all they can handle with the limit of $10,000 they have). So you see what a tremendous demand there is in the country for financing farmers. The truth is the system now is inadequate to finance the tiers. The Federal Land Bank at Omaha is asking to increase the i limit to $25,000. Notwithstanding the fact we have the Federal orve System and the Federal Land Banks which are serving the i&gt;le to their full capacity, and the old insurance companies which are loaning every dollar they have, there is not enough money in the country to supply this great agricultural industry. We can't begin to furnish the money these people need. Then isn't it an amazing spec - tacle to have somebody rise up somewhere in some public meeting and insult the farmers of this country by telling them they have too many banks in this country from which to borrow money, and recommend that tome of them be put out of business? Can you witness a spectacle more remarkable than the duping of a whole body of farmers them - selves, as was done in Omaha recently in the passage of a resolution advocating the liquidation of one arm of the Farm Loan System? It Is the most absurd situation I ever heard of. I tell it to you not for the purpose of criticism, but for the purpose of warning you against the propaganda that meets you at every turn of the road. It is worth while to know how and where and why you are going to be approached, and then you can decide upon the merit of the question intelligently. In this State the dairyman perhaps requires credit in a larger degree than the average farmer, because his improvements run into money much faster than on an average farm. So here we have a farmer who desires to erect a dairy on his farm as we did a few weeks ago. A man wanted to borrow $10,000 to equip his farm for a dairy. It was worth $300 an acre. He could take that $10,000 from us, and all he had to figure on was raising $700 a year. If he could raise $700 a year the debt would pay itself. It would be paid in full at the end of a period of thirty-three years. He could pay more at any time he wanted to after five years. If he wanted to pay a little penalty, he could pay all of it before five years. The point is, all he has to figure on is the pay - ment of $700 each year. If this dairyman does not pay off his debt sooner, and pays $700 a year, and uses all his surplus earnings for im - proving his stock or going into outside business If he desires to do so, at the end of thirty-three years the whole debt is wiped out. Suppose he had borrowed it from an old line insurance company for the same period of time and paid only 5V6 per cent interest semi- </seg>
            <seg id="p059">58 annually, Instead of 6 per cent and at the end of thirty-three years paid the principal. What would be the result? In the thirty-three years he will have paid $18,000 interest at 5% per cent. Then he owes the prin - cipal, which makes $28,000 he would owe at the end of thirty-three years, as compared with the $23,000 he will have paid the land bank at 6 per cent. Isn't that a remarkable thing? You do not realize how a 5% per cent loan would amount to $28,000 at maturity under the old system and a 6 per cent loan on the amortized plan would amount to but $23,000. The reason Is that every year you apply the saving of your interest on your principal. Every year your interest gets less, and what you save is us'ed to reduce the principal, reducing it so that you have actually saved $5,000 in interest in that time. Then you have saved re-writing it every five years at a cost of the attorney's fee for bringing title down to date, and at a cost of commis - sions from 1 to 3 per cent each time. I know a farmer who paid 4 per ceDt to get his loan of $4,000 renewed — $160 commission. Money was tight. It is usually tight at that time. (Laughter.) When you pay the commissions, the expense of examination of the title, the recording fees, and having the worry and bother every three to five years, it amounts to $2,500 more in the thirty-three years. As a matter of fact, a farmer will have saved under the ordinary expenses he incurs, $7,500 on a loan of $10,000 in thirty-three years on the amortized plan. It is the only way to borrow money, long terms and low interest rate and the loan amortized. Under the Federal Co-operative Land Bank method you borrow from your local association. I have no doubt many of you are members of some National Farm Loan Association and can bear me out in this. You borrow a thousand dollars from a Federal Land Bank National Farm Loan Association, and pay $50 into the capital of the bank. In other words, you make an investment, just as you would in a candy kitchen or a factory or bank or any other business. You have $950 left. Out of that you pay one-half of one per cent to the Secretary of the Association who makes the loan. That is a common practice. That would be $5.00. Then you pay the Federal Appraiser about $10; that would be a tootal of $15.00. Then you pay the local committee from $5.00 to $20.00, according to the method of each association. So that when you have gotten through, you receive about $910.00 on an average, and you pay $55.00 a year on that $910.00, which makes your loan cost just thirty cents on the thousand less than 6 per cent. Six per cent on $910 would be $54.60. You pay $55.00 interest to the Federal Land Bank; so you pay practically 6 per cent on the Federal Land Bank Loan, and 6 per cent in the Joint Stock Land Bank loan, plus $15.00 — ($10.00 for your Federal Appraiser and $5.00 for your abstract) — which makes the two practically identical. There is really no difference in the cost of the two loans. As Mr. Corey said yesterday, we expect if we can keep our bond rate up, we will be able to loan our money for less. We are allowed to </seg>
            <seg id="p060">• THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 59 loan at 6 per cent. We cannot charge more. We can sell the bonds at one per cent less, which leaves one per cent for all the bank's expenses. You know what you are paying these banks. It is no secret. You pay one per cent for all the expense connected with the business. Now here is our danger — the bonds must be sold on the market at par at 5 per cent. If we are compelled to sell them at a discount, then the discount comes out of the one per cent left for the overhead ex - penses, and it would soon close the banks all up; because they can't operate on less than that. So you can see how important it is these bonds be kept at par. Congress saw in the beginning these bonds would have to be sold on the market in competition with the tax free bonds of Chicago and New York and other cities and states. If we do not pro - tect them by making them tax free also, it will be impossible to sell them in competition. New York has issued one and a half billion of bonds. That is more bonds than the Farm Loan system would probably ever issue. They are as good as any in the world, and they are tax free. You cannot legislate against a state or city bond. The states have a right to Issue their own instrumentalities and the national gov - ernment can't tax them. If it did not make your farm land bonds free from tax, you would be compelled to sell those bonds in competition with other tax free bonds, and you could not do it. You could not sell them at all. They would be so reduced in price your system would be put out of business 1 . Senator Smoot proposes to tax the bonds issued by the Joint Stock Land Banks, so as to put them out of business. So we said to Senator Smoot, "This bill will kill the Joint Stock Land Banks if you subject the farmers' bonds to tax. Who would buy a farmer's bond with a tax say of one per cent, when he could buy city bonds at 5 per cent with no tax?" Nobody. That is as 1 clear as any - thing can be. It is just as simple as A B C. Senator Smoot said, "We want to drive them out of business." We said, "You say you are doing this to collect more taxes for the national treasury. In the first place, there aren't 2 per cent of farm mortgages ever taxed. The State of Nebraska recognizes the injustice of It so thoroughly that mortgages are not taxed at all in Nebraska. The national government recognizes IJiat." And so we told the Senator he would merely kill off one branch of the Farm Loan System, the Stock Banks and the other would be expanded; and would Issue the same number of bonds they both now issue. This would in no way reduce the number of tax free bonds, or be of any benefit to the treasury. He said, "We are going to put the Federal Land Banks' out of busi - ness later." He will shoot at the easiest mark first, because these banks are financed by private' capital, and they assume the public will be indifferent whether they survive or perish. Later on when the Joint Stock Banks have been crushed they can leisurely turn on the Federal Land Banks ?&lt;nd finish them. That is their whole object and method. If they can dupe the farmers of this coutftry into following that course </seg>
            <seg id="p061">NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION 60 as exampled by the absurd resolutions passed in Omaha and above re - ferred to, the Farm Loan Act will soon go into the discard. I believe I have covered the subject fairly well. There are so many things to say I could talk a week. But I understand you have another speaker on the program, and I will make these concluding remarks. We not only need the facilities we have now for financing the farmers of this country, but we need to improve and strengthen and enlarge these facilities. We need them all. Any farmer who permits himself to be carried away with any of these criticisms that are being made upon the system, will find he has merely joined hands with the mort - gage bankers without knowing it, and has delivered a solar plexus blow to his own system of credit. I have my money in this land bank system, but I could make twice as much if I had it out. Had I known the grief I would have and am having in getting the bank organized, and that I would have to spend my money financing this propaganda to save it from ruin I never would have put a dollar in the system. What the farmer needs is added capital — somebody to bring money into the system, not to take it out. There is not a farmer who wants to contribute to the capital of these banks. He does so only to get money. You farmers who belong to the co-operative Federal banks would rather have me furnish that $50 capital on ever $1,000 if it could be done, but there aren't enough of "me's" to do it. You need the money. You are a borrower, not an investor. Here is a branch of the Farm Loan System that comes along with outside capital to help finance the farmer, so we are aiding in the development of agriculture. It is a splendid system, and I want to tell you farmers you ought to stand by it through thick and thin and shoulder to shoulder against the common enemy now fighting you. I thank you. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: It is certainly a pleasure to have Congressman Stephens with us today, and I know you all enjoyed the address. He has given us food for thought, and that is what we are here for. It seems to me it is only fitting the members of the Dairy Association elect Congressman Stephens an honorary member of our Association. (This was done, amid applause.) MR. STEPHENS: I thank you, gentlemen. I do not know of any - thing I would feel more interested in being a member of than your splendid organization. As I stated, my interests are practically all wrapped up in agriculture. While I do not farm myself, I do it by proxy and love it; and I thank you very much. THE PRESIDENT: We will next have an address by a lady on the High Cos-t of Living. MUS. C. G. RYAN, of Grand Island. Mr. President: I am very </seg>
            <seg id="p062">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 61 Then, too, I know you are beginning to feel intimations meal time is approaching. However, cheer up! I am only going to stay a minute. I know your subject here this morning of dairy work is exceedingly important to you and extremely important to the nation. But I am bringing before you another subject that is exceedingly important to us all. There is probably nothing that is more in the thoughts' of the people at this time than the high cost of living. I come with a sug - gestive means for correcting the evils that have arisen in the last months. You know better than I am able to tell you of the two basic facts which have very largely contributed to the present conditions — an inflated currency, and shortage of supply. I shall not mention the former at all. It is quite beyond me. But I am going to talk a little bit about shortage of supply, and it is along that line the Department of Justice is attempting to offer us relief. The situation is this: Every time the consumer buys unnecessarily luxuries or extravagancies, he adds to the difficulties in the way of pro - duction. If you buy an unnecessary article, you are making it all the more difficult for the manufacturer to produce sufficient to supply the demand. For Instance, if you go to a merchant and he tells you prices are going up next month, and induces you to buy the thing you do not need, then you are aiding the manufacturer at the other end to put his price away out of sight. If the retailer buys in excess of his present demand because he is fearful prices are going up, he crowds the manu - facturer that much, and the manufacturer has not the competition. A wholesaler told me the manufacturers actually have no competi - tion, because everyone is crowded to the limit. He can not supply the trade because of the industrial conditions and shortage of raw materials. He puts any price he chooses on his product. The retailer has caught the contagion from us. Isn't it our fault if we cannot see where we are drifting; If we do not correct this high cost of living? I think it is. Believing it is, I accepted the appointment as Chairman of the Nebraska Economy Campaign, and ask for your co-operation. Women expend 90 per cent of the family budget and 65 per cent of your fur - nishings. That seems to be putting a good deal of responsibility and blame upon women; so perhaps you. think I am at fault to present this 1 to the men. But don't you hold the purse strings? Make them feel at the present time luxuries must be cut out. The bare necessities must do us. Let all the effort of the manufacturers or producers be put to the essential things of life, not to the non-essential. Tell your women not to be afraid to say, "I won't pay the price." If they can't get the necessary article at a reasonably marked figure, to do without, or buy something a little bit less expensive. It takes labor very much longer to produce the finer lines of things. It takes many more hours and men and more complicated machinery to produce the silk than the woolen garment; yet the merchant will tell you his simple garment remains on the shelves while the extravagant garment is sold. He will tell you that four years ago 10 per cent ot his </seg>
            <seg id="p063">62 shirt sales were silk; now 65 per cent are silk. If you go to your stores and demand silk shirts, you will get them just so far as the re - tailer and manufacturer are able to put them out. I have clippings from New York commercial papers that are pub - lished for the sake of the trade — not for you and me — saying this mad Intoxication of spending Is driving us to ruin; and it is a necessary pro - tection to the manufacturing industries and the dealers themselves that there should be called a halt. The little merchant does not see it yet, but the big man does. The honest dealer is not afraid of this propaganda. The dishonest one is afraid of this propaganda of economy. It is not only going to teach the doing without luxuries, but it is going to attempt to curb and catch the profiteer. Perhaps some of us may be in that line. If you buy things and lay them away because you are told they are going to be higher, you are in a degree speculating, and there you are at fault. Aren't you conscious there is a propaganda going about that prices' are going to be higher next season? You hear it every time you go to buy any article. The assistant to Attorney General Palmer says, "Prices do not go up. They are put up." Who puts them up? The consumer is responsible to a large degree in putting them up. Say, "I won't pay it. You can keep your article. The manufacturer can keep them on the shelves. I will not pay the price." Then watch how quickly they will go down. I heard a man praising the horse. He said the horse never volun - tarily himself went into danger; that if the horse got on the track it was the driver who was at fault. It occurred to me we American people need a little "horse sense." We are on the track, and we need to stop, look and listen. I thank you. (Applause.) PROFESSOR J. H. FRANDSEN: I am sure we are much interested in what Mrs. Ryan has said, but I would like to have her know some - thing about the difficulties the dairyman has been up against the past year or two. You may even suspect that he has been profiteering as much as anybody else; however a glance at his income receipts will disabuse you relative to this, and a good many people interested in dairy work have said they were finding difficulty in staying in the busi - ness at the price they were getting. One dairyman said he was worse off than the fellow selling sugar. He advertised he was selling at two cencs below cost. A farmer came in and said he was interested in the statement and wondered how he could do this; and the grocer answered that he didn't think he could make a profit if it wasn't for the fact he was selling so much of it! (Laughter.) He isn't selling below cost now, but he has been doing it quite often in the past. The Woman's Club of this city had a notion that shoes' and silk had gone up beyond reason; and recently they naturally came to the con - clusion there had been the same profiteering with the fanner. As one </seg>
            <seg id="p064">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 63 &lt; lady said, "It Is pretty nearly all water anyway, and it Is cheap enough on the farms." But there are a lot of things in milk that cost money. I showed them a chart which showed the things that went into milk. I showed that at the State Farm in 1914 we bought alfalfa at $10 a ton. This year we paid $30 — a 200 per cent Increase. Bran has increased about 100 per cent; cotton seed meal, 150 per cent; labor, 150 per cent, and practically everything a dairy farmer must use for milk production had gone up from 150 to 200 per cent. Milk at the present time — the top-notch price — has raised just 100 per cent. Considering the fact that everything he uses has gone up between 150 and 2on per cent I must insist that the farmers' demands are not unreasonable. Of course a boycott on milk might reduce the demand, but wouldn't It be a serious and a tragic thing for anyone, knowing the vital import - ance of milk; knowing the child's health may be permanently injured if the diet does not contain this most necessary of all foods to urge a boycott? It is not all pleasure to milk seven days in the week, Sundays and holidays thrown in. The dairyman has a large investment and must borrow a lot o£ money. He should have some encouragement to stay in the business, and I believe the more the better, not only for him, but for the consumer. What would happen if many went out of the business? Possibly there would be such a shortage of dairy products that there would be no competition, and as a result the consumer would have to pay what might be termed a fabulous price and there might not be enough to go around. I think we will want to give much consideration to this matter before we urge measures which would un - doubtedly discourage the fellow who even now is largely in the busi - ness for the welfare of his fellow men. A year ago at a Farmers' Institute, we were talking of keeping a system of accounts, and after the meeting a young lady said, "I want to tell you on our farm we keep absolute tab on everything in the household. I would like to show you my books." Here she had: Some one saidyJ'What is meant by H. O. K?" "Oh, I thought you knew. H. O. K. means that 'heaven only knows* how that money was spent!" (Laughter.) I want to suggest that the farmers, by not going into the details of bookkeeping as much as they should do, have lost track of some of the details that should be taken care of in their business. You would not expect the street car people to conduct their business without taking into consideration everything that goes ino the running of the cars. Sugar $ .50 Dress goods 8.50 Hat 12.25 H. O. K 67 Groceries 2.40 H. O. K 79" etc </seg>
            <seg id="p065">64 But we have not practiced that as much as we should. Just to bring out that one point and show what will happen when we begin to pay attention to the little things, we made out this chart, which is supposed to show in a business-like way the different things that enter into the production of milk. K it is good practice to take care of half a cent in a street car business or shoe factory, why not on the farm? I be- lieve there is no fair-minded person who will not admit the farmer is entitled to everything he produces plus a little profit. I know if we are goin£ to keep a man satisfied with the dairy business, we must give him a reasonable profit. The figures I am about to quote are based on experiments carried on in this and several other states: COST OP PRODUCING 100 POUNDS OP MILK Home-grown grains — meaning the more food we raise, the cheaper we can produce the milk % .25 Purchased grains, like cotton seed meal 56 Hay .' 58 Other dry forage crops, like straw 13 Silage — it takes care of the shrinkage 74 Bedding 07 Labor (human) 76 Labor (horse) 024 Hauling 35 Taxes, Interest and depreciation 26 Taxes, interest and depreciation on equipment , ... .05 Railroad service 01 Losses due to death 03 Miscellaneous costs 08 riring the war most manufacturers were granted 10 per cent plus. ' I believe the good dairyman is entitled to as much. This would add 39 f| Total . . . , *446 It is proper to give a little credit for the manure value. I have consulted experts who agree a fair reduction would be 12 qrp The value of calf at birth is offset by the sire service. This means the net cost of producing 100 pounds of 3% per cent milk is 14.34 That would make 45 or 46 quarts; so the farmer Is getting $0.0925. I wish Mrs. Ryan to have those figures, because I think she can do the dairy interests a great deal of good if she will have them in mind in her further discussions. MRS. RYAN: I hope I was not understood to say anything about boycotting. It is not intended to have anything radical in this economy campaign, which is being waged against the non-essentials. Certainly </seg>
            <seg id="p066">TfilETY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 65 fc there is nothing more essential than milk or eggs or batter. I even do not advocate the use of oleomargarine, because butter has elements which are absolutely necessary to our health. But the very people who are complaining of the price of milk and butter are buying the extrava - gancies and whining about the high cost of living! Those are the articles at which this 1 campaign is aimed. (Applause.) I PROFESSOR FRANDSEN: I am sure the dairy people are heartily accord with and will much appreciate anything Mrs. Ryan can do to p the dairy situation. kMR. CAMPBELL: One of the luxuries we have to cut down is the ury of sending our children away to school. If you are interested in t subject, come to Room 303 Agricultural Hall this 1 afternoon. The convention then adjourned until 1:30 P. M. </seg>
            <seg id="p067">66 THURSDAY AFTERNOON SESSION January 22, 1920 The Convention was called to order at 2 P. M. by the President, Mr. Jacob Sass, who announced that the first address on the program would be given by Professor Frandsen. THE PRESENT STATUS OF THE MILK MACHINE Professor J. H. Frandsen, Lincoln, Neb. Mr. Chairman, Ladies and Gentlemen: I am reminded of the story they tell of a good old Quaker, who does not express himself as freely as some of us. He was trying to break in a heifer that had never been milked. She kicked him down, and spilled the milk on him. He looked at the cow, then at his clothes, and said. "My religion won't permit me to swear at thee; my religion won't permit me to kick thee, but I have nothing against twisting thy darned tail." (Laughter.) I assume there are some dairymen who feel like expressing them - selves about that way about milking time. Then there are a number of young men in dairy work who are always looking forward to the machine way of doing things. They are interested in labor-saving de - vices. The scarcity of labor since the war and the high prices we have to pay have come along, and unite in making the interest in and de - mand for a perfect milk machine stronger than before. So a large per cent of the correspondence we get concerns itself with the milk ma - chines and their success from a practical point of view. Since there seems to be so much interest, I think something should be said about the status of the milk machine at the present time. I have looked over the experimental work done at the various stations, and have sent out questlonaires to farmers who are using the milk machines and I have tried to condense the information secured from those sources. As I can give a briefer written report I trust you will pardon me for inflicting this manuscript on you. (Reads.)' Because of the scarcity and the high price of farm labor, to say nothing of its quality, the interest in and general adoption of milking machines in dairy localities has been rather remarkable and has sug - gested to the writer the desirability of briefly summarizing the milk machine situation up to date. It is safe to say that there are but few real live dairy sections in America today, where the milk machine is not used successfully. Testi - mony of practical users, and available data from Experiment Stations where experiments with all the leading "makes" have been conducted for a number of years, have in my estimation fully established the fact that at least under average conditions and with ordinary producing herds of at least twenty cows the milking machine is both economical and practical. It goes without saying that a conscientious, intelligent man must be in charge of the work. To most wide-awake dairymen of today, the construction of the milk - ing machine and its operation are more or less familiar subjects. The </seg>
            <seg id="p068">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 67 pail must be much stronger than the ordinary pail in order to with - stand the greater outside pressure caused by the creation of the vacuum within the pail when the machine is in operation. It must also be large enough that there may be no danger of the pail becoming full and over - flowing into the vacuum pipe. Most machines have approximately the same shaped pail — narrow at the top with tight fitting cover which makes it easy to hold the vacuum. The pulsator is usually attached directly to cover of pail. The duty of the pulsator is to give alternate suction and release. By regulating the pulsator so as to give a long and slow pulsation, it is claimed that the best results are secured as regards a large teated, hard milking cow and a snort rapid stroke according to this theory will give best re - sults with a short teated easy milking cow. It is, of course, impossible to give any definite rule that will fit all cases — experience and observa - tion being the only safeguard. Teat cups of different machines vary considerable as regards style, shape and in material of which they are made. Some have universal teat cups, other machines have different sizes for different sized teats. Rubber tubings connecting teat cups with the pail are always made in sections readily detachable so as to be easily cleaned. There is alsc another piece of heavy tubing connecting milk machine with vacuum pipes. Some machines do not have vacuum pipes or tank and depend en - tirely on small simple pump arrangement near each milk machine unit to supply the necessary vacuum. However, nearly all machines on the market have pipes running in front of the cows, the full length of the barn. These connect with the vacuum tank and pump in the power room and with provision for at - taching milk machine unit near each cow. Most of the systems' are now provided with gauge and safety valve. The gauge enables the operator to know exactly what vacuum he has at all times, while the safety valve allows air to enter the system whenever the vacuum is up to a certain pressure. This does away with the danger of too much suction in tha teat cups. Manufacturers of machines explain that the vacuum tank should be large enough to hold a reserve supply of vacuum in order to maintain uniform suction even while the teat cups are being transferred from one cow to another. The pumps used to create the vacuum are of two general types — rotary and up and down stroke — both have proved satis - factory. The machines are of course, power driven. Electricity is the most steady power and if available is the most desirable form of power. However, other forms of power will do the work satisfactory — a two horse power engine will care for two machines. Cost of Outfit As is the case with all other kinds of machinery, there is 1 consider - able difference in figuring the cost of outfits. Some dealers include </seg>
            <seg id="p069">68 pump and piping in the price of the outfit, while others charge extra for pump, piping, installation, etc. However, at the present, roughly estimating, I believe it can be said that a double unit (milking four cows) including pumps, tank, piping and installation, will cost about $500.00. Some will cost more and a few types can be had for some - what less. Machine Milking vs. Hand Milking A number of inquiries relative to the comparative efficiency of hand milking and machine milking have been coming to us of late. Perhaps the best work on this subject has been done by the Michigan Station, which has carried on quite a thorough experiment from which we may draw some conclusions. A total of 93 herds were used; 42 of these were hand milked while 51 were machine milked. Figures on the total amount of time spent per cow and also per 100 pounds of milk, were kept for one year. The figures most of us want to see first are the ones showing which method required fewer hours to get the Job done. Here they are: On the average, it took 89.25 hours to hand milk a cow for a year, against 57.91 hours by the machine method. To these figures we must add to the hand method only 11.19 hours for the care of milk and utensils, against 13.37 hours for the machine method. From this data we find that the total amount of time spent per year for milking, washing utensils, and caring for milk was. 100.44 hours for the hand-milked cow, against 71.28 hours for the machine-milked cow. Putting it on a basis of each hundred 1 pounds of milk produced it was found that each 100 pounds of milk produced required a total of 1.42 hours by the hand method against 1.12 hours for the machine. From this test it seems that even though the machine must be care - fully washed, it still saves considerable time, and the time saved cer - tainly is an item worth consideration. It must of course be understood that this saving will be reached only when enough cows are milked so that the time lost in caring for the machine will be more than made up by the gain in the actual process of milking. Comparison of Machine and Hand Milking (Figures from investigation in cost of milk production by Michigan Experiment Station.) Machine Machine Milked Milked 15 Cows Over 15 Hand Machine or Less Cows in Milked Milked in Herd Herd 42 51 17 34 13.6 18.2 13.06 20.75 89.25 57.91 65.23 55.61 hrs Total number of herds. Average number of cows per herd . . Hours milking per cow per year . . . Care of milk and utensils per cow per year 11.19 13.37 14.71 12.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">69 THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION There are other features which must be given consideration. For instance, the use of the machine eliminates the hiring of some help which at best is hard to get. It permits' the milking of a much larger Eber than could or would be milked by hand method. Frequently operator can handle the machine even though his health, or condi - of his hands and wrists would not permit him to do the milking by hand. Also the machine is on hand Sundays and holidays and very rarely "gets sick." Effect On Cows Tn order to get information on this subject, questionaires were sent out by the United States Department of Agriculture. The following two questions were asked: (1) Has the use of the mechanical milker influenced the production of your herd? (2) Do you find that the ma - chine has magnified or lessened sore teats, gargets, milk fever and other udder troubles? To the first 156 replies were received, divided as follows: No Difference Less More if Anything 124 16 16 To the second inquiry, 129 answers were divided thus: No Difference Less trouble More trouble with udder disease with udder disease The South Dakota Experiment Station reports that after a lengthy experiment using all the different types of machines, and with cows of various breeds — they have concluded that by studying the milking char - acteristics of the individual cow and adjusting the machine to each cow's needs, that all the cows used in the experiment have been suc - cessfully milked by all machines. It should, however, be well understood that most of the experi - mentors stress the point that cows must have good udders with good average sized teats; that the cow should not be nervous and that the machine should be adjusted to the cow by an intelligent operator. The Milking Machine In Nebraska In this connection no doubt you will be interested to know some - thing regarding the use of the milking machine on Nebraska farms. To get this information a questionaire was prepared and sent to cer - tain Nebraska users who could be reached quickly. The letter and questionaire read as follows: Dear Sir: There are a number of inquiries reaching us regarding riblems in connection with the milking machine, and we are anxious get the assistance of men like yourself in answering matters of this 110 11 8 'otal time per cow 1 [ours milking per 100 lbs. milk . . . !are of milk and utensils per 100 lbs. milk 'otal time per 100 lbs. milk 100.44 1.26 .16 1.42 71.28 .91 .21 1.12 79.94 .99 .22 1.21 68.51 .2 1.0! </seg>
            <seg id="p071">70 kind. As a user of the milking machine you have undoubtedly had special opportunity to study it under practical farm conditions. We will, therefore, greatly appreciate it if you will take the time to answer the questions on attached sheet, assuring you that anything you may say will be considered strictly confidential. May I impress on you the fact that we wish a free and frank opinion from you, whether that happens to be for or against the machine. Thanking you for any assistance you may render us in this matter, I am, QUESTIONAIRE MILKING MACHINE DATA Number Name . Date Address Make of machine. Number of units.. When installed. Cost except power. Cost of power Kind and size of power. Breed of cows Number of cows milked. Number of operators Time required to milk. Number of men doing stripping if different from operators. Amount of milk. Amount of stripping. CARE OF MACHINES How often washed Is it steamed Kind of solution for rubber parts. How often is solution renewed. Have there been any udder troubles due to machine Describe fully Is machine satisfactory. Thirty-three carefully answered questionaires were returned to us and the facts summed up as follows 1 : Number of replies received 33 Kind of machines in use: Empire Sharpies Hinman Perfection Time machines have been used: Less than one year 9 Three years 4 One year 8 Seven years 1 Two years 10 Eight years 1 Number of units: Machines of one unit... Machines' of two units . . Machines of three units. Machines of four units . . 5 16 5 5 Machines giving no report of units " 2 Kind of power Gas 17 Electric 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 71 Report not given as to kind of power 11 Average horsepower used 2% Breed of cows Holstein 19 Jersey 1 Guernsey 1 Mixed or grade 10 Time required to milk each cow 2.8 min. Average number of cows milked per hour 21 Number of operators for machines: Machines having one 21 Machines having two. 8 Machines having three 1 Machines not reporting operators 3 Number of men doing stripping: Same as operators .' 26 Same as operators plus one 4 Same as operators plus two 2 Same as operators plus three 1 Average amount of stripping per cow 1 plus pints Lowest report of stripping per cow 0 Highest report of stripping per cow % CARE OF MACHINE How often washed: Daily each milking 11 Daily one milking 9 Twice a week 2 Once a week .' 11 Use of steam: Number using steam 9 Number not using steam 23 Report not given 1 Kind of solution for rubber parts: B. K 15 Lime water 12 Sterilized 2 Cold water 1 Salt water 1 Report not given 1 Rubber parts not washed 1 Solution renewed: Daily 2 Every two days 6 Twice a week 11 Once a week g Once in two weeks 2 Once a month 1 Report not given 2 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">72 UDDER TROUBLE DUE TO MACHINE Reporting none 27 Reporting some 5 Report not given 1 ON SATISFACTION OF MACHINES Satisfied users 29 Dissatisfied users 2 Undecided users 2 SUMMARY OF COMMENTS "In the same class as any other labor saving machines.' "Could not run a dairy profitably nor satisfactorily without it." (In use two years.) "Requires about a month to learn to use the machine." "Heifers with first calf like it better than hand milking." "It is better than a poor milker and not so good as a good hand milker." "Milk can be produced more 'sanitary' with less trouble.' "Only practical where herd is large enough that the use of ma- chine will cut down the number of men employed." "Hard quarters caused by leaving machine on too long or too soon after freshening." "A careless operator can ruin a herd of cows." "An unqualified success in the hands of a careful operator." "It cuts out the drudgery of milking and does not drive away the hired man." "It is more dependable than hired help. The more cows and the greater the flow of milk the more I am in favor of it." "As good results with machine as with hand milking. Conclusions In conclusion, it can be said that the standard well tried milk ma- chines, handled by a good operator are both practical and a labor-sav- ing apparatus. There have been and will likely continue to be some failures with milk machines, for the reason that many will fail to understand the mechanics of the machine, the necessity for keeping it clean, the failure to use care and good judgment in its operation, as well as neglect In carefully and promptly stripping the cows. The success of the milking machine can be greatly enhanced by selecting cows with well balanced udders and uniform teats and by eliminating very nervous cows, and by carefully studying individuality of the cows, and adjusting the machine accordingly. A. The operator should study each individual cow, and after he has milked her a few times he can soon gauge the pressure and vacuum he needs. A. There will be cows that don't respond as quickly as others. A. I know of one cow that as quick as you started the engine, her milk would start, and you had to hustle to get the machine ready. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 73 PROFESSOR FRANDSEN: This Is a Perfection machine. In the Exhibit Room we have the Perfection, Sharpies and Empire all hooked up. Those interested can go down and see them. THE PRESIDENT: Next we will have an address by Mr. Barney, the State Dairy and Food Commissioner of Iowa. THE IMPORTANCE OF DAIRYING Mr. W. B. Barney, Des Moines, Iowa Mr. Chairman and Gentlemen of the Nebraska Dairymen's Associa - tion: In being invited to come to Nebraska again, I am reminded of a story they tell of a gentleman who was conducting some Chautauqua work In Iowa. A few years ago they were a little bit short of helpers. He tells it in this way: He was desirous of getting some help to go out on platform work, and he learned of a party who was presumed to be fairly good, and asked him to come in and have a talk about it He concluded to try him, and sent him out. When he returned, he came over to see the party who had employed him. He had filled two or three engagements. The manager wanted to know what success he had had, but could not get anything definite. Finally he said, "Did you make good?" "Yes, I think so." "Well, how did they receive you?' "They received me all right." "Did they ask you to come back?' 'By golly, they dared me to come back!" (Laughter.) I was over here two years ago, and Professor Frandsen dared me to come back, and here I am. What I will have to say this afternoon is from the standpoint of a dairyman. I have been in the game since 1881, and was President of the State Dairy Association about four years before becoming Commis - sioner, and have been Commissioner ten years next spring. That reminds me of still another story. I do not want to over-recom mend myself, and this 1 will Illustrate it. It is of a couple of darkeys who lived in Des Moines. They had been working as chauffeurs for a couple of prominent men, and were quite well acquainted. One of them concluded to get married, so he did, and had been married about a week when it was talked around he was applying for a divorce. Finally the proprietor went to the other darkey and said, "Say, Sam, you are acquainted with this darkey who is applying for divorce. What is the matter? He has only been married seven days. I can't quite see why he should be getting a divorce." "Well, Sah, I don't Just understand it myself; but from all I kin learn, he sort of over-recommended himself." (Laughter.) What I shall say today is largely from what I have learned by ex - perience in the work. The facts are, I do not want to be boastful of what we have done in Iowa; yet I think we have made fairly good prog - ress along dairy lines. We have in the Dairy and Food Commission a </seg>
            <seg id="p075">74 department in which we employ fifty people. We have ten men who are engaged in dairy work alone. They are selected from among men who have either had four years' dairy course at Ames or some school such as you have in Nebraska or Wisconsin, or creamery men who have had dairy experience and an experience in creameries from ten to fifteen years. Then we have a Dairy Inspector who has general supervision of the dairy work, or perhaps I might better say supervision of the work of milk supply in the cities. The Department is organized in such a way we have the appointment of the milk Inspector in each of the cities of 10,000 or more. He is paid by the Department Jointly with the city. In some ways that is a good plan. In other ways it does not work out quite as well as it might. Politics" enters into it more than it should. Where the mayor or council changes in the city, we sometimes lose a pretty good milk inspector because some other fellow has been active in putting across a campaign for mayor or some of the members of the council. We have to appoint a man, or are asked to make a change and do away with a man who has been very satisfactory, and we are obliged to educate an - other man to take this place. We had twenty of those men. Then we have ten men who do food work, but part of the ten do some dairy work. Then we employ four men who do weight and measure work. I want to compliment the State of Nebraska on the reorganization you put across last year. I think the best work possible can be done under an organization similar to that which you have here. I know Illinois is doing nicely with that sort of an organization, having found it very satisfactory. Our conditions are Just a little different from what they are here. We have about four hundred creameries in the State. Perhaps thirty of them might be termed centralizers, and about two hundred are made up of creameries which are organized by farmers in the community around the creameries, and known as Farmers' Co-operative creameries. The balance are individually owned creameries, or stock companies. You can see with four hundred creameries, our proposition Is Just a little different from yours. Most of them are located in the northern two-thirds of the State. After the experience I have had, I believe the best way for the farmer in a densely populated dairy district to market his dairy products is through a well managed Farmers' Co-operative creamery. I want to lay stress on the "well managed." You can't operate and not have it well managed. We have very many that are well managed. We have a lot that are not. It is partly the duty of the men in my Department when these managers get into trouble to go out and help them out. Now we are Just as active in helping out the other creameries that get into difficulties, and to do what we can in southern Iowa to help the centralizers. kl may have Just a little different notion of this proposition from t of some of the commissioners over the State, but my thought is i: My experience leads me to believe if a man is not a big enough </seg>
            <seg id="p076">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 75 man In a place such as I occupy to get a wide enough vision of the whole dairy industry to help the centralizer as well as all the others, he is not a big enough man for the Job. I go on the theory the cen - tralizer is the forerunner of the Farmers' Co-operative creamery or the Individual creamery, and we are interested in the dairy game and want to do everything we can to put it across. That has been one of the troubles with the dairy people. They have been in a fight among themselves. Perhaps the centralizer was develop - ing dairying where you could not otherwise have a market. We have a number of counties without a creamery. There could be nothing done in the way of developing dairying unless there was a market. We are starting out this year going through the three southern tiers of counties with an educational proposition. We have four men — two in each team — starting at Keokuk in the southwestern part of the State and working through the three tiers of counties with the centralizers and the cream stations. They are co-operating with them and putting on two or three meetings a day at each of those places. Each team has a lantern and a lot of charts and things of that kind. We are going into the high schools and other places where we can get before the public. While it Is Just started, I know they are making quite a suc - cess of it. We started two years ago, but found the war was on and Red Cross work was taking a lot of attention, and the Liberty Bond campaigns were taking more. It was hard to get meetings of any size. We are having much better success this year than ever before. I feel this is due to the people of southern Iowa. We try to develop that country along dairy lines. There is a real reason why a section of country such as we have in southern Iowa is better suited to dairying than almost any other thing. The real facts are in the fertile prairie country we have in the northern part of Iowa and the eastern part of Nebraska, people do not have to dairy. There are so many other things they can do to make their land profitable. But there is a real reason why that country Is better suited to dairying than anything else. Take our southern Iowa country and it is quite hilly. A good portion of it washes badly. Our summers are longer down there; grass comes earlier in the spring, and we have feed later in the fall. ' ; ? :«¥■ *;fii I have sometimes wondered why it is land values are so much greater in the northern part of the State. In a measure, I attribute part of that to the fact the dairy cow came into her own In the northern part of the State quite a number of years ago, and she has helped to bring about a condition to put fertility back into the soil that had really gone. I am old enough so I remember when through the Decorah country they had raised wheat and oats and barley and such products until the fertility was gone. I bought a farm in Franklin county thirty years ago. It had been operated by renters for twenty - five years. I think there had been at least twelve renters on it. They had found It little easier to move their sheds and barns than to haul </seg>
            <seg id="p077">76 out the manure. (Laughter.) About the first thing I did was to buy two manure spreaders and hire a man by the month to haul manure, and he had an all summer's Job. The result is I can raise more than double on that place today than I could thirty years ago. The reason is the fact I have never had less than twenty to thirty dairy cows on the farm. The fertility has come back to the soil by reason of having those cows there. So I think the dairy cow has had much to do with the difference in land values in northern and southern Iowa. I believe I can show land values in northern Iowa on the same class of land range from $30 to $50 an acre higher than in the southern part of the State. I feel certain the cow will do it for almost any section of the country, and it is about the best way to get our fertility and be successful in agriculture. I often hear men say, "Land values are so high and dairy cows so high, I do not know whether it is a good time to go into the dairy game or not." I am rather optimistic about that. In the last few years instead of decreasing the number of cows, I have increased it, and I am not sorry for it. I cannot remember during the last thirty years when there was not a good deal of talk about over-production. The prices were never better for dairy products than right now. I think there is every reason to believe they are going to continue to be good. Re - member we have a country across the water that is very much depleted, so far as its cattle are concerned, and there are conditions there which will take several years to recover from. I was talking with a nurse from Germany recently, and she says milk has become so, scarce in Germany it is hard to get it unless you have children under four years old, or an invalid in the family. You have to have a milk card. It is going to take quite a time to get back the normal supply of cattle and milk in Belgium, France, Germany and those countries that have suf - fered by reason of the war. it seems to me there 'never was a time when as a side line a man could do better than to use a pure bred dairy sire and raise a good many dairy cows. I have never owned a beef sire. If you are going into the dairy game, take a Guernsey or Jersey or Holstein or Ayrshire, and go into it in a whole-hearted way. . I can remember when I was looked upon as a most undesirable citizen in Franklin county because I was going to spoil the steers by breeding Holsteins. It semed to the beef people we were going to spoil the steers in that country. I am free to admit the dairy breeds do not produce good steers. But here is an argument you can use to good ad - vantage at this time: If you have some good grade cows to sell, they will bring really more than your steers. There is no trouble in our country to sell good grade cows at $250 to $300 a head. One of the ways to get in the dairy business is to work into it, not to go into it. I understand men can throw away a lot of money by buying a bunch of pure bred cows and a high-priced sire. I tell them to buy a good dairy sire and breed him onto the cows you have, and </seg>
            <seg id="p078">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 77 work into it in that way. The first cross will make a difference of about fifty pounds per cow. Do you know what that would mean to Iowa? If every dairyman in the State of Iowa would do that, it would mean 51 million dollars increase in the production of butter in Iowa per year. I believe every doctor or lawyer would be benefited by doing that, for the reason that 51 million dollars could be used to pretty good advantage, and there would not be as much complaint about the high cost of living, as at this time. The high cost of living has been something of a study with me the last three or four months. I have had an investigation in the Depart - ment and it has kept me pretty busy. I will say if we had that 51 million dollars added to the income of our dairymen, it would help their problem as to the high cost of living. • I believe the time has come when the dairymen are going to be obliged to stand together. I think the time has come when they should talk. That reminds me of the story of a fellow who was an aviator. He had a couple of lady friends who had been coaxing him to take them up. He was afraid and thought they might interfere with the handling of the plane. Finally he said, "If each of you will agree not to say a word while we are up, I will agree to give you a ride." They promised, so they started. He had gone for some distance and finally he looped the loop, and all at once he felt someone pulling his coat. He looked around, and one of the girls said, "I must talk. Mary Is gone!" (Laughter.) I think it is time for the dairymen to talk, because I do not think they have had their entire amount of profit they should have out of the increase in their product as compared with some others. The increase in the cost of help, and the difficulty to get help, have been problems with the dairymen; but the war is over and it won't be so much of a problem from this time on. I have sometimes wondered whether or not the man on the farm was getting his share of what was coming in the way of increased wages. I have sometimes wondered why he was not getting a greater share. I cannot help but look at what organized labor, has done for its' people, and to compare that with what has been done for the man on the farm. Why has organized labor done for them what it has? Because it has been organized. The most the dairymen and farmers know about an eight-hour day is how to get in an eight-hour day before dinner and an eight-hour day after dinner. The reason they have been having to do that is because they are not well organized. I think it is time for you fellows to speak. You will never get what you are entitled to unless you do speak. In making this investigation on the high cost of living, I find the cloth in a suit of clothes in 1914 cost $4.58. In 1919 it was increased in price to $13.67, or an increase of $9.09. Now It is perfectly natural for us farmers to wonder whether the man who grew that wool got his </seg>
            <seg id="p079">78 share of that increase. I am led to believe he did not. What did the man who made that suit get as an increase? He received for making that suit in 1914, $4.98; in 1919, $14.47— an increase (or manufacturing that suit of $9.49. I wonder whether he understands his co-laborer must help to pay that $9.49? If I were to go to him, I am inclined to think he would be one of the first fellows to say, "I cannot help reduce the high cost of living, because I must take a less wage by doing so." The farmer is obliged to pay that $9.49 when he buys that suit of clothes. One of the reasons the labor unions are getting that increase is be - causo they are well organized. When they go to the state legislature or to Washington, what happens? They are listened to because they are organized, and that is Just the way you will be listened to if yon will organize and stand for what is right. I have never found the farmer or dairyman was standing for anything but what is right; but I think we have been slow about getting together. We have in Iowa today — and I think it is a good organization — united all of our farm bureaus into a Federated Farm Bureau organiza - tion. We have about 120,000 members of that organization, and it has increased 400-fold in the last few months. I think your organization is a good one. I have sometimes heard people say, "We have too many organizations." We have in Iowa a State Dairy Council that has been organized in the last year and a half, and it does not seem to interfere with the activities of the State Dairy Association. I think it is not what you get by hearing long - winded talks that is of value to you, so much as getting together and talking over your own business, and discussing Just such things as you did here on your milk machine question. Those are the things of real benefit to you. So I believe you can hardly have too many organiza - tions. We have a State Butter-makers' Association. For fear I overlook it, I want to speak of one thing I think is quite important. We have a law that provides for an 80 per cent standard for butter. I think you know there have been some activities along the line of having an 82 per cent standard unit. I took the matter up with one of our Congressmen who is Chairman of the Committee of Agri - culture at Washington a short time ago, and tried to have him under - stand an 80 per cent standard was about right; that we should have a Federal law providing for an 80 per cent standard. It would cost Iowa each year to increase that standard to 82 per cent about $1,800,000. This would either come out of the producer or be tacked on to the consumer. I think the reason we should have an 80 per cent standard is the fact most of our competition is working on that basis. I understand you have a law that is in a measure looking after the use of the tuberculin test on your herds. It is only within the last year in Iowa we have been compensated for reactors. It appears to me that getting the compensation we do, it is a mighty good thing for each dairyman to take it up and have his herd tested. While I have </seg>
            <seg id="p080">79 THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION never taken it as an extremely serious matter — this transmission of tuberculosis through the cow — yet at the same time, even though there is a bare possibility of something of that kind happening, I think it is a good thing from an economic standpoint for every dairyman to have his herd tested, because it may save a great deal of trouble. I recall a deal in Iowa that happened last summer. A gentleman had a nice herd of grade Holsteins and concluded to close them out and put in their place a herd of pure breds. In order to have the sale go off in fine shape, three or four days before the sale he called in a veterinary and said he wanted them tested. The result was about 60 per cent of that herd reacted! What happened? He did not want to hold the sale because no one wanted the other 40 per cent. If four or five years be - fore he had had the herd tested, he might have found three or four re - actors. If they had been eliminated and he had had a retest, the per - centage of reactors when he held his sale would have been so small as to be of no consequence. I am quite interested in the development of any section where a promoter might thrive. We have driven them out of Iowa. I am only speaking of that because in the development of your country out west you may be bothered with them. If you are contemplating the building of a creamery, the best thing you can do is to get in touch with your State College that will help you to put it across, rather than to have anything to do with a promoter. They "did" Iowa a number of years ago. What have we left through the southern part of the State? We have a lot of old shanties left as a monument to the folly of the pro - moter and the farmer who paid $7,000 for a $2,000 plant. My definition of a promoter is 'a man who sells something he hasn't got to people who pay for something they never get. (Applause.) We have only had a little trouble with them in the last two years, but I get right after them just as fast as I learn they are trying to do any - thing through our undeveloped part of the country. I speak of it be - cause I would like to put you wise to the experience we had over there. We got through some legislation that is reasonably helpful. There are products made up of cocoanut oil and skim milk. It is surprising to me when the State Department tried to get through a measure of this kind which we know is going to be helpful to the farmer, why some of the farmers are against the proposition. We did not ask the legis - lature to put a ban on this product, but to put a provision In our dairy law so that it should only be sold as an imitation product. It went through the Senate without trouble. We got over to the House, and found the people making these different products were in with a strong lobby, and there was every indication they were spending quite a bit of money against any restrictions whatever. It took considerable activity to put it through, but we finally did so. There is another thing I think is helping us quite a bit. We are doing away with the use of the word "creamery" or "dairy" or any of the products of cattle in Imitation butter products — in advertisements </seg>
            <seg id="p081">80 of oleomargarine and things of that kind. I think it is perfectly fair we should. I remember a few years ago a party in Illinois was making oleomargarine. He concluded it would be a good thing to have a nice barnyard scene and show where the milk was produced from which he made it. He had a nice barnyard, but he was not satisfied with the cattle he owned himself, so he went out over the different parts 1 of the country in search of better looking animals. It Just happened I had a cow that had been pretty successful in the show ring. He took a pic - ture of that cow, and instead of putting a picture of one of my red hogs or a sprig of cotton, he took my cow and made a composite picture, putting her at the head of the line. Under it he said, "This Is the celebrated Gelke herd of cattle from which the milk is produced that makes the wonderful brand of 'Good Luck' oleomargarine. He landed in the penitentiary. I think he was Just about as honest as many who do not go to the pen. So I think it is important you get your laws framed up so the dairy people won't be Imposed upon. Speaking of organization, the National Dairy Council is doing a wonderful work and getting to be an organization which will prove of vast good to the dairy interests. You cannot pick up a paper without noticing cranberries and various other products of nothing like the importance of our dairy products are being advertised extensively. Sometimes I hear a dairyman say, "We cannot afford to advertise." My answer is, "Then we really had better get out of the business, because there isn't any business that prospers 1 unless it is fairly well advertised." I think we are in just as good shape to advertise as many of these things, and we have a better story to tell. I understand the use of the name of one of these soft drinks has been sold for about $500,000. If we tell this story about milk, and stick to the truth, what is going to happen? We are going to increase the demand; keep the price so that there will be a profit in the pro - duction of it; and do what we can to make our homes better and to make us more prosperous. As to what we have done in Iowa, we have made an Increase of about eighteen million pounds of dairy products this last year, with a fewer number of cows than the year before. One thing we have not in - creased is dairy butter. In condensed milk we have made an increase. I want to say to you I feel I am encroaching on your time, and that reminds me of the story of a fellow about to be sentenced. The Judge Baid, "I will be obliged to pronounce sentence upon you. Have you any - thing to say to the Jury before I do so?" "Well, I don't know as I have anything to say. I don't consider it hardly worth while to say anything." "I will be obliged to sentence you to the penitentiary at hard labor for ten years." "Just wait a minute," said Mike. "Now is the time I would loike to have something to say." </seg>
            <seg id="p082">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 81 \ "Your opportunity is gone," replied the Judge. "Sure an' it isn't to the Jury I want to sphake. It is to you." "If you will make it very short I have no objection." "Well, it is this: I want to say to you I think you are mighty care- less of other people's time." (Laughter.) I do not want you to think I am careless of other people's time, and I am very much obliged for this opportunity of talking with you. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: We would like to hear from Mr. Prazeur on "What the Milk Producers' Association is Doing." MK. JOHN FRAZEUR: I am like the fellow who was going to give a lecture on "The Demon, Rum." I am "full of my subject." (Laughter.) But I would rather you would proceed with the business meeting first. REPORT OF THE COMMITTEE ON RESOLUTIONS RESOLUTIONS Your committee on Resolutions and Plans present the following to you as their report: RESOLVED, That we express to our officers, the President and Sec - retary, our appreciation of the business-like manner in which they have carried on the work of the Association, and the splendid achievements of the year in interesting the people of the State in the dairy business. RESOLVED, That we hereby express our appreciation of the work of Professor J. H. Frandsen as Head of the Dairy Department, and the excellent help he has been to our Association, both as to work at the Farm and that throughout the State. We desire especially to commend him for his work in assisting to develop a proper market for all dairy products. WHEREAS, we realize that it is of the utmost importance that our boys and girls become familiar with sound principles' of dairying to bring about the most effective organization and economic production of dairy products; and WHEREAS, we believe that interesting boys and girls in Calf Clubs and raising, calves is not only important to the dairy business, but that It is even more important in the development of character for the boys and girls of the State; and WHEREAS, we believe that there is a gross error in the slogan "Back to the Farm," and we believe that the real solution is "Stay on the Farm." Realizing this, the Dairymen's Association should encourage improved conditions through the placing of emphasis on proper dairy practice, and further realizing that these conditions can only be con - tinued by the on-coming generation; therefore be it RESOLVED, That the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association co - operate with the Extension Service of the College of Agriculture, the </seg>
            <seg id="p083">82 Farm Bureaus, and other organizations whose purpose is to improve rural conditions in fostering Boys' and Girls' Dairy Club work, and the board of officers be empowered to provide ways' and means of assisting in carrying on this work. WHEREAS, in the Nebraska State Journal of January 8, 1920, in answer to the question of comparing butter and oleomargarine, the Department of Agriculture of the United States is quoted as saying that there is no appreciable difference in the nutritive value of these two foods; and WHEREAS, this statement has been repeatedly proven untrue by exhaustive investigations Dr. E. V. McCollun, of the Johns Hopkins University, and also by Professor J. H. Frandsen of the Nebraska Dairy Department, and by nearly all modern scientists, which proves beyond a shadow of doubt that milk and milk products are absolutely essen - tial to the best development of the young; therefore be it RESOLVED, that the insidiousness of the propaganda of the oleo - margarine manufacturers which preaches such falsehood be combated Sth all the vigor and aggressiveness of which this Association is cap - le, and that we greatly deplore the ignorance which prompted the printing of said statement in the Nebraska State Journal; and be it RESOLVED, that it is the sentiment of this meeting and the will of this Association that our officers do all in their power to correct this erroneous impression and teach the people of Nebraska the real im - portance and necessity of using butter and milk products instead of in - ferior substitutes. WHEREAS, present conditions in the economic world are a menace to the nation, and believing as we do that much of the high cost of living, with its consequent unrest, is the result of shortage of supply; therefore, be it RESOLVED, by the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association, that we endorse the Nebraska Economy Campaign designed to enlist the volun - tary co-operation of all the people in reducing the prevailing costs by careful, conservative and economical living, and that we give our sup- port to the "Work and Save" movement. H. A. MORRISON, JOHN FRAZEUR, O. A. SEVERE, Committee. MR. C. E. MORSE: I move the adoption of these Resolutions, and that copies be given to the papers for general public information. The motion was seconded and carried. REPORT OF AUDITING COMMITTEE Lincoln, Neb., Jan. 23rd, 1920. To the Nebraska Dairymen's Association: We, your Auditing Committee, beg to report that we have examined and audited the report and accounts of the Treasurer, Mr: J. E. Palm, </seg>
            <seg id="p084">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 83 (or the year 1919 and find the same to be correct, and we are pleased to state that they are kept in a very concise and businesslike manner. Respectfully submitted, H. C. YOUNG, THOS. E. SNODGRASS, CHAS. GRAU, Auditing Committee. ELECTION OF OFFICERS Mr. H. A. Morrison, of College View, was nominated as President of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association for the ensuing year. It was moved the nominations be closed, and the Secretary Instructed to cast the unanimous vote of the Association for Mr. Morrison for President. The motion was seconded and carried. THE PRESIDENT: I take pleasure in presenting to you our next President, who is well posted on dairy affairs. I assure you you have made no mistake in electing Mr. Morrison. Calls for a speech. PRESIDENT-ELECT H. A. MORRISON: If I had thought anything about having to make a speech, I think I would have declined the nomination. But gentlemen, from the standpoint of things in our State, I think there is not a subject open for discussion that is more vital for the future progress of the State than the dairy business. If you had the privilege of traveling in the different states of this country, some of our western states are doing a great deal of work in the dairy business, and yet we have a much greater opportunity for this work in our own State — that is, the natural conditions in Nebraska are more favorable. I think if you could see what some of these western states have accom - plished along this line, it would be a great inspiration to you to return to your home State and build up the dairy business. It is generally conceded that the products of the cow are necessary to the upbuilding of the human race, as we know the cow is necessary to the bettering of farm conditions. In these recent years we hear a great deal about the high cost of living. When we get right down to the things the individuals must have, we come back to the farm every time, and especially the dairy farm. While that does not take care of these inflated costs, yet from the standpoint of getting to the people's needs we have found the place. Now we have this privilege of getting together in conventions and discussing how we can best bring some of these things to the people; how we can best improve our own conditions; how we can best improve our methods; bow we can best so interest the boys and girls who are already on the farms of this State that they may remain on the farms </seg>
            <seg id="p085">84 and progress there; how to bring up the standard of operation and enter into the development of the dairy cow in a special way. I say there is not a place in all the world with greater opportunity than is that home which is interested in the dairy business in the State of Nebraska. I thank you. (Applause.) Nominations for Vice-President were then made as follows: B. W.. Frost C. E. Morse The election of Vice-President was by ballot, resulting as follows: For Mr. Frost, 13 votes; for Mr. Morse, 25 votes. Mr. Morse was declared duly elected as Vice-President for the en- suing year. Nominations for Secretary-Treasurer were then declared in order. MR. JOHN FRAZEUR: I do not think we can do better than to retain our present Secretary; therefore I nominate Mr. J. E. Palm as Secretary-Treasurer for the coming year. The nominations were declared closed, and the President cast the unanimous ballot of the convention for Mr. Palm as Secretary-Treas- urer of the Association. Calls for speech. SECRETARY PALM: I am very poor at that, but I want to thank the gentlemen, and would like to say this: You can help us a great deal in giving us some idea of what you want done. There are a great many things to be done, and it takes a great deal of work to do them; but the men with me last year, and the ones 1 coming in this year, will be glad to do everything they can for your interests. It is of great benefit to us to get suggestions from you as to what you would like to have carried out. There are some things that can be done now, and others that would probably be better to defer until later. You will always find me at your service to do whatever you want me to do that is right Gentlemen, I thank you. (Applause.) THE PRESIDENT: Whenever you have any grief or want to know anything about dairying, just write to Mr. Palm. Whenever you come to Lincoln, go to the Lindell Hotel and you will find him in his office. It is always open for you. He is a real dairyman. He has a nice daily farm west of Lincoln. All the milk you get in the Lindell Hotel comes from his own place. He is going to have the most model dairy farm around Lincoln in a couple of years from now, Nominations for members of the Board of Directors were declared on ler, and the following nominations made: Charles Grau, Bennington (22) C. H. Gustafson, Lincoln (26) I Jacob Sass, Chalco (34) Professor J. H. Frandsen, Lincoln (33) </seg>
            <seg id="p086">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 85 John Frazeur, Omaha (28) E. W. Frost (20) H. C. Young (20) Those receiving the highest number of votes were Messrs. Grau, Gustafson, Sass, Frandsen, Frazeur, and they were declared duly elected. The President then requested the newly elected officers and directors to take their places on the platform. This was done, amid applause. MR. MORSE: I move the Nebraska State Dairymen's Association for the year 1920 adjourn. The motion was seconded and carried, and the convention adjourned, sine die. NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S BANQUET Lindell Hotel, Thursday, Jan. 22, 1920, 7:00 P. M. Jacob Sass, President J. E. Palm, Secretary Hon. Edgar Howard, Toastmaster The Milk Diet for Us A. L. Bixby, Editor of Daily Drift, State Journal Our Dairy Association Jacob Sass, Farmer, located near Chalco, Nebraska Dairy Cattle, How to Advertise and Sell H. A. Morrison, President Union College and Breeder of Holstein Cattle, College View, Nebraska. State Dairy Laws Leo B. Stuhr How Iowa Does It W. B. Barney, Dairy and Food Commissioner, State of Iowa The Cow and the Man J. H. Frandsen, Professor Dairy Husbandry, University of Nebraska BANQUET Thursday Evening, January 22, 1920 The Thirty-fifth Annual Banquet of the Nebraska Dairymen's Asso- ciation was held at the Lindell Hotel, Lincoln, Nebraska, with Hon. Edgar Howard, of Columbus, acting as Toastmaster. MR. JACOB SASS, of Chalco: Before I introduce our Toastmaster, I want to thank the Committee on Program and Arrangements for the splendid "eats" and the splendid program you have arranged for this Association. We have a gentleman here with us tonight, and after I introduce him, I want you all to take a good look at him. He is the youngest looking old man in the State. I have known him for over thirty years. Thirty years ago he did not look a bit older than he does today. One day I took advantage and said, "Judge, tell me how do you keep so young. Why is it?" </seg>
            <seg id="p087">86 "'Oh, Jake, you fellows have the Fountain of Youth on the farm, If you only knew It! I take a drink of milk early in the morning, again at noon, and at night before I go to bed. If I have a bad cold, I put in an egg and a little medicine, and I have what they call an eggnogg." I have great pleasure in introducing to you our friend, Honorable Edgar Howard. (Applause.) TOASTMASTER HOWARD: Mr. President, Ladies and Gentlemen: First of all let me acknowledge my thanks because of the courteous compliment spoken with reference to my health by my long-time fellow laborer. But I want you to understand that while this President of yours always tries to be truthful, he oftentimes gets the other thing mixed with it; and indeed, I never did put anything in a glass with milk in order to make an eggnogg in the right season. (Laughter.) This, Mr. President, is a strange duty for me to assume — the duty of Toastmaster at a banquet of this character. I do not know much about cows. I never milked but one, and then I made a mistake. It was a pet cow — a Jersey. My wife loved that cow and she told me she was entirely harmless. One day my wife broke a finger, and the eve - ning time came and the milking time was near, and my wife was more disturbed about the thoughts of that beautiful cow going over milking time than about her own broken finger. So how she did it I do not know, but she injected into me sufficient courage to induce me to at - tempt the milking. I told her I would try it all alone; she must not come near. She thought she should go with me and show me how. But for reasons which husbands know, I did not want her witnessing any errors I might make; so I tried it alone. I got on the wrong side of the beautiful cow, and the rest of the story is too sad to relate. (Laughter.) A toastmaster, it seems to me, on any and every occasion ought to have a vast fund of stories so as to keep the risibilities of his audience rising and their food digesting rapidly and properly. But what do I know of stories with reference to a cow? Not many. The fact of the matter is, I feel at this moment very much as I apprehend some of the barbarians felt in the old days when the Roman troops were not making as good headway as the Emperor and Senate thought they ought to make, and so emissaries were sent out to gather testimony regarding the slow movement of the troops' and the little force they displayed against the oncoming barbarians. It was discovered some of the gen - erals were growing very opulent, and the investigators had no trouble getting testimony on the field. Finally the Senate appointed a time for the hearing of the charges which had been made against the generals who had not stopped the invading army. The witnesses came. They were questioned. Not one of them remembered what they told the emissaries of the Emperor. They could not remember a thing about it. Finally one Senator was berating one witness shamefully because of his lack of memory. Another Senator rose and said, "I beg the Senator </seg>
            <seg id="p088">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 87 not to be so hasty. Indeed, how can the poor fellow speak the truth or anything else when he has a cow on his tongue?" Now if I finish that story and tell the truthful ending of it, you see my lack of cow knowledge has me in bad; but I must do it, and you can draw your own conclusions. It seems in those days that particular Emperor issued his coins with his own image on one side and the figure of a cow on the other. Forever after in that realm when the people wanted to say of another he had hush money, they said some - thing like— I sometimes think, my friends, that when we are investigating conditions in our country with reference to those elements which have worked so methodically and sometimes so successfully to retard the forward march of the progress of dairying and other producing elements of goodness in our own country for the welfare of the whole people, it would be well if some of our own senators would stop and ask the witness to remove a cow from his tongue, particularly if he be engaged with the legal department of the packers' trust. (Applause.) I do not want to get into any more trouble tonight than I can help. I have told you I cannot tell cow stories. I cannot speak the cow language as fluently as I would like. I always sympathize with those who do not understand thoroughly the language with which they have to deal. My sympathy went out to a Chinese gentleman whom I had met casually and had the honor of an introduction to him — and it was an honor, because he was a magnificent fellow learning Occidental way? very rapidly, and putting many of us real Occidentals to shame by his beautiful adaptation of them. One evening when I was in Washington I was invited to a lady's party, and she had a wonderful dinner and some speeches afterward. The guest of honor was this Chinese fellow — an attache of the Chinese legation. His name was Wan — Something. I do not know either in my language or his how he pronounced it. On finishing his speech, he turned to his hostess and said, "Now, Madame, I trust you will be so very good as to pardon me if I have cockroached upon your patience or the patience of your guests." A polite titter ran around the society crowd — we were all society people there. We tittered politely. None of us 1 laughed loudly. We do not do that in society. After it was over, the Chinaman, seeing he had made some break, went around among the fellows whom he knew attached to the other legations, and begged each one to tell him what kind of a bad break he had made. They all, like the polite liars they were, insisted he had not made a bad break at all, but that he had delivered a splendid address. But he knew better. Finally he came to a plain Englishman connected with the British legation — and what - ever else Jake Sass or any other American may think of an English - man, this is one thing for which we must give them credit: they are more direct than we. So the Englishman replied, "Yes, you did make </seg>
            <seg id="p089">88 an awful break!" "What was it?" "You asked that lady to please pardon you if you had cockroached upon her patience." "What should I have said?" The man Jumped up. "Never say that again. Always in a case of that kind you should ask the lady to pardon you if you have h'en - croached upon her patience." (Laughter.) Further pursuing my duties in this office, I take some pleasure — and some other things' — in introducing the first speaker on the program. I see he is assigned to respond to a declaration, "The Milk Diet for Us." I do not know who made this program. I do not know whether an editor made it or not. If an editor made it, the "us" means the speaker alone. If a man of any other calling made it, it means all of us here assembled. I am taking it for granted that program was prepared by an editor and that is an editorial "us" there instead of a general "us." So I am taking it for granted that this speaker will declare that the milk diet is for him alone. And I am glad of it. I do not want to walk through the world suffering from the horrible effects of the milk diet as does this man. Those of you who are sitting near, and those of you with younger eyes at some distance, may discover the effect of it. It is 1 coming out white on his eyebrow. (Laughter.) You can readily understand, knowing the heart of this man, why it is he is no longer a meat eater. He is a sentimentalist, and it may hurt your business in the cow-growing industry for either he or I to promote this sentiment in the world; but I cannot help it. I still eat a litlle meat but I would no more eat a piece of veal set before me than a piece of horse, both for sentimental and business reasons. The business reasons are apparent to everybody. My sentimental reason is my own, and it is always with me every time I look into the wonderful eyes of a little calf. I tell you people who never studied the - eyes of a little calf, you have missed something In life that you do not give those eyes a little more study. I declare to you — and I am pretty loyal to the women of my family — that I never saw a woman with more beautiful eyes than the average calf displays. That is my sentiment and I live true to it. I do not live true to everything, but I do to my sentiments, and those are my sentiments. And if this man, Bixby, whom I love, sometimes refrains from a meat diet and lives on a milk diet because of sentimental and business reasons, the same as I do, then I applaud him in the living. Otherwise I would not have much more regard for his views on a milk diet than I do for some of his political writings. (Laughter.) Now, ladies and gentlemen, it does give me real pleasure to present to you as our first speaker of the evening. Dr. M I L&gt; Bixby. I do not know whether he is or not, but he will answer the question. (Applause.) </seg>
            <seg id="p090">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 89 MR. A. L. BIXBY, of Lincoln: Mr. Toastmaster, Ladies and Gentlemen: I notice you have quite a long toast list, so I will not detain you very long. I once lived — or tried to live — I ran a newspaper and tried to live In the same town my friend Howard comes from. I found out a man could not be an honest man and run a newspaper there, and live. (Laughter.) I left the town, and have been in Lincoln ever since, and it has been a long time. So that today I can boast — if it be a boast —of having run a special column on one daily paper longer than any man in the United States except Frank Stanton of Georgia; but this man Stanton only furnishes about a column a week, and then goes fishing in between. I want to tell you a true incident about my Columbus experience. I want to tell it because I am afraid somebody else will tell it and won't tell it straight. (Laughter.) But it shows what association will do with a fellow. I had not been there more than two years before I needed money, and needed it mighty bad. I went to the bank that had induced me to come there, and told the cashier I wanted $800, and he threw up his hands. "Eight hundred dollars! That's a good deal of money." "Yes, it is; but I need it bad enough. I've got to have it." "I can't let you have it unless I would call a meeting of the directors." "Then for God's sake, call it!" He did. There was a German who was the vice-president of the bank. He was my questioner, and I knew I must answer right or there was no show of getting a loan out of him. "What have you?" he asked me. "Well, I have this office down here you know all about. That cost 1,700 of good money. Then I have a home at Fullerton I paid $1,500 or, and there is a $500 mortgage on it. Over at the barn I have a torse and two buggies and a cow, and a wife and five children, and when the nights get dark I am going to have some chickens. (Laughter.) That last remark settled it, and he let me have the money. I do not know how long the bank regretted the loan. But that is only one of the little things which goes to show I would have become dishonest If I had stayed much longer. And while that little expedient worked once, it would not again. So I got out of the town and came here, and am glad of it. But I soon began to receive calls the same as here. I do not know the man who invited me to come here and talk to you tonight, but I have had such calls; and generally when I answer such a call I ask what they will pay me. In this instance you are my neighbors, and I do not want to be mean to you. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">90 On one occasion a former president of one of your railroads, who lataly died, invited me to come to the Lincoln Hotel to a banquet. He did not say a word about my having to talk. I was reluctant about going, and said, "1 am tired out," but he said, "We are depending on you. You have to come." So my wife and I went over that evening and I looked over the toast list. It was a fine banquet, all right; but when I saw the toast list, it did not look so good. Right over my name they had "I. O. U." (Laughter.) I had had so many I. O. U.'s; I looked upon it as a personal thrust. I looked at what we had to eat, and did not want to desert. Don't misunderstand me. I wanted the dessert, but I did not want to desert, and concluded to stay. While I was eating, it occurred to me there was a whole lot in that I. O. XT. business. I thought this was a fact — that no man in this world can put his thumbs in his vest and say, "I owe no man anything." If he says that he's a liar, because the more you have, the more you owe; and if you haven't anything, you do not owe anything, naturally. But we are indebted to one another in a thousand ways. Our associations are such no man can live independently, and what he gets of material things are only borrowed, and he must pay it back. It would be mighty well for humanity if some of them would pay it back a d sight sooner than they do. (Applause.) Excuse my French. So that brought out a line of thought. I thought of the fellow I met on the street just a little while before. It was in the fall of the year, and chilly. He was shivering with cold. He looked in my face and said, "Mister, would you be kind enough to give me the price of a drink?" I said, "Are you right sure you don't want to fool it away for bread?" He said he was sick and had been riding on the bumpers. I said, "If there is ever a time a man ought to have a drink, it is under these circumstances." I gave him the money and watched to see he did not go to a restau - rant to throw it away. But it occurred to me if a man is hungry, I owe him bread. If he is naked, I owe him a suit of clothes; and if he is thirsty, I owe him a bucket of water — or as much as he cares for. I guess the amount is immaterial. I thought of another thing. It became personal then — this mutual obligation business. I said to them then as I say to you now: "I owe each of you a copy of my book, and you each owe me a dollar." Mutual obligation all the time. You know how many people are helped on the street by a good word. If you see a man looking down his nose as if he had had hard luck and been held up by a profiteer, say a good word. Speak kindly to him. He is your brother. I would like to carry this even across the ocean. I was abused here some months ago because I refused to declare myself 100 per cent American. No, I am not 100 per cent American; </seg>
            <seg id="p092">91 never have been, and never will be. I have interests that reach clear beyond America — all over this round earth in every land and sea. Whether he speaks my language or not, he is a brother man. I said we would not have two million boys fighting side by side with the French and English for the liberty of mankind if they were 100 per cent Americans. They are not, thank God! It is that attitude of 100 per cent nationalism that brought on this war. Germany held up the fact her people were 100 per centers, and Germany the only country on earth. We must get out of that notion, good, kind people. At the time of the Revolutionary War, Kosciusko, Count Pulas'ki, General LaFayette, and Baron Steuben from Germany, all came over here and fought side by side with our boys for freedom in America. I guess perhaps they would like to have been considered 100 per cent French, and 100 per cent Prussian, and 100 per cent Polish. But they were not. They were 100 per cent liberty-loving men, and I wish we had more like them in America today. Do you like that sentiment or not? (Applause.) If I had an ambition to display the knowledge obtained years ago of the ccmposite elements of cow's milk in its undeleted and undiluted state, it would be nn exhibition of pedantry for which you who know more about the subject than I ever did would not forgive me, and I doubt If I could forgive myself. From early infancy, the value of milk as a dietetic appealed to me with a force I seem to have been unable to resist. Had I done so, an early grave had been my portion, and the pleasant banquet of this pleasant evening would not. As an infant and as a growing boy, milk formed an important element of my regular feeds, but I did not know its chemical composition. I did not know that the yellow scum which rose to the uphill side of it by standing was carboniferous in Its composition, or that the curd contained the nitrogenous elements so essential to the building up of bodily tissues, sticking to the ribs like a democrat to a postoffice; or that the whey contained some sugar, a few unimportant phosphates, much water, and was chiefly useful in keeping hungry calves about two removes from the bone - yard. Johnnycake and milk were important items in my regular diet when a boy on the farm; and when mother — Bless her memory! — set the great pitcher of milk on the table for us boys to partake of ad libitum, the liquid had neither been pasteurized, to queer the natural taste, nor paralyzed by having been run through a separator and the car - boniferous part sent to the creamery. It was all there, praise God! To which circumstance I attribute the fact that I am all here, and able to sit up and take nourishment. Today — which means every day— I am dependent upon commerce for my inadequate milk supply. It comes 1 to me in large-mouthed bottles with paper stoppers, and the lack of flavor tells me it has been scientifically treated in more ways than one. It is "certified" milk — </seg>
            <seg id="p093">92 whatever that means; is chemically pure, and morally like unto Caesar's wife — above suspicion. When it stands, nothing of or about it rises except the price. Its chief value is to cook with, if you don't care what you cook. Yet I am here to declare, as one who has studied food values in and out of college, that as an article of diet, milk comes nearer to furnishing every element for the repair and maintenance of bodily tissue than any other one thing except wheat, and the most nourishing elements of wheat are removed in the process of making patent flour; so that we give the best to our cattle and hogs, and reserve the inferior portion for human consumption. Milk is not only invaluable as an article of diet, but wonderful as a prophylactic. Those who substitute it as a mealtime drink for tea. coffee, bevo, and wood alcohol, never need fear the terrors of inter - stitial nephritis, gastritis, appendicitis, hepatitis, and a dozen other itis-es that send one to the hospital, from which he can never hope to escape with a whole hide. Another thing, arterio-sclerosis is positively obviated, if begun in time, by a generous milk diet; and greatly relieved by it even in cases where the blood pressure registers above two hundred. Lord forbid that what I am now saying should be construed as propaganda for the benefit of the dairy monopolists who are putting some of us where we must beg for milk from door to door, or go without! I long to see the day when every honest householder who is not an advocate of race suicide will have a cow to go with his automobile and other necessities, and not only have milk enough to generously supply the needs of his own household, but a surplus to furnish the neighbors at say five cents a quart, or six quarts for a quarter. Not till that time comes will the world be what it ought to be as to dietetics. Farewell the ruin and the wreck. That now too oft we must record; When in each home a cow called Speck Gives all the milk she can afford. Each home provided with a cow This earth will seem more fair than now. I do not wish to aggravate Conditions that are none too fine, Yet do I view a better state With these prophetic eyes of mine When all the people can succeed In having all the milk they need. (Applause.) THE TOASTMASTER: After hearing that address, the best argu - ment that I can make in favor of an exclusive milk diet, as practiced </seg>
            <seg id="p094">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 93 by Dr. Bixby, is the physical and spiritual example of the efficacy of it In lifting Dr. Bixby to higher and better paths of sentiment, and to a higher place among the Immortals of Humor than he enjoyed before he began this exclusive diet. I know I have opportunity to carry to all of you a real pleasure by my promise very soon to present to you for such words as he may please to offer, your own President, Jacob Sass. I see he has me listed as "Honorable" Edgar Howard, and himself listed as plain Jacob Sass. He is more honorable than I in this — that he did not take part in the work of taking the kick out of lager beer as soon as I did. He is more honorable, because I began in taking part in taking the kick out of beer long before I quit drinking it, and Jake didn't. You people of the Association do not know, perhaps, what the crowning ambition of Jacob Sass* life is. I do know, because he told it to me confidentially. We were boys together, and he tells me many things, perhaps, which he does not tell you. He told me the crowning ambition of his life was that he might be able to invent some process in the interests of the boyhood and girlhood of America which would take the kick out of the cow as effectually as the govern - ment would take the kick out of booze. I do not know if he will ever accomplish it or not; but I have watched the way of this man for years, and never knew him to fail in any undertaking. I have real pleasure in presenting to you your own President, my boyhood chum, and my friend of the present hour — Jacob Sass. (Ap - plause.) MR. JACOB SASS: Ladies and Gentlemen: A good many years ago we used to come to Lincoln to our agricultural meetings. It was different then from what it is now. Often we did not get down to the Farm. We would come to the hotel and register, and there used to be a little corner somewhere — what was it they used to call it. Judge? Oh, yes, the grill room. And the boys would go in and put their feet on the railing, and you know how it went. "Come on, boys; have another one!" And a good many got too much of it and they did not attend the agricultural meeting. So my good friend, Howard, got busy. He said, "This stuff they are selling over the bar has too much kick in it. We must get rid of it." He kept working on and on. I watched him and thought he would not succeed. But they did. I put up the argument, "Here, Judge, why don't you want us farmers to drink a little lager? It is made of farm products. It is made of barley, and the other good stuff is made of rye and corn. What are we going to do with our grain?" He said, "You are far behind the times. Put it in something and manufacture it in some product where there isn't any kick. The best thing today for you farmers is to get dairy cows. Feed the grain to the dairy cows, and there is no kick in milk." So that's the time the farmers started the dairy business; and they are manufacturing a drink without a kick. </seg>
            <seg id="p095">94 A good many men. especially well-to-do people, take up farming and dairying as a pastime and as a pleasure. They like to see things grow out of the soil and develop, and a good many of them went into the dairy business and watched the development of the dairy herds. Was that a detriment to the farmers? I say no. They had the means to get good sires, good cows, and develop some of our very best animals, which could not be done by a man of average means. This fall I happened to be in Chicago at the dairy show there. It was the biggest surprise I ever had in my life. As I went through the dairy barn and saw those nice brown Swiss, those orange-colored Guernseys, the beautiful Ayrshires, and the massive Holsteins, I wondered how it was possible to breed up such nice cattle. I knew it took men of money to do it. And through those wonderful herds, we small breeders can improve our own. But the great mass of men and women, while they enjoy dairy farming, nevertheless must depend upon the farm for the support of their family and for the education of their children, and also for the accumulation of a competence to provide for a rainy day and old age. And they are therefore ambitious to make dairy farming profitable. The producer of milk — the manufacturer and the distributor of dairy products — are engaged in the same line of work. There should be an understanding between them as to the work each has to do, and there should be an equitable sharing of the returns, and the consumer should be supplied with the benefits of high-grade, wholesome dairy products at prices that are reasonable, but profitable. Gentlemen, about a year ago the farmers and milk producers got disgusted. They were producing milk at such a low price they could not keep up and could not keep the dairy herds. There were a good many, especially around Omaha and in Sarpy and Washington counties, who were getting rid of their dairy cows. They started an organization they called "The Mid-West Milk Producers' Association." It has helped them to a large extent. They are getting a fair price for their milk and are going back into the dairy business. I want to say to the creamery men il was a great help to them. I heard Professor Frandsen say today that Omaha was the biggest butter market in the world. I believe that in time to come, Nebraska is going to be the largest dairy state In the Union. (Applause.) We have an abundance of alfalfa and hay, and now that milk production is profitable, we are all going into the dairy business, and the creamery man, where he has handled one quart of milk, will handle five, and in the long run this will be a benefit. I will ask them to co-operate with us. We are going to t&gt;e fair. The motto of the Nebraska Dairy Association is "A square deal to everybody, and special privilege to none." I thank you. (Applause.) THE TOASTM ASTER: I notice by the program here that your next speaker is the President of a College. I approach the introduction </seg>
            <seg id="p096">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 95 of such a personage with fear and trembling. I do not know his measure — muscularly speaking. I do not believe I have ever had the honor, of meeting him. But I know the capabilities of a college presi - dent. I recall in the law department, some of my classmates were wicked boys and used that which produces liquid nicotine, and were careless about where they deposited it, and would let it trickle down the legs of their desks. One day the old President of the College happened to be sneaking around in the law room, and evidently had observed something of the situation. The Dean called him to a seat by him, and we went on with our class and finished the lesson for the morning hour. Then the Dean asked him if he had something to say, and the President replied that he had something very, very important to say. And this is what he said: "Those young gentlemen who are expectorating upon the desk legs must not expect-to-rate very high in their class." That is all. That was enough. I have been timid in the presence of college presidents ever since. Yet I must be brave and do my duty, and must tell you a story attaching to this particular president's name. It is said of him that he is also a very knowing man. Everybody admits that. He is also a violently prejudiced man. He deals in Holsteins. He is so prejudiced in favor of Holsteins, he tried to get possession of all the land adjoining him near College View, in order that there might be no other breeds associating in the same atmosphere with his Holsteins. (Laughter and applause.) But it may be he comes by that prejudice honestly. Do you know men come by prejudices honestly? To illustrate it: myself know this to be true. In Nebraska, Dr. Bixby and other people of his rough-neck kind arrogate to themselves the right to call ther men liars. They would not do that in Alabama. I was visiting oma friends in that State and the court was in session. There was a disturbance on the lawn, and the Court, ordered the sheriff to quell t. The sheriff went out, and pretty soon he came back and took his seat, and the disturbance went on. The Court rapped the sheriff and said, "Mr. Sheriff, didn't I tell you to stop that noise out there? It is disturbing the court." The sheriff stood first on one leg and then on another, and twirled his hat, and said, "Your Honor, I can't do it just yet. The d lie has been passed out there, and it hasn't been fit out yet." In our country it would not mean anything, but in Alabama it means a good deal, because everybody in Alabama regards the term "liar" as a blow, and the courts have so held. So much for the prejudice in a college president, which I trust yon will overlook because of the manifold blessings and benefits he has carried to those of you who want to make the Holstein the premier breed of the world. Again, as to his knowledge, I think I can illustrate the depths of it by citing a little scene at a banquet table in Iowa. There are </seg>
            <seg id="p097">96 two wealthy men who operate farm papers over there. Owners of farm papers always grow wealthy. They did grow wealthy through the efforts of the country advertisers to promote their circulation. These two wealthy owners made a money wager of a hundred cfollars. Mr. Meredith, the editor of "Successful Farming," is very wealthy. That is a good old Virginia name, and he should know better than to gamble; but he gambled one hundred dollars with Mr. Wallace of the "Farmer" over there that he could put a certain brand of "oleo" before this College President from Nebraska — this man who knows more about Holstein cows than the most of us — and the College President would not know it was oleo. So Wallace took him up, and the money was deposited in the hands of a spectator, and Mr. Meredith won the money. Ladies and gentlemen, I now have the pleasure of presenting to you President H. A. Morrison, of Union College. PRESIDENT H. A. MORRISON, of College View: Ladies and Gentlemen: It is a splendid thing sometimes not to be known. And sometimes it is a splendid thing to be known. It is even sometimes a splendid thing not to be known by an honorable Toastmaster, because we can be described in a general class, instead of being pointed out as one in particular. ' I am not very much like the little lad who said that when he grew up he was going to be a preacher, because he said a preacher could holler all he wanted to on Sunday. (Laughter.) On some of these questions, the viewpoint from which we look depends a good deal as to what our decisions are; and ordinarily we can see just about what we are looking for. I remember reading a story of a little lad who was in trouble with his mother, and she started for the rod and he started under the bed, and got so far she could not reach him. She thought she would let him remain until his father got home, and the little chap was very content to stay there a while. When his father came, his mother told him regarding the circumstance of the afternoon, and his father started under the bed after him. The little fellow turned around and said, "Is that you, Dad? Is she after you, too?" (Laughter.) I think, ladies and gentlemen, that even the committee which asked me to say a few words to you this evening on "Advertising" perhaps 'did not know they, also, made a mistake. But they will have to stand it now. Pat and Mike were going through the woods, and in the tree as they went along one of them discovered a wildcat. Pat said to Mike, "Mike, you get up and shake him down, and I will catch him." So Mike goes up to shake him down, and Pat catches him, and there is the flying of fur. Mike calls, "Do you want me to come down and help hold him?" </seg>
            <seg id="p098">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 97 "No. Come down and help me let him go!" (Laughter.) Now I do not know tonight but what it would be almost necessary tine to prove to you — I was going to say that I had really seen a y cow. Ot course that won't be entirely necessary. But that I i really felt the dairy cow — that might be necessary to prove; or at t there might be some who would raise the question. Our Toastmaster has told you one College President was very much prejudiced. I had about decided I would start in along the line and correct each speaker who has spoken to you tonight previous to this. The Toastmaster himself, in his introductory speech, told about milking a cow once and he made a mistake. If Mr. Young wasn't here, I would like to remind you it was a Jersey cow. I think that was the mistake, perhaps. (Laughter.) Then our friend, Dr. Bixby, called his cow "Speck." I think he should have called her Spot. I want to prove to you our Toastmaster really tells the truth in detail and in particular, so I have made these two statements. But I started out to undertake to prove to you that it isn't all just theory with me about this dairy cow business, and if you will pardon me, I will tell you my first introduction to the cow — I guess it was a dairy cow. I was a lad about seven years old, and in those days father kept what we called the "family cow." I had not been accustomed to milking her. My sister just older than I did the milking. One evening as she was milking I thought it would be interesting to find out the disposition of the cow, and I took out a pin and tried her disposition. Well, you can guess perhaps some of the rest. But a portion was this: As sister went to the house, I went, too. Father said, "Sonny, you can take the pail and milk the cow." From that day for about fifteen years, the cow and I were very intimately associated every night and morning. That was my introduction to the dairy business. Now, . who can tell what would have happened if I had not tried out the disposition of the old family cow? I was asked to say a few words to you tonight about the advertising business for dairy cattle; and I think we would all assume immedi - ately that we are talking in particular about the pure bred animal. I do not know whether the rest of you took notes or not. I did. Mr. Kby used a good scheme of advertising. Did you get it? I think said he owed each of us one of his books, and we owed him a dollar. r i3h I could take the same advantage that he has! I think the fundamental thing in our advertising business and in the breeding business of pure bred dairy cattle is to give a proper background.* I think that is the most necessary element in our advertising. I am not talking about the sheet you advertise on. I am talking about the element that will count most, and that is background. </seg>
            <seg id="p099">98 I think every man will admit in this day and age of the world and the way business is conducted, advertising is one of the big things. Every man, regardless of what kind of business he is engaged in, finds there are ways of advertising that are used. It is told that Mr. Douglas, the Shoe Man, when he went into the business, did not ha_ve very much money — I think $3,500 — and spent it lor adveitising, and started his business. There is a lesson to be gained from this. The first element I want to bring to you tonight is the need of our general advertising. I am not talking about advertising the Holstein or Jersey just now. I am not talking about any particular herds, or how we will dispose of a particular animal in our herd. But the question is of educating the business men on our farms to understand and appreciate and have the nerve to invest in pure bred dairy cattle. I wonder how many men there are on the farms of our State tonight who have cows they are milking giving only about 150 pounds of butter a year; and how many of those men know about cows in their own State that will produce from 500 to 1,000 of butter in a year? I think, ladies and gentlemen, our first move in a great advertising campaign is to bring home to these individuals the great gap between just "cow" and "dairy cow." I tell you there is a good deal more difference between them than between "shoes" and "Douglas shoes." A man who wants to sell a piano knows how to advertise. He goes into the country and gets stuck, or breaks a singletree — in these days I presume something happens to his engine — and he asks if he may unload his piano until he can come and get it. He opens it up and tells them to feel free to use it, never expecting to have to take that piano out of the home. And he never does. That would be a splendid thing in our dairy business, but it might be hard on the cow! * , But there are ways and means whereby we can bring to our neighbors and friends and to every man on the farm in the State and bear home upon him the fact that there are cows in his own State that will produce from four to ten times the amount being produced by the cows he ii keeping. And until we can make our men realize that, other types of advertising are not going to be of very great benefit. I am holding it as fundamental that we may force home to the minds of these individuals the need of a greater production on the part of the dairy cow. I am aware after men learn all this and hear a certain individual has a cow that will produce 120 pounds of milk in a day, they may believe it — that is, may believe that man can do it. The question is, "I could not do that." This is illustrated very well by a man I came in contact with In the hills of New Hampshire. He owned a little farm on which he had been able to earn a scanty livelihood. He heard about the great fertile plains of Iowa and Nebraska, so he sold out his little place </seg>
            <seg id="p100">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 99 I it twelve years ago and had the faith to come west, and the o only a few of the men grown up among those conditions have, came to this section of the country and traveled around from 3 to place, and saw land worth $200 an acre. It scared him out. went back home and said to the man who bought his farm, "I t my farm back." He tried to persuade him it was almost ssary for him to sell back his farm at the price he paid. The new er was a lumberman, and he said, "I will sell back that farm for price I paid you providing you will let me cut the timber off." the man finally agreed to it. The lumberman received $2,500 the timber and sold back the farm for $2,400. This man had a in of a more fertile farm. He had heard something about what is g done in the central west on these fertile plains. He had the e to start out, but his courage failed him. We as breeders of pure bred cattle must not only convince these individuals these animals can produce what we have proved they can produce, but we must convince them they can make them produce in this way. It is in that I believe we have the background of the advertising we must do in order to influence individuals either to put in herds of pure bred cattle, or to breed up their grade herds by using a pure bred sire. Then there is an element we must remember as breeders and sellers of animals of this type. We must remember in order to build a business — and all other advertising fails if we fail on this one Pt — we must be absolutely frank; we must absolutely deliver the Is to these individuals who start into the business; we must d back of them and let them rely on us until they have gotten enough so they can see their own way clear. I remember a man who bought a heifer of a big firm in the east, he failed to freshen. He reported this to the firm, and they said. You have kept her long enough. Come over and pick out any similar nimal that suits you, and sell off that animal for beef." That did ore to build up a business for that firm than any other single trans - ction, and it was the best advertising any firm could do under like onditions. So I say to you gentlemen tonight, that one of the big ea lures is reaching out and getting individuals not interested in the usiness today, and when we get in touch with men who have sions to build up. not only to give them a start, but to see they ave the opportunity to make good in the business they undertake. (I have seen men and women get interested in supplying their c trade in another way, even by buying the powdered milk. The t business is getting prevalent, and I almost begin to think some them have been taking lessons from the good old darkey, Ben cson. He was discussing which was the most intelligent animal, le said the dog, and some the horse; but old Ben Jackson said, goat am de most intelligent animal, and I kin prove it. I was ig over town one night and it was muddy. Passing along, I was </seg>
            <seg id="p101">100 all dressed up, and there was a billy goat tied out near the road. As I went to pass dat goat, he started for me and upset me in de mud. When I got up, I read on a big sign: 'Chew Jackson's plug,' an' he was chewin' my plug hat. (Laughter.) De goat he am de most intelligent animal." There are some people today slipping off, and instead of going to the cow for their milk, are going to the goat, not realizing one cow can supply as much as eight goats. Dr. Bixby has wished every family had Ihe old cow. Speck; but would every family have to have eight goats to offset the old cow? There is another thing our dairymen are wrong on. Our Toast - master has touched upon it and given you a beautiful story about it. Many have fallen for the idea of using oleomargarine instead of dairy butter. 'It makes me think of a good old darkey, who, when he went to meeting, said, "Breddren and Sisters, you all knows an' I knows I hasn't always done just what is right. I have stole chickens off'n de chicken roost, an' hogs; an' I got drunk an' slashed up people with my razor. I'se shot craps an' swore an' all dem things. But I thank the Lord there am one thing I have not done: I have not ever los" mah religion!" (Laughter.) We have hung onto the dairy cow and the dairy business in thought and in talk all our lives, and yet, like the old darkey, have reemlngly not been able to tell the difference between real good dairy butter and oleomargarine! Just a word in regard to specific advertising. I believe in advertis - ing animals for sale; we should frankly state what we have to sell, giving the price. There are all classes of individuals, each wanting an animal of this class or the other. Give to them the element or the principal characteristic of that animal that would lead you to think it was worth the price. It it has individuality, emphasize that; if pedigree, emphasize that. Frankly present to the public the element you want to emphasize in a clear, clean-cut, outstanding way, which is only for the purpose of bringing together the men who are looking for a particular type of animal which this proves to be. In this State where we have so many things some of the other states do not have — and this is impressed on my mind as I think of a trip I took in visiting different Holstein farms in New York and neighboring states. I was at a big farm in New York State out about ten miles from town and four miles from a freight station, and I told these men I was from Nebraska. You know and I know that the grain these men were feeding to those dairy cows, hauling the feed four miles to that farm, came from Illinois, Iowa and Nebraska. This man said, "I buy my alfalfa at Lexington." If these men on these places can build up the pure bred business and ship the feed from Lexington, half- way across the United States, what can Nebraska do in the dairy business if we get the vision and take hold of this proposition? </seg>
            <seg id="p102">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 101 I would like to see the time come when every farm had its pure bred dairy cows upon it. Of course I will say the beautiful black and white. But th~e time is coming — and it has come to some extent during the food conservation during the war — that men and women are getting interested in farm products. In fact, it has almost become rather fashionable in some of our cities for these individuals to be able to talk in farm language and use some of the farm vocabulary. There were two women riding out from Chicago, each one wanting to let the other know she knew something about farm life. They passed a lot with a bunch of cows. One of them said to the other, "My, look at those little cowlets!" And her friend, wanting to prove she knew the language of the farm, said, "Those are not cowlets. They are bullets!" (Laughter.) Let us make every man and woman in the State of Nebraska talk the pure bred dairy cow until we have them on every farm in the State. (Applause.) THE TOASTM ASTER: I will make the excuse for Dr. Bixby, who told me to tell you he had neglected to feed Speck this evening, and he Just thought about it. (Applause.) That would be about as nearly correct as the average things he says. (Laughter.) Ladles and gentlemen, some years ago, through no machination of my own, I was called to serve officially alongside of the next speaker on your program. At that time he was a member of the State Legis - lature, and he as a legislator had a hobby. He was the watchdog of the treasury, and preached frugality from morning to night. Somebody accused him of being a Scotchman, and he denied it. But the gentle - man making the accusation said, "You show all the earmarks of the characteristic trait of a Scotchman." Mr. Stuhr asked him what that trait was. Now in his own private capacity, Mr. Stuhr has none of the earmarks of a Scotchman. I am speaking of him in his official capacity. In his private life he would buy a drink whenever it came his turn, and sometimes oftener; but as a legislator, he was all the time insisting we should be more frugal in the matter of appropria - tions. So he insisted this gentleman should tell him what the chronic characteristic of a Scotchman was. "You said it was frugality. Do you see any great evidence of frugality in my general conduct?" "Not as a man, but as a legislator, I do. You remind me of a story. Three gentlemen were traveling together. They were all college men. They fell into the college habit of telling about athletic feats witnessed in their college days. The American said the closest contest he ever witnessed in his life was a race where two of the horses ran so evenly the judges were compelled to award the decision to one of them by the thickness of a hair on his nose. The Englishman and the Irishman agreed that was remarkably close; but the Englishman said he saw two yachts sail so evenly the decision went to one of them by the thickness of a new coat of paint on her prow. The Irishman said he knew a closer race than that. (Laughter.) </seg>
            <seg id="p103">102 Now, Mr. Stuhr, will you tell what you think ought to be done with reference to the matter of State Dairy Laws? (Applause.) MR. LEO B. STUHR: I am afraid the Toastmaster has made it rather difficult for me to start this, because I had made up my mind to refrain from stories, thinking you would be more interested in getting information with reference to dairy la/ws. But I do recall with a great deal of pleasure the association of two years ago. The honorable Toastmaster presided over an unruly Senate, and one of the very important pieces of legislation enacted during that rather stormy session was taking the kick out of practically everything but milk. I shall try to give you some information relating to the dairy laws of this State, because from requests for information that come to the Department daily, I am sure there has been a great deal of mis - understanding relating to certain provisions of these new laws. In the first place, I will take up the dairy law in particular.. There are several provisions that were entirely new, so far as dairy regula - tions are concerned, in this State. The first of these is the provision relating to licensing. I might say a few words explaining the licensing feature, and the advantages that are naturally gained from the licens - ing system. Licensing in a general way means regulation. It means there is a small fee imposed to regulate or control any certain law or any measure which attempts to check any particular activity. This license is not a new thing as applied to the dairy industry. The licensing feature in Iowa has been in vogue for a number of years. I believe Commissioner Barney has probably told you this afternoon that Iowa was one of the first states to have this provision which was probably brought about largely through the efforts he made at that time. Now the advantages derived from dairy licenses are several. In the first place, it means that the sanitary conditions must be carried out; that dairy products' must comply with certain regulations as to purity. It means that the public as a whole is benefited by the quality of the product they will receive. It is a license imposed for the sale of milk. It protects a man who has a first-class dairy and a first-class herd from the man who does not have such a herd or have conditions that are of the best. It gives additional protection in that the Department may revoke a license if there are any irregu - larities, or if some one attempted maliciously to violate the regulation carried with this law. Those are some of the advantages a licensing system brings about. I think the most frequent misunderstanding in regard to the license systom is just what it covers and who must have one. The law provides the owner of a herd of more than five cows, provided the product in milk or cream from such herd is sold for consumption as milk or cream, must be licensed. That means if a man sells milk product by distributing it himself to a dealer, who subsequently </seg>
            <seg id="p104">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 103 distributes it, he must have a license. It also means any dealer selling the product of a herd of more than five cows must have a license. The exemptions are manufacturing establishments, such as a creamery that does not re-sell milk; or a condenser; or an ice cream plant. These do not have to have a license. But very ofter you will find a creamery in turn will sell milk. It means the patrons of that creamery, and the creamery itself, must each have a license. The next section that seems to be very much misunderstood is the section relating to the testing of dairy cattle. This is known as Section 4 in the dairy law. It provides that all dairy cows, regardless of the size of the herd, must be tested by a licensed veterinarian one year previously, or the milk must be pasteurized. So you see there is no connection between the licensing feature and the, testing feature of the dairy law. The ruling the Department has placed on this particular section is that if the milk is sold to a plant which pasteurizes, it is not necessary to pasteurize this milk on the farm, nor is it required that that herd must be tested, although it is recommended all herds be tested, if possible. This does not mean, however, after it has been found that tuberculosis existed in a herd, this milk can be sold, even if pasteurized; because the section specifically provides no m.lk or cream can be sold from diseased animals. This is a section which is very much mis-understood. Only recently a great many circular letters have been sent out to try to interpret this so that it will be more generally under - stood. You may be interested in knowing what the Department is doing in the way of carrying out the provisions of the dairy law. I will say we have an inspection force that does only dairy work, which consists of a chief inspector and four district inspectors, each having about one-fourth of the State for his territory. These men are charged with doing the general dairy inspection work, consisting of product from the farm dairies, the cream stations, the distributing points and creameries — or the several phases of the dairy industry. They are also charged with the duty of examinations for new cream station outfits. You may be interested in knowing about the number of licenses that have been issued under the new dairy law. I will say all these licenses expire the first of July, so that the figures are licenses collected since July first. Number of dairy licenses 1,463 Creameries' 70 Test licenses 2,441 Wholesale ice cream licenses 58 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">104 Cream stations (approximately) 1,550 Retail ice cream licenses 64 Condensed milk plant licenses 4 Inspections of dairy establishments 795 Inspection of cream receiving stations l,05« The force averages about four and a half months that this Inspec - tion work has been carried on. Another feature of the dairy law that is new is the standardization of glassware. The law provides that this shall be standardized by the Dairy Department of the University and their stamp must be on this glassware wherever It is used for station work, or wherever milk or cream is bought on the butter-fat basis. One of the other important laws relating to the dairy Industry In which you are all interested, which was taken over by the Department of Agriculture under the reorganization, is the law relating to the tubercular reduction. This law, together with the section providing for the testing of dairy cattle under the dairy law, has opened up a very large field of activity, and it is needless to say, a very important one. I have a statement here by Dr. Deno of the Public Health Service of New York City, in which he says bovine tuberculosis is rapidly trans - mitted to the children, not in tuberculosis of the lungs, but of the Joints, etc. It is rarely transmitted from a bovine to an adult human being. You are probably quite familiar with the accredited herd plans', but I will say a few words on this subject which may be of interest. The last legislature made an appropriation of $75,000 to meet a like appro - priation from the Federal Government to indemnify herd owners for their tubercular cattle. The administrative work in carrying on this campaign is quite great. We have as high as ten veterinarians in the field doing this type of work. The Federal statistics show that the amount necessary for carrying on the work is about 33 V4 per cent of the value of the cattle destroyed. On that basis it would mean about $50,000 available for indemnifying of the herd owners who operate under the accredited plan by way of indemnifying them for reactors. The policy of the Department has been to work on the best herds. The dairy herds are given preference. The pure bred beef type is the next type that is preferred. In some cases it is the intent to take on herds of good grade cattle, if the money holds out. Under this plan, a man makes application, and he must comply with the rules and regu - lations set forth in the application, which Include the testing of his herd three different times at intervals of six months. If he has a clean herd, he will be placed in the accredited list. If there are reactors, he t indemnified to an extent of not exceeding $50 from the State and $50 m the Federal Government. He must live up to the sanitary and irantine requests, too. </seg>
            <seg id="p106">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 105 I will give you a few figures which, may be of Interest. It was adopted in Nebraska in September, 1918. During the rest of the year very little work was done. In 1919, the work for the first few months lagged considerably, hence it was not definitely known if the measure would be passed. After it was passed, the work was carried on more vigorously. The number of co-operative herds tested in 1919 was 274. This is groups of herds. The total number of cattle tested was 6,035. The number of reactors was 471, or 7.8 per cent. The total number of herds accredited to the present time is nine. The reason for that is, the time is just beginning to expire that these accredited herds will come in. There are in the United States 1,355 accredited herds of 35,204 head, on November first. The official teat had been made on 1,233 herds, consisting of 192,000 head. Under supervision November first there were 176 herds, consisting of 367,000 head. It shows the amount of work that is being done along this line. There are at present over 300 men engaged In tubercular reduction — both Federal and State men. To give you an idea of the rating of Nebraska with other states, I will say all states of the Union have adopted the plan. Minnesota, being the pioneer, has at the present time 216 accredited herds, com - pared with nine from Nebraska. There is something that is worth knowing and remembering, because it shows the amount of work and the standing that Minnesota has in the dairy world, as far as tuberc - ulous reduction is concerned. While I was in Chicago, a Senator from Minnesota who is a large pure bred dairy breeder, made the statement that he was shipping two critters to South Africa by express. The man had never seen the cattle. He knew this Senator was a great breeder, and there was no doubt but that the herd was clean. So you can see the importance that will have to be placed on this phase In future of keeping a herd clean, or the necessity of having the number of animals in the herd tested. It shows that while at the pres - ent time this is confined probably more closely to pure bred herds, it is lust a matter of time until it will be almost general. It will mean If a man is going to sell a dairy cow, the question will be, "Is that cow tested?" And in order to get a high price, that particular animal must be tested. . There is one other subject I think should be mentioned at this time, as a great many complaints are made from time to time. This 1 relates to the fees to be charged for the testing of dairy cows. You under - stand under the accredited herd plan, all of the testing is done by Federal or State men. No private man is permitted to test an ac - credited herd. Under the old law, private practitioners are permitted, after being recognized by the State Department, to test dairy cows for tuberculosis, under rules and regulations and after having been duly </seg>
            <seg id="p107">106 recognized by the Department. This matter has been taken up from time to time and the agreement was arrived at several months ago as to what constituted a fair price- for the testing of dairy cattle. The figures are as follows: $5.00 for the first animal; $2.50 for the next five, or $17.50 for six; $1.00 for the next fifteen, or $32.50 for twenty - one; $0.75 for each additional to fifty — about a dollar apiece. This means at all times an effort should be made to arrange for as many catt'.e as possible to get the best rate in having the cows tested. We have used every means we can in getting co-operation through county agents and veterinarians and inspectors of the Department, so that the closest co-operation would be obtained in getting these animals accredited at the best price for the herd owners. The Department has no authority of prosecuting anyone who does not live up to this agreement; but in a general way, I think the ex - ceptions are comparatively few. If there are any violations or exces - sive charges outside of this accredited scale, we will be glad to hear from you and make an investigation. I want to mention the prospects of the dairy industry in Nebraska. I think it is a very important subject. In other words, we do not want to lose sight of the fact Nebraska has all of the requirements that will make it a wonderful dairy State. The industry has probably not ad - vanced here quite as fast as in some other states; but I think it has been due to the fact there has not been quite as much intensive farm - ing in Nebraska as in some of the adjoining states where more land is tillable than in Nebraska. One advantage which Nebraska has in this respect is that it is a wonderful alfalfa state. It produces any form of grain necessary for feeding dairy cattle. Another point which Mr. Morrison brought out is advertising. The dairy industry in Nebraska is not well enough known. There has not been enough publicity in promoting the dairy industry. In getting this publicity, the thing to keep in mind is to bring out the details that you want the public to know. In a general way they are: Quality at all times; quality of your dairy product, whether it is cream, butter, cheose or milk. Quality should be advocated at all times. The Asso - ciation should promote quality. It is only by getting quality that the State gets a reputation beyond its borders. The same thing holds true in celling dairy animals themselves. The pure bred animals, the tested, clean herds — those points should be advertised. It means money and more money and reputation and advancement and a future to the in - dustry. It is only by keeping those things in mind the industry is* as - sured and Nebraska will be among the first of the dairy states. In closing, I want to say we have in the past held public hearings. Various parties having a grievance, such as a producer or a manufac - turer, where a public hearing would have a tendency to adjust matters, wers given this opportunity. The Department will be ready to hold hearings of that kind if you desire. I want to impress upon you the </seg>
            <seg id="p108">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 107 attitude of the Department in the enforcement of these laws. We want to give a fair and square deal to all concerned — the producer, manufacturer, distributor, and the public. If you have any grievance or anything that needs an investigation, we will be glad to make it. We want you to feel the Department of Agriculture is your Department and working for your interest and enforcing the laws that have been enacted. It is the duty of the Department to give the best results at all times. I thank you. (Applause.) THE TOASTMASTER: There has been a good deal said about ad - vertising tonight. I am a believer in advertising. That is my business, largely. I am also a believer in pictorial advertising. I note your next address is entitled "How Iowa Does It." Here is a living illustration of it. It happened in this way, not by design. The procession was on the way to Nebraska from faraway Virginia. It was getting toward winter time, and the Iowans suggested the folks had better stop with some relatives in central Iowa until the Missouri froze over so they could get across. You gentlemen of Nebraska interested in the dairy business ought to be able to learn a good deal from personal touch with the distin - guished dairyman who comes to you from Iowa — Mr. Barney, Commis - sioner of the State of Iowa. It does not say what, but I presume it also refers to Holsteins. He is a wonderful advertiser. He goes out - side the family to advertise. They tell me he has done-more to make a certain brand of oleo famous than any man in America. (Laughter.) He has loaned a picture of his prize cows to the manufacturer of oleo, and it is said to be the most popular brand on the market. I do noi know the connection between the legal department as regulated by this Commissioner and the oleo makers in Chicago, but no doubt Mr. Barney will make it all plain to you. MR. W. B. BARNEY, of Des Moines: Ladies and Gentlemen of the Nebraska Dairymen's Association: I presume your Toastmaster refers to a little incident that I mentioned in my talk to you this afternoon. I want to say I visit quite a number of states, and it may be worth while to you people to know that you have, in my opinion, a really good, high-class herd of dairy cattle out here at the Farm. I do not know of any state east or west — and I have visited a lot of them — with a herd that surpasses the herd I saw this afternoon. (Applause.) I want to say I feel certain that is largely due to the efforts' Professor Frandsen has exercised here. I know he has been whole-hearted in the work and has been doing everything he can to help the Nebraska dairy - men. I wish we had as good a herd at Ames. 1 cannot quite admit you have as good a school as we have, but I am obliged to admit you have a better herd of dairy cattle, and I am ashamed of the Iowa cattle when I see what you have here. I do not know who put up this proposition of the change in the way your laws are administered. It is an up-to-date proposition. I wisn we </seg>
            <seg id="p109">108 i i had the same thing worked out in Iowa. I know it does away with more or less duplication of work. I want to compliment the men. I presume Mr. Stuhr had a good deal to do with getting this worked out. Whoever did it is entitled to a lot of credit. I hope Iowa will be wideawake enough to put the same thing across in the near future. As I was sitting here, I was reminded ot a story I sometimes tell of a gentleman who got into a city about the size of Lincoln, and he did nut know the restaurants and made inquiry as to where he might get a good meal. He was directed by a boy to a restaurant and assured it was one of the best in town. When he had finished his meal he had three hairs left at the side of his plate. There was a colored fellow who had waited on him, and the man said, "Sam, I was advised this was one of the high-class restaurants in this city. I would like to know why I am served with a meal in which I find three hairs?" "Well, Boss, I'll tell you; if you just 'splain to me where you found dem hairs, I might gib you some reason to' it." "Well, I found that hair in the honey." "Huh, dey's nothing to that. Dat's puffickly easy to 'splain. Dat hair got in de honey out ob de comb." "Well, all right. Now tell me how that one got in the ice cream." "Dat's no harden than de first question; not a bit. I can 'splain dat away all right enough. It got in when dey shaved de ice, don't you see?" "You're pretty clever; but the third hair was in my apple pie." "Well, well, Boss, I just can't tell how dat third hair got in, 'cause I am sure dat apple pie was made from a variety of apples known as Baldwins, so I can't 'splain dat at all." (Laughter.) I see I am expected to say something about "How Iowa Does It." In what I shall say I may have to refer to some of my personal ex - periences in the work. I remember when I started I had a very good friend who was a democrat. I was a republican. We started about the same time in the dairy game. He had Jerseys and Holsteins, and I had Holsteins and Jerseys. Finally we came to the same conclusion — that if a man had one breed and took care of it well, he had his hands full. One day I met my friend, and he said, "Don't you believe we had better trade herds. Let's see if we can't get together and each have a breed. I know you like Holsteins, and I prefer Jerseys, and maybe we can make a trade." "That strikes 1 me favorably, and I will be glad to consider it, and will ask you to make me an offer." "My father-in-law is interested with me, and a brother-in-law. I will talk with them, and the next time I see you I will have a proposition to make." He had five Jerseys and I had three Holsteins. We talked it over. We agreed if we could make an even trade it would be all right I </seg>
            <seg id="p110">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 109 was there to make as good a trade as I could, but yet I wanted to make it, so I said, "How about it? Are you ready to make that trade?" "Yes, I guess we can, all right." "What will you do? How can we trade?" "I will tell you. I am going to be generous with you. I will give you our five Jerseys and we'll take your three Holsteins." "Why, is that the best you can do?" "It certainly is. If I had any more Jerseys, I'd give them to you." (Laughter and applause.) He was the type of man who enjoyed the Joke on himself as well as on anybody else. I think he told the story oftener than I did. We met at various dairy meetings and he never failed to tell that joke on him - self. Now J. J. Richardson was in the game at that time, and we were looked upon in the 'SO's as undesirable citizens because we were bring - ing in dairy cattle and spoiling the steers. Everybody in Iowa was feeding steers at that time. We have a State Dairy Association in Iowa, and it was one of the first organizations in existence in the State. I did not take a lot of in - terest in it until about twenty-five years ago. Finally I acted as Presi - dent for four years, and then I was appointed Commissioner ten years ago. . / While I was President of the State Association, we conceived the idea of getting an appropriation. After getting a number of the mem - bers of the legislature pledged for our proposition, we found pledges be - fore election were not always remembered after election; and when we did get down to brass tacks and the bill was referred to the committee, most of our friends had forgotten the promise they made us. We had the letters we had received. We went down to the legislature and re - minded these gentlemen what they said, and we finally brought it out of committee on a minority report. When we got it on the floor of the House and Senate we got by with it in good shape. I do not think today there was ever an appropriation made in Iowa that was of greater value to the people as a general proposition than that proved to be. Professor Van Pelt, one of the editors of the "Kimball's Dairy Farmer," was the first man to be employed in that work. We employed him and Mr. Estell. The result of that appropriation was the making of the Waterloo Dairy Cattle Show. I feel interested in any show that is doing the things they are. The first show put on by the State Dairy Association was not held at Waterloo. We decided something might be done that would interest a larger number of people than we had been getting out. I made this proposition: "There's a basement under the pavilion at Cedar Rapids, and If you want to pay the freight on a few herds of Holsteins, I will take them down, and we will pnt on some demonstrations and have some talks and show the people what a real </seg>
            <seg id="p111">110 good cow is." I suggested Mr. Van Pelt bring down some . Jerseys. We had about fifteen head there. There were no premiums offered. It was a success from the start. Everybody seemed to be interested in the cow rather than in the long-winded talks we had been having from time to time. We went the next year to Waterloo, and the State Dairy Associa - tion financed that show — not out of the appropriation made by the Legislature, because no part of that money could be used for this pur - pose; but we had a fund of $2,300 accumulated during the previous two or three years. I knew if we had a rainy day most of our money would be gone; but we had a good week and a fairly good crowd and came out making $50 or $100. The Waterloo people noticed there was something to it, and they were quite live and made us a proposition they would go in with us next year and take over the financing of the show, and give our Association $500 if we would meet with them and do what we could to boost the show. What was the result? Today we have a show at Waterloo — and some day you can have just as good a one at Lincoln — that is second only to the National Dairy Show. In fact, the cattle that we have at the Waterloo show very generally win at the National Dairy Show. I have been a director of the National Show since it was first organ - ized, and it has had a pretty rocky road until the last few years. Last year we made something like $75,000, and expect to have pretty clear sailing from this time on, because people have learned it is a thing of real value. One of the first things that got me into the notion that this license proposition was a good thing was this: Our ice cream men were re - sponsible for it. We did not have a standard for ice cream at that time. We had a good many ice cream manufacturers and they were having lots of trouble. The government ruling is for a 14 per cent standard, but without a State standard we were not active in trying to enforoce the ruling. The ice cream men kept coming and saying, "Such and such a competitor is making ice cream without putting cream in it. Why don't you get after him?" I said, "I don't know whether I can get very far in making a prose - cution or not." The Commissioner before me had not been extremely successful. But I added, "I will tell you what we may do. If we could have a standard enacted, there would be no trouble. I will send the inspectors out and we will ask them to pick out samples and see whether you have a real grievance or not." We found quite a lot of the product down as low as 3 per cent, and in some instances as low as five-eighths of one per cent! What in - centive had a man to manufacture a product and keep it up to a 14 per cent standard, against such trickery as that? It seemed to me if we could get a standard of ice cream that was reasonable, it would pro - tect the honest dealer, inasmuch as the people had beseeched us to find some way to put the dishonest fellow out of business. My thought was </seg>
            <seg id="p112">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 111 this: to make a license that would be reasonable. We fixed up our law so that it provided for a license fee of $2.50 for an ice cream man. We said, "The United States government is holding for a 14 per cent standard, and we will make ours at 12 per cent." Of course there was quite a little bit of opposition on the part of some ice cream makers, but we finally put it over. After the license fee was fixed, some of the manufacturers concluded they would not comply. The result was they were prosecuted. The Justice Court held in favor of the State. It was taken to the District Court and they held it was unconstitutional. It did not seem to me that was right, and I took it to the Supreme Court, and they held it was a reasonable stand - ard, and that the legislature had a right to enact a standard of that kind. The National Association of Ice Cream Manufacturers were not satisfied and took it to the United States Supreme Court, and they up - held our State Supreme Court. We have had very little trouble, espe - cially within the last year or so, with the ice cream men. For a long time they felt I was not friendly to them. Possibly 50 per cent of them did not. They have gotten over that. They now see it is a reasonable standard. We are having some trouble with Missouri, which has an 8 per cent standard. From Illinois they sell their 8 per cent product, but do not get very far because we find it out. We make it so uncomfortable for the fellow who buys his stuff over there, he is glad to trade with our people. That is one of the reasons I have been real strong for a license. It is not the money it brings to the State of Iowa. It is the fact you can put a man out of business if he does not comply with reasonable regulations. I have only revoked a very few licenses of the various kinds since I have been Commissioner. Why? Because I have not found it necessary. About all you have to do is to tell a fellow you are going to revoke it, and he is careful to do whatever you ask him to do if you are reasonable. If I would start to revoking licenses right and left, it would not be long until the legislature would take the privilege away from me. Our butcher shops and slaughter houses were in bad condition over there. A man can run a rotten butcher shop much cheaper than to keep enough of help to have a nice, clean place. We licensed our slaughter houses. I realize there are too many cattle going to Chicago that come back as beef to Iowa, so we encouraged the killing of cattle in the State, and it helped the men who want to conduct good, clean butcher shops and slaughter houses. It is our duty to help the man who is trying to do a thing, and do it right. I was interested in what the President of your College said about the shoe man — Mr. Douglas. It reminded me of a very pleasant week - end I put in in Massachusetts one time. I was over to visit Fred Field over Sunday. In the morning Mr. Douglas called Mr. Field and said he was going out with his yacht and would like to have Mr. Field and his, </seg>
            <seg id="p113">112 I family go out with him. Mr. Field said, "The Commissioner from Iowa is here and I do not think I can go." Mr. Douglas' answer was to bring him along. Before we started, Mr. Field said, "Before the day 1b gone, Mr. Douglas will spring something on you about advertising, and will want you to use it for him." I noticed Mr. Douglas was very friendly and had a nice line of drinks and was generous with them. He told me about his tramp through Iowa and how he had worked as a Journeyman in Des Moines, and I spent one of the greatest days of my life. Along toward evening Mr. Douglas said, "You go out over the State some, don't you, and talk at dairy meetings'?" "Yes, that is part of my work." "Well, look here. When you have told all the stories you can think of and have done what you can, why couldn't you occasionally speak of the nice afternoon you spent with Douglas, the Shoe Man?" (Laughter.) I think there is a lot in all of the different departments working in harmony. I know everything is not entirely harmonious and there is a good deal of bad feeling between some of the departments. A man can't always have everything his own way. You must sometimes do certain things that may go against the grain; but I think you should be reasonable, and that co-operation has a great deal to do with the success of anything. I do not believe in the kind of co-operation in which you are expected to do all the co-operating. Whatever success we have made over there is due to the fact we have been pulling together — the College and the Department and the State Dairy Association and the State Buttermakers Association — all pulling together for one common interest. We are all in this game to make the most out of it and to get the best results. I know here has been a good deal of feeling between the centralizers and the creamery people. I am glad to say a part of that is a thing of the past in Iowa. I think the National Dairy Show had more to do with bringing about a good feeling between the different dairy associations than anything else, because we became acquainted with each other. I got to know more Jersey and Guernsey men than before, and I found they were the same type as the people breeding the blacks and whites. It seems to me there never was a time when you could improve con - ditions and make it go as at this time. I want to give a reason why dairy products are going to come into their own. (Here the speaker read a table showing the human food that can be produced by farm animals from one hundred pounds of digestible material consumed by the animal, ranging from the cow, which produced 18 pounds from each one hundred pounds consumed, to the sheep, which only produced 2.6 pounds.) It appears to me the time has come when this high cost of living is going to be studied more than it has been in the past. For a long time </seg>
            <seg id="p114">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 113 we have been trying to educate our dairymen and farmers to try to feed their stock economically; but we have said very little in times 1 gone by about trying to feed our people economically. I have traveled over the eastern country and noticed the Berkshire Hills, and after making a trip through that country, it seems to me in Iowa you have more waste lands at your roadsides than some of those states possess. Go west and you find a rocky, hilly country. You find some climate in Cali - fornia and some other things they advertise very exhaustively; but you cannot live a great while on climate. It seems to me when the final analysis comes, as it will within the next fifty years in our country, we will be measured not by the scenery and those things, but by what it can do in the way of production of things that sustain life. When that final analysis does come, such a country as we have in Nebraska and Iowa, and through this section, is going to come into its own. I have sometimes wondered whether land at $400 an acre was not a fairly good investment when you come to think of the immense amount of other country we have over the entire western and a portion of the eastern part, that does not produce very much? I want to thank you for the invitation to come here. (Applause.) THE TOASTMASTER: If I did not have any instructions to the contrary, the first thing I would like to say with reference to your next speaker is to compliment him on his intense loyalty. He is a cow man, and the subject is his own. It reads, "The Cow and the Man." placing the cow before the man. I can compliment him in other directions. I can compliment him upon his ability in several lines. A few years ago when we were get - ting ready to whip the Kaiser, we did not think we were quite pre - pared. We were running trains out among the people, lecturing to them and telling them how to grow more things. Professor Frandsen and I traveled on one of those trains. We visited a great many of the prom - inent localities in our State, and always at night time we would come to some of the larger cities. While some of the professors would hold meetings and address the town people, the rest of us would scatter in automobiles to the school houses in the country. I thought many times if I had half the luck of Professor Frandsen I would consider myself fortunate, because he was always assigned to the back seat in an auto - mobile to go out to a country school house with the best looking girl on the train. (Applause.) When we were out on this train, Professor Frandsen had been talk - ing, and one fellow said, "This fellow seems to know everything. I am going to ask him about John's trouble. He ought to be able to help him out." So he went up to Professor Frandsen and introduced him - self and said, "I want to tell you the story of John's trouble and see If you can suggest some way to get him out of It." "I guess you had better bring John over and let him talk to me." Se he did. It seems there had been a Jew peddler in the neighborhood, and he had given him nothing for something, and he said to Frandsen, </seg>
            <seg id="p115">114 "Prom your great knowledge, tell me whether or not it would be a sin to cheat a Jew." The Professor told him his teaching was it was just as much a sin to cheat a Jew as a Gentile. "Are you sure?" The professor was sure. The lad turned away with a sorrowful cast of countenance. Professor Frandsen called him back and said, "I wouldn't worry about it. It won't happen." PROFESSOR J. H. FRANDSEN, Lincoln: Mr. Toastmaster, Ladles and Gentlemen: I have a ten-page manuscript here. I would like to inflict it on Mr. Frost and some of the other fellows here who have been acting up more or less tonight; but I am anxious to gain favor with the people who are still in their chairs, and, considering it is now 11:30 I am going to pocket the manuscript. THE TOASTMASTER: As a matter of courtesy to your friends, the Toastmaster will give you "leave to print." PROFESSOR FRANDSEN: I shall endeavor to have it published in the toastmaster's paper. You have noticed there is a feeling of intimate friendship between the Toastmaster and the President. They have exchanged stories of various characters. I want to add one. I do not know when it happened but it is related Mr. Howard was visiting in the vicinity of Chalco. They repaired to the smoking room after a very fine dinner. Mr. Sass said, "I have here a few select bottles of wine; here is some - thing else; and here I have a bottle of extra choice ten-year-old whisky; and then we have some buttermilk. Now, Mr. Howard, what would you like to have?" After a minute's hesitation, Mr. Howard replied, "I think I will have a glass of buttermilk." Mr. Sass said, "What in thunder is the matter with the whisky?" "Darned if I know, Jake; but there is something the matter with it or you never would have kept it ten years!" (Applause.) Mr. Frost called up recently and said he was breaking the record with one of his Holstein cows. She was giving 120 pounds, but he was laying plans to beat that record; but he added, "I am having a lot of trouble. I find Stuhr has bought the last hot water bottle in town." (Laughter.) Mr. Frazeur is more or less in trouble. He is worried tonight as you see. Very recently he was looking around one of those stores that are open late. The clerk was trying to sell something to a traveling man. Mr. Frazeur walked up pretty close, and when the fellow com - pleted his purchase Frazeur said, "What did you sell that fellow?" "A night shirt. Would you like one, too?" "No, I do not think so. I don't go out much nights." (Laughter.) </seg>
            <seg id="p116">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 115 • I want very briefly to mention a thing that has become traditional at our banquets — the matter of having as our guests for the evening the members of the University Dairy Judging Team who have won honors in the National Contest at the National Dairy Show. This year as usual we have this team with us, and I would like to have the team and the Coach, Professor Thompson, rise. (This was done, amid applause.) Professor Thompson was the Coach ot the team. I want to tell the boys that President Sass of the Dairy Association and Mr. Palm, the Secretary, told me they had just decided to vote a $100 appropriation to help you defray your expenses at the recent contest. That will mean $25 apiece for each one of you, and I hope you will express your appreciation to them direct. Now on account of the lateness of the hour what I intended to say about "The Cow and the Man" must be deferred to some ether time. COACH THOMPSON: The first thing I wlU speak about is what this contest is. It is held annually at the National Dairy Show under the auspices of the United States Dairy Division. The dairy depart - ments of the various agricultural colleges furnish teams of three men to compete with one another in the matter of dairy cattle Judging. Some of the best colleges in the United States are represented— Kansas, South Dakota, Iowa, Wisconsin, Michigan, Indiana, New York, South Carolina, Missouri, Ohio, etc. Mr. L. W. Ingham, who sits here, was the highest man in the con - test. Last year Mr. Lauritson, who has charge of our official testing work at the University, was the highest man. The team stood fifth in the National Contest. They competed in the Waterloo Dairy Congress. Nebraska was fourth. Nebraska did not have much preparation for that contest, and did not have the cattle to look at. They were shown at the Iowa and Minnesota State Fairs. Mr. Ingham won a $400 scholarship and a gold medal. (Applause.) THE TOASTMASTER: I presume it is now in order for the master of the feast to dismiss you. I want to express my pleasure at the privilege of having been called to perform this service. I presume it is needless for me to say you discovered I was not altogether familiar with your language; and if I have "cockroached upon your patience," you will forgive me. Good night! (Applause.) LI8T OF CONTESTANTS AND AWARDS IN COW JUDGING CON - TEST NEBRASKA DAIRYMEN'S ASSOCIATION MEETING, JANUARY, 1920 The usual dairy cattle judging contest put on by the Nebraska Dairy - men's Association was held on Friday, January 23d, and the $100 that was appropriated, awarded as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p117">116 Points Prize Hans Hansen, Lincoln, Neb 370 $17.25 Win. A. Doubt, Kearney, Neb 355 14.40 Carl Rydeberg, Wood River, Neb. (1530 No. 32d, Lincoln) . . 340 11.55 John W. Boehr, Hastings, Neb. (3321 S St., Lincoln) 325 8.70 Lee King, Central City, Neb. (3401 Holdrege) 325 8.70 Glenn Fit Man, University Farm, Lincoln, Neb 325 8.70 Wayne T. Gray, Clay Center, Neb. (2975 Holdrege) 310 5.90 Lewis H. Gray, Clay Center, Neb. (2975 Holdrege) 310 5.90 Elmer Prime, Arapahoe, Neb. (1971 S St.) 310 5.90 Chaa E. Barth, Lincoln, Neb., R. F. D. No. 5 310 6.90 Carl Jones, Polk. Neb. (2530 Q St.) 295 3.05 H. C. Crandall, North Loup, Neb. (3051 Starr St.) 295 3.05 James Adams, Marquette, Neb. (557 No. 16th) 280 .20 Homer Kremke, University Farm 280 .20 Grant Lantz, Omaha, Neb. (1230 Luckey Ave.) 280 .20 Cecil Crowell, Red Cloud, Neb. (3200 Dudley St.) 280 .20 Roy W. Kohler, University Farm ; . 280 .20 $100 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 117 LIST OF PRESIDENTS AND SECRETARIES SINCE ASSOCIATION STARTED 1920 H. A. Morrison College View, Neb. The list of secretaries of the Dairymen's' Association is as follows: Prof. H. H. Wing (now of Cornell) 1885-1886-1887 S. C. Bassett, Gibbon, Neb 1888-1896 inc. P. H. Vaughn, Fremont, Neb 1897-1898 S. C. Bassett, Gibbon, Neb 1899-1914 April 1 R. W. McGinnis, Lincoln, Neb.. 1914-1919 J. E. Palm, Lincoln, Neb ....1919-1920 Year 1885 188G 1887 1888 1889 1890 1891 1892 1893 President ' ■ Address S. C. Bassett Gibbon, Neb. J. Dixon Avery Fremont, Neb. W. G. Whitmore Valley, Neb. J. C. Merrill Sutton, Neb. J. W. Liveringhouse Grand Island, Neb. D. P. Ashburn Gibbon, Neb. J. H. Rushton k Fairmont, Neb. E. J. Hainer Aurora. Neb. Win. Sutton Table Rock, Neb. 1894 1895 1896 1897 1898 W. A. Carpenter York, Neb. B. R. Stouffer Bellevue, Neb. E. F. Howe Fairmont, Neb. F. H. Vaughn Fremont, Neb. Geo. E. Haskell Lincoln, Neb. 1893 1900 1901 1902 1903 1904 1905 1906 1907 1908 1909 1910 1911 1912 1913 J. J. King West Point, Neb. J. J. King West PoM(t, Neb. J. H. Rushton Fairmont, Neb. E. S. Snively Lincoln, Neb. J. K. Honeywell Lincoln, Neb. C. A. Clark Ravenna, Neb. L. D. Stilson : York, Neb. E. C. Glissman Omaha, Neb. H. C. Young Lincoln, Neb. A. E. Wilkenson Lincoln, Neb. A. L. Haecker Lincoln, Neb. Chas. Harding Omaha, Neb. E. T. Rector Omaha, Neb. C. F. Schwager Omaha, Neb. R. W. McGinnis Lincoln, Neb. 1914 1915 1916 1917 1913 E. M. Little Lincoln, Neb. J. S. Clark Ravenna. Neb. J. H. Frandsen Lincoln, Neb. O. A. Severe Palmyra, Neb. W. H. Ferguson Woodlawn, Neb. Jacob Sass Chalco, Neb. </seg>
            <seg id="p119">118 Co-operation in America has grown gradually for many years. The first co-operators were labor unions who co-operated to secure higher wages. Farmers lately have been co-operating to secure righer prices; but the first real co-operation among all Americans came during the war. when every young man able to, was compelled to fight, those who did not fight must work, and all whether they worked or fought were compelled to co-operate with everyone else to win the war, by fighting, by working, by saving, by buying Liberty Bonds, and in any way pos - sible, every good American co-operated with every other good American. That is true co-operation. For many years the system of supplying our larger cities' with milk has been wasteful and expensive. There have ';'■,■ been many attempts to remedy this, by farmers, co-operative organiza - }|fj tions, and consumers leagues, which have not been altogether success- e. Progress has been made in many places, and in the larger cities toe east. For several years milk producers' have been able to com- pel dealers to pay them a price for their milk considerably above that what they had been receiving. We in Nebraska, have read and heard of these organizations, and 1 their successors. In May, 1918, a mass meeting of farmers was held I in ttie Lindell Hotel, Lincoln, to protest against the cut in price of hogs alter the government guarantee of a price equivalent to 13 bushels of jp corn to a hundred pounds of pork. At this meeting milk producers as- w sociations were mentioned and a committee appointed to see what I could be done to remedy the situation, as it was here. The larger buyers of milk in Omaha and Lincoln were very independent, and when I approached by the committee of farmers said in plain English, that they w would set the price of milk and that they were paying all that they B could, and to show these ambitious farmers that that was the case | after the visit, reduced the price to farmers in one instance although | the price to city purchasers has steadily increased since "the earliest recollection of the oldest inhabitant." This committee, after holding several meetings and hearing the opinion of prominent men, secured the consent of Mr. W. J. Kittle, Secretary of the Chicago Milk Pro - ducers' Association, to attend a meeting in Nebraska and tell of their experiences. Mr. Kittle spoke to a large gathering at the Dairy Build- si ing on the State Farm campus in Lincoln, January 7th, 1919, and again in Omaha, January 8th, and urging the organization of a co-operative || corporation by the milk producers of Nebraska. A temporary organiza - tion was effected and we undertook to organize the milk producers of Nebraska. For six months I preached co-operation and took pledges from producers to buy stock in this corporation throughout Nebraska and western Iowa. On July 28th, 1919, the Midwest Milk Producers' Co-Operative Asso - ciation was organized at Omaha and on August 12th we opened an office in Omaha, and August 24th sold our first milk. We sold this milk through the Association, but delivered directly by the farmer to the purchaser. We continued in this way, selling to large creameries and shipping co-operatively by the farmers, who saw that the milk was </seg>
            <seg id="p120">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 119 properly weighed and labeled and sent their weights to our office until February, 1920. We were shipping an average of 1,200 gallons a day, at a price very much above what had been formerly received by our mem - bers. We were not yet able to handle near all the milk of our members. Some of the larger milk users would rather go bankrupt, apparently, than co-operate with a farmers' organization. As I said in the outset, co-operation is not true co-operation unless it is a benefit to all, and we felt that if we secured a better price for our milk without some protection for the public, this better price would be taxed on the con- Iner, and the burden be heavier than ever. The consumer is already ring enough money for milk. The city of Omaha, for considerable ie, has sold milk for seventeen cents a quart, and more than six - n cents when payment was made in advance, and $1.00 worth of tets purchased. This same milk delivered to the city by the farmers b purchased by dealers at six or seven cents per quart. The Mid - st, therefore, built a pasteurizing and bottling plant in Omaha, and selling now their milk to the people of Omaha at twelve cents per irt, not asking exorbitant profits, but realizing for the farmers a ;ter price than was ever received before. tThe city government is co-operating with us and the firemen are ling our milk. We are selling milk to all that will buy from us, ceries, restaurants, creameries, milk distributors and to all milk revs. We are selling butter, buttermilk, cream and cottage cheese, is just a case of cutting out the unnecesary distributing expense. b money is furnished by the farmers. I We have a $25,000 plant, and expect soon to put one in Lincoln. 3 farmers 1 are getting a price for their milk a little above that merly received. From the profits of the association a portion is set le to cover the depreciation and other expenses, the balance is ided among the stockholders, according to the amount of milk they I. Thus all the profits there are go to the men who produce the Ik instead of some one dealer making large profits off the labor many, the many receive small profits. They are trying hard to dis - irage us. We have worked for them for years; they are badly fright - id for fear they will have to work for themselves. We must stick ;e»her and work, each for all and all for each. Brother farmers will 1 do it? JOHN FRAZEUR. NEBRASKA'S RECORD BREAKER IN MILK AND BUTTER PRO - DUCTION By J. H. Frandsen, Dairy Dept., University of Nebraska Today Nebraska's milk and butter record is held by Tulip Pietertje Konigen 2nd, No. 165892. This is one of the greatest achievements in dairy production which has been accomplished in Nebraska's dairy history. All former Nebraska records of milk and butter production were broken by this animal as shown bv official tests of October 1919 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">120 I This new state record breaker produced 26,721.5 pounds of milk and 1,066.40 pounds of 80 per cent butter. This record exceeds that of the Holstein cow. La May, 122176, owned by the University of Nebraska, and who has a record of 26,602 pounds, by 61.3 pounds. This latest champion butter record for the state exceeds by 10.7 pounds, the 1,055.74 pounds butter record of the Jersey cow, Mermaid's Fancy Wax, 359225, owned by Mr. H. C. Young. This is a distinction which has been held by no other dairy cow in the dairy history of Nebraska. Tulip Pietertje Konigen 2nd is owned by C. H. Starke of Red Cloud, Nebraska. She was bred by R. B. Gillette of Little York, N. Y., and later owned by Cold Brook Farm Company, also of Little York, from whom Mr. Starke purchased this valuable cow. This record producer comes from a line of high producing ancestors. Her sire, Aaggie Cornu - copia Johanna Lad, Jr., has 56 A. R. O. daughters, eight of which have yearly records of over 700 pounds of butter. Tulip Pietertje Konigen 2nd is a half sister of Mr. Stark's herd sire, King Cornucopia Sadie Vale 83371, with 25 A. R. O. daughters, whose dam, Sadie Vale Pitertje 79740, has a yearly record of 21,446.8 pounds of milk and 1,050.7 pounds of butter. King Cornucopia Sadie Vale is an exceptional individual, as indicated by the fact that he was Grand Champion at the New York State Fair tl915. His sire, Aaggie Cornucopia Johanna Lad Jr., and his sire, ggie Cornucopia Johanna Lad, are the only bulls who have a daughter with a 31,000 pound milk record or three daughters with yearly records above 700 pounds of butter. Much credit is due Mr. Starke as a dairyman. He was wise in selecting this valuable dairy cow for milk production and succeeded against many odds, as the above record shows. </seg>
            <seg id="p122">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 121 His herdsman, Mr. Will Roberts, writes that "Besides being a great producer, 'Konigen' is a splendid indivdiual. She was Grand Champion cow at the New York State Fair in 1915, and still retains a strong in - dividuality." DAIRY EXHIBITS AT THE 8TATE FAIR J. H. Frandsen, Lincoln, Neb. Dairymen, farmers and consumers of milk products have found the dairy exhibit at the fair grounds a place to meet and review their common problems as well as a place to learn something new about this great food-producing industry. Mermaid's Fancy Wax, a quiet, unassuming little Jersey, standing beside her twelve months' butter production (1,055.7 lbs.), and her "cow's pantry" in which was the actual amount of feed she ate in one year, caused a great deal of in - terest and opened the eyes of many who were unfamiliar with a cow's possible capacity for consuming feed and producing butterfat. The various booths, the dairy demonstration kitchen, and the big butter statute were all centers of particular interest. Hanging conspicuously on the wall of the Jersey men's booth, and written in large black letters, was a sign which read, "Come on in and talk Jersey." A rocking chair or two, some beautiful pictures of famous Jerseys, and many facts and figures furnished additional lure to lovers of the fawn colored breed. The Holstein men were not to be outdone. Their booth, too, was invitingly arranged. They seemed to delight themselves particularly in milk and butterfat records of sensational Nebraska Holsteins. Holstein literature was plentiful and found its way into the hands of many breeders and prospective breeders of the big dairy cow. The booth of the State Dairymen's Association was a place of gen - eral dairy interest. Boosters for the industry as a whole were discuss - ing modern dairy affairs as well as relating anecdotes from days of pioneer dairying in Nebraska. The University booth was pre-eminently educational. By the use of the steremotorgraph a series of educational slides were shown con - tinuously. Among a number of wall pictures, a set of photographs showing the results of feeding dairy products to guinea pigs were per - haps the main attraction. A liberal supply of bulletins were available, and some one was kept on duty throughout the day to answer the many questions that were asked. A booth featuring the school work of the dairy department was maintained in the University Building. Some beautiful trophies won by the Nebraska Dairy Judging Teams came in for much attention there. The dairy demonstration kitchen must not be overlooked, especially since the ladies in charge put out the following sign: "If Johnnie doesn't like milk he will like milk-shake. Try one, no charge." All who tried one were convinced that these Home Economics girls could fix up a milkshake to please the most discriminating palate, and best </seg>
            <seg id="p123">,o </seg>
            <seg id="p124">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 123 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">124 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 125 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">126 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p128">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 127 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">128 </seg>
            <seg id="p130">THIRTY-FIFTH ANNUAL CONVENTION 129 I all they made it with ordinary farm kitchen equipment. Their ecial attention, however, was turned to the making of a variety of pting cottage cheese dishes. The dairy girls had their kitchen orated with big signs reading: "Use more milk," "Help win the war the high cost of living by using more milk products," "Milk is more lable than many other food products and may be used in a great iety of ways," "Many delicious foods are made from milk and milk ducts. Become familiar with them," etc. This attraction was pre - ed by the University Dairy Department, but was financed entirely the State Dairy Association. Perhaps no exhibit on the grounds was viewed by more people than was the huge statue of pure yellow butter, erected by the Nebraska Creamery Butter Manufacturers' Association. In picturing both the laborer and the business or professional man using dairy products for their food, it carried the theme, "Milk for All." Worked on butter easels and written in prominent places were such phrases as: "Ne - braska is a horn . of plenty to the hungry world. Bread, butter and meat are our products. We feed millions besides our own." "The reconstruction period requires plenty of healthful food. Use dairy products." "Butter is the greatest of foods. It contains more vitamines per pound, more energy and heat than any other farm product." "It takes little from the soil, but through its production adds greatly to the soil. Its production means live stock which in turn means economic farming." "Nebraska, a butter state. We have advanced from twentieth place to fourth place in production of creamery butter in the last twenty years. No other state in the union can show such a butter It is estimated by officials of the University Dairy Department and State Dairy Association that presenting to the people such facts as 1 these, including the dairy demonstration kitchen work, will cause a very material increase in the use of milk as a marked reduction in the high cost of living. As chairman of the Exhibit Committee, I desire to express my great appreciation for the good work and hearty co-operation of Mr. J. E. Palm, Secretary, and to the other officers of the State Dairy Asso - ciation, as well as to the members of this Association; also to all mem - bers of the Jersey and Holstein Cattle Clubs of the state, and to the members of the Milk Producers' Association, and to Professors Hen - drickson, Thompson and Lawritson of the Department of Dairy Hus - bandry. It was this whole-hearted co-operation which made the exhibit such a signal success. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>