<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA, The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat</title>
               <date value="1902">1902</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska BULLETIN or the AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA VOL. XIV. Akticle II. The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat. By T. L. Lyom Distributed April 4. 1802 LINCOLN. NEBRASKA r B a </seg>
            <seg id="p002">OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD KUKELL, President, Kearney GEO. F. KENOWER, Wisner BOSON ('. RICH, Omaha JOHN L. TEETERS. Lincoln E. C. CALKINS. Kearney C. J. ERNST, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS I A. BURNETT. 15 8a, Director and Animal Husbam L. LYON. B. 8. A., Associate Director &lt;md Agriculturist 9. DALES. M Ph.. Financial Secretary \VM \V MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF IT. Peteks, U. V. If.. Animal Pathologist . I'll. D., Botanist EL HlCBOUOV, M. A., Chemist L. Haeckek. B. Sc, Dairy Husbandman I HiiisKi;. B. 8c., Entomologist win H. Bakbouk, Ph. D., Geologist ■■■■OK. B. Sc.. Horticulturist V. P. Stout, C. E., Irrigation Engineer BEST, M. A.. Meteorologist T. Wiaxcko, B. Sc, Assistant Agriculturist R. Smith, B. Sc., Assistant Animal Husbandman H. Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist set B. Slade, B. A , Assistant Chemist W. Pekin. Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm </seg>
            <seg id="p003">By T. L. Lyon. The present northern limit of winter wheat production in the trans-Missouri region lies in th &gt;f Nebraska, thus limit ing the output to a portion only of the arable land in t! The spring wheat region protruding south from the Dakota, overlaps the winter wheat region to some extent, and thu winter wheat and spring wli -ide. The chief condition that disc-on inter wheat produc tion in northern Nebraska is the dry, cold, winter weather Spring wheat suffers from a number of ad\ i, due mainly to its late ripening. This habit increases the liability to injury from chinch bug and grasshopper depredations, am ially to injury from dry, hot weather. Winter wheat as a crop for Nebraska has enormous possibil ties. Not only are the lartre yields of this wheat such recommend its culture to the farmers of the State, but thequa ity of Nebraska winter wheat gives it a high standing amon rs and consumers. The conditions of climate that produc a milling wheat of superior excellence are found in the regio of country bordering on the semi-arid. It is worthy of not that the great spring wheat producing region borders on th semi -arid belt in the north, while the region that is fast becom ing the center of winter wheat production occupies a simila position farther south. It is very noticeable that the qualit of hardness in wheat impr - its culture approaches th semi-arid belt. Its advantage over spring wh&gt; ident i its larger yield, when not winterkilled, in its comparative free dom from insect depredations, and in the protection it afford the soil during a considerable portion of the year. All t considerations make it highly desirable to improve our white wheat in hardiness and quality, so as to extend its growth mor widely throughout the State and to increase its productive! Improvement in hardiness may be looked for either by the in BULL. 72, AGR. EXP. STATION OF NEBR. VOL. XIV., ART. I </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 troduction of hardy varieties, by rendering hardier by sdectioi varieties already grown, or by a combination of these pro nesses. Improvement in quality and productiveness is to b&gt; sought in careful culture, fertile soil and rational selection o To these ends this Station has tested, during the last fiv ears, one hundred and eighteen varieties of winter wheat many of which are foreign varieties, chiefly from eastern Rus a. These tests have thus far resulted in selecting a few American varieties as especially suited to Nebraska by reuse &gt; f their hardiness. Two of these, Turkish Red, a bearde wheat, and Big Frame, a smooth wheat, have been pushed nort nd west by distributing packages of twenty pounds of seed t ach of nearly four hundred persons living north of the Platt iver, or west of the 100th meridian. Reports from these at empts have been very encouraging, the great majority o rials having been successful. A number of Russian varieties have shown themselves to be very hardy, and it is possible that some of these will furnish he foundation tor varieties adapted to the northern portion of he State. These Russian wheats are generally late maturing sorts, which is a considerable disadvantage in southern Ne - iraska, but farther north this quality is less objectionable, and when a variety is sufficiently hardy to endure the winters its advantage over spring wheat is proportional to the difference n the time of ripening. Wheats from different sections of the country have shown decidedly different qualities when sown here from seed of the same variety grown at the Experiment Station. Seed from more humid regions, but from approximately the same latitude, matured later and did not yield so well as native seed, while seed from central Kansas matured earlier, and yielded slightly better than native seed. The relative hardiness of these alien wheats has not been thoroughly tested, there having been but two severe winters since they have been grown here. In the winter of 1896-97 and again in 1898-99, Turkey wheat from Kansas winterkilled almost completely, while Turkish Red from Iowa and Nebraska survived the winter creditably. Jud&lt;r ing from this it would not always be safe to use Kansas-grown </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 TEST OF VARIETIES. A large number of varieties of winter wheat have been teste&lt; during the past five years. Most of these varieties have been grown first in small amount it their hardiness, and late if they showed unusual hardiness and if the seed availabl sufficed they were tested on a larger scale. In all, 118 varie ties have been tested, of which a very small number hav demonstrated their ability to pass successfully through sever winters. Whatever may be the productiveness of a variety, it usefulness in the long run wilt depend upon its hardiness; con sequently it must demonstrate its ability to live through win ters of at least average severity to entitle it to a further test TESTS DUK1 ■'-97. Table I. shows the record of the test for the winter of ! 97. AH varieties were planted with a press drill September 22 or 23. TABLE I. ■ VARIETY D HKOWS IN EFFECT OF WINTER YIELD PER KB Turk.-y Bad. Iowa Partly killed Red May Kansas Entirely killed. . White Track Kansas Entirely kiUed. . Emporium Kansas Entirely killed. . Bearded Monarch. . Kansas Entirely killed. . Dallas Kansas Eutirely killed. . Extra Early Oakley Kansas Entirely killed. . 1 Kansas Entirely killed .. Kansas Entirely killed. . Democrat Kansas Entirely killed . . Fapjuhar Kansas Entirely killed. . Early Red Clawson. Kansas Entirely killed. . Theiss Kansas Entirely killed. . Lancaster Kansas. Entirely killed. . I Medal Kansas Entirely killed . Kansas Entirely killed. . ?t Chaff Kansas Entirely killed. . Kansas Entirely killed. . isier Kansas Entirely killed. . Egyptian ... Kansas Entirely killed. . nglish Kausas Entirely killed. . Mediterranean Kansas Entirely killed. . lanian Red Kansas Entirely kill© U bu-h. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat. Boyer Kansas Entirely killed. Entirely killed. Entirely killed. Jones' Winter Fife. Kansas. Fultz Kansas Penquit's Velvet Chaff Kansas Entirely killed. Entirely killed. Entirely killed. Entirely killed. German Emperor. . Kansas. Buckeye Kansas Valley Kansas Big Frame Kansas Partly killed.. . . 18.5 bushels Entirely killed Turkey Kansas Currell Kansas Partly killed. ... 9.6 bushels Entirely killed.. Zimmerman Kansas Entirely killed. Entirely killed. Seneca Chief Kansas Dawson's Golden Chaff Canada Entirely killed. The winter of 1896-97 was a severe one on winter wheat. The ground was bare of snow most of the time, which produced a condition too severe for even the Canadian wheat. Most of the wheats had been grown in Kansas for at least one year be - fore this test, which would perhaps make them more suscept - ible to the cold. It will be noticed that there was Turkish Red or Turkey wheat from Iowa and Kansas, and that the Kansas killed out entirely. TESTS DURING 1897-98. During the winter 1897-98, only Turkish Red, Big Frame and Currell varieties were grown. They were drilled in September 14 and yielded as follows TABLE II. VARIETY BUSHELS PER ACRE Turkish Red 21.4 Big Frame 13.5 Curn-11 16.1 The wheats did not winterkill, but were badly infested with chinch bugs, which occasioned the low yields. Owing to this fact the significance of the test as far as yields are concerned is lo TESTS DURING 1898-99. In the fall of 1898 a very considerable number of varieties of winter wheat were sown. These wheats were supplied through Mr. M. A. Carleton, Cetealist of the U. S. Department of Agri- Andrews' No. 4 Kansas. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">culture. The seed planted bad been grown for at least om&gt; year in Kansas, but many of them were of Russian origin. In tb table of results, under the head of "origin", is given.so far a known, the place where the seed was grown previous to its life in Kansas. The amount of seed of each was too small t permit of an accurate estimate of the rate of yield. The winte was the most severe experienced in this region since record have been kept by the U. 8. Weather Bureau. Th*' seed was drilled by hand on September ! TABLE III VARIETY ORIGIN T OF WINTER Ghirka Winter i Province of Kharkov. .. Partly killed. No name No name Entirely k Jones, Newark, NY . . Entirely killed Newark, N. Y . Entirely killed Early Arcadian. Pedigree Early Gene- Entirely killed see Giant Entirely k Newark. N. I Entirely killed Newark, Ht. Y Entirely killrd Early White Leader. Surprise Entirely killed Entirely killed Early Red Clawson . . Bearded Winter Jones, Newark. N. Y. . . . Entirely killed Southeast Russia . Entirely killed Dattel America Entirely killed Bordeaux. France. Entirely killed Genealogic W T hite Pulavka Russia. Entirely killed Russia. Entirely killed Champion Russia. Entirely killed Poland Entiiely killed Vyssoko-Litovsk Swedish HiimIi Entirely killed Egyptian Theiss. . . Russia Entirely killed Orlova Entirely killed Ent'rely killed Champlain Russia. Chiddam de Mars. . . ( D'Ar Way's Cross ] Hungarian, Russia. Entirely killed / Australia Entirely killed ( Improved Fife \ Boyer Entirely killed Entirely killed CUwson (D'Eautomne Rouge Barbu, Selected Bald f from Australia J Entirely killed Entirely killed Early May Jone9' Winter Fife Jones, Newark. N. Y Golden Cross J&lt;&gt; irk. N. I Standard Jones, Newark, N. T Jones, Newark. N. Y Jones, Newark, N. Y </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ThB A laptatiot find 1 'nprovttn&amp;n t of Wtnter Wheat. American \ • U . Entirely killed Banatka.. . Entirely killed Print: N'.w M Kntirely killet ■■■■• Entirely killei •r Entirely killed Walker KlMM Entirely killed Walker Kansas Kntirely kille Russian Hani New Mexico. .. Entirely killed Russian Hani New Mexico Entirely kille Orop Entirely kille Urop Entirely killed Kursk Entirely killod Kursk Entirely killo. Budapest Hungary Eutiiely ki)le&lt;l Budapest. Hungary Entirely kill* Crimea Entirely killed Crimea Entirely kille American Entirely killed American.. Entirely kille Japan Entirely killed Japan Entirely kille Nashi ... India. Entirely kille Nashi... ... India. Entirely killed Farquhar Entirely kille Farquhar. Entirely' killed Podolia. Ku~ ■. Entirely killed IVxlolia. Rom i Entirely killet .it's Hybrid Kansas Entirely killed d'sHybrid Kansas Entirely kille Canadian Wonder. ... Kansas Entirely kille Canadian Wonder. ... Kansas Entirely killed Big English Entirely kille '" Entirely killet Big English Entirely killed ell Entirely killed Buckeye Kansas Entirely killed Biu-keye Kansas Entirely kill. China Red New M, &gt; Entirely kill.- China Red Mew Mi Entirely killed Kansas Entiielv killed Kansas Kntiiely kille -Kalinovka Entirely kill.- Tangarotto Italy Entirely kille California Walker Entirely kill.- California Walker Entiielv killed Qiinrtz New M&lt; . Entirely killed Q«'Hilz Hm Hi Entirely kill.- ■&lt;t fed Bearded ttmrntM Entirely killed UMgBarrj Kansan Entirely killed K.d Bearded Kn- . Entirely kill.- UMgBarrj K;, Entirely kille Mennonite New M. Entirely kille in Amber Entirely kille Mennonite New Mexi.-.. Batirely killed (ierman Amber . Kntirely killed Zimmerman Kansa- ... Entirely killed Zimmerman Kansa- ... Entirely kille R'P e - New Mexico... Kntirely kille&lt; Ripe. New Mexico. .. Kntirelv killed ■ Entirely killed H Entirely kille Damrna Daruma Kntirely kill.- Twkey \l ~ , n Entirely killed Red Winter.. Samara, Russia. Entirely killed 'Vinter Poltava. Russia Entirely killed Russian English America Entirely killed Genealogic Red Russia Entirely killed n Premium New Mexico Entirely killed China White New Mexico Entirely killed Pr°&gt;'fero Italy Kntirely killed IfDArblays Hungarian. i Improved Fife, &gt; Entirely killed on French L Early White J </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 Ohirksi Winter Rn-- . Partly killed. harvi Yx Russia I harvested Thei&gt;s V. ■ rely killed t'rinnan.. 1 .: rely killed Rf I Winter Entirely killed li*&lt;l Heanled Turkish Red and Big Frame Entirely kille&lt; varieties were sown on a la Turkish Red and Big Frame varieties were sown on a larger scale. Chinch bug depredations cut down the yields of t scale. Chinch bug depredations cut down the yields of t to a great extent, and the damage not being uniform entirely estroyed the value of the test. Drilled September VAKIKTY to a great extent, and the damage not being uniform entirely destroyed the value of the I Drilled September 20. VAKIKTY Turkish Red ig Frame Turkish Red HI Big Frame TEST DUB] During the winter of l* ( .t!i-19»K&gt; the test of varieties was tinued. Many of those planted the preceding year were again tested, seed from the same source being varieties that produced seed. Of these the new seed w A.s only small quantities of seed were available it was not at tempted to determine the yield per acre. All varieties were planted on September TABLE IV VAKIETY KKKKC f OF M ST LODGED I&gt;A WINTER KI1 Egyptian Entirely killed . . Theiss Entirely killed. . Chaniplain Entirely killed. . Chiddam de Mars Entirely killed Pringle's No. 5 Partly killed Much. None.. July 2 Russian Hard Uninjured Much. None.. June 30 Crimean Uninjured Much.. None.. June 30 Nashi Partly killed Little.. None.. Ji Farquhar Entirely killed. . Zimmerman Partly killed. ... Littl. ue.. June 28 (From) Jones, Newark. N. Y Partly killed Little.. None.. July 5 Gold Medal Entirely killed Seneca Chief Entirely killed. . Big English Entirely killed. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Tht Adaptation and Improvement of Winter H heat 10 s' Winter Fife.... Entirely kilk I.. i.. I.. May Entirely kille Early (ienesee (iiant.. Entirely kille Ghirka Winter Uninjured Little.. None. July Early Arcadia Entirely kiilt Dattel Entirely kille Bordeaux Entirely kille I.. 1.. 1.. ilogic White Entirely kille Pulavka Entirely kille Champion Entirely killed Vysaoko-Litovsk Entirely killed. . lish Entirely killed .. Ghirka Winter. Partly killed. ... Little.. None.. July Yx Uninjured Much.. None.. July The U. S. Department of Agriculture sent to be tested four varieties of Hungarian winter wheat. The following state - ment regarding is^made in Inventory N etion of Seed and Plant Introduction. "This shipment comprises four of the best known of th Hungarian hard winter wheats. These wheats are the qual from which the higher grades of flour are made at Buda Hungary is about tlif only European country which ex ports flour, and therefore comes into competition with Americ in this commodity. Experts on the stock exchange at Buda pest claim that some of the Hungarian hard winter wheats pro duce a better grade of flour than do the best American wh&lt; This, however, is doubtful. These varieties are worth careful trial wherever the winters are mild enough to perm of the growth of winter wheats. Of the varieties included i this shipment the Bauat and Theiss are the best known. Bot varieties have a large quantity of gluten of a high quality, is doubtful whether the names applied to Hungarian wh' such as Tin-is* and Jlttmit, really represent distinct varieties o wheats. They are rather to be considered as indicating the lo cality from which the wheat was obtained, and these number may consist of a mixture of varieties. They probably diffe somewhat in different localities." These wheats were planted in the same way as the above, but owing to their late arrival not until October 27. TABLE V VAKIKTV Weuwsnburg Nearly all killed. Little.. Partly. July Banit Nearly all killed. Little.. None.. July Nearly all killed. Little. None.. Julv 7 Pester Boden Entirely killed I OF LODGED DAI WINTKK KIPKNIV. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 The late planting placed these wheats at a disadvantage as far as the effect of winter was concerned. During the same winter several other varieties were tested on a larger scale, among these being the Turkish Red, Big Frame and Currell, which had proven so hardy in previous years. Quite a large acreage of these was grown to furnish seed for the co-operative tests by residents in the northern and western portions of the State. A few varieties were received from the U. S Department of Agriculture, which on account of the fact that they had been successfully grown in R under climatic conditions somewhat similar to those of this region were considered deserving of a careful test here. They were drilled in September 11. The results were as follows: TABLK VI VARIETY HI- LODGED DATS Of VIKI.I Turkish Red Little None June Big Frame Little ie June 26. 84 bi, Currell Little None June 25. 25 bushels -lav 1 Little None July :.'. 22 bushels -lav* Little None July 2. Mbt Banat 3 Killed out entirely during the winter. Sandomir 1 Little None July 2. i From the government of Yaroslav. • From the government of St. Petersburg. » From Russia, but introduced there from Hungary &lt; Winterkilled to some extent. TESTS DURING 1900-1901. In the fall of 1900 only those varieties were planted that had survived the winter of 1899-1900. The number was thus cut down very considerably, but no variety was discarded until after two years' trial. The quantity of seed was still too small to permit of determining the yield per acre. All were planted September 17. TABLE VII VARIETY EFFECT OF BUST LODGED DA WINTER KIPKN Pringle's No. 5 Uninjured Little.. None.. June 37 Russian Hard Uninjured Mu«h.. Badly. June 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Crimean Uninjured Much. Badly. June 29 Naahi Uninjured Some.. Slightly June 27 Zimmerman Uninjured Little.. None.. June 27 (From) Jones. Newark. N. Y Uninjured Little.. None.. June 29 N. Y Ghirka Winter Uninjured Little. None.. June 29 Ghirka Winter Uninjured Little.. None.. June 29 Yx Uninjured Little. None.. June 29 Some other winter wheats received from the U. S. Depart- ment of Agriculture were tested. These were all of foreign origin and had not been grown here before except three of the Hungarian wheats, of which the home-grown seed was planted at this time, but of the Pester Boden variety that killed out completely during the winter of 1899-1900 the original seed was used. Extremely hot weather at time of ripening caused the wheats harvested this year and especially the later ones to reach the cutting stage prematurely. They have, therefore, not changed as greatly in time of ripening as would be indicated by the rec- ords. They were planted September 17. TABLE VIII VAKIETV EFFECT OF KIST LODGED DATE OF WINTER KIPKNIMi Weissenburg Uninjured Little.. Slightly Ju Banat Uninjured Little.. Slightly Jane 97 Theiss Uninjured Little.. None. . June 29 Pester Boden Uninjured Little.. None.. June 29 Steinwedel Entirely killed Budapest Uninjured None.. None... June 2" Early Baart Entirely killed King's Early Entirely killed Canning Downs Entirely killed Pootung Uninjured None.. None... June 21 Other varieties were sown on larger plots and the yields as- certained. TABLE IX. VARIETY LODGED DATE OF YIELD PEK K1PEN. ACRE Turkish Red Little None June M 39 bushels Big Frame Little None June 24 34 bushels Currell Little None June 24 23 bushels Yaroslav 1 Little None July 1 30 bushels Yaroslav 2 Little... None July 1 23 bushels Sandomir Little None July 1 16 bushels i From the government of Yaroslav. 'From the government of St. Petersburg </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 A quite extensive and fairly accurate test of the comparativ merits of the Turkish Red and Big Frame varieti uari for the northern and western portions of the Stat&lt;- by th* tribution of seed of these two varieties in those regions. B taking only those counties in which both varieties were grow and comparing the total results for each variety we ha comparatively fair method of comparison, the weak point bein the fact that each variety was tested by a different person anc hence there is no assurance that the conditions were the same but it is expected that the large number of testh will lai counterbalance this source of error. The subjoined table of results is made up from the results of tests of each variety in the following counties : Antelope, Boone, Buffalo, Burt, Cedar, Coif ax, Cuming, Custer, Dawson, Deuel, Dixon, Dodge, Garfield, Greeley, Holt, Howard, rick, Pierce, Platte, Stanton. Vallt TaBLK X U OK M.'MBF.ti PV VIELll VARIETY WIXTEK- WINTh I'EK 1CU KILLED KIM I &gt;■ Turkish Red T 12.0 tt.5 * Big Frame 104 16 These figures would indicate that the Big Frame wheat somewhat hardier, but that the Turkish Red was more prolific. A comparison of these results with those obtained at the Sta - tion through a period of five years shows a pretty cloa ment as far as yield is concerned. TABLE XI. VARIETY YIELD IN" BLSHELS PEL &gt; 1900 1901 Average Turkish Red U 81.4 28.5 88 H Big Frame 18J 11 I 34 M Currell 9-6 16.1 TESTS OF WHEATS IX NORTHERN AND WESTERN NEBKA- In the fall of 1900, three hundred and sixty-seven samples of wheats of the Big Frame and Turkish Red varieties were sent </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 tties living north of the Platte river or west of the 100th ian. Each experimenter received twenty pounds of , and agreed to plant and care for it, threshing it sepa - from his other grain, and to report upon the following i connected with its growth. I Sown on upland or bottom land? Depth to watery ■ Xnture of soil, i. e., clay, gumbo, loam, sandy loam, or 4. Nature of subsoil I Is there any alkali present Is the soil light or he;i ■ Method of preparing the soil for this crop Depth of plowing (if plowed )? 9. Previous crop? Date of sowing? KAniouuft)f seed per ac: Good or poor stand in fall? tion by windbreak or snow during winter.' 14. Condition in spring? 15. Date of ripening? BDid it rust, smut, or lodge? Date of cutting Yield of threshed grain per acre? ■ Comparison with other varieties raised by you or in vicinity? Remarks. The number of reports available for use in computing result from th« was 194. The accompanying table shows th number of tests, the number of cases in which the wheat wa destroyed by winterkilling, and the average yield per acre fo each variety in each county in which the tests were made Plantings later than October 1 were not included among th of losses by winterkilling, but the omissions from^thi cause were very few. Average yieldsjper acre were found.b, dividing the sum of all yields reported for any variety^in county by the number of such reports. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 TABLE XII NUMBER NUMBER VARIETY WIN IE K- YIEL1 TESTS KILLED ACRE Antelope Turkish Red J4 1 Big Frame •&gt; 1 17 Boone Turkish Red.. I D -'() Big Frame 0 8 Boyd Big Frame 1 0 Brown Big Frame 1 0 Buffalo Turkish Red 1 Big Frame 11 0 14 Turkish Red. 0 Big Frame 1 0 30 Cedar Turkish Red A I •i Big Frame ■) 0 Cheyenne Big Frame 1 0 "-J0 Turkish Red Col fax 0 Big Frame i) Cuming Turkish Red 1 Big Frame Turkish Red. i; 1 Big Frame 18 4 21 Dawson Turkish Red 9 1 Big Frame 11 0 ■&gt;■' Turkish Red. ■&gt; Big Frame 1 n Dixon Turkish Red 1 0 Big Frame 1 (I Turkish Red 4 0 19 Big Frame &gt;&gt; ■ is Big Frame 4 1 y Big Fr;i ... 1 0 4 Furnas Big Frame 4 I) Garfield Turkish 1: J Big Frame I 0 10 Greeley Turkish Re, 1. 1 0 -'0 Big Frame .) ia Hall Big Frame 0 Hayes Big Frame. 1 0 Hitchcock Big Frame u Turkish Bed. 1 0 Big Frame 4 0 10 Howard Turkish Red 0 ■) Big Frame 4 13 Knox Bie Frame 0 M Loup. Big Frame 1 H Big Frame 1 M </seg>
            <seg id="p016">The Adaptation and Improvement of Winter Wheat 16 Big Frame 8 0 11 Pierce . . Turkish Red . l o Ifi Big Frame I 0 12 Platte Turkish Red. 4 0 •&gt;? Big Frame. &lt;i 0 23 Sheridan . Big Frame 1 0 Sherman Big Frame | 0 2 Sioux Big Frame. . . 1 0 2.J Stanton Turkish Red. .. 1 0 Big Frame 1 0 Vallev Turkish Red | 1 \% •&gt; Big Frame 2 1 16 •&gt; Washington Big Frame 1 0 Total ... Iit4 19 The distribution of winter wheat was made with two object in view, namely, to help ascertain the ]&gt;ossibilities of winter it culture in thut portion of the State lying north of the Platt*' river and that lying west of the 100th meridian, and also ncourage experimental attempts to raise winter wheat in those regions. The latter object is being attained in a very marked degree : actically all those who made the t&gt;st are planting the again this year. In addition, large numbers of farmers have planted wheat this year for the first time. There is great dan that the industry will receive a setback should the winte prove a severe one resulting in the loss of large areas of wheat The adaptation of winter wheat to parts of that region canno be accomplished at once and should not be attempted on a large scale by single individuals with the belief that they hav found a sure crop for all seasons. - far as the attempt to gauge the possibilities of wiute wheat growing is concerned, that cannot be determined by on year's test, but something has been learned, and a beeinnin has been made by furnishing the Station with a corps of com petent volunteer experimenters who are provided with winte wheat of known origin, and who are disposed to continue it culture. In time, the results obtained by these persons wi throw much light on the subject. The results of the first winter, as shown in the table, are Merrick.. . Turkish Red ■„&gt; 0 _&gt;ij Kt'dwillow Big Frame. 1 l </seg>
            <seg id="p017">r **»•** J I £/# l/L c f(C H C l/J r inter '» flctXl. 17 very encouraging. Of the 194 tests reported, then' were only nineteen case* of complete loss by winterkilling le o these were doubtless due to lack of moisture in the fall. T were made in thirty-eight counties north of the Platte river o west of the 100th meridian. In only one county was there complete failure, and in that county only one trial was made. IMPROVEMENT BY ADAPTATION. Undoubtedly the ideal winter wheat for Nebraska is yet to be developed. Whether some of the varieties now in use, like th "Turkish Red", will form the basis for the improved whea or whether some of the Russian wheats will be found adapted to this region cannot be foretold. It seems probabl that varieties of somewhat different characteristics will be re quired in different portions of the State. The northern por tion will require a hardier variety than the southern, and th western a more strongly drought-resistant variety than th eastern. Early maturity is a desirable characteristic e' where, but become^ of more importance as wheat culture pro ceeds southward and westward. That much can be done towards adapting some of the &lt; monly-grown varieties to portions of the State not generally considered in the winter wheat area has already been demon - strated. One of the most promising varieties for this purpose is the so-called Turkey Red or Turkish Red or Turkey. Th" three names doubtless represent a wheat of the same local or - ein, namely, the Crimea. It is grown extensively in Iowa, Kansas and Nebraska, and even farth. original labitat resembles in some climatic conditions the trans souri country, the characteristics that favored it in the Crimea have made it useful here. It has, however, exhibited ouite a endency towards variation, and in the different regions in which it has been cultivated shows markedly different habits of growth. An experiment designed to show the difference be - tween representative samp! uiety from differem tions of the country was carried on at this Station in I and in 1 in m-iil. Turkish R&gt; .vheat wasobtai lithe Ohio Expel i -tation in eastern Ohio, the Ion &gt;n in 1 through the Kansas Station there was obtain- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 ed a sample from central Kansas. These samples and one o Turkish Red wheat that had been grown at this Station fo three years v;ere sown on contiguous plots of land. The rec ord of growth shows a great difference in the habits of thes four strains of what was without doubt originally the same va riety of wheat. That the Nebraska and Iowa seed were orig nally the same is certain, for the Nebraska seed had been ob tained from the Iowa Station three years before. The winter of 1899-1 91 &gt;0 was a very favorable one here for winter wheat and a comparison of the stand in fall and spring showed that there was no appreciable loss from winterkilling. The Iowa and Ohio wheats rusted and lodged badly, whil he Nebraska and Kansas wheats did not suffer in this way rhe Kansas wheat ripened a little earlier than the Nebrask and both of these before the Iowa and Ohio wheats. Ther was eight days difference between the earliest and latest ripen ng grain. The yield and weight of grain seemed to depend upon early ripening. All of these differences in growth of wheat from different States, but of the same variety, denote a ready tendency to - wards variation which enables the plant to adapt itself to its new environment. The possibility of adapting a variety of winter wheat to re gions of more severe winters is thus indicated. Such adapta tion has actually been going on for a number of years, which may in some measure account for the fact that winter wheat i now being grown in portions of Nebraska where twenty year ago it was considered an impossible crop. Wheat planted i a locality the winter weather is m&lt; -re than tha 1ADLL A KD Nebraska kd Iowa KD Ohio Date of sowing Stand in fill Sept. y lod t. 9 Good Sept. 9 Goo&lt;l pt. 9 Stand in spring »dged ■f ripening field of grain per acre. Veiirht of grain per bu.. ( lood None Very little Jun&lt; W.I bu. •4.1 lbs. ■&lt;&gt;d None Very little June 27 •27.", bu. 6-.V2 lbs. Good Badly Much July I I bu. 56.91bs. tod Badly Much July I 1 ha </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 to which it has been accustomed will ordinarily winterkill more or less. This may be enough to produce a practical fail - are of the crop or it may not, but the plants that do survive may become the basis of a hardier strain of wheat and the more re the season the more valuable for seed are the plants that are left. This should be borne in mind when one is in the act of deciding whether to plow up in the sprins a field of winter wheat that has been badly winterkilled. Con~ whether you can get seed that has survived such weather » you come to sow next fall. THE SOURCE OF SEED SUPPLY. Another point brought out by this experiment is the fact that the locality from which seed is brought will make a very great difference in the success of the crop the first year. The difference in the latitude of the various localities from which the wheats were brought was not great, but there was consid - erable difference in the amount of annual rainfall in these re- Iie winter hardiness of the plants cannot be said to have tested, as the winter was a very favorable one and all i through successfully. The characteristics that produced lifferences in yield were, time of ripening, ability to with - i rust, to remain erect, and possibility to utilize economic - the available moisture in the soil. t3 wheats from more humid regions were obviously at a vantage, and this is undoubtedly worth considering when lasing seed wheat. Whether on the other hand there is vantage in bringing seed from regions of less rainfall has een demonstrated. IMPROVEMENT OF WHEAT BY SELECTING LARGE, HEAVY KERNELS FOR SEED. In 1896 the Nebraska Experiment Station began an attempt to improve the quality and yield of wheat by selecting for seed kernels of more than average specific gravity. To select t kernels and separate them from the lighter a lution of calcium chloride in water was used. The solution \ </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 ciently d that when the grain was thrown upon it about half of the kernels floated and the other half sank. Those that floated were, of course, the light kernels and those that sank were the heavy. This method of separation accomplished lesired object, but was slow and cumbersome. An attempt was then made to use an ordinary seed fanning mill for the purpose, but it was found difficult to get a sufficient wind v to make an equal separation of the grain. After repeated ipts to get the plan on a practical basis a machine was dis - ced that was originally intended for a different purpose but which accomplished the separation satisfactorily and rap - idly and which after undergoing some modifications is now be - ing manufactured especially for this purpose. Another ma - chine is now manufactured that is claimed to accomplish the same end. The machine operates by directing upwards a current of air, velocity of which can be regulated. Into this current the grain is directed. The result is that the heavy kernels and the large kernels fall, and the light and small kernels are driven out. The separation thus accomplished is somewhat different from that effected by a solution, the difference being that the the kernels entirely according to their specific ity while with the air blast a large kernel of a certain tie gravity might descend with the heavy kernels, when if it were smaller although of the same specific gravity it would blown out. The number of light kernels that descend on account of their H is relatively small owing to the fact that large ker - ■ rule of higher specific gravity than small. The following test was made to determine the relation between the of wheat kernels- and their specific gravity. An average 4 wheat was nearly equally divided by means of two si three portions representing medium, small and large ker- Each of these portions was then thrown upon solutions of the same specific gravity, and the proportion by weight floated, or light seed, and the proportion that sank, or </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 TABLE XIV KIND Off HtBD HEAVY, I.KAMS UKAMS 1IKAVV: I.KUIT U.M 1 : 1.2» Small M.-.lium 1 : 1.11 Large 11.96. 8.04 1 : Tin- weight of light kernels among the small was nearly that of light kernels among the large Bring the last two years a number of experiments b made to ascertain the effect of this practical selection of , heavy seed upon the yield and quality. In the fall of 1899 a quantity of Turkish Red winter wheat grown at the Station and cleaned in the fanning mill d by the air current into two approximately equal por - tions. Each of these oortions was again run through th current. Of the heavy portion the heavy kernels obtained on nd treatment were retained and designated "Heavy it". Of the light portion the light kernels obtained on nd treatment were retained and designated "Light it". These were planted on adjacant plots of land and be - side them was planted the same variety of wheat but not treat - ed otherwise than being cleaned in the fanning mill. The yields were as follows : TABLE XV YIELD l'EK KIND &lt;JF SEED Heavy 2»5 bushels &gt;~. .j bushels Ordinary 23.0 bushels In the fall of 1900 a sample of the crop grown as "'Heavy wheat" was separated into approximately equal parts by the air current, and the heavier portion again separated, the ier portion being retained and called "'Heavy wheat." The crop grown as "Light wheat" was similarly separated, but the lighter portion was retained in each Phis was called '"Light wheat". The two portions thus secured planted on adjacant plots of land, as was also some of the wheat grown from the "Ordinary wheat" which seed was not treated except to clean with the fanning mill. The yiel 1901 were as follow LIGHT, KATIO </seg>
            <seg id="p022">„ TABLE XVI. KIND OF SKET) YIELD PER ACKE -».(.S bushels . narv -'•!. o bush. M.7 bushels Border to verify the experiment with Turkish Red wheat a ar test was made both years with the variety known as Frame. The method of procedure was exactly the same at above recorded. The yields in l ( .i00 were as follows: Ks shows an actual improvement from one year to the in the yield of wheat and a still larger relative iiu apared with the ordinary seed. This is a rational method for improving the yield and qualit of wheat, especially when used as auxiliary to selection ant ling of individual plants. It offers the farmer a simpl and practical method for improving his seed. It will be give a continued trial at this Station, and an attempt will be mad to determine what proportion of the wheat it is desirable to discard on account of lightness and smallness of kernel. 1 Allll. AV 11. MSB YIELD I'KB ACRE 25.1 In. Ordinary . ... 2."&gt; n bushels Light .... tt-Sbw Tlif yields in 1901 were: TABLE XVIII uno) viKi.D ram acu ■ 27.7 bushels Ordinary K.8 bushels Lifcht n.9bl The average yields for both varieties for each of the two &gt; is as follows : TABLE XIX VIKI.Il IS YIELD IN 1901 Heavy Ordinary 2ti.7 Imsh.-U .!."» 9 l)usheU ! 8 bushels 23.9 bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 Summary. t Of ]the"ll^varieties of winter wheat tested during the last ve years, Turkish Red and Big Frame have — hardiness and ield considered — been the b In 194 tests of these two v. - during 1900-1901 in counties north of the Platte river or west of the 100th meridian, Turk - ish Red yielded better, but Big Frame proved to be somewhat hardier. the 194 tests in the region above described, there were neteen cases of complete loss by winterkilline. tSome Russian varieties of w id promise well for the northern portion of t pecially if they can be made to mature earlier. tThe selection of large, heavy kernels for seed resulted, on ie whole, in increasing substantially the yield over seed heat not so selected. Wheats of the same variety, but grown in different portions of the country, when grown side by side showed much differ - ence in their habits of growth, which were greatly to the dis - advantage of the seed grown east of the Missouri river. The tendency shown by these alien wheats to adapt them - selves to local conditions when grown here for a numb - years, encourages the hope that Nebraska-grown seed may be - come adapted to all arable portions of tht» Suite. The yields of these wheats were nearly proportional to i tendency to early maturity. k Kansas-grown seed matured earliest and yielded best, but tirely winterkilled when Nebraska- and Iowa-grown seed of e same variety passed the winter successfully. Accepted for publication February 12, 1902. Errata Yx should read Red Winter on pp. 9, 10, 12. Red Winter should read Yx on p. 9. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>