<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00032.00008">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00032.00008</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Nebraska State Board of Health BULLETIN NUMBER THREE FEBRUARY, 1914.</title>
               <date value="1914">1914</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">JNcDFcisksi State Board of Health BULLETIN NUMBER THREE FEBRUARY, 1!U4. y OFFICERS OF TIIK BOARD JOHN' II. MOREHEAD, Governor GRANT G. MARTIN, Attorney Gkneral JAS. E. DELZELL, Suit, of Public Instructiom BOARD OF SECRETARIES. B. ARTHUR CARR, II. D., President, Lincoln, Nebraska P. F. DODSON, M. D., Vice-President, Wilhcr, Nebraska C. T. BURCHARD, M. D., Tri-asfrkr, Falls City, Nebraska H. B. CUMMINS, M. D., Ski kf.tary. Seward, Nebraska W. H. WILSON, M. D., State Health Inspfxtor, Lincoln, Nebraska WM. F. WILD, M. D., Dirfxtor Bacteriological Laboratory. Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Notice of Health Conference for March 11 and 12, 1914 3 Editorial 5 Nebraska Baby I Tcalth Contest 8 9 Visits of Health Inspector Report of Births \0 Report of Deaths 1 I Report of Contagious Diseases lfi Report of Divorces 18 C lassifkation of Divorces 22 Re|&gt;ort of Marriages 1 ! ' Stannary Report of Vital Statistics 1 21 Summary Report of Marriages and Divorces 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">3 \ Nebraska State Board of Health BULLETIN NUMBER 3 NOTICE T&lt;&gt; the Local Health Boards and Friends of Public Health and Sanitation in Nebraska. Ladies and Gentlemen: — The second Conference of State and iocal Health Officers will lake place in the Senate Chamber and jncoln Hotel. Lincoln. Nebr.. .March 11th and 12ta, 1!&gt;H. Your prw - nce and cooperation is necessary and desired. The Riibjcct of con - ervation is the vital topic today. The purpose of this conference is getting together of thoae who are personally charged with the duty of the conservation of the health of the people of the state of Se - braska. Our last state conference was a grand success. We had the great pleasure of having the assistance of Dr. Oscar Dowling and the celebrated Health Train of Louisiana. Also Dr. \Y. A. Evans of Chicago, Uncle Henry Wallace of Des Moines and many others. Our own Governor took an active part, and the address of welcome by Governor J. H. lforehead placed him a san ardent advocate of good health and sanitation, and welcomed the representatives of local and state Hoards of Health. This annual conference is the outgrowth of the state Public Health Association, which was made up of public spirited men and women whose ambition was to improve the health of the whole state. After a few years it was suggested that the State Board of Health take hold of the association and instead have our annual conference. Our initial attempt last year was a great success. The State Hoard of Health again recommends that the plan which worked so well last year be continued as follov B'hat every County, City, or Village, be requested to send their h Oflicer to this conference, and thai the net expense of travel otel be paid by such County. City, or Village, upon a certili- </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 The following resolution was adopted last year, which may lie shaped into a bill to introduce at our next Legislature. Ky Dr. Qnifley of North Platte; seconded In Dr. Fall of ce. t 1 Resolved, that it is the sense of this conference that the Legis - 1 of this State ihoold pass a law empowering the Secretaries ite Hoard of Health to call the City and County Health Officers lier once every six months, or more often as may be found &lt;ary. and that the expense of the Health Officers so called in be borne by the State." B rusting that each County, City, or Village, will be represented Health Officer at the above Conference. I remain. Yours for a better State. E. ARTHUR CARR. President. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Since issuing our last Bulletin we have secured an appropria - tion sufficient to establish a State Bacteriological and Pathological Laboratory. The Department of Vital Statistics has been in exist - ence for some time so that we are able by the proper working of the two to ascertain .just what parts of the state are the "sickt - or where the preventible diseases arc the most numerous, and an better equipped by the aid of the laboratory to remove the cause and assist the local physicians to cure their patients by rendering accurate aid. such as only a laboratory can furnish, by way of A special Bulletin lias been issued and sent to all physicians in ic state and to all Health Hoards and officers. We have therein ndcavored to explain fully how the benefits of the laboratory may &lt;• secured, and Ihe Board is making every effort to organize the tate for effectual health work. We feel that we can now give orrect information and useful advice on the sanitary questions lat may arise. And we are desirous of being in close and helpful elationship with the local Hoards and officers. We are now in position to do a certain amount of investigation and research ork, for municipalities when requesting our aid. and we are will - ig to give any assistance or advice that it is possible to give. Any part of this state, be it city, town or village, that has a large per cent of deaths or an excessive number of cases of Typhoid. Diphtheria. Scarlet Fever. or Small Pox to its credit, will be con - sidered as an undesirable place to locate or live] in. as these are preventable diseases. And their prevalence will indicate that those in authority are not protecting their citizens as they should and the locality will be known all over the state and nation as an un- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 of the collection of vital and morbidity statistics is to warn tl who arc well and desire to remain so. to keep out. and that the health authorities mini step in. By referring to the Report on vital statistics in this Bulletin any community can ascertain whether their standing in this regard is satisfactory or not. The State Hoard may he able to tell you where the trouble lies and you will probably find ii to he due to one or more of the following causes. 1st. You have either a health board which is inefficient, or 2nd. You have an efficient and qualified health board, but it is not hacked by the sentiment of the people, for no health officer can accomplish anything to maintain satisfactory sanitary condi - tions unless he has the backing of the people. Ird. Or you may have, as prevails in a great many towns, a i officer appointed simply because lie has certain political ing and the appointive power is desirous of using his political nee and takes no consideration of his ability or inelinatons tlth matters. You can rest assured that the sanitary condi - of a locality will never rise higher than the conception of Ffieer or the appointive power that created him. Every health officer should realize that it is his imperative and solemn duty to see that every reasonable effort is put forth to pre - sent the needless destruction of life and that as great an effort should be made to prevent sickness and suffering as is made to prevent diseases among cattle, hogs and horses, or to prevent the attacks of insects and diseases upon trees and plants of the farmers. Nations and states are very solicitous and exercise extreme care over our beasts and crops, and appropriate money liberally for their protection, but for the conservation of human life they are very conservative. If more money was spent in the prevention of distress, there would be less needed for its relief. The Stale Board fully realises that the work of a health officer is a labor of love, as in no department of public endeavor is there so little money available to carry on the work as in matters pertaining to health. ■n order that the best results may be obtained in sanitation he prevention of disease, it is absolutely necessary to secure id and co-operation of the physicians of Hie State, the natural liana and advisers along that line. Bhe Hoard was very much pleased with the interest manifested lysicians at the last Conference of Nebraska State and Local h Officers held in Lincoln on February. 1913. We were favored at that meeting with papers as follows ■importance of Complete Birth Registration, by Dr. YV. II. AYil- State health officer. Bhe quarantine, Dr. R. W. Connell, Health Commissioner of a. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Dr. Anna Cross. Health Officer of Crawford was prevented from being present at the meeting on account of her train being delayed. I Sanitary Water Supplies. In Prof. Condra. Stale University, as very interesting and instructive ami was highly appreciated • the Health Officers. Need of a State Public Health Laboratory hy Dr. II. II. Waite, University of Nebraaka. eonvineed those present of the necessity of h State Bacteriological Laboratory, and it was ihe unanimous vole of the Congl CIS that there should he a Laboratory established and equipped. Besides these papers which were all handled in an exceedingly competent manner, the following well known medical men partici - pated in the discussion: Dr. Koser. Dr. Xorden and Dr. Carriker of Nebraska City, Dr. Khidler and \)v. liana. of York, Dr. Towne of Omaha. Dr. Weber of Wahoo. Dr. .Marvel and Dr. Woodward of Aurora. Dr. Roves of Hebron. Dr. Milliner representing the I'. I'. Railroad, Dr. Hungate of Weeping Water. Dr. .1. Morrow of Sew - ard, Dr. Barker of the Stale University, Dr. .1. S. Leouhardt, chair - man of Board of Health. City of Lincoln. Dr. Auglc. Dr. Howe. Dr. Sward, ex-member of Ihe State Hoard of Health. Dr. 1'". Wilmeth, Dr. Jester. Dr. Woleott, Dean of the Medical Department of Uni - versity of Nebraaka, Dr. Bpradling, Dean of the Medical Depart - ment of Cotner University, Dr. Carr, Dr. Kail, \h\ Dodson of tin - state Board of Health. Special addresses of unusual merit were delivered by His V.\ ellency. Governor Morehead. Dr. ('row lev of Omaha. Dr. \V. A. •'vans of Chicago, lion. Henry Wallace of Des Moines. and ( speei - lly by Dr. Oscar Dowling, President of the Louisiana State Hoard f Health. The latter had with him as exhibits two of his "health ars" displaying sanitation work in Louisiana, lie is one of the inst widely and popularly known health workers in tip' United tates. The following towns were represented at the meeting: Peru, David City. Mead. Hebron. Mei'ook, Dorchester. Nebraska City, Omaha. .Madison. Pflger, Auburn, Adams. Weening Water. College View .Seward. Arapahoe. Greenwood. York. Bethany. (Sretua, Fre - mont. Lincoln. North Platte. Seotts Bluff. Grand Island, Hastings, Wahoo. Crawford. Aurora. Beatrice and WHbef. All manifested jrreat inteiest in the work, and the desire was expressed that stack a meeting might be held each year, and that the various municipalities should bear the expense of the attend - ance of their representatives. IThe State Board was very much gratified to have such pronu - ent physicians take part and interest themselves in the sessions, or no state has more able practitioners than Nebraska, and -with </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 ■ Ill liwflll W« must have the rapport of the profession, and we an willing and anxious to assist them in every way we can through the Laboratory, the department of vital Statistics, and with any information we are able to give. In future reports of such meeting! we expect to give full nt s of all addresses and discussions, but as this meeting was lg ago. and on account of lack of funds, and out of inability partially select proper excerpts from the mass of good raate - efore us, we are unable to give more than a general sketch of leeting in question. We shall strive however in the future to a more eomplete report. NEBRASKA BABY HEALTH CONTEST We have had baby beauty contests years and years — as if blue ribbons and pretty i'aces were the things that counted. Nebraska's Better Bsbiei this year at the State Fair were not judged by blue ribbons and pretty faces. Instead, fifty-two physicians, under the direction of Dr. W. IT. Wilson. State Health Inspector, made scien - tific examinations of the babies. Each baby was given a mental test and a physical examination to determine its intelligence, height, weight, muscular development, and many other points, all of which were recorded on a carefully prepared score card. Of 612 applications, ."till) were accepted, 483 were examined Vhe State Hoard of Health awarded the prizes from Umm cards. Many interesting points developed in going over these cards. Khe fact that city babies scored higher than rural babies wafl irise 1i&gt; nearly every one. I Why do we find this condition? 1 believe this can be illustrated e case of a woman with a sick child and a neighbor with a sick The woman with the sick child had to do what was within means. The woman with the sick hog could telegraph to hington: they dispatched a number of the finest government rts. All she had to do was to say "hog cholera." K'his is the education as it stands today in the relative value e hog and the child. MRS. M. E. VANOE, Superintendent Health Contest. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">e 9 I'LACh CAUSE. ..Genoa Scarlet fever .Diphtheria Scarlet fever Sanitation Weeping \\ liter Davey .Tecumseh Jan, is, mi:; Nebraska ( it y Scarlet fever Diphtheria Scarlet fever Scarlet fever Small pox Weeping \V ater Tecuniseh Jan. SO, 1913 itchfield Feb. | 1»13 Crete Feb. 5. 191 Winnebagc Infantile paralysis Scarlet fever Feb. lti, 1913 Falls City March .-&gt;. i;»i: Atkinson Typhoid fever Small pox -March 13, 191 .Rosalie March 17. 191 Jloldrfge Small pox -March is, mi .Grand Isl ud Insp. Soldiers Home Cyclone March 34, 19] Omaha '"ollegt V ew Scarlet fever Small pox Rosalit April IS 19] Mason ( y Scarlet fever Diphtheria Small pox April 1 I, 1913 .Univeri I'lace v \l»ril :.'), 1913 .Itica \pril 29, 1913 .Wahoo Small pox ..Meningitis Small pox Small pox ..Small pox Small pox ..Sanitation Diphtheria. .South S jx City it .Meadov ( rovt Holdre June l 1 . 1913 Hold« June 12, 1913 I'nion July I, 191 Ueshler August 9, I'll J'ltersbur \ugust 13, 1'. .Sidney Infantile paralysis lifantiln paralysis .Typhoid fever Sept. s, 1913 .Stanton Oct. 9, 1913 College View Oct. :a. I'.u .'"reighton SiikiII pox Nov. 7. 191.1 College V Typhoid fever Scarlet fever Small pox ie\v Nov. 1 ), I '.pi:: .Beaver Cr o Nov. 13, 191 Folk Nov. 24. r.H Oweola Small pox Nov. 30, 1913 .Small pox it Sc. ff Small pox 8, I'.M South Sioux City Small pox Diphtheria Small pox Diphtheria Sanitation Dec. !). 19)3 Oenoa Dec. 18, 191i Polk Dee. 1 I, 1D13 Wymort Deo. If., 101.1 Central City Dec. 22, 1913 Oretna Scarlet fever I&gt;ATK. I &gt;&gt;■(-. I. 1912 Dm. ."&gt;, 1*12 Jan. 3, 1913 Jan. 7. 1913 tn. 21, 1913 n. -.'7. 1913 Mar&lt;h 25, Ifil April s. |9] May I, 1913 May :i, 1913 May SO, 191 ..SoottM Muff .Reynolds Dec. 4. 191 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 BEGINNING DEC. 1, 1912 AMI ENDING DEC. 1. 1913. Male | Female | White I Col Amer. I Ger. [Scan. | Brit. | Boh- I l'iu-1 21 s 4;.:&gt; I 402 .!« u :: ■&gt; E elope i»4 '.&gt;.". l '.m.i 177 11! 5 4 2 Antelope 104 Banner ner 2 2 l l Blaine I 14 ne 14 M 31 39 . . _ Boone 139 134 271 2:!.". 14 12 3 4 Boone \ 135 Box Butte... M &lt;;:&gt; 153 I4i I ."■ 1 Box Butte... '.to Uoyd '.12 7:; Hi:, 149 11 4 2 3 Uoyd .... '.12 Brown M 99 1M 122 1 :t Buffalo M9 -'4.-) :»1I 4S1 18; 9 I 3 Hurt I7'.t 119 331 1 IN 4 M 1 Butler IN 1M 9M :!24 7 I 12 11 Cass 11;:: 1t&gt;4 397 :tOO U 7 1 1 4 Cedar IIS 170 389 :;:&gt;7 J7 1:1 2 Chase w&gt; 96 2 Cherry 99 K 117 114 ! 1 I 1 Cherry «2 :»:, 117 114 ! 1 I 1 Cheyenne .. M Cheyenne .. M 117 IN I 1 1 117 10!) ii 1 1 Clay 20s 193 381 363 II 14 1 1 Clay 2os is:t :hm 363 12 14 1 l Colfax 141 134 975 939 10 25 Colfax 141 Cuming 171 Cuming 171 l«»; :s:.7 26 8 2 - 5 Custer 113 2t&gt;* :»8i :&gt;72 I I 1 Custer 113 Dakota 68 Dakota 68 :&gt;4 122 11« :; 2 1 Dawes M Dawes 99 139 Iff 2 ; so 139 ; ltl . 2 Dawson 204 Uawson 204 lti'.i 178 399 5 7 2 6 lti'.l 3T3 353 5 1 7 I 6 ■&gt; M 4&lt;t I 2 Ueuel 15 Deuel 19 M 4&lt;t Dixon 109 190 939 'J24 ."i ."&gt; I Dodge 271 2&lt;i4 :&gt;:i.-, IM 2'&gt; 8 1 7 10 Douglas 19T9 1S44 3771 4."&gt; 99S1 913 9&amp;1 90 983 SM Dundy 4J 99 KM !&gt;■"&gt; 4 1 ' 1 Fillmore .... 1M Flllmore .... 169 151 317 :&gt;-' 11 7 3 13 1 Franklin .... 14-j it;7 9M 373 21 !i 3 1 9 Franklin .... 142 !t;7 :io'.i l I 373 21 !i 3 I Frontier .... si N 177 154 13 9 9 2 Furnaa 121 131 j 999 242 - 2 Furnaa 121 Cage 2:!0 Gage 2:!0 990 :.7d 536 29 j 1 I 4 Garden 33 7:) 99 1 3 ' Garden :ir Gaffield M «9 98 93 9 Garfield M Gosprr is r.; 91 ......... S2 9 Gosper 48 Grant 12 Great 19 9 21 91 '.1 21 21 ! ley 93 T9 |79 146 3 11 6 1 Creoley H 71 ITJ 146! 3 11 6 1 Hall 2&lt;57 2;;7 •.04 4.i:i 37 , 2 6 9 Hall 2117 Hamilton .. IN Hamilton .. 1«9 159 325 :io&lt;t 15 9 1 Harlan 115 104 939 200 4 3 2 1 Harlan 115 Hayes 21 Hayes 91 44 41 1 I Hitchcock .. S3 U 108 91 7 4 1 1 Holt 17S !.-,« 334 308 7 3 :i 4 9 Holt 178 Hooker M « 23 Hooker 17 Howard .... Ill Howard .... 113 99 206 171 fi 2-2 2 P. 2 Jefferson.... 179 1M 9T1 2 :uo 99 4 1 4 Jefferson .... 178 Tnhncnn 19") 1 fVT OOO OA« 1fii 1 1 1 I •&gt; 107 220 I 16 ■ 1 111 Johnson 122 Kearney .... , 104 93 107: 183 I 11, 1 K«ltb 42 34 76 73 3i 19 45 42 3 Keya Paha 26 Kimball l </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 OoaMjr | Male | Female! Wlilti- j Col. I Am. I Mr. I gcan.1 Brit- 1 Boh. I I T nel. Knox I 205 202 40."&gt; 2 349 26 21 T 2 Lancaster .. 1T04 15 1424 '.14 1 ill 1«J 16 Lincoln irto Ml 28 Logan 24 17 41 :;!i l 4i 4- MePherson. li 6 12 in Madison .... 2Xi 214 44t&gt; 1 398 Merrick 133 IV t&gt;; 2245 1 Morrill I M 40 TO Nance 13* 100 239 aie Nemaha 136 134 270 ■_!«•._; Nuckolls 144 luu 2«:t 2iii it Otoe ! . 2i'.i 169 :i85 ;4;i ::i Pawnee 14« 114 260 2."&gt;2 Perkins i&gt; 11 17 17 Phelps lit 108 219 184 S M 4 Pierce I7'.i K14 313 27C. 24 1 Platte 228 ■ 200 4:14 :;:&gt;'.• 29 it 4 i Polk I 1S7 119 266 21111 1 -I Red Willow 137 94 23.1 209 1 1 1 Richardson 339 214 4.v; 4:;f, id * 1 :;ti :;27 b I is 1 \&gt; j t i a It Scotts Bluff lM 111 222 1 Scotts Bluff 112 in 222 222 1 201! 11 ; 4 1 4 1 803 11 4 1 » Seward lTii 1G1 337 | Seward I7ii ioi Ml .. :(14 13 4 I 1 :t:i7 . :u4 13 4 12 Sheridan .... Ml 69 169 ! :,' Sheridan .... MM 69 169! :,' i:&gt;4 4 1 4 169 1 :&gt;4 8 4 1 4 Sherman.... Ill 116 tST ! Sherman .... Ill 116 t*T im ii r. I :; I 1* is i .).&gt;- 199 li r. :.' :; t ZZ7 Sioux . 9 10 l!&gt; Sioux 9 10 19 is 1 Stanton . It KIT ; Stanton . It 88 KIT 139 11 ! 7 I 2 l«7 - Thayer . 157 1 U 3(&gt;2 ' Thayer MT 14.') 302 27* -M :; . . 302 278 21 Thomas 8 2 10 Thomas 8 10 10 Thurston .... ir&gt;:i i:.s £M f..") Thurston .... ir&gt;:i 15S SM C&gt;.-&gt; 2S4 19 10 :; 1 -t 2.-.H ts 2^4 in in 4 Valley Ill) 94 204 Valley Ill)' 94 2(14 183 I 4 I I 3 204 183 I 4 I C 3 I SM 12 16 1 Washington 150 ; 135 MS ; Washington 150 ; 135 256 TJ 16 Wayne i:t&lt;&gt; 123 2:&gt;:: Wayne 130 US •.&gt;.-&gt;:: . 202 33 12 2 2:&gt;:: . 202 33 12 I Webster 172 162 Webster 172 1«3 :i:u SM . :!14 13 3 :: ........ \ 334 . 314 13 3 :: \ Wheeler .... 17 24 41 Wheeler .... 17 24 41 40 1 :!27 :{txi 10 »j. ii York 172 1M ::27 ; 13*51 ( 125O2 2601.", 138 York 172 1 &lt;;.-» :w, io :!27 :&gt; l l 13651 12.-.O2 36015 138 23719 lir,» sss 224 3«t .01.-. 138 22T19 1KW sss 224 SM 4 :S!)S ;o I i Sets of twins Male children Sets of twins Male children Female children Sets of triplets... Male children Female children Female children Sets of triplets ' Male children '. Female children DKATHS BY CXH'XTIKS, FROM MUM DKATHS BY COl NTIKS, FROM I)K( M DECEMBER 1912 TO BKBOM 1913. -. !•• KMBKK 1912 TO DKCKMBKK 1913. Antelope Blaine .. Antelope n Blaine M Rock M 30 04 SI 1 Saline 1M ISa :t4T ' ::o:; ij i i Sarpy "&gt;:! 5] n»4 !)4 8 1 Saunders .... I 2&lt;&gt;:; 1«8 371 :;^7 s u l </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 ?4 Boyd "... 4 o Brown Buffalo o|. ( Burt .31 Butler "_.._..___ Cass Cedar Chase 19 Cherry . Cheyenne nlot. • 41 (^lay • ; Col fax Cuming ___ ] ] 7 Custer ],-,- Dakota Dawes Dawson Deuel ' , 4 Dixon Douglas ..„___!".__ 8.3W Dundy Fillmore _J.__._ 1 1 1 Franklin Frontier Furnas " Gage Garden y Garfield ____LL._ I Gosper o ( Grant I 1 Greeley .. ■-,•■■ Hall JI Hamilton Harlan Hayes * Hitchcock Hoit ,;,, Hooker _UZZ 14 Howard ,-,,■ Jefferson Johnson Kearney Keith Keya Paha 4 Knox irr 4 Lancaster _ Lincoln * ■* Logan 3 Loup Madison Merrick Morrill - iiiui 1 111 m — Nance _____„ Neniaha Nuckolls _ *' " ••---.•---......-- J.\J"» Otoe .-JIlIIIZZ IN Pawnee .. r " 100 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Pierre Platte 180 Folk 84 Red Willow 83 Richardson 172 Rook Saline 1M Sarpy Saunders Scotts Bluff „ 113 Be ward Sheridan 46 Sherman 47 Sioux 1&gt; Stan ton Thayer ion Thomas 4 Thurston Valley 76 Washington .■ 100 Wayne 66 Webster 119 Wheeler I York 149 Total !&gt;K ATHS 1913. Typhoid fever Malaria fever Small pox B Scarlet fever 5 Whooping cough Diphtheria Influenza C'ohlera nostros Dysentery s Erysipelas Purulent infection and septicemi Tetanus Tuberculosis of the lungs Tuberculous meningitis. ... Pott' disease •&gt; Tuberculosis of other organs Syphilis Cancer of the liver and stomach Cancer of the peritoneum, intestines, and rertum Cancer of the female genital organs 2 Cancer of the breast. Cancer of other parts Other tumors n Acute rheumatism .. Chronic rheumatism B Exophthalmic goitre Ptomaine poisoning a </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 I Leuchaemia M Anaemia, chlorosis Alcoholism Other general diseases. Meningitis '.'t Poliomyelitis 1 1 I^ocomotor ataxia 1 4 Other diseases of the spinal cord IT Cerebral hemorrhage, apoplexy Softening of the brain Paralysis without specified cause General paralysis of the insane Other forms of mental alienation -&gt;l Convulsions IT Neuralgia and neuritis 4 Other diseases of the nervous system M Pericarditis 6 Acute endocarditis 13 Organic diseases of the heart Wl Angina pectoris I » Diseases of the arteries Embolism and thombosis M Diseases of the Veins, varices. haemorrhoids, phlebitis, etc Diseases of the lymphatic system i Other diseases of the circulatory system l Diseases of the nose and throat 4 Diseases of the ear 2 Diseases of the pharynx « Diseases of the larynx Bronchitis, acute Bronchitis, chronic 1 1 Bronchopneumonia 1 M Pneumonia Pleurisy M Pulmonary congestion Pulmonary emphysema Other diseases of the Respiratory System- Other diseases of the oesophagus I fleer of the stomach Other diseases of the stomach (cancer excepted) , l"T Diarrhoea and Enteritis (udner two years) Diarrhoea and Enteritis (two years and aver) 117 Appendicitis and typhlitis _ 14:; Hernia, Intestinal obstruction _ l II Other diseases of the intestines _ M Acute yellow atrophy of the liver Cirrhosis of the liver _ 71 Biliary calculi _ Other diseases of the liver _ Diseases of the spleen Simple peritonitis „ Acute nephritis _ !M) Other diseases of the digestive system... !&lt;• Bright's disease IM Other diseases of the kidneys and annexa 30 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 Calculi of I'rinary Puimf-m a Diseases of the uterus (non-cantorou Systs and tumors of the ovary rilpingitis and other diseases of the female genital organs ccidents of pregnancy Puerperal hemorrhage .. Other accidents of labor Puerperal sapticemia ... Euerperal albuminuria and convulsions angrene a iu »cute abcess uruncle s Diseases of the bones (tuberculosis excepted) Amputations 0 Congenital debility, icterus, sclerema, etc. Senility 1.293 Suicide by poisoning Suicide by hanging Sui'iile by firearms Suicide by other means Accidental poisoning Accidental drowning 41 Trauinatism by firearms Traumatism by auto Traumatjsm by railways, vehicles, etc. Injuries by animals la Excessive cold Kxoessive heat Lightning 9 Homicides Other external violence No cause S 111 defined cause Kncephalitis t DiWMM of thyroid body 111 defined organic di^ Other chronic poiaoniag KUcrthity (lightning excepted Other acute poisoning i Poisoning by food Hemorrhage 1 4 Ees of the joints in's disease es of tho skin gration 1 Absorption of deleterious gases (conflagration excepted) Hvdrocephalus 1 : Hydrophobia Binai parasites do i lO.RSfi Still Births Total H.254 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 BK(;iNXIX&lt;; DEC. 1, 1912 AND ENDING DEC. 1, 1913. c t . i.K.v.i I&gt;ii&gt;t lit-ria | Oar. S. Mm. I Typh Fct. I TabtrruL QuaJnied'Qiia.Wcl] Qua. I Died I Qua. I Died lRpt.1. 1 Died I Ki.Kl. In. ,| Adams 5 1 &lt;&gt; '5 Antelope .... 55 Q Blaine Boone i 2 9 1 Box Butte. ... 91 3 34 8 8 | ll i Boyd i Brown 1 Buffalo n - 1 1 1 1 Burt 8 14 1 6 1 Butler 1 Cass 8 "M b - ! i i Cedar Chase 1 l Cherry I Cheyenne 4 1 Clay l Colfax l 1!&gt; •&gt; ;i Cuming *&gt; 1 Custer ; 7 8 I 1 I Dakota 1 Dawes 1 - 1 . 1 Dawson 118 Dixon 40 I Dodge ! 16 1 :.'l l S l l Douglas 1 i Dundy Fillmore !&gt; I I 1 l Franklin Frontier Furnas Gage i * 1 " 1 Garden 1 Garfield l Gosper Greeley Hall 1 1 :: Hamilton l Harlan 1 Hayes 1 Hitchcock Holt 11 ii i Jefferson 16 Johnson l 4 1 o Kearney Keith Keya Paha Kimball 1 7 M 1 Knox ; :in ... 10 I a Lancaster .. 2 155 11 i 6 5 20 6 3 42 Lincoln 1 1 2 i 5 ... 1 . 1 ■ k Loup 1 Madison i l </seg>
            <seg id="p017">17 ■ Smallpox IScar.Fev.l DiptberU I Cer. 9. Men. I Typli- Fev, I Tutx-rrul. County ! I ! ! ! I 1 I I , I I t I I gua.!|)liMl|Qua.JDU-d| Qua. j Died I Qua. | Died JRptd. \ Died j Uptd.j IM.-d Merrick j | i 1 1 I I I I i 2 i o Morrill i . i : ! I I Nance 1 1 1 4 3 Nemaha , 1 | Nuckolls I 1 1 ' 1 | Otoe 5 2 1 ! 4 1 1 13 J 1 9 Pawnee 1« : I 1 a 1 1 1 .i Pierce : 6 ll 1 1 3 1 Platte 1 ■• 1'olk 3 6 1 1 1 1 Red Willow * Richardson I 1 Rock 1 Saline 6 21 l 1 ■ . Sarpy 1 Saundere I d8 I 1 Scotts Bluff 1 1 Scward 1 1 2 I ■ Sheridan 1 1 1 . Sherman I .1 1 32 1 1 — • 1 1 1 Thurston U 1 1 I Valley i g Washington 1 3 ■&gt; Wayne . I 1 1 1 Webster 4 I 1 14 1 •&gt; York 4 1 ! Total 1 358 1 5 1 371 1 48 200 I G'J ; 82 1 66 1 06 7:; IT -HU </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 County. 20 i i Boone fi Box Butte a *i Burt Butler 0 12 8 •.•I Cheyenne 13 II Custer Dakota Dawes Dawson II Deuel I Dixon Dodge Douglas Dundy Fillmore Franklin i Frontier • Garden Garfield Gosper i Grant -i Hamilton I.-. - Hayes Hitchcock Holt Hooker " Howard Jefferson Johnson Kearney Keith ! Keya Paha. Kimball • [ 3 Knox </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 /■• County. Lancaster Lincoln -&lt;i Logan l-ouP * MrPherson I Madison Merrick 7 Morrill 11 Nance 0 Nemaba Nuokolls 1" Otoe Pawnee Perkins Phelps , 11 Pierce Platte Polk 10 Red Willow 14 Richardson 1 * Rock It Saline 21 Sarpy Saunders M Scofts Bluff '. 14 Seward Sheridan ' 4 Sherman Sioux . Stanton ' l Thayer W Thomas Thurston - :l Valley s n Washington u Wayne Webster - "' Wheeler — ' Total - IP - IJ M.\KKl\&lt;iK KK1MIKTS 1912. Adams Antelope ' )(l 10 Banner Blaine 15 Boone FSox Butte I- 1 Boyd Brown Buffalo -'■• Burt 80 Butler 115 c a88 ....::: «» </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Cheyenne 1 ;n Dawes KM Dawson Hi Deuel 12 Dixon Dodge 274 Douglas : 2,:t7 Dundy 4 4 Killmore ! M Franklin Frontier Furnas 74 G«ge G&amp;rti&amp;H . • **7 Garfleld :;&lt;, Gosper it Grant Hi Greeley Hall Hamilton 1 19 Harlan -,, Hayes 1 j Hitchcock :u Holt |2« Hooker Howard -. 4 Jefferson Johnson Kearney - 1 Keith s Keya Paha Kimball Knox Lansaater .__.. t F ,,t» 1 Loup : .,i McPherson i Madison ._ 147 Xemaha Nuckolls _ 1 ]7 Otoe Pawnee { Perkins Phelps ; ______ pi er &lt;* : :..:: i no Platte 1 170 Polk 56 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">21 Kork _ 47 Sarpy - ' ll Saundfrs ts Bluff . . r \ lit' Sheridan 79 Sherman 60 Sioux Stan ton Thayer Thomas 14 Thurston Valley Washington 1' H Wayne 1M Webster Hi Wheeler 4 York 1G:&gt; Total 1 SIMMAKV KKPOKT OF VIT A I, STATISTICS I OR 1913 Total number of deaths 11.2.14 Total number of births 36,153 Total number of male children 1 Total number of female children l Total number of white children 26,01 Total number of colored children 1912. SIMMAHY KKPOKT OF MAKKIAf KS AXD DIVOm ES FOU Total number of marriages 12,5 Total number of divorces, suits, etc 2 Cause of divorce — Cruelty _ 9 Drunkenness Non-support 341 Desertion 4 IT Adultery Nature of decree — Number of divorces l/l* Number of divorce suits dismissed IM Number of divorce suits pending #41 Length of marriage — I'nder two years Between two and five years Between five and ten years 4'.»0 Between ten and twenty-five years Between twenty-five and forty years -^4 Between forty and forty-five years 4 Not given 56 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">I '■•! H j j I i j • Si S j I ! i | i I |l j Tli j j I i ; j j I I j I j I I I I j ••! j I | j i I 1 i i I ! j I n ■&lt; M:::':KH::;UMH;::;'::::i!o:Hlj:i::: oinkoi; www: » •! « » M h n -j u i; o. b « -i h i; « k - etc sr • M -III ill »a y» a to *■ m a : : hu^Qdm; r» n q» »a : cc 4» to : t-*c»o s.l ...i .L^r^ XITi ~ -I I a ? ? i 3. 3 « i Ii, i j i ] II iiwlll*&gt;lw&gt;*lll»*tillllli&gt;ti|lll 3 v: 7 *1 jiiijiiiinimiiiiiiiiuiliii ! &lt; M ; ; i : : ; i ; : : ■oo it-*: ::h* m I I M c» H u u : w s&gt;-: -aw: ootc: m: to : w ot h m m : : -a © M : ■ : ! : ! I : : : : I I : I i 0 - I i £ .A 2 I R P- S ~o 3 0 I i g 1 M • O MUM t9t9 " MtOU M — 1- I i | I I 1 ! I [I I II I 1 i i i i i i ! ok. ; m fr* I oo w : ; to : i : Ml mmm: *-* 1 &gt;-» *o *o : to -a : '*huc s II || II II J | | -* — : : t-» : : m Mill w ; to : i utou; co; co w oo : : mm: O: wh; : : Ki —22— </seg>
            <seg id="p023">e ■&gt;• i K I I- ' / V. B 1 -r 3C T t T « / X * * I- :- Mil Mi I I i ill II ! I s j n : : : : :»kn : :n : m n : t-i n &gt;h : ~ -.; i- : : : n «-&gt; ci : r~. i ee _::::: ; ! I I : Q C ill I | : », no i-i ac co n « &lt;» « o i- :i ci r- ■- - •: * ; ~ — s ■ — — ■- « cf II c g i I I I i I I ! i * I i ! j I I | i ! : 5 : : : : ; ; ■i I i i i 1 I 1 I S ! S S I 1 ! i i : S : ; : ; i ; ■ : — ■ ■ i I | | | ; | :rtN | | | ; :h j :h :n j |N I | j ) | )« ;« I! w* II 5 I::::' : : : ! i • ' '• '■ : !::::: : r- / a ft : n ; at M — : : " : «t • « * ; " • ■* * '&gt; " j ! — ~ « &lt;-■ &lt;o fc I g R&lt;lrl«e««H ; - — I! '" : «H »H |H»Jd : — It-NMHC - = £ j [ } p* ; : : | " ;~ - 1 j 1! i 1 :: - ::::: 1 flllililiilillliiliiiilllil —23— </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 ■ i «r?i Ir 1 ! H* B 5i Pi Hi! r. "i I ji |I 1 1 j || || ;:; || | ijfi || i|| | ::: i ■■: i ■■■:■: i i :: I: i : i i ;: : : i) I : i s I : ! : : : ! : I : : ! : ! : j ! : i £ i I • i JIIII1UU1IHUIL &gt;r ii I LI. J ...I L ■ i m ill m u: awwwoD: *. I : u I- I | if 2 n &gt; -. o ■ If III co ! kmm»: Kton^MciaUHtioinKuistii: *- 1 : &lt;c C I I I I i i I Ml »•! Ml i I i Kl i f Ml I i i I I i I •4 W M M ! $1 M -i I w : a&gt;: o&gt; ex o t-&gt; w w i-&gt; : en»«»uti«uK»: ea : ue « M ! I ! ! i e I ! mmmb: oo I : : ! mi m 1 »««&gt;-&gt;tsi-'! ucw! : e&gt; M I M 1 m w» " i i M ec I i : »»^mI w m p-&gt; en * M * : i o&gt; 5 x T O *1 o 3 P P x o I 0 I! - i I at I b*»m«hoh; K&gt;*.*.*-]uo&gt;*.»eco: u*tc m« - J IE I I I I Mi II i i i M ill Mi i i : : ku: : o&gt; : ►* i-&gt; : : : ta &gt;— : to: Oh: : Ml i-i&gt;4i-&gt;-) &gt; I i ! i i i I I I I I j i i i ! i ! i ! S i ! i ! i : : « : Ml : : (-&gt; eo : : um: ■* en o&gt; cm : Ml &amp; m i-&gt; : : o&gt; O a 5c" s a 7 a ■&gt; a ? i u I i ! * o&gt; w : © : Ml ; : cc o&gt; : w j i ! i &lt; i en : &lt; en i ■ : : i ; ! i </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>