<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00028.00016">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00028.00016</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Report of the Secretary of the State Prison Board and Advisory Board of Pardons.</title>
               <date value="1912">1912</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change> 
        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Dec ist, 1912. To HIS KXCEI.I.ENCV, Chester H. Ai.drich, Governor of Nebraska. Dear sir: II liave the honor to transmit herewith the report of the State Prison rcl and Advisory Board of Panlnns for that portion of the last bienniuni e the law became effective creating said Board, To-wit: July 7. 1911, to period ending November 30, 1912. Respectfully, J. A. Piper, </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Jill) 7. 18111, to ItavmlHT I. 18H2. MKMBKRS Kd«ahh G MAor.i, Linculn L)B. J. S. IUti.er. Superior </seg>
            <seg id="p003">State Prison Board &amp; Advisory Board of Pardons. To hit Excellency, Chester H. Almhch, Governor of Nebraska. Dear Sir: The personnel comprising the membership of said Boards — John O. Yeaaar, of Omaha, Edward G. Mapgi, of Lincoln and Dr. J. S. Butler, of Superior — net at the State Capitol on July 7, 191 1 and duly organized by electing John O. Yeiser Chairman of the State Prison Board, EH ward G. Maggi as Chairman of the Advisory Board of Pardons ind Dr. J. S. Boiler Vice-Chairman of both of these Boards I In compliance with the acts creating the two Boards they adopted rules regulations for the orderly transaction of business that might come be - them. Said rules and regulations appear in a seperate booklet. Since their organization three hundred and seventy-five applications have been filed for their consideration, classified as follows: for pardon one hundred and thirteen, for commutation of sentence sixty-two, and tor parole two hundred. I Upon receipt of an application a record is made thereof by the Secretary, - which it U forwarded to the Chairman of the Board to which depart - t it rightfully belongs, who either begins a preliminary investigation :ive thereto, or refers it to some other member for the same purpose, % bv the next regular meeting of the Board they would have gathered r information relative to all the cases that might be presented. The Board have concluded their findings as to two hundred and sixty - two applications, of which one hundred and twenty-five were for pardon or commutation of sentence, and one hundred and thirty-seven for parole. Of the cases considered for pardon or commutation of sentence twenty-nine were favorably recommended to the Governor, nine of which were on ac - count of serious illness, of such nature and condition as to endanger the life of the applicant, or to permanently affect the health of other inmates of the penitentiary. In the other twenty applications where recommendations were made for pardon the Board believed, after a thorough investigation. that the same should be granted. Paroles were granted to twenty-three of those whose applications were filed for pardon or commutation of sentence. I They declined to recommend executive clemency for forty applicants wrdon and thirty-three for commutation of sentence, and so reported, he thirty-nine applications considered for commutation of sentence they mmended a reduction of sentence for six, and that no executive clemen - e extended the other thirty-three. Their recommendations as to the ap - itions for either pardon or commutation of sentence were duly trans - ed to you for your consideration. Ethe two hnndred applications filed for parole the Board have disposed hundred and thirty-seven, having granted eighty-three, approved of to take affect later, and dented forty-two. This makes the total </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 themselves which they followed before coming to the penitentiary. Ethe men paroled twenty-eight have receivod their final discharges on t of the termination of their sentence, and two by reason of the recom - tion of the Board. Ki parol ng the men the Hoard have been successful in placing forty-six mis. thieving the surroundings in country life more conducive to re - lion and the forming of habits of industry. I it- eighty -seven men on parole who have worked for wages have re - in cash 314,402.00, besides the board of fifty-three who were mostly employ of farmers. In case an applicant was single and had aged s who needed assista-ce, one of the conditions ill the parole has been II. or the greater portion, of the wages he received should be paid to rents of such piisoner. Ii mi this report it might seem the board has been liberal in the grant - paroles but under the indeterminate sentence unless paroled those ced thereunder would need to remain the minimum term for the offense riore t&gt;ec jme- the arbitrary duty of the board to grant a parole when - leiiied as von thereafter as the maximum has l&gt;een served. The plan d by the board he- Ijeen to iuiomi e an investigation relative to each rr prior to or .&lt;~ s. on after the minimum term has lieen served; look - »ards a parole tor all who can he trusted lender such restricted litn-rty. KabuUted lists ot applications for prrdon. commutation of sentence, or '., with ihe conclusions of the Board, a|&gt;|iear later in this report. While a pu'ilic hearing is not required 1:1 considering an application for parole, the policy of Ihe Board is ko not final y decide a case until they have »hat inf &gt;rnution can l&gt;e obtained from the prosecuting witness. ..r witnesses, unty Attorney arfeo prosecuted the case, the Judge who presided dt the trial, if they are living, and from others living in the community where t.nce was committed, that they ma\ l&gt;e fully advised as to all that is possible for them to learn about the applicant prior to the commission of the is well as the meterial facts that were presented or admissions made tiv the prisoner at the time he was convicted. I The small percent of paroled prisoners that have escaped, or whom it found necessary to return to the penitentiary substantiates the fact that Board has exercised excellent judgment in granting paroles No porole anted until provision is made for employment. From our actual knowledge of the conduct of many of the men paroled, and from verified reports received, the Ixjard are well pleased with the re - • omplished under the Indeterminate Sentence and Parole Law The earning of nearh fifteen thousand dollars is an economic fact of considerable importance, but this is insignificant in comparison with what it has aided through restricted liberty, in restoring to respectable citizenship nearly one hundred people By this we do not contend that all of the men paroled will make good for all time, bat have :eason to lx-lieve more than eighty percent Al&gt;out one third of the inmates of our State Prison have come there un- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Reformation is not a substance that can be measured out in homeopathic doses to the prisoners, but it is something that he must be brought to feel the need of from daily association with men who are living examples of true citizenship. From our correspondence with the persons to whom these men were paroled, an well as their verification of the monthly report of the prisoner, we believe we have quite authentic information relative to them, and up to this date eighty-eight percent of the men paroled have made good. The following extracts from a few letters is convincing that some of them appreciate the confidence imposed in them, and are living up to their parole agreement and bid fair to become useful citizens: K Writes: Sir: Your kind letter received some time ago and was certainly glad to think that you were willing t* spare enough of your time to remember me. I draw $60.00 per month and have a contract for six months. Am liv - ing the simple life and it is great. * • • * Respectfully yours, Mr. Piper, I am going to call on you and have a talk with you I hope that I have done as you have instructed me and am going to lead a better life from this day on. "No more bad company for me." Another Mr. J. A. Piper, ■Secretary Prison Board rSir: Find enclosed my report for the month of which I hope will prove satisfactory. I am getting along just fine. My employer treats me just as if I was one of the family and I don't think I will have any trouble in stay - ing with them until I get my full release. Tnanking you and other members of the Board for this liberty, I am. Yours very truly, Another KJ. A. Piper, Sir: I received your most kind and welcome letter today and am answer - ing it. Was very glad to receive such a kind letter as this. * • * KYou don't have to tell me you have been a friend to me. I will say yon put me down as one that will shun bad company and strong drink, nking you for your kindness for what you have done for me, I will close Yours very truly t Piper, Sec. State Prison Board, Capitol Building, Lincoln, Nebr. D«mr Sir I received my final discharge this evening. I wish to thank the mem- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 bers of the Parole Board for what they have done for me and hope they will be pleased with my conduct and by my example that I have set. Hope they will take more interest in thoae who are still behind the bars of justice as there are some who need help, and there are some who do not in • waj. I If you wish to reform a prisoner do not keep him there too long, for one become hardened against society, and they do not care what happens ng their life. Hoping to have time some day to see you, I remain. Yours truly Another lays Dear Sir: I Maybe it would be interesting to you to know that I am doing just fine that I like my place and my work. I am doiug my Tery best to lead t 1 life and am sure that I will win out. Ex. (his employer) has done a great deal to help me get a new &gt;ld on life and I am very thankful to him and intend to show him that ly appreciate what he has done for me. Another writes Kara getting along fine. '• No more booze for me." * * * * *r: KAm getting along tine, Mr. Piper, have an excellent place to work and reated fine. I have over (150.00 saved Another that he is going to start a bank account the fust of December ■An employer writing regarding a prisoner that was paroled to him, le sentence is ah jul to expire, says: I hate to part with him but I want to do all I can to help him. He ii a member of the Brother of St. Andrews Cross, Y. M. C. A. and Temperance Secretary and a member of the very best standing. Now, Mr. Piper, any favor you may be able to help in his behalf will thank you for. Very truly, ■ Concerning another the Board received the following from a Minister of Gospel: To Hon. J. A. Piper, Sec'y. State Board of Pardons, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir; I This is to certify that I have known for about two months and w him to have been regularly employed on a ranch 1 % miles from this e; that he is giving satisfaction to his employer and abstaining from all xicants and disorderly habits of every kind. I Further I would say he has given himself to God, joined my church, at s regularly and is living an exemplary Christian life. I feel perfectly in giving him my unqualified recommendation as a man of sterling h. Any favor* he may receive are well merited. Sincerely, </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 Persons to Whom Paroles Were Granted Crime Sent'c'd Term Paroled Earn. Remarks Hrs. ste. 4-18-076 yre. 8- 1-11 111 health Disch. Exp. Sen. 9 18-11 R. Vincent R. M. Neiman H. A. Martin J. H. Krause A. Jacobs Man sit. 12- 1-08 loyrs. 9-11-11$ 280I Robbery I 1-09 54 yrs. 9 II-II $ 1538 I I Shoot to 9-19-102 yra. 9-19-11 umfd Chj». own farm Kill Disch. Exp Sen. 5-I9-12 Brg. and n-u-io i + yrs. 9-29-11 To work for father Disch. Lary. Exp Sen. 2-12-12 W. S. Spurrier A. Brana B. &amp; E 4-11-102 yrs.lio- 3-11 f 42 Disch. Exp. Sen. 12-11-11 Hrs. ste. 3-21-103 yrs.jio-ii-11 $ 561 Disch. Exp. Sen. 8-20-12 Man sit. 3-06-09 10 yrs. io-ii-ii Resumed farm work with F. Ossenkop W. K. Thomas C Lawrence H. Spence bis family Asst. to 9-12-08 lo^rs. io-ii-ii Escaped about 11-1 11 Kill B. &amp; E. 5-20102 yrs. io-ii-m Disch. Exp. Sen. 11-i-n - B &amp; L. 9-10-10 2$ yrs. io-11-iif 273 Disch. Exp. Sen. 9-24-12 Burg. 9- 1-086 yrs. 10-n-ii f 195 H. Whipple J. Gosmare H. Gallora H. Boche Shoot to 5-29-096 yrs. 11-8-IlJ 380 kill Shoot to 5-29096 yrs. 11- S-nJ 380* kill Man. sit. 1 3 16-08 ioyrs.iit-io-lll Assumed control of own premises A. Nelson Incest 5-15-03 i8yrs. II- 9-:i f 65; Shoot to 4- 4-094 yrs. 11-25-11$ 52 Disch. Kxp. Sen 5-30-12 S. Gionlana J. Me Michael H. Nyboe kill Gd. Lar.l 4-1610,5 yrs. 12-11-1 1 f SjoDwdl. 10-28-13 Robbery : 3- 4-1196 yrs. [12-12- 11 $ 250 W. Stratton Rurg. 11-25-103 yrs.112-12-11 $ 140 Violated parole. B. &amp; E. ! 4-14-1 -'-23-11$ i73jDisch. Exp. Sen. 11 29-12 H. C. Harrison T. Dolan 'Forgery 12 icj-io^ yr»Ji2-22-u'f 105'Disch. Exp. Sen. 4-11-12 Man sit. 11-26-103 yrs. 12-23-11 f 675 A. Schultz J. Garfield Burglary 4-11-077 yrs. 1- 2-12 $ 49 Disch. Exp. Sen. 4-15-12 Snoot to 1-16-097 vrs. 1- i-iaf 240 kill E. Bogdanovic H. Edrington C. D. Stevens C. Sweet B. &amp; E. 5-16-103 yrs. 1- 8-12$ 118 Escaped shortly befort Exp. Sen. Gd. Larc. I2-IO loa^yrs. 1-8-12$ 232 Ret. to Pen. 8-31 12 Asst. to 7-14-04 15 yrs. 1-8-11$ 538 rape </seg>
            <seg id="p008">2 8 Remarks ( has. Kne^er Gd. larc. 2 5211 L. M Hush Gd. ■ Marrv 1'ettit Hurj;.\ 4112 yrs. J yrs. II-IC . 5- 10 3 yrs. 20-09 J yrs. 2o-im2 yrs. 1 4- 1 ij 2^ yrs .} 1 - j 1 2 yrs. 25-10 2^ yrs. io-io isyrs. 25-103 yrs. 14- 10 2 yrs. 15-105 yrs. 27-05 10 yrs. • 9-1 1 2 yrs. 1-K.4 vrs. 4 yrs. ] yrs. 2- »-M» 2-Io-I2&gt; 480 Returned to pen. 9-12-1 Diseta. 10,3,1912 255 pisch. exp. sen. 11,17,1 Burg&amp;lar 9- 6-l2f 35 Iw. Manning iGd. larc 2-17-12$ 159 Disch. exp. sen. 11.27,1 504 3-"-'-&gt;i Ray Pierce Asst. to 4 injure . in. Hill Cid. larc. I* *-U-12|# 185 Disch. ezp. sen. 9,12,12 631 Disch. exp. sen. 10,26,12 43 Disch. exp. stn. 5,20,12 120 Discta. exp. sen. 11,29,12 'hs. Smith Hrs s. )-i»-ittf 5493 Jmi Hall Man sit 3-25-12* Dalbert I'reston Forgery 3 3-26-12$ 5459 Oscar Hamblin Asst to Drowned 3, 29, 191 3- 5-'2 body inj 5222 Luther Baker Shoot to 3 3-H12* 3-12-12I 4- 2-12$ 4 9-12 $ 413-12 J 4-15-12$ 4-30 12* 5- 6-12* 5 S-12* 5- 8-'2$ 5- 9-12 # 5-i7-i2i 5-20-12* 5-24-12* 3-3i-'2* 6- 6 12;J 6-11-12* 6-13-12!* 229 wound merv Bonney G&lt;1. larc. 6 17 i.arl Hanley Stab to 11 67 Disch. exp. sen. 7,12,191 wound has. Crow Hr*. stea. 4-i5-io5yrs. 4- 9-12} 120 ds, stem. 4 120 Win. Miles .111. Miles Shoot to 12-27-05 10 yrs. 4-13-12$ iuf&gt; Disch. exp. sen. 9, 1, ic kill Shoot to 1 2 luft Disch. exp. sen. 9, 1, 191 72 Disch. exp sen. 9,9,1912 i~ Returned 10,21,1912 kill at\ A. Owen Karl A. Owen Forgery I- 9-11 2 yrs 4-15-12$ 72 Disch. exp sen. 9,9,19 Forgery 1 Kennie Thomas itennie Thomas K. &amp; E. 5- 1- 10 4 vrs. 4-30 - 1 2 f 3s Returned 10,21,1912 k. &amp; : ..niel Branch Daniel Branch A&gt;st t.. 10 1-094 yrs. 5-6-12$ *3 Disch. exp. sen. 8,31,1 kill L. Homer Child ste 1- 1-095 yrs. j S-i2$ 2^4 Disch. 10. 28, 1912 Asst t s .i Disch. exp. sen. 8.31,12 294 Disch. 10. 28, 1912 45 Disch exp. time 9,11,12 kill ' L. Homer Child stc 1 mk~ Brooks Frank- »r&lt;K&gt;k&gt; R.libery 10- 1-08371*. S" •"'»! 45 Diich exp. time 9,11,1 &gt;hii C.Owen A-si to du' 4- 1 S-9-i2f 123 Rtibberv ii&gt; ; yrs. 1-095 vrs. 1 -1 1 2 yrs. 109 10 yrs. V"8 6 yrs. ] yrs. 29-06 10 yrs 24 11 2 yrs. A^sl todn 4 ■hu C . ( )wen 1*3 bo&lt;iy inj. body inj lorrestHummel l-'urrestiiuniniel Obt nion- 3- 1-1 1 2 jn». 5-1712$ 77 Disch. exp time 11,26 »-y fnlse p. !ias. T. Booton Roblwry 2- 109 lu yrs. 5-20-12$ 5 llscapeil Obt mon- ey false p. Chas. T. Booton Robberv 2 ■ »hn Slater Shoit to 12 93 kill 1 .us. Chirers Man sit. 11 4 u |Returned h, 23, 191 4590 John Berry Robbery 3 2.16 5600 P. J. Fluke Burglary I 8 Disch. exp. time 9 23, 1 2 ■4 Returned S. 30. 1912 red Atchinson Cr. tjaints; 6- h Ii&gt;5 yrs. nature </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 'ersons to om 'aro ies ere rant continue No. Name I Crime 'Sent'c'd Term .Paroled Karn. Name Crime Remarks 5483 Mollie Moore Gd. larc. 6-15-ic 4 yrs 62212$ 361 David W. Scott Hrs. stea. 6- j-ll( &gt;rs 7- 8-12$ 158 5843 Albert Lautfhlin Gd. larc. 10- 1-11 1-7 yrs 7- 9-12$ 140 5614 Jas. Harvey B. ft E 2- 1-1 jfiBl Win Kemplin Burglary 5-31- 1 9-12$ 256 "h.is. Western Hurnlary 1- I-II 2 yr- 7-10-IM 48 Disch. Exp Time 9-23-1912 Soaaabaad His. ate*, ft- 1 11 -• yrs 7-12-12$ 90 5554 Harry Johnson R K: E. 10 1-1 iped Joseph Svilla SI :&lt;&gt;&lt;&gt;t to 10- 1 10)3 yr&gt; 726-12J; 62 kill Ja^. Bradeen Hrs. stea 4 IV 11 l-IOJTf ' S - I-I2f 6&lt;j ■ W. P. Wallace Hrs. stea 8 3 -oS - vrs. - Dn act serious illness I- 1 1 Griffin Man sit. 4-II-II3 yrs S- ; v i2f 116 ■ Son liizer B. ft B. 1-22-1 1 4 yr- l'erlmeter Iiurgiarv i 7-1811 l-loyr S-12-I- 5431 A. Anderson Man sit. 3 24 II 13-12 f 131 5766 Walter Boyd iGd. larc. 8-21-1 1 I 73m 8 16-1. ■ I A. B. Carter iShoot to I 5-20-11S yrs. S-2o-12f u Kill H»rr» Foster Burglary 2- 9-113 yrs. 8-23-12 f 81 Bennie Williams Stab to 5-10-115 rrs. 9- 2-12$ 7S wound 5884 Frank Hensen Bigamy ! 9-30-11 !-7yrs 9- 5- 1 2 f On acct. serious illness ■F. M. Watson Rec. sto. 9-23-11 I-Ijty 9-10-12 property Chas. Morgan Burglary 7-18-11 i-ioyr 9-10-12$ 40 ' 5730 Dan McCarthy B. &amp; E. 7- 8-1 1 i-ioyr 9-10-12$ 5839 Jno. W. Dayly Forgery io-25:nli-joyr 9-10-12$ Returned 10-22-1912 Arthur E. Wing Gd. larc. 8-10-11 1-7 yrs 9-11-12$ 20 KK. White Robbery 5-8-103 yrs. 9-11-12$ Frank Reed Burglary 5-17-u 2 yrs. 10- 112$ F. L. Barnes Hrs. stea. 10- 2. 11 i-7yr»io- 2-iaJ 45 Disch. Exp. time 10-16-1912 Returned 10-8-1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">ac 10 Name I Crime Sent'c'd Term Paroled K&amp;rn erett Dye Burglary S- S II I-ioyr io- 2-12$ hos. Clyde Burglary S- 8-n i-ioyr io- 2-12$ as. Bryan Robbery 5- 6-1 1 15 yr*. 10- 2-12$ ink Kelly Burglary ' 1-13-09 S yrs. 10- 8-12$ yrs. 10- 8-I2i$ oe Gare K. &amp; E. 4-I9-O9I5 yn. 10- H-12I S7J2 H. T. Woefel Hrs. stea. 6-23-11,2 yn. 10- .S-12J &gt;45 Ray Feltz Gd. larc. 1 1 24 1 1 1 7 yr&gt; 10- 8-12$ \ cst Torey Patjtry 9 i-tlli 2oyr|io- 8-12* . m. L. MolineOb on R S-14-11 1 ioyr 10- 8-12$ Road oyd Oliver Rec. sto. 2-16-11I3 yrs. 10-10-12$ prorerty I'm. Kunlz Burglary 12 14-11 1 loyr 10-21-12$ \ alter Poe Burglary 7-2-111 loyr 10-23-12$ '5 Retnrned of own cord 11-19 1912 5809 If. S. Torrison Forgery 10-24-11 ■hn Morrii iBurglarv 10- 7-11 1 . H Sheldon Burglary 10 19-11 1 loyd Frances Gd. larc. 7-11-11 K. W. Butcher B. &amp; E. 11. 9-087 &gt;77i Walter West Steal mo n 9-10-1 1 1 ■&gt;8i7 Tex McDorman Larc. as 9-23-1 1 I bailee .rl Sorensen Larceny 2- 5-12 I mes Anderson Brk &amp; Ent 1 2-2 1 - 1 1 1 loyr 10-22.12 S 574 * Walter Poe Burglary 7- 2-nii niyr 1 1-25-12'$ </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Remark* 5894 Clarence Cain Gr larce. j-1-12 17 yrs Effective Jan. 1, 1913 5819 Chas. Lnkehart Gr larce. 11- 11-11 1-7 yrs Effective Dec. 31, 1912 5729 Cha». Leroy Brk &amp; eut 78 11 1-10 Effective when employ- ment is provided 5818 Chas. I&lt;ambert Cone stol 12-27-11 1-7 Effective Jan. 1913 propt 5792 C MrLaughlin Brk &amp; ent 10-7-11 1-10 Effective when suitable employment is provided 5897 P. K. Smith Forgery 3-11-12 1-20 Effective Jan. n, 1913 5903 Frank Valato Brk &amp; ent 3-28-I2 I-IO Effective Jan. 28, 1913 4996 J. B. Lillie High rob. 4-17-08 8&gt;rs Effective Jan. 7-17,1913 4971 Geo. Mathews Brk &amp; ent 3-17-08 8 yts Effective 4-1, 1913 5675 Rob't Parker Man sit 5-11-11 6 yrs Effective 5-9, 1913 5700 Sigmonil Fuller Brk &amp;ent 1-16-n 3 yrs Effective 1-16, 1913 5501 F. Martindale Hrs stea. 17-25-10 4 yrs Effective Dec. 1912 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Persons pp! ications or ere Crime ISent'c'dl Term Denied 'no T. Bridges Rape 1-2-08 10 yrs 9 27 12 1. Bums B &amp; R 5-1-1 1 1 yr I 25 12 Benedict Hrs. stea. S-7.11 13 yrs 7 9 12 Wm. Barrett Hrs. stea 6 9-09 7 yrs 9 24 12 '.'. S Bruns'in Bigamy 76-11 1-6 yr 10 8 11 R. L. Burke A. B H. 11 21-11 1-5 yr 10 9 12 ' P. Bridges Incest i 2 • - 10 9 12 Rape .1-0820 yrs 3 13 12 • Chivers Man sh. (-25-09 5 yrs 9 13 11 W.Crawford Cuttokill 10-14-1 o 7 yrs 11 8 II 1 lir. larc 12-22-10 5 yrs 5 8 i; ■ ington Burglary 1 2- 1 2-08 5 ym 7 His Rape 11-409 3 yrs 1 4 12 il Franklin H . robri'y- 2 12 11 --Ms Ast. b. h. 4-I4-11 2 yrs 7 . \ Jensen Burglarlv 1 1-5-09 F'Tgery IO 12 B &amp; ; . Hrs stea. s- 1 ■ 1 1 1-7 il is yrs 1 1 - O \ Mason Asst rol s 12 ilan B &amp; H. !en li &amp; E 4 12 11 l'ettit Rurglarly V. Root INmbuj vr- in 10 i! Riley &lt;"&gt;r. larc 7-IJ-I1 i-7yrs 7 IO 12 Bnrglarh 10 yn 1 1 1 . •out 1 fit. 1 2, 14.O9 9 &gt;' r * lo 1 C. Silver Gr. larc. 3.13,09 73m smith Ril S. G 2,25. 1 1 3 yrs 9 11 12 K. Stiae Gc larc 8 12 \\". Taylor • Thomas K ft K o 12 \V. Williams Rape 9,29.07 1 M. Williams B. &amp; E yrs 9 13 11 Wardlaw ,4 15 yrs 12 12 II White larc.fr. V. 11,29,11 ] 9 I2 V. Young Day roll 6,27,06 10 yn Hunter Aslt toK ;o yrs 7 1 / </seg>
            <seg id="p013">PP Crime Sent tied Term 57'5 Prank Allen Horse stealing 6 14 11 3 yrs 5796 Jay Anderson Breaking .S: enter 10 11 11 1-10 5777 Frank Allen (".rand larceny 9 21 II 1-7 5727 W. A. Becker Rec'd stolen propt 6 17 11 5 EWridge T. Bliin jHorse stealing 12 21 11 2-10 S910 J. Brown Forgery 3 30 12 1-20 5921 P. Krennan Forgery 3 22 12 1-20 5775 E. Cherrington Breaking &amp; enter 9 21 11 1-10 5919 C. Cordonier Ass't intent rol&gt; 4 17 12 1-3 Connelly Hi&gt;rse stealing 12 2u II 2-15 &lt;. Carney Breaking &amp; enter 4 14 12 1-10 Deleene Breaking &amp; enter 12 22 09 5 S. Klliott Rebbenr 12 30 06 i2-&gt;$ 5376 H. Kvers Attempt to rape 12 29 08 7 5880 J. Ernsdorff Larceny I 22 12 1-7 5776 J. Ell Breaking &amp; enter 9 20 11 1-10 5526 F. Etue .Man slaughter 9 27 10 7-+ v. Frenchy Burglary 9 30 1 1 I-IO Fourgenerations Horse stealing 9 25 11 1-10 5865 J. Fanning Burglary 12 15 II I-IO 4732 H. Gray Murder II 21 0615 5922 A. Gray Forgery 4 18 12 I-2O 5S16 D. Gasperson Rreaking &amp; enttr 11 9 n 1-10 5701 H. Hol&gt;bs Breaking &amp; enter 6 5 11 3 5837 W. Hanger l»'t intent to kill 9 27 11 1-20 5S40 N. Hardy Larc fr pr 12 12 11 1-7 5835 F.Henley Manslaughter 12 2 II 1-10 5679 F. Howard Breaking &amp; enter 5 13 11 10 5824 J. Hardin Brg. of box car S 4 11 1-10 5893 R.Irvine Obt money f'lspret 2 6 12 1-5 5731 G.Jones Larc fr pr 7 II 11 1-7 I). Jones Grand larceny 9 1 11 1-7 : I. Jackson Breaking &amp; enter 5 10 11 10 5749 J. Kelley Horse stealing 8 1 11 2 I,. Kawainato Grand larceny 1 1 25 1 1 1-7 King Breaking &amp; enter , 1 29 1 1 i-:o (".. King Horse stealing i 20 12 1-10 5704 N. Levato High robbeay 6 7 11 10 4971 ('.. Mathews Breaking &amp; enter 3 17 8 8 5742 P. Maloney Burglary 7 22 n 1-10 5924 O. Mansfield Man slaughter 4 18 12 1-10 54*7 J McKibbt-n Incest 5 18 10 6 i ; . McConnell Giand larceny 10 26 11 1-7 1 r. Nigel Asst intent to rob 3 30 1 1 6 Newlan Horse stealing 9 30 11 1-10 R. Parker Man slaughter 5 11 11 6 F. 1'avil Bigamy 10 14 11 1-7 . Percell Forgery 1 21 12 1-20 5*99 W. I'rovost Forgery 3 20 12 1-20 5099 B. Robinson High robliery 10 12 08 7 G. Rivers Holdup 12 22 10 7 5119 J. Smith Attempt to rob 11 1308 12 5906 L. Shivers Blackmail 3 28 12 1-3 5898 J. Sears Forgery 3 19 12 1-20 4907 H.Thomas Shoot intent to kill 12 120812 5741 Fred Woodworth Burglary 7 21 11 1-10 ;. Wilson Larceny 11 30 11 1-7 5861 H. Williams Burglary 12 23 11 1-10 5905 W. Whitefeather Grand larceny 3 21 12 1-7 4983 M. William.- Breaking &amp; ent 3 28 08 7 5857 J. Clarence Manslaughter 9 25 n 2 5820 D. Duncan Burj;lary 10 13 n 1-10 u— </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 That Have Been Favorably Recommended by The Board. Name Crime Sentence Yrs. Application For Albert Able* Burglary Pardon, Tuburculosis patient I 25 II 3 Fred Bishop iGd. larc. 9 8 ii 2 Pardon, t'rged by Co. Atty. &amp; Judge Pardon, Urged by Co. Atty. &amp; Judge Pardon, Seriously ill Harrvl Barlow Hrs. SttM 8 3 &gt;" I-IO George Davis Robbery 6 29 ii " Commutation to 8 years Pardon, Seriously ill Commutation to 2'/$ years Clifton Hall man Mur'er i 5 *5 O7 !2 Ray Holstrotn Burglary 7 1 11 1-10 'Jerry J. Hanks Rape 6 30 10 7 Wm. Hicks Robberv Pardon, Had served 20 mo. favorable 5 11 O9 1 on parole Hess Jr! Embezzle Pardon, Urged in person by District Judge who pronounced sentence Oran E 10 16 11 1-7 ment Martin Murray Brk &amp;ent 10 29 09 Pardon, Urged by Co. Atty. &amp; Judge Jesse McCoy Hrs. stea 9 n I Commutation, Very sick since died. Commutation, Serious illness since died. Pardon, L'rged by Co. Atty. &amp; Judge Pardon, Granted 9-25-1 1 3 VV M McPhail Forgery- David Newell Giv.whi: W M 7 5" 2 Giv.whis- 11 16 11 2 key tofri jjno. Pettipiece Hrs. stea 2 11 11 1 Loui* Priest Liquor to 4 n 11 2 Pardon, Urged by Co. Atty. &amp; Judge Pardon, 1 % mo. before exp. sentence Pardon, Pul. tuburculosis Indian Km. Roblev to 12 9 07 5 Rape R. Ramsey Foruica- u 14 10 3 tion Henry Southard Burg ;. &amp; Pardon, Poor health 7 15 " 1-3 Larc Jno. H. Sherer iSut. rape Pardon, Married complaining witness and gave child honorable parentage Pardon, Urged by Co. Atty. under 18 4 11 11 5 Joseph L. U pton Aiding 1-20 yean when convicted Forgery V. L. Williams Rape 29 e&gt;7 Commutation, to 6% years 9 10 5396 Aindee Wilson Brk&amp;ent Pardon, Have served acceptably en parole 15 months Pardon, Given benefit of jail time 1 7 io 3 Hutchinson Murder 10 13 °4 12 \ If red Jones Burglary 8 09 Pardoned, Pul. tuburculosis 3 4 A. Whiting Bigamy 4 2 12 i-7 Pardon, Reconciliation with wife and will provide for children antes Perry Murer2 Commutation, Two members favor 3 i O7 12 Maggi dissents 5527 Wm. Lawrence Forgery ■ ? 8 io Sick Pardon 2X </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Ion, or Commutation of ice, ecommended be Denied. Name Crime Sent'c'd Years Leo Angus Grant Blunt Henry Brown Haward Bailey 1 J. W. Connell Harm Dirksen John W. Dayly Thos. Davis Clide Ellington Jas. Evans J. P. Ernsdorff W. A. Fouse Arthur Frenchy C Gathright Edgar Goff Edw Gardner Wm. Howard A. Hawkins Win. J. Holden L. R. Herman Daniel Holler Geo. Johnson Ernest Kenison Martin Lampe Wra. Landford Jas. B. Lillie Chas. Lukehart Chas. Lambert Earl R. Martin Philliy Mauve F. Martimlale Wm. R. Miller Basil Mullen Edw. Morgal G. W McGuire 8. McPherson Jas Nolan 0. V. Olsen Jay O'Hearn C. Pumphrey Jas. Phillips C. D. Romero Thos. Ross H. D. Reed Fred Robinson Joseph Ruff Allied T. Staley Chas. Sherman J. L. Sumler Carl iwrensen Robert Sutton J. Tooman Andrew Tucker Chas. Taylor Jesse Young Murder 2° Gr. Urc. Murder Rape ! Robbery Rape Forgery Forgery Murder 2° High Robbery Larc. Murder Burglary Murder 2° Asslt. to kill Murder Burglary Murder Murder &amp; asslt. Asslt to rob Bigamy Murder 2° Murder Stat. rape Burglary High, robbery Gd. larceny Cone. sto. prop Stat. rape Brk. &amp; ent. Hrs. stealing Murder Murder 2° Stat. rape Brk. &amp; ent. Brk. &amp; ent. Brk. &amp; ent. Rape Murder Murder Murder Pass. frg. draft Burglary Brk. Scent. Munler State, rape Bigamy Robbery Brk. &amp; ent. Larceny Rape Murder Murder 2° Robbery Murder 3 25 06 IO IS IO 4 24 09 9 27 04 2 23 11 3 809 10 25 11 12 22 IO 12 19 07 12 7 IO I 22 12 3 I 08 9 30 II 6 7 06 1 24 II 3 5 01 4 11 07 12 21 98 12 14 04 3 3° II 2 23 11 12 23 10 6 3 08 7 2. 10 10 22 10 4 17 08 11 11 11 12 27 11 11 30 09 3 '3 °9 7 25 10 12 n 00 7 23 °7 6 I 01 8 10 09 9 23 " 5 15 08 9 "4 8 s 6 26 06 12 21 07 8 1 09 1 15 05 3 3' &gt;' 5 ■ " 3 2 10 4 18 09 2 17 11 11 30 10 4 24 09 2 5 12 6 4 11 3 29 99 12 23 03 12 14 11 10 15 02 io Life 2O 8 6 I-2O .s 16 15 1-7 Life i - io 2O 2 Life 6 Life 14 6 7 12 % 2 8 i-7 1-7 3 7 Life 2O 15 3 I-IO 5 2O Life ■7 Life io 2 I Life 5 3 5M i-7 io Life n 3-15 '3 *5 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">rr • That The Board Recommended be denied, (continued) </seg>
            <seg id="p017">rof Applic Now itions for Pi irdon, 1 Commutation of j itence, Pending bef&lt; &gt;re the ite Prison Board. Name Crime ISent'c'd Term Application for 4617 W. Bartee 5605 C. Briley 5249 I. Chambers r. Collins [. Cappell T. Davis H. Davis Dougherty K Fisher S761 A. Lackhart C. Miller McPheraon ! Patten W Rol&gt;erts S^4 B Stephenion y&gt;44 J Trimble C. Welch V Almaok ! Barker IV. Craig Chanev \V. Goodel Galbraith V. Hotden Headley |. Kt-lley Lind V. Miller ! Parker S6-4 H. Palmer Philtiert 'rval Phair 5-' 1 4 R. Ravmond Ruff J763 J R.ks 1 Srwrks ' ). Olson |. Wa'ker L. Allen F. Allen Ginger $868 R. Hamann S'67 J. Uib P. Moore 5654 R. Rvan 5685 A. Simpson H. Shank . Stevens 4652 C. Wain Murder Murder 2° Murder Murder Forgery Forgery Rape Burglary Murder Break &amp; enter Incest Break &amp; enter I Rape Asst to rape {Carry con. wep. Aaall to rob Break &amp; enter Murder Break &amp; enter Murder 2° Felonious asslt. Murder RoMiery Attpt bank rob Murder 2° Murder 2 0 Break ft enter Murder v&gt;-slt to rape i Murder Robbery lint to rape , Robbery jStat rape Laii'—y Crime agnature Munier 2° • Murder 2° Murder 2° Horse stealing Asslt int wound Car Vnowl fem'l Asslt to rape Horse stealing Grand larceny High robbery Arson Burglary Murder &amp; rob. 4 &gt;3 °6 '5 i 30 11 20 12 21 03 Life 1 3 00 Life 3 12 12 1-20 12 22 10 5 1 23 1 1 20 6 s 11 2 1 15 0820 8 19 11 1-10 4 I 11 IS 9 23 11 1-10 12 11 09 15 1 1 1 13 12 2 3 30 " 6 10 31 10 2| 3 14 00 Life 4 14 [2 1-10 11 28 05 Life 4 15 12 2-4 2 16 09 Life 5 "9 I'M 12 17 04 14 11 13 0623 6 22 1 . 12 911 1-10 12 11 00 Life 10 16 07 9 4 2 1222 11 4113-15 10 14 10 5 3 3 "9 10 4 18 . « 25 " 3 Life 6 7 02 20 4 26 06 20 3 10 06 20 6 14 11 3 7 13 II I-M 1 17 12 IO 4 12 II 2 7 2» II 1-4 2 16 I I 4 5 16 II 7 5 8 12 1-20 5 17 11 2 6 25 06 Life Commutation Pardoa Commutation Commutation Pardon Commutation Pardon Pardon Commutation Pardon Commutation Pardon Commutation Pardon Commutation Commutation Pardon Pardon Pardon Commutation Commutation Commutation Pardoa Commutation Pardon Pardoa Pardon Commutation Commutation Pan Ion Pardon Commutation Commutation Pardon Commutation Commutation Pardon Commutation Com. or Pardon Pardon Pardon Pardon Pardon Pardon Commutation Commutation Pardon Pardon Commutation </seg>
           
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>