<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00078.00022">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Factors Affecting the Performance of Kerosene Cook Stoves</title>
               <date value="1932-11">1932-11</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-16</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION RESEARCH BULLETIN 64 Factors Affecting the Performance of Kerosene Cook Stoves EDNA B. SNYDER Department of Home Economics LINCOLN, NEBRASKA NOVEMBER, 1932 </seg>
            <seg id="p002">TABLE OF CONTENTS Summary 3 General Theory of Kerosene Burner 4 Stoves Used 8 General Methods Employed 8 Measurement of heating time and thermal efficiency 8 Measurement of kerosene 9 Measurement of burner draft 9 Effect of Exterior Regulation of Draft 10 Effect of Alteration of Air Openings 12 Effect of Chimney Changes 14 Effect of Interchange of Chimneys 15 Studies on Grate Height and' Construction of Stove 17 Effect of height of grate above chimney 17 Effect of construction of grate 19 Studies on exposure of stove m relation to burner performance....l 9 Discussion of Results 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">SUMMARY The purpose of this investigation was to learn the effect of construc - tional details of the burner and the framework on the performance of kerosene stoves. Six stoves were used, four of the long-chimney type and two of the short-chimney type. Of the long-chimney burners; three were from the same manufacturer; the fourth was similar in appear - ance, but differed in performance. Of the short chimneys one burner used a wick, the other a lighting ring. The effect of: (1) draft varia - tions and constructional details and (2) the framework on the heating time and thermal efficiency of stoves was studied. To measure the draft, or velocity of air entering the burner, each burner was enclosed in a metal cabinet with an opening so constructed that all air entering passed through it and out through the chimney. Joined to the opening was a pipe containing a low-speed anemometer. Equal quantities of distilled water were heated through equal tempera - ture ranges, and the time required to heat the water and the consump - tion of kerosene were measured. From these data, heating time and thermal efficiencies were determined. Results show that the draft of long-chimney burners is greater than that of short and is affected by the height and diameter of the chimney and the size and arrangement of openings for air. Because of the greater draft in long-chimney burners, the rate of combustion is higher, resulting in a more powerful but slightly less thermally efficient burner than the short. Differences in performance of long-chimney burners are due to such constructional details as height and diameter of chimney, size and arrangement of openings for air (particularly in the flame spreader), angle of collar on which the chimney rests, and the distance between the flange and the top of the flame spreader. Such features are funda - mental because they direct air currents and mix air with kerosene vapor. No improvement in heating time and thermal efficiency resulted from interchange of chimneys on long-chimney burners from the same manu - facturer. The best results were obtained with the original combination. One combination was slightly superior in performance to the other three. An increase in chimney diameter on one short-chimney burner decreased the heating time but lowered the thermal efficiency. The performance of burners in the cabinet was generally superior to the performance on the stoves. These results suggest the importance of insulation of burners. Relative distance of grate from chimney top affected heating time and thermal efficiency. Heating time decreases and thermal efficiency in - creases as the distance between grate and chimney top decreases. How - ever, there appears to be an optimum distance for each burner because less than this distance results in the formation of soot and odor. The shape and weight of the grate and elevations on it are important factors affecting burner performance. Enclosure of the sides and back improves burner performance, especially where the stove is exposed to outside draft. Long chimneys are not affected by draft to the extent that short chimneys are. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Factors Affecting the Performance of Kerosene Cook Stoves EDNA B. SNYDER 1 Department of Home Economics In a previous study of the comparative performance of various types of kerosene stoves 2 it became obvious that a number of details of construction were fundamental m efficient performance. This study was undertaken to ascertain the in - fluence of certain constructional features on the rapidity of heating and thermal efficiency of the stoves. GENERAL THEORY OF THE KEROSENE BURNER Kerosene is a mixture of several hydro-carbons of the methane series. Its approximate chemical composition is that of tridecane, C l 3H 28 . It owes its adaptability to stoves to the fact that it has a low degree of volatility at ordinary tem - peratures and can be delivered by a wick or otherwise into the presence of a flame without explosion. It does not burn as a liquid, but must first undergo vaporization, which occurs continuously at temperatures above 150° F. A number of reactions are involved which depend upon the intimacy of mixture with oxygen, draft, and localization of heat. These reactions may be illustrated by the following equations : (1) C lB H 28 +20 O 2 -&gt;■ 13 CO 2 +14 H 2 O + heat (2) Ci 3 H 28 + heat -&gt;- C + mixture of combustible lower hydro-carbon gases (3) 2 C + O 2 -&gt;- 2CO + heat (4) 2CO + 0.. ; -&gt;- 2 CO, + heat (5) C I3 H. 8 + i3 WO, -&gt;■ 13 CO + 14 H.O + heat (6) C lB H 28 + 70, ■&gt; 13 C+ 14 H 2 O + heat In the first equation, which illustrates perfect combustion, maximum heat is obtained. For ordinary kerosene this is about 19,800 British thermal units per pound. The momen - tary effect of this heat is to decompose some of the kerosene vapor according to the second equation, giving lower hydro - carbon gases which are combustible as m the first, and carbon. The latter may be deposited as soot if chilled before it can be oxidized, but m the ordinary well-regulated kerosene flame, it first imparts luminosity and then oxidizes according to the third and fourth equations. The total heat output of the second, third, and fourth, assuming that the lower hydro - carbons m the second are all burned and excepting the energy lost m luminosity, is the same as m the first. 'The writer wishes to acknowledge the assistance of Prof. J. C. Russel of the Department of Agronomy, Nebraska Experiment Station, m the planning and carrying out of the study and m the arranging of the manuscript. 1 Edna B. Snyder, Nebr. Aer. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 48. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Performance op Kerosene Cook Stoves 5 Equations 1 to 4 presuppose an excess of oxygen, or air, the theoretical minimum supply being about 13 cv. ft. of air per ounce of kerosene, or 1.3 cv. ft. per minute m the ordinary burner that consumes six ounces of kerosene per hour. If the oxygen or air supply is deficient, the kerosene may burn with the formation of carbon monoxide as m the fifth equation or carbon (soot) as m the sixth, along with considerable un-i burned and odorous gases. Under these conditions, the heat obtained per unit of kerosene will be much reduced. Fundamentally, the kerosene burner must provide for three things : (1) Vaporization of kerosene m quantity adequate for the heat requirement. ' • (2) Bringing the vapor into contact with air m sufficient quantity to insure complete or nearly complete combustion. X 3) Direction of the heat without undue loss to the point of utilization. In the stoves classified as wick burners, m which the fuel is elevated by capillarity through a tubular cotton wick, the kerosene is vaporized at the exposed rim with the aid of heat from surrounding metal parts and by draft through openings m the base of the chimney. In the long-chimney type, which employs an open chimney, combustion occurs largely m the region of the wick and entirely within the enclosure of the chimney. In the short-chimney type combustion occurs both inside and outside the chimney, the flame coming m direct contact with the utensil. As stoves are constructed, the capil - larity of the wick is not a limiting factor m oil consumption ; otherwise the wick would char and burn away. The factors that may limit oil consumption are the area of wick exposed, which will vary with its diameter and degree of elevation, and the amount of heat and draft that produce vaporization. In the stoves classified as wickless burners, where the fuel is fed by gravity into a trough or bowl, initial vaporization is effected by preheating with a volatile fluid like alcohol or by means of an asbestos kindling wick. Subsequent vaporization is maintained by the heat of the metal parts or by the flame itself. In such burners the amount of fuel consumed is limited by the opening of the feed. In practically all stoves the kerosene vapor is mixed with air m some sort of chimney. Mixing is caused by the natural upward draft that begins to occur as soon as the burner is lighted. In a few stoves that have gravity feed without a wick, no chimney is used and the air simply rises through the perforated hot metal burner bowl. In chimney-type stoves, the features that affect draft would seem to be very important. Chimneys may be made long, which would tend to increase </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 T I IJ It] U Ifix— F 'B- 2 - — Short-chimney burner with wick. fm\ I /Jll r7\ I- Double-walled wick tube \&amp;h~ £n X« &lt;&lt; V2^ 2. Feed pipe. ||r iill Jl 3. Outer and inner combustion tubes 111 IS" "'ralU ill 4. Inner support II I :i'j 5. Chimney Fib. 1. — lioni-chimney wick burner. \t ■.'//'• ''.•'•'•'•'•'•'.'•' '.V'S I 1. Double-walled wick tube ■•'/•V*-'"'" •"•"•'•I '•'•'•'•'Wl \ 2. Feed pipe JBjv'* /"•'•' ''•''.''.'''; i'"l^S) / 8. Top of flame spreader \ lMm'"-' "V ■ * * "•'• '.''fll / 4. Collar on which chimney rests •'•''•'■'•"■■■'■''&gt;&amp;.&amp;' 5. Chimney . (TVjOT^i^i^^r 6. Arrows showinu direction of air vi/~Tj| / It' currents J—C~^ 7. Flanse fO\ «rra /Ov 8. Spanner \£J Ifc. [SJ Fist. 8. — Short-chimney burner using as - bestos kindler or lighting ring. 1. Asbestos lighting ring or kindler 2. Oil trough or burner bowl 3. Feed pipe 4. Inner combustion tube 5. Outer combustion tube 6. Drum or chimney </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Performance op Kerosene Cook Stoves 7 the rate of draft and cause a better mixture of air and fuel. However, this leads to a higher degree of combustion within the chimney itself, and at a considerable distance below the grate. On the other hand, chimneys may be made short thereby decreasing the draft but leading to greater combus - tion m the region of the grate near the bottom of the utensil. One of the most difficult constructional problems is the transference of the heat to the utensil on the grate. Heat is transmitted by the hot stream of air and gas that arises from the chimney. A portion is radiated from the flame itself and from the heated burner. For the heat to be well utilized, it must come into intimate and prolonged contact with the vessel on the grate. It would seem, therefore, that the closer to - gether the grate and burner are brought, the greater the de - gree of utilization. However, bringing them too close affects draft, which m turn affects both the completeness and place of combustion and the direction of stream lines of hot gases. As has been shown m a previous publication, 3 the area of the bottom of the vessei is very important. Likewise the focaliza - tion of the chimney and the deflection of the grate are im - portant, as is also every other factor tending to dissipate the heat stream before its heat can be absorbed. Superficially two stoves may appear to be almost identical. Actually they may differ considerably m efficiency. In heating performance, kerosene stoves may be expected to differ m two important respects. One is the rapidity with which they will heat whatever is supported on their grates. The other is the percentage of the heat of combustion which is utilized. The first may be designated as "heating time" and the second as "thermal efficiency". Heating time will vary with the size of the flame and the rate of oil consumption and m these respects is independent of thermal efficiency. Thermal efficiency is determined m part by the completeness of com - bustion of the fuel. However, all stoves can be adjusted, some more readily than others, to burn their fuel more or less com - pletely. Heating time and thermal efficiency both vary con - siderably with heat wastage. Any feature of the stove or factor exterior to it that allows a portion of the heat to waste prolongs the heating time and reduces thermal efficiency. As heat wastage occurs through radiation and convection from heated metal parts of the stove itself, and m the draft column arising from under whatever is supported on the burner, it would seem that attention to stove economy should be directed along two lines. The first is the study of the stove with respect to construction and performance under standard - ized conditions. The second is its use with respect to the 'Edna B. Snyder, Nebr. Art. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 48. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 8 utensils employed, exposure to draft, and care in manipula - tion. In this bulletin the former is considered. Specifically, the purpose of this investigation was to de - termine : 1. The effect on heating time and thermal efficiency of (a) the velocity of air entering kerosene burners and (b) the de - tails of construction of the burner. 2. The effect of the character of stove construction on heat - ing time and thermal efficiency of the burner. STOVES USED Six stoves were used in this investigation and are designated by number. 4 Numbers 1, 2, 5, and 6 were of the long-chimney type, No. 3 was a short-chimney wick type, and No. 4 was a lighting-ring type. Numbers 1, 5, and 6 were from the same manufacturer. They were similar in appearance to No. 2 and yet showed distinct differences in performance. Inspection disclosed considerable differences in such features as size and arrangement of air openings, curves in the collar, constric - tions at the top of the chimney, and height and diameter of chimney. Figures 1, 2, and 3 show details of burner con - struction. GENERAL METHODS EMPLOYED The burners in all cases were adjusted for maximum heat and were hot at the start. Difficulty was encountered in standardizing the flame. This is important since differences in flame height cause considerable variation in results. During preliminary attempts at flame adjustment, it was observed that when the wick was turned upward on long-chimney burners, a point was reached at which the luminous tips con - verged. Just below this point, maximum heat apparently was obtained, and this position was used for the flame in all cases. The flame was adjusted with a utensil over the burner. When adjusted before, it tended to "creep up" after the utensil was placed in position. For short-chimney burners the wick was adjusted so that the entire flame was blue. MEASUREMENT OF HEATING TIME AND THERMAL EFFICIENCY To determine heating time and thermal efficiency, a method was employed that experience has shown to be satisfactory in comparing all makes of stoves. 5 Four pounds of distilled water at an initial temperature of 86° F. (30° C.) were heated in a covered copper pan to a final temperature of 203" F. (95° C.), and the time required was taken with a stop watch. The temperature was taken with a mercury thermometer in - serted nearly to the bottom through a hole in the lid. The 4 Numbers 2, 8, 4, B, and 6 were used in the study reported in Research Bulletin 48, where they are designated as Numbers 4. 3, 5. and 12, respectively. 3 Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 48. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Performance op Kerosene Cook Stoves 9 pan used had a flat bottom and vertical sides. Its diameter was 9.8 inches and its depth was 3.5 inches. It was made of 16 - -mch-gauge material and had a weight excluding the lid of 1 34 pounds. The amount of heat required to heat the pan itself through the above range of temperature was 14.11 Bt v which is only 3 per cent of the 468 B.t.u. of heat required to heat the water through the same interval, and consequently was neglected m calculating thermal efficiency. Thermal efficiency was calculated by conversion of the usual formula, 0 Thermal efficiency - _ wt ; of m lbs, x 100 Wt. of kerosene m lbs. x 19,800 into the simple expression, Thermal efficiency 468x100 do x c.c. of kerosene MEASUREMENT OF KEROSENE To insure accuracy of oil measurement, the oil tank was removed and a burette graduated m cubic centimeters was suspended over the receptacle which held the oil tank. The oil level m the tank receptacle, which was automatically maintained by the tank, was located and marked. The burette was filled at the beginning of a test and the level maintained from it. At the end of /~W the test the level was \ accurately adjusted to JM :■:■■ j j|| mark, and the amount k jhmAV;' •■"?). tl .;. "(ij 3f oil consumed read *•' JY / 'j from the burette. V !^^^^AlsvCt j^^iS^T ! - I MEASUREMENT OF S?^^^^^^^^^-'."- '"^f' \ -..~.*-- j BURNER DRAFT iilsSKf^ili ~ ' lifrft—Mf' l To learn tne effect Nii^iflmpSra^'' I'S^fe ■• 1 °^ draft variations up- I ; '^w^BwB^w ' WiiiPSl' ' '-I on nea^ n X time and N|^^S^*^ -C l^^iC A tnermal efficiency, the I : 'W&gt;o*3^^^J\^mL ■ j burners were removed |:I:SJ^^^^^ &lt; g^^^Lr^ J^^^pi.l from their stoves and [■^^^^^""'■"■Ti^^Mfflra^^to^^'".} enclosed m a special P^^^'.V'^^^^^^^B^^^^^! l burner cabinet so con - [aHHg^^-.jy^^^^^^^^^#r: j structed that all air passing through them Fig., 4.— Showing burner cabinet. could be measured. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 10 The cabinet (Fig. 4) consisted of a metal box 18 inches high by 18 inches long by 20 inches wide. In this cabinet was supported the burner, with the chimney passing through an opening m the top. A pipe 6 inches m diameter and 45 inches long on the outside extended through the rear of the box to within 7 inches of the front. Inside the box above the opening was a 9-inch baffle plate for the purpose of diverting the incoming air around the base of the burner, as is done under the burner by the pan when on the stove. Joints were sealed with furnace cement so that all air entered through the pipe and escaped through the chimney. Over the burner was placed a simple rectangular frame to support the test pan at the same distance above the rim of the chimney as when on the stove. The lineal velocity of the m coming air was measured. 1 with a Tycos Ower low-speed' # s' anemometer. The dial read - -1 ings were taken simulta - * neously with the temperature 1 readings and corrected to % s' true velocities by means of •* I /f the calibration curve supplied o * B with the instrument (Fig. 5) . True Wind Speed In the that follow, Fig. s.— Showing calibration curve li nea l velocities have been for anemometer converted into volumes by multiplying by the cross-section of the pipe. As the draft was almost too low to be measurable m many cases, it was not possible to use a larger entrance pipe such as is necessary for a high degree of accuracy m anemometer, measurements. Also, many of the indicated velocities fell on the curved portions of the graph of true wind speed. Conse - quently the data on volume of air that are given m subsequent tables are to be taken as indicative of draft differences rather than as precise measurements. In making the tests, openings to the room were kept closed to avoid erratic results and a record was kept of the temperature. Since the range of room temperature throughout the period of tests was not more than 4° C, temperature effects on anemometer and burner per - formance have been ignored. EFFECT OF EXTERIOR REGULATION OF DRAFT Three burners, representing two types, were used m the draft studies. Two similar long-chimney burners, Nos. 1 and 2, had been found to differ considerably m performance. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Performance of Kerosene Cook Stoves 11 Burner No. 3 was used to represent the short-chimney wick type. No. 4, a lighting-ring type, was not used because the draft was insufficient to register on the anemometer. The several burners, without alteration, were successively in - stalled m the burner cabinet and tested with varying altera - tion m draft. The drafts studied were as follows: 1. Normal draft. Tube completely open. Cross section of opening 0.1936 sq. ft. 2. Restricted draft. Tube closed at the outer end to give an opening of 0.0708 sq. ft. 3. Slightly forced draft. Tube as m 1. Electric fan at re - mote distance (several feet) from end. 4. Slightly forced with opening decreased. Fan as m 3 with opening as m 2. 5. Excessive draft. Tube as m 1. Electric fan close to end (a few inches). Table 1. — Effects of variation m draft on performance Draft Volume Heating " Oil •• Oil used Thermal condition of air time used per minute efficiency Cu. ft. Mm. I c. o. c. c. P. ct. per mm. I No. I—Long1 — Long chimney I Normal 7.6 8.47 40.2 4.7 33.2 Restricted 2.7 8.50 42.8 | 5.0 32.0 Slightly forced 8.4 8.29 47.2 5.6 28.3 Slightly forced with opening decreased 2.8 8.28 46.0 5.5 29.0 Excessive draft 10.5 12.1 65.0 5.37 20.5 No. 2 — Long chimney Normal 8.3 11.66 51.8 4.3 25.8 Restricted 2.9 11.67 54.6 4.7 23.3 Slightly forced 8.8 11.80 60.0 5.0 22.2 Slightly forced with opening decreased 2.09 11.84 61.0 5.1 21.8 Excessive draft 10.7 15.2 66.2 4.35 20.1 No. 3 — Short chimney with wick i j i j Normal * 9.71 30.25 ! 3.2 44.2 Slightly forced 1 11.2 10.43 j 38.0 | 3.6 \ 35.1 •The anemometer turned a few revolutions and then stopped with normal draft on the short chimney burners. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 12 The data presented in Table 1 show the effect of variations in draft on the burners studied. Ten tests were made on the same burner. In general, heating time and thermal efficiency were not affected by restricted draft. Slightly forced draft decreased the thermal efficiency on both of the long-chimney burners, with little change in heating time. Heating time was increased and thermal efficiency decreased on the short-chim - ney burner. Apparently the increased draft blew the flame away from the utensil, thus decreasing the available heat. Excessive draft increased the heating time and decreased the thermal efficiency considerably. With no variations in draft either by restriction or forcing, the heating time was less and the thermal efficiency greater for burner No. 1 than for burner No. 2, the former requiring only about 73 per cent of the time of burner No. 2 and con - suming only 77 per cent as much kerosene. It will be recalled that the chimney on No. 2 was higher and smaller in diameter than on No. 1 and the flame spreaders differed in number of perforations for air. Both burners were provided with suf - ficient air for combustion and a surplus, and the velocity was comparable. Apparently the difference in performance of the two burners was due to details of construction affecting the mixture of air and vapor. EFFECT OF ALTERATION OF AIR OPENINGS To determine the constructional features responsible for the differences in performance of burners No. 1 and No. 2, the flame spreaders and openings into the bottom of the chimneys were altered and the results recorded. One after another the several types of openings around, under, and in various parts of the burners were successively obstructed with furnace cement, after which the obstructions were removed. After each alteration, the appearance of the flame was noted and the heating time, oil consumption, and air velocity were obtained. The results are shown in Table 2. It will be observed that no improvement resulted from alterations in burner No. 1. Almost invariably such altera - tions as were made had the reverse effect. Closing the open - ings on the side of the flame spreader had little effect on heat - ing time or thermal efficiency, but the appearance of the flame was altered. The most striking effect was produced by en - larging these openingk. The closing of openings in the side of the flame spreader on burner No. 2 resulted in a slight decrease in oil consumption with an increase in heating time. However, the appearance of the flame was changed. It was not possible to decrease the </seg>
            <seg id="p013">Performance op Kerosene Cook Stoves 13 Table 2. — Effect on burner performance of alteration of air openings m long chimney burners Modification Volume Heating Oil Oil used Thermal of burner of air time used per minute efficiency I C»«./t. I Mm. I c.c. I c. c. I P.et. I per mm. I I I | No. 1 I Normal ' 7.6 8.47 40.2 4.7 33.2 Outside of wick tube Openings closed around outside 7.6 10.71 48.0 4.48 27.4 Part of closures removed 8,1 8.87 47.4 5.34 27.8 Under flame spreader Openings closed 7.4 14.4 49.8 3.48 26.8 Part of closures removed ! 7.6 11.08 47.2 4.40 28.3 Top of flame spreader Openings closed ! 7.5 11.29 49.0 4.34 27.2 Part of closures removed 7.7 11.34 50.6 4.46 26.4 Inside of flame spreader Openings closed 5.8 10.52 41.2 4.83 32.4 Openings enlarged 8.1 10.41 57.0 5.47 23.1 Openings much enlarged 8.6 29.66 77.0 2.59 17.1 No. 2 Normal 8.3 11.66 51.8 4.3 25.8 Openings m and under flame spreader closed... 7.6 14.9 56.0 3.75 23.4 Openings under flame spreader closed 3.02 13.28 57.8 4.30 23.1 Openings on side of flame spreader closed 8.3 12.7 49.8 3.92 26.8 Openings at bottom of Draft insufficient to register chimney closed on anemometer. Flange filed down | 8.7 | 14.59 | 56.0 | 3.83 | 23.8 size of these openings so that effects could be noted. It is apparent that the smaller openings m No. 1 distributed the air rising inside the wick tube and provided for an adequate mixture of air and vapor on top of the wick. The short dis - tance between the top of the flame spreader and the flange on No. 1 tended to cause thin streams of air to be directed across the wick. Streams rising outside the wick tube were directed by the collar to meet those from the inside at the top of the wick. The angle of the collar on No. 1 differed from that of No. 2. Aside from differences m chimney construction, such </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 14 details as are mentioned are important in the superior per - formance of burner No. 1. EFFECT OF CHIMNEY CHANGES To determine the effect of changes in chimney height on draft, both long chimneys were reduced one inch. The re - sulting draft was insufficient to be registered by the anemom - eter for either burner when operated in the cabinet. Appar - ently the chimney height is related to air velocity and to the construction of other burner parts. With the reduction in height the appearance of the flame was altered, and odor was produced by each burner. To determine the effect of chimney changes, three chimneys were used successively on burner No. 1. These were made by the same manufacturer for different models of stoves, but all fit the same wick tube. The chimneys varied as follows : Chimney A — 9!4" high at central axis, 7%" outer altitude, 5%" in diameter; single wall; belonged to burner No. 1. Chimney B — 9J4" high at central axis, 8%" outer altitude, 5" diameter; double walled about half way upward from middle of wall. Chimney C — 10%" high at central axis, 9%," outer altitude, 5" in diameter; single wall. TABLE 3. — Comparison of effect of chimney changes on long - chimney burner No. 1 when operated in the burner cabinet Volume Heating Oil Oil used Thermal Chimney of air time used per min. efficiency Cu. ft. per min. Mm. cc. "cZc. | Percent Chimney A 7.6 8.47 40.2 4.7 33.2 Chimney B 8.2 8.23 42.0 5.1 31.8 Chimney C 8.3 8.53 49.4 b\6 27.0 It will be observed that the lowest air velocity was obtained with chimney A, which was the shortest. The highest air velocity was obtained with chimney C, which was the longest of the three. With the latter chimney, considerably the greatest oil consumption and the lowest thermal efficiency were obtained. ' The thermal efficiency was greatest with chimney A, but only slightly greater than that of chimney B. The heating time did not vary appreciably with the use of either chimney but was slightly less with chimney B, which had a double wall. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Performance of Kerosene Cook Stoves 15 EFFECT OF INTERCHANGE OF CHIMNEYS To determine the effect of interchange of chimneys on the long-chimney burners Nos. 1, 5, and 6, each burner was operated successively with its own chimney and the chimneys belonging to the remaining burners. Burner No. 3 was used for the short-chimney type. The manufacturer of burner No. 3 provides a "giant" chimney to be used on the same burner as the standard. It is constructed similarly to the standard chimney, except that it is 1J4 inches greater in diameter at its largest diameter and the lower part of the chimney is beveled. Data in Table 4 show that in general each long-chimney burner performed best when used with the chimney provided by the manufacturer, and that burner No. 1, with chimney A, seemed to be superior to the other burner-chimney combina - tions. Burner No. 1, used with chimney B, which was double Table 4. — Effect on heating time and thermal efficiency of interchange of the chimneys on burners Heating Oil Oil used Thermal time used per minute efficiency Min. c. c. I c. c. I P. ct. Long chimney burner No. 1 Chimney A 9-05 44.2 4.8 32.1 Chlmnev B 9.14 47.0 5.1 28.4 Chimney C 9.62 52.0 5.4 25.7 Chimney A reduced one inch in height 1 8.88 32.0 3.6 41.7 Long chimney burner No. 5 ■ " i Chimney B 9.58 44.5 4.6 30.0 Chimney A 9.71 46.0 4.7 29.0 Chimney C - 10-26 48.0 4.6 | 27.8 Long chimney burner No. 6 — ' i i i Chimney C I 10.52 \ 49.0 4.6 26.6 Chimney B ! 11-45 43.4 3.8 30.8 Chimney A j H-67 [ 47.6 | 4.1 28.1 Short chimney burner No. 3 Standard chimney 13.3 38.8 2.9 34.4 Giant chimney 11-53 40.0 3.4 33.4 "One inch in -height removed from the cylindrical part of the chimney. Character of flame changed with soot and odor. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 16 walled, gave better results both m heating time and thermal efficiency than with chimney C, which was higher and less m diameter. Burner No. 6, used with chimney C, gave a slightly lower thermal efficiency than when used with the other chim - neys. These results suggest the importance of the character of chimney construction m relation to heat loss. Chimney A, which is lowest m height and greatest m diameter, apparently lost the least heat. The greater diameter permits a cool cur - rent of air to pass upward around the highly heated com - bustion center of the chimney, seemingly preventing loss by radiation. The double wall of chimney B appeared also to prevent loss of heat, giving very similar results m thermal efficiency to those for chimney A. Chimney C, which was high - est and least m diameter, apparently lost the most heat. It will be observed that with burner No. 1, with its chimney A reduced one inch m height, the time was reduced and thermal efficiency increased. However, the character of the flame was changed, and soot and odor were formed. The results from change of chimneys on short-chimney burner No. 3 show that the use of the giant chimney decreased the heating time, and lowered the thermal efficiency. It is possible that an increase m draft resulted from the larger chimney, but previous tests showed that when operated m the burner cabinet the velocity of the air entering the burner was not sufficient to register on the anemometer for more than a few revolutions. In Table 5 is shown a comparison of the heating perform - ance of three burners when operated m the burner cabinet and when operated on the stove as sold. It will be noted that Table 5. — Comparison of heating performance of burners when operated m burner cabinet and on stove Heating Oil Oil used Thermal Burner time used perminute efficiency Mm. c. c. c. c. P. et. Operated m burner box No. I—Long1 — Long chimney 8.47 40.2 4.7 33.1 No. 3 — Short chimney with wick 9.71 30.25 3.2 44.2 No. 4 — Short chimney with lighting ring 10.6 39.0 2.9 34.2 Operated on stove — as sold No. I—Long1 — Long chimney 9.05 44.2 4.8 30.2 No. 3 — Short chimney with wick 13.3 38.8 2.9 34.4 No. 4 — Short chimney with lighting ring 12.6 39.6 3.1 33.7 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Performance op Kerosene Cook Stoves 17 results obtained in heating time and thermal efficiency were generally more satisfactory with the burners operated in the burner cabinet. Apparently the cabinet provided for higher burner temperatures and prevented loss of heat. That there was little difference in performance for burner No. 4 was probably due to the fact that this burner was not protected by the cabinet to the extent that Nos. 1 and 3 were. These results are significant in that they point to the importance of stove construction — that is, burner insulation. It is possible, however, that the additional cost of insulation might not be justified by the improvement in performance. STUDIES ON GRATE HEIGHT AND CONSTRUCTION OF STOVE IN RELATION TO BURNER PERFORMANCE Kerosene stoves show considerable variation in the con - struction of grates and framework. Aside from the im - portance of providing support for the burners and utensils, the probable effect upon the heating performance of the burners with various types of grates and framework appeared to be of sufficient importance for investigation. Grates vary in height above the chimney, in shape, in number and arrange - ment of cross bars, and in elevation above stove-top level. Some stoves are entirely enclosed on three sides, and some are partially enclosed, while others provide little or no protection at the back or sides. With frequent, opening of doors and windows in a kitchen, it seemed likely that exposure to drafts might be an important factor in satisfactory operation of a stove. EFFECT OF HEIGHT OF GRATE ABOVE CHIMNEY To determine the importance in stove construction of the height from the grate to the chimney top, an adjustable grate was constructed for use in this part of the study. It con - sisted of light-weight, parallel metal bars of sufficient length to reach across the stove top and thus provide the only support for the utensil. There were no cross bars such as are found on the regular stove grates. Aside from the ease of adjust - ment, a standardized grate eliminated variables due to dif - ferent types of grates. Burners No. 1, 3, and 4 were used. Results are shown in Table 6. _ Results show that for each burner, the heating time and oil consumption increased as the distance between the grate and the chimney top increased. With burners No. 1 and No, 4, the heating time and oil consumption were slightly less with the grate below. the normal height, but soot and odor were in evidence in each case. With No. 1 there was a tendency for the flame to "creep up" as the utensil was placed closer to the </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 18 TABLE 6. — Effect on heating time and thermal efficiency of height of grate above top of chimney Height of grate Heating Oil Oil used Thermal above top of chimney time UKed perminute efficiency Mm. c. c. c. c. P. el. Long chimney burner No. 1 2 &gt;"— normal .. 8/76 i^ j ~ z j 1" 8.30 37.2 4.4 35.9 2 8.70 38.0 4.3 35.1 3" _ 9. 88 44.5 45 300 3%" 13.00 53.4 4.1 24.5 Short chimney burner No. 3 (wick) 1%" — normal 12.00 33.5 2^7 | 39.9 2%^ 13.50 36.2 | 2.6 36.8 3%" 14.16 41 . 8 I 2.9 31.3 Short chimney burner No. 4 (lighting ring) 1%" — normal 12.7 32.8 I 2.5 40.7 I%^ H. 9 30.3 2.5 44.1 4% 13.2 46.0 j 3.4 29.1 Note: Measurements were made from bottom of pan to top of chimney. grate. The grate could not be adjusted below normal height on burner No. 3, because insufficient space remained to raise the chimney for lighting. The reader will note that results obtained with the experi - mental grate seem generally superior to those with the grates accompanying the stoves as shown m Table 4. With the latter, the heavier grates with numerous cross bars consume a por - tion of the heat from the burner. These results show the importance of correct adjustment of height of grate to chimney on kerosene burners. It is ap - parent that there is one optimum grate height for each burner. Similar results were found m tests on gas burners by the Bureau of Standards. 7 Findings by the Bureau show that as distance between the utensil and burner is decreased, the efficiency is increased but the minimum distance between utensil and burner is determined by the production of carbon monoxide. In the present study there was no means of testing the products of combustion. The only evidence of incomplete combustion was soot and odor. On any type of burner it is extremely important that the distance between utensil and burner be sufficient to prevent the formation of carbon monoxide. 'Technologic paper No. 222, Vol. 17, p. 77, Oct., 1922. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Performance of Kerosene Cook Stoves 19 EFFECT OF CONSTRUCTION OF GRATE To determine the effect of the type of grate on the heating time and thermal efficiency of a burner, grates from the var - ious stoves were used on burner No. 1. Each grate was ad - justed at the same height from the top of the chimney as was the grate belonging to the stove. It is of course obvious that differences m kind of metal, conductivity, weight, and shape would be variables affecting the results obtained. Table 7. — Effect of grate construction on heating time, and thermal efficiency on long-chimney burner No. 1 Grate Heating I Oil Oil used Thermal time I used per mm. efficiency Mm. I c.c. | c.c. | P. ct. Grate belonging to stove — I square grate with elevations 9.05 44.2 4.8 30.3 No elevations on grate 10.82 50.0 4.6 26.1 Round grate with elevations 10.01 49.0 4.8 27.2 Round grate — no elevations.. 14.3 61.0 4.2 21.4 Rectangular grate — heavier than grate belonging to I stove | 9.47 | 45.0 4^7 29.7 Table 7 shows that burner No. 1 performed best with the grate belonging to it. With no elevations on the grate, thereby retarding the circulation of air under the utensil, both heating lime and consumption of oil were increased. The use of the round grate increased both heating time and oil consumption, the greatest increase resulting with the grate with no eleva - tions. With the heavy rectangular grate, results were similar to those with the grate belonging to the burner. It may be that a square grate is preferable to a round one, since utensils are round and often of greater diameter than the grate. With the round grate, the free circulation of air might be prevented. It is apparent that the type of grate used over a burner is important m the performance of the burner, and should be considered m stove construction. STUDIES ON EXPOSURE OF STOVE IN RELATION TO BURNER PERFORMANCE To determine the effect of enclosure of burners on per - formance, the stoves were operated with alterations m frame - work, and the results were compared with those obtained with the stove as sold. The same tests were duplicated with an electric fan to create a draft over the burners. The fan was eight inches m diameter and placed m the same position rela - tive to the burner, for different stoves, and provided a draft such as is frequently produced by the opening of doors into a kitchen. </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 20 Table 8. — Effect of exposure of burners on heating time and thermal efficiency Condition of Heating . Oil Oil used Thermal framework time used perminute efficiency Mm. c. c. c. c. P. et. Long chimney burner So. 1 No outside draft As sold 9.05 44.2 4.8 30.2 Back exposed 9.18 ' 45.0 4.9 29.7 Sides and back enclosed 8.71 40.5 4.6 33.1 Exposed to draft from electric fan As sold 12.5 49.0 3.9 27.2 Back exposed 12.6 48.3 3.8 27.7 Sides and back enclosed 9.4' 46.0 4.8 29.0 Short chimney burner No. 3 (wick) No outside draft As sold , 13.3 33.0 2.4 40.5 Back exposed 13.2 31.6 2.3 42.3 Sides and back enclosed 13.6 30.0 2.2 44.5 Exposed to draft from electric fan As sold 18.5 39.2 2.1 34.1 Back exposed 24.8 53.4 2.1 24.5 Sides and back enclosed 14.6 33.5 2.2 39.9 Short chimney burner No. 4 (lighting ring) No outside draft As sold : 12.6 39.6 3.1 33.7 Back exposed 12.7 39.1 3.09 34.2 Sides and back enclosed 12.3 39.0 3.1 34.2 Exposed to draft from electric fan As sold 26.8 75.0 2.8 17.4 Back exposed 25.9 73.5 2.8 18.1 Sides and back enclosed 12.5 41.0 3.2 32.5 Note: No. 1 as sold was enclosed on ends with two large circular openings at back. No. 3 as sold had narrow strip UVi") across back — exposed cbove and below. No. 4 as sold had- 9%" strip across back — exposed above and below. Table 8 contains data showing the effect of exposure on the performance of burners. The results from burner No. 1 when operated with the framework of the stove as sold were similar to results with the back exposed, both with and without ex - posure to draft from the fan. Heating time was decreased and thermal efficiency increased with the burner protected at the sides and back. This was true both with and without ex - posure to draft from the fan, but m no case were results as high with the former condition as with the latter. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Performance of Kerosene Cook Stoves 21 Differences in framework had little effect on the perform - ance of the short-chimney burners when operated without ex - posure to draft from the fan. When exposed to the fan, these burners were affected considerably more than were the long chimneys. Differences in results with and without the fan were also greater with these burners than with the long chim - neys. The position of the fan relative to the burners was slightly in favor of the short chimneys, since the lowest part of the short chimney was considerably higher than that of the long. The effects on heating time and thermal efficiency of protection from draft from the fan by enclosing the burner on the sides and back were greater for the short chimneys than for the long. DISCUSSION OF RESULTS From a practical standpoint, the ultimate advantage of any stove to the consumer lies in what might be termed "practical efficiency". The popular conception of efficiency of a stove appears to be confused with rapidity of heating. It is quite possible for an efficient burner to be slow. The rate of heat - ing depends upon the rate of combustion, provided the burner is constructed so that the maximum value of the heat is utilized. To most people rapidity of heating is more essential than economy if the cost of operation is not at the same time excessive, and it is justifiable to sacrifice efficiency for the sake of economy of time. The higher chimney on the long - chimney type of burner, together with other features of con - struction, produces a draft sufficient to burn the oil at a high rate, thereby producing rapidity of heating. The draft lifts the oil vapor from the wick, so that combustion of the vapor and unburned carbon is completed before reaching the utensil. The protection of the flame by the long chimney prevents ex - cessive loss of heat. The constriction at the top of the chim - ney seems to make for a stronger impingement of the heat column against the bottom of the utensil above. Because the rate of combustion is higher in the long-chimney type, a well - designed burner of this type, or one which does not waste the heat produced, is more powerful than a short-chimney burner. The combustion tubes in the short chimney control the air circulation and convert the yellow flame into a blue flame which rises above the top of the chimney, where it comes in direct contact with the utensil. Excessive draft causes the flame to flare around the utensil and results in considerable loss of heat. When outside drafts occur, or the flame comes in contact with a cold utensil, there is incomplete combustion with production of less heat and the formation of soot and odor. The flame in the long chimney is protected, so that </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Nebr. Exp. Sta. Research Bulletin 64 22 combustion is not interfered with, and if properly adjusted the burner is quite free from soot and odor. There is no economy of time m having the flame directly beneath the utensil. Even the slightly higher thermal efficiency with the short chimney does not compensate for other factors m favor of a well-designed long-chimney burner. It may be possible to construct a long chimney so that thermal efficiency may be considerably increased by preventing heat loss. Relatively expensive construction, however, might not be justified by any resulting economy of operation. [2M] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>