<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00075.00012">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno/>
            <availability>
               <p/>
            </availability>
            <date>2010</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Lambs</title>
               <date value="1931-04">1931-04</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02-15</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment/Validation</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11-04</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>ByteManagers, Inc. </name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 256 April, 1931 Corn Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Lambs MARVEL L. BAKER Bulletin 30 of the North Platte Experiment Substation W.P. SNYDER Superintendent ■ ■ " ■ ■ . ■ ' ■ .""■' EXPBHIIMENTAL LOTS AT THE NORTH PLATTE SUBSTATION THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN W. W. BURR, Direjctob </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Corn, Wheat, and Rye for Fattening Lambs MARVEL L. BAKER During the fall of 1930, the interest of the livestock feeder in the value of wheat as a feed for fattening cattle and lambs seemed to justify some work in comparing -wheat with corn. At the same time, rye was a drug on the market. Elevator prices in the vicinity of No.rth Platte averaged about thirty cents per bushel. The territory adjacent to North Platte is one of the important rye-producing sections of Nebraska, no doubt because of the belief that rye is well suited to the more sandy soils of this region. Practically no experimental data as to its feeding value for cattle and sheep have been available. The desirability of securing such data seemed to justify the inclusion of rye in the experiment. The two following tests were conducted during the fall and winter of 1930-31. The one reported first ran from October 15 to February 7, a period of 115 days, and the other one ran from August 15 to Novem - ber 7, a period of 84 days. COMPARISON OF CORN, WHEAT, AND RYE, 1 15-DAY PERIOD LAMBS USED The lambs used in this test were white-faced Wyoming lambs purchased on the Denver market. They were a uni - form, thrifty bunch of lambs and graded good to choice. They cost $6.85 per hundred pounds at Denver, including freight paid to Omaha. Table I. — Comparison of com, wheat and rye for fattening lambs, October 15, 1930, to February 7, 1931, — 115 days — 50 lambs per lot . Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot :S Lot 4 Lot 5 Shelled Shelled Shelled ! Whole Whole . corn ,:orn corn wheat : rye Whole \ ' Whole Alfalfa Alfalfa i Alfalfa wheat rye hay hay I hay Alfalfa Alfalfa hay hay Average initial weight I 62.1 61 .8 61 .7 . SI .6 61 .8 Average final weight ' 91 .1 88.1 89J) 89.0 • 89.2 Average gain : ' .29.0 26.6 27.:l 28.3 . 27.4 Average daily gain : .252 • .2:11 ; .2.17 .216 I .2,18 Average daily feed: J \ Shelled corn ' 1 .06 I ! .53 .525 Whole wheat ! 1 ■•"&gt; | : -53 . Whole rye ... \ [ 105 .525 Alfalfahay 1-19 I l-&gt;9 1.10 i. 1.39 ; 139 Feed required per cwt. of gain: Shelled corn 419 &#132;...! 215 . 220 Wholewheat ." I 457 215 Whole rye ■ ; ••■»•' 22(1 ToTAI. CONCBNTRATFS 119 457 445 4:!U 410 Alfalfa hay 552 61)2 SSW 566 585 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Corn, Wheat and Rye for Fattening Lambs ■FEEDS USED The corn used varied a greatdeal, both in color and in mois - ture content. During the first eight weeks mixed and yellow com of the 1929 crop was used. It varied in moisture from 15.5 to 16 per cent. During the remainder of the test, 1930 corn was used. This was white and mixed corn, the mixed corn being practically all yellow. It varied in moisture from 20 to 25 per cent. The average moisture content of all corn used was 18.9 per cent. The wheat was hard red winter wheat of the 1930 crop, varying in moisture from 14.1 to 15.5. per cent. It averaged 14.5 per cent moisture. The rye was Rosen rye of the 1930 crop. Its moisture content varied from 13 to 15 per cent, with an average of 13.8 per cent. The hay was good-quality, second-cutting alfalfa. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE Five lots of fifty lambs each were selected from the 262 head purchased at Denver. The initial and final weights were averages of three individual weights taken on consecutive days. Individual weights were also taken at the end of periods of 28, 56, 80, and 100 days. All lots received alfalfa hay. They were fed the following grain rations: Lot I — Shelled corn. . Lot II — Whole wheat. Lot III— Whole rye. Lot IV — Equal parts by weight of shelled corn and whole wheat. Lot V — Equal parts by weight of shelled corn and whole rye. The lambs were fed regularly twice each day. The hay was fed after the grain had been eaten. MARKET AND SLAUGHTER DATA The lambs were delivered to the shipping yards at North Platte the day after the last weight was taken. They were loaded the next morning about 10 o'clock and were unloaded at Omaha at about 7:00 A. M. the following day. During the day in the yards at North Platte the lambs were fed nothing but prairie hay. They were sold on the Omaha market February 11, 1931, at $8.25 per hundred pounds straight Certain slaughter data, were obtained and are shown in the following table. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 256 Table 2.— Slaughter data Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Lot 5 o,, ... „,.. , ! Shelled Shelled SheUed Whole Whole corn corn Au'u llffi !7 e Whole Whole Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa ' wheat rye hay hay hay ' Alfalfa AlfaUa ' ' ■ ' . | hay hay Average shrink per head, lbs 1.14 ' 2.80 1.83 1.62 1^27 Dressing percentage, based on . market weights 4 6.22 46.58 45.09 46.22 45.86 Dressing percentage, based on home weights 45.64 , 4510 u ,. 43jg Carcass grades: Choice, per cent -.•&gt; ,. a,. Good, pe7 cent 2? ™ }5 6° 55 Medium or cuu. ,«r «;„■.:::: s ?4 ■•• 4 i . fj 3 ? FINANCIAL STATEMENT In the following financial statement, corn is figured at 47 cents, wheat at 56 cents and rye at 35 cents per "bushel. These are the average prices paid during the test for the respective grains delivered at the .Station. Alfalfa hav is figured at $11.00 per ton. ■ • TABLE 3. — Financial statement Lot 1 Lot 2 Lot 3 Lot 4 Lot 5 SheUed ; Who, Who.e W S^ AUa?fa ; llfX MfSa i "££ W^f hay hay hay Alfalfa ! Alfalfa ; | hay hay Average initial cost S4 BO «j ru ,, ■ ' .. __ Interest per head at 8 per cent..:' ' *fS |4 "i2 ■ **"?2 ' $4 "w l-^-fl Marketing expense per head I .si 'll '•lT • "if 'I, Average feed cost l 9U ,« "■• , -'• -11 Total average cost exclusive of 1W i 1 - 9S J- 78 AverlfpVtu^pltSea^ exclusive" • 6JB 7 - 03 ! V* «: 95 «"» AverageTofi?.:::::::::: 7 12 7 f« 7 ?i ; «•. ;.-t* Amount returned for each bushel' of ' ■ ' 3 ' ■ 47 grain: Shelled corn • - n Wholewheat ■ r« - : -- Wholerye -" 8 ' • ., Shelled corn and whole wheat .' i , ■■•»* Shelled corn aTid whole rye '.'.]',[ j " -;-i, *11.00^r P ton! &lt;! U * ed: C ° r " 4? Cent8 ' Wheat 5I! Mnt3 ' and W 35 ««» Per bushel; alfalfa hay . GENERAL OBSERVATIONS During th e&gt; course of the test, three lambs died in Lot 3, the lot receiving whole rye. Four lambs died in Lot 5, the </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Corn, Wheat and Rye for Fattening Lambs lot receiving corn and rye. One lamb from Lot 5 died after the close of the test and before the lambs were shipped. Whether these losses were due to the rye in the ration cannot be determined. In the opinion of the author, they were due to whatever ordinarily causes loss in the lamb feed lot and were not due to rye. Considering these losses, Lot 3 would still pay a profit of thirteen cents per head but Lot 5 would show a loss of thirteen cents per head. The 250 lambs put into the feed lot would show an average margin above cost of sixteen cents per head. The shrink in all lots was low. The dressing percentages, based on home weights, are approximately equal except in the case of the rye-fed lot. In this lot it was from 1 to 1*4 per cent lower than in the others. According to the carcass grades secured in this test, there appeared to be a slight advantage in favor of the lot that received corn alone. The two lots that received rye in their rations had fewer medium and cull carcasses than the wheat lots. They also had fewer choice .carcasses. From this, it appears that the rye lots were more evenly finished, although the wheat lots con - tained a greater percentage of well-finished lambs. The lambs ate both Wheat and rye readily, showing a slight preference for rye. Both grains were fully as palatable as corn. Considerable quantities of both rye and wheat passed through the lambs whole in this test. Wheat alone was probably the least satisfactory of the five rations. COMPARISON OF CORN AND RYE, 84-DAY PERIOD LAMBS USED In this test, fifty lambs from the 1930 crop produced at this Station were used. They were thrifty, vigorous lambs sired by purebred Rambouillet rams and out of high-grade Rambouillet ewes. FEED USED The corn used was mixed, mostly yellow, testing 15 per cent moisture. It was of the 1929 crop. Rosen rye of the 1930 crop was used. It tested 15 per cent moisture. At the be - ginning of the test, corn was selling for 80 cents and rye for 40 cents per bushel locally. The alfalfa used was very good quality second and third cutting hay produced on the Station farm. . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 256 Table 4. — Comparison of corn and rye for fattening lambs, August 15, 1930, to November 7, 1930—84 days— 25 lambs per lot Lot 1 Lot 2 Shelled corn i Shelled corn Whole rye Alfalfa hay Alfalfa hay Average initial weight . i 66.3 65.9 Average final weight 91.3 . ' 92.6 Average gain . 25:0 26.7 Average daily gain . . ■. . . . : .298 .318 Average daily feed: Shelled corn '.....: 1.06 .53 Whole rye ' . .53 Alfalfa hay. : 1.75 1.75 Feed required per cwt. gain: Shelled corn . .....! 355:0 166.0 Whole rye •■-■; ' 166.0 Total Concentrates ' 355.0 332.0 Alfalfa hay . . .". - 588.0 55 i^?^. EXPERIMENTAL PROCEDURE The lambs were divided into two lots of twenty-five each. Lot 1 was fed on shelled corn and alfalfa hay. Lot 2 was fed on a grain mixture of equal parts by weight of shelled corn and whole rye, and alfalfa hay. The initial and final weights were averages of three individual weights taken on consecutive days. Individual weights were also taken at twenty-eight day intervals. The lambs were fed regularly twice each day. The hay was fed after the grain had been eaten. GENERAL OBSERVATIONS The lambs were sold on the Omaha market November 12, 1930. Forty head sold at $7.75 and ten head at $7.00 per hun - dred pounds. • At the end of the test there was no apparent difference in the finish or quality of the two lots. The lots were not sold separately. . No slaughter data were obtained on these lambs. The lambs receiving rye ate it readily. In fact, they would pick it out in preference to the corn. Very little rye passed through the lambs whole. In this test a combination of corn and rye seemed slightly superior to corn alone. In the 115-day test, the difference in results was practically the same but was in favor of the corn - alone lot. It appeared that there was an advantage in favor </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Corn, Wheat and Rye for Fattening Lambs of rye when new rye and old corn were fed. This advantage seemed to swing the other way as new corn was substituted for old and as the moisture content of the rye decreased. The results show that even with poor prices for lambs, grains at the prices prevailing during the period covered by these tests can be marketed to advantage through lambs. For the average feeder, the initial cost of feeder lambs would have been less than that of the lambs used in the 115-day test. The farm price of the grains was considerably less than for the same grains delivered to the Station elevator. The results also indicate that, if advisable, wheat and rye may be used with advantage for feeding lambs. • The differences in gains in these tests were probably not significant but further work is essential in determining this point. ■■.■■:■ C5Mi </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>