<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00047.00014">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00047.00014</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Report of the Department of Public Welfare</title>
               <date value="1920">1920</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Report of the Department of Public Welfare NEBRASKA FOR THE BIENNIUM CLOSING November 30, 1920 H. H. ANTLES, Secretary </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">To His Excellency, Samuel R. McKelvie, Governor, State of Nebraska. Dear Sir: The Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare herewith trans - mits for your consideration a report of the biennium ending November 30, 1920. The object of this report is to give a fair statement of the work accomplished in the various bureaus of the department without burden - ing it with a maze of figures and technical language. Very truly yours, H. H. ANTLES, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 INDEX Bureau of Health 9 Bureau of Child Welfare 16 Bureau of Examining Boards 29 Chiropodist 31 Chiropractor 34 Dentist - 36 Embalmer 46 Maternity Homes 94 Nurse 59 Optometrist 76 Osteopath 78 Pharmacy 83 Physician and Surgeon 51 Veterinary 91 Bureau of Social Service 99 Institutions named 100 Private 100 State 101 Institutions in detail Private 103 State 106 County Institutions Poor farms 112 Jails H3 Paroles Penitentiary US Bureau Children Code Commission 117 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 5 While on Military Duty in Tours, France during the World War the writer was tendered the place as Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare. Showing this cablegram to the Commanding Officers of that arrondissement, orders were immediately issued for return to the United States and for discharge from Military Service. Transportation orders were issued for August 6, 1919, arrived in New York August 12th, was discharged from service August 14 and took up the duties as Secretary of the Department the morning of August 19th. After carefully studying matters pertaining to organization it was decided to form five Bureaus as follows: Bureau of Health Bureau of Child Welfare Bureau of Social Service Bureau of Children's Code Commission Bureau of Examining Boards Dr. I. H. Dillon of Auburn was appointed Chief of the Bureau of Health, Mrs. Emily P. Hornberger of Omaha (formerly of Lincoln) was appointed Chief of the Bureau of Child Welfare, and the Secretary of the Department is ex-officio Chief of the remaining Bureaus. The cordial feeling between the Bureau officials has been very pleas - ing to the Secretary. The untiring and unselfish co-operation by all employees of the Department has been so helpful that the results ac - complished have been far beyond our anticipations. In making up this report, the Chief of each Bureau has been re - quested to submit to the Secretary a summary of their activities. These summaries are herewith attached and make a part of this biennial report for the Department. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 BUREAU OF HEALTH E'he Bureau of Health was thoroughly reorganized into the following ons: Division of Epidemiology Division of Vital Statistics Division of Laboratories Division of Veneral Disease Division of Sanitary Engineering K While these divisions are distinctive, yet by their close relationship le Bureau they are made to function so that no person is idle at any - time, and quick assistance is rendered when and where most needed. Kthis way the maximum of work can be done with the minimum of &gt;te and overlapping is eliminated. The Department was very fortunate to be able to secure a man of the calibre of Dr. I. H. Dillon as Chief of this Bureau- His executive ability, his work as general practitioner, specialist and Army Surgeon gives him the poise and experience so necessary in this important work. The efficiency of the Division of Vital Statistics has been so in - creased that the Government has placed Nebraska within the Registration area and accredited us with showing 96% of all Deaths and 93% of all Births. The amount of work in the Division of Laboratories has been in - creased more than three fold and work so carefully done that the results obtained are seldom questioned. BUREAU OF CHILD WELFARE This Bureau was organized and placed into working condition Oc - tober 1, 1919. Mrs. Emily P. Hornberger was selected as Chief. Mrs. Hornberger, before she was appointed was a school teacher for many years. Her experience covered actual teaching in country districts, grades and high schools. She had about 12 years experience in Lan - caster County caring for delinquent, dependent, sub-normal and normal children who lacked a proper chance in life. She is exceedingly practical in her work — broad in her views, knows her work thoroughly and by ex - perience equally capable of caring for the normal as well as the sub - normal and defective children. The co-operation of this Bureau with Juvenile Courts of the State has brought very gratifying results. Thirty courts were assisted and the number of children looked after by each court varied from 1 to 171. A survey of the conditions of the childhood of the state was made </seg>
            <seg id="p007">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 7 in the fall of 1919 and the results compiled and tabulated and attached to this report. A fairly thorough investigation was made of Child Labor in the beet fields. Many children under eight years of age are worked for long hours in these fields, highly nourished with five meals a day, con - taining much meat and coffee, but poorly housed. Many beet field families live in mere shacks and outbuildings, leaky, screenless and altogether deplorable. The cause of overwork and abuse of children in the beet fields is the amount of money a family is able to earn in five months. Many expectant mothers work in these hot fields at heavy work almost up to the time of their delivery, and many more take babies only a few days old to the fields in their "little dog houses", and others leave the babies in care of children four or five years old, often locked in the shacks. It has been the intention of this Bureau not only to look after the delinquent, sub-normal and defective child but to equalize the chances for the normal child, and those retarded from any cause. The co-operation of the good people of the state has been very grati - fying. In fact it is the intent of the Bureau to get the people of every county to work out their own problems and we co-operate and assist wherever necessary. BUREAU OF EXAMINING BOARDS Under this Bureau is grouped ten of Nebraska's professions: Medical, Osteopathic, Chiropractic, Dental, Nursing, Pharmacy, Optometry, Em - balming, Veterinary Medicine and Surgery, Chiropody. The arrangement for these Boards centralizes work and responsibility to such an extent that records are in better condition than ever, that violations are much better looked after and renewals are used for the better preservation of records and files. The Department anticipates a permanent and correct history of these boards. The co-operation from all Examining Boards has been perfect. The membership of these Boards is, of course, chosen from among the licentiates in this state. It has been our policy to request the profes - sions in their State Association meetings to select a number of eligibles and recommend that the Board vacancies be filled from among these. All matters of professional qualification of applicants is left entirely to the Board members. In all matters of educational and moral re - quirements the closest co-operation between Board members and the De - partment Secretary are necessary. When there is any doubt about these requirements full investigations are made in all cases and the matter fully discussed at Board meetings before a decision is made- BUREAU OF CHILDREN'S CODE COMMISSION Under the law the Children's Code Commission is an independent </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 REPORT OF THE branch of the Child Welfare Bureau. In making up the personnel of this Commission it was thought best to make the Director of the Bureau one of the members of the Commission. The members of this Commission serve without pay and were "se - lected from the entire state; six from Omaha, six from Lincoln, one from North Platte, one from York and one from McCook. They have worked faithfully and well and will present to the Legis - lature fifty-five proposals tending toward a forward movement among the children of our State- Much credit is due the faithful and unselfish work of the members of this Commission. For days, weeks and months they have willingly given their labors to this great work. BUREAU OF SOCIAL SERVICE In this Bureau was placed the work of the Charities, Corrections and Paroles, with the Secretary of the Department as Chief of the Bureau and Mr. E. M. Johnson, former Secretary of the State Prison Board, was retained as State Parols Officer. Notwithstanding rumors, gossip and yellow journalism to the con - trary fewer paroles have been granted this biennium than any since the first biennium of the parole system. Fewer violations have occurred and less than 6% of violations have been for new crimes committed. This showing cannot be equalled in any state where an accurate set of records are kept Many people of the state think that men are paroled from the peni - tentiary as soon as they have served their minimum term. We have now in the institution, according to our books, 112 men whose minimum term has expired and yet they are still "doing time". One hundred of these are serving their first term, seven are serving their second term and five are serving more than their second term. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 9 BUREAU OF HEALTH December 31, 1920. Hon. H. H. Antles, Secretary, Department of Public Welfare, Lincoln, Nebraska. Dear Sir: There is transmitted herewith the biennial report of the public health activities of the State of Nebraska for the biennium beginning December 1st, 1918 and ending November 30th, 1920. Respectfully submitted, I. H. DILLON, M. D., Chief, Bureau of Health. (I. H. D.-B. M.) Biennial Report of Public Health Activities of the State of Nebraska For the Biennium Beginning December 1, 1918 and Closing November 30, 1920. During the period of time from December 1, 1918 to August 1, 1919 the public health activities of this state were carried on by the State Department of Health. On August 2, 1919 the Department of Health was replaced by the Bureau of Health which is one of the Bureaus of the Department of Public Welfare. The organization of the State Depart - ment of Health was divided into the following Divisions: Administrative Office, Division of Contagious and Communicable Diseases, Division of Vital Statistics, Division of Sanitary Engineering and Division of Labor - atories. These various Divisions were continued when the work was taken over as the Bureau of Health and to them was added the Division of Venereal Diseases as provided for in Chapter 252 of the Session Laws of 1919. Rules and Regulations covering all phases of public health activities were prepared by the State Department of Health and formally adopted on July 9, 1919. These Rules and Regulations were later approved by the Department of Public Welfare placing them in full force and effect up to the close of the biennium. The Administrative office of the State Department of Health was in charge of a Commissioner of Health, who when the work was changed to the Bureau of Health became the Chief of the Bureau and who is assisted by one technical stenographer. This office has general super - vision over all of the activities of the Bureau. All requisitions and vouchers in any way affecting the Bureau pass through this office. All incoming mail is delivered to this office where it is sorted and divided to the various Divisions. All postage, stationery and office supplies for </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 the various Divisions are furnished from this office. There are no records available of the volume of mail handled through this office for the first year of the biennium but during the last year of the biennium the volume of mail handled was approximately as follows: Culture tubes 13,896 This office has handled all of the work in connection with the school inspection law as provided for in Chapter 241 of the Session Laws of 1919. The material that has been furnished for public instruction along health lines has been prepared in this office. DIVISION OF CONTAGIOUS AND COMMUNICABLE DISEASES In Charge of the Director of the Division who is Commissioned as Collaborating Epidemiologist of the United States Public Health Service. During this biennium there has been organized in each county of the state and in each town or village the local Board of Health to whom the physicians report all cases of contagious disease for quarantine and control. These cases are reported each week from the County Board of Health to this Division and from this Division on Monday of each week a report is furnished to the United States Public Health Service of all cases of contagious diseases reported in the state for the preceding week. There are twenty-nine states making these weekly reports of which Nebraska is one. This arrangement with the United States Public Health Service was perfected during this biennium. During the year ending November 30, 1919 there were reported a total of 29,262 cases of contagious disease. During the year ending November 30, 1920 there were reported 33,845 cases of contagious disease. The increase in number of cases of contagious disease reported Incoming Mail ■etters 24,396 lards 16,680 'ackages 6,770 Circulars 540 Outgoing Mail Letters 44,736 Cards 5,400 Packages 4,824 Containers Received Containers for blood specimens 5,293 Containers for sputum specimens 600 Glass slides 1,960 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 11 is accounted for by the fact that there has been more complete reporting and quarantine of the contagious diseases during the year ending Novem - ber 30, 1920 than during the preceding year, rather than an actual increase in the number of cases of the various diseases. DIVISION OF VITAL STATISTICS In Charge of the Registrar of Vital Statistics This Division has charge of the securing of all data relating to births, deaths, marriages and divorces occurring in the entire state. As these statistics are reported into the Division they are edited, numbered, bound into volumes of five hundred each, classified a n d indexed by a card index system making them accessible and available for future use and reference. This Division has records of births and deaths going back to 1904 when the first Vital Statistics law was put in operation in this state. However, during the first few ye a rs of the law's existence the reports were not complete. It was only during the year of 1920 that the Division was able to show that they were receiving and registering over 90% of all births and deaths occurring within the state. After a thorough examination of the work done by this Division, made by re - presentatives of the United States Census Bureau they found that there was being reported 96.4 '/c of all deaths and approximately 95% of all births occurring in the state and the State of Nebraska was formally admitted into the registration area for Vital Statistics as defined by the United States Census Bureau- That the importance of complete registration of all births and deaths to the people of the state is increasing each year is evidenced by the fact that during the year ending November 30, 1919 there were three-hundred certified copies of the records issued and during the year ending November 30, 1920 there were 366 certified copies issued. The total births reported in the state for the year ending November 30, 1919 were 26,649. The total births reported in the state for the year ending November 30, 1920 were 29,484. The total deaths oc - curring in the state for the year ending November 30, 1919 was 13,087. The total deaths for the year ending November 30, 1920 were 13,320. Following the admission of the state into the registration area it is required that a copy of each birth and death certificate recorded during the year 1920 be furnished by this Bureau to the Division of Vital Statistics of the United States Census Bureau. All marriage and divorce reports are filed by the County Judge and Clerk of the District Court respectively on February 1st of each year for the preceeding year's record — hence the following figures only are </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Marriage reports 1918 — 10,748 Marriage reports 1919 — 14,074 Divorce reports 1918 — 2,237 Divorce reports 1919 — 3,359 DIVISION OF LABORATORIES In charge of the Director of Laboratories In this Division is performed all of the laboratory examinations in connection with the prevention and control of all forms of contagious disease. This includes water analysis as to its purity for human con - sumption and the various bacteriological and serological examinations that are necessary to establish diagnosis and control contagious disease. No laboratory work is performed by this Division unless it has to do with these diseases. That the importance of this work is being recognized more each year by the public at large and the medical profession of the state is evidenced by the increase in the volume of work placed upon this Division. During the year ending November 30, 1919 a total of 3,173 examinations were made while during the year ending November 30, 1920 a total of 12,721 examinations were made. DIVISION OF SANITARY ENGINEERING In charge of a Sanitary Engineer. This Division is charged with the making of sanitary surveys, ex - amination and approval of all plans and specifications for water works and sewer systems prior to the time of their installation; to examine into and to certify as to the purity and wholesomeness of the public water supply of all cities, towns and villages of the state; to examine and certify as to the purity of the water supplied by all inter-state carr - iers doing business in the state. During the year ending November 30, 1919 but few activities were carried on by this Division. During the year ending November 30, 1920 this Division inspected the water supply in sixty cities, towns or villages of the state; the sewer systems in twenty-seven; examined and approved the plans and specifications for water installation in nine cities and for extension to water systems in one; for sewer installation in eighteen and extension of sewer systems in twenty^-four cities, towns or villages in the state. DIVISION OF VENEREAL DISEASES In charge of a Director of the Division, who is a commissioned officer of the United States Public Health Service. The activities for the control of venereal disease in this state were started in the fall of 1918 and financed entirely by the Federal Govern- </seg>
            <seg id="p013">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 13 Eit but working in co-operation with the State Health Department, lowing the enactment of Chapter 262 and 265 of the Session Laws 1919 the State D3partment of Health promulgated rules and regu - ons establishing a Division of Venereal Diseases providing for co - operation with the United States Public Health Service and requiring the reporting and control of these diseases. The rules and regula - tions which were adopted have been continued in force by the Bureau of Health. There were reported during the year ending November 30, 1919 a total of 4,616 cases while during the year ending November 30, 1920 a total of 5,774 cases were reported. This does not mean that these dis - eases are on the increase but is accounted for by the fact that the physicians of the state have a better understanding of the aims and objects of the law and the rules and regulations adopted in conformity with the same and have been cooperating with the Division by report - ing promptly their cases. Each case is reported by a number and not by name of the individual patient. Only in those cases where the in - dividual discontinues treatment before cured is the name furnished to the Division Headquarters when the social protective workers get in touch with the individual getting the case again under treatment until cured. Effort is made to locate sources of infection and eradicate them. The Division assists in maintaning ten clinics in various parts of the state where those individuals who are unable to pay may go and obtain treatment free. This Division has carried on an extensive educational campaign along the line of social hygiene and sex education. During the year ending November 30,1920 there were given a total of 195 lectures by representatives of the Division reaching a total of 19,500 people. The Division owns five moving picture films along educational lines and these have been shown to 63,210 people in the state. 326,899 pieces of literature on sex education and social hygiene have been distributed within the state during the past year. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p015">FIRST BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE STATE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU November 30, 1920 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 CHILD WELFARE BUREAU ESTABLISHED Location Sufficient quarters and equipment for the Child Welfare Bureau were delegated to be furnished by the Superintendent of Public In - struction but the Administrative Code Law was enacted after the pass - age of the law creating this Bureau and it was apparent to all interested that the Bureau could best function with the Department of Public Welfare and by mutual consent of all concerned it was so placed. The equipment and quarters were furnished by the Department of Public Welfare. We began work October First, Nineteen Hundred and Nineteen. Organization Closely following the law that created the State Child Welfare Bureau, questionaires were prepared and sent to every school district in the State except three counties whose County Superintendents neg - lected to mail to the Bureau the published list of the teachers of their counties. We mailed these questionaires first to the teachers of the country •district schools and asked for the names of the parents, and address, and birthday of every child born in Nebraska in 1919-20. We hoped by this means, not only to collect valuable information for the Bureau but to assist the Vital Statistics Division of the Health Bureau in plac - ing Nebraska within the area of accredited states with our Government on birth reports. By means of this birth blank the names of 2,274 girls and 2,443 boys were reported to the Child Welfare Bureau by school districts, — a total of 4,717 children from October 1919 to November 30, 1920. Many of these children had not been previously reported to the Division of Vital Statistics. Our theory was that by going into the schools of every district of the state in this way we would get the birt" of the unattended child and it was to cooperate with the Vital Statis - tics Division that the names were secured. Enclosed with the above birth blank was a questionaire asking for the conditions and equipment of school houses, school playgrounds and also making inquiry as to wells, toilets, etc. This report as returned by the teachers of the various school districts of the counties of the state, received up to April 20, 1920 follows: Condition Play- School- No. Dis'ts Wells grounds Toilets house County reported Gd-Poor-No. App-None Good-bad-1-no Good Bad Adams 29 8 3 18 15 14 22 7 27 2 Antelope 43 17 3 23 12 31 26 17 26 17 Arthur 7 716321152 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 17 Condition No. Dls'ts Wells grounds Toilets house" County County reported Gd-Poor-No. App-None Good-bad-1.no Good Bad Banner 2 2 2 2 2 2 Blaine 43 1 43 122 Boone 39 20 1 18 19 20 33 6 2&lt;j 13 Box Butte 11 4 729911 11 Boyd 22 8 5 9 5 17 12 9 1 19 3 Brown 18 10 8 3 15 14 4 15 3 Buffalo 33 24 9 6 27 28 5 25 8 Burt 25 18 3 4 10 15 22 3 24 1 Butler ___ 29 22 4 3 9 20 21 7 23 6 €ass ___ 70 39 9 22 34 36 59 11 59 11 Cedar 83 39 11 33 13 70 68 15 75 S Chase 13 5 1 7 3 10 10 3 11 2 Cherry 42 15 4 23 7 35 34 7 1 38 4 Cheyenne 27 8 5 14 7 20 21 6 24 3 Colfax 18 15 3 5 14 15 3 15 3 Cuming 25 21 2 2 6 19 23 2 21 4 Clay 73 48 5 20 42 31 59 14 61 12 Dakota 95224581 9 Dawes 16 916 16 115 97 Dawson 39 24 2 13 8 31 30 9 28 11 Dixon 21 9 2 10 3 18 18 3 15 6 Dodge 50 45 3 2 15 35 46 4 46 4 Douglas 20 16 2 2 8 12 15 5 18 2 Dundy 10 5233764 10 Fillmore 67 25 2 40 28 39 49 18 56 11 Franklin 23 7 2 14 4 19 17 6 20 3 Frontier 20 6 1 13 6 14 14 6 17 3 Furnas 34 13 4 17 6 28 25 8 1 26 8 Gage , 120 71 10 39 32 88 106 14 111 9 Deuel 10 2 83782 91 Garden _ 15 12 3 4 11 10 3 2 12 3 Garfield 15 4 1 10 15 9 3 2 2 12 3 Gosper 23 10 5 8 3 20 19 4 19 4 Grant 53 214221 32 Greeley 31 12 1 18 5 26 21 9 24 7 Hall 21 19 2 11 10 19 2 16 5 Hamilton 46 31 15 17 29 40 6 43 3 Harlan 45 21 7 17 24 21 29 16 36 9 Hayes 15 1 3 11 1 14 9 6 11 4 Hitchcock 18 7 11 3 15 14 4 15 3 Holt 87 50 7 30 6 81 69 10 8 73 14 Howard 3 3 3 2 1 2 1 Jefferson 38 17 6 15 11 27 33 5 29 9 Johnson 58 34 6 18 11 47 53 5 54 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 Condition Play- School No. Dis'ts Wells grounds Toilets house reported Gd-Poor-No. App-None Good-bad-1-no Good Bad County Kearney 30 15 4 11 20 10 29 1 25 5 Keith 12 8 1 3 4 8 12 10 2 Keya Paha 20 6 3 11 2 18 16 1 3 18 2 Kimball 11 5 6 11 10 1 10 1 Knox 46 18 5 23 5 41 43 3 42 4 Lancaster 72 39 5 28 36 36 55 17 62 10 Lincoln 24 11 1 12 7 17 16 6 2 22 2 Loup 22 10 3 9 1 21 16 5 1 17 5 Madison 15 11 3 1 3 12 12 3 14 1 McPherson 41 3 4211 22 Merrick 60 56 2 2 28 32 46 14 52 8 Morrill 22 16 6 2 20 14 7 1 18 4 Nance 22 12 2 8 4 18 18 4 18 4 Nemaha 40 29 2 9 12 28 34 6 37 3 Nuckols 74 42 3 29 52 22 62 12 68 6 Otoe 41 26 3 12 7 34 35 6 39 2 Pawnee 27 23 2 2 6 21 19 8 23 4 Perkins 7 1616511 61 Phelps 23 12 5 6 10 13 20 3 12 11 Pierce 45 23 3 19 12 33 36 9 34 11 Platte 15 10 5 7 8 15 14 1 Polk 35 28 2 5 15 20 27 7 27 8 Red Willow 9414 9711 9 Richardson 25 20 2 3 6 19 20 5 23 2 Rock 14 8 6 14 923 95 Saline 90 57 7 26 14 76 76 13 1 76 14 Sarpy 18 14 4 3 15 16 2 18 Saunders 33 28 5 13 20 25 8 28 5 Scotts Bluff 13 10 3 7 6 11 2 12 1 Seward 36 19 1 16 14 22 26 10 32 4 Sheridan 34 12 3 19 3 31 25 5 4 31 3 Sioux 20 7 13 1 19 10 4 6 14 6 Stanton 38 27 5 6 14 24 35 3 33 5 Thayer 30 14 1 15 11 19 26 4 23 7 Thomas 11 8 329911 92 Thurston 5 5 5 5 5 Valley 56 26 4 26 14 42 44 12 50 6 Wayne 37 16 4 17 13 24 29 8 36 1 Washington 24 19 2 3 6 18 19 5 21 3 Webster 25 13 12 16 9 22 3 20 5 Wheeler 23 10 2 11 3 20 15 3 5 19 4 York 25 13 3 9 11 14 23 2 20 5 Total 2743 1544 211 979 802 1941 2192 499 48 4 2328 415- </seg>
            <seg id="p019">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 19 Using the above figures as a basis, the following is the estimated •condition of the school districts in Nebraska. Estimated No. Estimated Estimated Estimated School- Districts Wells Playground Toilets houses In State Good Poor None App. None Good Bad One None Good Bad 7168 4053 549 2566 2095 5073 5932 1303 123 10 6118 1050 We have made an earnest effort the past year to get exact infor - mation relative to present conditions affecting the general well being of the childhood of Nebraska and trust that no community will permit such hard conditions to surround the life of a child that it is next to imposs - ible for that child to grow up good. The tabulations were made from the signed statements of the teachers of our state. The returned questionaires cover nearly 38 per cent of the school districts of the state: — These reported districts contain about 23 per cent of the entire school population. This explanation is necessary to show why the different percent - ages are used in the estimate of the school ground conditions and phys - ical conditions of the children. It is necessary that we have this exact knowledge of existing con - ditions that we may know intelligently how to attack the problems in a state wide way that affect the general well being of the childhood of Nebraska. We want especially to help in those districts where there is great - est need: for child welfare includes all conditions, physical, mental, moral, and civic, that affect the interests and development of childhood. The reports as returned show that the wells and toilets of very many of the school districts of the state need special attention. Upon personal observation we find many school grounds poorly located and drained. The Sanitary Engineering Division in the Bureau of Health offers any help that their engineers can give at any time and teachers are requested to write them relative to matters of sanitation and drainage. In these questionaires the teachers also answered the inquiry re - garding the special classes of children, the blind, deaf, neglected, men - tally afflicted, dependent, crippled, and speech defects. A tabulation of the teachers' reports made of these children and given by county school districts is as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 TABULATION OF REPORTS OF TEACHERS TO THE CHILD WELFARE BUREAU, UP TO APRIL 1, 1920. On Special Classes of Children Speech County No. Pupils Blind Deaf Neg. Men affl. Dep. Crip. Def. Adams 1036 2 3 7 3 8 9 Antelope 1269 2 1 6 10 2 10 Arthur 83 11 Banner 42 11 Boone 1026 3 3 17 27 2 9 10 Box Butte 418 1 2 Boyd 682 16 9 6 9 Brown 279 5p lp 3 1 1 2 11 Buffalo 3670 2p 17 9 1 15 6 Burt 1 866 3 7 6 3 11 Butler 1050 115 6 14 9 Cass 2143 2 16 9 3 7 10 Cedar 2798 2 3p 23 12 13 12 Chase 352 1 12 Cherry 1262 2 5 113 Cheyenne 457 lp 2 3 6 Clay 2766 3 19 14 9 30 Colfax 930 16 3 7 13 Cuming 1335 1 lp 7 3 1 Custer 638 lp 24 2 6 Dakota 459 3 7 5 Dawes 124 7 13 2 2 Dawson 692 lp 4 11 Deuel 124 1 3 6 Dixon 737 2 5 3 3 7 Dodge 1237 1 4 1 7 11 Douglas 560 1 1 7 4 16 Dundy 317 -43 2 Fillmore _J 1525 lp 4p 8 9 1 4 18 Franklin 592 5 4 3 2 6 Frontier 590 3 14 3 Furnas 756 2 7 2 19 Garfield 192 2p 2p 13 1 Garden 354 2p 2p 1 2 5 4 8 Gosper 588 lp 1 1 4 15 Grant 67 2 1 Greeley 1007 lp 4 3 3 10 9 6 Hall 3032 lp 6p 2 7 3 8 7 Hamilton 1191 3 6 9 1 11 8 Harlan 1011 2 11 6 Hayes 249 11 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 21 County No. Pupils Blind Deaf Neg. Men affl. Dep. Crip. Speech Def. Hitchcock 190 1 Holt ___ 2188 lp 2p 8 5 3 6 Howard 659 1 12 1 16 1 Jefferson 2767 1 51 12 6 9 7 Johnson 767 2p 4 5 4 6 Kearney 613 lp 3 9 5 Keith 466 3 1 Key a Paba 402 lp 4. 1 2 1 10 6 5 6 Kiir.ball 196 3 1 3 Knox 1197 2p 4 4 14 8 Lancaster 13782 3 2p 9 17 15 43 14 40 Lincoln 394 lp 14 5 2 1 Loup 283 1 113 McPherson 63 1 5 Madison 329 11 1 Merrick 1736 2 2 7 7 Morrill 331 1 1 2 3 Nance 353 lp 1 1 3 4 Nemaha 1625 lp-2 2 10 2 6 8 2 Nuckolls 2399 lp 3 8 3 12 Otoe 913 lp lp 4 6 2 2 Pawnee 768 2p 7 5 6 17 7 10 Perkins 228 2 2 Phelps 320 1 1 Pierce 1722 2p 24 16 2 6 Platte 574 2p lp 14 Polk 832 2 7 10 12 6 10 Red Willow 138 3 1 Richardson 769 1 4 8 8 5 4 12 Rock 300 3 2 2 1 3 Saline 3057 lp 22 1 8 Sarpy 988 lp 3 4 7 Saunders 1311 2 15 3 2 5 31 13 8 Scotts Bluff 2726 20 4 3 Seward 1082 lp 7 3 2 3 Sherman 456 1 1 Sheridan 864 14 3 3 1 7 13 Sioux 263 lp Stanton 1443 12 1 2 Thayer 593 1 7 3 3 Thomas 129 2 2 6 8 10 Thurston , 272 lp 1 2 Valley 391 1 5 16 Washington 840 lp 21 30 3 3 10 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 The school census for 1919 shows we have 391,275 children of school age in the state. Taking this as a basis only 23 per cent of the school children were reported by the teachers to this Bureau when these figures were tabulated, April 20, 1920. Using the above totals and percentages as a basis of estimation for the state the following table should show quite accurately the real condition of the school children of the state. No. Pupils Blind Deaf Neg. Ment. Affl. Dep. Crip. Speech Def. 391,275 261 513 2043 1878 535 1669 2610 After we had located enough of the work to give us a start in each reported school district of the state we found that we had an abundance of material to work with, and but one stenographer and the Director of the Bureau to do practical work. This has made the work slow because of lack of executive people in the Bureau. We have however, the reports in the office and this should form the foundation for a broader field of work. An increased office and field force is necessary to successfully carry on the Child Welfare work in the State. This estimate of office and field force is made in our budget for the next biennium. When teachers gave information showing conditions which needed attention, questionaires were mailed again to the teachers with a letter from the department asking for a short family history and story of the case reported. Correspondence was taken up at once with teachers, parents, nurses, county attorneys and juvenile courts with a view of getting help to these needy children. Many of these questionaires were returned to us with much good information which assisted us in getting help to the children. The results obtained by the returned questionaires prompted us to organize the child welfare work for the state, using the county as the unit. We planned to perfect our first organization in the county seat of each county in the state and later in each township of the county, to co- Ete with the State Bureau. We asked that the personnel of these ittees be the representative, practical people of the community and nber of counties were partially organized. This plan of organi- No. Pupils Blind Deaf Neg. Men affl. Dep. Crip. Speec Def. County fayne 885 Webster 1049 1 2 2 2 6 1 5 2 7 4 Pheeler 338 brk 1066 1 2p lp 3 4 5 4 1 6 2 3 4 Total 89754 60 118 461 432 123 384 600 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 23 zation was taken over by an outside agency working in the state, mak - ing cur work to the people more or less confusing and for the time being we decided not to organize other counties, but asked established state wide organizations to take over our program. We met with hearty response and now have in most of the state wide clubs and organiza - tions, aetive constructive child welfare committees cooperating with the State Bureau. We shall be glad to know of any part of the state not so repre - sented and will endeavor to help organize the work in any unorganized community of the state. The names of these committees are reported to the Child Welfare Bureau at Lincoln, that counsel and information may be speedily se - cured on child welfare matters in any part of the state. The coopera - tion of the various organizations in this respect has been very helpful. They consider matters of prevention as well as. cure of neighbor - hood problems and are interested in Juvenile Court work, widow's pen - nons, child health, recreation, school attendance, humane laws and any conditions that will tend to do constructive character work for children- These committees are assisting us in solving the problems of equalizr ing the opportunities for normal children and also the educational op - portunities of the deaf, blind, crippled or maimed, child, the neglected, mentally afflicted, the dependent child, and child with a speech defect who unassisted must go through life ridiculed. Visits have been made to many counties in the state by invitation of county officials, churches, clubs and individuals to investigate and advise upon different local children's cases. Work has been done with County Attorneys and Juvenile Courts in thirty different counties in the state the past year involving many child - ren and we believe much opportunity has been given handicapped child - ren through these courts by the administration of the Mother's Pen - sion law and the Juvenile Court law. There are few neighborhoods not having their own child problems. The proposals of the Children's Code Commission, if written into law, will enable us to care for them much better in the future. Our county organizations are reaching many of these sections now. Splendid co - operation of local organizations have done wonders for many homes and children. Sometimes the enforcement of children's laws in smaller communi - ties is not a success because of feat 1 of local criticism and local "pull" in difficult cases. It becomes necessary to transfer administrative E. law enforcing powers from the local community to the county, state nation (as the White Slave Cases). A United States Marshal is ;n more respected than a town constable and more free to act in- </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 dependently. We wish the Child Welfare Bureau of Nebraska to serve every community and now have the machinery working which we hope will accomplish this end if sufficient assistance can be had in the future. It was made the duty of the Child Welfare Bureau to receive the reports of persons, courts, or associations (other than parents) having care or custody of dependent, neglected or delinquent children. We have not been able to receive complete reports in this line of our work because of lack of time and help to administer the work. The following is the yearly condensed report of persons, courts or associations (other than parents) having custody of dependent, neglected or delinquent chil - dren for the years 1919-20 who voluntarily sent in reports. Total number of children placed. a. Boys — 107 b. Girls— 73 c. Total— 180 Number of children who remained in home where first placed. a. Boys — 78 b. Girls— 60 c. Total— 138 Number of children who for any home. reason were removed from foster a. Boys in country — 8 b. Girls in country — 4 c. Total— 12 d. Boys in town or city — 1 e. Girls in town or city — 6 f. Total— 7 The report above covers two of the many child placing agencies. LICENSED MATERNITY HOMES Reports from the licensed maternity homes and lying-in hospitals are received monthly by the Child Welfare Bureau, checked over, and irregularities investigated as far as possible with the present inadequate office force. Number of births reported from licensed maternity homes and lying-in hospitals from January, 1919 to November 30, 1920, as follows: a. Boys — 1750 b. Girls— 1738 c. Total— 3488 Number of illegitimate births reported, a. Boys — 83 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 25 b. Girls— 72 c. Total— 155 Number of children reported to this office still born or died soon after birth— 260. Number of Children claimed by parents — 3488 Number of Children of illegitimate birth claimed by: — a- Mother — 56 b. Father— 2 c. Both— 6 • d. Grandparents — 2 e. Placed in private homes — 21 f. Placed in private institutions — 43 g. Committed to State — 13 h. Number of deaths — 12 Total number of births as given by the State Bureau of Health, Division of Vital Statistics for the biennium. a. Male— 13,798 b. Female — 12,842 c. Total— 26,640 SCHOOLS In traveling over the state one has great cause to be proud of the many beautiful school buildings in the state that are for the most part located in towns and cities- Some of the country school houses are comfortable but the great majority of them look and are such as were built many years ago, small, one-room houses with one door, windows and chimney and little equipment. The school house of the average country school district has little to recommend it as a community center. One of our aims is that school houses should be more attractive both in - side and outside. Sod school houses are not entirely gone in the hill country of the western and northern part of the state and some of these are in bad repair. All the country school districts in the state do not have school the required number of months each year. In one county visited the County Superintendent reports that there are five school dis - tricts in her county that can not have one day of school in 1920-21, three there are that can have but five months, and two districts that can have but three months of school this year because of lack of school funds. To what extent this prevails in other counties I do not yet know. Many of the country children take advantage of the school law for country dis - tricts and attend school only two-thirds of the school year. The County Superintendent of one county reported that her county had never had a normal institute because of lack of funds. Poor attendance at school is more or less prevalent over the state, especially in rural districts where there are no attendance officers and </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 people fear to report conditions because of criticism and lack of knowledge in handling human problems. tWe recommend the inforcement of school attendance by a county idance officer. This is covered by proposals of the Children's Code mission. PLAY LPlay, the earliest form of work, is a primitive instinct and almost the self expression of the young. Very naturally the mother begins her teaching by directing the play of her child that he may not injure Eelf or others and all too soon forgets the importance of that tion as a character builder and leaves the child to his own judgment h is perhaps the last quality of the human mind to develop and is iracteristic that few even grown-ups have in excess. kin money matters and matters of state, this fact is recognized by our and we call a child of legal age at twenty-one years, but in matters lining to moral conduct the child is held legally responsible at a i more tender age. IMany admirable traits of character can be driven home by means organized play, industry, patriotism, rights of others, leadership, fair - is, kindness, generosity, unselfishness, justice and cooperation; with ever increasing list. £ Judging by the equipment of playgrounds, we as a state have recognized the real necessity and educative value of play. After work and school hours, people both grown and small seek recreation. It is in the play time of life that crime has its inception and fulfillment. Vicious recreation leads to wrong thoughts, wrong actions, hence the necessity of right direction. The impulse of boys at a certain age is universally to organize into gangs. This is more or less true of the adult as well, only we do not call the organizations "gangs". We here cite clubs, and fraternal organizations of all kinds, including churches. These organizations are formed because of like beliefs. The gangs have the same basis of organization. s tA child according to the development of his mind or condition of his ie environment may dig a cave, monopolize an abandoned shack or d a tent sometimes with bows of trees for himself and friends with the primitive ideals of the Tree Dweller, Cave Man or Indian, with Cave Man ideals, knives, dogs, clubs, guns and a program for foraging food, characteristic of his tribe. Undirected, this is but a step to a little later period when larger things are taken. At this later time the organization is a little better thought out and often we find a written a,greement sometimes signed in the blood of the boys who pledge themselves to do what is assigned them and the "rustling eats" and equipment is assigned to those most likely to do it well, this will be the likeable hoy who likes </seg>
            <seg id="p027">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 27 and understands people. The taking of an automobile is but one step farther. The college "Frat" with the initiatory rites and love of making collections of things for their home is a little later development of the same idea. Three-fourths of the children of Nebraska live outside of cities with little thought given to play life. There is little apparatus, few shade trees, shrubs, or grass on the average school playground, and most of them have none. For these playgrounds, we have suggested as a be - ginning, generous sand boxes, turning poles, teeter totters, swings, horseshoe, and balls. All of this apparatus could be easily secured in any neighborhood with small cost. A playground organization should be formed in the neighborhood to co-operate with the civics classes of the children in school, to keep this equipment in condition and direct the activities. A platform for out - of-door programs and gymnastics of any kind mi,ght be added- A re - turned over seas soldier might be of help here in gymnastics and setting up drills. There is no reason why a movie might not be operated on the school grounds. An electrician assures me that he sees no reason why the power from an automobile might not be utilized to operate a movie ma - chine which would make possible the movie in home communities. There are yards of advertising film material that can be had for practically nothing. Enormous power for .good would come from joyous, clean pleasurable entertainment and inspiring recreation. Community singing, neighborhood pageants of history and theatri - cals of all kinds could be used as a play feature of any neighborhood and the school house and grounds should be suitable and available at all times. CHILD LABOR We believe the present labor laws of Nebraska for children are un - fair to them; that children should have their own labor administrative officers. Physical industry is as much a part of a child's education as mental industry and should begin earlier than our present law indicates; providing that child work is under responsible local and state super - vision. We believe that mental and physical labor should be administered with just ideals and that both are equally educative, and beneficial. CIGARETTES We are .giving out material sent to us from the International Anti Cigarette League, 601-02 U. S. Express Bldg-, 58 Washington St., Chi - cago, Illinois. Also many of the little pamphlets published by Henry Ford known as "The Case Against the Little White Slaver" which is one of the finest and most complete productions we have seen written along the line of tobacco and its effects on children and are encouraging any and all advancement against the tobacco evil among children. The </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 W. C. T. U. as an organization is making this a special feature of their work this year. SPEECH DEFECTS No provision is made by our state for children with a speech defect. Dr. Klenche says: — "Whatever form speech defects may exhibit and from whatever cause it may arise, it always exercises upon the whole individual a pernicious influence and gives specific expression to the mind and character. The abnormal mode of expression reacts upon the mode of thinking, the search for easy words, the incapacity of finishing a sen - tence, gives to thought an illogical character, a flighty expression and impresses upon it the character of uncertainty. The habit of speaking and thinking by fragments gives to the stutterer the capricious disposition which renders it difficult for him to persevere." From the Irrationale of Speech (Longman &amp; Co. Pub.) — "A stam - merer's life unless he be a very clod, is a life of misery, growing with his growth, and deepening with his knowledge of life and as his aspirations deepen." The returns from the Survey of Nebraska for defective children show that there are more children with speech defects in Ne - braska than any other defect and we hope help can be given them in the near future. We wish the Child Welfare Bureau of Nebraska to serve every com - munity and now have the machinery working which we hope will accom - plish this end if sufficient assistance can be had in the future until better machinery can be created. I wish to express my grateful acknowledgement to the Judges of Juvenile Courts and County Attorneys of Nebraska, to the educational people, clubs, organizations, officials and individuals who by their fine spirit of cooperation gave so generously of their help and support in this the first year of general child welfare work for the state. H. H. Antles, Secretary of Public Welfare; — For your good counsel, fearless assistance and hearty cooperation that has been such a large factor in making possible the work thus far accomplished in the child welfare work of Nebraska, I thank you with sincere appreciation. Respectfully submitted, MRS. EMILY P. HORNBERGER, Director Child Welfare Bureau. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 29 PREFACE TO BIENNIAL REPORT Of Bureau of Examining Boards, Department of Public Welfare Historical Comment — The 1919 session of the legislature created a Bureau of Examining Boards under the Department of Public Welfare. The Department of Public Welfare is made up of six bureaus of which the Bureau of Examining Boards is a part. The organization following the passage of this law did not take place until August, 1919. Mr. H. H. Antles of Lincoln was appointed director or Secretary of the Department and ex-officio secretary of ten professional examining boards, taking his office August 18, 1919, immediately upon his return from service in France- Under this system, called the Civil Administrative Code, all appointive offices under the Governor, boards, institutions and commis - sions, were consolidated into six departments, making the head of each department directly responsible to the Governor. Uniform reports of the activities of each division or bureau are made weekly to the head of the department who in turn compiles and submits them to the Governor. Division of Bureau — The Bureau is divided into eleven divisons as follows: Chiropody Chiropractic Dentistry Nursing Optometry Osteopathy Pharmacy Veterinary Embalming Medical and the Division of Licensure of Maternity Homes. For thirty-four years the records of licensure of professional groups of people in Nebraska have been shipped from one town to another ac - cording to the residence of the Secretary of the Board. When they grew too large for convenience in shipping, the old records were stored in garrets and cellars, many of them worm-eaten, musty and forgotten. After the call of the Secretary of the Department for the records of the Board, they were sent in promptly, and the standardization of records and systematizing of filing was begun. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Each professional board had established some splendid system or other which was useful for all of the professions. Thus the result of their experiences were used for the benefit of the whole Bureau. Staff— KThe staff at present consists of the Secretary of the Department of ic Welfare, who is ex officio secretary of the Examining Board, two : stenographers and one clerk on full time. The Secretary has charge of all administrative work, investigation of law violations and attends all board meetings and examinations. Headquarters — Headquarters for the activities of Board work are maintained at the Stat« Capitol. Examinations — After applications have been acted upon by the Board, the Depart - ment notifies the applicant to appear for examination- A representative from the department gives out examination numbers which are used on all papers. These cards are kept on file until the returns come in from the Board. The examination papers are returned to the Department Kthe report, and are kept on record for two years. Any applicant has any reason to believe that there was an error in the correction of his papers, or that his grades were not just, has recourse through the Ement. The secretary may, if he sees fit, call in qualified disin - :d persons for a review of these papers. Receipts are given to 3 of examinations for papers written. Applications are accompanied by an unmounted photograph taken recently and a certified photographic copy of diploma about 4x5 inches. Records — After the records came to the Department, all licensed and unlicensed persons were card indexed, applications with complete data placed in vertical files, and new and complete permanent register started giving brief information in regard to the applicant and a complete record of examination. Permanent registers were not started for nurses, phar - macists, and physicians and surgeons. Their permanent registers were complete and in good condition. Uniform license blanks were made for all professions under the Bureau of Examining Boards and exact copies in book form are kept for permanent record in the department, for the purpose of giving certified </seg>
            <seg id="p031">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 31 copies of licenses to licensees as occasion arises, and particularly, for reciprocity application. Finances — Sixteen different cash accounts are kept in the Bureau, one for each division and a separate account of renewal fees for each profession re - newing licenses annually. The expense of conducting the Bureau must come from the receipts of all the Divisions. Expenses are pro-rated to these Divisions according to the amount of work done for the Division. Violations — An investigator of complaints is sent out by the Department to fol - low up infringements of the law and to start prosecutions. In filing complaints for violations it is necessary to give facts and dates, so that the Department may have some foundation to work on. Attention to infraction of the law must be directed to the county attorney of the county in which the offense takes place. It is his duty to prosecute. The Department is helpless without his cooperation. The Bureau and the Department need the support of all the professions to uphold the law. CHIROPODY First Law — The first law governing the practice of Chiropody was passed in 1919. The bill passed by the Nebraska Legislature was a model passed on to the state by the National Chiropodists' Association. The first board appointed was as follows: the secretary of the state medical board, Dr. H. J. Lehnhoff and Dr. H. F. Gartner and Dr. F. E. Silvers, who were recommended to the Medical Board by the Chiropodists' State Associa - tion. The first meeting of the Board was held June 16, 1919, in Lincoln. August 29 and 30 the same year was held the first meeting to pass upon applications and to conduct examinations- Thoss whose applications showed that they had practiced chiropody in Nebraska for one year previous to April 1, 1919, were grantee! a li - cense without examination. They were 25 in number. Examinations were given to two r.pj&gt;iicams. who were not entitled to exemption licen - ses. Under Code — August 2, 1919, the Civil Administrative Code Law went into effect in Nebraska. This law provided that all examining boards be placed under one bureau in the Department of Public Welfare. The plan was to make a central office and to keep uniform records on all pro - fessional examining boards. The records of the Chiropody Board were </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 called in, and were incorporated into the Bureau of Examining Boards about September 1, 1919. Licenses for the waiver applicants and those successful in the first examination were granted by the Department of Public Welfare, coun - tersigned by the Chiropody Board. H. J. Lehnhoff, M. D. was presi - dent of the Board; Dr. F. E. Silvers, vice-president and Dr. H- F. Gart - ner, secretary. When the department of public welfare came into existence, it was necessary to reorganize the examining boards. Dr. H. J. Lehnhoff, being secretary of the Medical Board, was dropped from the Chiropody Board and Dr. F. F. Funder, a chiropodist, who was recommended to the department by the state association, appointed in his place. The Board then reorganized July 5, 1920 previous to the 1920 regular ex - amination. Dr. F. E. Silvers of Omaha was elected president, Dr. F. F. Funder of Omaha vice-president, and Dr. H. F. Gartner of Lin - coln was retained as secretary of the Board. Dr. Silvers resigned from the Board in February 1921. Finances — tA separate cash account is kept for the Chiropody Board, and all orts for the Bureau indicate which part is credited to Chiropody. ; waiver license fee was $10.00; the examination fee is $25.00. ce the department took over the work four waiver and eight exam - tion fees were received. One waiver and one examination appli - ion were withdrawn before action of the Board was taken and fees •e returned upon voucher on the office of the State Treasurer. Schools of Chiropody — There is no school of Chiropody in Nebraska The Board at its meeting July 7, 1920, reported the following recognized schools of Chiropody: California School of Chiropody, San Francisco. Chicago School of Chiropody, Chicago. Illinois School of Chiropody, Chicago. Middlesex College of Chiropody, East Cambridge, Mass. Ohio College of Chiropody, Cleveland. School of Chiropody of New York. New York City. Temple University, Philadelphia. Preliminary — The preliminary education required at the present time is two years high school or the equivalent. Three years will be required after January 1, 1922, and four years after January 1, 1925. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 33 Complaints — During the biennium five complaints have come to the Department. Three were minor and were disposed of without difficulty. One was recently licensed, and the fifth is still pending. Applications and Examinations — Applications find all matters pertaining to credentials are handled by the Department. When complete, they are acted upon by the Ex - amining Board. Each applicant is required to present credentials showing that he is not less than twenty-one years of age, that he has obtained a preliminary education equivalent to a two year course in an accredited high school, that he is a graduate of an accredited school of chiropody and is of good moral character. In addition, he must present an unmounted photograph of himself taken within the year, and a certified photographic copy of his diploma 4x5 inches. The fee for license is $25.00. The department rules that applications should be on file two weeks before the time set for examination, or meeting of the board. Otherwise applicants appear at their own risk. Applications acted upon favorably during the biennium were as follows: Waiver, 27; Reciprocity, 1; Examination, 4; Rejected, None; Failed, 4. The subjects in examination are as follows: Anatomy, Elementary Chemistry, Chiropody Practice, Chiropody Diagnosis. The required passing grade is 70 No reciprocity agreements have been drawn up with states having Chiropody laws, because of the inequality in requirements. The following states have Chiropody Laws: California, Colorado, Connecticut, District of Columbia, Illinois, Louisiana, Maryland, Mass - achusetts, Michigan, Missouri, New Jersey, Nebraska, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Rhode Island, Virginia, West Virginia, Washington and Wisconsin. The following chiropodists have been licensed during the biennium: Allbie, Earl J. — Omaha Gartner, Adam, Sr. — Lincoln Gartner, Adam John — Lincoln Gartner ,Herman F. — Lincoln Gartner, Leopold G. — Lincoln Halley, Margaret — Omaha Hupfer, Sophia— North Platte Johnson, Irene — Omaha Benda, Margaret F. — Omaha Burford, Carrie J. — Omaha Concannon, Geo. S. — Omaha Daly, Kathryn L. — Omaha Dow, Sarah A. — Grand Island Easter, Hazel M. — Omaha Fitzgerald, Rosetta — Omaha Funder, Felix F. — Omaha Lewis, Edith Belle — Lincoln Lohnes, Leon L. — North Platte </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 McAlpine, Lillian — Lincoln McElwain, Beulah — Omaha Miller, Chas. Roy — Lincoln Monheit, Moritz — Omaha Robinson, Jennie — Omaha Robson, Mary L. — York Scott, James W. — Omaha Sheeley, Oliver Newton — Grand Is- land. Silvers, Frank E. — Omaha Thornberry, Adele M. — Omaha Weeks, Howard W. — Omaha Zwisler, Nellie L. — Omaha Roy, John — Omaha Ryley, Ellen F— Omaha REPORT OF CHIROPRACTIC DIVISION BIENNIUM ENDING APRIL 1, 1921. First Law — The Legislature of 1915 passed a law relating to the practice of Chiropractic with requirements as follows: 1. Preliminary education, 4 years high school or the educational equivalent prior to entering college. 2. License without examination if satisfactory evidence is shown that applicant practicing in the state for two years has had a two year course of six months each in separate years. 3. License by examination — "regular four year high school course" — graduate of chartered school in good repute — two terms of six months each, and after January 1, 1916, three terms of nine months each. 4. Subjects of examination: Anatomy, physiology, chiropractic, symptomatology, nerve tracing, chiropractic orthopedy, hygiene, princi - ples of chiropractic, and adjusting as taught by chiropractic schools. 5. Passing grade — 60 per cent. General average required — 75 per cent. 6. Not permissible to administer drugs nor perform surgical op - erations ,nor to practice obstetrics nor osteopathy. Annual renewal of license — two dollars fee. The first meeting of the Board was called by Governor Moorehead in July 1915. Drs. H. C. Crabtree of Lincoln, H. J. Foster of Hastings, and J. R. Campbell of Norfolk were appointed upon recommendation of the Nebraska State Chiropractic Association The first business of the Board was to license the new members of the Board. Licensure — In 1915 — 117 waiver licenses were granted. 24 licenses were grant - ed by examination. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 35 To April 1, 1919 there were 146 chiropractors licensed in Nebraska. During the biennium, 13 were licensed, making a total of 159. Rejected during the biennium: Total 3 One application made in 1920 was withdrawn, because of change in loca- Appointments to Board — To be eligible for appointment on the Board of Chiropractor ex - aminers, the appointee must have been engaged in the practice five years in Nebraska. Recommendations for appointments are made to the De - partment of Public Welfare by the State Association. Under Code — When the Code took effect in August 1919, Drs. Joseph C. Lawrence of Omaha, J. P. Laub of Chapman and J. T. Gallamore of Fairbury con - stituted the Board. They were all retained and Dr. Lawrence was re - appointed to succeed himself December 1920. There is but one school in the state for the education of chiroprac - tors — the Nebraska Chiropractic College. Dr. H. C. Crabtree is the Dean and Superintendent. The total enrollment in the school this year There are 24 accredited schools in the United States accredited by the Xmiversal Chiropractic Association of The U. S. A. The course recognized in the Nebraska law covers three years of nine months each. Complaint? — There were 14 complaints made to the Department since August 1919. Five prosecutions were made, six were disposed of, three are still pending. There are 143 chiropractors in good standing with the Department, having paid their renewal license fees for 1920. The subjects of examination are: anatomy, adjusting, hygiene, nerve tracing, orthopedics, physiology, symptomatology. Reciprocity — At a meeting of the State Boards of Chiropractic held at Daven- "reliminary education not according to law .acking required professional education according to law (2 , </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 Elowa, January 11, 1919, — reciprocity agreements were drawn up een Nebraska, and Kansas, North Carolina, Connecticut, and h Dakota. A sliding scale for educational standards was established on the basis of three years of six months each as a minimum. It was agreed that one month's credit would be considered equivalent to each three months actual bona fide state practice under license. No application would be considered for reciprocity unless the applicant had practiced a minimum of one calendar year. The following states have regular chiropractic boards: Arkansas; Connecticut, Florida, Kansas, Minnesota, Montana, Nebraska, New Jersey, North Carolina, North Dakota. The Nebraska Chiropractors' Association and the Nebraska Branch of the Universal Chiropractors)' Association will hold regular annual meetings during the summer — the place and date not yet named. Chiropractors Licensed during Biennium Bender, Eva Estella — Lincoln Browning, Roy C. — Lincoln Drain, James R. — Russell, Kas. Gillett, W. Guy— Otego, Kas. Een, Mabel Jackson — Lincoln erman, Minnie Agnes — Lincoln nard, Byron — Callaway Markwell, James A. — Omaha Peterson, Mahlon Bluford — Dal- hart, Texas Reichstadt, Paul— Oakland, Cal. Smith, Fredetta— Milford Smith, Raymond — Milford Williams, Luvern Ashley — Lincoln REPORT OF DENTAL DIVISION Biennium ending April 1, 1921. First Law— tThe first law relating to the practice of Dentistry in Nebraska was ed by the 1887 session of the legislature, and approved March 23, Under County Clerk — Bona fide practitioners were required to file an affidavit cover - ing practice in the State, and upon payment of a one dollar fee, they were issued a license. New men coming into the state were required to present to the County Clerk a diploma from a reputable dental col - lege or university incorporated or established in the United States or in foreign countries. A copy of the diploma was made and upon payment of fee of one dollar, a license was issued. In removing from one county to another a dentist was required to file a copy of the record of his former registration with the County </seg>
            <seg id="p037">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 37 Clerk of his new residence. Changes in Law — It was specifically stated in the law that nothing in the Act should be construed to prevent physicians or surgeons from extracting teeth. The evolution of this particular clause is shown in an extract from the present law: "Nothing in this article shall prohibit Bone Fide students of dentistry from operating in the clinical departments of a reputable dental college, or an unlicensed person performing merely mechanical work on inert matter in a dental office or laboratory or a duly licensed physician from treating diseases of the mouth or performing operations in oral surgery." Fines for Violations — Fines for violations were fixed in the first laws from twenty to two hundred dollars, and were absorbed by the common school fund of the county where the offense was committed. This fine is now fifty to five hundred dollars. Under State Board of Health— In 1895, the licensing of dentists was placed under the State Board of Health consisting of the Governor, the Attorney General, and the Superintendent of Public Instruction. Amended 1903— Three secretaries recommended by the Nebraska State Dental So - ciety were appointed as examiners, or secretaries to the State Board of Health. The dental law was amended in 1903. According to these amendments all dentists practicing in the State were required to ob - tain new licenses. It was necessary only for those registered to file a copy of their former registration. New applicants coming into the state were required to take an examination if not graduates of reput - able dental schools. Graduates of reputable dental schools were grant - ed licenses upon the verification of diploma and payment of regular fee. The license was required to be filed with the County Clerk as it is at the present date. , Reputable Dental School — A reputable school at that time was one that required a prelimi - nary examination for admission, an attendance of at least three courses of six months each, no two courses in one year. This three year clause did not apply to those who had degrees granted prior to July 1892. As the law stands now the course is not specified but it must be ad - judged reputable by the Board and the Department and the institution in question must meet the requirements for graduation such that they would recommend it for recognition by the other dental colleges in the United States. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 TipnAnT r\T* rrTTn tiiLrKJill Ur Irit, Fees — The regular fee for examination is twenty dollars; for segregated examination, ten dollars, and for exchange or endorsement to another state, five dollars. The annual registration fee is one dollar. 1905 Board of Dental Secretaries — In 1905 the law was revised leaving practically the present dental law on the statutes. At this time the Board was increased in mem - bership to five. Annual registration was enacted. Brief amendments have been added since. The first secretaries of the dental board were: David A. Meese, president, Nemaha County; J. H. Wallace, vice-president, Douglas coun - ty; C. F. Ladd, secretary, Lancaster county; Woodson F. Smith, Fill - more county; C- S. Parker, Wayne County. Licenses issued — 1895 119 1909 52 1896 122 1910 39 1897 39 1911 41 1898 48 1912 31 1899 70 1913 38 1900 43 1914 44 1901 56 1915 69 1916 65 1902 52 1903 100 1917 64 1918 69 1904 119 1905 134 1919 102 1920 20 1906 72 1907 17 Total 1689 1908 64 Under Code- When the Civil Administrative Code took effect August 2, 1919, the dental board reappointed was as follows: M. O. Fraser, Lincoln, president; Geo. M. Boehler, Omaha, vice-president; S. A. Allen, Loup City, secretary and treasurer; J. H. Wallace, Omaha; Ferdinand Griess, Sutton. Mr. H. H. Antles was appointed Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare, and entered upon his duties August 19th. He asked the Dental Board to remain as it stood at least until the Bureau of Ex - amining Boards was organized. Dr. Allen forwarded all records of the Dental Board and in such splendid order that it saved the office staff much grief and time to get them in the desired order for the work of a consolidated office. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 39 Special Examination July, 1919 — The Board was handicapped on the issuance of licenses for the special examination of July incident to the confiscation of the examina - tion questions of the regular examination in June. A decision of the Attorney General on the interpretation of the law gave the Depart - ment authority to collect the expenses of the special examination which were prorated to the applicants of the July examination. The amount due from each applicant was $7.23: Later reports showed that all of this was collected, licenses having been held until the fee was paid. The Department in turn suffered an unfortunate circumstance in regard to the printing of licenses. They were held up for months for various reasons. Finances — A separate cash account is kept on all fees credited to the den - tists. All dental fees including renewal fees are deposited to the credit of the dental division. Expenses of the Board and examina - tion are taken from the examination and reciprocity fees; expenses of conducting the affairs of the Bureau are taken from renewal fees and pro-rated to the several divisions according to the amount of work done for that particular division. The expense of sending a delegate to the National Association of Dental Examiners annually is taken from the renewal fees. When there are funds available they are used for enforcing the law, and to send out an investigator of complaints. Changes in Board — Since the secretarial work pf the dental board has come under the juristiction of the Department of Public Welfare, the following changes have been made in the Board: Personnel of Board — Dr. E. W. Fellers of Beatrice was appointed to succeed Dr. J. H. Wallace of Omaha who resigned in August, 1920. Dr. Griess was ap - pointed to succeed himself. The Board reorganized with Dr. Boehler, president; Dr. Griess, vice-president and Dr. Allen was re-elected sec - retary. It was with regret that Dr. Wallace's resignation was ac - cepted. Dr. Wallace served untiringly on the Board for fifteen years, and was instrumental in bringing about standardization of the exami - nations and higher standards in the profession. Delegates to N. A. D. E.— The Board has sent annually since 1905, a delegate to the National Association of Dental Examiners. Dr. C. F. Ladd of Lincoln was the first delegate. Dr. S. A. Allen of Loup City was the delegate in 1920. The meeting was held in Boston. It lasted the usual two days, and was attended by one or more representatives from nearly every state. </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Dr. Jesse Miller of Maryville, Missouri presided. Among the subjects under general discussion were: National reciprocity, unification of state dental laws, college instruction, permitting non-licensed dentists to carry on post-graduate courses, and the work of the Educational Council of America. Dr. H. C. McKittrick, Indianapolis was elected President for the next year. Dr. Allen of Nebraska was appointed on the Com - mittee on Colleges. The Nebraska Dental Board elected Dr. Boehler as delegate to the 1921 meeting in Milwaukee. Fees to N. A. D. E.— Since November 1919, $65.00 have been paid to the National As - sociation of Dental Examiners as dues from the Nebraska State Board of Dental Examiners. This fund is used for the purpose of inspect - ing and accrediting dental schools and for other matters pertaining in a national way to dental education. State Dental Association — The Nebraska State Dental Society held its annual meeting in Lin - coln May 17 to 23rd, 1920. The 1921 meeting will be held in Omaha, May 16 to 19 inclusive. Nebraska Dental Colleges — There are two dental schools in Nebraska — The University of Ne - braska College of Dentistry in Lincoln, and the Creighton Dental Col - lege in Omaha. Both colleges lengthened their courses in 1917 to four years. In January 1921, the University of Nebraska added a fifth year, which is known as a pre-dental course. The total enrollment of the University of Nebraska College of Den - tistry is 143, and that of Creighton Dental College, 145. Preliminary Education — Fourteen Carnegie units are the required preliminary education in the dental law. Fourteen units are equivalent to twenty-eight high school credits on the basis of eighteen weeks of five hours each for one credit. Five applicants were rejected during the past two years owing to the fact that they were' unable to present satisfactory evidence of the required preliminary education. In three instances the board re - fused to accept the qualifying certificates of another state because they did not cover the required credits demanded in the Nebraska law. Violations — When the Department took over the secretarial work of the den - tal board the particular violator of the law was Mr. Frank Arnold Pat - terson who had practiced dentistry in the state several years without a license. Through the previous efforts of the Board, and through the Department and the inspector sent out under the Law Enforcement Division, Mr. Patterson was arrested, convicted and fined in July, 1920. He left the state. </seg>
            <seg id="p041">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 41 One violator who had been practicing in the state without a license has stopped practicing. There are numerous complaints coming in against the dental help - ers and the dentists who employ them. Some of these have been set - tled and some are still pending. Decisions of Attorney General — October 28, 1919 — In regard to issuance of license without exami - nation when an applicant practiced in the state regularly before 1905, and left the state and not taken out license. The Attorney General decided that the Department had authority to grant a license if the applicant possessed qualifications in other respects, and had practiced prior to 1905 a sufficient length of time to establish himself as a prac - ticing dentist — that he came within the provisions of this act, there being no date set in the law to terminate this waiver. February 4, 1920 — In regard to return of dental fees when the ap - plicant was found not eligible for examination or license. The attor - ney general said that there was no exception to the law and it should be interpreted word for word. Applications to Department — Applications for examination and reciprocity are made to the De - partment, and upon request copies of the law are mailed with the ap - plications. The application to be complete must show actual high school credits, satisfactory evidence that the applicant is of good moral character, that he has arrived at the age of twenty-one. He must show further an unmounted photograph of himself taken within the previous year, and a cei'tified photographic copy of his diploma about four by five inches or large enough to read easily the signatures and date of issuance. The application is accompanied by the fee of twenty dollars which is in no case returned. Segregated examinations have been given since 1917. The fee for segregated examination is ten dol - lars. A reciprocity application is accompanied by an exchange cer - tificate from the state in which the applicant is registered. In order to allow time for the consideration of the Board, to complete applica - tions before the action of the board is necessary, the department should be given at least ten days before the date of examination. An appli - cation may be withdrawn before the Board acts upon it. Acted upon by Board — All applications are acted upon by the Board. Regular applica - tions are not called to the attention of the Board until they appear to •conduct examinations. All applicants come at their own risk of being rejected by the Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 REPORT OF THE Examinations, Practical and Theoretical — Five days are given to the dental examination. The practical covers two days. Each applicant is responsible for a patient to work on and for his own instruments. The practical given at the close of the school year is conducted at both schools at the same time. The equipment of the school is available for the use of the board and the Clicants. The written examination is usually held in one of the legis - &lt;re chambers. The questions prepared by the Board are mimeo - graphed in the State House just before and during the examination. Each applicant is given a number by a representative of the Depart - tt. He fills out an examination card which is filed with the depart - t until the returns come from the board who report by number only. Subjects of Examination — The subjects of examination are: Anatomy, Physiology, Histology, Chemistry, Bacteriology, Dental Anatomy, Materia Medica and Thera - puetics, Biology, Metallurgy, Pathology, Oral Surgery, Hygiene, Juris - prudence, Anaesthesia, Prosthetic Dentistry, Operative Dentistry, Ortho - dontia, Radiography, and Crown and Bridge Work. Passing Grades — Passing grades are 75 per cent except in Operative and Prosthetic Dentistry. 80 per cent is required in these subjects. Failing in two latter branches the applicant fails to pass. Failing in these subjects the applicant fails to pass no matter what the average may be. Fail - ing in the first examination he is considered as a new applicant in the second and must repeat the entire examination. He is allowed the second examination within a year on the same fee and application. Reciprocity — The first reciprocity agreement made by the Nebraska Board was in 1906 after the organization of the five dental secretaries. Nebras - ka now has reciprocity with the District of Columbia, Iowa, Illinois, Indiana, Kansas, Minnesota, Michigan, Missouri, Ohio, and Tennessee on the basis of five years practice just previous to application. Reciprocity applications are accompanied by exchange certificates for which the ap - plicant pays five dollars to the Board of State from which he comes. Applicants for reciprocity are required to pass practical examination. They are subject to the same regulations as an applicant for examina - tion as far as patient and instruments are concerned. Examinations during Biennium — The examinations held during the biennium were: June 4-8, 1919; July 22 to 26, 1919; November 17 to 21, 1919; February 24 to 28, 1920; June 11 to 15, 1920; August 24 to 28, 1920; and November 15 to 19, 1920. The second, fourth and sixth were special examinations. </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 43 Results: 6]19 7|19 11(19 2|20 6|20 8|20 ll|20 ♦Examined — Rejected — Licensed — 90 108 88 20 2 88 *This does not include segregated. Rejections 6|19 7J19 11|19 2|20 6|20 8|20 11(20 with Total Seg. reject Anatomy 12 5 Bacteriology Chemistry 1 0 0 0 Dent. Anatomy Histology 15 0 4 2 Physiology 0 2 Materia Med. Metallurgy Op. Dentistry Pros. Dentistry Anaesthesia 2 0 5 0 2 0 2 0 10 0 8 2 Oral Surg. Oral Hygiene Pathology 1 0 6 10 Orthodontia Jurisprudence Practical 5 0 19 0 9 7 Crown &amp; Bridge Biology 13 1 2 3 2 2 3 2 Radiography Renewal Licenses — There are 886 dentists in good standing in Nebraska; 783 of these live in the State. Revocation- No licenses were revoked during the biennium. One license was revoked in 1909. 1921 Examinations — The next state board examination will be held June 7, 8, 9, 10 and 11. The practical will be held at the University of Nebraska College of Dentistry and Creighton Dental College June 7 and 8. The written will be held in Lincoln at the State House, the remaining three days. The following dentists were licensed during the Biennium: 0 0 2 2 0 0 1 1 163 177 4 3 0 0 0 204 6 0 3 G 0 204 9 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 0 0 0 1 2 202 163 163 3 3 7 0 0 0 3 149 5 0 0 0 0 149 2 1 1 0 4 0 0 3 2 162 149 14 17 0 0 0 0 149 1 0 0 0 2 149 9 1 0 0 0 149 6 1 0 0 1 149 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Albrecht, Delphine G. Lincoln Alden, Herbert R. Kimball Ball, Chester E. Chadron Barstow, Louis C Council Bluff Becker, Walter Wm Omaha Beckwith, I. E Albion Benson, Ernest E. Omaha Bering, Walter B Omaha Bockemuehl, Mark E Council Bluff Boland, Paul J. Omaha Brennan, William J. Concord Bryner, Carl H. Omaha Butler, Gareld L University Place Challquist, Fredolph C Mead Chaloupka, Louis J Omaha Cogan, Edward J Omaha Connolly, James P. Omaha Conway, Frank T Waseca, Minn. Cosford, Howard R Lincoln Curran, James H Waseca, Minn. Dougherty, Michael E Newcastle Drake, Robert G Omaha Dreyer, Everett L Auburn Dunlavy, Alva J Oshkosh Dunn, Arlo M Lincoln Edgar, Leonard O Lincoln Ellenberger, Polk Tekamah Erickson, Oliver L Virgina Fay, John C- Omaha Fleming, Paul D. Wilsonville Fuerst, Henry Otis, Colo. Gill, Charles L Friend Gradwohl, Harry M. Lincoln Greeson, Harlan B Fairbury Groom, Ray C. Plainville Gunther, Carl Lincoln Hansen, Elmer C K. C, Mo. Harbert, G. R- Omaha Hardlannert, Elmer F Omaha Harris, Harry E. Fairbury Hebard, Harry D. Nebraska City Hergenrother, Raymond M. Oxford Herkenroth, Herbert W. Omaha Hess, John J. Chariton, Iowa Hinman, Russel J. Redfield, S. D. Homer, Eben J. Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p045">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 45 Hughes, Ambrose I Hull, Walter L. Hyland, Lester A. Healy, Michael J. Ischauner, Artemas A. Johnson, A. Emanuel _ Johnson, Clarence B Jones, Paul Omaha Nelson Callaway Omaha -Osceola -Oakland Long Island, Kas. Omaha Kehoe, Will Dennis _ King, Glen S. .Monticello, I. Indianpla Omaha Kline, A. H. Koebele, Simon C. _ Korbel, Wm- John _. Laidig, Earl E. Lavelli, Albert W. . .Burns, Kas. Wilber Danbury Omaha Leschinsky, George K. A, Limperick, Arthur P. Linch, Clyde A. Loup City Willmar, Minn. University Place Logan, Robert C. _ Ludwick, Paul G. . Elliott, la. Lincoln Mach, Benjamin W Magnuson, Joseph A *Mahan, Glen E- Matheson, Foster M. McCue, C. Frank Chicago Marquette Gothenburg Hi,ghmore, S. D. Lincoln Miller, Howard L. Moore, Clayton J. Morrissey, David L. Muffly, Paul B. Murphy, Humphrey F. _. Clarinda Iowa Falls, Iowa Ryan, la. University Place Omaha *Mason, Henry C. Neff, Lyle G. O'Keefe, Everett B- _ Quade, Herman F. Omaha Lincoln Alliance Omaha Prague Palensky, John F. Parker, Joseph S. Percy, Alden E. . Omaha Creston, la. Peterson, C. Raymond Polk Pitzer, Charles H. Lincoln Plihal, James Lincoln Proskovee, Louis A. Prague Ralston, Orville A Lincoln Rapp, Frank W. Omaha Reese, Finis Carl Omaha Reinhardt, Dale H. Diller Reinsch, Claude E. Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Rice, Paul Valley Rider, Charles McCook Robinson, Chas. C. Merna Romans, Guy E. Denison, la. Romans, Robert M. Denison, la. Rosenau, Alvin B. Hastings Sattler, Lessing Robert Omaha Schmidt, Arthur H. Lincoln Schreiber, Edward J. Omaha Seal, Sherrill J Grand Island Sharp, Leland Vance Stromsbuig Sheehan, Philip York Shields, Frederick L. Sargent Singleton, John A. Omaha Stava, Ralph A. Omaha Sturgeon, Turner S. Denver Swanbom, Irwin P. Lincoln Swanson, Clarence H. Ravenna Swanson, Hjalmar E. Bertrand Thompson, Claude L. West Point Thompson, Fred E. North Platte Tiesse, Fred Clinton, la. (Deceased) Van Zele, Verlie Geneseo, 111. Wachter, Joseph H : Sutton Waldheim, Carlos Central America Walsh, Louis C Adair, la. Weisel, Benjamin O. Alexandria Woodson, Jack V. Deshler Yost, Howard North Platte Zehnpfennig, Fred L. Parkston, S- D. Zellers, Henry C Lincoln EMBALMING History up to Time of Code — The first law relating to the practice of embalming was passed in 1889. This law provided that the state board of health should appoint an embalming board consisting of three members, which board was to have charge of the examining and licensing of embalmers in the state of Nebraska. The law provided that no person should be allowed to prac- tice embalming in this state who had not successfully passed the state board examination. Privilege was given those already practicing in the state to register by waiver within six months after the passage of the act. However, as those licensed by waiver were not allowed to embalm the bodies of any persons dying from contagious disease, prac- tically all then practicing took the examination in order that they might have full privilege to practice. </seg>
            <seg id="p047">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 47 The board at its first meeting in July, 1889, agreed that Nebraska should establish reciprocal relations with Iowa, Illinois and Minnesota, but at the August meeting, this was reconsidered, because it was thought to conflict with the law. No further action with reference to reciprocity was taken until 1905, when it was agreed that Nebraska should recipro - cate with all states that would extend a like courtesy to Nebraska. No separate record of those licensed by examination and those licensed by reciprocity was kept until June, 1915. Up to that time, there were 958 licensed by examination and reciprocity. From June, _915, to the beginning of the biennium, 160 were licensed by examination and 27 by reciprocity. Very few changes have been made in the law since it was first en - acted in 1889- The members of the first examining board were P. C. Heafy of Omaha, president, Joseph Sondermann of Grand Island, secretary and E. L. Troyer of Lincoln, treasurer. Code- In August, 1919, under the civil administrative code, the embalming board was made a part of the Department of Public Welfare, and all records of the embalming board are now in the hands of this department. At the time the code went into effect, the board consisted of E. A. Miller of Kearney, Leo Hoffman of Omaha, and W. R. Maloney of North Platte. Upon the death of Mr. Miller in January, 1920, Mr. W. M. Hill of Hebron was appointed in his place, and the board at present consists of Leo Hoffman, president, W. R. Maloney, vice-president, and W. M. Hill, secretary. Finances — A separate cash account is kept for the embalming board, and when fees are deposited for the bureau, those for the embalming board are designated as such. The examination and reciprocity fee is ten dollars. Since the department of public welfare has handled the secretarial work of the embalming board, 39 examination and 19 reciprocity fees have been received. $50.00 dues have been paid to the National Association of Embalmers during the biennium. New Appointments — With the exception of the appointment of Mr. W. M. Hill to fill the vacancy caused by the death of Mr. E. A. Miller, no new appointments have been made to the board since the department of public welfare took charge. State association is requested to recommend new members for appointment and though the law does not state that those recommended must be appointed, the secretary of the department feels that the pro - fessions should have much to say about the persons appointed. </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Complaints — All complaints as to violations of the law are investigated by the department. Eight complaints have been investigated, of which three are settled and five are still pending. Course Recognized — The board has ruled that any applicant for license to practice em - balming must either be a graduate of a school of embalming, or have embalmed twenty-five bodies under supervision of a licensed embalmer. Preliminary Education — There are no requirements for preliminary education- State Association — The officers of the State Embalmers Association are — A. H. Hastings of Arcadia, president, P. J. Merten, Jr., of Blue Hill, secretary, and Charles A. Roper of Lincoln, treasurer. The next meeting of the Asso - ciation will be held in Omaha June 1, 2, 3, and 4. National Examining Board — Mr. W. R- Maloney, vice-president of the board, went as delegate to a conference held in September, 1920, at Springfield, Massachusetts, for the purpose of considering the establishment of a National Examining Board for Embalmers of North America. A committee was appointed to form a national board whereby all examination papers, questions, etc., would be made uniform over the entire country, and requirements for examination made uniform. The board is to report this year (1921) at a conference to be held at San Antonio, Texas. Mr. Maloney expressed the opinion that Texas had the best embalming law in the United States. Applications — All applicants for examination or reciprocity must fill out the regu - lar application blank, which must be accompanied by a fee of ten dollars, a photograph of the applicant, and a photograph of his diploma, if he has one. Examination — Subjects of examination are anatomy, embalming, hygiene, sanitary science, writtten theory, practical work. 70% is the minimum grade, and a general average of 75% is required. During the biennium, examinations have been given as follows: June, 1919; January 26, 1920; June 11, 1920; January 19, 1921. The spring examination of 1921 will be given in Omaha at the University of Nebraska, June 4. Reciprocity — Applicants for reciprocity must meet the same requirements as ap </seg>
            <seg id="p049">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 49 plicants for examination- Nebraska has reciprocity with Colorado, Iowa, Indiana, Missouri, Minnesota, South Dakota, Wisconsin and Wyoming. Applications Acted Upon During Biennium — During the biennium the following applications have been acted upon by the board: Examination 50 Reciprocity 23 Rejected, reciprocity ._ 1 The following have been licensed during the biennium: Examination Name Address Hebron Stromsburg John G. Albers Edwin L. Anderson Harry D. Backeberg B. William Bonham Glenn H. Bowhay Harold G. Brittell Frederick E. Butler John Cady Lanham, Kans. Pine Bluffs, Wyo. Liberty Gresham Ansley Beatrice Garland Beatrice Omaha William Christjaener William B. Clausen Mrs. Veretta Crane W. W. Crawford North Platte Scottsbluff Omaha Charles K. Drake Clarence J. Erickson Harry B. Farrington James H. Fisher Wisner Morrill Diller Everett Green Harry Haffner Omaha Wausa Omaha Omaha Du Bois Omaha Omaha Omaha Wauneta Rulo Mrs. Myrtle Hanks Harold B. Hardee Cornelius P. Heafey Anderson H. Hutton Joseph A. Janda Lloyd H. Johnson Silas Johnson Sepha M. Johnston Robert B. Knight Jerome Korisko John G. Love Omaha Columbus Edgar James M. McGhie Miles S- Macomber Fisher A. Musser Falls City Fairbury </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Dak Examination (Continued) Name Address Hastings Niobrara Hildreth Butte Cable C. Newman Edward Opocensky Francis W. Purdy D. B. Raymer D. D. Reavis, Jr. Mrs. May Reeve Norman F. Rockey George Schaaf Falls City Elm Creek St. Edward Harvard William J. Schroeder Henry E. Smith Lawrence David City Central City Lincoln Leslie W- Solt William F. Splain Fay W. Spooner Lucius M. Valentine Haziel F. Vogt Sargent Lincoln Bancroft Crookston Hastings Omaha Benjamin F. Wilkinson Verne C. Wisner Robert C. Yost Reciprocity Edward D. Albers Joas B. Boss Minden Hartington Charles W. Benson Nels I. Berge Hot Springs, So Springview Ralph A. Bonnell Omaha Alvin R. Christiansen James E. Cox Blair North Platte Otto I. Foersteman Alliance Hannah C. Gunn Henry Hoferer Sioux City Tripoli, la. Hansman H. Kramer Oscar Krill Omaha Torrington, Wyo, Harry N. Mansfield Hamburg, la. Louis C. Maxwell Victor W. Meyer Charles T. Miller Sioux City Omaha Harrison Fairbury George D. Read Guy F. Richards Wray, Colo. Sioux City Wray, Colo. Winfield S. Samuels Josiah Thomas Floyd H- Whitney Cumberland, la. Cumberland, la. Nell B. Whitney , Albert B. Wolfe Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p051">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 51 Medical History up to time of Code — The first legislation to regulate medical practice in Nebraska was in 1855, when an act was passed to establish the Nebraska Medical Society, and providing that in order to practice medicine and surgery in the state of Nebraska, applicant must be a member of this medical society, and licensed by it to practice. A second act was passed in 1881. Under this act, persons wish - ing to practice medicine in the state of Nebraska were required to reg - ister with the county clerk. In order to become registered, applicant must have graduated from a legally chartered medical college empow - ered to grant the degree of Doctor of Medicine; or have attended a full course of lectures in such an institution, and have practiced medi - cine continuously for three years, the last year of the three in Nebras - ka; or have been practicing medicine for a livelihood for ten years, the last two in this state. Ten years later, in 1891, an act was passed creating the State Board of Health, composed of the Governor, attorney general, and state superintendent of public instruction. This board was required to ap - point four secretaries to grant certificates to applicants* upon pre - sentation of diploma from a recognized medical college. From 1891 to 1903, 2863 applicants were licensed upon presentation of diploma; 162 were refused. In 1903, an act was passed requiring all applicants to pass the state board examination, in addition to presenting diploma from a rec - ognized medical college. During 1 the first six months of 1903, during which time applicants were given the privilege of registering upon pre - sentation of diploma, 498 were licensed by diploma, and 6 were refused. One applicant was licensed by examination during 1903. From 1903 to the beginning of the biennium, 1360 have been licensed by exam - ination, and 826 by reciprocity with other states. Three were licensed upon the basis of commission in the navy, and one after having passed the examination given by the National Board of Medical Examiners. Members of the first examining board in 1903 were Drs. Benja - min F. Bailey, of Lincoln, W. T. Johnson of Pawnee City, G. H. Brash of Beatrice, E. J. C. Sward of Oakland, and A. B. Somers of Omaha. The 1903 session of the legislature created the office of health in - spector, who was appointed by the board of health from a list recom - mended by the medical examining board. Since that time the work of health inspector and the medical examining board has been separ - ate and distinct. In 1917, a law was passed, known as the Fox Bill, creating the </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 state department of Health, and reorganizing the old department. Un - der this law, the office staff was appointed by the board of health, which consisted of the governor, attorney general, and state superin - tendent of public instruction. The board of four medical examiners was appointed by the governor. Code — In August, 1919, the civil administrative code law went into effect, which made the department of health a part of the department of public welfare, and designated it as the bureau of health. The mem - bers of the medical examining board at that time were Drs. H. J. Lehnhoff of Lincoln, C. L. Mullins of Broken Bow, S. J. Stewart of Beatrice, and J. E. Spatz of Fairfield. The code provided that only three members should serve on the medical examining board, and at present the board consists of Dr. J. E. Spatz, of Fairfield as president, Dr. E. T. McGuire of Mead as vice-president, and Dr. H. J. Lehnhoff of Lincoln as secretary. The code provided that headquarters for all examining boards should be in the Department of Public Welfare. Accordingly, the board of medical examiners was incorporated into the bureau of examining boards of the department of public welfare about September 1, 1919. Finances — Separate cash accounts are kept for all examining boards, and when fees are deposited for the bureau, those for the medical examin - ing board are indicated as such. Since the secretarial work of the medical examining board was placed under the jurisdiction of the de - partment of public welfare, 81 reciprocity fees and 85 examination fees have been received. Examination and reciprocity fees are divided equally among the members of the board. State Association — Officers of the State Medical Gothenburg, president and Dr. R. treasurer. The next meeting of coin, May 9 to 12, inclusive. Association are Dr. M. S. Moore of B. Adams of Lincoln, secretary and the Association will be held in Lin- Complaints — All violations of the law are promptly investigated by the secre- tary of the department. During the biennium, 24 complaints have been investigated, of which 16 have been disposed of, and 8 are still pending. Decisions of attorney general — January 21, 1920, the attorney general ruled that when an applicant had paid a fee, and then could not take the examination, the fee should be returned. </seg>
            <seg id="p053">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 53 Schools — The department of pub'.c welfare has the right to inspect the equipment and methods cf teaching in all medical .schools and collegas of the state, and has the power to refuse examination to applicants of any schools not meeting the required standard. Only applicants who are graduates of a Class A or Class B school, as designated by the American Medical Association, are considered for examination or rec - iprocity in Nebraska, unless, in case of reciprocity, they had begun their practice prior to time of classification of schools. There are at present two medical colleges in Nebraska, viz., the Medical College of the University of Nebraska, and Creighton Medical College, both Class A schools, and located in Omaha. Preliminary education — A preliminary education of four years high school is required be - fore entering upon a medical course. The approved course for a medical school recognized in Nebraska is as follows: The term medical college or school in good standing, for the pur - pose of this article, shall be defined as follows: (1) A legally char - tered medical school or college requiring for admission at least a dip - loma from an accredited high school of this or some other state, or a cei-tificate from the state superintendent of public instruction showing that the applicant has successfully passed an examination covering the branches of study embraced in an accredited high school course, which requirements shall be regularly published in all the advertisements and in each prospectus or catalogue issued by such medical college or school; (2) that said medical college or school in good standing sKall show evidence of modern methods in all its branches of instruction and dem - onstration; (3) that its equipment and facilities for medical instruc - tion shall be modern and shall be kept up to date by the purchase from time to time and use of such equipment as the department shall pre - scribe; (4) that said medical college or school in good standing shall keep and maintain a library consisting of up to date text books and periodicals dealing with medical subjects and questions; (5) that each such medical college or school in good standing shall have access to, own or control, a hospital, and shall conduct a dispensary for poor patients, in both of which the students of said medical college or school shall be required to regularly participate in the treatment of cases; (6) that said medical school in good standing shall have a faculty of at least four who devote their entire time td the teaching of medicine and its associated branches in said school and the remainder of the faculty shall be composed of representative members of the medical profession; (7) that such medical college or school shall also require as a requisite for granting the degree of M. D., attendance upon at </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 least four courses of lectures of eight months each, no two such courses to be held within one year and having a full faculty of capable pro - fessors in all the different branches of medical education, to-wit: anat - omy, physiology, chemistry, toxicology, pathology, hygiene, materia med - ica, therapeutics, obstetrics, bacteriology, medical jurisprudence, gynecol - °i?y. principles and practice of medicine and surgery, and especially re - quiring clinical instruction in the last two named of not less than four hours per week in each week during the last two courses of lectures. Examinations — All applicants for examination must fill out the regular application blank. This blank must be accompanied by the regular fee, an un - mounted photograph of the applicant, and a certified photographic copy of diploma about 4x5 inches. The fee for examination is $25.00, but an exception is made for graduates of Nebraska medical colleges, who are required to pay only a $10.00 fee. Subjects of examination are an - atomy, chemistry, obstetrics, gynecology, pathology, physiology, practice of medicine and physical diagnosis, surgery and bacteriology. The minimum grade in any subject is 60 per cent, and a general average of 70 is required. If a grade of 60 is obtained in three subjects, ap - plicant must take the entire examination a second time. During the biennium examinations have been given as follows: June, 1919; Nov - ember 12, 13 and 14, 1919; June 9, 10 and 11, 1920; November 10, 11 and 12, 1920. January 8, 1920, a special examination was given to two applicants, August 23, 1920, to two applicants, and January 14, 1921, to one applicant. The 1921 examination will be held in Lin - coln, June 7, 8 and 9. Reciprocity — Reciprocity is granted to applicants from other states having re quirements equal to those of Nebraska. All applicants for reciprocity must fill out the regular blank, which must be accompanied by the reg - ular fee, a photograph of applicant, and legally certified copy of diplo - ma. The regular fee for reciprocity is $25.00, but an exception is made for graduates of Nebraska medical colleges, who are required to pay only $10.00. Applicants for reciprocity must have practiced at least one year under license in the state from which they come. Ne - braska has reciprocity with Arkansas, Colorado, Illinois, Lousiana, Miss - issippi, New Jersey, North Dakota, Tennessee, Texas, Vermont, Virgin - ia and Wisconsin on the basis of examination only; with District of Columbia, Georgia, Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Maine, Maryland, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, Nevada, New Hampshire, Ohio, Oklaho - ma, Utah, West Virginia and Washington on the basis of examination, or diploma if applicant graduated from a reputable medical school be - fore August 1903, at which time the Nebraska examination law went into effect. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 55 Applications acted upon during biennium — During the biennium, the following applications have been acted upon by the board: Examination 76 Reciprocity 85 Rejected, reciprocity 5 The following have been licensed during the biennium: Examination Name Address Fred C Armstrong Norman Attwood Ray D. Balcom Gilead Omaha Omaha Dan W. Bolton John A. Borghoff Earl F. Camp Paxico, Kans. Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Raymond P. Carroll Leo W. Chain Ira Otis Church Floyd Collins University Place Ord Freeman S. Coolen George F. Corrigan Herbert H. Davis William F. Deal Charles L. Egbert Edgar A. Elliff College View Omaha Omaha St- Francis, Kans. Hastings Lincoln James North Evans Columbus Culbertson Lincoln William H. Fahrenbruck Clarence E. Frey Oscar W. French Earl T. Gangner Wallace A. Gerrie John C- Giever Alfred C. Graham Ralph D. Green Manuel Grodinsky Harry E. Harvey Walter C. Harvey Austin J. Hebenstreit Maurice C. Howard Thomas L. Houlton Charles B. Huestis Ernest D. Johnson Page Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Beaver City Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Glen A. Jones Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Examination (Cont.) Name Address Samuel L. Keller Fremont Omaha Norfolk Omaha Milton E. Kirkpatrick Rudolph E. Kriz Jacob N. Lande Edmund H. M. Lissack Eugene A. McCabe Lawrence McCormack William O. McDermott Hugh A. McDonald John P. McDonough Bernard McGovern Patrick H. McGowan James H. McLachlin Edward E. McMahon John E. Mannion Omaha Ponca Omaha Omaha Hastings Omaha Vale, la. Omaha Lincoln Omaha Ponca Fred R. Metheny William H- Melcher Walter C. Miller Harold R. Mulligan Edward J. Mulholland Bradford J. Murphy Floyd J. Murray Lincoln Omaha Council Bluffs Beatrice Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Hildreth Stamford Omaha Nathan Muskin J. William Neville Robert C. Olney Andrew M. Pederson Albert M. Pfeffer Omaha Lincoln Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Fremont Lincoln Omaha Paul H. Priest William T. Ranee Sol. E- Ravitz Isador Rips Francis X. Rudloff Andrew Sinamark Frederick W. Shank Howard C. Stewart Raymond Surber Waterbury Omaha G. Dean Tipton Frank J. Tobin Otto M. Troester James H. Walvoord Charles R. Weeth -Charles A. Weymuller Omaha Hampton Holland Omaha Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p057">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 57 Reciprocity Name Address John H. Adair Wall, So. Dak. Omaha Theodore M. Agnew Earvye H- Anderson Merton O. Arnold Charles G. Baird Stephen T. Bayle Peter W. Beckman Paul Black Omaha St. Paul Beatrice Dawson Lindsborg, Kans. Lincoln Edward A. Bowles Harry A. Briggs Albertus H. Buis Hebron Archer Pender Daniel L. Burgeson Hastings Hastings Omaha Edna F. Patterson-Burgeson Edward G. Cary Lille Forrest Chapman Placid N. Chaisson Lincoln Nebraska City Omaha Karl A. Connell Alexander J. Courshon Springview Omaha Clarence E. Cowles Ralph G. Cressman Philip I. Cromwell Earl E. Dale Hastings Henry, 111. Harrison Lincoln Edwin G. Davis William L. Davis Otto F. Dierker Wilfred G. Drouin Allison H. Dugdale J. T. Edwards Neligh Beatrice Holyoke, Mass. New York Omaha Arthur Omaha Lincoln Fred F. Fan- Shirley D- Folsom Guy V. Forney Earl E. Griggs Anthony L. Hawkins Charles Hayes Scottsbluff Omaha Hastings Alliance Charles Hibbe Thomas L. Howden Seth F. H. Howes William P. Hunnicutt William S. Hunter Mathaus H. Horn Pawnee City Grand Island Lincoln Fort Robinson Bethany Elgie M. Houghton Maurice C. James Elizabeth Jamieson Iven G. Johnson Cassville, Wis. Columbus College View Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Reciprocity (Contd.) Name Address Joseph H. Johnson Carl Kail Berwyn Lincoln Omaha Farnum Ashland Cook William H. Kingman Merton R. Kittridge John J. Lancer John F. G. Luepke Charles F. Lyle John C. Lyman Gilead Omaha James W. McCarty Earl D. McGill Rat, Missouri. Blue Hill Robert S. Martin Sidney A. Merriam William P. Miller George H. Misko Harris C. Moore Harold F. Morrison Ben E. Nicola Red Cloud Omaha Pawnee City Arcadia Brock Lincoln College View Verdigree John R. Newman Stephen B. Northcross John J. O'Hearn Omaha Council Bluffs Wymore Roy E. Peters Coskie A. Pruner Sidney O. Reese Roscoe C. Riddle Orville C. Reed Henry C. Ritchey Sol Rosenblatt Weaver A- Rush John F. Smith Samuel Sprecher Kennard Lincoln Omaha Hastings Bridgeport Superior Beatrice West Point Tripp, So. Dak. Aurora Edmund K. Steenburg James R. Taylor Sidney Edward M. Thies John C. Thompson Frank R. Vieregg Adda Mae Whaley Herbert Wiggins Charles A. Walters Joseph P. Weyrens Joseph H. Wheat Hartington Lincoln Roseland Charter Oak, Iowa. Omaha Winnetoon Alliance Omaha Registered on basis of U. S. Navy Commission John J. Freyman Great Lakes, 111. Great Lakes, 111. Frank Mills Hoacock Gretna </seg>
            <seg id="p059">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 59 Registered after having passed National Board of Medical Examiners Clarence Stiles McKee Geneva Geneva REPORT ON DIVISION OF NURSING Biennium ending April 1, 1921. First Law— At the regular annual meeting of the Nurses' State Association, in 1&amp;08, a legislative committee was appointed to investigate nursing legislation in other states preparatory to the introducing of a bill to the legislature of 1909. A bill was prepared, passed as written, and approved by the Governor, March 24, 1909. This law provided for three examiners or secretaries to the State Board of Health, composed of the Governor, Attorney General and State Superintendent of Public Instruction. The above Board was authorized to issue licenses until the Civil Administrative Code went into effect, in 1919. The examiners were required to be nurses engaged in active work, graduates for at least one year from a reputable training school requiring not less than one year duration in actual hospital practice. The requirements were: Evidence of good moral character, age 21, educational equivalent for admission to high school, graduate from training school of two or three years training. Graduates of special hospitals were required to have six months additional training after January 1, 1911. Those who had six months training and twelve months actual practice in addition were allowed to register without examination by filing application and pay - ing regular fee prior to September 1, 1910. Anyone having had two - years actual practice in nursing and recommended by four reputable physicians and passing the examination of the Board, was eligible for registration before January 1, 1910. Accredited Schools — In 1912, the first standards were fixed for the accreditment of schools for nurses. Amendments — In 1913 the law was amended to repeal the waiver on six months training and two years practice. It extended the time of registra - tion indefinitely on graduates of\ special hospitals who had six months additional training in an approved general hospital. 1915 — New Law — In 1915 the old law was repealed and a new law put on the stat - utes creating a board of examiners of five, recommended by the Ne - braska State Association of Graduate Nurses. The principal require - ments follow: Age was increased for registration to twenty- two; edu - cational requirements increased to one year high school, and time in </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 training to three years. The waiver on the old requirements extended to June 1, 1918. Nurses who graduated before January 1, 1905, were given the privilege of registering without examination before May 1, 1916. Headquarters provided for at Capitol — The 1915 law provided for headquarters for the Nurses' Examin - ing Board at the State Capitol. The records excepting those for im - mediate use had been kept at the Capitol since 1913. A full time secretary was employed by the Board in 1916 and office was provided at her place of residence in Omaha. The office equipment and records were moved to the State House June 1, 1917, where they remained under a full time secretary, the Examining Board, and the State Board of Health, until August 2, 1919, when the Civil Administrative Code went into effect. Under Code — The 1919 legislature amended the nursing law, making citizenship in the United States a requirement for license, the preliminary edu - cation was increased to two years high school or the equivalent, and hospitals not meeting the requirements of the American Red Cross pri - marily or by affiliation were required to do so. After the Civil Ad - ministrative Code Law was passed, the nurses' bill was amended to re - duce the fee from ten to five dollars. When the law was written into the Code it was not written in as it appeared on the statutes, and the nursing profession lost most of the foundation that they had in their Waiver Licenses — Under the first law, 465 nurses were licensed without examination. From that date until the beginning of this biennium, 1020 were licensed by examination, waiver or reciprocity. During the biennium, 411 have been licensed, 78 of these .by reciprocity, making a total of 1896 li - censed since the first law in 1909. Applications Rejected — During the biennium, nine applications were rejected, six because of inadequate training, one because applicant was not recommended by the hospital of graduation, and one because she was not a citizen. Subjects of Examination — The subjects of examination are: Anatomy and Physiology, Bac - teriology and Hygiene, Materia Medica, Obstetrics, Medical nursing, Surgical Nursing, Dietetics, Pediatrics and Acute Infections, and Ethics, Mental and Nervous Diseases. Examinations are held twice a year in May and November. </seg>
            <seg id="p061">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 61 Duplicate Licenses — There were two duplicate licenses issued during the biennium. Duplicates may be issued upon satisfactory affidavit showing that the original license has been destroyed, lost or stolen, and upon payment of a two dollar fee. First Board — The first Nurses' .Examining Board was Catherine Wollgast, now deceased, graduate of Good Samaritan Hospital, Sioux City; Victoria Anderson, of Methodist Hospital, Brooklyn, and Anna Hardwick, of New York City Hospital. Personnel of Board- At the time the Code went into effect August 2, 1919, there wers but three of the five members of the Board, due to the fact that the usual appointments were not urged May 1, pending the new appoint - ments expected under the Code. A full time secretary of the Board was automatically out of office, there being no provision for a sec - retary of the Board on salary. Misses Marie Wieck and Louise Brack - hahn of Omaha remained on the Board, and Ida Gerding of Beatrice was appointed as the third member by Mr.' H. H. Antles, the new Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare, and ex-officio secre - tary of all examining boards. Miss Wieck's term expired May 1, 1920. There being no recommendation from the State Association, Mr. Antles requested Miss Wieck to remain until appointment was made. Miss Jennie Higgins of Lincoln was appointed to fill the va - cancy and was also made inspector of training schools, for the fall of 1020. Miss Brackhahn is president of the Board, Miss Gerding vice - president, and Miss Higgins secretary. All of the training schools excepting two new ones were visited either by Miss Higgins or Miss Brackhahn during the fall of 1920. There were thirty-two training schools reported. Three hospitals closed their training schools during the year, and two hospitals opened training schools. Eighteen were recommended for full accreditment for one year and eight were recommended pending minor changes, im - provements, or adjustments, and five were recommended to have ma - jor adjustments such as records of training school, proper teaching equipment, proper instruction, and affiliation with other schools for work not adequately given in the mother hospital. At the time of inspection there were 203 students in first year, 204 in second year, and 225 in third year classes, or a total student nurse body of 632. Questionnaires sent out during the summer of 1918 show 628 student nurses in the training schools of Nebraska at that time. The maximum allowance given to student nurses by hospitals in Nebraska is $35.00, the minimum $6.00. Two training schools give </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 no allowance. Two thousand four hundred beds are represented in the hospitals having training schools. The minimum salary paid sup - erintendents was $100.00 a month and maintenance; the maximum, $200.00 and maintenance. Inspection of the schools in Nebraska, and in other .states, shows that certain reforms are necessary in nurses' training schools if they are to obtain a healthy growth. Among these needed reforms are better housing facilities for students, shorter hours of duty for stu - dents so that they are not reduced to such a condition of fatigue that they are deprived of the proper time for study and are unable to profit by the instruction for which they give their services, adequate services for practical work, part or full time nurse instructors, and closer sup - ervision of practical work. The following theoretical course suggested to the training schools is the minimum outlined by the National League for Nursing Educa - tion as presented in the National Curriculum: Preparatory or First Year hours Anatomy and Physiology 60 Bacteriology 20 Personal Hygiene 10 Applied Chemistry 20 Nutrition and Cookery 40 Hospital Housekeeping 10 Drugs and Solutions 20 Elementary Nursing Principles and Methods 60 Bandaging 10 History of Nursing (including Social and Ethical Principles) 15 Elements of Pathology 10 Nursing in Medical Diseases 20 Nursing in Surgical Diseases 20 Materia Medica and Therapeutics 20 Diet in Disease 10 Elements of Psychology (recommended) 10 Total 345 to 355 Junior or Second Year Nursing in Communicable Diseases 20 Nursing in Diseases of Infants and Children (includ- ing infant feeding) 20 Massage 10 Principles of Ethics 10 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 63 Gynecological Nursing 10 Orthopedic Nursing 10 Operating Room Technique 10 Obstetrical Nursing 20 Nursing in Diseases of the Eye, Ear, Nose and Throat 10 Total— 120 Senior or Third Year Nursing in Mental and Nervous Diseases 20 Nursing in Occupational, Venereal and Skin Diseases 10 Special Therapeutics (including Occupational Therapy) 10 Public Sanitation 10 Survey of the Nursing Field 10 Modern Social Conditions 10 Professional Problems 10 Emergency Nursing and First Aid 10 ♦Introduction to Public Health Nursing and "I Social Service 10 hrs. | ♦Introduction to Institutional Work 10 hrs. I ♦Introduction to Laboratory Work 10 hrs.j- 30 ♦Housekeeping Problems of Industrial Fam - ilies 10 hrs. ♦Special Disease Problems 10 hrs.i Total— 120 Total number of hours for the three years 585 ♦Subjects starred are elective, to be selected according to the student's future line of work. A complete outline of each subject may be found in the National Curricu- lum. The following hospitals in Nebraska conduct training schools for nurses : Alliance _ Beatrice - St. Joseph's Hospital Beatrice Sanitarium Lutheran Hospital Mennonite Hospital David City David City Hospital Falls City Community Hospital Grand Island Grand Island General St. Francis Hospital Hastings Mary Lanning Memorial Nebraska Sanitarium </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 Lincoln Bailey Sanatorium Esther's Hospital Lincoln Hospital Lincoln Sanitarium Orthopedic Hospital St. Elizabeth's Campbell Hospital City Hospital Norfolk General North Platte General Clarkson Hospital Fenger Hospital Ford Hospital Nicholas Senn Hospital Methodist Hospital Presbyterian Hospital St. Catherine's Hospital St. Joseph's Swedish Mission University Hospital Wise Memorial Morrow Lutheran Norfolk North Platte Omaha Seward York _. Note — It is found necessary to revise the accredited list at different times during the year due to the fact that recommendations are carried out at irregular times. Those interested are therefore requested not to depend upon any public list but are advised to consult the Department for authentic infor - mation as to the standing of schools for nurses. Preliminary Education — Student Nurse Certificates — Students entering training schools before June 1, 1920, were required to present evidence of one year high school or the equivalent. Since that time two years or the equivalent are required. During the biennium, 464 student nurse certificates were issued. Two hundred and seven of these had four years high school or more. Student nurse certificates are regularly issued when the student enters training or before she finishes her probation. Several student nurses have made up part of their high school credits through their own efforts or with the help of the hospital. Certificates are not issued to students under nineteen • years of age. During the war concessions were made and certificates issued to students of eighteen years and six months. Complaints — Fifty-nine complaints were received during the biennium. Twenty- </seg>
            <seg id="p065">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 65 five notices to these parties were returned unclaimed, indicating- that there were nurses who remained in the state a short time, practiced with - out a license, and removed to another state. Twenty became registered, seven were ineligible, and seven complaints were unfounded. Reciprocity — There is but one reciprocity agreement in nursing, and that is with Iowa. The qualifications are not uniform throughout the country and nurses are accepted from other states without examination on their indi - vidual qualifications. Nebraska accepted nurse registrants from the following states since April 1, 1919: California 2; Colorado 9; Georgia 1; Illinois 22; Iowa 18; Kansas 4; Kentucky 1; Louisiana 1; Massachusetts 2; Michigan 1; Minnesota 1; Missouri 4; New Jersey 2; New York 3; Oklahoma 1; South Dakota 2; Wisconsin 4. Nebraska endorsed applications of nurses to the following states: California 7; Colorado 13; Idaho 2; Indiana 1; Iowa 4; Kansas 5; Ken - tucky 1; Missouri 2; Oklahoma 1; Pennsylvania 1; South Dakota 4; Wy - oming 1. Affiliations — The University of Nebraska Hospital and the Methodist Hospital in Omaha offer affiliation to some of our smaller Nebraska Hospitals. Other hospitals with which Nebraska hospitals affiliate are: Illinois Training School, Chicago; Michael Reese, Chicago; and the Denver City and County Hospital. Special affiliations are offered in Omaha at the Child Saving Institute and with the Public Health Organizations. The length of affiliation that is required varies from four to twelve months. Affiliations with Institutions on Educational Basis — University of Nebraska — The University Hospital in Omaha affiliates with the University of Nebraska. Young women who wish to take a combined course for a degree may take a five year combined academic and professional course leading to the A. B. or B. Sc. degree according to the subjects covered, and to the nursing diploma. At least two years and four months of this time must be spent in the school of nursing. During the summer of 1920, a ten weeks preliminary course for nurses was conducted at the Hastings High School in connection with the Mary Lanning Hospital and the Nebraska Sanitarium at Hastings, under the supervision of Mr. A. H. Stahley, Superintendent of Hastings City Schools, and Miss Ethel Odegard who was Director of Training. The State Board for Vocational Education functioned in the Hastings course by reimbursing the local school board for three-fourths of the salaries of the teachers and supervising instruction and administration. The ten weeks' course covered the following hours: Nutrition and Cookery — </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 75; Chemistry — 75; Ethics — 15; Anatomy and Physiology— 75 ; Elemen - tary Course on Drugs — 10; Bacteriology and Hygiene — 75; History of Nursing — 25; Nursing Procedures— 40. Nursing Procedures were taught in the hospital from which the nurse probationer was sent. The result of the course was very satisfactory to the hospital concerned- It was the first attempt in the state to connect the nursing school with the high school system. The prevalent opinion of the nurse educators of the country is that the training of nurses will not be satisfactory until the training schools are connected or correlated with the public school system. The State Board for Vocational Education does not initiate such courses but is ready to assist if a written request is made by any Nebraska school A plan for time and subject credit which may be allowed in the nurses' training course was adopted by the State Board of Health in 1918, as follows: 1. Whenever a candidate for nurses' training shall present in addi - tion to a four year high school course credits equaling twelve semester hours in any of the following subjects — Chemistry, physiology, anatomy, bacteriology, zoology, botany, domestic science, dietetics, histology, phar - macy, physics, and in addition, cultural college credits making a total of sixty (60) college hours, said candidates may be granted time credit, of from one to three calendar months, by the training school authorities. 2. Whenever a candidate shall present in addition to a four year high school course, credits in the above named scientific subjects equalling eighteen (18) semester hours and, in addition cultural credits making a total of ninety (90) college hours, from three to six months time credit may be allowed. 3. To graduates of accredited colleges, presenting a mimimum of twenty-four (24) semester hours in the scientific branches above named, from six to nine months time credit may be allowed. 4. All candidates must have their credits evaluated and the evalua - tion signed by the State Superintendent of Public Instruction. NURSES LICENSED DURING THE BIENNIUM Name ■ Address Address Adams, Juvia, Ray Lincoln Adams, Mary E. Omaha Ahlstedt, Margareta Lincoln Almquist, Mary V- Omaha Anderson, Mabel A. Holdrege Anderson, Mae Bernice Omaha Anderson, Gertrude Marie Omaha Antram, Estelle B. Tobias </seg>
            <seg id="p067">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 67 Name Address Arbuthnot, Bess Baker, Clare Omaha Omaha Bates, Dessey K. Beebe, Vesta Long Pine Omaha Benning, Marguerite Council Bluffs Lincoln Bentley, Mabel Pearl (Mrs.) Berk, Anna M. Lincoln Bertranda, Sister Mary Bethea, Hazel Grand Island Ewing Biebesheimer, Maxine E. Bieber, Bessie Ethel Beatrice St. Edwards Omaha Bihler, Agnes Bishop, Olive Louise Blair, Ruth J. Omaha Lincoln Borg, Ruth Elvira Boyd, Hazel I. Wakefield Columbus Omaha Brackbill, Pearl B. Bradford, Elizabeth Brannen, Sr. M. Inez Brich, Georgia Omaha Omaha Pender Dunbar Omaha Venango Bricknell, Charlotte L. Brinker, Anna M. Broughton, Dolores V. Brown, Blanche Harriett College View Council Bluffs St. Edward Browder, Mabel Quick (Mrs.) Brunk, Bertha Brt, Rose Milligan Omaha Clarkson Buick, Lillian J. Bukacek, Etta J. Burgeson, Florence Burgess, Hazel Zadia Burke, Elizabeth V. Burke, Mary L. College View Omaha Lincoln Omaha Schuyler Lincoln Burkerd, Lola R. Byers, Harriet Carey, Josephine B. Carlson, Allida Lead, S. D. Hastings Cass, Bertha Willdora Charlton, Clara E. Christianson, Augusta V. Council Bluffs Omaha Holbrook Omaha Clancy, Mabel McMillian (Mrs.) Clark, Vineta Fae Omaha Norfolk Orchard Omaha Clements, Florence M. Clifton, Golda Violet Coffin, Vada *&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Name Address Cole, Eunice P. Omaha Ej, Florence Ann nell, Margaret k, Mira Jane Hastings Omaha Red Cloud Cordes, Willie Elmer (Mrs.) Corn, Alta College View Lincoln Corrick, Mary Cratty, Irene L, Omaha Elgin Crounse, Marie (LeRoy) (Mrs.) Crowe, Eileen M. Omaha Omaha Cunningham, Gladys M. Curtis, Viola Maye Fullerton Omaha Czaplik, Ottilia Omaha Danneeker, Mathilde Dawson, Ruth Elizabeth Davis, Sibyl C. Rulo North Platte Omaha Delaney, J. Teresa Denne, Maude Fremont Atlanta, Iowa Omaha Depweg, Sr. M. Gotharda DeWitt, Bertha Reed College View Spalding DeWulf, Margaret Diener, Eleonora Caroline Dixon, Lena Deshler Omaha Omaha Chester Drew, Anna Drapalik Duey, Ellen Marie Dugger, Vera Belle Dykema, Irene M. Ogenda, Kas. Lincoln Lincoln Beyer, Gertrude Julia irmann, Gertrude nhut, Vera Alice Eklund, Blenda Augusta Elliott, Julia Lightner Ernstmeyer, Rose Emerson Lincoln Holdrege Columbus Grand Island University Place Hastings Erving, Grace Vivian Evans, Ethel E. Farley, Edith May (Mrs.) Feuerstein, Rose G. Lincoln Fremont Norfolk Omaha Omaha Wahoo Finley, Ruth J. Fisher, Mabel S. Fitzpatrick, Mildred C. Fjellin, Emma A. Flannigan, Anna Fletcher, Avis Ellen Omaha Lincoln Foley, Margaret Mauree Hartington </seg>
            <seg id="p069">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 69 Name Address Foley, Mary Anne Ford, Ellen Teresa Omaha Omaha Frazell, Marietta Purcell Frazier, Grace Broken Bow College View Hastings Frederickson, Dagmar Frink, Lydia Pender Fulton, Dorothy R. Fairfield, Iowa Galda, Frances Omaha York Gallagher, Mary C. Ganzel, Eva J. O±oe City Milford Garner, Marguerite Garvey, Marian V. Gatz, Gertrude W. Gearhart, Nora A. Gishpert, Edith Albion Omaha College View Randolph Gibson, Neta Blanche Glasser, Sophia L. Gosar, Elizabeth Anna Graves, LaFern Crystal Griffin, Marie M. Hastings Bradshaw Omaha Hastings Norfolk Normal Grote, Bertha W. Guilfoyle, Kathryn Ellen Hadley, Mary Council Bluffs, la. Holmesville Hagquist, Anna M. Hanchett, Dorothy Hankins, Mary Helen Hanisch, Beata Omaha Papillion Omaha Rockville Upland Hansen, Marie Harris, Sophia E. Hart, Grace W. Beatrice Atkinson Lincoln Omaha Heidemann, Caroline Marie Heinen, Lydia K. Hampel, Elsie Omaha Bladen Lincoln Omaha Lincoln Omaha Fremont Omaha Lincoln Hooper Omaha Hansen, Anna Martha P. Hayes, Anna V. Heller, Julia J. Helsing, Ida Henricksen, A. M. Adele Hensen, Mathilda A. Herstein, Sarah Esther Hicks, Alice F. Himebaugh, Gail Hines, Irene Hill, Myrtle Huugate Hittle, Helen North Platte Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 Name Address Omaha Norfolk Roca Hobson, Lucille K. Hofeldt, Merle L. Hoffman, Eva M. Hofseth, Astrid Holan, Marie Omaha Omaha Omaha Lincoln Omaha Hollar, Lolu B. Houser, Mabel Howell, Peytona L. iMrs.) Hoyrup, Christinna Hastings Omaha Hyatt, Hattie Mae Hynding, Sine M. Tyler, Minn. Jarrett, Harriet Jensen, Esther C, Jerger, Sarah Johnson, Inez C- Johnson, Ethel Milford Harlan, Iowa Omaha Omaha Omaha Axtell Superior Omaha Holdrege Omaha Johnson, Hildore Elvera Johnson, Flora I. Johnson, Effie S. Johnson, Ruth E. Johnson, Frieda A. Johnson, Marie E. Johnson, Bessie M. Jones, Lillie Viola Johnston, Agnes W. Jonas, Alice L. Omaha Ringgold Axtell Omaha Clarkson Omaha Joos, Gertrude E. Jorgensen, Marentine L. Jugler, Inez LaVerne Kady, Elsie E. Benkelman Omaha Hastings Omaha Kavanaugh, Mary Irene Kaveney, Regina B- Kavanaugh, Sr. M. Marcella Keller, Belle Fullerton Omaha Octavia Omaha Kellison, Maud L. Kelly, Pauline Nell Kernan, Celestine A. Kerr, Florence Margaret Killeen, Bessie Creighton Omaha Akron, Iowa North Bend Blair King, Leta Faye Kirkpatrick, Mabel C. Kjar, Dorothy Anna Klein, Ludmila A. Kleinholz, Margaret V. Kline, Anna Omaha Holdrege Brainard Dorchester Omaha </seg>
            <seg id="p071">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 71 Name Address Beatrice Krauss, Anna Estella Krause, Ruby Constance Hartington Lagerquist, Hannah Larsen, Sadie Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Lavine, Eunice C. Lawler, Alicia R. Lease, Florence E. Leibee, Deborah R. Leonard, Alta (Mrs.) Levy, Juliet College View Shelby Basse tt Omaha Lincoln Norfolk Lincoln Stanton Greeley Lippincott, Maybelle M. Lodes, Fae R. Baer Loeffler, Margaret M. Lowry, Grace M. Lukefahr, Kathryn Lull, Hallie E. Luther, Ethel Grace North Platte Oconto McCabe, Grace Irene Evelyn McCreary, Alice E. Hastings Omaha McClintick, Henrietta Albion Omaha Herman Funk McGuire, Mary Katherine McKercher, Cleo Mae Malm, Sigrid E. Malzacher, Josephine Manning, Blanche Oakdale Lincoln Lincoln Mapes, Nelle J. Marsh, Lillian Falls City West Point Omaha Marschall, Elizabeth L. Marshall, Dollie Carter Martin, Anva Dorcus Martin, Allison Laurel Martin, Anna Dorcas Matzen, Emma Lincoln Omaha Omaha Columbus Havelock Wayne Melick, Florence Hazel Meister, Cecilia Mendelssohn, Blanche E. Miller, Gertrude University Place Minden Miller, Helen Rae David City Omaha Miller, Marie Margaret Miller, Viola Lincoln Minden Omaha Miller, Alydia Miller, Martha Hastings Arapahoe Norfolk Miller, Bernice Lucille Mills, Mae Mittelstaedt, Clara </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 La. Name Address Momsen, Irene L. Omaha Omaha Pontgomery, Nannie Pollack oody, Edith J. Hastings Schuyler Hastings Moore, Edith Mae Moore, Frances Beta Morgan, C. Blanche Moss, Frances Lenora Mower, Deborah Nebraska City Omaha Omaha Lincoln Omaha Omaha Hebron Omaha Lincoln Atlanta Chapman Eourer, Katherine oyer, Marie A. ullen, Nellie T. Murchie, Sue Henderson Murphy, Helen I. Murphy, Marquand Louise Murray, Ruth Ellen Musilek, Agnes Marie Neal, Lucie Emma Neal, Eura Omaha Omaha Nelson, Emma E. Nelson, Mary Esther Nelson, Sena College View Bassett Minden Herman Genoa Nelson, Viola Lillian Nelson, Rose Neugebauer, Adele New, Velma Del Steinauer Rushville Omaha Newhouse, Jennie Willard Newman, Nettie Omaha Newman, Ada A. Nicola, Blanche Mason City Omaha Nicolay, Sr. M. Euprosina Nielsen, Ella M. Omaha Dannebrog Noel, Olive B. (Mrs.) Nollmann, Emma R. Norton, Beth North Platte Omaha Omaha Omaha Oakley, Ella F. O'Connor, Nora Fremont Hastings Odegard, Ethel Janette Oertel, M- Hildegarde Olson, Charlotte F. New Orleans, Omaha O'Malley, Grace Omaha Omaha Omaha York O'Neill, Emma Mabel O"Neil, Margaret Opitz, Amelia Margaret CRourke, Hazel Veronica Osiek, Anna Omaha College View </seg>
            <seg id="p073">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 73 Name Address Wahoo Omaha Omaha Omaha Ceresco Omaha Omaha Packard, Helen Marie Palm, Florence L. Parker, Margarette Payne, Beatrice Muriel Pearson, Euphemia J. Peck, Laura E. Penwell, Lucin Mary Peterson, Dora Valnetta Peterson, Euphemia Dannebrog Lincoln Petersen, Mathilda Omaha Sargent Peterson, Mabel Taylor Peterson, Gussie V. West Point Kenesaw Peterson, Olga Pflueger, Lydia M. Phipps, Stella J. Pischel, Adele B. Plumb, Helen Mary Podoll, Elsie Irene Prasch, Julia Ellen West Point Harrison Pischelville York Norfolk Lexington Quinn, Alice M. Columbus Raffler, Lela E. Ralph, Ellen J. Rasmussen, Helen Reed, Dorothy M. Reed, Ellenore Lincoln West Point Herman St. Edward Omaha Richardson, Edith Ricketts, Grace M. Rivett, Helen E. Roberts, Lillian Pearl Robinson, Ruth F. Salem Omaha College View Omaha Beatrice Omaha Omaha Hastings Hooper Omaha Rock, Elizabeth Catherine Ross, Lucille M. Rose, Bess M. Russ, Elizabeth C. Rutschman, Amelia Salyers, Anna Arapahoe Lincoln Sampson, Elsie M. Samuelson, Laura Sanders, Grace K. Schechter, Helen Omaha Polk College View Seward Schuelke, Emma M. J. Scott, Leona V. Battle Creek North Platte Omaha Scott, Martha A. Seitz, Christine Rose </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 D Name Address West Point Hooper Sexton, Mabel Feme Shaffer, Anna May Sherwood, Ina Amarina Shreck, Anna 8. Beatrice York Republican City West Point Shriver, Gertrude M. Simpson, Mabel E. Sisler, Kathleen Geneva Skinner, Mabelle Skinner, Nelle Hastings Big Horn, Wyo. Omaha Slasor, Frances Ward Smith, Sarah Ethel Smith, Olive Hedrick, la. Lincoln. Smith, Esther Irene Smith, Selma Lemmel Smith, Minnie Edna Lincoln Beatrice Omaha York Snyder, Edith Montgomery Sohrt, Minnie B. Wahoo Sonderman, Elizabeth C. Speelman, Myrtle Grand Island Omaha Spurrier, Elfie Viola Bloomfield Omaha Spry, Cecile Tracy (Mrs.) Stainton, Alice Mary Omaha Starliper, Mary Stasch, Cecilia Steele, Mary E. Stein, Florence Steinbach, Ella M. Rapid City, S. Lincoln Beatrice Hastings Kearney Stenger, Catherine A. (St. Consolata) Alliance Stockham, Edithe J. Streeter, Florence Suiter, Anna Myrtle Swanson, Alice V- Broken Bow Hastings Indianola Monroe Talbert, Belle S. Seward Talcott, Sarah Elizabeth (Mrs-) Lincoln Theil, Catherine Lincoln Thiessen, Margie Ravenna Thomas, Grace Osmond Tompkins, Mabel L. Omaha Thompson, Lillyan Faye Franklin Thompson, Florence M. Omaha Thompson, Mary Ellen (Mrs.) York Thompson, May L. Omaha Thompson, Elizabeth Burt Omaha Thrasher, Thelma Eva Alexandria Tigbe, Mary Josephine Bancroft </seg>
            <seg id="p075">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 75 Name Address Osceola Clarkson Omaha Timm, Arvilla L. Tomes, Adela Olga Trailer, Grace V. Travis, Lola Evelyn Trojan, Lucile Anne Trauernicht, Johanna Tucker, Myra Lincoln Leigh Wymore Omaha Omaha Omaha Harvard Tully, Margaret Ellen Tupper, Mabel E. Turner, Jessie Mae Udey, Clara Blanche Omaha Wachtel, Mary E. Omaha Harvard Omaha Lincoln Lincoln Hebron Axtell Wadsworth, Maude Elizabeth Wagner, Kathryn E. Wass, Lucille A. Weichel, Selma K. Wellensick, Alvina M. Wendell, Esther Weyerts, Marie J. Venango Beatrice Whalen, Minnie Tinkham Whipple, Ruth Ann Nebraska City Bethany White, Bertha Grace Willard, Inez Omaha Norfolk Omaha Lincoln Omaha Lincoln Omaha Omaha Linwood Omaha Omaha Omaha Wille, Esther A. Williams, Elizabeth G. Wilson, Hanna L. Winters, Nellie T. Wirt, Addie N. Wittlake, Minnie P. Witzke, Mary S. Wood, Martha M. Wood, Ruth Woolverton, Doreatha M. Wray, Gladys Wright, Beata Louise Wright, Dorothy Eloise Wright, Mabel Kansas City Omaha Omaha Grand Island Wright, Marjorie E. Youngscap, Frona Omaha Zehm, Susie Belle College View &gt;j </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 REPORT ON OPTOMETRY DIVISION For the Biennium Ending April 1, 1921 First Law — The first meeting of the Nebraska State Board of Optometry creat - ed by the thirty-first session of the legislature of Nebraska, and duly commissioned by Governor Sheldon, was held at the Paxton Hotel Omaha September 27, 1907. Mr. C. C. McLeese of Davenport, J. C. Huteson, Omaha and Max J. Egge of Grand Island constituted the first board. tThe law of 1907 made it compulsory to have a license in order to lly fit glasses. Provision was made for three secretaries of five •s practice recommended by the Nebraska State Optometry Society le Governor. Those who were engaged in the practice of Optometry two years were exempt from examination. Annual renewal was dded for at one dollar a year. A licensee was required to display license at his place of business and to give a bill of purchase with signature, address, and number of license when he practiced away i his place of business. Use of Dr. or Doctor — t January 28, 1908, it was necessary for the Board to rule that a li - b would be revoked for using the title Doctor or Dr. or attending ty fairs under the protection of a state license. Licensure — Two hundred and sixty-nine exemption licenses were issued before the first examination. The first examination was held at the Y. M. C. A. in Omaha, January 29 and 30, 1908. Most of those who received exemption licenses took the examination and received examination li - censes. Before April 1, 1919, 269 exemption licenses and 304 licenses following the examination, were issued by the Nebraska State Board of t During the biennium, forty-three were licensed by examination and by reciprocity. The latter's grades on theory were accepted from »is and a practical examination was given by the Board. Code— kWhen the Civil Administrative Code went into effect in August, 1919, Board was comprised of the following members: F. C. Calhoun, of nee City, president; H. R. Tillotson, of Harvard, vice-president, and t. Combs of Omaha, secretary and treasurer. Personnel of Board — Mr. Charles S. Dixon of North Platte succeeded Mr. Tillotson upon K removal from the state during the summer of 1920. Mr. G. S. Dun - of Lincoln succeeded Mr. Combs upon the expiration of his term, </seg>
            <seg id="p077">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 77 January 1, 1921. There are 381 optometrists in good standing in Nebraska. The annual renewal fee is one dollar payable before the first of April. The Board held two regular meetings for examination during the biennium, and one special meeting for the re-organization of the Board at the time the records were turned over to the Department of Public Welfare. The subjects of examination and ratings are as follows Possible Points Written theory 500 Opthalmoscope i 60 The required points for passing are 825. There is no actual reciprocity agreement in Optometry, the laws not yet being sufficiently regular throughout the country. When an applicant is registered by examination in another state having equal requirements to that of Nebraska, his grades may be accept - ed providing he passes a practical examination. Violations from October 1919 to April 1, 1921 The Nebraska Association of Optometrists will hold its next annual meeting in Lincoln, May 2 and 3, preceeding the regular examination for licenses. This examination will be held May 4, 5, and 6 at the State Capitol. Retinoscope 60 Opthalmometer 50 Trial Case Handling instruments 50 Handling patients 50 Accuracy and General Findings 100 Neutralizations of Lenses 100 Bending frames to measurements 30 Oral 100 Total : 1,100 'omplaints unfounded 4 'ook examination 1 ,eft State 1 )therwise disposed of satisfactorily 6 'ending . 3 Total 15 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 Mr. B. B. Combs was a delegate from the examining board to Ihe National Convention at St. Louis, June 13 to 19, 1920. Optometrists Licensed during the biennium Name Address Fairbury Omaha Ackerman, Edwin B. Baker, Jay S. Beckwith, Orson H. Ber,ger, Albert H. Bilon, Louis V. Beatrice Kearney Omaha Lincoln Omaha Omaha Lincoln Norfolk Omaha Omaha York Boyd, Basil Brandt, Henry F. Cameron, Ralph A. Carlson, Clarence R. Coleman, Wm. B- Cop eland, Jacob Cubbison, Walter H. Davis, Kenneth D. Eveland, Harry D. Friedman, Arthur Hafner, Joseph J. Haworth, George W. Hazlett, Jesse W. Hertert, Lucien R. Hofmann, A. Council Bluffs Omaha Omaha Aurora Omaha Omaha Omaha Omaha Lincoln Omaha Omaha Lincoln Hug, Warren A. Kindy, Roy O. Maher, Thos. F. Melvin, Ormel J. Morrison, Neil C. Robir.son, Fred C. Seiple, Leonard R. Smith, Ralph Earl Truex, Dean S. Warde, Roy O. Woods, Albert D. Hastings Omaha Tecumseh Lincoln Lincoln Omaha OSTEOPATHY History up to Time of .Code — The first law regulating the practice of osteopathy in the state of Nebraska was passed in 1901. This law provided that any person wish - ing to practice osteopathy in the state of Nebraska must obtain a license from the State Board of Health. This license was obtained upon pre - sentaion of diploma. Under this law 219 were licensed. In 1905, the first examination law for the practice of osteopathy </seg>
            <seg id="p079">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 79 was passed. This law required that any person desiring to practice os - teopathy in the state of Nebraska must, in addition to presenting diplo - ma from a recognized school of osteopathy, pass the examination given by the State Board of Medical Examiners. Under this law 11 were licensed. In 1909, the legislature passed an act creating the State Board of Osteopathy, consisting of the governor as chairman, and five examiners appointed by the governor. This law, like the law of 1905, provided for license upon the basis of diploma and examination, and provided for reciprocity upon basis of examination or five years previous practice. Under this law 120 were licensed by examination and 46 by reciprocity up to the beginning of the biennium. Four were licensed by waiver under this law. The first examining board in 1909 consisted of Drs. E. M. Cramb of Lincoln, W. H. Cobble of Fremont, J. T. Young of Superior, C. B. Atzen of Omaha, and J. M. Kilgore of York. Code- In August, 1919, the civil administrative code went into effect, which placed the osteopathic examining board, together with other examining boards, under the Department of Public Welfare. This law also changed the required course in osteopathic schools from three to four years for persons wishing to practice in Nebraska. At the time the code went into effect, the members of the osteopathic examining board were Drs. J. T. Young of Fremont, W. L. Burnard of York, E. M. Cramb of Lin - coln, B. S. Peterson of Omaha, and F. E. MacCracken of Beatrice. The code provided that there should be but three members on the examining board, and accordingly the board was reorganized to consist of Dr. Cramb as president, Dr. MacCracken as vice-president, and Dr. Peterson as secretary. No changes have since been made in the per - sonnel of the board. Finances — Separate cash accounts are kept for all examining boards, and when money is deposited for the osteopathic board, it is designated as such. Since the Department of Public Welfare took charge, 18 examination fees and 13 reciprocity fees have been received. Schools — There are no schools of osteopathy in Nebraska, but the following - have been recognized as reputable schools, and graduates of these schools are acceptable in Nebraska, providing they fulfill all other requirements: American School of Osteopathy, Kirksville, Missouri; Chicago College of Osteopathy, Chicago; Des Moines Still College of Osteopathy, Des Moines, la.; Philadelphia College &amp; Infirmary of Osteopathy, Philadelphia,' College </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 I Osteopathic Physicians and Surgeons, Los Angeles, Cal.; Massachu - ts College of Osteopathy, Boston; Kansas City College of Osteopathy I Surgery, Kansas City, Missouri. Course Recognized — The approved course for a school of osteopathy recognized in Ne - braska is as follows: tThe term school or college of osteopathy in good standing shall be led as follows: A legally chartered osteopathic school or college re - ing for admission to its course of study a preliminary education il to the requirements for giaduation of an accredited high school, shall further require before granting the degree of diplomat or doc - of osteopathy, and (an) actual attendance at such osteopathic school or college of at least thirty-two months or four terms of eight months each, its course of study to include the subjects and the minimum hours taught in each thereof as follows: Anatomy, five hundred forty hours; Chemistry, three hundred hours; Pathology, two hundred fifty hours; Tox - icology, fifty hours; Pediatrics, one hundred hours; General Surgery, four hundred fifty hours; Obstetrics, two hundred hours; Histology, one hun - dred eighty hours; Physiology, three hundred hours; Hygiene and Diet - etics, thirty-six hours; Practice, Therapeutics, General Diagnosis, and Technique, one thousand fifty hours; Dermatology and Syphilis, forty-five hours; Orthopedic Surgery, forty-five hours; Gynecology, one hundred twenty-five hours; Embryology, seventy hours; Bacteriology, one hundred fifty hours; Comparative Therapeutics, seventy-five hours; Nervous and Mental diseases, one hundred fifty hours; Jurisprudence, Ethics and Eco - nomics, forty-five hours; Genito-Urinary diseases, forty-five hours; Eye, Ear, Nose and Throat, one hundred twenty hours. The number of hours herein prescribed for the study of any subject may be reduced not more than twenty per cent, but the total number of hours prescribed shall not be reduced. The foregoing requirements shall be published in each cat - alogue of such osteopathic school or college. Preliminary education — The Nebraska law requires four years high school or equivalent before entering upon an osteopathic course. Complaints — Twelve complaints have been investigated, of which 11 have been disposed of and one is still pending. State Association — The officers of the Nebraska Osteopathic Association are as follows: Dr. F. E. MacCracken of Beatrice, President; Dr. N. J. Hoagland of Central City, Vice-president; Dr. Lula L. Cramb, of Fairbury, Treasurer; Dr. Byron S. Peterson of Omaha, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 81 Examinations — Applicants for examination must fill out the regular application blank. This blank must be accompanied by the regular fee, an unmount - ed photograph of the applicant, and a certified photographic copy of diploma about 4x5 inches. The regular fee for examination is $25.00. During the biennium, examinations have been held as follows: June 17th, 18th and 19th, 1919; July 9th, 10th and 11th, 1919; February 5th and 6th, 1920; June 16th and 17th, 1920; February 1st and 2nd, 1921. Special examination was given to applicant desiring same in July, 1919. The next examination will be held in Lincoln June 15th and 16th, 1921. Subjects of examination are: Anatomy, Chemistry and Toxicol - ogy, Bacteriology, Obstetrics and Gynecology, Pathology, Physiology, Practice and Therapeutics, Surgery, Hygiene and Dietetics, Technique and General Diagnosis, Histology, Nervous and Mental. A general aver - age of 60% is required, with no grade lower than 70. Reciprocity — Reciprocity is granted to applicants from another state having re - quirements equal to those of Nebraska. All applicants for reciprocity must fill out the regular blank, accompanied by regular fee, photograph of applicant, and legally certified copy of diploma. One year's previous practice under license in state from which they come is required of all applicants for reciprocity. The regular reciprocity fee is $25.00. Ne - braska has reciprocity with Minnesota, Missouri, Montana, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Dakota, Tennessee, and Idaho, on basis of examina - tion only. The following applications have been acted upon during the bienium: Following are names of those licensed during the biennium: Examination Name Address Des Moines, la. Fremont Charles R. Bean Myrtle A. Bone John H. Broadston Charles O. Casey Aaron O- Clark John A. Clark Grand Island Des Moines, la. Crete Des Moines, la. Brooklyn, la. O'Neill Gregg H. Crusen Madeline Doyle Elmer H. Freeh Des Moines, la. Ixamination 3: Reciprocity 3! Waiver </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 Name Address Grace Hollinberger Harry P. Irwin Des Moines, la. Des Moines, la. Des Moines, la. Paul R. Kohlmeyer Donald M. Lewis Frank I. McConnell Casper E. Mikel Florence M. Mount Glen I. Noe Watertown, So. Dak. Des Moines, la. Grand Island Omaha Pauline, la. Chappell Daniel E. O'Connor Lome Huffman Riseborough Charles W. Robertson Des Moines, la Omaha Bruce L- Ross Nelle E. Ross Central City Central City George A. Roulston Harvey C. Salmen Edgar C. Skinner William K. Stefan Minnie K. Thompson Ethel I. Wheeler Philomena C. Wiewel Russell R. Williams Franklin J. Wirth Marcia H. Wirth Des Moines, la. Pawnee City Des Moines, la. Des Moines, la. Des Moines, la. Ira, Iowa Des Moines, la. Colfax, la. Des Moines, la. Des Moines, la. Reciprocity Name Address 2icCook Milton T. Boulware W. C. Chubb James A. Clark H. S. Dean Josephine Cook Finley Samuel C. Guilbert Dana Hansen William T. Hardy Claude D. Heasley Grace Dowler Horner Robert Q. King Columbia, Mo. Des Moines, la. Columbus, O. Omaha Truman B. Larabee Charlotte McCuskey Edmond J. Martin Webster City, la. Council Bluffs, la. Ellsworth, Kans. Atlantic, la. William B. Mehlenbacher Christine O. Mitterling Edward S. Mitterling Webster City Ja. Webster City ,1a. Logan, la. Earl M. Moats Anna E. Northrup Canada Atlantic ,Ia. Chadron Kirksville, Mo. Atlantic, la. Albion Canada </seg>
            <seg id="p083">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 83 » REPORT OF PHARMACY DIVISION Biennium Ending April 1, 1921. First Law 1887— The Nebraska State Board of Pharmacy was created at the time of the passage of the first pharmacy law in 1887. The Board consisted of the Attorney General, Secretary of State, the Auditor, the Treasurer, and the Commissioner of Public Lands and Buildings. They appointed a board of five secretaries having not less than seven years experience and selected from a group of ten recommended by the Nebraska State Pharmaceutical Association. The Board met for examination every 4 months- Besides giving examination, they were empowered to investi - gate complaints and cause prosecutions. Any man who filed satisfactory proof that he had been in business or employed for three years in com - pounding prescriptions was entitled to register on the payment of a fee of three dollars. A man having two years or more in practice as an assistant to clerks or pharmacists was permitted to register as an as - sistant but could not legally engage in business for himself or manage a drug store. Annual registration was provided for at this time at a fee of one dollar. Assistants were allowed to register at 50 cents. The fine for violations was ten to one hundred dollars. Pharmacists were exempt from jury service. First Examining Board — The members of the first Board were: Wm. Lute, Attorney General; C. H. Willard, State Treasurer; H. A. Babcock, Auditor; Joseph Scott, Land Commissioner; and G. L. Laws, Secretary of State. Name Address Frederick S. Roberts Myron R. Runions Frank H. Shambaugh Carl W. Sherfey Clarence E. Shifflett Roberta Smith Clara Bealafeld Stewart Colby, Kans. Pierson, la. Bostwick Lincoln Hebron Bayard Crete Harry H. Stewart C. L. Timmons Lerue L. Wade Crete Aberdeen, So. Dak. Altoona, la. Charles L. Wheeler Park P. Williams Ernest R. Wilson Ira. Iowa Omaha Smith Center, Kans. Waiver TT. 1 1_ _ 11 </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 The secretaries were: H. D. Boyden of Grand Island; Henry Cook of Red Cloud; W. C. Lane of Lincoln; Max Becht of Omaha; and A. E- Streitz of North Platte. Seals- Different colored seals were used on the licenses to represent the different qualifications under the law. The red seal was used for the man who had been in business or was employed three years or more; the gold seal was used on licenses by examination; and the green seal was used on licenses for registered assistants. First Examination — The first examination was held in Omaha, at the Exposition Build - ing May 10, 1887. The subjects given at this examination were: Practice of Pharmacy, Theoretical Pharmacy, Toxicology, Matena Medica and Chemistry. Under Code — When the Code took effect August, 1919 the following members constituted the Board: Personnel of Board — The new law provided for but three members. Messrs. McDowell, Mikkelsen and Strelow were retained. Mr. McDowell's term expired January 1, 1921, and Chas. P. Hildebrand of York was appointed in his place on recommendation of the State Association. Schools in Nebraska — There are two pharmacy schools in the State: the University of Nebraska College of Pharmacy, Lincoln, and the Creighton College of Pharmacy in Omaha. Requirements — To be eligible for examination according to the present law, a four year course in Pharmacy is accepted without practical epxerience; a two year course in Pharmacy is accepted without practical experience; a two Three years practical experience under a registered pharmacist are accepted. Preliminary Education — The preliminary education required by law is four years high school or the equivalent. The Department has communicated with all of the: . K. McDowell, President Lincoln /"ill Broockley, Secretary Edgar •. T. Haines Omaha [iels Mikkelsen Kenesaw ■. F. Strelow i Long Pine </seg>
            <seg id="p085">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 85 Pharmacists in the state asking them for their co-operation in locating young men who might be taking an apprenticeship, that they might be made safe on their preliminary education before they finished their ap - prenticeship. Applications are on hand for the verifications of prelimi - nary education of apprentices and certificates issued when acceptable showing that they have qualified under the law for their preliminary education, at the time of serving apprenticeship. Complaints — Since the organization of the Bureau of Examining Boards 33 viola - tions have been reported to the Department. A sheriff from the Law Enforcement Division was sent out to investigate complaints that had not been cleared by correspondence, with the following results: 5 employed registered men. 16 complaints were unfounded. 4 sold out. 3 quit practicing. 5 are pending to date. Decisions of Attorney General — October 27, 1919 — The Attorney General interpreted the law in re - gard to the fee since there was a contradictory clause showing two dif - ferent fees. The ruling was that the last named fee was the intention of the legislature and that it was in effect from the time the act was approved, April, 1919. This referred to the fee of fifteen dollars for examination and reciprocity. January 13, 1920 — The Attorney General handed down a decision in favor of garages' selling wood alcohol- His interpretation was that it was the intention of the legislature to regulate the sale of poisons for medicinal uses such as strychnine, arsenic, etc. That the sale of such other substances as gasoline, paint, or lye, etc. which are poisons and ordinarily sold by others than pharmacists did not seem to be included in the statute. March 19, 1920 — Ruled that according to the law on the statutes, graduates of a four year course in Pharmacy were obliged to pass an examination for state license. Records — Very little change has been made in the records of the Pharmacy board, except the filing of correspondence and the making of a card index for immediate use in the Bureau. Annual registration certificates have been reduced in size to a card that may be accommodated in a purse. The same size card is issued to all professions having annual renewal of license. The Department is following the method of the pharmacy board in the report of results of examination of all boards. </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 REPORT OF THE The following is a report on the examinations during the biennium: May Aug. Nov. Feb. May Aug. Nov - 19 19 19 20 20 20 20 Total Each time a man took an examination or failed in an examination he is counted a new applicant in summing up this report. Passing grade — The required passing grade is 65%; for general average 75% Practical Examination — The practical examination consists of compounding and dispensing physicians' prescriptions, compounding extemporaneous preparations of the U. S. pharmacopoeia and the National Formulary, making tests for purity of one or more inorganic and organic salts of the U. S. Pharma - copoeia, physical identification of not less than five inorganic and .organic salts, one or more microscopic examinations of a plant or part of a plant, physical identification of not less than ten plant drugs. Licenses issued before April 1, 1919 — The licenses issued by the Board before April 1, 1919 numbered 5,002. Biennium — Licenses issued by examination during the biennium 84 Licenses issued by reciprocity during the biennium 26 Total— 110 Annual Renewal of License — There are 1768 pharmacists in good standing for 1921 having paid their annual renewal dues to date. Reciprocity — All reciprocity is taken care of through the National Association of Ixamined — 'ailed— 'assed — 'ailed— Oral 29 4 25 1 7 3 4 0 24 18 6 2 21 14 7 0 50 23 27 1 14 5 9 3- 30 24 6 6 175 91 84 13 Pharmacy Materia Medica Chemistry Pharmacognosy Lab. Practice Pharm. &amp; Chemical Arithmetic Toxicology eciprocity granted 3 0 4 1 3 3 0 1 1 8 8 9 6 16 5 2 7 6 7 5 0 1 8 19 11 19 4 7 3 14 2 5 0 •3 12 15 21 20 0 16 0 2 34 63 50 60 3 21 11 26 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 87 Boards of Pharmacy, with headquarters in Chicago. Application is made to Mr. H. C. Christensen, 130 North Wells Street, Chicago. All states having membership in this association have established agreements on the basis of registration with a state having equal requirements and conforming to the agreements. The national requirements for reciprocity are: Age 21, four years practical experience in a drug store under the personal supervision of a registered druggist, endorsement of character by two druggists, exami - nation in Practical work, Pharmacy, Materia Medica and Chemistry, good standing in home state, two years practical experience in the work since registering, appearance before examining board, and practical examina - tion. The fee to the National Association is $15.00. This does not cover the fee to the State Board, nor the endorsement of the state from which the applicant comes. Mr. Niels Mikkelsen of Kenesaw was the delegate from the Examin - ing Board to the National Association of Boards of Pharmacy for 1920. They met in Washington, D. C, in May, 1920. Thirty-four states were represented in the joint session of the sections on Education and Legisla - tion. The various topics under discussion were: preliminary standards of recognition relative to proofs of high school qualifications; the equiva - lent of high school qualifications; basis of recognition of schools and colleges of pharmacy; systems of unit as basis for computing the value of "practical experience" submitted by candidates for state board ex - amination; the registration of "assistants" or druggists; payment of state association and annual renewal dues to examination board and control by legislation; and many matters relative to State Board exami - nations, method of conducting them, and means to improve present con - ditions. The general recommendations adopted by these sections of the N. A. B. P. were in part as follows: 1. Graduation from an accredited high school — preliminary educa - tion. 2- Graduation from college of pharmacy for entrance to state ex amination. 3. Adoption of system of units as a basis for computing the value of practical experience as presented in a paper by Mr. L. L. Walton of Pennsylvania. 4. Separate examination of assistants or druggists, 5. Combination payment of state association and annual renewal fees by law. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 6. Separate examinations of chemical and pharmaceutical problems; too many rather than too few questions; oral examination in Pas many subjects as possible to give the candidates who are are unable to express themselves in writing, another chance. The Association reported a wholesome growth during the year both ■with reference to reciprocity and other activities. 815 reciprocal appli - cations were issued since the New York convention, the largest ever issued before in a like period. t Forty-three states and the D- of C. constitute the active membership the Association and between which reciprocity is in force. California, w Jersey, Rhode Island and Wyoming have no membership without iprocity agreement. I The next meeting of the Nebraska Pharmaceutical Association will held at Columbus, Nebraska, June 7, 8, and 9, 1921, Mr. G. T. Haines Omaha is President and J. G. McBride of University Place is Secretary. PHARMACISTS LICENSED DURING BIENNIUM Name Address Auxier, Paul J. Omaha Averitt, H. C. Mullen Bawn, Joe Ravenna Bryant, Murl E. Broken Bow Butler, Fletcher A, Harvard Bighley, John P. Omaha Omaha Blythe, Clyde R. Bobisud, Milada Dodge North Platte Bogue, Edward V. Bowman, Ralph H David City Boyd, Wilmer W. North Bend Brockhoff, W. C. Seward Burford, Berenice Omaha Christensen, Oscar H. Omaha Coats, Mabel Omaha Coe, Ferrell A. Lincoln Colson, Wesley C. Stromsburg Craig, D- Cloyd Omaha Crosswart, Scott T. Earlham, la. Omaha Currko, Walter Danielson, A. T. Omaha DeFrance, Louise Gilead Doggy, G. O. Mitchell Durkee, Claude T. Coats, Kas. Dwan, Roy Elmer Oxford Engle, Frank H. Beatrice </seg>
            <seg id="p089">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 89 Name Address Omaha Omaha Omaha Esher, Orville J, Fenton, W. J. Fitzsimon, Vincent J. Fix, Louis C. Philadelphia Omaha Frahm, Rudolph J. Fraker, Philip W. Freinde, Glenn O. Feldhausin, Frederick Gilland, Chas. Edw. Gilbert, Ceciel Alliance Lincoln \ J. Omaha Sterling, Colo. Omaha Guinter, G. G. Lincoln Omaha Boyd Harlan, Glenn B. Herrington, Max R. Hess, Raymond B. Huffman, Elwood C Hunter, R. A. Lincoln Pleasanton Lincoln Jensen, Herman H. Johnson, Wilmer J. Knapp, R. B. Gordon Peru Kokrda, James Larsen, Ches. B. LeMire, Romeo Lewton, Harry R. Lohrberg, Rovland O, Lonie, Wallis G. Omaha St. Paul Waterloo, la. Lincoln Lincoln Rushville Omaha Look, I. H. Luebben, Mildred Lynch, W. J. Beatrice Thedford Falls City Gothenburg Clarinda, la. Arcadia Mac Leoad, S. R. Mahon, Arthur L. Manning, R. P. Marquis, Glenn Marphy, Arthur J. Mason, Ralph L. McClelland, Lee McEhinney, Frank D. McLean, R. F. Omaha Walthill Antioch Hastings Gibbon McReynolds, Gaude Milow, Edgar F. Moore, L. C. Falls City Johnson Pierce Omaha Nesladek, Geo. J. Neurock, Benj. Oakley, Enoch R. Ortman, Jno. W. Penner, Wm. E. Arapahoe Omaha Omaha Beatrice </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 Name Address Eustis Pickering, Floyd R. Pratt, Charles E. Proffit, W. E. Kearney Hastings Lincoln Omaha Redford, Helena I. Roberts, John W. Rodwell, Francis B. Ross, J. Henry Ainsworth Elm Creek Russell, Paul B. Wichita, Kas. Omaha Ruzicka, Richard Geo. Schmitz, C W. Hastings Spencer Alliance Chester Norfolk Prague Schreinost, Fred Scotten, Benjamin M. Sell, David A. Seymour, Jas. B. Simanck, Edw. John Skinner, E. R. Lincoln Smidt, Morton R. Smith, Wendall D. Stahlhut, Mark Stitzer, W. I. George, la. Silver Creek Nebraska City Lincoln Swanson, Charles Oakland Omaha Thompson, Alfred Thos. Tighe, Leo Francis North Platte Arapahoe Van Valm, Jesse F. Waggoner, I. M. Wagner, Pine Firth Omaha Walz, Chas. A. Ward, A. Jae Warren, John C. Weaver, Walter L. Wefso, Robt. Hartington Lincoln Beatrice Callaway Harrison Omaha Weher, Leo Fred White, Burt M. Whitney, Ruth B. Wilson, Chas. A. Wilson, Wm. B. Winterstin, Chas. F. Witty, Lee H. Crawford Geneva Omaha Lewellen Moline, 111. Gering Wood, Lawrence J. Wright, Ira W. Lincoln Beatrice Edison 2ike, E. E. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 91 REPORT OF VETERINARY DIVISION For the Biennium Ending April 1, 1921. First Law— The first veterinary law passed the legislature of 1905. This law provided for a Board composed of the Governor, Secretary of State, and the State Auditor. There were three examiners or secretaries appointed to conduct examinations and act professionally in advising the Board proper. The secretaries were required to be graduates of recognized schools of veterinary medicine. No one was allowed to use the title in - dicating that he had a degree of veterinary medicine, surgery or dentistry,, unless he had a license so to do. The examination given was such as would be required to obtain a degree in a reputable veterinary college. The required fee was $5.00. The fine for violation was $25 to $100. Amended — In 1913 the veterinary law was amended slightly, the requirements not being changed. The law specifically stated that the act ■ did not apply to those practicing unless they used the title. New Law — In 1915 a compulsory registration law was passed making it illegal for anyone to practice veterinary medicine without a license. Those who had practiced for ten years in the state and for one year in the county of residence were allowed to continue to practice on condition that they did not use or assume the title of any degree or part of a degree. Such unlicensed practitioner was obliged to file before September 1, 1915, an affidavit by ten freeholders of his resident county, that he had made the practice of veterinary medicine, veterinary surgery, or veterinary dentistry his continuous business for ten years and was a resident of his county for one year immediately preceding the taking effect of this act. The regular fee was ten dollars- Licensed to April 1, 1919 — From September 13, 1905 to April 1, 1919 — there were 171 prac - titioners granted permits to practice, and 459 veterinarians licensed to practice veterinary medicine, veterinary surgery and veterinary dentistry. Biennium — From April 1, 1919 to April 1, 1921 — 50 have been licensed by ex - amination. Two practitioners whose applications have been pending since 1915, were granted permits. There were twenty-two failures during the biennium. The first record we find of the personnel of the examining board was the year, 1913. G. R. Young, of Omaha, J. S. Anderson of Seward, and C. A. McKim of Norfolk, constituted the Board. </seg>
            <seg id="p092">92 Under Code-r- IWhen the Civil Administrative Code Law took effect in August, 1919, '. McGinnis, of Ord, J. C. Bowman, of Hebron, and J. S. Anderson, of ha, were the members of the Board. Dr. I. W. McEachran of Geneva succeeded Dr. Anderson. Dr. S. W. Alford succeeded Dr. McGinnis whose term shortly thereafter expired. Dr. Bowman's term expired January 1, 1921, and George A. Young of Syracuse, was appointed in his Personnel of Board — Officers of Board January 1, 1921. There are no veterinary schools in Nebraska. Applicants have been accepted from the following schools during the biennium: Recognized Schools — St. Joseph's Veterinary College San Francisco Veterinary College K. C. Veterinary College George Washington University Indiana Veterinary College Grand Rapids Veterinary College McKillip Veterinary College Kansas State Agriculture College New York College of Veterinary Surgery Chg. Veterinary College Ohio State Veterinary College Ontario Veterinary College The law now (April 1, 1921) in effect does not require preliminary or professional education. Violations — The violations reported during the period between August 1, 1919 and the present date, were twenty-five. 2 of these were graduate veterinarians 2 of these were county agents 7 of these were permit men 14 of these were other than above 6 complaints were unfounded 11 complaints were unethical advertising 2 complaints were for issuing certificates illegally 1 of these was eligible for license and has since become I. C. Bowman, Pres Hebron L W. McEachran, Vice Pres Geneva 3. W. Alford, Secy State House, Lincoln </seg>
            <seg id="p093">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 93 licensed 3 complaints are still pending Subjects of Examination — The subjects given in the examination in veterinary medicine, sur - gery, and dentistry are: Anatomy, Bacteriology and Pathology, Materia Medica &amp; Therapeutics, Obstetrics, Chemistry, Physiology, Theory and Practice of Medicine, Dentistry, Parasitology, Surgery. The required grade in Chemistry and Parasitology is 50%, these subjects being new. The grade required in other subjects is 60%. The general average re - quired is 70%. Reciprocity — There are no reciprocity agreements with other states, due to the fact that the laws relating to veterinary medicine are not uniform, and our own law was not on a sufficiently solid basis. The following vet tennarians were ! licensed during th&lt; ie biennium: Name Address tarbee, James S. of lard, J. Elldoras Jassin, L- B. ;hambers, C. H. A. LeRoy Jhrist, Frank H. Ihristensen, P. J. Jline, Merton L. lowden, Francis M. )obyns, J. Ellsworth )olan, Francis F. Jardner, Hyman W. Jibson, Samuel S. Jrau, J. A. iriffith, Benjamin laas, George Tans, H. M. lenderson, C. J. lines, L. J. Sutton Omaha Monroe Fremont Newman Grove Newman Grove Fremont Lincoln Oakland Alexandria Maxwell Creighton Randolph Auburn Wisner Arnold Ponca Newman Grove Hastings lolman, E. J. lurst, D. W. lurst, Fred M. illson, Paul M. ohnson, F. E. ohnson, Samuel R. Leith, George E. jarsen, C. E. jarsen, N. L. Decatur Lincoln Red Cloud Ames, la- Lincoln Hooper Hyannis Cedar Bluffs Cedar Bluffs </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 REPORT OF LICENSURE OF MATERNITY HOMES For the Biennium Ending April 1, 1921. The first law governing the license of Maternity Homes and Hospi - tals was passed in 1911. The enforcement of that law came under the State Board of Health and the Medical Examining Board until September 1, 1919 when it passed into the hands of the Department of Public Wel - fare. The law providing for the licensing of lying-in institutions was en - acted for the purpose of protecting the child born out of wedlock and giving him a square deal. The law applies to anyone who "keeps for care or treatment within period of six months, more than one woman during pregnancy, or during or after delivery, except women related by blood or marriage; or has in his or her custody or control, at any one time, two or more infants under the age of two years, unattended by parents or guardians, for the purpose of providing them with care, food and lodging, except infants Name Address Lent, Henry E. Checotah, Okla. Mack, Clarence E. Eennard Melchiorsen, Wm. G. Omaha Moslander, W. J. Alliance O'Brien, F. Tobias Bottineau, N. D. Ortberg, A. N. New Castle Perry, Carl C. Cook Riley, Glenn A. Nelson Ritter, Winfield R. Creston Sewell, R. H. Falls City Simpson, J. M. Alliance Slagle, Fred 0. Lewiston Smith, Samuel A. Talmage Spencer, W. T. Lincoln Stanton, Jay E. Clarks Taylor, Gilbert R. Palmer Tice, Harry R. Summerfield, Kas. True, Harry J. Bancroft Ward, Robert L. Lewiston Williams, E. H. Pawnee City Wise, H. A. Falls City Ziegenbein, Frank C. Memphis Practitioners (pending since 1915) Smith, Francis E. Verdon Stahly, Chris Milford </seg>
            <seg id="p095">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 95 related to him or her by blood or marriage, shall be deemed to maintain a maternity home or maternity boarding house, or home for the care of infants, or lying-in hospitals." This does not apply to homes, hospitals, organizations, or institutions that were incorporated after the approval of the Department of Public Welfare. Applications call for information concerning prospective number of lying-in to be cared for during the year, the bed capacity, sterilization facilities, method of care of the eyes of the new born, and recommendation of the Local Board of Health. It is the duty of the Local Board of Health to visit such places at any time, and as often as may be deemed necessary for investigation and inspection. Licenses are issued annually. The fee each year is three dollars. A person holding a license is requested to make a monthly report to the Department giving names and addresses of physician attending at birth taking place in such house or hospital, or attending sick infant; the name, age, and sex of children born on the premises or brought thereto, and age of child who is taken away, together with the name and residence of the parents, and the name and residence of the person taking such child away. The law requires also that the licensee report all deaths occuring on the premises in which the business is carried on. Still births are reported as births and deaths. Licenses were refused two persons making application. Investi - gation proved that these persons were unfit to safeguard the health, comfort, or morality of women and infants. It is unlawful to advertise the adoption of babies or to hold out inducements to mothers of children born out of wedlock or to any persons to part with their offspring. The following persons have been issued a maternity home or hos - pital license since December 1, 1919: Name Institution Address egidia, Sister M. ker, Clare (R. N.) iley, Benj. F. (M- D.) tigs, Mrs. Marguerite yer, Mrs. W. R. rackhahn, Louise (R. N.) rewster, F. A. (M. D.) ryant, Bertha A. (R. N.) uis, John (M. D.) urgeson, D. L. (M. D.) rothers, P. H. J. (M. D.) St. Mary's Hospital Columbus Clarkson Hospital Omaha Bailey Sanitorium Lincoln Broken Bow Pawnee Hospital Pawnee City Nicholas Senn Hospital Omaha Beaver City Hospital Beaver City Grand Island Gen- Hospital Grand Isl. Logan Valley Hospital Pender Nebraska Sanitarium Hastings Mason City Hospital Mason City </seg>
            <seg id="p096">96 Name Address Chinlund, Emil G. (Rev.) Immanuel Hospital and Deaconess Institute Omaha St. Luke's Hospital Omaha Morrow Hospital Seward DeBoer, Caroline (R. N.) Des Jardein A. R. (M. D.) Dimock, Mabel (R. N.) Dolores, Sister M. Des Jardein Sanitarium Lincoln Campbell Hospital Norfolk Sacred Heart Hospital Lynch David City Hospital David City Evans, Harriet Everett, O. W. (M. D.) Fall, C. P. (M. D.) Frink, F. L. (M. D.) Fuller, Blanche (R. N.) Kble, Mrs. M. W. ing, Ida L. (R. N.) Gilligan, J. P. (M. D.) Glasco, Mrs. Anna Lincoln Sanitarium Lincoln Beatrice Sanitarium Beatrice Newman Grove Methodist Episcopal Hospital Omaha Lincoln Lutheran Hospital Beatrice O'Neill Anna Glasco Maternity Hospital Hastings Glassman, Mrs. John H- Green, Mrs. M. B. Immanuel Maternity Home Omaha St. Luke's Hospital Kearney Harvey, Beatrice Atkins (R. N.) Henry, E. C. (M. D.) Midwest Hospital Scottsbluff Lord Lister Hospital Omaha Hedwig, Sister M. Hermana, Sister M. Hirsch, E. K. (M. D.) Howell, Maude St. Elizabeth's Hospital Lincoln St. Joseph's Hospital Omaha Taylor Lewis Memorial Superior Community Hospital Falls City Huberta, Sister M. St. Francis Hospital Grand Island Wise Memorial Hospital Omaha Hulette, Ida B. (R. N.) Hyland, C. M. (M. D.) Jackson, Mrs. W. G. Jensen, J. C Coolidge Hospital Palmer Broken Bow Hospital Broken Bow Fenger Hospital Omaha K, Sister M. (R. N.) son, Bessie (R. N.) St. Catherine's Hospital Omaha North Platte General Hospital North Platte Kee, McCabe &amp; Stewart, Drs. (M. D.) Republican Valley Hospital Cambridge Norfolk General Hospital Norfolk Keyes, Jean (R. N.) Long,F. A. (M. D.) Lutgen, C. A. (M. D.) Lutgen, S. A. (M. D.) Yeazel Home Madison Auburn Hospital Auburn Wayne Hospital Wayne Lynch, Potter &amp; Birdsall, Drs. Matzen, Mamie (R. N.) Fairbury Hospital Fairbury Columbus General Hospital Columbus Miller, C. J. (M. D) Moore, C. G. (M. D.) Mullong, E. R. (M. D.) Ord Hospital Ord Schuyler Hospital . Schuyler City Hospital Norfolk Cornish, Mrs. M. H. </seg>
            <seg id="p097">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 97 Ness, Lillian Salvation Army Rescue Home Omaha Nicola, B. E. (M. D.) Nebraska Sanitarium College View Swedish Mission Hospital Omaha Osterholm, Albin N. (Rev.) Payne, W. S. (M. D.) Neligh General Hospital Neligh Quirk, H. W. (M. D.) Rich, Max L. (M. D.) Crete Hospital &amp; Sanitarium Crete Rose Ellen Maternity Home Grand Island Roberts, Mrs. Eurena E. Roeder, Mrs. H. T. Robert's Maternity Home Crawford Maternity Homo Lincoln Rohlfing, Celina B. (R. N.) Rosalie, Mother M. Lutheran Hospital York St. Joseph's Hospital Alliance Sampson, Elsie (R. N.) Sayles, D- M. (M. D.) Schnitter, Mrs. Alice Shoemaker, C. A. (M. D.) Smith, Margaret Lincoln Hospital Lincoln Bayard Hospital Bayard Private Maternity Home Lincoln Shoemaker Hospital Lincoln Spencer Hospital Spencer Springer, Mrs. Bertha M. Stewart, Nellie E. (R. N.) Stewart, W. E. (M. D.) Aurora Hospital Aurora Stewart Maternity Hospital Omaha Dr. Stswart's Private Hospital Stratton Stiles, Mrs. Mabel Private Maternity Home Bertrand Mary Lanning Hospital Hastings Stump, Mrs. Alverta (R. N.) Sweazey, Mrs. Cora Seward Hospital Seward Thomsen, John H. (M. D.) Twinem, J. S. (M. D.) Frederick Hosnital Omaha Platte Valley Hospital North Platte Verges, C. J. (M. D.) Verges Sanitarium Norfolk Washburn, Mrs. F. A. (R. N.) Westphal, Sophia (R. N) Blair Hospital Blair Westphal Hospital Scottsbluff Wetherald, Mrs. Bertha White, Mrs. Marie L. Private Harvard Fremont Hospital Fremont Wiebe, Sister Magdeline (R. N.) Wieck, Marie C. (R. N.) Mennonite Hospital Beatrice Ford Hospital Omaha Wilmeth, F. L. (M. D) Willis, J. M. (M. D.) Wilsey, Frank J. Esther's Hospital Lincoln Dr. Willis' Hospital Araphoe Milford Hospital Milford Wilson, S. S. (M. D.) Wilson Hospital Nebraska City </seg>
            <seg id="p098"/>
            <seg id="p099">BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE BUREAU OF SOCIAL SERVICE FOR BIENNIUM CLOSING NOVEMBER 30, 1920. </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 X^ X I ± 1 1 j NAME AND LOCATION OF NEBRASKA STATE INSTITUTIONS 1. State Penitentiary Lancaster W. T. Fenton, Warden 2. State Industrial School for Boys Kearney R. V. Clark, Superintendent 3. Girls Industrial School Geneva Lena Ward, Superintendent 4. Nebraska Industrial Home Milford Evelyn Meyer, Superintendent 5. Nebraska Hospital for Insane Lincoln Dr. D. G. Griffith, Superintendent 6. Hospital for Insane Norfolk Dr. G. E. Carlton Superintendent 7. Nebraska State Hospital Ingleside Dr. W. S. Fast, Superintendent 8. Orthopedic Hospital Lincoln Dr. B. A. Firikle, Superintendent 9. Nebraska Soldiers and Sailors Home Burkett Addison Waite, Commandant 10. Soldiers and Sailors Home Milford J. O. Moore, Commandant ll. Nebraska State Institution for Feeble Minded Youth Beatrice Dr. S. J. Stewart, Superintendent 12. Home for Dependent Children Lincoln Amy V. Stevens, Superintendent 13. School for Deaf Omaha Frank W. Booth, Superintendent 14. School for Blind Nebraska City N. C. Abbott, Superintendent 15. Hospital for Tuberculous Kearney Dr. L. T. Sidwell, Superintendent 16. State Reformatory for Women York Dr. Alma J. Chapman, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p101">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 101 PRIVATE INSTITUTIONS Bethphage Mission Axtell Rev. C. A. Lonquist, Superintendent Child Saving Institute 42nd &amp; Jackson, Omaha Eva Pitzer, Matron Christian Orphans' Home Holdrege H. A. Gustin, Superintendent Crowell Home , Blair W. H. Underwood, Superintendent Father Flannagan's Home __r 4206 So. 13th St., Omaha Father E. J. Flannagan, Superintendent Good Shepherd Home _ 40th &amp; Jones St., Omaha Sister M. Raphael, Superintendent Home for Aged Negroes 3029 Pinkney St., Omaha Mrs. Jackson, President House of Hope Florence Mrs. Nettie Hart, Superintendent Immanual Deaconess Institute 34th &amp; Meredith Sts., Omaha Rev. E. G. Chinlund, Superintendent Jewish Old Peoples Home _ 2504 Charles St., Omaha Mrs. S. Ravitz, Superintendent Lutheran Orphanage Fremont Rev. J. F. Gnuse, Superintendent Mothers' Jewels Home York Rev. J. F. McAnally, Superintendent Mother Hull W. C. T. U. Hospital Kearney Mrs. Lillie Yoder, Manager Nebraska Children's Home Society 501-02 McCague Bldg., Omaha Rev. R. B. Rails, Superintendent Nebraska Masonic Home -Plattsmouth Sam Scott, Superintendent Nebraska Masonic &amp; Eastern Star Home for Children Fremont and Plattsmouth Mrs. Sadie D. Boorman, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 Odd Fellow's Home York J. W. Pittman, Superintendent Old People's Home 1325 Fontenelle Blvd., Omaha Mrs. Synthia Esplin, Superintendent Salvation Army Rescue Home 24th &amp; Spaulding Sts., Omaha Lillie E. Ness, Matron St. James Orphanage Benson k Father Steven L. Dowd, Superintendent Joseph's Home for the Aged , West Point Monsigneur Joseph Reusing, Superintendent St. Thomas Orphanage Lincoln St. Joseph's Home for the Aged , West Point Monsigneur Joseph Reusing, Superintendent St. Thomas Orphanage Lincoln t Sister M. Algildia, Superintendent yside Home i Hastings Sister M. Algildia, Superintendent Elizabeth Y. Henry, Matron Elizabeth Y. Henry, Matron Swedish Lutheran Orphanage __Stromsburg ish Lutheran Orphanage — Stromsburg Rev. Carl Franzen, Superintendent Tabitha Home 45th &amp; Randolph, Lincoln Rev. Ernest Walters, Superintendent Hon. H. H. Antles, Secretary, Department of Public Welfare. Dear Sir: It affords me great pleasure to have the honor to present herewith the report of the Bureau of Social Service which includes Charities Corrections and Paroles, for the biennium ending November 30, 1920. Eight months of the biennium were under the Board of Charities and Correction and State Prison Board. On August 1, 1919 the Depart- ment of Public Welfare took charge of the work which had been done under the above Boards and organized the Bureau of Social Service. The duties of the Chief Clerk of the Board of Charities and Corrections and the Secretary of the State Prison Board were assigned to the Chief of the Bureau of Social Service. They are briefly as follows: Inspecting Charitable and Correctional Institutions operated by the State, County, Municipality or private; organizations; Acting as Secre- tary and Custodian of records in the State Parole System; and being Chief State Parole Officer. We have officially inspected all the Poor Houses, the jails in 83 counties, many city jails, 15 State institutions which are under the man- </seg>
            <seg id="p103">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 103 agement of the Board of Control and all the private Charitable institu - tions in the State. Recommendations have been made concerning im - provements, renovations and conveniences in equipment. Also sugges - tions have been given in regard to the care and health of inmates, where possible, County Boards, Superintendents, Trustees and Managers have been interviewed personally about conditions in the institutions under their supervision. In other cases letters relating to the results of our inspections have been sent to the proper authorities. Where jails or poor houses were found to be unfit for the purpose for which they were intended, unsanitary or endangering the lives of those committed to them, they have been unhesitatingly condemned. Much good has been accomplished by these inspections am! recommendations; jails have been cleaned up and poor houses made more comfortable. We found conditions in the privately supported Orphanages and Homes for Aged People very satisfactory. These institutions supported by private funds and voluntary contributions, are well managed, fitted up with modern conveniences, sanitary, and equipped for first class work. The Board of Control visits the State Institutions under their super - vision at frequent intervals and keep informed about needed repairs, new equipment and the management. So our recommendations in re - gard to these institutions have been largely commendations. We have attended and kept a record of every meeting held for the purpose of considering paroles from the Penitentiary, secured employ - ment for the men going out, received reports from those on parole, vis - ited many of the paroled men in their places of employment, conducted the correspondence necessary to prepare applications for parole for the paroling authorities and kept all records in regard to each case coming under our jurisdiction. More in detail we shall report on the various parts of our work, STATE INSTITUTIONS There are sixteen institutions under the management of the Board of Control. This Bureau has an inspectional relation to these insti - tutions and may make recommendations to the Board of Control fr.^m our inspections. New buildings have been erected at the following places during the biennium: Girls Cottage at the Institution for Feebleminded. Ward build - ing, Superintendents house, power and commissary building at Hospital for Insane at Norfolk. Ward building and green house at State Hos - pital at Lincoln, kitchen and attendants quarters at Hospital for Insane at Ingleside. Commissary building with ice plant and refrigerators </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 at Old Soldiers Home at Burkett. Superintendents house and cow barn at Boys Industrial School at Kearney. Dormitory at Women's Re - formatory at York and a cow barn at the Industrial Home at Milford. Crowded conditions are found at, the Hospitals for Insane, the In - dustrial Schools, Penitentiary, Institution for Feebleminded, and the Hospital for Tuberculosis at Kearney. We have not found at any of the State Hospitals adequate provisions for the care of the criminal insane. Barred doors and windows are but reasonable precautions in the case of this class and they should be quartered so that it would be difficult at any time for them to commit violence upon themselves or others. The new buildings at the Hospitals for Insane and at the Institution for Feebleminded have helped a little to relieve the con - gestion at these places. The School for the Blind at Nebraska City was in very good con - dition, and doing a splendid work. It was necessary to fit up a hos - pital during the flu epidemic and it is intended to remain a permanent part of the equipment. The School for the Deaf at Omaha is one of the oldest of the State Institutions and some of the old buildings do not have up-to-date equip - ment. The industrial building really should be wrecked and rebuilt. A splendid work is being done at the School. The lip method of in - struction is used. The Home for Dependent Children is under an efficient manage - ment, is well equipped except in its kitchen arrangements and is doing a very creditable work. The meals are prepared at the Orthopedic Kitchen about 100 yards from the Home and brought through the open air in carts to the dining rooms of the children and attendants. There is need also for a sun room in connection with the babies' department. Plans are made for another new building at the Institution for Feebleminded in which provisions will be made for better kitchen, dining room and bakery facilities. The work of the Institution is very difficult on account of the class of inmates. A large farm gives outdoor employment to a great many of those who are capable of doing that kind of work. At the Industrial Home for Women at Milford the small farm is utilized for pasturing the dairy- herd and raising vegetables. The girls are taught home economics and some school work. Those who are admitted are in the Home but a few months and it is difficult to do effective school work. A splendid work is being done at this place. Some changes have been made in equipment at the Industrial School for Girls so that shower baths have taken the place of the tub baths. Arrangements have been made for another grade among the inmates. </seg>
            <seg id="p105">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 105 The colored girls are now placed in a separate grade from the white girls. Miss Lena Ward who was Superintendent of the Milford Home for Girls now has charge of the Geneva School and the work is being very efficiently done. The new hospital building at the Industrial School for Boys at Kearney supplies a long felt need. The crowded conditions necessi - tated some remodeling of the Administration building to provide quar - ters for another grade. School is conducted in each cottage. We favor a central school building and teachers who give their time ex - clusively to that work. The institution also needs a gymnasium which could also be used for an auditorium. The Orthopedic Hospital is doing an excellent work in the partic - ular line of cases which come to its care. Besides the regular work of the hospital surgical cases from other State Institutions are brought there for treatment. No one is received at this institution whose rela - tives or themselves are able to pay for an operation at another hospital. At the Penitentiary we find a very crowded condition and insuffi - cient employment. The broom factory has been taken out which leaves only the furniture factory and farm to employ the inmates. The man - agement is the very best. During the summer of 1920 about 100 men were worked on State road building which proved to be a very success - ful project. The institution is well equipped but with insufficient cap - acity for the charges sent there. There are two Homes for Old Soldiers and Sailors. One at Bur - kett the other at Milford, Both of them are full to capacity but are giving excellent care to those making their home there. At each place is a well equipped hospital with attending physician and nurses. In one building at Milford where both men and women have their quarters the toilets are poorly located. There is but one toilet room on each floor and one stall in each one is branded "For Ladies Only." This arrangement is objectionable. The new buildings at these Homes are modern and fire proof. Patients are admitted to the State Hospital for Tuberculosis upon their own application accompanied by a statement from the Commis - sioner of the County from which they come that they have been resi - dents of Nebraska for more than six months and are in need of treat - ment which the hospital can give. Some patients pay according to their ability from $10.00 to $30.00 per month. This hospital is filling a long felt need in the State and is doing excellent work- More equip - ment is needed in the way of buildings and appliances. There are three Hospitals for Insane; one at Ingleside, which has the largest number of inmates, one at Lincoln, which comes next in number of patients and one at Norfolk. These hospitals are equipped </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 REPORT OF THE with modern appliances for treating this class of people but are very much crowded. Even the new buildings recently erected at each place do not wholly relieve the congestion. The staffs of physicians and attendants are well organized at each place to do the most effective work. There is constant need of enlargement and added equipment at each one of these institutions. The State Reformatory for Women at York has recently been put into operation. The equipment is not sufficient for the work of the institution. The Superintendent and her helpers are doing their ut - most to do creditable work under the handicap of meager conveniences- As a result of the close attention given these State Institutions, by the Board of Control, they are kept in the best possible condition and the Superintendents and workers are highly efficient. We have tried to make reasonable and practical suggestions as the result of our observations at the various institutions with a desire to be helpful in making the work done at each place equal to any of like kind in the United States. PRIVATE INSTITUTIONS There are 25 institutions in the state doing charitable work and supported wholly or in part by philanthropic contributions. Great good is being done by these Homes. The aged are given kind and ten - der care, surrounded with comforts which help to make their declin - ing years bright and happy and given considerate treatment which their feebleness requires. Orphan or dependent children are given protec- Efrom a cold and unsympathetic world, supported and educated ugh their developing years, provided a home until taken under the of foster parents and through loving interest brought to a reali - zation of high ideals. The sick and afflicted are taken in and nursed back to health or cared for through their continued helplessness. The workers in these institutions are warm-hearted, sympathetic and loving ministers of human kindness. The cheering helpfulness resulting from their care and influence is beyond measure. These institutions are kept in first class condition. They are clean, sanitary, well equipped and splendidly managed. Five of them care for old people exclusively, seven receive old people and children both, two do hospital work in connection with the Home feature, nine care for children only and two are exclusively for unfortunate girls. The Bethphage Mission at Axtell is owned and operated by the Swedish Lutheran Church. It is designed to care for epileptics, insane, aged and incurables. The work is supported by voluntary contributions. </seg>
            <seg id="p107">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 107 A fee is charged for the care of patients who are able or whose friends are able to pay. The standard is as reasonable as the institution can afford. The management is vested in a Board of Twelve Trustees, in - cluding the President of the Swedish Lutheran Association, the Deacon Superior and the Superintendent of the Mission. A fine large build - ing for patients and a central heating plant have just been completed which gives splendid added equipment. The Odd Fellows Home at York is supported by this fraternal order. They have a farm of 160 acres. The institution is governed &lt;vy a Board of nine Trustees, six of whom are men and three women. The place is *a home for aged and indigent Odd Fellows and their wives, Rebekahs, and orphan or dependent children of Odd Fellows or Rebek - ahs. Children who have one parent living may be released from the Home at the age of sixteen years, those who are completely orphaned may have this for their home so long as they have no other. The children attend the York public schools. The buildings are in splendid condition, well equipped and excellent work is being done. The Sunnyside Home at Hastings is under the auspices of the Hast - ings Woman's Club. The building, a two-story stucco, is located on North Hastings Avenue, and is equipped with modern conveniences. The city donates light, water and heat. The business affairs of the insti - tution are in charge of a Board of Managers selected from the Woman's Club. A matron conducts the inside work of the Home. Any en - feebled or homeless person may be admitted and if they or their friends are able to pay for their care, Sunnyside receives a reasonable remun - eration for their maintenance. What is needed for the expenses of the institution beyond the regular income from fees is secured from voluntary contributions. The single room plan for inmates is used and it is highly satisfactory. It is the desire of the management to make the place a real home for those who are there. The place is in ex - cellent condition. St. Joseph's Home for Aged, located at West Point, is under the control and ownership of the Catholic Church. Persons are admitted to the Home without regard to their religious affiliations. If the ap - plicant for admission has no relatives who will take the responsibility of their care during their declining years they enter into a contract to relinquish all their funds to the Home, whether much or little, and the Home agrees to keep and support them for the rest of their life. Support is given to the institution by voluntary contribution also. Children as well as old people are received and cared for at the Home. Everywhere about the place was found perfect order, cleanliness, mo - dern conveniences and sanitation. The plan is to have a separate room for each inmate that can be called their home. A very commendable work is being done at this home. </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 The Good Shepherd Home in Omaha, is conducted and supported by the Catholic Church. Girls are received without regard to nation - ality or church affiliations. School is conducted to the eighth grade and a special course is given for thosei who desire to take that work. The institution is practically self-supporting by operating the Good Shepherd Laundry and a boy's suit factory. Girls are trained and fitted here to make their own living in an honorable way. A great and far-reaching good work is being accomplished. The Home is under the supervision of Sisters of the Good Shepherd. The St. James Orphanage, at Benson, is supported and conducted by the Catholic Church. Homeless, dependent children 'are received without regard to church affiliation. A school is conducted up to and including the eighth grade. When children are entirely surrendered to the Home they are adopted out. A Superintendent is in charge, assisted by Sisters of Mercy. The institution is in excellent condition. The St. Thomas Orphanage at Lincoln is owned and conducted by the Catholic Church, with Franciscan Sisters in charge. Children of any religious denomination may be admitted, but a preference is given to Catholic children. The institution is well equipped and splendidly managed. A day school is conducted where the common branches are taught as high as the eighth grade. Children living near the Orphan - age may attend the school and are admitted as day pupils. The in - stitution prefers to receive only children who are orphaned. Those who are completely surrendered to the Home are adopted out when suitable places are found for them. The Masonic Home at Plattsmouth is owned and operated by that fraternal order under the direction of a Board, including president, stockholders and trustees. Aged or indigent Masons their wives or Masons' widows are received into the Home. The place is splendidly fitted up with all modern conveniences for the comfort of those having a home there. Provision is made for attending the sick and feeble in whatever way they need. A children's Home is conducted in connection with the institution. A cottage in the care of a matron is used for this department. Every - thing about the house was arranged with the idea of making it a real home for the children occupying it. The place was neat and clean and we have nothing but words of praise for this Home. The Masonic Orphanage at Fremont is owned and operated by this fraternal order. The plan is to have a number of cottages with a company of about twelve boys or girls in the charge of a matron occupy - ing each house as a family. Two such cottages are now in operation. Orphans of Masons are received. The Masonic Board becomes guard - ian of the child and this is their home until of age or self-supporting. </seg>
            <seg id="p109">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 109 The children attend the public school and are taught practical indust - ries at home. The Lutheran Orphanage at Fremont is owned and operated by the Lutheran Church. It is managed by a Board of Directors with a Sup - erintendent in charge. Support is derived from contributions from all sources. Any homeless child may be admitted upon application and a child may be received for a definite period of time, but while at the Home is under the complete jurisdiction of the institution. When a child is placed for adoption the Superintendent retains oversight until the proper legal proceedings are completed. Mothers' Jewels Home at York is an orphanage under the juris - diction of the Women's Home Missionary Society of the Methodist Church, with a Superintendent- in charge. It is supported by volun - tary contributions secured by the Missionary Society. The institu - tion, has several buildings and school is conducted for those of school age up to the high school. The children are also taught practical industries. A music teacher from York donates her services to those who desire to take advantage of that culture. The institution is well equipped and is doing a splendid work. The Swedish Lutheran Orphanage at Stromsburg receives destitute or orphan children irrespective of their nationality or religion. The orphan child remains under the jurisdiction of the Home until eighteen years of age — the destitute child may be taken back to its parents at any time they are able to support it. The building is modern and in good condition. The work is supported by the Swedish Lutheran Church and governed by a Board of Trustees with a Superintendent in charge. The Christian Orphan's Home, near Holdrege, admits homeless children between the ages of one and sixteen years, without regard to nationality or religion. School is conducted as high as the eighth grade. The Home is under a Board of nine Trustees, with a Super - intendent in charge. Voluntary contributions received from all sources,, together with the proceeds from the half section of land connected with the institution, make up its support. Some of the buildings were in • need of repairs and in some parts new equipment would make the work easier. A large number of children are receiving the care of the Home. The Nebraska Children's Home Society, with headquarters in Omaha has been doing work in Nebraska for thirty years. The organization does not have a Home in which to keep dependent children, but places those who come into their care in homes where they may be adopted according to law. Rev. R. B. Rails is Superintendent. The work is supported wholly by voluntary contributions. The Child Saving Institute, located in Omaha, is a private insti - tution governed by a Board of Directors, with a matron and a head </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 nurse in charge. Children from birth to thirteen years of age are received. Homeless, dependent children are given a home until they can be placed in families where there is a probability of adoption. In some cases when those who are interested in a child are financially able, a fee is charged for the child's care. Medical attention is provided by students from the University Medical College. The Home is supported by voluntary contributions. The Salvation Army Rescue Home, located in Omaha, is under the supervision of the Salvation Army. The building has capacity to ac - comodate 25 girls and is usually fully occupied. After the girls leave the Home the management assists them to secure congenial employment and keeps in touch with them to guard them from future missteps. The work is supported by voluntary contributions. The Tabitha Home, located in Lincoln, is owned and operated by the German Lutheran Church. Old people, cripples, and children are admitted upon application. A preference is given to those of Luther - an faith, but under some circumstances others may be admitted. After an application has been favorably acted upon it is decided by the Board of Trustees how much the applicant shall pay for his care. If the person is unable to pay a reasonable amount the church from where the person comes assumes the financial obligation. Orphans or half or - phans are admitted on a similar plan. Funds are solicited by a field »snt for the support of the Home. The place is in excellent con - on and the very best possible care is being given to those in charge the institution. The Immanuel Deaconess Institute in Omaha is composed of the Nazareth Home for old people, an orphanage and a hospital. Several buildings are occupied by this institution which is owned by the Swedish Lutheran Church and in charge of the Emmanuel Deaconess Order. One building is occupied by the Sisters who have charge of the various departments of the institution. The building used for the old people was erected many years ago and is not so modernly equipped as the others. The large number of helpless and mentally unbalanced old people in the Home makes the work very difficult. The hospital* is well equipped and receives patients from Nebraska and other states. There are several doctors on the medical staff and one house doctor gives his whole time to the work. The Orphanage was clean, well arranged and the children receive loving care. The institution is sup - ported by voluntary contributions, some fees from patients who are able to pay and by apportionment contribution from the Swedish Luth - eran Churches- A great and good work is being done at this insti - tution. The Old People's Home, located at Fontenelle Boulevard and Bed- </seg>
            <seg id="p111">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 111 ford Avenue, Omaha, occupies an elegant new building fitted with all modern conviences. Every room has outside windows. Anyone over 65 years of age may be admitted to the Home for the remainder of their lives by the payment of a stated sum of money. It is a delight - ful place with every possible attention given to the comfort and happi - ness of those spending their closing years there. The House of Hope was established by Rev. Chas. W. Savidge for the purpose of providing a home for old people who are unable to care for themselves. The work outgrew the quarters at 1713 California Street, and now occupies an elegant brick structure on the Main Street of Florence. Spacious grounds surround the building and it is pro - posed to erect cottages for the occupancy as the institution's work expands. It is managed by a Board of Trustees and supported wholly by voluntary contributions. The Crowell Home at Blair is owned, operated and supported by the Methodist Episcopal Church in Nebraska. It receives old people or ministers who are affiliated with the Methodist Church. There are two beautiful buildings splendidly equipped. The Home is modern throughout and is doing an excellent work. The Home for Aged Negroes is located in Omaha. It is conducted by the Negro Women's Christian Association and is supported by con - tributions and legacies. At the present time they are receiving only women. The work is under the direction of a Board of Directors, with a Matron in charge. The equipment is only sufficient to accomodate six inmates. This Home supplies a long felt need among the negro people and soon must have more room to care for those who will avail themselves of this haven of rest for their declining years. At Kearney there is a hospital called the W. C. T. U. Hospital, which does charitable work, gives a home to the destitute and cares for the friendless who are ill. Patients, who are supported by the county are frequently kept there. The place is inspected by a repre - sentative of the Board of Health at intervals and is kept in very good condition. The building has electric lights and city water, but is, heated with stoves. A woman who acts as manager and head nurse is in charge. The work is supported by voluntary contributions. a Father Flannagan's Home for Boys in Omaha is conducted inde - pendently of any church or philanthropic organization and is supported by voluntary contributions. Any neglected, homeless or truant boy is admitted regardless of race or religion. Some boys are received from the Juvenile Court. One man gives his time to the work of finding boys who need the care of the Home. School is conducted to the eighth grade. Sisters of Charity have charge of the quarters and are the disciplinarians. The boys at the Home are from five to sixteen years </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 of age and are placed out when suitable homes are found for them. An excellent work is being done. The Jewish Old Peoples Home in Omaha has recently been opened by the Daughters of Israel Aid Society. The House is modern and large enough to accomodate a about dozen people. Those who are able, pay for the care which they receive at the Home. The remainder of the support is furnished by the Society. COUNTY POOR FARMS EIn discussing these county institutions the first consideration is inmates. They are defective or dependent. The defectives are feebleminded, blind, deaf, or epileptic. The dependents are diseased, poverty-stricken, aged or crippled. The next consideration is the kind of equipment needed to success - fully accomplish the work expected of the county alms house. The in - mates whose health will be affected by changes in the temperature of the building can be protected only by a heating system that will warm the whole house and keep the temperature regular. It is dangerous for trembly old people to handle oil lamps for light, therefore a light - ing system for each alms house is essential. It is difficult under the most favorable conditions to induce inmates of these institutions to bathe frequently, and the health of the occupants of the place very largely depends upon cleanliness. A water pressure system that will supply bathing facilities is a necessary equipment. Many of the county charges are sick or diseased and some arrange - ments should be made for a hospital section in the house where proper nursing and care can be given. Sufficient and respectable clothing should be provided by the county for its dependent charges. Because a person is receiving charity support is no reason for his being clothed in rags or insufficient apparel. Every home where indigent people are maintained should have ample fire protection, in the way of fire es - capes and fire extinguishers. Forty-four counties have Poor Farms in operation. Some others own farms which are not equipped for caring for County dependents. The Douglas County Poor House is a part of the County Hospital. Paw - nee, Lincoln, Hall and Buffalo Counties support their dependents by contract with private homes. Douglas and Lancaster Counties have Detention Homes for the temporary care of juveniles. Dodge, Wash - ington and Madison Counties have separate houses on the Poor Farm to be used for Pest Houses. The farms are operated under various plans: Twenty-eight super - intendents receive a stated salary and the county furnishes everything </seg>
            <seg id="p113">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 113 needed for the care of the folks sent to the Farm. All proceeds being turned into the County treasury. Twelve rent the farms and receive a stated amount for the care of the inmates. Two operate the farms in partnership with the County. Two receive the full use of the farm and a salary besides; under the agreement to care for all who are sent to the Farm. One receives the free use of the farm and is paid for caring for the dependents. Many of these alms houses have modern equipment. 21 have fur - nace heat, two have separate heating plants, 24 have water pressure systems, 16 have electric lights and two have gas lights, 26 have bath - ing facilities, 26 use oil lamps and 21 have stove heat, 37 are frame houses, 6 are brick and 1 stucco. Following the recommendations from the Bureau of Social Service, the following improvements were made at Poor Houses during the past biennium. A furnace installed at the Burt County Home; furnace and electric lights, Cuming County; electric lights, Dodge County; furnace and water pressure, Gage County; water pressure, Jefferson County; electric lights, Platte County; water pressure, Red Willow County; elec - tric light, Richardson County; and furnace, Webster County. The Detention Homes in Douglas and Lancaster Counties are mod - ern brick buildings. The Douglas County Home has 20 acres of land which is cultivated by the inmates. The place is well equipped with main building, hospital, laundry etc. Some school work is done here. The Pest Houses mentioned are frame buildings with no modern conveniences. Stove heat, lamp light, and no water systems. COUNTY JAILS In these days we have risen above the old idea of a prison being a place for punishment. The modern method of dealing with criminals has for its purpose reformation. A law violator is incarcerated to pro - tect the man and society — while he is restrained from his freedom he is expected to learn his rightful attitude towards others and his surround - ings and employment while in jail will have more to do with his reforma - tion than anything else. To lock a man in a dark, dirty, ill-smelling, damp and vermin infested jail will make him more vicious toward law and society, and to place a number of prisoners in loose quarters with nothing to do but exchange stories of criminal experiences, gloat over perverted justice and brood over real or imaginary wrongs done them, will multiply their criminal propensities. Men in jail, like other human beings, have natural im - pulses and enforced idleness represses the normal outlet of these impulses and results in some perverted expression of them. The congregate system enables young men to learn criminal practices and methods from </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 older and more hardened law violators. In order to meet the up-to-date requirements for modem jails, they should be constructed of fire-proof material, well lighted, even to the interior of the cells, with plenty of ventilating facilities, bath and toilet conveniences, furnace heat and electric lights. The doors and windows Eld be as secure as the cells- The room should be thoroughly cleaned l time to time, disinfectants used at frequent intervals, decent and cient bedding supplied, which should often be aired and fumigated. Arrangements should be provided for the separation of prisoners; juve - niles from adults, first offenders from those experienced in crime, and Ee awaiting trial from those under sentence, and separate quarters for en. Other work should be provided besides the care of the jail room cells. There are 89 County jails in the state. During the biennium new jails have been constructed in the court houses in Harlan and Wheeler Counties. The new court houses in process of construction in Sherman and Scotts Bluff Counties have plans for jail rooms. Other court house buildings which will be erected in the near future that will have provision for jails are Richardson, Platte, Thomas and Dundy Counties. Frontier, Garfield, Sherman and Gosper counties have jails within their court houses. I Of the 89 jails, 45 have separate buildings, 23 of them brick. 11 me and 11 cement stone. 27 are in basement rooms in the court ses, 5 on the first floor and 12 on the top floor. 69 of the jails have rtric light and 20 lamp light. 45 of them have some kind of furnace t and 44 are heated with stoves- In 53 jails the toilet facilities are the corridor, 14 have toilet equipment in the cells and 22 use the ket system. Only 27 have bathing conveniences. 36 of the number r e some provision to care for women prisoners and 8 have places for enile prisoners. (See Revised Statutes of Nebraska, 1913, Section , Page 1256.) We have condemned the frame jails of Brown, Clay, Garden, Loup, Rock, Stanton and Thurston counties because of fire danger and in - security of construction. The basement jails of Banner, Thomas and Nemaha counties and also the court house jails of Dakota, Dundy and Sarpy counties are condemned because of unsanitation and insecurity. We have many splendid jails in the state and the poor ones are rapidly disappearing. Through the recommendations from the Bureau of Social Service the jails of the state have been cleaned up, painted and made more sanitary. CITY JAILS We inspected and reported on 34 city jails and lock-ups as follows: </seg>
            <seg id="p115">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 115 Alliance, Auburn, Aurora, Beatrice, Blair, Broken Bow, Columbus, Fairbury, Falls City, Fremont, Geneva, Grand Island, Gretna, Hastings, Holdrege, Kearney, Lincoln, Madison, Nebraska City, Norfolk, Omaha, Omaha South Side, Plattsmouth, Schuyler, Scotts Bluff, Seward Stanton, St. Paul, Tecumseh, Valentine, Wahoo, Wayne, Wilber and York. These jails are located in various places, basement of the City Hall, back of the Fire Department room, on the first floor of the City Hall, at the Police Station or in a separate building. The two Omaha jails, the Sec kB Bluff jail and the Lincoln jail are the only ones which have bathing facilities. Seven have apartments for women prisoners. At Auburn and Blair new jail rooms have been fitted up- At Stanton a new jail was built in the City Hall. As a result of our inspections and recommendations many of the city jails have been cleaned up and put in much better condition than formerly. Only two are without electric light. Ten are heated with stoves and five have no toilet facilities. In a general way the city lock-ups are kept in very good condition. PAROLES The State Prison Board did the paroling until August 1919 when the Department of Public Welfare took over the work in accordance with che provisions of the Administrative Code Law. During that period of eight months the Board paroled 136 persons. In the same period there were 50 violations of parole. These were out of the 243 on parole dur - ing those months. Under the Department of Public Welfare there were 181 paroles .granted and during the period in which the Department has been in charge there have been 60 parole violations. These were out of the 294 on parole during the period under the Department. In accordance with the indeterminate sentence law, those committed to the Penitentiary for crimes other than murder, treason, rape and kid - napping, receive a sentence designating a minimum and maximum. After serving the minimum the prisoner is subject to parole, at the discretion &lt;;f the Secretary of the Department of Public Welfare- The previous career of each applicant is carefully investigated and becomes a part of the records in the case. The circumstances surrounding the commission of the crime receive due consideration. When all the facts obtainable concerning a prisoner are on file, it is decided when it is best to place him on parole. It has been the policy to hold a man on parole, a sufficient length of time for him to prove his intention to conduct himself in right relations E society. The law states that the period of parole shall not be less six months, but eight months has been considered a short enough and in some cases it is deemed best to hold them much longer than </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 this. During the biennium a discharge has not been recommended except for those who have complied with their parole agreement for the time specified. In dealing with applications for pardon, commutation of sentence or furlough the Advisory Board of Pardons conducted sixteen hearings and made recommendation to the Governor for commutation of sentence in ten cases which were favorably acted upon by the. Governor. Six cases were recommended unfavorably. It was recommended to the Governor that conditional furloughs be allowed in three cases. Every possible encouragement has been given to the men on parole. Employment has been secured for them and if there was found to be dissatisfaction on the part of the man or his employer, a new place was found so that the man could have opportunity to "make good". How - ever, in case of a violation of the parole agreement the parole has been revoked and the man returned to the Prison. The State Parole Officer, frequently makes trips to different parts of the State, where our paroled men are employed, to discover the condi - tions under which they are working and in some instances to investigate reports of alleged misconduct on the part of the paroled men. We find that a great deal of encouragement can be given the men by frequent correspondence with them while on parole and for this reason Iriendly letter is sent each month on receipt of their monthly reports, any misunderstanding should come up between the man and his em - yer, he is urged to communicate the matter to us. Many of our men are holding positions of honor and trust and their letters of appreciation for the privilege of having their liberty are gratifying to the Depart- Et, making us feel that we have a field for doing a vast amount of I for our more unfortunate fellowmen. It is with deep regret that we report the number of parole violations for the biennium. Out of the 424 men on parole during this period, 110 or 269?- of them failed to live up fully to their parole agreement. While this seems large on the face of the figures, there were but 24 of these or less than 67c known to us to have committed felonies while on parole. The violations have been; leaving place of employment without permission, leaving Nebraska without permission, failing to make the regular monthly reports and making false statements in the monthly reports. The following statistics are taken from the records for the biennium: On parole December 1, 1918 107 'aroli let d during b; nennium _31 'otal </seg>
            <seg id="p117">DEPARTMENT PUBLIC WELFARE 117 Respectfully submitted E. M. JOHNSON, State Parole Officer. NEBRASKA CHILDREN'S CODE COMMISSION The commission was appointed in September, 1919 as authorized by chapter 178 of the laws of 1919. It is a temporary commission expiring May 11, 1921. The fifteen members of the commission served without compensa - tion. The purpose of the commission was to make a study of child welfare conditions and laws in Nebraska and recommend legislation. Its recommendations are embodied in the report which has been made to the governor and has been printed and distributed to the legislature. Having completed this report, the work of the commission at the present time involves the presentation of the facts, on which the report is based, to the committees considering these bills in the legislature, the collection of further statistics, repoi-ts from other states and general information bearing on these bills, the classification of this material and presentation of it in proper form for use by the legislature, and presentation of such information and arguments as the members of the commission may have, •in person when invited by the committees of the legislature. As authorized by law, the commission has employed, since November 11, 1916, a secretary and for most of that time a stenographer both Discharged during biennium 205 Violated parole during biennium 110 On parole December 1, 1920 109 -205 .110 _109 Total 424 424 Paroled by Prison Board 136 136 Paroled by Dept. Public Welfare 181 181 Total 317 Revocations of Parole under Board 50 Revocations of Parole under Dept. Public Welfare 60 Total 110 Violations of Parole by Committing Crime 24 Returned to Pen. for Parole Violation 34 Returned to Pen. under another sentence 4 Deported 6 Delivered to Officers to answer other charges 9 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">* 118 REPORT OF THE giving full time service. The salary of the secretary is $150 per month and the salary of the stenographer is $85 per month. The work of these employees has included a great variety of activities including the following: compilation of the laws of Nebraska effecting children; send - ing out questionnaires to county and district judges, county and city superintendents of schools, heads of state institutions, and of private institutions caring for children and officers of civic organizations interest - ed in the welfare of children; tabulating and compiling the returns from these questionnaires; visiting many officials dealing with children sucn as juvenile court judges, superintendents of schools and institutions for children; holding of conferences in different parts of the state to discuss proposed child welfare laws; securing from other states and from state and National organizations reports by officials in child welfare work and I specialists in different branches of the child welfare problem; drafting bills for consideration by the commission; keeping records of the .mission and redrafting the bills as amended by the commission; sending out copies of bills prepared by the commission for discussion by various organizations in the state; preparing the final draft of the Kfor introduction in the legislature; drafting of the final report of the mission and assisting in revising the same and preparing it for publication. Respectfully submitted, C. E. PREVEY, Secretary. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>