<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00020">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00020</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  MACARONI WHEATS.</title>
               <date value="1903">1903</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>  
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION &gt;F NEBRASKA. Vol. XV, Article IV. MACARONI WHEATS. By T. L. Lyon. DISTRIBUTED MUCH 11, 1908. 1. Fretes. 6. Richi. 11. Velvet Don. 12. Kahla. 2. Kahli. 7. Gharnovka 3. Mohamed ben Bacbir. 8. Pererodka. 4. Yellow Gharnovka. 9. Kubanka. 13. Mahmou'li. 14. Adjini. 9. Kubanka. 5. Pelissier. 10. Black Don. LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, </seg>
            <seg id="p002">NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD (t»&lt; .(OCT. OF ..I UN.V....T.) QEO. F. KENOWER, President, Wisner E. V. FORELL, Kearney fN C. RICH, Omaha L. TEETERS, Lincoln CALKINS, Kearney ERNST, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS B. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director and Animal Husbandman T. L. LYON, B. S. A., Associate Director and Agriculturist J. S. DALES, M. Ph., Financial Secretary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF A. T. Peters, D. V. M., Animal Pathologist Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist s. Avert, Ph. D., Chemist A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc., Entomologist Erwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geologist R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Horticulturist O. V. P. 8TOUT, C. E., Irrigation Engineer G. D. Swezey, M. A., Meteorologist H. R. Smith, B. Sc., Associate Animal Husbandman J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Assistant Animal Pathologist 8. W. Pbrim, Assistant in Agriculture and Foreman of Farm </seg>
            <seg id="p003">MACARONI WHEATS. BY T. L. LYON What part the so-called macaroni wheats are to take in the farm economy of this region is yet to be determined. It will depend largely upon their productiveness as compared with other crops, and upon their market or feeding val Judged by the first of these considerations, as exhibited in the experiments here recorded, macaroni wheat would seem to be entitled to a place among the crops of at least a por - tion of Nebraska. The rather extensive distribution of this wheat made by the Bureau of Plant Industry of the 1 Department of Agriculture through this Station in 1902 was planned by the writer to give information on the following points: (1) The productiveness of macaroni wheat as com - pared with other spring varieties or with winter wheat; (2) the portions of the state to which it is best adapted; (3) the varieties best suited to growth in this region. While it is not possible to draw final conclusions from a test during one season, it is considered that results of sufficient value have been obtained to warrant publication. Especially is this the case in view of the large number of inquiries from persons wishing to know whether it will be a profitable crop for them to raise, and who can best judge of this by knowing what success has already been attained by others in the same portions of the state. For this reason individual tests, ac - companied by the conditions under which they were made, are reported. While this bulletin is published for the purpose of making known the results of experiments carried on with macaroni wheats in this state, it will be of interest to persons who may be considering the advisability of undertaking their culture to include a short description of the wheats, and of </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 the industry to which they give rise, as well as some evi - dence looking towards the possible market for the crop. APPEARANCE AND HABITS OP GROWTH OF MACARONI WHEATS. The macaroni wheats are so called because they are largely used in the manufacture of macaroni and other edible pastes. These products are much used for food in Europe, and are constantly becoming more widely used in this country. The wheats belong to the group Triticum durum, while the com - mon wheats, from which bread is made, belong to Triticum vulgare. The macaroni wheats are tall, with broad, smooth leaves. The heads are heavily bearded, being much more so than any of the ordinary wheats, and the plant when headed has much the appearance of barley. The heads are large and vary in color from light yellow to almost black, depending upon the variety. The kernels are large, very hard, having less starch than common wheat. They vary from light yellow to reddish yellow in color. The habits of growth of durum wheats adapt them to regions of light rainfall. They have great ability to with - stand drouth and heat, but require a rich soil, although they are notably tolerant of alkali. In some mild climates durum wheats are sown in the fall, but generally they are grown as spring wheats, and they must occupy that place in Nebraska at present. The principal durum wheat growing countries are Russia, Turkestan, North Africa, the drier portions of Argentina, Chile, India, and Asia Minor, and to some extent Spain, Italy, Greece, Roumania, Mexico, and the Central American states. FOREIGN MARKET FOR MACARONI WHEAT. One of the most important considerations in the attempt to introduce durum wheat culture into this country is that of a market for the crop. What the foreign demand for edible pastes has become in the last few years may be appre - ciated by reading the following facts taken from a report by Mr. Robert P. Skinner, Consul General at Marseilles: 1 1 U 8. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Plant Industry, Bulletin No. 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 "The European demand for macaroni wheat has increased with remarkable rapidity within recent years. The present consumption of macaroni wheat by the factories in Mar - seilles alone is 24,000 bushels daily. The output of macaroni and edible pastes in that city is limited only by the supply of wheat suitable for their manufacture. Throughout the entire Mediterranean country there has been a correspond - ing increase in the manufacture of these products. Semo - lina mills have been erected, or are in course of construction, in all the important wheat markets, and in the Levant, haps the largest semolina mill in the world is one recently built at Salonica, which has a daily capacity of over 7 bushels of wheat. "The supply of wheat for this large industry is not drawn from western or northern Europe, as the climate there is such that the proper quality of wheat can not be raised. Large quantities of durum wheats are now imported into France and Italy, from Russia and Algeria. These wheats make the best quality of macaroni, but owing to their scar - city they are frequently Mixed with the softer wheats from western Europe. Durum wheat from Russian seed is being grown in France in considerable quantity, but the product even from the first year's crop is not equal to the Russian - grown wheat. "There would seem to be no reason why there should not be a strong and increasing demand for American durum wheat to make good the deficiency in the European mark HOME MARKET FOR MACARONI WHEAT. Concerning the home market for durum wheats, Mr. M Carleton, Cerealist of the U. S. Department of Agriculture, writes as follows: 1 While the prospects are very good for a foreign market for these wheats sufficient to utilize probably all that we can produce for several years, an excellent market is also likely to be developed sooner or later in our own macaroni factories. At present all these factories, with rare exceptions, use the flour of common bread wheats in their operations. Of course this is chiefly due to the fact that heretofore it has been impos - sible to obtain true macaroni wheats in this country, and it is considered 'U. S. Dept. of Agr., Bureau of Plant Industry, Bull. No. 3. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 impracticable to Import them. Most of the factories realize the import - ance of using the semolina of such wheats as soon as they can obtain it In sufficient amount and of good quality. It will certainly be of the greatest advantage to the factories as well as to the growers to establish trade between them in the use of these wheats. The factories will thus be able to obtain either the wheats or semolina made from them at much less cost than the imported material, and the farmers will have the benefit of a quick home market Another strong advantage in using these wheats in our own factories, and which especially affects the consumer, lies in the fact that the homemade product, other conditions being equal, is always much better from the standpoint of simple freshness. We all know how much better fresh bread is than old, and what a nutty flavor newly-made flour gives to the bread. These facts apply with even greater force in macaroni making. All imported macaronis must of necessity have lost a large per cent of their flavor, and as the homemade product is made almost entirely from common wheats, it follows that the majority of American people really have never tasted the very best macaroni. More than all else the use of macaroni as a food is far from general in this country, and should become more popular. It is a comparatively rare food with us. A: already quoted in another place, in France alone the annual output of edible pastes is estimated at from 120,000,000 to 170,000,000 pounds. A considerable amount of this is of course exported, but there remains an enormous amount which is consumed In France. These pastes are among the most common and popular foods in that country. The same may be said of Italy. Let a sufficient amount of good wheat be grown and our factories begin producing from these wheats its best article possible, in a variety of forms, and there is no good reason apparent why such foods should not soon rank in popularity with our breakfast foods. HUNDRED AND ONE TESTS THROUGHOUT NEBRASKA. The durum wheats distributed in the spring of 1902 con - sisted of a number of varieties, most of which were imported directly from Algeria and the remainder from Russia, except a small amount grown in this country. It is perhaps un - fortunate that more of the seed was not of Russian origin, for the results indicate very plainly that it is more produc - tive than that from Algeria. Previous experience has also shown that seed grown at least one year in this region gives larger yields than imported seed. This, together with the fact that the season was not such as has been considered favorable for the growth of this crop, has made the test a severe one. Most of the experimenters received one bushel of seed which it was expected would be sown on one acre of land. No attempt was made to prescribe in what manner the land was to be prepared for the seed, or how the seed was to be </seg>
            <seg id="p007">7 sown. These and other unknown conditions that always enter into a test of this kind make it impossible to draw more than general conclusions, and make it desirable to report individual tests so far as space will permit. The following is the tabulated experience of each experimenter, omitting from necessity much interesting information that accompa- nied the report blanks from which this is compiled : ADAMS COUNTY Experimenter J. D. Evans. . . . A. H. Farrens. . Cbas. Kidd Post-office Kenesaw Hastings Kenesaw Variety of wheat Kubanka Mahmoudi Maraouani, from Algeria. Sown on bottom or upland ?. Upland Upland Upland .... Nature of soil? Loam with sand Loam Clay .. Date of sowing ? Last week Mar. March 27 March 8 ... Amount of seed per acre ? . . 1 bushel 1 bushel 1 bushel . . Good or poor stand ? Thin on ground Good stand .... Poor stand Date of ripening? Last of July . . . July 25. . Did it rust, smut, or lodge ?. Rusted badly . . Lodged badly . . Rusted Date of cutting ? Did not cut July 28 ... Yield of grain per acre? .... Did not thresh Did not thresh. 40 bushels. Comparison with other spring or winter wheat ... Better ADAMS COUNTY BLAINE. BOX BUTTE CO. Experimenter C. L. Mosier. . . E.D.Oldhani'j. A. Smith . . Post-office Juniata Brewster . . . Hemingford . . Variety of wheat Pelissier, mixed Kubanka . . . Yellow Gharnovka. . with Mahmoudi Variety of wheat Sown on bottom or upland ? Upland 2d bottom . . Part bot running np on slope. Nature of soil ? Sandy loam .... Sandy loam . Sandy loam . . Date of sowing ? April 21 April 7 April 7 . . a * _r i } 11/ i i__i_ if/ i i.«i_ l V...U.I Date of sowing ? Amount of seed per acre ?. . . \\% bushels ljjj bushels. 1 bushel Good or poor stand ? Good Fair Could have been thicker. Date of ripening? July 15 August 1 Did it rust, smut, or lodge ? . All lodged No, heads dropt from weight. Date of cutting ? Did not harvest July 29 About Aug. 8 Yield of grain p-r acre ? 19 bushels . . 20 bushels Comparison with other spring or winter wheat ... Better qual- Not so good ltv and yield! </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 BOYD COUNTY. BROWN CO. CLAY COUNTY. CUSTER CO. Experimenter Post-office Variety of wheat. . A. A. Cramer . . Bristow Pelissier John Korab . . . . W. D. McCord . . Lynch Ainsworth Kubanka Kubanka sown on bottom or upland ? %'ature of soil ? Upland Gumbo Upland Gumbo and sandy loam. April 10 1 bushel Medium Upland Sandy loam Date of sowing ? Imount of seed per acre?. . . iood or poor stand ? t: of ripening ? it rust, smut, or lodge?, of cutting? i of grain per acre ? parison with other ( ring or winter wheat. -J April 4 \\i bushels .... Poor August 1 July 20 Some smut July 26 '25 bushels Spring wheat, about 15-20 bushels. 1 bn. on 1)4 acres Good as could be expected for seed sown. July 21 |No July 31 25 bu. from 1J4 ac - Yield more than twice as much as spring wheat. August 1 8 bushels Better than spg. wheat accord 'g to stand. Experimenter 'ost-office Variety of wheat Sam'l J. Case.. Sutton Pelissier David Mitchell . S. L. Glover Sutton Weissert Richi Kubanka own on bottom or upland ? lature of soil ? )ate of sowing ? l mount of seed per acre ?. . . Jood or poor stand ? )ate of ripening? &gt;id it rust, smut, or lodge ?. Low land Loam March 10 1H bushels.... Good July 10 No Upland Sandy loam First days April K bushel Good stand July 20 No Upland Loam March 14 1 bushel Rather thin J»iy 20 Rusted )ate of cutting ? field of grain per acre ? omparison with other spring or winter wheat . . . July 15 6 bushels July 21 About 5 bushels 20 to 25 July 104 bu., 5 acres.. Far better than spring wheat; as good as winter. Not so good as winter grain. Winter wheat, 25-. 35 bu., spring, 12-14 bu. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Macaroni Wheats. 9 CUSTER COUNTY. DAWES CO. C. R. Krenz P. H. Marley Ijohn Walker F. J. Coil Hough . . Merna Mason City Mason City Pelissier Yellow Gharnovka Richi. Mohamed ben Bachir. Upland Upland Upland jUplaud . Clay Loam Loam Mar. 31 and Apr. 26 May 1 April 29 1 bushel 1 bushel . . 1 bushel Loam March 24 1 bushel 1 bushel . 1 bushel Bbu.on 7 acres. Good Medium Good Good July 20 July 21 July 21 August 9 No Lodged some, but got all Lodged some, but No Good of it. got all of it July 24 July 21 July 12 bushels 16&amp; bushels 20 bushels. . . IJuly August 9 About 30-35 bu. About twice as good. Leading wheat in Would n't have raised 5 Spring wheat sown this locality. bu. of ordinary spring at same time would wheat sown at this time, not have yielded 5 jbushels. BUFFALO COUNTY. BUTLER COUNTY. CHERRY. .. N. Gordon . . learney ellow Ghar- novka. Wm. Mueller. . Riverdale Pelissier John D. Hasik. Mat Hasik M. Hansen.. Abie Abie Gordon Yellow Ghar- Yellow Ghar- novka. novka. Bottom Loam March 20 1 bushel Fair July8 No July 8 13 bushels Winter wheat, 30-35 bushels. Upland Loam March 22 1 bn. to % acre. Poor August 1 Rusted August 1 18 bushels Spring wheat, 5-8 bu. Winter wheat, 30-40 bu. Upland Upland Upland ..... Dark loam Loam Black sandy March 27 April 1 April 11 .... \% bu 2 bushels 1 bushel Good Medium Very poor . . July 15 July 15 Not known. Very rusty ..... IGood deal of rust No July 18 ljuly 18..- Not known. 8 bu. , 7 lbs |8 bushels Estim. 1 bu. Spring wheat, Not so good as Not so good 10-20 bu. , win- sp'g wheat. Hurt as the Sea ter, 18-22 bu. by chinch bugs. Island. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Macaroni Wheats. DAWES COUNTY. DAWSON CO. DUNDY CO. |j. F. Howard Whitney John Donelson. . . M. W. Nesmith Experimenter Post-office Farnam Calvert Variety of wheat. Kubanka Yellow Ghar- Kubanka novka. Sown on bottom or Nature of soil? upland ? B -&gt;ttom . Upland Upland . .• Sandy loam Rich dark loam Sandy loam Early April 1 bushel... Date of sowing ? April Early in April . Amount of seed per acre? Good or poor stand ? 14 lbs. , */ie acre. . J^bu.,pressdrill Good Good Good even stand Date of ripening ? July 25 to 30 Cut down by hail July 15 to 20. . Did it rust, smut, or lodge ? Date of cutting ? No Slight rust No July 30 - Yield of grain per acre ? 29 bushels. Think I wouldlKilled by grass- have had 10-15J hoppers Comparison with other spring or winter wheat. . bu. on */i» acre. FURNAS COU TY. Jxperimenter J ost-office /ariety of wheat A. d'AUemand. Arapahoe Kubanka R. D. Griffith.. Oxford Yellow Ghar- novka. L. G Knuppel . Beaver City Mahmoudi .... own on bottom or upland ? Jature of soil? )ate of sowing ? amount of seed per acre ?. . . rood or poor stand ? )ate of ripening ? Upland Sandy loam .... March 24 1 bushel Splendid Not quite ripe when cut. Upland Sandy loam .... March 24 1 bushel Part good Cut little green. Upland Sandy loam March 28 1 bushel Fair July 10 )id it rust, smut, or lodge? )ate of cutting ? field of grain per acre? Comparison with other spring or winter wheat . . . No July 14 25 bushels Black rust July 20 18 bushels No July 15 10 bushels Yield better About one-half yield. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">Macaroni Wheats. 11 FURNAS COUNTY. A. Meyerle G. A. Prime Mark Prime J. H. Rosenfelt. . Holbrook Arapahoe Arapahoe Cambridge . Kubanka Yellow Gharnovka . Richi iKubanka .... Upland Upland Bottom Upland Black loam Loam Good soil Sandy loam March 7 March 12 JApril 25 (.March 15. .. 1 bushel ... N/mo of bushel 1 bushel |3 pecks Rather thin Good Poor Good July 15 July 14 July 20 Destroyed by cut- worms. No No No July 15 Julv 14 July 29 25 bushels 17.55 bushels 16 bushels Av. yield spring Spring wheat, 12 to Poor, grasshoppers wheat, 12 bu. 16 bu. ; winter, 25 ate leaves. to 45 bu. FRANKLIN COUNTY. FURNAS COUNTY. Albert M. Averhoff Geo. R. Moore Franklin Naponee Pelissier and Mah- Pelissier nioudi mixed. G. A. Anderson. . . Wilsonville Pelissier M. R. Crocker Arapahoe Pelissier Upland Upland Bottom Sandy loam Clay loam Black loam April 5 April 2 March 25 1 bushel 1 bushel 1 bushel Poor Rather thin Good Didn't wait for it July 22 July 4. to ripen. No No Lodged badly July 15 July 22 July 17 10 bushels 25 bushels 32 bushels Yield would have Winter wheat, 25 to been great but 40 bushels, chinch bugs came. Upland. . . Loam March 22. lJi bushels... Rather thin . . July 20. ... No July 20 24 bushels No spring wheat in this locality. We used to think 15 bu. good. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 HITCHCOCK COUNTY. GAGE COUN Y. GOSPER CO. HALL CO. Jrperimenter 'ost-office Variety of wheat M. V. Nichols . Beatrice . . Richi [bein Wm. Schievel- Arapahoe R. O. Adams... Grand Island... Pelissier Sown on bottom or upland ? Nature of soil ? Date of sowing ? Amount of seed per acre?. . . Good or poor stand ? Date of ripening? Did it rust, smut, or lodge? Date of cutting ? Yield of grain per acre ? Comparison with other spring or winter wheat . . . Medium upland Black loam April 4 1 bushel Good July 15 No July 25 9 bushels Upland Sandy loam April 25 5^ acre, tfbu.. Good July 5 No July 15 15 bu. from 14 bushel seed. Ahead of other spring wheat. Upland Sandy soil April 19 60 lbs. on % acre. Fair July 16 Rusted and lodg ' d July 18 10 bushels About one-third usual yield. Other wheat 20 to 10 bushels. Sxperimenter J ost-onice /ariety of wheat Jonas Lorance . . . Palisade Kubanka J. H. Ross N. L. Wemple. Culbertson Culbertson Kahla Kahla own on bottom or upland ? lature of soil ? Upland Loam Bottom land. . . Sandy loam .... Bottom Sandy loam .... )ate of sowing ? [.mount of seed per acre ?. . . rood or poor stand ? &gt;ate of ripening ? &gt;id it rust, smut, or lodge ? I bushel '.'.'.'.'.'.'.'. Poor July 15 No April 4 1 bushel Good Did not ripen . . April 7 to 10... 1 bushel Good Did not ripen . . )ate of cutting ? rield of grain per acre? omparison with other spring or winter wheat . . . July 15 Destroyed by grasshoppers. Destroyed by About as good as any in locality. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 HALL COUNTY. HARLAN COUNTY. H. W. Risley Geo. T. Ashby Geo. T. Ashby R. J. Ashby. Grand Island Alma Alma Alma. Mahmoudi Richi Adjini Yellow Gharuovka Upland Upland Upland Upland Upland Upland Upland Upland Loam . t Sandy soil Clay loam Loam Sandy soil Clay loam Loam Loam April 19 April 2 March 24 April 19 April 2 [March 24 March 22 March 22. 1 bushel . Good 60 lbs., \ acre. . . . 1 bushel 1 bushel 60 lbs., \ acre. . . . 1 bushel II bushel 1 bushel Fair Good Good Fair Good Good Good July 16 July 20 July 17 July 16 July 20 July 17 July 17 July 17. No Rusted and lodged No No Rusted and lodged No No July 18 July 17 July 17 July 18 July 17 July 17 July 17 July 17. 10 bushels 8 bushels. ...... . . 33 bushels . . . . . . . . . 10 bushels 8 bushels 33 bushels 7 bushels 7 bushels. Other wheat, 20 to As good as winter, As good as best win - 40 bushels. better than spring, ter; bet. than spring. Other wheat, 20 to As good as winter, As good as best win - 40 bushels. better than spring, ter; bet. than spring. Better than spring wheat. Better than spring wheat. HITCHCOCK CO. HOLT COUNTY. HITCHCOCK CO. John M. Williams. James A. Bibee . . . Thomas Dillet .... George Jonas Kubanka and Richi iRichi Pelissier Richi mixed. Richi mixed. Bottom Upland Bottom Upland Upland Upland Upland Upland Sandy loam and Sandy loam gumbo. Sandy loam and Sandy loam Sandy loam Sand and alkali .... Sandy loam Sand and alkali gumbo. March 3 April 20 April 21 March 24 March 3 April 20 April 22 March 24 1 bushel 2 bushels 1 bushel 2 bushels. 2 bushels X%, bushels 2 bushels 1)£ bushels Medium Good Medium Good Good iGood stand ... Good iGood stand. . . July 18 July 18 July 18 July 18 July 23 July 23 July 23 July 23 No No No No No 'Few smutty heads; lodged a little. No 'Few smutty heads; I lodged a little. July 25 July 26 22 bushels 25 bushels July 18 July 20 July 18 July 20 July 25 July 26 20 bushels 20 bushels 20 bushels.!..!..! 20 bushels 22 bushels 25 bushels 15 per cent better Better than spring wheat. 15 per cent better Better Better wheat, 10 to Better ( Spring wheat, 10 to than sprint? wheat. 23; winter wheat, Culbertson Star Star Atkinson </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Macaroni Wheats. HOLT COUNTY. Experimenter •ost-office Variety of wheat Theo. Kubart.. Atkinson Richi John Matejka. . Atkinson Pelissier Mathew Matejka. Atkinson Pelissier. . . Sown on bottom or upland ?| Nature of soil ? Upland Sand Bottom Black sandy loam. April 11 About \% bu.. Good July 25 No July 29 25 bushels Bottom . . Sandy loam Date of sowing ? Amount of seed per acre?. . . Good or poor stand ? Date of ripening ? Did it rust, smut, or lodge?. Date of cutting ? Yield of grain per acre? Comparison with other spring or winter wheat. . . March 24 % bu. per acre . Fair July 25 Lodged some . . July 29 19 bushels April 9... 1 bushel . Good July25.... No August 5 20 bushels. 5 bushels better than other wheat. 5 to 10 bu. more than spring; 5 to 7 less than winter. LINCOLN COU: *TY. Experimenter 'ost-office Variety of wheat J.and L. Brosius Whittier Adjini B. W. Gosnell... Myrtle Mohamed ben Bachir. pdyrtle .'.'.' Pelissier Sown on bottom or upland ? Nature of soil ? Date of sowing ? Amount of seed per acre ?. . . Good or poor stand? Date of ripening ? Did it rust, smut, or lodge ?. Date of cutting ? ' Yield of grain per acre ? Comparison with other spring or winter wheat . . . Lowland Sandy loam .... April 14 3 pecks Good Upland Sandy Last of April .... 3 pecks Fair July 26 Rusted August 1 10bu.,3pks Upland Sandy Last of April. . . 3 pecks. Fair July 26 .. Rusted August 1 10bu.,3pks... iio'.'.Y.. ....... July 26 30 bushels Will outyield common wheat Think it will outyield coin- I ! </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Macaroni Wheats. 15 HOLT COUNTY. HOWARD CO. KEITH COUNTY. Anton Tresnak John C. Herr VJ. Heiser A. P. Moore. Brnle Atkinson Farwell [f axton Pelissier Mahmoudi Mahmoudi Richi Bottom Bottom Upland «-% _ J 1 _ _ &lt;n« t » (&lt; 1 Upland Sandy loam Black loam Sandy Sandy loam April 9 April 10 April April 2. . 1 bushel. Good ... 1 bushel I bushel 1 bushel Good Good KJood July 26 Latter part July. . July [July 31. |No .... No Rusted a little [No' August 5 Latter part July . . . July 15 Cut down by hail . . 203? bushels 20 bushels 15 bushels 5 to 10 bu. moreNot so good as Better Up with winter wheat. than common winter wheat spring wheat. LOGAN COUNTY. Arthur Clark George Kramer. . . P. E. Tortel Simon Wright Gandy . Gandy Gandy Gandy Adjini Yellow Gharnovka Yellow Gharnovka Adjini Upland . Loam . . April 9. Upland Clay . . . Upland Upland Dark clay Loam April 10. \3 pecks . Good... April 8 April 20 3 pecks 1 bushel 5 pecks. Fair Good Good August 5 . . -ome smut August 11 . July 15. Rusted July 28 July 10 July 15 Rusted No' August 2 July 15 20 bushels fl.7 bushels 35 bushels 18 bushels. Better than spring; some winter wheat Spring wheat, 10 to 12 bushel*. Better than springJBetter wheat. better. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Macaroni Wheats. 16 MERRICK COUNTY. PERKINS COUNTY. Experimenter J. J. Hurst Post-office Central City.Nebr. Variety of wheat Yellow Gharnovka J. S. Beck.... Grant Pelissier T. D. Cwey... Elsie Pelissier Sown on bottom or upland ? Nature of soil ? Bottom % on sand and alkali; J ., on good black soil. March 22 1 bushel Upland Sandy loam . . Upland Sandy loam.... Date of sowing ? Amount of seed per acre?. . . March 29 Trifle over 1% bushels Good April 1 12 pounds Good or poor stand ? Date of ripening ? Did it rust, smut, or lodge ?. Date of cutting ? On alkali land, poor; good land, good. July Lodged badly Between July 15 and 30. No.'.'.'. '.7.7. ! ! Good August 5 No August 8 Yield of grain per acre ? Comparison with other spring or winter wheat. . . 10 bushels. . . . 10 bushels Winter wheat bet- ter. Better than other wheat Better PHELPS COUNTY. POLK CO. RED WILLOW. Experimenter Post-office Variety of wheat LJ. D. Taylor . . . [Holdrege Kubanka G. V. Rosene.. Stromsburg .... Mahmoudi .... I. R. Andrews. . . Indianola Kubanka and Richi. sown on bottom or upland ? •Nature of soil ? Date of sowing ? Vraount of seed per acre ?. . . iood or poor stand ? Date of ripening? Upland Loam March 12 1 bushel Good July 20 Upland Sandy loam .... March 31 1 bushel Good Never ripened well. Lodged August 6 3 bushels Upland Sandy loam April' 18 1 bushel Good July5 Did it rust, smut, or lodge ?. Date of cutting? field of grain per acre ? . . . . Comparison with other spring or winter wheat . . . Lodged July 20 28 bu., 40 lbs... No July5 15 bushel* Winter wheat, 30 to 40 bu. Winter wheat on same eleva- tion, 38 bu Other wheat abo't 10 bushels. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">Macaroni Wheats. 17 PERKINS COUNTY PHELPS COUNTY. Charles Eppler..|S. Wall. S. G. Berquist J. M. Hopkins Westmark Atlanta Grant Grant Westmark Mahmoudi Kahla Pelissier Kubanka. Upland Sandy . Upland. . . . Sandy loam Upland. Upland Loam . [Sandy loam March 27 March 25. 1 bushel . March 12 1 bushel . % bushel Little over J£ bu . . Thin ' Poor Thin IGood. July 25. July 23. Lodged July 28. (July 16 . Lodged. July 16. No;brokenbyhail No July 21 July 28. 22 bushels. 33.20 bushels Better Superior Winter wheat, 42 Spring wheat yield - bu.; spring, 18; ed 16 20 bushels. but little sown RED WILLOW COUNTY. tien Bolles.... Paul H. Hume.... Butler Jones W. A. McCool lder Indianola Indianola Indianola Yellow Gharnovka Pelissier Pelissier and Maraonani from Al- Kahla . geria. Kahla . gena. Upland Upland Black loam Upland Bottom Upland Bottom Upland Upland Black loam Sandy loam Sandy loam . . Sandy loam Sandy loam March 24 March 20 March 24 March 20 . . . . April 5 March 1 April 5 March 1 %, bushel 1 bu., % acre 3 pecks \% bushels 3 pecks 1^ bushels H bushel 1 bu., % acre . Good Medium Good Medium Good Good Good Good July 19 July 10 July 19 July 10 July 10 July 10 No No No No July Wl V... ...... July i2~. '..[['.'.'.'.'.. July 19 July 12 July 10 July 10 11 bushels i 19 bu. on % acre L'O bushels 'Taken in June by 11 bushels 19 bu. on % acre. . JO bushels Taken in June by grasshoppers. grasshoppers. Spring wheat, 6 Other wheat, 12 to bushels. '25 bushels. Spring wheat, 6Other wheat, 12 to Shows indication of being far su Shows indication of being far su - perior. bushels. 25 bushels. penor. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 RED WILLOW COUNTY. SALINE COUNTY. Experimenter . '&gt;eo. Maisel . . . J. W. Ingles . . . M. O. Johnson.. Post-office lianola Pleasant Hill . .Crete Variety of wheat [Pelissier Mahmoudi Mahmoudi Sown on bottom or upland ?|Upland jUpland jUpland Nature of soil? Good black soil. Sandy loam Date of sowing ? First half April. March 22 April 4. . Amount of seed per acre ?. . . 1 bushel 7 pecks 1 bushel Good or poor stand ? About a half Good Good . . . About a half Good Good stand. Date of ripening? July 10 |july 13 ™ ~'F^ o J J — |J — J — ' Did it rust, smut, or lodge ? No ISmut, % head Date of cutting ? July 10 July 22 Yield of grain per acre ? . . . . 24 bushels 19 bushels Destroyed by Comparison with other grasshoppers, spring or winter wheat . . . Better SEWARD COUNTY. SHERIDAN COUNTY. Experimenter Jay Oliver J. W. Burrows. James Egan Post-office uca Hay Springs. . . Albany. Variety of wheat. Mahmoudi Yellow Gharnovka Sown on bottom or upland? Upland Upland Upland Nature of soil ? 18-inch black loam Sandy loam. ... IC1 ay and sand. Date of sowing ? March 29 April 27 April 2 Amount of seed per acre?. . . 1 bushel 1 bushel 1 bushel Good or poor stand ? Poor Good Splendid . Date of ripening ? July 10 July 20. rit rust, smut, or lodge ?. Rusted and badlv. lodged No No Date of cutting ? July 10, August 5 Aug. 5. Yield of grain per acre? ... .Never threshed; too Too poor to 36 bu.. Comparison with other wet thresh. spring or winter wheat ... : Better </seg>
            <seg id="p019">19 SCOTTS BLUFF COUNTY. SEWARD CO. A. V. Fife J. L. Gilmore Fred Katzer James Krenk ... A. V. Fife [J. L. Giltnore Fred Katzer I James Krenk Gering Caldwell Caldwell Dwight . . Gering Caidwell. . Caldwell Black Don from Adjini Mahmoudi Russia. Black Don from Adjini.. Russia. IMahmoudi Upland Bottom Bottom Bottom . . Upland Bottom ; Bottom ttom Sandy loam Sandy loam Sandy loam Clay .... Sandy loam |Clay . . . Sandy loam Sandy loam April 1 April 1 April 20 April 18 April 1 April 1 . April 20 April 18 1 bushel (about) . . 1 bushel \% bushels 1 bushel . 1 bushel (about). .1 bushel IK bushels 1 bushel Fairly good Good Pretty fair Rather poor Fairly good Good Pretty fair Rather poor July 20 Aug. 10, not all ripe July 25 July 20 Aug. 10, not all ripe July 25. No No No' No No [No July -JO August 10 July 25 July 98 lAugust 10 July 25. 20 bushels 14 bushels 25 bushels Destroyed I 20 bushels 14 bushels 25 bushels Destroyed chinch bugs. chinch bugs. Spring wheat about Compared favorably same. with other wheat Spring wheat about Compared favorably with other wheat same. SHERIDAN COUNTY. SHERMAN CO SHERIDAN COUNTY Elmer E Randal Jules A. Sandoz. . . A. F. Smith E. H. Kittell E. H. Kittell. Rockville Colclesser Colclesser j Hay Springs Pelissier Yellow Ghar- Yellow Gharnvoka novka. Upland Upland Upland. Upland Loam. . Dark sandy loam. .Clay or gumbo. Sandy loam. April 7 April 8 April 24 April 1. 1 bushel Wbu. per acre . 1 bushel. X bushel Very good Good. Fair but little thin . Poor August 11 August 5. Lodged some Rusted. . . • - j o About August 1 Some rust No . August 11 and 12. . August 5. . 18}$ bushels Early in August. \Y%. bushels 5 bushels. Velvet chaff blue stem yielded 17 bu. Quality inferior. . </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 i ' WEBSTER CO 1NTY. YORK COUNTY. Experimenter Post-office Variety of wheat Rudolph Frey . . . Guiderock Velvet Don from Russia. Morrison Castle John S. Welty. York Gresham Richi Yellow Ghar- novka. own on bottom or upland ?. lature of soil ? )ate of sowing ? Upland Sandy loam March 10 Upland Sandy loam . . . March 22 Upland Loam March 13... [.mount of seed per acre ? . . rood or poor stand? &gt;ate of ripening ? &gt;id it rust, smut, or lodge?. lKbushels Medium July 15 No X% bushels... Medium July 10 Little smut, lodged badly. July 11 12 bushels 1J£ bushels Fair. . . July 21 Lodged &gt;«te of cutting? rield of grain per acre? .... omparison with other spring or winter wheat. . . July 15 p2 bushels July 22 U8 bushels . . . Three times as much as winter Think other wheat better. SHERMAN* COUNTY. STANTON CO. THAYER CO. Experimenter T. D. Wilson. . . H. E. Scripture. A. P. Hazard Post-office Ashton Stanton Hebron XT - 1_1_ «»_. . • i Variety of wheat I.Mahmoudi. Kahla Maraouni, from Algeria Sown on bottom or upland ? Bottom Second bottom . Upland Nature of soil ? Loam Clay Loam Date of sowing ? March 28 March 26'. . .. . . Nov. 2,'fa'li; Apr 1 13, spring. Amount of seed per acre ?. . . 1 bushel . 1 bu. on \ acre. % bushel in al Poor Good Good or poor stand ? | Poor Date of ripening ? |July 23 Ifuly 22 Can't tell .... Did it rust, smut, or lodge?. Lodged badly Some rust No Date of cutting ? July 23 July 28 Yield of grain per acre? .... 10 bushels, poor 18 bushels 3Ji bu. seed Comparison with other Jiacre. spring or winter wheat . . .Winter wheat, As good as any 30 bu.; spring, 10 bu. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Macaroni Wheats. 21 VALLEY COUNTY. Mrs. M. A. Barker. Joseph Masin. . VT ll. T Vincent Masin Ord E. A. Russell. Ord North Loup Ord Yellow Gharnovka Pelissier. Pelissier. Yellow Gharnovka. Upland Upland Bottom. Upland. Sandy black loam .Black soil Black soil I.oam April 1 April 7 |April 17 April 1 \% bushels 1 bushel 1 bushel I bushel. Good Good 'Good Good, little thin July 24 July 28 August 15.... July 26. No Little Lodged Lodged little July 24 July 28 August 15... July 26.... SO bushels .... :&gt;4 bushels . 30 bu.; sowed 1 bu. 16 bushels. . on % acre. Velvet chaff, 8 to Way ahead of 15 bu. other spring About same as Far superior to spring winter wheat, wheat. and winter i wheat. DISCUSSION OF TABULATED BEPOBTS. The reports on the productiveness of durum wheats as compared with other spring and with winter varieties are quite conflicting. In order to afford a clearer basis for com- parison, they have been tabulated by counties as follows: As good as or better than spring wheat. As good as or better than winter wheat. Poorer than Poorer than spring wheat, winter wheat 1 1 Adams 1 Blaine 1 1 1 Box Butte Boyd Brown 1 Buffalo 1 ! Butler 2 1 Cherry Clay 1 1 1 1 1 Custer 4 Dawes 1 Franklin Furnaa 3 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 As good as or As good as or „ .. _ ,, better than better than Poorer than Poorer tha spring wheat, winter wheat. *P™g wheat, winter whe The average yield of winter wheat in Nebraska for 1902 was, according to Bulletin No. 2 (Sept, 1902) of the Ne - braska Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics, 24 bushels per acre, and of spring wheat 12 bushels. The average yield for all durum wheats tested in 1902 was 18.3 bushels per acre. The durum wheats were grown principally in western counties, while the others were distributed over the state. From the data at hand it is safe to say that durum wheats yield better than other spring varieties, but how they com - pare in this respect with winter wheat in western Nebraska can not be definitely stated at this time. There were a number of reports of the durum wheats hay - ing rusted and lodged. Those raised at the Station were very badly rusted, and also lodged in places. They appeared to be fully as susceptible to rust as other varieties of spring wheats i Gage.. Gosper . . Hall Harlan Hitchcock Holt Howard Keith Lincoln Logan Merrick Perkins Phelps Polk Red Willow Scotts Bluff Sheridan Sherman rhayer Valley Webster AJ1 counties in which tested 1 4 i' I I i ■2 5 2 1 1 1 s 51 2 1 3 •&gt; I 4 4 1 1 "i" 9 1 31 1 I i l i 10 l r i 1 i l a \4 51 21 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">23 The average time of ripening was July 16, both for the tests made throughout the state, and for those made at the Station. The average time of ripening for sowings made before April 1 was the same as for those made after April 1. E'he average yield of all sowings made before April 1 was &gt; bushels per acre; of all sowings made after April 1, 17..") hels per acre. This indicates that, for at least the year orted, early planting was desirable. As macaroni wheats not easily injured by frost, this rule will doubtless hold a* for all ordinary years. The average yield per acre and number of tests of each variety were as follows : Oriein Yield P" r Number °f 6 " acre. trials. Variety. Emitting varieties of which there were less than five tests, average yield per acre for the Russian varieties was 21.2 lels, and for the Algerian varieties 17.6 bushels. Ii test of a number of varieties of durum wheats was made the Experiment Station. The unusually wet weather and rd windstorms interfered much with the growth of the eats, and doubtless decreased the yields. The test is there - e of less value than it would have been in a normal season. : varieties were planted March 20 to 27 and were put in ;h a press drill. Inka Russia noudi Algeria . auani Algeria . iier . igeria .... i Algeria . .nied ben Bachir . . Algeria . . w Gharnovka Russia i Algeria i Algeria Don Russia t Don Russia 25.0 bu. 14.9 bu. 26.5 bu. 17.8 bu. 14.6 bu. 16.9 bu. 17.4 bu. 23.0 bu. 18.0 bu. 20.0 bu. 22.0 bu. 9 9 2 22 9 I 16 5 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Origin. VUdpcr Pounds per Variety. acre. Pererodka Russia 14.0 bu. Velvet Don. Gliarnovka . Russia 9.0 bu. Russia 16.5 bu. Russia 14.5 bu. Yellow Gbarnovka. Velvet Don Russia 10.5 bu. Gharnovka Kubanka . . Maraouni. . Kahla Russia 12.0 bu. Russia 12.5 bu. Algeria 7.3 bu. Algeria . 7.3 bu. Richi . Algeria . 8.0 bu. Black Don. Mahmoudi . Kahla Russia 12.0 bu. Algeria . 6.3 bu. Algeria . 8.0 bu. Algeria 9.0 bu. Adjini Mobamed ben Bachir Yellow Gharnovka . . . Algeria 11.3 bu. Russia 13.3 bu. Algeria . 7.7 bu. While the variety test at the Station is not satisfac- very tory as indicating the variety best adapted to our conditions &lt;t K rings out strongly the superiority of the Russian varie- Thus, the average yield for all Russian varieties is 12.7 ids per acre, and for all Algerian varieties 8.1 bushels. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>