<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00040.00030">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00040.00030</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris</title>
               <date value="1916-03-15">1916-03-15</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">RESEARCH BULLETIN NO. 7 The University of Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA. A GENETIC STUDY OF PLANT HEIGHT IN PHASEOLUS VULGARIS. By R. A. Emerson. Distributed March 15, 1916 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD. HONORABLE PHIL11' L. HALL, Lincoln. HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WH1TMORK, Valley. HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFORD, Present. Kails ( HONORABLE FRANK L. HALLER, Omaha. HONORABLE EDWARD 1'. BROWN, Davey. y HONORABLE JOHN E. MILLER, Lincoln THE STATION OFFICERS. SAMUEL AVERY, 1'H. D., LL. D., Chancellor, ex ottiiio E. A. BURNETT, B. Sc., Director; Animal Husbandry. C. W. PUGSLEY, B. Sc., Director of Extenntm Serrice. Extrnxion Serric J. S. DALES, M. PH., Finar, relary FRANK C. DEAN, A. B., / Edik THE WORKING STAFF E. Mead WUCOX. Ph. D., Agricultural B&lt; F. W. Upson, Ph. D., A,j HI l. w. Cub, If. i:.. a h .1. H. (Jain, II. DC, .4) J. H. Frandskn, M. S. A LAWRENCE BRl NKR, H T. A. KlESSELBACH, A H. C. F11.1.KV. A. M.. r 'R. A. Emerson, D.Sc. H R. K. Howard, A. If., // C. B. Lee, A. M., AmoeiaU in Animal H Howard .1. Gkamuch, H L. L. Zook, B. Sc., A*suiat Agriculture, North Platt P. B. Barker, A. If., Amittani in Ayr Krwin Hoi-T, B. Sc. Atnatani in Ayrninimy tCroi J. A. Katclifk, A. M., A*si*lant in Experimental A Florence A. McCokmkk, Ph. D., Aacutmi in I James Cowan, If. E., Superintendent Experimental Sutmtat \alentine Mitchell. it FRITZ KNORR, B. Sc, Superintendent Experimental Substation RcHfned September 1, li»14. to become head of the Department of Plant Breeding. Cornell University, Ithaca, New Yor ■■Rpsigneri. G. A. Lovei.am., A. If., Mi W. P. Snyder, M.S.. Supt. M. H. SWBfK, A. M , AtsoeiaU in Entomolo$ 0mm K. K. Link. A. M.. Attialanl in An H. A. McComb, B. SC., Horticulturist ,,f 1 Platte. J. W. Calvin, H. Sc, Amittunt in Agri L. B. Stikdkvant, A. M., M. 1)., Auittani in Animal l',i E. G. Woodward, A. If., Anuteni in Dairy Husliamby. J. R. COOPER, B. S&lt; ., limiltamt in Horticulture. C. A. HELM, A. If., A. -&lt;fi.it mil in Experimental AyrotKimy. H. E. Vasey, A. ML, Assistant in Agricultural Botany H. L. Nye, Foreman l&gt;emi&gt;n.&lt;tration Farm, Oulbertson. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">CONTENTS. Page. 4 .summary Introduction 8 10 Previous investigations 11 Materials and meth&lt;xls 15 Growth habit in beans 24 Growth curvet habits of Inheritance of determinate and growth indeterminate 30 Inheritance of number of internode 31 Calculation of internode length 38 Inheritance of internode length 14 Factors for plant height their modification in crosses iegregation and possible 56 (14 Literature cited •it; Tables </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY. It is pointed out in this paper that many quantitative charac - ters of plants blend in F, of crosses and exhibit a wide range of variation in F., from which types like the parents or perhaps even more extreme and various intermediate forms can be isolated in F... Height of some plants is known to behave in this way. It is noted also that some quantitative characters, particularly height of several distinctly different plants, exhibit dominance instead of an intermediate condition in F,, followed by a 3:1 segregation in ¥■ and simple Mendelian behavior in later generations. When pole and bush beans are crossed, 3:1 segregation results whether the pole bean is very tall or only medium in height and whether the bush bean is very short or relatively tall. To determine the interrelation of these two types of behavior by an analysis of the factors concerned in height of plants in beans and by a study of their mode of in - heritance was the object of the investigations reported here. Mendel reported simple 3:1 segregation in F.. of crosses of tall and dwarf beans, both when the races concerned belonged to one species, Phaseolus rulgaris. and when one of them belonged to another species, P. multiflnrus. The results of von Tschermak, with crosses between dwarf races of the former species and a tall race of the latter one, were by no means so simple as those reported by Mendel and were thought to be due in part at least to the action of more than one genetic factor. Results previously reported by the writer demonstrated simple Mendelian behavior in crosses between "pole" and "bush" habits of growth in Phaseo - lus rulgaris. The methods employed by the writer in making crosses, growing the plants, protecting them from cross-pollination by insects, making records, etc., as described in detail in the body of this paper, are believed to have been sufficiently careful to make the results reliable as a whole. Pole and bush beans are shown to differ in a single character, habit of growth. Bush beans are determinate in growth habit. The main axis is terminated by an inflorescence when from about four to eight internodes have developed and cannot be forced to make any further growth tho provided with the most favorable conditions of moisture and temperature, and even tho the flowers be removed to prevent the drain of seed production. Pole beans are indeterminate in growth habit. The first flower </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Summary. 5 clusters appear at about the fifth to the eighth node and the others progressively higher as new internodes are added. Growth of the axis is terminated only by accident, unfavorable surroundings, the drain of seed production, and the like. If favorable conditions for growth are provided and if heavy seed production is prevented, pole beans can be kept growing for a long time if not indefinitely. Plants of both classes grow slowly at first and then increasingly more rapidly. In bush beans growth is terminated early in this period of acceleration in growth rate. In pole beans acceleration in growth rate continues for a considerable time, but retardation in growth rate occurs eventually because of the drain of seed production, increasingly unfavorable weather conditions late in the season, and the like. The twining habit common in pole beans is also exhibited by the taller bush beans when they are forced into very vigorous growth. Its failure to develop in bush beans as a whole is due to the fact that growth of the axis is terminated too soon. While bush beans are commonly more branched than pole beans, there are great differences within both classes with respect to this, so that branching habit cannot be used to characterize the classes. Pole and bush beans also differ in height in consequence of the difference in habit of growth. Obviously, height of plants depends upon number of internodes and internode length. Bush beans have a short axis in part because of a small number of internodes and in part also because of a relatively small mean internode length, the latter being due to termination of the plant axis early in the period of growth-rate acceleration. Pole and bush beans, then, are characterized by differences in height, only in so far as height is dependent upon determinate and in - determinate habits of growth. Races of bush beans differ mater - ially in height and the same is true of pole beans. Since the axis of a bush bean is terminated early in thej period of growth-rate acceleration, its actual internode length s con - siderably less than its potential internode length. The latter can be determined only by crossing the bush bean with a pole bean and by comparing the internode length of the plants of indeterminate growth habit thus produced with that of the pole - bean parent or by comparing both with some other pole bean used as a standard. The F_. pole-bean segregates of such crosses are better for this purpose than the F, plants, because increased vigor due to heter - ozygosis is much less in F 2 than in F,. By comparing the potential internode lengths of bush beans, as determined by this method, with the actual internode lengths of these bush beans, it is found </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7. that potential internode length can be determined roughly from actual internode length of the first five internodes of bush beans. It is also found possible to determine with fair accuracy the inter - node length of pole beans by measuring the first 15 internodes, which usually include the greater part of those formed during the period of growth-rate acceleration. It is shown that indeterminate habit of growth in beans is fully dominant to determinate habit, that sharp segregation occurs in F 2 resulting in a ratio of three plants of indeterminate habit to one of determinate habit, and that determinate habit is constant in F 3 while some indeterminate F&gt; plants breed true in F 3 and others segregate again into pole and bush plants. The difference between indeterminate and determinate habits of growth is, therefore, due to a single genetic factor. While number of internodes is directly, and internode length indirectly, related to habit of growth, these characters are in a way distinct from it. There exist distinct types of bush beans with respect to both number of internodes and internode length. The same is true of pole beans. Crossing bush beans of different internode lengths is shown to result in an intermediate condition in Fi and a wider range of variation in F&gt; with respect to internode length. The same re - sults are secured from crosses between pole beans of different internode lengths. A cross between a short pole bean and a tall bush bean is shown to produce tall pole beans in F,. F 2 consists, on the average, of three pole beans to one bush bean, but some of the pole-bean segregates have fewer and shorter internodes than the pole - bean parent and some of the bush-bean segregates have more and longer internodes than the bush-bean parent. The same results are shown to follow when a tall pole bean is crossed with a short bush bean. From the Fj bush segregates of such a cross there has been established a bush-bean race that has more and much longer internodes than the bush-bean parent race. The dominance of indeterminate over determinate habit of growth in a cross between pole and bush beans and the simple 3-1 segregation in F 2 are interpreted just as other simple Men - delian results are, namely, on the basis of a single dominant, genetic factor for the difference between the parents in habit of growth. The intermediate height in Fi and the wide range of variation in F 2 , from a cross between two bush beans or between two pole beans of different heights, are interpreted in accordance with the multiple-factor hypothesis, which postulates that heredi - tary, quantitative differences are due to two or more non- </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Summary. 7 dominant, independently inherited factors. The segregation into three plants with indeterminate habit to one with determinate habit accompanied by an increased range of variation in height of both classes of segregates, when a short pole bean is crossed with a tall bush bean or a tall pole bean with a short bush bean, are, therefore, interpreted by a combination of the single-factor and the multiple-factor hypotheses, or by what may be termed a modified multiple-factor hypothesis, the modification consisting merely in the assumption of inequality in dominance and in - equality in potency between the factors. One dominant factor is assumed to determine habit of growth and therefore to have a much greater potency in the determination of plant height than the two or more other, nondominant factors. It is argued that this modified multiple-factor hypothesis affords a more simple and direct interpretation of the results in bean crosses than does the hypothesis of a single unit-difference between all pole and bush beans, which necessitates the further assumption that the unit-factor is modified commonly, tho irregularly, in crosses between pole and bush beans. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">A GENETIC STUDY OF PLANT HEIGHT IN PHASEOLUS VULGARIS. By R. A. Emerson.'- INTRODUCT1ON. It is now coming to be expected generally that crosses between plant races that differ in quantitative characters will be inter - mediate between their parents in F, with respect to such charac - ters, that they will exhibit a wide range of variation in F_., and that from these F 2 segregates the parent types and various in - termediate forms can be isolated in F t or later generations. Over three years ago Emerson and East ( 1913 1 presented evidence that no less than 11 quantitative characters in Zea mans are inherited in this manner. In the same paper there were reviewed similar results of seven investigations having to do with some twenty quantitative characters in several distinct groups of plants. Some crosses between plants that differ much in size have seemed not to follow the behavior outlined above. Xotable examples of this sort are crosses between tall and dwarf peas (Mendel 1865, Lock 1905, Keeble and Pellew 1910 1, between tall and dwarf tomatoes i Hedrick and Booth 1907, Price and Drinkard 1908, and Gilbert 1912 1, between tall and dwarf sweet peas (Bateson and Punnett 1908), between tall and dwarf beans (Mendel 1865 and Emerson 1904 1, and between tall and dwarf maize (East and Hayes 1911 and Emerson 1911 1. In all these cases perfect dominance of tallness over dwarfness in F, and simple 3-1 segregation in F 2 have been reported. 3 The distinctness of these two classes of behavior with respect to what have seemed to be solely quantitative differences gives them a special importance. Interest in them is heightened by the fact that different quantitative characters of even the same plants are found to belong to the two distinct classes of behavior. Thus, size of seeds in beans belongs to the first class of behavior 'This paper was written in approximately its present form early in 1913. The original manuscript has been modified slightly by the addition of data and by references (mostly in footnotes I to recent papers bearing upon the matter under discussion. * Resigned September, 1914, to become head of the Department of Plant Breeding, Cornell University, Ithaca, New York. 1 Other characters beside tallness and dwarfness are concerned in some of these cases, namely, erect and prostrate habit in sweet peas (Bateson and Punnett 1908) and stout and slender stems in peas (Keeble and Pellew 1910). </seg>
            <seg id="p009">1 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 9 Emerson 1910), while height of plants has been put in the second class. In certain crosses between tall and dwarf maize me type of behavior results, and in other crosses the other type exhibited. Intermediate development in Fi and a wide range of variation in F_., characteristic of one of these classes, is now interpreted rather generally, tho by no means universally, ' by the multiple - factor hypothesis, which postulates that, external influences aside, quantitative differences depend upon two or more independ - ently inherited, nondominant, 2 genetic factors — a strictly Men - delian interpretation. Quantitative differences that show domi - nance in Fi, followed by a 3-1 segregation in F 2 , must depend upon a single dominant, genetic factor or upon factors that are coupled in inheritance. That some quantitative differences are due to a single factor while others are due to many factors need not, it might seem at first, occasion any wonder. In maize, for instance, seeds may differ much or little in breadth. When the parents of a cross differ much, many more individuals must be grown in F_. than when they differ little, if the parent sizes are to be re - covered. In other words large differences in breadth of seeds appear to be due to more factors than do small differences. Is it not to be expected, then, that some differences may be due to a single factor? The fact of prime importance in this connection is that both large and small quantitative differences in the same plant parts seem to depend upon a single factor. Thus, in crosses between pole beans and bush beans, the F, plants are always pole beans and the F : plants consist of approximately three pole beans to one bush bean. This is equally true whether the pole bean parent normally grows to a height of say 12 feet or only to a height of 6 feet and whether the bush bean is 2 feet or only 9 inches high. What happens when a tall bean is crossed with a very tall one? What results are to be expected from a cross between a short bean plant and a very short one? How does a cross between a tall bean and a short one differ from a cross between a very tall bean and a very short one? To answer these and similar questions was the purpose of the investigations reported here. 1 For an interpretation based upon the assumption that genetic factors are commonly modified in crosses see Castle 1912 and 1914a. 1 Both Shull ( 1914) and Muller (1914) have shown that lack of dominance is not essential to the multiple-factor hypothesis (referred to by Shull as the hypothesis of plural genes i. Shull's argument is based upon the assumption of the possible interaction of dominant factors of opposite effect, as an in - hibitor and a stimulator. Muller's contention is practically the same but is stated in terms of plus and minus dominant factors. A third form of statement for the same results is that part of the positive factors may be fully dominant and part wholly recessive. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7. This account deals with beans alone. Similar investigations are under way with maize in which are concerned both large and small "dwarfs" as well as "tall" plants of various heights. These studies have not been completed, but it seems unlikely that the results can be interpreted in quite the same way as are the results with beans. PREVIOUS INVESTIGATIONS. Mendel (1865) reported the results of a cross between a tall form of the common bean, Phaseolus vulgaris, 10-12 feet high, and a dwarf form of the same species (known then as P. nanus). He found tallness dominant to dwarfness in F, and approximately three tall plants to one dwarf plant in F». All F-_&gt; dwarfs remained constant in F 3 , as did some of the tails, while the rest of the F 2 tails segregated again in F 3 . Mendel also crossed a dwarf form of the common bean with a tall, twining form of the runner bean, P. muUiflorus. Owing to partial sterility, comparatively few individuals of this cross were grown. The results, however, were in very close agreement with those obtained from the cross between tall and dwarf forms of the common bean. In short, Mendel's results with beans were of the same sort as those of his more extensive and better known experiments with peas. Von Tschermak &lt; 1904 ) also crossed a dwarf race of P. rulgaris with a tall race of P. muUiflorus. Here again tallness was domi - nant, tho somewhat weakened, in F u but the results in F : were very different from those reported by Mendel. Of 144 F. plants only 26 were classified as tall and 118 were short, or a ratio of 1:4.5 where a 3:1 ratio was to have been expected. Of the short F 2 plants about one-third were constant in F, and two-thirds segregated again, a preponderant majority of their progeny being short and only a few of them tall, with occasional prostrate, very dwarf, giant, and intermediate plants. The tall FYs segre - gated in F 3 into a majority of tall, twining plants and a minority of short plants. Irregular F 3 progenies were also produced by the very tall, the very dwarf, and the intermediate F 2 plants. In a later paper, von Tschermak (1912) presented additional data from another cross between a short common bean and a tall runner bean. Fi plants were intermediate but nearer the tall parent than the short one. Of the F 2 's, 35 were classed as short, 2 as intermediate, and 18 as tall. F 3 's from F 2 short plants were, with the exception of one tall plant, all short. About four-fifths of these short F 3 's were constant in F 4 , but one-fifth of them produced both short and tall plants, 58 of the former to 4 of the latter. The tall F 2 plants produced in F 3 45 short, 23 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 11 intermediate, and 10 tall plants; and these intermediate and tall F 3 plants produced F 4 progenies that segregated into short, intermediate, and tall, the numbers from intermediate Fj's being 7:4:10 and from tall F.,'s 100:42:16. Von Tschermak concluded that this behavior necessitated the assumption of several factors for the difference in height of the parents and suggested that the results might be further complicated by numer - ical inequality in the formation of gametes and zygotes. Emerson (1904) gave an account of crosses between various "pole" and "bush" races of Phaseolus vulgaris. Of the 109 Fi plants reported, all were pole beans. In F 2 , 324 pole beans and 118 bush beans were recorded. So far as tested, all F 2 bush beans bred true in F 3 and later generations, some having been tested to F : . Of the F 2 pole beans, some bred true and others produced both pole and bush beans, 270 pole to 75 bush. It was pointed out in connection with this account that pole beans commonly differ from bush beans in at least three respects. They are generally taller, tho some very small pole beans, it was noted, are not much taller than some of the larger bush beans. As a rule, pole beans twine readily about supports, while bush beans do not, but it was noted that bush beans show the same tendency when growing with unusual vigor. The one characteristic difference was said to be that pole beans continue growth some - what indefinitely, while bush beans are virtually determinate in growth. MATERIALS AND METHODS. The studies reported in this paper have been limited to races of the common bean, Phaseolus vulgaris. A few crosses have been made between dwarf races of the common bean and tall races of P. multiflorus, but, both because the climate of Nebraska is unsuited to the growth of the latter species and because crosses between the two species are more or less sterile, it has been impossible to grow more than the F! generation of such crosses. Several years ago a large number of races of beans were ob - tained from reliable seedsmen. Some of the early crosses were made with plants grown from this commercial seed, but practically all of the later work, including most of that reported here, has been done with plants that have been grown in pedigree cultures and guarded against cross-pollination by insects for from one to four generations previous to the time the crosses were made. In all cases, whether the plants used in crossing were grown directly from commercial seed or from seed of pedigreed cultures, selfed seed from the parent individuals has been planted along </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. with the crossed seed, so that, if the parents happened not to be homozygous in their more prominent characters, that fact could be determined from their progenies. All plants, seeds of which have been planted, have been grown in an enclosure covered with fine meshed wire netting or under individual covers of very thin bunting, mosquito bar, or wire netting ( Figs. 1-3), except plants grown in the greenhouse in midwinter when no bees are present. Individual plant covers are not satisfactory where height of plant is to be studied, since they can scarcely be made large enough not to interfere with *' Fig. 1. Enclosure of fine meshed wire nett normal growth. Moreover, individual wire covers are difficult to manage, mosquito bar is too easily torn, and cloth of even the very lightest grades increases the temperature under it to an injurious degree in this climate. The large wire-netting enclosure is therefore now used exclusively. While many insects, including species of very small bees, gain entrance to the en - closure readily, they apparently do not effect cross-pollination. Even when grown in the open garden, beans are not cross-pollin - ated so largely as might be expected from the number of large bees found visiting the flowers. There is, however, sufficient crossing to make results unreliable when the plants from which seed is saved for planting are grown in the open. I have observed </seg>
            <seg id="p013">4. Gene th Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 13 from 0-10 per cent of undoubted crosses in the progenies or pure races grown in the garden. Crosses have invariably been made in the greenhouse during winter. The rather hot, dry weather of Nebraska makes it almost impossible to cross bean plants in the garden. The stamens are removed shortly before the flower bud is ready to open and pollen from another plant is applied at once. Occasionally an anther may be crushed in the process of emasculation and a grain of pollen thus comes into contact with the stigma of the same flower. Altho the stigma is always examined with the aid ant-covers of cheesecloth used to guard bush beans against insect pollination. of a lens after the removal of the anthers, partial self-fertilization occasionally results. It almost never happens that the parent races are so nearly alike that such accidental fertilizations cannot be detected when the F, plants are grown. Among Fi progenies, several plants apparently exactly like the maternal parent race have been tested thru two or three generations and in all cases have proved to be pure races. The records of all such plants occurring accidentally in F, progenies have been discarded in preparing the data for this paper. When planted, the seed of a single individual plant or of the cross of two individuals is given a family number, which is entered on the record card and used on the stake label to mark </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 the family in the garden. The several plants of a family are also given individual numbers based upon their position in the row and when necessary are marked by means of individual stakes. The record card of a family bears, in addition to the family number, the family and individual numbers of the selfed parent plant or of the two parent plants crossed. Seeds of each indi - vidual plant are kept in a separate receptacle bearing the family and individual numbers. Records are entered on the family cards under individual numbers only. All planting and harvesting Fig. 3.— Individual plant-covers of mosquito bar and cheesecloth used to protect pole beans from insect pollination. of seeds concerned in this study have been done by the writer or by assistants under his supervision. The records of habit of growth reported here have all been made by the writer, who has also made all counts of numbers of internodes and all measurements of internode lengths and plant heights. The internode counts and measurements were recorded in considerable part by Mr. E. R. Ewing, computer in genetic investigations. The writer is also indebted to Mr. Ewing for the calculation of most of the statistical constants used in this paper. Further assistance in checking these calculations has </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. been rendered by Mr. E. W. Lindstrom, graduate assistant in genetics at Cornell University. GROWTH HABIT IN BEANS. As was pointed out in an earlier paper (Emerson 1904), common beans are of two distinct types with respect to habit of growth. They are either determinate or indeterminate. The former are commonly called bush beans from the fact that they a rule comparatively short, erect, and much branched, are at Fig. 4. — Upper part of an old bean plant of indeterminate growth, showing flower buds at the upper nodes and mature pods at lower nodes. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui 16 while the latter are termed pole beans from the supports com - monly provided for them. In pole beans, the first flower clusters appear in the axils of the leaves at some of the lower nodes, usually the fourth to the seventh. As the plants increase in height and new nodes are added, flowers continue to appear in regular order from the lower to the higher nodes. (See Fig. 5.) It is not uncommon to find fully ripe pods at the lower nodes and newly opened flowers or or flower buds at the upper nodes of the same plant. (See Fig. 4. 5. — A young bean plant of indeterminate growth pole bean —with newly formed pods at node 5, flowers at nodes 6 and 7, and flower buds at nodes 8-12. Fig </seg>
            <seg id="p017">4 Genet Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 17 a Under ordinary conditions in the garden, it is true, pole beans do not continue to grow indefinitely, but termination of growth is apparently always due to unfavorable conditions of soil or weather such as low temperature, extreme dryness, etc., or to the exhaustion of the plants by heavy seed production. That this is true is shown by the fact that a race of small pole beans, which commonly ceases growth in the garden at a height of 1.0-1.5 meters with 15-20 nodes and perhaps dies long before the approach of cold weather, has been made to reach a height of 4 meters with 30 nodes when grown under the more favorable conditions of the greenhouse and when allowed to develop few K young bean plant of determinate growth — bush bean — with flower cluster terminating the axis at the sixth node. Fig. 6 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7. 18 pods. (See growth curves, Fig. 12.) Apparently growth would have continued longer in the greenhouse had not the experiment been discontinued. Under very favorable conditions, then, pole beans not only produce longer internodes but also more of them than under unfavorable conditions. The same indeterminate habit of growth is exhibited by all the branches of pole beans. In bush beans, on the contrary, usually only from 4 to 8 nodes develop in the main axis. Rich, moist soil and favorable weather increase the internode length just as in pole beans but apparently have little influence on the number of nodes. The main axis always terminates in an inflorescence. The flowers of this terminal inflorescence open first and the flowers at lower nodes only slightly later. (See Fig. 6.) Most of the pods mature at about the same time under ordinary conditions. If there has been a heavy setting of pods, and if conditions are unfavorable, the plants usually die when the pods mature. If the flowers are removed as soon as they form and if the soil and weather conditions are favorable, the plants remain alive for a considerable time, but the main axis cannot be forced to elongate further. The new growth resulting from this treatment always consists of secondary branches, usually from the lower nodes, and these branches, like the primary axis, terminate in flower clusters and cannot then be forced into further growth. Tertiary branches have the same fate. The terminal inflorescence of a bush bean is indeterminate in the sense that the lower flowers of the inflorescence open first and the upper ones last, but not in the sense that the inflorescence continues to elongate indefinitely. (See Fig. 7B. | The axis of the terminal inflorescence of bush beans develops apparently as a con - tinuation of the main axis of the plant. In Figure 7 A there are shown parts of the upper leaf and petiole of a bush bean together with the terminal inflorescence. In the axil of this leaf theredevelop - ed a cluster of flowers, similar to the flower clusters that develop in the leaf axils of pole beans, as seen in Figure 7C. A little higher on the axis of this terminal inflorescence (Fig. 7A), is a second flower cluster, but here a small bract takes the place of a leaf. The same is true of the third flower cluster. The fourth cluster terminates the axis of the inflorescence abruptly. The inflores - cence seen in Figure 7B developed a fifth flower cluster by which the axis was terminated. (The first flower cluster of this in - florescence, in the axil of the upper leaf, is not shown in the figure.) In certain races of bush beans, the terminal inflorescence consists of only two or three flower clusters, rarely of a single cluster in the axil of the upper leaf. The bush form of Lima bean (Phaseolus lunatus) is known to </seg>
            <seg id="p019">A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 19 have arisen as a mutation from pole Limas (Bailey 1895) and, since bush Limas bear the same relation to pole Limas as bush forms of the common bean do to the common pole beans, it seems probable that the common bush bean is a mutation from the pole bean. If this is true, the terminal inflorescence of bush beans may be regarded as a direct modification of the main axis of pole beans in which the leaves are reduced to mere bracts and in which the axis does not elongate indefinitely. The order of development of the flowers in the terminal inflorescence of bush beans remains exactly like the order of development of the flower clusters along the main axis of pole beans. In this connection, attention should be called to the fact that, while the axillary flower clusters of some pole beans usually consist of but two or three flowers, like the individual flower clusters of the terminal inflorescence of bush beans, many var - ieties of pole beans have an axillary inflorescence identical with the terminal inflorescence of bush beans rather than with the individual flower clusters of that inflorescence. Such a condition is shown in Figure 7D, where a small part of the main axis of the plant is seen at the right and parts of a leaf and petiole at the left. It is conceivable that bush beans arose from pole beans thru the failure of the main axis to develop beyond a certain node. In this case an axillary inflorescence of the pole bean would become the terminal inflorescence of the bush bean. On this supposition, however, one could hardly explain the presence of the flower cluster almost, if not quite, universally seen in the axil of the upper leaf of bush beans, as illustrated in Figure 7A. Usually the uppermost leaf of bush beans, which is here regarded as marking the end of the plant axis proper and the beginning of the terminal inflorescence, is at least as large as any of the other leaves of the same plants. The plant axis maintains its thickness to the upper leaf and there changes abruptly to the more slender axis of the terminal inflorescence. Sometimes, however, tho this is a rare occurrence, the upper leaf is very small and may even consist of only a single leaflet. The internode just below such an ill-formed upper leaf is snorter and more slender than in ordinary plants, so that the transition from plant axis to terminal inflorescence is somewhat gradual. Very rarely the axis of a distinctly pole-bean plant terminates abruptly in an inflorescence like that of a bush bean. The first plant of this sort to attract my attention was one of the small pole-bean race known as Snowflake. The plant was grown in a small pot of rather poor soil. When two months old, it had reached a height of 53 centimeters, formed 17 internodes, pro - duced a fair crop of pods, and practically ceased growing. It was </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 21 a typical pole bean both in manner of growth and as regards the order of development of its pods. It was then transplanted to a large pot of rich soil and all its pods were removed. The plant responded promptly to this treatment by beginning growth anew. Both the main axis and the single side branch began again to elongate with gradually increasing rapidity. The side branch continued to prow for some time and to form pods after the manner of a true pole bean. The growth of the main axis, on the contrary, after only four new internodes had appeared, was abruptly termi - nated by an inflorescence exactly like the terminal inflorescence of bush beans. Several other instances of this sort have since been observed. These plants, however, have all been grown under normal con - ditions, but have all occurred in the second generation of crosses of several bush-bean races with a single pole-bean race. These bush races have not given this result when crossed with other pole races and the pole race, in crosses of which these anomalous plants have occurred, has not itself been observed to show this peculiarity. Such behavior is not now understood but is being further investigated. On the whole, it seems reasonable to suppose that the terminal inflorescence of bush beans is formed as a continuation of the plant axis and that it has developed thru a modification of the indeterminate axis of pole beans. This interpretation is supported both by the occasional appearance of ill-formed leaves as a tran - sition from the plant axis proper to the axis of the terminal in - florescence of bush beans ard by the rare occurrence of plants that are typical pole beans thruout the greater part of their length, but whose axis terminates in a bush-beanlike inflorescence. The individual flower clusters of the bush-bean inflorescence are, then, to be regarded as the homologues of the axillary flower clusters or inflorescences of pole beans. In place of the leaves of the pole-bean axis, there occur in the terminal inflorescence of bush beans only small bracts suggestive of adnate stipules. In addition to determinate and indeterminate habits of growth, bush and pole beans differ in their ability to twine about supports. Circumnutation is strongly developed in all pole beans, but is not prominently exhibited ordinarily until after four or five internodes have developed, or until even later if the plants are growing slowly. Under ordinary conditions, bush beans rarely show prominent circumnutation, but, if forced into very vigorous growth, the long upper internodes develop pronounced circum - nutation. (See Fig. 8.) Twining habit is, therefore, not a dis - tinguishing characteristic of pole beans. Its absence from bush beans is incidental to the fact that their main axis is equivalent </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 Nebraska Agricultural Ezp. Station, Research^Bul. ? Fig s ■A bush bean with the twining habit exY upper fifth ternc to the first four to eight internodes of pole beans, in which twining is little developed, particularly if growth is slow. Bush beans usually have many branches and pole beans few branches, but this difference cannot be used to characterize definitely the two groups. When closely crowded together, bush beans often fail to develop branches. The shorter pole beans commonly have numerous branches and the taller kinds rarely fail to produce several branches. Degree of branching is in con - siderable part a varietal characteristic in both bush and pole beans. Finally the bush and pole classes of beans differ in height. This naturally follows from the determinate and indeterminate </seg>
            <seg id="p023">1 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 23 habits of growth of the two classes. Even the most vigorous bush bean cannot be expected ordinarily to reach a height, with its 4-8 internodes, that may ultimately be reached by even the smallest pole bean with its 15-20 internodes. If, however, length of particular internodes be taken as a measure of height, there is found in this respect no characteristic difference between the two classes of beans. Some races of bush beans have twice as long internodes as others and the same is true of distinct races of pole beans. Moreover, the internodes of some bush beans are * « Fig. 9. — (A) Very short bush bean. Triumph. (B) Very tall bush bean, Tall - bush, resulting from a cross between a tall pole bean and a short bush bean. (C) Short pole bean, Snowflake. (D) Tall pole bean, July. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 so long and those of some pole beans so short that there is com - paratively little difference in height between the two sorts. In fact, if the taller sorts of bush beans are forced by favorable soil, moisture, etc., and the shorter kinds of pole beans are retarded by unfavorable conditions, the bush beans will ordinarily exceed the pole beans in height. (Compare the plants shown in Fig. 9. i Internode lengths will be considered in detail in a later section of this paper. GROWTH CURVES. In all races of Phaseolus vulgar is, so far as I have observed, growth is fairly rapid at the start but soon slackens materially as the food tored in the cotyledons becomes exhausted and then becomes increasingly more rapid as the young plant becomes well established. In general, therefore, the hypocotyl is longer than the epicotyl, which, in turn, is longer than the second 1 inter- Internode numbers. Fig 10. — Growth curves of the main axis of (A) a medium tall bush bean, Red Marrow, 3,330 (■), and (B; a medium short pole bean, Snow - flake, 3,425 (t). The dots, connected by lines to form these and all later growth curves, indicate the heights of mature plants at the upper end of the designated internoie3. 1 Since the hypocotyl of a growing or mature plant cannot readily be measured, the epicotyl has been measured as the first internode. Thruout this paper, the first internode is regarded as beginning at the point of attach - ment of the cotyledons, the second at that of the primary leaves, the third at that of thejfirst trifoliate leaf, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p025">1 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 25 node. Usually, tho not universally, the third internode is longer than the second and occasionally, tho rarely, exceeds the first internode in length. In normal plants growing under fairly uniform conditions, internode length becomes increasingly greater from the third internode on until the maximum is reached. In plants of determinate growth habit (bush beans), maximum internode length for the main axis sometimes occurs at the fourth and sometimes not until the seventh or eighth internode, but, whatever the number, it is almost universally the terminal internode that is longest (Fig. 10). This statement could not Fig. 11. — Growth curves of the main axis— solid lines — and of the branches — broken lines -of (A) a very tall bush bean, Tallbush, 3,420 (,), (B) a medium tall bush bean. Red Marrow, 3,459 d), (C) a part of very tall pole bean, Fillbasket, 311 («&gt;, (D) a very short pole bean, Snowflake, 231 («). </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 hold if the internodes of the terminal inflorescence were included as a part of the plant axis, for they are shorter than the internodes immediately below them. The axis of the inflorescence is, however, so definitely differentiated from the plant axis proper that it is not included here in measurements of the latter. In plants of indeterminate growth habit the internodes are of comparatively uniform length for some distance on both sides of the longest internode, but sooner or later they become shorter. This shortening of the internodes is slight at first and increasingly more marked as growth proceeds. The growth curve for this period of retardation is therefore practically the reverse of that for the period of acceleration (Fig. 10). The iarger branches of bean plants manifest in general peculiar - ities of growth very similar to those of the main axis. Such curves are shown in Figure 11. Branches are as a rule more vigorous than the plant axis. This is particularly true of bush beans where, as is shown in Figure 11A and 11B, even the first internode of the branches is commonly considerably longer than the corresponding internode of the plant axis. It is not un - common for some of the branches of bush beans to reach twice the height of the plant axis. In Figure 11B is shown a bush bean of which the axis was 233 mm. high and a branch from the third node of the axis 535 mm. high. In pole beans, tho the branches are often somewhat more vigorous in growth than the plant axis, they are by no means universally so and very frequently grow less rapidly at the start than the corresponding part of the plant axis, as shown at C and D, Figure 11. It seems possible that the relative rapidity of growth of axis and branches may depend in part upon whether the branches start during the period of general growth acceleration or retardation and it certain - ly depends in part upon the weather. A cceleration of growth in the young plant is probably due to the fact that the plant is then constantly becoming better estab - lished. Its roots are gradually becoming better able to obtain water from the soil and its rapidly enlarging leaf area is contin - ually becoming better able to supply food materials for growth. But why should not this acceleration in rate of growth continue indefinitely in plants of indeterminate habit? Above all why should retardation in growth rate occur? It is unlikely that senility is to be considered in this connection. The heavy drain put upon the plant's resources by the development of a crop of pods and seeds doubtless has much to do with retardation of growth rate. This is particularly true of the smaller pole beans, which early set a heavy crop of pods. With the larger and later pole beans, the less favorable weather late in the season doubtless has a pronounced influence in retarding growth. </seg>
            <seg id="p027">4. Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris 27 Internode numbers. Growth curves of the small pole bean Snowflake. (A) Plant 2,424 Fig. 12 IB) grown in a large pot of rich, moist soil in the greenhouse and only a few pods permitted to develop. (B) Plant 2,424 (F) grown in a small pot of poor soil in the greenhouse and allowed to mature its full crop of seeds. (C) Plant 3,425 in grown in the garden during a rather hot, dry summer and allowed to mature a heavy crop of seeds. H </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. When heavy seed production is prevented and when tempera - ture, moisture, etc., are kept fairly uniform, retardation of growth can be avoided for a long time, if not indefinitely. In Figure 12 are shown growth curves of three plants of the same inbred strain of a race of very small pole beans, Snowflake I Xavy or Pea bean | . A and B were from seeds of the same selfed plant and C was directly related to them. Under the somewhat unfavorable conditions in the garden during a hot and rather dry summer (Fig. 12C), growth was at no time very rapid. The heavy setting of pods and increasingly unfavorable weather caused a marked retardation of growth at about the twentieth node and at the height of about 1 meter. With the more favorable temperature and humidity and somewhat deficient light of the greenhouse (Fig. 12B), growth was rapid at first but the development of a a considerable crop of pods and the deficiencies of the soil about 1.5 liters of a poor sandy loam brought about an early retard - ation of growth at about the fifteenth node and at a height of 1.5 meter. Under the same favorable atmospheric conditions, with w the advantage of abundant soil fertility about 10 liters of ri&lt; loam — and without the drain of heavy pod production, a sist t- plant (Fig. 12A) kept up a remarkably uniform grov ear the thirtieth node and to a height of four meters w periment was discontinued. 02460246024 InternoJe numbers. 1 Fig. 13 13 - — Growth curves of (A) and (B) medium tall bush beans, Red Marrow, 2,423 (B) and 2,423 (Fi, and of id and &lt;Di short bush beans. Triumph, 2,422 (A) and 2,422 if). Plants (A) and (Ci were grown in large pots of rich soil and plants (B) and (D) in small pots of poor soil. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">\ Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 29 Bush beans are, of course, influenced by unfavorable weather and soil conditions as well as pole beans but no retardation in rate of growth of the upper internodes comparable to that in pole beans is to be seen. The acceleration in rate of growth is lessened but the termination of growth is no more abrupt under unfavorable than under favorable conditions. Figure 13 shows characteristic growth curves of bush beans when grown in rich and in poor soil under favorable atmospheric conditions. These plants (Fig. 13 A, B, C, D) were grown at the same time and under the same conditions as two of the plants just discussed Fig. 14 14. Growth curves of pole beans. (.A) Snowflake 2,424 (F) grown under fairly favorable and comparatively uniform conditions in the greenhouse, i B i Snowflake 3,427 if I grown in the garden in a dry summer and irrigated twice. (C) July 3,956 fr) grown in the greenhouse under alternately favorable and unfavorable conditions. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 (Fig. 12A, B), A and C in large pots of rich soil and B and D in pots of poor soil. Plants A and B belong to a race of rather tall bush beans, Red Marrow, and plants C and D to a race of very short bush beans, Triumph. Plants A and B were from seed of the same self-pollinated plant of a previously inbred strain as were also plants C and D. That retardation in rate of growth in pole beans is often due to unfavorable, and acceleration to favorable, weather or soil conditions is seen in the behavior of plants grown in the garden during the dry summer of 1912 and irrigated twice. Figure 14B contrasts the irregularity in growth of such a plant with the regularity in growth of a plant (Fig. 14A) kept under the com - paratively uniform conditions of the greenhouse. Both plants belonged to the same inbred strain of the rather short pole bean, Snowflake. The extreme irregularity of growth of the plant shown in Figure 14C was induced by alternately favorable and unfavorable conditions. This plant was one of a rather tall race of pole beans, July, and was grown in the greenhouse. It was started in a rather small pot of rich soil and its growth forced by favorable tempera - ture and abundant water. Water was then withheld until it wilted badly, and for some time it was given only sufficient water to keep it alive. When its growth had almost ceased, it was transferred to a large pot of rich soil and again kept well watered. Under these conditions its main axis elongated rapidly until checked by a second period of artificial drouth. INHERITANCE OF DETERMINATE AND INDETERMINATE HABITS OF GROWTH The results of Mendel ( 1865), von Tschermak 1 1904 and 1912), and of the writer (1904) were reviewed earlier in this paper. Mendel described his results in terms of height, but from my own work I am convinced that the character pair with which he dealt was really determinate and indeterminate habits of growth. Von Tschermak also designated his plants merely as tall and short. While it is possible that the very irregular results secured by him are due to the fact that he dealt with a cross of very distinct species, Phaseolus rulgaris and P. multiflorus, it seems quite as probable that they are due to failure to disti guish sharply between habit of growth and other factors of height. The classification used in my earlier paper (1904) was based distinctly upon habit of growth, tho the classes were not there listed as determinate and indeterminate. The data then presented indicated clearly the perfect dominance of the indeterminate </seg>
            <seg id="p031">.4 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 31 growth habit, the definite segregation in F 2 into indeterminate and determinate habit with a ratio approaching 3:1, and the typical Mendelian behavior in F 3 and later generations of both the dominant and recessive characters. Since the publication of that paper, a large number of crosses between pole and bush beans have been grown, but, since these crosses were made pri - marily for the study of other characters, definite records of habit of growth for F. have been made in only a comparatively few cases. Including the records reported in my former paper, I have g own in all 948 Fi plants of crosses between pole and bush beans. Without exception these have been all indeterminate in habit of growth. 1 As parents of these crosses there have been employed 101 distinct races or strains, 58 of which were bush beans and 43 pole beans. Of the rather large number of F, plants, progenies of which have been grown, positive records are available of the offspring of only 32 plants of 16 distinct crosses. From these there were produced in F» 1,104 plants, of which 832 were indeter - minate and 272 determinate in growth, a ratio of 3.01:0.99, a variation from expectation well within the probable error for the numbers observed. Of the many F 2 bush plants tested in F 3 , accurate records of only 23 are available. All of these were found to be constant for determinate growth habit, having pro - duced 588 bush and no pole beans in F 3 . Likewise 24 F 2 pole beans are known to have bred true, having produced 686 pole and no bush beans in F :i . Again 40 F 2 pole beans segregated into pole and bush beans in F. t . The F ; , progenies of these heterozyg - ous F&gt; pole beans totaled 1,259 plants. In most of these cases, however, my notes indicate merely the fact of segregation without exact records of the number of plants of the two classes. It can be said then, by way of conclusion, that in Phaseolus vul - garis indeterminate and determinate habits of growth constitute a simple Mendelian character pair with indeterminate habit completely dominant. INHERITANCE OF NUMBER OF INTERNODES. While it is obviously true that habit of growth is an important factor in determining ultimate height in bean plants, it is one of the few size factors that can be definitely recognized and that can, therefore, be given separate treatment. In many crosses the parents of which differ greatly in height, growth habit can ' Since these records are merely confirmatory of the results previously reported in detail i Emerson 1904), it is thought sufficient to give only the summaries here. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui.'? be disregarded since the same habit is common to both parents. It has, therefore, seemed wise to consider growth habit as some - thing entirely apart from the other factors for height. This procedure greatly simplifies our problem — a fact that does not seem to have been recognized by some investigators. Up to this point we have been concerned largely with habit of growth. We come now to a consideration of other factors affecting height. Number of internodes plays perhaps an equal part with inter - node length in determining height of plants. It is a character that is obviously very closely related to habit of growth. Plants of determinate growth habit have a rather definite number of internodes, while those of indeterminate growth habit may have from comparatively few to very many internodes. It is true that certain races of bush beans show rather constant differences in number of internodes, but the fluctuation within a particular race — 2-4 internodes is greater than the average difference between the most diverse strains that have come under my observation. Some races of pole beans also commonly have more internodes than others, but number of internodes is here so greatly influenced by the weather and other external conditions that its investigation is beset with many difficulties. Under the comparatively uniform conditions that can be maintained in a greenhouse the difficulties are lessened, but it has been im - possible for me to make use of sufficient greenhouse room for studies of this sort. Not the least difficulty met, in carrying out an investigation of this kind in the garden, has been the breaking of the main axis of tall plants by winds. The taller pole beans, moreover, become so badly tangled that it is extremely difficult to make accurate counts. Some observations of number of nodes have been made, however, and they are presented here with a full realization of their unsatisfactory nature. The races used in these crosses were: Red Marrow, a tall bush bean; Triumph, a short bush bean; July, a tall pole bean; and Snowflake, a short pole bean. The two races of bush beans were chosen for crossing on account of the great difference in their height. This difference, it is true, is largely one of internode length, but the number of internodes of these races is of interest for comparison with the bush beans occurring in F. of bush-pole crosses. In Table 1 are shown the variations in number of nodes of the two bush races, of the F, and F-. generations of crosses between them, and of the bush plants that occurred in F» of crosses be - tween these bush races and the pole races July and Snowflake. All these plants were grown in the garden in 1912. The plants representing the parent races were directly descended from the </seg>
            <seg id="p033">A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 33 individual plants used in making the crosses. Owing to the small number of plants in any one progeny, progenies of like breeding were lumped together in making up the arrays. In mean number of internodes Red Marrow and Triumph differed by only 0.20 ±0.06 of an internode, or about three times the probable error of the difference. The means for the Fi and F 2 generations were almost exactly half way between the means of the parents. It is possible that the two parent races are not inherently different but that the slight difference observed in mean number of internodes was a mere matter of chance. The same would then apply to the intermediate number of internodes of F, and F... The number of Fi individuals was so small that the determination of the mean for plants of that generation has little value. It should also be noted that the difference between the mean number of internodes for F-&gt; and that for either parent lot was less than twice the probable errors of these differences. The variation in internode number as measured by the coeffi - cient of variation was somewhat greater in F_. than in either parent. The differences, however, are only from two to three times their probable errors. The most that can be said, therefore, is that, if this difference between the parents and the F, generation has any significance, it is that there is a slight inherent difference between the parents and that the somewhat increased variability in Fj indicates segregation of the factors that differentiate the parents. T he bush bean segregates in F 2 of the crosses between Triumph and July and between Triumph and Snowflake exhibited about the same intensity of variation as the F.» plants of the cross be - tween Triumph and Red Marrow. The variation was somewhat greater in case of the F 2 bush segregates of the cross between Red Marrow and July, the coefficient of variation being 13.98 ± 1.69 per cent. While this is greater than that of Red Marrow, which was 10.76 ±0.57 per cent, it is less than that of July (see Table 2), which was 15.61 ±1.42 per cent. Considered in con - nection with their probable errors, the differences — 3.22 ±1.78 and 1.63 ±2.21 respectively cannot be considered significant. It cannot therefore be told, without further breeding tests, whether the variation exhibited by these F 2 bush plants was due to segregation of factors influencing internode number. It seems possible, however, that a race of indeterminate growth 1 Here and consistently elsewhere in this paper the facts are interpreted in terms of the multiple-factor hypothesis solely because that hypothesis seems to the writer to afford the simplest adequate interpretation. He desires, however, to disavow any dogmatic notions as to the truth of this or any other hypothesis. A discussion of the matter appears later in this paper. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 34 habit, like July, would be subject to greater variation than plants of determinate growth. If this is true, the variation shown by the F 2 bush plants of the cross between Red Marrow and July should be compared with that of the bush-bean parent, Red Marrow, rather than with the pole-bean parent, July. Such a comparison suggests the probability that the parents of this cross may have differed by one or more factors for number of internodes and that these factors segregated in F... Whether or not the variation noted in the F» bush plants of the crosses discussed above indicates segregation of factors for number of internodes, there is less doubt in case of the cross between Red Marrow and Snowflake. The coefficient of variation of the F-&gt; bush beans of this cross was 19.65 ±2.18 per cent as against only 10.76 ±0.57 for Red Marrow, a difference of 8.89 ± 2.25. The genetic factors for number of internodes, in regard to which the parents of this cross presumably differed, must be distinct from the factor or factors concerned with habit of growth, for all these Fj bush plants must have lacked the factor for in - determinate growth and all must have had the factor for deter - minate growth. If this is true, the F 1 pole-bean segregates of this same cross should also have shown greater variation than the parents. By reference to Table 2, it will be seen that this was actually the case. In Table 2 are given the frequency distributions for number of internodes of the pole-bean parents of some of the crosses dis - cussed above, of the F, generation of these crosses, and of the F. segregates of indeterminate growth habit. The plants from which these records were made were all grown side by side in the garden in 1912. Owing to the small numbers of plants in individual families, the several families of each race and of one generation of each cross are thrown together, just as was done in Table 1. While it is recognized that this procedure is somewhat question - able, it is believed that the results are not vitiated materially thereby. The rather short pole bean, Snowflake, owes its low stature in part to a comparatively small number of internodes. The mean number of internodes was a little over 20. The much taller race, July, averaged somewhat over seven internodes more. The greater vigor of the F] generation of the cross of these races resulted in an average of a little over 30 internodes. The Fi progenies of the crosses between the tall bush bean, Red Marrow, and these pole beans had slightly fewer internodes than July but considerably more than Snowflake. The Fi plants of the cross between the very short bush bean, Triumph, and the com - paratively short pole bean, Snowflake, were among the most </seg>
            <seg id="p035">4 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 35 vigorous of all the plants grown in 1912. Tho both the parents are among the earliest races of beans, the Fi plants of the cross were later in flowering and in ripening seeds than any of the other crosses considered here. The same peculiarity was observed in F, plants of this cross as grown near Boston, Massachusetts, in 1911. The large mean number of internodes, over 31, shown by the F, plants of this cross is probably due directly to the vigor of growth and lateness induced by heterozygosis. This is indi - cated by the fact that in F. very few plants had as many inter - nodes as the mean of F,. The F.. plants of the cross between Snowflake and Red Marrow had practically the same mean number of internodes as did the F, plants. Unfortunately no records are available of the number of internodes in F : of the cross between the two pole beans, Snow - flake and July, or of the crosses between July and the bush races Triumph and Red Marrow. The variation shown in Fi of the cross between Snowflake and July was slightly less than that exhibited by the parent races, but the differences are too small to be significant. In F, of the Snowflake-Triumph, Snowflake- Red Marrow, and July-Red Marrow crosses, the variation was less than in the pole-bean parents but somewhat greater than in the bush -bean parents (Table 1). The small number of plants grown in F, families may have been in part responsible for this comparatively small variation. In F 2 the variation in the crosses between Snowflake and these bush races, as measured by the coefficient of variation, was greater than in even the pole-bean parent and much greater than in the Fi plants. In F 2&gt; of the Snowflake-Red Marrow cross, the coefficient of variation was only 3.81 ±2.08 greater than that of Snowflake but 9.51 ±1.44 greater than that of Red Marrow. The coefficients of variation for Red Marrow, Snowflake, the F, generation of the cross be - tween them, and the F» pole- bean segregates of the cross were respectively 10.76 ±0.57, 16.46 ±1.61, 10.73 ±1.29, and 20.27 ± 1.32 per cent. It will be recalled that the F 2 bush segregates of this same cross also showed considerable variation in number of internodes i Table 1), the coefficient of variation being 19.65 ± 2.18 per cent. The standard deviations are widely different for these lots, but standard deviation is not a good measure of variation for comparisons between plants so unlike as pole and bush beans. The full significance of the greater variation in the F 2 genera - tion than in F, or in the parents, as presented in Tables 1 and 2, and discussed above, is appreciated only when it is realized that the coefficients were determined for the pole and bush segregates separately. If the whole F 2 generation of either cross between </seg>
            <seg id="p036">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 36 pole and bush beans be thrown into one array, the variation is markedly increased. The array for the Snowflake-Triumph cross arranged in three-internode classes extends from 5 to 32 internodes and the frequency distribution is: The statistical constants are: Mean— 17.66 ±0.96 internodes. Standard deviation- 9.07 ± 0.68 internodes. Coefficient of variation- 51.34 ±4.72 per cent Similarly the frequency distribution for the whole Fi of the Snowflake-Red Marrow cross, in three-internode classes from 5 to 44 internodes is: 16-4—0—0—3—6—12 19 9— 2~\— 2-O— 1 The statistical constants are: Mean 21.00 ±0.78 internodes Standard deviation 10.16 ±0.55 internodes Coefficient of variation 48.38 ±3.19 per cent. The very large coefficients of variation shown by these ¥ t families, about 50 per cent, as compared with the much smaller coefficients for the parents and F,, from about 10 to 17 per cent, are plainly an expression of the F\&gt; segregation in habit of growth. Indeter - minate habit necessarily carries with it the ability to produce many internodes, while determinate growth makes impossible the development of more than a few internodes. But it has been shown that distinct races of pole beans, both equally indetermin - ate in growth, differ noticeably in the number of internodes they ultimately produce. Is it not possible then that a tendency to produce a large number of internodes, say 30 to 40, might be inherited from a bush bean, which, owing to its determinate habit of growth, is itself unable to develop more than a few internodes? Likewise is it not possible that a tendency to pro - duce a few internodes may also be inherited independently of habit of growth? These questions, if I have correctly interpreted my data, are given an affirmative answer by the results of the cross between Snowflake and Red Marrow. Snowflake showed a range of 12 internodes (14-26) and a mean of 20.48 ±0.44. The F, plants had a range of 12 internodes (20-32) with a mean of 26.56 ±0.48. The mean for the F 2 pole-bean segregates was 26.31 ±0.47, very nearly the same as in F\, but the range was 27 internodes 1 17-44 ). Red Marrow had a range of 3 internodes (4-7) and a mean of 5.78 ±0.05. The F 2 bush segregates of the cross between it and Snowflake had a smaller mean, 5.45 ±0.16. The range of varia - tion was the same as for Red Marrow, but the distribution was not that of normal fluctuation. While no new values not seen in 1 1—2—0—0—3—8—8-^4—2- </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 37 1 Genet Red Marrow were found in the F 2 plants, the relatively large number of plants with the extreme numbers of internodes, 4 and 7, suggests that it would be possible to isolate distinct types of bush beans in F : , from this F» lot. Only by further breeding tests can it be told whether this suggestion is correct. The F 3 genera - tion of this cross has not been grown, but fortunately I have partial records of another cross which afford direct evidence of the production of diverse types of bush beans from a cross between bush and pole races. The cross is one between Longfellow and Fillbasket. Longfellow is a rather short bush bean and Fillbasket is a medium tall pole bean. Counts of 10 to 20 plants each when grown under similar conditions in the garden in 1909 (except F 2 , which was grown in the greenhouse) gave ranges of variation and means as follows: Internode numbers Mean Range 17.3 14-22= 8 .21.4 18-24= 6 20.8 13-26 = 13 Fillbasket-Longfellow, F» pole Fillbasket-Longfellow, F? bush )\V From two Fj bush plants with 6 and 7 internodes respectively, two small F : , families were grown in 1910 each showing about the same range of variation as that of F* In 1911 near Boston, Massachusetts, were grown several F 4 families of this cross. One of these i Family 3,254) was from a bush plant with 6 internodes which was of the F t lot descended from the 6-internode F-. plant. The other lot 1 3,251) was from a bush plant with 7 internodes of the F., progeny of the 7-internode F, plant. In the same garden and very near these F 4 families, were grown several families of Longfellow. All of these were descended directly from the indi - vidual plant of Longfellow used in making the cross with Fill - basket now under discussion, but were four generations removed from that plant and therefore were its great-great-grandchildren. The several families of Longfellow showed only slight differences in height of plants. One of them (3,247) was examined for number of internodes. The results are given in Table 3. One of the F, families of the Longfellow-Fillbasket cross was very similar to the family of Longfellow of which internode counts were made, the means for number of internodes being 5.17 ± 0.06 and 4.94 ±0.08 respectively, a difference of only 0.23 ±0.10. The other F, family, however, had a mean number of inter - nodes of 6.44*0.08, which is 1.27 ±0.10 more than the first F 4 family had. The variation of the three lots, as indicated by the coefficient of variation, was so small and so nearly the same for Killbasket Fillbasket-Longfellow, F 6.2 4- 8= 4 5.3 4-6=2 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. all lots that it seems reasonable to conclude that the two F, families were breeding essentially true to distinct types with respect to number of internodes. It seems clearly evident from these results that a tendency to develop a comparatively large number of internodes, as bush beans go, was inherited in a bush - bean family from the pole-bean parent of a cross with a bush bean of comparatively few internodes. It may be concluded, then, in so far as any conclusion can be drawn from the somewhat unsatisfactory records here presented, that genetic factors concerned in the determination of number of internodes in bean plants are distinct from factors for habit of growth and are inherited independently of them, so that, with respect to number of internodes, it is possible, from a cross between a pure strain of bush beans and a pure strain of pole beans, to isolate types of both bush and pole beans with other internode numbers than those of the parent races. The bearing that this may have upon the possible modifications of genetic factors thru crossing will be discussed in a later section of this papt CALCULATION OF INTERNODE LENGTH Habit of growth -determinate or indetermina influence upon the average internode length of a plant as well as upon the number of internodes. It is obvious that a bush bean, in which growth of the main axis is terminated when the period of acceleration in rate of growth has barely begun, cannot have so great an average internode length as a pole bean, in which growth - rate acceleration has continued thru a long period. For instance. a race of the tallest bush beans that have ever come to my notice had a mean internode length for the first six internodes of the main axis of only about 37 mm. as grown in 1912. while the shortest pole bean with which I am acquainted, when grown under similar conditions, had a mean internode length of about 48 mm. for the first 15 internodes. The mean length of the first 6 internodes of these same pole-bean plants was, however, only about 33 mm. Obviously this large bush bean has an inherent tendency to produce longer inter - nodes than the small pole bean, but it cannot do so because its growth is terminated at an early stage of development. That such a tendency to produce long internodes is a characteristic of the tall bush bean is indicated by the F, progeny of a cross between it and the small pole bean. The mean internode length of the cross was about 34 mm. for the first 6 internodes and about 86 mm. for the first 15 internodes. The latter is 1.8 times the mean length of the first 15 internodes of the pole-bean parent. </seg>
            <seg id="p039">\ Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 39 Evidently the tall bush bean not only possessed potentially the character of long internodes but was able to impress that charac - ter upon its Fj progeny when crossed with a pole bean, whereby the partially inhibitory action of determinate growth was re - moved . It is plain from this that we cannot compare the average length of the few internodes of bush beans with that of the many internodes of pole beans. In order, therefore, that pole and bush beans may be directly compared, it is necessary to limit consideration to a definite number of internodes common to both types. All of the bush-bean races and crosses included in this study had a mean number of internodes between five and six. Since, if the comparison were between the first six internodes, a considerable number of bush plants would have to be discarded, only the first five internodes are here considered. For this com - parison all internodes above the fifth in both pole and bush plants have been disregarded and all bush plants with less than five internodes have been discarded. Even when consideration is limited thus to a definite small number of internodes, direct comparisons are not entirely trust - worthy. For instance, July is a pole bean of vigorous growth and therefore of relatively long internodes, while Snowflake is a slow growing pole bean and consequently has comparatively short internodes, but the mean length of the first three internodes Snowflake is greater than that of the corresponding internodes of July. Thus for 78 plants of Snowflake and 83 plants of July, jjrown side by side in the garden in 1912, the mean lengths in millimeters of the individual internodes from 1 to 15 inclusive were: Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 • 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 4 -2.\ 41 56 78 115 122 120 120 134 140 139 138 135 ) 24 25 28 38 45 53 62 73 82 84 77 63 The mean internode lengths in millimeters of these same plants is calculated at the end of any internode from 1 to 15 were, there - : ore, approximately: Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 1112 13 14 15 The difference between these two races in mean internode length is thus seen to change rapidly up to about the eighth internode and much less rapidly from there on. This is indicated even more clearly by means of the ratios of the internode lengths of the two races as calculated at the end of each internode from 1 to 15. July 19 17 19 24 31 39 49 58 65 71 77 82 86 90 93 Snowflake 26 22 21 22 22 23 25 28 31 34 37 41 44 47 48 Difference -7-5-2 2 9 16 24 30 34 37 40 41 42 43 45 </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. Such ratios, with the mean internode lengths of July taken as 100, are: Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 Ratio 100: 137 129 111 92 71 59 51 48 48 48 48 50 51 52 The mean internode length of Snowflake is, then, approximately 50 per cent of that of July, if internode length be determined at the end of any internode from the seventh to the fifteenth. Obviously a comparison between these races in respect to inter - node length is unreliable if internode length is determined at the end of any internode before the seventh. But, if either of them is to be compared at all with any bush bean, the comparison must relate to the first five or six internodes. The illustration used above is an extreme one. The difficulty in comparing pole and bush beans is not generally so great. Other examples will make this plain. It has been shown above that Snowflake is a small pole bean with a mean internode length about 50 per cent that of the tall pole bean, July. Triumph is a very short bush bean and Red Marrow a rather tall one. Let compare the mean internode lengths of 79 plants of Triumph and 73 plants of Red Marrow with those of Snowflake and July as given above. The comparisons to the end of the fifth internode are: Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 Snowflake 26 22 21 22 22 Triumph Ratio 100: 54 Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 Red Marrow 25 21 2U 22 24 Snowflake Ratio 100: 104 Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 July 19 17 19 24 31 Triumph 14 11 11 Ratio 100: 74 65 58 Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 July 19 17 19 24 Red Marrow 25 21 20 22 Ratio 100: 132 124 105 Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 Red Marrow 25 21 20 22 24 Triumph 14 11 11 12 14 Ratio 100: 56 52 55 55 58 From the comparison with Snowflake, it might at first seem that the internode length of Triumph is about one-half of that of Snowflake and the internode length of Red Marrow nearly equal </seg>
            <seg id="p041">4. Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 41 to that of Snowflake. The fact, however, that the mean-length ratio for Snowflake and Triumph is considerably greater for five intemodes than for four, suggests that ii might be still greater if it were possible to determine it for a greater number of inter - nodes. The only conclusion that can be drawn from the com - parison is the rather indefinite one that the potential internode length of Triumph is less than that of Snowflake, but probably not so much less as is indicated by the mean-length ratio for the first five intemodes, 100:64. By similar reasoning it is concluded that Red Marrow has a potential internode length greater than that of Snowflake, the difference probably being more than is indicated by the mean-length ratio for the first five intemodes, 100:92. Likewise, it may be said that the potential internode length of Triumph is considerably less and that of Red Marrow somewhat less than that of July. The direct comparison between Red Marrow and Triumph would appear reliable, for the reason that mean-length ratios are not far different when the comparison is made at the end of any internode from the first to the fifth. There is, however, a gradual increase in the ratio after the first internode. It would seem safe, therefore, to conclude that the potential internode length of Triumph is considerably less than that of Red Marrow but that the difference is probably not quite so great as is indicated by the mean-length ratio for the first five intemodes, 100:58. The only method available for accurately testing the potential internode length of bush beans is to cross them with pole beans and compare the internode length of the indeterminately growing plants thus produced with that of the pole-bean parent. For such a comparison the F 2 generation of the cross is to be preferred to the F, generation, because increased vigor due to heterozygosis is less in F : than in F,. There is an additional reason for this preference in case of beans. The difficulty in cross-pollinating bean flowers and the fact that only a few seeds are obtained from any one pollination, make it next to impossible to grow even moderately large numbers of Fi plants. Comparisons of the F 2 generation of Triumph-Snowflake (56 plants), Red Marrow- Snowflake (74 plants), and July-Snowflake (78 plants), with each other and with Snowflake, are given here: I nternode No Snowflake Triumph-Snowflake Ratio 100: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 1112 13 14 15 26 22 21 22 22 23 25 28 3134 37 4144 47 48 21 18 19 20 21 23 25 28 3133 35 37 38 39 39 81 82 90 91 95 100 100 100 100 97 95 90 86 83 81 I nternode No Red Marrow-Snowflake. Snowflake Ratio 100: : 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 1112 13 14 15 25 22 23 26 28 30 34 38 42 45 48 51 54 55 56 26 22 21 22 22 23 25 28 3134 37 4144 47 48 101 100 91 85 79 77 74 74 74 76 77 80 81 85 86 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. From these comparisons, it is seen that the differences in potential internode length between the bush beans, Triumph and Red Marrow, and the pole beans, July and Snowflake, as indicated by the previous comparisons of mean lengths of the first five internodes, are realized roughly in crosses between the bush and the pole beans. Thus the internode length of the Triumph- Snowflake cross is less than that of Snowflake, but the difference is not so great as that between Triumph and Snowflake. The mean-length ratio of Snowflake to Triumph, for the first five internodes, was 100:64 and that of Snowflake to the Triumph- Snowflake cross, for the first 15 internodes, was 100:81. The cross, therefore, occupied a position intermediate between its parents with respect to internode length, which was to have been expected. Again, the direct comparisons indicated that the internode length of Red Marrow was potentially greater than that of Snowflake but less than that of July. The Red Marrow-Snowflake cross showed that this was true. The mean-length ratio of the Red Marrow-Snowflake cross to Snowflake, at the end of the fifteenth internode, was 100:86, while that of the July-Snowflake cross to Snowflake was 100:71 and that of July to Snowflake was, as shown earlier, 100:52. That is, the Red Marrow-Snowflake cross had an internode length greater than that of Snowflake, but the difference between Snowflake and the Red Marrow- Snowflake cross was not so great as the difference between Snow - flake and the July-Snowflake cross, which in turn, of course, was not so great as the difference between July and Snowflake. That the potential internode length of Red Marrow is less than that of July is also shown by the comparison between the July- Snowflake and Red Marrow-Snowflake crosses, the length-ratio of which, for the first 15 internodes, was 100:82. Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 1112 13 14 15 July-Snowflake 24 20 21 24 26 30 35 41 46 5156 6165 66 68 Snowflake 26 22 21 22 22 23 25 28 3134 37 4144 47 48 Ratio 100: 103 110 100 92 85 77 71 68 67 67 66 67 68 71 71 Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 July-Snowflake 24 20 21 24 26 30 35 41 46 5156 6165 66 68 Red Marrow-Snowflake. 25 22 23 26 28 30 34 38 42 45 48 5154 55 56 Ratio 100: 104 110 110 108 108 100 97 93 91 88 86 84 83 83 82 Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 1112 13 14 15 July-Snowflake 24 20 21 24 26 M :S5 41 46 5156 6165 66 68 Triumph-Snowflake 21 18 19 20 21 23 25 28 3133.35 37 38 39 39 Ratio 100: 88 90 90 83 81 77 71 68 67 65 63 61 58 59 57 Internode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 1112 13 14 15 Red Marrow-Snowflake. 25 22 23 26 28 30 34 tt 42 45 48 51 54 55 56 Triumph-Snowflake 21 18 19 20 21 2.) 25 28 SI 33 36 37 38 39 39 Ratio 100: 84 82 83 77 75 77 74 74 74 73 7-i 7:! 70 71 70 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 43 That the potential internode length of Triumph is considerably less than that of Red Marrow, as was earlier indicated by direct comparison of the first five internodes of these bush races by which a mean-length ratio of 100:58 was indicated, is shown by a com - parison between the Red Marrow-Snowflake and Triumph- Snowflake crosses, between these crosses and Snowflake, and between them and the July-Snowflake cross. The internode length of the Triumph-Snowflake cross was 81 per cent of that of Snowflake which was only 86 per cent of that of the Red Marrow-Snowflake cross. Again the internode length of the Triumph-Snowflake cross was 57 per cent and that of the Red Marrow-Snowflake cross 82 per cent of the internode length of the July-Snowflake cross. From either of these comparisons, it follows that the internode length of the Triumph-Snowflake cross is 70 per cent of that of the Red Marrow-Snowflake cross, and this is also shown by the direct comparison of these crosses. That this difference between the Red Marrow-Snowflake and Triumph-Snowflake crosses, as determined from the first 15 internodes, is much less than the difference between Red Marrow and Triumph, as determined from the first five internodes, is not to be taken as an indication that differences in potential internode length of bush beans are not suggested even roughly by direct comparison. That the difference between the crosses was less than the difference between the races themselves was to have been expected, since Snowflake was intermediate between the bush races in internode length and should, therefore, produce crosses with these races having internodes shorter than those of Red Marrow and longer than those of Triumph. If the Red Marrow-Snowflake cross were exactly intermediate between Red Marrow and Snowflake and the Triumph-Snowflake cross exactly intermediate between Triumph and Snowflake, the difference between the two crosses should be one-half the difference between Red Marrow and Triumph. The difference between the crosses was 30 per cent of the larger cross (100-70) and the difference between the bush races was 42 per cent of the larger race (100 — 58). The difference between 30 per cent and 21 per cent (one - half of 42 per cent) seems a fair measure of the accuracy with which differences in potential internode length of bush beans can be judged from a comparison of the actual internode lengths of the bush beans themselves. The foregoing comparisons, as a whole, indicate that the po - tential internode lengths of bush beans can be determined roughly from measurements of the first five internodes. The length of the first 15 internodes is thought to give a fair approximation </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 Nebraska Agricultural Ezp. Station, Research Bid. to the mean internode length of pole beans. In general the period of growth-rate acceleration is finished by the time the fifteenth internode has developed. It is true that in some plants retardation in rate of growth begins somewhat earlier, but the retardation is so slow at first that the mean internode length is approximately the same whether it is calculated on the basis of 15 internodes or of a few more or a few less internodes. Since the growth-curve for the period of retardation in growth is roughly the reverse of the curve for the period of acceleration in growth, the mean length of the internodes developed during the acceleration period is not far from that of the entire plant. Thus the internode length of Snowflake, as grown in 1912, was 46 mm. for the first 15 internodes and 48 mm. for the entire length of the plants. Similarly the mean internode length of Fi of a cross of Snowflake with a very tall bush bean was 86 mm. for the first 15 internodes and 82 mm. for the entire length of the plants. It is believed that the plant's inherent growth tendencies are better shown during the period of growth acceleration than at any later period. The period is short and during it, therefore, the plants are not subjected to so wide a range of weather con- ditions as during their whole period of growth. Moreover, the practical difficulties to be overcome in measuring all the inter - nodes of pole beans are considerable. The upper part of such plants is usually badly tangled. The main axis is increasing more liable to injury from the wind in its higher internodes. Fro m all of these considerations it has been deemed best t the following presentation of results a consideration he first 15 internodes of pole beans and the first five inte bush beans. INHERITANCE OF INTERNODE LENGTH The races of beans employed in this study were, in the main, the same races — in fact the identical cultures employed in the study of the inheritance of number of internodes, namely, the pole beans July and Snowflake and the bush beans Red Marrow and Triumph. The peculiarities of growth of these races have been considered in some detail in the preceding discussion of methods of calculating internode length. A note regarding the previous breeding of the plants used in this study should be added. Except for a part of the plants of Red Marrow, the pedigree of all plants of any one race, the records of which are presented here, centers in a single self-pollinated plant three generations back, four plants in all, one for each race. All the crosses, likewise, trace back to the same four plants. These four plants were from </seg>
            <seg id="p045">Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 45 A Gem guarded pedigree cultures which had been under observation for *o generations, except the July plant, in which case the pedigree *an back only one generation. The records reported here were made in 1912 from plants grown in the garden. All the families containing pole beans were grown together in a small part of the garden. Owing to lack of room in this place, the bush-bean families were grown a few rods away on practically the same soil but where exposure to the wind was somewhat greater. Tho the differences were not great, the conditions as a whole were somewhat more favorable where the pole-bean families were grown. Even in this small part of the garden, the conditions with respect to soil moisture were not as uniform as desirable. Owing to the dry weather, all the plants were irrigated early in the season and again later. One end of the pole-bean garden was more difficult to irrigate thoroly than the rest and, in consequence, received somewhat less water. Fortunately the different races and crosses were arranged in planting so that all of them extended across both the drier and moister parts of the garden, except the F, families which, owing to the small number of plants, did not extend entirely across the garden. For this reason, as well as because of the small numbers grown, the records of F, plants are not entirely comparable with those of Fj and of the parent races. The plants of each parent race and of each F&gt; generation formed two rows across the garden. The records for these several lots are, therefore, it is believed, fairly comparable, tho the amount of variation within all the lots was increased to a certain extent by the somewhat unequal jnditions at the two ends of the garden. In Table 4, are presented the data obtained from the four races and their crosses with respect to mean lengths of the first ve internodes. As thus determined, the mean internode length of the bush-bean races was 24.41 * 0.31 mm. for Red Marrow and 14.28-0.24 mm. for Triumph. The F_. generation of the cross between these races had a mean internode length of 19.53*0.39 mm., almost exactly half way between the means of the parents. The range of variation in F_&gt; extended from the lower extreme of Triumph to the upper extreme of Red Marrow. The standard deviation and coefficient of variation of the F.. plants were some - what greater than those of either parent and considerably greater than the parents' average. Evidently internode length in bush beans is inherited in much the same way as internode length in maize and as many quantitative characters in various plants are known to be (Emerson and East 1913). The pole beans, July and Snowflake, and the cross between them present a different condition. True, the mean length of the </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. first five internodes of the F 2 plants, 26.36 ±0.54 mm., is very nearly exactly intermediate between the means of the parents, 30.09 ±0.77 and 22.65 ±0.32 for July and Snowflake, respectively. But both the standard deviation and coefficient of variation for F» are less than these constants for one of the parent races, July, tho they are considerably greater than those for the other parent race, Snowflake. Of itself, the fact that the coefficient of varia - tion for F 2 is slightly greater than the average of the coefficients for the parent races cannot be used to show a segregation in F.. of genetic factors for internode length, unless, by the same reason - ing, we are forced to admit also that there is segregation of an even greater number of genetic factors in case of the parent race July. While it is not unlikely that July is still heterozygous for factors concerned in internode length, it is highly improbable that it is heterozygous for more factors than F, plants of a cross between it and the very distinct race, Snowflake. If the high coefficient of variation for Fo, 25.61 =•= 1.55 per cent, is due to segregation of size factors as seems probable from other consider - ations, the still higher coefficient for July, 32.67 ±2.64 per cent. is yet to be explained. It seems likely that the great variation exhibited by July, with respect to mean length of the first five internodes, is a chance relation of its peculiarities of growth in the early stages of its development to the somewhat uneven soil moisture conditions of the different parts of the garden as noted above. From the data presented in the discussion of methods of determining inter - node length, it will be recalled that, tho July is extremely vigorous in growth after once growth is well started, its first two or three internodes are unusually short shorter even than those of the much less vigorously growing Snowflake. The mean lengths of each of the first seven internodes as determined from measure - ments of 83 plants of July and 78 plants of Snowflake are repeated here: Internode No 1 2 3 4 S 6 July 19 14 23 41 Snowflake 26 17 2M J4 Since the first internodes of July are so very short and some - what later ones so very long, the change in internode length is necessarily extremely rapid. If now this abrupt acceleration in growth-rate should begin in one plant with the fourth internode and in another with the sixth as might easily happen if, owing to a slight difference in soil moisture, the one plant germinated a little later than the other, so that the one had developed only three internodes while the other had developed five at the time of a heavy rainfall — the mean length of the first five internodes </seg>
            <seg id="p047">4. Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 47 would be strikingly different in the two plants. And, if a number of such cases occurred, the coefficient of variation in mean length of the first five internodes might be very high, even tho the ulti - mate heights of the several plants were almost the same and the mean length of the first 15 internodes showed little variation. That just such differences in the initiation of growth-rate acceler - ation did occur in the July bean is shown by the measurements of the first six internodes of two plants of the same family (3,434) that ultimately reached approximately the same heights. The individual internode lengths in millimeters were: lnternode No 1 2 3 4 5 6 First plant 22 16 38 96 126 220 Second plant 20 17 39 54 85 176 The total lengths of the first five internodes were 298 mm. and 215 mm. and the mean lengths, therefore, 59.6 mm. and 43.0 mm., respectively. The total lengths of the first 15 internodes of these same two plants were 1,579 mm. and 1,619 mm. and the corres - ponding mean internode lengths, therefore, 105 mm. and 108 mm., respectively. In short, July bean plants may exhibit great dif - ferences in mean length of the first five internodes and almost no difference in mean length of the first 15 internodes. In this connection the relative variation in length of particular internodes is worth noting. The coefficients of variation for each of the first five and for the tenth internodes of July (83 plants) and Snowflake (78 plants) are given below: July Snowflake Difference July shows considerably more variation than Snowflake in the third, fourth, and fifth internodes, somewhat less in the tenth internode, only slightly more in the second internode, and no appreciable difference in the first internode. While the coefficient of variation for mean length of the first five internodes of July was 32.67 ±2.64 per cent and that of Snowflake 15.81 ±1.01 per cent (Table 4), or a difference of 16.86 ±2.83, these constants for the first 15 internodes (Table 5) were for July 26.11 ±1.52 per cent and for Snowflake 27.68 ±1.86 per cent, an insignificant difference of 1.57 ±2.40. As will be shown later, when the first 15 internodes instead of only the first five are considered, segre - gation of internode length factors in F 2 is more plainly indicated. First internode Second internodt Third internode Fourth internode Fifth internode Tenth internode n 17.08±0.95 24.36*1.17 35.40*1.33 47.16*1.78 45.25*1.35 28.29*2.24 16.77*0.90 0.31*1.31 20.76*1.35 3.60*1.79 23.48*2.07 11.92*2.46 30.29*2.97 16.87*3.46 23.74*2.81 21.51*3.12 35.55*1.61 -7.26*2.76 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 Since the behavior of July with respect to mean lengths of the first five internodes has been shown to be so irregular, it could hardly be expected that the crosses between July and the bush beans, Triumph and Red Marrow, would give reliable evidence of segregation of internode length factors from measurements of the first five internodes. But there is no other comparison available for the F s bush segregates of these crosses. The coefficient of variation of the F» bush segregates of the July-Triumph cross ( Table 4 ) was less than that of July by 10.80 ± 3.74 and practically the same as that of Triumph, the difference being only 0.19 ± 2.93. The coefficient of variation of the F,. pole segregates of this cross was slightly greater than that of the bush segregates but not equal to that of July, the difference being 5.40 ±3.29 and 5.40 ±3.28, respectively. In F : of the July-Red Marrow cross, the coefficient of variation for mean length of the first five internodes was much greater than that of Red Marrow and somewhat greater even than that of July. In the statement below, the pole-bean segregates of F : of the July-Red Marrow cross are compared with July and the bush-bean segregates with Red Marrow. The calculations were made from measurements of 74 plants of July, 71 of Red Marrow, 57 of the F. pole-bean segregates, and only 12 of the F L &gt; bush-bean segregates. The coefficients of variation of these four lots of plants for each of the first five internodes are That such differences in the coefficients of variation between July and the F_. pole-bean segregates, as given above, are indications of segregation in F_&gt; of internode-lenjrth factors which differentiate the parent races seems unlikely. The Fj segregates of the July-Triumph cross showed consist - entjy smaller coefficients for the first five internodes considered individually than did July, notwithstanding the fact that July and Triumph differ more in mean internode length than July and Red Marrow and probably also, therefore, in more internode - length factors. The whole question with respect to these crosses can be decided only by further investigation if indeed any decision can be reached from measurements of only the first five internodes. It may be noted here, tho this will be presented in detail later, Internode No July-Red Marrow, ft pole July Difference 12 3 4! 19.65 27.52 48.62 66.06 49 17.08 24.:i6 36.40 47.16 45 2.57 :i.l6 18.22 18.90 3 Internode No July-Red Marrow, F 2 bush Red Marrow r\:a 12 3 4! 19.46 15.74 46.27 52.54 64 15.20 22.15 20.51 2:i.l8 28 4.26 6.41 25.76 29.36 35 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. A Genetk 49 that the F- pole-bean segregates of the July-Triumph cross, as well as of the July-Red Marrow cross, showed greater variation than did July with respect to mean lengths of the first 15 inter - nodes. From Table 4 it is seen that the variation in mean lengths of the first five internodes of the F-&gt; pole-bean segregates of the Snowflake-Triumph cross is less than that of either parent race. The F_. bush-bean segregates of this cross, on the other hand, had a greater variation than either parent race. When the individual internodes are considered separately, it is found that the standard deviations are, as a rule, greater for F« than for the parent races. The very small mean internode lengths of Triumph, however, make the coefficients of variation for that race larger in many cases than those for the F : plants. It is possible that the mean internode lengths of Triumph are relatively smaller than they should have been owing to the fact that the conditions under which the bush-bean families were grown were somewhat less favorable than those surrounding the pole-bean families. That this may be true is suggested by the fact that the mean internode length of the F, pole-bean segregates is considerably nearer that of Snowflake than that of Triumph — but this difference may in part be due to a somewhat increased vigor arising from partial heterozygosis in F* If normal internode lengths in Triumph and Snowflake are more nearly alike than indicated by the values found here from the first five internodes, less variation would be expected in F_. than if the difference between internode lengths of the parents were greater, but this variation should certainly not, even then, be less than that of the parents. From the data at hand, it cannot be said that any segregation occurs in factors for mean length of the first five internodes. The only cross between pole and bush beans yet to be con - sidered with respect to mean lengths of the first five internodes i Table 4 ) is that between Red Marrow and Snowflake. The mean lengthsof the first fiveinternodesare nearly thesame for both parent races, but the mean lengths for both generations of the crosses are greater than for either parent. This, like the results of the Triumph-Snowflake cross, may be due in part to the somewhat unfavorable conditions under which the bush-bean families were grown, whereby the internode length of Red Marrow was less than it would otherwise have been. If this is true, the same condition, which may have made the internode lengths of Snow - flake and Triumph differ more than they should, would tend to make the internode lengths of Snowflake and Red Marrow more nearly alike than they otherwise would have been. If, on further investigation, these conjectures are substantiated, that is, if </seg>
            <seg id="p050">50 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. Triumph and Snowflake are found to have nearly equal internode lengths while Red Marrow and Snowflake are found to have quite unlike internode lengths, the fact that the variation in F 2 of the Triumph-Snowflake cross was no greater than the variation in the parent races would be readily understood, as already pointed out, but greater variation would then be expected in F_&gt; of the Red Marrow-Snowflake cross than in the parent races. That this was just what occurred is seen from the data given in Table 4. For mean lengths of the first five internodes, the coeffi - cients of variation are for Snowflake 15.81 * 1.01 per cent, for Red Marrow 15.81 ±0.91 per cent, for the F 2 pole-bean segregates 33.33 ±2.16 per cent, and for the P, bush-bean segregates 22.86 ± 2.86 per cent. The range of variation in F 2 was 40 mm. for the pole-bean segregates and 25 mm. for the bush-bean segregates, as against 20 mm. for F,. 20 mm. for Snowflake, and 15 mm. for Red Marrow. Increased variation of F 2 over the parent races was also shown for each individual internode of the first five. By way of summary it can be said that there is distinct evidence of segregation in F_&gt; of factors for length of the first five internodes of two crosses between pole and bush beans. No evidence of such segregation has been found in case of two other such crosses. Where there is distinct segregation in Fj it should be possible to isolate types of both bush and pole beans of different internode lengths from a single cross of pole and bush races. No F 3 progenies of the crosses here under consideration have been grown, but very distinct types of bush beans with respect to internode length have been isolated from a cross of other varieties. The evidence of this will be given later. Table 5 exhibits the variations in length of the first 15 inter - nodes of some of the races and crosses discussed above. It is obvious that only plants of indeterminate growth habit can be included in the table. This eliminates from the comparison not only the bush races and crosses between bush races but also the F- bush segregates of pole-bush crosses. For the races and crosses that can be included here, the data are more reliable than those for the first five internodes. The reasons for this were discussed in the consideration of methods of calculating internode lengths. The mean length of 15 internodes is a better measure of internode length than the mean length of only five internodes. The mean length of the first 15 internodes in F- of the July- Snowfiake cross, 69.29 ±1.99, is almost exactly intermediate between the means of the parent races, 89.69 ±1.84 for July and 46.28 ±1.13 for Snowflake. In range of variation, the F, plants extend to the outer extremes of the two parents. The coefficients of variation are 27.68 ±1.86 for Snowflake, 26.11 ±1.52 for July, </seg>
            <seg id="p051">4 Genetic Study of Plant\Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 51 21.20 ± 1.90 for F, of the cross between them, and 36.90 =»= 2.37 for F-j of the same cross. The indication here of an F 2 segregation of internode-length factors in a cross between two pole beans of very unequal internode length is fairly definite. In every one of the four crosses between pole and bush beans, the Fj pole-bean segregates exhibit somewhat greater variation than the pole-bean parent, as measured by the coefficient of varia - tion, but not always as measured by the standard deviation. The coefficients of variation for July and Snowflake and for the ¥• families of their crosses with bush beans are While the indications are not so clear in some of these crosses as n others, the evidence as a whole favors the conclusion that there is segregation of internode-length factors in crosses between bush and pole beans, just as in crosses between two bush or two pole races that differ in internode length. Whether there has been segregation of genetic factors for internode length in F_. can be determined much more positively by the constant types that are isolated in F :i or later generations than by statistical constants calculated from the F&gt; generation and from the parent races.' No F 3 generation of any of the crosses considered here has been grown, but partial records of another cross give positive evidence of the production of bush beans of diverse types with respect to internode length. The cross in question is that between Longfellow, a bush bean with rather short internodes, and Fillbasket, a pole bean with fairly long internodes. The data for internode length were obtained from the same cultures as the data for number of internodes, which were presented earlier in this paper. From a small F 2 family of the Longfellow-Fillbasket cross, grown in the greenhouse in 1909, a very tall bush segregate was chosen and a few F : , plants were grown from it in the garden in 1910. One of the tallest plants of this F :t family was the parent of 1 Shull 1 1914 1 has pointed out the fact that increased variability of quanti - tative characters in F 2 might be due to the unequal stimulation of various degrees of heterozygosis &lt; unequal heterosisi of factors other than those directly concerned in the development of the quantitative characters in question and that somewhat diverse F 3 types might also be due to different average degrees of heterozygosis. No constant difference between extracted types could, however, be accounted for in this way. July July-Triumph Fj July-Red Marrow F, 26.11*1.52 percent 32.97 ±2.43 percent 29.62 ±2.03 per cent Snowrlake Snowrlake-Triumph Fj... Snowrlake-Red Marrow Fi 27.68*1.86 percent 28.20*2.02 percent 31.74 ±2.02 percent </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. an F 4 family (3,251) grown near Boston, Massachusetts, in 1911. A medium small bush plant was also chosen from the same F L family, a small F 3 family grown from it, and a medium small Fj plant chosen as the parent of an F, family (3,254), also grown near Boston. In the same garden with these F 4 families, were several lots of the parent race, Longfellow, all descended directly from the individual plant used in making the Longfellow-Fill - basket cross. All these lots of the bush parent were much alike in height. The plants of one of them (3,247) were measured for comparison with the two very unlike F 4 families. In making these records the total length of the main axis and the total number of internodes were determined instead of measuring each internode ■eparately, as has been done in most of the more recent work. The internode lengths reported here were calculated from the data recorded. As has been pointed out before, this does not give as accurate a measure of mean internode length as is obtained from a definite number of internodes, but it does nevertheless give some notion of differences in internode lengths between the three lots. Statistical constants for the three lots of plants are: Number of Standard Coeff ndividuals Mean deviat u 4 Lonsfellow-Fillbasket F," :J,251 Loncfellow-Fillbasket F, i,251 , 41 54.2*1.5 14.7*1.1 27.1*2.2 One of the F t families had, it is seen, somewhat shorter inte nodes than the family chosen to represent the bush parent of the crow, while the other F, family had internodes almost twice as long as the parent race. It is probable that the several families of the bush-bean parent would have been found to differ some - what in internode length, had they been measured, but certainly no such difference existed between them as between the two F ; families. Since these Fi families not only differed much in internode length but also showed some difference in number of internodes (Table 3), it follows that they differed also in height of plants. In fact the difference in this respect was remarkable. F, family No. 8,251 was one of the tallest lots of bush beans that I have ever seen. The mean length of the main axis in Longfellow (3,247) was about 137 mm., in the short F 4 family 1 3,254) about 121 mm., and in the tall F t family (3,251) about 349 mm. The extreme difference in height of plants of these families is shown in Figure 15. It is plain, then, that, while the segregation into pole and bush beans in F ; of a pole-bush cross is as definite as segregation in any simple Mendelian character, some of the bush segregates at least are very unlike the bush parent in height of plant. Longfellou 11,247 1 IK </seg>
            <seg id="p053">\ Genet k Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 53 Representative plants of (A) a race of short bush beans, Longfellow, B &gt; a race of tall bush beans, Tallbush, established from a cross Longfellow and a tall pole bean. The very tall bush-bean type, isolated as noted above ( Family 3,251 ) from a cross between a rather short bush bean and a fairly tall pole bean, has been grown for some generations and found to be fairly constant. The race will be known here as Tallbush. Since Tallbush inherited its tallness from a tall pole bean (the other parent race being a short bush bean), it is of interest to note that it transmits tallness to a part of its pole-bean progeny when crossed with a very short pole bean. The short pole bean chosen for one parent of this cross was Snowflake and the plants used were directly descended from those employed in the crosses with Red Marrow, Triumph, and July, discussed earlier in this paper. The Tallbush plant used in this cross was a direct descendant one generation removed from the F, family 3,251 of the Longfellow-Fillbasket cross noted above. In 1912 the parents and F, of the Snowflake-Tallbush cross were grown in the garden along with the plants recorded in Tables 4 and 5. The following winter a few plants of both parent races, a single plant of F, and a considerable number of plants of F 2 of the cross, were grown in the greenhouse in 6-inch pots of rich soil under conditions of temperature and moisture favorable to rather excessive length growth. </seg>
            <seg id="p054">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7. 54 The mean internode lengths, as calculated from the first five internodes, of the garden-grown parent races and F, are given in Table 6. Snowflake and Tallbush had mean internode lengths of 22.65*0.32 and 44.76 ±0.93, respectively. The mean of F, was 29.62 * 0.59, which is considerably below the average of the nwm of the parents. While the coefficient of variation of F . 17.23 * 1.45, is somewhat greater than that of the parents, 15.81 ± 1.01 and 12.76*1.50, it is not sufficiently so to demonstrate a significant difference in variability. Data for F ; of the Snowflake-Tallbush cross are given in Table 7. A* noted above, these plants were grown in the greenhouse during winter. Only a few plants of the parent races and only one plant of Fi were grown for comparison. Tallbush responded to the relatively high temperature and humidity and weak light of the greenhouse much more pronouncedly than did Snowflake, the internode length of the few plants grown being more than twice that of the same race as grown in the garden the summer before. It seems quite possible that a similar difference in response to the greenhouse conditions on the part of the several plants of F.» may account in part for the rather remarkable range of variation in internode length exhibited by that lot of plants. The average length of the first five internodes of the F 2 plants included in its range the extremes of the parent plants. It is noteworthy that this variation was quite as marked in the pole beans of F,. as in the bush plants. The tendency to produce long internodes, characteristic of the bush parent, was transmitted to a part of the pole-bean as well as to a part of the bush-bean offspring. Quite as noticeable is the fact that the tendency to form short internodes, a characteristic of the pole-bean parent, was trans - mitted to a part of the bush plants as well as to a part of the pole plants of F.. Here, just as in crosses between tall pole beans and short bush beans, habit of growth segregated in a 3-1 way — 88:31 to be exact — but both determinate and indeterminate types of plant were in fact very different from the respective determinate and indeterminate parent stocks. While the internode length of F, was distinctly intermediate between the internode lengths of the parent races (Table 6) and while the internode lengths in F-, ranged from one parent type to that of the other (Table 7), the height of the F, plants was by no means intermediate between the parents, nor was the F_. range in height confined to the parental extremes. The heights of the F,&gt; plants are shown in Table 8. The few very long internodes of the determinate parent, Tallbush, as grown in the greenhouse, made it practically equal the height of the indeterminate parent, Snowflake, with its more numerous but much shorter internodes. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">.4 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 55 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. The F s bush plants were on the whole considerably shorter than the bush parent, none being so tall as the taller plants of Tall - bush. It was among the F_. pole-bean plants, however, that the most remarkable variation was exhibited. The smallest of these plants were only about 35 centimeters high shorter than any of the few plants of Snowflake grown with them but not much shorter than are sometimes found among weak plants of that race. At the other extreme were plants nearly 200 centimeters tall a height not materially less than that attained by the taller races of pole beans when grown in as small pots as were these F : plants. The great variation in height of the F_. plants of this cross is perhaps made even more obvious by the photographs reproduced in Figure 16. It seems a clear inference from the data here pre - senie«l that a tall race of bush beans, which inherited its relatively great height from a tall pole-bean parent of an earlier cross, has transmitted tallness to its pole-bean progeny when crossed with a very short pole bean. Other factors for height of plant are, then, inherited independently of habit of growth. FACTORS FOR PLANT HEIGHT THEIR SEGREGATION AND POSSIBLE MODIFICATION IN CROSSES. It was noted in the introduction to this paper that quantita - tive characters, including height of plants in maize at least, are usually intermediate between the parents in F, and show'a wide range of variation in F-, thus furnishing a basis for the isolation of numerous quantitatively distinct types in F .,. It was also noted that some quantitative characters, particularly height of plants of several very diverse groups including beans, exhibit perfect dominance in F,, followed by simple 3:1 segregation in F_. and typical Mendelian behavior in later generations. That height of plants should in some cases fall into the one and in other cases into the other of these two classes of behavior presents an important problem. If the inheritance of quantitative charac- Un in general is to be interpreted on the basis of the multiple - factor hypothesis, it is to be expected that some quantitative characters will be found to differ by only a single genetic factor just as other quantitative differences may be due to three or four or ten factors. It seems probable, then, that, within any one species, and with respect to the same plant part, great quantitative differences are in general due to many factors and small quantita - tive differences to one or to a few factors, tho of course it is not maintained that all size factors, even in this restricted case, necessarily have equal value. In this connection see Shull 1914.) But the 3-1 segregation, denoting a single-factor difference, is </seg>
            <seg id="p057">i Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 57 seen in crosses between tall and dwarf (pole and bush) beans whether the difference in height of the parents is very great or only medium. Evidence has been presented in this paper to show that very tall and very dwarf beans (pole and bush beans) differ by a single fully dominant genetic factor for habit of growth. Pole beans are indeterminate in habit, growth continuing apparently as long as conditions are favorable. Bush beans are determinate in growth, the main axis being terminated by the inflorescence. One genetic factor for growth habit differentiates a very tall pole bean from a very dwarf bush bean just as sharply as it does a medium short pole bean from a medium tall bush bean. Evidence has also been presented to show that height of plant in beans is influenced by other genetic factors independent of habit of growth. These factors have to do with number of internodes and with internode length. It has been shown that pole-bean races, equally indeterminate in habit of growth, may differ considerably in the number of internodes ultimately pro - duced and also in the length of particular internodes and the mean length of all internodes. Bush beans also differ much in internode length and somewhat in number of internodes. Tho the evidence presented here is not all that might be desired, it is believed to be sufficient to show that both internode length and number of internodes in beans are inherited in the same way that most quantitative characters in plants are. An intermediate development in F t (often masked by the increased vigor of heterozy - gosisi, increased variation in F 2 , and the isolation of distinct types in later generations have been shown. The fact that the Fj generation of some crosses was not more variable than one or other of the parent races — whether or not this be due to irregular - ities discoverable in the parent races — cannot displace the positive evidence of increased variation in other crosses. It seems clear that, if the production of types unlike either parent in number of internodes or in internode length is due to a segregation of independent, nondominant factors for number of internodes or internode length in crosses between two unlike bush beans or in crosses between two unlike pole beans, then, a similar result must be interpreted in the same way in case of crosses between a pole bean and a bush bean. From a cross between a tall pole bean and a short bush bean, there resulted in F 2 a distinct segregation into approximately three pole beans to one bush bean. Evidently there existed between the parents a single-factor difference for habit of growth. But while these pole-bean segregates were all indeterminate in habit of growth some of them were much shorter than the pole- </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7. bean parent race, and, likewise while the bush segregates were all determinate in habit of growth, some of them were much taller than the bush-bean parent race. We need not conclude from this, however, that the single factor for habit of growth by which the parent races differed was modified in some way by the cross, so that, while only determinate and indeterminate habits were to be seen in Ft, they were in part of the individuals modified determin - ate and modified indeterminate habits. It seems more likely that there existed other factors for the difference in height of the parent plants besides the factor for habit of growth and that Elation of these other factors was responsible for the different U of bush beans and the different heights of pole beans noted ' Ft generation. From one of the very tall Fj bush plants of this cross there hat been established a race of very tall bush beans, known here as Tallbush, :Figs. 9 and 15) and this has been crossed with a race of very short pole beans, Snowflake (Fig. 9). Tall pole beans resulted in F, and there was a wide range of variation in height of both the pole and bush segregates in F... Apparently the factors for number of internodes and for internode length, which this very tall race of bush beans received from the tall pole-bean parent of the original cross, are able to reproduce the tallneas of that parent when associated with the factor for in - determinate growth secured from a very short pole bean. And, moreover, these factors have apparently segregated to produce diverse heights in both the pole and bush plants of this later F. generation from the cross between the tall bush bean and the short pole bean just as they did to produce the diverse types of the earlier F t generation from the cross between the tall pole bean and the short bush bean. If we were to account for these results by assuming a modifica - tion of the factor for determinate growth thru the influence of the tall pole bean employed as one parent of the original cross, we should have also to make the following additional assumptions: 1 1 ) That the modification affected the bush habit in different degrees in the case of the several F. bush plants, &lt; 2 ) that the modifi - cation is constant in the new tall bush race, (3) that the modified determinate habit was remodified in the cross between the tall bush race and the very short pole race, the modification again affecting only a part of the F, bush plants, (4 ) that this remodified determinate habit was able to modify the indeterminate habit in a very definite way in the cross with the short pole bean, so that the F, plants were all very tall pole beans, and finally (5) that this new modification of the indeterminate habit was able to appear in only a part of the pole-bean segregates of F 2 . </seg>
            <seg id="p059">A Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 59 The modification would then also have to be used in interpret - ing the results secured from crosses between two bush races or two pole races of different heights, for there seems to be no fundamental difference between such crosses and crosses between a pole bean and a bush bean. But, for the results from crosses of unlike bush or pole beans, the multiple-factor hypothesis affords a much more simple and direct explanation. It accounts for the intermediate development in F !( for the wide range of variation in F 2 , and for the constancy of some and inconstancy of other F 2 types. In many respects the results secured from crosses between pole and bush beans resemble the results obtained from crosses between hooded and Irish rats (MacCurdy and Castle 1907), and hooded and wild rats (Castle 1912). When hooded rats — char - acterized by pigmented head, shoulders, and forelegs and median dorsal stripe and white over the rest of the body — were crossed with Irish rats — characterized by pigmented sides and dorsal surface and a variable white area on the ventral surface — the Irish pattern was dominant in F, and segregation into Irish and hooded patterns with a 3-1 ratio occurred in F 2 , but the pigmented area in the hooded segregates was increased as was also the range of variation in amount of pigmentation. From this MacCurdy and Castle conclude: "Again, though the inheritance is clearly Mendelian, when hooded and Irish rats are crossed, the gametes formed by cross-breds are not pure, but modified, each pattern being changed somewhat in the direction of that pattern with which it was associated in the cross-bred parent." A strain of hooded rats with extensive pigmentation and a strain with restricted pigmentation were established by selection. When crossed with wild rats — totally pigmented — each hooded strain behaved as a simple Mendelian recessive, but the hooded segregates from the cross of wild rats with the extensively pig - mented hooded pattern were more extensively pigmented than the hooded segregates from the other cross. Crosses between hooded rats with restricted pigmentation and hooded rats with extensive pigmentation gave results similar to most crosses where the parents differ quantitatively. (Castle and Phillips 1914.) The fact of simple Mendelian segregation in such crosses has led Castle to maintain that only a single unit-character is involved in the experiment (Castle 1912, 1914), tho he admits the possibility that additional factors may be concerned (Castle and Phillips 1914) as first suggested by East (1912) and later discussed by the Hagedoorns (1914) and Muller (1914). That the hooded pattern differs from the Irish pattern in a single genetic factor will be readily admitted. That there are no additional factors </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 \rbrtuka Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. inllueiuing the extent of pigmentation in the hooded pattern but unable to influence the Irish pattern is not so clear. The behavior of crosses between a hooded strain with extended pig - mentation and one with restricted pigmentation affords support to the idea of such additional factors as do also the results of rrn—f between Irish rats and rats with extended hoods whereby the hoods of f t segregates are restricted rather than further ex - tended. In short, it seems possible that restricted hood may differ from extended hood by one to several genetic factors, just as tall bush beans seem to differ from short bush beans, and that Irish pattern may sometimes possess and sometimes lack factors for extension of the hooded pattern, just as tall pole beans seem to |MMMe»* and short pole beans to lack some factor or factors for internode length or internode number factors which, it appears, ran l&gt;e inherited independently of habit of growth and thereby be transferred from pole to bush or from bush to pole beans. I will admit that at first it seems unlikely that a genetic &gt;r could Ik- present in the Irish pattern of rats together with the factor that differentiates the Irish from the hooded pattern, without interfering with the simple 3-1 segregation resulting from a cross between Irish and hooded rats. The existence of factors for iniernode length independent of factors for habit of growth in beans presents no such difficulty. Apparently the only rela - tion that habit of growth bears to internode length exists merely by virtue of the circumstance that determinate habit arrests growth when the period of acceleration in growth-rate has barely begun, so that internode length of bush beans is ordinarily much Ink than that of pole beans. But to conceive the possible nature of factors for number of internodes independent of a factor for habit of growth in beans presents as great a difficulty as to conceive the possible nature of pigment-extension factors in - dependent of pattern factors in rats. The principal effect upon plant height of indeterminate growth u to extend the number of internodes almost indefinitely while that of determinate growth is to limit the development of inter - node* to a small and rather definite number. If there are, in addit ion to a single factor for habit of growth, other special factors for internode number, how can there result a simple segregation giving three plants with many internodes i indeterminate i to one plant with few internodes (determinate)? Let us see whether the multiple-factor hypothesis assumed thruout this paper to interpret the results as regards number of internodes in crosses between distinct bush beans and also in rnMMB between distinct pole beans can be combined with the single-factor hypothesis also used consistently to interpret the </seg>
            <seg id="p061">4 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 61 facts with reference to the inheritance of habit of growth — so that the combination shall afford a true picture of the results secured from a cross between a tall pole bean and a short bush bean, or a short pole bean and tall bush bean. Let us assume that difference in habit of growth between pole and bush beans is due to the single factor A and that the difference between a tall bush bean and a short one or between a tall pole bean and a short one is due to the two factors B and C. Let us also assume that A is a dominant factor and that B and C are nondominant factors. Finally, the following values, which are to be added to an initial value of three internodes, will be assumed for the three factors: Because .4 is dominant and B and C are nondominant, these factors, when in the duplex condition, will have the following values : A plant with the formula AABBCC is then — environmental influence aside a pole bean with 17 internodes, a plant AAbbcc is a pole bean with 13 internodes, a plant aaBBCC is a bush bean with 7 internodes and a plant aabbcc is a bush bean with three internodes. A cross between AABBCC and AAbbcc would give an F.. of all pole beans but with a somewhat greater range of varia - tion than that of either parent. Likewise a cross between aaBBCC and aabbcc would produce nothing but bush beans, but the varia - tion in F_. would be greater than in either parent. Crosses be - tween AABBCC and aaBBCC, between AAbbcc and aabbcc, between AABBcc and aaBBcc, etc., would give, in F,, three pole beans to one bush bean without an increased range of variation in either class over that of the parent races. Finally a cross be - tween AABBCC and aabbcc or between AAbbcc and aaBBCC would result in F, in three pole beans to one bush bean and both of the Fj classes would show greater variation than the parent races. The latter possibilities alone need be illustrated further. The formulae and numbers of internodes of the parents and F, would be: Or: A = 10 internodes B = \ internode C= \ internode AA = 10 internodes BB = 2 internodes CC = 2 internodes Parent AABBCC - 17 internodes. Parent aabbcc = 3 internodes. F, AaBbCc = 15 internodes. Parent AAbbec = 13 internodes. Parent aaBBCC = 7 internodes. Fi AaBbCc = 15 internodes. </seg>
            <seg id="p062">62 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 The formulae, number of internodes and frequencies of the neveral P, types would be: FYom the illustration niven above, it is seen that a combina - tion of the multiple-factor and the single-factor hypotheses, previously employed separately, can be used to interpret the tteU with regard to the inheritance of habit of growth and number of internodes in crosses between pole and bush beans. A 3-1 distribution of pole and bush types, together with wide variation in internode numbers in both classes, is realized as a result of the assumptions made. The range of variation observed in V of the crosses of pole and bush beans reported in this paper is much greater for the pole-bean than for the bush-bean segregates. This difference is not expressed in the hypothetical frequency distribution given above. But no account is here taken of the influence of environmental conditions upon the number of inter - nodes. In the discussions of habit of growth and of growth curves early in this paper, it was shown that environmental conditions esart a marked influence upon the number of internodes of pole beans while having little or no effect upon bush beans. Pole beans, in short, owing to their indeterminate habit, are capable at prolonged growth under favorable conditions but may have their growth arrested early by unfavorable conditions, while bush beans under very favorable conditions merely produce more branches, all of which are as determinate in growth as in the main FiaqtMacMa Formulae Internodes Frequencies Formulae Internodes 1 AABHCC 17 2 AabbCC 15 I i*ABB&lt;Y 16 4 AabbCc 14 : AABM'C 16 1 AAbbec 13 t AaBBCl 17 2 AaWcc 13 4 AABbCe 15 1 aaBBCC 7 4 /toBBTr 16 2 aaBBCc 6 4 AaBbCr 16 2 aaBbCC 6 • itafitfV 15 4 aaBbCc 5 4.4B«rr 15 1 &lt;w66CC 5 ! AABbcc 14 2 &lt;i&lt;ihWV 4 t iaHBcc 15 1 oaBBcf 5 4 AaHbcr 14 2 aaBbec 4 1 HWT 15 1 aabbcc 3 5 ylAfcfcCf 14 The frequency distribution for number of internodes found by iinm-mbling the above data is: irtaraodM ;{-4-5-«-7-8-»-10-l 1-12-13-14-15-16-17 fWiHMiriii 14 641 112 18 12 I Biwd bean* 16 . Pole beans 48 Ratio 1 3 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">.4 Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 63 axis. The difference in variation between the pole' and bush segregates in F 2 is no greater than that between pole and bush races. In the hypothetical formulae employed here, the factor A for habit of growth is assumed to differ in no way from the factors B and C, except in regard to dominance and to the mag - nitude of its effect upon number of internodes. As a matter of fact, the factor A must differ in another respect from B and C, for the axis of a pole bean with relatively few internodes is not terminated by an inflorescence and can be forced to elongate almost indefinitely, while the axis of the tallest bush bean is terminated just as abruptly as that of the shortest bush bean. If A were a factor for habit of growth alone without other relation to internode numbers and B and C and their like mere modifying factors, some of them, perhaps, concerned in general vigor of growth, time of flowering and of seed production, etc., the results would be the same. It is probable that size factors in general interact one upon another during development, a single factor sometimes being concerned in the development of several charac - ters commonly regarded as quite distinct and several factors at times being concerned in the development of a single character. Several indications of this sort have been observed in maize Emerson and East 1913). In the present paper numerous illustrations of the interrelations of growth habit, internode num - ber, internode length, time of flowering and seed production, and the like have been pointed out. By way of conclusion, it may be said that the known facts in regard to the inheritance of the quantitative character height of plant in beans yield readily to an analysis based upon a modi - fied multiple-factor hypothesis. The proposed modification con - sists merely of the assumption of inequality in dominance and inequality in potency of some of the factors concerned. It is probable that no geneticist would maintain that all the genetic factors concerned in the development of any quantitative charac - ter are necessarily equal in dominance or potency 1 , but, since the actual potency of distinct quantitative factors has as yet been determined in no case and since the assumption of equal potency of two or more factors affords a simple and sufficiently accurate interpretation of quantitative inheritance, no other assumption seems necessary except in cases like the one now under considera - tion. Whether this modified multiple-factor hypothesis will account for the facts of inheritance of plant height in case of such types as tomatoes, peas, dwarf maize, etc., is a question for future determination. 1 For a discussion of thi? matter, see Shull 1914, and Muller 1914. </seg>
            <seg id="p064">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. 7 64 In presenting this factorial interpretation of inheritance of height of plant in beans, the writer disavows any intention of maintaining that this is the only possible interpretation of the facts presented. Castle's hypothesis of the modification of genetic factors is another such interpretation i Castle 1914a). Perhaps neither is correct. Both serve the purpose of working hypotheses, in so far as they suggest the direction of further researches. Since one hypothesis may suggest certain lines of further investigation and another hypothesis may suggest other lines, it is fortunate that we are not limited to a single hypothesis. The multiple - factor hypothesis has been adopted here because it seems to the writer to afford the more simple and direct interpretation of the known facts concerning the inheritance of quantitative characters. This statement is made with a full realization that, whatever hypothesis is adopted, it must interpret the facts of inheritance derived from selection experiments as well as those obtained from cross-breeding. LITERATURE CITED Bailey, L. H The dwarf Lima beans. Bui. Cornell, \\ Y. Agr. Exp. Sta 87:83-101. 1895. Bateson, W., and Punnett, R. ( Sweet peas. Rpts. Evol. Com. Roy. Soc. 4:6-18. 1908 Castle, W. E. The inconstancy of unit-characters. Amer. Xat. 46:352 362. 1912. Pure lines and selection. Jour. Heredity 5:93-97. 1914. Size inheritance and the pure line theory. Zeit. induk. Abast. Vererb. 12:225-237. 1914a. Castle, W. E., and Phillips, J. C. Piebald rats and selection. Pub. Carnegie Inst. 195:1-56. 1914. East. E. M. The Mendelian notation as a description of phys ological facts. Amer. Nat. 46:633-655. 1912. East, E. M., and Hayes, H. K. Inheritance in maize. Bui. Conn. Agr. Exp. Sta. 167:1 - 142. 1911. Emerson, R. A. Heredity in bean hybrids. Ann. Rpt. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. 17:33-68. 1904. The inheritance of sizes and shapes in plants. Amer. Nat. 44:743-744. 1910. </seg>
            <seg id="p065">\ Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 65 ( Genetic correlation and spurious allelomorphism in maize. Ann. Rpt. Xebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. 24:59-90. 1911. Emerson, R. A., and East, E. M. The inheritance of quantitative characters in maize. Re - search Bui. Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. 2:1-120. 1913. ilLBERT, A. W. A Mendelian study of tomatoes. Ann. Rpt. Amer. Breeders' Assoc. 7:169-188. 1912. Hagedoorn, A. L., and A. C. Studies on variation and selection. Zeit. induk. Abst. Vererb. 11:145-183. 1914. Hedrick, U. P., and Booth, N. 0. Mendelian characters in tomatoes. Proc. Soc. Hort. Sci. 5:19-24. 1907. Keeble, F., and Pellew, C. The mode of inheritance of stature and time of flowering in peas (Pisum satieum). Jour. Genetics 1:47-56. 1910. Lock, R. H. Experiments with peas. Annals Roy. Bot. Gard. Peradeniya. 2:357-414. 1905. MacCurdy, H., and Castle, W. E. Selection and cross-breeding in relation to the inheritance of coat-pigments and coat-patterns in rats and guinea pigs. Pub. Carnegie Inst. 70:1-50. 1907. Mendel, G. Versuche tiber Pflanzenhybriden. Verh. naturf. Ver. Briinn, Abhandlungen IV, 1865. Translation published in Jour. Roy. Hort. Soc. 26:3-32 (1901) and in Mendel's Prin. Heredity A Defense, Bateson, pp. 40-95. 1902. M uller, H. J The bearing of the selection experiments of Castle and Phillips on the variability of genes. Amer. Nat. 48:567 - 576. 1914. Duplicate genes for capsule form in Bursa bursa-paetoris. Zeit. induk. Abst. Vererb. 12:97-149. 1914. TSCHERMAK, E. VON. Weitere Kreuzungsstudien an Erbsen, Levkojen, und Bohnen. Zeitsch. landw. Versuchsw. Oesterreich. 1904. pp. 1-102. Bastardierungsversuche an Levkojen, Erbsen, und Bohnen mit Riicksicht auf die Faktorenlehre. Zeit. induk. Abst. Vererb. 7:81-234. 1912. Price, H. L., and Drinkard, A. W. Inheritance in tomato hybrids. Bui. Va. Agr. Exp. Sta. 177:17-53. 1908. Shull, G. H. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">Bui. ? 66 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research IJ A t-; -H ID ■» t-; !O OJ &lt;C 2 OOOOOOri^ L- «._ ■-. •?.« •^ ifl t- t- t- X O 5&gt; co-e 1 «■* t-ixiea &gt;. ;i 7 X X ■— 00 &lt;C — OJIO Z-5 &lt;«. 7 ti uoijBjaud'j j- tj&gt;co rtiooiMn t- 00 •** OC ■— . "Si t»o:wu5«o6co "?: io ~ *n t£&gt; oo -^ x us 2 * w i: % ■ I-. j— — eg aj t-a &amp; •P.3 -9 i?o^&gt;o M H Sip •! 3c3c spmpiAipui 10 J«MJlUn \ 000C iSSM^^N t- , WO-JONNt- </seg>
            <seg id="p067">Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris 67 4 Genetic (C ■*■ \e •-! ■* t-; rt ,4 »H CmV* ■-&lt; 88 « hi CO t - 2S •^•co coco oo HI -H IOCO 00 CO o © © o o o CCT3 CO tf -^ CO CO TJ« iC SD t- »O U3 ©©© o© ?, ■"TOOCOOCOCO "SCO CM CM CO IN CO CVI OIN 2 H spsnpiAipui jo iaquin^ lOOOOiiTliQO &lt;C0O| m OJ IM CM &gt;-h i-i CJ i-ilOi « 7. ■ R -r 5. M X CO P ■ c « » E 7- .«" E H^i " * a " 5 5DCMCOCO 3 A ■*i-l»IN «« „ C-l t-cn|5 nn^i-i^ II ■r t-«c^eo oo nnI o * 00 CM »— ' »— ' ! 00 i— i CC ?• § 1 Tl 5 UOl}BJ3U3f) fah ■*. oi^cnio^ao to co « NMM1O-WM lOt-Lfi H .i^.L^ooi ioE^ c ?• I !«. K 5 li * ■M C 3 3 3 C C iS &lt; (/JTT-s W W 5C -OiN^t- •&gt;» &lt;B T» OS CO to CM OS t- CM H O» CO CO -&gt;1"O ■# CO ■*na &lt;o ■» a&gt; ■«■ oot» -H -H -H -H -« -H -H-H ©t^OtO^-CO &lt;O«OJ 4&gt; if I </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 Nebraska / Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui. L OICX 71 XI- J a ■~. bh Mm U5t&gt; x-c *?* ;?: ■* t- smnpiA &lt;|iun\ ? I"? z£ aoijEjduao I 5 u u </seg>
            <seg id="p069">/ Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgar!*. 69 \ &lt;;» Si h (I ii (■in ■SO 3i NO»»-»!C»»®N'*"" . O5 OS 00 IO — OC «&gt; ~ 5 „; _; ~j — — — ~^iwc&gt;itf3~Gc;cMoi?i f'5-2 -H^H-H-H-H-H-H-M-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H-H « rt to r-i r- rt CO t- —I t- t- OO O&gt; O&gt; 00 CO — CM CO &lt;£ &gt; 00 O 00 (0 CO ■*•'»' SO CM 00 t- CO Tf to CM US CO CO 00 _ us cm &gt;o cm "i- &gt;a od &gt;o c-^ — "'22"'^SiS S2SJ W o _* C4 — CO — CM — CM CM CM — CO CO — — N CM CO CM •O c CM — CM 3 U5 1 CM « ICO •&lt;» t~. t-, t-. U9 ■* Ol O! i «C ; "5 X •5 '5 -H-H-H-H-M-M-M-tl-H-H-M-H-H-H-H-M-H-M-M o&lt;&gt; xSSSHao^^onMnt^ooiOffln ~~ico3ico'i"i"»«e«5&gt;'»-"'-'«oco'oo&gt;oaot~ CO CM CO £. OC ; CO -* S S Si O O CN [50 ; CM « I OS t&gt;; « .^ oS SO C ; CM lO I- CO 00 t- 00 I- 00 e ; ■* CO CO O! i O -■-we^cj'^jji'-^^D^ft— COCMC0'^' 1 ~ ) t^*' pto^l 5! — cmcocm2cmcmSc-icocococmcmcmc-icmco is ;oioaocojit-'-**aoos© &lt; *i t «DC3^ | u3ooeoocco Sr-Sxiiao^t-qwNMt-oeiioaM ai«-«i" i «i'^«c^u5'^ T^co c^ oow sxt^ K-e i-^fN[- »•»■*»■»«- laasso-fioji; &gt;»io;oaoofieN«a^;M, m&gt;imt~ x -h — MOO-hOO — — 30 — tc« — m-*«oco3Ct-'fl'tg [- ?) » I* X t- X O if « K J: C TM'.CC»1 *Tfl-CON?3-*^t'(' : C^l &lt;fMO« 7-1 M « W NHMMnMnNMINNNW STIMlplAlUU; rtOOOOTft-lO — O — t-CMt-CMU5«»tCSg«l S I : : :_: "::::":: -~ ■' ■ P' ■ : £ L«~ :::-:::: : : : :-Ty\ : JJ i « I • ■ ■_ If 3 ■;;:_::: : -r :_-_: c^ « :« : _: «---«?! :« g| * : ; ; 2 -cm :■••-. f- « Oj i, m cm r^t^i CO — 00 CM •* ■&gt;* SO CO — CM'J'OOCC C £ M — ■ — ' S.- So ' 00 O5CC — u5CM»»!OCMO'-COOOCO"3&gt;Ot - t. CM CM — CM— — _T?_ «O is CO ■«■ ■* ■«• 00 00 00 Tf Tf — CM ■* 3S O CO •» — CM 5 cm eq _«« — -+ __jr? ■_ °° — 00 rcMOSCO&gt;OCM«DOO'-i'*CM f CMt-COCM — U I th re »-" T? CO -rti-ilfi CM CM CM— — — SO ' »/3 •— oo us :— '.'.'.'.'.'.'. jiq«H DQ--QQ Q Q Q C uoiimaiwQ a, o. a. euji; (£'[£&amp;£,' fc fc fc fc f£ fc ei. t * t£ X ■V« r. x .'■ •M «o - w os eo ■* ■»«• ■»• oo oo oo ■» •* — in ■* ji o co ■»• jj i2 5o i ffq OJ eO «5 WO 00 •- ■* O) f Nt-»N&gt;- i« NMN-" r. 1!H«H UOIJBJ3U9O fceufcOuBbBbfefiti 1 fcfctfcBtfcfc-l* ■ 2giS S^s: SSSoSSSS | — CI C 5 S^ i 5 3 44«D ■*■*■* ■* ■* ■* - 7. C a I S £ 5 x a -I ■*. 7 ■* -c 5 'C 5 lit* 1 t i i£j; n all a f | * i i ■oSo^t i i i o o a*'Ec"^^ 3 2 3 C c &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p070">Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station, Research Bui 70 •&gt; 1 i y. i X /: f. (Ccjoi-nonMwc ■pa 3oi3cnm-*t-o-&gt;i i o«o -NM-"M-"N MNNCCW'-'N^M^^ — M 3". X X CC I- S-2 3C — *B M 3 a, OB'S i — ■ n c^i — w — f ■ XA^9:XSiCCX S *- - • . — - ' •£3)t-SX«^X XXiCtltM jo jaqiun\ ust-Ki-ie- &gt;e — «o ?, £c X X s-;g 5. « 5 t S Si it EE r. -i uoiiBjrtiM;) X i^rrsxiox^x E 3 ■f O X X x x -n x ■* x "5 I £ (3 r s &lt; X-r X OOHOOt-OMOOiO </seg>
            <seg id="p071">\ Genetic Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgar is. 71 uouKJduo; ) a, Pli [l, </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 Nebraska Agricultural Exp. Station. Research Bui «9C 9 •»t-oooo«c S|EnpiA||)UI jo jaquin\ — oc — /. &amp;•! X. •ZL ?] J-. r. — N [- ?i « « 3-. S» X I ?] i X }iqttH A uoi^Bjauao a,a.Bh fc x tr i" I I- i 3 £« crtE- BB </seg>
            <seg id="p073">Study of Plant Height in Phaseolus Vulgaris. 73 A Genetii 3HH ~- ao cc * 2 s(BnpiAipui i 00 CO jii j.)(|iun\ '1 1- u T 9 -r ■-= e M^H ■ OS ■ X 10 l- &gt; M9 — J«1 B H UOUKJdUrf'J ___ _ =&gt;. act- 3» j-. 3: a-, os *s i 5 1*, "a h X i JS-c -?5 &lt; </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>