<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00037.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00037.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Board of Education Nebraska State Normal Schools Biennial Report To His Excellency John H. Morehead Governor</title>
               <date value="1917">1917</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change>
            <date>2007-09-19</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
        </change>
	        <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            
            <seg id="p001">Board of Education Nebraska State Normal Schools r Biennial Report To His Excellency John H. Morehead Governor Compiled by A. L. Caviness, Secretary LINCOLN, NEBRASKA JANUARY 1, 1917 The Hub. PrioKm ICtncy, Ne*r«ta </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Directory BOARD OF EDUCATION NEBRASKA STATE NORMAL SCHOOL MEMBERS APPOINTED A. L. Ca viness, Kearney Term expires 1917 T. J. Majors, Peru Term expires 1918 Dan Morris, Kearney Term expires 1919 H. E Reisrhe, Chadron Term expries 1920 Frank Pilger, Pierce Term expires 1921 MEMBER8 EX-OFFICIO G. E. Hall, State Treasurer Lincoln A. O. Thomas, State Superintendent Lincoln OFFICERS OF THE BOARD Dan Morris, President T. J. Majors, Vice-President A. L. Caviness, Secretary G. E. Hall, Treasurer STANDING COMMITTEES Auditing: Hall. Morris, Reischf Executive: Majors, Morris, Pilger, Reische Instruction: Caviness, Majors, Reische Printing: Thomas, Hall, Pilger Rules: Thomas, Majors, Hall SCHOOLS IN OPERATION PERU, opened 1867 KEARNEY, opened 1903 WAYNE, opened 1910 Chadron, opened 1911 </seg>
            <seg id="p003">LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL John H. Morehead, Governor of Nebraska. Sir: — We herewith transmit to you, as required by law, the biennial report and statement of expenditures made by this Board from December SI, 1914 to December 1, 1916. Original vouchers for all claims are on file with the state auditor of public accounts and duplicates of the same are on file in the office of the Board of Education. Respectfully submitted. A. L. CAVINESS, Secretary. </seg>
            <seg id="p004"/>
            <seg id="p005">BIENNIAL REPORT 5 BIENNIAL REPORT To Governor John H. Morehead: The services rendered the people of our state by its Normal Schools Is a most intimate and a most vital one. The teacher* of the boys and girls of today must be well trained for their important work. And the schools that prepare these teachers must be of the highest order of efficiency as educational institutions. That a training school for teachers may be in every sense efficient It must possess a strong faculty, ample and complete equipment, and the full confidence of the people it serves. FACULTY Each of our schools is especially fortunate in having a devoted group of earnest and enthusiastic men and women on Its faculty. During the past two years a few of our strongest educators have been called to other states by the lure of better pay or a wider field of usefulness. But by a process of careful seler-tion and by a conservative and graded salary in - crease the Board of Education has found it possible not only to make good every vacancy but for the most part to retain our most experienced ■workers. MATERIAL EQUIPMENT Enlightened economy at times demands the liberal expenditure of money. A great industrial plant calls for the outlay of millions of dollars before it is expected to yield any returns whatever. The greatest Industry &lt;&gt;t this nation, educating its children, can not produce the highest and best results if its material equipment be inadequate and of an inferior sort. The Board of Education has therefore deemed it wise to use all avail - able funds, after providing for the proper maintenance of each school, in erecting such buildings as will meet the most urgent and immediate de - mands of each institution. The training school at Peru, begun In the last biennium, has been completed, as has also the administration building 1 at ■Wayne. Out of the funds of this biennium there is being built an auditorium and a physical education building at Kearney, a physical and an Industrial building at 'Wayne, and an east wing to the main building at Chadron. When completed these buildings will supply temporarily at least the im - perative needs of the three new and growing schools, leaving the ollsr school at Peru to be cared for as future resources may permit. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION EXTENSION WORK People have confidence only in the things with which they are familiar. To extend their usefulness and bring more teachers In contact With the schools study center classes have been organized in many places. Faculty members meet these classes on Saturdays and so assist ambitious worker* who are anxious to improve themselves while actively engaged in teaching. Our normal school (acuities visit institutes, attend teachers' meetings. fend seek to render expert assistance wherever needed. They follow up the work of their graduates and help to make it a success. In fact, these insti - tutions are doing- for the school interests of Nebraska a work similar to that done by schools of agriculture for the fanning industry of our country. The act of the legislature requiring the Board of Education to provida special instruction for rural teachers has been complied with in each of the normals. Rural departments, with trained specialists in charge, have been established and every effort is being made to help the teachers of the country schools. Without doubt this is a field that deserves our most care - ful attention. BUILDINGS From the funds of last blennium a west wing to the main building at .Chadron was provided for, an administration building at Wayne, and a training school at Peru. Kearney has received first attention in the build - ing program of this biennium. A contract was let August t, 1915, for an auditorium to cost $ST,867.oo and this building will soon be ready for use. On June 23, 1916, contracts were signed for a physical education build - ing at Kearney to cost $52,195.00, an east wing for Chadron to cost »5] ,548.00, and a physical and Industrial building for Wayne to cost S64.S92.00. These buildings should be completed during the coining sum. tner, and they will serve to relieve the crowded conditions now prevailing at each of these schools. FUNDS The money appropriated by the the normal schools as reported by the foUowing: last legislature for the support of state auditor's office amounts to the liaised from the 1915 tax levy Raised from the 1916 tax levy Raised from the 1913-1914 tax levy. Interest on Endowment Fund to Dec, $367,822.84 . 383,132.86 59,350.19 1, 1916 15,808.24 $826,114.13 Out of the above funds there was set aside as maintenance for each school during the biennium: To Chadron $85,000.00. Kearney $160,000.00, Peru $180,000.00. Wayne $120,000.00 or a total of $545,000.00. This left sm.U4.is for buildings, other expenses and permanent improvements for all the schools. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">BIENNIAL REPORT T ESTIMATES It will require a material increase for maintenance during the coming biennium, due to caring for additions to the physical plants, larger number of teaching force to accommodate the increased enrollment at each school, and the increased cost of up-keep and repairs. The present levy of 85-1M of one mill should remain unchanged. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">HIENNIAL REPORT 9 Item. mi Mar. 8 Hall Brothers, Chadron I 281.85 Elmer Dovel, Chadron. wins, heating SM.M F. E. Mullholen. (5) Chadron dormitory 3,«10.a2 K. E. Mullholen. («) Chadron wing l.SM.M J. P. Riddle. (7) Wayne administration 4.7M.M April 13 J. R. Gettys. Board expense 40.00 Claflin Prlntinir Co. Bienniil report 1M.U Jennie B. Adams, proof reading IS. IS Harry Porter, Secretary's supplies 9.*# State Journal Co., binding minutes J.I* A. I.. Caviness. Secretary's salarx 1M.M A. L*. Caviness. Board expense 71 .90 A. H. Viele. Board expense IS. 14 Dan Morris. Board expense 22.89 J. R. Oettys., Board expense .'9 00 Thomas Rhlnehart. Way"e administration 1,576.75 Fdwarrt F. Schuri*. Wayne administration HIM .Tas. P. Riddle. Wayne lli.t* Jas. P. Riddle (8) Wuve administration K.M5.54 Gaertner &amp; P-eckenhauer. Wayne administration 423.86 June 23 Warren E. Rurre'le. Peru athletic field M.1&gt; T. O. Crawford. Peru athletic field g . SO F. M. Ivers, Peru athletic fleld M.M Meek Lumber Co.. Peru athletic field 217 . 7 J T&gt;. S. Wilson. Peru athletic fleld 8.?0 W. Rische * Son. Peru athletic field 544.09 F. W. Rische * 8on, Peru tralninij school 7,148. it Dan Morris, Board expense 11.44 J. R. Gettys, Board expense 14. •* A. L.. Caviness. Board expense 44 . 91 T. J. Majors, Board expense M . 24 A. H. Viele, Board expense 1«.T5 Federal Steel Fixture Co., Wayne administration S44.M Fuchs. Son &amp; Blind Wayne administration 1 .082.75 F. H. Jones. Wayne administration TM.M Korsmeyer Co.. Wayne administration 1.17*. 04 National Wood Works, Wayne administration 122.25 Nebraska School Supply Co., Wayne administration... 2,805. 41 Thomas Rhinehart, Wayne administration 278.25 J. H. Craddock. Wayne administration SM.M Auk . 3 Lewis Adams, Peru athletic field S3 . 20 Warren E. Burrelle, Peru athletic fleld 85. 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Items (•1 Mar. 8 Hall Brothers. Chadron f 288 . t5 Elmer Dovel. Chadron, wing, heating IM.N F. E. Mullholen. (5) Chadron dormitory 1(10.52 P. K. Mullholen. (6) Chadron wing l.&amp;M.M J. P. Riddle, (7) Wayne administration V7M.M April 13 J. R. Gettys. Hoard expense 40.00 Claflin Printing Co. Bienniil report 1(4. U Jennie R. Adams, proof reading 15.lt Harry Porter. Secretary's supplies &gt;.0« State Journal Co., binding minutes •.!• A. L. Caviness, Secretary's salar) 1M.M A. I* Cavinesa. Board expense 71 . »• A. H. Vlele. Board expense 18.14 Dan Morris. Board expense 22.8S J. R. Oettys.. Board expense .'9 00 Thomas Rhlnehart. Wiy» administration 1.57C.75 Fdward F. Srhuria:. Wayne administration 4(2. M .Tas. P. Riddle. Wayne 115. M Jas. P. Riddle &lt;Rt Wav-o administration 1C.SM.M Gaertner &amp; Beckenhauer, Wayne administration 423.8C June 23 Warren E. Burre'le. Peru athletic fleld t#.11 T. O. Crawford. Peru athletic fleld 8 . *0 F. M. Ivers, Peru athletic fleld «8.00 Meek Lumber Co.. Peru athletic fleld 287. Tl T,. S. Wilson. Peru athletic field 8.M F. W. Rische * Son. Peru athletic fleld (44. M F. W. Rische * Son, Peru training, school 7,148 . 2^ Dan Morris, Board expense 11.44 J. R. Gettys, Board expense 14. •• A. L. Cavinesa, Board expense 44 . »1 T. J. Majors, Board expense M . 24 A. H. Viele, Board expense It. 71 Federal Steel Fixture Co., Wayne administration S40.M Fuchs, Son &amp; Blird Wayne admin'stration 1,082.75 F. H. Jones. Wayne administration 7541. M Korsmeyer Co., Wayne administration 1,171. M National Wood Works, Wayne administration S22.2S Nebraska School Supply Co., Wayne administration... 2,805.41 Thomas Rhinehart, Wayne administration 178.25 J. H. Craddock, Wayne administration (M.M Aug. 3 Lewis Adams. Peru athletic field M.M Warren E. Burrelle, Peru athletic fleld 85.84 </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Q. If. Cole. Peru abtletic Held 41.48 T. O. Crawford, l&gt;ru athletic field S2 . «0 Lloyd Hays, Peru athletic field 66 . 60 Joe A. Hug. Peru athletic field 29.80 Forth Kelso, Peru athletic field 32 . 00 C. W. Majors, Peru athletic field 30 . 00 F. P. Majors, Peru athletic field 60.00 Conrln Medley. Peru athletic field 34.40 Meek Lumber Co., Peru athletic field 501 . 54 F. W. Setzer. Peru athletic field 12. 00 Frank Tobler. Peru athletic field 59 . 60 Stacy Vance, Peru athletic field 56 . 60 Charles Vernon, Peru athletic field 11. SO L. S. Wilson, Peru athletic field 6. 00 W. E. Young, Peru athletic field 16 . 00 Crown Metal Construction Co., Wayne administration.. 760.0') Leonard Peterson. Wayne administration 827.00 Luther O. Draper Shade Co., Wayne administration 299.55 Gaertner &amp; Keckenhauer, Wayne administration 863.75 J. P. Riddle, (9) Wayne administration 500.00 J. H. Craddock. Peru training school 189 . 74 Elmer Dovel, Peru training school 1,422 . 05 F. W. Rische &amp; Son, (3) Peru training school 6,436.33 J. H. Craddock, Kearney auditorium 1,157.34 Claflin Printing Co., Board expense 12.90 Dan Morris. Board expense 11.58 A. L. Caviness. Secretary's salary 100.00 A. L. Caviness, Board expense 42.37 T. J. Majors, Hoard expense 43.32 A. H. Viele, Hoard expense 12.71 J. R. Gettys. Board expense 24.05 H. E. Reische, Board expense 30.88 &lt;&lt;■•!. IS W. F. CrosK'ey. (1) Kearney auditorium 21.425.9C W. C. Lantz, Kearney repairs 341.50 Kearney Daily Hub, Kearney auditorium 4.50 Kearney Times, Kearney auditorium 4.50 Bee Publishing Co. Kearney auditorium 19.30 World Publishing Co., Kearney auditorium 36.45 State Journal Co., Kearney auditorium 28.00 Kearney Democrat, Kearney auditorium 4 . 50 Star Publishing Co., Kearney auditorium 30.00 George Wadsworth, Wayne well 303.60 F. H. Turney &amp; Co.. Wayne weather strips 511.70 G. M. Cole. Peru athletic field 27 . 20 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">BIENNIAL REPORT 11 Miles Comestock. Peru athletic Held 3 20 Lloyd Hays. Peru athletic field lf.tO Joe A. Hug, Peru athletic field 2S.0O C. W. Majors, Peru athletic fleld M.H F. P. Majors. Peru athletic fleld M.M Meek Lumber Co., Peru athletic fleld 141.00 O. J. Milestead, Peru athletic fleld 14.00 Frank Tobler, Peru athletic field M.M F. E. Vance. Peru athletic fleld 12. M Lewis Wilson, Peru athletic fleld 2.M F. W. Rische &amp; Son. (4) Peru training school 12,585.58 Harry Porter, Board expense 1 . 50 A. L. Caviness, Board expense l'j.42 T. J. Majors. Board expense 17. M A. H. Viele, Board expense 11.20 G. K. Hall, Board expense 11 . 44 H. E. Reische, Board expense SO. 34 A. L. Caviness, Secretary's salary 1M.M Dec 13 J. H. Craddock, Kearney auditorium 115. 00 Chicago Bridge &amp; Iron Works, Wayne water 2,286.72 Chicago Bridge &amp; Iron Works, Wayne water 71S.2S E. C. Archibald. Wayne water system Ml. 54 J. H. Craddock, Peru training school 7S5 . 04 F. W. Rische &amp; Son. (5) Peru training school..., 13.271.24 F. P. Majors, Peru athletic fleld 22.00 N. J. Randall. Peru athletic fleld 20.00 Meek Lumber Co., Peru athletic fleld 102.(2 Warren E. Burrelle, Peru athletic fleld 54. »S Rome Hotel, Normal Headquarters N. S. T. T 10.00 A. L. Caviness, Secretary's salary 100.00 T. J. Majors, Board expense 34. M A. O. Thomas, Board expense I*. IT Dan Morris, Board expense 34.14 G. E. Hall, Board expense 2S.M A. L. Caviness, Board expense 32.04 1916 Feb. 14 H. A. Webbert, Board expense, printing y SO Willard F. Bailey &amp; Co., Board expense, printing 15.50 G. E. Hall, Board expense 17.74 A. O. Thomas, Board expense 12.72 H. E. Reische, Board expense 27 . 24 A. L. Caviness. Board expense 29. 17 T. J. Majors, Board expense 21 . 54 Dan Morris. Board expense It. 44 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION A. H. Vlele, Board expense S .64 J. 8. Elliott. Board expense 11. « R. D. Overholt, Board expense 19 .44 J. E. Hciut z. Peru training school 873 . 61 Elmer Dovel, Peru training school S.S70 . 25 W. F. Crossley. (2) Kearney auditorium 5,462 . 95 City of Kearney, paving 1,074.01 Chicago Bridge &amp; Iron Works, Wayne water 395.00 April 10 A. O. Thomas, Board expense 5.M A. H. Viele, Board expense 8. SO G. E. Hall. Board expense : . . . 10.48 H. E. Reische, Board expense 85.96 A. L* Cavinofcs, Secretary's salary 100 . 00 Dan Morris, Board expense ... 22 . 56 A. L. Cavtn&lt;&gt;8«. Board expense 24.87 T. J. Majors. Roard expense 6 . 4P F. W. Reische * Son. (6) Peru training school 8.698.4? Wn\ S. Ya'ie». Peru training school 10.00 I&lt;ouix l^ewis. Peru training school 14.00 June 21 H. E. Reische. Board expense 60.76 A. H. Veile. Hoard expense SS.68 Dan Morris, Board expense 11 .44 A. O. Thomas. Board expense 14.05 T. J.'MaJors, Board expense 45.52 A. L. Caviness. Board expense 16 . 85 A. L. Ca viness. Secretary's salary 100 . 00 Willard F. Bailey Co.. advertising bids 8.00 Kearney Democrat ndvertifing bids 10.50 World Publishing Co., advertising bids 28.00 Bee Publishing Co.. advertising bids 25 . 20 Ralph Myer. Chadron dormitory attic '. . 160.70 Ralph Myers, Chadron dormitory attic 446.05 Harry M. Plummer, Chadron dormitory attic 124.25 Geo. C. Snow, advertising bids 10.50 J. C. Stitt, Chadron east wing, architect 996.10 W. F. Crossley, (8) Kearney auditorium 8,882.50 W. F. Crossley ,(4) Kearney auditorium 8,569.50 .1. H. Craddock, Kearney gymnasium architect 1,000.00 R. J. Armstrong. Peru training school 16.00 Crane * Co, Peru training school 94. 8S Eugene Dietzen, Peru training school 111.04 Elmer Dovei. Peru training school 1,841 . 05 Uoyd Hayea, Peru training school conduit, etc 46.25 Korsmeyer Co., Peru training school conduit 414.lt </seg>
            <seg id="p013">BIENNIAL REPORT 13 Louis Lewis, Peru cisterns 15.50 P. C. Mason, Peru training; school conduit 82.04 Meek Lumber Co., Peru cisterns, etc 489.82 Meek Lumber Co., Peru training school 224.84 R. D. Overholt, Peru power house U4.U F. W. Reische &amp; Son. (7) Peru training- school 10,829. M Sunderland Machine &amp; Supply Co., Peru training: school 211.99 Elmer W. Wilson. Peru power house 46.25 J. H. Craddock, Wayne gymnasium architect 1,297.84 Aug. 8 G. E. Hall, Board expense U.§4 H. E. Reische, Board expense 81. »8 A. H. Veile, Board expense 11 . 82 A. O. Thomas, Board expense 27 . 80 Dan Morris, Board expense 11 . 40 T. J. Majors, Board expense g.9J A. L. Caviness, Board expense 17.14 Wayne Herald, advertising- bids 12.00 Dan Quintbn, Kearney curbing- (29.26 W. E. Burrelle, Peru training- school 181.40 State Engineering- Co., Peru training- school 685.07 Elmer Wilson, Peru training- school 111.40 Sunderland Machine &amp; Supply Co., Peru training school 86.76 R. D. Overholt, Peru cisterns 60. 25 Omaha School Supply Co., Peru training school 248 . 40 Murray Iron Works. Peru manual training 1.076. DO Meek Lumber Co., Peru cisterns, etc 68.19 P. C. Mason, Peru training school 82.50 Lloyd Hays, Peru cisterns 74.75 Crane Co., Peru cisterns 0 82.0* Oct. 9 Dan Morris, Board expense 88. 24 A. D. Veile, Board expense 20.00 A. O. Thomas, Board expense 26.88 G. E. Hall, Board expense 28. 88 T. J. Majors, Board expense 87.40 A. L. Caviness, Board expense 44 . 85 A. L. Caviness, Secretary's salary 104.00 State Journal Co., advertising bids M.OO American Woodworking Machine Co., Peru tr. sch 2C6.00 Atwood Vacuum Machine Co., Peru training school .... 515.41 D. Donovan &amp; Son, Peru training school 586. 82 Cornell -Searle Co., Peru training school 2,671.90 John Armstrong. Peru training school 44. 00 W. E. Burrelle, Peru training school |j.u B. R. Cole, Peru training school S4.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p014">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Giant Manufacturing Co., Peru training school 111.05 IJoyd Hays, Peru training school 83.50 J. E. Houtz, Peru training school conduit 320.44 Roy Knapp, Peru training school 10S.75 H. W. Lawrence, Peru training school, grading S.40 P. C. Mason, Peru training school 127.25 Meek Lumber Co.. Peru training school, walks 189.14 Nebraska Material Co., Peru training school 245.76 Nebr. School Supply House. Peru tr. sch.. furniture 725.85 Nebr. School Supply House, Peru tr. sch., furniture 2,081.56 Omaha School Supply Co., Peru tr. sch., furniture 679.35 R. D. Overholt, Peru training school 445 . 54 A. E. Rische, Peru training school 241.06 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, Peru training school 875.55 Sunderland Brothers, Peru training school 377.26 Elmer Wilson, Peru training school 84.75 Burgess-Granden Co., Peru training school 1,000.00 F. W. Rische &amp; Son, (8) Peru training school 11,805.00 J. H. Craddock. Peru training school architect 199.50 J. H. Craddock. Kearney gymnasium architect 389.10 Walter Knutzen, (1) Kearney gymnasium 22,050.51 C. J. Burke &amp; Son, Kearney gymnasium 936.00 C. J. Burke &amp; Son, Kearney auditorium 286 . 00 W. F. Crossley, Kearney repairs 2,038.91 J. H. Craddock, Wayne gymnasium architect 487.50 J. P. Riddle, (1) Wayne Gymnasium 23,221.18 C. J. Burke &amp; Son, Wayne gymnasium 650 . 25 E. J. Huntemer, Wayne gymnasium 134 . 10 Crane Co., Wayne gymnasium Ill . 28 J. C. Stitt, Chadron east wing architect 312. 1« Frank E. Mullholen. (1) Chadron east wing 16,725.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 15 CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL CHADRON, NEBRASKA ROBERT I. ELLIOTT. President Chadron, Nebraska, December 1, 1918. To the Honorable Board of Education of the State Normal Schools' Gentlemen: — I hereby submit a report of the condition of the Chadron State Normal School for the past biennium and some suggested improve - ments for the next biennium. AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION A place will be set apart on the campus for agricultural purposes — a bain built, live stock purchased and a man hired to look after gardening, the live stock, the campus and such odd Jobs as may come up from time to time. This agriculture work will be started as soon as possible next spring. In providing our own vegetables, milk, pork, etc., we will, in my opinion, more than pay the expenses of the extra man and the purchase of the live stock. We have a campus of eighty acres and there is ample room for such a demonstration farm. Such a farm has already been authorized by the Board. NEW BUILDINGS We are in need of some new buildings. When the present building; is completed, we must begin to plan for a modern gymnasium and an audi - torium that will be adequate for the needs of the school. With the comple - tion of the present building, we will have plenty of class room, but we have no place at present, except the Railroad T. M. C. A. gymnasium for physi - cal training work. I am very anxious that we have a gymnasium as soon as the funds will permit. The Y. M. C. A. is about a mile from the present Normal site. ATTENDANCE The attendance is gradually increasing and I look for a marked in - crease in the near future. Many of the high school graduates of the west - ern section of Nebraska are looking this way for general training, and the graded as well as the country schools in western Nebraska are looking to this school for teachers. We have had between fifteen and twenty calls for teachers from the best schools in western Nebraska, during the past </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION month. Thi« shows the need for our institution, and as soon as the young people fully realize the advantages of this school, and the opportunities offered to teachers, many more will come here to finish the teachers' courses. STUDY CENTER We are organizing study centers in our territory and the instructors are always ready to spend their Saturdays in carrying on this work where ten or more students get together to pursue one or more lines of study. I believe there is a great field in this extension work, and we are going to give a great deal of attention to this in the near future. FACULTY We have a splendid faculty both in the Normal school proper, and the training school. Most excellent work is being done. In order to carry on the work properly, we must add some courses which other normal schools now have. In order to do this, we will need more instructors for the next biennium. The work in expression and drawing is now conducted by two of the training school teachers, the physical training is under the direction of one of the English teachers. While these teachers are doing excellent work, yet we will need someone who can devote ail her time to these lines in order to get the best results. We have yet no art department in con - nection with the Normal School. This, it seems to me. is one of the neces - sary departments in a state normal school. There is a splendid feeling and excellent spirit among the students of the school as well as the faculty. We have organized an orchestra, which is conducted by one of the members of the faculty. Basket ball and foot bail teams are in training. It is our purpose to get the students of the school to take part in one or more of the various organlations of the Insti - tution. It is our final purpose to dev elope the young people who come here, so that they may be able to go out into the world and do the most for humanity. Respectfully submitted, ROBERT L ELLIOTT, President. CHADRON Financial Report for Biennium, Beginning December 1, 1914, and Ending December 1, 1916. SUMMARY OF MAINTENANCE FUND Salaries of president and office force for biennium I 8,836.66 Salaries of faculty members for biennium 51,092.06 Salaries of employees for the biennium 4,506.93 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 17 Total coBt of telegraph and telephone 216.01 Total cost of fuel for the biennlum J.442.SS Total cost of departmental supplies for biennlum 1,488.16 Balance December 1, 1914 117,107.98 Appropriation for biennium beginning April 1, 1915 85,000.0* Sep. 8 The Korsmeyer Co., lighting fixtures $ 1M.17 21 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., supplies 6S.15 Oct. 21 Underwood Typewriter Co., stencils 13.00 Benton Dales, texts «.00 26 Library Bureau, library supplies 33.00 Sheridan Coal Co., coal 9«.71 Ashburn &amp; Woodruff, dormitory supplies. ll.M Orchard &amp; Wilhelm Co., rugs 72.00 Nov. 12 Mandel Bros., supplies 4.10 Harry Porter, office supplies 28.48 Underwood Typewriter Co., mimeog. ink 8.00 Chadron Hardware Co., supplies 13.90 Chadron Telephone Co.. rent and tolls.... 20.15 13 Western Biological Co., supplies 9.25 Ralph Myers, labor 17.25 25 Rudge &amp; Guenel Co., dormitory furniture 531.99 Beeckley-Cardy Co., class records 15.00 Dec. 3 Sheridan Coal Co., coal 206.49 4 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. supplies 29.67 5 Central Scientific Co., chemicals 129.41 Mrs. Mary J. Bolin, laundering towels.... 5.60 Miller &amp; Paine, rugs and supplies 7126 J. H. White &amp; Co., supplies 9».«7 8 Chadron Furniture Co., furniture 184.85 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced, postage. express, etc 305.97 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 105.89 Joseph Sparks, payroll. December 2,632.13 1915 Jan. 23 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, furniture 389.48 Chadron Telephone Co., rent and tolls.... 16.65 Miller &amp; Paine, supplies 9.85 Joseph Sparks, January payroll 2,526.75 Feb. 4 Morrison Lumber Co., coal and supplies.. 81.20 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 34.34 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">IS STATK BOARD OF EDUCATION 10 Sheridan Coal Co.. coal 478.89 24 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriter and supplies HIM A. Flanagan Co., supplies g.44 Rudge &amp; Guonzel Co., window shades 79.60 Carl D. Town, painting floors 33.80 Joseph Sparks, February payroll 2,669.00 Mar. 2 Sheridan Coal Co., coal 345.08 W. G. Fritcher, drayage 81.50 Eberbach &amp; Son Co., supplies 146.24 I EL O. Cronk, commencement music 12.00 George Erb. labor 174.00 Schwelger Lumber Co., lumber 76.67 4 Erwin Hopt, supplies 14.45 5 Chadron Hardware Co., supplies 8.95 Nebr. School Supply House, chairs 496.20 12 Chadron Furniture Co., dorm, furniture... 45.50 19 Industrial Education Co., dom. Sci. equip. 60.57 20 E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co., benches and tools... 82.50 Nebraska School Supply House, supplies... 33.38 29 Carpenter Papar Co., toilet paper 5.00 29 Standard Oil Co., gas machine gas 12.69 31 Mary J. Uolin. laundering towels 5.20 Joseph Sparks, March payroll 2,632.13 April 1 Harry Plummer. labor and material 1S6.6S W. G. Fritcher, drayapro 40.4s J. H. White &amp; Co., supplies 24.17 Carl D. Town, labor and material 24.50 Morison Lumber Co. lumber and coal 161.40 C. J. Walters, labor 5g 50 2 Harry Porter, supplies « 79 IntermVn. Ry. Lt. &amp; Pr. Co. cur. and sup. 158.75 F. A. Hood, rent Y. M. C. A S15.00 10 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 442 32 Ralph Myers, labor and material is.50 19 Sheridan Coal Co., coal 444 77 Joseph Sparks, April payroll 2,560.50 May 13 Bausch &amp; lamb. Optical Co., condenser.. 6.56 Everbach &amp; Son, thermometer 2.25 The Korsmeyer Co., mazda lamps 4.95 I The T'nderwood Typewriter Co 6.00 26 Remington Typewriter Co., machines 300.00 24 E. H. She'don &amp; Co., science tables, stoves 156.00 15 Miller * Paine, table linen, clocks 99.53 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 19 Joseph Sparks, May payroll 2,541.76 Wlllard F. Bailey Co., bulletins, envelopes 86.65 Sheridan Coal Co.. coal 85.05 Central Scientific Co., chemicals 17.92 The A. H. Andrews Co., chairs S21.90 Chadron Furniture Co.. furn. dormitory- -■ 2J4.40 George C. Snow, programs I J.75 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 390.82 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, dorm, furnishings 8J1.79 H. E. Grubbs. cement work 27.76 Griswold Seed Co., seeds 4.J5 18 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., diplomas and cert. 100.75 F. Fahnestock, water rent 150.00 SO A. Flanagan, primary supplies 27. 33 Industrial Education Co., dom. science.... 21.81 Joseph Sparks, June payroll 2,944.50 July 1 Carl D. Town, paint and labor 13.50 2 Harry Porter, office supplies 26.68 6 l.ilireau Hureiiu. desk 195.00 24 Underwood Typewriter Co., stencil 2.40 27 W. G. Fritcher. draying 82.62 Carpenter Paper Co., toilet paper 8.00 Morison Lumber Co., screens 624.S5 28 Harry I'lummer, plumbing 203.08 29 .1. H. White &amp; Co.. dormitory supplies 58.48 W. H. Reynolds, rent kindergarten room.. 60.00 R. McNair, dorm, furnishings 32.40 31 lntermtn. Lt. &amp; Power Co., current 84.53 Mary .1. Holin. laundering towels 5.60 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 74.20 Joseph Sparks. July payroll 2,917.50 Joseph Sparks, August payroll 459.25 Joseph Sparks, September payroll 2,705.25 Oct. 25 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 370.51 The Kearney Daily Hub, cards 20.00 G. O. Clark, work on grounds 16.25 Standard Oil Co., gas 1 2.93 Chadron Hardware Co., supplies 53.95 Keuffel &amp; Esser Co., tapes, rods and paper 18.01 Red Cross Drug Store, victrola and records 73.50 Remington Typewriter Co., ribbons 5.12 Standard OU Co., floor dress 10.80 Willard F. Bailey Co.. envelopes, bulletins 131.54 Robert Hood, rye 4.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">= 0 STATE UOARD OF EDUCATION L. E. Sprague, plumbing 23.85 W. W. Pascoe, hardware 2.85 Randall F. Blanchard, sand 6.00 M. E. Smith ft Co.. domestic science 25.53 H. E. Grubbs, excavating 115.46 W. G. Fritcher, draying 49.75 Joseph Sparks, October payroll 2,761.75 Joseph Sparks, November payroll 2,912.63 Dae. 18 Miller &amp; Paine, supplies 6.10 Standard Oil Co 29.30 S. C. Johnson &amp; Sons, dye 27.60 Industrial Education Co., domestic science 10.00 The Garlock Packing Co., hose and pack's 14.99 Central Scientific Co., science supplies 168.97 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 20.69 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., vac. cleaner, brooms 110.39 The Chadron Journal 6.50 The Prang Co., primary supplies 2.11 W. T. Stockdale, cash advanced 43.83 Dalton Adding Machine Co., repairs 3.37 Dennison Mfg. Co., rope, wire, glue 4.50 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 192.79 Mrs. M. J. Bolin, laundry 6.00 The McGraw Co., desk light, mazda lamps 39.01 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., floor dressing 97.65 Underwood Typewriter Co., stencil, brush 19.00 Harry Torter, office supplies 33.20 Morison Lumber Co., lumber and coal.... 151.30 Ralph Myers, material and labor '. . 96.30 W. G. Fritcher, draying 57.50 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., cheese cloth, curtains.. 9.64 Wm. Chaulk. labor 83.75 Intenntn. Ry., Lt. &amp; Power Co., current.. 95.70 December payroll 2,989.13 191« Janary, 1916, payroll 3,192.63 Feb. 18 Chas. Wilder Co., thermometer 1.00 Y. M. C. A. membership cards 220.00 Library Bureau, newspaper flies 6.32 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co 1,087.59 Whitcomb &amp; Barrows, dom. set. ch'ts, bks. 5.65 C. J. Walters, labor primary room 28.50 The Univ. Pub. Co., books 28.20 Carl D. Town, paint and labor 30.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p021">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL ■ State Journal Co., records 23.75 Remington Typewriter Co 50.00 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 180.08 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros 176.64 M. E. Smith &amp; Co., dom. scl .93 J. W. Skeen, rent Y. M. C. A. 30.00 Schweiger Lumber Co., paper and pins 8.45 Harry Porter, flies 7.55 Amy L. Paine, cash advanced 15.(0 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm, domestic science.... 2.S0 A. J. Ny strom &amp; Co., map 6.70 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Nebraska School Supply House 5.25 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, office and supplies 130.07 Ralph Myers, coal house 104.75 Miller &amp; Paine, clocks 27.00 W. H. Meeker, blue prints 3.00 R. McNair. lawn hydrant 160 The McGraw Co., light supplies 66.71 Ira Longcor, dormitory repairs 1.50 Library Bureau, domestic science 24.70 The Korsmeyer Co., fuses 8.48 Kalamazoo Vegetable Co., dom. scienc... 1.72 J. L. Irwin, correcting papers 13.00 Intermtn. Ry. &amp; Power Co 87.24 Industrial Education Co., domestic science 2. 66 The Home Candy Makers, dom. science... 2.50 W. G. Frttcher, draying 10S.40 The Educational Bureau, song books 104.00 Eugene Dietzgen. mech. draw 42.27 Ethel Delzell, mod. school 7.09 Flora Daboll, teacher rural school 52.00 Chadron Telephone Co., rental 60.37 Chadron Telephone Co., rental and tolls... 19.98 Chadron Garage Co., drives to Normal 2.00 The Chadron Chronicle, cards 10.00 Central Scientific Co.. chemicals 129.81 Carpenter Paper Co., cabinets and towels.. 11.50 Boston Cooking School Mag. Co., dom. act. 8.10 February payroll 3,151.51 March payroll 8,209.88 April 21 A. Flanagan Co., books and supplies 44.60 Intermtn. Ry., Lt. &amp; Power Co., current... 73.44 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 270.98 </seg>
            <seg id="p022">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION The H. W. Wilson Co.. truck 20.00 Whitebreaat Coal Co., coal 525.72 The Nebraska Teacher, adv 10.00 Romegrn H. Rivenburg, geom. tablets 9.00 J. C. Neff, piano tuning J.00 Nebr. Sch. Sup. House, paper and punch . . 20.00 Ralph Myers, work and repairs 41.72 Morison Lumber Co., lumber 54.60 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books 2.94 Kearney Dally Hub, grade and cr. sheets 12.50 Industrial Education Co., dom. science... 1S.77 Erwln Hopt, grain samples 21.50 Garden City Ed. Co |.i j W. G. Fritcher. draying 88.67 Durand Steel Locker Co., lockers 744.39 Eugent Dletsgen Co., draw, lnatr 10.(6 The Chadron Journal, cards 6.26 Ethel Delzell, milk dom. science 5.50 Bausch &amp; Lomb Opt. Co., baloptlcon 5S.95 Adv. Pump, and Compr. Co., valve springs 9.68 Thomas Charles, supplies 29.21 Orr A Lockett, manual training 86.18 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding 129.50 Central Scientific Co., chemicals 56.14 April. 1916. payroll 3,192.01 May. 1S16, payroll 3.190.88 June 28 Chadron Furniture Co., typewriter chairs, repairs JO.35 Andrews &amp; McNees, fumigation materials 19.60 Bee Publishing Co., subscription 4.00 B. B. Brooks, plumbing 59.20 Chadron Chronicle, announcements, notice for bids 45.00 Bausch &amp; Lomb Opt. Co., balop attachm't 31.50 Churchill Grinnelle Co., song books 8.14 Chadron Hardware Co., supplies 47.62 Thomas Charles Co 35.82 I&gt;emocrat Printing Co., cards, ink 3.05 Garden City Educa. Co., mod. school 11.61 Esterbrook Steel Pen Mfg. Co., pens 2.40 W. S. Gillam. furniture 177.95 The F. Hodgman Co., surveying book 2.50 George Brothers, letter heads 49.85 Library Bureau, shelving 125.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., paper 11.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p023">CHADRON 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL 23 Industrial Education Co 19 49 Paul Monroe, stereopticon slides 27.60 KaJamazoo Vegetable Parchment Co., do - mestic science J.15 Nebraska Teacher, adv 5.00 Orr &amp; Lockett Hdw. Co., manual training; 12.2S W. W. Pascoe, repair roof gutters 7.60 The Prang Co., mod. school J.96 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., supplies dormitory 89.50 M. E. Smith Co 7.17 K. H. Sheldon &amp; Co.. man. train, benches.. 79.05 Nebraska School Supply House, paper.... 26.00 Standard Oil Co., gas 17.8J W. T. Stockdale, rural training 124.(1 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 207.14 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co.. floor paint 24.75 Nebraska Teacher, adv 5.00 J. A. Munkres. domestic science 86. 15 The H. W. Wilson Co.. library ma* M.OO J. H. White &amp; Co., hardware 112 (5 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., botany slides 7.S0 Wa'dorf Bindery Co., binding books l.K Underwood Typewriter Co., ink 12.00 Intermtn. Ry., I.t. &amp; Power Co., light 7».M George C Snow, bulletins .cuts, paper 189.15 Morison Lumber Co, lumber and coal.... 574.30 A. C. McClurg tt Co., domestic science 14.52 Central Scientific Co., science 52.99 J. L. Hammett Co., mod. school 9.20 June payroll 1,092. IS July payroll 3.256.50 Aug. 10 W. G. Fritcher, freight, drayage 22.11 Johnson-Beghtol Co., towels 19.94 The Nebraska Teacher, adv 5.00 International Harvester Co., slides 15.00 Durand Steel Locker Co., freight 21.28 Central Scientific Co., chemicals 17.80 John Sorenson, labor on ground 5.50 Harry Porter, ledger, indea, ink 27.86 Chadron Telephone, service 27.14 City of Chadron, water 110.96 Morison Lumber Co., coal and lumber.... 116.96 H. F. Maika, wood alcohol, shellac 4.16 J. H. White &amp; Co., supplies (.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 STATE HOARD OF EDUCATION The Chadron Journal, bulletins, envelopes 23995 J. A. Munkres. domestic science 32.65 Underwood Typewriter Co., stencils 16.20 George Loewenthal, Janitor 13.50 Paul Sparks, janitor 21.00 Carl D. Town, supplies ] .20 George Erway, labor 1.50 G. D. Clark, labor 5.00 Intermtn. Ry., Lt. A Power Co., current... 87.29 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 81.60 Orr &amp; Lockett Co, manual training 43.96 Chadron Furniture Co., furniture 90.50 Remington Typewriter Co., machine 50.00 J. A. Munkres, labor 10.50 A. A. Andrews Co., desk, bookcase 26.00 Chadron Furniture Co., furniture 17.25 Chadron Hardware Co., tanks 13.90 Thomas Charles Co., mod. school 14.0" Randall Bros., supplies 5.35 R. C. King (expense voucher J. Sparks).. 134.19 August. 1916. payroll 697.62 September, 1916, payroll 3,297.83 Oct 19 R. I. Elliott, cash advanced 141.52 Chadron Telephone Co., service 9.28 Harry Porter, ledger 3.60 George Brothers, letter heads 66.10 Intermtn. Ry.. Lt. * Power Co., current... 29.60 Morison Lumber Co.. lumber 188.35 Hammond &amp; Stephens, diplomas 12.00 Randall Brothers, supplies 7.28 Chadton Hdw. Co , hardware 64.28 Ralph Myers, labor 230.50 Bausch &amp; Lomb Opt. Co.. balopticon reprs. .70 Clara Wilson, kindergarten 1.88 W. H. Reynolds, kindergarten 60|00 J. H. White &amp; Co.. supplies 13.78 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm. office supplies 4.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 180.01 Red Cross Drug Store, varnish 9.58 M. E. Smith &amp; Co.. domestic science 9 50 J. H. Beck, map 2.95 Harry M. Plummer, plumbing 267.95 Standard Oil Co., floor dressing 16.34 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furn. and supplies.. 42.28 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 25 Central Scientific Co., chemicals 340.35 W. a. Fritcher, drayage and freight 17.84 J. I. Holcomb Mfg. Co., supplies 24.10 J. A. Munkren, domestic science CIS Kearney Daily Hub 87.50 October. 1916, payroll 3.376.33 November. 1916, payroll 1.524.56 3 89.132.69 Balance in fnd December 1, 191C 12.J75.29 »102.107.»8 $102,107.98 INSTITUTION CASH Balance in fund December 1, 1914 I 6J.1I 1914 Dec. 10 Sent state treasurer 400.00 School Arts Pub. Co.. M. S. material f 1.50 NelMe S Trufant. M. S. material 2.00 Atkinson. Mentzer fr Co., H. 8. material.. 2.36 G. Schirmer. music 18.71 Goodyear- Mm rshall Pub. Co.. supplies 20.53 Theo. Presser Co., texts 8.37 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. material 2.(3 American Book Co. .texts 62.J0 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., texts 36.61 Chas. E. Merrill Co., texts 5.76 Ginn and Co., texts 93,90 Henry Holt &amp; Co., texts 2.00 D. Appleton * Co., texts 4.61 Benj. H. Sanborn Co., texts 4.00 Chas. Scribner's Sons, texts 19.59 Houghton MifTlin. texts 1«.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, texts 48.00 Macmil'an Co.. texts 51 34 G. Schirmer Co., music 20.00 Goodyear- Marshall Pub. Co., supplies 2.30 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co., supplies 1.09 1*1 April 12 Sent state treasurer 250.00 Macmillan Co.. books lt.00 Ginn &amp; Co.. books 6.50 Silver. Burden &amp; Co.. books 2.28 Allyn A Bacon, books 14.40 D Appleton ft Co., books 4.25 University Publishing Co &gt;.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">26 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION The A. H. Pa'.mer Co., books (.(5 Isaac Pitman &amp; Sons, books 17.25 Thomas Charles Co.. M. 8. supplies 5.78 Garden City Educational Co., supplies 12.24 A, Flanagan Co., supplies 17.02 G. Schlrmer Co.. music 27 09 Alyse M. Swedberg, music collections 100.00 Goodyear-Marshal) Pub. Co., supplies 6.61 G. A. Craneer Co., music 15.17 School Arts Pub. Co., supplies 2.50 June 21 The Century Co., books 21.60 Garden City Education Co., M. S. supplies 4.25 Tho8. Charles, M. S. supplies J4.62 The Century Co., books 9.60 Macmillan Co.. books J5.»4 Allyn A Bacon, books 11.20 Henry Holt, books 11.00 Goodyear- Marshall, cards, paper 11.86 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., books 50.00 University Pub. Co 24.63 Ginn &amp; Co., books 7.82 American Book Co.. books 51.60 BenJ. Sanborn &amp; Co., books ».74 Industrial Education Co., books 24.00 Webb Pub. Co., books 25.01 Isaac Pitman &amp; Sons, books 6.81 Orange Judd &amp; Co., books 7.88 Lemcke &amp; Buechner, books 21.57 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 15.27 Chas. Scribner's Sons, books 24.00 July 24 Nebraska School Supply House, maps 12.89 Oct. 21 G. 3chirmer Co., music 22 00 June 10 A. C. McClurg * Co., bioks 1S6.61 Augr. 5 Sent state treasurer 450.00 MfcM Nov. 11 Sent state treasurer Sent Htate treasurer Credit by % George Mileage bock. 1.35 Dec. 20 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. books 26.16 G. Putnam's Sons, books 4 86 Whitcomb &amp; Barrows 1.00 Goodyear -Marshall Pub. Co., books 28.80 Henry Holt &amp; Co., books 1.68 Garden City Education Co., books 5.20 Carpenter Paper Co., paper and pads 10.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">CHADRON 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL 27 Macmillan Co., books ll».2O Scott. Foreman ft Co.. books 19.44 Qinn A Co., hooks 134.14 Isaac Pitman ft Sons, books 11.21 Amer. School of Home Econ., books 1.80 Esterbrook Steel Pe nMfg. Co.. pens 8.75 Irving O. Banghart Co.. record books 2.87 American Book Co 10.(8 Houghton, Mlffln Co., books 12.24 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 111.00 Silver, Burden &amp; Co., books 24.24 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., supplies 22.94 A. Flanagan Co , supplies 75.03 Democrat Printing Co., library furniture.. S.40 Dec. 1 0 Sent state treasurer 1916 Feb. 12 Sent state treasurer 18 Chas. Scribner's Sons, books 7.68 Isaac Pitman * Sons, books 9.12 The Macmil'.an Co., books 5.84 A. C. McClurg * Co., cards 12.56 Hough ton MifTlin Co., books 1.S4 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., books 5.77 Ginn &amp; Co.. books I2.M Garden City Educational Co., books 1.S5 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., books 1.50 D. Appleton ft Co., books 26.20 American Book Co 1J.44 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 8.00 April 1 Sent state treasurer 12 The Public School Pub. Co., books l.M Isaac Pitman &amp; Sons, books • 11.21 The Macmillan Co.. books 4.S4 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 1.50 McGraw-Hill Book Co., drawing and surv. 8.91 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co., blanks, books 1S.68 Ginn &amp; Co.. books 26.32 Allyn &amp; Bacon, books 21.60 26 Alyse Swedberg, music instruction 200.00 May 27 Sent state treasurer June 28 The Macmillan Co.. texts 30.00 Isaac Pitman &amp; Sons, texts 2C.78 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. texts 6.41 The Macmillan Co.. texts 21.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">28 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Henry Holt A Co 5.88 Silver, Burdett &amp; Co., texts 1.84 The Century Co., texts 21.82 Henry Holt &amp; Co., texts 3.98 Alyse Swedberg 161.75 June 7 Sent state treasurer 201.2S S69.25 July 8 Sent state treasurer Balance Dormitory room rent 1,871.29 Aug. I Sent 8tate treasurer 4S5.56 10 Industrial Education Co., supplies 1.80 D. Appleton &amp; Co.. texts 43.07 American Book Co., texts 35.80 D. Appleton &amp; Co., texts 18.75 The University Pub. Co., texts 11.52 The Maemillan Co. .texts 6.56 Silver, Burdett &amp; Co 1.14 G. Schirmer Co 111.48 Auk. II Sent state treasurer 5.15 Oct. 4 Sent state treasurer 414.08 19 Carl D. Town, varnish 25.00 American Radiator Co., supplies 11.99 Alyse Swedbers, music collections 42.67 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. texts 63.36 Goodyear-Marshall Co., texts 39.63 March Bros., M. S. supplies 4.16 The Manual Arts Press, manual training, . 2.94 Allyn &amp; Bacon, texts 30.96 Bobbs-Merrill Co., book 1.00 Dr. M. B. McDowell, medical services 63.00 H. E. McCrosky, service 12.40 The Underwood Typewriter Co., machine. 50.00 Columbia Carbon and Ribbon Co 15.00 Chadron Furniture Co 30.70 A. Flanagan Co., M. S. supplies 40.01 Nebr. School Supply House, books, etc. 47.08 Nov. 5 Sent state treasurer 250.70 Balance in fund December 1, 1916 2,770.31 $ 6.IS8.68 I 6.338.68 LIBRARY ISalance in fund December 1, 1914 J, 648.03 Dec. S A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. books $ 30.90 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">J» CHADRON STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 1915 Jan. 23 Miller &amp; Paine, subscriptiins 127.40 Feb. 13 Sent to state treasurer 24 A. C. McClurg, books 12.7» Henry Holt &amp; Co., books J.22 Mar. 9 The H. W. Wilson Co., renewals 17.00 April 10 Joseph Sparks, cash advanced 25.56 May IS The H. R. Hunting Co., books 35.00 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co 12.60 July 2 Sent to state treasurer Oct. 23 Carrie Munkres, books 5.85 Nov. 11 Sent t^&gt; state treasurer IS Dec. 10 Sent to state treasurer 1916 Feb. 12 Sent to state treasurer IS The Gordon Journal, subscription 5.00 Gordon, the Magazine Man, magazines... 119.15 Nebraska State Journal 3.50 April 6 Sent state treasurer 13 World Publishing Co 4.00 May 27 Sent state treasurer July 8 Sent state treasurer Aug. 3 Sent state treasurer 11 Lucy Clark, books 12.00 A. N. Marquis, books 5.00 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co., books 7.00 A. L. A. Pub. Board, booklist 1.00 Oct. 4 Sent to state treasurer 20 A. C. McClurg: &amp; Co 458.85 The H. R. Hunting Co., books 21.00 The John Hopkins Press, subscription.... 1.00 Middle West School Review, subscription 2.00 Nov. 4 Sent state treasurer Balance in fund December 1, 1916 1.848.02 C I TKT KS </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL KEARNEY, NEBRASKA GEORGE S. DICK, President Kearney, Nebraska, December 1, 1916. To the State Board of Education: My dear Sirs: — I beg to submit herewith a report of the condition of hte finances, the progress, and the needs of the State Normal School at Kearney, for the biennium beginning December 1, 1914, and ending De - cember 1. 1916. Very respectfully. GEORGE S. DICK. President. Kearney. Nebraska, December 1. 19L6. I hereby certify that the attached report, covering the finances of the State Normal School at Kearney from December 1, 1914, to December 1, 1S16. is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief. GEORGE S. DICK, President. Subscribed in my presence and sworn to before me this 23rd day of December, 1916. J. S. ELLIOTT, (SEAL) Notary Public. DEVELOPMENT OF THE SCHOOL In planning for the growth and development of this institution, our report will take into consideration the following: I. The needs of a fully equipped State Normal School at Kearney, II. Kearney's present condition — the part of this equipment already here. III. Material equipment necessary to complete the plant. THE NEEDS OF A FULLY EQUIPPED TEACHERS' SCHOOL If a teachers' school is to successfully serve the people, its equipment must be good in these five lines: (1) Faculty. (2) Libraries and Labora - tories. (S) Buildings and Furniture. (4) Campus, Playgrounds, Garden and Farm. (5) Ways and Means of carrying the service to the people — to teachers not enrolled in the institution. FACULTY. Men and women, to carry on this important work and to be responsible for the success of the institution and its service, must be carefully selected for their education, training, and success. They must bo </seg>
            <seg id="p031">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 31 inspiring, sympathetic, and of the highest type of alround Christian char - acter: they must be persons of exemplary habits whose real devotion to service causes them to live effective lives in their spirit of successful co - operation with the other factors that go to make a real teachers' school; they must have in every sense the qualifications and the true spirit of real teachers. LIBRARIES AND LABORATORIES. This faculty muit have the necessary tools that will enable them to do the very best teaching accord - ing to the latest approved educational theory and practice. These tools may be known as Libraries, Laboratories, Equipment and Supplies for both indoor and outdoor work. BUILDINGS AND Fl'RNITURE. These teachers, with their libraries and laboratories, must be housed in substantial, spacious, attractive, suit - ably furnished buildings, with abundance of the right kind of light, heat, and ventilation. LOCATION AND ARRANGEMENT. These buildings should be care - fully located on wisely chosen, artistically arranged, and well kept campus, playgrounds, gardens and fields. The supply of teachers, library, labor - atory, buildings and grounds must be such by selection, classification, ar - rangement, as to meet every need of a student in his education and train - ing. It must be remembered that he is going out to undertake the physical, mental, moral, and spiritual education and training of tomorrow's citizen - s-hip, as he takes charge of the boys and girls of today. EXTENSION WORK AND FOLLOW-UP SERVICE. There must be ways and means of connecting up with people in charge and with others interested in the public schools of the state. With the teachers at work, school officers, patrons and their children, there must be constant and live contact, not only that these may be helped, but also that the teachers' school may be ever alive to real conditions and always alert for improve - ments in matters of teacher training. This phase of service is generally known as "extension work," as It is the way in which the institution and its equipment ii effectively carried out to the people. Among the various ways in which this Rervice is rendered, the following are the most common: (a) Real academic work and entertainment for those unable to enroll in the school. &lt;t&gt;) A study of the organization, management and teaching of the public school for teachers and school officers, (c) Inspirational work — that which follows up all these good things with constant care and helpfulness for those who have graduated from the school as well as for the assistance of the large )&gt;er cent who have not had this valuable train - ing. This «ervice is Justly due every graduate or student who goes out from a Normal School to teach. KEARNEY'S PRESENT CONDITION 1. Three central buildings. There are three central buildings well planned, all under one roof, which is esi&gt;ecially good for the protection. </seg>
            <seg id="p032">32 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION convenience and economy of time to students and helpful in the general management of the school. In these buildings there are offices, halls, reci - tation rooms, laboratories, and an excellent library well planned, finely lighted, and containing nearly 14,000 up to date, carefully selected books well adapted to a teachers' school. The library is in charge of specially trained, very capable and highly appreciated librarians. There is also a well organized training school consisting of kindergarten, primary, grades, and junior high school, furnishing a general laboratory for the application of principles underlying the most modern ideas of school organization, management, teaching and training. In this training school the seniors get their valuable practice. It is now located in crowded quarters and needs better accommodations. 2. Rural demonstration schools. To meet the demand for the training of rural teachers, there are associated with this institution, three demon - stration schools. One, a ten -grade, one-room, two-teacher school six miles east of Kearney. Another an eight-grade, one-room, one-teacher school four miles north. A third now in process of erection, an eight-grade, two - room, one-teacher school three miles west of Kearney. S. Direct work of the Faculty. The various departments are man - aged and taught by well prepared highly successful teachers presenting the most modern courses of study in each particular line according to the latest and best principles of education. 4. The Dormitory. There is one dormitory accommodating about eighty young women. This is presided over by a very capable woman well suited to have charge of a good home for young women. 5. Boarding department. The boarding department accommodates about 260 students in the regular year, and last summer term furnished from 1000 to 1200 meals daily. Excellent board is being served here at $2.75 a week, or 20 cents a meal. The dining room is crowded and boarding facilities should be increased. C. Central heating plant. There is one central heating plant doing good work keeping all rooms, with very little exception, in good condition, even in the coldest weather. Without additional boiler supply it will take care of the auditorium when attached, but this is thought to be the limit of the present capacity . 7. The Auditorium in process of erection. The new auditorium now nearing completion will furnish the school a much needed convenience for general assembly in the various activities of the school — chapel purposes, lectures and entertainments. The third floor of this building, will furnish a home for the Music department (public school, piano, voice, violin) there - by releasing a large room to be used by the English department. The old chapel room will be remodeled and equipped as a home for the Commer - cial department. </seg>
            <seg id="p033">KKAHNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 33 v New Cvmnaaium in process of erection. The completion and equip - ment of the gymnasium now in process of erection will (111 a long tilt want. An effective physical education department will be organized, in charge of specialists in this line. This will furnish also a center for the social life of the school— a place very much needed at the present time. There is some playground equipment on the campus, an enclosed athletic park just west of the main building, and west of that a few acres used by classes in agriculture. MATERIAL EQUIPMENT NECESSARY TO COMPLETE THE PLANT The following material equipment Is necessary to complete the plant if it renders to the people the service for which it was foundd: 1. A Training School Building. The characteristic feature of any teachers' school is a well planned, thoroughly equipped, spaciously housed training school. In this we are sadly lacking; hence, one of the first and must imperative needs is — (a) a suitable building to house this depart - ment in keeping with the needs of the school; (b) a well planned and com - plete model rural school building on the campus, that it may be of conven - ient ; ccess fur demonstration and observation in rural teacher-training work. 2. A Farm. A Nebraska law requires that the Normal Schools train rural teachers. In order to do this according to the most approved theory and practice, a suitable tract of land, properly equipped as a small farm, is necessary. S. Greenhouse. The greenhouse allowed last year was not built, aa it was thought best that buildings now in process of erection should be pushed to completion before others were started. It is needed. 4. Industrial Arts Building. The departments of industrial arts are crowing, but are handicapped by the small housing and meager equipment. The trend of the times is indicative of the need of a special building to ac - commodate these departments and the growth that such improved housing and equipment would immediately encourage. 5. Library Building. Today in nearly every line of school work much attention is given to the cultivation of the habit of good reading. Of the nearly 14,000 volumes of books and the fine collection of pictures, faculty and students make excellent use. The present llbiary room is crowded, both as to place for books and for the accommodation of students. A library building will soon be a necessity. 6. More Dormitories. The desirability of dormitory life for young students and the growing demand from our patrons leads us to commend the erection of two more dormitories, one for the use of young women and one for the use of young men. 7. Central Heating Plant. This plant must be enlarged next yew by the addition of one more boiler and the change of coal bins, in order to meet the increased demand for heating of the new gymnasium. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">34 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION ENROLLMENT Regular Year Collegiate Secondary Total 1814-15 282 240 522 15 Summer Term 48« 401 887 Total for year and summer term, count- ing each student but once 723 533 1.258 1»16-1« 288 288 554 ■1« Summer Term 550 401 951 Total for year and summer term, count ing each student but once 711 (22 1.333 1»1«-17 To December 18, 19H »13 180 4*1 1914-15 Correspondence I Study Center, (Credit and non-credit work) 140 1915-16 Correspondence 8 Study Center 778 1918-17 Correspondence 20 (To 12-18-18) Study Center 976 Enrolling for Music only: 1»14-15 Regular year • 15 Summer Term 21 U15-1S Regular year 34 1»16-17 To date 15 16 Summer Term 42 Number of faculty members 38 Employees Regular 7 Students IS 25 CERTIFICATES AND DIPLOMA8 1914-15 Elementary 40 First Grade State 115 Degree, Bachelor of Education t 1915-16 Elementary '. 58 First Grade State 124 Degree t Expenditure! for the Biennium, 1914-16, SUMMARY OF MAINTENANCE FUND Expenditures from last appropriation, as per item- statement herein % 27,230.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p035">KEARNEY 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL 35 Expenditures from present appropriation, aa per itemized statement herein 125.9S4.M $158,1«5.1« Salaries of president and office force $ 15,211.40 Other services, as speakers, etc 611.01 Record books and printing 0 1.895.95 Telegraph and Telephone 421.52 Postage 570. J8 President's traveling expenses 459.09 Office supplies, expenses, etc 1,202.16 Express, freight and drayage 819.78 Salaries of faculty members §7,222.0! Departmental supplies 3,196.29 Extension work 797.87 Furniture and equipment 2,248.24 Salaries of employees 16.361.95 Fuel 8,521.03 Light 1,272.90 Water 292.72 General supplies 1,0(4.08 Depreciation repairs » 522.55 Grounds 451.21 $151,«5.1« SUMMARY OF INSTITUTION CA8H FUND Textbooks, as itemized herein $ 2.914. »7 Dormitory Water 252.il Light «27.00 Fuel (gas only) 122.88 Furniture, etc S54.05 Repairs til. 58 Laboratory — Domestic Science 193.86 Manual Training 136.11 Physical Sciences 7*1.24 Biology 109.47 Agriculture 136.59 Typewriters, etc (07.41 Music (piano, etc.) 1,773.90 » s.iir»» </seg>
            <seg id="p036">36 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION SUMMARY OF LIBRARY FUND Books and periodicals, as itemized herein t 4,043.80 Furniture and equipment, as Itemized herein 583.50 Supplies, as itemized herein 568.9* Printing:, as itemized herein 27.60 $ 6.22S.8S FINANCIAL STATEMENT, Maintenance: Amount in fund December 1. 1914 t 19.H6.1S 1914 Dec. 11 Additional appropriation 10,000.00 % 29,1«5.18 Disbursements: 1914 Dec. 15 Hibberd Brick Co., repairs $ 7*.41 R. C. King, express, etc 9S.S6 W. F. Crossley, repairs 10.55 Geo. S. Dick, trav. eip 64.65 Anna E. Caldwell, Y. W. C. A 18.60 Heasly Grocery Co., supplies . ., 33.91 Whitebreast Coal Co., fuel 1,095.40 17 H. A. Small, supplies 30.00 R. C. King, pay roll 5,177.70 1915 Jan. 28 R. C. King-, pay roll 4,901.40 Feb. 26 R. C. King, pay roll 5,182.80 Mar. 30 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 165.00 Robert I. Elliott, salary 160.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 155.00 A. J. Mercer .salary 155.00 H. O. Sutton, salary 166.00 O. W. Neale, salary 155.00 R. F. Richardson, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 R. C. King, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 145.00 Alma Hosic, salary 145.00 Etta. Brown, salary 145.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 140.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 140.00 C. E. Benson, salary 140.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p037">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 37 Sarah Brindley. salary 1S7.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 137.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 126.00 Mary Crawford, salary 120.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 120.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 120.00 Lula E. Wirt, salary 1 15.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 115.00 Chas. H. Wellers, salary 115.00 Marlon Wellers. salary 110.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 100. 00 Blanche E. Riggs. salary 100.00 Kthol M. l-anpdon. salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 1*0.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary M.M J. A. Stryker, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzsn, salary (5.00 Harriet Sutton, salary 65.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 65.00 Vera W. Kayser, salary 60.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 W. C. Pierce, salary 60.00 W. H. Thomas, salary 43. 3S Carl Melin. salary 30.00 Robert Shaw, salary 30.00 Fred Schmeeckle. salary 30.00 Waid Balcom. salary 21.00 Charles Reed, salary 21.20 Roy Young, salary 21.20 Leslie Rich, salary 20.80 Ralph Lewis, salary 20.80 B. F. Walker, salary 21.g0 Clyde Knott, salary 15.00 Helen Boentje, salary 6.00 M. W. Forsythe. salary 2.40 Paul Dale, salary , 5.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 5.00 April 20 B. R. Noyes Garage, repairs 2.75 Robinson &amp; Miller, supplies 11.69 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., lights 365.28 Whitebreast Coal Co., fuel 3,016.28 Kearney Steam Laundry, supplies 11.25 C- H. &amp; K. B. Finch, supplies 3.83 </seg>
            <seg id="p038">38 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION E. A. Eck, repairs 100 Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing 171.94 Kaufmann &amp; Wernert, supplies 2.50 Kearney Telephone Co., telephone 23.0S A. E. caidwell, y. w. c. A. calendars 7.50 C. P. Lucas, repairs 6.10 H. A. Webbert, printing 110.55 W. C. Lantz, repairs 2.60 J. A. Allhands, labor 16.00 Sunderland Machine Co., supplies 6.J2 The Willis Music Co., supplies x.Jg Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 1J.12 ■Western Supply Co., equipment 76.33 Eimer &amp; Amend, supplies 5.31 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 7,J8 Root &amp; Stillwell, printing 5.28 Bob Mclntyre, repairs 2.00 Kearney Daily Hub. printing 4.60 Kearney Hdw. Co., supplies 7.25 Nebraska Telephone Co., telephone 24.S8 City of Kearney Water Works 58.88 City of Kearney Water Works 26.26 Western Union Telegraph Co., clock 16.00 T. W. Maus, band equipment 40.00 Underwood &amp; Underwood, slides 21.77 Leedy Mfg. Co., band equipment 105.52 Carl Fischer, band equipment 24.28 Lyon &amp; Healy, supplies 8.00 Frank Holton A Co.. band equipment 63.95 Empire Store, supplies 9.13 Gaston Music Co., tuning pianos 6.00 Geo. S. Dick, pay roll account 150.60 Dalton Adding Machine Co., ribbon 1.00 W. F. Crosaley, repairs 39.25 Cambridge Botanical Supply Co., supplies 8.20 Ward's Nat'l Science Estab., supplies 41.00 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., supplies 9.20 Midway Gas Co., fuel 19.39 J. A. stryker, advertising tags S.00 A. H. Andrews Co., equipment 4.31 Goder-Hemann Co., equipment 8.40 Harry Porter, supplies 8.75 Remington Typewriter Co.. equipment 60.70 Omaha News Co., supplies 8.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p039">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 39 Deniler-Manuel Furn. Co.. supplies J.15 G«o. S. Dick, freight, dray, etc 176.»* C. H. Stocking &amp; Co.. supplies 51.11 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., light* 2J2.S8 Geo. S. Dick, traveling expense 81.2 J Heasly Grocery Co.. supplies 5«.18 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., lights 97.58 27.JJ0.M Amount Reverting to Treasury t 1.034.83 Appropriation available April 2, 1915 $160,000.00 Disbursements 1915 April 26 George S. Dick, salary $ 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 165.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 165.M C. N. Anderson, salary 156.00 H. O. Sutton, salary 155.00 O. W. Neale. salary 155.00 R. F. Richardson, salary 156.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 145.00 Alma Hosic, salary 145.00 Etta Brown, salary 145.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 140.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 140.00 C. E. Benson, salary 140.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 137.00 Sara L. "Garrett, salary 137.00 Anna K. Caldwell, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 120.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 120.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 120.00 Lula E. Wirt, salary 115.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 115.00 Charles H. Wellers, salary 115.00 Marion Williams, salary 110.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, sa'ary 100. UO Blanche E. Riggs. salary 100.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 90.00 John A. Stryker, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen, salary tkM </seg>
            <seg id="p040">40 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Harriet Sutton. salary 65.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 65.00 Vera Kayser, salary 60.00 Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 20.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Robert Shaw, salary 30.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 Carl Melin, salary 30.00 Fred Schmeeckle. salary JO. 00 Wald Balcom, salary 20.80 Charles Reed, salary 19.60 Ray Bixler, salary 18.40 B. R. Lewis, salary 21.20 B. F. Walker, salary 20.00 Roy Young;, salary 21.20 Leslie Rich, salary 10.00 Clyde Knott, salary 16.00 Helen Hoentje, salary 15.00 Ralph Eggleaton, salary 10.00 W. H. Thomas, salary 50.00 May 28 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 165.00 Robert I. Elliott, salary 160.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 155.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 H. O. Button .salary 155.00 O. W. Neale, salary 155.00 K. F. Richardson, salary ' 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 H. H. Gibson, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 145.00 Alma Hoslc, salary 145.00 Etta Brown, salary 145.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 140.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 140.00 C. E. Benson, salary 140.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 1 J7.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 1S7.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 126.00 Mary Crawford, salary 120.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 120.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p041">KEAKNEY 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL 41 Charlotte Lowe, salary 120.00 i.ula E. Wirt, salary 1 15.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 116.00 Chaa. H. Wellers. salary 116.00 Marion Williams, salary 110.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 100.00 Blanche E. Riggs, salary 100.00 Ethol E. Langdon, salary 100.00 Bessie 8. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 90.00 John A. Stryker, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen. salary 65.00 Harriett Sutton. salary 65.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary J5.00 Vera W. Kayser, salary 60.00 Mabel P. Scout t. salary 20.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 Carl Melin. salary 30.00 Robert Shaw, salary JO.OO Fred Schmeeckle, salary 30.00 Waid ltalcnm, salary 21.20 Roy Vedder, salary U.20 Ray Bixler, salary 17.M ■Wilson Moor, salary 17.M B. F. Walker, salary 2J.M Roy Young, salary 19.40 Leslie Rich, salary 10.00 Clyde Knott, salary 15.00 Helen Boentje. salary 10.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 11.00 June 24 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 165.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 160.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 155.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 156.00 H. O. Sutton, salary 156.00 O. W. Neale. salary 155.00 R. F. Richardson, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 H. H. Gibson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 145.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p042">42 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Alma Hosic. salary 145.00 Etta Brown, salary 146.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 140.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 140.00 C. E. Benson, salary 140.00 Sarah Brindley. salary 1S7.0O Sara L. Garrett, salary 1 J7.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 1 25.00 Mary Crawford, salary 120.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 120.00 L.ula E. Wlrt, salary 115.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 115.00 Chan. H. Wellers, salary 115.00 Marion Williams, salary 110.00 Emma E. Hanthorn. salary 100.00 Blanche E. Riggs. salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Erne H. Abbott, salary 90.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 90.00 Ajmes Knutzen, salary 65.00 Harriet Sutton. salary 65.00 Vera W. Kayser, salary 60.00 Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 40.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Morris Halcom salary 60.00 Carl Melin, salary 30.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 65.00 Waid Balcom, salary 39.20 Roy Vedder, salary 16.80 Ray Bixler, salary 2S.80 Ivan Linder, salary 16.80 Roy Young, salary 16.00 Mllford Forsyth, salary 10.0O Mae Murphy, salary 12.50 Ralph Henline, salary 12.50 W. J, Braham. salary 110.00 E. W. l.antz. salary 100.00 Grace Sylla, salary 90.00 Clare Maokin. salary 90.00 Jane Lindsay, salary 70.00 Dorothy Hurlbut, salary 100.00 Raymond Kirk, sa'ary 80.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p043">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 43 Miriam Anderson, salary 70.00 Margaret Dick, salary 44.00 Myrtle Thygesen, salary 12.50 Nelle McBee, salary J0.00 Mrs. Olive Strong;, salary 99.75 W. A. Haberstro. salary 36.33 Jane Pinder, salary 4.81 Wilson Moor, salary 1C.M 2« Midway Gas Co., fuel »0.22 George S. Dick, freight, express, etc M0.40 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 4.70 C. F. Bodlnson Hdw. Co., supplies 145.05 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., light.. 5».9« City of Kearney Water Works, water 17.48 Nebraska Telephone Co 31.59 Kearney Telephone Co 20.98 Chaa. P. Lucas, repairs 8.50 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co.. supplies K.I 2 C. E. Benson, trav. exp 11.78 Beckley-Cardy Co., supplies 2S.S5 E. H. Sheldon Co., equipment 80.00 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., supplies 176.25 Allan J. Coleman, supplies 8.00 Patterson &amp; Co., supplies 1.10 Kearney Floral Co., for grounds 40.75 George S. Dick. trav. exp 34.90 L. C. French, sweeper 20.00 S. A. Courtis, supplies 6.77 West Disinfecting Co., supplies 6.50 Harry Porter, supplies 6.05 Willard F. Bailey, printing 68.75 W. H. Richardson, labor 1.50 Kearney Steam Laundry, supplies 15.S5 Kearney Opera House, commencement... 15.00 Armitage- Olson Drug Co., supplies 19.85 Willis Music Co., supplies 5.12 Kearney Hdw. Co., supplies 4.65 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., repairs 2.40 R. F. Richardson, trav. exp 16.61 Empire Store, supplies 16.00 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 25.20 H. A. Webbert. printing 31.50 F. S. Webster Co., supplies 25.00 Mclntoeh Stereopticon Co., supplies 12.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p044">44 8TATE BOARD OF EDUCATION The Book Store, supplies 5.65 Fred C. Meyer &amp; Co., supplies 1.87 Aug. 4 Georgre S. Dick. July salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, July salary 165.00 R I. Elliott, July salary 160.00 C. N. Anderson, July salary 155.00 A. J. Mercer, July salary 155.00 H. O. Sutton. July salary 155.00 O. W. Neale, July salary 155.00 R. F. Richardson, July salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson. July salary 150.00 H. H. Gibson. July salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, July salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, July salary 145.00 Etta Brown, July salary 146.00 Marion C. Smith, July salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, July salary 140.00 Carrie E. Ludden, July salary 140.00 C. E. Benson, July salary 140.00 Sarah Brindley. July salary 137.00 Sara L. Garrett, July salary 1S7.00 Anna E. Caldwell, July salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, July salary 120.00 Charlotte Lowe, July salary 120.00 Lula E. Wilt, July salary 115.00 Nellie E. Barton, July salary 115.00 Chas. H. Wellers, July salary 115.00 Marion Williams, July salary 110.00 Emma E. Hanthom, July salary 100.00 Blanche E. Riggs, July salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, July salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, July salary 90.00 J. A. Stryker, July salary 90.00 H. R. Tollefser., July salary 130.00 Ames Knutzen, July salary 66.00 Harriet Sutton, July salary 65.00 Fred Schmeeckle, July salary 65.00 Vera W. Kayser, July salary 60.00 Mabel P. Scoutt, July salary 40.00 Carl Melin, July salary 30.00 Mae Murphy, July salary 12.50 Ralph Henline, July salary 12.50 M. W. Forsyth, July salary 10.00 W. H. Hardy, July salary 85.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p045">KEARNEY StfATE NORMAL SCHOOL 45 Morris Balcom, July salary (0.00 John Marshall, July salary 75.00 Waid Balcom, July salary 52.00 Roy Vedder, July salary TIM Ray Bixler. July salary 27.M Wilson Moor, July salary 22.8* Ivan Linder, July salary 27. SO Roy Young, July salary 27.60 W. J. Braham. July salary 110.00 E. W. Lantz, Juiy salary 100.00 Dorothy Hurlbut, July salary 100.00 Grace Sylla, July salary 90.00 Clare Mackin, July salary 90.00 Raymond Kirk, July salary 80.00 Jane Lindsay, July salary 70.00 Miriam Anderson, July salary 70.00 Margaret Dick, July salary 40.00 Myrtle Thygesen, July salary 65.00 Nelle McBee, July salary 30.00 Olive M. Strong, July salary 314.13 W. A. Haberstro, July salary 275.17 Jane Finder, July salary 53.82 9 George S. Dick, trav. exp 10.77 Denzler-Manuel Furn Co., furniture 41.65 Willard F. Bailey, printing 140.89 W. F. Crossley, repairs 21.80 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., light.. 30.95 Midway Gas Co., fuel 6.15 Klopp &amp; Bartlett Co.. supplies 16.25 C. N. Anderson, use of horse-campus 5.30 Nebr. School Supply Hous.e supplies 7.50 Gaston Music Co., pianos 662.50 Empire Store, supplies 2.S0 H. A. Webbert, printing 20.76 Patterson &amp; Co., supplies 4.10 City of Kearney Water Works 15.53 Cardinell-Vincent Co., supplies 2.15 Bob Mclntyre .repairs 7.25 Crane &amp; McGlennan, supplies 5.00 George S. Dick, freight, express, etc 247.08 23 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 40.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p046">46 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 John Marshall, salary TS.00 Waid Balcom, salary 48.00 Sep. 27 Q«org« S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 165.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 160.00 H. O. Button, salary 160.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 H. H. Gibson, salary 160.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 145.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 145.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 1S7.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Blanche E. Rigrgs. salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wirt, salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 1 20.00 Charles H. Wellers, salary 115.00 Marion Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthom, salary 106.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John Ludden, salary 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Erne H. Abbott, salary 95.00 J. A. Stryker. salary 75.00 Agnes Knutzen. salary 65.00 Harriet Sutton, salary 65.00 Margaret Dick, salary 60.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Vera Kayser, salary 25.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p047">47 KEARNEY 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL Mab«l P. Sooutt. salary 20.00 PhtUp Person, salary 30.00 M. W. Forsyth, salary l«-0* John Myera, salary 1*00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 12.50 Paul Dale, salary 1250 W. H. Hardy, salary 8500 Morris Balcom. salary 60.00 John Mai-shall, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom, salary 7.«0 Roy Young, salary 18.20 I. H. Linder, salary 16.00 H. R. Hohlfeld, salary 8 00 H. W. Hohlfeld, salary 8.00 H. O. Woodring, salary 6.50 L. T. Waterman, salary 5.90 Oct. 23 J. D. Saunders, supplies 4.99 W. J. Neal, building storage cases 47.75 Kearney Hardware Co., supplies 1.65 Denzler-Manuel Furniture Co., furniture.. 192.89 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 24.00 C. F. Bodison Hardware Co., supplies S0.74 Midway Gas Co.. fuel 11.J2 Willard F. Bailey Co., printing 228.20 J. A. Stryker, trav. exp 36.04 F. H. Schurger, labor 85.00 Harry Porter, supplies 25.60 Klopp &amp; Bartlett Co., supplies 7.58 Morris Budney, supplies 1.50 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Power Co., light.. 62.59 William V. Didricksen. supplies 4.10 Vocational Supply Co.. equipment 20.00 Ward's Nat'l Sci. Estab., supplies 46.80 Western Union Telegraph Co.. clock 15.00 Gardner-Grovenor Co., equipment 85.65 Nebraska Farm Journal, advertising 11.20 Kearney Telephone Co 21.64 Pierce Hide &amp; Fur Co., supplies 1.75 H. A. Wehbert; printing 82.00 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co., supplies 27.55 Nebraska Telephone Co., supplies 44.46 Empire Store, supplies 7.20 George S. Dick, freight, express, etc 160.96 City of Kearney Water Works 30.91 </seg>
            <seg id="p048">48 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture 55.50 George S. Dick, president's trav. exp 9.78 Kearney Steam Laundry Co., supplies 22.60 Kearney Flora! Co.. supplies 3.50 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., supplies 196.15 26 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 165.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 160.00 H. O. Button, salary 160.00 It R. I. Elliott, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 150.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 H. H. Gibson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic. salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 137.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary- 125.00 Blanche E. Riggs, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wilt, salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Charles H. Wellers, salary 116.00 Marion Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 105.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John E. Ludden, salary 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 95.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 75.00 Agnes Knutzen, salary 65.00 Harriet Button, salary 65.00 Margaret Dick, salary 60.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p049">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL, SCHOOL. 49 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Mrs. H. H. Gibson, salary 24.00 Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 20.00 Albert Johnston, salary 50.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 45.00 Philip Person, salary 30.00 Harriet Knutzen .".20 M. W. Forsyth, salary 16.00 John Myers, salary 16.00 Ralph Kggleaton. salary 12.50 Paul Dale, salary 12.50 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balcoin. salary S0.0O John Marshall, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom, salary 31.00 Roy Young, salary 25.00 I. H. Linder, salary 23.00 H. R. Hohfeld, salary 19.40 H. W. Stoetzel,. salary 20.20 H. E. Woodring. salary 15.60 L. T. Waterman, salary 17.40 C. N. Anderson, study center 5.0* Geo. E. Martin, study center 15.00 John Ludden, study center 10.00 J. H. Stoutemyer. study center 10.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 5.00 R. I. Elliott, study center 5.00 Chas. H. Wellers, study center 5.00 Lula E. Wirt, salary 5.00 Not. 26 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 165.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 160.00 H. O. Button, salary 160.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 150.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude II. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 146.00 Grace E. Steadman. salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 140.0ft </seg>
            <seg id="p050">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 50 Anna V. Jennings, salary 117.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 126.00 Blanche E. Riggs. salary 1 25.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell. salary 125.00 Charlotte I/)we, salary 1 25.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lu'a E. Wirt, salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Charles E. Wellers. salary 115.00 Marion Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 105.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John Ludden. salary 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 95.00 J. A. Stryker. salary 75.00 H. R Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen, salary 65.00 Harriett Sutton. salary 65.00 Margaret Dick salary 60.00 Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 20.00 Albert Johnston, salary 25.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 30.00 Philip Person, salary 30.00 M. W. Forsyth, salary 16.00 John Myers, salary 16.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 12.50 Paul Dale, salary 12.50 Harriet Knutzen, salary 5.00 Harriet Knutzen. salary 5.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 W. I* Saunders, salary 50.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom, salary 26.40 I. H. Under, salary 25.00 Roy Young, salary 21.10 H. R. Hohlfeld, salary i».4« H. W. Stoetzel, salary 2|.w H. E. Woodring, salary 20.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p051">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 51 L. T. Waterman, salary 20.20 C. N. Anderson, study center 10.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, study center 5.00 C. H. Wellers. study center 5.00 Lula EL Wirt, study center 10.00 1915 Dec. 18 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Qeo. E. Martin, salary 1(6.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 160.00 H. O. Button, salary 1*0.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 180.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 1 55.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 150.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer. salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 137.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Blanche E. Riggs, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell. salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell. salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wirt, salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Charles E. Wellers. salary 115.00 Marion Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 105.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John Ludden, salary 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Ctarrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 95.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 75.00 H. R Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen, salary 65.00 Harriett Sutton. salary 65.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p052">52 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Margaret Dick salary 60.00 Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 20.00 Albert ohntson, salary 25.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary S0.00 Philip Person, salary 30.00 M. W. Forsyth, salary 16.00 John Myers, salary 16.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 12.50 Paul Dale, salary 12.50 Harriet Knutzen, salary 5.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 86.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 W. L. Saunders, salary 50.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom, salary 16.20 I. H. Under, salary 19.70 Roy Young, salary 19.60 H. R. Hohlfeld. salary 21.00 H. W. Stoetzel, salary 20.S0 H. E. Woodring. salary 16.60 L. T. Waterson, salary 15.80 L. C. Smith, salary 5.00 C. N. Anderson, study center 15.00 Lula E. Wirt, study center 5.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, study cented 15.00 Geo. E. Martin, study center 15.00 John E. Ludden, study center 5.00 R. I. Elliott, study center 6.00 C. H. Wellers, study center 5.00 21 Cambridge Botanical Supply Co 14.05 Daily Times Publishing Co., printing 25.S6 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 5.40 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co.. supplies 19.30 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co., supplies 12.15 F. H. Gilcrest Lumber Co., fuel 1,062.44 L. J. Butcher, pictures 28.90 C. J. Burke &amp; Sons, repairs 60.04 Geo. S. Dick, traveling expenses 72.01 Geo. S. Dick, freight, express, etc., 158.08 Kearney Hardware Co., supplies 12.10 City of Kearney Water Works 20.63 Nebraska Telephone Co If .(6 Kaufmann &amp; Wernert, supplies 7.90 H. A. Webbert, printing 24.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">KKARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 53 Empire Store, supplies 2.80 Hibberd Brick Co., repairs (.04 A. Flanagan Co., office supplies 53.85 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., supplies 14.25 Kearney Steam Laundry, supplies 8.15 The Willard F. Bailey Co., printing 24.7» A. Hospe Co., equipment 10.S0 Jenkins Bros., supplies 7.«6 Mason-Webb Disinfect Co., supplies S8.55 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., light W.0» Midway Gas Co.. fuel 12.T7 Dept. Agronomy, Uni. of Neb., supplies... 29.86 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture 21. IS Neb. School Supply House, furniture, etc., 21S.42 G. Schirmer. supplies 67.84 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 44.41 Rand McNally Co.. equipment 206.10 A. Schoenut Co.. equipment 18.00 Carpenter Paper Co., supplies 22.80 M. E. Healey. supplies 11.70 Katheryn Laughlin, advertising 12.50 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 12.50 Underwood Typewriter Co., equipment 11.50 Kearney Foundry &amp; Mach. Co., repairs . . . 18.50 The McGraw Co., lights 1».6J 1916 Jan. 27 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 1(5.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 1(0.00 H. O. Button, salary 1(0.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 1(0.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 150.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosir. salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 146.00 J. H. Stoutemyer. salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 187.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p054">54 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Blanche E. Riggs, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell. salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wlrt, salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Charles E. Wellers, salary 115.00 Marion Wellers. salary 116.00 Emnia E. Hanthorn, salary 105.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John Ludden. salary 100.00 L. B. Sipple, salary 40.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 95.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 75.00 H. R Tollefsen. salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen, salary C5.00 Harriett Button, salary 85.00 Margaret Dick salary 60.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 10.00 Philip Person, salary JO.OO Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 25.00 Albert Johnson, salary 25.00 M. W. Forsyth, salary 16.00 John Myers, salary 16.00 Ralph Eggleston. salary 12.50 Paul Dale, salary 12.50 Harriet Knutzen, salary 5.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 W. L. Saunders, salary 50.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom. salary 20.50 I. H. Under, salary 12.40 Roy Young, salary 2S.20 H. B. Hohlfeld. salary 14.50 H. W. Stoetzel. salary 11.90 H. E. Woodring, salary 9.00 L. T. Waterman, salary 11.50 Archie Kring, salary 5.00 C. N. Anderson, study center 19.82 </seg>
            <seg id="p055">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL 8CHOOI. 55 R. I. Elliott, study center .■ lt.St John E. Ludden, study center H.10 Geo. E. Martin, study center 24.14 J. H. Stoutemyer, study center 28.87 Lula. E. Wirt. study center 10.74 Feb. 19 Neb. School Supply House, supplies *5.40 Rogers &amp; Scott, furniture J0.4O Empire Store, supplies 20.W Densler-Manuel Furniture Co 50.W Midway Gas Co.. fuel H-16 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., supplies 51.»8 F. H. Gilcre8t Lumber Co.. fuel, etc 1,424.22 The McGraw Co., lights 21.5J Rand McNally Co.. map «-70 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. furniture ...i 4«.50 S. A. D. Henline. supplies *-75 American Radiator Co., supplies 48.41 Mclntosh Stereopticon, lens 1.61 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., light ««.ll Kearney Telephone Co 16.80 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 W. F. Pailey Co.. printing 212.«O Nebraska Telephone Co l*-40 H. A. Webbert, printing «6.** City of Kearney Water Works 17.40 C. F. Bodinson Hardware Co., supplies . . . 8«.18 W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co., supplies »1.7« J. D. Saunders, supplies 24.72 George S. Dick, freight, express, etc J97.58 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 .i Geo. E. Martin, salary ' 70.00 C. X. Anderson, salary M5 00 R. I. Elliott, salary l«6.00&gt; R. I. Elliott, salary 185.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 156.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 150.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alina Hoeic, salary 150.00 Maricn C. Smith, salary 146.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 140.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p056">56 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Anna V. Jennings, salary 137.00 Etta Brown, salary 126.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Blanche E. Riggs. salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell. salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell. salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 1 25.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wirt. salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Charles E. Wellers, salary 115.00 Marion Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 105.00 Kthol M. Langdon. salary 105.00 John Ludden, salary 1 00.00 - L. B. Sipple, salary 160.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Kftle H. Abbott, salary 95.00 Bert Danley, salary 75.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 75.00 H. R Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen. salary 65.00 Harriett Sutton, salary 65.00 Margaret Dick salary 60.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 30.00 x Philip Person, salary SO.OO Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 25.00 Albert Johnson, salary 25.00 M. W. Forsyth. salary 16.00 John Myers, salary 16.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 12.50 Paul Dale, salary 12.50 Harriet Knutzen, salary 5.00 Blanche Warner, salary J.20 W. H. Hardy, salary 86.00 Morris Balcom. salary 60.00 W. L. Saunders. salary 50.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Waid Ualcom, salary 16 70 I. H. JJrdPr. xjilary 20.60 Roy Young, salary 20.60 If. IS HohlfeM. en ary 27.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 57 H. W. Stetzel, salary 21.00 H. E. Woodring. salary 18.30 L. T. Waterman, salary 1 2.40 Archie Kring. salary 10.00 Geo. E. Martin, study center 14.15 Lula E. Wlrt, study center 21.01 J. H. Stoutemyer, study center 5.00 C. N. Anderson, study center Ml R. I. Elliott, study center 8.SS R. M. Shreves, study center 10.00 J. E. Ludden, study center 5.95 Gertrude H. Gardner, study center 15.00 L. B. Slpple. study center 5.85 Mar. 27 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 170.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 165.00 H. O. Sutton, salary 185.00 R. I. Elliott, salary H5.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman. salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 1 J7.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Mlanche E. Riggs, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell. salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell. salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wirt. salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton 120.00 Chas. H. Wellers 116.00 Marion Wellers 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn 105.00 Ethol M. Langdon 105.00 John E. Ludden 100.00 B. C. Danly 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p058">58 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Sarah lirindley 100.00 Sara L. Oarrett 100.00 Bessie S. Black ' 100.00 Effie H. Abbott 95.00 J. A. Stryker 75.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen 65.00 Harriet Sutton 8S.uo Margaret Dick (0.00 Fred Schmeecklc, salary 30.00 Philip Person, salary 10.00 .Mabel P. Scoutt. sa'ary 25.00 Albert Johnston, salary 25.00 M. W. Forsyth, salary 16.00 John Myer, salary It. 00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 1 2.50 Paul Dale, salary 12.50 Harriet Knutzen, salary 5.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 W. L.. Saunders, sa'ary 50.00 John Marsha'l, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom, salary 17.50 I. H. Under, salary 17.40 Roy Young, salary 18.90 H. R. Hohlfeld. salary 27.10 H. W. Stoetzel, salary 20.10 H. E. Woodring, salary 11.50 L* T. Waterman, salary 10.70 Archie Kring, salary 7.50 Geo. E. Martin, study center 6.20 L,ula E. Wirt, study center 10:49 C. N. Anderson, study center 27.J4 John E. Ludden, study center 5.60 J. H. Stoutemyer. study center 10.00 L. B. 8ipple, study center 5.00 L. B. Sipple, salary 1 60.00 April 12, J. D. Saunders. supplies 33.87 Geo. S. Dick, freight, express, etc 244.92 W. F. Bailey Co., printing 175.31 C. F. Bod in son Hdw. Co., supplies 46.95 C. J. Burke &amp; Son, repairs S0.67 Heasly Grocery Co., supplies 8.45 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co., supplies 18.64 </seg>
            <seg id="p059">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 59 P. H. Gilcrest Lbr. Co.. fuel, lumber 1.000.50 W. L. Stickel Lbr. So., supplies 1 2.35 Bob Mclntyre, repairs 1.75 Kearney Dally Hub, printing 16.00 W. C. Lanti, repairs 2».75 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 H. A. Webbert. printing 14.00 Western L'nion. time service 15.00 Nebraska Telephone Co 12.25 Midway as. Co., fuel 21.ll Kearney Water A Electric Prs. Co., light . . 81.M City t&gt;f Kearney Water Works 29.18 The McGraw Co., light 14.47 Tablet &amp; Ticket Co.. supplies 8.28 Vocational Supply Co., equipment 102.08 The Klenzo Mfg. Co.. supplies 5.00 Burgess-Nash Co., equipment 22.(0 American Playground Device Co., equip... 10.00 A Flanagan Co., supplies 20.25 H. Channon Co., equipment 1-88 Rand McNally Co., equipment S.84 P. P. Caproni &amp; Bro., equipment 81.00 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., equipment.. (2.10 E. H. Sheldon Co., equipment 89.25 John &amp; Johnson, supplies 8.00 The Willis Music Co., supplies 8.70 April 26 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 170.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 1(5.00 H. O. Button, salary 165.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 165.00 L. B. Sipple, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 .1 S. Elliott, »ulary 150.00 Gertrude I f. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Setadman, salary 1 45.00 Carrie E. Ludden. salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 137.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p060">60 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Blanche E. Riggrs. salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 125.0* Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wirt. salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Chas. H. Wellers, salary 115.00 Marlon Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn. salary 105.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 10B.0O John E. Ludden. salary 100.00 B. C. Danly, salary 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bcaaie S. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 95.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 75.00 H. R. Tollefsen. salary 70.00 Agues Knutzen. salary" 65.00 Harriet Button, salary 65.00 Margaret Dick, salary (0.00 Fred Sohmeeckle. salary 10.00 Philip Person, salary 10.00 Mabel P. Scoutt. salary 25.00 Albert Johnston, salary 25.00 M. W. Forsyth. salary 16.00 John Myer, salary 16.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 12.60 Paul Dale, salary 1Z.50 Harriet Knutzen, salary 3.60 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balcom. salary 60.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom. salary 2S.70 I. H. Lander, salary 22.10 Roy Young, salary 22. SO H. R. Hohlfeld. salary 21.»0 H. E. Stoetzel. salary **.OO H. E. Woodring. salary 21.20 L. T. Waterman, salary 28,60 G*o. E. Martin, study center 2».»6 Lula E. Wirt. gtudy center 20.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p061">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 61 J. H. Stoutemyer, study center 10.00 C. N. Anderson, study center 18.14 John E. Ludden, salary 12.50 L. B. Sipple. study center 6.S0 R. I. Kllntt. study center 5.00 May 29 Georsre s. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 170.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 165.00 H. O. Sutton, salary 165 00 R. I. Elliott, salary iss.oo L. B. Sipple. salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. s. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Setadman, salary 145.00 Carrie e. Ludden, salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary U7.oo Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Blanche E. Rises, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 125.00 Charlotte Ix&gt;we. salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wirt. salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Chaa. H. Wellers. salary 115.00 Marion Wellers. salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn. salary 105.00 Ethol M. Langdon. salary 105.00 John E. Ludden, salary 100.00 B. C. Danly, salary 100.00 Sarah Brlndley. salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 95.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 75.00 H. R. Tollefsen. salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen, salary 65.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p062">STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 62 Harriet Sutton, salary 65.00 Margaret Dick, salary 60.00 Fred Schmeeokle, salary J0.00 Philip Person, salary SO.OO Mabel P. Scoutt, salary 25.00 Albert Johnston, salary 25.00 Paul Dale, salary 25 - 0 ' M. W. Forsyth. salary l«00 John Myer, salary 16.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 12.50 Harriet Knutzen, salary 7.20 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Waid Balcom, salary 28.00 I. H. Linder. salary 21.40 Roy Young, salary 25.30 H. R. Hohlfeld, salary 27.20 H. W. Stoetzel. salary 25.20 H. E. Woodrlng. salary 19.70 L. T. Waterman, salary 2S.50 Lula E. Wirt, study center 11.14 Geo. E. Martin, study center 20.40 J. H. Stoutemyer. study center 10.00 June 27 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 170.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 165.00 H. O. Sutton, salary 185.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 165.00 L. B. Slpple, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary .- 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden. salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer. salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 1S7.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 126.00 Blanche E. Riggs, salary 125.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p063">KEARNEY 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL 63 Cora O'Connell. salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 1M.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 126.00 Lula E. WIrt. salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Chas. H. Welters, salary 115.00 Marion Wellens, salary 115.00 Ethol M. Uingdon. salary 106.00 John E. Ludden. salary 100.00 Sarah Urindley. salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett. salary 100.00 Heasie S. Black, salary 100.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 115.00 H. R. Tollefsen. salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen, salary 85.00 Harriett Sutton, salary «5.00 Margaret Dick, salary 60.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 65.00 Alfred C. Nielsen, salary 25.00 Paul Dale, salary 50.00 Mary Kirk, salary 26.00 L. T. Waterman, salary 20.(0 Leslie Lewis, salary l».70 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 Morris Balrom, salary 60.00 John Marshal, salary 75.00 Roy Young, salary 21.10 E. J. Jelden, salary 26.80 L. J. Vedder. salary 12.10 J. L. Rich, salary 1 1.80 B. F. Walker, salary 22.40 L. E. Gunderson. salary 12.00 Lloyd White, salary lZ.gO J. E. Bradburn. salary 1.20 Geo. E. Martin, study center 6.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, study center 5.00 W. J. Hraham. salary 125.00 Fannie Conkling, salary 100.00 M. S. Pate, salary 125.00 Ralph Henline, salary 100.00 J. F. Matthews, salary 125.00 Eflle Miller, salary 100.00 Alice Florer, salary 100.00 Grace Sylla, salary 100.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p064">64 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Troy Welper, salary 75.00 Frances Dearborn, salary 100.00 Chas. H. Hetrick, salary 75.00 Rose Clark Price, salary 40.00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture S7.60 Dennison Mfg. Co., supplies 3.61 Cudahy Packing Co., supplies 12.00 E. B. WilUe, labor 10.80 United Chemical Co., supplies 98.30 I .yon &amp; Healy, supplies 3.73 F. 8. Webster Co., supplies 25.00 A. J. Nystrum, map 5.70 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., equipment. . 83.50 College Book Store, supplies 1.81 The John Danner Co., furniture 46.S7 Acme Roll Ptg. Co., printing 70.37 George BroB. Griffiths Co., supplies 1.54 Underwood Typewriter Co., supplies 2.00 Neb. School Supply Co., furniture, etc,... 88.70 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Mason-Webb Disinfecting Co., supplies .. 72.00 Beckley-Cardy Co., supplies 19.80 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., light 39.33 Midway Gas Co., fuel 23.61 City of Kearney Water Works 29.41 Kearney Telephone Co 16.61 Nebraska Telephone Co 14.25 Hibberd Brick Co., repairs 65.00 Patterson &amp; Co., supplies 9.25 N. Oergen, labor 10.90 Kearney Hdw. Co., supplies 31.35 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 49.80 H. A. Webbert, printing 4.40 Kearney Steam Laundry Co., supplies 21.23 Chas. A. Hazlett, equipment 56.05 W. L. Stickel Lbr. Co., supplies 48.30 Kaufmann &amp; Wernent, supplies 10.55 King's Department Store, supplies 17.25 A. C. Killian Clothing Co., supplies 29.50 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co.. supplies 27.76 C. F. Bodinson Hdw. Co., supplies 58.50 Carpenter Paper Co., supplies 16.20 George S. Dick, freight, express, etc 233.67 J. D. Saunders, supplies 24.39 </seg>
            <seg id="p065">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 65 F. H. Gllcrest Lumber Co., fuel, etc 608.9O George S. Dick, traveling expenses 29.40 F. C. Scott, furniture 1*6.20 July 22 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 170.00 C. N. Anderson, salary l«5.0O H. O. Sutton, salary 165.00 R. I. Elliott, salary 165.00 L. B. Sipple, salary 180.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 150.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Alma Hosic, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 145.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 145.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 145.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 140.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 1S5.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Mary Crawford, salary 125.00 Blanche E. Riggs. salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Lula E. Wilt, salary 120.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 120.00 Chas. H. Wellers. salary 115.00 Marion Wellers. salary 115.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John E. Ludden, salary 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 H. R Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Agnes Knutzen. salary 65.00 Harriett Sutton. salary 65.00 Margaret Dick, salary 60.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 65.00 Alfred C. Nielsen, salary 25.00 Paul Dale, salary 50.00 Mary Kirk, salary 25.00 L. T. Waterman, salary 28.80 Leslie Lewis, salary 28.80&gt; W. H. Hardy, salary 85.0O </seg>
            <seg id="p066">66 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Morris Balcom, salary GO.(HI John Marshal, salary 75.00 Roy Young, salary 20.40 E. J. Jelden. salary l«.20 L. D. Vedder, salary 17.10 J. L. Rich, salary 10.80 B. F. Walker, salary 18.60 Lloyd White, salary 11.00 August Luedtke, salary 19.20 Jess Bradburn, salary 12.40 W. J. Braham, salary 125.00 M. 8. Pate, salary 125.00 J. F. Matthews, salary 125.00 Fannie R. Conkling. salary 100.00 Ralph Henline, salary 100.00 Effle Miller, salary 100.00 Alice Florer, salary 100.00 Grace Sylla, salary 100.00 Frances Dearborn, salary 100.00 Troy Welper, salary 75.00 C. H. Hetrick, salary 75.00 Rose Clark Price, salary 40.00 Naomi Nelson, salary 40.00 Nelle McBee. salary 40.00 Florence Randall, salary 40.00 George Arnold, salary, two months 120.00 Aug. 11 8. A. Courtis, supplies 18.0S C. P. Lucas, repairs 10.15 GuNton Music Co.. records, etc 29.55 Willard F. Bailey Co. printing 49.80 The A. I'. Schmidt Co., supplies 4.10 Bigsby Rotary Mfg. Co.. equipment 1.50 Frankel Carbon Paper Co.. supplies 76.50 Minneapolis Pa|&gt;er Co., supplies 26.20 E. H. Sheldon Co.. Equipment 4.50 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 9S.85 Wrought Iron Range Co., equipment 100.50 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., supplies.. 10.75 Kearney Floral Co., plants for grounds.... 45.80 W. L. Stickel Lumber Co.. supplies 14.90 Armitage-Olson Drug Co., supplies 2.00 8. A. D. Henline. supplies 2.66 Midway Hotel, exp of speaker* 13.50 City of Kearney Water Works 33.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p067">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 67 Kearney Water A Electric Prs. Co.. light . . 4«.O5 Midway Gu Co.. fuel 14.14 Heaily Grocery Co. supplies ».7O Bodinaon Hdw. Co., supplies 10.J5 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co.. supplies 6.33 F. H. Gilcrest Lbr. Co.. repairs 28.85 Nebraska Telephone Co 12.S6 J. D. Saunders. supplies 20.11 A. T. Anderson, pictures 9.50 Omaha Nebraskan, advertising 6.00 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 12.75 Denzler- Manuel Furn. Co.. furniture. ... 27.75 George S. Dick, freight, express, etc 6»«.41 Robinson &amp; Miller, supplies 10.20 H. A. Webbert. printing 25.15 F. C. Scott, furniture 249.00 14 George S. Dick, traveling expenses 24.12 22 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 George E. Martin, salary 90.67 L. B. Sipple, salary 144.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Sara L. Ganett, salary •. 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 85.00 John Marshall, salary 75.00 Morris Balcom, salary 60.00 George Arnold, salary 60.00 Paul Dale, salary 50.00 Sept. 27 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 210.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 170.00 H. O. Sutton. salary 17O.«* L. B. Sipple. salary 170.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 155.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 155.00 Alma Hosic, salary 155.00 M. S. Pate, salary 155.00 Ralph W. Noyer, salary 155.00 J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 150.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 150.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 150.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p068">68 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION J. H. Stoutetnyer, salary 145.00 Lula E. Wirt, salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 1S7.00 Alice Florer, salary 1S6.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 135.00 Mary Crawford, salary 130.00 Blanche E. Riggs, salary 130.00 Etta Brown, salary 126.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caudwell, salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 125.00 Charles H. Wellers. salary 115.00 Marion Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 110.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John E. Ludden, salary 105.00 Eme H. Abbott, salary 100.00 John I. Engleman, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Margaret Dick, salary 80.00 Harriett Sutton, salary 70.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 30.00 Alfred Nielsen, salary 30.00 Paul Dale, salary 25.00 L. T. Waterman, salary 20.00 Leslie I^ewis, salary 20.00 John Myer, salary 20.00 Ralph EgKleston, salary 15.00 W. H. Hardy, salary »0.00 John Marshal, salary 80.00 Morris Ualeom, salary 65.00 George Arnold, s&gt;alary 60.00 Jacob McNulty, salary 25.00 H. R. Holfeld. salary 16.40 G. E. Holfeld, salary 17.40 H. E. Woodring, salary 10.90 D. A. Krinr, salary 15.40 John Scholtz, salary 15.10 Lloyd White, salary 11.30 Arnold Trotier, salary 10.50 Eugene Hueftle, salary 10.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p069">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 69 Waid Balcom. salary 11.80 Florence Kellog, salary 5.00 Lottie McKean, salary 5.00 Blanche Heaeock, salary 5.00 Sarah Brindley. salary 100.00 Oct. 19 F. H. Schurger, repairs 2«.10 George S. Dick, freight, express, etc 502.21 Kearney Steam Laundry Co., supplies 9.86 Klopp-Bartlett Co., supplies 42.50 W. F. Bailey Co., printing 2S6.56 F. H. Oilcrest Lbr. Co., material for rep 277.20 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 34.35 Kearney News &amp; Stationery Co., supplies 6.55 Butcher's Studio, pictures 7.00 S. V. Roudtez, painting banners 8.75 Kearney Telephone Co S8.08 Kearney Water Works 11.88 Midway Gas Co.. fuel 2.28 C. F. Bodlnson Hdw. Co., supplies 45.70 C. J. Burke &amp; Son, supplies 91.87 C. P. Lucas, repairs 42.90 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co., supplies 25.70 Hibberd Brick Co., repairs 7.00 The Empire Store, supplies 48.17 Kearney Foundry &amp; Mach. Co., repairs . . . 22.50 W. C. VanAndel &amp; Son, furniture . .". 15.«0 S. A. D. Henline, supplies 12.85 J. S. Barlow, furniture 11«.5« West Disinfecting; Co., supplies 284.50 Ward's Nat'l Sci. Estab., supplies 94.25 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., light 68.84 27 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Geo. E. Martin, salary 210.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 170.00 H. O. Button, salary 170.00 L. B. Sipple, salary 170.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 155.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 155.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 155.00 Alma Hosic, salary 155.00 M. 8. Pate, salary 155.00 R. W. Noyer. salary 155.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 150.00 Grace E. Steadman. salary 150.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p070">70 8TATE BOARD OF EDUCATION J. S. Elliott, salary 150.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 145.00 Margaret Dick, salary 80.00 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 150.00 Lula E. Wirt, salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 1S7.00 Alice Florer, salary 135.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 1S5.00 Mary Crawford, salary 1 30.00 Blanche E. Riggs, salary 1 30.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell, salary 125.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 125.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 125.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 125.00 Chas. H. Welters, salary 115.00 Marion Wellers, salary 115.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 110.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 100.00 John I. Engleman, salary 100.00 Evelyn Dilley, salary 30.00 Sarah Brindley. salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 109.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Harriett Sutton, salary 70.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 30.00 Alfred Nielsen, salary 30.00 Paul Dale, salary 37.50 L. T. Waterman, salary 20.00 Leslie Lewis, salary 20.00 John Myers, salary 20.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 15.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 90.00 John Marshall, salary SO. 00 Morris Balcom, salary 65.00 George Arnold, salary 60.00 .Jacob McNulty, salary 55.00 H. R. Hohlfeld. salary 19.30 G. E. Holfeld, salary 18.90 H. E. Woodring, salary 16.10 John Scholtz. salary 13.50 Lloyd White, salary 8.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p071">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 71 Arnold Trotier. salary IS. JO Waid Balcom. salary K.00 Dewey Kring. salary 12.30 E. Hueftle. salary 12.70 Geo. E. Martin, study center 't«M M. S. Pate, study center 10.00 R. M. Shreves. study center 16.00 H. O. Sutton, study cenetr 5.00 Alma Hoslc, study center 5.00 Marion C. Smith, study center Mi J. H. Stoutemyer, study center 5.00 Florence Kellogg, salary 6.M Lottie McKean, salary t.00 Blanche Heacock, salary (.00 John Ludden, salary '. 106. OW Nov. 25 George S. Dick, salary 250.00 Qeo. E. Martin, salary 210.00 C. N. Anderson, salary 170.00 H. O. Sutton, sa'ary 170.00 L. B. Sipple, salary 170.00 R. M. Shreves, salary 160.00 A. J. Mercer, salary 156.00 B. H. Patterson, salary 156.00 Gertrude H. Gardner, salary 156.00 Alma Hosie, salary 155.0* M. S. Pate, salary 155.00 R. W. Noyer, salary 155.00 Marion C. Smith, salary 150.00 Grace E. Steadman, salary 150.00 J. 8. Elliott, salary 150.0* J. H. Stoutemyer, salary 146.90 Carrie E. Ludden, salary 150.00 Lula E. Wirt. salary 140.00 Anna V. Jennings, salary 137.00 Alice Florer. salary 116.00 J. A. Stryker, salary 135.00 Mary Crawford, salary 130.00 Blanche E,. Rigrgs, salary 130.00 Etta Brown, salary 125.00 Cora O'Connell. salary 135.00 Anna E. Caldwell, salary 1 25.00 Charlotte Lowe, salary 125.00 Catherine Hicks, salary 126.00 Nellie E. Barton, salary 125.00 Chas. H. Wellers, salary 115.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p072">72 8TATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Marlon Wellers, salary 116.00 Emma E. Hanthorn, salary 110.00 Ethol M. Langdon, salary 105.00 John -E. Ludden, salary 105.00 Effle H. Abbott, salary 100.00 John I. Engleman, salary 100.00 Evelyn Dilley, salary 100.00 Sarah Brindley, salary 100.00 Sara L. Garrett, salary 100.00 Bessie S. Black, salary 100.00 Margaret L. Dick, salary 80.00 Harriett Button, salary 70.00 H. R. Tollefsen, salary 70.00 Fred Schmeeckle, salary 30.00 Alfred Nielsen, salary J0.00 Paul Dale, salary 25.00 L. T. Waterman, salary 20.00 Leslie I-ewis. salary 20.00 John Myers, salary 20.00 Ralph Eggleston, salary 15.00 W. H. Hardy, salary 90.00 John Marshall, salary 80.00 Morris Balcom, salary 65.00 George Arnold, salary 65.00 Jacob McNulty. salary 55.00 H. R. Holfe'.d. salary 16.80 G. E. Holfeld, salary 16.00 H. E. Woodring. salary 20.40 John Seholtz, salary 14.10 i.loyd White, salary 1J.90 Waid Balcom. salary 19.40 Eugene Huef tie, salary 1 5.40 Dewey Kring, salary 12.70 Arnold Trotier, salary 5.10 Geo. E. Martin, study center 15.00 M. S. Pate, study center : 10.00 L. B. Sipple, study center 10.00 J. H. Stoutemyer, study center 5.00 Alma Hosic. study center 5.00 Mary Crawford, salary 5.00 Blanche E. Riggs, study center 5.00 Marion C. Smith, study center 10.00 Florence Kellog-g, salary 5.00 Lottie McKean, salary 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p073">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL ■3 Blanche Heacock, salary 5.00 L. R. Gillette, salary 16.40 $125,914.80 1916 Dec. 1 Balance In fund J7.727.44 INSTITUTION CA3H 1915 Amount in State Treasury December 1, 1914, Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt Deposited with State Treasurer. Receipt Deposited with State Treasurer. Receipt Deposited with State Treasurer. Receipt Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt Sale of mileage book of W. A. George $ 1.754.15 Feb. 5 Mar. 8 April 19 May 6 July IS Oct 7 Oct. 30 98.312 609.83 99.350 M7.SS 100.946 315.28 101.679 586.00 104.582 2.0SS.41 107,214 1.473.4* 3.35 1916 Mar. 3 July 11 Nov. 7 Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt. Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt. Deposited with State Treasurer. Receipt. 112.015 1,818.90 117.398 2.715.87 120.731 2.376.80 1914 DISBURSEMENTS. Dec. 15 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., dormitory Chas. P. Lucas, dormitory Sunderland Marh. A Supp. Co.. dormitory Bob Mclntyre, laboratory Kearney Telephone Co., dormitory Univ. of Chicago Press, text books Kearney Hdw. Co., dormitory Kearney Steam Laundry, dormitory K. O. Holmes, text book Willard F. Bailey Co., typwriter Theo. B. Robertson Soap Co., laboratory. C. F. Kodinson Hdw. Co.. dormitory Ginn &amp; Co., textbook The Gregg Pub. Co., textbook E. A. Eck. dormitory , Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co., dormitory W. M. Welch Mrg. Co., laboratory Beckley-Cardy Co., textbook Marshall Paper Co., typewriter Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., dormitory Elmer &amp; Amend, laboratory </seg>
            <seg id="p074">74 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 7.81 Artificial Ice Plant, laboratory 2.80 Woldenberg &amp; Schaar. laboratory 332.71 W. L. Stlckel L,br. Co., dormitory 28.20 F. H. Oilcrest L.br. Co.. dormitory 11.45 Kearney Daily Hub, typewriter 2.75 Robinson &amp; Miller, laboratory 1.J8 Kearney Foundry &amp; Mach. Co., laboratory 21.00 McKinley P»b. Co., textbook 11.00 Nebraska Telephone Co 21.40 Midway Gas Co., dormitory 17.97 City of Kearney Water Works, dormitory S2.S4 Thomas Charles Co., textbook 25.24 American Multlgraph Co., typewriter 1.00 The Macmillan Co., textbook 33.60 A. Flanagan Co., textbook 7.80 Remington Typewriter Co 10.00 F. 8. Webster Co., typewriter 8.50 C. B. * E. B. Finch, laboratory 5.40 Lyons tt Carnahan, textbook 13.83 H. A. Webbert, typewriter 47.50 Byrne &amp; Hammons Dry Goods Co., dorm. 70.00 1915 April 20 Neb. School Supply House, textbook 217.48 American Book Co., textbook 12.24 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook 18.78 BenJ. H. Sanborn Co.. textbook 3.47 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. textbook 85.67 l.'niv. of Chicago Press, textbook 18.S2 Silver Burdett &amp; Co., textbook 43.76 Hinds. Noble &amp; Eldredge, textbook 6.00 The GrepB Pub. Co., textbook 14.04 McKinley Pub. Co., textbook 2.64 Chan. E. Merrill Co., textbook 9.56 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 15.4S Chas. Scribner's Sons, textbook 18.00 June 24 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbook 2.59 D. C. Heath &amp; Co 6.58 Ky. Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., dormitotry . . . 65.97 Scott Foresman Co., textbook 12.96 City of Ky. Water Works, dormitory 17.25 Oinn &amp; Co., textbook 36.12 American Honk Co., textbook 10.80 Am. Multigraph Co., typewriter 18.85 l.ucien Smith, dormitory 15.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p075">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL, SCHOOL 75 Kearney Telephone Co., dormitory 10.00 F. 8. Webster Co., typewriter J4.00 Au«. 9 The Macmillan Co.. textbook l.M D. C. Heath * Co., textbook M.44 Heasley Grocery Co., laboratory 54.78 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 140.49 D. Appleton Co., textbook 14.10 American Book Co.. textbook 41.(8 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. textbook J.ll University Pub. Co., textbook 28.55 Chas. P. Lucas, dormitory JJ.27 City of Ky Water Works, dormitory 10.28 Kearney Water ft Elec. Prs. Co., dormitory 2(.&lt;0 Denzler- Manuel Furniture Co., dormitory 54.»0 Bausch * l^imh Optical Co., laboratory . . 2S.01 Oct. 23 E. A. Eck, dormitory 99.05 Kaufmann &amp; Wernert, dormitory 7.S5 American Book Co., textbook 7.M Chas. Scribner's Sons, textbook 7.75 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook 15.M Omaha Gas Co., dormitory vio Remington Typewriter Co M.M McKinley Pub. Co., textbook H.fg Robinson &amp; Miller, laboratory l.f 1 Silver Burdett &amp; Co., textbook 1.1 1 Switz Paint &amp; Glass Co.. dormitory »7.I7 Ky. Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., dormitory 77.»» City of Ky. Water Works, dormitory 2S.40 Kearney Telephone Co., dormitory 10.00 Globe- Wernecke Co., typewriter 224.00 C. J. Burke * Son, dormitory 51.46 Ky Artificial Ice Plant, laboratory 5.55 Denzler -Manuel Furniture Co., dormitory 10.70 Geo. O. Wallace, dormitory 10.95 Dec. 20 J. D. Saunders. laboratory 18.52 W. F. Crossley, dormitory K2.09 Kearney Hdw Co., dormitory 35.«5 G. Schirmer, textbook 11. JO Ky Water &amp; E!ec. Prs. Co., dormitory CJ.8C Midway Gas Co., dormitory 21.81 City of Ky. Water Works, dormitory 21. M C. J. Burke * Son. dormitory 28.50 American Multigrraph Co., typewriter ' J.ll Chas. Scribner's Son*, textbook 2.90 University Pub. Co., textbook 2».1» </seg>
            <seg id="p076">76 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., laboratory 264.70 Dec. 21 Thos. Y. Crowell Co., textbook 12.00 Rand McNally Co., textbook 5.12 C. H. Stoelting Co., laboratory 76.25 American Book Co., textbook 48.19 University of Neb., textbook 43.55 J. A. Parks Co., textbook 15.18 Chas. E. Merrill Co., textbook 15.82 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 48.08 Bobbs-Merrill Co., textbook 7.50 Silver Burdett Co., textbook 8.50 HouRhton Mifflin Co., textbook 9.60 Ginn * Co., textbook 76.21 The Mamillan Co., textbook 102.09 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. textbook S2.00 Chas. P. Lucas, dormitory 22.30 Scott Foresman Co., textbook 11.94 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 26.S7 1916 Jana. 27 E. H Staubitz, music instruction 10.50 Rose Clark Price, music instruction 10.38 Feb. 19 Omaha News Co., textbook 8.64 W. F. Crossley, dormitory 49.00 City of Ky. Water Works, dormitory 21.18 Midway Gas Co., dormitory 1S.82 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., dormitory 61.75 Kearney Telephone Co., dormitory 10.00 F. H. Schurger, dormitory 10.76 American Book Co., textbook 9.4S G. Schlrmer, textbook 24.18 Ginn &amp; Co., textbook 50.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook 10.00 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbook 25.65 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 17.06 University Pub. Co., textbook 3.36 Denzler-Manuel Furniture Co., dormitory 12.25 26 Rose Clark Price, music instruction 93.62 W. A. Haberstro, music instruction 32.38 E. H. Staubitz, music instruction 7.00 Mar 27 W. A. Haberstro. music instruction 85.75 E. H. Staubitz, music instruction 17.50 April 13 Artificial Ice Plant, laboratory 1.40 The Bobbs-Merill Co., textbook 2.25 Hammonds &amp; Stephens, textbook 5.67 W. B. Sounders Co., textbook «.. 13.86 </seg>
            <seg id="p077">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 77 Lyons A Carnahan. textbook 47.82 Row Peterson * Co., textbook J.6« Sturgis &amp; Walton, textbook 41.20 Columbia College of Exp., textbook 10.87 The Century Co., textbook 25.00 The American Book Co., textbook 19.95 Silver Burdett 4 Co., textbook 2J.51 Glnn &amp; Co., textbook 9.19 The Macmillan Co., textbook 171.27 Gregg Pub. Co., textbook 16.47 Underood Typewriter Co. typewriter 4S.40 Univ. Publishing Co.. textbook 7.20 Houghton MifTlin Co., textbook 31.29 City of Kearney Water Works, dormitory 24.88 Kearney Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., dormitory 62.45 Midway Gas Co., dormitory 18.S1 April 26 W. A. Haberstro, music instruction 99.75 Rose Clark Price, music instruction 63.00 E. H. Staubitz, music instruction 21.61 May 29 W. A. Haberstro, music instruction 102.18 Rose Clark Price, music instruction 48.11 E. H. Staubitz, music instruction 17.50 June 27 W. A. Haberstro, music instruction 144.12 Rose Clark Price, music Intsructlon 98.00 E. H. Staubitz, music instruction 20.13 28 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbook 39.63 Remington Typewriter Co., typewriter . . . 4.15 Yawman &amp; Erbe Mfg. Co., typewriter 64.00 Silver Burdett &amp; Co., textbook 254.75 Vocational Supply Co., textbook 9.6O Manual Arts Press, textbook 8.11 Ky. Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., dormitory 50.89 Midway Gas Co., dormitory 23.11 City of Ky. Water Works so.4« C. J. Burke &amp; Son, dormitory 12.09 Kearney Telephone Co., dormitory 10.00 July 23 W. A. Haberstro, music instruction 207.18 Rose Clark Price, music instruction 124.25 E. H. Staubitz, music instruction jo.ll Aug. 11 McKlnley Pub Co., textbook 9.J4 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbook 9.20 American Book Co., textbook 48.99 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbook 17.74 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook mi The Bobbs-Merrill Co., textbook 56.25 </seg>
            <seg id="p078">78 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Houghton Mlfflin Co.. textbook 118.84 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, textbook 120.86 The Macmillan Co., textbook 32.00 Rand McNally Co., textbook 35.00 A. Flanagan Co., textbook 18.98 Ky. Water &amp; Elec. Pra. Co., dormitory 54.2J Univ. Publishing Co., textbook 20.00 W. C. Lantz, dormitory 8.80 Artificial Ice Plant, laboratory 8.40 City of Ky. Water Works, dormitory 28.58 Midway Gas Co., dormitory ttJI Denzler- Manuel Furniture Co.. dormitory 35.25 Sep. 27 Mrs. Olive Strong, music instruction .... 53.38 Montague Worlock, music instruction . . . Hill Oct. IS The Century Co., textbook „ 21.60 Henry Holt &amp; Co.. textbook L'2.8&lt;&gt; Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbook L'9.40 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbook 9.60 McKinley Publishing Co.. textbook 21.00 The Macmillan Co., textbook 41..12 Ginn &amp; Co.. textbook 39.17 Kearney 'Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co.. dormitory L'7.^0 Midway Gas Co.', dormitory 5.35 W. C. Lantz. dormitory 38.5 Kearney Telephone Co., dormitory 2.50 City of Kearney Water Works, dormitory 12.08 28 Mrs. Olive Strong, piano instruction 113.75 M. Worlock. voice instruction 91.88 Nov. 25 Mrs. Olive Strong, piano instruction 108.50 M. Worlock, voice instruction 93.63 J8.812.M Dec. 1 Amount in fund $5,262.36 LIBRARY. 1915 Amount in State Treasury, December 1, 1914 $ 4,180.00 Feb. 5 Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt 98,332 200.00 Mar. 8 Deposited with State Treasurer. Receipt 99,350 45.00 April 19 Deimsited with State Treasurer, Receipt 100,946 5.00 May 6 Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt 101,679 15.00 July 13 Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt 104,582 2,320.00 Oct. 7 Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt 107,214 815.00 1916 Mar. .3 Deposited with State Treasurer, Receipt 112,015 305.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p079">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 79 July 11 Deposited with State Treasurer. Receipt 117,1*8 .'.340 00 Nov. 7 Deposited with State Treasurer. Receipt 120,711 900 00 tn.l».M DISBURSEMENTS. 1914 Dec. 15 Library Bureau, supplies 15.25 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 21.00 J. R. Holcomb Co., books 13.30 Dodd Mead &amp; Co., books 5.(0 Waldorf Bindery, books 7S.58 Root &amp; Stilwell. printing 9.25 Rand McNally Co., books 17.50 Walter S. Houton, books 101.03 The Boston Book Co.. books 39.12 1915 April 20 Waldorf Bindery Co., books 28.40 Hansen Bennett &amp; Co.. magazines 235.45 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 2.50 Nat'l Eduo. Association 2.00 The Science Press, books 3.00 Neb. State Hist. Soc., dues 2.00 Gaylord Bros, supplies Florence Chandler, books 121.15 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 565.0* June 24 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 1 2.00 Educational Aid Soc. pamphlets 1.00 Florence Chandler, books 90.00 R. L. Polk &amp; Co.. books 6.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co 194.81 H. A. Webbert, printing 4.20 Journal of American History 3.00 Warwick &amp; York, books 10.50 Gaylord Bros., supplies 1 3.60 Aug. 9 The A. S. Barnes Co., books 2.68 Oct. 23 R. L. Polk &amp; Co, books 3.00 Waldorf Bindery Co.. books ' 91.78 A. C. MeClurg &amp; Co.. books 20.06 The Richey Co., books 1 18.00 Dodd. Mead &amp; Co.. books 42.50 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., furniture 40.00 Bee Publishing Co.. subscription 4.00 Dec. 21 Mrs. E. K. McDowell, book 1.75 American Inst. of Child Life, book 5.47 </seg>
            <seg id="p080">80 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Current Events 4.00 H. L. Hayward, books 100.00 Gaylord Bros, supplies 25.40 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co 184.97 1916 Feb. 19 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 458.11 The University Prints Co., pictures 2.40 The H. R. Huntting Co., books 89.18 Hansen-Bennett Magazine Agency 258.30 The Thompson Pub. Co., pictures 2.1S Artemus Ward, book 7.00 Cosmopolitan Print Dept., pictures 3.36 Home &amp; School Art Shop, pictures 17.25 Waldorf Bindery, books 97.53 Nat'l Educ. Association, publication 2.00 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 32.40 The Richey Co., books 1 8.00 Ky Water &amp; Elec. Prs. Co., light 31.40 April U Perry Pictures 8.3S Dodd, Mead &amp; Co., hooks 85.01 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 35.70 Nat'l Conf. Char. &amp; Correct, pamphlet 1.75 Minneapolis Book Exch., books 5.00 0. G. Waffle, books 150.80 Nebraska Hist. Soc., dues 2.00 Waldorf Bindery, books 6.20 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 397.77 Library Bureau, furniture 35.67 E. G. Tunks, books 10.00 Geo. S. Dick, library of cong. cards 26.40 June 28 Review of Reviews, subscription 2.40 Drama League of America, pamphlets... 5.00 Supt. of Pub. Prop., Wis 2.00 The Willard Co., books 1.84 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 20.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 56.94 A. Hospe Co., record albums 3.60 July 1 Baker &amp; Taylor Co.. books 366.32 Aug. 11 Library Bureau, furniture 66.00 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co., books 28.36 Gaylord Bros., supplies 1.00 Ward Bros., books S1.14 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 5.34 The Bee Publishing Co., subscription 3.00 The Willard F. Bailey Co., printing 7.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p081">KEARNEY STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 81 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. furniture 90.00 Kearney Daily Hub, printing 7.00 Oct. 20 George S. Dick, postage 15.00 The Baker &amp; Taylor Co., books 1«.54 Art Metal Construction Co., equipment... 2C0.0O Romeyn 13. Hough, books 87.75 The Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing 2.50 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. furniture 127.50 $5,223.«J 1916 Dec. 1 Amount in fund $5,901.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p082">82 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION PERU STATE NORMAL SCHOOL PERU, NEBRASKA D. W. HAYES. President Peru, Nebraska, December 1, 1916. To the Nebraska State Board of Education: Gentlemen: — I am pleased to submit herewith the biennial report of the Peru State Normal School. This includes a detailed statement of the receipts and expenditures for the biennium up to December 1, 1916, to - gether with an estimate of the funds needed for the next biennium. There is also included a brief outline of the needs of the Peru looking towards it expansion in the sphere of its influence, together with its needs in ma - terial equipment. The year 1916 marks the closing of the first fifty years of Peru's his - tory as a State Institution. Starting as a Methodist Seminary in 18C5, it was turned over to the State of Nebraska and made a State Normal School by the act of the first State Legislature in 1867. Its growth and in - fluence may be measured in a small degree when it is remembered that in that time Peru has grown from a school employing two faculty mem - bers and enrolling but little more than half a hundred students to an insti - tution with a faculty of approximately 40 members and a net enrollment of nearly 1400 students. During this time approximately 30,000 different students have been enrolled in Peru. 2,684 graduates from the advanced courses have gone forth, nearly all of them into the public schools of Nebraska. Some idea of the rapid development of Peru in recent years may be gained by considering the fact that one-half of these graduates have completed their work within the past seven years; and this during a time when the standards of scholarship are at the highest point in the his - tory of the school. The Peru faculty was never better prepared for its particular work than at the present time. Practically all heads of depart - ments have at least the degree of Master of Arts, and all have had a broad, rich experience as school teachers. The President of the school is desirous of expressing to the State Board of Education his appreciation and hearty approval of the methods now employed in financing the State Normal Schools. No one factor has proved of greater importance in broadening the scope of the State Normal Schools' usefulness than the present method of financial support. While the 85-100 of a mill levy may not provide for all the buildings that may be </seg>
            <seg id="p083">PERU STATE NORMAL 83 desired, we believe that by rigid economy and a careful method of con- serving the funds that the present 85-100 of a mill will prove adequate for maintaining the State Normal Schools In such manner aa to bring them to a high plane of efficiency. The following is a detailed statement of the enrollment during the biennium beginning with the regular school year, September, 1*14. and ending with the summer school in 1916: Reg. Year S. School Reg. Tear 8. School 1914-'15 1914-'15 1915--16 1»15-'1« Collegiate students in resident at- tendance 418 677 425 «40 Secondary students in residence at tendance 219 196 221 150 Extension students 40 SO 66 20 Study centers . . 65 Totals 665 801 766 810 In elementary training school, not included in the above 153 150 Totals for each year of biennium, counting none twice: 1914-'15 1915-1* College students in resident attendance 834 909 Secondary students in residence attendance S50 33:. Extension (correspondence courses) (0 60 Study center courses 6f. Grand totals 1,244 l.SM In Training School, elementary grades 15S 150 Enrolled the present year, up to December 1, 1916 Collegiate students in resident attendance 389 Secondary students in resident attendance 167 Extension (correspondence courses) 17 Study centers 200 Total 793 1914- f 15 1915-'1« The number of graduates from advanced courses 204 186 Number of students receiving Elementary Certificates.... 86 94 Number of students receiving Life Certificates 181 138 Number of faculty members teaching full time, (excluding office fore* and assistants), 39. </seg>
            <seg id="p084">84 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE SCHOOL The following brief statement will indicate something of the ideals which should reasonably be expected to be attained within the next few years. In many of these points Peru has already reached these ideals. The Peru State Normal School has never lost sight of the purpose for which it was established; namely, the training of teachers for the public schools of Nebraska. It has ever strived to meet the growing needs of Nebraska's schools by furnishhing, so far as its faculty and equipment would permit, teachers for the different departments of the public schools of the State. Until a dozen years ago there was no other State institution which made any pretense of training teachers for the public schools. Hence, Peru was called upon to furnish many of the city superintendents, high school principals and high school teachers, teachers for the grades, and rural teachers. Peru is still called upon to meet these various requirements of the public schools. It was her mission to set the pace for professional training of teachers, and it is within the scope of her ideals to continue one of the leaders in this grand and noble work. There are needed an - nually at least 600 new teachers in the high schools of the State. It is entirely beyond the power of the University to furnish tenchers to meet this annual requirement. To do so would mean an annual enrollment of at least 3,000 teachers. In fact, at least one or two State Normal Schools will need to bend every effort to assist in the preparation of these teachers if Nebraska is to maintain her place in the field of education. In addition to this, at least 1,300 new grade teachers must be graduated every year in Nebraska in order to fill the ranks of those who drop out of the profession. In addition to this, approximately 2,500 new rural teachers are needed each year. It is needless to say that since at least three-fourths of the money for the support of the State Normal Schools is derived from the country districts the Normal Schools should share in the responsibility for training rural teachers. It is in this direction that the greatest expan - sion of the Normal School should come in future years. Training For Service Believing that a vital part of the training of a teacher is the training which she receives in service, it will be Peru's purpose to increase its use - fulness through its extension department. This will necessitate more liberal expenditures in the development of study centers and correspon - dence work ar begun by the school within the past three years. Rural Department To properly develop our rural education will necessitate a Model Rural School Building that shall be an example of what is expected in ma - terial equipment. To meet the twentieth century ideals in rural school </seg>
            <seg id="p085">I'KKl' STATE NORMAL 85 development, there will ne»d to be ample grounds for agricultural demon - stration punxmes. as well as room for the teaching of the industrial arts to the boys and girls on the farm. Buildings and Material Equipment Peru was started when the State was poor. As a result, the older buildings on the campus are of the make-shift type, and are lacking in the permanency that characterizes the buildings of more recent years. To make Peru a complete plant it will be necessary to include in her building schedule a Science Hall to take the place of the old warped frame structure which has been used for that purpose for the past quarter of a century; the building; contemplated should be of modern fire-proof construction to cost approximately $65,000.00. The old main building constructed over forty years ago should be completely overhauled and made into a modern fire-proof structure. When so remodeled it will accommodate the indus - trial and fine arts of the school, such as manual training, domestic science. agriculture, public school art and public school music, clay modeling, and the music departments. It will also furnish rooms for the literary organ - izations. The cost will be approximately 125,000. 00. Peru's building cam - paign would also include an addition to the dormitory. At the present time only about one- fifth of the girls attending the Normal School are able to secure accommodations at the dormitory. Approximately $40,000.00 will be needed for this purpose. The beautiful chapel which was constructed ten years ago contains a fine auditorium but its usefulness is greatly im - paired because of its poor acoustic*. The proper remedy would be either to construct a second ceiling, or to line the room with some sound-absorb - ing material. The cost would be from $3,000.00 to $4,000.00. Campus Improvement and Addition* There must be added to the present campus at least ten acres of ground for demonstration purposes in connection with the Agricultural and Rural departments. This could well be in connection with the rural dem - onstration school building and would serve not only the agriculture stu - dents of the Normal School in all departments, but would be especially advantageous in the training of the teachers who will go into the rural schools. The roadways belonging to the campus should be paved, thus ending a constant source of annoyance from dust and ever recurring repairs. Peru has a beautiful campus of sixty acres — perhaps the finest natural campus in the I'nited States — but much of it is in such a wild state that it cannot be used. A few thousand dollars expended in clearing out the debris, seeding it to suitable grasses, fencing, and further care would make it one of the beauty spots of America. This should, without question, be </seg>
            <seg id="p086">86 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION a part of the plans for the future development of Peru. Also the time will come when It will be necessary to construct a sewer extending through the town of Peru to take care of the sewage from the Normal School grounds. Approximately $160,000.00 to $180,000.00 will provide for the buildings and other material equipment contemplated in the plans outlined, and will render Peru fit for greater efficiency in the service of the State of Ne- braska. NEED8 FOR THE COMING BIENNIUM The following estimates represent the minimum needs for the bien- nium beginning April 1, 1917: 1. Operation Expenditures — a. Salaries Administration, salaries of president and office force....! 17.7S5.0O Faculty (number now employed) 129,655.00 Assistants 1,100.00 Additional faculty 5.795.00 Employees 15,360.00 b. Administrative expenses, including printing, telegraph and telephone, postage, president's traveling expenses, office supplies, express, drayage, freight, speakers, de - partmental supplies, and extension service 10,050.00 c. Physical Plant. Furniture and equipment, fuel, light, water, general supplies, depreciation and repairs f 23,245.00 Total Maintenance $203,000.00 2. Physical Plant Improvements. Additions, overhauling and modernizing old building. ...$ 25.000.00 Improvement of grounds 10.000.00 Science Hall, if funds permit 65,000.00 Condition of the Appropriation Funds of the Peru State Normal School, Peru, Nebr., December, 1, 1916. SUMMARY OF MAINTENANCE FUND Salaries of president and office force for biennium $ 15,185.00 Salaries of faculty members for biennium 115,140.16 Salaries of employees for biennium 11,963.03 Total cost of other services, as speakers, etc 381.68 Total cost of record books and printing 1,962.99 Total cost telegraph and telephone 335.31 </seg>
            <seg id="p087">87 PERU STATE NORMAL Total cost postage 1 ,071.42 Traveling expense of president (4«.1« Total cost office supplies, etc 1.2M.M Total cost freight, dray and express 1.7M.12 Total cost departmental supplies 1.127.11 Total cost extension work 1W.JT Total cost furniture and equipment 2,407.61 Total cost fuel 1 l,41$.0l Total cost light «0».»4 Total cost water 1.55J.M Total cost general supplies 2,520.77 Total cost depreciation repairs 2,8(0.(1 Total cost additions physical plant Ml.M Total cost Improvement grounds 807.17 MAINTENANCE FUND. Halanre December 1. 1»14 •. *25,M8.»» Appro, ir ation of Biennium beginning April 1, 1915 1-"."'M.OO Kalance December 1, 1914 $25,188.98 1914 Korameycr Co., electrict supplies $ 97.59 Dec. 17 Milwaukee Dustless Brush Co., brushes.. 24.00 Monarc i Palr.t Co.. carb. roof paint 58.84 Neb School Supply House, crayons 24.60 S. W. Hacker, cards, etc 24.50 J. Hanlon. plastering 15.00 Ralph M. Hill, assist in laboratory 4.S0 S \V. Hacker, 4 sets leaflets, cards 8.00 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense S4.55 Freeport Gas Mach. Co., mantles, globes 3.70 F. M. Gress, trav. exp., extension 1.1 2 Wm. Gaertner &amp; Co., phy. lab. apparatus 115.(0 Crane Co., supplies for power house 37.51 Cudahy Refining Co., engine oil 31.78 D. Donovan &amp; Son, sup., general repairs. . 26.17 Fisher Bros., supplies for office, etc 80.90 W. E. Burrelle, grading 8.50 Rose B. Clark, trav. exp., extension 7.t« H. O. Cole, supplies general repairs 10.38 W. W. Barnes, glass and general repairs 17.05 Alamo Engine &amp; Supply Co., castings .... ».*0. R. J. Armstrong, grading park road 15.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p088">88 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Fred J. Gilbert, work cleaning dormitotry 44.30 Maker Hros. Engraving Co., cut new bldg 3.T.". Lynns-AHiis Co.. supplies for power house 103.7.' Sunderland Much.. Supply Co.. supplies... 71.94 Standard Oil Co.. machine gas 58.12 Rand McXally 14.8(1 H. E. 1 'attersun 2.65 R. D. Overholt, Reg:., cash adv.. postage. f reisht. etc 214. R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv.. postage. fre'ght. etc R. D. overholt. Res., cash ad\ .. |&gt;ostag*\ freight, etc 32.4 .i Meek Lumber Co., lbr.. Janitor's cottage.. 3S1.»« Root &amp; Stilwell. printing 1-0.' 0 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 1.178.03 I* R. I). ( )verholt. Reg., sal. pay roll. Dec. • 5.998.86 F. M. Ivers. hauling coal 98.62 i:u Feb. 1 R. D. Overholt. Reg., sal pay roll Jan. 5.927.66 F. M. Ivers. hauling coal 104.61 Fel R. D. Overholt. Rf-g., sal pay roll Feb. 5.S44.96 F. If. Ivers, hauling coal 150.58 April 1 R. D Overholt. Reg., pt. Mar. sal., pay roll 4.091.16 Balance Aprii 13. 1915 12.S2 $25.3X8. !&lt;S 25.388/ 8 MAINTENANCE DEFICIENCY 1913-15. Paid From General Fund. April 21 R. D. Overholt. bal. Mar. salaries, pay roll $1,875.00 N P. Donovana &amp; Son, «up. for power house 31.2" Sunderland Mach. &amp; Sup. Co.. hale waste 13.13 Y. Michel, hauling cinders 10.S0 Korsmeyer Co.. lamps, electric supplies . . 79.02 Clark Bruce, tuning pianos 4.00 W. W. Barnes, supplies for gymnasium S.35 R. D. Overholt. Res;., cash adv. laundry, supplies, etc 35.64 Root &amp; Stilwell. printing 12.28 Standard Sanitary Mfg. Co.. repairs 13.97 Standard Oil Co.. gas machine gas S8.19 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Supply Co.. repairs.. 23.36 </seg>
            <seg id="p089">PERU STATIC NORMAL 89 Irl \V. Wright, bubbler drinking fountain 4.50 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 1,543.22 1 111 |&gt;&lt;-rl:i 1 I'nlilishini; Co., hup. psych, lab... 15.00 Im|&gt;erial Hrush Co., janitor's brushes..-. 4."&gt;.^0 F. M. Ivers. hau!iiiK coil 49.28 H. W. Johns- Man ville Co.. cement for power house, etc 38.07 Kewanee Koilder Co., end bars 8.00 Korsmeyer Co., electrical supplies 7.50 Joaeph Kolar. meat fi&gt;r domestic science.. 4.58 W. W. Mardis. groceries domestic science 7:'.'i Meek Luml*-r Co.. lbr. for repairs, etc.... 17.M The J. i.. Mott Iron Works, rprs. fountain 12.50 Chas. H. Miller, net brain stem and spinal cord 8.00 Mid-West Electric Co.. electrical supplies 20.00 Xebr. School Supply H. desk, bookcase, etc. 44.71 Orr &amp; Lockett Hdw. Co.. man. train, equip. 123.74 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. freight. dray, express 68.67 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. postage... 260.71 R. D. Overholt, Rep., cash adv. telephone, laundry 10.06 B. E. Armstrong, hauling: 19.20 Willard F. Bailey Co., printing bulletins.. 108.06 Willard F. Bailey Co.. printing bulletins.. 74.8S Rose B. Clark, trav. exp., extension T.»:' J. C. Chatelaine, clock and repairs 7.00 H. O. Cole, snow scoops and nails 3.70 Crane Co., supplies for power house 51.11 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense 107.52 S. W. Hacker, printing 7.35 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co.. festival music 16.62 F. M. Gregg, traveling expense 9.62 Fisher Bros., sup. gen. repairs, office, etc. 55.56 Earl Fisher, Treas., Vil'age of Peru, water rent 601.88 Imperial Brush Co., janitor's brushes 43.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. laundry, telephone, etc 69.24 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 969.51 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. freight, dray, express 56.68 Cudahy Refining Co., oil 78.25 Total t 6.715.65 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">90 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION MAINTENANCE Biennium Beginning April 1, 1915. Appropriation biennium beginning April 1, 1915 $180,000.00 April May 28 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, Apr. payroll. $ 6.015.7S 28 R. D. Overholt. Reg., salaries. May payroll 6.042.76 F. M. Ivers, hauling coal 126.66 Clarence Hyslop, carrying mail Apr., May 6.00 June 28 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, June payroll 6,821.46 Nebr. School Supply H., bookcase, etc... 58.J1 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 1,095.(4 Warren E. Burrelle, hauling cinders, etc.. 55.65 H. O. Cole, nails and trowel j.75 T. O. Crawford, labor on grounds 26.00 Cudahy Refining Co., engine oil 11.00 Culbertson &amp; Bedell, ribbon diplm's, etc. 9.S7 D. Donovan A Son., repair supplies 38.60 L. R. Eastman, Bus. Mgr., 50 Peruvians... 100.00 Roger Geib, work on drawing tables S6.00 Homer C. House, trav. expense, extension 25.88 Lyons Atlas Co., lifting hook g.77 F. M. Ivers, work on athletic field 6.00 Magic City Printing Co., printing 85.50 W. W. Mardis, Dutch cleanser, matches.. 9.76 Meek Lumber Co., shingles 102.28 A. J. Morley, tuning grand piano 5.00 Narraganset Machine Co.. supplies phys. training dept 56.31 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co., lumber drawing tables, etc 318.50 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. telephone, laundry, etc 65.7 J R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. stamps and envelopes 166.80 R. L. Polk &amp; Co., one Nebr. Gazetter 6.00 Root &amp; StilweM, pr.nling state ex. paper 27.50 C. H. Stoelting Co.. physical lab. supplies S.45 Taylor Instrument Co.. 1 sPhysmomometer 25.00 H. P. Whitmore. framing two pictures . . 4.C0 L. S. Wislcn. labor on grounds 33.00 Claud E. Hutchinson, roll top desk 20.00 Fisher Bros., office and model school sup. 179.00 Aug. 6 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries. July pay roll 6.068.1,3 12 H. O. Kenaston. 50 hours labor 10. 00 </seg>
            <seg id="p091">FERf STATE NORMAL 91 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. telegrams and telephone 35.8S J. I. Jolcomb Mfg. Co., liquid soap ... 11.25 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense S5.7O F. N. Dorland, oil 1.25 S. W. Hacker, printing 12.25 Joe Glasgow, labor drawing rm. equipment 46.00 Roger Oeib, labor drawing rm. equipment 46.00 Dixie Feary, Asst. in German Dept 11.70 Culbertson &amp; Bedell, groceries, dom. sci. 4.81 Central Scientific Co., laboratory supplies 112.26 R. D. overholt, Reg., cash adv., freig.it drayage and express 112.70 E. J. Newman, filling In diplomas, certifi - cates, eta 51.60 Scott-Omaha Tent tt Awning Co.. rent on tents • (.00 K. (&gt;. Polzel. spec'al police service (.25 D. Donovan A Son, general repair supplies 28.05 Sunderland Bros. Co., supls. athletic field 69.50 Standard Oil Co.. gasoline, and oil, etc., 8.15 R. D. overholt. Reg., cash adv. rural school special, etc 2«7.98 F. L. Whitney, repairing sewing machines 8.00 Sunderland Much. &amp; Supply Co., supplies 224.08 Neb. School Supply House, wall map. Asia 9.82 Milwaukee Corrugating Co., ga!v. shingles (.10 Meek Lumber Co., general repair supplies 1.(5 The Korameyer Co., sup. for elec'iers., etc. 132.(2 Sunderland Miich. &amp; Supply Co., supplies 19.00 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., dip. and certificates 201.25 Earl Fisher, Treas., water rent to July 1,15. (1.04 Cudahy Refining Co., oil M.45 George Bros., invitations to corner stone laying 8.50 27 R. D. Overholt. Reg., salaries Aug. pay roll 1,212.00 Sep. 27 Oct. 25 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries Sept. pay roll 6.101.50 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries Oct. pay roll 6,199.21 Cudahy Refining Co., floor oil 19.80 Cornell-Searl Co., chower baths 115.20 G. M. Cole, repairs on campus 100 00 H. O. Cole, repair fiippHes 5 70 Elizabeth Cleland. exp. buying equipment 4.17 Chaa. H. Ditson &amp; Co., music 17.M W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., microscope* 261.10 </seg>
            <seg id="p092">s: STATE BOARD OF EDLCATIOX Wm. Warnock, cabinet for psj chology rm. 64.00 T. E. Vance, library and office supplies... 7. TO Frank Tobler. work on gen. repairs, etc.... 90.00 Sunderlanri Ala i. A: Supply Co.r supplies 49.5 Sunderlam! Mach. &amp; Sup. Co.. 2 sets grates 1X0.00 Standard • til I'o.. gas machine gas 12/3 Standard Oil Co., gasoline and oil 9.05 F. C. Smith, for state fair exhibit 20.22 Sherwin-Williams Co., agri. supplies 3.60 Rudse * CJuen«el Co.. furniture office of Dean of Women 98.20 E. A. W. Rowles. stools for drawing room 18.23 Queen-Gr&gt;iy Co., steep ta^e chain 7.30 The Frederick Host Co.. man. trn'g. sup... 111.10 The Prang Co., pottery models 10.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv., freight. drayage, and expresM 76. 2T* R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv.. freight. drayage and express 76.16 R. U. Overholt. Rep., cash adv. telephone.. 27.20 Buff * Buff Mfg. Co., marking pins. etc.. 3.11 W. E. Burrelle, hauling cement, team work 68.12 Bausch * Lotnl) Opt. Co., balopticon, etc.. 226.30 Baker Bros. Rng. Co.. cuts for catalogue... 12.15 The Willard F. Bailey Co.. cat. and envlps. 261.95 N. O. Nelson Mfg. Co.. pressure tank closets 220.00 The Nemaha County Herald, stock sheets 35.00 Omaha Hardwood I.br. Co.. lbr. man. trng. 73.75 Orr &amp; Lockett Hdw. Co., supplies man. tr. 113.08 J. W. Armstrong &amp; Son., repair gutter, tr. building 188.15 Midland Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass 7.62 Meek Lbr. Co., lbr. general repairs, etc 80.43 W. W. Mardis. Bon Ami. etc 3.30 Magic City Printing Co., envelopes 11.00 The Korsmeyer Co.. electrical supplies.... 2S.24 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. band instrs. 133.03 Clarence Hyslop, mowing park 24.00 Loyd Hays, work on general repairs 60.00 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 17.M S. W. Hacker &amp; Co., printing 1».«5 Haskins Brothers Co., soda ash «.4O Fisher Bros., supplies for repairs 119.08 D. Donovan &amp; Son., nails and galv. iron.. 8.72 D. Donovan &amp; Son. supplies for repairs... 32.27 </seg>
            <seg id="p093">PERU STATE NORMAL 93 Culbertson &amp; Bedell, rib. for diploma., etc. 5.58 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. stamped envelopes, etc 313.24 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies.. 31.(4 Nov. 30 R. D. Overholt. Reg., salaries, November Payroll 6.308.10 Dec. 24 R. D. Overholt, Re., salaries, December payroll 6,295.00 :o W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., laboratory supplies 14.«7 Warren Webster &amp; Co., water-seal motor 48.00 L'nited States Gypsum Co., plaster parts.. 2.48 D. Donovan &amp; Son., supplies 43.05 Fairbanks, Morse &amp; Co., scales 150.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 1.830.98 Western Electric Co., copper wire 62.18 H. O. Cole, supplies 19.86 Crane Co., power house supplies 14.10 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co., music, festival 51.42 Crane Co., power house supplies 10.66 Crane Co.. power house supplies 29.01 P. W. Carr, walnut wood 56.10 Willard K. Bailey Co., printing bulletins.. 84.04 T. O. Crawford, labor 2.00 Cambridge Botanical Supply Co., lab. sup. 28.80 Culbertson &amp; Bedell, groceries dom. science 10.00 Cudahy Refining Co., engine oil 11. 00 Hardy Furniture Co., furniture 63.73 Fisher Bros., supplies 8.38 Baker Bros. Engraving Co., 2 cuts 8.70 F. M. Ivers, hauling coal 209.85 Imperial Brush Co., brushes and dusters.. »l.go D. W. Hayes, traveling expense 104.88 The Lincoln, Fine Arts Shop, framing pic - ture 7.50 The Korsmeyer Co., electrical supplies 12.»7 The Kny-Sheerer Co., specimen Jars 7.00 W. H. Jewell, weighing coal 6.50 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., music 3.20 Meek Lumber Co., lumber repairs, etc.... 33.47 The McGraw Co.. lamps 68.1 9 E. J. Newman, plates and slides 4.88 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. telegrams, telephone 27.80 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 14.08 Midland Glass &amp; Paint Co., wire glass.. I. 9.42 </seg>
            <seg id="p094">94 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. freight, dray, etc 41.02 The Plant Study Co., laboratory supplies.. 8.00 Sunderland Machinery &amp; Supply Co., pow - er house supplies 14.17 Standard Oil Co., gas machine gas 41.30 Root &amp; Stilwell, printing circulars 7.70 Richards &amp; Conover, repairs 5.41 Earl Fisher, Treas., water rent 28.0S 1916 Jan. 20 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, January payroll 6,120.10 Feb. 19 C. H. Congdon, chart rollers 4.S2 Fisher Bros., supplies 8S.60 Clark Bruce, tuning pianos 5.00 Mrs. Emma YecK, cleaning gymnasium... 6.00 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 1,485.31 Ward's Natural Science Establishment, model ear 15.00 Ward's Natural Science Establishment, model spinal cord 35.00 IT. S. Tent &amp; Awning Co., gymnasium seats 131.79 Sunderland Machinery &amp; Supply Co., pow er house supplies 46.76 Hayden Standley .oil, etc 16.25 Standard Oil Co., gas machine gas, etc.... 53.93 T. R. Simpson, labor 60.80 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, screens 7.00 Frederick Post Co., drawing boards 6.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. postage and supplies 80.62 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. telephone, freight, etc 81.3S R. D. Overholt, cash adv. exp,. freight, etc. 213.78 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 32.29 Nemaha County Republican, printing cata - logs, etc 111.76 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10. 00 Meek Lumber Co., lumber, repairs 39.09 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 47.56 W. W. Mardis, supplies 13.90 The Kearney Hub, printing vouchers 33.75 H. W. Johns-Manvtlle Co., supplies 13.44 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., instruments, music 25.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p095">PERU STATE NORMAL 95 F. M. Ivers, hauling coal M.01 Irwin Hopt, agriculture supplies 27.40 D. W. Hayes, traveling expenses 61.83 S. W. Hacker, printing 20.45 M. E. Good, supplies 21.21 Joe Glasgow, stove for manual training... 4.00 Wm. Gaertner &amp; Co., laboratory apparatus J2.75 Frankel Display Fixture Co., triplicate mirror 28.45 O. L. Duncan, labor 42.00 D. Donovan &amp; Son, supplies, repairs, etc... 2S.55 A. B. Dick &amp; Co., mimeograph supplies... 2.65 Cudahy Refining Co., oil 26.00 Crane Co., power house supplies 109.06 H. O. Cole, power house supplies 7.60 Colglazier &amp; Landolt, toilet paper 82.40 Central Scientific Co., apparatus 9J.8O W. E. Burrelle, labor 12.40 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., Menissus condenser 5.60 W. W. Barnes, supplies 78.80 C. L. Barnhouse, 30 "Educators" 6.00 Baker Bros. Engraving Co.. 1 cut 2.93 Emil Ascher, music 4.00 American Commercial Corp., mail sack 4.29 Feb. 25 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, February payroll 6,287,30 Mar. 20 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, Mch. payroll 6,306.40 April 12 J. A. Hays, expense to Omaha 3.40 F. M. Ivers, red cedar poles 8.00 F. M. Ivers, hauling coal 243.10 The Korsmeyer Co., electric supplies 95.82 National Refining Co., valve oil 27.00 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 37.67 Jacob North &amp; Co., printing stationery. . . 148.00 Office Equipment &amp; Supply Co., cards.... 13.80 L. R. Parriott. making cabinet 43.30 The Perolin Co., of America, boiler comp'nd 140.00 Harry Porter, office supplies 11.20 A. R. Scott, llus. Mngr. Normalites 115.00 T. R. Dimpdon, labor 10.00 Standard Oil Co., gas machine gas....... 35.S4 Underwood Typewriter Co., duplicator 33.15 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co.. coal N7.S5 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 2"&gt;.«9 </seg>
            <seg id="p096">&lt;&gt;•; STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION American Surety Co., of N. Y., bond 12.50 liaker Bros. Engraving Co.. half-tone 4.60 The Willard F. Bailey Co., pig. bulletins.. 158.95 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co.. net weights, etc. 27.54 W. E. Burrelle, labor 7.50 Central Scientific Co., supplies 76.40 Cornell-Searl Co., closets • 80.58 Crane Co., repair supplies 37.83 Cudahy Refining Co., engine oil 17.60 Cudahy Ileflniner Co., engine oil 11.00 Culbertson &amp; Bede'.l, supplies 12.06 W. X. Delzell. irav. expense, extension... 5.86 Henry Disston &amp; Sons 14.45 D. Donovan * Son. supplies 27.10 O. L.. Duncan, labor 27.00 George E. Ellis, silverware and dishes 46.05 Earl Fisher, Treas.. water rent 351.62 Eureka Supply Co., paper towels 11.58 Earl Fisher, Treas., shortage on water rent 84.65 Fisher Bros., supplies 44.50 M. E. Good, groceries (l'imcsti ■ science... 10.30 S. W. Hacker, printing 42.40 J. I. Holcomh Mfg. Co., liquid soap 11.00 R. D. ( ivorhi.lt. Reg., cash adv., freight. etc 193.88 R. D. Overholt. Reg., oash adv. supplies... 60.X6 D. \V. Hayes, traveling expenses 107.33 April 21 R. D. Overholt. Reg.. April sal. pay roll... 6.256.45 May 25 R. D. overholt, Reg., sal. May i&gt;ay roll.... 6,376.68 June 27 R. D. Overholt. Reg., sal. June pay roll.... 7,254.60 28 \V. W. Barnes, supplies 26.33 Bnusch &amp; Tx&gt;mb Opt. Co., cover glasses... 4.19 J. D. Bishop, section P. O. boxes 10.00 Buff * Buff Mf«. Co., surveying tools .... 6.40 C. H. Congdon. rollers and pulleys 7.60 V. I'. Caproni &amp; Bros., modeling casts.... 11.62 Courtis Standard Tests, edu. meas'mts . . . . 17.81 A. B. Dick &amp; Co., stencil paper 3.72 I&gt;emocrat Prtg. Co.. pamphlet cases 7.41 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co.. music 21.10 Mrs. Elizabeth Crawford, trav. exp., extn 5.40 Arta Draper, janitor Honey Creek school .. 13.50 D. Donovan &amp; Son. supplies 22.18 Wm. Gaertner &amp; Co., sl&gt;ectrometer 46.00 Fisher Bros., supplies 7.15 </seg>
            <seg id="p097">1'KRU STATE NORMAL. S. \V. Hacker, printing 55. IS Federal Steel Fixture Co., locker 100.44 The Win. B. Duck Co., electrical supplies 18.75 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense M.7S The J. W. Jenkins Sons Music Co., music. . ».1X F. M. Ivers, hauling coal 117.1* Imperial Brush Co., janitor brushes 84.00 Meek Lumber Co.. repair supplies 164.40 The McGraw Co., lamps 4J.J0 The M. C. Lilley Co., band uniform* 95.00 E. J. Newman, tilling in dip. and certif. 27.53 Office Equipment and Sup. Co., oak cabinet 25.&lt;0 The Nemaha Co. Herald, panoramic views IS. 00 N*. &lt; &gt;. Nelson, pressure tank closets 11.00 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 Neb. School Supply House, supplies 28.1» National Refining Co., floor oil 88.55 National Assn. Audubon Societies, charts 4.50 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Supply Co., supplies 44.39 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Supply Co.. supplies 84.50 Hayden Standley. oil 5.00 E. I. Rouse, traveling expense 14.99 Standard Oil Co., perfection oil 9.08 Scott-Omaha Tent and Awning Co., rent on tents 14.00 Rand McNally &amp; Co., maps 7.00 J. W. Pepper &amp; Son, music 12.18 Frederick Post Co.. supplies 15.15 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. supplies . . 137.99 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. supplies .. 188.62 L. Weasel's Sons C, ribbon 7.00 Whitebreaj't Coal and Lbr .Co., coal 1.023.2* Teachers' College, charts 4.00 W. W. Mardis. supplies 6.1« Meek Lumber Co., repair supplies 65.00 D. Donovan &amp; Son, repairs 27.05 July 23 R. D. Overholt, Reg., July salaries (,843.50 Aug. 11 S. W. Hacker, printing 22.75 T. E. Vance, toweling «.2O The UnJ. Publishing Co.. class books 25.00 Sunderland Mach. &amp; Supply Co., rep. sup. 77.4T Standard Oil Co., gas machine gas 40.97 F. C. Smith, water rent to July 1, 1916 309.85 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash freight, dray etc 329.58 R. D. Overholt, Re«.. cash adv. freight. </seg>
            <seg id="p098">98 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION drayaife. etc 162.43 A. J. Nystrom ft Co., German pictures.... 9.00 E. J. Newman, filling diplomas and certf. 12.96 National Refining Co., engine oil 17.10 Milwaukee Dustless Brush Co., cleaners 30.00 Meek Lumber Co., lumber 6.94 W. W. Mardis, Dutch cleanser 3.65 Rosa V. McWilliams. shrubs 10.00 J. Kolar, meat for domestic science 5.80 H. Hallenbeck. belt lacing 3.00 D. W. Hayes, traveling expense 42.23 D. Donovan &amp; Son, repair supplies 11.20 Cudahy Refining Co., engine oil 14.00 Crane Co., repair supplies 10.80 H. &lt;"&gt;. Cole, repair supplies 21.65 B. R. Cole, labor 45.25 L. F. Chard, 100 Peruvians 200.00 E. P. Carey, livery to demonstrat'n schools 5.00 Fisher Bros., repairs 36.06 Aug. 30 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, August pay - roll 1,297.00 Sep. 23 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, September payroll 6,631.«0 Oct. 19 F. C. Smith. Water Com'ss'n'r, water rent 125.31 F. C. Smith, state fair exhibit and work manual training 122.13 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. freight, dray, etc 440.72 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. postage, etc. 43.33 Royal Typewriter Co., one typewriter 50.00 E. L. Rouse, traveling expense 1S.78 Laurance Rouse, mowing campus 39.80 Rand, McNally Co., maps 7.40 Omaha Nebraskan, advertising 6.00 J. Wm. Ogg, moving man, training shops 30.00 K. J. Newman, post cards, etc. for state fair exhibit 13.25 Nemaha County Republican, printing J75.88 Nebr. Buick Auto Co., bolt meter, battery 35.0« Narraganset Machine Co., manoumeter . . . 9.09 Missouri Inter-State Paper Co., paper 10.14 G. &amp; C. Merriam Co., 2 dictionaries 21.80 Meek Lumber Co., repair supplies 4.74 C. B. Mapes. work 48.75 Magic City Printing Co., printing 63.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p099">PERU STATE NORMAL 99 Carroll Lewis, work mo win* campus 15.00 S. W. Hacker, panoramic views IS. SO E. E. Fricke, work 42.50 Fisher Bros., blue print paper, etc 51.95 D. Donovan A Son, manual training sup - plies and repairs 11.98 A. B. Dick * Co., paper and Ink 1.79 Davoe &amp; Raynolds Co., modeling tools .... (.07 Crane Co., supplies SS.C1 Colglazler &amp; Son, pipe Clenao 10.44 Cambridge Botanical Supply Co., biology supplies S.90 Central Scientific Co., biology supplies.... 43. SO Oct. 23 R. D. Overholt. Reg., part salaries. October payroll 2,465.40 Nov. 25 ft. D. Overholt, November salaries 6,698.30 Dec 1 Balance 42.031.54 $180,000.00 »180,000.0« INTEREST ON ENDOWMENT FUND Oct. 23 R. D. Overholt, Reg., salaries, part of Oc- tober payroll :..% 4.271.00 INSTITUTION CASH Summary Institution Cash Fund. Receipt*. Total received for dormitory S 3,624.25 Total received domestic science laboratory 4S1.2S Total received manual training 997.J0 Total received physical science laboratory 2SS.2S "total received biology laboratory 608.50 Total received agriculture laboratory M.OO Total received textbook rental 5.890.13 Total received typewriter rental 505. 6* Total received piano rental and private music 4,041.05 Total received sale of property S71.M Total received extension work 170.00 Tota lrecelved training school 1,501.82 Total received elocution JM.25 $18,851.14 Expenditures. Total cost of textbooks $ 5.0W.9* </seg>
            <seg id="p100">100 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Total cost water, light, fuel at dormitory 2,489.37 Total cost dormitory furniture 455.22 Total cost dormitory repairs 762.76 Total cost domestic science supplies 562.92 Total cost of manual training 1,018.25 Total cost physical sciences 704.90 Total cost biology 256. J4 Total cost agriculture 101.04 Total cost typewriting supplies 601.55 Total cost music fees and private music 4,104.07 Total cost training school supplies 1,086.17 Total cost from sale of property 173.56 Total cost elocution 40.00 Total cost extension work 50.00 $17,480.14 Balance December 1, 1914 $ 6.14S.62 1914 Dec. 9 Sent state treasurer S66.07 Dec. 17 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks $ 56.20 Thomas Charles Co., model school supplies 45.36 Culbertson &amp; Bedell, groceries dom. science 28.01 C. H. Congdon, pitch pipes 4.64 Atkinson, Mentzer &amp; Co., textbooks 20.00 }•:. C. Atkins &amp; Co., repairing saws 9.70 W. W. Barnes, vlctrola, records, etc 125.84 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.. textbooks 46.80 M. E. Good, groceries for dom. science.... 2.87 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 84.08 Fisher Bros., model school and manual tr. supplies 34.10 Emerson College Publishing Co., textbooks 4.20 Emerson College Pub. Co., textbooks 8.75 Chas. H. Ditson, music for glee clubs 8.36 Chas. H. Ditson, music for glee clubs 11.06 W. W. Mardis, groceries for dom. science 5.59 L. E. Knott Apparatus Co.. lab. apparatus 6.70 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., music for band and orchestra 31.94 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbooks 59.68 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks 56.80 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 14.40 Kffie Ellis Perfleld, keyboard charts 3.00 A. N. Palmer Co., material for penmanship </seg>
            <seg id="p101">PERU STATE NORMAL 101 classes 20.58 Oxford University Press, textbooks ».*) J. A. Parks Music Co.. music dee clubs... 3.81 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. work with textbooks Hit Nettie Meyer, 87 H per cent tuition private lessons 8«.OO Chas. E. Merrill Co., textbooks 47.S1 Meek Lumber Co, lbr. for man. training. . 11. 52 Chas. Scribner's Sons, textbooks 8.36 Scott Foresman A Co., textbooks 28.84 C. H. Stoelting Co.. laboratory supplies... 12.42 C. H. Stoelting Co.. galton whistle 8.12 Rand McNally Co., textbooks 9.60 Sunderland Machinery &amp; Supply Co., steel for manual training; 11.13 Row, Peterson aV Co., textbooks 36.00 T. E. Vance, combine ts for dormitory..... 5.00 St. Louis Biological Laboratory, lab. sup. 1.76 Rita Thomas. 87 H pet. private piano les. 100.00 University Pub. Co., record sheets H. S 6.00 Silver, Burdette Co., textbooks 28.80 John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.. textbooks 15.23 Whltebreast Coal &amp; Lumber Co., coal 807.72 Clarence Hyslop, salary dorm, mail Dec... 3.00 Dec. 19 1915 Jan. 15 Sent state treasurer 301.12 Feb. 1 Clarence Hyslop, Jan. salary dorm. mail... *■** Feb. 6 Sent state treasurer 1,432.3" Feb. 22 Clarence Hyslop, Feb. salary dorm. mail.. 3.00 Mar. 3 Sent state treasurer 492.83 April 3 Sent state treasurer 286.S6 April 12 Clarence Hyslop, March salary dorm, mail 3.00 April 26 Culbertson &amp; Bedel], groceries dom. science 40.11 Standard Oil Co., gas machine (as 51.10 H. C. House, traveling expense 5.68 The Normallte, "Normalites" 100.00 L. L. Mardln. oil 3.03 Remington Typewriter Co., carriage 1J.T5 D. C. Heath &amp; Co.,textbooks li.tO P. C. Hay den , rubber stamps music dept. . . 4.50 M. EL Good, groceries for dom. science 6.04 Olnn &amp; Co., textbooks 71.61 Fisher Bros., kindergarten supplies 4.45 Chas. H. Ditson * Co.. festival music 67.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p102">102 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Wm. B. Duck Co.. aeroplane model for manual training ~ . . . . 3.25 Central Scientific Co., phys. lab. apparatus 185.85 L. C. Smith ft Bros. Typewriter Co., one typewriter 50.00 Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., textbooks 4.51 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co., typewriter desks... SJ.50 Scott, Foresman &amp; Co., textbooks J.16 Remington Typewriter Co., rent 5.«0 The Prang Co., textbooks 16.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. lab. sup. etc 20.05 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. postage 30.00 R. D. Overholt, cash adv. textbooks, etc. . . 29.20 C. H. Condgon, music readers, writing pd». 5.16 Nettie Meyer, 87 1-2 per cent private voice voice lessons 165.00 Meek Lbr. Co., Ibr for manual training.... 40.85 Malay ft Dion, lbr for manual training... 100.15 Manual Arts Press, textbooks 8.36 Macmillan Co., textbooks 326.08 Macmillan Co., textbooks 111.68 Longman, Green &amp; Co., textbooks 87.77 8. C. Johnson &amp; Son, stain, wax, man. tr. 40.65 Houghton. Mifflin Co., textbooks 61.44 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbooks 25.60 Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks 11.25 Whitebreast Coal &amp; Lbr. Co., coal 842.19 Waldorf Bindery Co.. rebinding books 31.50 A. R. Vinneege ft Co., lbr for man. tr 21.J4 T. E. Vance, cabinets for dormitory 13.50 University of Chicago Press, textbooks . . ■ 84.53 Universal Textbooks Co., textbooks 14.55 Underwood Typewriter Co., typewriters .. 60.00 The Prippensee Mfg. Co., typewriters 25.00 Rita Thomas, 87 1-2 per cent private piano lessons 300.00 Homes C. Stokes, meat domestic science . . 5.95 Chas. Scribner's Sons, textbooks 27.84 S. H. Avery &amp; Co., piano rent 156.00 Atkinson, Mentzer &amp; Co., textbooks 3.19 Allyn ft Bacon, textbooks • 14.87 Cambridge Bot. Sup. Co., biol. lab. sup. 18.94 Cambridge Bot. Sup. Co., biol. lab sup. 10.05 Rausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., biol. lab. slip. 5.98 W. W. Barnes, sup. for man. tr. and lab. 11.55 </seg>
            <seg id="p103">peri; state normal 103 American Book Co., textbooks 40. M Cudahy Packing Co., laboratory supplies 1.25 (Jrr A Lockett Hrw. Co., man tr. supplies 71.M Thomas Charles Co.. kindergarten supplies 1C.7* Whitcomb A Barrows, textbooks 20.85 \V. M. Welch Mfg. Co., chem. lab. supplies 120.48 Central Scientific Co., biol. lab. supplies 30.52 Thomas Charles Co.. kindergarten supplies 21.47 Colglaxier A Lanholt. groc.. domestic sci. 105.71 May 3 Sent State Treasurer 25 June 7 Sent State Treasurer June 28 Fisher Bros., laboratory lupplies 7.15 Thomas Charles Co., kindergarten supplies (.54 &lt;&gt;rr &amp; Lockett Hrw. Co.. man. tr. supplies 22.81 Omaha Hardwood Lbr. Co.. lbr for man. tr. 119.33 Nettie Meyer, tuition private voice lessons 235.00 Meek Lumber Co., lbr. for man. training 77.4J Macmillan Co.. textbooks 12.45 Normal E. I.ovcll, accompanist for Miss Meyer 10.60 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 25.»7 Win. Gaertner &amp; Co.. rheostat f .20 M. E. Good, sup. for domestic science 18.74 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. supplies 15.82 The A. N. Palmer Co., paper 4.00 The A. D. Benway Co., dormitory furniture 61.17 Helen Chase, tuition private violin lessons 30.00 Crescent Machine Co., manual tr. supplies J.70 H. &lt; ). Cole, nails 3.5© D. Donovan &amp; Son, dormitory repairs .... (2.14 American Book Co.. textbooks 114.(0 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co.. music 12.54 W. W. Barnes, model sc'iool, lab. supplies 16.00 The Van Everen Co., book covers 4J.70 1'nderwood A I'nderwood. 18 sterescopes 17.10 Rita Thomas, tuition private piano lessons 235.00 Row. Peterson &amp; Co., charts domestic sci. 12.50 Remington Typewriter Co.. ribbons, rent 17.00 Vena Stahl, tuition private piano lessons.. 35.00 Clarence Hyslop, carrying dorm, mail, June 3.00 July 7 Sent state treasurer 2.5M.U Aug. *&gt; Clarence Hyslop. carrying dorm, mail, July 3.00 Aug. 1 2 Sent state treasurer 12 H. C. Stokes, meat for domestic science... 6.2* Rita Thomas, tuition private piano lessons 47.S2 </seg>
            <seg id="p104">104 STATE BOFJARD OF EDUCATION Sunderland Machinery * Supply Co.. en - gine castings 1S.88 University of Chicago Press, textbooks 15.91 University Publishing Co., textbooks 24.00 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., laboratory supplies 15.50 Vena Stahl, tuition private piano lessons.. 9S.36 Silver, Burdett A Co., textbooks, etc 74.64 Chan. Scribner'8 Sons Co., mod. sch. books 4.77 Nettie Meyer, tuition private voice lessons 139.88 Plant Study Co., laboratory supplies 8.15 Plant Study Co., laboratory supplies 11.27 Henry Holt &amp; Co., textbooks 22.00 R. D. Overholt. Reg., work textbook library 32.75 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 4.44 Newson &amp; Co., model school books 5.04 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., music 7.58 Houghton Mifnin Co., textbooks 48.00 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 47-81 Lyon &amp; Healy. music 10.42 Thomas K. Lewis, cane for man. training 7.28 Joseph Klima, tuition private cornet less'ns 19.25 S. H. A very &amp; Co., piano rent 153.75 American Book Co., textbooks, etc 31.99 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., textbooks 15.00 Colglazier &amp; Landolt, groc. for dom. science 1S.81 Helen Chase, tuition private violin lessons 27.7C C. 8. Brimley, laboratory supplies 5.(1 Fisher Bros., lab. and mod. sch. supplies.. 7.15 Doubleday. Page &amp; Co., textbooks 10.68 The Cudahy P'acking Co., sheep heads, lab. 2.50 Ginn &amp; Co.. textbooks 28.40 Foote Mineral Co., geology supplies 10.50 Cambridge Botanical Sup'ly Co., agric. sup. 9.25 Aug. 27 Clarence Hyslop. dorm, mail, August 3.00 Sep. 17 Sent to state treasurer 7.21 Sep. 27 Clarence Hyslop, dorm, mail, Seutember.. 3.00 Oct. 6 Sent to state treasurer 1.922.27 Oct. 26 C. C. Birchard &amp; Co., song books 16.00 W. W. Barnes, supplies dorm., lab., etc. ... 16.36 American Book Co., textbooks 36.96 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 16.80 Mid West Electric Co., ball, model school . . 2.64 Nettie Meyer, tuition private voice lessons 100.00 Me«k Lumber Co.. dormitory repairs 58.35 Manual Training Supply Co., blue prints.. 8.32 </seg>
            <seg id="p105">PERI" STATE NORMAL, 105 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 166.80 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 50.00 McGray-Hill Co., textbooks 47.W I. yon ft Healy, music 15.40 Lyons &amp; Carnahan, typewriting books .... 4.60 J. Kolar, ice for domestic science S.20 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks 48.00 Hough ton Mifflin Co., textbooks 14.4* Henry Holt Co., textbooks 87.24 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks S8.80 The Gregg Publishing.* textbooks 3.8S M. E. Cook., groceries for dom. science 3.91 Glnn &amp; Co., textbooks 94.J2 Ginn ft Co.. textbooks 98.64 Fred J. Gilbert, cleaning dormitory 12.75 Fisher Bros., supplies 237.97 D. Donovan ft Son, supplies 35.05 W. I.. Davenport, milk for dom. science... 9.8S The Cudahy Packing Co., sheep heads 7.50 C. H. Congdon, pitch pipes 4.(1 Columbia College of Expression, textbooks 14.40 Colglazier &amp; Landolt, groc. for dom. sci. .. 10.91 Thomas Charles Co.. art sup. model school 11.11 The Van Everen Co., book covers 37.62 T. E. Vance, comhlnets, pitchers for dorm. 15.S5 University Pub. Co.. model school books.. 18.24 The University of Chicago Press (8.22 Rita Thomas, tuition private piano lessons 14.09 Vena Stahl. tuition private piano lessons 130.00 L. C. Smith ft Bros. Typ. Co. 1 typewriter 50.00 Silver. Burdett ft Co., textbooks 29.00 Benj. H. San born ft Co., textbooks S5.04 Row. Peterson ft Co.. textbooks 30.00 Remington Typewriter Co.. ribbons 4.00 Rand McNally ft Co.. model school books 5.76 Theo. Presser Co., music 5.49 Peru Canning &amp; Mfg Co.. ice. dom. science 14.15 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies. . 16.17 The Ohio Pottery Co.. modeling clay 4.75 R. T&gt;. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. work in textbook library 40.30 Central Scientific- Co., laboratory supplies.. 1(1.(7 Clarence Hyslop, dormitotry mail for Oct. 1.00 Nov. 3 Sent to State Treasurer 17 Credit from St. Treas., sale of mileage bk. . </seg>
            <seg id="p106">106 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION 23 Clarence Hyxlop. dormitory mail, Nov 3.00 Dec 6 Sent to State Treasurer 342.09 Clarence Hyslop, dormitory mail 3.00 20 Vena Stahl, private piano lessons 180.00 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 6.11 Underwood Typewriter Co., 1 typewriter. . 50.00 Oxford University Press, textbooks 7.20 The A. N. Palmer Co., school paper 7.11 J. W. Pepper &amp; Son, laboratory supplies.. 5.13 Powers &amp; Powers 8.80 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., textbooks 10.45 Rudge A Guensel, desks 37.50 G. Schirmer, music books 3.02 American Book Co., text hooka 1.84 W. W. Barnes, victrola records 50.00 Helen M. Chase, private violin lessons 3.49 Thomas Charles Co., model school supplies 58.68 Colglaxier &amp; L&lt;andolt, groc. domestic sci.... 15.10 The Wm. B. Duck Co., electric supplies... 11.87 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 63.69 D. C. Heath A Co., textbooks 9.92 M. E. Good, groceries for dom. science... 8.58 Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks 13.08 Keuffel &amp; Esser, borer 8.96 W. W. Mardis, groceries domestic science 12.05 Miller and Paine, burlap 7.04 Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons !&gt;5.00 Orr &amp; Lockett Hdw. Co., dado head 8.65 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies.. 26.64 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding books 12.1 0 Scott, Foresman * Co., textbooks 8.45 Clarence Hyalop, dormitory mail 3.00 1916 Jan. 13 Sent to State Treasurer 261.14 Feb. 3 Sent to State Treasurer 1,376.70 19 The University of Chicago Press textbooks 78.81 H. C. Stokes, meat domestic science 3.59 Silver Burdette &amp; Co., textbooks 9.60 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., textbooks 15.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies.. 32.79 Omaha Hardwood L.br. Co., lumber 129.56 Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons 80.00 Meek Lumber Co., repairs 6.87 Manual Arts Press, textbooks 8.44 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 44.95 </seg>
            <seg id="p107">PERU STATE NORMAL 107 The Macmillan Co., textbooks T.M John W. Luce A Co., textbook* M.M Houghton Mifflin Co., textbooks 57.(0 D. C. Heath A Co., textbooks 28.80 The Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks 9.0« The Greeg Publishing Co., textbooks 7.10 Glnn A Co.. textbooks 54.14 Ginn A Co., textbooks 72.51 J. Fischer &amp; Bro., music S.S2 Geo. K. Ellis, domestic science supplies 13.00 Chas. H. Ditson A Co., music 7.89 Culbertson A Bedell, groc. dom. science ... S.58 Colgl&amp;xier &amp; Landolt, groc. dom. science.. 3S.27 H. O. Cole, line for dormitory 19.25 John Church Co., music 3.87 Thomas Charted Co., supplies 26.83 Central Scientific Co.. lab. supplies 104.7* American Book Co., textbooks 3.84 American Book Co., textbooks 19.39 Feb. 25 Clarence Hyslop. dorm, mall for February 1.00 8(7.01 Mar. 4 Sent to state treasurer Mar. 20 Clarence Hyslop, dorm, mail for March 8.00 April 3 Sent to state treasurer 21 CM April 13 S. H. Avey * Co.. piano rent 15(.00 Cambridge Botanical Supply Co., supplies 3.20 Thomas Charles Co., mod. sen. supplies... 33.54 Colglazier &amp; Landolt, groc. dom. science.. 7.38 Eugene Dietzen Co., blue print paper S.tO D. Donovan A Son, supplies 37.70 Ginn A Co., textbooks 12.00 Fisher Bros., model school supplies 5.80 D. C. Heath A Co., textbooks 91.20 Houghton Mifflin Co.. textbooks 20.77 The J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., music 4.(5 S. C. Johnson A Son, stains and wax 27.00 Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons 115.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 17.(9 Remington Typewriter Co., ribbon 4.00 Singer Sewing Machine Co., repairs (.95 Vena Stahl, private piano lessons 175.04 The University of Chicago Press, textbooks 8.99 I'nderwood Typewriter Co.. supplies 14.90 T. E. Vance, groc. domestic science 4.71 The Van Everen Co., textbook covers 84.56 Whitebreast Coal A Lumber Co 839.48 </seg>
            <seg id="p108">108 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION April 26 Clarence Hy slop. dorm. mail. April 3.00 May 3 Sent to state treasurer 344.62 Hay 25 Clarence Hyslop, dorm, mall. May 3.00 June 9 Sent to state treasurer 800.91 June 27 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies.. 31.64 R. D. Overholt, Reft., cash adv. supplies.. 9.82 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 24.S1 The Bobbs-Merrill Co., textbooks 27.00 The Bobbs-Merrill, Co., textbooks 22.27 Silver, Burdett * Co., textbooks 3.23 Row, Peterson &amp; Co., textbooks 3.42 Remington Typewriter Co., repairs 7.20 Frederick Post Co., drawing paper........ 10.00 Western Stoneware Co., modeling clay 6.50 T. K. Vance, combinets and pitchers 22.65 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 135.00 Royal Typewriter Co., typewriters... 170.00 Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons 226.00 The A. N. Palmer Co., paper 9.10 Vena Stahl. private piano lessons 165.00 Scott. Foresman Co., textbooks 4.84 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 16.87 Hough ton MifTlin Co., textbooks 11.77 D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 1.29 A. Hospe Co., kindergarten supplies 10.10 M. E. Good, domestic science supplies.... 5.74 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 74.76 D. Donovan &amp; Son 17.81 Fisher Bros., supplies &gt;.O5 Longmans, Green and Co., textbooks 4.73 J. Kolar, domestic science supplies 5.18 J. W. Jenkins' Sons Music Co., music S.08 Miller &amp; Paine, domestic science supplies 6.75 Miller &amp; Paine, hampers 17.75 Beebe &amp; Runyan, chairs for dormitory .... 73.50 American Book Co., textbooks 3.87 Bennet Oven Co., oven for dormitory 168.00 Central Scientific Co., laboratory supplies 41.11 Thomas Charlea Co., art supplies 5.46 Colglaxier &amp; Landolt, domestic science sup. 28.89 Geo. E. Ellis, domestic science supplies... 5.70 W L. Davenpost, domestic science supplies 9.95 Culbertson &amp; Bedell, domestic science sup. 2.89 Clarence Hyslop. dormitory mail S.00 Meek Lumber Co., coal for hospital 9.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p109">PKRU STATE NORMAL. 109 John Curtis, lumber manual training 10.25 July 7 Sent to State Treasurer 2.185.M 23 Clarence Hyslop, dormitory mail for July.. 1.90 Aug. 2 Sent to State Treasurer 510.04 11 S. H. Avey * Co., piano rent 13S.50 W. W. Barnes, victrola records K.M Cora F. Brundson, teaching expression class 40.00 Thomas Charles Co.. model school supplies 12.88 Cudahy Packing Co.. sheep heads 5.00 John Curtis, lumber 8 J.«0 ('has. H. Ditson, music K.lt Fisher Bros., supplies 12.81 Everett Fraln Co., lumber 41.01 Ginn * Co., textbooks 2».«« Oinn * Co., textbooks 51.36 D. C. Heath Co., textbooks 12.51 Houghton, MilTlin Co., textbooks 6«.0O Paul Kies, private violin lessons 57.11 H. V. Landolt, domestic science supplies.. 23.82 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. typewriting instuctors 4. SI The Macmillan Co.. textbooks 1*5.84 Meek Lumber Co., lumber 30.92 Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons 53.39 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 52.4S The Plant Study Co.. biology supplies 9.00 Remington Typewriter Co., 6 typewriters.. SO.OO Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. hampers 15.20 Ben]. H. Sanborn Co.. textbooks 7.59 Srott Foresman &amp; Co.. textbooks 12.00 Silver, Burdett Co., textbooks SO.OO Vena Stahl. private piano lessons 87.02 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 41.57 Western Biological Sup. Co., biology sup. 13.50 Peru Canning &amp; Mfg. Co., ice 21.71 Irvin Caldwell, dormitory mail Auk. &amp; Sep. 6.00 8ep. 2 Sent to State Treasurer IS. 4* Oct. 4 Sent to State Treasurer 1,874.18 19 Western Stoneware Co.. modeling clay 7.50 Underwood Typewriter Co., commerce sup. 18.81 University of Chicago Press, textbooks.... 65.74 Rita Thomas, private piano lessons 110.00 Silver, Burdette Co., textbooks M.TJ Scott. Foresman Co., textbooks 1 7.28 Royal Typewriter Co., ribbons 7.00 Mrs. M. Pyles, work at dormitory 21.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p110">110 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION The Prang Co., textbooks (.00 The J. A. Parka, music 1.55 The A. N. Palmer Co., model school sup 1».2B R. D. Overholt, Reg., ca»h adv. supplies.. 45.20 Mickel's Nebraska Cycle, records l».5O Nettie Meyer, private voice lessons 125.00 R. M. Medley, papering dormitory $.00 The Macmillan Co., textbooks 170.88 H. U. Landolt, domestic science supplies.. 15.17 Houghton MifTlin Co., textbooks 54.48 Henry Holt, Co., textbooks 40.80 D. C. Heath ft Co SS.CO Gregg Publishing Co., textbooks 7.62 M. E. Good, domestic siience supplies 6.38 Ginn &amp; Co., textbooks 129.43 Everett Frain Co., lumber 6.26 Fisher Bros., supplies 39.23 D. Donovan &amp; Son, mattresses, etc., for the dormitory 67.85 Culbertson &amp; Bedell, supplies dom. sci... 2.52 The Cudahy Packing Co., sheep heads . . . 7.50" Central Scientific Co., laboratory supplies 41.89 Central Scientific Co., laboratory supplies 89.87 W. C. Burgess, domtstic science supplies.. 2.80 W. W. Barnes, dormitory supplies 5.95 Atkinson Mentzer &amp; Co., textbooks 40.00 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 78.00 Oct. 23 Irvin Caldwell, dormitory mail October... 3.00 Nov. 4 Sent to State Treasurer 160.1* M Irvin Caldwell, dormitory mail November 3.00 10 Balance 6,516.62 323,996.76 $23,996.76 LIBRARY. Summary Library Fund, Receipts. Total received for matriculations $5,710.00 Expenditures. Total cost of books and periodicals $5,211.21 Total cost furniture and equipment 156.33 Total cost supplies 1*8.41 Total cost printing and slides 110.95 Total $5,876.89 </seg>
            <seg id="p111">111 PERU STATE NORMAL Balance reported Dec. 1. 1914 *2,«12-M 1914 Dec. 9 Sent to State Treasurer 70.00 10 Democrat Printing Co., library supplies.. J.5I Comatock Publishing Co., books *.»0 H. W. Wilson Co., periodicals 27.00 Library Bureau, library supplies 11.00 J. M. Hansen, Bennett Mag. Agency, mag. subscriptions 1 year 127.90 Ernest Hertzberg A Sons, binding mag 107.17 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 11.25 1915 Jan. 4 Sent to State Treasurer 25 00 Feb. 6 Sent to State Treasurer 40.00 Mar. 3 Sent to State Treasurer 50.00 Apr. 3 Sent to State Treasurer 18.00 Apr. 30 The Baker &amp; Taylor Co.. books «71.76 A. C. McClurg, &amp; Son, books S8.87 H. W. Wilson &amp; Co., periodicals 4.00 Warwick &amp; York ».10 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding 228 vols. . . . 106.00 Union Library Association, books 9. SO State Jour. Co., 2 cop. "State Jour." 1 yr. . . 10.00 Nat. Conf. Charities and Cor. proceedings 2.88 Omaha Daily Bee. 2 cop. sub. 1 yr 8.00 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. supplies . . 10.82 Florence Chandler, "Pedagogical Semi." . . 15.00 Ernst Hertiberg &amp; Sons, binding mag. . . . 17.»7 Himebaugh &amp; Browne, World Best Poetry 12.00 Knights of Columbus, Cath. Truth Com., Cath. Ency 29.00 Julius Kuhlm,an. books 6.83 Leonard Scott Publications. Periodicals . . 4.50 The Mathematics Teacher, books 6.00 May 3 Sent to State Treasurer 5.00 June 28 Dem. Printing Co., pads and cards 8.20 Ernst Hertzberg &amp; Sons, binding mag. . . . 72.25 Library Bureau, catalog cards 18.40 Neil Morrow Ladd Co., books l«.*0 World Publishing Co.. subs. World-Herald 4.00 Teachers College, books 4.50 Oinn ft Co.. books 3.19 Remington Typewriter Co., repairs 2.25 July 7 Sent to State Treasurer 1,101.29 Aug. 12 Sent to State Treasurer 5.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">112 STATK BBOARD OF EDUCATION Aa*. 22 Ga&gt; lord Bros., supplies 4.85 Pac. Hort. Corres. School, pamphlet* 3.34 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding books 21.50 The Boston Book Co., dramatic index .... 3.50 Dodd. Mead &amp; Co.. Encyclopedia 92.20 The Baker &amp; Taylor Co.. books 262.94 W. W. Barnes, sub. to periodicals 22.00 Oct. 6 Sent State Treasurer 920.00 Oct. 26 The Baker &amp; Taylor Co., books 516.76 Democrat Printing Co., supplies 18.10 Gaylord Bros., books S.OO R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. sup., etc... 18.00 Library Bureau, two cabinets 77.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. mag 22.01 The Richey Co., books 58.00 The Universal Binder, binders magazines. 30.00 University of Chicago Press, Jour. Ecology 3.75 Nov. 3 Sent to State Treasurer 10.00 S5.00 Dec. « Sent State Treasurer Dec. 20 Leonard Scott Pub., contemporary 4.50 The Baker &amp; Taylor Co., books 281.83 The Bee Publishing Co., renewal 2 copies.. S.OO Charles W. Clark, books 6.40 Current Literature Pub. Co., books 37.80 N. E. Fain, books 39.60 Ginn &amp; Co., books 4.63 Harvard University Press, measurements. 4.58 Ernst Hertzberg ft Sons Co., binding mag. 97.58 Himebaugh A Browne, books 7.25 Houghton Mifflin Co., books 4.67 The Moore-Cottrell Subsc. Agyc, magzs. .. 339.00 R. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. mag. etc S.38 Harry Porter, manilla folders 3.25 Russel Sage Foundation, meas'mta. scales 3.50 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding books 42.75 The H. W. Wilson Co., books 23.00 German Publication Society, books 60.00 C. H. Stoelting Co., lantern slides 26.95 St Louis Biol. Lab., lantern slides 20.00 Neb. State Journal, renewal. 2 copies 7.00 Missouri Valley Film Co., lantern slides.. 193.61 Midland Securities Co., books 591.28 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., books 26.16 Dr. J. T. Lees, lantern slides 7.50 Democrat Printing Co., supplies 4. JO </seg>
            <seg id="p113">- PERL' STATE NORMAL 113 The H. W. Wilson Co.. booklets 11.21 K. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies 7.42 Harper's Weekly, renewal 4.50 R. D. Overholt. Reg., cash adv. supplies . . 29.21 Remington Typewriter, repairs 6.00 C. H. Stoelting Co.. lantern slides 8.«4 World Publishing Co.. renewal 4.00 1916 Feb. 3 Sent State Treasurer 13S.0O Mar. 4 Sent State Treasurer 10.00 April a Sent State Treasurer 10.00 June 7 Sent State Treasurer 5 00 23 R. D. Oveiliolt, Reg., cash adv. supplies 5.46 T. H. McAllister, lantern slides 22.75 Library Bureau, cabinet for slides 5S.S2 Dodd. Mead and Co., year book 7.20 Democrat Feinting Co., supplies 5.(4 Boston Book Co., dramatic index 4.00 Anna Bernkopf, lantern slides 14.00 St. Louis Biological Laboratory 17.50 The H. W. Wilson Co., readers guide 24.00 The H. W. Wilson Co., reader's guide Suppe 4.00 Henry Malkan, set travelogs 27. SO July 7 Sent State Treasurer 1,615.00 Aug. 2 Sent to State Treasurer 5.00 11 Gaylord Bros., supplies Ml Library Bureau, cards 10.50 G. E. Stechert &amp; Co., books 757.52 Oct. 4 Sent State Treasurer $20.00 19 Teachers Mutual Book Supply Co., books 16.1} Theo. Presser Co., books 8.1 S It. D. Overholt, Reg., cash adv. supplies... 3.87 Nelson Hanno Printing Co., supplies 3.68 Library Bureau, oak base 24.00 Lemcke &amp; Buschner, books 5.47 Ernst Hertzberg &amp; Sons, binding magazines 121.27 Democrat Printing Co., supplies 4.17 Nov. 3 Sent State Treasurer 15.00 Balance November 30, 1916 2.444.07 Total $ 8.322.96 $ 8.322.M </seg>
            <seg id="p114">114 STATE BOARD OK El&gt;i;CATH&gt;N WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL WAYNE, NEBRASKA U. S. CONN, President Wayne, Nebraska, December 1, 1916. To the State Board of Education of Normal Schools. Gentlemen: I am pleased to submit you herewith the biennial report of the Wayne State Normal School. This includes a detailed report of the expenditures during the past two years and an estimate of the needs for the ensuing biennium. The growth of the school has been very gratifying. The most satisfac - tory part of this growth is to be found in the better preparation of those who apply for admission. When the state purchased the Nebraska Normal College the equipment was so poor that very few high school graduates were attracted. The reputation of the place as a school where a short* cheap review course could be had was a positive detriment to the building up of a state normal school. The completion of the Library and Science Hall followed by the completion of the Administration building placed the Wayne State Normal upon an entirely new footing. Since the completion of the Administration building the percentage of the students of college rank has more than doubled This experience has led me to believe that the equipment of an institution must be kept somewhat in advance of the actual needs in order to best serve the interests of the State. Faculty. Practically no change has taken place in the personnel of our faculty since the organization of the school. Each year one or more members of the faculty have asked for a leave of absence in order to prepare them - selves further for their line of work. This policy is encouraged for the reason that it brings new ideas to the institution and keeps the faculty in touch with the* latest advancement in the training of teachers. Within the last four years every member of the training school faculty, including the Dean, has S|&gt;ent from a semester to two years in some eastern professional school. A number of other members of our faculty have also secured leave of absence for study. Without a single exception those who have asked for leave of absence have returned to the institution and have in this man - ner added strength to our already excellent corps of teachers. </seg>
            <seg id="p115">WAYNE STATE NORMAL, SCHOOL 115 Extension of Campus. The grounds contain but ten acres. These should be extended on* block to the west, one to the south and half a block to the east, making an addition of seven and a half blocks. Real estate men who are In a position to know the values of adjacent property, estimate that this extension Would be worth about $30,000. These extensions, together with the croaa streets which the city of Wayne will readily abandon, would give a plat of ground containing about twenty-five acres in all for the Normal School. Inasmuch as all of this property is platted and now contains nine small residences and a number of others will doubtless soon be erected, it is a matter of economy to make this investment now and not wait until the price becomes prohibitive. Part of this added ground should be utilized for a proper athletic field, part of It for demonstration in agriculture and another part should be used as a model rural school ground. Training School The old auditorium building has been fitted up and is being used at the present time for a training school. Inasmuch as the training school is the very thing for which the Normal School stands, a better building should be provided than it is possible to make out of the old building. A modern training school should have large, well-lighted school rooms. In this building there should be provision for Domestic Science and Manual Training for the grades. There should also be a consultation room and a number of class rooms, an assembly room for the junior high school and a recreation room to be used by the children on stormy days. It is impos - sible to make such a building of the present one and for this reason an appropriation should be made of not less than $75,000 with which to con - struct a modern, up to-date training school. Modal Rural School On the grounds, but apart from the main buildings, there should be a school equipped as model for rural schools. In this building there Should be conducted an ungraded school made up of the children from near-by districts. The rural people are ready and anxious to transport their chil - dren to such a school. This would be a sane method for the training of rural teachers, as we would have rural children In a rural school being trained under rural conditions. It would take but a minute's time for the student to go from his regular normal school work to the rural school near at hand. To attempt to have a rural school as a demonstration school In the country makes it so inconvenient that it is practically worthless as a training school for rural teacheds. </seg>
            <seg id="p116">116 8TATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Each year there has been a gradual Increase In the number of special students until at the present time there are nearly fifty special music stu - dents besides about one hundred fifty enrolled in absentia and study center classes. None of these are Included In our regular enrollment. The total cost of the Normal School to the state for everything except permanent improvements during the years 1914-15 and 1915-16 was approximately $120,000. The combined enrollment for these years, not including the train - ing school, special students and study center students, was 1740. This makes a per capita expense of approximately $69.00. The number of graduates for the six years since the state took over the school is in the advanced courses, 3, 23, 33, 42, 50, 61, for the respective years. The number of those receiving the elementary state certificate during the six years is 86. During the entire time we have had a more or less definite organization in the preparatory department which has sought to give elementary preparation for rural teaching. Classes have been organ - ized for these students in Methods and Management for rural schools. They have been permitted to do observation work. Since no certificate can be granted by the school to these students, all who wish to teach secure county certificates on examination. Several hundred have received train - ing in this way since the organization of the school and have gone into the rural schools where they have rendered creditable service. Their suc - cess and our experience with them convinces me that a well organised rural department in the Normal School would render valuable service to the educational interests of the state. Estimate for Maintenance for Biennium 1917-19. Growth of School Year 910-11 Preparatory Secondary Collegiate 173 115 50 Tota 538 1914-15 380 133 289 799 915-16 416 170 355 941 Salaries of faculty and administration f ( 99,800.00 Employees Fuel, water and light Freight, telephone, telegraph, drayage Printing, postage, office supplies Furniture and equipment 10,640.00 13,800.00 2,000.00 2,600.00 9.000.00 Traveling expenses 800.00 Lectures, commencement, special Instruction 1,200.00 Study Center Depreciation repairs 1,600.00 5,000.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p117">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 117 General supplies , 4.000.00 Total $150,240.00 Respectfully submitted. U. S. CONN, President, FINANCIAL STATEMENT MAINTENANCE FUND Summary of expenditures from December 1, 1914, to November 30, 191(. I. Administration — 1. Salaries of president and office force $ 12.29C.jO 2. Other services, as speakers, etc (7(.84 1. Record blanks and printing 1,542.48 4. Telegraph and telephone 278.82 5. Postage 679.92 6. Traveling expenses of president 690. M 7. Office supplies 572.19 8. Express, freight, drayage 1,458.54 n. Instruction — 1. Salaries of faculty members M,»S2.7I 2. Department supplies 1,(11.99 3. Extension work (4.87 IH. Physical Plant— 1. Salaries of employees 8,407.14 2. Furniture and equipment 5,288.50 3. Fuel 5,702.1b 4. Light 1.4(6.(8 5. General supplies 4.08C.52 (. Depreciation repairs 4,799.50 JV. Physical Plant Improvements — 1. Sidewalks and improvement of grounds 1,121.81 Total expenditures f 120,497.07 Transferred to the General Fund 3,939.52 $124,436.59 </seg>
            <seg id="p118">118 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Detailed Statement of Expenditures for the Biennial Period Be- ginning December 1, 1914, and Ending November 30, 1916, As Per Vouchers on File With State Auditor: Balance in fund for biennium beginning April 1, 191S $ 28,045.03 Appropriation for the biennium beginning April 1. 1915 120,000.00 1914 Dec. 11 Clyde Beckner, labor on tunnel J 52.88 H. W. Barnett, dray age 8.75 Willard F. Bailey Co., bulletins 73.41 W. E. Beaman, supplies for dom. science 60.46 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor 47.50 U. s. Conn, advanced for postage 60.37 U. S. Conn, adv. for freight and express. . . 62.83 L'. S. Conn, adv. for freight and express... 73.95 V. S. Conn, advanced for labor 97.29 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 36.06 Crane Company, supplies 148.85 Crane Company, supplies 84.81 H. B. Craven, hardware 117.10 Crescent Machine Co., equipment 311.25 Carhart Hardware Store, equipment 13.00 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., sand, lbr., cement 185.S0 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 12.45 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 52.88 C. A. Fisher, sand and cement 102.82 Freeport Machine Co., repairs 39.00 Gaertner &amp; Beckenhauer, bookcases 81.25 A. G. Grunemeyer, supplies 8.70 A. G. Grunemeyer, supplies 4.35 Heco Envelope &amp; Paper Co., paper towels 12.00 W. H. Hoguewood, hauling coal 168.70 Jones' Bookstore, department supplies.... 24.(1 Kewaunee Boiler Co., grate bars 41.40 W. A. Jones Foundry Co., equipment 88.40 John Lud wickson, hauling coal 152.00 Lyon &amp; Healy, band instrument 4.50 The McGraw Co., copper wire 7.62 The McGraw Co., fuses, sockets, etc 5.49 Marshall Field &amp; Co., playgr'nd apparatus 7.50 Marshall Field &amp; Co., equipment 10.85 National Wood Works, lumber 60.00 Nebraska Democrat, printing 28.50 Nebraska Telephone Co., services 22.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p119">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 119 J. C. Num. brooms, etc 1S.M Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co,, lumber... 15.70 Omaha Sch. Supply Co., pencil sharpeners 4.58 Orr A Morris Co., dom. science supplies... 26. 8 J Frank Powers, drayage 33.50 Leonard Peterson &amp; Co.. tables 164.00 Pittsburg Wireless Equipment Co., equip. 111.40 Platt Iron Works Co., repairs (.SO Harry Porter, office supplies 11.07 Fairbury News, printing 7.50 Rand, McNally &amp; Co., histories 4.80 Rand McNally &amp; Co., globes and maps 32.80 Row, Peterson &amp; Co.. supplies 4.80 Rand. McNally &amp; Co., books 3.20 Theo. B. Robertson Soap Co.. Janitor sup.. 8.80 Root &amp; Stillwell, printing: 3.28 Ralph Rundell, janitor supplies 33.36 , Singer Sewing Machine Co., 2 machines.. 48.00 Standard Oil Co., oil and gasoline 20.10 L. J. Snow, drafting set 18.00 A. G. Spalding &amp; Bros., apparatus 135.24 City of Wayne, electric light service 239.92 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 1,444.17 W. M. Welch Mfg. Co.. certificates 10.5u W. M. Welch Mfg. Co., diplomas 52.50 Henry R. Worthington, equipment 75.00 I". S. Conn, principal's trav. expenses.... 88.65 Teachers and employees. December payroll 3.725.60 II 1915 Jan. 20 Teachers and employees, January payroll 3.806.53 Feb. 20 Teachers and employees, February payroll 3,937.20 Mar. 20 Teachers and employees, March payroll... 3.806.10 April 13 Willard F. Bailey Co.. bulletins 175.90 W. K. Beaman, dom. science supplies 34.73 W. El Beaman. Janitor supplies 5.35 Rudolph Becker, labor on tunnel 7.20 Central Scientific Co., laboratory supplies 119.47 Central Scientific Co.. equipment 137.4« C. A. Chace &amp; Co.. coal 109,56 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 22.21 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 11.11 U. S. Conn, cash advanced 14.71 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 58.49 U. S. Conn, advanced for drayage. postage 49.46 T7 S. Conn, adv. for freight and express... 150.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p120">120 STATE BOARD OF EDICATION U. S. Conn, adv. for freight and expiess... CO. 00 U. 8. Conn, principal's trav. expenses.... 8J.M U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 18.CS U. S. Conn, principal's trav. expenses C7.75 Crane Company, equipment 54.98 Crane Company, equipment 112.81 H. B. Craven, hardware 51.00 J. E. Dennis, labor on grounds 30.38 Draper Shade Co., window shades 72.80 Wm. S. Duck Co., laboratory equipment... 35.54 Educational Bureau, 200 hymn books 104.00 Farwell, Ozmun. Kirk ft Co., equipment... 61. SI Felber"s Pharmacy, laboratory supplies... 4.C0 Fidelity, Casualty Co., bond premium 7.50 A. Flanagan Co., supplies KM Wm. B. Duck Co.. laboratory equipment . . 2S.88 ♦ Furchner, Wendte &amp; Co., sundries 6.85 Glnn &amp; Co., commencement music 9.C0 A. G. Grunemeyer. supplies 5.50 Hammacher, Schlemmer &amp; Co., equipment 25.74 W. H. Hog-uewood, hauling coal 165.70 F. H. Jones, sundries 1S.56 F. H. Jones, victrola and records HuM The Korsmeyer Co., electric supplies 15.89 John Ludwickson. drayage 9.85 l.yon &amp; Healy, band music 5.74 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 18.56 Don B. Mayfleld. extra copies of Goldenrod 100.00 Winnie Meier. assisting in office 7.60 Neva Milner, pianist 1S.C0 J. G. Mines, clocks for training school.... 5.25 Model Pharmacy, laboratory supplies 5.50 Paul Monroe, stereopticon slides 100.00 Nebraska Democrat, printing S2.75 Nebraska Telephone Co., services S4.21 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 44.16 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 52.67 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 10.C8 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 Platte Iron Works Co., repairs 8.00 W. D. Redmond, expense of conference 15.88 Remington Typewriter Co., cabinet ■ 15.00 Remington Typewriter Co., wide carriage machine CC.25 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. 4 doc chairs 8S.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p121">WATNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL. 121 Budge tk Guenzel Co., t desks 66.00 Ralph Rundell, janitor supplies 21.80 E. H. Sheldon &amp; Co., equipment 21.84 Clara Smothers, office assistant 60.76 Wilbur Spahr, labor on grounds 8.10 Standard Oil Co., oil and gasoline 8(.51 Wayne Herald, printing 21.90 City of Wayne, electric light service 575.7* Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 2T1.TS Transferred to General Fund 3.939.52 April 20 Teachers and employees, April payroll.... 3.732.88 May 25 Teachers and employees, May payroll 3,792.00 June 28 Teachers and employees. June payroll.... 4,047.50 W. K. Beaman, dotn. science supplies S4.S1 Central Scientific Co.. laboratory supplies 64.55 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses St. 27 U. S. Conn, advanced for Annual 100.00 U. S. Conn, adv. for freight and express.. 184.07 V. 8. Conn, advanced for sundries 25.80 IT. 8. Conn, commencement expenses 36.50 U. 8. Conn, advanced for labor 263.22 U. S. Conn, advanced for postage 52.43 Wm. B. Duck Co., laboratory supplies 12.41 W. H. Hoguewood, hauling coal 178.40 F. H. Jones, office supplies 22.54 Irvin A. Medlar, stationery 44.00 Nebraska Democrat, printing 21.60 Nebraska School Supply Co., supplies 17.75 Nebraska Teacher, advertising 2 50 Nebraska Telephone Co., services 36.05 Harry Porter, supplies W.83 Root &amp; Stilwell. office supplies 222.85 Rudge &amp; Guensel Co.. furniture 144.55 28 J. R. Rundell. Janitor supplies 33.70 L. C. Smith Typewriter Co., machine 50.00 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 20.85 Thomas Rinehart, plumbing 11.10 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., supplies 22.44 A. Flanagan Co., supplies 27.50 Aug. 4 Teachers and employees, July payroll 4.280.60 9 Abel-Pederson Company, wall paper 10.47 A. G. Bohnert. services 22.30 Lester Bechner, labor on grounds 104.15 Carhart Hardware Co., supplies 54.85 Central Scientific Co., supplies t.M </seg>
            <seg id="p122">122 STATE HBOARD OF EDUCATION C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lbr. and sand UJ.10 Thomas Charles Co., supplies 22.14 U. 8. Conn, advanced to janitor 10.00 U. 8. Conn, advanced for sundries 72.77 U. 8. Conn, advanced for labor 157.11 U. 8. Conn, adv. for freight and express... 91.39 U. S. Conn, advanced for lectures 124.45 U. S. Conn, advanced for postage 68.50 U. S. Conn, Dedication expenses 76.00 Crane Company, supplies 105.86 H. B. Craven, hardware 61.66 C. M. Craven, photographs J0.00 Crescent Machine Co., repairs 4.60 Economy Drawing Table Co., tables 182.4S Farwell. Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., labels 8.49 Felber'g Pharmacy, supplies 5.60 A. Flanagan, supplies 1 J.76 Gamble Hinged Music Co., music 3.66 C. A. Gilson, door plates JO.OO W. H. Hoguewood. dray age 78.40 A. Hospe Co., framed pictures 110.00 E. W. Huse, printing; 20.00 F. H. Jones, onlce supplies 7S.50 F. H. Jones, department supplies 39.10 F. H. Jones, three pianos 676.00 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 87.84 National Wood Works, molding 12.00 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 21.50 Omaha School Supply House, baskets 9.90 Peck &amp; Hills, settees 87.84 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 12.»0 C. H. Stoelting Co., supplies 41.86 University Pub. Co., class records «.12 City of Wayne, electric light 93.60 Ward's Natural Science Establishment, supplies 31.23 Chas. H. Ward, laboratory supplies 12.00 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., kalsomine 22.60 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., floor dressing 196.82 Klug &amp; Heckendorf, cement sidewalks... 900.47 Nebraska Telephone Co., services, 11.20 Nebraska Democrat, advertising 5.30 Orr A Morris Co., supplies 40.90 Tindale Cabinet Co., cabinet 65.00 Teachers and employees, August payroll . . 840.00 </seg>
            <seg id="p123">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 123 SO Teachers and employees, Sept. payroll 4,064.00 Oct. 22 J. J. Ahern, Janitor supplies S1.T7 Willard F. Bailey Co.. catalogs 118.3* Lester Bechner, labor on grounds 121.64 Baker Bros. Engraving Co., halftones 33.15 W. E. Beaman, janitor supplies 3.75 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor 70.01 U. S. Conn, adv. for freight and express. . 83.40 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 44.42 Carhart Hardware Store, hardware 90.15 Crane Company, supplies 62.81 H. B. Craven, hardware 21.48 A. D. Cook, strainer (1.7S Central Scientific Co., supplies 102.S1 J. E. Dennis, labor 115.76 Detroit Publishing Co., booklets 2J.50 Farwell. Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., locks 14.34 A. Flanagan Co., floor brushes 42.25 Frost Manufacturing Co., repairs 19.70 L. L. Gray, plastering 80.10 Gaertner &amp; Beckenhauer, desks 43.50 Geography Supply Bureau, lantern slides 46.80 A. E. Hering, labor 72.26 W. H. Hoguewood, hauling coal 130.85 Houghton, MlfTlin Co.. classics 1 9.20 Jones' Bookstore, department supplies.... 50.81 Keewanee Boiler Co., repairs 13.45 McGraw Company, electric lamps 21.57 Model Pharmacy, laboratory supplies 7.(5 Nebr. School Supply House .toilet paper.. 25.50 Nebr. Telephone Co., services 18.70 Norfolk Daily News, advertising 21.00 Philleo &amp; Harrington, fire-brick clay 137.50 Harry Porter, paper 29.50 Ralph Rundell, janitor supplies 11.26 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Co.. furniture 44.26 Standard Oil Co., oil 6.44 U. S. Conn, sundries 73.97 Sani-septic Disinfecting Co., supplies 8.75 University Pub. Co., class records 9.15 Underwood Typewriter Co., typewriter 50.00 City of Wayne, light service 102.00 Welch Mfg. Co., laboratory supp'lec »5.»3 Welch Mfg. Co., department supplies 53.52 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass 29.49 </seg>
            <seg id="p124">124 STATE BOARD OF EDU CATION F. J. Kloghoft. resetting boiler S17.26 C. A. Chace * Co., lbr., plaster, etc 522.10 23 Teachers and employees, October payroll. 4,231.25 Not. 23 Teachers and employees, Nov. payroll 4.285.60 Dec 18 Teachers and employees, December payroll 4,190.38 J. J. Ahern, janitor supplies 19. 35 Lester Beckner, labor on ground 111.J8 Carhart Hardware Co., equipment 38.60 Carhart Hardware Co., hardware 14.67 Central Scientific Co., supplies 83.99 C. A. Chace At Co., lumber, sand, cement. . 199.00 Clarke's Garage, repairs 9.56 U. 8. Conn, advanced for sundries 46.33 V. 8. Conn, advanced for postage CS.70 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 28.88 U. 8. Conn, adv. for freight and express. .. 116.62 Courtis Standard Tests, education leaflets 4.80 Crane Company, supplies 77.86 Crane Company, tank and heater 116.85 H. B. Craven, hardware 39.00 Crescent Machine Co., saw blades 3.54 A. Flanagan Co., duplicator, etc 10.58 Gasoline Supply Co., gasoline 13.24 Gaertner &amp; Beckenhauer, 8 doz. charts.... 170.00 A. G. Grunemeyer, plumbing supplies 8.30 W. H. Hoguewood. hauling coal 292.40 Jones' Bookstore, office supplies 30.50 Marshall Paper Co., toilet paper 21.00 M. T. Mclnerney, labor on grounds 62.20 Nebraska Telephone Co., services 2S.70 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 20.00 Nemaha County Republican, ptg. bulletins 64.32 Orchard &amp; Wilhelm. art supplies 10.75 Platt Iron Works, p° limbing supplies .... 9.7S Harry Porter, drawing*paper 35.00 Rand, McNally Co., globes and maps..... 132.S1 Ralph Rundell, Janitor supplies 8.50 Singer Sewing Machine Co.. 3 machines.. 76.00 Standard Oil Co., gasoline CCS City of Wayne, light service 252.72 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., floor dressing 80.03 Whitebreast Coal Co., coal 1,532.85 1916 Jan. 25 Teachers and employees, January payroll 4,270.10 Feb. 18 J. J. Ahern. janitor supplies 7.29 </seg>
            <seg id="p125">WAYNE STATE NORMAL, SCHOOL 125 American Multigraph Co., repairs 1.72 Baker Brothers Engraving Co., halftones.. 2C.C4 Buckeye Manufacturing Co.. repairs I.St Carhart Lumber Co., hardware 12.75 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., sand, lumber, cement.. 47.06 Thomas Charles Co.. department supplies 61.(4 C. E. Conger, drayage 14.20 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor 19.74 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 18.42 U. S. Conn, advanced for postage 45.00 U. S. Conn, adv. for freight and express.. M.79 U. 8. Conn, adv. for freight and express.. 20.80 U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 25.25 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 38.38 H. B. Craven, hardware 2.65 Crescent Machine Co.. supplies 5.04 J. H. Foster, brick 9.00 A. Flanagan &amp; Co., dumb bells 11.00 C. A. Gillson, door plates 5.56 F. Gaertner, bookcases 101.80 A. E. Hering, labor 42.1« W. H. Hoguewood, drayage 40.80 Jones' Bookstore, office supplies 6.09 Jones' Bookstore, piano 225.00 Korsmeyer Co.. electric supplies 20.79 McOiraw Company, electric supplies 23.74 Neva Milner. pianist 15.40 J. G. Mines, clocks for Training School... 12.00 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Nebraska Telephone Company, services... 24.S6 Orr &amp; Lockett Co., equipment 25.00 Plttsburg Wireless Equipment Co.. equip. 92.89 Frank Powers, drayage 6.00 Harry Porter, department supplies 30.25 Ralph Rundell. janitor supplies 21.20 Standard Oil Co.. gasoline 10.95 Sunderland Brothers, marble 8.11 Standard Oil Co., gas and gasoline 54.25 Thordarson Electric Co., transformer 31.00 Chas. H. Ward, equipment 81.25 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 28.90 City of Wayne, light service 117.36 Teachers and employees, payroll for Feb. 4,263.75 Mar. 25 Teachers and employees, payroll for March 4,288.00 April 10 J. J. Ahern, Janitor supplies 18.33 </seg>
            <seg id="p126">126 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION LJllie Baum, coal 81.00 W. E. Begman, supplies 32.55 The Boston Store, bird glasses S0.00 Carhart Lumber Co.. supplies 6.75 Central Scientific Co., laboratory supplies 58.42 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lumber, sand, cement 33.00 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 9.39 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor 18.20 U. S. Conn, adv. for freight and express. . . 153.75 Crane Company, supplies 40.65 Economy Drawing Table Co.. stools, tables SS.46 Farwell, Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co., wire 7.9S Flanagan &amp; Co.. inkwells 4.44 The Goldenrod. extra copies furnished 100.00 Herald Publishing Co., advertising 25.00 M. E. Hering, labor 11-83 Hermann Postcard Co., souvenir cards. . . 29.00 W. H. Hoguewood, hauling coal 114.30 Jones' Bookstore, department supplies 26.S7 Mary Meyers, services as nurse 15.00 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 18.97 Neva Milner, pianist 6.00 National Wood Works, furniture 192.00 The Nebr. Democrat, paper and envelopes 16.50 Nebr. School Supply House, supplies 23.00 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Omaha Printing Co., stencils 6.44 Remington Typewriter Co., desk clamps.. 3.10 Robbins &amp; Meyers Co., motor set 282.40 U. S. Conn, advanced for postage 62.02 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 9.94 Roberts' Drug Co., turpentine, etc 7.15 Nebraska Telephone Company, services.. 25.80 Ralph Rundell, janitor, supplies 11.10 Standard Oil Company, oil and gasoline... 30.67 S. R. Theobald &amp; Co.. supplies 7.25 Herald Publishing Co., printing bulletin . . 66.00 Whitebreast Coal Company, coal 957.57 U. S. Conn, advanced for extension work. . 55.00 26 Teachers &amp; Employees, April pay roll 4.237.75 May 20 Teachers &amp; Employees, May pay roll 4,184.75 June 28 Acme Roll Printing Co., catalog envelopes 99.10 J. J. Ahern, Janitor supplies 4.79 W. E. Beaman. supplies 83.59 Gordon Bechner, labor on grounds 23.17 </seg>
            <seg id="p127">WAYNE STATE NORJtAL SCHOOL 127 Lester Bechner, labor on grounds 13.50 Carhart I-br. Co., clover, blue grass 12.50 Carpenter Paper Co., supplies, toilet paper 20.00 Central Scientific Company, supplies 72.86 Thomas Charles Company, supplies 14.01 U. 8. Conn, advanced for sundries 42.67 U. S. Conn, adv. for Baccalaureate sermon 50.00 U. 8. Conn, advanced for postage 54.57 U. S. Conn, adv. for freight &amp; express 40.58 U. S. Conn, advanced for postage 52.85 V. 8. Conn, traveling expenses 14.14 C. E. Conger, drayage 7.05 Courtis Standard Tests, supplies 32.J5 Crane Company, supplies 79.01 O. W. Crossland, shrubbery plants 22.00 H. H. Hahn, board meeting expense 11.62 K. Henderson, auto hire 9.50 Wayne Herald, printing 87.95 A. E. Hering. labor on grounds 20.00 W. R. Hoffman, equipment 42.00 W. H. Hoguewood. drayage 76.75 Huse Publishing Co., grade records 52.25 Kearney Daily Hub, printing vouchers 18.00 Neva Milner. pianist 56.25 Nebraska Democrat, printing 26.25 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 5.00 Nebraska Telephone Company, services . . . 25.91 Harry Porter, mimeograph paper 17.00 Standard Oil Company, gasoline, gas 49.46 Mrs. A. Sherbahn, demestic science laundry 5.45 Taylor-Holden Company, drawing paper. . 10.70 Herald Publishing Co., printing bulletins.. 99.20 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., supplies 63.09 28 Teachers &amp; Employees. June pay roll 4.S27.5O July 2S Teachers &amp; Employes, July pay roll 4.42S.25 Aug. 8 J. Ahem, janitor supplies 31.82 W. E. Beaman, supplies 46.64 Thomas Charles Co., art supplies 85.23 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 39.7J U. S. Conn, traveling expenses 2S.18 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor 44.75 U. 8. Conn, adv. for freight and express.. 50.70 U. 8. Conn, advanced for Senior Annuals 125.00 Clarke's Garage, repairs 4.90 C. H. Congdon, readers 2.16 </seg>
            <seg id="p128">128 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION H. B. Craven, hardware 128.25 Carhart Hardware Store, hardware 58.45 Carpenter Paper Co., toilet paper 20.00 Central Scientific Co., supplies 18.85 Aug. 8 Central Scientific Co., laboratory supplies 22.60 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., coal, lumber 65.30 J. E. Dennis, salary as fireman 55.00 Gasoline Supply Co., oil and gasoline 22.60 Frank Gaertner, furniture 82.50 W. H. Hoguewood, drayage 35.50 Jones' Bookstore, office supplies 61.90 Jones' Bookstore, department supplies 67.60 Korsmeyer Co., terminal lugs 4.13 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 17.66 Nebraska Telephone Co., services 30.98 The Nebraska Democrat, printing 5.25 The Nebraska Teacher, advertising 10.00 Omaha Nebraskan, advertising 6.00 Harry Porter, examination paper 32.50 Roberts' Drug Co., supplies 5.25 Ralph Rundell, janitor supplies 7.50 Standard Oil Co., gasoline 38.39 Teachers' College, education tests 4.15 University Pub. Co., class records 24.10 Welch Manufacturing Co., diplomas 203.34 Ward's Science Kstab., supplies 30.00 Herald Printing Co., printing 13.65 30 Principal and employees, salary for August 870.93 Sep. 26 Teachers and employees, salary for Sept. 4,167.00 Oct. 9 J. J. Ahern, Janitor supplies 7.36 Bee Publishing Co., advertising 6.90 Carhart Lumber Co., hardware 10.54 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lumber, cement, plaster 204.30 Chesterman Company, equipment 132.60 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 20.26 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor 34.30 U. S. Conn, advanced for postage 77.81 U. 8. Conn, expense of State Fair booth... 28.20 U. S. Conn, advanced for extension work.. 9.76 U. S. Conn, adv. for freight and express... 62.62 Crane Company, supplies 23.88 Cudahy Packing Co., soap polish 1.00 A. G. Grunemeyer, plumbing supplies S.20 A. K. Hering, labor on grounds 18.55 W. H. Hoguewood. hauling coal 7S.20 </seg>
            <seg id="p129">WAYNE STATE NORMAL. SCHOOL 129 Huse Publishing Co., advertising 21. 0* Kearney Dally Hub, printing bulletin.... 111.00 The McGraw Co., electric supplies 31.95 Nebraska School Supply House, chairs... 138.00 Nebraska Telephone Co., services 25.5&lt; Omaha Structural Steel Works, beam.... 28.30 Omaha School Supply Co., supplies 135.40 On- &amp; Orr Co., janitor supplies 12.30 French I'enn, labor on grounds 13.50 Theo. B. Robertson Soap Co., Janitor sup. 42.17 Standard Oil Co., oil 15.30 G. H. Thompson, hauling coal 75.M City of Wayne, light service 84.32 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., glass and paint 56.73 R. L. Will, drayage «.7O 24 Partial payroll for October 2,033.35 Nov. 28 Payroll for November 4,400.00 Nov. 30 Balance 23,608.43 (148,045.02 $148,045.02 LIBRARY FUND Recpt. Balance December 1, 1914 % 2,725.17 1914 Dec. 31 Matriculation fees, December lsu.uo 1915 Jan. 31 Matriculation, fees. January 305.00 Feb. 28 Matriculation fees, February 10.00 Mar. 31 Matriculation fees, March 15.00 April 30 Matriculation fees, April 26.00 June 30 Matriculation fees, June 1,1(5.00 Sep. 30 Matriculation fees, September t&gt;3u uo Oct. 31 Matriculation fees, October 30 00 Nov. 30 Matrciulatiun fees, November 110.00 Dec. 31 Matriculation fees, December 30. )0 1916 Jan. 31 Matriculation fees, January 450.00 Feb. 29 Matriculation fees, February JO J»0 Mar. 31 Matriculation fees, March 16.00 June 30 Matriculation fees, June 1,315.00 July 31 Matriculation fees, July 10.40 Sep. 30 Matriculation fees, September 6 35 Oct. 31 Matriculation fees, October 10.04 </seg>
            <seg id="p130">130 8TATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Nov. SO Matriculation fees, November 30.00 Tota! * 7,880.17 Disbursements 1*14 Dec. 11 Grumiaux Subscription Co.. magazine list. I 165.55 Library Bureau, equipment 9 50 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 14S.58 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books 105.85 1915 April 13 Boston Book Co.. reference books 271.00 V. S. Conn, advanced for books 17.66 Democrat Printing Co., equipment 5.95 Norman A. Forsyth, equipment 197.40 Grumiaux Subscription Co., magazine list 12.05 Ernst Hertzberg &amp; Sons, bind'g periodicals 45.03 Krnst Hertzben? &amp; Sons, bind'g periodicals 5.75 George J. Hess, equipment 25.00 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 479.97 Nebraska State Journal, subscription 5.00 Norfolk Daily News, subscription 3.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding periodicals.. 4.19 Harry P. Whitmore, framed pictures 162.50 Omaha Daily Bee, subscription 3.00 June 28 Library Bureau, library supplies 12.10 PoIk-McAvoy Company, directory 6.00 Aug. 9 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 262.27 Oct. 22 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 8.29 Dodd. Mead * Co., Year Book 6.30 Charlotte M. White, magazine list 185.65 Dec. 18 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 39.89 1916 Feb. 18 U. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 16.67 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 349.15 Nebraska State Journal, subscription 3.50 Norfolk Daily News, subscription 3.00 Omaha Daily Bee, subscription 3.00 Waldorf Bindery Co., binding periodicals.. 78.66 H. W. Wilson Co., readers' guide 8.00 World Publishing Co., subscription 3.00 April 10 American Book Co., reference books 10.28 D. Appleton &amp; Co., Year Book 3.00 Library Bureau, equipment 10.15 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co., reference books 52.60 </seg>
            <seg id="p131">WAYNE STATE NORMAL. SCHOOL 131 Harry P. Whitmore. framed picture* 1*0.00 Chaa. Scribner's Sons, reference books.... 74. OB June 23 Dodd. Mead A Co., reference books 92.00 Library Bureau .equipment 100.00 A. C. McClurg A Co., reference books 12.56 Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons, encyclopedia ■ ■ ■ • 96.00 Chas. Scribner's Sons, reference books 11.80 O. O. Waffle, reference books 189.70 Waldorf Bindery Co.. binding 8.65 Harry P. Wliitmore, equipment 21.60 Auk. S Hazel Hoobler, reference books 4.98 A. C. McClurg &amp; Co.. reference books 51.01 Dodd, Mead &amp; Co., Year Book 5.»7 O. Broes Van Dort Co., reference books... 16.55 M. E. Hoobler, reference books 3.95 Oct. 9 Lincoln Fine Arts, statuary 89.25 A. N. Marquis &amp; Co., reference books.... 5.00 Musical Blue Book Corporation. Blue Book 4.00 Sioux City Journal, subscription 3.00 The Tribune Company, subscription 3.00 Charlotte M. White, magazine list 185.65 Balance November 30, 1916 4,006.37 $ 7,8*0.17 INSTITUTION CASH FUND Summary of Cash Receipts from December 1, 1914, to November 30, 1916 1 . Dormitory roomrent $ 9,325.55 Laboratory — a. Domestic Science 369.05 1). Manual Training 1,110.12 o. Physical Science 250.09 d. Biology 140.00 e. Agriculture 22.0« 3. Textbook rental 2.579.04 4. Typewriter rental 292.2.1 5. Piano rental 213.00 6. Rent or sale of property 1,620.39 7. Extension work 16.00 Total receipts $16,437.40 </seg>
            <seg id="p132">132 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Detailed Statement of Receipts For the Biennial Period Beginning December 1, 1914, and Ending November 30, 1916 Receipt!. Balance December 1, 1914 I 2,065.64 1914 Dec. 1 W. P. Canning, et al., commercial blanks.. COO 3 Elizabeth Klngsbury, collected, broken lights 4.40 F. H. Benshoof, kindling 1.00 4 John C. Alexander, textbook 1.10 Foster-Barker Co., refund on bond 1.50 7 A. E. Hering, lost key .50 10 W. P. Canning, commercial blanks . .45 16 A. W. Christensen, textbook .85 22 Rudolph Becker, textbook .86 31 Dormitory roomrent for December 204.30 Textbook rental for December 54.50 Manual Training fees for December 54.30 Laboratory fees for December .76 Typewriter rental for December 7.00 Piano rental for December 175 1915 Jan. 2 J. J. Coleman, sewer connection 22.50 5 Walter Scott, et al., textbooks 1.30 9 Rachel F. Fairchild, textbook 1.10 18 U. S. Conn, rental on residence..., 185.00 25 Clarence Lin ton, et al., textbooks S.50 30 J. G. W. Lewis, collected from students . . . 32.95 31 Roomrent for January 992.16 Textbook rental for January 86.00 Manual Training fees for January 108.15 Laboratory fees for January SO. 75 Domestic Science fees for January 16.00 Typewriter rental for January 17.00 Piano rental for January 7.00 Feb. 2- J. M. Wiley, collected for books 4.50 S Hudson Tidrick, broken light .50 8 J. C. Alexander, et al., textbooks 5.15 S J. J. Coleman, collected for music 8.25 27 George Denkinger, kindling 2.95 28 Dormitory roomrent for February 190.S0 Textbook rental for February 17.65 Manuarl Training fees for February 104.50 Laboratory fees for February .50 </seg>
            <seg id="p133">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 133 Typewriter rental for February 6.60 Training School tuition for February 4.50 Piano rental for February 2.00 Mar. 6 Ralph McAtee. textbook 45 8 Raymond Deuel, et al., commercial seta... 8.80 31 Clara Hajek, textbook 1.06 George Denkinger, lumber 1.50 Roomrent for March 308.00 Textbook sales for March 16.16 Textbook rental for March 1.00 Manual Training fees for March 1 15.00 Laboratory fees for March 2.00 Typewriter rental for March 9.50 Piano rental for March 4.00 April 1 August Chinquist, et al., textbooks 5.41 M J. P. Riddle, 23 tons of coal 115.00 29 John McTee. broken panel 1.50 SO George Denkinger, kindling 1.75 Roomrent for April 171.90 Textbook sales for April 7 00 Textbook rental for April 14.00 Manual Training fees for April SS.06 Typewriter rentad for April 11.00 Piano rental tor April ;.00 May 17 J. P. Fitch, lumber 10.00 26 E. J. Huntemer, lumber 2 00 27 F. Q. Dale, lost key .50 31 Edith Stocking, textbook .75 Roomrent for May 494.55 Textbook rental for May 149.50 Textbook sale for May 61.60 Textbook fines for May 2 .3u Manual Training fees for May 45.M Laboratory fees for May 2.25 Typewriter rental for May 4J.0O Piano rental for May 11.26 June 7 Luella Bush, et al.. textbooks 11.80 9 C. L. Wright, et al., textbooks 1.25 T. H. Britell, collected for breakage 8. JO 11 Peter Baker, kindling 1.00 14 C. L. Wright et al.. textbooks 2.45 16 George Denkinger, coll. for broken lights.. 1.50 21 Olive Stinton, et al.. textbooks 6.70 James Garrett, lumber 5 60 30 Roomrent for June 1,042.(0 </seg>
            <seg id="p134">134 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION tl Library fines 12.40 Textbook rental for June 421.25 Domestic Science fees for June H.OO Laboratory fees for June 11S.SS Manual Training fees for June. 24.25 Typewriter rental for Jane 7.50 Piano rental for June 26.50 July 5 lva Sala, et al., textbooks 4.90 Laboratory breakage 4.90 Dormitory roomrent for July 17.80 Textbook rental for July 44.35 Manual Training fees for July S2.90 Piano rental for July 3.50 Sep. 1 Earl Schroer, broken panel .50 3 J. P. Riddle, lumber 288.10 7 U. S. Conn, rental on residence J77.50 8 E. B. Franske, wireless apparatus 37.00 16 Howard James, et al., bookkeeping sets... 4.50 30 Roomrent for September 1,146.20 Textbook rental for September • 273.00 Domestic Science fees for September 12.25 Laboratory fees for September 110.75 Typewriter rental for September 14.00 Piano rental for September 8.00 Oct. 12 Mrs. J. M. Hart, kindling .75 29 H. H. Hickman. sewer connection 22.50 tl Roomrent for October 14.00 Textbook rental for October 9.00 Manual Training fees for October 34.05 Laboratory fees for October .75 Typewriter rental for October 1.00 Piano rental for October 7. 00 Nov. 18 A. L. Dragon, lamp 1.00 20 W. A. George, credit on mileage book 3.35 30 Roomrent for November 87.40 Textbook rental for November 69.19 Manual Training fees for November 51.45 Typewriter rental for November 1.00 Piano rental for November 1S.0O Dec. 2 J. J. Coleman, music books S.00 31 Anna B. Bright, library lines 4.»1 Roomrent for December 112.80 Textbook rental for December 7.00 Manual Training fees for December 60.95 2J Bessie Lauman. textbook .50 </seg>
            <seg id="p135">WAYNE 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL 135 Piano rental for December 191S Jan. 31 Agnes Finigan. laboratory breakage Anna B. Bright, textbook sale. Roomrent for January 7«7.»« 117.55 7«.07 Textbook rental for January Manual Training fees for January.. Laboratory fees for January Domestic Science fees for January. Tyi&gt;ewriter rental for January J2.00 4t.«« 35.00 ■Ml Piano rental for January Feb. 4 Elmer Bartels, et al., banking sets 7.00 Roomrent for February 411. DO Textbook Library fees for February Manual Training fees for February. Laboratory fees for February Domestic Science fees for February Tyi&gt;ewriter rental for February . I*M 128.85 16.25 35.50 13.2* 10.0« Piano rental for February Mar. 6 BenJ. H. Sanborn, credit on old books 31 Ada Woodruff, et al. textbooks 12.55 Roomrent for March 358.»5 Textbook rental for March Manual Training for March Laboratory fees for March . 23.55 45.40 Domestic Science fees for March. Typewriter rental for March Piano rental for March April 20 N. Eicher. kindling .50 30 Roomrent for April :*-2.*o Textbook Library rental for April. Laboratory fees for April Manual Training fees for April. Typewriter rental for April Piano rental for April .... May 5 F. C. Grant, education leaflets 2 Collections for laboratory breakage. 31 Fred Nyberg, et al., banking sets Wm. Lang, et a!., broken lights. Roomrent for May 687.30 297.44 Textbook Library rental for May. Domestic Science fees for May.... 1 Manual Training fees for May Laboratory fees for May Typewriter rental for May . . </seg>
            <seg id="p136">136 STATE BOARD OK EDUCATION Piano rental for May 14.50 June 14 U. S. Conn, rental on residence 255.00 22.50 U. 8. Conn, electric light service. 17 P. L. Franklin, education leaflets .07 19 8. A. Lutgen, mangel 5.00 SO Sale of Textbooks 6.25 Roomrent for June 1,075.90 Textbook rental for June 551.00 Manual Training receipts for June. Laboratory fees for June 8.00 90.75 Domestic Science fees for June. 24.6: Typewrites rental for June Piano rental for June 17.75 40.50 July 5 J. M. Wiley, heater 25.00 22 Irvin Sala. microscope 4.00 C. F. Lehr, et al., education leaflets. 2.14 24 J. J. Coleman, music books 21.50 28 Peter Hajenga, bookkeeping sets 2.00 29 Library fees 18.97 Laboratory breakage collected 2.50 11 Sale of textbooks for July 7.00 Roomrent for July 47.15 Textbook rental for July 5.00 Manual Training fees for July Laboratory fees for July Domestic Science fees for July Typewriter rental for July . . . MlM 14.00 .65 2.00 Piano rental for July 4.25 Sep. 19 Walter Tidrick, et al., bookkeeping sets... 30 Sale of textbooks for September 6.00 5.88 Roomrent for September 1,229.15 Textbook rental for September 360.66 Manual Training fees for September Laboratory fees for September 46.45 105.75 Domestic Science fees for September. Typewriter rental for September Piano rental for September 90.50 M.76 7.50 Extension work for September. 10.00 Oct. 30 E. J. Huntemer, supply pipe 1.98 Dewey Jewell, et al., bookkeeping sets.. 4.50 SI Textbook sale for October 5.80 Roomrent for October 111.80 Textbook rental for October Manual Training fees for October Laboratory fees for October 4.00 1.75 .n </seg>
            <seg id="p137">WAYNE 8TATE NORMAL SCHOOL 137 Domestic Science fees for October 1 2S Piano rental for October * 00 Extension work for October 4.00 Nov. SO Roomrent for November M.79 Textbook rental for November 8.00 Manual Training fees for November 1.09 Domestic Science_feei for November 1 00 Typewriter rental for November 7.00 Extension work for November 4.M Piano rental for November (.90 Sale of property tor November 1.(2 Total receipts for the biennium * 18,501.04 SUMMARY OF CASH EXPENDITURES FROM DECEMBER 1, 1914, TO NOVEMBER 30. 1916. 1. Textbooks 2. Dormitory — e. Other services and expenses 1,633. SO Z. Laboratory — a. Domestic Science 278.97 b. Manual Training I,14t.l4 c. Physical Science 265.11 d. Biology 141.16 4. Rent or sale of property M9.18 Total expenditures 115,816.8* Detailed Statement of Expenditures From the Institution Cash Fund for the Biennial Period Beginning December 1, 1914, and Ending November 30, 1916, as per Vouchers on File with the State Auditor. Disbursement*. 1914 Dec. 11 J. J. Ahern, supplies $ 17.11 Carhart Hardware Store, supplies U.90 C. A. Chace &amp; Co., lumber &amp; plaster 67.80 H. U. Craven, supplies 28.76 U. S. Conn, advanced for labor 30.20 U. S. Conn, refunds to students 48.SS ooks $ I 2.J16.88 Itory — u Light ). Fuel 1.075.04 2,»»0.1» :. Furniture, etc 1. Repairs 1.816.55 S.821.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p138">138 STATE BOARD OK KDLTAT1ON Gaertner &amp; licckenhauer, rent on pianos.. 52.50 A. El Hering, salary as preceptor 12.50 Katherine Lively, services as matron (5.00 Nebraska Telephone Company, rent 14.40 E. R. Rogers, services 21.50 l.ydia Skiles. services as matron 20.00 Shu'theis Pharmacy, supplies 6.40 Whitebreast Coal Company, coal 440.74 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 18.27 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 64.78 Goodyear- Marshall Pub. Co.. textbooks 8.8» D. C. Heath &amp; Co., textbooks 6.00 The Macmillan Company, textbooks 12.95 Charles Scribner's Sons, textbooks 9,60 Manual Arts Press, textbooks 10.52 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co., kalsomine 9.60 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co., paint 41.40 Remington Typewriter Co.. ribbons 7.00 1915 April 13 V. S. Conn, refunds to students 30.95 H. B. Craven, bows, pitchers 1S.65 Curtis Sash *t Door Co., storm windows. . . . 123.50 Oaertner &amp; Heckenhauer. shades, etc 30.20 Crane Company, plumbing fixtures 50.00 A. E. Hering. services as preceptor 20.00 The Korsmeyer Company, lamps 103.37 Katherine Dennis, services as matron . 60.00 Katherine Lively, service* as matron 81.00 Albert F. Mitzlaff. wardrobes 604.80 Thos. Musselman, services as preceptor.... 20.00 Nebraska Telephone Co.. rental 11.50 E. R. Rogers, salary as preceptor 20.00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel Com|«ny. furniture 60.50 Lydia Skiles, service* as matron 80.00 Whitebreast Coal Company, coal 901.48 A. Flanagan Company, books 6.31 Charles E. Merrill Company, books 6.88 Scou, Foresman * Company, books 4.J2 American Book Company, textbooks .... 9.60 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 126.05 Goodyear-Marshall Pub. Co., invoice sets.. 4.72 Greeg Publishing Co.. textbooks 18.65 D. C. Heath * Company, textbooks ».48 Henry Holt &amp; Company, textbooks 3.S9 Lyons &amp; Carnahan. textbooks 28.80 </seg>
            <seg id="p139">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 139 The Macmillan Company, textbook* «5.78 Chas. Scribner's Sons, textbooks J1.20 Silver, Burdett &amp; Company, textbooks 1».12 University Publishing Co., textbooks 18.00 Row, Peterson Company, textbooks 24.00 Central Scientific Company, supplies 7.51 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Company, lum- ber for Manual Training 104.87 National Wood Works, lumber of Manual Training 277.60 Pioneer Glass &amp; Paint Co.. supplies 9.75 Sioux City Iron Works, iron, coal 4S.89 Orr &amp; Morris Company, supplies 6.85 C. C. Burchard A Company, music books.. - 14. -Hi Goodyear-Marshal! Pub. Co., com. sets .... 23.58 Leonard Peterson &amp; Co.. tables 24S.80 Varsity Supply Company, supplies 22.71 J. P. Riddle, extras on contract 79.90 June 28 John Church Co., music books J.0« IT. S. Conn, advanced for sundries 40.75 Katherine Lively, services as matron 51.00 Manual Arts Press, textbooks 15.«8 National Wood Works, lumber 25.60 Nebraska Telephone Co., services 15.00 Lydia Skileg, services as matron 40.00 City of Wayne, electric light 195.76 Aug. 9 Carhart Hardware Company, supplies 2«.01 U. S. Conn, refunds to students J7.85 Crane Company, plumbing supplies 105.55 H. B. Craven, supplies 9.45 Daisy B. Fletcher, services as preceptor... 10. 00 Mrs. Mary Fox. services as matron 25.00 Gaertner &amp; Becknerhauer, shades, etc 76.00 Eva Graves, services as preceptress 10.00 A. E. Hering, services as preceptor 5.00 Katherine Lively, services as matron .... 2S.80 Bea A. Murphy, services as preceptress. . . . 10.00 Mel Norton, paper hanging 16.S0 J. C. Nuss, dormitory supplies 25.97 E. R. Rogrers, services as preceptor 26.00 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, rugs 24.80 Rudge &amp; Guenzel, latches, etc 57.75 I.ydia Skiles, services as matron 20.00 Western Glass * Paint Company, supplies 11.80 Russel &amp; Irwin Mfg. Co. keys 6.52- </seg>
            <seg id="p140">140 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Nebraska Telephone Company, services . . 6.00 American Book Company, textbooks 12.00 Century Company, textbooks S.JO Funk * Wagnalls, textbooks «.(0 D. C. Heath &amp; Company, textbooks 11.17 The Macmillan Company, textbooks 39.56 A. C. McClurg &amp; Company, textbooks 6.63 Row. Peterson &amp; Company, textbooks 11.00 Thomas Charles Company, supplies 44.03 Lewis Institute, supplies 8.98 National Wood Works, lumber 123.50 Omaha Hardwood Lumber Co., lumber 6.50 W. E. Beaman. supplies 14.58 Remington Typewriter Co., ribbons 16.50 Underwood Typewriter Co., 3 machines . . 150.00 Underwood Typewriter Co., ribbons 7.00 Gaertner A Beckenhauer, piano rental . 78.75 Oct. 22 Crane Company, supplies tt.lt Mrs. George Denkinger. cleaning ha'.U 15.00 Felber"s Pharmacy, supplies 7.75 Mrs. Mary Fox, services as matron f 1.10 Farwell, Ozmun, Kirk * Co., locks 11.00 Gaertner &amp; Beckenhauer, furniture 68.46 Mrs. Emma Hart, services as matron 55.80 A. E. Hering. services as preceptor 7.50 Model Pharmacy, supplies 48.26 Nebraska Telephone Company, services . . 9.80 Orr ft Morris, Co., curtains 23.36 Roberts' Drug Company, alabastine' 4.05 Western Glass &amp; Paint Company, paint .. 60.85 City of Wayne, electric lights 76.16 C. A. Chace * Company flooring 99.90 C. Classen, carpenter work 36.00 John Bingold, painting 81.15 N. O. Nelson Mfg. Company, repairs 9.50 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks S9.C0 American Book Company, textbooks 111.36 Glnn &amp; Company, textbooks 153.97 D. C. Heath &amp; Company, textbooks 97.20 Henry Holt &amp; Company, textbooks 3.87 The Macmillan Company, textbooks 128.00 Manual Arts Press, textbooks 15.85 Newson &amp; Company, textbooks 39.17 Charles Scribner'u Sons, textbooks 14.40 Silver, Burdett * Company, textbooks -ii.Tfi </seg>
            <seg id="p141">WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL 141 Sioux City Iron Company, iron, etc 23.40 Levi B. Walker, laboratory supplies 7.20 Ward's Natural Science Estab., supplies.. 64.80 W. E. Beaman. supplies 7.11 C. L. Barnhouse, music books 8.40 John W. Evans, tuning pianos 10.00 James C. Stitt, services as architect 95.00 25 Salaries for October 36.50 Nov. 2S Salaries for November S7.00 D»c 18 Salaries for December »1.00 TJ. S. Conn, refunds to students 12.50 Nebraska Telephone Company, services... 1100 J. C. Nuss, brooms 39.3S Whitebreast Coal Company, coal 985.99 Gaertner &amp; Beckenhauer, wardrobes 35.55 Nebraska Democrat, blanks 1.25 Roberts' Drug Company, supplies 6.0S Farwell, Ozum, Kirk &amp; Company, supplies 12.71 Sioux City Iron Company, supplies 8.20 Dec. 18 W. E. Beaman. supplies 21.50 American Book Company, textbooks 12.40 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 54.24 Henry Holt A Company, textbooks 15.56 Hinds &amp; Noble, textbooks 2«.4O Silver, Burdett &amp; Co., textbooks 11.52 W. B. Saunders &amp; Company, textbooks . . . 101.94 Frank Gaetner, piano rental 42.00 Lyon &amp; Healy, music supplies 15.41 Lyon &amp; Healy, music supplies 17.84 A. A. Chance, laying brick M.70 Hydraulic Brick Company, brick 98.12 W. O. Hanssen, laying brick 10.50 Philleo &amp; Harrington, brick and mortar . . . 32.00 Carhart Hardware Company, hardware . . . 78.10 National Wood Works, lumber for man. tr. 189.50 John Sherbahn, brick 80.00 Frank H. Thielman. carpenter work 21.60 1916 Jan. 25 Salaries for January 75.00 Feb. 18 Carhart Lumber Co., pitchers, basins 1.15 U. S. Conn, refunds to students 12.86 H. B. Craven, supplies 16.J5 The McGraw Company, Mazda lamps 68.90 Nebraska Telephone Company, services... 12.00 Pioneer Glass ft Paint Company, paint . . . 36.54 </seg>
            <seg id="p142">142 STATE BOARD OF EDUCATION Rudge * Gueniel Company, blankets, etc.. 80.00 City of Wayne, electric light 249.12 Houghton. MifTlin Company, supplies (.48 Olnn &amp; Company, textbooks 8.00 The Macmillan Companay, textbooks 74.48 Manual Arts Press, textbooks 32.96 A. C. McClurg &amp; Company, textbooks 19.98 BenJ. H. Sanborn Company, textbooks S0.24 The German Store, supplies 12.S6 Mrs. A. Sherbahn. laundry for dom. scl. .. . 4.30 TV. E. Deaman, supplies 49.19 National Wood Works, lumber 46.28 Central Scientific Company, supplies 59.98 Underwood Typewriter Company, ribbons 7.00 Remington Typewriter Co., mach. less exch. 20.00 ("has. H. Ditson &amp; Co., music books 23.94 Goodyear- Marshall Pub. Co., banking sets 31.00 City of Wayne, supplies 42.40 Russell, Irwin Mfg. Company, keys 7.57 Frank Gaertner. furniture 98.20 Salaries for February 109.00 Mar. 20 Salaries for March 95.60 April 23 Nebraska Telephone Company, services . . . 12.00 City of Wayne, electric light 258.80 U. S. Conn, refunds to students 27.00 Rand, McNally &amp; Company supplies 4.32 Chas. Scribners' Sons, textbooks 5.74 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks ~ 1.34 Gregg Publishing Company, textbooks .... 6.23 La Salle Ext. University, textbooks 30.60 Chas. Scribners 1 Sons, textbooks 14.40 Theo. Presser Company, textbooks 6.19 National Wood Works, lumber for man, tr. 171.00 Bausch &amp; Lomb Optical Co., repairs 7.90 Central Scientific Company,, supplies 17.56 Felber's Pharmacy, supplies 3.90 Model Pharmacy, supplies 6.S5 Central Meat Market, meat for dom. sci. 9.15 Frank Gaertner, piano rental 31.50 Chas. H. Ditson &amp; Co., music books 6.84 26 Salaries for April 70.00 May 20 Salaries for May 66.00 June 23 American Book Company, supplies 10.48 C. A. Chace &amp; Company, lbr., sand, cement 364.10 Farwel!. Ozmun, Kirk &amp; Co.. sand ppr. etc 10.73 </seg>
            <seg id="p143">143 WAYNE STATE NORMAL SCHOOL Frank Gaertner, piano rental ll.M Frank Gaertner, furniture 148.50 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 17.M The Macmillan Company, textbooks 41.20 The Nebraska Telephone Company, services 10.05 A. C. Norton, painting 12S.00 Remington Typewriter Co.. ribbons l*.00 Remington Typewriter Co., mach. lea exch. 20.00 W. B. Saunders Company, textbooks 14.85 Underwood Typewriter Company, ribbons 7.00 City of Wayne, electric lights 173.80 Ward's Natural Science Eatab.. supplies . . 24.10 J. H. Wendte &amp; Company, supplies 10.17 Western Glass &amp; Paint Company, paint... 207.05 26 Salaries for June 64.70 July 28 Salaries for July 63.00 Aug. 8 American Book Company, textbooks 50.98 P. Blackiston's Sons, textbooks 16.00 Carhart Hardware Store, pitchers 9.87 National Wood Works, lbr. for man. tr. ... 133.20 1*. S. Conn, refunds to students 30.85 C. A. Chace &amp; Company, lumber 100.45 Goodyear- Marshall Pub. Co.. bank sets 7.11 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 16.5» Lyon &amp; Carnahan. textbooks 30.61 A. C. McClurg &amp; Company, textbooks 10.5« The Macmillan Company, textbooks 119.03 A. C. Norton, painting 255.00 Nebraska Telephone Company, services... 12.00 Mrs. A. Sherbahn, laundry for dom. sci 4.70 Benj. H. San born &amp; Company, textbooks.. 3.7* Variety Store, broomp, wallpaper 32.M John Van Range Company, repairs 15.7* John Van Range Company, repairs 25.4* City of Wayne, electric light 122.40 Sep. 27 Salaries for September 85.40 Oct. 9 H. B. Craven, hardware 1*1.70 C. A. Chace &amp; Company, lbr.. cement 309.40 Crane &amp; Company, supplies 142.35 U. S. Conn, refunds to students 22.35 J. E. Dennis, labor 60.50 Frank Gaertner, supplies 28.65 Nebraska Telephone Company, services . . . 11.00 A. C. Norton, painting, paper hanging 195.60 Western Glass &amp; Paint Co.. calcimo 34.50 </seg>
            <seg id="p144">144 M. J. Bruce, cleaning dormitories 14.40 Allyn &amp; Bacon, textbooks 10.20 American Book Company, textbooks 1S.04 Ginn &amp; Company, textbooks 148.74 Henry Holt A Company, textbooks 8.S2 D. C. Heath &amp; Company, textbooks 28.20 Macmillan Company, textbooks 24.00 H. M. Rove Company, textbooks 12.90 University Publishing Company, textbooks 8.90 Central Scientific Company, supplies .... 55.29 Central Scientific Company, equipment.... 14.S0 Thos. Charles Company, supplies 8.4S Levi B. Walker, supplies 4.80 W. E. Beaman, supplies 24.01 S. R. Theobald &amp; Company, supplies 15.05 Sioux City Iron Company, iron 14.15 Frank Gaertner, piano rental 21.00 24 Salaries for October 72.20 Nov. 29 Salaries for November 67.80 Total disbursements for the biennium ....$ 15,816.89 Dec. 1 Balance in Cash fund 2,686.15 * 18,503.04 Interest On Normal Endowment Fund. 1916 Oct. 24 Salaries, Partial payroll for October I 2, 440.00 </seg>
            
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>