<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00022.00005">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00022.00005</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT OF THE Agricultural Experiment Station OF NEBRASKA, PRESENTED TO THE GOVERNOR FEBRUARY 1, 1909</title>
               <date value="1909">1909</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">HE MVERSITY OF NEBRASKA WENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT THE Agricultural Experiment Station ot NEBRASKA Present hRSOR FERRl'ARY 1, 1909 LINCOLN, NEBRASKA U. S. A. </seg>
            <seg id="p002"/>
            <seg id="p003">t l! 88/, ;ii I I \ M S LETTER OF TRANSMITTAL 1'hk University of Nebraska V(,R1( ILTIKAL KXPKRIMKNT STATION rlloici/. Axhtoit C. Shallenbtrgrr. (rocernor of Nebraska: accordance with the act of CUagraai approved March 2, the act of the genera] assembly of the State of Nebraska March 31, 1887, establishing and regulating experiment have the honor herewith to submit the Twenty-second port of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station. K. A. Burnett, I, MHRt. Director. GOVERNOR'S CKRTIFKATK mk of Nebraska, Executive Dkpartmkm-. Lincoln, Fkbruarv 1, 1909. Burnett, Director Xibraxka Atirintltural Experiment I hereby acknowledge receipt of the Twenty-second Annual Report of t he Nebraska Agricultural F.xperiment Station. Ashton C. Shallenberger, Governor. m </seg>
            <seg id="p004">t IV THE OFFICIAL ROSTER OF THE STATION THE GOVERNING BOARD im .....T. or th. inmir) HONORABLE CHARLES S. ALLEN. Lincoln. Pruiiml. .Ttm expires 19U HONORABLE WILLIAM G. WHITMORE. Valley HONORABLE FREDERICK H. ABBOTT. Aurora HONORABLE VICTOR G. LYFOBD, Kails City HONORABLE CHARLES B. ANDERSON. Crete HONORABLE GEORGE OOUPLAND, Elgin Term expires 191 Term expip Term expin Term expires 191 Term expires 191 SAMUEL AVEKV. Chnncrllor. J S. DALES. I- THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE CHARLES S ALLEN SAMUEL AVKin E. A. Bl KNr THE STATION OFFICERS THE WORKING STAFF E. Mead Wilcox, 1'h. 1&gt; tral Hi F. J. Alway, I'h. D.. Agricultural Chi H. R. Smith. B. 8c.. Animal Hutbam A. T. Peters. D. V. M., I A. L. Hak.ikkh. B. Be. \ . Da LtwiWCl Bui nf.h, B. S&gt; MONTOOMB«T, B. S Frank J. Phillip*. M. 1 / Erwin H. Bahbour. Ph. I).. &lt; G. R. Chatbikn. A. M.. lln/i R. A. Emkkson B. 8c., // O. V. P. Stiht. C EL, Irrigation G. A. Luvki.am), B. S&lt; •.. Metro Alvin Kevskk. A. M E. P. Snydkk. M W. Pr&lt;iSI.KY. B // J. H. Cain. M. D. C. iicii M Animal Patholog* L. B. Sturdevant. A. M it I'nt'halwi Venus \V. Pool. A. M.. Anutaxl in Agricultural Baton K. M. Little. B. So.. Amiatmmt in limn/ Huaban M. H. SwK.Nk. A. M.. Aamutmmt in Entomology Robert K. Howard. B. So. in Agr., Assistant in Horlirult P. B. Barker. A. B., Assistant in W. W. Birr. B tant in Soils ami Crons. \,&gt;rth Pintle 8. W. Perix, Farm Superinttrulent *By an act of the lecuWture of the State of Nebraska approved effect February 15, 1899, the State Treasurer became ex ofieio custodial Experiment Station fund on and after July 1. 1899. tA. BURNETT, B. S&lt; ., l&gt; M. \V. MARSHALL, Extcutin Clerk R. ft Tkimhill. A. If., AmutmHt m Agricultural eh </seg>
            <seg id="p005">V l'ABLK OF CONTEXTS I'kansmi itai. iii rOVERXOR S CEHTIFICATK ill Of THE Station i v ) Review xperimental work vii rubercuioaa viii amp fever ix H«&gt;^ cholera jx Cattle feeding x Pig feeding x Milking machines xj mall grain xiii expenmenta h l'latte Station \ \\ inter wheat on summer tilled land wheat xv ne Ik feeding x\ i »n Staff xvii Institutes xviii 'ii \ wledgementa xx VTKMKNTS II Vdams fund xxii pplemental funds \xm Appropriations by the State ubstation (North I'latte) . Farmers' Institutes x\iv </seg>
            <seg id="p006">I \ i i VI APPENDIX Directions for thk Control ok Nebbasea I'i.am Di&gt; with tablk of contknts INHERITANCE OK Col.oK IN THK SEEM OF IIIK COMMOM M PhaseoluK tmlfmrU, with Table of Contents rE Life History of thk Cedab Rust Fungus, '&gt;','/ sporangium jmmperi-nrffimiamm &gt;&lt; n\\ ., with T of Contents Thk Influence &lt;&gt;f Chemical Stimi i.ation dfon the 1 DICTION OF PeBITHECIA \^ M tldliosjioni jMlinpi Bpeq DisSK.MINATION OF TUBEBCl l."-!~ BY THE MaNUBE OF 1 kkctki&gt; Cattle Introduction Demonstration of tubercle bacilli in the fece*. . The Investigation Method of investigation Results of the investigation Appeanuice of eowi which are passing virule tubercle bacilli Conclusions Bibliograph '\d Hkport of the Xebbasj </seg>
            <seg id="p007">VII TWENTY-SECOND ANNUAL REPORT EXPERIMENTAL WORK rork of the Nebraska Agricultural Experiment Station for ent year liars been as follow The lines of investigation in the Experiment Station are of two -&lt;»•-: First, those which are technical and scientific in their tor, endeavoring to discover scientific principles which may bearing on practical farm problems; second, the adaptation ntific principles already worked out to the practical needs tanner The investigation! carried on under the Adams Act are, by the litations of Congress, confined to original investigation along ientihc lines, in an effort to accumulate information of a character and to work out the application of this knowl- to practical agricultural questions. Of necessity, on account mited appropriations, the number of problems which can be ied under the Adams Act are limited, and have been confined Station to a study of the relation of food to the deposit of I matter affecting the strength of bones in pigs; to the I of determining humus in soils, the composition of humus, e effect of tillage and crop production on soil fertility. These igations have also included: a studv of hereditv and the v&lt; ing on heredity in plants; a study of plant diseases, ffe&lt; specially those which affect farm and orchard crops; a study of le relation of leaf area to water loss and growth in the corn plant, and a laboratory study of tuberculosis in hogs to determine if possible how to detect tuberculosis in the living hog; also to de - termine the methods of transmission of the disease from cattle to The other funds of the Kxperiment Station, such as the Hatch fund appropriated by the Federal Government and State appro - priations, are available for less technical lines of investigation which mav have the most immediate and beneficial influence on </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebraska VIII \ l&gt;. the general farm practice of the State. In this connection be said that the work of the Experiment Station at the plant has entirely outgrown the appropriations available perimental work, so that no new lines of investigation 1 v undertaken in the last two yean except those which 1 inaugurated at the North Platte Station. The line: gation now in progress would be much facilitated ;m&lt; lines of work might l&gt;e undertaken if the State wen specific appropriation from the general fund to promott of the central experimental plant A very thoro review of the work in progress at t! was made in the Twentv-first Annual Report and it to repeat here the results recently published in this R&lt; of cattle have been tested for tuberculosis, aggregating 360 of which M.K per cent have reacted. The animals it been destroyed, either by sending them to market ( and an officer of the Department. All this work h speetion Of 1 &gt;y killing them under the supervisioi &gt;een .11 available for distribution. Tuberculosis. -ProgTetw has l&gt;een made in the Btudy ol culosis in hogs, for which a special appropriation i made by the lust Legislature, this sum l&gt;ein«; supplemer Fe&lt;leral funds and by assistance from private sources. Tb has been done largely at the packing houses in South Omi in the tracing of infected hits which were condemned in the ] house to the farms on which they were fed and endeavi determine the cause of infection on individual farms. operation of the Federal Inspectors in the packing h secured, so that they have reported to our office the rec animals condemned at the South Omaha slaughterhouse! Federal inspection is maintained. The cooperation of the house was also secured in reporting the owners or the li from which condemned animals were received. A repre* of the Station visited these farms to ascertain the sou re whether thru the milk or thru the (vrv&gt; or thru diseased att&lt; Representatives of the Station visited 280 farms on whicl hogs or cattle had l&gt;een reported affected as indicated ! demnations on the South Omaha markets. Kb a result, fi </seg>
            <seg id="p009">ty-aeeond Annual Report IX t nf the owners of cattle, indicating their willing - te mm) their desire to have their herds clean and ber, the IJureau of Animal Industry of the United s ■e Department of Agriculture at Washington has detailed to assist the Station in testing herds thruout veterinarians are supplied by the (iovernment The only provision required by the (iovernment lera who have their herds tested consent to clean up w iiid destroy the animals that react. in 1 Fever. The Station has made careful investigations to xtent of the prevalence of swamp fever in the State. tin been somewhat prevalent in the region of Hoi* umy other counties in the northwestern part of the nited cases as swamp fever which upon investigation result from other causes. The Department has ist-mortem examinations and also investigated the parasite in the horses which died from swamp fever this worm has any connection with causing the possible factor which might account for the iduced in this disease has been studied without much progress which would lead to its successful treat- VariouH medicines are being tried on animals that are he disease, luit up to the present time 90 per cent affected have died and those that recovered have eful afterwards Mm. Cholera. Experiments have been made within the last Government method of hyperimmunizing hogs These experiments have l&gt;een fairly MM These experiments have l&gt;een fairly successful it hogs may l&gt;e immunised by the simultaneous in- : h&lt;&gt;&lt;rs may l&gt;e immunized by the simultaneous in- lent lilood and of serum from blood drawn from 'iit blood and of serum from blood drawn from hojfs viously been kyperimmuniied against cholera. In experiments on the Station herd the loss of hogs by this method 10 per cent. Many trials by the Government have been .v il. but the results of investigations have not been re succ&lt; iniforiii. Investigations are under way to see if this method can e perfected so that the cost of treatment may l&gt;e reduced and the ethod made practical for commercial purp </seg>
            <seg id="p010">Agricultural Experiment Station \,l X nt native valut bran, Unset »ch fed w iveragt nt V alia i n&lt; ■&lt; oi bones, reported addition of ground produces a marked f the bones when tabl&lt; Cattle Feeding. — Cattle feeding experimc ducted with individual steers to test the coap so-called protein supplements, namely, wheat new process eottooaeed cake, and alfalfa hay. &lt; corn and shredded corn-stover. The largest pounds per day I were made OB the ration seed-cake as a supplementary food, followed 1&gt; linseed-meal, in the order named. The largest profits w on the ration containing alfalfa followed 1 cottonseed-cake, wheat bran, and linseed-meal, in In two form linseed-meal proved more either bran or cottonseed-meal. In the test ht process cottonseed-meal was used for t he first results than have ever been secured by us w seed-meal. Cottonseed-meal and linseed-m&lt; cent of the full grain ration ted. bran 25 per In comparing a lull feed of corn. pounds per daw for a period of four 1 ration of 17 pounds and another of stover forming the roughage in all 1 identical on the two larger rations, col and alfalfa $7 per ton. The profits were lower than on the other two nai Pig Feeding.— In fattening corn, reported in Bulletin 107. the hogs made supplementary foods were used and reache given length of time. The cheapest gains receiving no supplementary food after tlw pasture, altho other experiments indicate has l&gt;een more profitable than the feeding of corn w supplementary food. The effect of food on the breaking strength in Part II of Bulletin 107, indicates that the bone, tankage, or skim-milk to a corn ration effect on the quality and the breaking strength fed to growing pigs, as shown by the following up half of the roughnea corn alone. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">ecoitd Annual Rt jhiiI XI Kadiu Keiimr Tibia. Humems. and All bones ulna. ation i bo shows that the thickness of the ■ .-*■&lt; 1 and that the cell w;,lls were thicker and eon - ineral matter where a supplement ary food was tion than where eon alone was fed. When bone- thickness of the hone walls increased about ih'c gravity "f the hones was greatly inert harder and denser than where no supplementary Mil. kim. MACHINES. During the past year extensive experi illetin IDS. These investigations show that heifers n apparently give letter results by machine aged cows that have been accustomed to hand ne cows are not adapted to machine milking; nd and machine methods of milking have heen milk Bow; that manipulation of the udder is v in some instances before the milk can be hine; that one milker may operate two machines tory work; two milkers operating four machines &gt;f three men milking by hand; one operator with wor an milk between ten and eleven cows per hour. two machine; t was found necessary to thoroly wash and boil the milking machine &gt;arts after each usage in order to produce milk which is as sanitary is that resulting from careful methods of hand milking. The man iperating a milker must thoroly understand the care and man - agement of dairy stock and t&gt;e persistent in the attention to details n order to get good results. From these studies it would appear tfth of be KM) /founds lire u-eight of )&lt;/.•.- «/ time of daughter. 276 -'."&gt;-&gt; 434 341 325 :t43 309 ."&gt;.".."■ 37f&gt; :t&lt;*', im-milk MO Mil) :..«» "&gt;-»() 409 74(1 till mil ground Im.ik- '.Hi tt&gt;."&gt; 71."» Ml f the milking machine have Ihmmi in prugn </seg>
            <seg id="p012">Agricultural Experiment Station of Nebnuh XII \ 1 for large hen that the milking machine u fine ones, and we believe it would milking where fewer than 30 e» * he impractical to iws are milked. Investigations have been in p and select improved strains o alfalfa. Among the varieties oi nursery which have been tested two superior varieties ha\ ■ yield per acre has been 4 bushel Rolling winter wheat in the m rogreaa in an effo f wheat, corn. 01 selected wheats D the field for t developed in w &gt;re than th( ii in has given of 5 bushels per acre for the past ."&gt; years. Hart wheat in spring has given an in&lt; e in in years of more than normal rainfall. H seven veal Corn. A com old unseleeted se&lt; selected strains for yield, onlv a par bushels per acre and the 1(1 acre, or an average ot 20 than for the II) (owes in individual rows, in tl ii over the remnants of the MM) i selected strains of corn wer from which these strains we yield of 0 bushels per acre t indicate that we cannot rea d corn without testing iml which of the ears selected have the highest prepotent 10 11 ears to plant an acre of corn, and since the high yielding strai when once isolated by planting in the w nietl iVlll (oi tinue to show thia high yielding character to a consider it is practical for the grower of improved seed ,rth an im ! &gt; bushe highest yielding e KM) liiglie&gt;t yieldin) to transmit :i high yielding character. Since it require </seg>
            <seg id="p013">7 ml Ann mil Re /tort nt)j-x XIII V (iKAIX ev. and w e Ma \ \ i .vit e advantage ot [ be State und( Ifalfa on the 1 urge area to practice this method in the selec field planting. electing about one hundred of the best ears and separate row. Before the sprouting ears have ild detassel all stalks which do not show There arc saved M many M are needed of the best rows, to plant in the breeding plat next year. rom the best yielding rows are used for planting Experiments are in progress with winter oats, win - inter eininer in an effort to develop winter vari - rdy for considerable areas of the State. i of'the fertility of the soil and the effect of crop loess soils of the State indicates that to main- rganic matter erosion by water and by wind o far as possible. The burning of stalks and voided, and all barnyard manure should 1* re- Kven if these precautions are observed, there ecline in the cultivated fields unless legumes be t other fields Ik 1 fed and the manure applied alfalfa the nitrogen, humus, and unhumified C increased at the same time that profitable maintained sen made in a limited way to test the effect of en in Lancaster. Johnson, Pawnee, and Jefferson irk is done argely at the expense of the cooper- is a rule that the addition of nitrogen in the fertilizers always increases the production of lea the profit of the crop where ■ grain crop is grown ■ been some yean in crop without much atten - maintaining the fertility of the land. Thes^ her with those above mentioned indicate that sary to produce a profitable crop and maintain « supplied by the use of clover and alfalfa used grain crops. There can l&gt;e little question I placing all cultivated land in the older sections t a rotation which shall include grass, clover, ind for two or three vears in a 7-year rotation. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">XIV Agricultural Ex inn mod Station of A ndicatt A 1 is sin t rn grow videncf t \ 1 ee \f &gt;ii bushel* erahh ng hel Some statistics recently gathered on this subject where land which has been for some veare in crop line years in crop grass for two &lt;&gt;r three years. th&lt; tility of the Ian ( creased. This is indicated bv ii the yield of corn following gr: land for some years in grain cr With tin crease in production and in th&lt; ifit from I" perat I system of crop rotation, it can ly be pc -il.lt tli alile rotation should include t rowini grains, interspersed with alfalfa, or of suitable pi ml'h I M E \ Cooperative experimen State in testing varieties extending the area of wi ntei and winter oats: in the te&gt; the effect of the applicat fertilizer, or a phosphorus on crop production Experiments in cooperation w Agriculture are in progress, to ini| of hard winter wheats: to introdi control apple seal) and eodling-i: effect of tillage and of crop rotatii the alkali-resistant crops; to male of the State; and to determine tht and impurities of seeds distribute THE NORTH • Winter Wheat on Summer Tin perinients carried on to test the effe( growth of winter wheat give almost ie for the have been: in 1906. 42 bushels per acre; in 190 acre; in 1908, from BO to 67 bushels per acre on ( n grown under field conditions. Wheat on adjoin ncrease of al&gt;&lt; mpared with farmers will continue a rinck yields on the North Platte Station </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Twenty-tet Annual Report XV A ) T \(, Wh i Nebra rv lei mse t&lt; 1 1 \mon fa t ;e purpose Alfalf I 'erennia ■( &lt;&gt;:t roduced, in the same years, from 20 to 24 bushels yield of 41 bushels in 1906. a year with 9.13 inches I rainfall. The two leading varieties of winter the Kharkov introduced thru the United States Agriculture and the Turkey lied, a s andard variety his State. at. — The tests of spring wheat at the North Platte Heated a decided advantage of the durum wheats ariety of spring wheat which is in common use in ka The average yield of a leading variety of nr the past three years on land which has grown a his year has l&gt;een 28 bushels per acre, where the ncal variety has been but 17 bushels. Some farmers ned to discriminate against the growing of durum they did not sell at as high a price on the market uid local spring wheats. The Station has proven that durum wheats are worth at least as much as )ound. in feeding hogs, and that at current prices wheat is a profitable crop to use in feeding live vestigationa in the growing of barley have shown iriety of barley is superior to any of the introduced barley is a more profitable crop than emmer or feeding purposes, since it gives a higher yield i higher feeding value. varieties of oats indicate that the Kherson variety, altho some of the introduced sorts, if may be reliable and profitable. The work of shown that an early oat has a great advantage hruout all of western Nebraska, since it is likely favorable weather conditions than exist later ual forage crops, sorghum, or cane, has given the iv results. Kafir corn and milo maize have been d extent but have not yet proven equal to cane for &gt;roveo itself to l&gt;e greatly superior to any other » crop for land where alfalfa may be grown, </seg>
            <seg id="p016">XVI .lyi'icult u rut experiment b the pr f the wine uixlf ;t N m _'(&gt; n &lt; 1 i wintering Nebraska •'/ be done on almost all of the valley lands .if western N't on many of the table-lands where no alfalfa is pawn at time. There is hardly a section in the western part &gt; where some small fields of alfalfa may not l&gt;e found grc natural farm conditions and producing much more f could l&gt;e grows under the same conditions with any otht cane or some quick-growing annual cro I'latte Station indicate that on l&gt;ench 30 feet above water 4 tons of alfalfa pt normal crop. The value of this forage horses, and hogs has been shown to be i cane in stock feeding, as reported ii . The yields a nds which are acre may l&gt;e i n the winterii perior to prai Bulletin 105 reported n Bulletin No. Hi winter wheat. It has been proven that prior to sowing winter w Miff moisture in the land to practical and that a reasonable crop of wi minimum rainfall where, withou probably fail. Summer tii than winter wheat, on account o; drift in winter, altho then pring sown crops can be grown w Experiments in tree planting and in in progress at the Substation for the p excellent growth where good stock and given. Cottonwood trees more than 10 in two seasons from selected one-year- The results of this work will be report* &gt;t Gkowing Hogs. Extensive invest determine the most profitable metho alfalfa is to l&gt;e used at a leading porti itions an it the ratu periments are reported in Bulletin 95, more recent exp be reported in subsequent bulletins. Cattle Fkedixc. — Experiments in cattle feeding undertaken to determine the most economical methods o cattle upon feeds which are commonly grown in v Experiment* in dry-land farmii tilhige should 1k&gt; used upon limited </seg>
            <seg id="p017">/, XVII orghum hay, alfalfa hay, anil a mixture of the other kind* of forage named. The first is published in Bulletin 10,5 and the second with yearling stem at the present time ;&lt;■&lt;! anil fed as calves upon the rations named nued thru the present and a succeeding winter to nnulative effect of these rations and the c&lt; under these different methods. The resul' ment indicate that alfalfa hay or alfalfa mixed with ity of prairie hay or of cane gave much more Mtis- results than where prairie hay or sorghum hay is fed Where alfalfa formed the whole or a part of the ration, gained thruout the winter. Where no alfalfa was used i. the animals always lost weight and went upon grass g lighter than they went into the yards in the fall. in progress to determine the effect of growing hay and alfalfa pasture in comparison with iirie pasture and also in comparison with prairie rairie pasture. These experiments were started in l(t()7. and at the present time indicate a marked ad- X fa forms a part of the ration IHK STATION STAFF Within the past year the following changes in the Station F I). Heald resigned as Agricultural Botanist, and Dr. E. 'ad Wileox \\ as employed to fill the vacancy. t&gt;eginning September l'.tO.X t.Mr. A. F. Magdanz. Jr., A. B., resigned M Assistant in Animal usbandry. Mr. ('. W. I'ugslev. B. Be., was employed to fill this isition. beginning Septeml&gt;er 1. 1908. Miss Stella A. Hartzell. A. M.. resigned as Assistant in Agricul - jral Chemistry, and Mr. R. S. Trumbull. A. M.. was employed to fill this position, beginning July 1, 1(M)S. tMr. F. F. Denny. A. B., resigned as Assistant in Horticulture ay i. 1908. Mr. Robert F. Howard, B. 8. in Agriculture, was &gt;pointed to fill this position beginning December 1, 1908. </seg>
            <seg id="p018">Agricultural t. ni Station t&gt;j Nebraska XVIII I i •&lt; ii &gt; Mr. Martin Nelson. M. S.. resigned as A— l-tunt in October 1. 190*. Field ( oi Mr. Myron H. .Swenk. A. M.. has Ufii employed as Entomology; Miss Venus W. Pool. A. M.. Assistant in Botany; Mr. P. B. Parker. A. B., Assistant in Soils; an Burr, B. 8c., A&gt;- istant in Soils and Crops at the Subst Platte. Assistai Agricult ,1 Mr. W :tti&lt;in. N \\ IMPROVEMENT Since the last Report, a veterinary laboratory has for the Department of Animal Pathology, at a cost This was made necessary by the destruction of the House, which was located in the middle of the main q the campus and was no longer suitable for the work of iccii er *ll&gt; )(M \n Dei ment. This building had to l&gt;e I ,he general scheme of improve! About $7. ."&gt;(M&gt; has been expended campus; otherwise no expend itu made since the last Annual Her KAKMKH* \ giving systematic instruction in two or three t Institute, which are included in the followii name t of crops and the maintenance of soil fertility; principh butterm and the development of the dairy industry; the breeding, selec and judging of l&gt;eef cattle; the breeding, selection, and ju :u of swine; the breeding, selection, and judging of horses; the and management of poultry; the care and management oforch d lectures and demonstrations in domestic science, including; tl relation of food to the body; the composition and cooking of meat rn down in the de\ lit which is 1kmii«i Several members of the Experin production; selection and growing of -ce&lt;l in Fanners Institutes during the year. One hundred and seventy- - five Institutes were held during the year clewing June 30, I90S 150 Institutes are scheduled for the current year. The Farmer- Institute Department desires, in addition to carrying on the prt Institute work, to establish a number of short schools of agriculture ■which shall continue fur one week at suitable points in the State </seg>
            <seg id="p019">Ticenty-sK-ond Annual fUfmrt XIX the preservation of fruits; canning jellies, etc. ; salads and desserts; tchen economy, including the use of the fireless cooker; with 'inonstrations in all these subjects. The home economics division tanners' Institute school might also give instruction in the ieeoration of houses, beautifying the home grounds, ventilation sanitation, and other subjects which are of special inten MB on the farm. There is at the time a great demand from ie people in various parts of the State for more extended oppor - inities for agricultural education and for many demonstration which shall be near at hand in order that they may be of greater value to the locality. It M probable that the Farmers' Institute school would come nearer to furnishing the information required at a minimum cost than any other plan which can be levised. and that even tho other methods of distributing agricul - ural knowledge are thought to be necessary the Farmers' Institute means of disseminating such knowledge should not be :ed During the present year the Hoys' and Girls' Agricultural Clube, der the joint supervision of the Fanners' Institute Department d the State Department of Public Instruction, have held a large mber of Institutes, at which about 11.000 boys and girls were in e \ agricultural societies meet at the University each year name of Organized Agriculture, the following societies pa ting: Association of Agricultural Students, State Yeter- Medical Association. Poland-China Breeders' Association, Duroc-Jersey Breeders' Association. Red Polled Breeders' Associa- Aberdeen-Angus Breeders' Association. State Board of Agri- Gate Horticultural Society. State Poultry Association, Nebraska Dairymen's Association. State Swine Breeders' Associa- tate Bee Keepers' Association, State Home Economics ation, Improved Live Stock Breeders' Association, Corn Im- provers' Association. Shorthorn Breeders' Association, and Farmers' Institute Conference. PUBLICATION Bulletins giving the results of investigation in the Experiment Station are published in editions of 20,000 to 25,000 each, and are </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Affiiciiltunil Experiment Statio Xebraxh XX kn till! nt ntere-u ed on t i I E. 1) i distributed free of charge to any resident of the State plication. There is at the present time a regular within the State of about ltt.o(M) names. These arc being added to, and it is desired that all farmers who an in the publications of the Station should ask to be pi regular mailing list. The publications of the Station named in the last Annual Report are as follows: Twenty-first Annual Report. Presented to the Go V) 29, 1908. .VIMM) copies Bulletin No. UW&gt; (Vol. XX. Art. VII). Does it l'a Nebraska Apple Orchards' By R. A. Emerson and 1 tarv to Corn in Fattening Pigs: Part II. The Kff tributed DecemU-r 1. 1908. 25.000 Bulletin No. 108 (Vol. XXI. Art. II). Milking M A. I.. Haecker and E. M. Little. Distributed l)e&lt; 8,000 copies Bulletin No. \W (Substation Bulletin N III). Crop Production in Western N&lt; tivation. By \V. P. Snyder and \V. W Bulletin No. 28. Bunt F. D. Heald. Distributed April 15, 1908. 5,001 Press Bulletin No. 29. Pocket Gophers. Bj Distributed Mav 1. 1908. 25.000 ACKMIW I.KIM.KMKN The agricultural press, especially those pap&lt; the State, have shown their appreciation of the work of the i periment Station by giving liberal space to the experi reported and in every way facilitating the extensi agricultural knowledge. Distributed May 2, 1908. 20,000 m V , ft Bulletin No. 107 (Vol. XXI, Art. I). Tart I. I Breaking Strength of Bones. By E. A. Burnett. I) </seg>
            <seg id="p021">Twenty-teeond Annual Re/mrt XXI v HK AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA FINANCIAL STATEMENT HATCH KIND RECEIPTS y the I'niversity tstatel treasurer from the of the United .Stairs, installment for the r ended June 30. I!***, under approved March 2, 1887 i, Hatch the act of fund! l."&gt;.0()0 00 EXPE.NDITl KKs. TV XII ndry auppK 1 machinerv mil tixt xpense; expena 115,000 IK) 1.V000 (K) </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Agricultural Experiment Station XXII \ ebraski FINANCIAL STATEMENT- Continue ADAMS FIND RECEIPT Received by the University iiamiiii from the treasurer of the United States, installment for the fiscal year ended June ,M). 1!XIS. under the act d Congress approved March ll&gt;. l'.ttMi Adams fund . EXPEND Salarie; Labor Postage and stationery Freight and exp; Chemical supplies Seeds, plants ami sundry Feeding stuffs Library Tools, implements and machinery Scientific apparatu- Live stock Traveling excuses Buildings and land IKHI INI </seg>
            <seg id="p023">centy-second Annual Report XXI XXIII •i i NAXCIAL STATEMENT— Continued UPPLEMENTAl Fl'NDI RECEIPTS y the University (state) treasurer than the Tnited State for the &gt;enent of the experiment station r the year ended July 31, 1908. and sub- i\. 1907 5,304 37 23,711 80 tc KXPKNDITI'H K8 2,596 35 2,615 64 465 54 860 54 92 74 2,170 29 5,712 96 882 51 126 00 841 51 4,290 71 396 11 100 00 1,006 69 6,858 58 $29,016117 29,016 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">xxiv Agricultural Experiment Station o\ F1NAN&lt; IA1. STATEMENT— Continued APPROPRIATION'S m Til VTION SOUTH I Balance, Noveinlier M). \'M)7, of lag at ion from il • nerml fund i j x|»Tiincrital Milistatinn at Norll two years I'lidiiig March 31, HHKI IM ElzpenditurM, oaa year to Noveml suiH-riiiteiuU'iirc. supplies, labor. ds, machinery, ti&gt;»»U and bettemi Appropriation balance, November 30, 19US *17.91ti .1. DAI.F Financial Secn-tarv Lincoln, Nebr. January 30, 1909. FABMEBS lN&gt;Til: balance. Xovemlier 90, 1907. of b(utktive appropri- ation from the state (reneral fund for mamten.i farmers' institute*, for the two fHUn eudng March 31. 1909 Expenditures, one year to Noveml&gt;er SO, M*&lt; p - superintendence. clerical service, labor, lecturer- workers' services and expenses, printine. supplii 17. Hit I </seg>
            <seg id="p025">THE LIFE 1 January 1. 19&lt;H» Dr. F. I) lnlx-r 1.1 (Ki HISTORY AND PARASITISM OF DIPLODIA ZEAE SCHW.) LEV.* I \| WlLCOX, Wl&gt; \k.\i- \V l'..ol INTRODUCTION Kxperiment Station has, for several 5 investigation of ttif "coin-stalk" diseae The Department lilein. has made an extensive study of tte&lt;l with moldv co n. ( &gt;ne of these fungi. Keen shown by this investigation to bo the ear anil to affect other dry-rot" of tin plant. It is deemed t his species, which has been under investigation and postpone the publication of our studies mgi to some subsequent time. SYMI-ToMol.ix'Y uees in the ear a condition which may probably the majority of corn-growers i molded. In the early stages of this rot or acks. no external evidence of the presence of ■tected. The kernels in such cases may have appearance. However, if a kernel 1» ear one finds a thin whitish covering of the ip. and upon breaking the ear flaky in seen on the surface of the corneous margins aneed stages of the rot the following characters ment very light in weight, shriveled up and darker ed with a healthy ear. publication November l'.KlN; preprints distributed Hi'aM severed his ecaaaettoa with this Experiment Station on iv I &gt;r E. M.Wiloox hat preparttl the manuscript for the printer. 1 f Agricultural Botany, to publish :it this </seg>
            <seg id="p026">2 Agricultural Exj)erimenl Station of Sebraska 2. The kernels are either brown appearance. They beco attached to t lie cob. 111 role 3. White tiakv mass. kernels and in the sulci. flaky i mycelium may l&gt;e I ml PYCN pyenidia formed on t he I and break thru t he epid&lt; This is typical of t he spa lew However, t I situated in a si roma. In particularly to the gener; \l I) diplodia, all of \\ I straight or usually slight I. I'l. IX. fig. 16. 1 &lt; 'i cell. Size 24-33 o microns. t went v-four hours on A \&gt;i a somewhat longer time i&gt; ajrar A gemi-4 ube arises of the spore. (See PI. IX. CULTl'R \l.]i II \l; \i I I.I When grown on glucose aear. asrar. ely* pyenidia are not formed. ( )i PI. VIII. fig.13) or sterilized corn-stalks &gt;&gt;ee l'l. VIII. lie. 14 however, the pyenidia are pi •eel in nidia are formed* also upon p&lt; ■touch containing - 10 cit ric acid ♦This ol&gt;MT\aiiim m made by Mi&lt;&lt; Ethel ('. Field, :i graduate stu&lt; this Department. 4. The most chaiiictt pycnidia "" ' 1"' furfai ■ (See PI. I\ The pycnklia formed in natun The conidi or carrot one srct s ;i \vhit( </seg>
            <seg id="p027">7 •enty-Second Annual Report 3 &lt;lu&gt;ws the great loss in weight resulting The reduction in weight applies and not to the cob Av. wt. of com Wt. of M on on ear of this mohlv ear of II) 11 I 11 11 ii 1 ) ii l 8 &lt;• 9.5 8.0 8.0 J y s 4 ;i of weight is over 50 per cent. MI'I.uMA L T PON INDIVIDl'AL KKR.NELS. the hyphae enter the kernel at its base, leteeted in this region. From this point the kernel and are found in both the Thru the action of an enzyme, either i or by the iti— 1 'ing cells of the the fungus stimulation, the starch grains PL IX, figs. 17-19) and finally completely to of corrosion u the same M that due to the i uion." The starch grains in the embryo are corrosion and disappear Not only does the fungus use up much of the food stored in kernel hut at the same time the viability of the kernels is pletely destroyed as was shown bv germination tes- I'l.oDI V o\ THE WEIGHT &lt;&gt;K THE KAR. length tliis'length Ounces 13.0 </seg>
            <seg id="p028">Agricultural Experiment Station of Xebraska 4 I'AUASITISM OF DIPLODIA. To learn something of the parasitism of To learn something of the parasitism of t lie fungus determine the prevailing natural method of infe&lt; determine the prevailing nal ing inoculations* were made during the summer inoculat ■►ii-- were m&amp;de as follows L Among t he silks. Into stalk (punct ure) Into husks (punetu Between husks Total . The general results inoculation e follows: 1, Puncture inoculations into the hu - of pollination, produce typical dry-rot e 2. Puncture inoculation.- he stalk development ""of typical immersed pyenklia :{. When the fungus mycelium i- simplj the silks, near the time of pollination, more t ears were secured than by any other method seems evidently to l&gt;e the prevailing method by v enters the ear. Among t he silk: Into stalk (pun Into husks i ■ &gt;ui I' Het weei rot ated as follow 2. Puncture inoculati development of typical imn :{. When the fungu \i the silks, near the time «&gt;f pollina ears were secured than by any other met I 4. Little or no infection takes during the same season. In other fected at about the same time. The pvcnkl tween two and three weeks after infect time the ears which have remained uninfected far developed and the kernels too han of the fungu *Mr. K. A. Wolf, now of the University ot Texas. Austin. Fexa very iniportant s*"n ice&gt; in making reconl </seg>
            <seg id="p029">Tu-fnty-Si inmtal Rei&gt;ort 5 lrv-n&gt;t of corn iti Neb below. Counties from which c been examined arc indicated by the ■in made to learn it- Nebraska. Burrill and Barrett' report it resent in other states YNONOMY AND RELATIONSHIP. nal descriptions are quoted to show the ruler consideration Sehweinitz I., v. S.. Syn. Car. 79)', rara sed bene distincta Zeae, Salem et Hethl. S. omnino tecta. epider iolis soli.- prominulia) satis el. iipomta, lirevis. utrinque acuminata, ■ubeoo binis vel ternis tantiim in caespitulo farctis. ilemuiu evacuati mum al &lt;»stiolis latis, uniliiiicatis. saepe unico." 4&lt; S nlitti ,■ &gt; ii nmtuiiu I&lt;«&gt;i-Liil..\ -' yrf/o Berkeley ,s Serial ae I may its, a. s]&gt;. : maculis panri elevatis; pent her iis paueis; ostiolo unico blongia curvulis uniaeptatis. On dead culms of Zea mays. Cincinnati. Ohio. THIBITIOX (•! IHI'l.oDI A ZEAF. May 1. 1n4I. T. a. Lea, Eaq </seg>
            <seg id="p030">6 Agricultural Exj^erimext Station of Xebraska " Habit t liai of S/ihiu •IIKl often purple-brown, punctiform, or subellipt linear, containing very ici conical ostiolum. S|,c Beptate. Very differ ie ;i]&gt;lic w Heiliariuu Is-Jn Dirfodia 1) na ost iolis rectis \ H Si,f, 2(17 ,s 1) ovnles vert aign Sul all&lt; &gt;ii «r droite 1SS-4 Dlnlwl r. epi conico-acut obtusiuscul sept at w, vi\ "Hal,, il maydis in Carolina, O quens Currey* pve« (1. e. 1' i&gt;f Spka* ria tea* \ aken froi II show that the §po our plant. Saccardo* uw (Berk.) Saccardo lull tin c verbatim quotation of 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p031">ity-tSscond . 1 HHunl lit w • a SchweinHi as the lype of hit ■cording to the law of priority the n Diplodia rtchw.l Lev. and not • Ik' related t&lt;&gt; the following two s\ ich occiii- on Z&lt;ii majf*: i Karlc' from which it differs by the and K .' from which it differs in havin| which it iliffcrs by t lie which it differs in having BlBLHXtH \\'\\\ ill and its ( 'ailscs. Hid its Cause 27:_'li' 213. Kxp.Sta.Record 19:104s |i)4(» 213. Kxp. St a. Record 19:104s HM'i. \| in&lt;ii. London Journ. of Botany 6::i_'ti. loiim. of Motanv 6:.i_'t&gt;. &gt; li irrett, .1. T. li 1KRETT. .1. 1 11. ciic. Ill Kxp. Sta. 117:1 :&gt;. Kxp I ."» ! . (in. II Kxp. Sta. 117:1 &gt;. Kxp. Sta. 20 c Fructification of the Simple Sphaeriae Fructification of the Simple Sphaeriac Hookerian Herbarium. Trans. I. inn. So prian Herbarium. Trans. I. inn. 8oe. oo 'I. .■&gt;'.!. fig. 1_'V l_'s : i . I i U 1 1 . Mull. ub 24:_"» 30. 24:.'! !\ EKH \l; I ■. B. M. K. M 1 II. Of 2 le-known Plant I 1 D ■ N. s. 23:»i_M I. 11. 23:i&gt; s ■olofrjques. Ann. Sci. Nat. Bot. I 1 I 9:_'.')^. u in. 3:M-\ \7\. ,1,. \nii. Sci. \at. Hot. I 1 1 9:_'.Vs \ 3:^7M :i71 ) ;orum in America Boreali media ■:■ \m. I'hilo-. Hoc. 4:_'D7 </seg>
            <seg id="p032">Kip. I. A normal car Ty infected with LHplod ■iinii&lt; T </seg>
            <seg id="p033">9 tlie *ilk&gt; el </seg>
            <seg id="p034">1 ig ."&gt;. Typical mokiy ear reMtlting tlini the husk-. Numerous \&gt;\ Im-k-. </seg>
            <seg id="p035">Plate IV Fii vcnulia on the opposed surfaces of tl «&gt;l tl alveoli of naturally inoeulat«d ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p036">V liij. 10. I've \ </seg>
            <seg id="p037">Plate VI Kig. 11 A :{-l&lt;X'ular pycnulium in the stronia. </seg>
            <seg id="p038">I ig. 12. An immersed pycuidiiim in a husk </seg>
            <seg id="p039">Fig. 14. Pure culture cm sterilized roro-8 talks </seg>
            <seg id="p040">Fig. 1"). Germinating iportt. Fig. !•'■ Typical conulia. Note one spore which i&gt; bis. Fig. 17. Normal com starcli-graiiis. Fig. IS. Digestion of starch-grains in 1 1 1&lt; ■ endfMpenn due to Diplodia Fi£. lit. Digestion &lt;&gt;f rtarch-grmins'in'the embryo due m Diplodia. </seg>
            <seg id="p041"/>
            <seg id="p042">w \ J "\ |)1UJA B|I1JOU| ,ll|( |III1I(U\ </seg>
            <seg id="p043">DIRECTIONS FOR THE CONTROL OF NEBRASKA PLANT DISEASES. HY WILCOX, I'm. l&gt;.. Phofehsor of Agricultural Botany \M&gt; Adjunct Professor of Agricultural Botavt. </seg>
            <seg id="p044">TABLK OF CONTEXTS Introduction Fungicides Ammoniac*] Copper &lt; Bordeaux Mixture irl Lime-Sulfur Wasl Lime-Sulfur W a- Potassiuin Sulfitl Alfalfa {Medicago Dodders flora and raet Leaf 8] Apple ( Mai ii.- Bittcr Rol Black Rot {Spka Crown Gall Fire Blijrht or Pi Fly Speck (/.&lt;/&lt;/.■ Hairv Hoot Rust (Cfymna Scal&gt; ( I i Sooty Blotch (Pk Barley (// Black Rust or Stem I / Red Rust or Oral gimp / Covered Smut i ( 'stilt f ie Smut i I sliiui/ii Bean (Phtueoltu vulgari Anthracnose or l'od Spot (Colletotrichum lit Beet {Bttn vulgar Leaf S]&gt;ot (C« rcoapora uti Soft Hot (Bacterium t Blackberry (Rubue .•&lt;■;».) s Anthracnose {(ilomsj Crown Gall •&gt;■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p045">&lt; 23 4ii 41 \ 'lisa 41 i/i mi 1 4| Hole (CylindrorporiuM pudi) 42 42 4.' 4:&lt; uiit mi 4.1 Perono/tlasmopara cubei . . . V-i 44 Mi (leu i S/iIkii iiithicn mtirs-rti: .... 44 i / 4ti *•• •••-.-. liust (Puccinia araminin a 4 • &gt; IJust {Puccinia coronata) ... 47 s 49 19 4'. lihfilit Asiinhfitu jii.si) . . 4&lt;| Mildew {Eryxipk) communi*) 50 1\ *\clerotin\ (0 .')1 :,1 Scab or Black Spot [C'ladotporium carpopkilum) . . .")_&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p046">24 Conti ills Yellows Pear (1'yrus eommunt* Fire Blight or Pear Blight (B Scab (VetUuria pirina) icilluit a in ill" Plum [Prunu* domestica) Brown Hot (Sell ml i it in inirt &lt;l" Canker t Leaf Spot or Shot Hole (( Potato (Solatium tuberosun yi jnl iiiiii Dry Hot (Fumti'iiiii ozysv* Early Blight (.!//&lt; •h&lt; Internal Brown Spol I. ate Blight and Rot [Phytophth&lt; Scab (Ooapora acoi Soft K01 (Bacillux solatiat Sprout ing Raspberry I fi«6iu »p. AnthraenoM Gloeotpo Crown (iall Rust (Gymnoconia mt&lt; Hose (£m n/&lt; Bhit'k S])ot I Actiniini urn Mildew iS/ihat mlhini h u Hve (Secale cumli i lavieejm pur pur ea i Orange Leaf Rust {I'liccin &lt;/ Sorghum. Kafir Corn. Broom Com Head Smut (Sphacdotheca reiliana) mini Kernel Smut (SpKaeelotket i Borah Strawberry (Fntgaria chili Leaf Spot. Rust or Leaf Blight (SphatrtUi Black Rust or Stem Rust a qraniinis tnt Orange Leaf Rust [1'iiccniia Loose Smut t,l'stilat/t&gt; tritici) Stinking Smut or Bunt (Tillitm fottai Tomato (Ljfcoptra icum etcvUntum Rots Wheat (Trittcum .-/&gt;.) . . . </seg>
            <seg id="p047">DIRECTIONS FOR THE CONTROL OF NEBRASKA PLANT DISEASES. INTRODUCTION. wing interest in the control of plant d, 1 Botanists of various Experiment Stations to prepare Ipray Calendar*" lot use in their respective states tion has bees prepared to meet this need in Nebraska We believe the method of treatment is such as to render the material neatest value to farmers and fruit growers. Our plan has state very clearly and briefly the following points regard- he diseases mentioned A. Symptoms and Cause of the d\- B. Methods of Control or Prevention. Bibliography containing references to some of the most recent or useful literature generally accessible to farmers and fruit growr s are arranged alphabetically by their prevailing under the various crops, which are also arranged aimer. The scientific names of the various Bl causing the various diseases are given for the re is manner can any misunderstanding l&gt;e avoided. FUNGICIDES. only such fungicide! are described as require \ tiona for their preparation. Other simpler formulas VMMONIACAL TOPPER CARBONATE Copper carbonate 8 ounces Ammonia ; i pints Water 30 gallons Dilute the ammonia with water and add the copper carbonate. Use just enough of the ammonia to dissolve the precipitate formed. Dilute with water to make ."&gt;() gallons. (25) K Mead \Vil&lt;c&gt;.\ and R. K. Stone. nnection with the ■pectal rtiwuw! </seg>
            <seg id="p048">Agricultural I: ni Station Neb 26 BORDEAUX MIXTURE We {live here only the following standard referred to as 5-5-50 Bordeaux. The other forn in the text are prepared in the same manner 1 amounts of the lime and copper eulfate. i\t Quicklime (not slab Water 1. Dissolve t he coppei gallons of warm water, mixing. Dilute 2. Slake the lime very ea then dilute to t went 3. Pour the above tw into a barrel. i. mi I.I I U This is \videl\ as a fungicide w: Sulfur Lime Water Slake the lime and then water to permit of easy ham is dissolved. Strain and ad Apply while fresh. UME-MULFUB Sulfur ("flowei \\ ASH (SELF-BO boil the mixture violently for several minutes necessary to prevent burning, and more w if the mass gets too thick to stir, but the cooking when the minimum quantity of water us used, usually from 6 t( 8 gallons being required. A piece of old carp' Copper sulfate (blue vitri Lllli' I") IXlllIllls Wat.-: 50 gallons "Place the lime in a 50-gallon barrel and | &gt;&lt; &gt; 1 1 r a 2 or 3 bucket of boiling water over it. Immediately add tl another bucket of hot water. The heat from the slakiii" lii l </seg>
            <seg id="p049">7 cotul A n n mil Ht/Mut 27 \ ) s H K r. &lt; 1 W )4 M tin- hnrrt'l helps to keep in the heat. The •"in twenty to thirty minutes, depending lime. When the boiling ceases, dilute with &gt;tl gallons, stir thoroly and strain thru a lima to the inch in order t&lt;&gt; take out coarse all the sulfur should be carefully worked POTASSIUM SULFID •i ounces 111 irallons siiim sulfid in a gallon of warm water and lesired amount. This solution will not kpep made ii]&gt; fresh each time you desire to spray Bailey, L H u(K. V. A., and Taylor. 0. M. Spray Nozzles. Bui Mo. Exp. 8ta. 10:87-115. Heald, F. I) Calendar. Hul. Xe Insect Pest and Plant r Bureau 1:1-12. Fi Insecticides and Fungicides: Chemical Composition and praying in Bloom. Bui. N. V. Geneva Exp 8ta 196:399-460. l'i. 1-3. fig. 1-6. ruit-sc-t tinsi of Sprayed Blossoms. Mul. N. V. Genera Kxp. Sta. 196:1-1.V. I'l. 1. fig. 1-6. Mixtures and Spray Machinery. Bui. N. V. a Exp. Sta. 343:315-370. PI. l-i.i. Mixtures and Spray Machinery. Hpt. X. V. a Exp. Sta. 1908:321-386. PI. 21-35. \ Mixture as a Fungicide. Bui. Div. Veg. nd l'ath. U. S. Dept. Asrr. 6:1-V&gt;. tivenessof Certain. Preparations. Farmers' Bui 146:1-14. lixturee and Appliances for Spraying. Bui. \\ Exp. Sta. 93:65-1 IS. PI. 1-12. </seg>
            <seg id="p050">28 Af/ricultural Experiment Statu Nebraskt Fungi 1:1-18 I &lt; /, l'HM) Some Important Insecticides, Fungicides and Ai for their Application. Bui. Mil. Exp. Sta. 65:5."&gt;-s Fig. 12-30. 1908 Self-boiled lime sulfur Mixture as a 1 cide. ('ire. Bur Fig. 1-2 Smith. H. I. lltttfi Spraying to Control or Prevent Injury fr and Plant Diseases. Insecticides and Fungi Georgia State Bd. En torn. 19. Stubenkaucb, A. \ 68 1.17-lss. PI Swingle, W. T. 1896 Bordeaux Mixtu e. its Chemistry, Pin and Toxic Kffect n Fungi ami Alg Phvs. and Path I". S. Dept. Agr. 9:1 ALFALFA M,,l LK)1)1)KHS iCusiutti urn,, h ■I, The dodders are flowering plants ground and lend up slender yellowish aet if they do not come in contact with about the alfalfa stem and branches and rootlike structures which penetrate the host plai from it for the dodder. The lower part of the do and it beeomea a true parasite. In the case of Cusciitd it has l&gt;een found that the naustoria live over winter in the crow of the alfalfa. This fact renden the dodder problem a v&lt; one indeed. 1., Do not plant dodder seeds! Have your seed tested lx fore planting. Johnson. \V. G., Townsknd. C. 0. and Gocld, H. I' Scott, \V. M. Plant Indus. I'. S. Dept. Ajrr STEVKNS. F. I. IND WOGLClf, H. S l'.MKi Spraying Mixtures and Machinery. When ami H Spray. Bui. N. Cur. Exp. Sta. 193:l-:i2. Fisr. 1902 Important Details o 681.17-Isn IM 1-&lt; There are five Bpec urvenri*, eptikymum, indecora found in alfalfa and elovi Th </seg>
            <seg id="p051">7 nty teeond Annual Re)x&gt;rt 29 S9S II MX A. 1 Mi 1 •us 1 A r iv.il COMHs, 1 1S&lt;) 1S9 Sturgis. \\ 1900 be ground and burn if confined to small Held -plow up and reseed M Dodders Infesting Clover and Alfalfa. Cat. Div. Bot. l\ 8. Dept. Agr. 14:1-7. Fig. 1-2. The Vitality, Adulteration and Impurities of Clover Alfalfa and Timothy Seed for Sale in Iowa in 1906 Bui. I&lt;»wa Kxp. Sta. 88:1-6'.). PL 1. fig. 1-8. . F. \\i) Freeman, (i. F. Alfalfa Seed. Its Adulterants. Substitutes and Their Detection. Bui. Kans. Kxp. Sta. 133. ) Clover and Alfalfa Seeds. Bui. Ohio Kxp. Sta. 142. . ('.. Fhkni h, (;. T. and Wilson. .1. K. Troubles of Alfalfa in New York. Bui. N. V. (ieneva Kx|). Sta. 306::«l-416. PI. 1-12. LEAF SPOT (f'xeuiloprziza medictufini*) . mses yellowish spots on the leaves and in the ts the small black fruiting bodies appear. The ■arly summer. Somewhat similar spots are often the rust fungi. is prevalent on you'ig plants they should not mowed too close v. r fields should l&gt;e mowed early to avoid loss of leave iVth may not l&gt;e seriously affected. I) Alfalfa Leaf Spotting. Pantdopesiaa msdicagini* (lib.) Sacc. Rpt. Del. Kxp. Sta. 3:7'.)-S4. Fig. 7-11. The Alfalfa Leaf Spot Disease. Pa$mi*ptmm medi- Alfalta Leaf Spot Disease. Pmudepau* mcdinr/i nis (Lib.) Sacc. Rpt. Iowa Kxp. Sta. 1897:15.5-160 Fig. 1-4. ( The Leaf Spot of Alfalfa 1898:281-282. H., Buchanan, H. E. and Kim. ('. M. saginis (lib.) Saec. Bui. Iowa Kxp. Sta. 36:N&gt; Fiji. '.». Rpt. Conn. Kxp. Sta. </seg>
            <seg id="p052">Agricultural Exper V 30 nt Slot APPLE (Malu BITTEB HOT OR RII'K ROT C ripening fruit. This spot becomes somewhat and I&gt;eneath it the apple has a bitter tast&lt; one of its common names. On t colored summer fruiting bodies at ii &gt;&lt;• uted over the tree by the rain. Cankers are developed on t fruit is produced. Spore the fruit and produce the t\ 1. Remove canker.- di 2. Pick and destroy tl canker which is usi A. Spray with 4-4-."&gt;&lt;) He V. Six nil weeks B. Repeat after ('. Repeat I). When Alwood, \\ . 15 ls'.M Ripe Rot, or Bit Station 40:57-82 1902 Orchard Studies \ \ Ya. Exp. Station 142 -M'.t-l: Blair, J. ( l'.tOT Bitter Uot of Apples. II Bui. 111. Exp. si 117:4s BURRILL, T. .1 1&gt;M&gt;7 Hitter Hot of Ap] 1902 Prevention of Hitter Hot. Cite. 1 56:1-3 1902 Bitter Rot of Apples. Bui. 111. Exp. Station 77::;." PI. C, fig. 1-12 Scott, \Y. M 1&lt;H&gt;6 The Control of Apple Hitter Rot. Bui. Bur PI; I 1 PI This fungua causes a brownish-i From these bodiea the spon spirally twisted, mass. The s|»&gt; 111. Exp. Station 118 :.'&gt;.~&gt;:M&gt;&lt; is Burrill, T. .1. and Blair, .1. ('. lad. U. S. Dept. Agr. 93 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p053">Kil Report 31 7- A S99 '] Ex HI '1 I H I s 1 . ( er Rot of Apples. Bui. Bur. Plant Ind. D. 8. Agr. 44.1-54. PL 1-9. Fig. 1-9. \I'K HOT (Spkatroptit malorum) the mature fruits to rot and finally develop Small brown spots appear on the leaves levelop on the branch' troy all cankers ■•-ted for apple scab and bitter rot will New York Apple-Tree Canker. Bui. N. V. Geneva &gt;. Sta. 163:179-206. PI. 1-6. New York Apple-Tree ("anker. (Second Report.) \. V. Geneva Kxp. Sta. 186:205-213. PI. 1-4. CKOWX GALL. there are two general types of galls, the cause of fully understood. These galls may be hard or luent near the graft union but are often found even diseased tree testroy all affected ■Mich diseased 1 will tend to spread the disease thruout the union with cloth. This will give a keep nut bacteria, etc. Observations on Crown-Gall of Apple Tree: Va. Exp. Sta. 140:1n.V_M2. Fig. 27-37. wn-Gall and Hairy-Root Diseases of the Apple Bui. Bur. Plant Ind. V. S. Dept. Agr. 90:1-7. •its Some Stem Tumors or Knots on Apple and Quince rrees. Ore. Bur. Plant Iml. V. S. Dept. Act 3-1-16 Fig. 1-10. Rolfs, F. M. and Hall. F. H. 1901) Hairy Root. Bui. X. V. Geneva Kxp. Sta. 191:300-301. &gt; H \NI&gt; 8P UI.DINC. 1&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p054">brtub 32 Agricultural Experiment Station tun U.S. D* I ( \\ ( I Von Schkknk. H. and Hbbgcock, (1. (■. 1906 The Wrapping of Apple Grafts and Its Rd Crown-Gall Disease. Bui. Bur. Plant Ind Apr. 100:1-12 KIRK BLIGHT OR PEAR BLIGHT (Hnrillus mm/tm The bacteria causing this well-known disease enter t or by wav of the flowers. They are often carried by one flower to another. The leaves on the young shoot and then later the twigs themselves become blackene&lt; Sunken pits or "blight cankers" are often found on wood. Fruit may Ik- attacked, producing watery ul surface accompanied by decay and brown discoloration 1. Cut out the blighted twigs as fast as they appe 2. Cut out all blight-cankers down to the healthy ■rounds with corrosive sublimate solution I I pi of water) and paint with a heavy 1 i 3. Avoid bruising or wounding of tre&lt; Rosettes of very small roots spring from the ma there are few if any large branch roots on affected tree the suggestions as to control given for apple crown-gall. M in "2 above. 4. Destroy or clean up all &lt;&gt;ld pear ami ap| orchard. ."&gt;. Avoid excessive use of nitrogenous manun ti. Plant lTiost resistant varieties. 7. Persuade your neighbors to join with you in against this dangeroua diaeas Sturois, W. C. 1895 Fire Blight (Micrococcu* amylovoru* Bi Conn. Exp. Sta. 1894:1 i:M 17. Whktzki.. H. H. 11&gt;CK) The Blight Canker of Apple Tree-. Bui. N Exp. Sta. 236:«&gt;0-i:is. Fig. 49-84. Kl.V Sl'KCK (Leptotkyritm p The fungus forms groups of several small black s surface of the apple, hence the name of disease. ( M'te: with the sooty blotch. 1. Spray as for apple •ooty blotch. HAIRY ROOT. </seg>
            <seg id="p055">I I 33 v r », R. A mi.-) Aiii 88:1 H. 1) ss'.t Apph I'l. 1 V II s II ( la. 1 1. ( i &gt; I tityium junt fMri-nrtfintanae oti appear on the leaves. In these spots l&gt;e formed on the upper surface and several project from the lower surface. The apple ion's produced in the yellowish gelatinous pple" which appears on red cedars in the le neighborhood must I&gt;e treated in either Is iwn and burn. uid burn the cedar apples." This is only •apples"' are present. doubt. cable when hut a few ig methods are still in resistant sorts. Scab and Cedar Rust. .'1. Fie. l-'.t. Bui. Xebr. Exp. Uusts. Kpt. U. S. Com. Agr. 1888:37&lt;MS1. 1-1L'. ire. Div. of Hot. Nebr. Insect IV- Disease Bureau 1:1-4. Fig. 1-4. •dar Apple Fungi ami Apple Rust in Iowa. Bui. sp. Sta. 84:1-%. Fig. 1-11. Apples and Apple Leaf-Rust. Circ. Ala. Exp 2.1-11. Fig. 1-2. abby spots appear on the fruit, which is not the broken surface of the apple near these scabs ling to other fungi to enter and produce serious • ults in a great increase of "windfalls"' and p. The same fungus produces spots on the ame leaves the "perfect" stage of the fungus iaon. The twigs are at times affected. I burn the leaves during the fall. &lt;-50 Bordeaux mixture as follows ust. Apple Leaf Rust. (Qywtmmfmrmnfiim '&lt;'AB uatia). </seg>
            <seg id="p056">34 Agricultural Experiment Station &lt;&gt;j Sebra* A. When the cluster 1&gt; open B. After the petals hav&lt; C. During a wet season— SOOTY BLOTCH (/' The fungus forms olive-b In severe cases several (if thest the entire surface of tlie appli this is associated with the H\ 1. Spray as for scab. A t about half grown seems hot. BARLEY BLACK RUST ol&lt; STEM The leavt lines and streaks. Th this is followed l&gt;v a s • &gt;f the li - showing a distinctl or telia stage. Tl light showers or lie and rather hot. 1 rust occurs also on and squirre I 1. Destroy the n: 2. Other thiiu damage will be done bv tl 'A. Sow the seed as e 4. Sow the seed in su start. 5. Use varieties which are BOLLEY, H. L. Wheat Rust. Bui. Ind. K: 1906 Rust Problems, Fact-. 0 1'ussilile Means of Control 26 N Dak. I 68:(H)7-&lt;)76. Fiji. 1-1 </seg>
            <seg id="p057">ml ■ 35 ( \ • Cereal Rusts of the United A Physiological Investigation. Bui. l)iv. Yeg. Phys. and Path. 16:1-74. l'l. 1-4. Rusts. Bui. Bur. PI. Ind. U. S Dent Art. 63 :!--».•. PI. 1-2 the Grain-Rust Epidemic of 1904 Fanners' Bui. V. S. Dept. AfT. 219:1-24. Fig. 1-6. ikk. A. s. wi) Carlkton, M. A V&gt;:&gt; Preliminary Report on Rusts of Grain. Bui. Ka*a. Exp. Sta. 38:1-14. PI. 1-3. v.i4 Rusts of Grain II. Bui. Kana. Exp. Sta. 46:1-9. E. W. 5 Preliminary Report on Rusts of drain. Bui. Kans. s 38:1-14. PI. 1-3. 4 Rust^ of drain II. Bui. Kans. Exp. Sta. 46:1-9. \\ "Jils Rust of Cereals and Other Plants. Bui. 8. Dak. Kxp. Sta. 10t: 1-20. Fig. 1-.'). nd Other Plants. Bui. S. Dak. Kxp 109:l-L'O. Fig. 1-5 &lt;( .-1 OB ORANGE LEAF Kl hot implex). )K ORANGE LEAF RUST (Fuirinia ntt mpUx) is rust is found principally on the leaves. These tx range in color with a powdery appearance due to develop - the spores which are usually arranged in patches rather isually arranged in patches rather ies. Later small dark spots and small short lines appear es. Later small dark spots and small short lines appear leaves. The red spores belong to the uredo stage and the The red spores belong to the uredo stage and the &gt; the telia This rust develops a little earlier than m rust but under practically the same conditi st develops a little earlier than ler practically the same conditions. Apply the same remedies .-, red for the black rust. COVERED SMI T (f Stilayo hor.i - si time the heads contain no seed hut appear a.s dark The spores do not blow away as with loose smut. -ted for the black rust. VKRl I) Ml ntain no s«»ed but appear aa dark 1 Secure seed free from smut. It this can not l&gt;e done, any of the treatments recommended he treatments recommended ley may l&gt;e used. Among these the Mollified Formalin is to l&gt;e preferred. \ these the Mollified Formalin M, ■ I! L 897 New Studies Upon the Smut o" Wheat. Oats and Barley with a Resume of Treatment Experiments for the Last Three Year.-. Bui. X. Dak. Exp IM09-162. - nut o" Wheat. Oats and a ey with a Resume of Treatment Kxperiments the Last Three Yean. Bui. X. Dak. Exn. Sta. Bui. X. Dak. Kxp 27: H )&lt;•- It;.' «. (i. I'. I 1 900 Loose and Covered Smuts of Barley (Vttilaft hordei - Kell. and UatUago nudn (Jens.) 8w.) Bui. 111. Kxp. Sta. 67:317-318. PI. I). </seg>
            <seg id="p058">36 Agricultural Experiment Station Xebras BEAN ANTHRACNOSE (Hi l'oD si'oi ' Black specks or cankers wit develop on the pods and leaves. Rust times found on the seeds themselves. Tl pod into the seed which is in ntact with it. See diseased seed will show the canker spots on the cotyledons ai then later on the pods and leaves LOOHE SMUT (l/rfilap &gt;s At harvest time the heads contain do seed but appear to I powdery masses of black spores. The spores are often blown awl by the winds before this time, leaving only the bracts or Infection takes place at flowering time and the fungus groi into the embryo of the developing seed. From such an ii. seed a smutted plant will develop the following year. This ami may lx&gt; prevented by the Jensen modified hot-water treatment Soak in cold water for ."&gt; hours: then soak in water at perature of 12.')° for 15 minutes. Every farmer should maintain a small isolated seed plat to d velop healthy seed free from smut infection. From thin small pi; all smutted heads should be removed and destroyed. ('l.IMI)N, (I. 1'. l(»(). r ) Ustilagineae or Smuts of Connecticut. Bui State Geological and Natural History Survi Freeman, EL M. and Johnson, E. C. 1909 The Loom Smuts of Barley and Wheat. Bui. Bu Plant Indus. l\ S. Dept. Agr. 152 1-48. PI Heald, 1". I). 1906 Seed Treatment for Smuts of Winter Barley Rp Nebr. Agr. Exp. Sta. 21:45-53. </seg>
            <seg id="p059">, -\4 tumd A n n mil Report 37 \ planting fron no value. pnils five from the disease. inj; the plants when they are wet. nts with .")-.")-.")() Bordeaux as follow lanta come thru the ground \\ W t \\ Disease of Beans. Bui. I.a. Kxp. Sta. 116 1-1 1. Fig. 1-3. H. R see of Pepper and 101:1-21. Re. 1-15. ins. Bui. La. Kxp. B. Fiji. 1-1 :&gt; ) Bean Diseases and Their Remedies. Bui. N. J. Kxp. 151:1-28. PI. 1-4. fig. 1-9. II 11 Diseases of Beans. Bui. N. Y. Cornell Kxp. 239:l ( .i")-l ) 14. Rg. UM»-1 I N M. and Tkmpi.k. C. E BEET LEAF Sl'( 1 1 &lt; ,\n spots with a reddish purple margin appear on the leaf. These spots increase in size and number leaves are expanded |»m|s hav. lestruction of diseased ]&gt;lants may be of Report on the AnthraenoK &lt;&gt;r Pod lean Anthracnoee. Bui. N. V. Cornell Kxp 255.4l».M47. Rg. 217-222. \nthracnoee of beans, ("ire. l)iv. of Hot.. Insect Pest ;uul Plant Dis. Hureau of Nebraska. 6:1-4. Fig.1-3. </seg>
            <seg id="p060">Agricultural Experiment Statu 38 .\ i hra* ■hi hi. In i v&lt; * \ lose. Hj and in severe attacks the leaves may be killed outri way the production of BUgar is very much reduced. 1. Do not &gt;rro\v beets on the same ground t\v 1899 Three Important Fungous Diseases of th Bui. V Y. Cornell Exp. Sta. 168:335-363. I 49-63 TOWNSEND, CO 1902 Some Diseast il I i ■ ' Meet . ' ' Rei Dept. Agr. 72 HI-KIl 1M 1OFT lo&gt;i This is a bacterial material. Manner and 1. Avoid planting heel 2. Develo] from well-drained soil. fBTCALT, H l&lt;»04 A Soft 1 Metcalf)- Itpt. Nelir. I 17 BLACKBERRY (ft ANTHHAf Ntisl Honey-colored spots with the leaves. Lighter colored s| canes. 1. Select new plants from health 2. Cut out and destroy old cam the fruit is gathered. 8. Spray with 5-5-50 Bordeaux aa i A. When new canes are 5-10 in&lt; B. Repeat twice at intervals of 10- 4 d 1892 Field Experiments for Raspberr \. N. J. Exp. Sta. IMl:266-26 12. Spray with 5-5-50 Bordeaux in cases wher dciuic of the iliseas*- is expected. Di ooak, B. M. :&lt;. Beets grown on \\ H U.STKD, B. I). </seg>
            <seg id="p061">Report 39 ( 4 A I \ 897 A t X. &lt; I) I I \. A ! M. A snl icnose of Raspberry and Blackberry. Special Mich. Exp. SU. 26:51-52. Fig. 37. aenoM of the Black Haspl&gt;erry. Bui. X. V. va Exp. Sta. 124:261-274. Tplate. ran ire-red in color and are produced in iwer surface of the leaves. The hyphae idy portion of the stein tad leaf stalks, i the roots, the leaves, or at the bu The germa may live over winter at- itation eels before planting for 15 minutes in either: tion of 1 ounce of corrosive'sublimate in KMHI ■s T df*water. tion of 1 pound of formalin in 30 gallons of water. e Prevention of R:ispl&gt;erry-Anthracnose by Cul- Methoda. Rpt. Conn. Kxp. Sta. 1899:274 CROWN OALL. cencea appear &lt;&gt;n the roots and lower part ■struv all affected plant ifected stuck. RANGE HIST (Gymnoconia interstitialu) he leaves, rendering treatment ig out and burn all infected plants. nay with Bordeaux to hold the disease somewhat in cheek R, B. &lt;&gt; 14 Orange Rust of Raspberry and Blackberry. 8] Bui. Mich. Ezp. Sta. 25 :"&gt;(»-", 1 . Fig. :*6. .;. \. •:? Orange Rust of Raspberry and Blackberry. Hul 111. Kxp. Sta. 29:27:-S-3&lt;K). PI. 1-4. CABBAGE ( .'■ m). BLACK H&lt; &gt;T &lt;trit). is a bacterial disease characterized by the developnieni </seg>
            <seg id="p062">Agricultural Experiment Station ixka 40 Harding, H. A.. Stkwart, F. C. and Pbucha, II. J. 11I04 Vitality of the Cabbage Black Hot Germ on ( . Bui. N. V. Geneva Exp. Station. 251:17, I'l. 1. LL, H. L. \ bacterial rot of cabbage and allied plai Smith, K. F. The Black Hot of the Cabbage. Fanners' Bui. I \ t ( of Affected Leaves. Bui. N. Y. Geneva Km 232:43-65. I'l. 1- CARNATION &gt; 1) Illl 1«&gt;1 1. Gather and des 2. Grow the most Heald. F. 1) 1«M)7 The Hud-H 103-;- 17. I'l. 1-ti II Silver Top of Jum Rl'ST il On the leaves dark colore the epidermis allowing the bli 1. Grow only the most re 2. Select your cuttings fn 3. Spray with a solution &lt; gallons water as follow A. In the field once \v B. [a*the greenhouse ne&lt; 4. Keep your carnation house that leaf surfaces are free from n ust Wis. Exp. Station. 66:l-:&gt;(» Fi-i. 1-15 Dept. Agr 68 : 1 -_» 1 . Stewaici m&gt; Babding, II. 1903 Combating the Black R bail*' bv the K This fungus a no value. A spci probably aids in 8TEWAKT, V. C. KSV Unix 1908 The Kporotrichum B ■]\\k 8ta. 7&gt;M </seg>
            <seg id="p063">'ail i\€port 41 it 1) I s'H 1) VI 4 I 1 KA1 S V( non n i ■e | A ten Carnation Rust. Bui. N. Y. Geneva Kxp. 100:33-6*. Fiji. 1-2 CHERRY yFrunu*) BLACK KNOT (I'lmmyhtia enters thru wounds or cr Vs a result of the growth tnorlxi.vi tcks tad develops within of the fungus the I to an abnormal growth; the hark is ruptured x posing a soft velvety cushion of fungus threads 3 cushion is at first yellowish hut turns to an olive irmvii color. The surface of this knot is covered upright threads on which the summer spoi. numbers. Durinj: the winter on the same knots fe develops in which spores are formed in ■ nside of the numerous cavities in the outer part of lie fall and winter cut out and hum all the knot ted and wild plums and eherrk ooperation of your neighbor! in waginj: wai estroy the Black Knot of Plum and Cherry I An Appeal. Bui. N. .1. Kxp. Sta. 78:1-14. Fig. 1-7 lack-Knot of Plums and Cherries, and Method I'reatment. Bui. N. Y. Cornell Kxp. Sta. 81:633-656. 1-6 ■ear on the leaf and when these diseased area - ic leaf the appearance which is responsible for the shot-hole. The English MoreUo and Montmorency iticularly susceptible. Younjr trees in the nur - kille&lt;l outright by this dis. S. A. sill' Black Knot of Plum ;ind Cherry. Bui. N. V. Genera Exp. Sta. 40:25-34. Rg. 1-9. i). B. I). BROWN ROT (&amp;i*r*tt*M frmd Brown Hot.) I SI'Ol OK SHOT HOLE (Citlindrmporium padi) pear on the leaf and when them diseased </seg>
            <seg id="p064">42 Agricultural Experiment Station A ( braska 1. Spray with 3-3-50 Bordeaux &gt;llo\v V. Just before tin- blossom pen. H. When the fruit is free fron the alvx /Hl(i' ! Dis. Burei :tll Takt. L. I{ l'.tixj Cherry I .eaf-MIit Rp M Exp 19 108-104 CORN /' *; MOI 1.1) 1) years of short crop diseased plants may or less mouldy anix and often small 1)1; Upon tearing opei grey and has a el takes place about t brought over from tl value for feeding pur will become the eent&lt; 1. Remove ears. HlKKILL. T. J. AM) Bakhi 1908 Dry Hot of Corn. (ire. 1 )\. E. M.. KM» I 117 w 1) 22 MM)'. i A Studv of Corn Mi \ i 31:37-39. RUST (Pu This rust has somewhat the appi hut each pustule is .surrounded by the di The leav&gt; vered with reddish l» t mi ( '. Two weeks lat( I). Two weeks later thai Hkin, W. H. l-.Ki.s Cherry Shothole (Cylindro of But. Insect \\-&gt;x and ¥\$l 1. &amp; This mould or Hkai.d. 1" 1). Wii.( l'.to'.i The Life-History and P iiw.) Lev. Rpt. Sebr. Stevens, V. L and Hall. .1. &lt;;. ot </seg>
            <seg id="p065">ml Aiiniml Report 43 \\ \ \ I'll) H, I red ;iiid later become dark brown. prominent about the first of September. uuch damage. Ml 1' (Uttiiaoo an t greyish anil later break open and k powdery mass erf spores. The disease may occur vi's. on the tamel, and most frequently on not infect the seedling as do the smuts ■y. It will infect any growing point at any a. The fungus growth is entirely local. vented bv the treating of the seed. masses by removing from the field and spores will germinate in fresh manure, hence ■sli manure on the fields where the crop was badly CUCUMBER (( VNTHRAC'NOSE (Cttttaluk ithum lui/mnrium i appear on the leaves, petioles and stems. In lall yellowish fruiting bodies develop. Control and Bibliography consult Ciicuml&gt;er — Downy • WXY MILDEW (Pemurplmmmopan re appear large angular yellow spots usually The oldest leaves are attacked first and wards the tip of the vine. Warm moist the disease. When the vines begin to ■'run everv 10-14 davs thruout the season (I. 1 I.") Downy Mildew, or Blight, Peronoplasmopera cul&gt; - (B. and ( '.) Clint., of Muskmelons and Cucumbers. Rpt. Conn. Kxp. Sta. 1904:329-362. PI. 29-31. F. EL, SimuNK. F. A. and Stewart, F. C. 1898 Sniavinji Will Savethe Pickle CroD. Mul. N. Y.Gmm is Spraying Will Save the Pickle Crop. Mul. N. V. Geaen .■)-.■)-.-&gt;{ I Bordeaux as follow Kxp. Sta. Pop. Kdit. 156:1-S. PI. 1-2. </seg>
            <seg id="p066">44 Agricultural I ni Station i Orton. W. A. [905 Spraying for Cucumbers and Melon Di» Bui". 231:1-24. Fig. 1-s Orton. \Y. A. and Garrison, \\ . I) 1906 Methods of Spraying Cucumbers. Bui. S. (' 116:1-M»&gt;. ' l'l. 1-4. Sklhv. A. D. 1V»7 Prevalent Diseases of Cucumbers, Melons, an Ski.hv, A. 1). ls&lt;(7 Prevalent I 1 f Cucumbers, Melons, and Bui. Oliio Exp. Sta. 89 :(•(»- 1_'_'. l'l Bui. Ohio Exp. Sta. 89 :(•(»- 1_'-_'. I 1 Shkldon. .1. I.. L9O4 It Melons ami Cucumbers During 1 Shkldon. .1. I. 1004 Diseases of Melons and Cucumbers During 1004. Bui. W. Va. Exp. Sta. M:121-138. l«t()4. Bui. W. Va. Exp. Sta. 94 : 1 2 1 - 1 :is SiHHINK. 1 \ IND &gt;h« W(l . 1 ('. 1898 Spraying Cucumbers in the Season of lvi.s. Y Geneva Exp. Sta. lft.375-398. PI. Rept. N. V. Geneva Exp. Sta. 1898ti7 13-17. 1 Vis leneva Exp. Sta. 166:375-396. 1' Stkwaki. F. C. In'.iT The Downy Mildew of the Cucumber; Wli and How to Prevent It. Bui. N "&gt; 119:153-182. l'l. 1-4. 1VI7 Further Experiments un Spraj N. V. Geneva Exp. Sta. 138:ti:&lt;t&gt;-»;4» GOOSEBERRY I /. l'OU DKHV MII.M.U 1. Gooseberries should l&gt;e planted on well-drain Stewaht. 1 •'. C and How to 1 1897 Further Experiments on Spraying N. V. Geneva 1 138:63) N. V. ( GOOSEBERRY 1'oU DKKV MILDEW 1. Gooseberri where there is tree circulation of the air. 2. Prime "ff the drooping branches. 3. Destroy the weeds in the plantation. 4. Spray with a solution of 1 mince &lt;&gt;t potassium where there is fre 2. Prune off the di&lt; 3. Destroy the weeds iii 4. Spray with a solutio 2 &lt;rall&lt;&gt;ns of water as follows: A. When the buds are opening. Repeat every week until the fruit is harve* K. ('. I'. L8B7 Spraying in ls'.t" to Prevent Gooseberry Bui. N. V. Geneva Exp. Sta. 133:4vi-."&gt;&lt;m'i. 1899 Treatment for Gooseberry Mildew. Bui. N. Y Exp. Sta. 111:153-164. I'l. 1-2. 2 gallons of water as follows A. When the buds Close, C. P. 1897 Spraying in IN'.i" to Prevent Gooseberry M 1899 Treatment for Gooseberry Mildew. Bui. N. Y. G </seg>
            <seg id="p067">'"/ .\nntitil Report 45 GRAPE ir its pedicel. The spores produced by can infect only the stem, tendril, leaf or trape. They will germinate and penetrate the oduee the summer spores in small chamben In the spring these same ehamben produce n which the spores are produced within Remove all "mummied" fruits when you prune the vines. in the spring and turn under all old fruits and Hake the rotted fruit and dead leaves, under furrow and cover with a hoe face cultivation and destroy weeds ami Keep vines thoroly sprouted: if necessary sprout twicf iO Bordeaux as follow \. From the appearance of the third leaf until the middk leaves on the new growth particularly well. the foliage becomes den- .er att( horo work. nmoniacal M JuK later use 80-100 gallons to the acre: have a KM) lhs. and a nozzle with a one-sixteenth nozzle with a one-sixteenth 1904 Spraying drapes for Black Hot in Krie County. I'enna. 66:l-lti. Fig. 1-2. Edson. A. \\ 1903 The Black Hot of tlu Grape in North Carolina and V Car. Exp. Sta. 185:133-156. It- Treatment. Bui. 1). \\i) Wilson. I l'.io.s The Black-Hot of the (irape and Its Control. Bui. N. Y. Cornell Exp. Sta. 253:367-3KX. Fig. 177-187. BLACK ROT (Gvigiumtia of this fusgua is produced &lt;&gt;n the Mack pper carbonate u follow Mul. Pa. Exp. Sta </seg>
            <seg id="p068">46 Agricultural Expt Xeb nt Sin Scribner, F. L. 1888 Report on the Fungus Diseases (if the Grap Bui. But. Div. I". S. Dept. Agr. 1:1-136. I'l. 1886 Report on the Ft \ Mul. Hot. Div S. Dept. Aer. 2:1-1 W. V 1891 Some Fungous Diseases of the Grape. Bui. Exp.SU. IV. l't. 4:97-118. Fig. 1-26. 1891 Some Fungous I) ■( he drape Exp.SU. IV. l't. 4:97-118. Fig. [-26 Selby. A. D. Selby. A. D. 1001 Grape lU&gt;ts in Ohi« Hul. Ohio Exp. Sta. 125 1901 Crape Rota in &lt; &gt;! ■ Exp. Sta. 123 S ■ Fig. 1-3. l c .io_&gt; The Relati f Grape Spraying to Public Bui. Ohio Exp. Sta. 13O:V_'-4ti Wilson, C. S. and Reddkk, 1). 1909 The Black Roi of the Grape and Its Control. Report. Bui. N. Y. Cornell Exp. Sta. 266 i Fig. !-:• 1902 The Relat I'ul Bui. O 130 i Hi Wilson, C. S. and 1! kddi 1) l'JO'l The Hlack Roi of 1 he Grape ami Its ( Report, liul. N. V. ( 266 k 99-110. Fie. «m-i in LETTUCE / LETTUCE Dli&lt; U' OB P.i ' : du&lt; u 1 oi; This fungus and causes a very Midden "wilt" or "drop" of the plant: small white bodies about the &gt;ize i&gt;f pin heads which ar found both on the - it the dead | found both ( resting Btages of the fungus and serve to earn resting sta season to another. The d - rularlv ii season to anoth house lettuce. house lettuce. I. In i;i-eenhouse&gt; the lie&gt;t method i- lepth "f '_' to 4 inc 2. Covering tl sand or soil is v 3. Maintain 4. If the above nictlio soil for each crop Stone, (J. E. and Smith. R. I 1900 The Hotting of Gre« Hul. M ih&lt; .( Sta. 69:1-40. Fi- 1-10 OATS (I BLACK RUST OH STEM RUST ./ This rust very closelv resembles the Black rust of barley and wheat. Hn barlev rust nor wheat rust nor can these be attacked The leaves and steins first become covered with reddish brow e </seg>
            <seg id="p069">•cond Annual Report ntu-. 47 n dark brown r black. By the time the ecome black the plants are usually very much damaged. f li&lt;;ht rains or dews followed by lie it her arc ideal for the rust. This any of the native grasses also. Seep down the native grasses around the held. eing equal, the earliest varieties will t&gt;e least to have the plants mature early. such a manner aa to give all plants an even which have shown themselves to lx&gt; rust Hil liography of Barley— Black Rust cm &gt;\VX HIST OH RKD RUST (Pucrinia eonmatu the one most frequently found on oats. It occurs ives which frequently become almost crusted over wderv summer spores. These also occur on the xtent. Later in the season the small dark lines thcs&gt; are the winter spon the lame conditions favor this rust as pointed [ or stem rust of oats. Oats growing in verv rich severely attacked its growing over stack stackyard psted for oat black or stem rust are Bibliography at finrlrj HUrk Rust). HIDDEN SMUT (UttUage \t harvest time the heads contain no seeds but in their place t masses. In threshing, t h- en up and the spores scattered. Some of these ttached to the oat grains. These spores are sown K'IMIIIK mil infection takes place only when the seedling .vith th before it appears above the ground. The fungus vt laments or byphae keep pace in their growth with that of the oat plant itself </seg>
            <seg id="p070">48 ultunil Experiment Station Nebraska 1. For smaller amounts of seed use cither one of tin n&lt; given for barley smut, or the following for oat loos* modified formalin method is the most convenient. 2. For larger amounts of seed the chimney met! rapid and should l&gt;e used whenever pi hit LOOSE SMI 1 At harvest time the heads contain no seed but appear t 1" powdery masses of black spores. The away l&gt;efore harvest time leaving little but the empty times only a barren stalk. Th iV which they adhere. InftM very small. The fun&lt;; their growth with th r^ This smut may be prev for barlev smut. 1 The Modified Formalin Method (No. 2) i- tin Where large amounts are to be treated the Tower Met satisfactory Construct a chimnev H On the inside shelve side. Mv means the grain near the top in be allowed to lie in a bin or removed to another bin. Tl dried by running thru the place of the formalin spray. H treated in an hour at a cost (Consult the Bibliography of H lowing:) Arthur. .1. C. 1905 Rapid Method of R Bui. Ind. Kxp. Sta. 103. Goff, E. S 1901 The Prevention of Oat Sm pecial B w Kx Sta. Kellekman. W. A. and Swim, i.k. YV. I 1886 Preliminary Report on Smut Oats. H Kai Kxp. Sta. 8. 1890 Report on Loose Smuts ofCen Rpt. Kan Kx, Sta. 2. </seg>
            <seg id="p071">7 ml Annual Rt 49 W. 1 nt of Smut in Oats and Wheat. Farmers' Dept. Agr. 5. lent of Oat- few Smut. Rul. Ill of Oats for Smut. Hul. 111. Exp. Sta. 64. revention of Stinking Smut in Wheat and Loose event ion of Stinking Smut in \V in Oata. Farmers' Bui. I ONION (Allium cepa). UIUT (I'rocyatis cepuh- n Outs. Farmers' Hul. V . S. Dept. Agr. 250. ONION (AUium cepa). SMUT (Urocyttit cepulue t appeals as black lines on thi tppeara as black lines on the green foliage ■ I develop on the scales of the b develop on the scales of the bulb. when plante&lt;l in clean soil rare when planted in clean soil rarely have smut. ip rotation. itation. \\ ting seeds drill into the rows KM) pond linji seeds drill into the lows da of air-slaked lime to the acre. i H 1- H INK. F. A. AM) STKWUiT. F. C r and Lime for Onion Smut. Bui Lime for Onion Smut. Bui. N. Y. Geneva Sta. Pop. Edit. 182:1-V Sta. Pop. Edit. 182:1-V \. 1) Smut. Preliminary F.xperimen Ol Smut. Preliminary Experiments. Bui. Ohio Sta. 122:71-n4 Sta. 122 71-N4 evention of Onion Smut. Hul. ention of Onion Smut. Bui. Ohio F.x) 131 r-.-&gt;i. I MM. V ('. F. A x peri men tc on the Sulphur-Lime Treatment for ments on the Sulphur-Lime ' Smut. Hul. X. Y. Geneva K\n V. Geneva Exp. Sta. 182:145- Pl. 1 PEA /' mttrun \1 SPOT, l'(H) SPOT (&gt;K BLIGHT {Atmkg* F i ■in of the seedling near the ground severe cases the plants may wilt and die. particularly in Diseased spots appear on the leaves and if the dis- ves may die. On the pods there lembling very much those of the like the anthiacnose fungus. ows thru the pod and into the seeds in which it will winter over. 1. riant none but healthv seed from healthv fields. Tying up the vines and spraying with Bordeaux mixture le in seeming healthy seed peas. vt )(&gt;tS </seg>
            <seg id="p072">50 Agricultural Experiment Stai \( braska Halsted, B. D. lS'.t4 Some Fungous Disease:- of the Pea. Upt. N. .1 M Sta. 1893:357-362. Fie. 30-32 Van Hook, .1. M. MKKi Blighting of Field and Garden Peas. Powder M of the Pea. Bui. Ohio Exp. Sta. 173 49 Fig. 1-12. POWDERY MILDKW / This disease may be recognised I by the mycelium of the fungus on the cleaves and st he mycelium of the fungu fungus may live over wint&lt; 1. Spray with 5-5-50 I ;us may live over winter on the 1. Spray with 5-5-50 Bor«i&lt; at iatervi until tin Hook. .1. II. l'.NKi Powdery Mildew of the 171:247-249. Fig. 12. PEACH BROWN Hoi S and at intervals ?AM Hook. .1. M l'.KKi Powderv Mildi 178:247-249. Fi PEACH I HOWN RO1 Causes a spotting of the leaves a rot of the fruit. The fruit bec&lt; numerous brown puetuli and • i-ot of the fruit. Tl with numerous brown ] eased fruits may fall tot! mies" until sprint;. ( &gt;ti may develop Beany outg produced. il fruits may fall to the ground oi until sprini;. i I develop Beshy outgrowths on llH'fd. 1. Plant the most resistant vai 1. Plant the most resist) l&gt;e immune hut some are less mmune hut some are less injurei 2. Keep the trees well pruned : 3. Thruout the season pick an 2. Keep the trees well pruned and thin out t 4. In the fall gather and bun 1! or remaining on the trees ."&gt;. Spray with 4-4-50 Bordeaux as follow A. Before the buds pen. (i. Spray with self boiled lime-sulfur wash as follows A. When fruit is about inch in diameter B. Repeat every two weeks until about two wet on the fruit is ripe. </seg>
            <seg id="p073">// Annual R, 51 \ s 1907 12 \. 1 1/ 50 I ( M yt'.t l i 164 -V. A \ \. I tOO Peach \eg. PI. 1 ranches that appt Rot. Hul. Oregon Exp Sta. 57:1-15. Fig. 1-7 i: e Peach. Rpt Mo. State Hd. of Hort 'N5-2N9 rena. Tru Acad. Sci. St. I. -97. PI. 18-21 Hot of Peache a frudigi na Peraoon) 269. Fig. l-'t. EAF CTR1 / ly curled and swollen and covered all of the leaf may become curled. Infection of leaves in the spring may take pluct perennial mycelium &lt;&gt;f the twig if or (l&gt;) spore infection. Tin tion takes place by the second method sulfur or 2 pts. blue vitriol to ."&gt;&lt;) gallon ill and Plum Pockets. Hul. N. V. Cornell Kxp 73:319-355. PI. 1-20. Leaf-Curl and Notes on the Shot-Hole Kffeet of iies and Plums. Bui. N. V. Cornell Kxp 167-388. Fir o4-7i&gt;. Leaf Curl. Its Nature and Treatment. Bui. Div Phys. and Path. U. 8. Dept. Agr. 20:l-2m O ROSETTE. of unknown cause. It derives its common characteristic rosette-like groups of small :it various points on a diseased tree. luins and Other Fruits Bui. Ga. Kxp imial in the small twi^s which •«&gt;ks before buda &lt;&gt;iH&gt;n -"&gt;() Bordeaux mixture just m buds begin to Ml The Prevention of Peach Leaf Curl. Bui. N. Y. Cornell Exp. Sta. 180:31&lt;&gt;-:m. </seg>
            <seg id="p074">52 [(/ric ult urul Experiment Stdt X, h 1. Destruction of infected trees is the onlv method ot' cont Bailey, L. H. iv.14 Peach Yellows. B (1 N. Y. Cornell Ex 75 408. Fig. 1-G Selby, A. D. 1896 Peach Yellow Mu Ohio Kxn 1898 Pouch Yellow n Ohio Exp. St 92: lit Fig. 4-5. PI. 1-2 Smith. E. 1 1891 Additional Eviden m the ( •o Yellows and Pei Rose PI. 1 Hid. 1) \ , md Path. 1:1-0." 1893 Experiments with Fertilizers for Preventioi if Peach Yellow g, 1889-92. Bui. 1) Dept. Act. 4:1-197. Y, md Path. I . 8 Peach H( 17:1-20. Fig. 1- Brown or nearly 1 &gt; 1 fruit : then spot.- may e the rtift is confined to result. !. Spray dormant trees 2. Spray with :{-:&lt;-")( I 1 A. Before the tilo Selby, A. I). 1904 Peach Diseases III. Studies ii Curl and Scab. Bui. Ohio I 148 YELLOW Like the rosette the cause The symptoms comprise the develop: premature ripening of the fruit in tin appear. 1. Destruction oi miected ti only method of control. (Consult Bibliography (if IVach I 72:193-201 Fie. 1-6. PI. 1 L8M Peach Yellows]ai SCAB OH BI..U K SPOT &lt;( B. Again after t\v </seg>
            <seg id="p075">/ A hi, 53 K M B e \ lv lv MITH. I 1 PEAR 1'ijnu communix). riven under Apple Fire Blight and in it of nitrogenous fertilizers used and avoid dent growth of young wood. :int varieties \\ curreiice and Treatment of Fire Blight in Pear Orchard. Bui. Va. Exp. BU. 136:49-66. lti-L'l). 1) » on Tear Blight. Hpt. Del. Exp. Sta. 12-1900: 43. Fie. 1-3. No Pc • Blight ;,nd Pear Canker. Bui. Del. Exp L-8. Fig. 1-7. 52 B. Th and Prevention of Pear Blight. Yearbook S. Dept. Agr. 1895:295-300. Mi Ui (Vrnturia y, nna this disease are the same as for apple scab. develops on the old leaves on the leaves and scab of clean up and d&lt; troy all dead leaves in the •very winter with Bordeaux mixture limt'-sulfur-salt. as follows \. When the buds are slightly swollen. 0-."&gt;0 iu\ When, about a week later, the petals l&gt;egin to show. -."&gt;() Bordeaux. A !&gt;4 Experiment* in Preventing Pear Scab. Rpt. N. Y, Geneva Exp. Sta. 12-1893:094-717. PI. 7-8. !I4 Experimenta in Preventing Pear Scab in 1893. Bui N. Y. Geneva Exp. Sta. 67:1S3-2O4. Fig. 1-2. E K)5 Pear Scab. Bui. Calif. Exp. Sta. 163:1-18. Fig. 1-9 Ill OR PEAB BLIGHT (Bacillus amylovonu) of the fungui t stage emuKi </seg>
            <seg id="p076">54 Agricultural Experiment Slat Net i ski a PLUM (Prunu CANKER The exact cause (if the well-known canker cherries has never been determined. P LEAF BPOT ("R 8HOT HOLE {Cytimdrwtftr (Consult Cherry Leaf Spot or Shot Hole. /"' POTATO (Sol, DRV ROT This rot attacks the tubers while still in th entrance to the interior thru the in the skin of the potato. It may lie (let or woody. If slightly disc: place the rot will develop in th potatoes in the bin. Th not been infected. In the sto check by the following measures 1. Throw out all tubers show 2. Throw out all bruised ami 3. Store in a cool dry place: t 40° F. Clinton, ('.. P 1895 DrvKnd-Rot. Bui. 111. Exp. Sta. 401.V.I-14 Smith, E. F. and Swingle, I). B. 1904 The Dry Hot of Potatoes Due to 1 55 EARLY RI.IC.H1 !// This disease appears about the time the plant.- are in blooi in the" form of small grayish-bn by faint concentric eirch \vn sp( Inch are ke 1. Spray with 4-4-.'&gt;0 Horde ginning when the plants are six inches high. BROWN ROT (/BdmrnHmia fnttti* I'each — Brown Hot. of a ring inside of the pot.-i companying it the potato !*■&lt; some extent by planting onl Bui. Bur. Plant End. V. S. Depl PI. 1-V ut\ at intervals &gt; *\ t \\ * • wcet- </seg>
            <seg id="p077">7 •cond Annual Report 55 ntu- M W. .1 (»()7 1 \ \ 1 S'.H lvt Stewart, I I'M) 1 "tops" and hum them to prevent the ve Bibliography of Potato— Late Blight and Rot.) INTERNAL BROWN SPOT. ndicates. this dinfuwf is characterized bv the spots in the tuber. This it a rather obscure ly has its origin in some physiological dis - i organism has yet l&gt;een connected with it. sternal Brown Spot of the Tuber. Bui. Maine Exp- Sta. 149: 318-321. Fig. 1 IK BLIGHT AM) ROT {Phytophthora mfestam). juh causing tliis disease enters the leaves thru the these stomates later emerge the threads on spores arc produced. Not only are the la spores are washed down with the soil and I t of the tubers. ."&gt;() Bordeaux as follows When the plants are "Mi inches hii;h. every 10-14 days — making 5-7 applications 50-100 gallons to the acre at each application. 1) Dwny Mildew. Jor Blight, PhytopkUutrm injestan* Mont.) DeBy., of Potatoes. Rpt. Conn. Exp. 1904. :«;:;-:&lt;s4. PL :V_&gt;-37. H.. Stewart, F. ('. v\i&gt; Bubtace, H. .1. Effect of Certain Aiscnites on Potato Foliage. Bui. N. V. Geneva Rxp. Sta. 267:- &gt; «:M ) S4. PI. 1-2. fig. 1. ( Potato Diseases on Long Island in the Season of Bui, N. V. Geneva Exp. Sta. 101:09-86. Spraying Potatoes on Long Island in the iSeason of 1S96. Bui. N. V. Genera Exp. Sta. IS 233-250. PI. 1. fie. 1. ('.. Eustace, H. .1.. French, (i. T. and Sirbink, F. A. Potato Spraying lvxperiments in 1906. Bui. N. Y. Geneva Exp. Sta. 4*0:237-321. PI. 1-2. </seg>
            <seg id="p078">56 Agricultural Experiment Station o Stewart, F. ('.. Eustace, H J. and SiKiUNK. F. A 1902 Potato Spraying 1 xperiments in 1902. H 221 :236-263. X. \ \ n SCAB (Oo The common name well in known disease. Other cai scab and the whole question 1. If the soil is badly ii several years mav l&gt;e necess; in 2. Plant onl] ■i. Treat the either A. Solut f wat( 1?. Soluti Arthur. J. C. 1897 Formalin for Pi Kxp. Sta. 65 ;i Bolley, H. I 1890 Potato Scab: A 1'. I 1891 Potato Scab and I Jones, L. R. and Edsoh, A. \V. 1901 Potato Scab and It&gt; Pi 85:109-120. Fig. 1-2 Morse, W. J. 1907 The Prevention of Potato Bui. M 141:81-92. Hie become soft. wet. soggy, and have an offensive It gains cracks in the tuber due to the drv rot to bruises Geneva Exp. 8ta. Bl:235-263. 1903 Potato Spraying Experiments in 190.5. H Geneva Exp. 8ta. J41:251-292 I'l. 1-12 1905 Potato Spraying Experiments* in 1904. H Geneva Exp. 8ta. 264:9.V_&gt;o4. PI. 1-lti. 1906 Potato Spraying Experiments in 1906. M Geneva Exp. Sta. 171:153-229. PI. t-5. 256. 277-287. 1*1 Dak. Exp. Sta. 4 SOFT ROT {Bacillus tola This rot is due to bacterial acti&lt; often follows or accompanies t he drj </seg>
            <seg id="p079">Twenty-second Annual Report 57 &gt;vhm prod 1 Discard all cut and bruised potato? 1 dry cellar. The temperature of the cellar it 40° F. V Bacterial Disease of the Tomato, Eggplant, and Irish Potato (Bacillus solanacearum n. sp.). Bui. Div. Yeg. Phys. and Path. 0. S. Dept. Agr. 12:1-26. PI. 1-2. ite in the spring considerable loss is sustained sprouting. K potatoes dark, dry and at a temperature of about RASPBERRY iRutrus rp.). ANTHRACNOHE (dloeosporium venetum). Blackberry Anthracnos CROWN GALL Blackberry Crown (iall). RUST (dymnoconid interstitial™ Blackberry Rust). ROSE BLACK 8POT (Actmonema rosae ick patches of the fungua mycelium appear on vere attacks these patches may cover the entire nay outdoor roses with 5-5-50 Bordeaux as followi A. When first spots appear on the leaves. B. Repeat three times at intervals of 8-10 days. &gt;prav greenhouse roses with ammoniacal copper carbonate ,veek until the disease is checked. MILDEW (Sphaerotheca humuli and pannosa). ■ leaves, buds and young shoots l&gt;ecome covered with a covering of the mycelium. The numerous summer spores the leaf a powdery appearance. In the greenhouse keep the steam pipes covered with a : equal parts of lime and sulfur mixed in water. SPROUTING. </seg>
            <seg id="p080">58 Agricultural Experiment Station 7 A. Spray 2-3 times with solution of potassiun ounce to M) gallon of water) every 7-1(1 d; B. Dust 2--i times with sulfur every 7-10 davs RYE (,sv alt rtrrnlt ERGOT (('/« 7&gt;* purp This fungus disease attacks the ovary and transf an inch long an&lt; an inch in diameter. This mass is known as "e storage organ of the fungus. The spring follow le spores. These infect the ovaries in fungus is perpetuated from year to year. The fung Bummer spores which spread th&lt; This disease also occurs on mai it becomes a source of dan of the cultivated grass( other? 1. The irrass should he so that no ergot will lie forme 2. Patches that are l.adl to destroy the ergot as the gr« ■i. I iras-es around the rvc l&gt;e kept mowed dow 4. Some authors recommei contain ergot with the smut trea o. In saving seed the ergot sin Hul. N. 23:1-7. Fig. 1-3 McCarthy, (I 1891 Plant Diseases and How N Car. Exp. Sta. 76:20 Williams, T. O. 1893 Home Plants Injurious to 81 D Ex, Sta. 11:40-43. 2. Out-of-door roses .should Ik- treated in i M wavs : a purplish-black ma» about In this "ergot" produces a numbei wild rye grasses, wil Heald, F. D. and I'ktkhs. A I 1906 Ergot and Ergotism. </seg>
            <seg id="p081">59 &lt; 1 t ORAXCE LEAF RUST (/ lelv resembles the leaf rust of wheat. The owever does not grow on rye nor vice versa. &gt;\v lines and patches of powdery orange red spread until the whole leaf may \&gt;e covered formed beneath the epider- This rust occurs also on aruund'the Held Ke( he native grass* tiny the volunteer rye that conies up before the regular in such a manner as to give all the plants an •ties known to lie rust resistant graphy of Barley Black Rust i SORGHUM, KAFIR CORN, BROOM CORH (Sorgktm ntly&lt;tre HEAD SMIT (Spharelothrrn nilinnn destroys the whole head. At harvest time the velop but at the point where they should l&gt;e there ass of spores much resembling the smut of corn. with formalin, hot water or Milestone method following suggestion seed from fields known to be free from head smut, e that this seed has not l&gt;een threshed bv \ nery that was used to thresh smutted sorghum. mi have once secured clean seed, raise vour C. At" eed and OH your own machinery in taking it Bibliography of Sorghum — Kernel Smut.) KERNEL SMIT (S^hncelothtca .wnjhi \ time the heads contain no seed but are made up of of spores which is so well protected by the ! that the smut may not be noticed until harvesting or even ireshing. The spores are scatteredfin threshing and some of Later there an tics the teliasporc </seg>
            <seg id="p082">60 .~\(jric utturnl tj x jM'i'i tut' nt iSttilioH oj ka them adhere to the seed. These are sown with the plant Incomes infected l&gt;efore it readies the surface of 1. Secure free from smut. 2. Grow your own seed and harvest and thresh it w own machinery. 3. If you must plant smutted seed treat it methods given for barley smut. Clinton, (i. P. 1897 Broom Corn Smut Freeman. M. K. and Umbesgi 1906 The Smuts of Sorghum. Circ. Bur. Plant Ind. V. S. 8 STRAWBERRY [Fro LEAF SPOT. HIST OH LEAF BLK Light brown spots with purplish leaves, which may die 1. When settine c leaves before taking the plant 2. Cut down the plants i gathered. 3. Spray with 5-5-50 Bo 4. Plant the most resists Bailey. L. H. 1VI4 Leaf Blight. Bui. N. \ 79 Fig. 1. TOMATO ( I. a.,,,,, H( ) IS There are several distinct sort different organisms. These can oft certainty by a specialist only. 1. Keep the vines off the ground to permit of good ventilat entilatioi 2. Spray with 4-4-.")() Bordeaux xture if necc Pool, Vents 1906 Some Tomato Fruit Rots During 1'tllT. Rpt. Nebr Hul. 111. Apr. Kxp. Sta. 47 . H. .1. C. A. Soon after crow B. Repeat thm Exp. Sta. 21:3-33. PI. 1-2. </seg>
            <seg id="p083">I nn mil Ht[M&gt;rt 61 s i IZAHKTH H I 1 . The Blossom End Hot of Tomatoes. Technical Bui. WHEAT I Tnticum vulynn \ K Kl SI OR STKM HIST (Pucriuia fframinU tritici). t is very commOB in years having ■ good rainfall aiul leys practically the entire crop. It seems to It - spring wheat than on winter wheat when l«&gt;th arc •me community. Among the spring wheats the acaroni wheats seem to l&gt;e least affected. It first ddish lines on the leaves and stems. These i:n id size, often running together to form large streaks me dark brown or nearly black. In both stage.- inteer wheat and some of the early sown wheat d rust. It is probable that in this region the rust er in the winter wheat and some of the wild grasses rust starts again in the spring. In some localitie ing the barberry hedges are affected with a cluster nother form of this rust. Where this occurs the i much inoii' severely rusted in the vicinity of the &gt;wn all barberry hedges. t try to grow both winter wheat and spring wheat section. ilunteer wheat. way as to give all plants an even chance. [&gt;g8 being equal, early wheats will suffer least, resistant varieties. K twn the wild a le the seed, sowing only grain of perfect form t &gt;perlv till and drain the -oil. ll. Practice the most desirable crop rotation It the Bibliography of Barley— Black Rust). Pi- Mas-. Exp. Sta. 3:1-11). Fig. 1-6 [iiently bordered by the ruptured epidermis. In ecially wild barley and wild </seg>
            <seg id="p084">62 Xifi'tc nit lu'til hj'pt nun tit i^hitntn X, ORANGE LEAF RUST d'u This rust is very common on tht parent somewhat earlier than the I&gt;1 principally to the leave*. The rust first a| powder on the leaves. This grad whole leaf is covered. This is the summer stage. L; followed by the winter spore stage consisting of and patches formed under the epider or summer spores, remain alive for son is harvested and infect the volunteer wheat and later the f wheat. Here it lives ov he wint plant and is ready t t the infection i luster cup st tti ■ of this rust is not know rust also occurs on somt ust also occurs uii some of the wild grass wheat Krat»3». I h vlwat grasses. I h 'se help to parry the f till fall and during tin ill fall and during the winter. The pli and seed selection ml seed selection recommended for the 1 ■vice here. 1 f service here. The campaign against Ix carried on at t arried on at t'i &gt; same time. (Consult the Bibliography of Barley Black LOOHE -Ml I At harvest time the affected heads en t (Consult the Bibliogr&amp;pl v of Bar I .( K &gt;: E SMI I At harvest time tin as black powdery masse blow the spores away 1 head and a few bracts s black powdery masses of spores. In tt )low the spores away leaving only the n viim lead and a few bracts or scales. Infection takes place at flow nto the embryo of the developing seed eed a smutted plant will develop the fol ray l&gt;e prevented by the Jensen A. Soak the s ■&lt;&gt;(! for ■"&gt; hou nay l&gt;e prevented by the Jensen modifiei A. Soak the s ■&lt;&gt;(! for .*&gt; hours in col H. Pla«3 in water kept at \-M) J V. t C. Spie.id out on a clean floor or d NOTE: jThis treatment is very sevei H. Pla«3 in water kept at 130° I C. Spie.id out on a clean floor oi Tains will lie killed. A fourth to a half l han under ordinary conditions, i. e.. inste per acre two and a half to three should be w (('(insult the Bibliography of Barley I i </seg>
            <seg id="p085">\nnual Report 63 7 •and »' \ STIX KING SMtT OK HINT (Tilletia foetant). the affected heads contain do seed but in their ■iries filled with black smut masses having a dis- In threshing, the false lorries are broken open icattered; some of them adhere to the grains spores are sown with the grain and the wheat cted before it appears above the soil. This age not only in reducing the yield but wheat ide in the market as it is unfit for milling ■ !• prevented by any one of the methods and oat smuts. For small amounts the it lalin Method is easiest to apply. For large amount: method cited under oat smut is most advantageoui I) Stinking Smut of Wheat. Press Bui. Nebr. OS H t i. 28. Reprinted as Bui. Nebr. Insect Pest Si Plant Disease Bureau 2:1-S. Fig. 1-3 k. AND SWINGLX, W. T. IAN, W 190 Pre ninary Experiments with Fungicides for Stink Smut Of WlTeat. Bui. Kans. Agr. Exp. Sta. 12. reatment of Stinking Smut in Wheat. Bui. Col. \gr. Exp. Sta. 79. </seg>
            <seg id="p086"/>
            <seg id="p087">INHERITANCE OF COLOR IN THE SEEDS OF THE Bt R. A. Emerson. COMMON BEAN, Phaseolux vulgar*. </seg>
            <seg id="p088">CONTKN'J Introduction Prmenm and absent Total and partial pi Total pigmentation I a ten Factors concerned in pic Mottled and .-elf pig Latent mottlini Theories regarding n Relation of mottling Relation of color liv Summary. </seg>
            <seg id="p089">i Emer 1UH4 INHERITANCE OF COLOR IN THE SEEDS OF THE COMMON BEAN, Pkmmthu ndgaris. H\ K. A. Eami INTRODUCTION. 1 began crossing races of beans whether there are any definite prin - heritanm in croMbred plants. During the ork tu earned on as rapidly as my limited it this first work was done in entire ignorance 1 by Gregor Mendel many years l&gt;efore and n after my hybridization experiments were without saying that all my later results have ■ cars while this work was being carried on, ne of the results secured were published. 1 nation of the second of these papers, the work ipted by other duties and was all but aban- ig to assistants and thru the help of the Adams tabled to take up the work on a much more ever before. During the two or three d Ix' devoted to the work, considerable h could not then be studied. A large ■dentally destroyed without any it What remained has recently 1 records of it have been made. Then and nade have been brought together to serve the more extensive work now being undertaken records as have to do with color inheritance are Utho many of them are fragmentary, it is be ve real value, particularly when considered in ■ important results recently reported by othjr r li^ht of Mendelian principles ree yean. Recently by transferring much K. A. Ann. K|&gt;t. Nefar. \&gt;:r. Expt Sta. 15::JO-43 (1902) and 17: 33-88 </seg>
            <seg id="p090">AfricuUural^Experimenl Station of V r' Kin- I ■ A (ran The carefully guarded The method - the work were dei two seasons, all the pi frame covered with wii variably used individui supported by a frame of plants has always been done ii has been performed durin. about, in which case the flowe I have often found it conveni shorten the name*. of the races, wl confusing them with similar name- ;( forms are used in this paper as I have shortened them, togethe or less conimonlv used. </seg>
            <seg id="p091">R&lt; 69 dividual plant &lt;-&lt;&gt; ( liven I'nil. Black Wax leu W Wa\. Davis White Wax Dwarf II. Black Wax 14 Pod (iuldeii Wax. 1 Wax. P.. I Keenev'a Rustless Gulden Wax. i\ \\ White Marrow Fiel Kailv Mohawk. \ Field. White Navy. \ M Par </seg>
            <seg id="p092">Agricultural Experiment Sta 70 V hi P. :{. Details of the individual plant cover. I Plain «iili »n 11. Lightmuatin suck drawn over the ■ .1 . : . 1 . the item mi . rolific Black Prolific Black \\ Hound l'od Kidney Round Pod Kidney VV:i Scarlet Flageolet Scarlet Flageolet '■■ Tennessee Tenni Ultra Ne I'lus Ultra. Wardwell Wardwell's Kidney Wax. Warwick l'.arl\ Warwick. Yellow live -Improved Yellow I PRESENCE AND ABSENCE i '1 PICMKN In all cases that have come under my n of pigment in bean seeds has been dominant pigment. The recessive allelomorph, unpi always appeared in ]■'., and has tnvariahly bred true i tions. The pigmented 1" : . individuals likewise, in 1. ha: ■nera the} have been tested, have followed Mendelian e\|ie&lt; of them having ln^en homosygoutu and a part het« us respect to the pmenee of pigment. The numeriri a be- tween the different forms has, on the whole, been </seg>
            <seg id="p093">oml A annul Report 71 expectation. The exceptions have been nail numbers dealt with in certain cases, le writer and his students illustrating the »ean seeds are as follows, the first named ng the nan-pigmented one: Davis-Challenge Pod, Davis-Ultra. Davis-Scarlet Flageolet, Da via- Ward well, July- Warwick, Navy Navy-Challenge Black. Navy-Wardwell, Navy k \ -Ultra, Marrow-Paris, .lones Stringless-Golden :less-Hyl)rid ."&gt;7. Jones Stringless-Burpee String - iennaii Black. Of the F, individuals of the II pigmented and none without pigment. from some of the above crosses, 280 were pig- hite, a small excess of whites over the one - ige 98). Twenty-five F 2 whites produced white seeds. In two cases these white re - i the F, generation and in one case to F 5 nice of pigmented forms. Seven pigmented iced ( .ll F, plants all with pigmented seeds. gmented F, individuals yielded in F, 101 pitf - vhite individuals, or something more than 2,") \l. AND PARTIAL I'KiMKNTATION lave pigment either over the entire surface only a part of the surface. In the latter lly appears around the "eye" of the ■ without pigment. The pigmented area in greatly in extent in different races and thin a race. In some races it is reduced the hiluin, while in others it sometimes four-fifths of the surface of the seed. etited bean has l&gt;een crossed with an eyed \YI iceurred in F, to the exclusion of the eyed type. In F, the eyed form has again appeared and in true. Some of the totally pigmented F, individuals have bred true while others, on being self-fertilized. pigmented and eyed forms. The de- tailed results of these crosses are shown in the following tables. </seg>
            <seg id="p094">Total Currie ■ Golilen \\ WardweU ■ CiuJleoi fioldoii Wax • Mo [otal Carrie ■ Golden WardweU ■ Challenge Bli Goldpu Wax ■ Mohawk Total 16 pected. there having Lh&gt;&lt;&gt;ii onlj of them as of the partially pigmei \\ Carrie • G«Jd&lt; Wardwcll ■ L'hallcii) Golden \\-i\ M.i The totally pigmente 72 it ii rut I: Tablk I. —Resiil : totally pit liil limns. Nib I'un-F •,llv Pan |&gt;i!Xlll Currie T ■ Golden U WardweU I. illener Bkek 1 Clolder, Mohawk 7\ Yellow i;&gt;. Horticultural / I... ,! ,fi.-r the i </seg>
            <seg id="p095">■. 73 the small number of F, plants se - real significance is not apparent. F, ind vidu&amp;la, there was a slight excess Is, the ratio of the two types lentt F, individuals ' Hi are i id that all of the :S"&gt; F, individuals 1111 n some cases the offspring were too few to he parents. This is true of all issitvm Golden Wax and Golden Wax X Mo - if Wardwell X Challenge Black. Some however, were almost certainly yielded 23 totally pigmented individual: tented ones. Similarly, the results in few for proof in all cases, that the later generations point even more grown 38 F, plants with eyed (partially nd 3 of these yielded ti.~) eyed individuals ii; MENTATION LATENT IN WHITE HI mented («yed) Immii^ This fact was noted and illustrated in without any appreciation of have been made, the results iiir table IW Ann Rpt. Nebr. Agr. Expt. St:i. 15: 41 190-J teroiygoua with respect to total dentation were homozygous with raped were homozygous with n From 4 F, partially pignu iced 750 V, individuals of the eved &lt;xU' totally pigmentod - F, plants haw prod </seg>
            <seg id="p096">74 Africvttwrml Experiment Station I Navy U • ■ WmpIwiII A WardweU S. N»vy H Waniwell E. Davis II' Keeney Kustlew \ i~ II Jones Si riniilt — II i lulilrn ' \\ ToUl •" II'.' indi&lt; Fen 1", \vl which had whi! Tlu I'., plants \\ pigmented seed, ii F, plants with eyed seeds and 13 white. This shows the presence of pigment respect to the absence of t( ved plant produced 5 pa totally pijrinented individuals in 1 •'... Its more than indicate its possibl to the presence of pigment and the absence of total pigmentatioi 3 eyed, and S white individuals, show gametous with regard to both the presence i cut Tabi.f. III. -ReautU 0/ ero** II l( Jones Stnn_ IIvIh Hybrid ~&gt;7 E. Jw traded whites with res] One totally pigmented F, plant yit pigmentation. Two totally pigmented F, plants yielde of 17 F, plants. !t totally pigmented, 8 white, ami non&lt; having been apparent y bomogametoua toward total pignu tho heterogametous to the presence of pigment. One </seg>
            <seg id="p097">1 •ll Rt / I 75 8 totally pigmented plants in \\, su_ igmanted F. plant produced -i do white individuals in F,, enough iturc toward total pigmentation, i rents, DavU, Jones Stringiest, and Navy, •ter such that, when pigment is present, surface of the seed. This character can - ally pigmented parents, Keen •&gt; Rustless, Wax. and Hybrid 57, else those races would !&gt;:■ instead of eyed. The charact n is latent lin- ImHs (ONCKHNKI) IN PIGMENTATION. ■ choHpn to express the relation of the totally pifl - ly pigmented, and non-pigmented types &lt;&gt;f hean ion two distinct factors: first, presence of pluc to the absence* of pigment, /&gt;: and. tlisence of a factor for total pigmentation, umption, four gametic formulas are |&gt;os- ntation. nelltatlon. tation, total pigmentation latent. tltion, either visible or hit 'lit. vet been fo\md by me to have formula 4. inglesH, the only white races that have thus indicating formula •{ for •Tlio ti-nn "factor," ;i&gt; lien' uaed, meana simply one of tin clfinciits that have :ir character to ap|«':ir I h.T from an &lt;&gt;rir mistii. If the pigmented ami non-pigmented eonditiom of h.it tl arc not similarly "|H)larizf.l. lam lm toward !&gt;&lt;&gt;th the characters homogametoua toward the prmenc ■ irents simply became it cannot !&gt;;■ seen ex- it' pigment. have yielded totally pifjmenteil ypotheoa thai a faetor miy be ■•entirely" abtent ilarity of expression" in tin- somi (Cook), it i: </seg>
            <seg id="p098">76 Agricultural Experiment Station 0/ A them. Several white races, when have yielded in F, only toi in F, totally pigmented a pigmented ones. If eithei 4, tome &lt;&gt;f the F, plants s details of the crosses are s nut imiiiiii'li xcellentlv In shorl. »t ii 1 li&lt;- pteaence-a able "expli union ot two hirly that pi of ;i particul \\ hat was |"&gt;ii Inter. Breedere' Ass ited above, as inde </seg>
            <seg id="p099">rnty-second Annual tit i 77 ] 1 1 d u-ith non-frig- mi ntt (I hi o &gt; NnniU'r of plants. NurnU'r of plants. Pi r, - . - - - - ~i - — * • z . - z - r /. — a £^ if 1 u -• u t I A II 0 6 23 0 6 l:ivi- II | 0 0 4 I 0 1 0 0 I 4 I u l I I 0 n .") U 2 (I t&gt; .5 0 2 I t II (I 17 0 10 t il 0 :! 17 0 10 &gt;ivi- II 2 0 (17 0 4 0 0 17 0 4 •') ii 0 41 0 20 T 8 ii 0 15 I) 3 s 0 o ! |5 I) 3 14 II (III (I 13 14 II (111 0 !■_&gt; :«&gt; ii I) 39 0 13 a» n it \ : :c.i it 13 17 il I) 31 ii 8 17 n 0 , 31 il 8 8 ii 0 21 0 4 ti i) 0 21 (» i (l:.ck r. I &lt;&gt; U 30 II 8 II II ,; M 0 8 13 ii il 19 0 I 1 n it 10 0. I 0 4 \\ I n it / 7 ii (i tiir(M-»- Strinul.-- I 2 (III in Black T 7 (l 0 ItiiriNf Strinfdi-ss / .' (I II Hl:i&lt;k T - (1 (I 1 II il I l.ri.l 102 II 10 0 10-J II 121 0 0 256 0 • 121 0 0 266 0 96 ■ conclusively enough that the white that the white r • •Hull Navy, do not have formula 4 {pt). The re however, add still more evidence in the Xavv. ilo not have formula 4 nit). The re- ■ vidence in the Navy. The Davis-Blue Pod, Davis-Scarlet -Challenge Black i 1. in F,, from hints. 226 white-seeded ones; from (i totally ded ones; from ii totally uals. si totally pigmsnted ones; and from 2 l ii'iitcil ones; and from 24 merited !•', plant*, 129 totally pigmented and 44 tcl Fj plants. 129 totally pigmented and 4- mI bsana were produced. The white races N duced. The white i s. and Hybrid 102 were not carried to F, .is well as David and Navy, has already beer pigmentation latent by the production a -pririLT in F. from a cross with an eved race </seg>
            <seg id="p100">78 Agricultural Experiment Station &lt; It M regretted that the race known as H further. It was produce) I) Rustless, the latter an eyed race. From tl extracted whites should a without total pigmental mercial races of l&gt;eana i .\ mentation latent ing any whit« offsprin tion li\ ! one 1 1 1 : i \ plant's from t! pigmentation tation in tot« It is possible in determining th and E or &lt; . the ] sence of partial lit poKsihli eved beans by form S. No totally pigmented 2. If there is such a lie plants. No white-seeded crosses of totally pigmented with eyed beans. 1 four such crosses, howevi ain F, progeny (see Table I pigmentation, it should be wl I 5, 6, or 7). No such result ha Navv-l '£, being hypostatic to T, is not visible wfceo 1 for total pigmen mentation would (2) 1'T, . (3) I'll-. (4) J pigmented Ik&gt;mii!&gt; (formula 3) it should viel bean by 1 1 owing two pigmente&lt; merited bean by i nnwiiig two \ a have Ik'cii made, namelv Navv-Mi 'Bateson, \V. Science, n. &gt;.. 26: »&gt;: </seg>
            <seg id="p101">ml Annual fti 79 inglesH-Hybritl 102. Such a result roduction of a purple sweet pea by Even tho no such results ;ire ever till exist. If it were present in all lih 1 7. &lt;&gt;t those given above, would l&gt;e us types would then give the same ton /' and T existed, as at fir- hat there are separate factors for red pigmentation, say E. K. etc. Kan ithin narrow limits of fluctuation, in which is reduced to a very small spot about the Kidney). In other cases the eye pigment ir more of the entire surface of the - In still others there is marked variation in ye pigmentation (Golden Wax. Wardwell). wen given the matter as yet. hut one of my Wax &lt; Mohawk) gives some little support t large-eyed or medium-eyed beaai may produce the reverse of this is not to be expected. 1 " lokinjr to the explanation of the relation of entation. that is based upon the assumption or pigmentation about the eye and the other back of the bean, is to Ik- dismissed at present in or absent from different parts Maize has pigment in the endosperm arp. or the reverse, or pigment is pn lent from both. Hut this has to do with There is no definite line between the dorsal ean seed. It is simply a matter of whether the entire surface of the seed or only over U of it. In ease of partial pigmentation merited. I have never seen a bean with the back pigmented and the eve white. Batoson. \V. Proe. Inter. Coafataaea am I'lant RmaiBf ami Hyhridiiation Hart. *&lt;«■. \. V. 1:5 (19 'Ann. Rpt. Xpl&gt;r. Apr. Expt. Sta. 16. PI II (1902) </seg>
            <seg id="p102">80 Agricultural Ex]H V SI Eyed pigmentation in beans guinea pigs." The eyed con nearly comparable t pigment centers in gum&lt; as red in one and black in gions in fowls do and the hack of another. Whether thr &lt;-\t&lt; in eyed beans not been determine "Allen, (I. M. 1W. \r \l '-It is pn— iLst thai tb Ix-aiis. The pipn inurli broader al \\ hen tlic ptgim t lie liiluni. In iii'l ro wine extending fmm near that of tin- l: I y a very small micropyle sjhpi i iiiiii-pifniicnttMl a Imiken and bordered iv very ird). In the lam body of the eye-»pot in a broken prcncral ilirceticm the Btargilu ol hack of the si'cil. thus practic; t\v&lt;i mit apota. Eyed pigraenta ring, itudied by Tschennak, wl pigment, (ir of two such bands, which may or may not be i chics "MucOmiy. H. ami Castle. W. E. I "Castle. \V. K. Carnegie hist. Pub. 23 "Davenport, C. 15. Arner. Breeders' Assne. 3 "MacCurdy, H. and Castle. W. \. Cumecie ln&gt;t. Pub. 70 ogous to t lie pigment centers in spc than to pigmented regions in nntiz pigment center in beans insti SuiiifUiiic- the in:irsri line (Yellow Ew </seg>
            <seg id="p103">■Hill R 81 I VX ) SELF PIGMEXT PATTERNS leeds nf beans, whet In ther as a single solid color self color, " or as a mi lor. " mottling i led bean seeds vary greatly kc the form of narrow ■id or arranged somewhat » imetimes thev occur as irregular mere specks. Where lisiht i mosaic, the pattern is very k or all lijrlit. the pattern is tinct. Even in case of plant* with normally may Ik- less plain in individual luleraiice of the dark color. In eas ig, the occasional predominance i&gt;: ilt to distinguish between the mottled t is almost impossible to »j ii ossed with mottled ones have yielded In F, mottled and self-colored in- I'he ratio of mottled to self on the whole n particular cases it has varied widely ring, which m.r. :,i in &gt;»-lf- ibed mottled beans as :i mosaic of vaiioM \nn. Kpt. Nebr. Agr Expt Su. 15::*7: 17: &gt; Rpt. Nrhr. Agr. Expt &gt;t:i. 15: H7: 17: i iat true white mrrlv occurs in the mosaic of colors. lief that true white nircly uetuw in the rnosnir of colors. practically white by comparison with en ;i|&gt;|H-;ir |.r:ictic.illy white \&gt;\ rompuris. ■ Mi dared comparison witli white they usiully - Imt on ilirrct coniparison with white they usually y eoloted. The direct conip:iri&gt;.iii is most casil\ The direct comparison is most easily in:nle .■,1 bean* wham light s|H.t~ of Um tjm happen to lie outride the ej tho true wUk here light s|&gt;ots of the eye hapi*-n to lie constituent of the mosaic in mottled it would still ordinarily Ik' possible to ■an containing white in the mosaic ■il (eyed i one, owini; to the distribution of the peculiar to the two lype-. The tyjx's would i inheritance as tho no white occurred in the ■1. ;v merely would need revising </seg>
            <seg id="p104">82 Agricultural Exferimer Si, \ from this ratio. From similar Croat 58 mottled and 2(1 self-colored ind ment of my crosses is given in the fo \ S Parenta Cwrrie S.« &gt; Golden Wax */.».... Wardwell .1/ &gt; Challenge Black S. Bad \ alciitinr M ■ Burpet strint; BurjKf Stringles:- S • Warwick .1/ Paris M. x Ultra S Mohawk M. X lit r Mohawk M. v Scarlet Fl ■ I. Dwarf Horticultural .1/ ■ Scarlft 1 Dwarf Horticultural M ■ Litre .- Yellow Dwarf Horticult Total only. Again 4s (it he mottled and ~&gt;7 self-colorei Green x Warwick, the ind in F 3 hut the total numbei determined. This makes it homosygotee and beterozyj O!fi seeds, all s«-lf colored. in F, plants that produced 1 T*» 4 other mottled F, individuals «; mottled and 1()4."&gt; self-colored &gt;&lt; On the whole the self pattern In certain cases the ratio of mot t lei '•Tschermak. E. Wcitere KrauungMtudien an p. 50 Zeit8chr. Landw. Versuclisw. (1904 Tabi.f: V. — Result* of crossing .S." = self colon-.! ■ U Thirteen relf-colored I Similarly, ."i mottle homozygoU's and heterozygu latter are probably n&lt;H grea self-colored K_. plants of this </seg>
            <seg id="p105">\ initial Sept 83 1 I M.ittl 6 ilmost exactly 2 - Warwick), the I. In other eases itiu was 7. 1) : I. In if this same i heteroxygote nottleil seeds, instead of self-colored ■ected. The details of these crosses / xtlj-rolorat if Number I. Self. White 0 0 II II o 0 II II II I (I Mit crosses including five white races were secured in F,, as seen from the cods and ."&gt; with self-pigmented ones. tern were undoubtedly not hybrid at iltv emasculation of the Bower* tempted cross of Ultra by Marrow r seeds. Two of the four plants i pattern. MINI MOTTI.IM «■&gt; (if self-colored with white race I) 0 II I) 0 0 (I 0 I) 0 0 " 113 62 i 70 &gt;i ir, hi beans. "S ■ ■ ■ • ■ ■ ■ is ta M ia 10 o i 1 l.-» I 1 13 H </seg>
            <seg id="p106">. i tfr taut ii i m t* sin SI, that grew had the dwa rather slender, orange parent. Ultra. The other t\v a tendency toward runnei F, individuals of the I'ltia-M N'avv cross, one attemnl rpsu pod, how of the Ultra-N habit. The do&lt; pod w th m 1 rii btrinirle other plant, t The mottling slijiht differenci th:' prepondera plant, or any &lt; pattern u as no '-It nay nen linage to etaaa a |.l:i were pl.iinlv s&lt;&gt; marked while dc My rcMxin fur doing tliis is that, on tlie same plant with weO mot not at all mottled, just uincaaeo a varicgatcil petuail plant, for i white Howen ami w\ Hum a non-variegated plant. It i- ; varieties tn pwidmie nme Bowers show the variegation. The no* pattern to lie seen in every individual seed or flow rather plump, orangi just as in the |, the mother pai were &lt;l&lt;&gt; tli" polk an even </seg>
            <seg id="p107">md Annual Rf/iorl 85 f soil' with white races, as will be seen I. there occurred mottled, self, and seen that the three lots do not it ion to each other expected in a di- 113:52:70 while 133:44:5* i the demands of theory. In short, there I and too many self and white individuals, in&lt;: in almost exactly tn&gt; same &lt;■ possible significance of the will be 1 98 v of these cr&lt; -ted in Fj v few .rv.i. Of ) 1',. h'ftec n mottled F tied. PI self, It of 1' . Si * ! no mottled lded SO nt ti t of !•'. self-colored in- both to 1 w; ither of which nt but homo- presence t an toward the and (3) that ttli leterogam ttliii": and th nt and heteroeam the presence of mot - existed or not d"termined from my to occur in the ratio &gt;nt. but the third and Whether the other two p&lt; «ible &lt;•! ]•", mottled individuals not I The four classes would 1) 4 1. The first and second were pn urth were not demonstrated, which is not strange when only nottled !•'., ])lants were tested and pi&gt;;ht of them produced fifteen too few offspring to make the test of value. Both Tschermak" Loc. cit. p. 46 Tiprin and 1 1 whil •. Two m id no whil ' i xlivii! nils i:i F v liul IK) - ttl •&gt;.! i K , all s-if- I -.1 F, ■ there were two tyi&gt;»&gt;H of mot- to both presence of pigment other humogametom to the ■\|M'Ctt </seg>
            <seg id="p108">m, Agricultural Experiment Station o and Shull 24 report that no m - &lt;&gt;f white with self-eolo mottled pattern. ttled indiv Before proceeding to been advanced to account f&lt;&gt; results of crossing white wit I are shown in the following I Table Nil. Res \l \\anlwcll 1/. ■ H, \i-fiii-y KumI. &gt;-U. i 4 arrow II'. Paria 1/ Navy W. ■ Pari« .1/ 'aria M. ■ V.vy II Navy II ■ \\ : ,nhv,ll 1/ \\ ■.•irilw.-ll M. ■ Navy II Navy M ■ Warwick .W Inly" II. ■ \\:,r»ick 1/ ones Sinimlo- II'. llv l.rid 57 &gt;/ Hylri.!.-.7 M. Total 60 Jones StrinzieoN II \V.-,\ \l 1 0 Thus in I ratio of mottled to while from all the 1) were grown from the* Of the F., plants produced from Golden Wax, 12 were mottled, _' 7 white F, plants yielded 4"&gt; F, plai « of the two self-colored F, plants 'I "Shull, C. H. Amer. Nat., 42:439. - there w&lt; was considerable varial -••s was 103: A4, which is possible to jrct from 137 im Sum .if Purer </seg>
            <seg id="p109">ml Report 1/ 87 ."&gt; self-colored plants and bo t gave 8 mottled and no other offsprin I FURIES HK(i\KDIN&lt;; MOTTLING. white with self-colored races that resulted re considered to be mosaics of the colors tlio even at the time it was noted that the lottled seeds did not always correspond to parents.-" Later I still regarded the mottling e parent colors, hut could not explain the be- ll 1 lie assumption that the mosaic was the inonohvlirid ;arded mottling as a pigment pattern inherited lent and interpreted the occurrence of mottled t s ; &gt;lt by white beans as due to the presence i inactive) condition in the self-colored II believed that not all self-colored races ("Hundert anc?) had this latent character. He furthermore tliiifi. The one. brought from latency Kreuzungsnovum), he regarded as an ever-sporting ■ t } i mottled and self-colored individuals in equal The other, existing as a visible parent charactt . lie considered to be a constant Mendelian character. Hurst-" suggested to me that "the mottled character dour and probably dominant to it and w a latent state by the white-seeded race which illy extracted from a mottled hybrid." He with large numbers the F, plants would l&gt;e white in the ratio of !t: -i : 4 considered the factor for mottling to !&gt;e latent non-pigmented parent race. He assumed two Ann. Hopl. Xehr. Ajrr. K\pt. St:i. 15:37, :is (190J fj Rept. Ncl&gt;r. \&amp;. Kvpt. Sta. 17 f 4-C.7 (1904 /.or. cit.. pp. 47 Persoual correspondem ■sp. nil. G. H. Science, n. s.. M: 792-794 ive in !•'., 22 mottled, 17 self, mid W2 (1907). </seg>
            <seg id="p110">88 ■ Itural Ex/* Stat factors. I' or p fm 1 the pica M nee in nent m fur the presence or aba parent was believed to ha /' white parent the formula n.M m suited, in I\. I'M It ivn pected that in 1 We the dihvlirid ratio of 9: 3: 1. W lh. -I Shull i to m ■ tctor M ' As point — arily if this hypothesis lade visible by erosmng coi ivjxithesis. it would lieconu Mtttern can be latent in self scherinak believed, just as Mgmented individual (pM). t While remembering that ?ncv l&gt;y crossinir. does not must not forget that there I e to mottling. Tschermai in "Amer. Nat. 42:433-439. this expect ;il ■ 1. self td seM-colore Tscth tl IV! r progeny of sixtee As noiiUcd out liv SI !■&lt;■( </seg>
            <seg id="p111">iii n mil Report 89 ip their interrelation. In a to explain the relation &gt;■■{ otl izvgous condition to the mot- tliat thev are two distinct char- itlv ich other. I let M represent t of mottling and X the sort that does not I out that there might then Ik' eijrht possible pure bean races, as folio 1 . with mottling latent. ■ ittliii": latent out latent mottling. l/.V. white, both inottleis latent. Mx. white, one mot tier latent. 7. pmX, white, other mottler latent. 8. pmx, white, neither mottler latent. mottler latent. Further. I endeavored t&lt;&gt; show that, whether X is hypostatic ■ed to sh i\v that, whether X is hvpostatic M (&gt;!■ the reverse, the above formulas could lx&gt; assigned to the the above formulas could Ik&gt; assigned to the crent rac?s irf l&gt;eans that have been used in crossing so that the ions results secured by Tschermak. Shull. and myself might l&gt;e \|&gt;lained. But while the hypothesis explains the results been used in crossing so that the mak. Shull. and myself might l&gt;e hypothesis explains the results it have been secured thus far. it sujrjrests results that have not yet been secured. A further test of the hypothesis, made by i white race assumed to have formula 7 (pmX) with a \ further test of the hypothesis, mad: 1 by t e race assumed to have formula / (pmX) with a ttled race {PMX or I'M.iK should, if the hypothesis is correct. I'MX or PMjt), should, if the hypothesis is correct. ult in mottled. s"lf. and white individuals in V. in one of the three md white individuals in V. in one of the three f which has a familiar look to the student owing ratios, none of which has a familiar look to the student Mendelian inheritance, namely. 11: 1:4. 21:3:8, or 33: l"&gt;: Hi. one or other of these ratios should he obtained, or approxi- en large numbers are dealt with, it would not onlv rvation in accord with the hypothesis, but would elation of A' to .1/. If either one of the first two ratios .V is hvpostatic to M . while if the third ratio is found. X M. The ratios of mottled to self in th&gt; and practically 2 1 in the second case inlike that it should not be difficult to determine quite Am Breeders' Ass. 5: 368-376 </seg>
            <seg id="p112">Agricultural Expert nu Xel 90 Slut i positively the relation &lt;&gt;f the two &lt; liable tests eaa Ik- made to determini crossing a self race having formula ( i i formula 2 {PmX ■ PMi Notwithstanding the i tested mildly in a recent pa| if it in these word tit the facts wll. and I ( at lea tho it n charade! receive*! offered an ex] causes the inott a |)iece of a ch any rate the tw&lt; •ret her. If tliis h uf non-mottled li one (if the correl loss df the other ( the loss uf 1 &gt;&lt; it h i i it ettce referred to, pics mi to slmv nuilas. that his correlation In-put I in my paper In what follow* I li \v V( pothesis but have in&lt;»lifi forms used elsewhere in t ,1 I'.KI' notwithstanding tne rea&lt;iy e\\ by Shllll'H hypothesis a&gt; extend 'c| liotli parei says ■■ Lei true have in single chrom Kuhstancra \\ "IVncmal euficapuodenee, Jun </seg>
            <seg id="p113">7 / Annual H&gt;jx&gt;rt 91 '/- \ tbsent, and indicating gametii YZ. the eight possible pure types become latent her mottler latent. ther mottler latent. • mottter latent, h niottlers latent both iiuittlers latent. me mottler latent. &gt;ther mottler latent. either mottler latent. definite formula to each of the races that have such that all the results known to me will he etinite formula to each of the races that havt that all the results known to me will he the exception that some white races (Navy. exception that some white races (Navy. I and VII must lie assumed to be mixed, some plants t be assumed to be mixed, some plants md others 14 or 15. No amount of cross nd others 14 or 15. No amount of e individuals of such a white race would re- individuals of such a white race would re- ■ two hypotheses under consideration explains two hypotheses under consideration explains i. The independent-factor hypothesis seems own. The independent-factor hypothesis seenw &gt;ss probable than the coupled-factor hypothesis. &lt;s probable than the coupled-factor hypol s with it is its assumption of two entirely in- with it is its assumption of two entirely in- ie viable expressions of which are identical, ns the visible expressions of which arc identic:! 1 , not found necessary in explaining th- inheritance ound necessary in explaining th- inherit Another difficulty is tho n?CS«ity of assum- Knottier difficulty is th? n?e?ssitv of assum- «culiar nature that it is visibly expressed only liar nature that it is visibly expressed onlv undition. Gametic coupling, the fundan coupling, the fundamental ilition. (lame vpothesis. is a 1 -ss difficult conception and thesis, is a 1 -ss difficult conception and iv.' wide application to plant and eninal ition to plant and enimal P a of two factors being necessary for the cx- two factors being necessary for tin ■r is not new. such characters being known in tcter is not new. such characters being known in animals. If this coupled-factor hypothea imals. If this coupled-factor hypoth ■- f mottling in s^lf-colorsd beans is due to tepara ling in sjlf-colored beam is due to tfpantim* in cas .' of latency of color modifiers in white ist as in cas' of lat?ncv of color modifiers in white n due to combination as sujijtested by Shall. 34 lie to combination as sujijte^ted by ShuQ." ■ il&gt;le by means of appropriate cross's, many of owing, to determine quite positively which II. \iii.t. Nat. 42: 439-441 </seg>
            <seg id="p114">92 Agricultural Experiment Station X, I. one, if either, of these hypotheses is correct. I mals are constituted in this peculiar way. It however, to mention in passing as well as mottling (variegation) in ing field for investigation in this com It tainlv, variegation bre« Is trut in maize (Calico corn). In case of some other does not breed tn,. Squaw " corn, a t &gt;]&lt;;■ i of white with black i to disap|H-ar in a If that mottling in con aleurone. similar to t! stead of being produ&lt; U and A or ) live nucleus and o or by the separate formed by the hi generative nucleus W "Bauer, K. Ber. l&gt;. "Ixx-k. H. H. Ann. Roy. 1 "Webber, H. .1. U.S. Def*. &gt;t \ \ make \\ • ml irener itiv on the other, divide x*| u black suptr eon witl ■Iv r whit ones to U- starchy. Botli White Kit with pollen of Bhick Mi ica kernels that wen- mottled black and « to the cross, but all were starchy the mottled grains from the Golden CJ M. s|H'nn. had alone given rise to any pai enough to inquire whether any otl aleuroae, breed however, has si (1900). Some of my m riplitly interpreted then only result in mottling of the black aleunnu cause the black "islands" to !&gt;&lt;■ unifomilv liv laid hy yellow endosperm in every .-iid generative nucleun, bea </seg>
            <seg id="p115">I Annual Report 93 nlv slight traces of red, when crossed yellow puds almost covered with bright red While the matter has not l&gt;een fullv in- ue well-known races of bMM, however, narked with red and tweed true to this char- It may even turn out that c Ttain charade wcribed by Cook as being giwn expression or as by crowing but which disappear in later genera- UU for instance, arc of the same nature as the A' Y and Z factors in beans. 3 ' V'lloN ()K MOTTLING TO 0OL0K HYPOHTAIO&amp; s shown that certain bean colors are hypostatic to ight yellow (the color seen in Long Yellow itic to oran&lt;re-l&gt;rown (seen in Ultra), orange dark brown to black. He has shown that the Black has dark brown latent by hyp &gt;wn Ultra has light yellow latent in the Burpee Strinjrless by Giant Stringless," the and the latter orange-brown, indicates that • filed plants occurred, but there were range is not latent in the dark brown wer in the scale than orange should have Challenge Black with Scarlet &gt;f n Webber ■..1 liy|x&gt;thexis by the fact that produtW unins tliat :irc yellnw or I am iwilt, pafcM tliat are inotlltfi 17 :.'.!! Depi. Airr.. Kurt-au Plant Indus., (ir. is (1908) and Bui. ■ irnatlv t&lt;&gt; l&gt;&lt;- regretted that ('&lt;M&gt;k has not published a ition in detail at the ix'diun-e records will be awaited the greatest interest by all ■liiilmll of heretlity Nat. 42: 44.1-446 (10 A i Ann. I ipt. N.l.r. A k T. Kxpt. Sta. 17:61-64 (1904). crtain races of l&gt;eans having yellow hat plants which as a result &gt;&gt;f cross- [xiils are beterosygoua with respect to the hypostasis in the dark brown race. In F,, low &lt;M&gt;r s&lt;&gt; fur remit* u[M)ii which the iri-iiiTalizations presented Full of suggestion are the brief statements </seg>
            <seg id="p116">94 Agricultural Esjh iment Static \eb Flageolet, I have found dark red to !«■ hyi :i cross of Scarlet Flageolet with Ultra, the ft colored seeds were recorded as vellow-hrown. This indii red may he hypostatic to orange-l Some years ago I crowed the &lt;1 with the reddish purple mott wn. Some years ago I crossed the dark brown less with the reddish purple mottled Ix-an Warwick. M are very unsatisfactory from the st are very unsatisfactory from the standpoint of color descriptioi hut nevertheless they show plainly hut nevertheless thev show plainly that there \\ with respect to color only two clasr with respect to color only two classes of self-color least four classes of mottled bean: least four classes of mottled beans. The self col dark brown and a sort of orange-bi dark brown and a sort of orange-brown. In some of t seeds dark brown predomin seeds dark brown predominated an e some of the former, and also in BOI some of the former, and al while in others it was not. My not while in others it was not. M\ have been a purplish color present have been a purplish The important point The important point, of which then were more kind were more kinds of mottled «eedn tl may assume that Burpee Stringle.* may assume that Burp Warwick the formula MdOR (A/ brown, () orange, and H forms in the relative numb? : MDOR, mottled darl '.I MIX),, mottled dark ■ MdOR, mottled oran mottled oranc !l m DON. self dark hi !i 1 3^.mD0r, self dark brow n 3 uhIOR, self orang 1 mdOr. self orange From this there could 1 on s -lf-color &gt;d beans, nam?lv however, he four sorts of mottled beai k'fpottatic colors &lt;(/■(■ risiblt wh "I in mottled assumption, if true, will explain pest ion may seem more reasonable mottl (1 beans exhibit a m saic ot several d rare to find less than three colors, or intensities of color, in mott l&gt;eans. We can conceive of mottling as of such a nature that </seg>
            <seg id="p117">md Annual Hijxnt 95 .'/ ■en ,v i\ I [ON i 1 i Cr. iv l&gt;. I 1907: M e development of a color in certain grou levelop in others, and that it acts upon the •ndently. Then, from the formula M DOR ; brown to develop in some spots and not to The same would l&gt;e true of imip !■»■■ might overlap the dark brown one. Where together, only the brown would show, owing is hvpostatic to brown. Where the 01 ie brown, however, it should be visible. In it by chance appear in some spot where ! nor orange. In case some other color, hvpo - named, were present, it might show it.self in occupied by the colors epistatic to it. In re present, a few small spots should be white. s are present, it would seem that there should onsiderable size. This, however. I have not to note some of the corollaries of the theory of What will happen when two races having I? If we cross lit! It with hl)r. th -re me individual in sixty-four with the formula s. about one and one-half per cent of the F, Inti. tho having the factor P, which is lack te beans discussed earlier in this paper. it this is the explanation of the results record - and bv Halsted. 11 both of whom ha - of pig men ted white beans from [■Hissed Waehsdattel, n. with Scarlet ltumit self-colored, light r. a l&gt;ean with M ri &gt;ss numerous white - crossed a light brown and got white-seeded us hybrid beans were ic-pink. From this ( in 1',. Halsted alsi ■en. with Scarlet Runner Tsehermak states that 1 Hot. I &gt;•-(&gt;« . N. .1 Ayr (nil. :.■ K\pl. Sta. 1906: 47 1 (()!.( )U HYPOHTASIS TO ALBINISM </seg>
            <seg id="p118">96 Agricultural Experiment Stall V grown at considerable distaiicc from to the fact that with respect to otbei types bred true. He believes thai cidental cross-pollination in isolate) results could not have been serin sted's hvbrid beans were also grow the! lCt( II &gt;l\ w II w but he recognises the possibility thru insect agency.'" If the | in tli' - was due to acci led race, t he crosx mus Halsted's Ihmiis and on 1 that its effect might hec&lt; ive case It is significant pigmented beans rec renoe of non-pigmei fact of even ei 1 H Runner. The lat were present it sliniil The brown-seed 'il brown is hypostatit purplish color. The should produce, on t kite-seeded plants in 1 en until generations later tl for by the fact that too few 1 Halsted surest s that " Th« ■eeded strain, and the seed used iave contained more or less of t he mottled purple of the norma &gt;rown seeds of the 'Tennessee' ma 1 o produce white." I do not tal -st that one or other of the pare hru a previous cross with a wli II "Personal SSfNBBMMBMM itifi in the |&gt;r H&amp;lsted'a exp&lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p119">Twenty-second Annual Report 97 x V •t I 1 r l l&lt; 1 H 1 l White beat ( 1 &gt; "Shull, G. H. Amer '•Bateson, W. Hort, iould have produced in F, one white waded plant r. if both original parents bad white F, plants should have been white-seeded. With ireat ■ chance as one in four, white seeds would almost certainly ■ed in F, &lt;&gt;r 1',. It is probable that Tennessee ested do " tendency to produce white" if it had a race having brown either visible or latent and let Runner would not have shown the "tendency" ased with a race having either black or reddish Bet, in discussing the occurrence of white in these at white was latent in either parent. White in :irded not as a positive character but merely as rment or of all pigment modifiers or of both pig - t modifiers. Black, or any other pigment niodi- t (invisible) in a white bean on account m iient. Likewise pigment can l&gt;e latent in a white ration from all pigment modifiers. We are here tency due toaeparatiom rather than to ayy—fi n discussed under the head of the I elation of for the reason that it is only by regard n offered here, to account f i colored parents, could hav n White beans thus produced, i. e., by tin ii nt bat liners, should res unit - /'/;/; F, &lt;/'M IK &gt; It eet p ir results \p, 13 lOJS 1. and A2:4*), 44 ttee. N. Y. I:.". (1902 i matter of kypottaaia rather than oi production I at. linarv white beans, tin til ' I two ('&lt;:&gt;: 1, four colors ru »: 1. If th </seg>
            <seg id="p120">Agricultural Experiment Stai white parent l&gt;ean has neither pigment nor pign crossing it with a pigmented bean 1 should give an F, progeny of pigmented and white individuals the ratio of 9: 7, or 1.29: 1. [f the pigmented parent lias t modifiers, the ratio should lie 4"&gt;: 19 189 (17. or 2.v_' 1; if four e !i forth, constantly approaching but As pointed out in the first part pigmented beans with pigmented ones results ii proximating -i . 1. l»nt with a slight excess (if white- to U' expected in all rases where the visible or latent colors of the pigmented parent are i the visible or latent eol&lt; as the latent colors of the white parent. The percentag as the latent coin excess of whit excess of white- will depend upon the combined numtier modifiers present in the two parents. If the combined n modifiers present ii i two, each parent having a single modifier, the 1', ratio &gt; two. each parent h 2.37: I : if three 2.'A7 I: if three or four, _' s '_' 1 or l'.'.i.") l. respectivel peaching quite -i. I. Such speculations as tin chief value, perhaps, in making one cautious about an 'exceptions" to Mendelian behavior on the im that one is at the time unable t.&gt; explain. that one is at the ti MMARY. Sl'MMAin The presence of pigment. /'. in bean m The presence absence of pigment, /&lt;. the two conditions const it ul absence of pigment morphic pair inherited in typical Mendelian : Total pigmentation dominates partial morphic pair inherited in typical Mel Total pigmentation dominates part F,. In 1% both forms occur. Eyed 1 . indi\ F,. In F, both forms homoiveous while some totally piemeni homosygoufl while some totally pigmented one* and some are heterozygous. This would be the expect and some are heterozygous if total pigmentation and eyed pigmentation constituted if total pigmentation and eyed Mendelian character-pair. In keeping with recent N tendency, the pair is here considered to l&gt;e presence. T, •ence. t. of total pigmentation. Ii used in these experiments havt probable, however, that the eyed con the presence of a distinct character. E there mav l&gt;e two or more distinct characters, E . E cerned. No bean has vet been shown to lack /: </seg>
            <seg id="p121">■mud A nnual lit port 99 '/- 11 is Intent in certain non-pigmented (white) if these white races with eyed races give white offspring in F r These same &gt;ssed with self-colored ones, the F, individuals F. both mottled and self-colored individuals true while gome of the former breed true ie two types again ■cans crossed with self-colored one.s produce F. and mottled, self, and white individuals in ite beans similarly crossed produce self-colored tho, as pointed out by Shall, it dues not !&gt;■ lie latent in some white beans and not in experiments here reported are concerned. type lirst noted, when crossed with mottled ndividuals in F. and only mottled and white beans of the second type yield, from similar well as mottled and white individuals ii reported, crosses of various self-colored nothing l&gt;ut self-colored offspring. Tschermak, on •ttl.'d F, offspring from one such CTOI i i ir 1 1 1 l&gt;e latent in self-colored beans. t t ■t of my own experiments might lie explained behavior of an allelomorphic pair. M of mottling, .1/ iH'inji visible only in the Shall and Tschermak — ( 1 ) an F, 4 instead of 9: -i 4 from a cross of self- iil ure of any of the mottled F, li mottled F, offspring from a cross explained in this way. to account for the facts known. U and A tlependently of each other, their only relation hat due to hypostasis. .!/. the factor re- pattern of ordinary mottled races, is a un led with totally pi^mentcd ones, as is to be I individuals in 1'.. % tattern is dominant to self-color. When ndent-factor hypothesis, assumes two factors Mendelian facton ilo, while X is sup: </seg>
            <seg id="p122">100 Agricultural Experiment Station aska a to !&gt;»• of such a nature that it is visible only in the heter d by Shull. The second, &lt;&gt;r coupled-f state pothi 'I by Spillman, assumes two factors, pothl jested by Spill man, assumes two factors, Y al / such that mottling beeonea visiMe only when both ar such that mottling becomes visible only when both together, and assumes that they are coupled in inlieritan together, and assumes that they are coupled in inheritaiu relations as those suggested by these hypotheses offer an i: relations as those suggested by these hypotheses offer an inten field for further investigation. The mottling character is conceived to ln&gt; of such field for further investigat iceived to be ol sue that when present it prevents the development of a &lt;• that when present it prevents the development of a color i coli groups of cells, allowing it to develop in other cells, and such that group* of cells, allowing it to develop in other cells, and it acts toward the different colors independently. 11 it acts toward the different colors independently. Tl make it possible for any color to lie visible in mottled s( make it possible for any color to lie visible in mottl* in the presence of colors epistatic to it. Evidence it in the pie n'licc "I colors epistatie to it. hvidenct of this is furnished by a cross of a mottled race with a s( of this nil one which resulted in only two sorts of self-colon-' one which least four sorts of mott ii in F,, Crossing any two pigmented Iteans that have m least four Cross common should result in the production of a definite | conn of white-seeded individuals in V... the white color l&gt;einji &lt; of whit&lt; absence of absence of all pi" rs, IS. I). H. etc.. rather tl /; ) absence of p mint for the absence of pi white beano in boi h Tsclu white bean red mottled I hite red mottled 1m pri duced « i : pn duced produce c&gt; It :i d I', I ' Hoi while In - should while In hi wiM r, except rent lack \'( r, ( ami ! and lint mon wit] mentcd ]):;ii 2) where the wll I has pij; mcnt( (1 \): lacks ;.ll pig nd the pii:mented parent iei i single pi] m. 'lit but have pigment modifiers with colored beans having different modifier iiulividiials in !■', in ratios from approximat S: 1, acconline to the combined number of pigment modifier nt in th" two parents. The greater the combined number the nearer the ratio approaches :i 1. This may account for thf </seg>
            <seg id="p123">ual Report 101 one-fourth expected in my crosses of lv F, ratios of from about 1.3: 1 sea of pijrmented beans with either pigment nor pigment modifiers, (touched closely onlv when the number igmented parent is large. Attain crosses te ones that have pigment but lack pig- in 1', ratios of from 3: 1 to ratios increasing with the increase in the pigment modifiers in the colored parent. </seg>
            <seg id="p124"/>
            <seg id="p125">THE LIFE HISTORY OF THE CEDAR RUST FUNGUS jitnijUii-rin/iuidiKii Sctiw. 1^ F. 1&gt;. Hbald, I&gt;h. 1) </seg>
            <seg id="p126">CONTENTS. Introduction Distribution in Nebras Cause of the rust The life history of the ■t Production of Normal symptoms Deviation Time of mat the palls Period of reinf Revised life Injury to the apple Spraying experiment Germination i Germination of &lt;\» </seg>
            <seg id="p127">THE LIFE HISTORY OF THE CEDAR RUST FUNGUS nianae Schw. F. 1). Hkai.d, I'h. 1). * INTRODUCTION. if tin 1 disease known as the " cedar in half in tlic state together with the ■ilar trees and the apple crop has led to repeated 1 to the nature of the disease ami methods for f the dis.Ms ■ led the writer to that tli • cycle of development &lt;&gt;i tin 1 fungus which causes with th' generally accepted opinions. t anv disease intelligently, the life own. hence the study was undertaken as a special problem. the funiius lias been observed to de - ■pteil ideas will he noted in the con- t DISTRIBUTION IN NEBRASKA. 1&gt; Survey during the lestimi is very abundant ihundance of the part to the general ornamental tree and for this fact the extensive \ Wealth v and Jonathan, specially susceptible to development and spread of the disease are ideal. (See map. p. 114. t Re^iuiit-d September 1. I'.Mts </seg>
            <seg id="p128">108 Agricultural Experiment Station CAUSE OF THE RUST. cedar (Suhinii Virginia] while a second stage in its c\ velomnent leaves, fruit or twin of th mis host where it produces th i known to scientists, am who still in&gt;i apples" and THE LIFE HISTORY F THE FUNGUS HI- !'H( The but with the lii nut tin- yellow i size from and they may 1 and 2.) Wh give the dis&lt; as&lt; the frails are \&lt; these structure: 'A). In cas will lie of medii her will lie siiia infections, the weigh to cause a cunsp i.KUMIN ATloN ()| Kach relatinouM ma which very non begin t" perminu mycelium may lie produced from both may germinate, one generall In the typical germination, each « a lateral proee— which bean a se that eight sporidia may oripi the germinatiim takes place with th \ w 1 ho cedar rust is caused l&gt;y GymnoMfKtranffiuir rirginianme, which lives at one stage of its lite histor U tlie accial st </seg>
            <seg id="p129">I n n mil Hi ixi/7 107 ml compact (fig. 4a). but with elongated growth results the promycelium will be ed in VI t&lt;&gt; 24 hours. In the s. but with the production of the ml empty ami the sporidia alone ■ntecl protoplasm. Some deviations from rV shown when someof the proinyeelial cells \it into somewhat elongated tridia are produced direct from the the previous formation of a promyce- [ON Hi SI'OHIDIA AND INFECTIONS sori begin to dry, the sporidia are many of them fall upon the surface onditioiis are favorable they germi- n the leaves, v luce infections by the entrance of the ps ot n is much the largest. During the three inder study at Nebraska, the n either two or three, with ion. YMPToMS OF HIST i &gt;N THE APPLF l the upper surface of the leaves as pale following the drying of the sori, and occupied by the development of the the host, and finally with raf t xteinal symptom* become evident. As the -pots become larger and assume a deeper 7 ng orange-colored. In a few weeks after the c cells of the |&gt;nimvoeliiim have one or two infection threads (fii »une fruits ur twigs ofsus- tissues of the host. During iilin may !*• produced, pin-head. These spots U'i;in to "cedar apples" have Ix-eii in the infection, however, takes place </seg>
            <seg id="p130">108 cultural Expt nl Still i Web ;/, ■iix first appearance of the spots, minute pustules appear n of each, and these later show as small black specks. '1 ma. win shaped structures sunken in t known at the present time t i history of the fungus. With the continued le noticed in the spots on the upper &gt;ides of the leaf. Tin beneath the spot cushion or Mister one-fourth to one-half inch in diamet is produced. It or duster-cups are prw \\ hen tin each shows of spores at t h&lt; may lie split and 7 and DEVI Vllo.V Hii (lit YMPTOMS ' just been describ* infections. In n the leaves mav 1 1 have been com pie t ordinary sized appl When a lar a leaf tin in less numerous infei leaves remain on the Severe infections defoliation, while in Ugh extent. In the cat of apples the rust spots entire season, at tinie.- This is noticeably the case in sue other deviation from the normal which the leaf tissue is killed ai circular patch of dead brown ti cluster of black pyenia at its centi the Hen Davis v liamett specks represent the openin </seg>
            <seg id="p131">1 109 :i undergo any further cteristic l'hyllosticta-like ap - mi these dead areas may \&gt;e Cladorporium or Altermirin, •ult to determine if their de- IK ill llowt \t sprint:. The date for the le tvith the time when the h'rst i idjacenl trees shows dearly that •C ipplcs" distinctly visible. June 20 this record that "cedar apples" are ret ilava to four weeks In-fore the aecia of il ready to permit the dissemination of The ac photograph shows i small green en ~ the axil of a scale HE 1'KRlol) OF REINFECTION (&gt;K THE CKDUt ring with the first i. During the month of Oetolier Hitler of tin in uthor in regard to the According to previous ctiona upoa the cedar &gt;pl ■&gt;" which mature in The time of opening of the iirst aaeia at tlic first appearance of the " cedar apples" June 17. June 14. aecia have lx&gt;en Iii the early stage July 1-26 accunlinjr t&lt;&gt; and continue! thruout the \l \1 i it 1 TYO FTHEAECIA \M&gt; FIRST. I -&gt; E( CAI.I.s ON THE CEDAR. ( &gt;l)~i de iluriiii; the past yea :m &gt; rt &gt; M ) rv </seg>
            <seg id="p132">ill 11 nil K 110 nt Sta V only one to two per cent of the at the temperature of the field or garden. This was del means of hanging-drop cultures made at different |&gt;eriod&gt; the month. This would confine the reinfeetioi the months of Julv. Au experiments to be described still further substantiate t KKVISKI) LIFE HISKiHV ( )1 THE Fl'XC of the life hi durili"; the intuit h of M produce spori The first viabli two followin of the cedar ta IS plolllH r, wl the resun month of June and at the end and form. 11 with the ret ui characteristic ; that it require of the cedar ti gelatinous son i n elatiin twenty-tl the perioi INJURY TO THE APPLE AND THE The "cedar apple" fungus jirow* upon DAR and the apple, and is pro complaints were largely in comic the apple leaves and fruit A diagram lwis Ix'cn const ructetl t&lt;&gt; &lt;'\ observations g The " cedi Mi&gt;t«'(l. 'I'll mainder &lt;&gt;f tin tisMU S irf tilt formation of </seg>
            <seg id="p133">mini A n II it'll H 111 pond, the injury to t. indirectly tha possibility of fruit pro- I. the injury to tli ■ tw iry to tli • twit; 1 vari -ti •- i»f apples the young fruits may !&gt;■ very The infection may be localised and ivsult in ■ fruit with a slight reduction •&lt;■ th- in- young fruits may l&gt; ■ very localized and result in v.-rv mirk'd ; The amount of injury which the il ■ foliage may lie very great. In the sus- be verv ereat. In the su»- vhich stand adjacent to cedar trees, almost id adjacent to cedar trees, almost ■ affected, frequently so seriously that th ■?d yellow color even from a distance. In such defoliation follows an&lt;l thus sends the tree into n from a distance. In such follows and thus sends the tree into weakened condition. - er rest in a weakened condition. • if injury to tli ■ cedar tree varies with tli ! severity varies with th ■ severity id the age of the tree. Artificial inoculations of Artificial inoculations of i only needle leaves were attempted but were in wen attempted but were in sful. The field observations in different pwi that tiers from twenty to thirty years old were r vat ions in different parts of i twenty to thirty years old were lil • to infection and suffers I the most from the the most from the irasite. In many places severely infected cedars dying and there call be little doubt that the verelv infected cedars there can be little douht that the nsilile for their destruction. (Fig. I"). 1 n. i Fig. 15 SPRAYING EXPERIMENTS. SPRAYING EXPERIMENTS pple trees for the prevention of rust has met with he prevention of rust has met with f success by orehardists in Nebraska 1 ' 9 ami the ■ &gt;v orchardists in Nebraska 1 ' 5 anil the h ■ failure is due to the quickness with which in - gplatinoua condition of th" cedar apples. Kxperi - by th? writer showed that a delay of 12-24 hours vith which in- 1 f the cedar apples. Expert- dit how &gt;d that a delay of 12-24 hours uak ■ th? spraying of no value. no valui •xperimsnts in spraying th ■ cedar are on record. th' spraying might !&gt;:■ designed to kill the telio- •&lt;lar are on record. \ signed to kill th" telio- n lould be mad" when the "cedar apples" first h • "cedar apples" first -. or should bs made to prevent the reinfection to prevent the reinfection rmin »ta mad" from the teliosporea of the tion testa mad" from th" teliospores of the h .")-l-.")') Bordeaux showed th' complete failun fM produce spondia. It doe^ not seem, however </seg>
            <seg id="p134">Agricultural Experiment Sin' 112 that spraying ;it this p&lt; fully planned spra the cedar wen of small cedars in the I with 6-6-48 Bordeaux i»l their vitality during field temperature. The practical ap of " cedar apples " must U'pi The reduction of the nuinlx value in preventing the int&lt; the life of valuable cedar of the fungus, spraying should redact ci cent of spores examh ture of 26-28 degrees &lt; sufficiently to prevent any material inj </seg>
            <seg id="p135">113 valuable assistance from it lined lination tests of spores anil the H. \V. Barre, now of demon College, mid laboratory assistance; Mr. W. H. dais: and Mr. F. A. Wolf, nee in completing the BIBLIOGRAPHY \ Rust, Hul. Nebr. Kxp. Sta. \ ( 88 I'm. l-i Cedar-Apples of the United mm Vnniv. Mem. Boston Soc. Nat. Hist. 1880 ri i F. I) &gt;pus. Science N. Ser. 26 !M liyillll 11 1 \Y. H mis Cedar Rust (Gymnosporangiuwi macro jmt). Cire. l)iv. Hot. Insect 1'est and Plant Dis. Bur. Nebraska 11-4. Fiji. 1-4. MMKL. I.. H 1905 The Cedar Apple Fungi and Apple Rust in Iowa. Bui. Iowa Kxp. Sta. 84 1-36. Fig. 1-11 jvk, R. F s 190s Cedar Apples and Api 1, Leaf Rust. Circ Ala. Kxp. Sta. 1: 1-11. Fig. 1- HETZEL, H. H. W 1902 Notes on Apple Rust a l'roc. Indiana Acad. Science 1902 255-26 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p136">7 — 1 •r r &gt; - •" • Vv • /• *^ t— • r : )J^f-yi i / ; •r f^ Jl _A -7 x f J4N \ &gt;L _f A-FF^ K •-4- - v— ■ v / /T7T ' i • "7t =Tifli: ± -d-A H 1 ; / — 7-s u y — t&gt; \ /TT7\ , H Z' 1/ » i \ 4 — -\_ ~\ \ \ 1 "■J— \l"" 4 ""- : — "I /7 x-7 ' / I I \ 7rrr / / •fr •f &lt; DC LlI Z I j / / r ) I Ji </seg>
            <seg id="p137">Plate I. ; * : jn&gt;t beginning to show telia. Natural beginning to show tcliu. </seg>
            <seg id="p138">PUATC II 3. Large "cedar apple" in the gclatiaoiH condition. Thi telia at this stage may contain 95 per cent water. </seg>
            <seg id="p139">Plate III (ierminatiiin of tcliospiin ical prniination, compact form; (b) pical germination, nlnnotwt ty(K&gt;: (c) Promycelium showing variati^ lins|iore showing sparioia proaueed direct. lunation of tporidM. </seg>
            <seg id="p140">\ \ V \iria cushion.- before i </seg>
            <seg id="p141">Plate V \l i leaf </seg>
            <seg id="p142">* Fig. 8. Pycnia, upper surface of leaf </seg>
            <seg id="p143">Plate VII Fie. it. Knlar u mt; of a group of :uvi:i </seg>
            <seg id="p144">Fig. 10. leaves showing aborted I'livll </seg>
            <seg id="p145">I' LATE IX r ■^ B, -.liowin^ yoiinjt iialls on cedar and aecia Mine day. from adjacent tr falo </seg>
            <seg id="p146">» r * K V X K * « * N E 1 i V • M f * A ./ Fig. !'_'. Drawing slinwiiigy </seg>
            <seg id="p147">1 I 1) li XI l'l.ATE Cedar dppU 3anm Jo-r. 3 3 ~T~ VClaster-cupt — maUre »OTt t * I it &lt; not Time o( {\J_ Injection jrf &lt;c o « It II il /o / 14 JanQ Jarv I 2 X 3 3 Wls produce ,U^ SQTi, ti y + -&gt;|| 3~ I) Time oj L« InttctioTv w icVbU J-M H'0 7 uStcr-caVt Tv-m. (I \r.\ecb«m| f — f nature «■ 1 /o // HI 3an Q X J totts ptoduct U 14»V_O 81 IIH. VJ Injection ClasttT-cup« matuTt 19 08 u I 9 c 0 II LU i L* i * the life history of tin' 'cedar apple" fungus. The e refernil to as "chtttern ■cup </seg>
            <seg id="p148">l'ij;. 14. Drawing from a pi the rust. An ap| </seg>
            <seg id="p149">Plats XIII h&gt;- f </seg>
            <seg id="p150"/>
            <seg id="p151">rE INFLUENCE OF CHEMICAL STIMULATION UPON THE PRODUCTION OF PERITHECIA BY MELAXOSPORA I'AMPEAXA SPEC I). Hkai.d and Venus W. Pool. </seg>
            <seg id="p152">UPON THE &gt;SI'&lt;&gt; THE INFLUENCE OF CHEMICAL STIMULATION PRODUCTION OF PERITHECIA BY MELA\ PAMPEASA SPEG U\ V. I). Healo \m&gt; Vknus \V. 1 It has been shown in olisni of one fungus may | other fungus. Further in\ of the same count describes tl tween MeUmotpora was first isolated ii connected witl The perfe&lt; upon ami imon had recently inft report eel u grow outside of the l this time, how* ospora appear method cultures of the /■ thecia did BOt appear. A no growth of Md and yet the Mcospon hanging drop culture is evident from the facts w I After repeated effort one lium. From this other cultures were conidia or perithecia evei • *Resi K n.-&lt;l ftii|ilnwlii I I. l!Hls ii description Cultures of this /•'&lt;/.* mained apparently pi After repeated ettort one being transferred to a cultun slowly produced a scanty </seg>
            <seg id="p153">I 1/ H&lt; 131 il&gt;e with Fuaarium monili- n were employed in the same manner, development while the other Fusarium eulmorum caused a scanty 11 tit' the hanging drop cultures of Fusar- wing together failed to reveal any at - o such m was described \&gt;y DeBary' U tspora pararitiea. Deliarv says: ''The died Bpore, which is ."&gt;-(i microns in :rowii in water or in nutrient solu - lian the transverse diameter of the Melantmpora, the niemlirane which sepa- — « » 1 rowth in length is deflected us to develop. The greatest 111 influence the di- to five times the length illation ••! perithecia did not DeBary describes, it is evident the medium upon which ;. the stimuli..-,. That .vas shown as follows: The on f tori urn gaUarum and of Fuxar- ml the medium .sterilized at 110° C i in abundance. When Fusarium "i i/tillarum. perithecia abundance. Two other undeter- ussioii of a germ-tube at each ex- on a hypha of Istuin. which is state of nature, the germ-tube be- hypha of the In &gt;st and then de- jerm-tube eoraea into pontact coalesce with one another. But distance from a growing hypha irocure this in plants grown on a Its "tiiutll 111 W'Mtrtfi ifl i\t*ttt*nt£*t\ ntact with the nerm-tube, mil six weeks upon ordinary </seg>
            <seg id="p154">132 Agricultural Exj" Statit ' These media were then inoculated with the sterile mvceliui Mrimmttporm which had l&gt;een obtained from the ascospon This was repeated several times with the result *t hat m old culture of Fuaarium or Basisporium was used the format the perithecia were formed in four to seven days. I from a two-weeks' old culture of Ha simulating effect upon the sterile .1/ older cultures, instead of this effect l&gt;eii 1 1 ll it inhibited the grow the mycelia of F. moniliforme andfi.t that the aciditv was much increased. analysis showed the pi is therefore evident that oapora requires certain &lt; duced bv F. man fungi. olits. In pure cultures perithecia and then only were present the peril h&lt; 10-15 davs. The senior author has as Sordmia longieaudata prodi lowing a copious growth of /' same Sordarin always fails to compost which has not previoi HIHI.KMiH AI'II 1. DkBaky. A. Mvceiozoa and Hacter 2. Molliard, M. perithecia w:is entirely inhibited. If younger became powonoua until it inhibit A careful titrstion of tin- hm Molliard 5 has ilt lssT Comparative Morpl 1903 Hole &lt;ics bucteries dans la production d des Aacobolua. Compt. Rend. 136 899-901 3. Saccardo. 1'. A. 1888 Sylloge Fungoruni 7 563. </seg>
            <seg id="p155">133 Fig. 1. Mature peritliecium "f Milunospora pampeana. Fig. 2. Germinating mw^W of the same. </seg>
            <seg id="p156">I&gt;. \"\f,. :i. Lonytiirtiiwl netionol kyouag perith U, laniiniiiia </seg>
            <seg id="p157">DISSEMINATION OF TUBERCULOSIS BY THE MANURE OF INFECTED CATTLE. \. T. Peters and Clarence Emkimon. </seg>
            <seg id="p158">DISSEMINATION OF TUBERCULOSIS BY MANURE OF INFECTED CATTLE. THE Bv A. T. Peters and Clarence Kmkksun INT KnlHCTION Schroeder ami Cotton bv their work published in B NO. !t!i of the Bureau of Animal Industry, on "The Da Tuberculous Bacilli in the Knvironment of Tuberculous ( have aroused considers conclusions indicate that one nl the conmiom I- for the tubercle bacillus from t the intestinal tract, :m«l that bacilli M ami still retain their viruleix bercukMM cattle a place similar to tl tuberculoiu persons. The report ol Aninu.l Industry for 1907 say* "Tl Rated that the commonest mode for cilli from the bodies of tuberculous at about 40 per cent of the tuberc mptomt iij disidsi are expelling and (1 that tubercle bacilli passed with \vs are actively pathogenic.'' 1 If 40 is the intestinal tract, and that bacilli are passed thru iiul still retain their virulence. They ascril of tuberculous persons. Th of Aninu.l Indus: rv for 1907 strated that the commones bacilli from the bodies il&gt;er that about 40 per ecu show no symptoms of diseas the ]&gt;(■!■ cent, without much doiil tuberculous cows are included. These results are indeed s since, if definitely established, we &gt;h which is of far-reaching importance tamination of milk would offer a meal tubercle bacilli in dairy products, and consideration localise hogi ate commonly permitted t the same pasture and feed lots with cattle and since. 1 •Clarence Knierson. Ph. D.. Assistant in Animal Pi 136 </seg>
            <seg id="p159">Annual Report 137 i i t\ NSTKAT 1 M Ex t xannn \Y ■&lt; tinea pi 11 by this organism, its presence in cow list ant source &lt;&gt;f danger to them. Cotton- examined seven samples of feces from tuberculosis. They claim to have found, by ion. tubercle bacilli in five of these samples, Inoculation and ingestion experiments were »f four of the cattle, with the result that be passing virulent bacilli. Beebe* made a larger number of examinations, male under experiment. Some of them were five times for virulent bacilli in the feces. considerably from those of Schroeder and were able to demonstrate virulent bacilli in the ow and this one was badlv affected with tuber- ('ing constantly present in the nasal secretion. Mohler' have demonstrated the ability of the pass thru the intestinal tract and retain was shown by feeding healthy eattle a culture bacilli. The manure from these cattle was ucntal pen of four hogs. Three out of the four ith the diaeas ION OK TtHKRCI.K HACIIX1 IN THE KKCI&gt; at the start to mention a few important things an examination of cow feces for the tubercle irst place it should l&gt;e borne in mind that a ativn dlitiii is of little mine. In cow feces we li morphologically similar bacilli which stain I which by means of the ordinary miscrosopic ■ unable to differentiate from the tul&gt;erele tubercle bacilli might be (and the proba - true in many cases) present in such small nicroscopic examination would be inadequate This was true in the feces of cow No. 2$ of the nent Station, in which tul&gt;ercle bacilli were animal inoculation while repeated micro - ons failed to reveal them." ort to animal experiment for absolute proof, i is the most serviceable for this purpose. Even </seg>
            <seg id="p160">138 A (/ric alt u nil Experiment Station \ thru* here we cannot rely merely on the product nodular formations, because Rabinowitcl give rise to these. The nodules should l&gt;e examii cells and the histologica) picti re tul&gt;ercle noduli. must have demonstrated it a tuberculous nodule. Invest ion ex peri men of demonstration infection in theae it &lt; that hoes readih ami if we coiili the experiment The application before utilizing The cow were tor the over Ml per cent hi of these were in e feting from the &lt;1 test. lour of t Ik males at the Nel tuberculin test had Keen the examination. METHOD iH l.WI.S The feces were taken from I hi' n spoon. This was inserted rotated as it was withdrawn. I)iH material was verv seldom eneounti The investigation includt stained spreads of the mater N n attempt was made to determine th bacillus by the microscope, believing Before we can sav positive fecea contains virulent tubercle I iceptible animal the ch </seg>
            <seg id="p161">1 ml 139 ; the manure was suspended in ed. The guinea-pigs succumb - e or septicaemia in only a few nea-pi nit .in KKsn.TS OF THE INVESTIGATION 11 are indicated in the following investigati that in twenty-two out of forty-one samples icilli morphologically similar to the tubercle list rated by the microscope. Subsequent in - wed that of these twenty-two samples only the forty-one samples) were passing viru- This brings out the fact before mentioned xamination is untrustworthy in demonstrating •ow manure. which were passing virulent tubercle bacilli .vcre in good physical condition and from their liaease would not have been suspected. The third. is poor but the symptoms of the disease were not mber cf acid-fast bacilli in her feces, as revealed &gt;t\ was exceedingly large. In every field a number ■ located, and in one place an area of degenerating clinging to it was found. cow No. 20 was such as to arouse no sus- Her feces contained fairly large numbers which were virulent tul&gt;erele bacilli interest because of his exceptionally fine irge Aberdeen Angus bull, remarkably He, however, sutlers a persistent but moderate assing virulent tubercle bacilli in his fei if this evidence we cannot disregard a possible manure even tho the appearance of the animal hat only those samples of manure in which ■ demonstrated microscopically were utilized cuts. The probabilities are that some of n which the microscope did not reveal acid-fast bacilli con- ilent germe of tuberculosis. The one positive case at M I'sota Experiment Station was constantly negative to ic examination. </seg>
            <seg id="p162">140 AgricuUuratlExpt Staiu A temporary scarcity of guinea-pigs ne&lt; of those samples in which the preset »f tlu w; most probable. APPEARANCE OF COWS WHU'H \RK PASSING V1HI TUBE1 I.I \C1I.I.I part-lit lv in good physical com of infection may scatU explain this by tl their sputum, am anil virulence creted without havin This reasoning appt suits and bv the work iif the N tract. Their excreti the disease in Cotton. "It must in bacilli in the t'i testinal tract. This migh a sloughing gland hut it of necrotic, or diseased, ti genera] opinion that in all an frequent organs affected. It some stage of the infection eliminating and swallowing material which contains the gen Cows which harbor extens t a chronic cough of severe grade 1 are more apt to have the virulent germs in their manure, wi shall, nevertheless, have to suspect every cow which reacts to the tuberculin test. According t&lt;i Schroeder am M;m\ bacilli do not :t|)|x :-ulosis is .due tci an into: tcstinal mucoM of cattle The pretence of ml*' of a communication lict a cnronir cough m severe grade may s ance. Altlm animals which present </seg>
            <seg id="p163">•/ d Annual Report 141 CONCLUSIONS aeilli may pass thru the intestinal tract of heir virulence. Hi in the feces of cattle may readily con - uts and cause infection in ha - lation and a microscopical examination of are necessary to definitely establish the acilli in cow feces. lents with hojrs, previously proven to I* v application of the tuberculin test, an 1 1 not be permitted to run in the same pens llv if the latter are known to l&gt;e tuberculous. H 1) iducts from tuberculous cows, even tho there the udder, are a source of dancer to man. of tuberculous cows which show no symptoms ih excrete virulent tubercle bacilli in their ently lar&lt;:*' to make this an important factor in iiberculoms. HIHLKXiKAPHY oratory Bulletin No. 41 H Animal Industry Bulletin No. &lt;»!t. Experiment Station Bulletin No. 103. Animal Industry Bulletin No. *-v demonstrating tulx&gt;rcle bacilli in the manure </seg>
            <seg id="p164">142 Atin'c nit u ml Experiment Station A '. TubU demon tinting tin renultx a n 22 ■ood N,,v N \ N \ N N X X X X .VI good NoV M iHM&gt;r N,,v. id :&gt; stixhI 111 kiki.1 „ . 1(1 |HM&gt;r fi Nov. in (Ki good ... in 87 good Nov. hi (Mi K&lt;«»1 X&lt;» 4S pood "Ml 14. ! good N, N ■ood Km 11 nod 15 k&lt;kmI N J4 &amp; « i(i Nnv 17 i K'""' U Nov :&lt; , H'xti n Xn Nov 3N KikhI H No\ 22. poor | No\ -Ti p««i y Nov 102 i«M.r A Nov 13 k«mh1 Nui rj good Nov 16 good Nov 20. pkhI Nov. 17 101 |H&gt;or Nov. 1 1 H'&gt;oil I Nov. 19 50. . pood Nov. lit PkhI Nov. 19 43. pkiiI I Nov. l&lt;i 47 pmhI B Nov \ N S N v a-" "1 Xi&gt;v 4 . . i giKxl I Uov 100 good | Nov 1S)1 good D.T. Ltl J()J I good I)cc. 20 203. good I),-,-. 20 204 I good l&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p165">SECOND W \l REPORT OF THE NEBRASKA SEED LABORATORY ereotu interested m either the growth il seeds. The following Tables are self the more important results secured. &gt; nf the X&lt;-I&gt;ri&gt;k:i Seed Labors* &gt;ry. Bid. Xel&gt;r. Kxp. Sta. 110 Kin 1-1- Tliis n|K&gt;rt ineludea ■ more popular account of year's work together wiili illustrations anil descriptions ininon weed LOOX, I'm. I).. riHiii in hunu 111 in««ii Bniin, t'&lt;illalx&gt;rator in Charge. Wl) NKI.I.i: STEVENSON, A IV. L*aoBATon Aid. Moratory, I'nited State* Depart timl of Agnciil* INTRODUCTION. iTcscnts the more technical results secured by the Laboratory during the second year of its opera- ihe fiscal year from July 1. I90K, to .Inly 1. l!M&gt;&lt;). i. as will he seen by reference to Table II. the work my lias increased about •"&gt;() per cent over the pre- nl while, as before, about half of the samples were Nebraska fanners and seedsmen, yet samples were thirteen states in all. It is evident that the work &gt;rv is commanding more and mure of the attention </seg>
            <seg id="p166">144 Agricultural / iU Station Xeb Table I. — G&lt; Colorado. District of Columbi IlliiKii&gt; Iowa Kansas Minn Missouri. Montana. Nebnalu New York South ('arolina South !&gt;akcit.i Itah inral nary tij thi tirn )i-k. , shu ■ nqrnp ideal wi /(» sum 1 1, Us. Identi- No. of Kviiiii- I'urity • UTM samples fication iiatinii nation 1908 1909 1M6 1909 I'.mis 1909 19U8 1909 1906 1909 (I o 0 I) 30 36 r.-' i) II n il il II i&gt; 1 1 n :; il II ii 5 il II ii II (i t l is 1J9 5 '.i 59 .'1 (I 7 n ,, I 54 ins ii .; is 'i I .". 9 59 18 :;;; is ii ! ii ii i ! " &lt; " i (, , 6 il I SS ' in </seg>
            <seg id="p167">7 "id Annual Report 145 &lt;~, yr .«..-, ls.)i,S,[| 7 &gt;^iu,).\\ y "■"■&gt;') uiurexg Jlflliwpi rt B 5 i /. - " t. * ■' 61 3 alfi i £ I i\\\ *" r- ?z -r 7t 3i 3 O &gt;-* tO , . = '= i S3 55 3 ■&gt;&lt;l a !H -M 2 S.M|SIH • AIU1I,[ s,)|&lt;iuu:s ~ [2 * " ~~ "' Hill fill </seg>
            <seg id="p168">146 Agricultural Experiment Statu \ebrt ' r .)3i:j.ia\ " 72 7 •i 5 \ \ •r ; I ( . I [ I : II 1 1 1 n : \ | - - - I. - /. ls.»i|3ij| — i- aiuu,i II. .III.. 11)1111. &gt;l'l [■.Hl.i.ku s.)|clllli:- |l&gt; J. I II!! D I'M"] </seg>
            <seg id="p169">147 Tin nlij-sicittid Annual Rtport r S A -• « f /■ •' r f S- — * X I- f :: f r f / '- ri / ri ?) -' •m • . — * i — /. 5 ■ t- S 2 £ i *3 C it 'r-l 'r :g r -i - s\z n i - a —. a ri ?. tz •- t- ?i s ri Ism jjlsla g=-|s&gt;J-3 1 ill Ml </seg>
            <seg id="p170">148 Agricultural Experiment Station Sebras </seg>
            <seg id="p171">d Ann unl Rt/x&gt;rt 149 7 K (a found in &lt;il}alja No. ,lt SAM PLUS M WHICH mi vii COMMON \ V\IK (ireen foxtail Rnwrinn thistle. l.aml&gt;'s-&lt;|iiart«'r Amaranth. . . . 151 i 5 -•&gt; • Ml But'kliiirn M Sweet elover. Yellow foxtail ."&gt;! »7 Old-witch grass. :t9 Barnyard grass... '.Hi 36 1- reiiiont 's sjnmrfu iH 35 32 Roequette 3o Wad chicory.. H 28 .'.". 25 a IT 17 Sandbur. 17 Sanilhur 17 Yellow trefoil Curled dock.. Wild carrot. . Yellow trefoil tf Hi Curled dock. 15 I.') Wild carrot. . 15 SiiimM-scccUmI alfalfa dodder.. 14 Ragweed.... 14 (lover dodder. 13 Spreading panicurn 13 I-iel.l dodder.. 12 11 Chinese mustard. 11 Chinese mustard Wild buckwheat II Wilil buckwheat. 11 11 11 11 10 U) 10 in 10 Common mallow. 10 Common mallow ( iumweed. (iumweed.. 9 '.» Wild sunflow Wild sunflower.. 9 9 Small dowered mclilot I Small Howered melilot s Spreading amaranth Spreading amaranth Bird's f&lt;Hit trefoil Poverty weed. Bird's foot trefoil 7 Poverty weed. 6 li Shaftel 6 6 t&gt; t&gt; Large seeded alfalfa dodder 5 l.ars;e-se«'ded alfalfa dodder .&gt; 5 .) Lady'a tlmmli 5 Lady'H thiiml .) Rough rusli s;ras&gt; 5 Rough rush siras: Forked catch-Hy. Hairy stick 5 Forked catoh-Hy. 5 .) Hairy stfekseed. 4 i 1 4 \ 4 4 Nijllit Bowering catch-fly.. 4 Night Bowering catch-Hy 4 w 4 4 ( (nv 1ktI&gt; 4 4 Hoary ereai 4 4 </seg>
            <seg id="p172">I all Agricultural Experiment Station oi Sebraxk \ IKVIIhK NAMK ('In nD/iDiliuiH murale Nettle-leaved _ I'lnntnijii aritfata. Hr:u Plantayo riti/iln. HI Prunella rultfaris. lie \mpett Verbena haxtatn Euphorbia pretl Lepidium apetal \|k Siiln rpinima Trifol ftumei action* KraorotAi* nlf, I'mbellijerai .-/» Runu Sola eii/nl ■ J uncut sfi I'ii nil ii »i I nthyll Euphorbia - Data Ho*act a Polygon \ i rl» nit art i \\ Tiitasj Acalypha Turin* mult 'I linllil "i lancenlatv Comvolrufru tp ■us 8) Ornil' ujius tp Camelina nalira I'ablk \\. Kind m IKS I U IC NAMK 'i ririili*. PinUago i Situ rtn &lt;ilaum. . Rumex aitpUM Green f-&gt; Hliick-c. Yellow foxi (urli'il ilnpk Digitaria wanguinalu 1 .;&lt; r&gt;r&lt; Digitaria humijuia Hmall ( n xtrirta. 11 Trigom iln v /&gt; Huilbirkiit hirta </seg>
            <seg id="p173">I nty-*econd innual Report 151 \o. Of SAMPLES IX WHICH POUND \IM1I\ XAMK Small cral&gt;-Kra» ."HI 17 U Lady s-ttmml&gt; Buekhorn. Lamb's-quarten. capillate. old-witch graai 35 Ragweed. 35 :ih. Barnyard cr:. Barnyard grass Sheep sorrel :U aretoneUa Sheep wjnd :'.l l.anp' cr in Large er ib Am .r nit 1 1 Am .r uith. . . . -■&gt; '-.ufitiiirliiii preslii Spurge noctiflora Night-Dowering eatch-Hv -'I IS 13 13 1J I I '.i g s ti I li I ''irunttn dichotomifiorun.. Spreading panicum carota. Wild carrot . Spiny siila. . 'P p (irasWB ( ir-asties I jiiiirni CliincM' rniiHtaril. . Chinese mustard. Braetcd plantain Rough rush grass Heal-all. "lantaga itnstntn. Hraotc.l plantain iporobohu asper Rouch rush gran 'ruiullti tutsan*. Heal-all.. ( 'liarliK'k eaefoHa. . . White vervain Europeao vervain White vervain European vervain tp •'lium fremontU Krennnit's ■now loot... [ralypha rirginicum. Thro'-seeiled inerrury.- u lantiu/o major.. I'lantain. . hastntii . Blue vervain Blue vervain '■.nujroMis .&lt;;). . . . • mined a. ,) 4 t °a*palum wtarrum. Slender |iaspalinn Slender paspahim Cinquefou. t "nlinlillii monapelienn* CinqueCou. :s 'nnx rp, Sedi;e :i p olygonum nniulnri. . Knotweed.. B :&gt; 3 hniithirii in,' Kveniiifi praBMM Evening prnMoae if Kiipliiirlnii mticulntn. . Milk purslane. 'us Hi., l'ield dodder. . Milk purslane 3 Field dodder .5 &lt;ils,*l&lt;t kuli trnuiftilio. . Russian thistle. 'uaeuta epHkj/mum. . Clover dodder.. liinctolDlum. Bull thistle Russian thistle :s th Clover dodder 1 Hull thistle I'urtKUm himchuiitr xilrirola. . Woolly panieuin "nHirum huiultuiiif sili-iroln. Woolly panicum u-h •&gt; LepuiiuM apetaium Apetalous peppergraa*. 'amthna tativm. I.arire-seeded fals«' Hax. Ap^talous pcppeigr— lul ( I.arsre-seeded false Ha\ ■ &gt; \l \l uhlenlwruiu wp. 'endtru* mrolininniix. Sandlmr. ■&gt; iinihru." rarohnianut.. Sutdbur &gt; inthyUis ndinrnnn. . . . Kidney vetch. ■&gt; \nthimis totulu. May- weed... ■ &gt; itripkx wp. ■&gt; Cum] tn&gt; 1 TrifoHvm up 1 Hull us Intintus Velvet grass 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p174">152 Agricultural Experiment Station 'isk-a »AMP SCIENTiriC NAMI MMMN NAMf WHICH Trifolium m Trifolium plijormi -. l.inario tpm Annytilli* Of ('(imum mnnilntiim Rabbit'* fool clove Suckling clover Round-leaved toad-flax Red pimpernel. Ajmga rip; Rarbnrea vuhjun ('trsium urn us Hntmu* IJi. Jun&lt; it* s/i Agropyro* rep* T ri jtiliunt suareoien* &lt; Upsi lln Uiir*&lt;i-i&gt;&lt;istii Ehjllius sy H"sa ip Mil i In! us alba. . Eragrttsti* n Thlns[ - l.i/mlnun iijH-lnhi Xepeta rntnnn Irn jnnthijii/iii SCIKXTIFK* S'AMI Hrnmus *t cult n u AoropyroH n i&gt;* n ( hinn)nnliiim iillmm Hlimi.i ('tint fHtsitm tp 1 .a fi jut hi t'rhi Hutu . a iirtirin jiilni Digtiaria mwfm'nafi ThUupi nn-insi Hnisxicii j ii unn Klynmx sp I'olyijtmum iirirulnn Srir/mx n/i Srtnria n'ritli* ( kx-toncue Knotted hedge-panley Smooth tiawk'i beard. Bugle Winter creiw. Table V. Kind I int'll foxt \\ intiT creiw ( ':ill:l&lt;i:l tlllstli'. Black mustard Quack-Kntr Sh;iftcl ShcplnTil '» pur-r Swwl el'' a l'ielil penny-cr \|x't;tlou- |K-|&gt;|M-ri;r;i- ( utinint Mamli .-I l( in i (I si nl I ml i n ii iruli \ v \i h Cbeal s Quack . Lamb 's-quart fry (urlcil dock Kurupean stickaeed White vervain Large crab-graai Field pennycrean Chineae mustard. Knot weed </seg>
            <seg id="p175">■ ml Annual Ht /x&gt;rt 153 XIUI J.1AOIJ Amomij 1X1UI • - &gt;- — • « • M -I — X ~ — — *' i 1 J ■&gt;1^l\ Htf unifofiuj^ ri ri *i wnui'j |Ui:i|JJ() ti/Hfiof] /: vn luouf/ liup.&gt;H ''■r zL 2 •u s. U— JM • * xC i v- s. I i £11 S I 2 1 i ■ni'i.vv AOfl ]WH nttptttl im&gt;,i AI(1OU1(X ■miv JJ* .ia'j i|si|Sir.j , &gt;&lt;l mni}o r i *HA )s,ij .\mi|ii:,&lt;j^ mf»»,i I ss,)|ll.ttV c* 5H: i- = SPT-s 5?fc"SJ? £"■&lt; ai x u. S a. x </seg>
            <seg id="p176">154 Agricultural Experiment Station Xebraska ■UIUVIUI i»AO|3 .»(isp: pus Ainoiii; i ajujxnii ssi:j; ( ■' jd.Mi|.i a|iq_\\ j tunijo/u i J,)A()|O )«&gt;{ •vkj/iiji/ uniii&lt;i/iui J.(A(l|.» K(IB[Y wri/riMi/iy uini/olij i )j||iiu mMiud;) II.I)]II)I DIJK/'S' ■Ml|&lt;| A - &gt;(JI1|UJ\| .■/ ;«/,/ A1|l&lt;&gt;[lll | K.»;i&lt;j&lt;y I! il' : JI\ li.lflliK 06o3tp»ft r.M ,&gt;a'j i|si|au;.| 'iinijo-j "'•1.1 'I A\n|,i:.,] V '/ junpt\» i SS1?J» |iJIM|JJ( ) ■lllllji| s^.l[l|.«\ ■ IMKJJ/ ||&gt;.'H IH//K » V ■l s. 5;~ ;-_/ / - _ - ■/. - x SB r. </seg>
            <seg id="p177">Twenty teeemd Annual Rejtort 155 ?i — ~i -\ ri ?i ?l 71 r-i m n x a 5 i. 1 mMim&amp;vAmn « » rS§§l1-|irJiJJ-?.S 3-8.111.-1.1 J — - &gt; =-;7 -£—'--£— r_ * i — - t- — — </seg>
            <seg id="p178">Agricultural Experiment Station Web 156 "/ ainjxnu jdAop a^isfs pur aihoiui) aanixin; jd.\&lt;&gt;|0 .&gt;l!MA\ xuid.ij iiiminju I jjao|j jwh txitjfiud uitujotuj^ J,)AII|.) .&gt;^W|\ iuninji)fiif mntfofm l.'lljiu iii:uu&lt;); ) DJI/OJl /&gt;U/'/»s' md »mq a!|.)!iiii.&gt;\| (/ («.,/ AI||OIIII I i)luil 111 ni/ y, / l: .H'MI\ — z r- 7"/l IW8 .iaj i|s||Su;.| mniftrj x«U lunuttss &gt; ifi&gt;&gt; '&lt; iiinui'i WUlJ&lt; JllJS.)j \M.|T.I|\ &gt; — "a"S a -/. ~ </seg>
            <seg id="p179">7 LtmtMJ Rf'iwt 157 7 </seg>
            <seg id="p180">Nebraska .Agricultural t,X[Mri ttitnt station "i 158 aiiijxiui jjaoij J?(1S|« ]&gt;UK Xnl&lt;)Ull| .UlllXIIU S8BJJ) JdA»|D Jll'I.W suxUj. umijofu.i JOAOp p^H Jd.\O|J .»(|S1\ iuitl&gt;iMjtiy umijnju i l.)[l!'ii iii:iiu.i; ) p.;f/i//' pum/'s' isiu^ ■•iil'l a"?(jh|ii.&gt;\| /// i»i,l Al|l&lt;&gt;lll! I jii mn&gt;\n,j K i\ K )\\ mntfo'i x«U urn / Ij A.I|&gt;!M|\ .m)**./ \X» |ui:i|jj|, t'tii-i Hunjli n/fifjv(i — i:j3 .imoai| ss.i|iia\\ doipay i«;/r&lt; v 5 ■r. '■ x I. XV^ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>