<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00034.00029">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00034.00029</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE LINCOLN, NEBRASKA, U. S. A.  NEBRASKA BOYS' POTATO CLUBS GROWING POTATOES</title>
               <date value="1913">1913</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-13</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Distributed March 24, 1913 THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE Lincoln, Nebraska, D. S. A. NEBRASKA BOYS' POTATO CLUBS GROWING POTATOES By .1. R. Cooper Department of Horticulture IThe Boys" and Girls' Club Work in Nebraska is conducted he University of Nebraska in cooperation with the Bureau 'lant Industry, United States Department of Agriculture. DEPARTMENT OP AGRICULTURAL EXTENSION C. W. PUGSLEY, Superintendent </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Clubs) Alfalfa Management I. Cost of Growing Crops in Nebraska a 3. Testing Seed Corn. I Cooking ami Sewing (Boys' and fiirl&gt;' Clubs). Part I. — Judging Horses and Cattle ( Boys' and Girl Part II.— Corn. I Part III.— The Home Garden. Spraying Apple Trees. Smuts of Nebraska Cereals. 7 I Care of Milk and Cream on the Farm. The Selection and Care of Seed Corn. Organization of Nebraska Boys' and G Organization of Nebraska Boys' and Girls' Clubs. Cooperative County Farm Demonstrators. Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs. (Growing Potatoes.) Ee above bulletins will be sent free to residents of request to College of Agriculture or NEBRASKA EXPERIMENT STATION. Lincoln Nebraska </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Growing Potatoes Pbject of the organization is to encourage and instruct its I in agriculture, particularly the best methods of growing for market and exhibition, to use better seed, better meth - better crops and at the same time conserve soil fertility. Growing Potatoes for Contests. In preparing this bulletin the writer has attempted to give sugges - tions concerning all the important points which should be observed in order to produce good crops of potatoes. The different steps arc taken up in order just as the grower will proceed. The suggestions herein offered are taken from experience in the fields and are those which the Experiment Stations and the most successful farmers find to give the best results. In addition to the following advice herein given, good judgment vamst be employed in following out each step. Plan each operation carefully beforehand and do the work thoroughly. Seek the advice of the successful potato growers in your neighborhood. From them ran be learned many helpful things which may otherwise not be ob - tained. Watch every little detail of their work and follow their lead. Good land, good seed, good judgment and good work will produce good potatoes. Choice of Ground. The first thing to do is to choose the ground. The best soil for potatoes is a deep rich sandy loam, which contains plenty of well rotted vegetable matter. The soil should be so light as to offer no great resistance to the enlargement of the tubers or potatoes. The mbm lil should be of such a nature as to allow the water to soak away rapidly. Land that remains too wet makes soggy potatoes. Heavy clay soil should be avoided. Choose land which is fairly level and does not overflow during high water. flfalfa or clover land on which some other crop has been grown year, or land which was manured the year before, is very good potatoes. Do not manure land on which potatoes are to be </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Kted the same year. Never plant potatoes on the same ground ; than two years in succession, and better still not more than year. Preparation op Soil. The ground should be plowed early the fall before. If the soil is not too heavy early fall plowing (in July or August) followed by the harrow later to keep weeds down is l&gt;est. 1 f the ground is heat y. it should be plowed just before freezing in the fall, then run over lengthwise and crosswise with a disc harrow, the discs being almost straight. The ground should be plowed seven to ten inches deep This leaves the soil loose which favors the proper develop - ment of the potatoes and gives a larger feeding area for the roots. If the ground cannot be plowed until spring it should be plowed a - early as possible and deep. Do not plow under trash. This material interferes with planting and cultivating and binders the passage ■&gt;! soil water from the subsoil to the soil where the roots obtain their supply. Early in the spring the ground which has been fall plowed should be double disced and harrowed. If the potatoes are planted early no further preparation of the soil is necessary, but if planted late the ground should be harrowed often enough to kill the young Seed Potatoes. iDtatoes weighing 6 to 8 ounces, 3 1 '. to 4 inches long if oval, or to 3 inches through if round, are best for seed. Such pot., have 0 to 16 eyes each, if the stock is good. Small potatoes : too many eyes and large potatoes too few eyes compared to the of the potato. Planting large potatoes makes the cost of seed high. Good seed potatoes should have eyes fairly deep and well ned, but not too numerous, and a smooth, thick, tough skin, itoes which become pointed at the stem end and have a large iber of eyes are poor for seed purposes. Northern grown seed (potatoes raised in Red River Valley) give better results than our home grown seed, unless special care is taken in caring for, selecting and storing our home grown crops. North - ern grown seed gives better yields, but is ten days to two weeks later than native seed. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">5 Seed Selection*. It is a common belief that potatoes "run out'', that is, no longer produce good crops after being grown for a number of years in the NKK locality. There is a great deal of truth in this, due generally to lack of selection and improper care of potatoes. With proper care and selection there is no reason for this "running out". Here is a way to secure and keep a good stock of seed potatoes : Let each boy do some experimenting for himself along this line. Take ten to twenty well shaped, smooth potatoes, cut them into the same size pieces and plant in separate rows, one potato to a row, placing a numbered stake at the end of each. When the potatoes are matured (!is, r each row by itself, examine and weigh the potatoes. Select jxitatoes from the best yielding rows for your seed next year. It woatd be well to continue this work by saving one good potato at lca&gt;t from each row and planting again the next year and treating as l&gt;efore ; better still to keep the entire product of each row and plant again in separate rows and make the selection the second year. If this cannot be done, it will prove very beneficial to at least make hill selections. As soon as the potatoes are matured, when the vines are nearly but not quite dead, dig the hills separately with a potato fork. Reject all hills which do not have eight to twelve good sized, smooth potatoes. From those which have this number or over, select the potatoes which have grown well below the surface of the ground, as those which lie close to the surface are liable to be in - jured from the heat of the sun. Figure I. — A good type of Potatoes for Seed. Note the uniformity of size and shain* and the evenlv distributed well defined eves. -T^ * * </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Xcbraska Pays' Potato Clubs. K Figure II.— A poor type of Potatoes for Seed. Note the lack of uni - lity in size and shape, and the poorly defined weak eyes. Figure III. — Potatoes which have "run out". Note the small, irregular shape and the numerous eyes. Condition of Seed. Condition of potatoes is very important in selection of seed. There is always a loss of vitality in sprouting and having the sprouts removed before planting. The potato eye is not a single bud, but a collection of buds, and when the first sprout is broken off several smaller and weaker sprouts are formed. Seed potatoes should be hard and firm. Sprouted potatoes are usually shriveled or flabby. [tltjt </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Xcbraska Boys' Potato Clubs. 7 If an early crop is desired potatoes may be placed in thin layers, where the light is bright but where the sun cannot strike them. Sprouts will appear within a few days when the potatoes may be cut and planted. This will make the crop from one to two weeks Vaueth IK Six-Weeks, Bliss Triumph, Quick Lunch and Acme are early potatoes. None of these varieties, however, make extra yields. They are desirable for early potatoes for home use or n extra early market. The Early Ohio is medium early and the ]w&gt;pular potato in Nebraska. It is :i heavy yielder, a fair sr and is more extensively grown than any other variety. The Cobbler, Pearl, and Rural New Yorker are the best late varie - for this state. Medium early potatoes give best results in aska, except under irrigation or where there is plenty of late when late potatoes do well. Treatment ok Sk^d Bkfore Cuttijh Dry rot is causing a great deal of damage to potato growers in Nebraska. If the stem end of a diseased potato is shaved off, brown thread like strands may be seen extending into the potato. This dis - ea&gt;e which causes rot grows while the potatoes are in storage. When this diseased seed is planted the new potatoes in the field become dis- Msed. Much of this may be prevented by cutting off the stem end of the potato, being sure to remove all the discolored part and throwing it away, then dipping the seed in a solution of formalin, I pint to 30 gallons of water, or corrosive sublimate, 1 part to 1000 parts of water. Place the potatoes in a gunny sack and submerge them and leave them in the solution for two hours. When removed from the solution spread on a platform to dry, then cut and plant. After being treated potatoes should not be placed in anything which has contained untreated ix&gt;tatoes l&gt;efore. </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Cutting the Seed. t&gt;tatoes should not he cut more than four or five days ahead of ting. Unless planted at once they should not be placed in large and should be stirred occasionally, to prevent heating. A few Ifuls of land plaster scattered over each sackful of cut potatoes help to cure the cut surfaces. i&gt;tatoes should be cut one or two eyes ko the piece. The nuni - of eyes is often of less importance than the size of the piece, i piece should weigh at least •"&gt; i to i ounce. A medium sized to should make six or eight pieces. The piece in all cases must irge enough to support the young plant until its roots are large lgh to supjx&gt;rt it. Bake the potato in the left hand, stem end up, and cut each piece Kcnrivehr as indicated. The bud end of the potato always coa - 5 numerous eyes and should be split into two pieces. Figure Y. — ( nmparison of a 14-V.t oz. and a 7'_. oz. potato before cutting, Figure IV. — Scabby Potatoes. * </seg>
            <seg id="p009">9 B. and C Comparison of a 14£» oz. Note the same number of eyes and seed potato make such seed too expensive. and a VA oz. potato after cutting, pieces. The large pieces of the big Planting. Potatoes need a great deal of water while the tubers are forming in order to develop in a pro|&gt;er manner and produce a good yield. Therefore, they should be planted early enough to have the new potatoes form daring the season when there is most moisture in the ground For this reason it is best to plant soon after the tir&gt;t of April, although some years when late rains occur late planting is lietter. Planting in Western Nebraska will necessarily be somewhat later than this. When planting is done on a large scale, machine must be ned, but for smaller fields other methods do as well. The "rural trench" sv^tem is good except where the rainfall is too great. In this method a furrow 4 to 6 inches deep is made with a common lister with the subsoil attached. The potatoes are dropi&gt;ed by hand in the bottom of the furrow and covered by harrowing or cultivating the ridges down. At first the pieces are covered only two or three inches deep. Figure VL — A. Diagram for (Jutting Potatoes for Seed. B. and C Comparison of a 1444 oz. and a 1 l A oz. ootato after </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 The ridga are gradually worked down by harrowing until the pota - toes come op. Roll enough dirt into the row each time to cover the young weeds. tuother good wav is to farrow the ground out 4 to 6 indies deep a common stirring plow, or a single shovel plow, drop the toes and cover with a cultivator. The seed must always hi - red with moist dirt. Depth of planting depends upon the condition of the soil, the ai'.iount of moisture present and the season of the year. In cold, wet or heavy soils or for very early planting, the planting must not be as deep as in warm, light, or well drained soils, or where late plant - ing is practiced. The old seed piece should be at least three inches below the surface in any kind of soil when the young potatoes begin to set. The young tubers never set below the old seed piece, but always a'x&gt;\e it. so in shallow planting as the potatoes increase in size they push through the surface of the grand and are injured by the heat of the sun. Three to four inches below the surface i&gt; about right for the heavier soils and where there is plenty of rain. Deep planting in heavy wet soils may cause the seed to rot. Farther west, where the soil is lighter and the rainfall less, four to six inches deep is letter. Knotty, irregular potatoes arc more liable to occur where too shallow planting is practiced ; and where planted too deep, potatoes are more liable to disease. Shallow planting cannot be remedied by hilling the plants except in cases of heavy rainfall. E'idth of rows and distances apart of hills in the row depend 1 the size of seed piece, the kind of soil, the water supply and the Sty of potatoes. Large pieces should be planted farther apart smaller ones. The lighter the soil and the less the moisture ent, the farther apart the plants should he Early varieties may lanted closer together than late varieties because the plants are Her and fewer potatoes are produced to each hill. Where the soil is medium, neither very light nor very heavy, or where there is plenty of rain, rows should be thirty to thirty-Mx inches apart and the hills ten to twelve inches apart in the row. In lighter soils and where the rainfall is less the rows should be thirty - six to forty-eight inches apart and the hills fifteen to twenty-four inches apart in the row. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Figur VII. — Early Potato Vine with Tubers. Note the small vine and root s vs t tni 3nfi t h t k smsii nnnit^r of ix it n 1 1 u»c \ a t Vi#» \\ 1 1 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 Nebraska Boys' Potato Clubs. V r igure VIII.— Late Potato Vine with Tubers. Note the large vine and system and the large number of potatoes. Figure VIII After the potatoes are planted the ground should be harrowed often to keep it loose on to]) and to kill any young weeds. As soon a&gt; the plants are large enough so that the rows can be followed a cultivation, seven to eight inches deep, should be given, going as close to the young plants as possible without disturbing the roots. Many of the young plants will be covered, but this will not injure them. Three or four days after this cultivation the field should be harrowed. A harrow may be used profitably until the vines are large enough to be injured by being broken down, when harrowing should cease. After this the cultivation should be done at intervals of about seven days and just deep enough to stir up the surface of the ground thoroughly. Care should be taken not to run the shovels too close to the plants after the first cultivation, increasing the dis - tance as the plants become older. Tubers must never be disturbed Cultivation. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 by the plow after they begin to form. Cultivation should be con - tinued as long as poMihte without breaking or tearing the vines. It does not injure ]x&gt;tatoes to be cultivated after blooming if the plow - ing is not deep or close to the plants. A common two-horse culti - vator is best for the first deep cultivation, after this a culti - vator with three or four small shovels on a side, or a five-shovel, one - horse Junior plow should be used. It may be necessary to use a hoe to get weeds out of the rows. Weeds rob the soil of moisture and plant food and it is a bad policy to allow them to grow in the potato Mulching. Ifulching is valuable in sections where drouth is liable, and for ving seed potatoes in dry climates. It protects the potatoes from heat of the sun, keeps the soil moist and cool and keqjs down ds. Plant the potatoes in the regular way and apply a mulch of n wheat straw three or four inches deep over the field just as potatoes are coming up. Insects and Control. Many insects feed on potatoes. The most important are Colorado Potato Beetle. Blister Beetle, Stalk Borer, and Flea Beetle. These may all be controlled by the use of Arsenate of Lead. Mix thor - oughly 3 pounds of Arsenate of Lead paste in a little water. Then make up to 50 gallons. Use 50 gallons to an acre of potatoes. Apply when the eggs of the Colorado Potato Beetle are beginning to hatch. These eggs are of a bright orange color and are fastened in clusters to the underside of the leaves. At the time these eggs are hatching the potato plants will usually be six to eight inches high. The poison solution should cover both leaves and stem of the plant in order to kill all insects. The more pressure with which the liquid is applied the better. For only a small patch a knap-sack sprayer holding four or five gallons and costing two to five dollars will an - swer the purpose. For larger patches a barrel pump on wheels or one which can be set in a spring wagon is better. These outfits com - plete cost from ten to twenty-five dollars. \Yheel power and gas engine sprayers are used for large fields. Disease and Control Erlv blight is the only disease which attacks the foliage of the ing plants in this state. This disease causes the leaves to ne spotted and to wither and roll up on the edges and tip. It is prevented but not -cured by Bordeaux Mixture, therefore the vines should be sprayed before the disease appears. </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 Xcbraska Hoys' I'olato Clubs. Eiere is a question as to whether early blight causes damage gh in this state to warrant spraying with Bordeaux. Unless the ,se has proven destructive in the past spraying for insects with nate of Lead alone is recommended. 11 making Bordeau Mixture for potatoes the best formula is 5 nds of copper sulphate. 5 pounds of lime to 50 gallons of water, solve the copper sulphate. I ]»und to I gallon of water, by &gt;us - iing it in a clean sack at the lop of a barrel so that it is just cov- I by the water. In another barrel slack quick lime, adding water le rate of I gallon to 1 pound of lime. When ready to make the ture two more barrels are necessary. Into one put 5 gallons of &gt;er sulphate solution and add 20 gallons of water. Into the T put 5 gallons of lime solution and add 20 gallons of water two solutions are then poured together into the barrel contain - the spray pump. If one desires to mix only a small quantity the e proportions may be used in smaller quantities. K&lt;&gt; spray for both insects and Early blight use Bordeaux made in regular way and add 3 pounds of arsenate of lead, being sure lix it thoroughly in a little water before putting it into the Bor - ix mixture. Commercial lime and sulphur should never be used on potatoes. Large growers use the potato digger to harvest the crop. Smaller fields are usually harvested by throwing the potatoes out with a plow. It is best in a small plat, especially where grown for contests, to dig the potatoes with a potato fork or spade to avoid injuring the tubers. Harvesting. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Xebraska Bovs' Potato Clubs. 15 Storing. Potatoes intended for seed should be dug as soon as ripe, placed in small piles on clean straw and covered with two or three feet of straw. A lward cover above this to shed rain is good. Just before the ground freezes in winter, a pit should be dug one to two feet deep covered on the bottom with 12 inches of straw and the potatoes placed in a long pile on the straw ; then covered with 10 to 12 inches of straw and 4 to 6 inches of dirt. After the dirt freezes 2 to 3 inches deep, cover with more straw and 3 to 6 inches of dirt, or with manure. A vent should be left in the top for ventilation. In tln&gt; way potatoes keep well without sprouting until planting time. Potatoes mav be stored in the cellar if it is cool and dry. The cellar may be light if the potatoes are for seed, but if for table use should be kept in the dark. Cellars must be ventilated and kept cool. Potatoes for table use may be stored in pits, but they are left in the ground until fall, then dug and buried just before freezing weather sets in. Selecting Potatoes for Exhibition. Make a large selection first, then choose from this number those wanted for exhibition. Become familiar with the score card and select each potato with these different |*&gt;ints in mind. Score Card iok Potatoes. Variety Value Score Uniformity of Exhibit 20 Trueness to Type 10 Shape of Tuber 15 Size of Tuber 15 Eyes 5 j Texture of Tuber 5 Soundness 1° Freedom from Blemishes 15 — Total 100 Contestant's Name- </seg>
            <seg id="p016">16 ■niformity of Exhibit : — Potatoes must be uniform in size, color shape, and have well defined eyes of the same depth. Irueness to Type: — Each potato should be typical of the variety rhtcfa it belongs, i. c. the characteristics should be clearly de - 1. enabling one to easily identify it. Shape of Tuber: — The shape of the potato will depend largely ui*jn the variety, but the round or oval shape is preferred. I yes: — The eyes of the jwtato should be medium deep, well de - 1 and not too numerous. Deep eyes cause waste in peeling. How eyes are low in vitality and too many eyes denote pa &gt;r stock. Kin: — The skin may be whitish, brown, radish, yellowish brown, nr black, depending on variety. It may be thick or thin, tough ittle. A thick, fairly tough skin is preferred, lenticels not too inent or potatoes sunburned. Bexture of Tuber: — This is determined by cutting the potato, lirly tine grained, brittle texture is preferred A tough texture I not cook op mealy and is usually poor in flavor. I mildness :— Select potatoes that are sound and lirm. not wrinkled flabby. Hollow potatoes are objectionable, likewise any internal iloration indicating a diseased condition. The judge should cut ! potatoes in each exhibit. Rreednm from Blemishes:— The judge will deduct from score for i s]xns. or skin ruptures from any other diseases, cuts, bruises, tches or other defects. Packing for Shipment. As loon as the selection is made each potato should be wrapped in r. placed in a box lined with several thicknesses of newspaper , , . . . Explanation of Scokk Carp. </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>