<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00015.00027">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00015.00027</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA.  BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA.  DESTROYING PRAIRIE DOGS.</title>
               <date value="1904">1904</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">BULLETIN No. 86 The University op Nebraska. BULLETIN OF THE AGRICULTURAL EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA Volume XVII, Article II. DESTROYING PRAIRIE DOGS. By A. T. Peters aot&gt; S. Avert. Distributed Octobbr 15, 1901. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">AORICILTLRU EXPERIMENT STATION OF NEBRASKA THE GOVERNING BOARD ITHI HIOINT* Or TH. UMIVIM.Tf) JOHN L. TEETERS, President, Lincoln EDSON P. RICH, Omiha ELISHA C. CALKINS, Kearney CARL J. ERNST, Omaha CHAS. S. ALLEN, Lincoln WM. G. WHITMORE, Valley THE STATION OFFICERS (A. BURNETT, B. Sc, Director and A limal Husbandman L. LYON, Ph. D , Associate Director and Agriculturist S. DALES, M. Ph., Fnantial Secretary WM. W. MARSHALL, Executive Clerk THE WORKING STAFF H. R. Smith, B. Sc., Animal Husbandman A. T. Peters, D. V. M., Anitnal Path &gt;,'jgisl Charles E. Bessey, Ph. D., Botanist S. Avery, Ph. D., Chemist A. L. Haecker, B. Sc. A., Dairy Husbandman Lawrence Bruner, B. Sc, Entomologist Erwin H. Barbour, Ph. D., Geologist R. A. Emerson, B. Sc., Hort culturist O. V. P. Stout, C. E., Iirigation Engineer G. D. Swezey, M. A., Meteorologist J. H. Gain, M. D. C, Ass dale Animal Pathologist W. P. Snydhr, M. S., Superintendent Experimental Substation North Plate S. W. Peri.n, Farm Fort man </seg>
            <seg id="p003">BY A. T. PE : D 8. AVERY. The prairie dog of the Plains is too well known to B readers to require an extended description. It is of eoone in no way related to the dog family, but is a rodent bearing the scientific name of Ci/noinyx htdootOMHHU. A full scription of the animal and his habits from the pen of Dr. C. Hart IferrUun can be found in the Yearbook of the 1&gt;&gt; partmeut of Agriculture for 1901. Proa time to time the Station lias received requests for advice as to the best method of handling the prairie pest. In response to the numerous inquiries, field experi - ments were undertaken in 1!M)&lt;&gt; and a Press Bulletin on the Extermination of Prairie Dogs was issued on July 17 of that year. Largely owing to the indifference of nonresident land owners and the destruction of the dog's natural &lt; the trouble has grown to a marked degree. The immediate occasion of the present work was the passage of an act by the last session of the legislature introduced by the Hon. W. C. Brown of Keya Palia county, the text of which i follows : "Prairie Dogs "593. Sec. 62. ( Prairie dogs, nuisances. ) That the pres - ejice of prairie dogs upon lands in Nebraska is hereby de - clared" to be a common nuisance, on and after July 1st, 1903, and the owner of lands whereon such nuisances thereafter BOLL. 86, AGR. KXP. STATION OF NKBR. VOL. XVII, ART II. INTRODUCTION. I'UUPOSi: OF THIS INVESTIGATION. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Destroying Prairie Dogs. shall infest or occupy is hereby declared to be a maintainer of such nuisance, after such date. (1903, S. F. 69, 1). "Sees. 62-65. 'An act declaring prairie dogs to be a nui - sance, and to provide for their destruction as such; ami making the harborer thereof liable for the legitimate penses of their destruction.' Laws, 1903, S. F. 69. In effect July 9, 1903. i'594. Sec. 63. (Extermination.) It is hereby made the perative duty of any land owner to totally exterminate ;h prairie dogs upon any lands owned by him by Novem - ■ the 1st, 1903, and if not done on or before that date it is •eby made the duty of the overseer of highways of the &lt;lis ct wherein such land is situated, and which is occupied infested by such prairie dogs, to proceed forthwith at any 'e after November 1st, lito.'i, when notified by any person when he shall discover that any lands are infested or in - lited or occupied by prairie dogs, to destroy such animals the most expeditious manner appropriate for such pur- &gt;!*5. Sec. 64. (Overseer of highways — Duties.* Said overseer shall be paid for such services in the carrying out of the provisions of this act at the rate of 93.66 per da,\ gether with all expenses necessarily incurred by him for poison or other suitable material and apparatus for sucli purposes used. He shall keep a correct itemized statement of his fees and expenses for such services performed on each r of land, and by September 1st, 15)04, of each year thereafter, certify under oath the expense incurred and vices rendered upon each tract of land to the county clerk of the county wherein such lands are situated. "596. Sec. 65. (Taxes.) The county clerk of said county shall enter the sum so certified by said overseer against the land upon which such expenses were incurred and services rendered, and enter the same upon the tax list of said coanty, which sum shall be collected by the county treasurer as other taxes, and the said sum shall be a lien upon said </seg>
            <seg id="p005">Destroying Prairie Dogs. 8 land on and after the delivery of said tax list to said treas - urer the same as other taxes." POISONING OF PRAIRIE DOGS. E'he following paragraphs are taken from the Press Bul - n just referred to: "Few persons realize the amount of damage done by prai - rie dogs, and hence no organized force has been exerted against them. The damage done by these little pests con - sists in killing out the grass, which they do very extensiv and as that part of the country in which they exist is al - rt entirely used for grazing purposes, it is necessary that land be saved against their ravap "The treatment that has proven ni&lt; live is the of strychnine and potassium cyanide. The formula is as follows : "Dissolve three ounces of strychnine and one-half pound of potassium cyanide in one quart of boiling water; then add to quarts of molasses and one teaspoonful of oil of ai ir. Then place one bushel of wheat in a tight r» (so there will be no loss from leakage) and pour the : going solution over it. It should then be well stirred while an assistant slowly sprinkles into the mixture four pounds of finely ground corn meal. The molasses renders the liquid adhesive, so that it will fling to the grains of wheat. The object of using the corn meal is to absorb the superfluous liquid or syrup and thus enable the grains of wheat to carry a larger amount of poison." Dr. Merriam in the article just referred to suggests I less poison may be used successfully, and Bulletin No. lltf of the Kansas Station presents the modified formula as fol - lows: "Strychnine Poison. Formula No. 1. — Dissolve one and one-half ounces of strychnia sulphate in a quart of hot wa - ter. Add a quart of syrup — molasses, sorghum, or thick sugar and watei* — and a teaspoonful of oil of anise. Thor - ont?hlv heit and mix the liouid hot Dour it over a </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 rel of clean wheat and mix completely. Then stir in or more pounds of fine corn-meal. The quantity of corn-meal will depend upon the amount of extra moisture lent. There should be enough to wet (very grain of the wheat and no more. Care should be taken that there is no leakage from the vessel in which the wheat is mixed. Let the poisosed grain stand over night, and distribute it in the early morning of a bright day. Ise a tablespoonful of the wheat to each hole occupied by prairie iloiis, putting it near the mouth of the burrow in two or three little bunches. Do not put out the poison in very cold or stormy weather. It will keep for a considerable time, and is much more ef - fective after a cold period, as the animals are then hungry and eat the grain readily. A bushel of wheat should jMiison 1,000 to 1,200 holes. An excellent substitute for the oil of anise in the above formula can be made by soaking two ounces of green coffee berries in the whites of thn Let this stand for about twelve hours and use the liquid instead of anise oil." IThe following extract taken from the Nebraska Press Rul - :in No. 13 shows the methods of application and the re - sults obtained : S "First, in preparing the poison great care should l&gt;e taken at the exact proportions are used ; that the poison is coin pletely dissolved; that no more water and syrup are use&lt;l than the recipe calls for, as one bushel of wheat will not take up and carry more than this amount of liquid. After the liquid has been poured into the wheat the whole should ■e well stirred until all of the wheat has come in contact with the syrup and the poison is equally distributed through the whole mass. It should be used the same day that it is prepared, in order to obtain the best results. The way u&lt; apply this is to take some of the poisoned wheat in a tin pail and sprinkle about a tablespoonful of it in and around each hole. Do not leave it in lumps or bunches, as cattle or other k might possibly eat it, although our experience showed that the danger from this is not great, as cattle were all </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Destroying Prairie Dogs. 7 to range over the towns that were being thus treated, and none were injured. It is best to take a strip about two rods wide, set stakes at convenient intervals to avoid going over the same ground twice and also avoid missing any of the holes. Where there is more than one person operating, the stakes may l&gt;e set to indicate the ground that is being gone r, the operators keeping about two rods apart and chang - „ the stakes over to the outside as the person next to the poisoned ground comes to them. The best time to comm - operations is during a period of warm, clear weather in the winter. The advantage of operating during the winter is that the grass and roots upon which they feed are dead and frozen, and hunger compels them to eat more freely of the poisoned wheat. The poison mi to do its work within forty-eight hours. In about a week or ten days the town should be gone over a second time, as there will be, of course, some dogs left, of which about fifty per cent will usually be killed by the second application. During the mating season in the spring the remaining dogs will con - gregate, and then as soon as the young ones begin to appear above ground the poison can again be distributed." The Kansas Bulletin No. 116 gives equally gratifying re - sults from using the modified formula. The cyanide of pot - ash in the original formula has a tendency to precipitate out the strychnine. In the modified formula the poison all remains in solution. OBJFCTIONS TO POISON. Most farmers and ranchmen dislike to handle poison for obvious reasons. Not only is there a personal nervousness connected with handling deadly poisons but the danger of poisoning children, live stock, and especially birds, is al - ways present. For cleaning out small towns, fumigation with carbon bi - sulphide is still the favorite method in spite of the cost and labor. Finally in most towns a certain number of animals not be induced to eat poisoned food, so that a complete </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Destroying Prairie Dogs. rmination with poison alone is very difficult. In view of these facts a number of laboratory tests were made in order to show the effects of certain fumes and gases on ani - mal life. LABORATORY TESTS IN FUMIGATION Pised instead of prairie dogs, which could not be con - ly obtained at this station, pocket gophers which had ptured in steel traps. It is to be assumed that these i would be affected by gases in just about the same prairie dogs. Animal No. 1 was placed in a 10-quart bottle and \ ounce of calcium carbide added. Sufficient water was poured in to decompose the carbide, generating acetylene The bottle KB then closed. After one hour the animal, although in tress, was still active. Mimal No. 2 was treated in the same way as No. 1, ex - that about i a teaspoonful of carbon bisulphide wu I instead of the acetylene. The bottle was closed with a stopper h before. The animal became unconscious almost instantly and death followed in about twenty mini Other animals showed more resistance and in some O death would not occur for over an hour. Animal No. 3 was treated as above, except that water containing: hydrogen sulphide gas was used. The animal died almost instantly. We estimate that this gas is at teas! twenty times as effective as an equal weight of carbon bi - sulphide. If a cheap and safe method for generating and applying this gas were ai hand, it would be an ideal agent. Animal No. 4 was treated exactly as No. 2, except that a light hydrocarlnm oil was used. This substance is obtained as a by-product at the Pintsch gas works. It will be de - scribed later. The results were about the same as with car - bon bisulphide, except that the animal remained longer in an unconscious condition before expiring. The animal be - came unconscious in a short time and its death seemed to be onlv a matter of time. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">Destroying Prairie Dogs. 9 a\ II 1 III &lt;l 1 JM O. O yi «8 lP^fl.W?d GX3.CT1 V flS O. 4» OXCCOl IDflt the hydrocarbon used was a by-product obtained at the Omaha Gas Works. The results were exactly the same as 4. except that the animal did not become unconscious quite so quickly and expired more quickly after becoming uu. NATURE OF THE PINTSCH GAS HYDROCARBON. E substance is a by-product formed in the condensa- Pintsch gas. When the gas is compressed to fill the m i cylinder of the railroad -. 1/10 of the entire quantity liquifies. This liquid is useless for illtunina purposes. As it is a constant product of the Pint factories, we may assume that it will be abundant as long as these factories operate. Chemically it consists of benzene (benzol C B H 6 ) saturated with volatile gases and inixed with heavier hydrocarbons. Its vapors are heavy and readily Kit rate into the recesses of the holes. It doe* not seem &gt;e absorbed as readily by the soil as carbon bisulphide. : URE OF THE HYDROCARBON OBTAINED FROM OOAL • This substance is very similar to the Piutsch hydro lion, except that it is less volatile and contains some nap - thaline in solution. This is the well-known substai in moth balls. FIELD EXPERIMENTS WITH PINT8CH HYDROCARBON. In September, 1903, the writers experimented on the farm of Hon. W. C. Brown, using both the Pintsch hydrocarbon and carbon bisulphide. The method of application was that usually followed in applying the sulphide. A piece of drv horse or cow chip sufficient to absorb about 2 teaspoonfuls of the liquid was used. After saturating with the liquid it was pushed down the hole as far as possible with a stick. the opening of the hole tightly closed with the sod. As the hydrocarbon oil is very cheap, rather more than that amount is to be recommended. The greater number of the holes </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Destroying Prairie Dogs. we treated ran for about 4 feet at an angle of 46° and then changed to a vertical direction. It is desirable to push ihe chip until it falls to the bottom of the hole, although this is not possible in all cases. Particular care should be i?n not to allow dirt to rattle down the hole so as to cover chip and absorb the vapors. Three holes were dug out Springview and a dead dog found in each instance. No erence could be observed in the part of the field treated k l'intsch hydrocarbon and the part where carbon bisul - phide was used. Certain observations, however, lead us to believe that a successful test can be made only by constantly king at a dog town until all holes in it have been treated. HOW TO KXTKUMINATJS AN ENTIRE TOWN BY FUMIGATION. It seems to be commonly assumed that a town may be ally exterminated by working at it at odd times just as one might try to eradicate a field of noxious weeds. Such, however, is not the case. If only part of the town is treated, the Hogs from the remaining portion will open up many of the treated holes. Owls, as also gophers, may open up holes. After a few weeks one sees, on going over the treated part, a number of live dogs and many open holes. Hence, hi siimes that the treatment has been a failure. To make a tugh test, go over the land every few days for two weeks, ng all opened holes. RESULTS WITH MARKED HOLES. In the various towns where we have worked, it has been our custom to mark holes that we have seen the dogs enter. After treating them with a liberal supply of hydrocarbon have covered these holes with a pyramid of sod suffi - tly large to discourage dogs from attempting to dig in from the outside. Out of some fifty holes so marked not has been found open, even after several weeks had uipseu. </seg>
            <seg id="p011">11 Through the courteaj of the Omaha &lt;las Works, several barrda of this product were placed at our (! lent results were obtained at the North IMatte Exj)eriinental Substation and at M»M&gt;k. Nebr. Its tost is somewhat less than the Pintseh product, and it MOM to be a little more efficient in its action. We were able to notice no difference between the results obtained by the two hydro - carbons. REPORTS FROM THE FIELDS WHEN PINTSCH HYMt" •&lt;&gt;n Monday, the 20th, I got enough help to go over the entire town of twenty i Then I worked it all over &gt; day for six days following. The seventh day I did not find any sijjns of work on the part of the dogs. Then I did not look at the field for three days, when I found three pi that had been worked by the pest. All of the opened up holes were treated and I have not seen any sijnis of since. M. I). Tbusskll, Purdum. Nebr If. I). TurssEU.. Purdum, Nebr." E think everything is favorable in dog town. Of course id a few doga every day or so on treated grand, but I , in almost every case, find holes that were missed in tment. (April 2 "The prairie doga are, I believe, done for on the Harper ranch. I have not seen any for several days. However, the fore part of last week I found a few holes opea and promptly closed them. I have pot six dogs since you left. (June 19.) "It is with pleasure that I write to definitely inform that I have not a prairie dog on my ranch. (July 5.) UEI'OKTS FROM FIELDS WHEN COAL CAS HYDUIX'ARBON Pie dogs have nearly all passed into the beyond. A few out occasionallv. I found four live boles this morning •J. \V. FIakper, Thedfonl, N&gt;br." </seg>
            <seg id="p012">12 and immediately used t fie hydrocarbon. A little care will "W. P. Bntder, North Platte. Nebr." I have seen but very few live dogs since the find appli - »n of th. Quite a number «»f holes have Ikm-h opened from the outside in almost every instance. I think one holes in a half a day. Almost every time I ted a bunch of opened holes, I found an untreated hole in th" near vicinity. This led me to believe that the opened holes were nearly always the work of a dog who had D K doctored.' I believe ninety-five per cent would be a vative estimate of the number of treated holes which ■ 1 successfully the first time. "Ralph H. Seable, North Platte, Nebr." ION IN HEGAKI&gt; TO THE USE OF THE HYDKOCAUBONS. isoline and the petroleum benzine are not effective. "Tar drips" and heavy oils of any sort have given unsatis - results. Any hydrocarbon to Ik* effective must readily vaporise and not leave behind more than a small quan - tity of solid or liquid residue. Only the Pintacb hydrocar - boo and the one furnished by the Omaha (las Works have n found to be effective. Although letters were written to tically all the other gas works in the State, none of them •i-d us a similar product for experimentation. We have not investigated by-products of coal gas works outside of the State. They are not poisonous in the ordinary sense of the word. The same precaution should be used in handling them as in isoline. They take fire less easily than carbon Iphide and are less explosive when their fumes are mixed with air. If the same precautions are observed which one would use in handling gasoline, there is no danger co&amp;ni with their use. </seg>
            <seg id="p013">13 Destroying Prairie Dogs. .THE COMPARATIVE COST OF POISON AND FUMIGATION. The cost will depend, of course, upon various conditions. such as freight rates, price of labor, and especiallj the num - ber of holes per acre. The number varies from about 2" 125. Carbon bisulphide is estimated to cost about 1 i per hole. Calculating either of the hydrocarbons at 1 Hi the cost per gallon of the bisulphide and allowing for the use of double the quantity, tip \onld be at the rat. Pt a cent per hole. The poisOB has ben vari - estimated at from 2 to 20 cents per acre, according to tlie number of holes and t he amount of grain scattered about each hole. The Pintach hydrocarbon can be obtained at many Sthe Western Pintsch Gaa Works at tin I "&gt; cents jkt lion in tank car lots or at the rate of 10 cents per gallon in small quantities. The company, however, requires the purchaser to provide container and paj cartage. The Coun- cil Bluffs Pintsch Qaa Works will furnish the hydrocarbon on these terms. The Denver Pintsch Qaa Works disposes of their entire product through the Denver &lt;;;is Oompi This company will furnish the Pintach hydrocarbon at the S rates. It will also provide barrels and pay for cart - •livering the filled barrels to any freight depot in Den the rate of 12 cents per gallon in barrel lots or 26 per gallon in tin cans. It is possible also thai Pintsch hvdrocarbon could Im&gt; secured from the factories at Tcxarkana, Khivve]&gt;ort, El Paso. San Antonio, Ft. Worth, and Houston. The Omaha (his Company will furnish the coal gas hydrocarbon, including cartage and container's, f. A sample of "Fume," a preparation of carbon bisulphid manufactured by Edward Taylor, of Penn Yan, N. Y., was found to contain hydrocarbon sulphid. This agent makes it . at any freight depot in Omaha, at the following rai i barrel at $2 50 1 barrel at 4 25 per barrel 5 barrels at 4 00 per barrel 10 barrels at 3 75 per barrel </seg>
            <seg id="p014">14 tot the most efficient fumigators known. If it were not the cost of this product (10 cents per pound, f. o. b. En Yan, in 50-pound drums), it would have been quite ecessary to look further for an agent to destroy dogs by igfttMHL NOTES ON THE APPLICATION OF THE HYDROCARBONS FOE II MIGATION. Iii every prairie dog town there are three classes of ho ctually occupied by the doga, (2) holes deserted by dogs but now occupied by owls, (3) holes ■•occupied ex - by ail occasional snake. It is not always easy to dis nish between these three classes. The surest but most expensive way to exterminate a town is to treat every hole, an apparently deserted hole is merely a second entrance to an occupied hole. If this is not closed, fresh air will enter and the dog will not be suffocated. Probably the onomica] way of exterminating a town by fumiga - tion is as follows: Let one man proceed in advance with a ind cover up ail apparently deserted lioles with a sod. He is to be followed by another man who inserts into each remaining hole a cow or hone chip saturated witli the hydrocarbon. The third man closes all the treated holes. Working in this way. three with a boy to run errands can i- twenty acres of an average dog town per day. After going over the field the Ant time it is comparatively the owner to drive over it each day carrying a sack of (hips, a jug of hydrocarbon, and a spade in his buggy. He ran then treat any missed or opened holes in a eompara - ly short time. COMBINATION OF POISON AND FUMIGATION. {F\&gt;r very large tracts covered by prairie dogs, it is prob - e that a combination of poison and fumigation will prove st economical. Poisoning should be done during the time year when food is scarce. After distributing the poison •e or twice, some time should be allowed to elapse. At </seg>
            <seg id="p015">15 fend of this time when unoccupied holes can be readily tinguished from those occupied by dogs, the remaining dogs can be killed by fumigation. About the only advantage in using poison at all is the saving of labor. It MOM to be kiry to resort to fumigation in the end U&gt; entirely ?rminate a town. si m mary. 1. The prairie dog in Nebraska has increased t«&gt; such an extort that sufficient jfrass is destroyed every year to keep many hundred head of stock. '2. Four years ago a very successful formula was worked out at this Station. Since that time other investigators have found that a somewhat less amount of poison is sufficient. E. Farmers and ranchmen dislike to use poison and in ay cases prefer fumigation even at a much gr&lt; se. In comparatively few cases will poison alone irely clean out the pest. 4. The writers proj&gt;ose the use of very cheap hydrocar - -. which have already been used in the complet initiation of several towns. t&gt;. Information is given why holes hfCOTOC opCBed. The \ of constant attention for a number of &lt;la\ ph a si zed. Every large towns a combination of poison and fumi - ith a hydrocarbon is suggested as the most econoni- </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>