<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00021">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00021</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>Winter Lab Feeding 1919-20, 1920-21, 1921-22</title>
               <date value="1923-10">1923-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">•*""'" &lt;•» ■■■■»•«« p«,.. </seg>
            <seg id="p002">Bulletin 197 Winter Lamb Feeding 191*10, 1920-21, 1021-22 BY W. H. UAVIN DEPARTMENT OP ANIMAL HUHBANDRY LOT. 1. FED CORN AND ALFALFA HAY For general farm practice corn and alfalfa hay »eem to be the most favorable ration available to Nebraska lamb feeders. THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXPERIMENT STATION LINCOLN F. A. BURNETT, DIRECTOR </seg>
            <seg id="p003">tl " ' ll till s • *•' : s •»«• • 1 •«»&gt;ee- i r- i •* » ■ ??:?: - ■ I J w&lt; N« - «. I ill i j ii Mi i" 1 &lt; I K IsSSSSS \s 8 sss | - - n* |1 IS U£2*ul 3 d i- I - 5 ~ Z t*a ® • ". - ?T— «• &lt;Ct~ — 3 — .a Si — «JI •* I jj I ■ ■ Jill * p J si: a §9 w sa««S£s- s c s' M n 1 1 i- £ - - _i p :n I 5 Hfjjais - n t wuU==r s c i" -: B - wu-»== 5 _5 JS • «5 ;sss - I gjjs sa—s252 s. « * ; liU Slllliii jL 1 . i I i ! lit liliii ii iji Uif'jiH i 1 s 1^ i z - </seg>
            <seg id="p004">SUMMARY I. The addition of corn silage to a shelled corn and alfalfa hay ration (Lots 1 and 2) did not increase gains but did increase cost of gains 8 1 * per cent and decreased profits. II. The addition of corn silage to a shelled corn, alfalfa molasses meal, and alfalfa hay ration (Lots 3 and 4) also reduced the gain, in - creased the cost of gain, and reduced the profit. III. The addition of corn silage to a shelled corn, linseed oil meal, and alfalfa hay ration (Lots 5 and 6) had a similar effect, the gains being less, the cost of gain greater, and the profit lower than when silage was omitted. IV. Silage did not return more than the market value of the corn grain which it contained. V. In practically every case during the 3 years, silage reduced the selling price of the lambs, indicating that finish was not commen - surate with gains when lambs received silage. VI. Adding a small amount of molasses meal to a corn and alfalfa hay ration (Lots 1 and 3) increased the gains by about 6 per cent but increased the cost of gains that the profit per head was slightly esi VII. Adding molasses meal to a corn, corn silage, and alfalfa hay ration (Lots 2 and 4) increased very slightly the gains, increased the cost of gains, and reduced the profits. VIII. Molasses meal did not improve the appetites of the lambs, failed to replace its own weight of other feeds in the ration, and did not put a better finish upon the lambs than when it was not fed. In fact, the lambs to which both molasses meal and corn silage were fed averaged a distinctly lower selling price during the 3 years than did any of the other groups. IX. Linseed oil meal added to a corn and alfalfa ration (Lots 1 and 5) increased the gains 14 per cent, increased the cost of gains nearly 8 per cent, and increased the profit per head. X. Linseed oil meal added to a corn, corn silage, and alfalfa ration (Lots 2 and 6) increased gains, cost, and profits in like manner as when no silage was fed. XI. Linseed oil meal apparently improves the value of silage, probably thru supplementing its protein deficiency. When silage is to </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 197 be fed, some protein concentrate should undoubtedly be fed in limited quantity along with it. XII. By producing rapid gains, linseed oil meal will enable a feeder to market lambs earlier than he otherwise could, but this may not always be an advantage. Had the lambs receiving no oil meal (Lot 1) been held till their weight was equivalent to that of the oil meal lambs (Lot 5) and had the market remained stable, they would have made greater profits than the lambs receiving a protein supple - ment. XIII. For general farm practice, corn and alfalfa hay seem to be the most favorable ration available to Nebraska lairb feeders. Lambs receiving this ration (Lot 1 ) in 3 trials made the most economical gains, and sold for the highest figure when marketed. Their selling price was equalled only by that of the group which received linseed oil meal (Lot 5). Economy of gains and selling price are the most important considerations, rapidity of gain being secondary since it may be offset by an additional week or two of feeding. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">Winter Lamb Feeding 1919-20, 1920-21, 1921-22 BY WILLIAM H. SAVIN Nebraska is preeminently favored in her location, climate, and crops as a feeding state. Omaha is the second greatest lamb market in the United States and the main arteries of communication between the ranges of Wyoming, Montana, Colorado, and Utah, and Omaha cross Nebraska. The crisp, dry cold of Nebraska winters favors feeding without shelter and makes work about the feed-yards relatively easy. The abundance of alfalfa hay and corn which is to be had on most Nebraska farms, and which must be marketed in some manner, makes winter livestock feeding almost a necessity. Farmers have very little choice but to adopt the feeding practice appearing most favorable for a given season. Along the Platte Valley at one time were extensive lamb - feeding plants belonging to large operators who bought up the farmers' grain and hay and fed lambs by the tens of thou - sands. But these have gradually become fewer and farm feeding of from 1 to 3 or 4 carloads has become increasingly prevalent. Thus it is the home-grown ration which is of primary interest in Nebraska lamb feeding economy. Nebraska is not a state which produces great quantities of by-product feeds. Practically all the more concentrated feeds of this class need to be shipped into the state. But there is an extensive industry within the state in the manufacture of alfalfa molasses mixtures, and considerable amounts of such feeds were fed during the recent high-price era. The silo has never acquired such a following in Nebraska as in Wisconsin and some other more eastern states, but its value as a part of the lamb feeders' equipment is a topic of some debate. All in all, the great majority of farmers use a straight ration of corn and alfalfa in lamb fattening, and in past experiments at the Nebraska station this combination has proved about as acceptable as any in the production of economical gains and final profit, but it is desirable to know how other commonly employed rations compare with it, and, if possible, to find one that will be an improvement upon it. During the 3 winters, 1919-20, 1920-21, and 1921-22, lamb feeding trials were conducted at the Nebraska Experiment Station to test the addition of certain supplementary feeds to the simple Nebraska ration of corn and alfalfa. The work </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 197 was carried on for 3 years under substantially the same con - ditions with the thought of checking the 3 years' results care - fully against each other. It was believed that agreement of results from at least 3 tests is desirable before final claims are made for a piece of work of this nature. Market values, both of feeds and of animals, have changed a great deal during the period of experimentation, but the requirements for a given amount of gain may be considered applicable to any time ; and the replacement values of the supplements in terms of corn and alfalfa (which constituted the basal ration), may be trusted, since in this regard the 3 years' tests agree quite closely. Certain differences in degrees of finish as indicated by difference in selling price may also be considered to have significance. OBJECTS OF EXPERIMENTS LThe objects of these experiments — or they may be con - ;red as one experiment — were to reach a definite conclusion regarding the value of adding corn silage to a corn and alfalfa ration, either alone or in conjunction with a limited amount of molasses meal or of linseed oil meal ; to study the value of adding a 50-50 mixture of alfalfa and cane molasses (later referred to as molasses meal) to a corn and alfalfa hay ration or to a corn, corn silage, and alfalfa hay ration ; to study further the advisability of supplementing a corn and alfalfa ration with linseed oil meal in a limited quantity ; and to study the value of adding linseed oil meal to a corn, corn silage, and alfalfa ration. DURATION OF TESTS The first of these tests ran from October 21, 1919, to January 27, 1920, a period of 98 days; the second, from No - vember 19, 1920, to March 1, 1921, a period of 112 days; the third, from December 20, 1921, to March 22, 1922, a period of 92 days. The 3 periods averaged 100 2 3 days, during which time a gain of approximately 35 pounds per head was put on the lambs. During the second trial the weather was quite warm so that the lambs took less feed per day and gained less rapidly than was the case in the other 2 tests. ANIMALS USED The lambs used in this series of tests were rather light, this being partly due to the fact that the summer of 1919 </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 was very dry on the range, and lambs weighing from 55 to 60 pounds were scarce at the market. After having con - ducted the first test with light lambs, it was deemed advisable to continue with that kind. Fifty-one-pound lambs were bought the first year, 52-pound lambs the second, and 56 - pound lambs the third. The third year it was difficult to get lambs of the best quality weighing less than 56 pounds, as there had been a good summer on the range and all lambs coming to market that fall were heavy. The lambs used thruout this work were very uniform in quality and in breeding, as indicated by a predominance of the fine wool type. Merino blood was strong in all the lambs, altho none of them were wrinkly necked. Fully half of them had gray or spotted noses. The lambs were of the "choice feeder" grade and cost the top of the market in Omaha the days purchased. Spread in weight was relatively slight, as more lambs than were needed were purchased each year in order to eliminate a few of the heaviest and lightest lambs. The lambs used in 1919-20 and 1921-22 came from Wyoming ranches, while those used in 1920-21 were of Idaho origin. The lambs purchased September 27, 1919, cost $11.45 per hundredweight. They were run on bluegrass pasture at a charge of 1 cent per head daily until October 21, when the experiment began. During this time they just about held their weight. When the experiment started, this pasture charge, plus freight, commission, and shipping expense, had increased the cost of the lambs to $12.40 per hundredweight. The lambs purchased October 22, 1920, cost $12 per hundred - weight. They were fed alfalfa hay in dry lot until November 9, at which time their cost per hundredweight was $12.30, which was considered their cost into the experiment. The lambs purchased on December 15, 1921. cost $9.50 per hun - dredweight in Omaha. Their cost into the experiment 5 days later was $9.95 per hundredweight. EQUIPMENT The experimental feeding plant in which these experi - ments were conducted consisted of an open shed 20 feet deep, divided into 10-foot sections opening into small, open yards on the south. The first year these yards were but 35 feet long, but before the second test was begun they were extended another 16 feet, so that there were approximately 500 square feet of yard space and 200 square feet of shed room for the 30 lambs in each lot. The grain and silage were fed in open </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 bunks in the yards, while the hay was fed under cover. Water and salt were available for the lambs at all times. EXPERIMENTAL ROUTINE Weights. — The lambs were weighed individually on 3 consecutive days at the beginning and again at the close of the experiment, an average of these 3 weights being taken as the initial and final weights respectively. The lambs were also weighed in groups at the end of each 28-day period to ascertain the progress they were making. Feeding. — The lambs were fed grain at 7 a. m. and at 4 p. m. and hay immediately after the grain was cleaned up. In the lots receiving silage, the silage was first put in the bunks and the grain poured over it. Silage and grain were fed in amounts which the lambs would clean up within half an hour after feeding. Hay was kept before the lambs at all times but the amount was so regulated that there was very little "weighback." Lambs Dying During Trial. — During the first experi - ment 7 lambs were lost, in the second 2, and in the third only 1. Note was made when these lambs went off feed and their weight was taken at that time. Whatever gain they had made was credited to the gains of their respective lots and the number of days they were in the experiment was counted in the total number of "lamb days" of their group. In order to follow out this method it was necessary to figure the number of lamb days of each lot separately. The average daily gain was obtained by dividing the lamb days of each lot into the total gain made by that lot ( including the gains that had been made by the lambs which died). The average daily gain when multiplied by the number of days of the experiment gave the gain per lamb during the trial. RATIONS FED The rations fed in this trial were as follows: Lot I. Shelled corn and alfalfa hay. Lot II. Shelled corn, corn silage, and alfalfa hay. Lot III. Shelled corn, molasses meal, and alfalfa hay. Lot IV. Shelled corn, molasses meal, corn silage, and alfalfa hay. Lot V. Shelled corn, linseed oil meal, and alfalfa hay. Lot VI. Shelled corn, linseed oil meal, silage, and al- falfa hay. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">9 From the start the lambs were given all the alfalfa hay and corn silage which they would consume. The molasses meal and linseed oil meal were fed in amounts approximating 1/7 of a pound per head daily at the beginning and continued in that amount thruout the period. The shelled corn was started at about 1 6 pound per head daily and gradually in - creased as the lambs would take it, so that they were on full feed in from 4 to 5 weeks. FEEDS AND FEED PRICES The corn and alfalfa hay used were purchased locally and were of good quality. Care was taken to use alfalfa hay of about the same quality as is available to most lamb feeders, this being mostly first or second cutting hay. The corn silage during the 3 trials was quite uniform in quality, having been made each year from corn which would have yielded about 6 1 •_) or 7 tons of silage per acre including 35 to 40 bushels of grain. The corn was relatively ripe when ensiled, and water was added in the silo. All the silage came out very sweet and seemed always to be palatable to the lambs. The linseed oil meal was "old process" pea size. The molasses meal was made of 50 per cent cane molasses mixed with an equal weight of standard grade alfalfa hay. During the trial it was noted that the molasses had not been altogether uniformly mixed with the alfalfa, some sacks being much stickier than others. The lambs did not especially relish the molasses meal at any time. Altho the amount of it fed with the shelled corn at each feed was small, the corn was usually picked out before the molasses meal was cleaned up. The chemical analyses of the feeds used are given below : Table 2. — Analyses of feeds used Feed I I Moisture Ash Crude Crude protein fibre N. free extract Ether extract Percent [Per cent Per cent j Per cent Percent Per cent Ihelled corn tlolasses meal ... linseed oil meal rorn silage Llfalfa hay 12.82 18.64 8.03 71.38 . 6.49 1.31 9.67 | 2.41 7.64 9.03 16.92 5.43 36.21 10.48 1.86 2.47 7.19 7.89 13.83 34.28 70.16 47.02 33.98 16.36 35.59 3.64 .86 5.88 .75 1.94 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">PRICES OF FEEDS The cost of feeds and consequently the cost of gains dur - ing this 3-year period underwent violent fluctuations. The financial statement for any given year is therefore of little value at the present time. The feed requirements for a given amount of gain may be considered reliable, however, for any time, and by applying current feed prices the results of these trials may be applied to any year. The actual prices paid were as follows : RESULTS OF THE THREE YEARS' EXPERIMENT Results of 3 trials will be considered here as 1 trial with 90 lambs per lot and extending thru a feeding period of 100 2/3 days. Tables may be found at the end of this bulletin giving the figures in detail for all 3 experiments. SILAGE IN THE RATION Various opinions regarding the value of silage in lamb feeding are held by farmers. Silage is not as commonly in - cluded in fattening rations in Nebraska as in some more east - ern states; but because of the role which the silo can play during dry years when the crop of grain is short, some in - quiries are received at the Nebraska Station regarding silage for lambs. Whenever silage has been fed to lambs at other stations, the best results have been obtained thru inclusion of a protein concentrate. It was expected that this would prove true in this experiment, so the real point of this phase of the investigation was to ascertain what the addition of corn silage plus a protein supplement would contribute to the economy or efficiency of the corn and alfalfa fed. Other experiment stations have not been altogether in agreement upon the question of adding corn silage unsupple - mented to a corn and alfalfa hay ration. Previous work at &gt;. — I ee&lt; pnc€s Feed 1919-20 1920-21 1921-22 leUed corn ftr bu. oUsses meal per km inaeed oil meal per ton orn silage per ion Ifalfa hay ftr Urn I 1.40 40.00 80.00 10.00 25.00 $ .42 30.00 50.00 6.00 10.00 i </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 the Nebraska Station, however, has tended to favor the corn and alfalfa ration rather than the corn, corn silage, and alfalfa ration. The present 3 years' work bears out conclusively the former Nebraska results. From Table 4 it will be noted that altho the average daily gains made in Lots 1 and 2 were relatively close, a small dif - ference is in favor of Lot 1 which received no silage. For the entire 100-day feeding period, the total difference amounted to 1.6 pounds per head in favor of the standard ration. Table 4. — Does it pay to add corn silage to a corn and alfalfa ration? The true test of the value of a feed when added to the standard ration, however, is its replacement value in terms of the feeds which make up the standard ration. The table shows that practically 1 pound of silage was consumed per lamb daily, this amount causing a reduction of about 0.14 pound of corn and 0.2 pound of alfalfa in the daily consump- dumber of lambs per lot 90 Corn Alfalfa Corn ax \erage initial WEIGHT per head lbs. .VERAGE FINAL WEIGHT per head .Ibt. verage gain per head lbs. verage daily gain per head Ib. 53.64 88.07 34.23 .340 53.26 86.02 VERAGE DAILY RATION lbs. per head Shelled com Corn silage Alfalfa hay 1.29 .99 1.15 .99 .79 Feed required per 100 lbs. gain lbs. Shelled corn Corn silage Alfalfa hay 378.04 355.65 304.49 242.43 291.65 100 LBS. SILAGE REPLACED Shelled corn Alfalfa hay U*. At. JSi Feed coot of 100 lbs. gain . $7.01 $7.62 Selling price per act. $15.35 115.18 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 197 tion of these feeds. To produce 100 pounds of gain on the lambs in Lot 2, 304 pounds of corn silage were fed in addition to all the shelled corn and alfalfa hay which the lambs would consume. They naturally consumed less corn and alfalfa than where no silage was fed, but this difference was less than might have been expected. In production of gain, 100 pounds of corn silage replaced 7.35 pounds of shelled corn and 16.16 pounds of alfalfa hay, or 1 ton of silage replaced a little better than 2 x /g bushels of corn and practically 1/6 of a ton of hay. By applying any given market prices to the corn and alfalfa, it will be possible to estimate about what should be the value of corn silage when fed to lambs under the conditions of this experiment. At the price charged, silage was unable to make as cheap gains as its equivalent in the standard feeds. Table 4 shows, also, that the lambs which received the standard ration out - sold the silage-fed lambs on the market. The difference amounted to only about 1 per cent, however, and it is possible that the finish on the silage lambs might have been improved to equal that on the check lot if they had been fed a week longer. — •&gt;— • , In Lots 3 and 5 small amounts of molasses meal and lin - seed oil meal respectively were added to the basal ration. In Lots 4 and 6 similar amounts of these concentrates were added, and all the corn silage which the lambs would eat was fed in addition. This amounted to about 1 pound of silage per head daily. In comparing the gains in Lots 3 and 4 it will be noted that the addition of corn silage to the ration apparently re - duced the gains. This reduction is slight, but it Is significant that the average daily gain in Lot 4 was less each year than the gain made in Lot 3. The average of the 3 years' work shows a total gain for the 100-day period of nearly 2 1 ■&gt; pounds in favor of the no-silage lot. The replacement value of corn silage when added to a corn, molasses meal, and alfalfa hay ration is no greater than when added to a corn and alfalfa ration. One hundred pounds of silage fed in Lot 4 replaced 9 pounds of corn which is slightly more than a like amount of silage re - placed in Lot 2, but only 13Vfe pounds of hay which is less than in Lot 2. Besides this, more molasses meal was required for a given gain when silage was fed. A ton of silage replaced nearly 3V4 bushels of corn and 272 pounds of alfalfa hay, but from this must be subtracted 18 pounds of molasses meal. This charge of molasses meal against the silage is occasioned by the fact that, altho the same amounts of molasses meal were </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 fed in Lots 3 and 4, the gains produced where silage was added were less than those where it was omitted. Comparison of Lots 5 and 6 demonstrates again a reduc - tion in gains, possibly due to the addition of corn silage to the ration. The lambs in Lot 5, which received corn, linseed oil meal, and alfalfa hay gained approximately 2 1/3 pounds more during the 100-day period than did those in Lot 6, to which corn, linseed oil meal, alfalfa, and corn silage were fed. Table 5. — Does it pay to add corn silage to a ration of corn and alfalfa hay supplemented by a limited amount of molasses meal or linseed oil meal? per art. $15.22 $15.07 | $15.35 $15.30 Selling price Lot 3 Lot 4 Lot 5 Lot 6 lumber of lambs per lot 90 90 90 90 90 Corn Corn Corn Mol. Meal! Corn L.O.M. Mol. Meal Silage L.O.M. Silage Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa \ Alfalfa Corn M Corn Corn Meal, Corn L.O.M. ■ ■ = .iol. Meal Alfalfa j Silage 'L.O.M. Silage Alfalfa ; Alfalfa j Alfalfa .VERAGE INITIAL WEIGHT per head Ibt. .VERAGE FINAL WEIGHT per head lbs. verage gain per head Ibt. .verage daily gain per head Ib. 63.61 89.97 36.34 .361 53.34 53.70 53.52 87.29 92.86 90.52 33.93 38.96 36.64 .337 .387 .364 .VERAGE DAILY RATION, lbs. per head Shelled corn Molasses meal Linseed oil meal Corn silage Alfalfa hay 1.31 .15 .99 1.13 .15 1.66 .79 1.35 .14 .97 1.16 .14 " 1.04 .74 Feed required per 100 lbs. gain a*. Shelled corn Molasses meal Linseed oil meal Com silage Alfalfa hay 361.65 41.76 274.48 334.40 44.48 297.35 234.04 348.54 318.93 36.68 ! 38.44 285.38 j 251.55 { 203.66 100 LBS. SILAGE REPLACED Shelled corn Supplement . Alfalfa ...m». .. ....As. .. lbs. 9.16 .91 13.60 10.38 .62 16.78 Feed cost of 100 lbs. gain $7.40 $7.94 $7.55 $7.96 </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 In Lot 6, about 1 pound of corn silage was eaten per head daily in addition to a full feed of corn and alfalfa hay, and the limited feed of linseed oil meal allowed. This 1 pound of silage reduced the consumption of corn about 0.2 of a pound and the consumption of alfalfa hay by a similar amount. When fed in conjunction with oil meal, corn silage showed its greatest replacement value. One hundred pounds of silage replaced 10.38 pounds of corn and 16.78 pounds of silage, at an expense of 0.62 pound of linseed oil meal. Putting it an - other way, a ton of silage fed Lot 6 saved 3.75 bushels of corn and 1/6 of a ton of alfalfa hay minus 12.5 pounds of linseed oil meal. All the foregoing tends to show the very low feeding value of corn silage in the lamb ration. Since the corn silage used in these experiments contained from 5 to Wbushels of corn to the ton, it would seem that it had, thru the process of ensiling, lost some of its value as a fattening feed for lambs. The fact that the lambs receiving silage sold for less per hundredweight on the market should also be taken into consideration. This would indicate that the silage-fed lambs did not have as firm a finish as those receiving no silage. The succulence of silage seems to have growth-producing properties rather than fatten - ing properties, so that the finish of silage lambs is not com - mensurate with their gains. What then may be considered the role of corn silage in lamb fattening rations? Possibly it may be stated as follows: Silage, once it has been made on the farm, must be fed to livestock, as it has market value in no other form. Possibly after silage has been put up for the purpose of feeding cattle, the cattle market may take an unfavorable turn or some other circumstances may make it inadvisable to feed the silage in that way. If, on the other hand, the lamb market is particu - larly advantageous, a feeding value not very much less than the usual cost of the silage may be obtained by feeding it to lambs. In general, however, it would seem inadvisable to build a silo for the express purpose of supplying silage in lamb feeding. VALUE OF MOLASSES MEAL AND LINSEED OIL MEAL Many lamb feeders who employ a concentrate supplement at all feed it in large quantities in order to increase the rapid - ity of gains rather than the economy of gain. The supple - ments were fed in limited quantity in these experiments, how - ever, in the belief that a small amount of supplement would </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Winter Lamb Feeding 15 demonstrate its value in the lamb ration from an economical standpoint better than a large amount, even tho the lambs might have taken more. Both the molasses meal and linseed oil meal were relatively more expensive than the feeds in the basal ration. Table 6. — Is it profitable to add molasses meal or linseed oil meal to a corn and alfalfa ration? The gains produced in Lots 3 and 5 favor the use of a supplement in lamb feeding, providing this supplement does not run up the cost of gain too much- A greater gain of about 2 pounds per lamb was realized when a small amount of molasses meal was added to the ration than when it was omitted. Nearly the same number of pounds total feed was consumed per hundred pounds gain when the lambs were fed molasses meal as when no molasses meal was fed. In Lot 1 Lot 3 Lot5 umber of lambs per lot 90 9D Corn Alfalfa Corn Mol. Meal Alfalfa Corn L. O. M. Alfalfa Average initial weight per head lbs. Average final weight per head lbs. Average gain per head lbs. Average daily gain per head Ib. 53.64 88.07 34.23 .340 53.61 89.97 36.34 .361 82 S8 :lt, Average daily ration Shelled corn M olasses meal .... Linseed oil meal . Alfalfa hay lbs. per head 1.29 .99 1.31 .15 .99 1.35 .14 .97 •'EED REQUIRED PER 100 LBS. GAIN lbs. Shelled com Molasses meal Linseed oil meal Alfalfa hay 378.04 291.65 361.65 41.76 | 274.48' 348.54 36.68 251.55 100 LBS. SUPPLEMENT REPLACED Shelled corn Alfalfa hay lbs. 39.25 41.12 80.43 109.32 'EED COST OF 100 LBS. GAIN $7.01 $7.40 $7.55 Selling price W cut. $15.35 $15.22 115.35 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 197 other words, 100 pounds of molasses meal replaced 39 pounds of corn and 41 pounds of alfalfa hay. Since cane molasses is considered by some people to be practically equal to corn and since alfalfa hay is undoubtedly much the same in feed - ing value whether mixed with molasses meal or fed alone, it would appear that the molasses meal fed the lambs in Lot 3 did not give quite as good an account of itself as might have been expected. It being a mixture of 1 part molasses and 1 part alfalfa, we may consider that 50 pounds of mo - lasses replaced 39 pounds of corn, and that 50 pounds of ground alfalfa when mixed with molasses replaced 41 pounds of loose hay. One year out of the 3 the lambs in Lot 3 which were fed molasses meal were appraised at the market 40 cents a hundred lower than the check lot. The other 2 years their selling price was equal to that of the check lot. From this it would seem that very little difference in finish may be expected from adding molasses meal to the ration, altho the average selling price of Lot 3 for the 3 years taken together was 13 cents per hundredweight less than that of Lot 1. If molasses were sold in the form of molasses meal at a lower price than an equal amount of corn, the use of molasses meal in the fattening lamb ration in larger quantities might be justified; but since the price of the meal is higher than the price of a similar amount of corn and alfalfa, its use in large quantities would scarcely be warranted. The claim is made by some that molasses meal will increase the palatability of the ration and that thru its use larger consumption of the cheaper, home-grown feeds will be obtained. The in - clusion of a small amount in this test was primarily for the purpose of trying it out as an appetizer. The consumption of corn and alfalfa was practically the same in Lot 3 as in Lot 1, however, and the only increase in total consumption was in the molasses meal fed, so that it seemed to have very little value in inducing greater use of home-grown feeds. The greatest gains were obtained each year in Lot 5, the group which received linseed oil meal in addition to the basal ration of corn and alfalfa. The average daily gain of 0.387 pound per head was very satisfactory; and when the fact that this figure is an average of 3 years' gains is taken into account, it is evident that the addition of a very small amount of the oil meal is capable of making the gains rel - atively high. During the 100-day feeding period, the lambs which received linseed oil meal made nearly 5 pounds greater </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 gain per head than did those receiving no linseed oil meal in addition to the corn and alfalfa. This would mean that the lambs receiving a ration of corn, linseed oil meal, and alfalfa reached a marketable weight fully 2 weeks earlier than did those which received no linseed oil meal and this factor might have considerable importance at certain seasons of the year when it would be important to market a group of lambs at the earliest possible date in order to avoid a rush on the mar - ket. In general, however, this advantage is offset by a some - what similar advantage at other seasons of the year in not having to market the lambs at a given time, since it some - times pays to wait until a glut on the market has eased up. The use of linseed oil meal may be said to have had a slight tendency to increase the total consumption of feed, as each year the group receiving linseed oil meal ate slightly more corn than did the group which did not receive a supple - ment. It will be noted also that the amount of linseed oil meal consumed almost replaced its weight in corn and better than replaced its weight in alfalfa hay. In other words, 100 pounds of linseed oil meal saved 80 pounds of corn and 109 pounds of hay. These results were fairly constant each of the 3 years, indicating that considerable dependence may be put in old process linseed oil meal to increase the rapidity of gain and to effect a noticeable saving of other feeds in the ration. The quality of finish was also of the best when linseed oil meal was used. Each of the 3 years, the lambs in Lot 5 topped the market, thereby equalizing in price the lambs in Lot 1. Packers sometimes complain that linseed oil meal lambs "go soft" when fed too long, but this seldom occurs if they are marketed before they exceed 90 pounds per head. Since gains made by Lot 5 were more expensive than those made by Lot 1, the difference in net return in favor of Lot 5 came about only thru greater gains. If the lambs in the check lot had been held until their gains were equal to those of Lot 5 they would clearly have returned a greater profit if the market had remained stable. When a farmer has corn silage to feed in addition to his corn and alfalfa, will it pay to add a limited amount of molasses meal or linseed oil meal to such a ration? This problem may be studied by comparing Lots 2, 4, and 6. The lambs in Lot 4 gained somewhat more rapidly than did those in Lot 2 but only 1 pound greater gain was made during the 100-day period, and by comparing Table 7 with Table 6 it may be noted that the lambs which received both molasses meal and corn silage in addition to the standard </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 197 ration did not make as great gains as those which received simply the standard ration of corn and alfalfa. As to replacement of feeds, the molasses meal effected a saving in shelled corn rather than in corn silage or alfalfa hay. One hundred pounds of molasses feed replaced 48 pounds of Table 7. — Is it profitable to add molasses meal or linseed oil meal to a corn, corn silage, and alfalfa ration? Lot 2 Lot 4 Lot 6 Number of lambs per lot w HO Corn Cora Corn ; Mol. Meal L. O. M. Silage Silage Silage Alfalfa Alfalfa Alfalfa Average initial weight per head lbs. 53.26 53.34 53.52 Average final weight per head lbs. 86.02 87.29 90.52 Average GAIN per head /(&gt;«. 32.62 33.93 36.64 Average daily gain per head lh. .324 337 .364 corn, but the alfalfa hay and corn silage (combined) replaced amounted to only 35 pounds. If the replacement value of corn silage fed to Lot 4 is translated into terms of corn and alfalfa, as ascertained from comparison of Lots 1 and 2, 100 pounds of molasses meal fed to this lot amounted in round numbers *&lt;&gt; Average daily ration lbs. per head Shelled corn ' Molasses meal Linseed oil meal Corn silage AKalfahay Feed required for 100 lbs. gain lbs. Shelled corn Molasses meal Linseed oil meal Corn silage Alfalfa hay 1.15 .99 .79 355.65 304.49 242.43 1.13 .15 1.00 'it 334.40 44.48 297.35 234.04 1.16 .14 1.04 .74 318.93 38.44 286.38 203.66 - 100 LBS. SUPPLEMENT REPLACED Shelled corn Ibx. Corn silage lbs. ! Alfalfa hay lbs. 47.77 16.06 18.86 95.53 49.71 100.86 -I Feed cost of 100 lbs. gain COST OF 100 LBS. GAIN $7.62 $7.94 $7.96 Selling price per net. $15.18 $15.07 $15.30 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">Winter Lamb Feeding 19 to 50 pounds of corn and 20 pounds of hay, which is hardly as good a showing for molasses meal as where it was fed without corn silage in Lot 3. The use of linseed oil meal in addition to a corn, corn silage, and alfalfa hay ration, however, is a different story. The second greatest gains of the experiment came from this combination. Lot 6 having an average daily gain per head of 0.364 pound in the 3 trials. The lambs which received linseed oil meal in addition to the corn, corn silage, and alfalfa hay ration made 4 pounds more gain during the hundred days than did the lambs in Lot 2, which did not receive oil meal, and these gains were slightly more desirable from the packer's standpoint as is indicated by an average of the selling prices for the 3 years. The highest replacement value of a supplement was ob - tained when linseed oil meal was added to a corn, corn silage, and alfalfa ration. When fed thus, 100 pounds of linseed oil meal replaced 95 pounds of corn, 50 pounds of silage, and 101 pounds of alfalfa hay. Converting the corn silage into its equivalent of corn and alfalfa, 100 pounds of linseed oil meal replaced 99 pounds of corn and 109 pounds of hay. The cost of 100 pounds gain in Lot 6 is almost a dollar higher than in Lot 1, where neither silage nor linseed oil meal was used, indicating that altho a fair amount of corn and alfalfa were replaced, not enough was saved to warrant paying pre - vailing prices for silage and linseed oil meal, especially the former, to add to the basal ration. Most of the recommendations put out by other experiment stations for the use of silage in lamb feeding include the use of linseed oil meal in connection with it. The addition of both these feeds to a corn and legume basal ration is, by some, considered an ideal lamb fattening combination. It is appar - ent from our results that the greatest replacement value for linseed oil meal was obtained when it was fed in connection with silage and the greatest replacement value for silage was obtained when fed in connection with linseed oil meal. The ra - tion including both these feeds was excelled as a gain producer only by the ration in which linseed oil meal was fed without silage. Recommendation of linseed oil meal as a lamb feed, then, seems rather more warranted than recommendation of silage, but if the latter is to be used, the best gains can be produced by the addition of a limited amount of linseed oil meal along with it. </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 197 CONCLUSION From the foregoing discussion of results obtained with the 6 rations employed in this experiment, it is evident that it was possible to make money feeding lambs during the period 1919-22 with existing prices of lambs and feeds. The tables at the end of this bulletin show that the lambs were fed at a loss the second year but that excellent profits were made the other 2 years. So long as prices fluctuate there will always be an element of uncertainty in the feeding business, but at the present time (1923) the relation of lamb prices to feed prices is such that a satisfactory return may be ex - pected from the investment of labor and money in lamb feeding. Charging 70 cents per bushel for corn, $50 per ton for linseed oil meal, and $15 per ton for alfalfa hay, the gains in Lot 1 would have cost $6.92 per hundred and those in Lot 5 $7.15. These prices prevailed thruout the past feeding season in the vicinity of Lincoln, they being very near the average of prices during the 3 years of this work. An old saying is to the effect that it takes 400 pounds of corn and 300 pounds of alfalfa to produce 100 pounds gain on western lambs. The average of 3 years shows Lot 1 requiring somewhat less than these amounts of feed for 100 pounds gain. Assuming 30 pounds to be the amount of gain usually put on the average lamb while in the feed lot, the groups of lambs receiving the check ration required just 2 bushels of corn and 87 pounds of alfalfa per head for finish - ing. Lot 5, which received linseed oil meal, required for this amount of gain 1% bushels of corn, 11 pounds of linseed oil meal, and 75 pounds of hay per head. Lot 6, the best silage group, required for 30 pounds gain 1 2/3 bushels of corn, 11.5 pounds of linseed oil meal, 86 pounds of silage and 61 pounds of hay. In general, then, 15 pounds gain may be expected per bushel of corn when fed with a legume hay. [:&gt;X] </seg>
            <seg id="p022">Winter Lamb Feeding 21 0 II : : I M I II* « ! I ~n ~~~ r i nfi 1 ? I! -" i 5 1 . •» 8*° i ft I O»t-Nt~c;c:«— X j: i s 3*| «* | i«^5iil*| 1 f I i* K II : : H : _j_J 11° I z - : | : | I! i h ilk s »*e [j ie ' 2 -■? - g" 5 ;8 s --^-il^s - I* 5 nil » »W •» » * h ii : II ii ii |_ £s|:8EFsi! 82 :s ss isilsii ssssssssig -. e SI So bS * * II II : : : : ! 1 I IP 7 o i s n s — ~ — n ri — 3~ II! I 3 * 5fi &gt;ia 2 2 i]hh\ s^=|iSS|5 ts i" 1 II II :': ':': II II ** f | I r^~l : : : II II • TT : « ■ - : : : • ■ • II II O.l — c~ =N?a^ p — -»• *n tco»o«e — o — v ,«:, f 2* I! an -i:; 2 |!;!|si «»-5ISlH P - e 13 !•&lt;•■.■•? I «1 • ■ —.\ «1 3'ImI isMMnNaMH ! e I ■« •&gt;-. i i h 31 X I E__fe II : ? I |l|3 iiSlilli illl|ijI4|l i i s 1 mill 1 i i ■\ : : : ; ; = = = = = = =i = ; ;:;;;;:; ■iiiiil i i I i i frSlfM IS II S S I </seg>
            <seg id="p023">** © • Sm&lt; ''~ t^..' ~ ~*. . ' . . ™ 'i . **? . *^ *■• ~ x . T *i ~ » *° II R . II II H [I =s 5 4 II | II M II II » 1 II 1 J I_ Z s eaHh 3 -" 2= *«': S28S88S3 s Jo » I i ~ II n ii ii ii l_ _J i i ! I I- ; 2 o EilL^lj 5= A §S ill 5SSSS825 3 il Is I It II [!_ ■ II H I TT I i i ii r l ~ i B i ii rr~ i I B " II II : : II I! i ii " 1 Ii i ii ii . ii ii n ii \ Ml! H! 3 ! IN! ! !!ii Mlllil! ! ! I 1 I r° f S3o niiiiii § | Kill i iiilii </seg>
            <seg id="p024">23 i ' 1 iO ' © &lt;C i I ft ■ -rt-L-9i*3»o t-lgi; ~i cxt- — «»^«oomk* « sa .- r-' — - 4rt — — ' *t-«oo»w ifl i S lo ■M Km T.&lt; : ■ 5 r l;s:S||*|| M«65«3 * h P a S «, •I i. « -? •: c ;! : L JMiUE!!8vwl«i%U WMfelhCli * iH^KrnsiPi 83 " 1^ $S . :Siisii SSSS.gSc.S! Si )■ |« 8 ■ * N 1 SS - *« s°°u *|i° i" ~K&lt; ■ * •••«;•;• » •*-. (if 5 t i;* ■ s. u &lt; --? 11 : • : : : : : : II 3 :::::: 5 « . ?? : a y 1 5 jpf^is iiiiiilti | s i 2 I : 1 i • • • ■• 2 !i s=_!Jt"°£ r - ! £ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>