<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00019.00010">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00019.00010</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>NINETEENTH BIENNIAL REPORT OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane AT LINCOLN TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER 30, 1908</title>
               <date value="1908">1908</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
	        <change>
	           <date>2007-09-12</date>
	           <respStmt>
	              <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
	           </respStmt>
	           <item>Enrichment</item>
	        </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">NINETEENTH BIENNIAL REPOR I OF THE SUPERINTENDENT OF THE Nebraska Hospital for the Insane AT LINCOLN TO THE GOVERNOR FOR THE PERIOD ENDING NOVEMBER SO, 1908 1908 THE WOODRUFF-COLLINS PRESS Lincoln. Nil*., I* S A </seg>
            <seg id="p002">HOARD OF PUBLIC LANDS AND BIILD1NCS t. Henhy M. Eaton, Cotnmiwioaer Public Landa and Buildings Prendeni George C. .Ii nkin . Secretary William T. Thompson Attornev General Lawson &lt;;. Brian State Treasurer RESIDENT OKKICEKS John T. Hat, M. 1) . Superintendent Hakhison A. WlOTON, M. D First Assistant Physician Hallk Kwing, M. D. Second Assistant Physician L. B. Pilsblrv, M. D Pathologist Albekt D. CiILMORE, Bbq Steward Cora L. Damrow Matron NON-RESIDENT Fredekk k A. Sri kk Chaplain </seg>
            <seg id="p003">Hon. George L. Sheldon. Governor of Nebraska: ■ Sir I have the honor to submit the 19th biennial report of hospital for the two years ending November 30, 1906. i There have Ix'en no changes in the officials of the hospital ng the period. Dr. L. B. Pilsbury, pathologist, was granted a e of absence from August 1st to December 1st. 1908, for the pur - of studying Psychiatry and Mental Pathology in Europe. H. A. Taylor, of University Place, acted as a substitute in Dr. lurv's absent II am pleased to be able to report that the two years just pa !&gt;een years of peace and progress for the institution. There been no accidents of a serious nature, the officers have worked .rmony, the employes have as a rule been faithful and efficient, ondition of the institution and the grounds has been improved any ways and the patients have received. 1 believe, good care treatment. By an act of the last legislature the Hastings asylum was changed from an institution for the care of the incurable insane to a ing hospital and the Board of Public I. amis and Buildings in the spring of 1907 divided the state into three hospital districts. I'nder this arrangement we have since April 1 . 1907. admitted insane patients from only fourteen counties, namely: Cass. Dodge. Douglas Johnson, Lancaster. Nemaha. Otoe. Saunders. Sarpy. Saline. :d. Pawnee and Richardson. Inebriates and drug habitues are still admitted from all parti of the state. This change accounts for the small number of admissions during the present biennium as compared with previous periods. The change in the law by which all of the three institutions are placed on the same basis, requiring each hospital to receive and care for patients from a certain dis - trict, is in my opinion, much better for all concerned than the plan of trying to separate the curable and incurable anil caring for them in different institutions. I At the beginning of the biennium there were present in the ital 548 patients. 40 of whom were inebriates and drug habitues, ng the biennium we have admitted patients of all classes to the </seg>
            <seg id="p004">LAND (OMMISSIONKKS RCPOHT 134 ■amber of S36. Of these 422 were admitted as insane and 414 as inebriates or persons addicted to the excessive use of morphine. ne or other narcotic drugs, 22 were returned from parole, 6 transferred from other institutions making a total number treatment of 1412. The total number during the period dis - k ped, transferred, paroled and died was 863 leaving nt in the hospital on the 30th day of November 1908-559 f whom are inebriates and drug habitues. A detailed ment in regard to the admissions, discharges, etc.. will be found in Table No, 1. The average number of patients actually ■nt in the hospital was 551 which is 40 le.-s than the average number present during the previous biennium. The number of deaths during the biennium wa. 91 of which :i were inebriates and CAKE Of PATIENTS The wards of the hospital have not been overcrowded to such an extent as they were in the previous period, and on that account vel&gt;een able to make the patients more comfortable. Thetrain - chool for nurses has been continued with very satisfactory During the biennium we have graduated twenty-two We have in training at the present time eight in the senior .•nteen in the junior class. We have tent out from time to time nurses on private cases. Our school is affiliated with the Illinois Training School for Nurses and we have one nurse taking the postgraduate course of six months in Chicago. We have increased the number of lectures during the past year and our physicians are giving their time and interest in behalf of a thorough course. The plan of employing women nurses for sick and infirm patients has lx»en continued and has l&gt;een very satisfactory. Patients who are physically able have been employed as much as l.le and they have done a greater part of the work on the farm. in the kitchen, garden, laundry, bakery, barn, green house, etc. It needed by everyone who has had experience in the care and treatment of the insane that employment of some kind is the best means for keeping them in a contented state of mind, best for the promotion of their general health and in many cases it act- potent curative agent. During the past year a new form of employment has been in- troduced under the direction of Miss Lillian B. Stuff, Supt. of Nurses. especially among the women patients. This work consists of </seg>
            <seg id="p005">135 ■I system of basket making, fancy needle work, painting Stuff was sent to Chicago during the past summer to attend a course of instruction offered by the Chicago School of Civics and Philanthropy. The course in this institution was given to : the value of occupation as a means of directing energy. Work suited to all grades of patients from simple childish sanies to skilled handicraft was taught, thus attempting to bring l&gt;aek the capacity of patients for muscular coordination, self control and pleasant profitable pastime. liENEKAL HEALTH OF PATIENTS The general health of the paiients as a rule ha.- been j There has been very little acute siekitvss among them during the period. There have been a very few mild cases of diphtheria and also a few cases of erysipelas but no other infectious di icept - uberculosis. There are always more or les~ tubercular in institutions of this kind and in the past year we have had more than usual but the deaths from tuberculosis were only one more during the biennium than the former one. Last spring about twenty-five patients were suddenly attacked with acute sick twenty-two being women and three men. Microscopic tests showed their disease to t&gt;e tuberculosis of the lungs. These patients were scattered about the building and it became a serious problem to properly care for them and at the same time isolate them and pre - vent further spread of the disease. It was finally decided to place the women in one of the dormitories of the brick building, to pro - vide a separate table for them in the dining-room and to keep them out of doors as much as possible in charge of a special nurse. The men have been treated in the infirmary ward and kept apart from the other patients as much as possible. Two of these women have since died in the hospital from the disease, and two others ren to their home. Those remaining in tKe hospital have done and most of them now show but few symptoms of the disease. Me I have developed during the past nine months. In order to provide l&gt;etter care for these patients it is recommended th inclosed porch l&gt;e built on the south side of the tubercular ward enough to furnish sleeping quarters for at least a part of the ntfl in the open air. This porch could l&gt;e built at an ex; of about $1,000. 1 do uot consider it necessary or advisable to pro - vide a separate building at this time for this class of patients. There eight deaths from this cause during the present biennium while during the previous biennium there were seven. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">136 TUBERCULOSIS \MoN(, THE CATTLI In June of this year Dr. Peters, of the state university, undo direction, tested our dairy herd for tuberculosis. Fiftv-sevc were given the tul&gt;eiTulin test and 21 of this number reaetei to the test and were condemned. In August 34 other cows wei ■ and .") of these were condemned. The third test wi • in October last. 7 cows l&gt;eing tested and 2 condemned. 8 i these condemned cows t&gt;eing in good condition were killed and afu being ins|&gt;ected by Dr. Peters were used for t&gt;eef. On August 24t 21 head were shipped to Omaha subject to inspection. 15 of th numl&gt;er passed the government inspection and were sold for bee and »i were condemned as not fit for l&gt;eef and destroyed. W 1 for the cattle shipped $4:?N.2S. There are a large numU :tle on the south farm which have not yet l&gt;een subjected t It is proposed to have the test made there during th • t and it is recommended that all of our cattle l&gt;e tested once until the disease is entirely eradicated. 1)1 PSIlM XNI \c - What to do with a man who lias a morbid, uncontrollable ng for alcohol or for other stimulants and narcotics, is a ion which forces itself at times upon every county. City ami county jails detain a man until he is over his spree and there the efforts usually must Keligious influence is a potent factor in effecting a true cure for dipsomania. Private institutions do much good. Nebraska is one of the few states which l^elieves it is s duty to step in and require several months treatment • hospital, of men who cannot on account of poor eircum - tford to pay the private institutions or who refuse to take other treatment. As a man in a storm exposed to the l&gt;enumbing influence of cold soon fails to realize his danger, and in returning consciousness resists all help and wants to continue in his false security, so the true dipsomaniac, under the baleful influence oi drugs and drink, resists interference in his l&gt;ehalf and wants the right to continue on his downward course. Such men can best ha ed by the state. Nebraska having decided to treat these eases should endeavor to make the treatment adequate. One ward of this hospital accommodating about 50 men was devoted to this purpose and nearly 700 patients have here received systematic ■ ment since the dipsomaniac law was passed. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">137 On December 1st. 1908 there were present in the hospital 38 men and during the two years 5 men previously treated wen (ed and 397 others admitted, each remaining two or three ths. Ninteen women have been sent here out at present there no women inebriates in the hospital. Considering the men e 440 have been treated in the past two years. I The present accommodations have not been adequate 1 built to house 5(1 sub-acute cases of insanity has l&gt;een used for treatment of all varieties of dipsomaniacs and drug habil needed treatment is not the same for all. If a case of delirium tens is admitted he must be put witli the insane to prevent other inebriates from W'ing kept awake during the night. If one mes very ill he has to be sent to the hospital ward for the insane. These men who are very susceptible to depressing influences, de - a small separate building where the morphine, chloral and lie users can be kept apart from the alcoholics. Three properly equipped wards each with room for 20 or 25 patients would allow the most modern and scientific treatment. Such a building could ■instructed for twenty or twenty-five thousand dollars. The good results of treatment with the present inadequate quarter! where all classes of dipsomaniacs are kept in one ward can l&gt;e much enhanced by a proper classification, enabling more individuality in treatment. The reason an appropriation for this building is not requested is localise it is thought that the most urgent need is for a building for the insane. $50. (MM) was asked two years ago to con - struct a hospital building for men. The need becomes more im - perative as time goes on. A basement ward in the building en in the early 70's planned to room 40 well men has been converted into a hospital ward to treat cases such as pneumonia and typhoid - of the acute insane. A side room 6-J feet by 10 feet was fitted with a table anil instrument cabinet. The existing plumbing pre - &lt;1 the establishment of a sink or running water ordinarily re - quired. In such a treatment room as this, minor surgery and ngs averaging 103 cases per month is attended to. The quiet sick and infirm insane men are here waited upon by women nurses. On an average 40 sick and infirm are cared for daily. On another ward are many patients who are too noisy to be in the basement with cases such as pneumonia but who are acutely ill and should be cared for in the proposed building. Smaller wards are needed, one for the acute insane of the quiet type, another for the acute in- </seg>
            <seg id="p008">138 I of the noisy and agitated type and another for the convalescent &gt;t kitchen and a hvdrotherapeutie department should l&gt;e pro- L If only one building is to be furnished it seems to l&gt;e the duty of the state to provide for the insane rather than the The green-house which was in had condition ha. been partially .It and put in first class shape at an expense of about SI .(MM), the most of the work l&gt;eing done by t he regular employe •. The poultry - i yards have been enlarged and a new brood-house 100 tec; heated by hot water, and incubator cave built and a serious mpt made to raise poultry on a large scale. During the part 000 chicken- and ducks have been raised and it is irht twice that Dumber can each year in the future. have been placed on the halls of wards 1 and 4 for rd -J for women and a large number of the Bleeping ave al-n been provided writ I To pn l ward orth wing the foundation \ it It Portland eel i tile drain placed at the bottom of the foundation all around the surface I During the pa t summer the external surface of the two mai ii gone over by mechanic! . the cornice and otht i metal parts painted and the wall, thoroughly repaire* ever it was needed. Much general repair work and paint in lone on the interior of the buildi ved to Iw' in better condition than they have heel lor man I, although we did not have funds enough to do all in the wa that should have been done. A penal appropriation was made of f 1,000 to purchase and i an electric pump and motor, a duplicate of the one already The contract for this was let by the Hoard of Public Lands Buildings in the spring of 1907 and the pump wa- placed in tion during the summer. A special appropriation was also • to enlarge and repair the water reservoir but when the matter to 1h&gt; investigated it was found that the money appropriated not sufficient to make the change thought to Iw necessary. The 1 of Public Lands and Buildings decided not to use any of this money but to wait for further funds. The Hoard favors abandoning the re;&lt;ervoir entirely and substituting a stand pipe. The reservoir REPAIRS &gt;iNI&gt; IMPROVEMENTS </seg>
            <seg id="p009">139 i&lt; on leased ground. The lease is dated June 18, 1885, and runs 1 years, the state agreeing for the use of this tract of land. 150 feet by 226 feet, to furnish the owner water to the full capacity one inch pipe. This reservoir has a capacity of aboul 150,000 Ions. It is built of stone and cement and is covered with a roof of wood and tin. The roof and the cement lining are in bad condition and pressure from the reservoir is not sufficient to supply wa' - the highest parts of the building. Plans have been made by a com- Bit engineer to raise the walls of this reservoir 8 feet and tli a flat roof, reline it with cement, all of the new parts 1 inforced concrete. This would give a capacity of 225.000 and would give sufficient pressure. A reliable firm offen do this for $"2.5&lt;M). A new stand pipe to take the place of this \ oir 7.") feet high and 15 feet in diameter, having a capacity ol about KKUMK) gallons would cost about $5. (MM). Two years ago an appropriation of Stt.(MM) was asked ! furnish an ice and cold storage plant but was not granted. We often have great difficulty in storing enough ice for the use of the institution and last summer our ice supply was exhausted by the ■!' July, necessitating the purchase of ice the remainder of the summer. In my opinion it would Ik 1 more economical and more satisfactory in every way to equip our cold storage plant with an ice machine rather than to depend upon natural ice as we are obliged to do now. An appropriation of $6,(KM) is again asked for this pur- It will probably be necessary during the next two ye: purchase a new engine to run the small dynamo as the old ODt in use for many years and is out of date anil liable to gi\' at any time. This will require a special appropriation of £i Two years ago an appropriation of $50. (KM) was asked for to provide a hospital building for men and as the appropriation was not made the recommendation is repeated. FINANCIAL STATEMENT IND APPROPRIATIONS NEEDED During the biennial period there was expended from the ap - propriations made by the legislature $195. L'OS. JO. There was spent for permanent improvement* t3,379.04 and the balance 1191,829.16 was for ordinary expenses and general repairs. There wa Snded from the cash fund 125,431.58. Of this cash fund $17,084.06 s received from the counties for the board and care of inebriates ii the balance was obtained from the sale of farm products, etc. </seg>
            <seg id="p010">140 he average number of patients present during the two yean S51 the per capita cost was $'AAS 14 or $14.50 per month, not leiing the money received from the counties for the board and ■ if inebriates. If we add to this the amount received for the ■I and care of inebriates 117,064.06 the total amount expended for maintenance and general repairs would amount to 1208,913.21 which is $:&lt;79 1") for the two years or ll.VMI per capita per month. Expenditures from December 1. MM Hi to March 31, 1907, from the appropriations for periods of two years ending March 31. 1907. Balance of appropriations unexpended opriations of April 1. 190? and amount remaining unexpendeil Novem!&gt;er 30. l'.IOS Appropriate&lt;l Balances MH&gt;7 Nov. 30. l'.Mis Officers' salaries $19. 700. (Ml 13.308 34 Employt 54.000. 00 9,293 05 Maintenance 1 15.000 00 _&gt;S..i«»7.06 134,736 17 134,736.17 ml*M 1 . l'.HNi. a~ per report Deficiency appropriation H. R. No. r&gt;'.iA Estimated deficiency appropriation H. K. ended for officers' salaries . No. 534 $3,000.03 $: 10,556 35 10,000.00 K tided for employes' wages nded for services chaplain aded for fuel and lights 7.1(1") 49 ::&gt; oo .S.I 7.") 58 ended for board and clothing... 129.03 Expended for paint- and oils 28 nded for repair* for laundry.. 165 ended for new fire hose 198 60 Expended from Deficiency Appropriation H. R. No. 534 10,556 35 Expended from Estimated Deficiency Ap- propriation H. R. No. 534.. (t.ti7.") O.") »nded total I ice of Estimated Deficiency Appro- 114,215.79 priation H. K. No. 534. 324 «••"» Balance of funds (lapsed I 195.43 </seg>
            <seg id="p011">141 Repairs and improvement* Electric motor and pump $7,500.00 1.000.00 1,000.00 1.000 OO Enlarging and repairing reservoir. $198,200.00 7.207 59 Total \&gt;H I M&gt; ■ I 71 Cash &lt;&gt;n hand last report Cash received for care of dipsomaniacs. .$17,084.05 Cash received from sale of livestock 1,988 38 1,988 38 Cash received from sale of hides 1.04J 36 Cash received from all other sources 1.589 23 24.704.02 $28,358 .f&gt; Total C expended from December 1. 1908 to April 4. 07 as shown by vouchers on Hie $8,51 1.91 rpaid into the State 1 reasury a- shown by receipts on file 1X..V17 12 1,299.73 Cash on hand $2n.:^ 7ti Total EX I'KNSKS fUH RENT $19,700 54.000 115,000 Officers' salaries Employes' wages Maintenance 10,000 General repairs $198,700 Total EXTRAORDI N MO EXPE Nfi t. $50,000 New building for men New engine 1,000 ti.ooo Artificial ice and cold storage plant Enlarging and repairing reservoir or building standpipt 5.000 from $'2,500 to Total ESTIMATES OF APPROPRIATIONS NEEDED FOR YEAR8 1909 AND l»10 aw.ow </seg>
            <seg id="p012">142 The appropriation asked for for the period l&gt;eginning April 1st, 1909. for salaries, wages, maintenance and general repairs amounts to $19S. ?()(). Estimating that there will he "&gt;6(i patients present this will then amount to $3.54 . N2 per capita for the two years or $14 7s per month which is thought will l&gt;e sufficient provided we continue to treat inebriates and receive payment direct from the eountii During the last two years the bookkeeper, Klsie M. Beck, under Slireetion of steward has added to the old system of bookkeeping [ger showing all purchases, a contract record, a permit record, took hook has been made more complete and the accounts are believed to l&gt;e in letter shape than ever bel The report of the steward and the pathologist and the usual tical tables will he found in another portion of this report. bin conclusion I wish to thank the Governor of the state and members of the Board of Public Lands mid Buildings for their orm kindness arid encouragement. .1. T. Hw. Superintendent. Lincoln, Nebraska. November 30, Hills. KKI'OKT OF THK PATHOLOGIST To the Superintendent &lt;• During the past two years routine examinations of pathological material have been conducted as follows: A- a standing ordei :i as possible after an insane patient is admitted a sample of urine is obtained and ttie findings reported to the physician in charge. For the dipsomaniacs the routine is not followed out so completely but specimens are ex - amined whenever desired. Miscroscopic examinations of the blood and sputum have l&gt;een made whenever asked for. as well as bacter - iologic examinations of effusions, exudates. false membranes, cere - pinal fluid, etc. The few patients who have contracted diph - theria have l&gt;een subjected to an immediate, rigid quarantine and the disease has spread but little. While the Widal test has been a very few times for diagnostic purposes the results have al - l&gt;een negative as no case of typhoid fever has occured in the institution during the last two years. Altogether there have been 868 urine. 45 blood. 58 throat. 26 stomach. 87 sputum and I Widal Respectfully, </seg>
            <seg id="p013">143 HOM'ITAI. FOR INSANK, LINCOLN ( examinations made. There have Ik-cm 15 post mortetns conducted. In each instance the consent of friends was previously obtained. A great deal of the baeteriologic technique employed ha - in connection with the -y tematic ami frequeni examination of th« water supply. Specimens of water from the Btoraf v..ir through which most of the water used by the hospital passes, have been examined every ten days or two weeks as to the varieties MM approximate number of bacteria present. During the fall month an examination is made each week. The direct water supply, tha is the water as it comes from the pumps, was found to contain s (tective covering of the com plained by the fact that the protective covering oi the eon basin, which i. a wooden dome : heathed with tin. had ileterioi sufficiently s&lt;. that crevi, -d. especially where the covering joins the stone and concrete foundation. At the present time mice might gain entrance in places and there are slight opening* m the roof through which the dejecta of birds which frequeni the dorm could be washed during each rain The ln'st wav to remedy the defects in the reservoir would be to deepen the concrete basin by raising its sides about eight feet, to reeoat the inner surface with cement, and to cover the entire with a cement roof. The entire reservoir should lx&gt; banked with earth. By making the only trap door perfectly tight and carefully sealing it there could then lx&gt; little or no possibility of contamination. This plan would give greater pressure, a more adequate supply of water, and solve the water supply problem at the institution for vears to come. few organisms of any sort thai very little attention was paid to this source. On two oeca ioni colon or colon-like germs have found in considerable numbers in the reservoir and immediately the water was run out. The first time two or three dead annuals discovered, in the other instance there »* no visible evidence of contamination. After draining, the reservoir was thoroughly scrubbed, refilled to the brim with water, copper sulphate added in the proportion of about 1 to 6.000 and allowed to remain for several h&lt; hich the solution was carried away through all the ma i r erviee pipes of the watt m. Immediately such a treatment the number of suspicious micro-organisma fell to such a minimum that the ulueose bouillon U ative. The presence of dead animals in the first instance can only bt </seg>
            <seg id="p014">144 The present laboratory is quite convenient and is exceptionally well lighted. The equipment for the daily routine of urine and sputum analyses is perhaps sufficient. It is impossible to do much with pathological tissues M there is no microtome. A new micro - of the rotary type is needed badly. An auto-clave for the ■ rilization of culture media, a blood-pressure recording ■ id an apparatus for measuring the pressure &lt;&gt;f the fluid of the spinal cord are all but necessities if the lx*st pathological along the lines which are met with at this institution is to be Perhaps the greatest need of this department of the hos - pital is a new morgue which should be supplied with a proper autopsy table, instrument cabinet, an ice chamber ami heating ties. The present structure is lacking in all the above facil - tnd it should !&gt;e replaced with a new structure, not only for general scientific reasons but from a sanitary standpoint as well. I For the last four months the regular pathologist. Dr. L B. bury, has l&gt;een abroad studying along pathological lines and work lias beea carried along by Dr. H. A. Taylor during that -. The pathologist! wish to thank the superintendent for the luragenient and material aid given the department. Respectfully submitted. H. A. Tatlok, Acting Pathok&gt;| </seg>
            <seg id="p015">KRAI. STATEMENT FOB THE THIRTY KMiHT YEARS KM) ING NOVEMBER 30, 1908. (INSANE ONLY) " x '*• — ~ — &gt; 9 B ||| | I I I I I | || j I « 4 &gt;« J5* w i 5 3 as as 1 Z ■?. ?. S£&lt; 1871 87 S7 s 3 I 1 12 ."&gt; ! lsT.' ."&gt;ti _•!• 86 2(1 .-&gt; I 2 •"&gt; 1x73 M 3s 14 lit .' I II 2 1^; I M 17 78 12 ii 1 .'■ 1875 Hi M 82 -'it I 5 1 1876 (il 72 133 30 .1 I 1 3 1x77 93 .12 U."&gt; -M 0 J I 13 W v |x_&gt; :;\ 1 1 | 1 II 1879 120 117 237 42 18 2 I N 160 114 274 14 II 7 t 15 [881 193 124 317 18 Hi I 17 230 1C.4 394 71 18 6 1 25 »273 2(Mi 47!) 71 47 52 I 23 282 204 4Mi 71 22 l!t 20 3&lt;K) ls.i ."&gt;4.'&gt; m :« :*7 36 202 SCO W M Kt 1 2 21 :i7l 202 .')7(i 96 lit 22 I I M 400 219 1119 72 21 8 2 2 2/i 302 1(»4 5M 72 :&lt;o 5 6 2 l'.» i 12 :«W 201 :{ 513 s:&lt; 22 2 2 1 32 41 :&lt;2(i 1S(» 1 .")l(t 81 19 41 1 27 I :Uli 200 4 5H ti7 21 40 2 2 -i\ It 273 242 3 518 92 :«» Hi i 2 21 I 317 269 I 587 90 41 26 I 2 24 17 1895 341 255 2 ."ids 115 28 28 2 I 30 1886 348 225 "&gt;73 101 22 22 1 Id :u ls&gt;i7 351 216 5 "&gt;72 93 27 8 3 1 2:i 1898 3(K( 226 586 73 14 | 81 a 2 30 19 1H99 330 253 6 588 106 14 1 2 2 36 2 KKK) 368 250 t&gt;19 90 17 !• 2 3 28 16 1901 3(i."&gt; 358 9 732 , so 17 7 3 II 27 I 1&lt;»&lt;)2 .^{l 47(i ."&gt; 1012 !()."&gt; 60 20 7 4 52 86 1903 ."&gt;lti .\.U) 16 UMi2 166 !»l 23 4 I 61 17 1904 513 ."&gt;24 17 1064 113 79 20 7 4 :&gt;4 so im r &gt; 588 4."&gt;.&gt; 19 KM')2 121 sr&gt; 21 lo 19 KKMi ;&gt;.&gt;9 338 19 !H7 "&gt;7 47 14 11 2 71 77 1907 506 255 21 784 7.1 12 8 (i 1 48 13 .VH) H)7 15 682 37 20 '.) 3 ■ '.•7 131 100 26 317 42 341 (.1 :-wi .~&gt;7 107 ."&gt;t 89 32 182 516 I si; 109 181 130 91 3 .11 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p016">146 TABLE NO I •UPIHTKIN INHANK l!t&lt;)7 \'M\\ Siitiinia- 2 Yean £ s !((.") nod from puoie I (I I II ii n I il I I in il."&gt; .'."..') w tig i.,; I'mier treatment 317 4117 7M J7.'&gt; «)7 t.vj ||s .VS.". uiiiii)! NovcnilxT .'^1 Ute ntuiitier tn-ate&lt;l 1 1 K I i . MM. Suiiiiii i 1907 I'.HIS - ~ -pital at beginning of y. I I'nder treatment J.V) '».'''&lt; 1 17li .«) il removed Remaining N&lt;&gt;veiiil&gt;er :■«) S tB 4s (I 4s 4S I) 4S Average numlier treated := &gt;.-&gt; :u.i 506 17.' $» ."KM&gt; 165 IUA .Vts I ''IT _'U IS s &gt;i 17 ■&lt; ii -i _' (i 2 "&gt; ii I VHhi Imyi 1 1 ' u\ :c. :.-. is ig 37 :&gt;s :&gt;[ 112 M HI I-' 13 7 I 7 k .&lt; 6 B 4 13 17 t I (i :i 7 .')! 4(1 !M (( ;{ A .",! 13 1 (• I 3 (I A 4 (t A 28 is _'l 16 +&lt;&gt; 11 4i -'II I4.'&gt; IM . 75 171 !!-■ 17.' :&lt;L's 500 179 332 511 I7!» :«.' .".I! 107 :«n SO5 17t&gt; :&lt;:il 507 1 72 :« i INKHt 42 I 4ti U 1 M 43 I «| -' 4*1 12 (I 1 1 189 B IS) 100 (i :«&gt; 23 (i •_» l () 1 .I :i i&lt;)_' :«»7 II L'43 HO 11 171 .«() 0 -&gt;3 .53 (I 1 I ,i 1 17 414 10 459 19 355 ■ 184 11 195 19 411 </seg>
            <seg id="p017">147 TABI.K NO ■&gt; TYPE OF DISEASE n K PATIENT ADMITTED INSANE .Men Women Infection-exhaustion psychos* Febrile delirium ■ &gt; Post febrile psychoses t Ic psychoeef Uremia Alcohol Cocaine Opiun 1 1 lit I 1 I 1 1 Knoia or paranoid states* (•-depressive paychose --lit ia. preeoz 6 -I 10 51 58 m 28 ■ &gt; Psycho-neur Epilepsy Hysteria 16 21 .) 4 4 Psychaatbenia Organic diseai 1 1 I'.i i Blution melancholia e psycboaea (i 26 25 23 Imbecility Not insane 15 14 1 s Total 239 183 INEBRIATES AND DKCii HABITUES Men Women Total Ak-ohol :WH 9 Drug Habit :U § 42 Total 17 </seg>
            <seg id="p018">TABLE NO. 3 COCWTI1 ! \YH1&lt; H PATIENTS WERE ADMITTED Insane Inebriates and Drug Addicts Men Women Men Women Total Adam- 1 1 I'd n Antelope v ■ Bonne S • Box Butte 1 ' bVowa l ■ Buffalo 1 2 I Butler 1 -I 4 Boyd . 2 • '.i 4 8 ,, one :i : - i C.lfax 1 10 i! Custer fi v &gt; Dakota 1 ■ Dsvw 1 ■ ■ M Dixon 4 4 Dodge B B 24 1 « Douglas fi:'. M 48 3 IM „„„.!&gt; ■ Killmore 4 1 2 " Frontier 5 lift ■ Gage 13 I •&gt; 2 • Hall 10 2 I! Hamilton X 1 .!, 1 1 2 .... 4 B -d 5 Holt 1 • Jefferson 3 6 ii 4 4 16 M I\"l 111 </seg>
            <seg id="p019">HOSPITAL FOB INSANE, LINCOLN 14 ( .» Kearney - Knox 1 1 Lancaster 5H 15 K) 143 Madison l-» 14 Merrick. 4 ' ■'&gt; Nance... ' ' Nemaha -1 -' : &lt; Nurkolls.. -' 2 6 Hi Otoc « 9 1 lt( Pawnee -' -' - Phelpa 1 1 * l'ierce 1 4 l'latte -I '■&lt;&gt; Polk Red Willow 4 12 7 Richardson 9 12 Rock 1 I Saline 6 5 H 1 20 Sarpy 1 5 3 Saunden 15 9 5 Seward 10 2 5 1 18 Stantun ■ • 5 Scotta Bluff 6 1 7 Thayer 2 2 6 10 Thurstun 4 4 Washington •' Wayne s s Webster 11 - York 3 .... 7 in Thomas 1 ■ Total .. 23fl 183 397 17 PATIENTS AT THE LINCOLN BTATE HOSPITAL. NDVKMHKH -U) . 1906 Insane Inebriates and Drug Addict- Countic Men Women Men Women Total Adams 2 2 4 Antelope 1 </seg>
            <seg id="p020">I 150 ■&gt; I \ Box Butte.. 1 Brown 1 ' Buffalo I ' l II Butler 1 3 1 Cherry l Cheyenne 1 ('lav - : * ■: Coif ax 1 -' » Turning 1 1 Cuflter ' i ■&gt; Dakota ' 1 5 7 1 13 Dodge Douglai 47 s &lt;&gt; 11 Fillinorc -' •"&gt; 1 s •&gt; Franklin 1 1 1 Frontier 1 Furnas - :{ l Gage M 1&lt;» l GraeJey 1 l •&gt; i 1 Hall 1 . 1 Hamilton I •* &lt; 1 1 Holt | ¥ rr .Jefferson - 6 - s Johnson 1 8 2 •&gt; Kearney 1 ! Knox 3 3 Lancaster M 6 3 Madison 1 ) 1 Merrick 2 1 Nemaha -^ Nuckolls 1 4 II (Hoc 5 12 Pawnee 4 |6 1 Perkins 1 1 Phelps 2 3 ; </seg>
            <seg id="p021">151 HOSPITAL rOR INSANE, LINCOLN a 3 1 12 11 1 s 13 1 . 1 1 1 ,) 1 1 1 1 4 1 4 1 1 Y.Y2 4n Polk ■ &gt; Red Willow. 1 Richardson .) Saline I Sarpy •&gt; Saundere Sou aril Sheridan Sherman Thayer Thurston Yalle&gt; Washington Wayne Webster York... 1 I* n known T-.tal 17V 17«. TABLE NO. 4 \,,K- OF PATIENTS VDMITTKI) Insane [nebrifttea ami Drug Addicts Men Women Men Women 10 to l") 1 ■ 15 to 20 9 9 1 '':' _»() to - ) "» 22 18 17 - _».') to M) 25 25 44 M) to 35 30 20 51 3 '" 85 to 40 &gt;&gt; J&lt;i 7:i 3 '-■: 40 to 4.") 29 In 58 „, 4."&gt; to 50 _&gt;4 15 59 ,03 50 to 55 55 to 60 ■16 15 40 16 9 24 2 60 to 65 16 8 15 . ... 65 to &lt;0 70 to To 8 4 6 ti 9 2 1 : </seg>
            <seg id="p022">152 75 i 12 3 15 ■&gt; •&gt; Total 239 183 :W7 17 TABLE NO. 5 (IVIl. CONDITION &lt;)F PATIENTS ADMITTED Insane Inebriates and Drug Addicts Men Women Men Women Total Married Single W.i 98 232 14 447 11)1 :&gt;4 120 1 276 Widowed Divorced 1'nknown 24 25 24 1 74 5 •") 15 1 26 ti 1 ti 13 Total 2:w 183 :i«.)7 17 s:&lt;6 TABLE NO. 6 NATIVITY OK PATIENTS ADMITTED Insane Inebriates and Drug Addict Men Women Men Women Total Austria 4 1 • &gt; Belgium Bohemia 4 6 10 s Canada ■) 2 13 1 Denmark 1 1 5 « Kngland 6 L3 &lt; Finland 1 : France 1 German v 12 32 7:&lt; Greece •&gt; Holland 1 i Hungary 1 Italv 1 Ireland 5 6 11 •»■&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p023">153 1 1 Japan ■&lt; •&gt; Moravia Norway Persia 1 ■&gt; ••i ■&gt; N Russia : &gt; i Scotland Sweden M 12 15 « Switzerland United States Unknown ■&gt; :,7\ 157 132 270 12 4 l .,, 183 397 17 Total 239 TABU-: NO. 7 OCCUPATIONS OF PATIENTS ADMITTED Insane Inebriates and Drug Addicts Men Women Men Women Total Actor Artist 1 1 1 • ) Agents Bakers a ' 1 1 6 s Bartenders Blacksmith! Bar ben ■) 10 s A ■ &gt; Brokers Butchers 1 •i ■ ) .) &gt; 21 2S Carpenters i 1 Cattle buyers Clerks 1 25 1 lit .) Cigar Makers Collectors 1 1 I •&gt; 1 6 s Cooks I : Domestics Dentists 6 .i 1 ■) J Dressmakers Draymen 4 :i Druggists 5 </seg>
            <seg id="p024">154 iciana ■) 4 tationary •&lt; Engineer*, locomotive : leers, civil I Farmen T'.t 7 A Farm laborers »• 4 1(» tionarv. I en. locomotive 1 r :i \ • 1 pssmakera &gt; •) 4 \4'-i 13 I.tH Hotel-clerks 4 4 4.") sT 132 Irvmen 4 4 I i :5 3 ei 1 1 &gt; men 1 1 11 5 14 s .&gt; Merchants 1 14 Millers 1 1 4 :i &lt; l ; 19 1 ! 5 10 is 1 1 I'luint.. 1 ■) 3 iiers 1 1 Prim &gt; i Prostitute 1 1 Railncul laborers. ti ! Shoemakers. ,i ri agent 1 1 4 1 i lographers. . . 3 2 1 1 aphers 1 .... 4 111)1 1 O </seg>
            <seg id="p025">1 155 11 Traveling salesmen Tailors 3 1 1 Veterinary Burgeons Washwomen 1 13 lit ■&gt; No occupation Unknown 14 1 6 i 183 397 17 Total 239 TABI.K NO. CAU8ES OF Dt E \TH Men Women Total Acute Artic-ulav Rheumatism.. 1 ' Accident 1 ! Bronchitis ■ &gt; -' Brain tumors 1 1 Cerebral apoplexy Cerebral meningitis • ) 1 •&gt; Carcinoma of stomach 1 1 Carcinoma of uterus 1 ! Chronic nephritis I Enteritis ... o Endocarditis .1 ' Epilepsy Epithelioma of face Exhaustion of acute mania 1 2 ■&gt; Exhaustion of acute melancholia 1 1 Exhaustion of senile dementia. :&gt;, 1 * Exhaustion of delirium 1 ! Intestinal hemorrhage-ulcer. .! — - - - Organic brain disease Organic heart disease Secondary anemia Pneumonia ti 4 1 2 1 Paresis 12 •&gt; 14 Peritonitis Pulmonary tuberculosis Pvpmifl .... 2 ."&gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p026">156 Senility ti 8 Uremia I 1 2 Total -17 44 '.»1 TABLE NO. ( .t For the Year Ending November 30. 1907 I'M IT I. VTION Men Women Total No. of inmates present at beginning of fiscal year 303 345 "&gt;4^ No. received during the year 423 167 No. discharged or died during the year 412 176 No. at end of the fiscal year 214 336 Daily average attendance ii. c. No. of in- mates actually present) during the year 210 341 V&gt;1 Average No. of officers and employes during the year 42 52 M EXPENDITURES Current Ex| 1. Salaries and wages 136,851.10 2. Clothing 6.67 3. BubMtence 48,394.53 4. Ordinary repairs :&gt;. :•!.-)&lt;) si 5. Office, domestic and outdoor ex pense 16,159.59 Total $113,431 89 Extraordinary Expeni 1. New buildings, land, etc $2,067 71 2. l'ermanent improvements to exist ing Imildings 1.423 74 Total $3,491 4o Grand total $116,923 34 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">157 TABLE NO. K) For the Year Ending November 30. 1908 POI'l I. U'KIN Men Women I No. of inmates present at licgiiming of fiscal 2\A :«6 vear No. received during the year :&lt;4i) 109 14 ( .i No. discharged or died during the year ■V2~ 1 13 140 No. at end of fiscal year 221 XV2 Daily average attendance li. e. No. of in- mates actually present) during year 219 332 .551 Average No. of officers and employes during the vear 40 55 EXPENDITURES Current Expenses 1. Salaries and wages 137.072. 1-' 2. Clothing ■2.711 55 3. Subsistence. 53,276.09 4. Ordinary repairs 3.587.29 5. Office, domestic and outdoor e\ 6.935.39 |)ense Total $103,582.44 Extraordinary Kxpenses 1. New buildings, land, etc 2. Permanent improvements to exist - ing buildings 134.00 Total 134 00 (Irand total 1103.716 44 The Steward Makes Report Pertaining to the Product of the Farm and Garden r \ h m Corn 5,500 bushels 2.600 bushels </seg>
            <seg id="p028">158 eed 1,150 bushels straw SO tons ie hay 120 tons Alfalfa hay 420 tons Tune hay :m) tons Millet hay 70 tons Cane hay 45 tons 160 tons corn .")() bushels 2.000 bushels CATTLE \\I) H()(,&gt; butchered 87,122 pounds •'iitchereil 6.420 pounds butchered 16.6W pounds M)Aiin Total number galhrati milk 74.4&lt;&gt;"_' pllrwM milk 3,102 H 'Ions milk 10 lions milk 3,102 58 .lions milk 101 Mi crape |&gt;er cow 2.360 average |&gt;er cow 2.9M gallon gallons Dail pp number cows milked 4H Dail L'e numl&gt;er cows milked 4H poi 1. im From April _»:{. l'.tos to December 1. l*&gt;os f»s:&lt; dozen- :u»7i KS S'J GARDEN Kind Quantity Husliels Pecks Hunches Head:- Number Jl )( i 27 2 MTJ 26 H 2 •SIT 1 9821 M0 Cauliflower 707 1311 Cherries 2 2 Corn, sweet 127 2 1407 doz. ears </seg>
            <seg id="p029">159 Cucumbers.... 162 2 Dill stalks V, Kgg Plani ■) ■&gt; 148 Greene &gt; (ireen Peppers Jl 3 Horseradish •"&gt; -i Huckleberries 38 quarts Lettuce XV2 5798 &gt; Muskmelone (is Onions, old. '279 Onions, doz. hunches 747 Parsley 1 Parsnips. 115 1 Reaches 1 1 Peas 137 1 Peppers 3 206 - y Pickles :&lt;7 Potatoes I1W Potatoes, sweet 352 Pumpkinf S3 Radishes 74 1 '.»%:? Khut)iir»&gt; 144 &gt; 1297 Sage 4 Ibe. Salsify 16 ■*&gt; Spinach 4i Strawberries :&gt;M quarts Tomatoes, ripe. s_'l 3 Turnipt 652 Watermelons. n7 ( V8H RECEIVED KHilM 8 WE OP K\HM \ \ 1 &gt; ( UIDKN PKOliriT, Uli . Cattle Hogs Hide* Hay 1,355. 10 1,042 310.37 Millet Seed 744.42 Wheat 177.10 Pasture I06.50 Tomatoes Huard for Horace 28 m </seg>
            <seg id="p030">I. AND COMMISSIONERS REPORT $160. -TJ Iron (old) M . 87 </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>