<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00056.00009">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00056.00009</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>The Nebraska Farm Family Some Land Tenure Phrases</title>
               <date value="1923-02">1923-02</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-12</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Bulletin 185 February, 1923 The Nebraska Farm Family SOME LAND TENURE PHASES J. O. RANKIN TENANCY OFTEN A FAMILY AFFAIR ner furnishes the tenant son this good house. The family relationship of 45 Nebraska farm tenants to their landlords affects our tenancy problems greatly. AGRICULTURAL E*XPERIMENT STATION OF THE UNI- VERSITY OF NEBRASKA AND UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">SUMMARY BY LINES The (arm family is a most important factor in agriculture. Page Family relationship affects rental terms and is affected in many ways by tenure variation. Page 3. Nearly half the tenants are related to their landlords. Page 4 Xlost related tenants have practically as much interest in the com - munity as owners. Page 5. Such relationship reduces the number of farms on which tenure problems may become serious. Page 6. Harder bargains are driven and rental terms more strictly enforced when landlord and tenant are unrelated. Pages 7-9. Marriage runs high and i&gt;ercentages of single and divorced, low among farmers. Pages 9-11. Part-owners are most generally married and least generally widowed or divorced. Page 12. Western Nebraska farmers an&gt; a little more generally married th those of eastern Nebraska. Page 13. Hired men are low in percentage married and widowed but high ir percentage single and divorced. Page 14. Farmers average 40 years of age — owners 4.'.::, part-owners 4 and tenants 36.1. Page 15. The average age of farmers at marriage was 2&gt;&lt; year wives about 4 years less. Pages 16-1 x. Children per married farmer number 2.."&gt; — more in the western a fewer in the eastern areas studied. Page 18. Children away from home are largely those of owners. Pag Nearly half of the farmers and their wives were born in Nebraska and between a seventh and an eighth in foreign countries. Pages 20-23. Nine-tenths of the children were born in Nebraska, but many in other counties than those of present residence. Page 2:: Owners and tenants seem about equally well educated, but their wives have a little more school training. Page 2.".. Serious ill health has affected men more than their wives and part owners more than owners and tenants. Page 29. </seg>
            <seg id="p003">The Nebraska Farm Family SOME LAND TENURE PHASES 1 J. O. RANKIN The family is recognized as our most important social group because it is the basic unit of our society. Altho it is the sub - ject of countless volumes and briefer publications, few have dealt with the effects of country life in its various aspects upon the family. So it has seemed well to gather together such data on the subject as could be gleaned from surveys of about 1,145 Nebraska farm homes in the 10 selected areas shown in Figure 1. FIG. 1 — WHERE THE FACTS CAME FROM Theae areas represent a wide range of Nebraska conditions, but no radical tliffer - -neea in farm family characteristics. About 125 farms were studied in most areas •xcept that in Logan County and in the Fillmore area indicated by the cross which ras surveyed in cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement. Farm tenure and family relationship affect one another in many ways. One of the most obvious is the softening of the terms of the lease when the tenant is the owner's son, son-in-law, or other near relative. This is a case in which the family tie is the cause and a loosening of economic demands is the effect. In other cases economic factors are the causes and the farm family or the household feels the effect upon its health and education, upon age at marriage, and in innumerable other ways, as when lack of funds limits school advantages or causes overwork and ill health. 'Based mainly on the result* of a survey conducted in cooperation with Drs. C. J. Galpin and L. C. Gray of the Office of Farm Management and Farm Economics, United States Department of Agriculture, in 1920. The manuscript was read by a representa - tive of that office. Some data are included from a survey made in cooperation with the Interchurch World Movement in 1920. Acknowledgments are also due to Dr. George Elliott Howard and a number of other members of the faculty of the University of Nebraska, to tabulators, and to 1 or 2 field men in each of the area* for securing schedules. </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Nebraska Expkrimext Station Bulletin 185 TENANTS RELATED TO LANDLORDS Nearly half are related. — Nearly half (44.6 per cent) of the tenants studied in the areas shown in Figure 1 are related to their landlords. The vast majority of these related landlords these related landlords vast majority of ALL LANDLORDS RELATED TO TENAMT5 Landlords unrelated 273 ■ 55.4 201 I 40.9 «t 12.6 'Includes data from all areas surveyed except the Walthill area -Includes such relatives as uncles, grandparent*, and brothers-in proportionately divided between "landlords related" and "landlords un - related." are fathers, fathers-in-law, mot hers, or brothers of the tenants, but some are mothers-in-law, uncles, jrrandparents, or brothers - in-law, while one wife was reported as the landlord of the farm which her husband was operating. The landlords are rarely re - ported as being distant relatives of the tenants. 'Excluding the Walthill area because the presence of Indian lands rented to white tenants artificially increases the proportion of landlords unrelated to their tenant*, and distributing the unspecified proportionately between related and unrelated. FIG. 2. RELATIONSHIP OF LANDLORD TO TENANT Nearly half of all landlords are related to their tenants and more than half of the related landlords are either fathers or mothers of their tenants. Very few landlords rent to distant relatives. Table I. — Relationship of imuJlord t" tenant' All Share -rash Share Cash Number Percent Number Percent Number Prrrrtit Number Percent Ml landlords 4MB I 100.U M «.« 166 i S3.7 28 I 5.7 Landlords related 202 41.1 89 lri.l 97 19.7 16 | S.2 Father 96 19. i ;12 (.1 VI 11.6 7 1.4 Father-in-lkK ■ U 13 *.« I 17 3.5 2 0.4 Mother 20 4.1 12 4 (1.6 4 0.8 Mother-in-law 4 0.8 S 0.6 0 0.0 1 &lt;&gt;:&gt; Brother'- 7 1.4 4 0.8 &gt; I 0.6 0 0.0 Other near reUtiv* if 7.9 23 4.7 - 14 2.8 2 i 0.4 Distant relative 4 0.8 &lt; 2 0.4 2 0.4 0 I 0.0 Not specified' 41 8.3 I 26 5.3 | 12 2.4 3 0.S Landlord* related- 219 44.6 I 97 19.7 104 21.1 IX 3.8 </seg>
            <seg id="p005">The Nebraska Farm Family 5 There is no very wide variation from one part of the state to another in percentage of landlords found related to their tenants if we exclude the Fairfield-Clay Center and Stromsburg areas, where an unusually high proportion — nearly 3 tenants out of every 5 — are related to their landlords, and the Walthill area, where the presence of Indian lands introduces a feature that is not typical of any considerable portion of the state. In no other area studied is as low a fraction as one-quarter of the landlords related to the tenants. In the Cambridge area, largely inFurnas County, nearly 3 tenants out of every 5 are related to their land - lords, but in the Grant area in Perkins County, still farther west, the proportion is only 2 out of 5. It is thus impossible to say from the areas studied that as we go from the oldest eastern Ne - braska areas to the more recently settled western ones the per - centage of landlords related to tenants decreases. Perhap* a better way of suggesting the influence of length of time the area as been settled has upon the relationship phase of tenure is to MMMbr t lit- percentage of all farms operated by tenants related io their landlords. This is done on a later page. Kind of relationship.— Nearly half the related landlords are fathers of the tenants to whom they are related; more than venth arc their fathers-in-law, and about a tenth are their mothers. About 1 out of every 30 is a brother, and 1 out of every 50 a mother-in-law, leaving only 1 out of every 50 to be mtcd for as ;i distant relative and 1 out of 5 as moderately ly related, e. &gt;r.. an ancle, a grandparent, or a brother-in- aw. The father! and fathers-in-law seem even less inclined than ither related landlords to drive hard bargains with their son ,iikI son-in-law tenants if we may judge from the fact that they re the only '2 classes of relatives more than half of whom rent n a straight share basil instead of on either the share-cash or cash basis. This results, in part at least, from the fact that the southwestern areas practically all the related landlords ;ire either fathers or fathers-in-law and these are the areas in which greater percentage! of the tenants rent on a share basis, whether related or not. than in the eastern portion of the state. Related tenants as community members. — The fact that so great a majority of related landlords are fathers, fathers-in-law, or mothers of tenants makes it highly probable that in such eases the tenant or his wife will own the farm eventually and that during the period before ownership the tenant will enjoy most of the advantage* of tenancy with few of the disadvantages often charged against it. Such a tenant should have everv in- </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Xkukaska Experiment Station Ih ixetix 185 centive and take even* possible precaution to improve the farm and prevent soil depletion. He has doubtless in most rases grown up in the eomniunity and is hardly less a part of its activities than the owner operator of the same neighborhood. There is hardly less reason why the related tenant should take a vital interest in the school, church, and other community activities than he would if he already owned a farm whose finan - cial value and home uses they affected. He is in many ways an apprentice or owner on probation working under wise and sym - pathetic guidance on the farm which he has in many cases known and studied since his childh I. so that he can (jet better results from it than from one he does not understand so thoroly. He is already adjusted to the community and is able to fill his place in it with all the efficiency that his inherent ability makes possible. Real tenure problem on few farms. — It nearly half of Ne hraska's tenants are related to their landlords, the more acute tenure problems have been felt, so far at least, on only a rela - tively small fraction of the farms — that fraction not operated by owners, part-owners, or related truants, hut by tenants not re - lated to their landlords. As ."&gt;7.1 per cent are operated by own - ers, part-owners, and managers and 44.6 per cent of the remain - der, or lit.l per cent of all farms, by related tenants, the more acute tenancy problems, it seems reasonable to suppose, affect only the remaining 28.8 per cent of Nebraska's farms which are rented by unrelated tenants. The percentage should of course be greatly reduced by omission of a large but unknown percent - age of the unrelated tenants who have good landlords and fair contracts. A small but unknown portion of the owners are doubtless in difficulty because of having purchased their farms at too high prices. All mortgage indebtedness will become more trouble - some to owners should low prices of farm products continue long. Mortgage indebtedness that has not been burdensome in times of rising prices may introduce serious tenure problems should long-continued low prices come. Until that time, how ever, our serious tenure problems are largely, but not entirely, concentrated in the 23.8 per cent of farms operated by tenants not related to their landlords. Of these, doubtless only a small proportion operate under conditions which cannot be remedied by proper understanding of the problem on the part of both landlord and tenant. Until still further investigation can throw more light on the </seg>
            <seg id="p007">Tiik Nkiwaska Fa km Family 7 problem, it must remain a matter of personal opinion and con - jecture how many of the l!:i&gt; per cent of Nebraska farms oper - ated by tenants not related to their landlords fall into th.e "problem" class. Those who are unwisely or unfairly treated by their landlords, who are unduly victims of misfortune, or who lack thrift constitute a problem. It is to be hoped that the vast majority even of the unrelated tenants are not in the prob - lem class, but that they are fairly treated, thrifty, and using tenancy as a healthy means of attaining ownership as rapidly as a limited supply of farm land will permit. Society has a right to demand that a farmer prove his fitness to use land efficiently before full ownership gives him full control over an absolutely ential but limited and valuable resource. FIG. 8.— EFFECTS OF RELATIONSHIP ON CONTRACT The closer the relationship the leu likely the share-cash contract is to be made or Uy enforced. Relationship and rental terms. — Among tenants related to their landlords, nearly half have share contracts and over 2 out of every 5 have share-cash agreements, while 1 out of every 9 rents for cash. Among unrelated tenants, more than 2 contracts out of every :i are on the share-cash basis. Share-cash tenancy contracts are thus much less frequently found among tenants related to their landlords than among those not so related. This is true in every area studied. In case of this relationship, strictly economic phases of the rental terms appear to be partly submerged in the family relationship. There appears to be a greater tendency toward the feeling that the tenant should not bear the burden of fixed cash payments regardless of bad crop years or unfavorable markets. Cash tenancy on the other hand is almost as frequent among related as among unrelated tenants, but in some instances at least the related landlord administers the cash contract quite liberally. That share tenancy without cash payment for any portion of the farm is predominant among the related tenants but rather </seg>
            <seg id="p008">8 Nebraska Experiment Station Bvixetix 185 S — ooewooie ci- o ' £ = "^ l « »OMRce» c- o -C a i s "■* i ""°" b « ••- - j i X I c i ■^ 1 I | S 83SSS8'« Sg I \ = M- 1 I S^S^i^ m I !l jffSiiii ■§■£££§§£ els a -4 z Il|5J|f]i|i| I I ii " 8 - ■ i I { « S2"S=2= *4 g rh - 1 i ■ I assists :&gt;i 3!*i!ii*x. I </seg>
            <seg id="p009">The Nebraska Farm Family 9 exceptional 8010111; the tenants not related to their landlords is suggesed by what has already been said. This statement is not without local exception. In harmony with it the Grant area in Perkins County has 19 out of 20 related tenants operating on a straight share basis ; but 2 out of every 3 unrelated tenants are also working under the same type of contract, because the type of farming here makes the share tenancy seem best in an un - usually large proportion of cases regardless of relationship or absence of relationship. The hay and pasture lands are doubt - less the main things for which eastern Nebraska share-cash tenants are paying cash rent, but in the southwestern Nebraska FARMERS NEBRASKA: 1900 AREAS SURVEYED: 1920 FARM LABORERS NEBRASKAM900 AREAS SURVEYED.I920 Married FIG. 4.— IS THE SINGLE FARMER BECOMING RARER? data at hand suggest but do not prove that the marriage rate ii rifting among i farmrrs. areas hay and pasture are relatively less important and are so :-heap that often no separate cash charge is made for them. In the Polk County area near Stromsburg, only 1 out of 3 even of the related tenants is on a share basis, and in the Gage County area near Filley about 12 miles east of Beatrice the pro - portion is only about 1 out of every 4, as compared with 4 out of 5 in the Nehawka area in Cass County, 3 out of 5 in the Milli- gan area in Fillmore County, and more than 3 out of 5 in the Cambridge area in Furnas County, — in spite of the farther west - ern location of this last-named area. MARITAL CONDITION Marital condition of operators. — Of the 1.044 farmers studied, 1,033 are men and 11 are widowed women. Of the men, 893 are married. 108 single, 28 widowed, and 4 divorced. These </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Nebraska Experiment Station- Bm.i.etix IM * &lt; i ■/-. r. 3 3 1! 53 ?J X &gt; ca c tc n — X ri I sss- si - : » ; - : - : • tj -;i X T. ? &lt;. 1 a s^ J ■■ j I §| M i?: [- *&lt;• - | I T E C I i ri J i I ! t P M yji^Jllinti fin Jii ti 7 * M. .2. _|j s$ = z t* s?s ■« is ■*■ Hi* s </seg>
            <seg id="p011">The Nebraska Farm Family 11 proportions agree remarkably closely with those of the Twelfth Census, taken 20 years earlier. It is true that the figures of the present survey show only two-thirds as high a percentage single as do the 1!HK&gt; census figures, but the earlier figures include with the single all whose marital condition was unknown. In the present survey not a single ease was left thus unknown. Farm laborer figures for the 2 periods are not in such close ogreement. The 1920 survey shows that three-fourths are single us compared with more than nine-tenths in 1900.' Divorce rates PER CENT 20 30 40 SO 60 70 80 90 100 ALL FARMERS OWNERS PART-OWNERS TENANTS SHARE-CASH SHARE CASH HIRED MEN ZO 30 fcO 50 60 70 80 90 100 fiBB Momed gggg Single VZZ&amp; Widowed m Divorced FIG. 5. FARMING AS A MARRIAGE COMPELI.ER ix out uf every 7 farm operators studied are married, but the proportion is lex 1 out of every 4 among hired men. f-ein to Ix rising very slightly among operators, but quite rap - lly among farm laborer*, both per 100,000 total population and per KM).(M)l) married population, if the numbers included in the 1920 survey can be regarded as great enough to be significant. All the :&gt; divorced hired men and :5 of the 4 divorced farm opera - tors were reported from the Thurston County area. Divoree rates in the I'nited States are generally higher in counties having most of their population in cities of 100.000 or over, and they are rising more rapidly in such counties than in 'Including "unknown" whose number is unspecified. Occupations U. S. Census 1900. 328. </seg>
            <seg id="p012">NkHKASKA Exi'KMMKXT STATION Hi l.l.KTIN 1 *."&gt; 12 those whose population is rural or is in smaller cities. In Ne - braska, this large city divorce rate has been outrunning that of the open country and smaller cities more rapidly than in any other state except Iowa. 1 The percentage of farm operators married average 85.5 and vary from about 80 in the Logan and Thurston County areas and 82 in the Milligan (Czecho-Slovak) and Cans County areas to about 87 in the Polk (Swedish) and Perkins County areas, 89 in the Gage County area, and 91.3 in the Furnas County area. TVn.n All linn Part- Mana r e twners ■&lt;h«r.- AU mk Shan- Cash Per cent 10.4 Average age, yearm . ... 2S.9 2K.5 .14. h Divorced Number 4 Per cent 0.4 0. I Average age. years. 42.5 ' !«.' 'Includes 11 widowed women who are farm operators with the aid of the : Part-owner« are farmers who own part of the land they operate and rent add tional land from others to farm with their own. The census classification of tenants is followed here. The share tenant pays for the use of the land a fixed fraction of the product. The cash tenant makes a fixed payment regardless of the sixe of crop he happens to raise. The share-cash tenant pays a share for some of his land and cash for a part usually for the pasture or hay Tenure and marital condition. — Part-owners are more gen erally married than either owners or tenants, the single and widowed each constituting a larger percentage of both awaen and tenants than of part-owners. More than 3 times as lar;re a percentage of tenants as of part-owners are single, and even owners are less rarely single than part-owners. The owners are ■Marriage and divorce: 1867-1906. I. 18-19. U. S. Census Bureau Tabu: \.-.\&lt;je m&lt;&lt;l umritnl condition of operator, Number' Avenge age. years . 1.044 40.0 M ! 45.3 169 40.8 m 36.1 *81 ' 1W :it.i MJ 6S 3«. ilarried Number Per cent Average age, years . Age at marriage. . - . ■I 8S.5 I I" - 26.1 ■I i 87.2 I 46.5 149 93.6 41.5 26.2 410 81.4 :i?.ti m : 2M 131 K5.0 77.4 H.1 36.8 25.S ■ :(7. 25. Vidowed 1 Number Per cent Average age, yean . Age at marriage 39 3.8 SO 2 2«.6 m «.4 M.I K 2 1.3 5S.5 23.5 M 2.6 45.8 « | 2.1 .1.0 46.1 38.6 t».. 27.5 2 3. «2. 29. •ingle , Number 1 108 22 8 Trt ■ 32 </seg>
            <seg id="p013">The Xkhka&gt;ka Farm Family 13 about •") times as frequently widowed as the part-owners and -Mo times as frequently as the tenants. Share-cash tenants are more generally married than either share or cash tenants. Divorce &gt;f&lt;'iiis equally common among owners and tenants, but no very positive generalization on this point should be based upon so few cases. Among the 139 part-owners none are divorced altho nearly a fifth of them are living in an area that furnished most of the divorce reports among owners and hired men. These differences in percentages married are hardly ex - plainable entirely on the basis of either age or economic well - being, or both combined. The part-owners with an average age nt' nearly forty-one years are -I 1 " years younger than the owners and nearly ."» yars older than the tenants, yet they are even more generally married than the owners, whose age and eco - nomic condition might lead one to expect them to be more gen - erally married than either of the other 2 classes. Even when we add to the percentage of the owners married a very high percent- widowed resulting in part from the presence of widowed romen among owner operators, we still have not as high a per - entage of owners who ever have been married as we find among younger, less well-to-do part-owners. This very high percentage married and low percentage widowed among part-owners suggests unusual physical vigor, good health, and longevity on the part of both the part-owner nd his wife. Such morbidity data as were secured, however, do show thai part-owners are freer from serious illness than &gt;ther tenure classes. Marriage more general in western Nebraska. — The percent married operators appears to be greater in the western than in the eastern areas, but this rule is not without exception. In the N'ehawka and Walthill areas in Missouri River counties about 4 owners out of every "t are married, as compared with more than !• out of every 1(1 in the Cambridge area and more than 5 out of every (i in some of the intermediate areas. In fad the areas may be said to fall into 2 groups; (1) one in which about 4 out of every 5 operators are married and (2) one in which the proportion is about 9 out of every 10. In the first group fall the Neliawka. Walthill. Milligan, and Stapleton areas, while in the second fall the other areas. The sandhill area Widowed most variable -The term "widowed"' as used wives are dead and women whose here includes both men whom stands a little below any otht </seg>
            <seg id="p014">Nebraska Experiment Station Hi ij.etin 1H."&gt; 14 husl&gt;ands arc dead. The percentages widowed in the different areas range from 1.5 in the Filley area in (iage County to f&gt;.7 in the Xehawka and Milligan areas in (ass and Fillmore Counties. respectively. Perhaps the numbers included are too small to serve as the basis of any generalization. Certainly it is difficult to see any geographic regularity in their variation. In every area except one the owners have a higher percentage widowed than any other class. Not a part-owner is reported as widowed except in the Stromsburg and Grant areas in Polk and Perkins Counties. Single operators by areas. The single operators rang.' from Cambridge area to over 1"&gt; per 6.:J per cent of the total in the cent in the Stapleton and Walthill areas in Logan and Thurston Counties. In every area except that about Stapleton in Logan County the unmarried or single include higher percentages of the tenants than of either the owners or the part-owners. In every area, share-cash tenants have smaller percentages of single operators among their number than either cash or share tenants, perhaps because the unmarried tenant is more likely to be re - lated to the landlord. He is perhaps more likely to be h son still living at home but renting from his father or mother. We have already seen that the share-cash contract is l&lt;-ss frequent among tenants related to their landlords. HIRED MEN Tenure of employers. — Part-owners most generally have hired men and owners least generally have them, the tenants standing in an intermediate position. Only about 1 out of every respectively. Taiii.k "i. — l'&lt; •■!■&gt; '■&lt; -ntiii/i mf "/" i-nttirx xnmlt . All I fc» n&gt;r - Part owners Starr- Canty Town All (wk ! Stare 1 1 All ..^....;. '*•* *•* *■' 15 - s ll " s '•-• Cms Nctawta I2.i Z.Z 10.0 20.3 18.2 22.2 Cl»y FmirtWd 7.S 0.0 «.2 II. I 8.7 20.0 Gaar Filley 8.8 4.5 7.2 11.8 9.2 18.2 Fillmon- Millicsn 12.3 10.5 0.0 17.6 lti.T 21.4 Polk Stromnburg 8.8 2.1 0.0 1T..I 9.8 28.6 Thuraton Wmlthill 15.3 10.4 6.9 21.1 22.2 27.3 Southwestern Ncbrmnk* Furnu rmmbridfv i.3 4.7 M 9.7 9.1 13.S Prrlnnx Grant 9.4 0.0 (.2 17.3 11.1 17.1 Loan.. StapU-t.m 13.1 SJ ».O 8.7 ».» t.S ; Cadi m M 33.3 0.0 66.7 18.2 •.0 so.o M </seg>
            <seg id="p015">Tiik Nkiihaska Farm Family 15 ■ '&gt; even of t In* part-owner*, however, lias a lured man, as com - pared with 1 tenant out of every 4Vs» or 2 out of every it. and 1 owner out of every 7. The hired men. then, seem to be dis - tributed among operators of the various tenures on the basis of average size of farm, since the part-owner has both a greater average total acreage and a greater tilled acreage per farm than cither the owner or the tenant. Marital condition. — The married hired men are even more coventrated on farms of part-owners. 1 part-owner out of every 11 having a married hired man as compared with 1 tenant out of every MO and 1 owner out of every 40. The part-owner is l' L . ti mi's as likely as a tenant to have a hired man of some kind and I times hs likely to have a married hired man. This same part - owner is about twice as likely as the owner to have a hired man of some kind, but nearly 4 times as likely to have a married iri'&lt;) man as the owner. AGE OF OPERATORS AND THEIR WIVES Average age. — The average age of farm operators is 40 years. This includes no retired farmers, but does include some whose sons are doing the work because of the father being crip - pled or in poor health or for some other reason retaining control and financial responsibility without doing the work. It also includes a few widowed women who have control and financial responsibility, but whose sons do part or all of the farm work. In the various areas the average ages of operators of the differ - ent tenure groups usually vary only about a year — usually much less — from the general averages for those of the same tenures in all areas combined. The exceptions are the Cambridge and Mil - ligan area averages of 42.6 and 33.2 years, respectively. The (irant area, still farther west than Cambridge, shows an average of only 40 years and in general there is no apparently conclusive hasis for asserting any general tendency toward either higher or lower ages as we go from east to west in the stale. Age and tenure. —The :&lt;74 owners average 45.:J years of age, the 157 part-owners 40.8. and the 501 tenants 36.1. Share ten - ants average nearly 3 years younger than cash and share-cash tenants, perhaps in part because so many of them are sons of owners. The Fairfield and Milligan areas show a much greater difference than the differences just stated between the ages of (1) part-owners and tenants on the one hand and (2) part-own - ers and owners on the other hand. In the Cambridge and </seg>
            <seg id="p016">Nebraska Experimknt Station Biixetix 18."&gt; 16 Stromsburg areas these differences are somewhat greater but iu the Filley area they are much less than the average difference. In the "Walthill area the part-owners and tenants art' almost identical in age. In the Kehawka area the 10 part-owners have reached only 30 years of age, while the 64 tenants average 39.1 ; but the Grant area just reverses this, with 48 part-owners who average 44.7 years as compared with 4'IM years fur the 27 own - ers in that area. Managers average 33.4 years of age and hired men :!1 years. Among the married hired men, those on tenants" farms are much older (44.4 years) than those on the fa tins of either part-owners (35.4) or owners (32). The single hired men on tenants' farms. however, are younger (29.6) than those on part-owner--' &lt; :{4.(i but a little older than those on owners' 28.5) farms. Age and marital condition. —Married farmers average 4&lt;&gt;!» years old, or over l'fj times as old as single ones (29.9 years . but only about four-fifths as old as widowed operators i50.2 years). Of the 39 widowed operators. M are men, but 11 are women operating farms with the aid of sons and sometimes oP hired help also. Of these widowed women operating farms, ti are owners and 4 are tenants. Of these 4. :! are share-cash ten - ants. The widowed women average 4ti years of agfl and in every case sons are living in the home altho in some instances part of the work is done by hired men. In one ease the only son years old. and there is no other help reported. The 4 far who report themselves as divorced average al&gt;out a year a half older (42.5 years) than the married farmers. Age at marriage. — The operators who are inarrit nearly 26 years of age at time of marriage and their wivei i little over 22. Owners, part-owners, hired men. and managers all averaged about 26 years of age at tune of marriage, but ten - ants averaged only about 25. The owners" wives were nearly '2'A years of age when mar - ried, part-owners' wives a little over 22. and tenants" and hired men's wives nearly 22, while managers' wives were less than 20 years old at time of marriage. The owners were thus less than half a year older than the part-owners and a little more than a year older than the tenants at the time of marriage. It is diffi - cult to say what significance, if any. should be attached to these differences. It may be that the figures should be regarded as indicating a more or less well-defined land owning class in which marriage is a little later in life. If so. further analysis of the </seg>
            <seg id="p017">The Nebraska Farm Family 17 f ALL FARMERS THEIR WIVES OWNERS THEIR WIVES PART-OWNERS THEIR WIVES ALL TENANTS THEIR WIVES SHARE-CASH THEIR WIVES SHARE THEIR WIVES CASH THEIR WIVES MANAGERS THEJR WIVES Age at ma fig ACE AT MARRIAGE AND AT PRESENT now and wms a little older at time of marriage than the part - ■ is a difference of about 4 yean in age between husband and Th ..III. I h if. how that those who art- now tenants on their lata might ■then* farms also married later in life than the tenants who ire not of this land owning class. Age of operator at marriage. Area averages almost iden- ical with tlie average for all areas are shown by the (ia&lt;re, </seg>
            <seg id="p018">18 NeHUA.SK A KXPEKIMKXT STATION Ul'IXETIN 18.*» Thurston, Logan, and Perkins County areas. The Furnas County area, however, shows a higher average age at marriage than any other area studied — 27.6 years. Of the two areas populated mainly by those of immediate foreign descent, the Swedish area stands above all other areas except 2 and the Czeeho-Slovak area stands l&gt;elow all others except 1. Wives 4 years younger.— The married operators an- 4 years older than their wives. The difference is greatest in owners' homes (4.6 years) and almost exactly the same among part - owners as among tenants. The difference is a little greater (4.4 years) among share than among share-cash (:i.8) and cash (3.9) tenants. Among hired men the difference is nearly 6 (.").8&gt; years and among managers more than S (8.4) years. The greatest differences occur in the Fillmore County area about Milligan and in the Logan County &lt;&gt;r sandhill area, but the Cms and Thurston County areas also stand above the average. The Polk County area, peopled mainly by farmers of Swedish descent, stands almost exactly at the average of all areas and so does the Perkins County area — the westernmost studied. Years married. — Married operators have been married 15.1 ears, the owners 19.2, the part-owners 15.3, and the tenants 11.7 •ears. The share-cash tenants have licen married a year longer 12.3) than the cash tenants (11.3) and nearly a year and a half onger than the share tenants (l().!»i. The Clay County area •perators have been married longer (17.4 years i than those in ny other area, due to the unusual length of time the owner •perators of this area have been married — 2(i years, or more than twice as long as the tenants of the area. Wives and housekeepers — Of 1,844 farmers, 693 or nearly !» out of every 10 are married. Part-owners are much more gen - erally married than owners or tenants in both eastern and west em Nebraska areas, but in the southwestern areas the tenants are distinctly higher than the owners and only slightly below part-owners in percentage married. The westernmost or Grant area has the highest percentage married, while the area about Milligan stands lowest but has the greatest number of house - keepers other than wives. A number of other eastern Nebraska areas show percentages married not very different from that of the Milligan area and stand with it in the group in which between four-fifths and five-sixths of the operators are married. Children. — There are 2.211 children in the homes studied, or an average of 2.5 among the 8!*.") homes in which wives are pres </seg>
            <seg id="p019">1'iik Nkhkamka Farm Family 19 ••lit. Almost without exception the number of children per family increases ;is we $;&lt;i from the eastern to the western areas — from 2.2 per family in the Xehawka and Walthill areas in the Missouri River counties and 2.:] in the Cambridge area in Furnas County to :{.-") in the Grant area in Perkins County. These figures for the individual areas include all children of these operators, whether now at home or not, but include only living children. Only -i'.\] children of these homes are now living elsewhere. Owners have slightly larger families than part-owners, the tenants coming much further behind with only 2.4 children per married tenant as compared with 3.4 per married owner. This in about the relative showing that might be expected when we remember that owners and part-owners are older and have been married much longer than tenants. Number per family and per household. — The figures just stated show an average family of 4.5, if the 331 children who have left home be excluded in order that we may determine the number actually living in each house. Other members of the household besides the natural family were almost negligible under l!t20 conditions. In 1920 the rural population of the I'nited States showed an average of 4.5 persons per family and l.ti per dwelling, while the urban figures were 4.4 and 5.1, re - spectively. In the West North Central group of states, of which Nebraska is one, the rural figures for 1910 were 4.5 and 4.6 and the urban figures 4.4 and 5.1, respectively, but by 1920 each of these 4 figures had decreased a little. 1 Both the family and the household become larger as we go from eastern to western Nebraska areas, as a result of the facts just noted that (1) the number of children is greater and (2) wives are more generally present. This combination of influ - ences is offset in some slight degree in the southwestern area by the total absence of parents of either operators or their wives and the practically entire absence of other relatives, hired girls, or other members of the household besides the husband, wife, and children. Children not at home. — Of the 331 children who have gone from the 1.034 homes to reside elsewhere, 169 are sons and 162 are daughters. Of these, 226 are the children of owners, 42 of part-owners, and 65 of tenants. Of the sons, 130 are farmers, 5 are teachers, and 3 are clerical workers, while the other 31 are engaged in miscellaneous or unspecified occupations. Of the Thirteenth Onsun jf the United State.. 1910 Volume 1. 1286-1290. Fourteenth Onuun of the United States. Population : 1920. Dwelling! and Famili** </seg>
            <seg id="p020">20 Nebraska Kxi-kkimkm Station Bulletin 1S3 daughters, 131 are housekeepers, 23 teachers, :$ clerks of one kind or another, and 5 are engaged in miscellaneous occupations, including a home demonstration agent employed by a county farm bureau. * All of the sons and two-thirds of the daughters who are teaching school are the children of owners. All but 1 of the clerical positions are also held by the children of owners, but only 6 clerical positions are reported among the entire :{:&gt;1 chil - dren now living away from home. Most of these children not now at home arc adults who have established homes of their own or secured employment which took them away from their parents' homes, but '1 are the son and daughter of a widow living with their grandmother while the mother operates a farm. Of the sons. '1 are employed in garages. 1 is a blacksmith. '1 are bankers. 1 works in a sugar factory. 1 is a merchant. 4 are engineers. "J arc 1920 in the Army, 1 an insurance man. 1 an electrician, 1 a county surveyor. 1 a dentist. 1 a baker, and "_' arc salesmen, while still others are carpenters, masons, and farm hands. One son and '1 daughters are reported as away from home attending college or university but probably most of those away from home attending sehoa are regarded as still living in the household. BIRTHPLACE OF PARENTS AND CHILDREN Birthplace of farmers and their wives. -About a h'ttl farmers were born in the counties in which thev ai In the eastern Nebraska areas this is true of about but in the southwestern areas of onlv about 1 ou1 of every I'll 25 farmers. More than a quarter were born in other coun Nebraska, nearlv two-fifths in other states, and mark in foreign countries. The principal tenure variation from these genera] aver is shown by the birth of nearly a fifth of the owners in for countries. In percentage born in the county in which they ar now farming, owners, part-owners, and tenants are all very close to the general average. The foreign-born percentage is nearly twice as high among owners as among tenants, with part-owners about midway between the i&gt;: the :\ are practically identical in percentage born in the county in which they are now t'armin but tenants stand highest in percentage born elsewhere in Nebraska. In the Stromsburg area in Polk County, where the popula tion is very largely of Swedish descent, only a quarter of </seg>
            <seg id="p021">The Nkhkaska Farm Family 21 — XN« XX — ?i~ mm *§:: SJ" li?3 liF6j&amp;3J&amp;6f Its H a! 5 O &amp; i c I life i JiL M 7. = tff © X ||i SS = S HI ids 3 !fi M ■* t- S55 ~ — — rr t: x c-. t- -r •ft is?i ;«*■ ::3^ S5S ;2S W i-r:x c! x x nooei m-*- ? — — - SS? =£8 8S2 f~rr — ■- - i|| 5S:E C iC « 99 « X « » •* K5 2 •1 \i\ = li — .-..- .t — ?l o: — tn ot-« onc&gt;) 111 &gt;^ 5 i!5 «H i " X T t - !- X « o ■* ■* n «r 80 « 3SS SSSSSS- ■i 1 — ! L i r ! ill •* &lt; HI §2S — XX o s o -It^ie — A r- n — t- . — « x » — T. M «Oi» — — SSO t-XW jOOtt-t-t"* — - ? » -x:i:i:iri ic-*w -;.-' — — -r » i -' x x r* n - t~ l- is t- - </seg>
            <seg id="p022">22 -^ KHR A S K A Yj X I 'Kit I M K N I ATM 'N' 1*1 1 .1 .1. 1 IN 1 N. i farmers are foreign-born; while in the Million area, where Bohemian or Czecho-Slovak farmers predominate, between a third and two-fifths of each tenure class are foreign-born, as their settlement in this region is more recent. In southwestern Nebraska less than a twentieth of the farm - ers and their wives were born in the county of present residence. but the percentage of foreign born is also very low. Two men out of every ■"&gt; in these areas were born in other Nebraska coun - ties, leaving nearly half of them to be accounted for as coming from other states; but the women just reverse these proportions, as nearly half of them were born in other Nebraska counties and 2 out of every •"&gt; came from other states of the I'nitcd St;et''&gt;. This seems to indicate a tendt marry afterward and for wome ■ncy for men to move first am n to move less than men befor they are married. Twice as many of the men as of the women were born in foreign countries. After marriage, however, shorter migrations were by no means ended, as indicated by the fact that nearly half the children were born in counties other than those of their presefit residence. In the eastern Nebraska areas studied, nearly 1 farmer out of every •"&gt; is foreign-born, as compared with 1 out of every 7 for the state as a whole and about 1 out of every 1:? in thi' southwestern Nebraska areas studied. In the eastern Nebraska areas the foreign-born include about 1 out of every 4 owners. but only about 1 out of every 7 part-owners and tenants, while BOm ' ' H 'X5E.E: '*"""' BORN ELSEWHERE IN NEBRASKA 70 — itirrm _ ?o TtMOWTS TENANTS FIG. 7. -BORN IN NEBRASKA Nearly half of the men and their wives and nearly nine-tenths of the children wer &gt;orn in Nebraska. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">Thk Nkhraska Farm Family ■_»:» in the southwestern Nebraska areas the foreign-born constitute almost twice as great a percentage of the part-owners as of cither owners or tenants but are found less frequently among all tenure groups than in eastern Nebraska. Doubtless this concentration of the foreign-born in the owner and part-owner groups occurs in part because the foreign - born arc largely among the older members of the community and in part because many come from countries where land owner - ship is so greatly desired and standards of living are so efficient as to enable them to attain land ownership here rather readily. The foreign-born women, on the other hand, are the wives of the foreign-born part-owners rather than of foreign-born owners or tenants, as only half of the foreign-born owners have foreign - born wives as compared with -i out of every 4 foreign-born part - owners. N IN OTHCR STATES THAN NEBRASKA BORN IN OTHER COUNTRIES *• Mf I IS LC«H FIG. ».- BORN IN OTHER STATES OR COUNTRIES A little greater proportion of men than of women were born in other states or in Birthplace of children. — The children in these farm homes naturally differ from their parents in that (1) less than 1 per cent of them were born in foreign countries, (2) less than 10 per cent were born in other states, and (3) much larger percent - ages were born in the counties in which they now live and else - where in the state of Nebraska. In eastern Nebraska more than half of the children were born in the counties in which they now live. The fraction is not far from half in each important tenure group except that 7 out ill 8 1 1 1 III) II l( IIJI.ll.ll TENANTS TtNANTS </seg>
            <seg id="p024">24 Nkhi:a&gt;ka Experiment Station Hi i.i.etix 185 of every 10 children of part-owners were born in the county of present residence. This fact, coupled with the additional one that a quarter of the part-owners' children were l&gt;orn elsewhere in Nebraska and not a single one in any foreign country, leaves only 1 out of every 25 to be accounted for as horn in other countries or not definitely specified as born in Nebraska. In the southwestern Nebraska areas only about 1 child out of every 10 was born in the county of present residence, 3 out of every 4 were born elsewhere in Nebraska, and about 1 out of every 7 in some other state of the United States. There is very little variation from these figures in the chief tenure groups, the most striking variation being that nearly twice as great a per - centage of the share-cash tenants' children were born in the counties of present residence «s in ease of those of the other operators. The Fairtield-Clay (enter area figures agree reasonably closely with those of eastern Nebraska areas in general except that only about 15 per cent of the owners' children were born in the county of present residence, nearly three-fourths of them being born elsewhere in Nebraska and about 1 out of every 8 born in other states. Nearly four-fifths of the part-owners' children were born in the county of present residence altho t-ie part-owners have been married as long as the others in this area. In the Stromsburg area 5 out of 6 children were born in the county of present residence and practically all the rest were born elsewhere in Nebraska, only 5 being reported as born in any other state and not one in a foreign country altho the opera tors in this area are very largely of Swedish birth or descent. Much the same may be said of the children of the Milligan area. where the people are mainly of Bohemian or Czechoslovak origin, except that the tenants here report 1 out of every 12 of their children as born in foreign countries and 1 out of every 24 as born in some state of the T'nited States other than Nrhnwkl Only 1 of the 157 children of owners and part-owner! In this area was born in any other state and not 1 in a foreign country. These 2 communities of people of more immediate foreign origin than the others certainly cannot be accused of too fre - quent or radical shifting of location. These 2 areas are to be contrasted sharply with the more distinctly American but much newer Grant area in Perkins county, where only 2 children of the entire 322 found were born in the county, 68 being born in other states and the remainder elsewhere in Nebraska. The Filley area in (rage County shows a higher percentage of the </seg>
            <seg id="p025">The Nebraska Farm Family 25 children of operators of all tenure groups born in the county than any other area studied. Birthplace of hired man and his family. — The 188 farm laborers were largely in the eastern Nebraska areas studied. The Cass County area near Nehawka not far from the Missouri River had one-fifth of them. Altho the hired men were largely living in the regions in which the operators and their wives were to the greatest extent born in the same state and county in which they are now residing, 65 of the 188 or more than one - third were born in other states, or 59 or a little less than one - third were born in other Nebraska counties, and 14 or 7.4 per cent were born in foreign countries. This leaves only 35 or less than a fifth who were born in the county of present residence. Only 36 of the 188 hired men were married. Of their wives, '2'2 or more than three-fifths were born in other states and only 4, or 1 out of every 9, in the county of present residence. An - other ninth were born elsewhere in Nebraska, 1 out of 12 in a foreign country. of the 90 children in the homes of hired men, 36 or exactly two-fifths, were born elsewhere in the State, 30 or one-third were born in other states, and only 1 was born in a foreign country. This leaves only about a quarter born in the county of present residence. These figures indicate, as one might anticipate, that both the married and unmarried life of the hired man have been somewhat migratory and that the migrations have in a consid - erable percentage of the cases been greater than merely across county lines but that they have rarely been across the national boundaries. Mere mental instability or lack of encumbering property or other ties may lead to short migrations when accom - panied by only the most moderate physical and mental energy and economic resources. Longer migrations are, however, usually undertaken only by individuals or families of more than ordinary mental and physical vigor or of economic resources above the average. EDUCATION Operators and their wives. — There seems to be very little difference in the general average of education among farm oper - ators of the various tenure groups. Part-owners and their wives do fall a little — but only a little — below both owners and tenants and their wives. The men are reported as having com- </seg>
            <seg id="p026">,'C. I X z I I aazoaa ■». i &gt;■■ ; ii| SSS2SSSSSS2 25 "M ? r K c at ei.c«a-n&gt; x I - I I *1°, h :*.t o . B i ™ I I xx oiot xV oa tc x x x «: c I E •'♦"'••"•W" t-' ad «' as x' « x t^ x' « i- 2 XI- ■&lt;■ » -: 4 1 "i i ■ ! i •*«=&gt;. =.9=.=. «». E .£ oeoco or-&gt;i oo i | c —o« 3000 oo S I J »£:2 ««odoe s'e ._ c- c»* o' o* x x x !-' «' =' a x x 1 181 — 0 I S t- — t-. =&gt; O © 99 » t- O O # « O ( - i- t- — t - x x sc t^ x t - ;i- 1*1 " «g t»x»x»»'x«'»^ xV jm I | tS-vXXX-FSONSn OO 1 ! =■ ! xxt^oixt^ait-'x'aJt- xw jg liuixbiVi'a'x .i I _ I g &gt; 1 !ojt-«kOW5X — S O « O - 1 1 &gt; i s. Z . . • ■ • • • • • ■ • • • * I - ! In,,,, ■ </seg>
            <seg id="p027">The Nkhra.ska Farm Family ■27 O O O N u)Ot0O9)t"OOOOO -rir'r-^ioei-t^ocxdoo^t^act-' »NXO»-;)«X01iO'»U)U5'»» t C — T i r? Tji us « «j x i- O5 ai o »' o ai t- x OOSiSt-00x»N«NntDMn«X ti rf L j / i B^j m _J B L*J '^i— jj «»iOUSO"*"fNNTfiO-'*»a31X y- i I » V 2 g -HNso^uswtoc^oooooios'osoJoioJo S£SS?gSSsSg£S£S££g2 «• &lt; ro i-x3ia-&lt;Nn»io»t-xaio- •mn &lt; 5 I N«M« NM«N«K«MH t-ce^*-H©«D«&gt;o»ooqc^jaO'&lt;(i;oooooooq ** cj tc co oi u= in o t- ?o — 10 « o i&gt; ■ -g rr — r: r: u; ■-£ i- 1^ x d oi » x d oi 5 -5 oc to © — to to m &lt;e &gt;o •* n o) os to ■* &gt;a y. E ~- ?i "5 "5 «5 t- F- OS O&gt; OS © O» 0» O&gt; O&gt; "' Ol010NXiO»OiOJ5NOrtMM03C g- </seg>
            <seg id="p028">■ Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 185 pleted an average of about 8 grades and their wives about &gt;'- grades. There seems to be substantially the same general average education of farmers and their wives in the western and eastern areas and no evidence that any section of the state is distinctly above or below the rest in education. Education of children.— The children of farmers of all tenures and of all areas show substantially the same number of grades advancement in school work up to the age of 13 years. Above that age the children of the Walthill area in Thurston County fall rather markedly and consistently behind those of the other areas. It is not until we reach the age of 15 that we find any marked and consistent difference between the children of owners and tenants in average school grade attained. From that age on, however, the children of owners show distinctly greater educational advancement than those of either part - owners or tenants. The Xehawka area in Cass County stands above all others in school grade that had been attained by the children of most ages above 9 years. The Filley area in Gage County stands next to it at a good many ages above li\ These 2 areas, where edu - cation would thus seem to be most highly prized, have both been the scenes of consolidation of schools in recent years. The fact that no children 7 years old or over arc found wh have not made some progress in school is in line with the t'ac that only 1.9 per cent of Nebraska's population over 10 years r age is illiterate — unable to write in any language. Only 1 stai has a lower illiteracy rate. 1 Nebraska farms have drawn their foreign-born immigra largely from countries which have a lew illiteracy rate. For t reason its illiteracy rate has not been raised by immigration have the rates of many other states. High school and university education of children. — Aln a third of the tenants' children 14 years of ayre or more have completed 10 grades or more of school work, as compared with nearly two-fifths of the part-owner! ' children and between two - fifths and half of the owners' children. A fifth of the tenants' children 16 years of age or over are high school graduates as compared with a fourth of the part-owners' children and be - tween a third and a fourth of the owners' children. This lag of the tenant children behind those of owners and part-owners is 'Talbot. Winthrop. Adult Illiteracy. Bui. 1916. No. S5. Bureau of Education. Dept. Interior. Paves 5 and 10. </seg>
            <seg id="p029">The Nebraska Kakm Family ■ still further emphasized when we note that only 1 tenant child out of every 50 18 years old or more has completed at least 2 or more years of university or college work as compared with about :{ times that proportion of owners' or part-owners' children of the same age. Only 1 out of every 50 among tenants' children, 20 years old or more, has completed a university or college course as compared with nearly twice that proportion of owners' children and nearly 3 times that proportion of part-owners' chil - dren of that age group. Of the 525 sons and daughters of own - ers, part-owners, and tenants, 20 years old or more, 19 or 3.6 per cent are university or college graduates. Education of hired men and their wives. — Hired men have progressed almost as far in school as their employers, but their wives fell 2 full grades below the operators' wives. The figures here given for hired men are not comparable with those for hired men's wives in the same way as are those for farmers and their wives. In each ease single, widowed, and divorced men are included as well as the husbands of the women whose edu - cational attainments are averaged. In case of the hired men, however, the single are several times as numerous as the mar - ried hired men. Serious illness. — In all tenure groups ill health is much more prevalent among men than among their wives, doubtless because of greater exposure to the elements, infection, accidents, and heavy manual labor. It was much more frequent in the eastern than in the southwestern Nebraska areas, especially among men. Tenants have had little more and part-owners about 50 per ent more ill health than the owners. Among the wives, how - ver, this is reversed, as owners' wives have had about 50 per ent more serious ill health than those of tenants or part-owners, arying in the mmc order as their average ages, — that is, the wners' wives who are older than those of either part-owners or tenants have had the most serious ill health, and the tenants' wives who were younger than those of either owners or part - mwiu ts have had the least serious ill health. This is in part ex - plained by the fact that the ill health reported was not confined I.* 1 * tn the previous year or decade but included that which has oc - curred during the entire period of family life. It was therefore cumulative and tended to be reported by greater percentages of the groups of greater average age. Possibly they tended to be - come more subject to illness with advancing years, also. </seg>
            <seg id="p030">30 Nebraska Experiment Station Bulletin 185 i C OWOOO anooo I C ■ ■i. — NOO US — ioisxo s * ot-t-teo 2 i - x tD — »NO »■• 3 i - .- — - &lt; « y o si m o us ■/■ E «1 II ii g§2 ON t-0500 I 1 o n 55 w o - — — O «■ EC M N OVOOHt- §! 4 |: I MN»«n 3T CSSMW S« .- :S 111! &lt;o a «?-«&lt;=&gt; ; m « scsex — £35"- </seg>
            <seg id="p031">The Xkbraska Farm Family 31 Among both men and women, influenza, appendicitis, and 'operations" were the items most frequently specified, but here the agreement ends. No other 1 cause of ill health was specified in more than 1 or 2 eases among women, while among men rheu - matism, typhoid fever, pneumonia, and accidents were each listed in from •"&gt; to l.'J cases among the 734 eastern Nebraska operators. 'Among the 734 eastern Nebraska farm homes studied, serious illness reported by men includes 27 cases of influenza, 18 of appendicitis, 15 operations, 13 eases of rheu - matism, 8 of typhoid, 8 of pneumonia, 5 accidents, S ruptures, S of stomach trouble, 2 of blood poison. 2 of asthma, and one each of "poor health," gallstone*, smallpox. brain fever, lumbago, lung fever, erysipelas, paralysis, heart trouble, catarrh, ulcers of the stomach, diabetes, and chronic indigestion. The reports for women include IS eases influenza. 14 operations, 5 cases of appendicitis. 2 childbirth*. 2 cases of kidney trouble, and 1 each of rupture, asthma, lumbago, gallstones, uremic poisoning, broken arm. deafness, "female trouble," rheumatism, typhoid fever, nervous trouble, heart trouble, and lung trouble. [SM] </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>