<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00007.00002">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00007.00002</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>CONSOLIDATION OF RURAL SCHOOLS</title>
               <date value="1903">1903</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
		       <change>
		          <date>2007-09-06</date>
		          <respStmt>
		             <name>Katherine M. Heupel</name>
		          </respStmt>
		          <item>Enrichment</item>
		       </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">District School No. i, Hall County, Nebraska Teacher's Residence, Property of District Nc. \, Hall County </seg>
            <seg id="p002">William K. Fowler, State Superintendent, Lincoln, Neb. An address delivered before the Department ol School Administration, National Educational Association. Thursday morning, July 9 IT.i, bu.jject is usually more fully expressed as The Consolidation of ool Districts, the Centralization of Rural Schools, and the Transporta - ol Pupils at Public Expense. The ideal plan contemplates the discontinuance of the small schools within a given area, say a congressional township, and the maintenance of one grad2d school instead at some point near the center of the town - ship. To illustrate: suppose a township to be divided Into nine rural school districts, each comprising four square miles of territory, with a low assessed valuation, a high tax levy, a small, neglected and dilapidated frame cchoolhouse varying from 10x24 feet to 24x30 feet, with three win - dows on each tide and one window and a door in one end, a stove, and without basement and interior closets. This schoolhouse, if located at the center of this school district of four square miles, will be two miles by section line roads lrom the homes at the corners of the district. School is maintained six, seven or eight months during the year, under the jurisdiction of a board of three trustees, and in our busy western section of the country, is usually taught by a young woman under twenty - one years of age, who is paid $30 a month for teaching or " keeping " school, building fires and " sweeping out." In this school we may find an average daily attendance of sixteen pupils, a high estimate by the way, representing all ages from five to twenty years, all grades from the primary to the high school and occasionally with two or three high school branches crowded in, and from thirty to forty recitations daily. The attendance is irregular and spasmodic, and tardiness is often the rule, children continuing to arrive until ten o'clock. Pupils are " pat back " term after term by the " new " teacher, as records are usually destroyed or lost. Apparatus is either unknown or out-of-date, black - board scanty and furniture rackety. This is the good old-fashioned " deestrick skool " taught by the new woman of twenty who has suc - ceeded and supplanted the old man of forty — and of forty years ago! I -Consolidation or centralization proposes to discontinue these small ricts us separate organizations, and these rural schools and school - ses. and to establish in lieu thereof one central graded school for the nship. housing ten or more grades in a four-room frame or brick •olhouse, well constructed, correctly lighted, heated, ventilated, and ed, with basement and Interior closets, a janitor, a principal and e other teachers, thirty-six pupils and three grades to the room. ve to fifteen recitations daily in each room, and to transport the Is by public conveyance to and from the schoolhouse daily. We Id then have a township board of education of five or seven members. Id and could pay the principal 160.00 to $75.00 a month and the e assistants about $45.00 a month each. With reference to the </seg>
            <seg id="p003">2 attendance of pupils, nine times sixteen is equal to four times thirty-six. But the attendance would be better, larger, more regular, pupils would be more punctual, and their progress provided for systematically. Their health would be better and better cared for, and their happiness would be greater. This is the extreme view and ideal plan, perhaps, before and after taking consolidation and centralization. But conditions in many rural communities may be vastly improved by consolidating and centralizing in part, by discontinuing permanently or temporarily a school district and uniting it to an adjoining one. Knsolidation of schools and transportation of pupils is operative to er or less degree in the following states, either under provision of by sufferance: California, Connecticut, Florida, Georgia, Hawaii, Indiana, Iowa, Kan - sas, Louisiana, Maine, Massachusetts, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, Nebraska, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, North Dakota, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, South Dakota, Texas, Vermont, Wisconsin; and in the five provinces of the Dominion of Canada under the Macdonald plan. ARGUMENTS FOR CONSOLIDATION 1. It insures a much larger per cent of enumerated pupils enrolled 2. Reduces irregular attendance. 3. Prevents tardiness among transported pupils. 4. Pupils can be better classified and graded. 5. No wet feet or clothing, nor colds resulting therefrom. 6. No quarreling, improper language, or improper conduct on the way to and from school. 7. Pupils are under the care of responsible persons from the time they leave home in the morning until they return at night. B Pupils can have the advantage ' of better schoolrooms, better , better ventilated, and better supplied with apparatus, etc. 9. Pupils have the advantage of that interest, enthusiasm and con - fidence which large classes always bring. 10. Better teachers can be employed, hence better schools. 11. The plan insures more thorough and more complete supervision. 12. It is more economical. Under the new plan the cost of tuition per pupil on the basis of total enrollment has been reduced from $16.00 to $10.48; on the basis of average daily attendance, from $26.66 to $16.07. This statement is for the pupils in subdistricts Nos. 10 and 13, Lake county, Ohio. 13. It permits a better grading of the schools and classification of pupils. Consolidation allows pupils to be placed where they can work to the best advantage, the various subjects of study to be wisely selected and correlated and more time to be given to recitations. Pupils work in GRADED schools, and both teachers and pupils are under syste - matic and closer supervision. 14. It affords an opportunity for thorough work in special branches &lt; </seg>
            <seg id="p004">3 such as drawing, music and nature study. It also allows an enrichment in other lines. Bit opens the door to more wesks of schooling and to schools of er grade. The people in villages almost invariably lengthen the year and support a high school for advanced pupils. 16. It affords the broader companionship and culture that comes from association. 17. It quickens public interest in the schools. Pride in the quality of work done secures a greater sympathy and better fellowship through - out the township. The whole community is drawn together. K Public barges used for children in the daytime may be used to rt their parents to public gatherings in the evenings, to lecture , etc. K Transportation makes possible the distribution of mail through - whole township daily. By transportation the farm again, as of old. becomes the ideal place in which to bring up children, enabling them to secure the advan - tages of centers of population and to spend their evenings and holiday time in contact with nature and plenty of work, instead of idly loafing A- about town. Blown. / - . The teacher's work is so well organized that the average recita - ;riod is trebled. One or two large families cannot " freeze out " the teacher n. The farmer apd his family are more content with their self - r.ning occupation. ■. Ethical culture is afforded free from the dissipations of social manifested in cities. ■ Parents who are observant say that the cost of shoes worn out/*' ;ing to the separate schools and the cost of medicine and doctors'^ ore than pay for the transportation. Transportation makes it easier to maintain a quarantine in case of disease and prevent the spread of contagion. SBy centralization there will be fewer and better teachers in our It will be a case of the survival of the fittest. Better salaries paid those who do teach, thus enabling a person to make it pos - acquire a high school and normal training before attempting B28. By centralization all the children of the township have the same ice for higher educational advantages, which under the present plan five or ten persons are able to get by leaving home and going to city. 29. By centralization we go a long ways toward the solution of the problem, " How to Keep the Boys on the Farm." We bring to the farm that which he goes to the city and town to secure. Such a school may become the social and intellectual center of the community life. With a library room, music, debating club, etc., our boys and girls will hesitate to leave home and such a school for the uncertainties of city life. Cen- </seg>
            <seg id="p005">4 Elization will not only keep the boys on the farm but It will help to ■p the b:g boys in the school. ARGl'MENTS AGAINST CONSOLIDATION. ■ Depreciation of property; decreased valuation of farms in dis - where schools are closed. E2. Dislike to sending young children to school far from home, away i the oversight of parents; and to providing a cold lunch for them er thta a warm dinner. IDmger to health and morals; children obliged to travel too far d and stormy weather; obliged to walk a portion of the wa the t?am, and then to ride in damp clothing and with wet 1 able conveyance and uncertain driver: association with so many en of all classes and conditions; lack of proper oversight during wn hour. 4. Insufficient and unsuitable clothing; expense to parents of prop - erly clothing their ciiildren. ■ Difficulty of securing a proper conveyance on reasonable terms the parent is lllowed compensation, of agreeing upon terms satis - y to both parents and school officials. Local jealousy; an acknowledgment that some other section of nship has greater advantages and is outstripping any other lo- P. Natural proneness of some people to the removal of any ancient lark or to any innovation, however worthy the measure, or however received elsewhere. BLess freedom of the individual pupil to advance at a rate to him. 9. Saloon at the canter. It. Too long distances; bad roads, blocked in winter for weeks. 11. Invasion of individual rights. ■I. If fatal diseases are carried to or start in these schools, then all of the children of the township are exposed to them. THE RURAL SCHOOL PROBLEM: A SOLUTION. CWMClidztlcn of Schcol Districts, Centralization of Schools, and Public Transportation of Pupils. From the Seventeenth Biennial Report of the Department of Public In- struction, State ot Nebraska. El have great faith in the rural school, in its powers, and of what it do for the individual pupil, but I think the result of its work on average does not compare with the work of the best city schools, and jot under the present conditions. How to improve the present ins is a serious problem, and I know of but one solution. Rural mail rery is now spreading through this western country. Roads are MN roved. Telephones are coming into common use in the country well as in the cities. Many counties in Nebraska have organized </seg>
            <seg id="p006">5 supplies and provisions, lor broken castings tor larm machinery, for twine for the binder, lor drugs and medicines and tor hundn other little things will be by telephone, and thereby one-halt of the time usually expended in securing them will be saved. We nui-t enrich rural life and increase the advantages of the fa and his family in order to counter; to city. A cmu I nil tin issu ..-d ot population at th:- (Jilted States ■adily increased each decide teat in 1860, Z2.C per cent in 1880, ct the flow of humanity Irani country last year states that the p;-rc -ntage in cities of MM 0* more inhabitants It was :.A per cent in 17!&gt;". |] r c nt in ISM, and HI pef or more inhabitants in lSv 8: in is and in These figures are significant. They mean that irom 1880 to 1 - us in every one hundred ot our population moved from country or village to city and none moved back. From 189&lt;&gt; to 19&lt;»&gt; tour or five us in every one hundred moved from country or village to city and none moved back. What shall we do to be saverl lrora our great c. Shall we permit the decay and destruction of our pure country li: shall we endeavor to bring some of the great comforts and conveni' and advantages of city life into the country? lor years we have been working at cutting up Nebraska and its Ees into small school districts. Schools of a lew pupils are the and large schools are the exception. What inspiration can of a school ot three or four or half a dozen have to do good work? El no life, energy, inspiration, emulation or desire to excel. The hool is dead spiritually and intellectually, and I have sesn many a small school that might as well have teen discontinued as far as practical r. Milts were concerned. You may be doing well under the conditions. rat what are the conditions? How could they be much wwl Coor. mattered old schoolhouses, sometimes lacking paint, with cannon-ball ;toves. and cheerless yards; while in our cities we are building modern, scientific structures, correctly heated, ventilated, lighted and seated built of brick, sometimes with stone foundations and with beautiful sur - roundings. Many of the best schools of Nebraska are in towns employ - ing Irom three to six teachers. There they have but two or thiM claaam in i-ioh room, with all the rooms in one building, a principal \vh&lt;&gt; what each class is doing, thereby securing better and clo n than is possible in larger place rty. and a janitor to look after Khy do you not have the same impossibility. Let me suggest eastern states. Thirty years in your rural communities? It is to you what has been done in some ■00 in Massachusetts they began Bli/.ing their rural schools by public transportation of pupils in vans gons. About ten years ago the plan had reached Ohio, and in st tew years it has spread intp Indiana, Illinois, and is now being ;ly advocated in Iowa. Briefly the plan is this: Instead of nine districts with about four sections of land each, teachers with sal- in 19oi. T ':e p-.-rcfntage of our population that lived in cith &gt; </seg>
            <seg id="p007">6 aries of about $35.00, and an average enrollment of twenty pupils, we have in the center of the township a brick building of four rooms, with forty-five pupils in each room, and two or three grades only. We may have a principal of considerable training and experience, who receives a salary of from $C0.00 to $75.00, and teaches the highest room. The three other teachers receive about $45.00 each. There is a janitor who looks after the building, its heating plant, its toilet rooms or outbuildings and the grounds generally. There may be sheds in which the horses are kept during the day. The pupils are gathered from various parts or the township by covered vans or wagons that start at 7:45 a. m., or at a stated regular time, day after day. and cover an established route, pick - ing up the children along the way and delivering them at the schoolhouse at about 8:45; distributing them again after four o'clock in the afternoon. Where the plan has been in operation, the drivers selected are clean, capable, sober men, not given to profanity or tobacco, and are paid $25.00 or $30.00 per month. They furnish their own team and wagon, with lap robes, and as a rule, carpet their vehicles and provide seats; let me say right here, that in bad weather, in rain or storm or strong wind, I would rather my child would ride five miles in such a vehicle than walk one or two miles. In pleasant weather, I would just as soon have him walk CONSOLIDATION OF SCHOOLS. To overcome the many disadvantages in the present rural school m in Nebraska, and for the purpose of giving every farmer's girl and boy in this noble con/monwealth opportunities equal to those of the girls and boys of the village and city, we recommend to the careful considera - tion of every rural school board and to the fathers and mothers in these rural districts the consolidation of schools and the transportation of pupils. Consolidate, or centralize, the weak districts into a common cen - tral school, conveying the pupils from every part of the greater district or the congressional township to and from the central schools by means of covered vans or wagons, in charge of clean, capable, careful drivers. Such a plan would now be legal, as the six-mile limit in the formation of school districts has been removed. And we already have the trans - portation law. Notice the following provisions of Nebraska School Laws. 1. One district may be discontinued, and its territory attached to other adjoining districts, upon petitions signed by one-half of the legal voters of each district affected. (Subdivision 1, Section 4, Fourth Condl- 2. The six-mile limit in the formation of school districts has been removed, and districts may now be formed extending more than six miles in any direction. 3. The district board may (and usually should) close the weaker and smaller schools in a district and transport the pupils at public ex - pense to any other school in the district. A board of education of a city, or a board of trustees of a high school district, by a two-thirds vote of the entire board, or a district board of any school district in this state </seg>
            <seg id="p008">7 8 authorized by a two-thirds vote of those present at any annual or 1 meeting, is hereby empowered to make provision for the trans - ion of pupils residing within said district to any other school a said district) to which said pupils may lawfully attend, whenever stance from such schools shall render it impracticable for said to attend without transportation. (Subdivision 5, Section 4b.) 4. Or, the district board may close school and transport their pupils at public expense to a neighboring district without forfeiting the state apportionment. A board of trustees of a high school district, or a dis - trict board of a school district inlt^is state, when authorized by a two - thirds vote of those present at any annual or special meeting, is hereby empowered to contract with the district board of any neighboring dis - trict for the instruction of (all) pupils residing in the first named district in schools maintained by the neighboring district, and to make pro\ for the transportation of said pupils to the above-named school of the neighboring district under the conditions named in the preceding sec - tion: Provided, That school districts thus providing instruction for their children in neighboring districts shall be considered as maintaining a school as required by law; Provided, further, That the teacher of the last-named school shall keep a separate record of attendance of all pupils from the first named district and make a separate report to the director CONSOLIDATION IN OTHER STATES. In answer to an inquiry for the latest phase or condition of the con - solidation of rural schools, the state departments of public instruction of the several states sent the following brief expressions of opinion in addi - tion to the printed matter hereafter referred to: ARIZONA — There has never been any concerted action in Arizona in the matter of consolidation of rural schools; we having such a sparsely settled country and the districts being in many instances «ey - eral miles apart, the consolidation idea cannot be satisfactorily worked to any extent. We have no matter, printed or otherwise, bearing on the subject. When the population has become more dense, there will be closer relations between districts and the plan of consolidation may be more seriously considered. ! CALIFORNIA— There was a measure enacted at the recent session he legislature (Assembly Bill No. 532). As yet it is only an experi - it in California, but I anticipate good results from it when it shall e been tried. Of course, I do not think it 'adapted to many sections mr state, only to those portions where there^are good roads and well ulated communities. COLORADO — Conditions are such in Colorado that we have prac - tically done nothing in this line, but interest is now being awakened. DISTRICT OP COLUMBIA — As we do not have to deal with rural schools as they obtain in a state, we have no printed matter on the sub - ject. For the same reason there is nothing I could say from a practical point of view that would be of service to you. </seg>
            <seg id="p009">8 K3ORGIA — Consolidation has gradually been going on in this state, gh there have been no laws passed on this subject. The matter is rgely with County Boards of Education. In most cases they have ded very slowly in the matter and have obtained good results. ILLINOIS — There seems to be a widespread interest in this state about the matter of transportation. There was no legislation passed during the last session of the General Assembly. I think, however, by the next biennial session the sediment will be so strong that the legisla - ture will be disposed to act. , IOWA— The work of consolidation goes forward merrily in this KANSAS — Consolidation is rapidly gaining favor in this state. Where it has been tried there is no fault to find with it. MICHIGAN — We have just secured the necessary legislation by which we are now able to centralize schools, using a portion of the public money for the transportation of pupils. That was all that was neces - sary, and we are now in shape to begin an active campaign and to reach some definite practical results. BINNESOTA — I have nothing original to add to our bulletin at this We have but three or four consolidated districts in Minnesota as it in about a dozen places schools are temporarily suspended and pi!s are being transported at public expense to adjoining districts. Pinter, upon my recommendation, this plan was legally authorized. MISSOURI — We have not done much in Missouri along the line of consolidation of rural schools. We have a law authorizing it, but the people have not consolidated in more than four places, and only in two of these have the schools been consolidated; in the other two it is simply district consolidation. ERTH DAKOTA— Consolidation has been tried in several of the i in this state, and the reports which we have on file indicate s plan is entirely satisfactory and a .great improvement over the em. EIO — This plan gives general satisfaction in this state where the ms are at all favorable, and I personally believe that it is the of the question of better schools in rural districts. t OKLAHOMA — We are just beginning the plan in Oklahoma. It is g discussed in every county. We are having trouble, however, he - e most of the districts have bonded and cannot ltase their identity. OREGON — We are crowding the consolidation idea and -are meet - ing with very much encouragement, although we have not had any districts, as yet, consolidate. It takes time to overcome the inertia of long settled customs and so we will not be at all discouraged if the movement advances slowly. I am particularly anxious that no districts do consolidate unless they make a success of it. We find the best way to get it before the people is to present it in mass meeting and have be - fore the people maps showing the boundaries of the districts, roads, </seg>
            <seg id="p010">■ SOUTH DAKOTA — So far as this department has been able to learn, the work attained in such schools has been superior to the single district ■ and has been a saving to the people of about one-fourth. The at - tendance has also been better. Especially is this true of students of the higher grades. TEXAS — Very little has been done in this state in the way of con - solidating rural schools. There are perhaps one or two counties which have during the past year to some extent tried the consolidation plan, but these few cases have not been sufficient tor a test. I have in nuhlic addresses and in letters irom the department encouraged the consolida - tion ot schools. I hope Texas will soon appreciate the advantages of the consolidation plan. I'TAH — In my recommendations to the last legislature. I suggested that all school districts in a county be united in one, and that M governed and controlled by a competent board of education con; - ol five, seven or nine members, according to the class of the cour. • said but a few words in regard to the matter, simply stating that in my opinion such consolidation would aid materially in unifying and str&lt; ening cur present cciiool system. A bill thus to provide lor tli dation of the school districts was presented to the legislature, but it failed to pass. Consolidation is being effected in many of our con however, on a smaller scale. The central school is steadily increasing in numbers. Again, Utah's rural districts are somewhat diffaient from the rural districts ot most states. Towns have sprung up at the mouths of canyon streams. There the people live, while the farms are from one ■ miles from their homes. PERMONT — Vermont is making some progress in the matter of idation of rural schools. The hilly nature of the state is a difficulty in the extension of this movement. The peopl are always conservative and make assured, though moderate. ; WYOMING — The community of Wheatland, in the county of Lar - amie. of this state, requested my opinion last winter as to wheth not. under the law. they would be permitted to consolidate several ot chools and to furnish transportation for pupils. I looked into the law and rendered an opinion to the effect that I believed they WOT warranted in consolidating, providing, of course, they were able so to decide. Upon my suggestions or opinion they decided to consolidate, and I understand now that the same is in operation, but can give you no in - formation' as to whether successful or not. From my knowledge of the locality referred to I am of the opinion that consolidation would be more successful there than in most localities. In numerous portions of this state I do not believe consolidation advisable and the reasons ar REFERENCES. I append herewith a list of printed articles on the consolidation of school districts, centralization of schools, and transportation of pupils, </seg>
            <seg id="p011">10 ft. schools successfully.) AUSTRALIA — Report of the Minister of Public Instruction of Vic toria for the year 1901-1902, p. 20, 21, 39, 43. ■ALIFORNIA— Assembly Bill No. 532, or Senate Bill No. 482, An act ling for the formation of union school districts and the mainte - therein of union schools, 1903. I CONNECTICUT — Report of the Board of Education together with eport of the Secretary of the Board, 1899, Conveyance of Children, 1-145. Report for 1900, Laws relating to education, Ch. ix, Con - tion of School Districts, p. 52-60; Conveyance of Children, p. *M7- Report for 1902, Conveyance of Children, 186-188; Consolidation locls. 332-335. ELORIDA — Biennial Report of the Superintendent of Public In - ion for the two years ending June 3, 1900 (From reports of county ntendents) 331, 341, 352, 379, 391, 412. Summary, 19. fEORGIA— Thirtieth Annual Report from the Department of Edu - for 1901, Consolidation of Districts and Transportation of Pupils, Consolidation of Rural Schools and the Transportation of Chll - by M. B. Dennis, 98-106. BAWAII — Report of Inspectors of the Department of Public In - ion, December 31, 1902, Consolidated Schools, 23. BAHO — Biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public In - on, 1900, Rural School Districts, G-7. K.LINOIS — Twenty-Fourth Biennial Report of the Superintendent blic Instruction, July 1, 1900-June 30, 1902, Consolidation of the Districts once more, 11-14. INDIANA— Twentieth Biennial Report of the State Superintendent blic Instruction for the school years ending July 31, 1899, and July 00, The Rural School — (a) The Small School, (b) Transportation of 3, 520-587. Twenty-First Biennial Report for years ending Jul&gt; and July 31. 1902, School Economy— (a) The Small School, (b) A Organization in the Country, 155-1G1, Consolidated Schools. 727-762. B'WA — Biennial Report of the Department of Public Instruction for ?riod ending September 30, 1901. Ch. II, Consolidation of Schools ransportation of Children. 29-97. (Issued in pamphlet form). KANSAS — Thirteenth Biennial Report of the Department of Public ction for the years ending June 30, 1901-June 30, 1902, The C&lt;&gt;n - tion of Rural Schools. 38-48. Circular of Information Regarding lidation of Rural Schools. March 1. 1902. LOUISIANA — Biennial Report of the State Superintendent of Public Education. 19001901, Attendance, C-8. PARYLAND— Thirty-Sixth Annual Report of the State Board of tion for the year ending July 31. 1902, Minutes of the Association lool Commissioners of Maryland, Session of 1902 — Resolution of Superintendent commending consolidation of rural schools, xliii. MASSACHUSETTS— Sixty-Second Annual Report of the Board of </seg>
            <seg id="p012">11 Education together with the Sixty-Second Annual Report of the Secretary of the Board, 1897-1898. Consolidation of Schools and the Conveyance of Children, by G. T. Fletcher, Agent of the Massachusetts Board of Edu - cation, 435-459. Sixty-Third Annual Report. 1898-1899, Expense of Con - veying Children, 155-159. Sixty-Sixth Report. 1902. Conveyance of Pupils. 101-104. e MICHIGAN— Sixty-Fifth Annual Report of the Superintendent of &gt;lk; Instruction for the year 1901, The Rural High School, 5-11: An estigation of the Centralized Schools of Ohio, 12-30; Transportation Pupils, 31-34 (issued also in pamphlet form). MINNESOTA — Twelfth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction for the school years ending July 31, 1901-1902, Bulle - tin No. 1 — Consolidation of Rural Schools and Transportation of Pupils at Public Expense. 271-290 (issued in pamphlet form). MISSOURI— Fifty-Third Report of the Public Schools for the year ending June 30, 1902, The Rural School Problem, 4-11. MONTANA— Circular letter of the state superintendent on The Con - solidation of Schools. t NEBRASKA— Sixteenth Biennial Report of the State Superintendent Public Instruction, January, 1901, Transportation of Pupils and In - struction in Neighboring District, 40-42. Seventeenth Biennial Report, January, 1903, The Rural School Problem: A Solution — Consolidation of School Districts, Centralization of Schools, and Public Transportation of Pupils, 400-409. School Buildings and Grounds in Nebraska. Department of Public Instruction, 228-2G5. NEW HAMPSHIRE) — Fifty-Second Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1902, Consolidation. 278-279. EEW JERSEY — Annual Report of the State Board of Education and ; Superintendent of Public Instruction for the school year ending 30, 1902, Reports from county superintendents on the transportation )ils. 59. 84. NEW YORK— Forty-Second Annual Report of the State Superin - tendent for the school year ending July 31. 1895. The Consolidation of School Districts, LXXXVII. Forty-Fourth Report. 1897. The Rural School Problem, XI. Forty-Sixth Report, 1899, Consolidation of School Districts, B5-5C. Forty-Seventh Report, 1900. Consolidation of School Districts, 11; Contract with Adjoining Districts, 13. Forty-Ninth Report. 1902. Con - solidation of Weak Districts, lxix. NORTH CAROLINA— Biennial Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction for the school years 1900-1901 and 1901-1902. School Dis - tricts, xviii-xxvi; the Rural Schools, Iviii; Signs of Hope and Evidences of Progress, lx, 3rd paragraph; Consolidation of Districts, 3G5-373 (Edu - cational Bulletin No. 1). t NORTH DAKOTA— Seventh Biennial Report of the Superintendent Public Instruction for the two years ending June 30, 1902, Consolida - l of Rural Schools. 24-28 (issued in pamphlet form): 300, 303, 291. NOVA SCOTIA — Annual Report of the Superintendent of Education </seg>
            <seg id="p013">12 lor 1.116 j Glr Pli &gt; 1 1 ni^ o VI 1 J ol. 11^ ' 1 luaLltJU Ul O^vlHJllO, Al . fHIO — Forty-Seventh Annual Report of the State Commissioner of on Schools lor the year ending August 31, 1900, Centralization Law, Forty-Eighth Annual Rerort, l?01, Centralization of Schools, KTARIO — Report of the Minister of Education for the year nsolidation of Schools and Transportation of Pupils, xxii xxvii. OREGON — Filteenth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of Pub - lic Instruction, 1902, General Survey of Educational Work. HMM. ENNSYLVANIA — Report of the Superintendent oi Public Instiuc - r the year ending June 3, 1901, Centralization of Schools, vi-vii. Laws of Pennsylvania, 1902, Consolidated Districts. 2-4. BUEBEC — Report of the Superintendent ot Public Instruction for ;ar 1901-02, Protestant Schools, xx, xxi. RHODE ISLAND — Fifty-Seventh Annual Report of the Commis - sioner of Public Schools lor the year ending April 30, 1901, Size of Schools, 73; Extracts from Reports on Consolidation and Transportation. Appendix, 27. 29, 33-35, :J7. C4. 101, 129-131. Public Laws Pertaining to Education, 1903, Ch. 1101. An act providing for the better maim; public schools in the state (in pamphlet torm). SOUTH DAKOTA — Sixth Biennial Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1901-19K2. The Centralization of Rural School circular letter of state superintendent, 15; reports from various counties, : 77, 79, 94. EXAS — Thirteenth Biennial Report of State Superintendent of Instruction lor the scholastic years ending August 31, isoi. and 31, 1902, The Real Harmony between the Law and Appropriate s Methods, etc., 15-16. BERMONT— Thirty-Seventh School Report of t'.ia State Superim I Education, October.. 1902, Union of Schools and Conveyancs of J4; Educational Thought and Effort, 5C; statistics on n ion. 134; county reports, 140, 194, 219, 222. EVIRGINI \— Biennial Report of the Superintendent of Public In - cticn. 1900-1901, The Rural School, xxvi; Consolidation and Trans - ation, xxvii-xxviii. BASHINGTON— Sixt?enth Biennial Report of the Superintendent lie Instruction, 1902. Consolidation of School Districts. 183-184. EEST VIRGINIA — Biennial Report of Ihe Superintendent ot Free s for the two years ending June 30, 1902, Centralization and ("on - ion ot Schools, 27-29. I WISCONSIN — Biennial Report of the State Superintendent for the ears ending June 30, 1900. Transportation of Rural School Children blic Expense, p. 18-24; Report of the Committee of Six on Rural Is, p. 25-3G; Report for 1902, Consolidation of School Districts and portation of Rural School Pupils at Public Expense, 41-62 (issued letin form). Commissioner of Education, Report for 1898-1899, Ch. XI, Con- </seg>
            <seg id="p014">13 MM, Ch. Ill, Consolidation ot Schools and Transportation ot Pupi Visit to the Centralized Schools of Oiiio; Consolidation of Schools and Conveyance of Children (Report ma;'.e by G. T. Fletcher. ag?nt Massa - chusetts State Board of Education); Transportation of Pupils in In - diana; An Inquiry Regarding the Conveyance of Scholars in E shire: Transportation of Pupils in Nebraska and Instruction in coring Districts— 161-213. Report for lMtlMl, Transportation of to School, giving status in twenty-two stati 101. Journal of Proceedings and Addresses of the Fortieth Annul 1 .V ing of the National Educational Association, held at Detroit. Michigan, July 8-12, 1901. Centralization of Rural Schools, Lewis D. Bonebrake, State School Commissioner of Ohio, 804-811. Forty-First Annual Meet - ing. Minneapolis. Minn.. July 7-11, 1902. The Financial Phase oi the Consolidation of Rural Schools. Charles A. Van Metre, county sir tendent. Muncie, Ind.. lUttt; Progress In Consolidation of Rural Schools, J. W. Olsen, state superintendent public instruction. St. Paul. Minn.. 793-797. Department of Agriculture, Year Book. 1901. Some Problems Rural Common School, A. C. True. 133-154. Report of the Committee of Twelve on Rural Schools, appoiii the meeting of the N. E. A.. Denver. July 9. 1895. The County as the- t'nit ol School Organization. 1X3-1XS; Comparative Coot ol the Township and District Systems. 1SS-1S4; Transportation of Pupils, ltt-140. Report of a Visit to the Centralized Schools ot Ohio — A Stmi the Centralized Schools of Ohio. O. J. Kern. Roc'.iford. 111. Report of a Visit to the Centralized Schools ot Ohio by tht Superintendent of Michigan and Hon. A. E. Pal 31 or, Lansing. Mir Equal Education in Connecticut. W. Scott. S3cr3tary Na-.v Edii Leagus, Cambridge. Mass. A New England Education Policy. W. Scott. Ca-n!&gt;ri(lg?, Mass Possibilities of the Country School, and the New Elucati- n ; Country Child. 0. J. Kern, Rockiord, 111. k Circular to the Protestant Boards of School Commissioners and istees of the Province of Quebec, and Appendix. Boucher ■!? La 1! ebec. Canada. b Centralization of Rural Schools. J. Fred Olan J .er. superintendent of &gt;king3 county. Brookings. S. Dak. Riview of R3Views, December. 1902, 702, Consolidation of Co union s. Frank Nelson, Topeka, Kas., Consolidation of Common Schools. Shaw, 70G. L Outlook, December 27, 1902, 981-984, Country Schools— The , C. H. Matson. Forum, March. 1902, 103. Consolidation of Country Schools and the Conveyance of Children. Clarence E. Blake. Educational Review, October. 1900. 241. Transportation of Rural School Children at Public Expense, A. A. Upham. </seg>
            <seg id="p015">14 Schools? Robert L. Myers, Harrisburg, Penn. The Value of One Act. Robert L. Myers, Harrisburg, Penn Pennsylvania School Journal, published by Superintendent N. C Schaeffer, Harrisburg. Penn.; August, 1902, Centralization of Township Schools, Superintendent W. W. Ulerick, 68-70. April, 1903, Leadership and Rural Schools, Superintendent Samuel Hamilton, Allegheny, 446 451; Township High Schools, Arthur J. Simons, 452-455. Btfoderator-Topics, published by H. R. Pattengill, Lansing. Mich., , 1903, A Report of Progress, State Superintendent Delos Fall, 524. 1C, 1903, Centralizad Schools, Commissioner Elliott, Oakland, Mich., May 14. 1903, Procedure in Consolidating School Districts, State rintendent Delos Fall, C25. June 11, 1903, Rural High Schools. 712. Normal Instructor and Teachers' World, published by F. A. Owen Publishing Co., Dansville, N. Y., June, 1903, Need of Secondary Instruc - tion in Country Schools, State Superintendent Alfred Bayliss, Spring - field. 111., 9. Eerican School Board Journal, published by Wm. Geo. Bruce, i, November, 1902, Consolidation of Rural Schools, Arguments in if, 8. ■he School Journal, published by E. L. Kellogg &amp; Co., New York April 4, 1903, Consolidation of Schools, 375; Rural School Condi- W. S. Diffenbaugh. 375-377. June 27, 1903, Centralization of Rural Is, 781-784. Ke Western Journal of Education, The Whitaker &amp; Ray Co., pub - , 723 Market St., San Francisco, June, 1903, a special number on idation of School Districts and the Transportation of Pupils. ■he World's Work, published by Doubleday, Page &amp; Co.. New York May, 1903, Teaching Farmers' Children on the Ground. George lies. Education, published by the Palmer Company, Boston, Vol. XIX, The Rural School Problem, John Ogden, 261, 413. Address on Education for the Improvement of Agriculture by Jas. W. Robertson, Commissioner of Agriculture and Dairying for the Do - minion of Canada, printed by Wm. Macnab, 3 Prince St., Halifax, N. S.. 21-29. Improvement of Education in the Rural Schools, Jas. W. Robert - son, Ottawa, Canada. Eie Educational News, Edinburgh, Scotland, July 4, 1903, The Group- Our Public Schools, C. H. Owen; July 25, 1903, The Rural School m and the Inverness Congress, C. H. Owen. Atlantic Educational Journal, Richmond, Va., July, 1902, Concen - trated School Districts and the Schoolhouses for Them, S. F. Venable; The Movement for BetterX Schoolhouses in North Carolina, Annie G. Randall; The Housing of Rural Schools, Robert Frazier; An Ideal Rural School, Lawton B. Evans. May, 1903, The Power of an Idea— A Story and a Suggestion, David E. Cloyd; Extracts from Addresses made at the Sixth Conference for Education in the South. June, 1903, The Ideal Rural School, Charles S. Ball; Consolidation in Tennessee. </seg>
            <seg id="p016">15 ber, 1902, The Centralization of Rural Schools, C. G. Williams. October, 1902, The Centralization of Rural Schools. A. B. Graham. December, 1902, The Centralization of Rural Schools at Kingsville, O., L. E. York. January, 1903, Gradual Consolidation of Rural Schools, A. H. Dixon. February, 1903, The Centralization of Township Schools, John J. Rich - eson. The School News, Independence, Mo., June, 1902, Central Schools and Transportation of Pupils, W. H. Johnson, Superintendent Jackson county, Missouri. September, 1902, Central Schools and Transportation of Pupils, \V. H. Johnson. November, 1902, A Rural High School. December, 1902, The Rural High School, J. B. McDonald. January, 1903, Transpor - tation of Pupils in Ellsworth County, Kansas. W. \V. Maze; Report of Raytown High School. Texas School Journal, Austin, Tex., December. 1902, Rural Schools, John C. Moore; Transfers, J. H. Hill. January. IMS, What We Want— Rural Schoolhouses. The People. Cambridge, Mass., July, 1899, Dublin. N. H.. School Mat - ters; Natural School Unit; Editorials. June, MM, Equal Education in New England. W. Scott, secretary New England Education League. Au - gust, 1901, A School Study of a New England Town. March-May Transportation. June-August, 1903, A School Experiment. American Education, published by New York Education Co., Albany N. Y., February, 1903, Two Views. LThe Advocate of Christian Education. Berrien Springs. Mich.. March, 3, The Consolidation of Schools; Centralizing Districts. The Canadian Teacher, published by the Educational Publishing Co., Limited, Toronto, Canada, September, 1901, Centralization of Country Schools (editorial). October, 1901, Centralization of Schools. Ko ber, 1901, Centralization Again (editorial). December. 1901. Centraliza - tion at Last. William S. Carter, Inspector of Schools. January. Centralization Again, M.-D. Worden (with editorial comment). F ary, 1902, Centralization Again (editorial). May. IMS, Centralization of Rural Public Schools, M. Parkinson (editor). The World Review, Fine Arts Building, Chicago. Passing of the District School, M. Vincent O'Shea. Univer - isconsin. School Education, Minneapolis, Minn., January. 1903, Rural School nsolidation. W. M. Hayes, University of Minnesota. Midland Schools. Des Moines, la.. March. 1902. Buffalo Center Town - ship Graded School, J. C. Johnson; Consolidation in Pottawattamie County, Superintendent McManus; The Consolidated School System, O. V. Holcomb. Farmer's Tribune, Des Moines, la., June 17. IMS, Is the Central School a Fad? Has it come to stay? O. E. Gunderson. Successful Farming, Des Moines, la., February. 1903, The Consoli - dation of Rural Schools. </seg>
            <seg id="p017">16 Centralized Schools, G. H. Campbell. Farm, Field and Fireside, published by the Howard Co., Chicago, i, 1903, Farming to be Taught in the Rural Schools. She Family Herald and Weekly Star, Montreal, Canada, February 11, A Novel Experiment in Rural Education (an outline of Sir William onald's plan for th-j improvement of education in the rural districts e consolidation of schools and the establishment of gardens for i study), Geo. D. Fuller. The Nebraska Farmer, Omaha. Neb.. July 30, 1903, The Consolidation untry Schools (editorial). EThe Farmers Call, Quincy, 111., December 11, 1902, Better Coaatn iM.ls. January 22, 1903, Consolidating Country Eahools. January IMS, Move up, Brethren. March 19, 1903. ConsoK-_-.L\i School Bill. 14, 1903 ; Farmers should be Heard on School Consolidation. Francis Jvesey. The Ohio Farmer, Cleveland, O., April 24, 1902. Gustavus, O., C ntral Schools, C. G. Williams. September 4, 1902, Centralization of Schools. April 23, 1903, Centralize the Right Way. Kerald, Wabasha, Minn., May is. L. P. Cravens. 30, 1901, Centralization of Rural Register, Blue Earth, Minn.. May J. F. Oilman. 30. 1901, Concentration oi Schools, THE SITUATION IN NEBRASKA BANNER COUNTY. Eiring the past school year the number of school di.tricts has been d irom 38 to 34, by uniting to each of two dtetric s aJjoiniug dis - and to a third one two other districts. In the latt =r case the idated district (No. 8) camprises 30 sections of land, wU!l a census children of school ag?. The tax levy, enrollment an 1 average attendance are practically unaffected, but the ter:n ot i I . Free transportation is not provided. ■[strict No. 5, two districts united, includes 21 sections, with a I census of 34. Conditions are similar to those in No. 8. aini rka advantage appears to be in a larger, better school. ■ strict No. 7, two districts united, includes 34 sections "irh a census of 19. Conditions are similar to those in No. 8 ani No. 5, ith a slight increase in enrollment. MRS. W. E. HEARD. BOX BUTTE COUNTY. 1 have worked tor the consolidation of a number ol districts during the past year, but without success, although the plan to form 4 districts from 7 is still being agitated, and we hope to succeed before October 1, after all concerned understand the situation better than at present X J. W. BAUMGARDNER. BROWN COUNTY. Owing to the sparsely settled territory we cannot bring about con- </seg>
            <seg id="p018">17 soliilation of districts to any extent at present, but in the more thickly settled parts I think an attempt would be successful if there were some means of meeting the citizens in a systematic way. ESTELLA M. DANIELS. BUFFALO COL'NTY. consolidation of two groups of school met with much encouragement in my I shall make an effort for the districts this summer. I have not efforts in the past. T. N. HARTZELL. BURT COUNTY We have no centralized schools article on this subject in several of with both iavor and opposition. in this county. I have published an our county papers. The plan meets EUGENE BROOKINGS. BUTLER COUNTY I have tried two places in the county, but the main objection given by the patrons is the greatar cost of running a consolidated district.* CEDAR COUNTY Four districts were united about two years ago, forming District No. 84. which has 28 sections and a school population of 1C9. The district still has four schoolhouses and a U-ac.ier for each one, as the people have tnus far refused to vote bonis for tha csntral school.iouse. A. E. WARD DAWES COUNTY An adjoining district has been consolidated with District No. 25, forming 18 sections with a school population of 30. This consolidation was effected April 1, 1903, and only one teacher will be necessary for the school. Last year the two districts levied 15 and 12 mills respectively, Ci enrollment in the two schools was 20 and the average daily attend - ee was 12. During my term of office twelve districts have been consolidated in Dawes county. Th-re has nearly always been opposition at the time but later entire satisfaction has resulted. During the past year back taxes have been paid up in many of the districts giving a surplus of funds which has kept several districts from consolidating that would have done so if they had been short. Trans - portation has never besn tried. H. L. FISHER. DIXON COUNTY Petitions tre cut for the consolidation of five districts and three have bean returned, but the others must have been lost or the people are too busy to attend to them. MARY McKINLEY •Note — But the income is greater with the same levy, and the school vastly better. JOS. C. HRUSHKA. </seg>
            <seg id="p019">18 Bistrict No. 32 was discontinued last fall and its territory attached . 98, forming a district of 18 sections with 23 pupils of school age. one teacher will be necessary. District No. 18 has been discontinued and attached to District No. 80, except one quarter section which goes to the Maywood district. About five years ago a district comprising six sections was at - tached to the Curtis district. This consolidation has proven most unsat - isfactory. There are at present two families residing in the portion annexed, six and six-and-one-half miles from school. They could drive to school, but are unwilling to do so. To furnish transportation would cost more than the income derived from their portion of the district. If separated from the Curtis district their income would scarcely main - tain the required amount of school. For two years a school has been held for them, four months this year, three months last year, paid for in part by the Curtis district and in part by the parents. Both teachers were beginners. The work was very ordinary, but the pupils' attendance was perfect. This case is a sample " problem." MRS. CLARA L. DOBSON HARLAN COUNTY. EPhe proposition of disbanding the small schools, or rather of hold - io school in the district but sending the pupils to adjoining schools paying tuition out of district funds, is worthy of consideration. Last District No. C3 acted upon such advice and voted to hold no school following letters from officers of the district tell how well the plan ;ed. No complaint has reached this office from any patron. Atlanta, Nebr., April 18, 190 Superintendent U. C. Breithaupt — t reply to your letter must say for my part am perfectly satisfied le way we managed our school last winter. And as far as I know, 3t are all satisfied. The tuition for all of the pupils all winter cost us any more than it would have cost to pay the teacher one if we had run our school. MRS. JOSEPHINE KRASOMIL Atlanta. Nebr., April 13, 190£ Superintendent U. C. Breithaupt Your letter of April 2nd has been received: in reply will say that our experience of sending pupils to adjoining schools has been satis - factory the past year. The pupils received seven months' schooling. One boy that attended school in Atlanta missed only one day out of - months. The cost of tuition is $41.50. One month's school in our own district would cost nearly that much. OSCAR LONN I believe several districts will follow this plan next year, U. C. BREITHAUPT. HAYES COUNTY. Three districts have been discontinued during the past year, and </seg>
            <seg id="p020">19 their territory united to two others. The new District No. G:: consists of 28 sections, with a school census of 40. One teacher is required instead of two. the tax levy has been reduced from 25 to 15 mills, and the en - rollment increased from 30 to 38 pupils. District No. 25. formed of three united districts, comprises 25 sec - tions, with a school census of 5C. The number of teachers necessary has been reduced from three to one, and the former insufficient levy of 25 mills to 20 mills; this would have been reduced still further were it not for old debts. When these are paid off the levy will probably be re - duced to 10 mills. The enrollment has increased from H5 to i». G. H. PICKETT HITCHCOCK COUNTY. Seven school districts take advantage of the " Contract for the In - struction of Pupils in a Neighboring District " law. JAMES O'CONNELL. HOOKER COUNTY. Districts Nos. 1 and 3 have been consolidated with No. 2, and we are also uniting with No. 2 all unorganized territory, but this is a matter that has not been entirely accomplished, and we have not had any school under the new plan.* The consolidated district comprises 15 Cwnships (540 sections), with a school census of 125. Two teachers .11 be employed the ensuing year, instead of three as heretofore. L. H. BROWN •Note — I believe Hooker county and several other counties in Ne - braska might with profit be consolidated into one school district, the School District of County, with a board of six members, one central school carrying high school work, and as many outlying rural schools as might be necessary. — W. K. Fowler. KEITH COUNTY Districts Nos. 12 and 43 were united last year, forming a district of 42 sections. One teacher is employed, the tax levy has been reduced from 15 to 10 mills, and the enrollment and average daily attendance slightly increased. WESLEY TRESSLER KEYA PAHA COUNTY. tTwo districts were united, with a school census of 19. One teacher employed, the tax levy has been reduced from 25 to 15 mills, while enrollment has increased from 12 to 18 pupils, and the average daily endance, from 2 to 8 pupils. Rthis county we have 58 districts. It seems to me that these be consolidated so as to make 29. Last year I published two s on this subject without effect, as it seems every voter wants a schoolhouse within half a mile of his house. Considering the conditions in this county, it would, in my judgment, be better to divide the county into three districts, one in the east, one in the west and one in the center. Build three schoolhouses large enough and teach all the grades from the primary to the twelfth, also erect dormitories and boarding houses for </seg>
            <seg id="p021">20 the pupils, appoint matrons to care for them and not allow any pupil to attend under eight years of age. The same funds that run our present system would support the above. There would be no tardiness, no days absent, no dread of blizzards and no wet feet. I shall be glad at any time to support anything in the line of con solidation. JOHN SCHE1E LANCASTER COUNTY There has been no consolidation effected in this county, but we have one or two precincts where the people ought to bs interested, as they are remote from any high school. W. A. HA WES McPHERSON COUNTY. Our schools are so isolated that consolidation Is not practical. Schoolhouses are built where the settlements are. There are children in the county who have no school privileges, on acount of 'tih.tancas from the schoolhouses and not enough deeded land or other pr with which to run a school. There were two private or subscription schools in the county this past year, and some families moved to towns in adjoining counties for the purpose of sending their children to school. Some districts have two schoolhouses, and in one (No. 3, the Lemley district) school was taught in each school building at different times and some of the pupils were able to attend at both schoolhouses. thereby receiving nine months' schooling. Two-thirds of the county is yet unor - ganized into school districts. MRS. BLANCHE E. CLINi OTOE COTNTY. Etricts Ncs. 14, 15 and 1C were united with the Nebraska City district some years ago. Transportation is provided lor the flf - pils ol old No. 14 over one wagsn route six miles in length. R. C. KINC. PAWNEE COUNTY kWe have a number of small disLricts in Pawnee county which I k could, with advantage, be consolidated into, larger districts with transportation. Especially is this trua in the western and .south - western portions of the county. I hive talked consolidation in places where I thought it especially adapted and I intend to discuss it in our county school journal. I hope we may have consolidated schools in the not far distant future. J. C. WADDELL PERKINS COUNTY. t District No. 82 was annexed to No. 7 forming a district of 3G sec - i, with a school population of 23 and one teacher, although formerly one was required as instruction in a neighboring district had been Ided under section 4c, subdivision 5 of our school laws. A. SOFTLEY. </seg>
            <seg id="p022">21 in 1900 district No. 27 was united with district No. Tti (the Monroe school) forming a new district of about If square miles, with a school eaWMH of 195, requiring three teachers where previously three had beem employed. There is one wagon route about ZVz miles in length for IS children. The levy last year was 25 mills. The enrollment last year was 14:; and the average daily attendance 88. Before consolidation the enrollment was 20 and 82 in the two districts, a total of 102. and the average daily attendance was C3. But the town of Monroe has growa considerably since the consolidation was effected. L. H. I.EAVY RED WILLOW COUNTY. We have been making some progress in consolidation. District No. 59, with a valuation of JG.21G, and census of eight pupils has beea annexed to District No. C, the village of Lebanon. District No. 40. with a valuation of $G,455. census of nineteen pupils, has been annexed to district No. 70, the village of Bartley. Others are talking consolidation. EUGENE S. DITCHER. RICHARDSON COINTY. No consolidation is reported but districts Xos. \1 and M have closed their schools and contracted wit'i No. IT (the Humboldt school » uader the provisions of section 4c, subdivision o. tor the instruction of their pupils. One district maintains a wagon route about five miles in length and carries eight pupils. All patrons and pupils are well pleased with the plan. I think several districts will make similar contracts next GEO. CROCKER. SARPY COUNTY Ko school districts were united last winter at Ft. Crook. The con - ?d district comprises about five sections, with a school census of pils, and four teachers. The district is too new to make com- parisons ot the naw conditions with the previous ones. G. P. MILLER. SCOTTS BLUFF COUNTY. E Three school districts paid the ricts. One district has recently tuition of their pupils in adjoining been increased by the addition of CG sections of unorganized territory. Four dormant districts I without organization) have money ahead; two others are merely keeping up an organization in order to pay off their indebtedness, when they will unite with other districts. A number of our school districts are in favor of consolidation and are only waiting until things become a little better settled. I think in the next few years more can be done to get the county schools consolidated than ever again, for they are now making changes and talking plans for improving the school buildings, and after they once build it will be a difficult matter to effect the change. AGNES LACKEY. </seg>
            <seg id="p023">22 * b There has been no consolidation effected during the past year, le of those that consolidated one year ago or more are expressing siderable dissatisfaction. The entire number of school districts in the county is 107. Through the continual changing of our citizenship and new people coming in. it is likely that a number of the inactive dis - tricts will do business again soon. WALTER R. KENT. THIRSTON COUNTY. LLast year district No. 7 was discontinued and united to fractional trict No. Cl of Dakota, Dixon and Thurston counties. M. A. FENNELL. TORK COINTY tWe tried to effect consolidation in Arborville township two years —that is. we held two meetings — but the people were afraid of it we quit. Two or three of our smaller towns are doing some planning bat no definite steps have been taken. The town districts want to have surrounding districts unite and keep the school in town. I believe that It can be done — in time. ED C. BISHOP. </seg>
            <seg id="p024">SCHOOL DISTRICTS IN NEBRASKA SCHOOL oisinibis in neonftORn. ~ iii! z z z z z 1 z n Adams I 78 Antelope 113 Banner 38 I I j j 4 34 Blaine 15 1 I 1« Boone 80 1 81 Box Butte 62 I 4 j Boyd 78 ; 1 | 1 79 Brown 45 j 45 Buffalo 119 ' I U» Hurt 69 1 1 1 6S Butler 92 | j ' 9» Cass 101 1 101 Cedar I 80 | 1 | 81 Chase 62 | I-. | i 6J Cherry \ 72 I 1 ' I .... 71 Cheyenne | 96 ' j ! | 1 95 Clay I 78 | ! ! ! ' 71 Colfax 61 ! I ! I ' 61 Cuming | 78 | I | 1 78 Custer I 241 I I ' 2 \ 23» Dakota \ 38 ! | ' ! 31 Dawes | 92 1 1 1 1 1 91 Dawson I 89 I I I 89 Deuel | 65 ! I I 2 | 63 •&gt; Dixon I 80 ; I I ; 8« Dodge 83 M Douglas 63 63 Dundy 48 ! I | 49 Flllmore I 91 ! I , I | 91 Franklin 71 ' ' I I I 71 Frontier 109 ; j I I 1 10« Furnas i 103 I \ I 1 1 101 Gage 157 I | 2 | 15! I Garfleld I 25 j 1 1 25 Gosper 56 | j | ' 5C Grant 6 I '. t 6 Greeley | 58 ! 1 1 5« Hall j 73 I I 7J — \ Hamilton 98 &lt; | i I Harlan 81 ! 1 1 I -&lt;0 Hayes I 60 I ! 2 51 Hitchcock I 76 ] 1 1 1 7« Holt I 188 | 1 I I 187 Hooker I 6 | I I I 2 « Howard 71 j 1 1 71 Jefferson | 100 | | 1 | | | 101 </seg>
            <seg id="p025">county. * : 5sS: =5g tt 'SB ■ £ &gt;. i« •r. ■ocff: -o= It u&gt;,o r- 1 : &amp;i§ : »^c "^S « : Z Z g SC 35 Z I i Johnson I 79 | i I I I 79 Kearney | i | i C9 Keith I 43 I I I II 1 I 41 Keya Paha I 58 , I 58 Knox I 113 1 1 1 114 Lancaster | 138 I i ! 138 Lincoln ! 110 ! \ | ! llo McPhereon t 1 f I ; 8 N«nce I C3 ! I I I 05 N«ckolls 91 1 1 1 1 91 Otoe ; 102 , I I I 102 Pierce I C7 : 1 , I C7 Platte I 78 I I I | 78 Red Willow 83 ! I I I I 83 Richardson | 104 1 ! 104 Rock I 03 I 1 1 1 I I 02 Saline I 119 I i I \ 119 Saunders 114 I I I I I 114 Seotts Bluff j 28 I ' | 1 | | 27 Sheridan I 95 j I 7 I I 88 Sherman | 74 | | I | 74 «o« I 25 I I | ' 25 «»nton I 55 I I I I I 55 Thayer i 98 j I I I 98 Thomas I 5 1 | | 5 Thurston 22 1 1 l 22 Valley , 03 , C3 Washington | 55 | | | | 55 W*^ I 80 I I 2 1 i 82 W«*ter 79 79 Wheeler I 35 i I I 35 York | 102 1 i i i 102 Totals j CC66 2 14 \ 23 I 17 I 6642 </seg>
            <seg id="p026">1899 6705 1901 6675 1870 797 1875 2405 1880 3132 1885 42CC 1890 C243 1891 6417 1893 6630 1894 CC41 1895 6C93 189C 6731 1897 6741 </seg>
            <seg id="p027">A Detailed Statement of the Number and Distribution of the Small Rural School* in Nebraska, 1901. THE PROBLEM: WANTED— A SOLUTION I: ii rpn h ■32 : -2 «*- «"» o x COUNTY. gS SB |B : g|| g» gs SB : g| — isS §S §1 11 : § 83 §° u a - a 5 1 1 14 22 Adams i Antelope I 27 35 1 A I 9 4 0 Banner 1 4 2 1 Blaine 25 Boone 2 18 12 25 13 2 Box Butte Boyd 1 12 19 3 17 11 1 Brown Buffalo I 6 18 44 26 Burt 1 10 22 20 Butler | 2 11 16 32 Cass * 20 25 Cedar 5 14 16 14 Chime I 11 22 9 | 2 Cherry | 5 26 14 8 25 27 10 5 Cheyenne I 25 27 16 5 Clay 2 3 21 21 Colfax 2 2 12 20 Colfax Cuming 1 10 20 20 82 70 35 19 0 4 17 4 20 13 C 16 0 14 23 15 15 24 5 7 1 21 19 24 0 29 21 1 4 14 9 8 19 10 5 Fillmore II 11 17 19 Franklin 20 14 1 frontier 6 30 33 24 Furnas 9 10 39 21 Gage I 3 22 55 37 Garfleld [ 2 I 11 5 | S Gosper I 4 15 19 10 Grant 0 3 1 0 Greeley | 6 19 15 5 Hall I 2 I 6 I 20 11 Hamilton I 2 11 33 20 Harlan I 2 I 21 24 16 Hayes I 9 15. | 13 | 9 Hitchcock I 11 34 16 6 Holt | 58 66 t 29 | 14 luster lakota lawes &gt;awson teuel rtxon - lodge kniglas lundy </seg>
            <seg id="p028">• c &gt; m Si hi III U %1\U: H': - 5 * COUNTY T. «« • g B ■ r = • Hooker ' 1 • 1 • Howard 1 12 | 15 20 Jefferson I 2 16 30 IT Johnson ! 0 10 23 18 Kearney I 7 22 14 22 Keith 15 ■» I Keya Paha | 5 24 16 3 Kimball I 7 4 1 1 Knox '■ 6 22 34 25 Lancaster 1 5 6 32 ■ Lincoln i 17 30 25 10 Logan I 3 I S Loup : 1 9 4 2 Madison \ 0 14 20 28 McPherson ! I I I 2 0 Merrick ' 4 8 13 IS Nance 6 18 I 21 11 Nemaha 0 7 25 16 Nuckolls 5 19 19 20 Otoe 4 19 34 18 Perkins I 31 14 4 22 Phelps 3 7 30 15 Pierce 16 22 15 30 IS rmw 1 ■ *« -- *«» Platte ! 5 8 . 22 20 o Polk 0 1 6 18 20 Red Willow I 9 23 18 14 Richardson 1 10 24 30 Rock I 10 21 13 1 Saline ! 1 11 32 27 Sarpy I 14 1 7 Saunders 0 8 19 37 Scotts Bluff 3 5 3 5 Seward I 2 14 32 15 Sheridan 18 39 18 7 Sherman 5 21 21 11 Sioux 4 9 I 5 S Stanton 2 13 15 11 Thayer 4 13 27 18 Thomas 0 0 0 3 Valley I 2 18 20 8 Washington 0 4 9 21 Wayne 1 19 30 IS Webster •••:-l 0 | 11 1 25 i 19 Wheeler '. . 12 I 8 4 1 Yori &lt; 1 13 24 30 I 1' Totals [ 489 1352 | 1687 | 1243 </seg>
            <seg id="p029">■ These statistics are taken from the annual report of the &lt;;&gt;unty superintendents of Nebraska ior the school year LMt-lML Tli y show that the small schools are greater in number than most of us knew. There are 489 schools with an average daily attendance of flw or 1,841 with ten or less; 3.528 with fllteen or less: 4,771 with twenty or There are about G.300 strictly rural school districts in Nebraska. This makes nearly three-lourths of our rural schools in each of which is an average daily attendance too small for vigorous, interesting and profit - able work, either educationally and socially or financially. No time need be spent in rehearsing these lacts. No school can claim conditions lor good work il it have less than twenty-five pupils-; yet there are 4 771 rural schools in Nebraska in operation with an average daily attendance ranging from one to twenty pupils. I believe we are all ready to unite upon this proposition — the pupils in these small rural schools must lie collected into larger and better schools with better teachers, better paid. ■ It does not matter how much we deplore the condition which makes consolidation of schools necessary, the fact remains that it is the only rational solution of the question that has been offered." THE EMERSON CONSOLIDATED SCHOOL DISTRICT. Prhis consolidated school district was iormed, by petition, in the ig ol 1902, uniting district No. 7 of Thurston caunty with fractional ict No. 01 ol Dakota and Dixon countiss. The consolidated district ists ol 23 sections in Thurston county, 5% sections in Dixon county ■'Ctions in Dakota county. Old district No. 7 of Thurston county contained three schoolhouses poorly located. These were moved to new locations and two new school •uiluings were erected. No bonds were issued nor was any extra tax levy neceaaar? lor this purpose. The tax levy in old district No. 7 of Thurston county had be .i mills for a number of years. The tax levy in district No. Cl belore the consolidation had been 25 mills lor two years, or since the number of saloon!- in Emerson was reduced. The tax levy in the new consolidated district No. Cl is now 25 mills, and three saloons pay $o:n) license each. The real estate in Thurston county, being Indian reservation land, is not taxable. The valuations on personal property are much higher in Thurs - t county than in Dakota and Dixon counties, or, at any rate, more aal property is assessed in Thurston county than in the other coun - ties. A shortage of neaily $1,000 existed lor the past school year, •wing to the larga expenditures for buildings and new books. If the tax levy is kept at 2b miils. the revenue for next year will be amply suffl- Ee have one central school building, including a high school at on, and five rural schoolhouses. In all of these schools we mity of textbooks and course of study. No work above the eighth grade is permitted in any of the rural schools. All high school work is done in the central building in Emerson. T'.ie superintendent riiitl </seg>
            <seg id="p030">■ rural schools once each month, and all teachers are required to meet with the superintendent once each month. E. h. McMillan THE POWELL CONSOLIDATED SCHOOL DISTRICT. Two school districts were consolidated at Powell, in Jefferson county, Nebraska, in the spring of 1902. The consolidated district comprises ten and eleven-sixteenths square miles. During the school year ihout thirty children were transported at an expense of J198 for the nine months. The total enrollment was 87 pupils, with an average attendance of 51. The total number of children of school age was 90. During the last year before consolidation the total enrollment in the two districts was C4. with an average attendance of 43. I'nder consolidation there were fewer cases of tardiness and more regular attendance. The cost ol maintenance during the first year under consolidation was some - what Increased, but the teachers' salaries were raised ten dollars a month each, and tha school is now better equipped in every respect. County Superintendent F. A. Carmony and Principal C. W. Samms both speak of the plnn in the highest terms and say it is a success in every particular. A RURAL HIGH SCHOOL. Kuskin is the high school of a consolidated school district in Jackson county. Missouri. Four common school districts united to form the pres - ent district. The formation was made April, 1902. The district is about five and one-halt miles square and lies in a practically level country, mainly agricultural. Tha present enumeration for the entire system of schools is 3_J, an increase of CO pupils since its formation. The enrollment in the high school last year amounted to about thirty pupils for the entire year. The averag-a daily attendance, notwithstanding the severest winter lor travel we have had for ten years, is in excess of the average for the entire county, including the village and town schools. Pupils furnish their own conveyances, riding or driving a distance of one to five miles. The school has been highly satisfactory and has stimulated a most commendable pride in the rural schools of that section. Not only is interest taken in the high school, its property and environment, but equal interest has been aroused in the several grammar grade schools. Money is willingly and judiciously expended to make the schools better. Yards are kept in good condition — all yards were previously provided with shade except the high school. One hundred fifty tress were planted here Arbor Day under the direction of a landscape gardener employed for that purpose; the yard includes four acres. Another year an additional teachsr will be added, after which three years" high school work will be carried. When the second teacher is engaged the eighth grade will also be taken from the other schools, giv - ing each high school teacher two grades in addition to relieving the </seg>
            <seg id="p031">30 The board is thoroughly imbued with the idea of making the school distinctively rural in its course of study. It expects as fast as the change can be made to teach the elements of agriculture, introducing it into the other schools in the nature of observation work. There is a strong sentiment in the district in favor of centralization of the five schools and transporting the pupils at public expense. It iB probable the General Assembly at its next session will enact such a law. If it does there is little doubt that this caunty will have at least one centralized school, with pupils transporte;!. within three years. Nor does the one district represent all the sentiment in favor of con - solidation in the county. Other places have tried but have failed thus far to carry it. They will continue to try and their success in the near future is practically assured. \V. H. JOHNSON. Independence, Mo. RURAL SCHOOL CONSOLIDATION. W. M. Hayes. Professor of Agriculture, University of Minnesota. The writer recently made a two days' trip into the country south of Andover, Ashtabula county. Ohio, to study the problem of rural school consolidation. One object was to learn more about the relation of con - solidation of schools and the problem of introducing into such schools studies relating to agriculture, rural home making, and country life. Four consolidated schools were visited and on the whole the plan seemed to be a material improvement. The evidence strong that the minority who at first objected to consolidation of schools are gradu - ally being converted to the new system. The cost to the township is higher than formerly, but the cost per student in daily attendance is less. There is more schooling secured, because there is more regularity in attendance, less tardiness, and the pupils remain in school a greater num - ber of years. The expense to the farmers is less than in sending their children away from home for studies of a high school grade. The teach - ing is more effective, because of better superintendence, better grading of work, and more concentration and specialization on the part of teachers. townships are five miles square, and in three of the four places ited, the school is located at the cross roads, at or near the center of the township. Usually near the consolidated school one finds a country store, a blacksmith shop, and a post-office. The fourth place visited was a village of 1,500 inhabitants. The village school district includes a few square miles of surrounding country. The country people have built their separate school at one end of the village. In this case the move - ment to consolidate with the village school failed to pass the vote at the county election. These townships are in a district of heavy clay soil and the roads are at times very muddy. Though well graded, they are not graveled. One school proposes to have a vacation of one month in the spring until the roads are dry Ordinarily, one school van is required for each original </seg>
            <seg id="p032">31 nine school vans, or "kid wagons" as the people call them. Each of the owners of vans receives for service nearly the same salary as a grade teacher, or thirty dollars per month. The salary of the van owner varies with the distance traveled and the character of the roads on the respec - tive routes. The vans are plain, light farm wagons with a band wagon box. They are provided with top and side curtains. The children are better cared for than where they must take long walks to school. The pupils can dress to keep out the cold and parents know that their children are taken directly to school. The driver sits on a stool inside the van and keeps good order. The schoolhouses are two-story wooden or brick buildings with four or five rooms, costing $4,500.00 to $G,000.00 each. High basement rooms are provided in which the children can play. Each school is provided with two or three acres of ground. The play grounds have been well graded. No trees have as yet been planted. Very little is being done in decorating the grounds with ornamental shrubbery. The rooms in the lower story are used for pupils doing graded work, and the rooms in the upper story are used for pupils doing high school work. The course of study is quite general. The sciences, such as chem - istry, physics, and botany are lightly touched upon. The principals in these schools receive $65.00 to $80.00 per month; assistant principals, $35.00; and other teachers, $30.00. Though the soil is generally good, the country beautiful and well improved, many of the vigorous farm boys are leaving the farm for the cities. The schools were doing more to accelerate this exodus than to instill into the pupils an appreciation of the industrial and other possibilities of their truly beautiful country. In private conversation, or with chalk in hand, before the high school pupils the writer assisted the principals in mapping out possible ten acre school farms beside these schools. These plans usually included a modest cottage for the principal, possibly with a room so equipped that his wife could teach classes in sewing and cooking. A small stable was planned for at least a cow and a few pigs. Nearby was to be built a chicken house. Play grounds were surrounded by different varieties of trees and shrubs. A small area in front of the schoolhouse was de - signed for an ornamental lawn. A small orchard was planned where could be planted one or more trees of numerous varieties of apples, peaches, and other fruits. The proposed garden plot contained space for growing vegetables and small fruits and places for cold frames in which to start early plants. Nearly half the land was divided up into half acre plots for field crops. The principals, teachers, and pupils seemed interested in the general plan of school grounds outlined, and in many of the special features which were woven into a scheme to connect the work of the school with their home interests. The writer, in studying the point of view of these teachers and pupils, was impressed with the belief that this general line </seg>
            <seg id="p033">■ An argument for preserving the identity of the rural schools: Let the city schools work more toward the city industries and let the country schools emphasize country industries. This work, once it is properly or - ganized, will soon become more interesting than some of the studies of the common branches. But it has been proven that this kind of work has in many cases assisted the pupils in their general scholarship. In these townships a "sugar bush" is found on every farm, along highways and streams. The hard maple is found in rows, in groups, and growing singly. Other trees, including clumps of grand evergreens, are growing about the old farmsteads. Not even in the scenes of au - tumnal colorings in Minnesota has the writer seen such beauty. Land sells from $25.00 to $40.00 per acre in this region. The normal value is nearly double these prices. The people are seeking city life, and the schools are helping to educate them for city life, rather than to train them for making the most of this most beautiful country. — School Education. Minneapolis. </seg>
            <seg id="p034">O ■■I H cr 9 3 o 3" </seg>
            <seg id="p035">I ■■' \ </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>