<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI.2 id="npd.00045.00019">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nebraska Public Documents Project</title>
            <author/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>University of Nebraska Center for Digital Research in the
                            Humanities</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Lincoln, NE</pubPlace>
            <idno>00045.00019</idno>
            <availability>
               <p> </p>
            </availability>
            <date>2007</date>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title>A Dozen Hens in the Back Yard</title>
               <date value="1918-10">1918-10</date>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2007-09-17</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>Paul Fajman</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Enrichment</item>
         </change>
         <change>
            <date>2006-11-28-05:00</date>
            <respStmt>
               <name>OCLC Online Computer Library Center Inc.</name>
            </respStmt>
            <item>Initial Creation</item>
         </change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>
            <seg id="p001">Extension Bulletin 49 Reprinted October. 1916 A Dozen Hens in the Back Yard F. E. MU8SEHL A Model Back-Yard Poultry House THE UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA COLLEGE OF AGRICULTURE EXTENSION SERVICE LINCOLN U. S. DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE COOPERATING </seg>
            <seg id="p002">t I iculture University of Nebraska College of Agriculture THE EXTENSION SERVICE THE GOVERNING BOARD (The Regents of the University) Honorable E. P. Brown, President, Davey Honobarle J. E. Miller, Vire President, Lincoln Honorable Frank L. Haller, Omaha Honorable Victor G. Lyford, Falls City Honorable Philip L. Hall, Lincoln Honorable Harry D. Landis, Seward THE UNIVERSITY OFFICERS * Samuel Avery, Ph. D., LL. D., Chancello W. G. Hastings, A. B., Aiting Chancellor J S. Dales, M. Ph., Financial Secretary EXTENSION EXECUTIVE STAFF Chas. E. Gunnels, B. So Director R. E. Holland, B. Sc. County Agent Leadei Lew T. Skinner, B. Sc, Secretary Mrs. Emma Reed Davisson Home Demonstration Lcat C. A. Lewis, B. Sc, Agricultural Editor C. W. Watson, A. M., Junior Extension Lett THE EXTENSION COUNCIL E. A. Burnett, I). Sc.,J)ean Lawrence Bruner, D. Sc. Chas. E. Gunnels, B. S&amp;\, Director Entomology F. W. Upson, Ph. D., Agricultural Chemistry *L. W. Chase, M. E., A. E., Agricultural Engineering W. W. Burr, B. Sc, Agronomy R. F. Howard, A. M., Horticulture H. J. Gramlich, B. Sc, Animal Husbandry L. Van Es, M. D., V. S., G. A. Lovelani), A. M., Meteorology E. Mead Wilcox, Ph. D., Animal Pathology and Hygiene Plant Pathology J. H. Gain, M. D. C. Animal Pathology F. E. MUSSEHL, B. Sc, Poultry Husbandry J. H. Frandsen, M. S. A., Dairy Husbandry H. E. Bradford, A. M . Principal, Srhool of Agr 'Absent on leave. E. A. BURNETT, D. Sc, College of Agriculture; Director, Expe Station H. C. FlLLEY, A. M., Farm Management Alice M. Loomis, a. M.. Home Economic* </seg>
            <seg id="p003">A DOZEN HENS IN THE BACK YARD A business man living in a small town in western Nebraska decided last spring to keep a few hens in the back yard for the purpose of supplying his own table with eggs. Being a good business man, he kept an account of the feed cost and of the eggs produced by his hens. He admits some surprise at finding that his strictly fresh eggs were costing only about sixteen cents per dozen. With good management back-yard poultry keeping is profitable, because considerable material from the kitchen, garden and lawn can be utilized for poultry feeding. The original investment is slight and labor is not an expensive item. A flock of a dozen hens will supply the average house - hold with plenty of fresh eggs, with some to spare at certain times of the year. The essentials for successful back-yard poultry keeping are healthy, vigorous birds, a comfortable but not necessarily expensive house, and sensible feeding prac - tice. HOW TO START There are two possible ways of starting the back-yard flock. A start may be made with baby chicks in the spring or with well-developed pullets in the fall. Unless one has had some previous experience in raising baby chicks and unless quite a bit of space is available for a range, starting with nearly matured pullets is more desirable. If a dozen well-matured pullets of a practical, standard bred variety can be secured in the fall from a poultry breeder or general farmer who has the advantage of free range for raising his stock, a practical start in profitable poultry keeping will have been made. These birds should be kept for one year, this being their period of most economical egg production, after which they may best be used to furnish the "big end" of an occa - sional dinner, thus helping to conserve more of the red meats, pork and beef, for our Army and Navy. After a year's serv - ice in the laying flock, birds of the American and English </seg>
            <seg id="p004">4 Extension Bulletin No. A9, College of Agriculture classes (Plymouth Rocks, Rhode Island Reds, Wyandottes and Orpingtons) will be worth almost as much for meat as was originally paid for them. OPPORTUNITIES FOR THE BACK-YARD POULTRY BREEDER Poultry keepers who are fortunate enough to have several lots available for poultry keeping often develop quite an in - come from the sale of breeding stock, especially cockerels, to farmers and other poultry keepers. More space is needed where young stock is raised than where only mature hens are kept and more difficulty is encountered in raising young chicks, than in feeding mature birds, but many city poultry keepers are raising chicks very successfully. Fig. 1.— This hen laid 198 eggs in 365 days. She typifies the vigor, strength and capacity which are essential for high egg production. The selection of a good practical variety that is already well popularized is the first step in successful poultry breeding. Selection of stock for uniformity and conformance with stand - ard requirements as well as for increased egg production will popularize your particular strain with poultry keepers who are in need of breeding stock. </seg>
            <seg id="p005">A Dozen Hens in the Back Yard o THE HOUSE A house six by eight feet, or eight by eight feet, floor dimensions, is large enough for a dozen hens. Perhaps there is an old barn or woodshed on the premises that can be re - modeled into comfortable quarters for the flock. The essen - tial qualities which make a house comfortable for the hen are dryness, adequate ventilation without drafts, and plenty of congenial sunlight. The house should face the south so that more sun will be available during the winter months. The fixtures for the interior of the house should consist of a dropping board, three nest boxes about 14 inches square, and a shelf or stand raised about 18 inches above the floor on which to place the water pan, grit and shell, and dry mash hopper. FEEDS AND FEEDING PRACTICE All the kitchen, garden, and lawn refuse that is at all adapted should be used for feeding the back-yard flock, but other feeds will be needed in addition. Back-yard poultry keeping should not be made an excuse for careless manage - ment in the kitchen, but should supplement our present efforts to utilize all possible resources for food production. Small ¥\g. 2 — Cross-section plan of a back-yard poultry house. </seg>
            <seg id="p006">6 Extension Bulletin No. U9, College of Agricultun Fig. 3 — Floor plan of a back-yard poultry house, showing location of equipment. </seg>
            <seg id="p007">A Dozen Hens in the Back Yard i potatoes and even potato peelings when cooked, lettuce leaves, celery leaves, beet tops, lawn clippings and miscellaneous table scraps that cannot be used in any other way may con - stitute part of the ration for the flock of a dozen hens. Some animal feed such as commercial meat scrap, green cut bone, skim milk or buttermilk should also be included in the ration. The hen is a meat eater and will not do her best unless some animal feed is given. A practical and economical poultry ration can be built up around a well-balanced dry mash. This is a mixture of ground grains and by-products. Besides the dry mash some feed in a coarser form should be fed in a litter of leaves or straw so that the hens will have to exercise. Exercise is essential to keep the hens in vigorous health. The laying hen must be a healthy one. The following rations and feeding practice are suggested. If other feeds are more easily available they may be substi - tuted for some of those given in these rations. Wheat is purposely left out of this ration as a war measure, but wheat by-products are used in the mash. Hens will lay well on a "wheatless" ration but they cannot produce many eggs on a "meatless" ration. Dry Mash (Parts by weight) 2 parts corn meal. 2 parts shorts. 1 part ground oats. 1 part meat scrap. Before hens at all times in Small Hopper Oyster shell. Grit. Before hens at all times. Green Feed Sprouted oats, cabbage, mangels or beets, lawn clippings in summer and dried lawn clippings for winter feeding. For win - ter use the lawn clippings may be moistened with hot water. a box or hopper. Scratch Feed 2 parts cracked corn. 1 part oats, barley, kafir, or a mixture of these grains. A great many feed dealers are now making dry mash and scratch feed mixtures for poultry. When these can be secured at a reasonable price they are just as satisfactory as home mixed feeds and the disadvantage of buying small amounts </seg>
            <seg id="p008">Extension Bulletin No. 49, College of Agriculture 8 of each of the feeds used in the mash and scratch mixtures is overcome. Insist on a liberal percentage of clean animal protein (15 to 20 per cent) when ready-mixed mashes are used. The disadvantage of buying poultry feeds in small quanti - ties at relatively higher prices may easily be overcome by com - munity co-operation in buying feeds. It is suggested that quotations on mixed feeds, both mash and scratch, in ton lots be secured from feed dealers and that ten or twelve poultry keepers in each community co-operate when buying their poultry feeds. FEEDING OUTLINE I. When to feed — How often : Two or three times a day when birds are confined. Reason : To keep them exercising. II. How to feed : 1. Evening feed — Scratch feed made by mixing several whole grains and coarsely cracked corn, thrown into deep litter. Enough so hens can go to roost with full crops. 2. Morning feed — Half as much scratch feed as in eve - ning, thrown into the litter when chicken house door closed in the evening after hens have gone to roost. Supply fresh water first thing in morning. 3. Noon feed — Mash moistened to a crumbly consist - ency with skim milk or buttermilk or, if these are not available, with water. May contain cooked potato peelings, cooked grains as oats or barley. Ill How much to feed : It is estimated that hens which are kept confined will eat from 70 to 90 pounds of grain and mash in a year. The small breeds such as Leghorns will eat the smaller amount. This means that each hen will eat three to four ounces a day. Good feeding prac - tice consists in feeding about equal amounts of dry mash and scratch feed. Then a dozen hens would eat about I 1 - pounds each of grain and mash each day. A quart of the mash mixture will weigh ap- </seg>
            <seg id="p009">.4 Dozen Hens in the Back Yard 9 proximately 1 V-&gt; pounds. One quart of the dry maah and one quart of the whole grain ration would be enough to feed a dozen hens about one day. The skillful feeder is not, however, guided in the amount given by any definite rule but rather by the appetite and inclination of the birds. The more the hens can be made to eat and still keep in good laying condition, the greater the surplus of food material available for egg production. The above suggestions, therefore, are given until the caretaker has acquired feeding ex - perience of his own. ig. 4. — Sectional view of dry mai ;h hopper. HOW TO CONTROL MITES AND LICE Lice and mites are the two most troublesome poultry para - sites. Lice are biting insects which live on the hen's body. To control lice, dust with a commercial louse powder or make a powder according to the following formula : Mix thoroly one part of a coal-tar disinfectant (such as zenoleum, creosote, creolin, etc.) with four parts of gasoline. Add plaster of Paris to this until all the solution is absorbed, then spread the mixture on a board or newspaper to dry, away from the direct sunlight. Dust this powder thoroly over </seg>
            <seg id="p010">10 Extension Bulletin No. k9, College of Agnculture the body of each bird, particularly around the fluff. Powdered sodium fluoride is also recommended, this chemical being used in smaller amounts than the coal-tar, plaster-of-Paris powder, first mentioned. Mites are the little spider-like parasites that live in the cracks and crevices of the roosts and walls and come out to feed on the hens at night. These parasites can very easily ba controlled by spraying the roosts with a mixture of one part of a coal-tar disinfectant and four parts of kerosene. The liberal use of a two or three per cent solution of coal - tar disinfectant about the poultry house after cleaning will aid in keeping it sanitary and comfortable for the hen*. The hen is naturally a clean animal and will repay efforts in this direction by producing more eggs. Cleanly practice about the poultry yard will also make poultry keeping more popular with neighbor!. Where dropping boards are used, the droppings should be removed dally, Poultry dropping! arc very useful as a gar - den and lawn fertilizer and much of this by-product can be put to good une in this way. If possible it is well to alter • nate the poultry yard and garden every other year. With a portable house this Is easily possible. ImlrliiKil In I'rnf I W, WJligllli f.rr till. rhflMlnua III till* I* IAMI </seg>
            <seg id="p011">.4 Dozen HfHM in the Back Yard 11 llUJf.'l tfunli-ii than u A DOZKN (JOO1) HKNS Will lay an average of 150 egg* each per year Will lay h total of 1,800 per year. Will fiit ulioiit |M(i pound* of wratch IV.-.I Will eat about 4M0 poundit of manh feed (made of by-product* ). Will need leM of the above feeds, however, If and table ncrapn arc wlwly uacd. A doMn good hen« will return a better profit large flock of ncrubu, </seg>
            <seg id="p012">&lt;«i k h'.iliHHlini Ihilhlm \n, ////, ('iillrfji 1 of Afjrlnillini \'l tut** t't ¥h\ TO *¥,W » HIIHKM IN (OHM Horn In thw rm'uni n( tm* N*lirn*kH IimU ynn\ M&lt;« !• TwkIv« HUndNrd t/rwi H«*n» of m bmdHO'lNy »ir«ln ToiMl firvtf InM from Jumk ito, MH7, to Jun«* St/&gt;, N«l |)rortl t\" i. Thi« «««■!» MwrHiriul 1 7ft ««(» p«r l»lr&lt;l for th« y««r l»l»»»liMH;i in ""iiwrftii" &lt;;( iinKllte »*f|iiiiiiimi f&gt;ixit«iwn mnik A L"'lll?." u "f A Mf""/ (( "* »«« ' » ••••I'K'IKIOWI »r ♦kH.mII.K* .Hf.llJ.MIII.tf J1 F Itll.lN'.ll, MU*"l#f I ii in |,|&lt;M Vm\ viml MA | </seg>
         </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI.2>